<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00013.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00013.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION</title>
               <date value="1904">1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION J. I. WYEH, Jr.. President. Librarian I'mv-kksiiy op Nebraska. E. BENJ. ANDREWS, CHAMUELLOR OB- THE CSIVIKSITY OF NEBRASKA. W. K. FOWLEH, State Sdperintendhut of- Public Instruotiom. H. O. LINDSAY, State Lieiharian. T\ L. HALLGS, Omaha Pi-blic Library. EDNA D. BULLOCK, Secretary. LINCOLN. NOVEMBER 3O. 19O4 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Lincoln, November 30, 1904. t Excellency, John H. Mickey, Governor of Nebraska: Complying with a requirement of the law creating this Commission, I have the honor to present herewith the second biennial report of the Nebraska • Library Commission, covering the two years ending November 30, 1904. As the Department of Public Instruction supervises, directs, and counsels the schools of Nebraska, so the Public Library Commission is concerned with avelopment and highest efficiency of that other great branch of edu - i carried on in the ! cfa centers in the Library, and which chiefly means the printed l&gt;ook. To make u . clean, useful hooks more abound in Nebraska, especially in the remoter parts of the stat&lt;\ matter of our special care. Ke following report by our secretary and active executive officer, which ;s our work with some minuteness, is heartily commended t' as indicating the scope and nature of our activities and the C tn they have met in all parts of the state. truly. T. T. WYF.R, Jr., President Nebraska Public Library Commission. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">I V </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">The Nebraska Public Library Commission. This Commission, having been in existence •barely three years, finds the library movement in the state largely centered in the work of this office. It will be shown that all that was needed to quicken into life a multitude of library centers was some central bureau where information might be ol" and help given. This has been the work given into the care of this Co:: sion, and this brief record of progress will surely gratify all who realize that, magnificent as is the material record of the state in the past two year best index to the real life of the commonwealth is written in the amb of her people for higher things, and the educational facilities at the command of the humblest and remotest of her citizens. Our splendid public schools, our state Normal school, our University, are our just pride, but these schools, beyond the intermediate grades, are, after all, for the few, and for limited Is. Our first rank for low percentage of illiteracy must be maintained, and we must not stop there — Nebraska must place the means of continued education within the reach of all her people, and must see to it that the eager to improve their opportunities. Ethe fine educational showing made by the state at the St Louis expo - the library was given next place to the schools as a factor in the 1 culture of the state. No one who saw the exhibit there made by ission could fail to see that the public library has become a di-' of the educational development of the state. Some idea of the awak - that promises to elevate the library to its proper co-ordinate place with 100I may be gained from the records of this office. Meetings of the Commission. During the biennial period covered by this report, the Commission has held three meetings for the transaction of routine business. The old officers were re-elected, and in October, 1903, Miss Daisy I. Lutz, of Blair, Neb., was elected to assist in the work of the office, it having grown to such proportions that the Secretary could no longer attend to the office routine and satisfac - torily administer the larger affairs of the Commission. The executive work is left almost wholly to the Secretary, who makes full reports of all work done and all important moves in contemplation to the members of the Com - mission, and secures their approval and co-operation. Much of the individual time and sincere effort of the members is devoted to the details of the work, and to this strong personal interest in the extra trust imposed by law upon them is due, in a large measure, the abundant and apparent success of the work undertaken. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">4 The legislature of 1903 appropriated $6,000 for this Commission. This sum, while not so much as was asked for, has enabled the Commission to live, and to accomplish results quite beyond all reasonable expectations. A number of desirable lines of work can not be undertaken until a larger ap - propriation makes more travel, more books and equipment, and more office room and assistance possible. By the practice of economy, the amount ap - propriated has been made to maintain the work undertaken in a creditable state of efficiency. The business of the office continually increases along lines that can not fail to prove a benefit to the cause of education in the state. The Commission only waits the increase in resources to extend the benefits still further. Library Extension Ehe most important feature of the work is that of "encouraging the ishmcnt of libraries where none exist 1 ' — a task enjoined by law and than justified by the results. Appreciable progress toward a universal a of public libraries for our state has been made ; but it is only a mition of what is before us. The Massachusetts library commission can proudly point to the results of fourteen years' work — for no resident of Massachusetts to-day can live away from the library's sphere of influence; no child in all that common - wealth but is entitled to library privileges, and may continue his education throughout life. Nebraska — with no crowded, smoke begrimed cities, with wide sweeps of virgin soil, with great undeveloped resources and limitless aspirations, has said to this Commission :— "Encourage the founding of libra - ries where none exist," to the end that some proud day, we, too, may be able to tell the world that nowhere within our borders could be found a man or woman whose thirst for helpful and useful books could not be, in a I ure, gratified. In so grand a work, we are able to say with confidence that a beginning has been made. Not only have a number of places, under the guidance of the Commission, established libraries during the biennium, but many more have been set to thinking. Little libraries in Sterling, Talmage, Randolph, Waterloo, Pender, DeWitt, Wisner, Carroll, Winside, and Ashland have Einto being in response to the popular movement which has been fos - by the Commission and participated in by the state Federation of i's clubs and other organizations. Similar projects are in contempla - tion at Oxford, St Paul, Clarks, Havelock, Neligh, Fullerton, and many other places. To all such places literature has been sent, hundreds of letters have been written, visits have been made by the Secretary, and every pos - sible encouragement given. Audiences have been addressed, influential citi - zens have been appealed to — and never, in the end, without result. The near future is bound to witness a library epidemic in the villages of 800 in popu - lation. Since an increase in the assessment roll of a village will give the library greater possibility of revenue, many villages will see the way to estab- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">5 for a two-mill levy in the a\ liraska village will bring in money— merely enough to keep the library aliv&lt; philanthropy the task of enabling it to grow. Every town in the state having a populati library supported by taxation, and a library building— in of Mr. Carnegie, or of some former citizens, and in one case the bin 'aid for l&gt;y local subscriptions. Then cities 1km MOO in population, and four of these have flourishing public Itbrai I fifth one h.i V. M. C. A. library. Of Id towns having o\ d less than 3,000 population, only 13 have public libraries an. ve association librari k Obviously, this Commission has a great work before it, and t 1 Ay in laying foundations for future libraries by educating the people to the library idea. This work, of note is with the schools. School Libraries If Nebraska children are accu wisely administered collections of 1m pabik, school, or home librarie! tomed to the use of m nks at school, the future of librar is assured. The citizen of to-day ma Ejle to get on somehow without the help or companionship of 1 hall take care that the citizen of to-morrow, having found is help and companionship, will regard books as an imperative equip - town, sc1kk)1, and home. tour work with schools, we have had constantly in mind the d by Meivil Dewey at the second international in 1S97. Mr. Dewey said : "It is almost within our memory that we have conn ment that the state owes an elementary education to every boy and girl « its limits : not alone as a right to the child, but as a matter of - practical wisdom on the part of the state. And this broader concept! followed closely by a second and broader one, that every boy and girl is entitled not only to an elementary education, but to something high have met no competent student of the subject who dares deny that her the state must recognize that education is not alone for the young, for lii s, in schools which take all of the time of their pupils, but must r adults as well ; and not alone for short courses, but all through life—: our recognized teaching institutions alone, but in that study outside of or working hours that may be carried on at home. I may sum it up : sentence : Higher education for adults at home, through life. In this education, which must hereafter Ik- recognized side by side with school Bthe library is the great central extension teaching, mo agent round which study club and the other allied A forward movement alor.. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">6 school districts to possess any books aside from text-books, our work has been truly pioneer work. We have endeavored to reach every one of the 6,666 school districts of the state with the suggestion that a school library be started, that only good books be selected, that reasonable prices be paid to reputable dealers, and that intelligent use be made of the books for the benefit of the whole community surrounding the school. Library Day. EK detailed program for Library day, October 23, 1903, was prepared and from this office to county superintendents for every teacher in the state. Library day in 1904, a similar program was prepared by the Secretary printed in the "Nebraska Teacher," while letters from this office called Mention of county and town superintendents to it List of Books. A graded list of about 500 titles recommended for school libraries was compiled by the Secretary, and printed, with directions for the economical purchase of the books. Copies of the list were distributed to county and city superintendents for their teachers. It is not uncommon for a teacher to write to this office telling how much money is available to spend for library books and asking the Secretary to select the books. Some county superin - tendents have instructed their teachers not to purchase library books without king this Commission. We have made every effort to protect the dis - tricts from the fraudulent book concerns that so frequently beguile district fathers into paying five prices for worthless books. Some gain has been made in this direction, but much remains to be done. There is no adequate way of ascertaining how many school district libra - ries there are in Nebraska, how many books they contain, or how much money is being spent. Replies received from questions sent to over 400 county and city superintendents indicate that considerably less than half of the districts have any libraries at all, but that the aggregate sum spent last year for school library books must run up into thousands of dollars. This money is largely the result of entertainments, box suppers, commencements, and gifts, occasionally supplemented from the school treasury. It is not unusual for a single entertainment in a rural school to bring from $20 to $50. Responses from 14 county superintendents who were able to give definite estimates of money expended for school libraries show that in those 14 coun - ties over $6,000 is known to have been spent last year. Many other counties report considerable money spent, but are unable to give estimates of the amount. The schools of Richardson county spent over $1,700 on school libra - ries last year. That is the banner county as to per cent of districts having school libraries, 98 districts out of 104 having a start in that direction. Paw - nee and Gage counties report an average of over $5 per district spent on school libraries last year, while Butler county reports an average of $10 for </seg>
            <seg id="p009">7 report nearly $ ,ir for library books. It should be remem ed that the rural or village school library is quite different in character ! in the cities having good public libraries. Where :re is no other library, the school library serves a general library purpose &gt;e community. Probably the largest and best school district library in te is that of Pawnee City, but there is no public library in that city. and the school library is doing a double duty. Where there is a good ; library, the field of general literature is left to it, while indispensable refer- ence books and supplementary reading are supplied by the school library. arc usually purchased from regular school money. This is the ideal condition, but only a few districts can attain it. le rural school library must be both reference and circulating, and effort to make it adequate to its field of service will continue to be put forth by this Commission. To help such schools get the best books for the least money is the constant concern of this office, and many dollars have been directed into profitable and useful channels that might otherwise have betn spent for inferior or useless books at exorbitant prices. Instruction to Teachers. The use of books being quite as important as their acquisition, much time and earnest effort have been devoted to instructing teachers as to the ii gent use of books. The young person who has seen few books other than the meager school texts is not in a position to make the school libra- powerful educational agency that it ought to be. Five weeks of the summer of 1903 were devoted by the Secretary to instruction on the use of books in the Junior normal schools, and c teachers' institutes. County and district teachers' meetings have also been addressed, books exhibited, and conferences held with teachers at various points in the state The results of all this work with schools can not be tabulated. It can only be conjectured from the increasing correspondence with schools and the steady growth of school libraries. That the ultimate end to be attained is one of inestimable importance to the state is beyond dispute. The rural school of to-morrow will have its well-planned and ornamented school yard and garden, properly constructed school buildings with up-to-date me of lighting, heating, and ventilation, and improved and more decent ideas of sanitation. It will have ample equipment, not the least of which will be a properly selected and intelligently used library. Along this line of progress. this Commission will continue to move, assured that no other field offers more profitable employment for its activities, or promises more benc the state. List of Books for Presents for Children. A list of books suitable for presents for children was printed and widely distributed in the state, in the hope that better books might find their way into homes. The list was greatly appreciated in the state, and has been called for from a number of other states. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">8 Improvement of Library Management, The second duty imposed by law upon this Commission is that proving libraries already established. A marked improvement in library methods is everywhere to be seen. Under the direction of the Secretary public libraries of Wayne, Wakefield, Syracuse, Central City, Coir Holdrege, and Superior have been accessioned and classified, and methods of loaning and administration in general inaugurated. Loar have been devised for numerous libraries, and many suggestions made to improve the efficiency of both libraries and librarians. Trained Librarians. The need of special preparation and fitness for library work is more and recognized by library boards. That much of this change of sent ■ to the influence of this Commission there can be no doubt. Literature on the training of librarians, as well as on all topics connected with library administration, has been sent to all library trustee-; and librarians. Library l»oards have been asked by the Commission to send their librarians to summer schools of library science, or at least to encourage them to go by giving them leave of absence with pay. In a number of cases this has been done, and Nebraska has been represented in the Iowa and Wisconsin summ by seven librarians during the past two years. The librarians of eight i eleven largest public libraries in the state are especially trained for their some of them being regular library school graduates, others having had summer school training, and still others being trained by studying and working in well managed libraries. I his is a remarkably good showing, because, on the part of a numi" librarians, attendance at the summer school can be accomplished f-sacrince. Salaries are not high enough to warrant any such exp le prospect of anything better in the way of compensation is not le, with library funds in the state that they promise to remain in until w permits larger library revein In the still smaller towns, there has also been improvement in adminis - trative methods, largely aided by personal visits from the Secretary. Library Buildings. Ie Carnegie library buildings at Kearney, Hastings, Grand Island, and Omaha are nearly ready for occupancy, while Fremont and Beatrice sen enjoying their nicely appointed libraries for some time. Tli. mblic library has just accepted $7,000 from Mr. Carnegie for a build - •ther of the smaller towns are about to follow the example of Hol - md the coming biennium promises to be an era of library build Library boards are encouraged to make use of the Commission in the planning and equipment of their buildii is to proper fill lighting, ventilation, and other details have n in a number of </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 I) help libraries to select the best lv&gt; e of the probh commission. A number of library conn chiefly in the -ued a Suggestive list of bo mall libraries, bi-n and a Handbook of library organization. These publ: ■een distributed by this Commission to all libraries in the r a library having money I- in (or advice as to t: fulness of certain books, or asks to have tin elected by the Seer The general character of the l&gt;ooks bought is letter. The writings of M •he "'Duchess," and similar- authors, are being replaced by virile and wholesome literature. More and better luniks for t added to the libraries. To get '"the : ! for the largest number at the least cost' 1 has been the maxim of the library pr : i e general Periodicals. Bhave been encouraged to collect sets of the leading peri' sis for reference collections. M;iny valuable periodicals are being used e fires instead of being preserved i In a natnb Ecting on our suggestion, periodical o have bn useful and almost priceless material thus rescued from di ice we receive gifts of periodicals and assist libraries in filling out I 8 Whenever the office room and office force of the Commission will per - lis clearing house of periodicals will be greatly extended, and a n latic collection of this useful material inaugurated. The V. r commission has saved thousands of dollars to Wisconsin libra t this way. Study Clubs Eireat activity is apparent among the studious people all over the among these is the state Federation of women's di •• parental &gt;n to the Library commission gives these clubs an urgent claim on the ion and activities of the Commission. A collec- idy outlines is n our office for the use of clubs, and many ap) for these and for suggestions have been responded to. Lists of bo-'i- il loan collection are sent to all the clubs, and the numb such books is constantly increasing. Special Loans INcbraskan who finds that the resources of his own community are e in any given line of study is entitled to our assistance ■d means permit. We ha m in the haivl lubs, and schools for study purpose-;. A wide One man in Logan county has Ixirn ;t a Hurl number </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 can history; women s clubs all over the state have books on the subjects they are studying. As an illustration of the possibilities of this branch of the work, the following letter, which comes from a sand-hill county having no &lt;ls, is quoted : Bour article in the Illustrated Ree, December fi, 1903, on The Traveling , mentioned a special loan collection, the lx&gt;oks to be loaned si- "I have not gone to school as much as I should have. Am 19 ye.v in 9th grade. Should like to attend the Agricultural College next yt later. Have never seen manv farm books, though I've read some papers. 1 like to borrow something to help me prepare for the something to teach about increasing fertility of soil in the Also stock judging, hog raising, tree planting, caring for succulen' What must I do to get a book?" This letter is as eloquent an argument for more extensive provision for 'ranch of the work as we can place before the p over the state, if we had but means to find them and provide for them they are found, are just such young people, who are feeling their way to a higher and more effective plane of usefulness than their environment can offer them. What possible investment of money could yield larger returns than one which will increase the value of our best natural resource — the minds and energies of our voting people? This feature of the work is capable of indefinii n. Indeed, if it were not for the books given to us by the Federation of women's club the possibility of sometimes supplementing our resources with those of the University library, we could not do this work with the limited funds at our command. We do not aim at a large collection of books for this purpose, except as they are suited to general use, but the problem of housing even our present possessions is troublesome, and more room as well as more money is needed. In the future, we expect to greatly extend our special loan work along practical lines, working in cooperation with the officers of far - mers' institutes, women's clubs, state associations, schools, and librar • the end that the arts of comfortable living and intelligent industry may be Technical Collections. A beginning of what we expect to see become a large collection on veterinary, medical, technical, agricultural, and related topics has been de - posited in this office through the efforts of Dr. Peters, of the state Experi - ment station. These books are deposited here to be loaned to the people of Nebraska. Any state society having a loan collection along the lines of its special interest may deposit its books with us, to be cared for and loaned to those who need them. There is no limit to what may be accomplished in this direction. It is one of the profitable lines along which we may work whenever we have sufficient means to do so. Meantime, the foundations are being laid. These collections will be the only ones of their several kinds which are available for persons who can not go to the libraries. The books in our other state and public libraries are in constant use and can not be </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Although the traveling library represents but one of the many act o' this Commission, it is, perhaps, our most successful instrument in the work of library extension. The term ''library extension" is interpreted to include everything, from the purchasing of a book by a citizen who b library in his home, or the substitution of a good book for a poor one on the family bookshelf, to the starting of a school library in a rural school public library in a city. Thus it comes that this Commission is just as much interested in awakening the desire for good and useful reading in the re - motest home as in encouraging the establishment and correct adminisr of public libraries. We believe that there is no surer way to inspire p with a desire for good hooks at home, at school, and in the library tl; (rive the people an opportunity to see and read the best books that the book trade affords. This, then, is the first task set for the traveling libra task so magnificent in its possibilities that the accomplishment of but a small portion of it would justify the expenditure of all state funds so far de. to this Commission, as well as affording ample satisfaction to those who have had the work in charge. Kie first traveling library was sent out from this office in December, It went to a barber shop in Loup City, where, during the three months stav, 270 books were borrowed. The barber was an intelligent man, ?eply interested in the welfare of his community. He had the true spirit. If he found a book that he thought would interest some spe - rson, he called that person's attention to it. He read, or looked books and was able to talk about them with the borrowers. We have any other librarians who were equally interested, and to whose intelli - gent and helpful spirit has been due, in a large measure, the results that justify our pride, as Nebraskans. in the achievements of the past three years. The librarians of our traveling libraries are not paid for their work as libra - rians, except in terms of satisfaction .in being of service to others. The libraries have been kept in school houses, dwellings, post-offices, stores, de - pots, hotels, newspaper offices, parsonages, and a variety of other places — and the business men, ministers, teachers, and others who have served as librarians, have responded loyally to the instructions from this office have insisted that the use of the books must be free to all members of the community, and that all who get mail or trade in the town are eligible as borrowers. In this way, the books have reached many remote neighbor - hoods. At intervals, additional suggestions go out from this office. As soon as the finances of this Commission will permit, some one from this office will systematically visit the places where traveling libraries are located, helping to organize local library associations, and to create interest in the books and extend their usefulness. In time, we expect to emulate the example of the Wisconsin free library commission, and hold library insti - tutes for the benefit of the librarians of our traveling libraries. These are some of the things the traveling library should accomplish. It is a mistake </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 administration. The locomotive is a magnificent creation, but it has to t manipulated with brains as well as brawn, or it is of no more use than ; heap of scrap iron. The same may !&gt;e said of libraries. The right boo reach the person who need 11 as the one who wants it. if th libra' taJ leaven. The lump will remain a him &lt;• leaven is properly distributed. We have i -aveling li and the M librarians in charge have so generally caught tli • of using the library as an educational force that we feel that tli hand when personal work with them will prove the efficiency ■n, and justify any reasonable demands that this Commission may mak ty of public spirited Xebra^k Our traveling libraries have 134 places in 6»i counties in the pas t this moment, they arc risking places ranging from 1' ty around to McCook, Bridgeport. Gordon. Laurel, Homer, Wai them are in rural school houses, cross roads stores, and farn They have made 2'&gt;f&gt; round trips, and M libraries are mam During this time 33,147 volumes have been borrowed. The total number o mes is about :i,4i&gt;0. so that each volume has had an average circ:; ITie average number of borrowers in a pi: -o that th. numbf r of l&gt;orrowers enrolled in the state is in the neighl&gt;orli' When it is &lt;\ that most of the books lx&gt;rrowed have beei ■veral persons beside the l&gt;orrower, in many ca being rea&lt; iloud at home, it can be seen that our 3.4&lt;M&gt; book* have beer good use of. If we had done nothing but purchase books and admin the traveling libraries, the average cost of baying one book and circu lating it 9.7 times would be $2.04. Anyone at all familiar with librar would testify that the money was well spent, provided that the book; '&gt;f a proper character. A traveling library make it up, contains 40 volumes, one &gt;ich are fiction for adults, another fourth .r children, and the balance are history, travel, useful arts. etc.. equally divided between children and adults Experience has proved these proportions. The fiction is most c?refully selected. Each library contains some, of the old, standard n&lt; -ome of the later, popular books. Many novels of the realistic school that could, with perfect propriety, be put on the shelves of a large city 111 nitted from the traveling library We aim to have nothing that in tone, uplifting in influence, or that will not either instn ■h legitimate amusement. Special attention is given to the select i children's books, for we l&gt;elieve that i give the boys and gir ska ever. chance. The following letter, received last week a farm tion given the sou will see, this I n patronized as much as they 1&gt;een. This is because of the work that i- . during the 1 MMMer, but when wint. the library, anil many have been taken during the veryone is looking </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 me. can have any idea how much our library H ng day when it arrive-;, ami urce of pleasure until a nev. Kahe is sitting on the lounge now reading ; finish it before next Saturday. Mr. Hunter ha wn the t ■ 'Sharp eyes' and 'According '■ back with the \nd I wuh that you would find a lxx&gt;k on zoology to loan sp&lt; for Babe and me to read this winter wrt in a sp tor Kthel Davis, a book on elementary psycl Permanent Traveling Library Statians. ral small public libraries whose inoon lasted in the c of administration are permanent station:; for traveling libraries. Tim nient gives such libraries fresh Ixxiks every three month helps them to keep up interest. A permanent station is a place that ha - raveling library upon condition that we send for five years. Harvard, Osceola, Culbertson. Douglas. Murray. Wakefield. Dannebrog, Valley. Laurel. Gordon. Sterling, and Carroll are our pern: is. The twelve libraries paid for by these communities are amor. ~t in our collection, and cost about ine of these p!ac&lt; ilt, the library having been paid for out of school funds. Sue! uicleus for a little local library. In a number of places the tra v has grown into a full fledged public library in an incredibly time. The presence of the books in the community helps create the lore books and for a permanent collection. Beginning with ' of little libraries has been started in this way. Wakefield. roll. Talmage, Laurel, DeWitt, and Sterling are among these places. School Traveling Libraries. | r e have had four school traveling libraries in the hands of counts ■ndents. These liooks are loaned by the roperinti volumes, to districts, in the hopes of inter, libraries and in the expectation that the ■ of school libraries will result therefrom. Care of the Books ie beginning of the work of this Commission certain gloomy ? icsied that the lx&gt;oks in the traveling libr:&lt; tch carelessness or dishonesty. Tt is gratifying to Ik? able to in tin with a record of nearly 40,000 loans, the libraries are condition, and that all books that have been lost or unreasonably have been replaced by the lxirrowing communities, with the •lunies. I'nlike the ruli her library commi are required by us of borrowing commui ied with a simple "arrange for the proper care </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 pugns the motives of the people of Nebraska. Contagious Diseases. Other objectors feared the spread of contagion by means of books. We have had four volumes destroyed by health officers at traveling library sta - tions. These have been paid for by the borrowing communities. By con - ferring with the State board of health, and with local health officers, and requiring our librarians to follow our instructions, no instance of any spread of contagion can be traced to the traveling libraries. Rural Library Associations. Recently a rural library association was formed in a school district in Otoe county, with a traveling library as a foundation for its work. The library is in a fanner's home, and under the intelligent guidance of this man, what splendid work those 40 volumes can do during a winter ! If the Secre - tary of this Commission had but the means and time to organize similar as - sociations all over the state, what a wonderful amount of latent possibility could be developed and directed! The traveling library is our best appliance for promoting the mission of books, for a good book is ever its own best argument. It is the endeavor of this Commission so to use the traveling library as to encourage the public and private purchase of more and better books by the people of Nebraska. The results of the work already done are only partially tangible — as the best results of all such work can never be a matter of record. The future of this phase of the work is magnificent and inspiring, and has no limit save the boundaries of Nebraska and the provision made" by the state for forwarding Library Legislation The rate of progress in library affairs is so satisfactory that we may well wonder whether further legislation is needed. It seems clear, however, that school libraries ought to have some recognized basis, that public libra - ries should be able to get larger revenues, and that the idea of a system of country libraries should receive consideration and encouragement. The general trend of opinion among school superintendents, as shown by replies to our questions concerning school libraries, is in favor of a law requiring the setting aside by school boards of a certain per cent of the annual income of the districts for the purchase of library books. There is good reason to doubt, however, whether mandatory legislation of this kind would accomplish what might be hoped from it. It is already lawful, ac - cording to a decision of the State Superintendent, to pay for library books from school funds. Many districts are doing this, and many more are rais - ing more money from outside sources than would be possible for their boards to set aside for library books. The State Superintendent is constantly urging the subject of school libraries on the attention of teachers. This Commis- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 t, be superfluous. If the new revenue law is finally adjusted so as to increase assessments in cities and villages, the two-mill library levy would probably suffice in the larger towns. Meantime, city councils hn educated that tlu-&gt; be willing to vote the full two mills to the libraries. Here, again, this •n will endeavor to aid libraries in the work of attaching public ment to themselves. B county system of libraries is worthy the attention of lau authority granted to county commissioners to levy a tax to bo 1 in paying such public libraries as may be established, in order privileges may be extended to everybody living in the county. giving village Ixxirds, in places unable, to support libraries be used in paying the nearest good public library for makiiu sub-stations for their libraries, would place Nebraska in line wit ssive states. Field Work I he greatest need of this Commission is more time and mone&gt; During the biennium the Secretary and President have tra\ miles in the field work. The Secretary visited Plattsmouth. On mt, McCook. Holdrege, Kearney, North Plattr , Syracuse, Central City, Tecumseh, Pawnee City. DeWitt, ( a, Norfolk. Wayne. Wakefieid, Geneva. Harvard, and Peru. Eivel is a most profitable expenditure of our funds, but, owing to the activities we are engaged in, we have not been able to come itact with all parts of the state as it seems desirable to do more for this purpose alone could be expended during this coming Other Library Commissions. We can not attempt to compete with other states that set asid* $fi,000 to $75,000 a year for library commission work. We have tain to study the needs of Nebraska without regard for the enterpri - sister commissions, and to apply our limited funds to the best advantage of rate. Massachusetts, New York, and other eastern states give state aid to libraries, have complete systems of library inspection, hold library and do an immense amount of field work, including the editing and printing of literature on library administration, and send their cornn; workers to national conferences and to study the methods of other 1 commissions. EiVe have aimed to progress gradually along the lines of natural &gt;' nt, and to render the state the largest possible return for the sum given our charge. In this we have attained a degree of success that merits a er expression of confidence in somewhat increased resources. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 APPENDIX. Books added during the bicnnium. By purchase 2013 By gift Traveling lib. stations Publishers 157 157 Others Total additions Previously reported Total acce^- 4400 Duplicates to replace lost or worn o .md paid for by others 31 Paid for by Commission IS by others and replaced It books. 2 Expenditures for biennial period ending November :'.fl. 1904. APPROPRIATION APPROPRIATION if l&gt;ooks for school libraries New and enlarged edition. - . restive list of books for a small library, recommended by the library commissions of Wisconsin, Minnesota, Iowa, Idaho. Dela ware, and Nebraska. Nebraska edition. Buying lists of recent books recommended by the same commissions and published by the Wisconsin commission. Bi-monthly. Handlnxik of library organization, compiled by the library eomnn of Minnesota, Iowa, and Wisconsin. Nebraska edition published by - courtesy of the Minnesota commission. How to start a library. will be sent to anyone in Nebraska upon app!i&lt; 1SU1-3. MO II IMB-.i. WUOO (Salaries Supplies Books Travel $ 33 ,:&gt;?, -,oo ■40 11M $ir;o2.+o $17'." $6000 'reviocsly expended 47M.» $4000.00 Balance $11 Publications. in ircular of informati [ion. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Traveling librarie been sent to the following places: First congressional district. WHKRK OR BY WHOM KEPT 'H LIBHARH - chili tional p I MAMK OF PI HI School Rural school Ic (R. F. D j. College View . Pulilic librarv- &gt;&lt;&gt;uglas .. Store I Store k Creek ....Rural school . Rural school . . Lancaster county mcaster county ....County superintendent 1 iperintendent 1 9. Lancaster cotmtv mcaster county School district IS t School district - t ncoln ncoln University farm . I University farm I 11. Louisville School I ■uisville Public library [unlock V. If. C. A. I Murray . Ston 'rmal «il : iwnee county School district ! I '.Icm Editor , nth Bend . Sterling . • I racuse Public library ... R. F. n.1 School district 10 l almage . . Public library I i .-umseh Public library -4. I'nadilla School School I nisville Public library i r dock Murray •rmal 16. Pawnee county School district -~nlem uth Bend : Public librarv . . . . n 1 School district 10 l Public librarv Public librarv School Second congressional district. Second congressional district 1. ISellevue . School levue 2. Blair ... X Papillion School Ward school . Ward school •.pillion Rl -ite office - Real estate offio 4. *Valley . . Public librars ,lley . iterloo Public library 'J " Waterloo Woman's clu!&gt; Woman's club 0 Waterloo (R. F. D.) School &lt;! 0 Waterloo (R. F D") School distn I Third congressional district. Third congressional district. 1. Bancroft . School 1 . Rancroft . . . 2. *Carroll ... ■?. Cedar Rapid School : 2. *Carroll . . Public lihrarv \-dar Rapids . Store . nierson ' n Public library Store I nerson ■&gt; Klerton (R. F old . Farm Flowing well r School Homer 8. *Lattrel 9. Leigh !ic librarv </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 KAMI OF PI.ACK VHIIB OR BY WHOM KEPT NO. OF LIB* A»I KB KVJIT 10. I-oretto ... Depot 11. Meadow Grove 1 12. Monroe School eligh 14. Pender Reading room Public library . . 4 tPlainview (R. F. Randolph D/&gt; Store Woman's club 17. Schuyler Woman's club 18. Scribner ... . Public library r Silver Creek Stanton Store Public library 21. *Wakefield A' inside . 23. Wisner . . Public library Store Public library 4 Fourth congressional district. 1. Adams W. C. T. U 2. Ashland Public librarv 3. Aurora W. C. T. U 4. Aurora County superintendent . . . .• I 5. Beaver Crossing Store 8. Davenport School 7. DeWitt Public library 8. Diller School 9. Endicott Rural school dicott Dwelling . . . l 11. Exeter Dwelling 12. Fairmont School 13. Friend School . .... 3 14. Geneva School 15 Germantown 16. Liberty Store . l Telephone exchange . School 17. Ohiowa 18. *Osceola Public library 19. Pleasant Dale School . 20. Rising City (R. F. D.) Farm tSteele City . Store Stromsburg ... W. C. T. U. 23. Tobias Bank | 24. Western School . K. Wilber (R. F. D).. Farm ... Z6. Wymore Store I Fifth congressional district. 1. Axtell (R. F. D). Farm 2. Bloomington . . County superintendent S. Blue Hill . School 4. Clay Center County superintendent : </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 ovLmAKiBaarirt ifAME OF PLACB WKK*B OK BY WHOM KBTT *O. 5. *CuIbertson 8. Elwood . . Barber shop Post-office 1 7. Grand Island 8. Haigler County superintendent 1 School 3 9. 'Harvard Y. M. C. A ... « L Hastings (R. F, Hayes Center . Holbrook D.) Farm — 2 County superintendent School 13. Holdrege 14. Holdrege 15. Huntley 16. Imperial 17. Kenesaw 18. McCook 19. McCook 20. McCook 21. Nelson . 22. Oxford . 23. Palisade Junior normal School Post-office ... 2 School Post-office School Junior normal ... ... 8 Public library .... School .4 Public library Rural school ... 2 24. Phelps county 25. Riverton .... Farm Rural school 26. Stamford 27. Stamford 28. Superior 29. Upland , Dwelling ... 2 School district 10 . School Rural school Sixth congressional district. 1. Alliance . . 2. Alliance . . 3. Brewster . . 4. Bridgeport 5. *Dannebrog 6. Elm Creek County superintendent School Store . . . . 1 Bank School School ♦Gordon Telephone exchange . . 8. Kimball County superintendent 9. Gothenburg 10. Lexington . It Loup City 12. Luella .... W. C. T. U Store 2 Store . . 3 Dwelling ... I IS. Minatare Dwelling 14. North Platte 15. Overton County superintendent School . . 16. Purdum 17. St Paul Dwelling . . . % Woman's club School 18. Scotts Bluff 19. Springview 20. Trenton . . . Post-office .2 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 MAMB OF PLACK K&gt; OK BY WHOM KtPT K l.m tllKI HUT &gt; alentine Junior normal 1 22. Valentine . :y superintendent ilentine . . . 1 Summary. libraries have been to 130 places in tin countk ;y ha\e mm und trips. The average minilxv of I in a plao EK) volumes have a reported circulation of :i.i.l-l7 in two years, permanent traveling library stations havi ial&gt;lisbed. volumes have been seTit as special loans to TS places. Public Libraries of Nebraska. public library is one that is established by or. inance under the state law. A Year Popula- No of Fstab- t f OI1 Volumes Borrowers TOWN lished bion 1900 1209 1870 ! 4m -hland 1904 1477 174 3 Beatrice 1893 7875 8500 400U * i Central City 1891 1571 15(10 ollegeView 75 olumbus 1901 3522 1450 Him rete 1873 2199 4000 I avid City. 1890 231 M 'eWitt.... ... 1904 I airburv. . .... 1900 1340 1523 rails City. L901 3022 2673 12 Fremont 1901 7241 3532 .rand Island i 7.V 4 8064 I 14 I Hastings 1887 7188 2500 iloldrege 1895 3007 1020 381 lumboldt 18a3 1215 4000 180 IT Kearnev I 1890 5634 4063 &gt; .incoln ... 40169 10770 11142 .ouisville 1901 738 266 McCook 1902 2445 I 2400 Nebraska City 1896 7380 3987 &gt;maha 1S77 102555 57864 i 14414 &gt;sceola 1901 882 215 i'lattsmouth. 1886 4964 4085 ! 1000 -cribner... 1900 MB -eward.... 1885 1970 1460 '^(J0 -helton 1898 HO) outh Omaha 1902 250 2000 sterling 1904 -yracute 1898 1209 falmage 1904 363 ; 19 .'ecumseh 1500 ■ : Wakefiel.l . . 1902 500 ! . 1903 M8 36 York ♦This library, having been twice destroyed by fire, has one- more organized. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 riation and Other Public Libraries not Supported by Taxation. TOWN NAME OF LIBRARY Ye»r estab- lished | JSL 1 Blair 2 Bridgeport .... 3 Broken Bow . . 5 Chadron 6 Crawford 8 Fairbury 9 Fullerton 11 Harvard 12 Hebron 14 Nelieh 15 North Platte . . 16 Omaha 17 I Omaha 18 Pender 19 Pleasanton .... 20 Stanton Wayne Blair assoc. library Pubic library Ladies' library association Public library City library Pound memorial library Ladies' library association Jefferson county teachers' library Nance county teachers' library H. L. Smith library Y. M. C. A. library Teachers' library W. C. T. U. hospital library Public library R. R. Y. M. C. A. library Y. M. C. A. library Swedish library association Public library Pleasanton library Stanton library association Ladies' library association Sutton library association Public library Public library Public library lv*i 1903 we 1904 1888 i887 1902 1885 1888 1904 1890 i879 1901 1901 1902 1884 1902 1902 1903 1903 1*5 m S m m .... m t I </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 TOWN NAME OF LIBRARY Year estab- No. of lUhed volumes • rand Island . . Nebraska soldiers' home incoln Nebraska state library 3 Lincoln Nebraska state hist, society library. . 4 I Lincoln Nebraska penitentiary iseo 1867 1878 1903 1 NAME OF 8CHOOI. Ye J£, TOWN Bellevue Bellevue college 1884 lethany Cotner university 1891 Jlair Dana college .... !hadron Chadron academy .... College View . . ' Union college 1891 Crete ... .mecollege 1872 "ranklin inklin academy ... 1887 r remont emont normal college .... Jeneva State industrial school for girls 1892 Grand Island . Grand Island college 1894 lastings Hastings college 1882 /incoln. lty of Nebraska 1869 leligh .... academy 1881 Omaha . .wnell Hall 1866 )maha ! Creighton college .... )maha j Presbyterian theological seminary . . . 1892 )maha . . '■ braska school for the deaf Ib9t&gt; •era ite normal school 1878 antee Santee normal training school .... Jniv. Place . . . ] Nebraska Wesleyan University 1883 yahoo Luther academy 1883 Nebraska normal college 1892 J&amp; I Weeping Water Weeping Water academy. 1894 iSS York York college 1895 State Libraries not Already Mentioned. </seg>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027">27 4000 to 8000 population 1000 to 2000 population — Con. ♦Beatrice •Fremont tHebron •Humboldt Lexington Madison Grand Island igs Kearney Minden tNeligh raska City *Plattsmonth North Bend Oakland On! 3000 to 4000 population mbus ! &gt;ury Pawnee Ponca folk Red Cloud St. Paul Sidney t. North Platte tStanton 2000 to 3000 populati m Stron tSottoa Tekamah Univ. Place &gt;ok Solmyler mseh oo ng Water \ViI!&gt;er 800 to 1000 population Alma more Blue I fill 1000 to 2000 populatif ■n ' r i&lt;l(je land Am ♦College View &lt;hton ■ken Bow tral City Iron Decatur Genoa Gothenburg flartington 1 City tlTnrvard Ffooper Fullcrton Humphrey Loup City Lyons TIavelock * Public Library. nation Library. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Dodge •Osceola tPender Elmwood Fairmont Florence Franklin Gibbon sr Gordon Greeley Center Greenwood ;sr tfa Sioux City cuse Howell Indianola Juniata Table Rock Valentine Kenesaw tLaurel *Louisville Milford 500 to S00 population Ainsworth Arapahoe t Bancroft Battle Creek Newman Grove Oakdale Orleans Osmond tOxford Papillion Pierce mfield Plainview Blue Springs St. Edward Salem Brownville * Sterling Tilden Cedar Rapids Tobias tValley Clay Center tCrawford ta City *DeWitt ♦Wakefield Wood River Valparaiso Gifts and Bequests During the past two years the only gifts of any magnitude are from Andrew Carnegie to the public libraries of Beatrice, Hastings. Kearney, and Grand Island; Beatrice receiving $3,000 additional for a building. Hastings and Grand Island receiving $20,000 each for buildings, and Kearney receiving $10,000 for a building. •Public Library. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>