<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirty-Sixth Annual Report OF THE NEBRASKA State Horticultural Society Containing all the Proceedings of the Summer Meeting Held at Aurora, July 28 and 29, 1904, and the Annual Meeting Held at Lincoln, January 17, 18, 19, 1905.</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NEBRASKA State Horticultural Society II the Proceedings of the Summer Meeting Aurora, July 28 and 29, 1904, and the Meeting Held at Lincoln, Jan- 18 and 19, 1905. M. RUSSELL, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Mivkt of Nttoraaka: lance with le^al requisition, the annual report e Horticultural S&lt;x-iety for the year 1905, L. M. Russell, . Horticultural .So. 1 fully submitted. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">er of transmitted. Ottii . Standing commiti Membership list. Constitution. By-Li Proceedi eedings Annual meetiaff. Fruit clistrii ' Eretary'a report. </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">Christy, Johnson H. S. Harrison, York ml V • dent K M. Pollard, Nehawka L. M. Russell, Lincoln Peter Yoongers, &lt;:&lt;• DIRECTORS. Omaha - </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">I' 1' 1» I ( SYNOIO V .1 . Hriiv C. H. Barnard, Table I METEOROLOGY &lt;; I) Sweezy, Lincoln OMOLOGY AND ORNITHOLOGY Prof. L. Brunei-. Lincoln. HE UNIVERSITY OK EXPERIMENT STATION. NEBRASKA E. F. Stephens, Cret« GEOLOGY. E. H. Harbour, Lincoln FOKKSTY K. T. Hartley, Lincoln iabi.k CDLTURK. K. A. Emerson, Lincoln. ORNAMENTAL GARDENING. .1. H. Hadkinson, Omaha. 'IK L. C. Chapin, Lincoln C H. Barnard, Table 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">11 Iowa Denmark, [owi Delaware, Ohio Fort CaJhcmn i Springs, M iid Rapids. Michigan ParksH'v. Virginia Johnson Julian Spicer, Oi Pawnee &gt; Table Lincoln Post Office Unknown Flor. Kea Cedar Bluffs Cheney Kingston. Grand Junction &lt; Joli: ( s. w </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 n. W E I L. W. B. I'. tin row ; H. ;s(.n. .1. i; W. H H N W. E. W a in. .1 M i; a Erflin{ Flotli. Paul B. C. enburg, H H. H H •Furnas. R. \\ A Kiitii, &lt;; h . Charlea H ell. E. N Gurn.-y. C. W. nsiin, J. H A Erris. W. R rris. W. T. ( </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 ill! Farnam Si Pasadena, California Fairl Pur.i - San .ln&gt;' A Hit \rlin_ Arlii Arlii B&lt; mlt'va rd A \ • Akla Cnadilla Unadilla Greeley t Colorado City, Keai t </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Y Kn. Frank n. John K. M Oft i.-ll. .1. C I, M. H. H El H. Alfr. 11. J. If. M. 1. Don. L. D. s I. 8 - H th, H. L. 0. F. Frank G a, J. W. Taylor, Fredrick W. Tiffany, M. D. \ ( \ B. Paul W ft p. Strand, {j. A.. Swan, W. G. Swezey, G. D. Tanahill, Wm. St. Lou I </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 J Omaha Arlington Post Office Unknown Washington, D. C. Fremont A I. MEMBERS. University of Minn&lt;- Glenwood, Iowa Shenandoah, Iowa AT. MEMBERS Shickley Scotts Bluff Tecumseh R. F. D. 5 Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 STITI'TION Article I. HorticulturH - BThi roinotion ot poi f fi&gt;i . aiui life hon&lt; nent II 1&gt;« if dii • tin- &lt;&gt;fti( inual lie I I).' f rawn on the I with ' ,f the 8 mil perfi Ky &lt;&gt;r txtard of din </seg>
            <seg id="p017">1 tl ins ■retnrv shal if m-oceedintrs of all meetings &lt;&gt;: mts mi the :is counter in &gt;r nublication and e&lt; bv the statuti ith tl' lent prepare all ] ■v arrangements for all meet ietv and mirine to t nits drawn on him by the ident ■ if the te president and id tli- f his ilntii rinani tors d ident. v ird of di i h for their board v it an annual renort in ci)irinn inual 11 hold tw( Id in id Monday in </seg>
            <seg id="p018">■ I (if A^rr v t !V I. A.11 oft tinut* 4. Tlie amount allow • Krs. one from each horticulti dinii committee of thi tnding committee XIV. 1! lin^r of tl tlinjf the one in v ■arcl of (1 the reading of the minute ■rology i' 1 its relation to Hori ■ •ninn. 7. These by </seg>
            <seg id="p019">utttinu of the Nebraska s t Aurora, July 28 and 29, 1904. s </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021">21 MEETING V l'-TH. ! i;&lt;&gt;&lt; KKi)iN&lt;;s ie Nel Horticultural him. Hamilton county, Following PROGRAM Mayor Jos&lt; Eto W. W. Tatum. I'rcs Columbian Club „. rticultura] E&lt;i Hon. K von ForHI, Regent Univ&lt; '» ow I G Frank Harris ds" Exeter Youni s1 " I 'ret. K. A. Emerson Pliilliiirmonic Orclx Wood Bros. Qua Mrs. J. G.Alden Miss Allie ManninK (i. A. Marshall </seg>
            <seg id="p022">LTUB \v Musi* and make a good displ; THE PRESIDENT: Tl SummtT meeting of ti \V&lt;- will first have an in s oar Heavenly Father, 'I i and perfect gift. And at this t A-ould return unto Ibee &lt;&gt;ur than! providence W« hl.-ss Th.'.- that Thou ha grow and the herbs to bring forth r 1 1 • • •ar fruit. We thank tor the boui irding i.Jlt l\ - </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 I i i \ :i t i PI l it thank Thee that Thou Id as this: that then v and comfortable. And rsel helps that will in life. We thank Tl i grant, our Patl hts that will do us good, am what ha-s been done ■ to us to put forth oup-energi&lt; do greater Rood in the ful ■; now. help us to honor T: 1 when Thou art done with u&gt; It'si, Amen ■ of welcome was to In- g\\ ; out of the city and i ily de if tin Nebraska Horticultural The development of Nebraska has lefined lines. Our people have n&lt; it in force tin' large numbers of new mt speak for the advancement i and women who, having lived in this are unable to look back and re - in a far more primitive I reneraled all other ilong this ed to me in the nature of a query; only possible reason that can be as- ire of broad mind and keen intellect, rtunity to elevate and have no f&lt; ind expressing beliefs concern- that may be presented for contro- 1 us the opportunity • e h;t\ r in this ■ t thought, for mutual iray that Thou will be in t the pleasure of listening to Mr. F </seg>
            <seg id="p024">in its geological : i. young ynunj; in its historical re&lt; climate, its production or its inha farther hack than ' t ■t to look upon Nel </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 n away in the lumber ind piled on the s, Mi id iind Mexi&lt; tich are gradually &gt;iny the scrutii ilished by the throw a Hood of xplorations in the (I he nations thai ) their dead t nted sutt ,v irs before tl M msei ■d t cifiit and xtv-six \- er James I of England, and comnu .nia: twi ward tu I &gt; V &gt;at upon tin* united throne red; the ]■■ d produ&lt; 4 tnts dei i ion from one of the servii ago in the Montreal, the identical voyage down the iwn hand, and bearing »11 the a p. drawn in the which now forms tl if Ne- he Missouri is to a point ttitude; the Platte river is laid down in Indian tribes which </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 i Bi t&lt;&gt; our city uill 1 itu who are present will a tend, ou ■»&lt; B manner the g will our sister s1 n&gt;k t&lt;&gt; N . jus' n, tli- rit of th&gt; tion. [Ap] thril with a feeline &lt;&gt;f </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 ,v i Nebrasl t thing tha ( However, it is with ■ntleinan win Mi mi. titute for Mr. Harrison cannot add t hank the citizens of An utiful place to meet ii. eat dt'al of good from our It is particularly pleasing t&gt; Nebraska all my life, and one of my liis part of tlif state was on the ed that it would he the garden Iking about horticulture. &gt;tv, that it is an institution ler the representative workers in 1 that it has its stated mee' Lincoln, at the capital, in January in touch with the scientific find at these meetings all of roccur, and the experimei before the people. It is at these bring out the results of labor. igo what we know today through would be far in advance of what ind its agriculture. And I believe nds more to the development of our I societies of the state. We have j r*o/*&lt;»iv&lt;i rtirwu't' fvom the mown ni' who Ill 1»&gt; »ble t irupriution of $2,500, % exhibit &lt;&gt;f fruit and flow- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">\ Mr. M i I </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 w ii re tv ( ts ti ould have his own immunity. I that Mr. Har the citizens of mi to an enjoj cial dub. lmittee of on you wili </seg>
            <seg id="p030">KB, Oft n, I v 10, which should •uld h* E:ne time I many. I think it would be committee, and let the seer !■ of dividing the c YOUNGERS: I think Mi. ed in' Mr Y and that whicl " Kan properly iir be authorized 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 n their di&gt;' (1 to help divide the members of the tini? took I*. M the lows s VEKSITY r that is going ' Marshall and ad I will in- omposed of nine. &gt;XD - isday, July 28th, 2:00 p. m theComii RAL EDUCATION n: "The [ am p&gt;inii to i il education in the e ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p032">1 do it tnougntu ■ Ey will n;iturall,\ horticult </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 It I young women who ning. But ii ing our colleges for i equip intil th when they take an in- For instance, the child, by the insi uit take place. So the little bud, if it is only a brief time, i full blown flower. That is the al child; the unnatural child is inhood or womanhood and things. And it iv se they dont like it. No attention to mathematics learn to count the combii That is th« I ■ oat when the child is md living tl most attentii the child when we to the unknown. We wi- that, and we . and all that. Now when ment. when they naturally y to them, you must go back them will study botony and plant this kind of instruc nsive pr&lt; v reach thai s. They taki &gt;tiun and that are activi f growth thai irst tiling that must b« whit i • ural to the child; child abstract things, and the ti&lt;ms. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 study. It does not require a man whose lock know a great deal about the bugs, aniii; child's desires to know these tiling child, or five-year old child, and at this t - that are alive in the child, and aft* find that he is fond of nature, a man wl It does not make him dwarf his instincts i.v tt .ibout t .at da ■ from their i might li er of things. Hut tl line, and to think if I bought iad money enoug -~ front my mind and have th&lt; in th&lt; term horticulture i)i' to cultivate, from which w» of a field, and gives us an in • horticulture has tin think a n -t that i.- him a better phil their logii upon phj Of til' nd wo tion of garden literally, while think if we live mor pore: </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 t x t ml n ,vl I ha i relationship that seems 1 backyard, and so I think I • in the west, to id there have the trees that I lat have been growing there, there, and all that one might •on Id enjoy. I think I would place I could find. Why if our prairies in an at- nk a little more shrubbery ikyard make it the most lings with your family. The mm the conventional i would satisfy the youth and surroundings. While horti- he man who is growing fruit, he individual who is growing s, it also appeals to the indi - towns. where the culti lideration. And it is valuable and finer sensibilities of the 10 comes home from the I been kept occupied with the in any different busint ionn lots throwing It will recreate him and n - work. Now it it Known, that ma: has a man must have the pn light live right with his twelve hours is neces fticient by tl &gt;luca And I tell you v jmanitarian standix&gt;int, ■• anil point that pht or nil. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">, flficient to bring about tfa i who have studied this &gt;■ that a man may be trna trusted on Saturday ni:_ nei M planting all kind- t ind i I was ((lad hi liort thin and again began planting fruit '4. And If this is tru&gt; irfao bi braved the dan^c: hot w </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 i r l I t .v I ■ginning, in this state, men mnot grow apple tr» id been here for thirty - ,id no idea ntry. r«&gt;, and I thinl- only in Richardson tern ]&gt;ortion of our - that the northeast pa chards could grow, it was 1 in • Sioux City I tan any where in tin nth hope that these th than th' good, substantial farm ints, (lowers and I is nothing that a rid than to see the ore! and the flowers that I unity wh&lt; hints, I will show you . led the highest point, it has i will show me a community the swine; it he I : the pri and horse to • 1 think v d Uhi t of it p! and the children hort tim&lt;&gt; iiyo that • 1 yet we find tin • to my house a few i ration cannot be over • country. Th»&gt;iv is nothing in s ;i trood, substantial I ssion that this country &gt;t enough upon cultiv ir Tillages should </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 that grow up in a place of this kind will h will bet; and they will tx«Kin to study th.-s.- things in tin an at' ' tn t! . in k t met ] our r will Th. II hi- ■HOW I GROW CHERRII </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 I I t t r that it that r\nd then I t (inart ( 1 ir v t i your ground plowed from - ind throughly. Then lot broken. Out your lim . train your t; my who think when inuld But it is like a pig in the pen. i in a pen, and then say we have got nothing more to do until t of trees you have got to keep them j. bark bound, b. - fruit its natural si/' nird on it; the leaves look - 11 you the way to prevent it. the do that way. t way, I make up a buel and rub it thoroughly with &gt;out three table sjx)onfuls Hour and mix that with white- I do so with all &lt; tender, the tree growing That is the way I do tat way than I do other wa it them in the ground and would. Bat it was not ■ prown up with ordinary sprouts s&lt;xm take the strength from the late in the t should iid small fruit and hence In on i my thing &gt;lant corn and leave it t orn has to 1k&gt; tended hat the ting to can of fruit v should be oi noming more to uo until T that way. In 01 3 old. '1 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 T but I i pic-kin^ ed up, t) i v tret some I wou "Wli </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 ( v () led d I trot i ■t I to be cultivated, and V loose; the looser the better, ;n »\v. When the t roe bee t and packed around the nut since mint dead, limbs sawed off and last year my t 1 line, and they all bent down to ny trees, the limbs would have iiken off. I keep my trees ten - and they didn't break off, and ff from them here. Iha\ ■d in fruit trees, and my « t have made a growth of I put out a year ago this spring S that 1 got, well satisfied with it. And I anted into fruit from Shennan - iruit. but my trees are (in tin^r I lear home as pos- liinate better, and I think you int. I believe that is all 1 ultivate them every year, but ■ I around them becai. - nd them bee;. r.v y lecomes sickly and dies out in a xteen years old are as nice and terries on, M nice as 1 Harrison Bros, of York, and I find vated, and did they in- </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 F K&lt;&gt;u in the gro in my law Ri&lt; • \ 'i Kl I Die </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 with me is how did he measure my cherries in half bushels, and isbel. (Applai s you see them there (indicat" that bought cherries from me, ng to the question of the kind of ik there is any doubt but the tree as e Late Richmond; that has fruit that ripens irly Richmond. s ago all the Montmorency through this Richmond. We have since disco j been disseminated all through. A . and there are several tyjx's of Mont it about the same time, within four or peand in size and productive!! ;but all of the Montmore: n that the Montmorency ordi w York, is one of th&lt; we have in this ir tret ive the stems im: tate in regard to the Late Rich Mortmorency instead of Late Richmond. I had rymen are about as ignorant Montmorency, the large nne, *hfr Dorr's place this chmond </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 rly I y </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 Perhaps you all know in the subject of cultivation. I English Morello that cultiva- in takes it to keep warm uard againts heat. ratht ad two or th the roots of these carried our English mewhat heavy growth. We through the last two years the trees in a fair condition iltivation will not sons, but if there is an ei surface and gives them a \&gt;- twenty-five times original I got They did a- ill not stand our nd it. I am speaking Early Richmond. For Hamilton county mulching is just n raising of fruit ition has carried our kn^list; ■d nearly all of them, and gav&lt; lture. In what way does cul- y valuable in wet Bcnaona :' it. This particular orchard jrteen kinds when I markably well: thej )lantation in Colorado under r. and I planted, in the extrem&lt; on, I many kinds of cherries in in. The Montmorency i dard cherry. I have had ex </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">American Association of Nur- 1 had the pleasure of visit .:ia, through the courtesy and invitations of the tion in 1892, we n the planting. In ncreas ■tion contained nearly l(X),000 orchards containing \tlanta, v. ; to May i tion and ekman Bros., which contained 710 ly peach with a small a delightful dri- ly entertained by Berckinan Bros., &gt;kl fashioned Bai &gt;nsisting &gt;gs and other good things in propoi rvmen. The tabi under k, and the drive had created a Peaches were piled high upon the tablt n of the year w;i- delightful time in the to Ma topped over night. rchard of J. H. Hale, l-d contains 2, i lias iT t&lt; uind excelli lition. As Mr. Albaugh is - 1 note his w ng the orchard of peach. His I vi' the nurserymen a (1 his Willinghai F n s II 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 lining \ ■ y ■ three montl ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 : . off tlic limbs aiul M'lii. I thought fH APP \ I! AND prevalent in «'ll the more ■t killed. Tl apparent. [1 folia. ait by attacking th td drop early. Tin* than ii For instance, after the freeze in bloom, thi </seg>
            <seg id="p050">y </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 !)b\ ition uit ofth Hits ravish patches of a similar tee fig. 2). If the ley frequently drop </seg>
            <seg id="p052">spnn. I r from tl </seg>
            <seg id="p053">• </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 &gt;?*&amp;* &lt; 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 l)c changed «le to add t&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 1. Where the out difficulty it is per- chardist edarl ■t lonathan. and Wealthy. Of tl \v The Wealthv I ane. rounded by land ot luid Bordeaux of phatt v ad begun to ex s n all sides not a single tree SOIlIt :-chard, hint-' ih and cedar rusi Rallsi »Iaiden Blush, then ,1. The Rails incline in ptibli the from the m- direct - ying was given i from tht ivinic included et. Tin' </seg>
            <seg id="p058"/>
            <seg id="p059">59 A !:J 4 1 1 4 4 I hit t ,v V May A'ith \ d M nd tin lid M Jonathan M (1 p] ivini,'. May earh </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 t \ M </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 * to : ,! Jin. praying, Ma ibby fru nd Maid. 'ii Blush per cent on un • nd spnt n practically all cases, was tor spraying •rayinj early and on&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 </seg>
            <seg id="p063"/>
            <seg id="p064">■ i If th &gt;uld ind. I* nt S ! y in which i' " i found t to quit&lt;&gt; rigidly. To n 4 ]X)unds quicklin 4 jKiunds copper sulphat </seg>
            <seg id="p065">if II .V </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 but li for ;i ' "f not 1&lt;^ t»*n recommended, will iv. however, tor » 1 1 iere Ed orange colored ( i days or tw&lt; - during winte </seg>
            <seg id="p067">w 1 n any &lt; . d ■dar t rees. which know anything a I cannot killed by d &gt; cedar ti at I </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 t Mr. Hi li </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 t 1 ( M \ </seg>
            <seg id="p070">■ \\ C'HAll t 1 ! M tird in! orello. LA Mkmw en why ch&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 it tc think d I know will w Mr. s \v«. ill tin n|)s. There </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 H \ 1 A </seg>
            <seg id="p073">l.v il xpai tv t </seg>
            <seg id="p074">■ le dar - ke the drill n • kno* with less injury </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 tt til til. I 1) T IrtVS tilt dry in* quickly, and </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 t ( \ M 1 ( i \V - V r </seg>
            <seg id="p077">&gt; \ </seg>
            <seg id="p078">umu li En.'. Th. I' M in the worn out a run down condition of the lai Tl : th </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 ; Ai ; i I Anifi try. Th« t t t t t relv and uintries of the United fry country home. N«&gt;t liat we might be proud to : rom. We atural foi </seg>
            <seg id="p080">w i ind w lould thing By ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 Vnotlr anted t Hud plenty of ■ \v - nthis I v I /round and planl .vouhl prepare 1 1 1 &gt; 11 plant the plants with i ae plant. Plant just the i deep. Either is desi ru n the fall very little. 1). n&lt; r , not ini ire than oni id allow it Ni &gt;w about v ow and be happy with ■ than ot I lit the horticultural I ■ l ture through tl a solved. If it t i •y in aot ison, dry in aut t' you ha von hav&lt; grow canes and prow canes and &lt;1 a young planted a young !i i. Some obj Some obi' Yo them all I •in all t &lt;&gt;;_'■ - m when v t cf the </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 sap tlif inni&gt;.t ;i of the immnd in tli&gt; I Tl t nd w only in tl: currant in th« bum t Then or In nish want plant n v In UV'n dt-pth. I just ■ The the middle of t planted tiMi deep. 1' ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Wolf. "■ e Lombard and the Shippi Abundance. I words 11 if they wish t. if the state I would fitted that ) A. 15 I Thei the : largely - for mixing 1 .■an have plums by us Milton or ■ ■et a i lid rt'collilllt': fifty varieties. I: The are they tent, and th erimenting in an country is too o; s in you ' </seg>
            <seg id="p084">I would ut a . V. autumn. Nortl chart i i ■ you i kMu. Ma it. Th. order n </seg>
            <seg id="p085">&gt;ut if you &lt;!' )inpli -plant- be kept up? ind o nine lat time you wax- in I'd. to th»&gt; tact that Most &lt;&gt;f the hurt ■d to \\V can den would lik I don't &gt;wn (I ( it di&gt; 4 but jld be compi ftv miles north of dv weath&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 i Membkh: I Mk. Haki Mb. &lt; Mr. Wil \ dcro </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 \v dent .l.-l to (If II. I We mlH. Whil- lly on 4 from whai \s'k -till honing ■ tton grow ion &lt;&gt;f th&lt; have their hitfli I ... *^ ( . </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 n Nebraska be their ■ draw l).i. laving with d \\ ■ I il unt I. c I) </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 the apple teach ■ tli pplc ICC I it- fruit in .VI and the apple in to intermingle, m &lt;&gt;f tin- f 11 t ition and up-t&gt; it ■ ined out of ■ f. ind is in Do these thin'': ie ownt hard ton m I time and do more worh ■an on workinj. e willing to do better work. Fourth d worthless limbs id in- CHARDIXG IN N'KHK.x \11 of in . sun r 4 &gt; 1 irlv - t iV without in plai when </seg>
            <seg id="p090">lullv ( ■ ntidt We noted </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 and the mini. localities. We »ther and li v Ni'li nmn aiti V WO] 'in t n&lt;&gt; doubt in I iditions. Th&lt; 11-' tiT. and Hf plants vai Missouri than to ■ is good, a lar^ r «' r that growth iripe when wintei Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 county, one of twenty planted with Mi- \rkansa of tli luant Turning U Mr, H hitrh as The finest Jon </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 \ ,n^, nineteen miles south- kburn, fourteen miles south - ninety-three apple t From this on this orcl i with what apples they i ipples they &lt; : hundred and four b ashel,ori - rd two j ■ • varietu ind four bush- hard I ■ ntv liout i barg, Colo . N C. Roth sburtr. I Roth i orchard. At Mitchell, i ful orchard. At Mitchell, ; ng line, Mr. -iven an appl&lt; and p m an average cash value vomintr line, Mr. Ed •uliar feal growing fruit of crowing fruit ip. Under irrigation th&gt; ■ Whenever the orchard i fruit fruit . the pi the planter ig .v •n «_r enough to i uifh to i of fruit. In this i advant rkcd advantag s to that for in t! We it advant. . ■ advant 11 in the production oi ruit last fall round •hards in </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 kind i Mr. ' </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 by i Our confidem mtinuiriL.' iti-d tliis spring in a Wv. W more fruit v 1&lt;« arkei \IS1N( et I • </seg>
            <seg id="p096"/>
            <seg id="p097">97 further Y( \Vi&gt; which nt ■ I in 'I till now w&lt; (ported and this col ■ in bringing new tiling I am quite well. I y and have is they will \MKNTALS which t. I&gt;-t ub!&lt;&gt; ones, very n&lt;&lt;l&lt;\ blood prolific of all June till Novemtx </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 1 \ </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 ,v i n (• ii r </seg>
            <seg id="p100"/>
            <seg id="p101">101 {( &gt;M i I I Ill . y&lt; &gt;u .1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p102"/>
            <seg id="p103">103 ■ i T 1 ,v 1 the i V l)uvinK a t rt ,vith ilxmt (1 too hard, pro - planting. N ation at onct II shovels you can r four inches wide the line to &lt; ten days, plants. Hy 1 then you nj^c'i old I planting, issible to plant ly in the Thei r buy nt n that y when j^ood condi n a bucket ransfer from tht» </seg>
            <seg id="p104">**N </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 th. t M ml of a hac 1 in thinking the nial (1 knowing th;it ti&gt; ardcn is soil is standing X na n onsii not what you id understand ah without planted; or, if by inated l),v tl • a failure Mut by your ground </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 1 \ that v n my i the plant, and upon in- fs in - about tin • ce what I ha\ it mai y, and I want to say this, ition about it, and you 1 the I the fifth, you will n , and all at once you tind our rows tiling that patches. For in n furnish these requis likely with i (t until after the head that is alre - ■&gt;(■ tliis is )&gt; nutict' what I have six&gt;ken from that ground and &gt;vith ii iching v-i by itscli li the old pro rt, and bank&lt; t in di&gt;t;i extremely rich ground .imls the p early poi </seg>
            <seg id="p108">u </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 will last from oin the i nouidi ltfi. V,,u planting a raft upon iage there In on I. nk a 1l&gt; mid not but I tter ■ &lt; na, \\ III' L M.- and 1 tli kind nan to ini on a very larg tion cost him mother _ lour students ir.v of po - und tile </seg>
            <seg id="p110"/>
            <seg id="p111">111 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 1 ality I want rmers institute continue to send feel confident is well taken. I mil she planted her , and then she blamed the hie stuff attend the agricultural lint . of time on I ind horticulture. ind we want those farm i'ir own farms during the y more for a six months ir. During the inn they are getting aluable education as we e for nine months in all the tim&lt; original moisture. 1 fro,, i K've the vtT\ tecause \\ 1&lt;&gt; which is wortl ,v irrigation? x months in the year, i utter part of April. V A-ork. Pore I about cultivating tht rop. fit by plowii ly, of harrowing, </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 In till;' - tivat ■ &gt;ut in tin happened to see him a culti </seg>
            <seg id="p115">115 toll vou doing 111'' Mtli. inl«\ t which Ml iittU &gt;t ti &gt; pay ind it dix's not buying f this man is "join^ t« \ </seg>
            <seg id="p116">t ■ will tint! Tl six months i n* during tl s. Tin - months. \\V </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 would be it would bulletins that are pub- - T int? (1 be. Tli t\ hat is a very isehold econorn ion to have a building of, ami then we &gt;e along this line, ttl. agriculture &lt;1 ] making id now at the University Bouton. who I think t import that I edui-a ition is all. t i nt Ri is it is T il ]&gt;er r oina i tit-ant us t entertain and he </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 iriel tion i ■; continu ml and fra thy ed t( Mos (1 then the i is iin occasion LC&lt;x&gt;d enoi; oi prof- ment to he woi i ne.v in e hundre illy ilur sion. In St map ot - requiren vnd is nearer wh. f the cliiss. It is henhouse. The ad hybrid teas. .olden Gate, Minnie ■ rein Aug </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 will have another The bread winni A not hard P growing n from tlic when planted in I •apply or four ii luring t! d noi </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 ed an nd one ot ruit which 1 runt on- mon fruit .md it lias st that particular dis he death of a fruit tree may ular ions or im tant part. Any or ■ of the death of the it the same time ntil after the firs 'rail OF I'lMMT TR1 &gt;st importani int. dis inds, hailstorms odents, and </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 t \ The mid through </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 bli^hi of thf Po lirl.y son for the failure rently noi nous - st(K-k and make the which attach </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 n nail is unknnwi arKA f • h round </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 the t rrv can })&lt; iX tin ni ■oijnizetl !&lt;■ fungus it ne shot-bole ildew in i, and the heart rot (/' rious in negh the fungus obtains a foothold there is ,vn rot and mildew ought not il sprayed the d hich has done so much urin&lt;r the past t us. is by y of the cherry d The y industr braska is ally the Rich lit 'ports it &gt;ctions of the twenty per cent of the early A r thr&lt; Morellos and other chei e will run over ninet ■. killed. Estimates fn&gt;ni it the damag ed by roni my ol that the damage \v is no I to. It - sible to </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 til </seg>
            <seg id="p127">t Statt Hall. State I </seg>
            <seg id="p128"/>
            <seg id="p129">129 1 i i i ■ i i ! ■ 1 Ball Farm, Lincoln, ). in., with President ('In gram, which t on tab A. M to Know? School of Agriculture President Christy \V A. Anderson, Ord St. \a&lt; K. M. I &lt; 'i ( \V. Putrsley. Woodbine. Iowa M. Howar - Bluff E. I J. H. Hadkinson, Omaha Univ« ivd, Hastings </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 (if I ) know II position tig w c in </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 I (1 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">133 S! ( ( S s I t </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 l)Ut W </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 I'M CMKUKIKS I in \ wild plui my I nd hills" and in abundant I hthai uliar w Tl il the ting i ml w Tl dune r i wild wt 1 tea number «l _nn-d hit ■ .Hid th&lt; intinj' they bl&lt;&gt;&lt; at when ri|X ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 Eil in at la ml </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 I </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 f V 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 r I ' 1 an&lt;i We t ( t \ t </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 </seg>
            <seg id="p141">141 ruit ittra o tit t* i N i t I th D v \s I the ( M \ ( </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 ■ h rat &lt;1 v </seg>
            <seg id="p143">143 fr. \ 1 for ,v St. I l).v - s X ( s &lt; N llt'V Hon. ( v </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 H 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p145">145 t I) </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 i r ! N M </seg>
            <seg id="p147">147 lit t. tu t der \ n and r S W ,v t X ) (t </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 </seg>
            <seg id="p149">149 s s )an W </seg>
            <seg id="p150"/>
            <seg id="p151">151 Hen he \U'n XKi nkins med Dver hey said, to K Uvn Davis TIk'v lollars p&lt; Da ;::r tlu- lit I5&lt;&gt;n Davis i rough Davis ?v Ben </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 H.'ll I); M ( l» i &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p153">rni .1. I ) Ben l&gt;;i is thi 1 x N yar \ t et w </seg>
            <seg id="p154">154 r carry on t would likt \ : ( C I </seg>
            <seg id="p155">155 we drew up a all over the </seg>
            <seg id="p156">Tii - don&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p157">157 ndofthe ■t lii«h looking privili and it is (1 tWi Had tl - (i ■ \l y.D ( nin-r. The ( t l\ id ln-avil n&lt;c kinds do t u^ht aid arc the won the small fruits, - rawberries and t! 1 the ■• *1 quality, and .],,.■ j rricrai i"ll </seg>
            <seg id="p158">158 will </seg>
            <seg id="p159">159 ill. and we find - and the for you further from til furrows a little nds flooding d&lt;H'S Oil' er flooding and owed and fitted for ht mam plants t ontinual iadi in when yo a th«* iterinc the allow oistuiv in the 1 it To know i us th. distant </seg>
            <seg id="p160">160 \ </seg>
            <seg id="p161">I 161 I igain. However, I will r ■dling work in Minnesota. We are c, and are quite proud of t this wi ng apples a good ted Hut the one of grar nderful variety in many ectioi i autumn apple, it is When Mr. Gideon origi or age d it after his wife. After Mr. Gidi xperiment station for the purpo» In connection with this we went to re now trying to get the | rtly before Mr. ' wenty or thirty thousand M xperimented with them. This work - ago, and w&lt; 'ting They look nice and mak&lt; Horticultural Society offered dling apple that should be ive the good quality of the Wealthy, Malinda. That mon&gt; iraska can have it i: ind there is no humbug Horticultural Society we dlinp apples of merit. So you see courage the growing of seedling a ill Ret a lot of varieties that are well era Mini We have a seedling committee ninittees in fact. One of these this one thousand dollar premium. - that have been made in competi- t are from ten of the northern nk. Then we have another seedling committee on ■s growing throughout the state. I •ught to have a seedling committee </seg>
            <seg id="p162">162 ■ ■ ind uuld rt»]xirt d nat • DR. H you i 1 which Surprise in my opini&lt; Minn&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p163">163 had trouble Montana people had on lmended as doing v out in tine condi- With us the Wealthy is a irly winter apple. It ml a equality lingiy fin&lt; d for this plum is all right. i &gt;ns oi" re - will now pass on to the next number Horticulture.' 'by Mr. E. P. Stephens STERN HORTICULTURE Nebraska unties of ; Central and n practically unknown horticulturally. vening to the fact however that there icts as well suited to the u' iul Colorado counties to the vahV oup rivers, which at • a depth of from four t' dand i &lt;&gt;u have here i word about the country. 11 il tfood and capable of irri- »• million acres is already i we l, jiderable are , •( *^ t vo </seg>
            <seg id="p164">164 I are no quarrels bet wet' 0 no litigation in tl by nature &gt;nt advant but .f K-n fe • •no llen&lt; ■ me of tlie finest .Tonatliar Nil id p o irr struct th uminer will be ( w niven fertile </seg>
            <seg id="p165">165 A ntir i ( Nurtl A t I) N I ( Myers six miles south of K of extraordinary size and d orchard of D. C. Blackburn in - of Grimes Golden gave 'ruit. From less than an acre of milies and marketed six-hundred le sui In Lincoln county of the Missouri river, irri- thy and promise large profits. a bushel and three pecks • found suceesssful are Duchess, hues Golden, Utters Red, Plum ening, Jonathan, Ben Davis, Wine - tern Greening, and Janet, vo-hundred and fifty to three-hun- ■ iuri river :. and M. in extreme western sip, and Jonathan have suffered &gt; may be remedied by protecting ies for that region are found in a - Greening which are equally vein 1 twenty one varieties of bud - lummer, their third r-old trees drooped under the s without a failure. h hardier than those includes for that region are found in a Jthy, Whitney N&lt; To this may In the David Hunter of Omaha, peach I ; far i ..odgepole, and at yoming line. i planting </seg>
            <seg id="p166">166 W ( H ( v N vn N i </seg>
            <seg id="p167">167 ,va differs very little from that The great aim is to con- frequent shallow culture. a, and should August. During the months the ground should be tirst y freeze up wet. Until in dependence should be matures should have an y grow to large siae and &gt; 1 buds earlier and therefore rn Nebraska ighten the outlook for ska. That part of the fruit upon which the When those uit V Neb 1 i s hould be allowed icn aepenaenue siiuum ire When tht' 1 into ds planted at an with bright sun- illy manufactured for this g the branches back is of tern Nebraska. s fail to bud out within two uliar method. Construct he trunk of the tree up to .1 and keep it moist. ion of gap, but will enable I will almost This treatment is of par ihad&lt; who s can leave ti I soil nn the earth once in thirty &gt;uld be kept dry. </seg>
            <seg id="p168">United States by far than the fruit distrk Utah, Idaho and Washington. Western N fast freight trains on trunk well lands we grow, Mi. - all did IV S( Tr. inde &gt;ad -!&gt;ortation. T corn me i' Id lik&lt; I und&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p169">169 t South-I &gt;, s ) to go before that asso- So I move then that a com - o find out when and where this increments to wait on them and \ B usually found that we can get kk! reason for it. xpect to ask for anything that is stern Nebraska Fruit Growers' .1 a committee of five on their committee will appoint, of their number to see the Trafii i at ion meeting if 1's motion is all right. If we t something reasonable. There - much interested in this luced by Mr. E. F. Stephens ty: iblications of this society havt Historical Society rooms ■d by t xtends its hearty good will and storical Society to secure gislaturt \i SION 1 to meet and confer ition until 2:00 P. M ciety on application ■ to freight r &gt;tion to the effect </seg>
            <seg id="p170">170 s T 1 ,V Ki 1 11 jiein i&gt; 1 Thi </seg>
            <seg id="p171">171 d in • nikl. mman f&lt; s lature mbles demic und illy ad 111(1 it : which tained and ircuit \ ■d that bai aftii t. Such lint d now generally n time of rapid al nature of dise; ha nt pathology es an important branch table h for nment Bureaus i ith a truth that ner will as little mil patholi \ ut a knov </seg>
            <seg id="p172">172 a captair j n&gt;i [V t i of anatomy or a sailor hope to becomt ing navigation. " Even though tl know much about how plants live and i, much of his information mu: • . The old time botanist, ■ig needles, and possibly compound relation to the mo of the middle nl laboratory n bine a k in regard t of an &gt; wn limit • rt who Plan- n wli n art ■ fluei ! ch of plant '■ulturist: tli&lt; I naturally fall to tl the i]) tl D ins iliar with th&lt; product rilliant re </seg>
            <seg id="p173">md much is being accom- lly ii direct scientific value but of horticulturists and v work as preeminently y, altho in the broadest appliea - 1 inorganic, and insect troubles f the methods used in in tic organisms that I wish iot my purpose to enter int&lt; ent methods that may be used by the ridedly complicated, but to character of the work possible ints that are important as tht of our cultivated plants: the il have no hesitation in using the •rtance of these simplest of all or- nan activity has made the name a the smallest living organisms Probably not many of you have sen their devastatioi •e- blight. 1 ' that deadly die niliar to all of you. What llions. The nough 1 le tree in the state of Nebi ou an idea of their minutent'ss. If v side, their total thick t in Another way: I should h. ight germ ines to get a body irnation rust, yet that is almost be- lin, I should have to multiply this irge as a number seven shot. If numi g a hollow sphere, 1 to spare inside it for something like acteria. Such statements are of ve you an idea of the minutent tnge then considering their minute - the methods for studying and hand- a single sheet of rny manu- </seg>
            <seg id="p174">lintf ' 1 »ia' I nt tin Th S (1 &lt;&gt;t apple, cberrj like in a Thf advaiw until re&lt; priii </seg>
            <seg id="p175">175 ! s, but it lifold prol plication &lt;&gt;f the study of ■(■suits in ! ■ ■s his ord id analine Idinir bat! lowers had to prow his n ler in 01 urns kinds, his difficulties would a a ho wished to study ba&lt; i. The horticulturis &gt;s out The plant patho s blight ind moulds t ardn&lt; id grow thorn u irt "f an art and fun&lt;ii, wh le plant. Jusi ent purpo ria and : far more delicate in se plants, and cons i-ying ■ ■ as in a bed in such into the soil, you </seg>
            <seg id="p176">Sundering tht aismi inn pure cult things that have to net th nint • entu: and fun inutei i.v l) t 11 ir ry m t \v but little bet were tirsi btained . it of the beyond ;i question that a \i ite, four steps involving ime in laboratory and green-ho The denn ganism with the d&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p177">177 f the i -• estimated that </seg>
            <seg id="p178"/>
            <seg id="p179">179 i llent res i. •eding is I (1 plicated methods that perfect for the proa ind laboratory, it is not mlated results of nin&gt; i knift it and ixperieni irs. that in d nt K»'t a blight in abject, and I be h of proD ulturists, and prac- ■■rs to still fur- Jtion of the m that the plant • ientitic study of ndation. Much to the futur. ■i had becom&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p180">M </seg>
            <seg id="p181">181 K)d mow? g. I whom ited x it (I &lt; \n tind simi Now it is this &gt;f life, trying T for ire his ructure they animal: </seg>
            <seg id="p182">182 inp things, th&lt; r n </seg>
            <seg id="p183">183 namely t: 1 ; • th a plant: it must t. and if any of the t will suffer ood constitui ently suffer for r injure their ti^ : common in n works ■ part it will pa t And i II enough ist have what we call a the constitm body arc pres- Now and t regions ther&lt; &lt;1 by the appli </seg>
            <seg id="p184">184 I / </seg>
            <seg id="p185">185 «U t t t!i •t •h or luc f is not th the </seg>
            <seg id="p186">186 nary </seg>
            <seg id="p187">187 manifest. V sufticent supply of that it suffers from identical with through in into a making heti king fticient andc nit blow than with weeds in young, and at the fruit gt n their work on his Still able t&lt; ,vinds. Allied to through - We Now ■ (spon vintr the nuch UHlK tinlv </seg>
            <seg id="p188">188 </seg>
            <seg id="p189">189 iidvt'i K.XIMM and ■pointed a comni H. GreenandJ. H. Hadkinson, to tl n " • xllinjj </seg>
            <seg id="p190">1 »URTH - I). I . </seg>
            <seg id="p191">Soil, cli oduction of all considerable ex ity.ani modified only ch man can do. The soil, or id. when exhausted by ex- it divide from the Missouri xtr so many dist Ii rn ■ ura I n -fall, are the tween the Platte and ility than in s and while te wi iust have </seg>
            <seg id="p192"/>
            <seg id="p193">i </seg>
            <seg id="p194">194 I plant: </seg>
            <seg id="p195">Win. .)• John Smit IllZil (1 horticultural - columns something of some bud cnowledKe gent ind just could for his in ry one to be a Harrison or a Stevens. I do to one of </seg>
            <seg id="p196"/>
            <seg id="p197">197 . ml 111 n II I n lontv t&gt; t doi I </seg>
            <seg id="p198">198 I) I) •( ii n ( *( ■ t </seg>
            <seg id="p199">199 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p200">V / ! \ ♦ </seg>
            <seg id="p201">201 ( 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p202"/>
            <seg id="p203">mpy, ne t rut'. Keiffer pears, I had ! \v&lt; Kt " I noticed that the I decided tl on and l» </seg>
            <seg id="p204">204 \ 1) </seg>
            <seg id="p205">t </seg>
            <seg id="p206">Only t </seg>
            <seg id="p207">207 t i very urge sked I ilk'd upon to oil, or explain to </seg>
            <seg id="p208"/>
            <seg id="p209">209 OF PRUNING nsw of u-sil ommon To re •owtl Hi's xl t&lt;- it ion of ;i large num - ■owtli ol it having infill, «'.s The removal of ]&gt;S O|M&gt;nS pa its sunsciild. ilso destroy the nches represent a (I liavc been directed to used in building abom ol the </seg>
            <seg id="p210"/>
            <seg id="p211">211 Ki t und Dortiur lect and the hea •njrthof tli </seg>
            <seg id="p212">212 t t to K&lt;&gt; "N v C&gt;d arc </seg>
            <seg id="p213">213 this paper pass, and I Mr. Williams says. ! s bes \1 would vou think it ■vorth while to diameter. Wounds v rapidly if the cut off at all wil tlnn-r sonnt'i too large night in in close Whit. tore yesterday, and 0 offer now, but I do ad the opportunity of this good meeting. I dressing wou it'll from jeaper thing 1 ha*. .'(I from </seg>
            <seg id="p214">H &gt;rt for iiful </seg>
            <seg id="p215">I i til rnt&lt; Norway t!i o 11 to UK ml it in He ought stalk any a man s s &lt;&gt;r coming ument. Let nted thesi is von can. an </seg>
            <seg id="p216">216 111 ten .i transplanted. You should p&lt; ir own sti&gt;dliiiL'N l»l of tin-in People ;t, M will I I 11 fairly well. The Jack pine . ornamental I others ad then 1 - and then thi on«- of tli«' hardiest, thrifties «th skil ■,'ush </seg>
            <seg id="p217">217 ■d the tii- v of them d handling. Ann nvth borvitae idvised me n thrifty and hardy. the ink was dry, ' iind IS tl 1st w id is now X one - right in t raising thing like this i tiful in tlif summei verm? town rd the i ■ n brown. Did I say 1 .vhcn we think of a good man then goes wrong, and The lied Cedar, like tin- In d civiliza in .1 him. recommended was awakened in the prop . we did not want to know nvented the process of having! He had them by the n him. The blight wiped out They could not stick to is just to grow and i iey got ambitious ng at them at a distant but a near inspection sh&lt; apple trees had been playing Well, t 1 mil it </seg>
            <seg id="p218">218 I \]&gt;osi I ha S </seg>
            <seg id="p219">219 t&gt;d hard t&lt; her side drop tht'ii ,vith &lt;r&lt;«ul t d uix&gt;n it 1 think it is ;i short K. Douglas Stir &gt;rtli Whit.- r which will . inv otlit'i-. and \lpimi sun. th.- R I 'on he fall. It wlit-n it is very young in be raised by th» old from the a green that grows when once • ■n anywhere in th&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p220">E north-west where with car« jplo have had ;i prejadioe against t transplant them readily from the T I think \ QOUffh. I li; I 1 could ind ditr tl I could sa had perl I kn&gt; KHitll ii,- The Phr b»&gt;lt. hut it has n&lt;&gt; hi </seg>
            <seg id="p221">221 Concolor and the Pun They cannot be^rown (1 should be sandy killful men should v facility should he for the i bv the million, It would pay for - t ontracts for plant there is no pi '['he I'. S. Experiment Stai production. Per xperience with ■ •ymen p A plunging rain inal ided, and mus Land invaded by angle v among the worst pests the and that one iiul pliable, and the} short time, and it may be ; ind a s ndred fold. The blizzards of be checked, and wt mmic-r v Whi -tilled with ti \\ e a delightful sanitarium. Tl nd grow well it • urdy </seg>
            <seg id="p222">H* </seg>
            <seg id="p223">n&lt;l nut tnrist /. 1 by ap Yet n n Northern \ ,r in ( )&lt;t&lt;»l»'i- and tarrying un d dil dark Tlic other Northern now These t« s ititT having the r has </seg>
            <seg id="p224">224 s \ I) </seg>
            <seg id="p225">\ ' Smiir K rrow, (.'hip s Northern Si y-two p (thai (thirty nine i i consumed, &lt;ind ■■ </seg>
            <seg id="p226">i white ir W northern econom i i ■of wild fruit </seg>
            <seg id="p227">t the hitter incl Caterpillars a ndred o) </seg>
            <seg id="p228"/>
            <seg id="p229">229 S s .v Jt d liri </seg>
            <seg id="p230">\ \ t </seg>
            <seg id="p231">231 t xaminat ! I Ma\ and w &gt; es 1 1 regular]] </seg>
            <seg id="p232">232 </seg>
            <seg id="p233"/>
            <seg id="p234">234 </seg>
            <seg id="p235">235 it, plant &gt;ur per cent, plant slightly oaten. racter as th lurgum i s. wild g onstitutes t altogether constitutes elevei liscussed in detail in (1 in detail ii (i Wood bellied Wood-pecker the heavier tin heavier timberol but little part in the It is not very fond of in - i. while tiring that it plays but little part in the hards. It is not very fond of in wenty six pereentofits food;ai n. wl.il- y the adults, which I the adults, which form t of larvae. Cat. l greedily. Tru v. The wild fruit ntir wild grapes, Virginia and raa 'I s - ( '" rn ls ies thus d' A'Kl- ,re both present ndant eastwardly the these birds are well they the accompanying illus illy identical and will bt </seg>
            <seg id="p236">Mitinu of'them. Fli( </seg>
            <seg id="p237">237 </seg>
            <seg id="p238">I) 11 al list t </seg>
            <seg id="p239">1 and Fir Btictirium amy iiisinu tli it ion ol t . Is of the 1 ■•■ Rot, ill circuiai lintr circle </seg>
            <seg id="p240">1 t . I ,v mv \\ </seg>
            <seg id="p241">241 II L 11 111 III.V with Bordeaux as where there ike tht' form uni^us known Hot ('anker, which occur* Mitt Hot fungus ■ occur &lt;&gt;n any age, but is more likely to ltrh and cracks las b&lt; \ mixtur ■ il should bi and tw mi ation, savs t!. ir two cli pillar ;emei of the ground Kjome &lt;|uit&lt;' large nutrition. Th&lt; •'round, hut if tli« general sickly appearanc**, An examination s r* »&lt; &gt;t s ;it and </seg>
            <seg id="p242">242 tell I ird w 15 A .1.1 // 11 I </seg>
            <seg id="p243">243 Inch rob the Botany of th* T ry. are dew which c erv coat. Tl 'ii be iresrreatly wind. ind eive rist illy llfl'ICill nnugh t&lt;&gt; b 1 (1 w Dr. Bes &gt;wn as Id \Vh«»n it i y Kenm skin is finally to a nink color rown and the ina\ urrents of air, by the apples art&gt; in j)iles </seg>
            <seg id="p244">244 U T &lt; s \ V </seg>
            <seg id="p245">245 J* -- y t </seg>
            <seg id="p246">246 e f -*i / % 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p247">247 If eked 1&gt;.\ ssur I «■ first at tin- i iind pt t '■ lit'!- I) t t (1 by &lt;lf ct rat -inuul ;mil in ,V1 ynij; \v&lt;&gt;. ..•s to living wound it Oklahoma station thai I Hi' on tht' trunks of the tn \ SIX I ditch </seg>
            <seg id="p248">248 HI A n </seg>
            <seg id="p249">249 r/n/llo n inc-Ii in r.l find s of an d to tfivt A spraying in rt M&gt;n a pray n days I Bor Tlir would ollows in th&lt; soon as lowt-i </seg>
            <seg id="p250">y tin N N \ i I' \l)l(lc 1 s • ■ l ( 'in. * </seg>
            <seg id="p251">251 - i'. Horticulture! I known i: itt&lt;Mi more in ss of con I' I to show in ural I Ex 1 &gt; Orona, Me Newark, Del n y \gricultui Hrum CONTROVERSY The in at tlh </seg>
            <seg id="p252"/>
            <seg id="p253">253 and until iftirni. •own of th( sor Selby in bulletin liM i i'u-Ii causes this sort of produce the And in bulletin 1 1 1 he 'd on bv the &lt; &gt;h plantation affected nil to the extent • he A dime's yrown n n int i-i&gt;duced. showed a inii bun :id to show that from w! spindlii &lt; ill of tl the n '&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p254"/>
            <seg id="p255">255 hut t I bright and &gt;ted entirely to m Ml authoritii ould be rt'jc KISON AS DELEGATE TO THI ULTURAL SOCIETY. Mini n &lt;&gt;f tli«» 1 nade it merit. Ni 1 and hen tic band of t* | &gt;uslit*d &lt; &gt;n to ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p256">256 1 Pliev </seg>
            <seg id="p257">257 nir and d A S Carrv this (u ml it M ■ Manitoba. r i X.' A St I'; - )W was only one "f it, t tandin^by the original Concord jri-ape is; that humble nding new things, in (be fields of ibraska and Terry &lt;&gt;f read an extremely interesting M Mail: ■ onditions wou The wri1 &lt;&gt;ntf and garden. He •f flowers ful ■ ban diamond*, which t&lt;&gt; thousands of horn- bad :n en put </seg>
            <seg id="p258">258 11 H w I' \V S &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p259">1 ,v i r I ■ is rev. I ■ Uukintt w lev fall. H t I t t \ </seg>
            <seg id="p260">260 in M tion i </seg>
            <seg id="p261">261 er t&gt; ■ ( Will ■ral mi SSIOll with pra&lt; shintfton t t'tTort that manv i i nd ■ w ntv I think th (I [( jrht t llnitf </seg>
            <seg id="p262">262 I ■* </seg>
            <seg id="p263">263 determii plan! olored fruit. The -.but w full of we was the Rom entionetl '■ ond would !)• • the e Montinorency a "»&lt;l 1 lie' oven that Un- ions here. I i.l th.- Warfield, b. i and clii ;tl &lt;&gt;t her vai {INC SIIKIHS ndlv donated bv liev </seg>
            <seg id="p264">264 it litt A I thirl [ do dr.iv. i tin \| </seg>
            <seg id="p265">265 ( &gt;ctober and berries was with &gt;gg Company of Thre ime the ad planned, and Will report fully on this &gt;&lt;&gt;Z EXPERIMENT STATION //■ i attend the is follows ive mad' ral plats, altogether a I. Kain is sufficient driest land in the ,\11 the Plum ' Others lil September. ■ty tiiii and loaded with the indv land mak&lt; i I predict th outdo th' commercial way. In better soils and n en varieties of i" ■ ■:. and tli - rill. s. </seg>
            <seg id="p266">266 le ti kill \v ■N. till' and plums are \v ■ hink it i id liardi </seg>
            <seg id="p267">267 xnd have not soph grown quite extensively gopher can be turned with a New - tickena orGrouse o contend with. There are thous - and tlif blossom bud ind fruit on, approve new variel inler m producing ne efforts ii in orchard . them . Executive Hoard ; ..f the NVbraska Kxt </seg>
            <seg id="p268">s i u r~mrr. - :&gt; W' IS w eeilt^ - j^ = \T&gt;x ; — - !■ * \ | 1 — * M i i«5 - </seg>
            <seg id="p269">■ ■(I the matt ;d Pawn. mnend i plant intj (.'.Hiii. rly Whil s Maide nintc. M )• - lundf nt ■ Transparent. Cole's Quince. - lied. M v. Flora Belle. Plumb's Cider, Fan s I McMahon's Whiti i no. Wine Sap, Windsor, Jonathan. N W, Greening, Salome, Ingrain. 1? end Missouri Pippin and Iowa ton. Thurston, Wayne, ) COMMITTEE ON REDISTRICTING THK STATE. u' list of fruits and orna- in^r in Nebraska, i Hintics of Richan 1 |). .lull:: ppir, and Vi nf, r Cass, Sarpy. Douglas, recon henango Strawbei lican Summer I ' </seg>
            <seg id="p270">Duchi - - </seg>
            <seg id="p271">271 mil S R«d, Patton's i, X. \V.(, M. 15. TwiR. ' I, Minkltw Boone, Nance IX njf varieties i dec! for </seg>
            <seg id="p272">&gt;■ 272 To be added fo Wine Sap. ■ml &lt;hok pin, and Walbridg Suinn H \ W Goldei Por I) Suiiii) White, Red Ju Autumn: Wealthy ning, Wolf River, and Winter: Wine £ ing, .Janet. Baton Blush. Grin ind Hi For District No. 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p273">); ■ 1 ( idan ni </seg>
            <seg id="p274">274 in up ict 1" i \\\ ■ w I) r- damp 94 IA.r I- </seg>
            <seg id="p275">275 nd Early Richmond, ral plantin ly Richmond, Mont Dye! Y irlv Richmond, Mont v Richmond Dvt'hou v Richmond, Dye 'stheim Early Richmond, Mont 1 V 1 I)\ • Early Richmond, I dw i-ly Richmond, Mont nd Early Richmond, Baldwin. Dvehou&gt;- 1 Early Richmond, Dye i h Morello Early Richmond lv liichmond, Mont ) ■lloand Terry ni'ly Richmond, English 1 1- </seg>
            <seg id="p276">X i» I » </seg>
            <seg id="p277">Victoria ( &lt; Victoria 1 Lu. ,v 1 Dwarf Jam I). H In 11 r ). n H"ii&lt; r hton. anil ) H Houj'hton. and A </seg>
            <seg id="p278">278 strict N&lt; * end C agtn I) It </seg>
            <seg id="p279">pion, Crosby. Hill's Chili, Early R'w Wright for general tnd for trial in balaiv [Yiumph nl.v Alexander, II \insm ( "ooled nd Hill's Cl pion. Triumph, id -iid Early Champion, Crosby. Alexander. Triumph, or trial. ml Wi onimend Alexander. Triumph. ler, Kari.v Ri 1 'hili. Wright, ider, Kari.v Rivers, Hill's Chi: Early \l \lexandei Bai-tlett. Sheldon. Flemish Beauty, </seg>
            <seg id="p280">280 \ I \ </seg>
            <seg id="p281">W 1 ( </seg>
            <seg id="p282">I&gt; 282 District No. 14. Wyant. Garden. Hawkeys, and Lombard. St ict N&lt; • : .watt Dis Turn* For Dis Fur 1 1 - Cumberland. I For District No. 1 sommend Foi and De Wolf, and W ■ &lt;.'uiiil&gt;&lt; For Dis </seg>
            <seg id="p283">( ( \Y ) Sainj IISTRICTING THE STATE. BAKB erkies id Wartield are Pistillat- nmend Senator Dunlap. Splendid, , and August Lather. •o Splendid, ami nato • 'nd Mederwood, Wartield. ( we recommend the following vari- and \ erwood, Brandywine, Clyde, lendid are Staminate or ted with Staminate varieties for we recommend Senator Dunlap, mple, and Warfield. amend Senator Dunlap, Splendid ndy. itor Dunlap. end Senator Dunlap. Warfield, nd Senator Dunlap, Warfield, Splendid. commend Senator Dunlap nator Dunhi :ent. Dunlap. Sample. ,v(«ai </seg>
            <seg id="p284">284 1 tl I». </seg>
            <seg id="p285">285 perdowa Weeping Elm Weeping Birch. t Whit.' Birch </seg>
            <seg id="p286">286 stnut (S. E. part stnut Ex h Eropean Mt. Ash K-k Walnut. Hors. f (.'lit an ()] Butternut. Maple .an M &gt;erry in Quince : anjrt ut. Sprue&lt; I'unp E~-i&gt;ruci A. .1 C. B &lt;;. n. Ti ;phe&gt; SKINS </seg>
            <seg id="p287">287 ( SECRETARY'S REPORT. drawn on the Treasurer: 'ing ■ 12 00 &gt; rankG. Stephi tolllino W I porting winter meeting stone, I)ray;i_ - shed t State Farm for - furnished ai irmfor Lun&lt; l , Ml: uul Expi from lowa i. M. Russell, , M. m i; , M try 1 M. Russell, S 1 S H Mim'L' fiiT* &lt;t:itinn&lt; \*Ml*»ntin^» :trn] StiK-k for stations Valentine and M. Kellogg &lt; Si ck for Valentine station Balance reporting winter meeting I u lit'in Summer in( ( ngers, !'■ I'tM- diem Sumn I ing H. &lt; Jreen, Per diem H S. Harrison. Marshall. I 4 J. I rt pay reporting Summer meeting North A: Co., Printing programs \V I 1 Fair 1 m G W C 11. Ha lid ihi </seg>
            <seg id="p288">1 B. I. I. 141 ('. B. ■ - i;. t. ( (&gt;. M 151 &lt; L. Men. I ). W. .1. M. Ko Inhn I&gt; A. 1' i 171 John Peekn 172 Qui .1. M. Russ&lt; 174 Stoke nuttc 177 Smith 0. EL Trii </seg>
            <seg id="p289">289 ■ , 1 &lt;, </seg>
            <seg id="p290">290 Arnold M \ .1 G c II I. W L. M. Ru 121 L. M. R« L. M. Ru 1-J4 Marshall Hi rjr, &lt;■ mm R. M Kell 127 .1. W Bre t </seg>
            <seg id="p291">1 </seg>
            <seg id="p292">171 John i i lillei J. M. Ri unutt 177 17- &lt;&gt;. R. Ti 1 Ray 11.- s i:,t G. N l 1 1 c H. G I Gi &lt;;. A. .Mai W. .). lilvs L. M. Ru8 \. \iix,Xh &amp; »b Nort] Miller &amp; I'aine L. M. Ku L. M. Ru Nebraska Pftper A Dr. A T. I'.- L. II. Bus </seg>
            <seg id="p293">293 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p294"/>
            <seg id="p295">295 : t u </seg>
            <seg id="p296">296 </seg>
            <seg id="p297">297 a lnr &gt; 1 </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>