<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00032">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00032</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>State Wide Activities of the College of Agriculture</title>
               <date value="1923-01">1923-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">December, 1922 Pram Mth Annum! Report 100 Worth While Accomplishments of the College of Agriculture the Past Two Years AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE College of Agriculture of the University of Nebraska exists for the purpose of educa - tion, experimentation, and dissemination of agricul - tural information thruout the State. It aims to give a maximum of assistant* in the solution of practical farming problems to everyone who ask&lt; for it. If. after looking over tin- circular, you are inter - ested in some special feature, and would like to know how you can apply it to your own farm or your own problem, write to the college. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">100 Worth While Accomplishments of the College of Agriculture the Past Two Years 1. Enrolled an average of more than 1,300 students each year in its college, secondary schools, and short courses. 2. Published over 220 individual bulletins and circulars with an aggregate edition (including reprints of old bulletins) of over 800,000 copies. 3. Promoted the growing of seed potatoes in northwest Ne - braska, which today equals any region of the United States for the production of seed potatoes. Only a few years ago growers were importing seed potatoes from other states to Nebraska, not knowing that superior seed could be grown here. Certified seed potatoes from Nebraska now sell for approximately $360 per car more than table stock. Over 4,000 acres were listed for certifica, - tion in 1922. Nebraska dry land seed (certified) yields 100 bushels per acre more under irrigation than seed that has been irrigated two years. There are 10,000 acres of irrigated potatoes grown in Nebraska each year. The best varieties of potatoes for both the dry land and the irrigated districts of the State have been determined. 4. Developed and promoted the Nebraska type poultry house. More than 200 of these poultry houses have been built the last two years from plans furnished by the College. 5. Has the distinction of being the only college in the United States that has developed a cow that has produced more than 1.000 pounds of butter fat in a year. ♦".. Enrolled 4,559 boys and girls in 1921 and 5,857 in 1922, in 15 different clubs, promoting a practical interest in things agricultural. 7. Completed tests of 85 tractors sold in Nebraska, under the provisions of the law passed by the Legislature. v . Introduced a plan whereby dairy bulls are loaned to Ne - braska farmers by the College for the purpose of raising the standards of milk production. Farmers making uje of this plan must agree to keep milk and butter fat records on their herds and on the daughters of the bull. This is the most generous and far-reaching plan of the kind ever offered farmers by an agri - cultural college. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station. Circular 18 9. Distributed agricultural news and information weekly to over 700 newspapers and magazines. 10. Discovered that the farm tenant situation in Nebraska is not as serious as has been represented. Approximately 45 per cent of the so-called tenant farmers were found to be near - relatives of the owners, and did not belong to the strictly tenant class. A study was made of over 1.000 farms to secure these facts, which are now being published in bulletin form. 11. Developed and supplied 140 rural women's clubs with courses of study. 12. Has shown that calves produce beef on one-fourth less feed than older cattle. This work is now in its third vear. Bv a greater use of calves for feeding, more l&gt;eef can be produced with the same amount of total feed. 13. Completed a test of N00 hybrid strawberries and is now growing *&gt; of the l&gt;est hybrids for trial in various sections of the 14. Conferred the degree of Bachelor of Science in Agricul - ture upon 76 graduates, and the degree of Bachelor of Science in Home Economics upon 4(&gt; women graduates. 15. Installed experimental Hour mill and baking laboratory to study the milling and baking qualities of Nebraska wheat. Mills are giving more attention to buying wheat on the l&gt;a~w of these qualities and the work of the Station will l*&gt; of great assistance to Nebraska farmers in developing the&gt;e qtialiti 16. Answered inquiries regarding nearly 4(K) different kinds of insects. Gave individual advice to at least :5.000 Nebraska trmers regarding insect problems. Answered 160 to J(Kt such ;ters a month. 17. Gave 115 live stock judging demonstrations in Nebraska, with an average of iV2 people in attendance at each demonstra - tion. 18. Promoted the serving of hot lunches for school children in over 100 schools of the State. 19. Maintained a dairy herd of between 00 and 100 pure - bred cattle of the Holstein. Jersey. Ayrshire, and Guernsey breeds, with about 45 cows in milk. The average production of 44 cows in 1921 was 9,448 pounds of milk (391 pounds butter </seg>
            <seg id="p005">100 Worth While Accomplishments 5 fat), and the average of 47 cows during the first 10 months of 1922 was 9,291 pounds of milk (403 pounds butter fat). 20. Trained 17 agricultural college men for the profession of teaching and placed 13 of this number in Nebraska high schools as teachers of vocational agriculture. Trained 37 agri - cultural college women for the profession of teaching and placed 33 of thi&gt; number in Nebraska high schools as teachers of home economics. 21. Acted as host to lf&gt; fanners" organizations meeting at the college each year. 1-1. Introduced a plan of vitalized agriculture in 18 schools of the State, building toward a state-wide and practicable sys - tem of teaching agriculture in grade and high schools. •_'3. Placed college graduates in teaching positions or experi - mental work in colleges in Georgia. Kansas. Colorado. Michigan, Oregon. Iowa. North Dakota, Maryland. California, and Vir - ginia. u&gt; well a&gt; in the United States Department of Agriculture. 24. Completed barberry survey and eradication work in 65 omitii ■-. doing away with this notorious harl&gt;orer of wheat rust. 25. Conducted -1 state high school stock judging contests, in each of which more than 20 high schools entered teams. H Conducted 4 cattle feeding experiments, 4 sheep feeding experiments, and 7 hog feeding experiments, looking to reducing the &lt;&lt;&gt;&gt;t of meat production. Trained student stock judging teams which won first place nt National Swine Show at Peoria. 111., in 11)21, and second place at the -Internationa] Live Stock Exposition at Chicago in December. 19*20, with 21 college teams contesting. •2*. Carried out 58 drainage demonstrations on Nebraska farms. 20. Distributed farm account books to 7.000 fanners 30. Conducted short courses in general agriculture, veter - inary work, automobiles and tractors, poultry raising, and dairy - ing for fanners who could not s]&gt;end an entire semester in the college. 31. Carried on over 178 pruning and spraying demonstra - tion- in alHnit 25 counties. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 32. Exhibited champion grade and cross bred steer at In - ternational Live Stock Exposition in December, 1920; Champion Galloway steer, Champion Chester White barrow. Champion pen of Chester White barrows, and Reserve Grand Champion pen of barrows, at International in 1921. Exhibited Champion Hereford steer and Champion Shorthorn steer as well as Grand tpion beef carcass at Denver in 1921. At the January. Denver show, exhibited Grand Champion barrow as well tampion Chester White, Duroc Jersey, and Hampshire : &amp; ribbons on cattle, including Champion Angus steer, Re- Champion Shorthorn and Champion Herd of Shorthorns. $4,000 in prizes was won on stock at these shows. 33. Made inspections of dairy herds at 10 State institutions under the State Board of Control, an aggregate of 742 dairy cattle. Upon the recommendations of the college, scrub bulls at than institutions were disposed of. cows were better fed and cared for. methods of handling milk were improved, and milk production increased. 34. Answered 9,000 letters of inquiry regarding i&gt;oultrv from May 1, 1920. to October 2G. IMS. 35. Offered correspondence courses in agriculture. Since this work was established, 61 students have completed such courses. 36. Distributed information to 4,000 farmers regarding treatment of weevil-infested grain. 37. Carried on a Nebraska National Egg- Ikying Contest. Birds from different sections of the State and different farms were entered in a contest at the Agricultural College. Average production per hen, Kil eggs: previous year. 154 eggs. 38. Carried out seed certification work. In 19*22. 136,455 bushels of wheat and oats in 33 counties were certified for purity and freedom from disease, furnishing definite -ouiv.- of pure strains. 39. Made more than 4.300 production te^t- of dairy cattl for advanced registry. 40. In coo|)eration with Federal Government, maintained county extension agents in 45 counties. 41. Published a 150-page bulletin. "Corn Investigations." </seg>
            <seg id="p007">lvRJ *&gt; ''Kill i\ i !I1I.K AX*CX)M PI.IS1I MEXT8 7 giving detailed results of a long series of experiments with Ne - braska corn. 42. Distributed sufficient hog cholera serum to vaccinate 400,000 hogs and blackleg virus sufficient to vaccinate 100,000 cattle. 43. Developed and advocated in Nebraska, plan of growing soy beans in corn for ''hogging down." Soy beans serve as a cheap protein supplement to corn. In 1921, 250 farmers in eastern Nebraska were following the plan. By 1922 the number had increased to more than a thousand. 44. Developed within the last year a portable colony brooder house for chickens. Fifteen of them have been built within a radius of 10 miles of Lincoln within the last year. 45. Three hundred and seventy-eight judges have been fur - nished to 125 county and community fairs during 1921 and 1922, us follows: livestock. 151; poultry, 59; soil products, 81 ; home economics, 87. 46. Established the first cooperative bull association in the State, in Saunders County. 47. Graduated 109 students from the School of Agriculture at Lincoln, a secondary school of the College. 48. Carried on 44 farmstead demonstrations, showing the best arrangement of farm buildings and fields for convenience and profit. 49. Carried out health and nutrition campaigns for both children and adults. In 1921 over 30 health instruction enter - tainments were given especially for children and in 1922 40 lecture demonstrations to 9.070 people, mostly adults. 50. Promoted an accredited flock poultry project with over 400 farmer members to date. The members agree to put their poultry raising on a scientific basis, by culling, breeding, and ted ing. as advocated by the Agricultural College. Flocks are accredited when certain production records are attained. II. Made a careful study of the types of reading matter which appeal to Nebraska farmers, thru a survey reaching 1,500 farm and village homes, and published a bulletin dealing with the subject. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 18 U52. Gave 15 demonstrations in .shearing sheep, docking e, etc. 53. Promoted the growing of sweet clover in Nebraska. This plant doubles the stock carrying capacity of pasture over ordinary grass. Conducted demonstrations in 10 counties. 54. Enrolled nearly 100 army vocational students in Trades School in poultry, agricultural engineering, and dairy courses. 55. Started a comprehensive series of investigations and ex - periments in weed control. ."&gt;•;. Promoted the use of Kherson. Nebraska No. 21, anil Burt oats. Ninety per cent of the acreage in the State is now made up of these varieties. Kherson was originally introduced to America by the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. ."&gt;". Carried on a grasshopper campaign in the North Platte valley, saving tli&lt;" fanners thousands of dollars. 58. Distributed 4S0 ounces of strychnine, sufficient, when prepared, tt» poison iJO'2.000 prairie dog burrow-. .V.). Disseminated strains of Kanred. Nebraska No. ti. and Nebraska No. M, early varieties of winter wheat. Forty per - cent of the acreage in the State i- made up of these varieties. 60. Introduced and promoted a fruit and vegetable budget to encourage greater and more even consumption of those prod i let &gt; as a means to health. Promoted an increased use of dairy products in diet. til. Carried out 7 demonstrations to show proper constru lion of farm buildings. 82. Carried out experiments t.&gt; determine the efficiency of tillage tools, as regards power requirements, different kinds of -oils. etc. »M. Added 4 new boys' and girls' clubs, including farm ac - counts, to encourage the l&gt;oys and girls to develop into business - like farmers: radio, to keep pace with that development; keep - well club, to promote health: and the rope club, to teach meth - ods of tying hitches, splicing ropes, etc. t'4. Designed 5» complete plans of buildings and grounds for countv fairs. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">100 Worth While A&lt; ( ompijshments 9 65. Carried out a campaign, urging late sowing of fall wheat in 1921, thereby avoiding a serious outbreak of the Hes - sian fly. 66. Carried out 14 irrigation demonstrations. 67. Distributed 5,168 l&gt;oxes of pocket gopher poison to fanners. This wa&gt; sufficient to treat 30,000 acres. 68. Surveyed portions of the State for soil acidity. 69. Outlined ant) put into effect a comprehensive series of experiments at the State orchard at Union, designed to answer the orchard problems of eastern Nebraska. 70. Introduced and provided families with score cards in order to keep check on children's health. Four hundred fami - lies- were tlitis supplied. 71. An&gt;\vered 10,500 personal letters regarding the care, feeding, and management of live slock. 7± Carried out extensive investigation of the purchasing power of Nebraska grains and made studies over a long period of years of the relations between production and price. Also studied the factors affecting hog prices. These studies will soon be made available in bulletin form. 73. Inspected all shipments of plants from foreign countries not previously inspected by the Federal Government at port of entry, to prevent the introduction of dangerous insect pests and plain diseases. 74. Thirty lessons in dietetics were given to the nurses at the University Hospital in Omaha by a member of the home economics staff. 75. Under the provisions of the State law, the College cali - brated more than 100.000 cream bottles, more than 6,000 milk bottles, more than 2.300 pipettes, and more than 3,500 cream weights, thereby preventing the use of inaccurate glassware and cream weights. 76. Conducted millinery and dress construction schools for leaders, who in turn held schools for other women. More than 5.000 dress forms were made, at a saving of $10 each, and more than 3,500 hats were made, at a saving of $5 each. 77. Compiled a carefully prepared history of the College of </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Agriculture from its earliest beginnings 50 years ago down to the present time. Ur8. Assisted in the organization of 8 county live stock lers' associations. 79. Gave 90 butchering and meat-cutting demonstrations. Meat butchering, canning, and soap-making demonstrations were carried on in 20 counties of the State. 80. Held 2 live stock feeders' conventions each year. 81. Introduced a "live baby" at the home management house, giving home economics girls practical training in child care. 82. Carried out 79 community tests in 32 counties, demon - strating the type of seed corn ear l&gt;est adapted to local condi- 83. Conducted 25 farm account schools, showing farmers how to put their operations on a business basis. 84. Wrote over 3,600 letters to farmers answering questions dealing with farm engineering and building problem-. 85. Promoted the smut treatment for oats and wheat, the latter being a new project. b86. Carried on 60 soil erosion demonstrations, showing rmers by actual example how soil washing can be successfully mbated. 87. Introduced courses in institutional management, prepar - ing women for managers of tea rooms, cafeterias, institutions, etc. 88. Distributed over 3,000 blue prints of farm building! and equipment. 89. Started experiments to determine the best cultural prac - tices in growing and curing alfalfa hay. 90. Carried on an infertile egg campaign and a dry-mash feeding campaign among poultry raisers. 91. Supplied a model farm exhibit to 12 county fairs. 92. Carried out 12 farm water supply demonstrations. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">100 Worth While Accomplishments 11 93. Conducted 46 income tax schools for farmers. 94. Assisted 500 farmers to begin keeping books and cost of production records dealing with one or more lines of farming. This was to enable them to determine the most economical meth - ods of handling their farms. Supplied over 1,100 enterprise records to farmers, for keeping track of individual crops. 95. Members of the agricultural college faculty have visited mi nt than 60 high schools to assist teachers of agriculture and home economics in organizing their teaching work. 96. Examined twice all of the nurseries of the entire State to determine their freedom from dangerous insect pests and plant disases, and issued 94 certificates to the owners or mana - gers of these nurseries enabling them to sell and make shipments into other states. 97. Supplied 100 communities of the State with programs for community meetings each month. This is a new line of work. 98. Published and disseminated lists of fruit plants, orna - mental shrubs, and flowers best adapted to the different counties of the State. 99. Established practice teaching centers in the high schools of Waverly, Eagle, University Place, and Havelock, for the pur - pose of training teachers of agriculture and home economics. 100. Attended 12 conferences of teachers of high school agriculture to assist in carrying agricultural education into the local farm communities. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 18 SOME NEW BULLETINS OF THE COLLEGE (Published in 1922) STATION CIRCULARS Hog Houses for Nebraska. Circular 14. Insect Pests of Stored Grain and Their Control. Circular 15 Preparation of Laboratory Specimens as an Aid to the Diagnosis of Animal Disease. Circular 16. The Common Intestinal Round Worm of Swine. Circular 17. STATION BULLETINS Winter Wheat in Western Nebraska. Bulletin 179. Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes. Bulletin 180.' Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers. Bulletin 181 and Bulletin 184.' Varieties of Potatoes for Nebraska. Bulletin 182. Experiments with Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers. Bulletin 183.' The Nebraska Farm Family. Some Land Tenure Phases. Bulletin 185.' Potato Diseases in Nebraska. Bulletin 186.' EXTENSION CIRCULARS Disinfection and Disinfectants. Extension Circular 5. Prevention of Swine Diseases. Extension Circular 221. Establishing the Home Orchard. Extension Circular 1230 Managing the Home Orchard. Extension Circular 1231. Graded Eggs Bring Better Prices. Extension Circular 141 Fowl Cholera. Extension Circular 1412. Essentials of Poultry Hygiene. Extension Circular 141 RESEARCH (OR SCIENTIFIC BULLETINS Corn Investigations. Research Bulletin 20. Studies of Immunity Against Hemorrhagic Septicemia. Research B letin 21. A Study of Environmental Conditions Influencing the Development of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host. Research Bulletin 22. Relation of Environment and Other Factors to Potato Wilt Caused by Fusarium Oxysporum. Research Bulletin 23.' ■The College of Agriculture has bun Write for complete lists. "Out of print •In press. Ready for distribution ear </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>