<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00009.00014">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00009.00014</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>FORTY YEARS OF NEBRASKA AT HOME AND IN CONGRESS</title>
			            <date value="1902">1902</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-16</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-08</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">104 


Iivid Batter, first governor of the state of Nebraska, was 
in the state of Indiana near Bloomin^on, Monroe County. 
iabor, L829. At that time in tke went educational facilities 
• so very indifferent that fanners' sons were doomed to 
r public life, very trenerally developed more by application 
¦vere toil and the treasures of personal experience, than by 
iiical scholastic culture. 

Whether sii|M'iintendeni of a Wisconsin stock farm before of 
aye. or assuming the charge of a large family and an embarassed 
estate on the death of his father, or cominjr out of the financial 
crisis of lsr&gt;7 with "an inheritance of loss." lie was prepared 
for new ventures and future encounters. Arrivinji in Xebrask;) 
in 1S5S. still a voting man. little did he suppose that in ei&lt;rlit 
years' time he would he enrolled amonjr the executive* of states. 
Bagagiag in mercantile ]&gt;iirsuits in Pawnee City and in raising 
and aesttag in live stock, he was soon established as a persever 
inn ! &gt;nd successful man of business. Efficiency and prominence 
s.i. in marked him for a leader, and prior to his nomination toi 
asveraor he had served three years in the legislature. 

itCOtdtag to the provision of the state constitution, the first 
ion was to convene on the Fourth of July, 18(5(i; and tc 
body was delivered the first message of the first governor &lt;&gt;t 
new state. As this period marks an era in our political 
tence. it may not l&gt;e inappropriate to present it in full: 

(Irntlrmcn of the Si ante and Housr nf Reprrtrntatiir*: In accordance 
with a time-honored custom, that reaches back 
to the beginning 1 of our national existence. I assume the 

THK STATE &lt;i&lt; )VKKX()KS. 

&lt;;&amp;amp;lt;&gt;VKHX()H DAVID BUTLER </seg>



            <seg id="p002">1 </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
105 


privilege of addressing the first senate and house of representatives, 
chosen by the popular will, since Nebraska was 
elected to lake her rank as one of Hie sovereign states of 
he I'nion. The position in which we stand to-day is pecuiar 
to our national economy, and affords an instructive 
Mimnient upon the character of our institutions and their 
adaptation to the needs of a progressive i&gt;eo|&gt;le. While in 
a territorial condition, we have, necessarily. l&gt;een dependetii 
upon the general government for Metal mid civil protection, 
for the appointment of our executive and judicial 
)fficers, and for annual appropriations to defray the ex&gt;enses 
of a territorial government. Now that the rapid 
ncrease of our population and the proportional development 
of our resources have given us sufficient strength 
and stability to dispense with the temporary guardianship 
afforded by the Organic Act while passing our minority in 
the family of the Union, we propose, quietly and peaceably, 
n accordance with numerous precedents afforded by other 
states, and in response to the invitation extended to us by 
an act of Congress of 1864, commonly called the Enabling 
\ct. to take upon ourselves the responsibility of state government. 


The auspices under which we ask, at the door of Congress, 
for admission into the Union, are extremely favorable 
to our future happiness and prosperity. The tide of immigration, 
checked for a season by the disturbing influences 
of the great civil war, is again pouring with increased momentum 
over the western banks of the Missouri, and now, 
although a year has scarcely elapsed since the close of the 
rebellion, our population has probably increased one-third: 
our prairies have been taken up with unexampled rapidity 
by enterprising settlers, and herds of cattle and fields of 
luxuriant grain change, a.s if by magic, the solitary wilderness 
to the appearance of civilization. 

The question of state government, as it has been submitted 
to the people, has not been sprung precipitately upon 
them. No exception can with propriety be taken to the 
manner in which it has been brought before them. It has 
lieen thoroughly discussed: first by the territorial legislature 
that drafted the constitution, then by the press and 
by the people at large, and the result of the vote upon 
the state constitution evinces that a majority of the people 
of Nebraska deliberately prefer the rights and privileges 
appertaining to a state to the more imperfect organization 
of a territory. The objection to the admission of Nebraska 
by Congress, on the ground of a scanty population, 
cannot be urged with any appearance of consistency. At </seg>



            <seg id="p004">
tlic timr of the passage of the "Enabling Ait" by Congltsa 
in 1"&gt;r&gt;4. the population of Nel&gt;r;isk;i was estiniateil 
at 38,000. As no accurate census lias been taken since that 
time, the exact inerease eannot he stated, lint from the 

returns of the assessment of 1 
immigration during the fall of 
anil from the number of votes 
sufficient data are presented tf 

•ii."&gt;. from the great influx of 
IMS, anil Ike spring of 
east in the rerent election. 
estimate, with probable ac- 

curacy, that it will not. by the time Congress can take 
action upon the &lt;|iiestion of her admission, fall short of 
711. (Mid. This, so far from beiner lielow the standard of new 

average. That it will l&gt;e any 
in the Inion to give Nebraska 

states, is really above the 
grievance to the older state 
a greater representation in 
law. is an evident fallacy. 

Congress than is prescribed by 
In apportioning representatives 

to other states, although a population of UMI.onn is required 
for each member, yet several of the states have each a representative 
in Congress for a fractional part of the stated 
number, often less than the population of Nebraska. In 
addition to this, it will l&gt;e found, upon reference to the 
census returns of the different states, that not only have 
the majority of them been admitted before their population 
was up tu the standard of representation, from time to time 
increased by Contrress. lint in at least one case (that of 
Florida) a -tate has been represented for years, upon the 
congressional floors, by two senators and one representative, 
that has not at this moment a ]H&gt;pulation exceeding 
that of Nebraska, and which has never in its history measured 
up to the legal standard. That the people of Nebraska 
and of all ihe territories, now or to be organized, would 
suffer injustice were it requisite to the admission of a state 
that she should have the number of inhabitants required for 
a representative is evident, not only from the foregoing 
statements, but from the guarantees given them in the 
treaty by the provisions of which Louisiana was ceded by 
France to the I'nited States in ISO:!, and which embraces 
nearly all the states admitted since the treaty was made, 
and the present western territories, with the exception of 
those ceded by Mexico. In the third article of that treaty 
we find the following language, than which nothing can be 
more explicit and clear: "The inhabitants of the ceded territories 
shall be incorporated in the union of the United 
States, and be admitted as soon as possible, according to 
the principles of the federal Constitution, to the enjoyments 
of all the rights and immunities of citizens of the I'nited 
States: and in the meantime they shall be maintained and 
protected in the free enjoyment of all their liberty, prop- </seg>



            <seg id="p005">
rtJT iiml the religtoa which they profess." Now, what is 
neant by the expression "a-; soon as possible, according 
to the principles of the constitution."' if it is not to be interacted, 
as soon as their wealth and population shall be sufficient 
to support a state government? It could not have 
been in contemplation that an inexorable sliding 
should l&gt;e established, increasing- from time to time, to keep 
&gt;ace with ihe development of older communities, to which 
each new territory must measure up or be kept out from 
ler right of representation and self-government. 

If the people of the Atlantic states could support their 
respective state governments with population ranging, in 
some instances, considerably less than that of our territory, 
then it reasonably follows that the time contemplated 
in the treaty, specified by this somewhat emphatic expression, 
"as soon as possible." has arrived for the state of Nebraska. 
While it is a subject of regret that the majority for 
the constitution wa&gt; s&lt;&gt; small, yet an impartial examination 
into the causes that tended to decrease it will do away with 
most of the significance that might be attached to that 
circumstance. Nebraska, while sending her full quota of 
volunteers to the national army for the suppression of the 
rebellion, contributed very little in the way of direct taxation 
for the prosecution of the war. While most of the 
states were obliged to offer large bounties to induce enlistments, 
we were wholly exempt from such burdens, and 
the close of the war found us neither impoverished by 
heavy taxes nor weighed down with a heavy debt. The advantage 
thus enjoyed by our tax-payers over those of other 
sections, though really adventitious, carried great weight 
as an argument in favor of a territorial form of government 
to minds not accustomed to study much the science 
of political economy. Another argument used against 
the constitution was of a very different nature, and was 
found in the instrument itself, in the clause defining the 
extent of the elective franchise. Hut this vexed question 
seems now about to be placed beyond the reach of agitation 
by an amendment of the constitution of the United 
States which has already passed Congress, and now awaits 
the ratification of two-thirds of the states, which in due 
•course of time will permanently settle the political status 
of the African. 

Within the last two years the wealth of the territory has 
increased with even greater rapidity than the population. 
In lsiu the taxable property of Nebraska was returned as 
$11,000,000: in 1*65 at $13,000,000. This year the returns 
alreadv filed in the auditor's office indicate a total of </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
108 


$18,000,000. The same ratio of increase will give us in 1m'.7 
the sum of $35,000,000: but taking into consideration the 
unprecedented increase of emigration, and the large amount 
of capital introduced by the rapid progress of our internal 
improvements, it will be safe to estimate the amount of 
taxable property in 1867 at upward of $40,000,000. 

The railroad interests of Nebraska are assuming large 
proportions. The work upon the main line of the Pacific 
Kailroad is progressing at the rate of one mile per day, 
and in a few weeks the track of iron will extend two hundred 
miles west to Fort Kearney. If the same energy shall 
be displayed till its completion, but a short time will elapse 
ere it will wind its way beyond our western boundary. 
This road completed, together with the various connectingbranches, 
now in contemplation, or in process of construction 
to unite us with the great eastern roads and the gulf 
of Mexico, we shall have abundant facilities for transporting 
our surplus products to the eastern, southern and western 
markets. The importance of the early completion of 
these highways of commerce is not overlooked by our enterprising 
people, and must be felt even by a casual observer 
who should to-day cross our broad fields, where the cattle 
graze upon a thousand prairies, and the earth seems oppressed 
by the burden of ripening grain. Measures have 
been recently taken in several counties for the development 
of our mineral resources, and the present indications are 
that coal exists in inexhaustible quantities in Nebraska. 
It cannot be long in the natural order of things before the 
attention of capitalists will be directed to our mines and 
coal will in good time fill the breach caused by our temporary 
scarcity of timber. 

To a community so comparatively wealthy as our own the 
burdens of a state government must be light; and when we 
take into the account the inevitable impetus to be given to 
emigration and the introduction of capital by the adoption 
nf a state constitution, we can but come to the conclusion 
that financially we shall be upon a much better basis in 
w&gt;7 with a state organization than in MM M a territory. 

The duties of the present legislature, though important, 
will not probably occupy much time nor entail very much 
upon the treasury in the way of appropriations. I'ntil the 
seal of legality is placed upon its records by our admission 
and consequent recognition by Congress, its action should 
be limited to the business actually necessary to put in motion 
the machinery of state. The election of United States 
senators, who shall, in conjunction with our congressional 
representative, present our petition at Washington, is of </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
109 


course the first and most important step. That your counsels 
will be guided 1 &gt;v wisdom and patriot ism. the fact that 
you come fresh from the people, to whom the issues of the 
ila\ have been presented with distinctness and abilit}-. 
I to afford the strongest pledge. 

The amendment to the Constitution of the t'nited States. 
recently passed by Congress, and submitted to the action 
of the several states, to which I have incidentally referred. 
should, in my opinion, be acted upon during the present 
session. It is the embodiment of the reconstruction policy 
of Congress — a policy long considered and carefully digested, 
and which is apparently the wisest, the most expedient, 
and the most conformable to the spirit of our 
institutions, of any that has been suggested, or that can 
be adopted. It gives a promise of an early solution to the 
main questions that have threatened the national life, and 
if fully carried out in letter and spirit, will, as I think, 
restore harmony and concord to the national councils and 
reaffirm in our Constitution the fundamental principles 
enunciated in the Declaration of Independence, that all men 
are created free and equal. It is not necessary for me to 
enter into the piirtieidnrs of the amendment at present, as 
I shall take an early opportunity to communicate it to 
your honorable body. 

Financially I am able to report the territory in a healthy 
condition. The light debt incurred by us during the Indian 
troubles, in defending our frontiers, forms the extent of our 

liabilities. Congress will, doubtless, in accordance with 
established precedents, reimburse us for our expenditures 
in calling out the militia against the Indians, as soon as our 
just claim shall have been properly represented. To these 
and especially to the financial tact and energy of our 
present territorial administration, are we indebted for the 
gratifying fact that our bonds will bring in the market 

ninety-seven cents on the dollar. In this respect we have 

advantages not often possessed by a new state, and which 
will tend to alleviate any additional burdens that the 
change in our form of government may impose. There has 
ne\er been in our history a finer prospect for an abundant 

har\cst than at present. He who sends the "early and 

latter rain" has blessed us most abundantly, and to Him 
should our hearts go forth in gratitude for His many mer- 


We believe that the time is not far distant when the prod- 

ucts of our soil shall make our name familiar in the com- 

mercinl marts of the farthest clime— when our prairies 

shall be dotted with comfortable dwellings and tracts of </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
110 


growing timber, from the Missouri to the mountains, and 
when our churches and sehoolhouses. greeting each other 
from every eminence, shall be the index of the intelligence 
am! moral worth of our citizens. That the future of Nebraska 
will jrive a frlorious fruition as the reward of our 

anfruine hope*, is hit firm trust and is the prayer of every 
rood citizen and patriot. 

This session, of eijrht days' duration, resulted in the eleclioii 
of I'nited Stales senators, as follows: Thomas \Y. Tipton hav 
iuj: been nominated as a republican, and .). Sterling Murtoa as 

a democrat, twenty-nine votes 
and twenty six for the latter, 
duly elected. And twenty-Bin 
M. Thayer. and twenty-six for 
Thayei- was also declared duly 

having been cast for the form m . 
Thoinas W. Tipton was declared 

votes baring been cast for John 
Andrew J. l'oppleton. John M. 

elected a Senator. 

On the fourth day of April. 1887, the governor issued his'proi 
lamation for a session of the legislature to convene on the six 
teenth of May ensuing, and sixvitied thirty-one subjects for it 
special consideration, in order to accelerate the transition from 
the territory to the stale; while to this called session h 
delivered a very exhaustive message explanatory of the necessity 
of a s]&gt;ecial session. Among other things introductory he said 

No state lias ever entered the Union under more favorable 
auspices than our own. Practically free from debt, our 
credit is sound, and our resources entirely available for 
present and future needs. Our facilities for communication 
with the east and south have been greatly increased during 
the past year, and the Boeky Mountains and shores of the 
Pacific are rapidly drawing near to us, as the construction 
train of the Inion Pacific makes its daily progress westward. 
The tide of immigration, that at the close of the 
rebellion commenced to pour over our borders, has experienced 
no abatement, but has continued, with accelerated 
qpasd, to people our fertile prairies with hardy pioneers, 
and to contribute the necessary labor and capital for the 
development of our latent wealth. 

The conclusion was as follows: 

Gentlemen, I cannot conclude without expressing- a hope 
that in all your deliberations the spirit of harmony and </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
( 

-f 

.,f 

T 

¦ov&lt; 

I 



11 

&lt;l-*n,t.v of . hvtehtte body, may be carefully preservedthat 
every Mwn bmgki „,, f((I . vollr ,, )nsillel , lt i()n 
meet w.th unprejudiced and unimpassioned examinationthat 
OB new ,Ut*, through your wisdom ud prodesee may 
IB-crib, upon the opening pages of its history a record unsullied 
by ,he petty, yet hitter, warfare of local interests 
and that every member of yo,, r body may bear in perpetual 
remembrance that he owes not merely a d,,tv to the particular 
sectton that he represents, but that Nebraska, as an 

integral state, now ealls npon him for the unselfish 'service 
Of h.s head and heart. tendering in all sincerity our humble 
acknowledgments to the Giver of all good, for our preservat.on 
and protection as a people, since the date of our 
organization u a territory, uniting with our sister states 
in ¦Tatit«de to Him for Mis guidance of the American lie- 

PnbHo, through the tempest of treason an,l armed rebellio B 
to the haven of peace and renewed prosperity, let a 

emnly join in an invocation to 
for the continuance of his f 
may ever yield its bounteous lit 
of the husbandman, and that th&lt; 

the same Almighty I'ower, 
'oateriag care that our soil 
o the intellisrent toil 
e peaceful conquests of combe 
as enduring as the truth 
rsal freedom, which forever 

merce and mechanical skill may 
of the jrreat principle of univer 

ures them of victorie 

•i, rbe 27ti ami 28th &lt;lavs «,f October, 1868, a s,,,.,ial session 
the lejrislatun- was boldn at Omaha for the appointment 
pr.'si.lemial electors, of which the girrcriiw said: 

the I'nion. the time prescribed 
the legislature has not arrived. 
state you have once convened b 
At that time your attention wa 
portant questions, gramimg out 
mestic government, which were 

for the regular session of 
Since the admission of the 
y the call of the executive. 

directed to the many iniof 
the change in our dopressinp 
upon us f or im- 

mediate action. You have therefore been called together at 
this time to make such provision for the appointment of 
electors of president and vice-president of the United States 
of America as you in your wisdom shall deem best. 

his business Winjr accomplish*-,!. Mr. Majors, since lieutenant 
ernor. offered the following resolution: 

Hrmlral. By the senate and house of representatives concurring, 
that we respectfully, but earnestly, urge upon the 
next president of the Inited States, General V. S. Grant, 

Ill c-onse.jm.1,,-,. of the recent admission of Nebraska to </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
112 


tin- appointment of the Honorable John M. Thayer in his 
cabinet: who will, by his long residence on the frontier, 
and his acquaintance with the resources and developments 
of the West, and with the necessities of the people, be enabled 
to advance the interests and prosperity of this great 
;iiul arrowing country. 

Mr. Freeman moved to strike out "General &lt;Jrant" and insert 
'Horatio Seymour." which was lost, and the resolution adopted. 

An a&lt;t having passed the legislature. July. 1S(&gt;7. "for the location 
of the seat of government of the state of Nebraska, and for 
the enaction of public buildings thereat." the governor, the secretary 
of stale, and auditor, being the commissioners to perform 
said duty. did. on the 29th day of July, 1867, establish the capital 
at the village of Lancaster, on grounds including state lands 
ami the old surrendered town site of Lancaster. And thus the 
sale of town lots inured to the financial benefit of the state, having 
amounted to ?7fj,713 during the first year thereafter. The 
commissioners whose names were thus identified with Lincoln 
;is siate capital, were (Jovernor David Batter, Thomas 1'. Kennanl. 
Bee rotary of State, and John Gilleapie, Slate Auditor. 

The new seat of government was made prominent, in the governor's 
message of January !Sth, lW.t: 

This roininodioiis and well appointed hall, these substantial 
\\:tlls. this entire l&gt;eautiful edifice, this enterprising and 
thrifty town, sprung, within the last eighteen months, 
from the open prairie and to-day contributing, directly anil 
indirectly, to the prosperity of an area of more than ten 
thousand square miles, this has liecu accomplished without 
cost to the state or individuals. It lias contributed to the 
enrichment of both. It has added to the wealth of the state 
not less than five millions of dollars. Nor have the public 
benefits lieen yet fully measured. 1 would, in this connection, 
recommend that provision l&gt;e made for the sale of the 
remaining lots. So much of the proceeds as may l&gt;e neces•ary 
for that purpose should be appropriated to the construction 
of the dome, included in the original design of 
this building, and the fencing and ornamenting of the 
grounds, and the remainder to the erection of a building for 
state university and agricultural college. 

The grounds upon which the old state IMMM stands \\er«-given 
bv the citizens of Omaha to be used bv the territory </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
113 


for the erection thereon of the state capitol. In addition 
to this, the city gave toward the completion of the building 
$30,000 in bonds, which have been redeemed. 

On the fourth of March next, the state will have removed 
from them all its movable property and have ceased to occupy 
them for the purpose originally designed. I recommend 
that they be granted to the city of Omaha for a high 
school on the condition that when they shall no longer be 
used for that purpose they shall revert to the state. 

Recurring to the above subject, in his message of January 6th 
1*71. wo have: 

By the provisions of "An act to provide for the sale of 
unsold lots and blocks on the town site of Lincoln, and for 
the location and erection of a state university, and agricultural 
college, and state lunatic asylum," approved February 
15th, 1869, the commissioners were authorized to sell all the 
unsold lots and blocks on the town site of Lincoln; to construct 
the dome of the capitol building: to erect a state 
lunatic asylum at a cost of $50,000, and a state university 
and agricultural college at a cost of $100,000. "On the 8th 
of November (1870) the [asylum | building was formally ac 
cepted, and on the 1st of December completely furnished 
and ready for the reception of patients. Orders were 
issued and the patients from the Iowa Hospital and the 
different jails throughout the state, in all numbering over 
thirty, removed to the asylum, where they are now receiving 
the best care. 

The message of 1871 made mention of the State Cniveraity: 

This institution, established on a broad Uisis. and liberally 
endowed by your predecessors, is not as yet open for 
the reception of students. The board of regents have been 
appointed and organized, and have taken some steps preliminary 
to the selection of the faculty. 

Our university building is a source of pride to the citizens 
of our state, and is a model not only in architectural beauty, 
but in its internal arrangements, and its adaptation to the 
purposes for which it is designed. Let me express the hope 
that the legislature may always be ready to foster its interests 
by wise, legislation. 

Having presented the necessity of a state prison in his official 
communication of 1869, that of 1871 reported progress: 

The legislature, recognizing this necessity, made provision 
for the erection of ¦ penitentiary, on lands previously </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
114 


set apart for that purpose, about three miles south of Lincoln, 
and also for the sale of lands donated to the state, 
by the general government, to aid in the construction of 
such an institution. The contract for building- the penitentiary 
was awarded to Messrs. Stout and Jamison, at a contract 
price of $307,950. They are executing their work in a 
niamier alike creditable to themselves and the state. The 
labor of the convicts is hired to them at the rate of fortytwo 
cents per day, for each convict who is able to work. 
I am pleased to notice that under the present arrangement 
the condition of the prisoner is in every respect much improved. 


No net an amount of responsibility had bera cast ipoa an\ 
in-.-x ions governor, as to the man-rial interests of the people of 
NVbraska. Butler's term of occupancy might properly be called 
ih&lt;- creative period of the state. Immigration was to be induced 
and fostered by all practicable means, education provided for 
tin ir descendants, penal laws enacted for their protection from 
the vicious, and a stale militia for safety from savages; constitutions 
framed, amended and adapted to constantly varying 
necessities; a capital city established as the home of the state, 
and so located as to become a great railway center. The wisdom 
of the location, and the general acceptability of administration, 
bail to extinguish early prejudice and vindicate the propriety 
of original design. 

The financial statement as given in the message of 1871, re 
ported a balance in the treasury of ? 77,886. Said he: 

I am pleased to note that the material wealth of the state 
has been rapidly increasing. The assessed valuation of 1868 
was about $32,000,000. That of 1870 was over $53,000,000, thus 
showing the gratifying increase of $21,000,000 in two years. 

The document concluded: 

Invoking for your deliberation the guidance and blessing 
of Him who controlleth all things, I express the hope that 
your session may be productive of the highest public good, 
and honor to yourselves. 

At the time of his first election, in 1866, Governor Butler, republican, 
had a majority of 145 votes over J. Sterling Morton, </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
115 


democrat. In 1868 his majority over J. R. Porter, democrat, wa» 
-:-27. In 1870 the majority over John H. Croiton was 2,478. 
Bat in this, his third campaign, charges were made against him 
of great irregularities in administering the school fund of the 
state. His political friends claimed that no harm could come to 
the state from a re-election, as the legislature would be republiearn, 
and they would examine the case and do justice in the 
[in-iuises. Accordingly, by the sixth day of March, 1871, eleven 
armies of impeachment were presented by the house of repre- 
M'liiatives, to the senate as a Court of Impeachment, one of 
which charged Governor David Butler with having appropriated 
to his own use f 1*5.nS1.L'&lt;J of school fund, derived from the general 
trnment, and that "in this he had committed and was guilty 
misdemeanor in office." To all the articles he interposed 
ific denials, and affirmed the borrowing of the school fund 
the placing on file a mortgage to secure the same about the 
of January, 1871, which would be three years after the 
Tal of the money in the state treasury. 

Three months after the convening of the court (June 1, 1871) 
he was found guilty of "a misdemeanor in office," and the sentence 
was that he be removed therefrom. The managers of impeachment 
were Honorables J. C. Myers, J. E. Doon and Dr. 
Forest Porter. Honorables Clinton Briggs, John J. Reddick and 
T. M. Marquette were counsel for the defendant. 

On the day preceding the rendering of the decision the governor 
presented to the speaker of the senate a proposition for 
settlement as follows, but as the Court of Impeachment had no 
control of a settlement it proceeded to decide upon a "misdemeanor 
in office" : 

To the Honorable, the President of the Senate 

I take the liberty, on the re-assembling of your honorable 
body, to communicate with you upon the subject of the 
five per cent fund. Early in the spring of 1868, soon after 
the collection of that fund, I made a loan of the state of 
the sum of $16,881.26, and afterwards amply secured the 
same by bond of mortgage. This was done in perfect good 
faith and with the understanding that the transaction was 
perfectly legal. Many, however, of my fellow citizens differ </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
1 

1.. 


with me as regards the legality of the loan and the suffiienc.v 
of the securities, and while I am unchanged in my 
opinion on the subject and conscious that 1 have at im 
time done other than my duty in the premises, I am ready 
and willing, in order that the subject of dissention inav be 
-cd of, to deposit in the state treasury the full amount 
of such loan with interest from the 25th day of May, 1809, 
the date of the arrival of the fund in Lincoln in charge of 
the deputy state treasurer, and I ask the passage of an act 
providing for the cancellation of the securities. I sincerely 
trust that this proposition on my part may be received in 
the same spirit in which it is made, and that harmony may 
again prevail in the administration of our state government. 
" David Butler. 

Executive Department, Lincoln, May 30th, 1871. 

•bruary 20th, 1873, a select committee made report 

F. 

We find the claim against ex-governor David Butler, 
amounting originally to $16,881.26, due the five per cent 
fund, which, together with interest now due, amounts to 
$23,664.84, in a very unsatisfactory condition, there being 
no securities properly on file in the state treasurer's office 
as security for the payment of this debt. Ex-governor Butler 
has submitted a proposition to your committee, to transfer 
to the state the residence and adjoining grounds, now 
occupied by him as a homestead, in payment of the above 
debt upon the following terms: For the house, outbuildings, 
80 acres of ground, and furniture contained in the 
main building, the state to allow the sum of $30,000, to be 
paid as follows: Principal debt, $16,881.26; interest, $6,283.58; 
warrant on general fund, $6,835.16; total, $30,000.00. Your 
committee has the foregoing proposition under careful consideration, 
has visited the premises and carefully examined 
the house and grounds, and has reached the decision to 
strong-ly urge the passage of a bill for an act to provide for 
purchasing a governor's mansion. 

Instead of adopting the committee's recommendation, the legislature 
passed an act, March 3rd, 1873, "To provide for the liquidation 
and settlement of certain claims with David Butler.'" 
And in accordance with said act, April 4th, 1873, a board of com 
inissioners reported, "That we have examined and appraised 
3,400 acres, the lands of David Butler, in quantity sufficient to 
liquidate the indebtedness of David Butler to the school fund of </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
117 

STATE GOVERNORS 

the state of Nebraska," to which Gtoreroor Robert W. Jhmtwm 

Ei^ht jean after the fKi.^si had gone into the possession &lt;&gt;f 
• iiivcinor I in tier, the legislature passed ;i resolution rescinding 
ih&lt;- verdict of removal from office; and sine tin- sri ilement. on 
the supposition that the :'..4OO ac-n-s of surrendered land had 
become valuable and the slate could all'ord to refund the amount 
oret and aliove the liquidated del. t. a hill for that purpose wan 
presented Iu ''"" legislature, i«ut has not been enacted into law. 

aye his oflkial approval of tbe same date </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
118 


ACTING GOVERNOR \V. II. JAME8. 

1-71-1- 

Willi.im H. -lames was a native of Marion County, Ohio, and 
received his early education in the common schools of tin- Stan;md 
from the Marion Academy. He was alternately farmer. 

Rk. and mechanic, and finally student at law, having eat) 
w oftice in IS.".:'.. 

The dale of his settlement in Nebraska was in isr.T. three 
- after the territorial organization. From this time until 
lection as secretary of state in 1870, he had given we 
attention to legal practice, surveying, and the duties of register 
land office for five years under appointment of President 
Lincoln. His term of acting governor commenced with the lm 
Ichmeiit of Governor Butler, March 4th, 1871, and continued 
January 10th, 1873. The legislature convening but once 
ry two years, lie delivered his only message January 10th. 
3. and three days thereafter was superseded by Governor 

Among the subjects presented for consideration we find the 
admonition that prison discipline should seek the protection of 
•ty, and not attempt "vindictive punishment," greater unity 
of action between the regents and faculty of the state university 
demanded, special attention to be given the insane, idiots, and 
imbeciles, pardoning power to be exercised with great care, 
laws enacted to protect capital coming to the State for investment, 
and usury laws repealed since "capital is timid." 

There remained in the state treasury- January 18th, 1871. 
;7.547: receipts to December 31. 1872, $1,183,074; total 

fl,220,6tl. Disbursements, $1,022,233; balance in treasury 

to credit of the several funds $98,3 

Inasmuch as the exercise of "doubtful and dangerous author 
it.v" had given him an administration, "of few days and full of </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
119 

STATE GOVERNORS. 

t 

&lt; 

Alter the actiag governor'* intelligent diaqnintion apoa the 
¦erapalou care to I bacned in the use of pabUc money, and 
"the impolicy of resorting to doubtful ami dangerou aathoritjr," 
it is a little astonisliintr that tke slate senale felt called ujion 
lo ask what disposition had been made of a particular fund, in 
charge of the governor, of which the auditor and treasurer had 
I report; and further that a senate committee had to report 
t he admitted that he had not done right in retaining a 
[ain f&lt;i..'M)0 — and would pay it over on the order of the le^is 
ire, and though he promised to make a written statement to 
committee in the course of the same day, had failed to 

E those early days of crude laws and new and unexpected de 
ds, it was attempted to palliate delinquencies and indiscrei 
from the demands of public wants, though there was great 
ter of establishing precedents in favor of "private needs.'" 

rouble," he deemed it well t&lt;&gt; &gt;r&lt;&gt; upon record u to mi 

it we 

»f public funds. 

While it is true that pvblic money should !&gt;&lt;• touched 

with the most BcrupnlotM consciousness of authority, i' 

equally true thai the evecuthe officer of the State should 

not !&gt;&lt;• iirirecl to a stretch of lc^'al or cDiistitiitional author- 

Iity by reason of insufficient provisions, to meet any de- 
mands on the State, frowiaf out of the proper administra- 

tion of the laws. A violation of the law growing out of a 

B public want, may furnish a precedent under which a private 
need may he met. And 1 fee! that I can not too Strongly 

urg-e upon your attention the importance of a careful exam- 

ination into the wants of the state irovernment and the 

making 1 of such specific appropriate. n&gt; as will remove all 

necessity or excuse for the exercise of doubtful and danger- 

\&lt; 

e 

re 

o </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
120 


t 

• iOVKKNOIJ KOltKltT W. Fl UNAS 

1 -::',] 

Born in l s -4. an orphan ;ii eight, a printer's apprentice ai 

seventeen vc.iis of age, and editor of a Miami County, Ohio. 
paper in liis twenty-third year, the sabjeci of tliis sketch began 
life courageously and in earnest. During forty-mVe yean ex 

Uoveraor If. W. Furnaa lias been a very active and Intelligent 
worker for 1 1 1 « - interests of Nemaha county and the State ot 
Nebraska. The town &lt;&gt;f Browaville knew him as a Fourth ol 
July orator in L856, and rabaeqnently as member &gt;&gt;f the tow« 
council and the board &lt;&gt;f education, as a trustee of church 

property, leading member of tit" Masonic order, and a practica 
ilorist and landscape gardaer from The beaaty of liis home sm 
rounding*. The county had the benefit of him as editor of it 
first paper, president of her agricultural society, a cultivator o 
nursery stork for orchard and groTe, and dealer in choice livt 
siuik of all descriptions, and member of the legislature an* 
constitutional convention. The State had his services as pies 
dent of her agricultural association, and of her horticultural 
pomological, and historical societies, and as regent of her univer 
sity and governor. Early in her history he was active in placin 
her fruit on exhibition in Boston, Philadelphia, and Richmond 
Virginia, and in securing premium*. In 1885 Governor Dawes 

said, in a message relating to a state display at the New Orleans 
exposition: 

With liis characteristic energy and enthusiasm Mr. Furnas 
entered upon the work placed in his hands; and the result 
of liis work, so untiringly and industriously performed. 
is witnessed in the magnificent display of the various resources 
of Nebraska now upon exhibition in New Orleans; 
;i dispkiv that has called forth encomiums from the press 
of the country, attracting general attention and eliciting 
from those who have not visited Nebraska expressions of 
wonder and astonishment at the great extent and variet\ 
of he </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
li. W. Fl'RN \ 


( 



;:;::, </seg>


            <seg id="p020">
Ii iiMiijjnitioii of distinguished services tin- legislature 
ed the gorenor with a vote of thanks and ;i goM m 
the publication of an address upon the origin, liistorv. 

i Kinjr." In- made mention of 
liis New OrleaJM supervision: 

\s mi 

veil the distinguished 

vein lire awa 

li. 

\ on nir airricultural L r iant. »sliinl 
ami l'i uti iini'il EJffoaitiom, 
When I accepted the position 

lilaska. at the Wurhl's I ml 
New Orleans. La., 1884-5. 

in tin- great staple prod net of 
tanner 1 Huntr to th&lt;- 

int 

\ 

upon its fold* "Corn is 

K 
I" 

ilaiin kimr for any otli. 
llv at the Cotton Centennial, was 

in nowise orttio 

pa 

ire. Cotton, su^'ar. anil tobacco 
otuberances, savinir by actions, 
louder than words, "How dare 

&gt;r 

which ar 

Min 

wheat fields jrlinteit.' 

mr next door neiirhlmr at t 

1 

iklir 

the superiority of wheat 

invoking th 

aiil her ill obliterating our ban- 
Kaasas, Illinois anil Oak 
aetnrinjr liuire artifieial ears to 
of t'hrstn- Ci, until Muminiith. For 

ner inscription. Colorado, 
thenisehes to work mnnu 

ntertained doiiUts as to our aliilitv t» 

Hut we "fimp-ht it out on that line." and came home "with 

our banners still flying." 
it were. I am hold to ass 
factors of culture in the 
dence in the sale of eraf 
eliinates, and conditions, 

And now in ealiner nionie 
rt the belief that amotifr all the 

United States corn takes prece. 
as l&gt;est adapted to more soiU 

used for more purposes, furfor 
man and lx&gt;ast. has more 
anomic value, ffives more jrrain 

nishes more nutritive food 
commercial, cultural and ec 

to the acre than any other cereal, more fodder than any 
of the grasses, piits our beef in prime order, fattens our 
pork, is the basis of our butter and cheese supply, furnishes 
immense manufacturing 1 material, has twice the value of 
cotton, worth fifty per cent more than wheat, its influence 
on the prosperity and wealth is greater than that of any 
other cultivated plant, and to the transportation eompa 
alas "has millions in it." Appealing to the previousus 
report it appeared that in a particular year eorn ex- 

ises of corn, entitled "Com i 
iiiiinistiiines attendant ii|x&gt;n 

-inner. I ill" 

xposit ion. \v;is "To arms" "in 

lipae our natural growth 

intain Hie .idvancpd position taker </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
122 


seeded wheat, oats, barley and rye, in bush 
;iiul surpassed them all 103 million dollars. 

The president of the Doited State* Bade him one &gt;&gt;f ¦ com 
mission to examine into the agricultural capabilities of California. 
Oregon, Arizona, and New Mexico, and a forester of 
the national agricultural department. He was agent of the 

Omaha Indians in Nebraska 
and of tin' Second Mebraaki 

iind Colonel of an Indian brigade 
cavalry in ISC.:?, which did duty 

under General Sully against 

the Sioux Indians. When the 

agricultural department at Washington was allowed a cabiae 
otlicr. many of the friends of Governor Furnas hoped the pres 
idem would select him as thai secretary. The first official proi 
tarnation of the observance of Arbor Day was issued by hiii 
two years after Mr. Morton's resolution establishing it. am 
eleven years before the State made it a legal holiday; and hi 
enthusiasm in that direction lias only increased as the year 
have added to the wisdom of the enterprise. 

In the campaign under General Sully of the regular army 
the battle of White Stone Hills was fought September 3, 1863 
two hundred miles altove Fort Pierre, Dakota. Reporting n 
suits, having described the amount of scouting necessary 1 
locate the enemy. Colonel Furnas said of the battle and th 
conduct of the Nebraska troops: 

The battle now raged with great fury for some time on 
both sides, the enemy successively by a desperate charge 
attempting my right and left flanks, but they were repelled 
with slaughter. They fell in every direction in front of my 
line by the unerring 1 aim of my brave soldiers, who, both 
officers and men, fought with the coolness and courage of 
\eterans, exposed as they were to a galling fire from the 
enemy the whole time. Their loss in killed and wounded 
will not fall short of one hundred and fifty, as scouts sent 
out next day after the battle report their dead as scattered 
iimt the country for miles on the line of their retreat, and 
their wounded as twice that number. The casualties in the 
Second Nebraska Cavalry are seven killed, fourteen 
wounded and ten missing. The officers and men under my 
command are not only entitled to my thanks, but the confidence 
of their country for their bravery, efficiency and 
promptness on this occasion. Not a man in any rapacity 
flinched a particle. </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
123 


I 

Under date of September 16, 1st;:;. Qencrftl Sully thanked tbe 
roopa in order Number 62: 

In separating from this brigade, the Second Nebraska 
Cavalry, the commanding general takes the opportunity of 
thanking Colonel Furnas and the officers and men of the 

regiment for the gTeat assi: 
in the late campaign, and f 
they have obeyed orders. 

tance they have rendered him 
&gt;r the cheerfulness with which 

&gt;r 

This was followed the next 

(1 

ay by a farewell letter to the 

¦olniicl commanding 

HEAIKjrAItTERS 

N 

W. Expedition, 

Fort Antie 

am, D. T., Sept. 17th, 1 

IHai: Colonel: — As we are about to separate after months 
of hard campaigning, you to your family fireside, I where I 
may be ordered, I can not part with you without thanking 

i to me in the duties of the 
Colonel, if yon ever BgaJa 

you for your valuable ser&gt;ice 
late campaign, and I hope, 
throw away the "pipe of peac 
I mav have the pood fortune 

:," and buckle on your saber. 
to have you assoeiated with 

With the kindest feelings 
vour obedient servant, 

for your success, I remain 
Ai.f. Sully, Brig. 0m. 

At the expiration of the term of service, when mustered out 
at Omaha November 30, 1863, Colonel Furnas took leave of his 

command by issuing order Number 12. the latter part of which 
is here quoted: 

The battle of White Stone Hills and its results will ever 
be an all-sufficient voucher for you. There you displayed 

oolness and courage unsurpassed, even by veterans. The 
ieverest chastisement ever inflicted upon Indians was ad- 

ministered by you. To you of the Second Nebraska Cavalry, 
who participated in that battle, is due that victory, and 
you alone. For it you are entitled to the thanks of your 
country; for it a gTateful people of the northwest will ever 
hold you in remembrance. It was a proud day for you and 
amply rewarded you for all the toils and hardships you endured. 
Should your country ever a train require your 
ices, it knows you will be as prompt to respond in the 
future as in the past. We now separate to g-o to our respective 
homes. The best wishes of the colonel commanding 
attend you. Coi.. R. W. Fl'R!fAB. 

B* order of H. M. Atkinson, {iliiilunt </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
124 




(inventor Robert YV. Furnas was the second in the list of 
tai&lt;- executives. In his inaugural address of January 19th, 

is?::, after declaring that liis aim should l&gt;c "to serve faithfully 
a people who had sn nseronly confided the sacred trust." Inpledged 
himself that no dim would be left unperformed in ad 
vancin^r the Btate to an honorable position. "While elected by 
one of the political organizations of the day. m.v duty now is hi 
i In- w hole people." 

He said of the theatre of action. "Here we are laying nton 

ie foundations than otherwise, for those who are to come after 

We arc compelled therefore, to a very great extent, to meet 

emergencies and demands as they arise and present themselves 
tor our consideration." Inasmuch as our land endowment for 
schools embraced "one-eighteenth of the entire public domain." 
he believed in the near future that -our whole educational *\&gt; 
teni. from common school to university, could, with careful 
management, be made entirely independent of state aid." Com 
ins; to his favorite theme of agriculture, it was commended to 

intelligent and devoted supervision: 

I !n* ari'a nf country embraced within tl 

niits of imr State being peculiarly and almost exclusively 
( an agricultural character, together with the fact that 

occupy the keystone place in this gigantic lran&lt;-\lis 
ri arch of agriculture, the settled national axiom tha 

natioi I, individuals, and civilisation! prosper ai 
agriculture thrives, or recede as it languishes, renders thil 
branch of industry, in a irrcat measure, the fonndatioi 

that prosperity in store for us 

As if the treeless prairies were supplicating for moisture and 
hade, in their aid was invoked the supervision of a state for- 

ester, with premiums to stimulate culture. The theory of tax 
ation recommended that, "in a free gOTrmmmt like ours, sus 
taining burdens should be borne proportionately with mean 
and ability to contribute," and that, as between lines of trans 
poitation and the people, "mutual efforts and labors should be 
followed with mutual accommodations and benefits: wholesonn 
judicious, impartial legislation, tending to serve the public good. 
should not be lost sijiht of dariag your labors." In order that </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
125 


stati-. couty, and municipal bonds should be advanced to par. 
registration was urged in order to establish value with the pur 
iliiiser; and with equal urgency attention was called to the utility 
i»f immigration agents and documentary statements of the 

"unsurpumed fertility of our fifty million acres of vacant lands." 
An a]&gt;|»-al was made in behalf of the claims of the United ft 
i'int&gt;nni&lt;il EmpmUttm &lt;&gt;f 1*7»&gt;. and of that at Vienna in 1*7 i. 
so that evidence of Nebraska's capability to furnish desirable 
homes for toiling millions could be understood by the people 
of our own and foreign lands. In behalf of the peace and quiet 
in our "New West," from personal observation and the experi 
ence of many years, he recommended the removal of the Indi 
.ins from the midst of our settlements, and locating them els»-where, 
by themselves. Deprecating hasty legislation, and prof 
fering hearty co-operation, he assumed the reins of govern 
incut, "invoking the aid of Him who guides and governs the acts 
&lt;&gt;f individuals, as well as rules the destinies of nations." 

E Governor Furnas served but one term in office, two yean» 
ed between the time of delivering the foregoing inaugural 
lis final and only message. The message may be considered 
r three heads: principles discussed, farts stated, and rec 
endations made. 

T'nder the head of revenue he said: 

Government being universally recognized among- the 
wants of men, its maintenance is provided for by contributions 
from all interested in its existence, by a system 
familiarly known as and called taxation. In this, the true 
principle is, that each subject ought to contribute to the 
support of the government by which he or she is protected, 
as nearly as possible, in proportion to their respective abilities. 
No good citizen will consider it a burthen, or imposition, 
thus to contribute. While it is contended that auy exemption 
from taxation is wrong in principle, it is equally 
objectionable in practice. The exemption of one dollar 
from taxation, only opens the door for ten more to illegitimately 
evade. For instance, in this State, as shown and 
stated, the total property valuation for taxable purposes, 
is a fraction over eighty millions of dollars, while the fact 
i.s, there is not less than three hundred million dollars 
worth of property in the State, which should be made to </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
126 


yield revenue. With universal and equal taxation, promptly 

collected, the poor man, designed to be benefited by exist\emptions, 
will have by far less to pay than now; so 
mail an amount in fact, that the tax gatherer will be unalilc 
to make change. It is not persons of limited means 
who obtain the advantage of either exemptions or evasions; 
t&gt;tit they of more ample possessions. 

The policy of the State should be the better education of 
the industrial classes. Our future wealth is in the fertility 
of our broad acres. These demand skilled labor, that they 
may produce a maximum of commercial value, with a minimum 
of human labor. Only by calling to our aid every 
available means of cheapening productions, can we bring 
our products into successful competition with other states 
nearer the great markets. The work is fairly begun. It 
needs but your fostering care to make it an institution not 
only of pre-eminent utility in the development of the commonwealth, 
but every way worthy the State and the age. 

While upon the subject of the state prison, he called attention 
to "a fact prevalent to-day, not only in this country, but throughout 
the world, that all well governed and successfully conducted 
prhin— have ceased to be mere instrumentalities for the punishment 
of offenders, but on the contrary partake of a reforma 
Tory character." 

Acting upon the principle that if "industry is a moral 
power outside of the prison, and morality is an economic 
power outside of the prison," they bear exactly the same 
relations to each other inside of the prison. And, further, 
the more a prison is made reformatory, the more profitable 
will it prove economically. While it is true some men are 
born thieves, in the great majority of cases they are not so 
from choice, but from misfortune. The innate criminal is 
treated as a diseased man. Incarceration simply serves to 
place those incapable of self-restraint, in safe keeping beyond 
the power of injuring any one. The object, to impart 
an education, intellectual, moral, industrial and economic, 
as will put it within the power of the prisoner when 
liberated, to keep out of crime. Therefore, society is more 
interested in the reformation of a criminal, than in his punishment. 
Apain. in the &lt;zreat majority of cases of imprisonment, 
innocent and dependent families are the real suf- 

He &gt;;ii&lt;l of the agricultural college </seg>


            <seg id="p026">
STATE GOVERNOR* 

ferers, and should not be overlooked. To this end convicts 
should, in the matter of labor, be paid a just and 

quitable compensation for labor performed, and after delucting 
sufficient to defray the actual expense of maintenance, 
the remainder be paid to the necessitous families, 
or in case of none such, reserved for the convict at the time 
of liberation. This would not only provide to an extent 
or families so often rendered destitute, but would awaken 
self respect and incite to pood behavior and habits of industry, 
that would follow, and lead to future usefulness. 
The system of leased labor of convicts, at mere nominal and 
speculative rates, as practiced in this State and some others, 
s wrong in principle and pernicious in all its tendencies. 
Ljibor, whether inside the prison walls, or outside, should 
ye worthy of its hire. Properly stimulated and manipuated, 
the convict labor in our state prison, could be made 
to yield the State triple what it now does, and still leave 
a balance for the convict or his family more than the entire 
sum now inuring to the State, — the meagre sum of 
Forty-two cents per day. 

The most embarrassing, responsible, and difficult duty to 
perform devolving upon the chief executive, is the exercise 
of the pardoning power. None but the experienced can 
comprehend the situation. In nothing, nor even in all else, 
is he exposed to such censure. In almost every case he 
encounters acrimonious criticisms from those who know 
none of the facts, and have never given the subject a moment's 
thought or consideration. Extremists argue that 
this high prerogative should never be exercised to set aside 
the verdict .or sentence of a court, when the facts are, 
it was created and vested for that sole purpose and no 
other — can be used for no other. The framers of the constitution 
and the lawmakers, had that object directly in 
view. The courts themselves recognize and appeal to it as 
such. They convict and follow sentence with an immediate 
application for executive aid, or clemency, to set aside 
what they have just enunciated, claiming that the law, in 
cases made and provided, is imperative, requiring strict 
observance of the form and letter. I am convinced, however, 
as to the great impropriety of vesting this high power 
in any one individual, especially with such meagre regulations 
as are found in the statute books of this State. A 
pardoning board or council to act in conjunction with the 

executive, with power to command the attendance and pres- 
Kof papers, and administer oaths, would better meet 
• Miirrtrenev. </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
128 


¦Ill 

Rfofc the railroad question had assumed all its wbMfM 
itanec lie §vre expression to the following views: 

There are those who, failing to comprehend fact.*, arr 
prone to charg-e all the ills with which business Inter— U 
are afflicted, and of which they complain, to ihe railroa&lt;l 
companies; and hence there is, just now, conflict in some 
portions of the country. While I wish it distinctly understood 
that in no way am I an apologist for any man. corporation, 
or anything tending in the least to oppression or 
monopoly. I am free to assert what I conceive to be a wellfounded 
belief, that railroads have made the West, and that 
their value is incalculable and universally conceded. True 
they have in instances Uccome .strong, powerful, and profli 
gate organizations, resulting in wrong and oppression. This 
is the natural and inevitable tendency of the concentration 
or aggregation of great wealth, it matters not whether 
in railroad, bank, or manufacturing organizations, individuals 
or in whatever capacity it may act. While it is the 
duty of "the people, in whom all power reposes" under our 
form of government, to protect against any and all reckless 
and unscrupulous acts, let them come from what 
source they may, it is a mistaken idea that mere legislation 
will cure the ills with which business and morals are ofttimes 
afflicted. 

These statements of fact and opinion may also !&gt;&lt;¦ qaoted 

Our population has quite doubled itself within two years 
past, numbering now. without doubt, at least three hundred 
thousand souls. 

The balance on hand at date of last report, December 1st, 
HMJM7. Receipts from that date to date of present 
report. $1,469,408. making total receipts from all sources, 
of $1,667,695. The total disbursements were $1.4:;:;. I 

State warrants are now and have been for a year |iast 
at par. The State has no bonded indebtedness. 

The state university, insane hospital, blind and deaf and 
dumb asylums and state normal school were all reported 
as well officered and in good condition. 

The fifth annual reports of the warden, inspectors, physician, 
and chaplain, in detail, are transmitted, by which it 
will be seen that the number of prisoners incarcerated is 
fifty-four. The total current expenses of the prison for 
the two years, 1873 and 1874, are shown to be $58,000.43, or 
an average of about $538 per prisoner per year. The total 
amount of convict labor at forty-two cents per day is 
$4,.'.4.';.&lt;&gt;4. or nearly forty dollars per prisoner per year. On 
this labor, there i- now due from the contractor, unpaid. </seg>


            <seg id="p028">
129 


1.1. Kstimate for the coming two years, $45,000. Bat 
&gt;ne oases of sickness have occurred within the past 
ars, and but one death since the establishment of the 
With the appropriation made by the lefrislature 
at purpose, an excellent and well selected library of 
lumes is provided and in use by the prisoners. The 
in reports favorably and encouragingly as to the 
improvement, and reformatory tendencies of inmate*. 

TATE LAND! 

There were donated by the general government, known 
,ie lands, seventy-two sections. From this there hare 
.ppropriated by legislative acts: for the benefit of the 
slate normal school, twenty Met!—; U* the model farm, 
in connection with the agricultural department of the state 
university, two sections: for the use of the insane hospital 
one-fourth of a seetion. There hare been sold to various 
persons, as per deed record in this office, seventeen thousand 
five hundred acres, leaving a balance undisposed of 
and on hand, of twelve thousand seven hundred and forty- 

l.cted and approved, to 
lions donated, four and one- 

four acres. There remain to 
complete the seventy-tu 

nth section 

it 1 

VIVU.M l.AM&gt;» 

IXTEKNAI. IM1 

been selected and confirmed, 
P.y acts of the legislature, 
been appropriated and conto 
aid in the construction 
fact the records show, that 
before contirmat ion, thirty- 

Then were donated and h 
t'ne hundred thousand acri 
the whole of these lands h 

a V 

;y\ 

or purposes designate* 
oads and Mdgi 

¦thousand four hundred and seventy-six acres have been 
ed more than the State owned, or was entitled to. 

PUBLIC 111 II.1HV- UMM 

There have been received twenty sections designated as 
for public buildings. The whole of these lands were, by 
met of February l"th. 1-71. transferred, or appropriated to 
aid in the eOMtrneUon of Ike state penitentiary. 

I'KNITKNTIAKY LAHM 

I, ere were donated for the erection of a state peniteny, 
fifty sections, which, in addition to the twenty see's 
before named, made seventy sections applicable for 
purpose. Of these there have been sold and used in 
erection of buildings, forty three thousand one hundred 
eighteen acres. Laving on hand, undisposed of, one 
isand six hundred anil &gt;.vcntysix acres. 

iSDii of hastily deeding </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
130 


I Nl VER8IT1 I AM 

leventv-two sections wer 

lonated 

i'&lt;! mil 

tinned 

ai.iiii 11 i i i: m 

COLLEGE LAND 

Ninety thousand acres were donated 

which eighty-nine thousand four hundred and sixty 
bare been continued, leaving ti\c hundred and forty 
\et unconfirmed. 


The school hinds alone, if sold, would 
boo] fund Of over 120, 1,000. 

EDUCATION 

port of the Superintendent 

for the years 1-7:: and 1*71 i 

most BTatif 

of education. At the cl« 

were 

it 

the State 

The present l 

rt shows 

il I at a fraction over 

imh) raluat 

rears. The total number of 

pupils at 1h 

Is7-' was 51,123: at the cl&lt; 

of W4. 72,991, showing a 

u tlie two year 

'1,868. Th 

iool money apportioned 

IT 


rears 1*71 anil 1872 was somewhat over $370,000. The pal 

two years the total amount apportioned was nearly 
100 of an increase. At the close of the vear 1*7:.' then 

r_' qualified teachers in the State. The re| 

;&amp;lt;nd 1*74 show 

l\( OLS 

II Y !»1- 

The capital city. Lincoln, as originally platted, cona 

if two hundred aixl eighty-seven blocks, or three thou 


four hundred and forty-s 
donated for public 
One hundred and 
sideration of lots in the 
lots were donated to the 

veil lots. Of these sixteen Mocks 

squares and railroad depot pur 
fifty-five lots were deeded in eonold 
Lancaster town-site Twelve 
State Historical Society, (oil 

the various churches and benevolent societies, and twelve 
to the Lincoln Steam Mill Company. Two thousand nine 
hundred and thirteen lots were sold for the afrfrreiraof 
two hundred and ninety-three thousand three hundred 
and fifty-eiffht dollars and seventy-tive cents Three hundred 
and fourteen lots remain unsold. The unsold I" 
principally in the Salt (reek bottom, and of DO considerable 
value at present 

100,000. Ai 

eirhi liti mlro] buildinga, an&lt; 

&gt;v the Superinl </seg>




            <seg id="p030">
K report b\ Governor Furnas, January. 1*7:'., revealed the di* 
ion mail*- of .*&gt;IM).IHMI acres of land donated for internal ini 
einenls as follows: 

To Burlington ami Missouri K 
To I'.rou nville. Kurt Krarncv a 

K. R 

50,104 iKT' 

.¦me] Pacific H. IJ.. 19,1 
uri Valley U. R...1M.9M men 

To Fremont, Klkhorn A' Mi.^si 
To Midland Pacific R. ¦ 
In Omaha anil Southwestern 
in Omaha ami Northwestern 
To Sioux City and I'acitic I!. 
In Gam count* for bridges. 

973 acr 

K. i: 100.010 men 

B 
i; 

¦ arn 
4T.:;'-'T sen 
Ummi acr 
I.ihiii air 

i: 

uitv for bride 

VM.r.i)^ a 

1,3*1 acr 


On the first day of January 

then' wen inn 1 thou- 

sand one hundred and 

mid sixtv-iiine hundred! h* 

) miles completed railroads in the Stale: Inio 

Pacific. 459.90 mill's: Burlington and Missouri Hirer in Ne 

aska. 190.75 miles: Atchl 

n and Neliraska. tin. 7s mil 
5U miles; Midland I'acitic. 

Joseph and Denver. 

miles; Omaha and Southw 

tern. 4T.n."i miles; Fremont. Klk 
50.75 miles; Omaha and North 

n and Missouri Valley 

City and I'acitic. 26.M mil 
•v. in miles. 

IX 

rownville and Fort Kearn 

The proraptaeM and s«-lf sat 

riflcine zeal with which Ooreraoc 

tuas nii-t and ¦Misted to wmmiy a peal slate i-alamiiv. in 
•ndfin of aid from the state treasury, merited the geMfWM 
inendation of those who had hearts to fed and a willing 

ii act. 

KHONTIF.P 

HABD8HIP8, 

Our own State, like most other portions of the country 
at lar^e, especially the West, has been afflicted the past 

season with short crops, by reason of drouth and grass- 
In, pper devastation. While the injury has been greater 
than for anj' and all causes heretofore in the history of the 
Territory and State, and can not be otherwise than dis- 

I Hill aglag particularly to the agriculturists, there is no 
disposition manifested to abandon any portion of the State 
V- soon us satisfied as to results narrated, and as greatly 
exaggerated reports were in circulation as to prolrable 
wants and suffering that would follow to those in the new </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
132 


ounties and on the extreme borders, I immediately placed 

myself in communication with the official authoritie 

each organized county, in order to ascertain, as near as po: 

silile. the actual and true condition of affairs. Reports 

were promptly received from each, from which it was thin 
thought by all conversant, that the emergency could and 

would lie met within ourselves. No power being 1 vested 

in me to make expenditures, and desirinfr to avoid the expense 
of an extra session of the legislature, especially as 
the time for the regular session was so near at hand, I 

uked ¦ number of well-known, reliable and responsible 
citizens from the various parts of the State to meet and advise 
with me. its to the better and most effective mode of 

providing for the wants of those who hail been rendered 

destitute. This committee met promptly at Lincoln, on 

the 1-th day of September last, and after deliberation and 

unsultation, organized, under provisions of the general in 

orporation art. the Ketratka Relief mid Mil Society. A copy 

»f circulars issued, and convening the committee, pro 

nij- and articles of incorporation, together with the de 

tailed operations and labors of the society, to the ".1st da; 
nt December last, are ben with submitted for your infor 

nation. From these it will be seen that the active dutie 
&gt;f the organization have devolved upon an executive con 

inittee of five worthy gentlemen. General K. O. C. Ord 

nations in kind. Total receipt 

4'i 

Supplementing thia voluntary aciion. Congress enacted an ei 
tension of tine in behalf of homesteaders, and a cash appropria 
lion of |3O,6O0 for the purchase of sifds. to be distrib«ted ¦ sating 
the absolutely destitute (or the meceeding year's plaatiag. All 
pereoM who made settlement in Nebraska since L87S, are un 
able to understand the true import of "grasshopper devasta 
Pi." The first visitation of these terrible ]x-sts was in the fall 
lMiii. when a iMirtion of the corn erop hail tnatni-ed and the 
later planted and fall wheat furnished their supply of food. 
Ilariag deposited their efrp; and died before the bediming of 
Eer. the people lived in painful expectancy of greater destruc 
when the gemial i-ays of ¦priag should jjive life to a new and 
nous brood. Hut their subsequent expel leace taught them. 

'ommander of the department of tin" Platte, chairman. 

le 

The reporta of the secretary and treasurer show tin 

ash receipts from all sources to have been 137,279.73. Do </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
133 


that as soon uh able to fiy migration might ensue, or the drenching 
rains of spring CUM their destruction. Eight years then 
after in the fall of 1S74. again they came in clouds that almost 
eclipsed ilic sun and coveted the grand as storms of snow, and 
stripping tields of all llieir fodder and eating into the husks of 
unripe ears, left them to must and rot upon the stalk. Early 
in May the fields of wheat and rye. of barley and oats and early 
planted corn promised luxurious crops, while orchards and 
gardes*, with nurseries of fruit and forest trees were promising 
;i most satisfactory growth. Mul hatching season being past 
the ground in parts of the State was literally covered, so that 
the foot and carriage wheel wherever moved crushed and ground 
their thousands. Trendies were dug around grain fields in order 
ti entrap moving armies before prepared to fly, and when partly 
filled, straw distributed ;ind burned. Low pans of sheet iron 
filled with coal oil were placed at points where they had to move 
along the sides of houses or board fences, into which they 
jumped and were destroyed. Large put, with coal oil, drawn 
by horses, were passed over the tields of young grain, and as 
the insects rose and fell ujxm the fluid they were gathered by 
the bushel. But it was only necessary to make the experiment 
in order to realize how utterly futile must be the effort to control 

descending showers or falling snow. Powerless as children be 
fore a tornado, as the promised crop vanished, and every hope of 
payiag debts and taxes disappeared, and visions of wife and 
little ones pleading for fowl and clothing haunted him and of 
farm stock starving, and of sheriffs and red flags abounding, 
many a toilsome farmer, despairing, shed tears of anguish, 
till the work of desolation was complete came the time of migra 
tion. when about the fifteenth of June. L87S, the clouds lifted 
and lloated westward. "Hoping against hope," at so late a day 
wheat tields were plowed up for corn, corn fields re-planted, 
summer crops attempted as never before, of buck-wheat, turnip-* 
.mil potatoes, and under die smiles of a beneficent providence 
Thanksgiving Daj in November found a great majority of the 
people aroaad frugal hoards, and in places of public worship. </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
134 


One third of tin- corn crop hardened for Market, two third* 
made |M&gt;rk and beef, showing conclusively, that with a favorable 
fall, frost coining laic the crap) run lie aaatared between the 
lirst of .lulv and &lt; tetober. 

of numerous and valuable recommendatioa« we have the lo 
lowing: that in voting for bonds for count v and other pwposi's 
mere majority should noi obligate the property of a large minoi 
itv. Inn a two-thirds vote should be required; that nothing shoul&lt; 
be exempt from taxation, but every s|MM-ics of property shoal 
bear its due proportion, on its actual cash value: that the popt 
lar demand for a constitutional convention lie granted; and tha 
in order to check fraud, all lionds issued in the State should 1&gt; 
registered by the state auditor: and that inducements he o 
fered to capital to invest in manufactures and developing in 
provements; and especially, that Measured lie adopted for a stat 

exhibit, of natural ;m»l artificial resources, ;it the anticipated 

II 

national iM-ntciinial exposition of lsTfi. In ruiieludiiif* a nmsi 

&lt; &lt;nn|»!-&lt;-licnsi\ &lt;• and critical message li«' said: 

I have now performed the last ami most Important offi- 

cial obligation devolving upoa me. and am prepared to 
\acate I lie chair of state, and turn over the archives to a 

successor selected by the popular expression, anil wlio. I 
know, will cheerfully anil readily co-operate with you in 

iicn laudable effort to promote the prosperity and welfare 

for whom von ami he are joint representatives </seg>



            <seg id="p034">
135 

When Uoveraoi Garbet liecame ¦ titiaea of Mebraaiu Inmtwd 
all the training and experience necessary to adapt him to 
his surroundings. At that time he was thirl \ ¦¦seven jean of 
having lieen bora in Logan county. Ohio, in 1888. His education 
m principally acquired before iea&lt;hinjr liis aereatecata fear; 
¦abaeqaeat to which time be removed t&lt;&gt; Clayton county. Iowa. 
Entering the army in the war of 18C1-M as a private in the Third 
.Missouri Regiment, he afterwards recruited Company I). Twin 
rent! Iowa Infantry, of which he hecame first lieutenant ami 
afterward captain. His next experience was fmir years in Cali 
fi'inia among the ¦tirriag scenes of that slaughter house of li. 
.md of thrilling adventures. Without fear of Indian depn-da 
linns, be inok iiji. and maintained, an ahnde in Red Willow. Well 
•-tc-r Coaaty, when lie had only heen |&gt;recedi-d \&gt;\ two families. In 
i he comniuiiily rliat grrw up around him. he beeaate probate 
jaage and repiesentalive in the legislature. From a \ears ad 
ministialion of the register's duties in the United Stales land 

"tnVi- in is"4. be was promoted to the goTCi aotaalp. and was rf 
elected in lsT&lt;». 

Pi assuming the datiea of governor, •lanuary lu'. 1&gt;7."i. \| ¦ 
ier prc Hated a clear, coacioc and surticiently coaapreha 
trural. In this document he called the special attention of 
legislature to the subject of economy. 

its infancy: hut iMUifeM a-- 

imnoiiwealth is in 

md her 

wealth larjri'ly pnwpectiTC 

futnrt- depend* irrcatlv upon the dltreel and prndeni 

ffa 

he said 

I lie tciwifiicx nt the aj. r «" is toward over-legislation, over 
;i\ati&lt;' 'r;n;ii.'iiiii-r 1'tie lessons of history teaeh us 

forms consist, not in doing something 

GOVERNOR SILAS liAKMKH 

l-T.-.-l-7'l 

Deprecating hastj legislation </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
136 


new. lint in undoing something 1 old: and the most valuable 
laws have been those by which some former laws hawbeen 
repealed. 

Ie would administer the affairs of tbe State as a pradeat man 
ndividual affairs, and congratulated the j&gt;eoplc upon the fart 
o bonded debt and hut a slight floating indebtedness. He ad- 
Lted a new constitution, that should be equal to the iitcreasdeinarids 
of a new people and adapted to the ex]&gt;erience of 
•lastic Bad progressive community. 

In gentlemen of the joint convention, it will 
be m\ greatest pleasure t-o eo-operate with you in any anil 
all things pertaining 1 to the welfare of the State. It is just 
that we cannot escape the record which we ourselves will 
make. It is a favorable omen that the public mind is more 
active, and the public conscience more sensitive than ever 
before in the history of the State. We have now within our 
borders the population anil natural resources, sufficient to 
establish a state in fact as well as in name. This result 
will lw best achieved by guarding the public credit as a 
sacred trust. 

Finally, impressed with a sense of dependence upon the 
Supreme Kuler and creator of all things, and ,,iiriilful of 
our responsibilities, let us dedicate ourselves to the work 
of executing faithfully the important public trust committed 
to us by the partiality of a confiding 1 constituency. 

Eie Irgialatnrr of 1S7."&gt;. to which lie delivered his inaugural, 
just received ihe retiring message of (iovernor Furnas, and 
e Mr. Carher's tirst annual message hears date January 5, 
. siine the legislature only convened every other year. 

Gentlemen of the Senate and Iliiii-e of Representatives: 
I cordially welcome you to the capitol of the State. Since 
the meeting of the legislature, at its last regular session, 
there lias been framed and adopted by the people, a new 
constitution, which went into effect on the first day of No\eml»r, 
]-7.',. This being the first regular session since it 
iH-came the suiuenie law. it i.s safe to say that it will be 
ihe most important one since our admission into the Union. 
1-iws :ire to be made and repealed; interests fostered and 

maintained, anil in your deliberations you may justly retfect 
that you are letrKlatinir for- a peopli' characterized by 
intelligence, energy, and a spirit of justice </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
137 


Taking up the Mibjeel «&gt;f state finances he showed 

As ap|&gt;ears from the report of tin- .-^ t ;i t &lt; ¦ t reasurer. her 

with transmitted, the balance in the treasury. November 

tli. 1S74. was $U:&lt;4..'i4:&gt;; and there lias been received up to 

November 30th. IT'S. Sl.459.306. making a total of $1.6 

for two years 

Hi' also Rare a.s ili-liimiifiii t 

ixi's ilic amount of $765,815 of 

which not morv than one third was likHv to be rolli'iti-d 

I he report of the superintendent of public Instruction 

hows that our common schools are keeping pace with the 
'rowtli of the State in wealth and population. 1 doubt if 

liny stale in the I'nion can exhibit more gratifying result 

in this res|M'(t. There are sixty organized counties in 

the State, divided into two 

thousand five hundred and 
number of children of school 
hundred and ninety-one. l&gt;e- 

ten school districts. The total 

ujre. is eighty-six thousand on* 

Ing an increase of thirteen thousand two hundred over H7I 
Of this number fifty-nine thousand nine hundred and sixty 

six attend the public school 

There are : t.: ;?» l teachers em 

salary of £14. J4 |&gt;er month. 

We have I'.is4 school lion 

iilued at 11.385,736. The total 

Ehijrhl.v conimi-udt-d tin- ' 
tv. and anticipate! lli&lt;- t 
of the whole Stan " 

e administration" of tin- uui 

when it would "bwom« 


report, the cost of educating 
university of Nebraska. ;is 
universities and colics;. 

nipared with that in state 

this character in other itatt 

is almost un|&gt;arnlleled in 
Increased from one hundred 
hundred and eighty-two in 

niiniv." The attendance ha 

and thirty-two in lsT4. to tw 

that the legitimate expense of the institution must 

have increased 

i r the institution for the Mind tin- gareraor reported ttiai 
I- liad beea reeeiTed Ity tin- tnateea dwing the i&gt;asr two years 
l."&gt;7. and sjl-expeaded hut tw«j hundrvd and twi-ntv dollars. 
nilding of sufficient capacity to acinnnnodati- tift.v pupilx. 
cost f9.7i&gt;5. Be i-e|M)rrtHi a n«»w building for thi* I»t*af and 

ployed ri'icivinir ;m armg 

receipt! of the last fiscal year from all sources for common 
school purpose- were ll,M3,fT3. The total expenditures 
for the MM period were tl.0M.974. 

¦wi 
imi 

It appears from the regents 
« sinyle student in th»- st:it&lt; </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
138 


Dumb Institute under way. at a coal of $14.4!ir&gt;. and dariBg th&lt; 
|.ast !w&lt;&gt; yean tlie number in attendance was fifty-three. 

ittendance was fifty-three 

This important branch of our educational system | Nor- 

mal Schooll seems to be in excellent condition. The beni 

lit s of tin' school are already felt in the State and the 

results that may be safely anticipated in the future fully 

justify its maintenance. The total enrollment of students 
for the vr;ir l*?'i was two hundred sixty-ei^ht. and the average 
attendance per term was one hundred and forty-two. 

For the last term of the vear the enrollment was one him 

dred and ninety-six. The average cost of the school |mm- 

term as shown by the report of the principal, 

The working of this bent 
Insane] for two years pri&lt; 
hausted an appropriation 

lent institution | Hospital for 
to November, 1876, had ex- 

v 

ii 

if m.746, of which amount 
counties having patients in 
ceding vears one hundred six- 

had been charted 

1&lt; 

i he hospital. Daring two y 
ty-four patients had been 
reported as recovered; nine 

T 

r treatment. Fifty wen 

II IK 

as improved: unimproved, six: 

lii tin- matter &lt;&gt;f tin- penitent 

1 practical reforms ami benerolenl results, ami reported a 
ige of wardens in the interest of less severity and better peril 
influence. Mis sensible and humane ideas can lie best ex 

pressed in liis own words. 

Hie younger class of criminals have been separated from 

he more vicious and hardened and night schools daring 

he winter have been established with excellent results 

These reforms, in connection with the g I time act giving 

prisoners an opportunity to shorten their terms of sen 
lence bv good conduct, h;ive Im'imi productive of much good 

There is sufficient room in the west wing of the buildin 

for a reform school, which could be conducted by the samp 

officers, and put in operation at small expense. This would 
completely separate the younger criminals from the older. 

anil furnish better opportunities for educating and reform- 

Bg them. The penitentiary being completed some branch 

of industry should be established al the prison for the pur- 

¦ f utilizing convict labor. It is absolutely essential to 

the good government of the prison that the inmates lie 

kept at hard labor for a certain number of hours each dav 

r;i|&gt;&lt;»(l. one: died, five: and nincty-1 luce remaining. 
Tin' expense per week fur board and clothing of patients 
il board of officer* «:is for 1876 $2.14. 

ii-v convicts the governor Bought </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
139 



Kiirh in his administration it hrCMMI necessary to organize 
military companies on tin- western frontier of (lit- State, and |&gt;r&lt;&gt; 
. ure from the general government arms and ammunition. In 
accomplishing this he gave bond in the sum of 818,000, for the 
return of tlie guns wlien demanded. Another similar ClueigeBCJ 
.nose in the rase of t he &lt; 'enteniiial Exhibit ion of 18TC, the 
¦tMV kariag failed to make an appropriation. The governor as 
sinned the n*s|H&gt;nsibilit v of borrowing of banks a sufficient 
.imoiiiit to enable the State to obtain a creditable showing and 
'¦ei eive a ]ireiiiiiiin on soil and ¦pplei. 

tie message gave the population of tlie Stale in the spring 
s~c, as being 267,748. Having submitted fads and opinions 
lie question of usury, of banks and bankers, a proper dN 
of the vast land endowment of tlie Stale, and amendment of 
&lt;. and submitted an elaborate statement of the necea 

f a geological survey, with official report! of state officers, 

oniliided with a hearty promise of legislative cooperation. 

His last official communication was made to the legislature of 

~!». after four years of administration. From a glowiag rf 

ipitnlation of past progresR, he found additional sources erf con 

R illation in the condition of the finances, which showed that 
total receipt for the two years ending November. l!*7S. wns 
08,337 and that the assessed value of taxable property, 1878, 
was (74,389,535, beiiifj; an increase of $:».n77.!l."&gt;7. over the pie 
viousyear. and that the condition of the common schools, of the 
normal school and state university had exceeded the most san 
K\pectalions. and the conditions of the charitable insti&gt;ns. 
"devoted to the care and education of our childrea of 

CTOW," were tloiirishinj: 

These sources of commendation were supplemented by valuable 
ninieiidations. First, that provision should be made for 
in}: the salt springs and "Otilixiag the lands donated for their 
development ;'" and that an agricultural bui^au of report! and 
siatistics should be establishe&lt;l for distribution, such as to induce 
iminijnniion; that fish culture should receive OMOWagiBg 
slat ion; thai the Indian control should be gives over to the 
departni.-nt : and the laws r&lt;-ceive a careful revision. </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
140 


His plea for a reform school 
iiiul intelligent, containing: refe 
stales, ami saying: 

for juvenile offenders was hearty 
rences to the experiences of other 

in recommending the est 

ablishment of an institution of 

ihis kind ir the State, I do so believing that charity for our 
wayward youth invokes it and the full performance of a 
righteous duty to humanity demands it. 

1 have an abiding faith in Nebraska's future. Indeed, 
who can not luive. when we compute the value of the increasinp 
flocks that dot her vast domain, and the productive 
wealth of her million acres once subdued and yielding 
golden harvests to enrich the husbandman. 

With a sound and wholesome code of laws for its corner 
stone, we may liuild up here a commonwealth in this center 
of the continent that shall swell the high wave of commerce 
(urging between the mines of the West and the 
marls of the Kast. and. maturing- as it advances in ape, it 
shall stand prominent in the grand galaxy of states. 

I sincerely trust that your deliberations may be conducted 
in harmony and attended with those beneficial results 
so confidently anticipated by your constituents. To 
those officers with whom I have been associated in the conduct 
of public affairs. I extend my warmest thanks far 

their uniform kindness and 

eourtesv. 

And now. in relinquishing 
niy charge four years ago, I 
knowledpnients to a most j 
and upon them, yourself. 

¦ the high trust committed to 
desire to make my grateful ac¦enerous 
and indulgent people; 
and the State, I invoke the 

ontinued favor of Almighty God </seg>


            <seg id="p040">
141 

GOVERNOR ALBINU8 NANCE 

In the career of Albinus Nance we have a splendid illustration 
of the energy and pluck of Young America. He was born in 
March, 1848, at Lafayette. Stark County, Illinois. At the age of 
sixteen years we find him -a soldier in the civil war. He passed 
through the war with only slight wounds. :l nd was mustered out 
with his regiment. Next we find him i n civil life, a student at 
Knox College, at Galesburg. Illinois, where the foundation for 
his professional life was established and where h.&gt; was admitted 
to the bar in 1870, in the twenty second year of his tge. 

Jf his better genius should not fail him. all his past sin&lt; esses 
indicated early achievements in the future. Soon thercafte 
he graduated as a pre-emptor and farmer, and hecttM a representative 
in the Nebraska legislature; was chairman of the state 
delegation in the Republican National Convention at Cincin 

naiti in 187G; and in the same year again elected to the legis 
lature and made ¦peaker of the house of repr;&gt;s.Mitativus, while 
still under thirty years of age. With the dawn of I8ffi, in the 
thirty-fifth year of his age, he had added to his other t^uinph 
and scivic.-s. four years in the gubernatorial chair of ki*rtdopted 

state, and was retiring to private life respected for ma^l^ irtues 
and official integrity. 

The inaugural address of Governor Nance gave the p&lt;\putytion 
of the State in 1881 as over 40(..0.)d. with not note rhV one- 

tenth of its area under cultivation, and only about one third of 
the State populated. 

The Great American Desert had receded as s.-tt lenient advanced, 
and he predicted that soon, as an agricultural stale. Ne 
braska would have no superior, with a large amount of land devoted 
to grazing in the western part. The time was most auspicious, 
as good crops had been secured for several years and 
financially the people were exceptionally prosperous. He urged 

1879- IS </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
142 



p 

ili«- claims &lt;&gt;f agricaltnre and horticulture, of equitable lawa. as to 
inteiosi and capital, and placed the moral and inielleitual cul 
in iv aad protection of the people &lt;&gt;n an even higher plane thai 
exemption from Indian and monopolistic domination. II** madit 
a source of congratulation that a high standard of insimctior 
had been attained in the schools, with an endowment of sea 
si'ii.ooo.iinn. Four years thereafter, at the expiration of hiond 
term of two years each, his statement ,,f progress was ver\ 
cheering. 

On the third of January. L883, Governor Nance delivered In 

last 

message to 1 lit* legislature, 

with the following introdu&lt; 

t 

ion 

ninth/mil of till Si null 

mill Ilimxi u\ I't'i&gt;rrxrn1ntins 
'en conferred upon yon at a 

Legislative authority lias In 
auspicious period in the hi 
lasi regular session of the 
marked decree of prosperity 

torv of the State. Since the 
legislature there has been a 
in c\er\ department of indus 

the future. A brief review 

f our siate history inav I 

profitably considered in this 

connection. At the date of 

admission into the Union in 

braska was estimated at 70,000, and the aggregate value of 

taxable pro]&gt;erty of the Siatt 
tion at the present time, as 
moderate increase n\er the o 

was •20,115,252. The popula 

stimated on the basis of a 

of 1880, is not less than 

iHHUKK). The total as~cs&gt;ed 
by the "-rand assessment roll 

value of property as shown 

the state auditor is B»8,537,47 

The sparse settlements in 1 

•r.T were remote from centers 

of trade and railroad connection, and were deprived oi 
tin st of the comforts of life. The people of Nebraska are 
now brought into close relations with the commercial and 
social world, and it is a gratifying" fact that every organised 
county in the State, except eight, has railroad facilities. 
Two principal agencies have accomplished this transportation. 
The homesteaders, under the liberal policy of 
the jreneral government, accepting a heritage which in itself 
"as a valuable legacy, haw toiled from year to year with 
untiring- energy and splendid success in improving the lands 
thus secured. The capitalists of this and other countries 
having a degree of faith in our future which has been more 
than justified by results, pushed the work of railroad ex- 

try. and our growth in population and wealth lias bei-n a 
marvelous emit, eren to those who had indulged the most 
sanguine anticipations in contemplating the possibilities of 

im;t. tln&gt; population of N&gt; 

if 1882, on file in the office of </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
143 



nl -»— in Rtkrukl with unexampled Mai, and thus 
,,ened the way for the \mrf* immigration whirl, followed 
rom the eaatera states ami the ..1&lt;1 world. The poHej ..t 

ir«-iit-ral gofenmrat, in grntiH aid to nttroada, a 
vinir homesteads to -el tiers, was designed to promot 

geacn] welfare, and it speedily frsive , 1S a railroad sy, 
, which ba&lt; been a poteal airency in developing our nut 

irought us to a period of pioapar 

mentioned 

plateil with feelinirs of pride liv every 

v wl 

Nebraxk 

triag fire* the treasury balaace as *:u:;.ois ; ,i the ead &lt;&gt;f 
-si tern, it was bow, in 1883, S4TJ.114. Inasmuch as s'.t^.'t.M 
due the State as interest ami rentals. &lt;&gt;n sales and leases 
hod lands, he newmmtmiiBi that school land coBtrwta he 
¦II, -d in .as.-s of default, l.elievinf? that persons had bee-. 
holding thes.- lan&lt;ls for s|«-«ulati\e pwipwei. &lt; &gt;n schools lie said 

The school attendance in l^O was I1S&gt;M, an benM 
14.770 over tin- number in attendance the previous yea. 

&gt;|M-rty is estimated at ttJKi,1H* 
enilowinent ha* increased fron 
¦ame proportion as the inereast 
the iacrease per capita has no 

The total value of school pr 

rived from thi 

year to year, in about the 
¦-¦_ population, consequently 

jiaterially chanped 

ity were coiijrr.il ulaled that di» 
settle&lt;l in indication of enlarged 

usefulness and prosperity. His previous message gave the Nor 
mal school 276 students while the one of 1883 reported 818. Th.-state 
library numbered 21,487 volumes. The attendance upon the 
institute for the deaf and dumb, toiag his administration had 
increased from seventy five to one hundred and twenty, at an 
PxpeWK per capita of $3.29 for maintenance per week. The pat 
rmage of the institute for the blind remained about stationary, 
and at a cost of 9&amp;S3 per person per weak. There had been M 
special in. tease in the number of penitentiary convicts and the 
numb-i- of deaths annually, there being but one during his in 
tumbency. Under the fostering care of Governor Nance's admin 
iirtraiion the Reformatory came into existence and had received 
thirtv seven inmates. &lt; &gt;n retiring he said in its behalf: 

l'lie pntetiesl co-operation of the :i\h&gt;\ 

tie friends of the Vni\&lt; -n 
tin).' questions were beBg </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
144 


The tendency of the reform school to repress and pre- 
M-nt the commission of crime is indisputable and if supported 
on ;i liberal scale it will prevent large expenditures 
for the punishment of hardened criminals. If viewed only 
from a humane standpoint the school should have every 
encouragement, as it enables the State to rescue a large 
number of children from vicious surroundings and give 
them the advantage of a Rood education, together with well 

tahlished habits of industry 

The Home for tin- Friendless also dates back to 1881 

The legislature of 1881 provided for the erection of a 

me for the friendless, and made an appropriation for 

hat purpose, subject to the conditions specified in the act 

n compliance with which the institution has been located 

Conceding the great advantage! to the State, by virtue of the 
limulna imparted to settlement and traffic by railroad construe 

lion. th&lt;- governor gave prompt consideration to the compara 
ii\&lt; l\ new question of legislative control: 

the state of Illinois I'vciy phase of the question has 

nsideration daring tin- past twelve years, and 

of a board of Kailroad Commissioners, equitable 
•ansporta t ion have been established and many of 

complained of corrected. I also invite your atthe 
laws of Iowa providing for the organization 

a board of railway commissioner* ami to their suhsticin 
reports and proceedings. The general results in that 
ale have justified the acts of the legislature creating that 
.aid. The reports of the commissioners, both of Illinois 

Iowa, contain a mass of valuable information, bear- 

upon every feature of the question, and may be studied 
h profit by all \\ln&gt; are interested in Mealing impartial 
islation upon this subject in our own State. 

After giving information relative to many items of business 
and enforcing many duties upon the legislator*, Governor Nance 
csnic to his tinal conclusion: 

\s my official term is about to close. I recall with pleasre 
the kindly relations which I save sustained toward 

those who occupy official positions throughout the State 

o the stafc and heads of state institutions with 
liom I have in-.n associated during the past four years, I </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
145 


tender my sincere thanks for their earnest co-operation and 
uniform courtesy. 1 also desire to express the gratitude 
I feel toward the people of Nebraska for the steadfast support 
which tluv have jriven me in my efforts to execute 
the laws with fidelity. The steady and vigorous growth 

if our younp commonwealth during 1 the period that I have 
iccupied the position of chief executive, has been a source 

of continual satisfaction, and I ardently cherish the hope 
that the future of Nebraska may he one of uninterrupted 
prosperity. 

1 Miring the summer and fall of 1882 an active canvass of thf 

Srai •¦ was made in behalf of the "right! of suffrage," an amend 
incut to the constitution betag submitted to extend the right 
irre»i&gt;ective of sex. The discussion which followed the passage 
of the amendment was participated in by most of the distinguished 
orators of the Tinted States, such as Susan R. An 
thony. Klizabeth &lt; 'ady Stanton. Mrs. Sewell, Mrs. Hinman, and 
numerous others. As early as L8M, by invitation of members, 
that pioneer worker, Mrs. Amelia I.Iooiiht of Iowa, presented 
the cause before the legislature of Nebraska. The rejection of 
the amendment by the vote of 1883 argues nothing against the 
willingness of the people to keep step with the oitw&amp;rd march of 
progress. All preliminary acts have been passed and heartily 
approved by them, and although they declined a place at the 
head of the column, they will finally occupy it. Already they 
haw made woman the equal of man in the marriage contract 
and the divorce court, in trade and transferring and holding 
property, in the collection of wages, and the right to bring suit 
at law. whether married or single, and in the professions and 
trades, and clerical positions, limited only by ability, inclination, 
and taste. On the assumption that they who are specially inter 
ested in a subject shall be allowed to discuss and control it, they 
hare provided for women's votes in school meetings. Presently 
old -fogyisui, prejudice, and ignorance, will cease to control, and 
the honestly conservative will decide that the rights of women 
to influence through the ballot should be conceded in county 
and state. The vote in behalf of the amendment was 25,756 and 
against it. 30,t!!t:{. The manufacturers of spirituous liquors, the 

ii </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
146 


retailer*, and many of the drinkers, were a^ united phalanx 
against it. on the ground iliat the ballot of women would be directed 
against the trsjfe and in behalf of sobriety, pure morals, 
and better government. 

As the high license or Blocunb liquor law was approved am 
signed by (iovernor Nance, it seems appropriate that the event 
preceding it should be recorded imng the results of his admin 
istraiion. During the early administration of the Territory. Nt 
braska coald claim a devoted band of temperance workers. Bu 
while a large element of the population consisted of single Btei 
an&lt;l families holding only temporary resiliences, with recent in 
migraata from lands aaacquaiBted with reatrietiTe or prohibrtor 
legislation. eraji a reform in a license system was difficult of a&lt; 
complishinent. So early as 1881, an act was passed to amend on 
of 1868 requiring "an applicant for license to pay for the use o 
the school fund not less than sM.-i.Ilt) nor more than 1200.00 a 

the discretion of the county commissioners." As the population 

became more settled and homogeneous, permanent associations 

were established. Delegates from thirteen local lodges organ 

ized the "Good Templars" in is&lt;;7. and in L881 the local bodies 
numbered 113 with a membership of 5,000. The organisati f 
the Temple of Honor and the Bed Ribbon &lt;'lul&gt;s date back to 
1&gt;77. This revival of interest, much accelerated by the splendid 

services of John 15. Finch, antedated the failure to pass a pro 
hibition bill in 1879. In 1881 the legislature, declining to pass a 
proposition for an amendment of the state constitution in favor 
of prohibition, did finally enact what was known as the "Bloimnli 
Law." in honor of its originator, Hon. ('. B. Btocnmb of 
Jefferson county, which was approved by Governor Nance 1-Vb 
ruary. 1881. In order to secure some semblance of prohibition, 
the law made it a penal offense to sell or give away intoxicating 
liquors in any precinct or township where thirty freehold petitioners 
could not be found; and in any case made it discretion 
an with county boards to decide the expediency of granting 
K-nse. A prohibition county could thus elect a board to carry 
t heir will. It prohibit) d utterly the sa'e to "minors, appreat- </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
147 


tices or servants under twenty one years of age; and to Indians, 

insane persons and idiots and habitual drunkards." The same 
principle was applied to the protection of about fifty-five days in 
t he year, on Sundays and He. lion days. The advocates of reform 
had contended, that the rapport of paupers, criminals, insane.and 

I and the lotobtrj &lt;&gt;f wives and children and community were 
•Iv due to the traffic in liquors and should not be borne by 
q»offmtH»l and helpless, ihrough public taxes and social 

cliai ilies. This propooitioa was conceded by provisions, that the 
retailer should pay all damages It— Mug to the community or 
individuals, and rapport all paupers, widows and orphans made 

so l.v the traffic; and pay for all civil and criminal prosecutions 
urowinj; out of it. 

The amount of license was to be not less than |500 nor more 
than M.niMi. and a t.oiid in a penally of &gt;Ci,IMMl was to tie ijiven 
with which to defray leg*] damages and costs, h was mad. 
a crime to treat or give away liquors to be drunk in any saloon 

r place where they were sold, or to obttrart the view of doors 

or windows willi screens, paint, blinds, or other articles. This 
law. under which the traffic was to live, if it existed at all, was 
the most fearful commentary on its infamy ever published, and 

more desirable for them than 
almost utter impossibility of 

was only accepted by the craft a&gt; 
legislative prohibition. lint the 
patting ils provisions in practice 
extended I In- saloon h.v iinscrupll 
! morals from replenished 

and the interested protection 
.us politicians, and thu paral 
school treasuries, caused the 

t ids .of temperance to desire another effort at legislative pro 
tion. In lxsr.. an act passed the legislature, providing that 
r the tirst of January. 1888, "No certificate shall be jjrant.-d 

to any person to teach in the public schools of the state of No 
hraska. who has not passed a satisfactory examination in physi 

irv and hygiene, with special reference to the effects of alcohol 
n the human system." This was considered a valuabl-itioa 
to reform literature. All necessary preliminaries hav 
been arranged, a prohibitory amendment proposition was 
¦d upon in November. 18M, but failed to receive a majority </seg>


            <seg id="p047">
148 


i^:;-i 

Tin- lifili governor &lt;&gt;f Nebraska was born at McConneUtrille 
Morgan eoanty, Ohio, January s, 1845, where the fust elevei 
years of his life were ipest. In 18M, by the removal of his 
father's family, he became a resident of New I'ort. Wisconsin 
His father's health failed in the practice &lt;&gt;f medicine, and then 
was ample opportunity for an outlay of youthful energy on tin 
land that had been purchased. 

Working on the farm during the season of cultivation. an&lt; 
attending common school in winter, Mpplemented with two 
reran in the preparatory department of Western Rewrre Col 
lege, Ohio, and a six months coarse in a business college in Mil 
waukee. Wisconsin, constituted the extent of his a-jricullura 
and educational acquirements. The death of his father having 
rendered his gradmatioa in college impracticable at this tiin&lt; 
liis self culture was continued during four vears preceding • •• 
tober, 1888, by the reading of law. while clerking in a store 
Having determined upon the law as a profession, in L8€8 he en 
leied the office of John EL Dawes. of Fox Lake. Wisconsin. an( 
was admitted to the bar in January. 1871. 

The same year. 1871. in the month of September, he located 
at Crete, Saline county, or rather anticipated the eMBiag of the 
beautiful little city, for a can-crop had been cultivated upon 
the townsite the previous year. Work apoa the Bmrliagton and 
.Missouri River railroad Daring reached the counly and crossed 
the Mae River, enthusiastic Imatigranta fancied a railroad cen 
tre. the home of niamifact tires and remunerative eommerei 
Bat immigration must produce business before litigation coulc 
famish remunerative practice for the legal profession, and a&lt; 
cordiagly we find the yoaag attorney devoting himself to mer 
Btile jiursuits for the term of six years. In lsTT he opened a 
office and has continued in the practice until recently. 

JAMES \V. DAWKS </seg>


            <seg id="p048">
149 

Mm politics were always a certain ami nrmmtml crop, and could 
be had for tin- gudnriBg, and a merchant of courteous add 
an honorable trader, and a kind and indulgent creditor oee«| 1 
an enviable position anoag public aspirants. Aeeordiagly we 
tind Mr. Dawea a Member of a constitutional &lt;-onv,.ntion in 1ST.",. 
four jean after hh advent to the State, and in 1871 a state senator 
from Saline County, and from that date for six years chairnian 
of the Republican state centra] committee. For four yean 
following 1880, be •erred his party as member of the national republican 
committee, having bee« a delegate to the convention 
of 1880 at Chicago. True to the traditions of his New England 
ancestry and from his own mature convictions, he welcomed and 

espoused die establ ishmeti t of 
tional denomination and lias se 
for seventeen years. In 1882 h&lt; 
competitors -I. Sterling Morton 

Doane college by the ( 'ongrega 
"Ted it as a trustee and secretary 
was fleeted governor, having as 

Democrat, and H. &lt;;. [ngeraoll, 

Independent: and was re nominated and elected to a second tern 
in 1884, having again Mr. Morton as an opponent, with J. B 
Miller. Prohibitionist. Without intending to trace the ofticia 
career of Governor Dawes in these brief introductory allusions 
it can not he out of place to suggest that his .ours.- and success 
should inspire the honest ambitious youth of the State who ar. 
not inheritors of wealth or aids in advancement to coveted Hides 
and oflicial poaitioaa, 

On the fourth day of January 
ered his inaugural address: 

L883, James W. Dawes deliv- 

Gentlemen of the Smotr 
Having been called by tlie jx 
in tlif capacity of their ehi 

mill House of JfcpnMMtftNMH 
ople of Nebraska to serve them 
'f ex.-.utive. it is in obedience 

to tiine-honoreil eiistmn that I appear liefore v.»u to-.lav. 
In enteriiifr llpon ,)„, Mwanigt of the duties' pertaining 

to the position, I am deeply 
bilities and the magnitude of 
ing-. It is my determination 
the service of the people, an 
honesty of purpose and earne 

impressed with its responsithe 
trust placed in ray keepto 
devote my best efforts to 

1 I shall serve them with all 
st endeavor. 

In obedience to the requirements of the constitution, the 
officers of the executive department and ,,f all the public 
institutions of the State have severally reported to the </seg>

            <seg id="p049">
150 


governor. An cxaminat inn of nrlom reports will satisfy 
the most critical thai the affairs of the State are ill .1 sat- 

isfactory conditioa; and they furnish ample evidence of the 
fact that the interests of the State have lieen in able and 
trustworthy hands. For a detailed statement of the conditioD 
of affairs you are referred to the message of my pre- 

decessor that lias just been read to yon and to the reports 
above mentioned, which are full of valuable information 

coacerning public affairs. 1 would ask for them all a careful 
and painstaking examination at your hands, and that 
the various saggestfoMS and recommendations therein contained 
may receive the consideration to which their merits 
entitle them. This examination should be early and careful 
and you will find that economy has characterized public 
expenditure* and efficiency and faithfulness been manifest 
in all the state departments and institutions. I submit 
the following- suggestions and recommendations. 

He then sujrjjested nrch a course of legislation as should attract 
inuiiifrration to the Slate, stimulate every agricultural and 
horticultural interest, advance common school education, sustain 
the state university, invigorate all benevolent institutions commensurate 
with the demands of advance*! humanity, develop our 
hidden resources by a geological survey, organize a sufficient 
and available militia, and protect the people against the sale 
of fraudulent patents and bogus stocks. 

Takin-: uj&gt; the railroad question where his predecessor had 
advanced it. lie jrave it a reasonable and prudent presentation, 

as follows: 

In this connection I will quote from article eleven (11) 
entitled corporations, of the constitution of Nebraska, sections 
numbered four (4) and seven (7): Siet'mn ). Railways 
heretofore constructed or that may hereafter be constructed 
in this State, are hereby declared public highways, and shall 
be free to all persons for the transportation of their per- 

sons nnd property thereon, under such regulations as maybe 
prescribed by law. And the legislature may from time 
to time pass laws establishing reasonable maximum rates 
of charpes for the transportation of passengers and freight 
on the different railroads in the State. The liability of railroad 
corporations, as common carriers, shall never be 
limited. 

Section "!. The legislature shall pass laws to correct </seg>


            <seg id="p050">
151 

and prevent unjust discriminations and extortions 

n all ekuget of express, telegraph and railroad companies 

in this State, and enforce such laws by adequate penalties 
to the extent, if necessary for that purpose, of forfeiture 
of their property and f ranch: 

These citations are made for the reason that I wish to 
•ring- liefoiv your minds directly, and in the most forcible 
manner, the fact that by virtue of these provisions in our 
fundamental law the people have reserved to themselves 
absolute power in all matters pertaining to the correction 
•f abuses, extortions or unjust discriminations upon the 
&gt;art of railroads or other corporations. 

Kuilroads may be justly regarded as among- the most important 
factors in the rapid development of our State, and 
t is of vital importance to all interests that they be sustained 
and encouraged, for it must be remembered that 
such corporations are indispensable to the material prosperity 
of the State. They have in the past been dealt with 
generously by both the Nation and the State; and there is 
o-day no sentiment among- our people such as demands 
hat the railroads should be either destroyed or crippled to 
he extent of impairing- their usefulness or so restricted as 
&lt;&gt; deprive them of a legitimate return upon capital invested, 
f the railroads have been unjust, the people will not in 
urn be unjust. The people can not afford to be unjust to 
•»ny interest, but will be careful that the rights of the publicis 
against corporations are protected by efficient law. It is 
uil.v asked that such control and regulation be had as will 
M just and fair considering- the respective rig-hts of both 
he people and the corporations. This is no unreasonable 
lemand. It is such a demand as keeps steadily in view the 
mportant fact that with our resources as yet all but undeeloped, 
we must not repel capital by legislation such as 
vould hazard our best interests. 

The custom of granting- passes, on the part of railroad 
corporations, to state officials and members of the state 
I'iri slat ure. is one of long- standing 1 , and I might say, of 
dmost universal practice. While I do not believe that 
&gt;as.sis have been given or intended in the nature of a bribe, 
or for the purpose or with the expectation of improperly 
influencing- the action of individuals, or that they have been 
considered by those who may have taken and used them as 
placing- them under any obligation, direct or indirect, the 
fact yet remains that a pass represents value, and its accepiance 
is for that reason of doubtful propriety. To the 
end that the representatives of the people may be enabled 
to avoid even the bare suspicion of having been improperly </seg>

            <seg id="p051">
152 


influenced in their action or 

in the faithful discharge of 

their public duties, it is recommended that a law I uactcd 
prohibiting the granting of passes to officials of the 

f passes to officials of the 

executive department of the 

¦tale, member* of the lecris 

latiire. anil to nny of the das 

f officials who. by &gt;-• 

f their public position, may 

have it within their power 

ither to confer or withhold 

f 

Rvora or benefits to railroad 

irporation.s 

In conclusion I wish to I 
ulciilati-d to promote the h 

.-sure you. that in all matter! 
jnor, property and general welha\e 
mv earnest co-operation, 
discharge of the duties of the 

fare of the State, yon will 
and that entering upon the 

executive department it is in t lie Arm belief that you will 
extend to me your uenerous aid and counsel. 

When Governor Dawea delivered his tirst biennial imn 
•liinuarv n. 1885, In- gave the balance of funds &lt;m hand in tli 
treasury at *44J.Mii. iiiid the assessed value of taxable proper! 
of the State at 9123,615^86. He declared that all of the pnhli 
institutions of the State were in excellent hands. Of the noa 
pital for the insane he reported "410 received daring the pas 
two rear*, which added to the former number of 873 made 
total of 683. of the amber treated, 323 have been diacharga 
144 of whom were restored to mental health. (i!t mini) hiiprovei 
&lt;&gt;'¦'&lt; uniiii|iroved were retamed to their counties, and tort} 

three died duiinfr the two years." 
He said of the Borne of the Friendless 

The Home was opened to receive inmates January 1st, 
tad since that time has received, adults 95, children 
133 — making a total of 22S. There have been surrendered to 
the Home 73 children and of this number 57 have been 
placed in good homes in this State. 

It appeared from the report! tli 
years. 141 had all ended the Deaf i 
ous application* had been made 
minded persons, of whom we had 

at daring his fust term of two 
and Dumb School, and nuinerfor 
the reception of feeble 
in 1880, as shown by the cen- 

sus, 356; and hence the recommendation of a separate institution 
for their benelit. During the same time thirty six pupils had 
been in attendance upon the School for the Blind. To the credit 
of the school, its industrial department had an exhibit at the </seg>

            <seg id="p052">
153 


131 discharged from the Pen- 

There had been during this term 

itentiaiv and 17s receive*, leaving of whom 23 were in for 


The State Befera School is entitled to special ¦Otke, of which 

overnor said: 


Under the law regulating- the — lglW&lt; of this institution, 
boys and pirls under sixteen years of ape found guilty 

f any crime except murder ur manslaughter may l&gt;e re¦ive.l. 
This school was established and intended not for 

punishment, strictly speaking, but rather for education 
and reformation; a place of restraint and correction for 
tfcoM for whom such treatment may suffice to restore them 
to an upright life and fit them for future usefulness. Standing 
between the youthful offender and the institution prepared 
for and whieh should receiv ily hardened criminals, 
the interests of society demand that a liberal policy should 
be pursued. in carrying out and promoting the objects for 
which it was created. The school has at present H inmates. 
In August, 1883, the contract was let for an additional build- 

B*, at a cost of *:i7,410. This building has been completed, 

and is now ready for use, and 1 am informed that applications 
for admission, now on tile, will exhaust th- 

accouiiuodations so furnishe 
the great importance of the 
the organization of this ref 
mend for it reasonable supp 

1. I would impress upon you 
work we have undertaken in 
inn school, and would recom- 

:&gt;rt and encouragement 

he educational exhibit showed a constant and healthy prog- 

I 


Xebraska is justly proud of her common schools, and 
much of their efficiency is due to the wise planning and well 
directed effort of our present state su|x-ri..tendent of public 
instruction. The following statistics will be found of interest 
as showing tin- development of our State in the direction 
of her Amies! educational interest, the common school. 

¦.103; boys, MM**! girls, 
.ills; boys. Tl.iisO; girls. 65,938; 
employed. I .Ml; males. 1,906; 

Total number of school ag&lt; 
100,40."; total enrollment. 131 

total nunilxT of teachers 
females, 4,144; school house 
ber of school houses, 3,662; 

I built in l- 'otal numtotal 
value of school property, 
3 \ fund, $3,'.i77.-J16; temporary 

¦?J.T-f).:!85; permanent scho&lt; 
school fund, $l,021.JJv 

He gave the attendant- at State Normal School at 470 for past </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
154 


t years, and gradlMtit M. The library contained 2,000 vol 
*. and the attendance was increasing at the rate of 20 per 
The dove of peace once more hovered over the University, 
(he whole attendance last year was 282. The announcement 
an industrial or agricultural college had been established, 
a practical farmer in charge, was accompanied with the 
umendation that liberal appropriations be made. 

Agriculture is the leading and most important industry in 
the State. An examination of the report of the State Board 
of Agriculture, which (rives a detailed statement of their 
proceedings, plainly shows that their work has been well 
done, and that the aid given this board has been well bestowed. 
While the prices received for our farm produce 
are not as remunerative as at other periods in our history, 
yet speaking in general terms our agricultural interests, 
as shown by crop statistics, were never in a more prosperous 
condition. The horticultural interests of the State are 
in a flourishing condition, and it has been established beyond 
a doubt that Nebraska is a fruit state. The matter of 
successful fruit culture is one that enters largely into the 
economy of home life, and I am safe in saying that no one 
tinny has done more to attract favorable attention to our 
State than the magnificent displays made by our Horticultural 
Society at the different competitive exhibitions, in 
which, in a majority of cases, they have received for Nebraska 
the first prize for their display of fruits. The Agricultural 
and Horticultural societies deserve your fostering 
care as most serviceable agents in developing our State, 
and as aids in placing her in the rank to which she may 
justly aspire. 

The goveraor reported the 

second case of escheat, in which 

BO heirs to the estate of Peter I 

Anderson being found in Kearney 

county, the amount of |l24ti W 
intendent of education and by 

as turned over to the state super 
him deposited in the treasury for 

I benefit (if the school fund. He also remembered the State 
lorical Society approvingly, complimented the economical 
hods of the Fish Commission, and reported the State Library 
."{.ItliH volumes* and in good condition. He urged the import• 
of keeping pace with sister states in the organization of the 
tia, slated that the contract for the main building of the </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
155 


I capital was dosed at *4:t!».ls7. that the eoatraetor'i bobs' 
beea Hied in the sum of f:iOO.0nn. and further that | 
bee* transmitted to the Lincoln Monument Association at 
ii&lt;:ticl(l. Illinois, in accordance with the act of February. | 
I'l-oiiiiuendin}; an additional appropriation for the Hew &lt; &gt;r 
s Kxposition the governor paid a high compliment to «-x 
¦rnor Furnas for his part in preparing an exhibit and said 

As it was deemed of greatest importance to the interests 
f N«*l&gt;raska that she should be npumlij at 

int meeting of tin- State Agricultural and Horticultural 
•¦ties they agreed to advance $1.(MHI each from the funds 

at their disposal and look to the legislature to reimburse 

them. The remainder, $3,000 
at Lincoln and Omaha upon 
and members of the ajio\e ¦ 

was obtained from the banks 
the personal notes of myself 
K-ieties, for which you will be 

ked to provide 

A 

new feature of the BMBOafl 

involved the creation of a board 


itc charities, and health. Of the former he said: 

The creation of a board of this character will be a step 
the direction of II I ill lag a more just, humane, and ecounical 
administration of public charity and correction. 

Of 

the latter: 

A communication has been received at this department 

from the National Hoard of Health, setting forth very fully 

the danger that menaces the people of this country in the 
apprehended appearance of Asiatic cholera, and earnestly 

reqaeatiBg that the attention of the lep-islature be called 

to this subject, and to the urgent necessity of appropriate 

legislation providing means whereby the most thorough 

unitary service, state and local, may !«¦ immediately oranized. 


tttetntion was also called to the necessity of such laws as 
Id jjnanl against the spread of "infectious or contagious dia 
« among the stock of the State." The doctrines of his in 
iral were reiterated on the subject of railroad supervision, 
statement of revenue from educational lands, December 30, 
, was veiv satisfactory and cheering: </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
156 


There were under lease MI^M acres, appraised at $M? 
44. and bearing an annual rental of HM,91* at an av.ia 

valuation of $-'.4!» per acre. There were under sale 4(11, 40 

the unpaid principal of which is hwnlug six per eent 
nn 93,111,542 and amounting- to tlM,TS2. There were 

-CT of the permanent funds invested in securities, t 
annual interest on which is SM. .&gt;.-,, making- in all a teni| 

rary fund from land receipts alone, of $4:12,257 per annum 

There are still vacant and unappraised 1.47*.&lt;1SG aci 

common school lands, or about one-half of the original 

grant. 

The whole number of acres of land owned by the State December 
1st. L884, were: Common school, 2,7M£83; Agricultural 
College, §»,080; Iniversitv. 44.'.mh; ; Normal School, 12JB82; Saline 
lands. i::.:!(is : Penitentiary. )&gt;7«: total. 2,!)il7.177. 

Kving officially called legislative attention to the question 0 
&gt;ad supervision, and clearly elucidated the fact that tin 
constitution gare full and adequate power in that behalf, it mus 
hare been very gratifying that the legtelatare so promptly me 
the (|iiesiion. The ad passed provided for a Hoard of Haihoai 
Commissioners consisting of the attorney general, secretary 0 
state-, and auditor of public accounts, with a secretary for each 
to represent him. and granted as complete control of railroad 
as if they had been the personal property of the Hoard, sale onl 
'-.\.,-pted. and limited only by the terms of charters and stat&lt; 

laws and "the safety, convenience and interest of the public 

To proted the fOUg and throw safeguards around the de 
pendent and unfortunate, in the humane spirit of the governor's 
message, acts were passed, first, that all employers of femal. 
help in stores, otli.es and schools should furnish chairs, stool 
or seats on which to rest when duties permitted relaxation; kc 
ond. providing for a female assistant in the medical departmen 
of insane hospitals; third, that no censorship should be exercised 
over the correspondence sent from or addressed to the inmates 
of insane hospitals, but every facility should be furnished for 
K correspondence; fourth, that "every person unable to earn 
ing on account of bodily infirmity, idiocy, lunacy or other undable 
cause." should be supported by certain relatives spec </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
157 


ilifil in the law; fifth, that bodies of unclaimed paupers might 
be given up for dissection to medical colleges under bonds, and 
by an order of a court, to be used within the State only, and "in 
a manner that shall be private and in no wise shock the sensibilities 
of the community where procured or dissected"; and 
sixth, that tobacco in none of its forms, nor cigarettes, shall be 
given or sold to any minor under fifteen years of age. In a spirit 
of reform and economy grand juries were to be convened under 
the discretion of the courts. In simple justice, females having 
property taxed for school purposes and children of school age 
were allowed to become voters in school district meetings; and 
by another act. all persons were declared entitled to the same 

civil rights in inns, public conveyances, barber shops, theatres 
and other places of amusement. 

B compliance with his recommendation an appropriation of 
was made, to be annual, in aid of the State Historical Sod 

ety; and it was declared to he 
to have its reports printed and 
ments. 

i "state institution" and entitled 

distributed as other public doci 

There lias never been a mort 

valuable set of joint resolutions 
that of IMS, memorializing Oh 
it many politicians were Tfiag 

passed by a legislature than by 
-. Considering the fact th 

that "the duty of tariff tax." imposed by the general government 
on Imported articles, was not paid by the consumer, but by the 
foreign importer, it became a matter of exultation with revenue 
reformers, that Congress was implored to place the material, of 
which barbed-wire was made, on the free list, because if not. 
the people had finally to pay the duty. In the same spirit, and 
for the same purpose of cheapening transportation upon produilions 
carried over railroad bridges which cross navigable streams 
of the United States. Ooagress was called upon to demand the 
abolition of all tolls upon those spanning the Missouri Hiver in 
Nebraska. And, inasmuch as railroads having land grants were 
delaying to receive patents for such lands, in order to escape 
taxation upon them, the importunate demand was made, that 
they be compelled to receive patents as fast as due. </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
158 


On the delivery of his final meaaage, of January &lt;&gt;, 1887, ai the 

end of an official term of four years, lie discovered no state interest 
Impaired; bat a steady advance in all material concerns 
Tin- benevolent and other state institutions added the usual pet 

cent of healthy advancement to their statistical statements c.f 


Tin- organizations of the counties of Dawes, Logan, Sheridan. 

¦se. Blaise and Sioux, were announced during the two pre 
dc rears. The recommendation of two ream before, in regard 

to a State Board of Health, was re-affirmed, in behalf of "tin 
*th and life of the citizens of the Slate." Favorable rel'eren. 
made "to the time which is not far distant, when Nebraska 
following the example of oilier states, will feel the necessity c&gt; 
establishing a Soldiers Home, for the care and support of th 
II and disabled veterans of the late war." The amount o 
S87 had been received by the general government and place* 
he credit of the state treasury. While. the slate census o 
1883 had cost f39,774, all of that amount excepting sri.nl.-; htu 
been paid by the general government. 

From a thorough understanding of the school system and the 
administration of its landed estate. Governor Dawea aJBfmcd 
that its condition "may well excite the envy of others, who liav 
ing received the same munificent grants, have managed them less 

wisely. 

In the matter of railroad supervision he approbated the recent 
legislation, looked to Congreaa for interstate legislation, and 
called for conservative and just disposition of the question. 

This sketch may close witli his farewell to his constituents ami 
the executive office: 

Nebraska, passing through the days of infancy and youth, 
lon«" since entered into ttie period of vigorous life and 

The iiroiMi valiiiii ion of the taxable property of the 
State in IMS \\;is 1133,418,699, :m Increase of I9.WI.III h 

tie 

compared with the ¦ me lament of 1 S M. The mhmbcbI of 

f\c the value of the property of the State for the pur- 
of taxation as $143,932^70, piviiiir a total hiciwi 

two rears of 120.316 </seg>



            <seg id="p058">
tands to-day ainonjr the pro. 

perous and prominent eom- 

miniwi'alths of the Nation. In 

material progress and upon 

all lines of devel 

piiicnt the 

t rides of improvement have 

nt. The 

change* that have been in- 

been without prf 

wrouprht into her 

history are 

marvelous and far-reaching. 

all occupations, stimulating 

The throb of pn 

filling 

all industries, int 

iisifvinir all 

activities, is strong and con- 

stant. To. tli 

who in the 

iwal of their confidence 

have ro honored 

lie, from whom this great trust " 

i\«'il. I wish. 

re eloafag my relation with the executive 

office, to make p 

found aelinowleiljjinent : and in conclud 

wish and hope that the fu- 

inp mv m&lt; 


ture of Ne 

nav. under 

continued guidance of th€ 

r of Nation 

that of !&gt;¦ 

ike 1 , hapiiiness and prosper 

it v iiniiiteirupted </seg>

            <seg id="p059">
160 


GOVEKXOK JOHN MILTON THAYER 

1887-1WM 

As governor, he delivered his inaugural January 6th, 1887 
from which, by liberal quotations, it is easy to create his idea 
citizen. Such ;in one measuring up to his standard, would, in 
education, dearly illustrate the value of "thoroughness instea&lt; 
of &lt;|uantiiy" and the worth of "practical studies more than orna 
mental," and the infinite utility of "the languages of the presen 
instead of the aged past." As a legislator he would enact "such 
laws as the public interests demand, to protect the rights of al 
the people." He would affirm "that there is no condition o 
human beings &lt;»n this earth so pitiable, so deplorable, as is th 
condition of those from whom the light of reason has forever de 
parted, and who linger in life, driveling idiots or raving maniacs." 
And inasmuch as they arc shut in from the world, he would de 
mand that all penitentiaries, jails, almshouses, houses of correc 
lion, reform schools, homes for the friendless and poor house 
should be subject of careful inspection. He would demand a 
••uniform system of taxation according to values and not accord 
ing to ownership." 

As between railroads and the people, his theory would be 
that while ''railroads are a necessity to the people, the people are 
also a necessity to the railroads." He would respond cheerfully 
to the declaration, "our sympathies should ever lie with thos 
whose lives are devoted to daily toil"; and in the exercise of the 
elective franchise he would not fail to act upon the declaration 
"the purchase and sale of votes is a crime of the most heinou 
character against the State, against society, against civilization.' 
Among his political maxims would be prominent, "No one ha 
any light to make money at the expense of the State." Seated in 
the shade of his own artificial grove, hear him exclaim, "One of 
the pleasing features of civilization in this State is the planting </seg>


            <seg id="p060">
161 

and growth of trees"; and caressing his beautiful live stock and 
receiving their submissive returns, and remembering how often 
they are neglected and abused, with what noble emphasis he &gt;-x 
claims. -There are human brutes as well as dumb brutes." 

At the time the governor delivered his first biennial mes&gt; 
the following statement showed the condition of the treasui 

Disbursements. Deceinlier 1 

1 

16. to November 

4.^44.- 

Itnlanee in treasurv Noveml 

r ML W 


At .he end of his second elective term it stood as follows: 

December 1. IMS, cash on hand 

¦ 

Fotel receipt 

1.IV27 14 

November 30, l-*s;». disbursements since Decem- 

ber 1. l*ss 4,023,378 94 

November I!'). ISM. balance on hand 

1,599,2 

The Auditor's Report gave in 1888 

The assessed valuation of the taxable property of the 
State in 1887 was $lf&gt;o..-,OC&gt;.:. &gt; r,r,. ¦_&gt;.-,. being an increase of $16,- 

573.69.V7l as compared with the assessment of lssti. The 
-meiit of MM tfave the value of the property of the 
State for the purpose of taxation as $176,012,830.45, ffiTiag 
a total increase for two vears of $32,080,249.94. 

rm the next Auditor's Report the following is taken for the 
1889 and 1890: 

The assessed valuation of the taxable property of the 

being' an increase of 6,750,-mmmmmtm 
of 1888. The asof 
the property of the State 
$184,770,304.54 giving a total 
7.484.09. 

State in 1889 was $182,763,538.41, 
717.96, as compared with the a: 
sessment of 1890 gave the value 
for the purpose of taxation as 
increase for two vears of $8,75' 

These two reports covered the 

assessments of four vears or 

two biennial terms. During his term of four years he received 

12 

Nnvi-inlier ISO. 1S!H). receipts sim-f IViemlnr 1. 
im mm 

Balance in treasury November 30, 1886 tMI.IHl W 
Receipts, December 1, issr,. to Nov. ::n. l^s* iJMJ 
Total receipts 5,180,881 70 </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
162 


and deposited in the treasury of the State five per cent ou sales 
of government lauds, and otherwise, $281,246.20. 

If the Message, closing the year L8SO, delivered to the lefjis- 

Ere of 18!tl, had been specially 
at, to separate between the 
marking the half-way period 
abounded in mine complete 
tutions. 

intended as a monuniiMiial doc 

first and fiftieth years of state 
between them, it could scarcely 
statistical statements of public 

The 1ot:il enrollment of s 
been iteadily grow lag from 
were, all told, 4n&lt;"&gt; students: 

tudents in the University has 
year to year. In 1SS7-S there 
in 1888-89 there were 427: in 

1889-40 there wen 47.".. For the current year of 1890-91 there 
!ir&lt;&gt; already enrolled Hi students in all depart incuts although 
but one-third of the year has passed. Of this number 
208 are young- women, and 303 are young- men. In the 
first two years the students are preparatory, and duringthis 
time the work is nearly the same for all. After this the 
student pursues the studies which are peculiar to his 
course It is found thaf twenty per cent of the young men 
and young women pursue the classical course; IS per cent of 
the men and G."&gt; per cent of the women the literary course; 
45 per cent of the men and 15 per cent of the women the 
industrial coin 

From the biennial report of the prineip.il of the Nebraska 
State Normal School, it appears that during the year ending 
December, ISM, there were in attendance in the Normal 
School proper 572. Of these 370 were ladies and 192 gentlemen. 
Fifty-nine graduated in June of that year from the 
two courses, the elementary and the higher. 

For the year ending December, ISM, there were 553 in attendance, 
of whom 395 were ladies, and 160 gentlemen. One 
hundred and twenty-eight graduated from the two courses. 
of whom seventeen were of the higher course. Nearly all 
of these graduates, and many of the undergraduates, are 
now engaged in teaching or in school work. As a significant 
fact bearing upon this point, it was ascertained that at the 
late assembly of teachers which was held in Lincoln, the 
largest in the history of these meetings Of the State, about 
one-sixth of the entire enrollment were persons that had 
been connected with the Nebraska State Normal school, 
most of them graduates of either the elementary or higher 
course. 

The public schools in this State are in a prosperous condition. 
The continued faith and confidence of the people in </seg>



            <seg id="p062">
our public school system is shown by the fact that the sum 
of $4,215,463.41 was contributed to their support for school 
year 1889-90. Of the common school land 225,419.43 acres 
lave been deeded, and 517,902.89 acres are still vacant. 
The annual interest upon sales now amounts to 226,-006.95, 
and the annual rental charged is $190,927.96, making 
-i total annual income from these lands of $416,934.91, to be 
apportioned to the school districts of the State in addition 
to the revenues derived from the investments of the permanent 
school funds already in the treasury. During 1 the 
past two years the State has received from these lands in 
principal, interest, lease rental and added interest, the sum 
of $1,141,211.00, which already exceeds the receipts of any 
previous biennial period since the establishing of this department 
in the state government. 

The report of the warden of the Penitentiary presents 
the following statement: 

Total number of convicts received since the organization 
of the prison up to November 30th, A. D. 1S90, 1,S57; total 
number discharged since organization of the prison up to 
November 30, A. D. 1890, 1.44:"; total number of deaths during 
the same period, 2fi; number in the prison November 
30th, 1890, 387; number in prison December 1st, 1888, 338; inirease 
in last two years. 49; received in last two years, 394; 
discharged in the last two years, 296; died, 4. The management 
and discipline of the prison is deserving of the highest 

mmendation 

The biennial report of the Nebraska Hospital for the Inline 
shows that there were in the hospital November 30th 

!^»-. three hundred and ninety-two patients; that there have 
been received during the two years three hundred and 
ninety-eight; that there have been under treatment during 
the period seven hundred and ninety patients; that there 
have been discharged and recovered one hundred and fiftyfive; 
improved, sixty-one; unimproved, seven; not insane, 
eight; transferred to other state institutions, one hundred 
and sixty-three; died, fifty one; and that there remain in 
the Hospital at the close of the period, three hundred and~ 
twenty-six, with sixteen absent on parole; a total of three 
hundred and forty-two patients, therefore, still on the rolls 
of the Hospital. You will note from the very complete report 
of this institution that there have been discharged as 
recovered 39 per cent of all cases admitted, and that the 
death rate has been only 6*4 per cent of the whole. 

The report of the Superintendent of the State Industrial 
School, located at Kearnev shows that since the ornnizm- </seg>

            <seg id="p063">
164 


tion of the school 471 boys, and 149 girls have been committed 
there by the courts. Of this number, 281 boys and 
67 girls have been paroled, pardoned, discharged by legal 
process and otherwise. Ninety per cent of those who left 
were regularly discharged, and at least eight out of every 
ten of these are doing well; many of them holding responsible 
positions. The present enrollment is 275. The educational, 
physical, and moral training has been carried on as 
thoroughly as possible. Kach inmate attends school from 
four to five hours each day during nine months in the year. 
Statistics show that at the time of commitment 61 per cent 
of the boys were idle. H per cent were attending school, 
and is per cent were at work. Of the girls :;:; per cent were 
idle. M were at work. :S2 were at school. 

The report of the Superintendent of the Home for the 
Friendless will make known to you the condition and operations 
of this institution: 

NumlKT of inmates in Home December. IMS, 110: admitted 
since December. IMS, 4O2: surrendered to friends. MB; 
placed in homes. DO: returned to friends. 34; number for 
whom work was found. 54; absent to other institutions, 10; 
deaths, 77; Dumber in Home December, 1890, 111; total. Sis. 

The Home for the Krii'iidli 
amount of good. 

Id 

tlie message c&gt;f ISS'.I lie said 

In this institution the waif; 

of humanity find comfort 

able homes, and kind motherly care. It is conferring a 
blessing upon the State, and upon humanity. Those in 
charge are imitating the example of their Divine Master 
in relieving human suffering. They are gathering in and 
saving the abandoned: their institution is in reality the 
home of those who have no home. I trust you will regard 
it with favorable consideration. 

In 

anticipation of the report of the State Board of Agricul- 


Gov. Thayer echoed the universal opinion of patrons in 

the following language: 

While nearly all the conditions and environments of the 
work for the year 1890 were of adverse character, extraordinary 
efforts on the part of the management, exhibitors 
and patrons were crowned with unusual success. For reasons 
well known to all, crops were short, and the people, 
in many instances, discouraged. Still there was never be- 

i&lt; accomplishing a jrreat </seg>

            <seg id="p064">
165 


fore so grand a presentation of the products, resources and 
possibilities of the State. This was true more particularly 
in the matter of direct products of the sod, thus .showing 
in a marked degree our wonderful capabilities as well as 
the characteristic energy and industry of our people. At 
the State Fair, the Horticultural Society succeeded in bringing 
together the best exhibit of fruit which has ever been 
on the grounds, and it was thought to be as good a one 
as was made by any state fair in the United States last 
year. 

In addition to the stereotyped items of Governor's message, 
&lt;;&amp;amp;lt;n. Tliavcr had many new subjects thrust upon him, as the 
result of the marvelous progress and changed condition of the 
State from her infancy to majority; for in reality the end of his 
Becond term closed the first quarter century of her existence as 
a state in the Union. In his biennial message of 1889, he said of 
the Union Pacific Railroad: 

The kind of settlement, which the Union Pacific makes 
with the government, does not interest the people of Xebraska 
nearly as much as the question of lower and reasonable 
rates. In regard to all railroads in this State, this 
principle, this right, must be asserted and maintained, 
namely, that no higher schedule of rates shall exist in Nebraska 
than prevails in Kansas or Iowa, or other states. 
The board of transportation now possesses full power. If, 
however, anything is wanting, it should be given them. The 
members of the board should be chosen by the people. 

In 1891 he expressed the following sentiments: 

Observation cannot have failed to convince any one that 
there is a growing disregard for the sanctity of the ballot. 
Too many regard it as merchantable instead of being the 
grand right of American citizenship. Too stringent enactments 
can not be made for guarding the purity of the ballot. 
There are many who seem to have no proper conception of 
its value. They look forward to the election when they 
may offer their votes for a price just as the farmer looks 
forward to the coming of the harvest time. What is known 
as the Australian Ballot System evidently comes nearest 
to preventing frauds on the elective franchise. The testimony 
from those states where it has been tried is that it 
has accomplished the purpose for which it was designed, 
and has given general satisfaction. I, therefore, unhesitatingly 
advise its adoption in this State. </seg>

            <seg id="p065">
166 


The experience of the last two years has made it iipparent 
that public warehouses are a necessity in order to protect 
the interests of the farmers. A year afro the price of corn 
was 14 cents a bushel. It is now selling nt an mn|li of 
45 cents per bushel. Had a warehouse law similar to that 
of Illinois and other stales been on our statute book, its 
beneficial results would have been of almost incalculable 
value. I, therefore, recommend the passage of a law with 
an emergency clause providing 1 for public warehouses with 
suitable provisions for holding grain and other products by 
compelling 1 the warehouse men to receive, ship, store and 
handle the same without discrimination. Warehouse retaken 
for the grain thus stored are equal to the best 

commercial paper 

I he (lovi'rnor had an opportultj of testing the practical utilof 
the National Ghurd, which was mustered and officered 
er liis own administration, when they were called upon in 
of the Regular! in suppressing an Indian outbreak. 

I cannot too strongly commend the promptness and patriotic 
zeal manifested by the officers and members of tin' 
National (iuard when the order was issued for them to take 
the field. It reminds one of the days of '01 when loyalty 
and patriotism seemed to inspire all hearts. 1'ortunately 
the Indian war on our northern borders has been brought 
to a close. and the National Ouardssent forward for the protection 
of the settlers have been returned to their respective 
homes. It gives me great and sincere pleasure to say 
tliiit all the reports from the region where they performed 
their service commend them in the highest terms for their 
soldierly l&gt;earing. and their faithful discharge of the duties 
devolving upon them. The service to them was new, and 
it was rendered in severe weather, subjecting them to cold 
and privation, yet their duties were performed without a 
murmur, and they rendered most valuable service to the people 
in shielding them against the probable attacks from hostile 
Indians and in restoring 1 confidence to all. General 
Colby and all his command have won for themselves the 
unbounded respect of the people of the State, and have 
made a reputation in which all citizens will take just and 

laudable pride. 

Ee thus refers to the work 
lion in 1889: 

the Live Stock Sanitary Com 

of 

At the beginning of the work 
isted in nearly every count v in </seg>



            <seg id="p066">
167 

Af 



its insidious ravages has been, and is still a determined one, 
and so far successful that at the present time forty counties 
are reporting no mmm. The law, as amended by the last 
legislature, allowing payment of indemnity of animals destroyed 
by the State, has greatly facilitated the reporting of 
suspected rases and prevented the secreting of the di 
It has proved a blessing to poor and deserving- farmers, 
many of whom are entirely dependent upon their horses 

ml mules for means of support, and to whom the payment 
f this indemnity is a boon, while the State is being- relieved 
f a terrible KOtuge, dang-erous alike to man and 

evcral persons lime died of it in the past two years in thi 
&gt;tate, having contracted il in caring- for afflicted animals 

and mules have been de-sion 
sinee November 30, 
UWUl of indemnity alneravrinir 
W3.M per head, 
xty-six counties, showmtr 

roved by the li\e stork rommi 

to December 1. 1888. Tht 

lowed fur the same was $36,071.50, 
These animals were destroyed in I 

use amount of labor prc 

leevted in all seasons of 
he most energetic efforts 
h a result can be shown. 
the people of the State 

the year, and it has only been by 
on the part of the board that sn 
The work is most satisfactory tc 

"hose interests arc directly connected therewith 

(&lt;•!• asserting the cncijrv and success of the Fish CommiBand 
the building of a large, roomy, two -story house for a 

hei-.v, he outlined the situation as follows: 

The fish car also provided for by the last legislature has 
been procured. It is a neat, substantially constructed car 

of the usual size, and furnished with the best facilities for 
distributing and handling fish. Its cost has not exceeded 
the sum appropriated for that purpose. The work of the 

distribution of fish to remote 
greatly facilitated and with le 
tained by the old methods of 
in cans by express and baggage 

parts of the State has been 

Ml than heretofore sustransporting 
the young- fish 

cars, and express companies 
trout and black bass; also 

especially, in handling ycarlin; 
a saving in expense, with the 

co-operation of the railway 

companies hauling the car and its attendants free of expense 
to the State. Large improvements have also been 
made at the state hatchery by the construction and improvements 
of the ponds, new apparatus, and improvements 
to the old apparatus. In the year 1889 the commission 
procured fish eg-gs, successfully hatched them, and also 
raised in the state ponds a larger number of different 
species of fish than at any former time, and successfully 

I-ifrht hundred and thirty lior </seg>

            <seg id="p067">
168 


distributed them into the waters of the State. The total 
number of fish of all apes thus given to the water in that 
year was 15.221 .610. In the year MM, the total distribution 
of all ag/es amounted to 21.731.21*5. The introduction into 
our waters and cultivation of (Jernian carp has been attended 
with very gratifying results. This excellent food 
fish has hitherto been underestimated as to its intrinsic 
value. Its successful and profitable cultivation has been 
fully demonstrated. The fish hatchery is an establishment 
of preat advantage to the people. 

of objects of interest, and not yet consummated, or of recent 
date, may In- added. Hunks. Trusts. Deep Water Harbor, Irresponsible 
Detectives. Hoards of I'liarinaev and Pardons, and 
Irrigation. 

Keccnt occurrences have drawn attention to the condition 
of state banks and banking institutions. 1 respectfully recommend 
the enactment of legislation which shall provide 
for fre&lt;|uent examination of these institutions and which 
shall secure protection to depositors and stock-holders. 

Ee governor advocated t lie continuance of the sugar bounty 
e grounds that others might engage in the manufacture and 
coin]K-titioii would prevent a monopoly. 

Since the session of the last Legislature, and as a result 
of the liberal action of that body, there has been established 
in this State a most important industry. I refer to 
the making of sugar from sugar beets. It is my firm conviction 
that this will prove to be one of the great industries 
of the future in the West and in Nebraska especially. The 
Oxnards have put in a plant in (irand Island at a cost of 
nearly three quarters of a million dollars, and have daring 
the last three months turned out about one million pounds 
of the very finest, quality of sugar. The starting- of the establishment 
at Ormad Island wan an experiment. The season 
has been an unfavorable one on account of the dryness. 
The business was new to the farmers. But the experiment 
has merged into a complete success, so much so that the 
Oxnards are now putting in a similar plant at Norfolk. In 
ten years you may expect to see Nebraska the leading sugar 
producing |&gt;tate of the I'nion. Other states will take hold 
of this new agricultural pursuit, and the West will supply 
the sugar of the country, and the price to the consumer will 
be reduced from twenty-five to thirty per cent. I earnestly </seg>

            <seg id="p068">
169 


advise against repealing the law granting a bounty on the 
manufacture of sugar. That bounty was given as an inducement 
to open up that industry in the State; to induce 
parties to come here and put in plants and encourage the 
manufacture of sugar. To repeal this law at this time 
would be an implication of bad faith. It would, in effect, 
be an act of repudiation. Let the bounty remain and other 
establishments will follow those already started. 

Among other things of note we find the following concer 
the report of the ('omniisHioner of Labor: 


A great deal of trouble existing between employer and 
employee would be avoided if an honest effort was made 
by the former to show that he had other than a monetary 
consideration of his welfare. It is to be regetted that there 
arc very few employers compared to the number, who ever 
cress the threshold of their employees' homes, with a purpose 
of inquiring into their circumstances. Whenever this 
lias been done it has been marked with good results. Chapter 
II. deals with the question of loan and building associations. 
Any process that will assist the man of limited 
means to secure a home should be supported and thoroughly 
advertised. Local loan and building associations have done 
very much in this respect. Statistics on this subject will interest 
the \viii. r e workers ami others anxious to secure 
homes. 

The following excerpts are of general interest 

If wisdom and statesmanship can devise legislation which 
shall suppress and destroy a gigantic evil which has grown 
up in these latter days under the name of trusts, whereby 
the strong oppress and destroy the weak, I pray you to exercise 
that wisdom and statemanship. anil blot out the great 
wrong. 

The subject of a deep harbor on the Texas coast has recently 
received much attention in the trans-Mississippi 
region. The establishment of such a harbor into which 
ships of the heaviest draft could come without obstruction 
would remove the most serious obstacle to commercial 
traffic over the (iulf of Mexico, and would open a new and 
competitive route to the sea. I advise that you forward a 
memorial to Congress, asking it to lend a helping hand to 
the accomplishment of this important purpose. 

I recommend the enactment of a law prohibiting the introduction 
of a bodv of Pinkerton men, so called, into the </seg>

            <seg id="p069">
170 

¦o 






Hi. 

State, or any other body of men not residents of the State, 
for the purpose of police and protection duty. 

The provisions of the law at the lusi wasioa cresting a 
Board of Pharmacy are now in successful operation and are 
proving- to be a source of great benefit. The result is that 
we now have educated pharmacists. No one can serve as a 
druggist clerk unless he has had a thorough training in the 

drnggiat'a profession and pas 
examination. This is a mntU 
health of all the people. The 
beneficial institution. There 
macists in Nebraska. 

sed a thorough and successful 
r which eOMeraa UkC life and 
Board of Pharmacy is a most 
are now 1,909 educated phar- 

It is within the bounds to 
executive department lias d 
years. It is true in the depar 
MM I can verify from experiene 
least, and probably one-third, 
tion of applicants and appeals 

say that the business of the 
uubled within the last four 
tinent of the chief executive, 

o. One-fourth of the time at 
is taken up in the considera- 

for pardons. The executive 

ought to be relieved of a large portion at least, of this 
labor. A board of pardons would reach this result, and the 
creation of such a board is recommended. 

Very general attention is being- given to this subject of 
irrigation in the western part of the State, and I commend 
it to your favorable consideration. I would further respectfully 
recommend that a joint resolution and memorial 

be passed by the Legislature 
the adoption of further nece: 
the arid lands of the West. 

urging- Congress in favor of 
sary measures for irrigating 

To 

the list of benevolent and 

educational institutions in the 

re wire added, or opened during the term of his incumbency, 
in number, the first in order of time being the Institution 

;it, 

Ptebie Miaded Youth at Beatrice, Gage County, the cost of 
building being flS.l'ls. 

The result of the work in the school rooms can be seen 
in detail by reference to the superintendent's report. Manual 
training, such as farm and house work, with sewing for 
the girls and brushmaking for the boys lately added, has 
been carried on as circumstances would allow. From a personal 
inspection of the children's work, I consider the industrial 
department worthy of full equipment. This work 
demonstrates the usefulness of such an institution, and 
that many of these persons can be made sulf sustaining, 
who, without a course of proper training-, would be depend- </seg>

            <seg id="p070">
&lt; 

t 



rr 


ents, if not a dangerous element in society. There are on 
file at the institution 254 applications for admission, and 
on December 1st, 134 inmates, thus leaving many applicants 
unprovided for. The superintendent has knowledge of 84.! 
feeble minded persons in Nebraska. The State has made 
liss provisions for this class, in proportion to their number, 
than any other. These helpless children make an 
urgent appeal to the humanity of the State, and I recommend 
that your body make provision for their proper care 
and training. I commend the management of the institution 
as being painstaking and economical. 

In the same year, 1887, the Norfolk Hospital for the Ins 
osting |84,2!il'. was opened for patients. 

The main building of this hospital was erected in 1S85, 
and in 1887 it was opened for patients. Since the meeting 
of the last Legislature two wings to the main building have 
been erected. The report of the superintendent shows that 
during the two years from December 1st, 1888, to November 
30th, 1890, there were admitted as new cases, two hundred 
and nineteen, one hundred and thirty-seven males, and 
eighty-two females. Total under treatment for the two 
years, three hundred and forty. The percentage of recoveries, 
based on the total number under treatment for the 
last two 3 - ears, has been over forty. 

K 18.88, the Home at Grand Island was completed for the 
ion of soldiers and sailors. 

The report of the commandant of the Soldiers' and Sailors' 
Home shows that there have been 238 members admitted 
to the Home during its existence. Of this number there 
are at present 150 members on the rolls of the Home roster. 
Of these forty-eight have been honorably discharged, 
twenty summarily, and four dishonorably discharged. Sixteen 
have died at the Home. There has been an average 
attendance for twenty-eight months, or since the Home 
was opened, of 6S. Appreciating the hardship of separation 
of husband and wife, and actuated by a humane instinct, a 
provision was inserted in the law for the admission of the 
wives, and children under fifteen years of age, of the soldiers 
who were compelled by their straitened circumstances 
to seek homes within its walls. Seven double cottages 
were erected accommodating fourteen families. 
Congress enacted a law providing for the payment to each 
state which has a soldiers' home $100 a year for each in- </seg>

            <seg id="p071">
172 


mate of that Home. This will aid largely in payment of 
the running expenses of this institution. 

Kan act of the Legislature of 1887 a Nebraska Industrial 
was established, to be under the supervision of the "Wo- 
Hoard of Associate Charities." 

The institution was located and opened for the admission 
of inmates May 1, 18S9. Whole number admitted to November 
.1(1. MM, is fifty-nine, thirty-eight of whom were of 
American parentage and seventeen of foreign. The average 
number of adults present in each year is twenty-eight. 
Average number of children cared for in each year is twenty-three. 
Qood homes have been found for seventeen. 
There are now in the Home thirteen children. The object 
of the Home is to reclaim the fallen, to bring them under 
frond, wholesome, Christian influences, and thus secure 
their reformation. I believe it is fully accomplishing the 
purpose for which it was created. It is in consonance with 
the spirit of true philanthropy and good will, and should 
be encouraged. 

Kii XT— t of the over-crowded condition of the asylums for 
insane at Lincoln and Norfolk, and the policy of separating 
incuralile from the more hopeful, another building was pre'd 
at a cost of £&lt;;:}.&lt;mmi located at Hastings. 

This institution was opened for the reception of patients 
August 1st. IMt, at which time were received forty-four 
patients from Lincoln: November 12th. 1MB, fifty patients; 
and again April 26th. 18M, thirty-two patients, making a 
total of one hundred and twenty-six patients received from 
Lincoln. November 12th. 1S89, there were received from 
Norfolk twenty-two patients. There have been received 
since August 1. 1 '-SO, from the different counties twentysix 
patients, making a grand total of one hundred and 
seventy-four received. There are at present one hundred 
and sixty patients in the institution, one has been discharged 
as cured, one is out on parole, and one has escaped. 
Since August 1st, 1889, there has been eleven deaths. 

Ei a Governor who feels himself the head of a great family, 
y member of which was entitled to his official and humane 
itions. in case of unforeseen calamity, the drouth sufferers of 
appealed with painful demands. On the first intimation of </seg>

            <seg id="p072">
173 


Ition and suffering he recommended the county commissionf 
the stricken district to organize means of relief. By No 
¦er he called upon the public to give heed to the Macedonian 
Come over and help us" ; and in order to add to his knowl 
and make it critical, sent two agents to traverse the coun- 
The result was his organization of a Relief Committee, 
which the contiguous railroads co-operated by carrying supfive 
of charge. In his message to the Legislature of 1891, 
said: 

It is safe to conclude from the information thus obtained 
that six thousand and eleven families will require fuel and 
provisions during 1 tlie winter and spring, and nine thousand 
nine hundred and thirty-eig-ht families will need gTain and 
seed. Those people in the portions of the State in which 
crops have been blasted by hot winds and the drouth, have 
become the victims of misfortune from no fault of their 
own. They are worthy, honest, anil industrious as any 
people in Nebraska or any other state in the I'nion. They 
are our own kith and kin- they are our own fellow citizens. 
This question of relief is of stub a magnitude that it has 
become a state affair: Nebraska cannot afford to permit 
the report to g-o abroad that any one within its borders 
had died of cold and hunjrer. It is rich enough, it is able 
enough to take care of its own people. We want no help 
from abroad. I most earnestly recommend an appropriation 
with an emergency clause of two hundred thousand 
dollars ($200,000) for their relief. Further appropriations 
will 1m&gt; necessary. The necessities of those people require 
it; in the highest sense. Christian duty sanctions it: humanity 
dictates it, and God Almighty commands it. The injunction. 
"ISeinember the poor and the needy" is as binding 
now a.s when tittered by the Holy One two thousand 

rears ago 

Ehe subjoined recommendation closed an earnest appeal to the 
islature in behalf of the Columbian Exposition. 

I recommend an appropriation of $150,000 with an emergency 
clause, for the purpose of inaugurating and maintaining 
our exhibits. Citizens of Nebraska who attended the 
Paris Exposition were humiliated by the small and insignificant 
exhibition of its products made there. I trust N'ebraskans 
who shall attend the Chicago Exposition, and all 
should attend it, will not be subjected to a like humilia- </seg>

            <seg id="p073">
174 


tion. The display from this State should be such as will 
make every dweller within its borders more proud of it 
than ever before. The display should be such that every 
one can exclaim with exultant satisfaction: "That represents 
my State." 

Ordinarily. Qorenw Thayer would have been called upon for 
his retiring BMaaage as soon as the Legislature of January •;. 
1891, was organized and ready in joint session, to receive it: 
which would have been followed by the inaugural of his s\v 
sur. Hut. inasmuch as the speaker of the house, on account ai a 
conti'st pending, on the part of J. H. Powers, Independent candidate 
tar Governor, against James E. Boyd, refused to examine 
and proclaim the result of the election till such contest was 
settled, and only did it by virtue of a mandamus issued from the 
Supreme Court of Nebraska, and as the contest was not abandoned 
till the latter part of January, his message was not called 
fur until the following day. Thus Governor Boyd delivered his 
inaugural just one nionlh after the commencement of the Leg 
islative session. 

In the meantime, on the Kith of January. John M. Thayer cum 
meiired proceedings, in the Slate Supreme Court, to oust Gov 
eiiiiir I'.oyd from ofiice. charging that he was not a citizen of 
the I'nited States when elected, having been born in Ireland, and 
Mm naturalized in the United States. The case having been 
argued March 12th, 1891. and the opinion of the court having 
been announced May oth. reinstating Thayer and ousting IJoyd. 
which was just one month after the adjournment of the I. 
lature, these officials changed places once more — Thayer to art 
as Governor till a successor should appear, "elected and aval 
ifled." and Boyd to apjw-al to the Supreme Court of the I'nited 
States. After nine months, in the highest tribunal known to 
our laws, an opinion in favor of Governor Boyd was delivered 
by chief Justice Fuller, reinstating him. and retiring Governor 
Thayer to private life. 

Ee contest waged by Governor Thayer against James E. Boyd, 
upon the basis that if naturalized, the laws of the United 
*s, in that behalf, had been the instrument by which he had </seg>


            <seg id="p074">
175 

Eined to rltiwinhip; and that he should be able to show court 
rds establishing the fact. Admitting the correctness of this 
tion the Supreme Court of Xebraska'deeided that James E. 
d was not a citizen when elected Governor. 

I tut the Supreme Court of the United States gave Mr. Boyd 
equivalent for court naturalization, in "collective naturaliza-1" 
by the admission of the State of Nebraska, and from the 
gal presumption"' that his father had been naturalized during 
son's minority. If that mode of gaiiiiug citizenship had been 
viously amplified as the Supreme Court gave it prominence 
his instance, it might be a question whether this action would 
ever have been filed, on the decision obtained from the Supreme 
Court of the State. Prior to this time the legal profession had 
¦ever been furnished with so voluminous a digest of sporadic 
• ;i
175 

Eined to rltiwinhip; and that he should be able to show court 
rds establishing the fact. Admitting the correctness of this 
tion the Supreme Court of Xebraska'deeided that James E. 
d was not a citizen when elected Governor. 

I tut the Supreme Court of the United States gave Mr. Boyd 
equivalent for court naturalization, in "collective naturaliza-1" 
by the admission of the State of Nebraska, and from the 
gal presumption"' that his father had been naturalized during 
son's minority. If that mode of gaiiiiug citizenship had been 
viously amplified as the Supreme Court gave it prominence 
his instance, it might be a question whether this action would 
ever have been filed, on the decision obtained from the Supreme 
Court of the State. Prior to this time the legal profession had 
¦ever been furnished with so voluminous a digest of sporadic 
• ;i^&gt;-s of naturalization. These are fully set forth in the s 
unlit of (liivciniir Boyd'l administration, in this volume. gt;-s of naturalization. These are fully set forth in the s 
unlit of (liivciniir Boyd'l administration, in this volume. </seg>

            <seg id="p075">
176 


OOVERXOR JAMES E. BOYD 

No man lias reached the Governor's chair of Nebraska with 

more real pioneer experience than James K. Boyd. Nine year 
a citizen of Buffalo county as farmer and ranchman, at a tinn 
when warring tribes of Pawnees and Sioux claimed the saint 
region as individual hunting ground, and only had a coerced re 
spect for the Wood River settlement, on account of its near loca 
tion to Fort Kearney, inured him thoroughly to the privations 
of a new and undeveloped region, a capricious climate and fre 
(jiiency of Indian alarms. 1 hiring the same period he superintended 
a store for a lime, at Kearney, and as a railroad contractor 
graded three hundred miles of Union Pacific track. Before 
the frontier experience, from 1886 to 1888, he had resided in 
Omaha as a carpenter and contractor, and when lie returned in 
1868 he entered at once into city improvements, and organized 
the Northwesters railroad to Blair, building it and acting as its 
president. In the meantime he was engaged in cattle grazing on 
the plains of western Nebraska and subsequently in Wyoming. 
Since 1S72 lie has been banker and pork packer on a large scale, 
employing as high as 170 men. Before his election as governor 
his legislative training was in the state legislature and in two 
different constitutional conventions. He was member of the 
board of aldermen for the city of Omaha, while as a presiding 
officer twice mayor of Omaha and president of the city board 
of trade, he had become familiar with the duties of an executive 
ruler. 

Before the city of Omaha had outgrown her modest halls, he 
anticipated her coming wants with the beautiful and artistic 
Boyd opera house, and as soon as the flood tide of population 
demanded wider borders the '"New Boyd" supplanted the old, 
as the beautiful edifice overshadows the cabin. 

At the time of his election as governor he was fifty-six years 

1891-1893. </seg>


            <seg id="p076">IAS. E. BOYD.</seg> 

            <seg id="p077">
177 


of age, having been born in Tyrone. Ireland, in 1834, whence he 
came to Ohio in 1844. and thence to Nebraska in 1856. Of state 
governors, the arrival of General Thayer in 1854 ante-dates him 
by two years, while Governor Furnas also claims 1856 as his 
advent; Bntler 1858; Garber 1870, and Nance and Dawes 1870. 
Thayer and I&gt;awes are of New England ancestry, Bntler and 
Garber of Virginia, Boyd of Irish, Furnas of South Carolina, 
and Nance of French parentage. Furnas, Garber, and Dawes 
were born in Ohio, Boyd in Ireland, Thayer in HamehH 
Butler in Indiana and Nance in Illinois. At the time of election 
Nance was thirty years of age, Butler and Dawes thirty-seven 
each, Garber forty-one, Furnas forty-eight, Boyd fifty-six and 
Tliayer sixty-six. 

In the campaign of 1890, the People's party or Independents, 
often called the Alliance, as most of them were members of the 
Farmer's Alliance, became a formidable rival of the old parties 
and elected a majority of the legislative members, while the democrats 
elected the governor and the Republicans the balance of 
the state officers. The Independents also elected two members 
to Congress and the Democrats one. As soon as the result of 
the 4th of November election was known, contests were commenced 
against the democratic candidate for governor and 
against the republican candidates for the other state offices. 
When the legislature convened on the 6th day of January, 1891, 
the Independents contended that no inauguration of officers 
Bbould take place till contests were decided, and of course no 
canvass of votes in joint session and proclamation of the same 
be made before such final decision. After a conflict of authority 
between the newly elected speaker of the House, Hon. 8. M. 
Elder, and the lieutenant governor, president of the senate, the 
chief justice of the supreme court caused a writ of mandamus 
to issue to Speaker Elder, commanding him to "open and publish 
the returns, and declare the persons shown by said returns to 
have the highest number of votes for each of said executive offices, 
duly elected." In this manner James E. Boyd was declared 
duly elected. 

13 </seg>

            <seg id="p078">
178 


This mandate, of course, did not intend to annul the pending 
contest, but to place in power the "prima facie" elected officers 
Wibject to all future contingencies. Accordingly the 20th day 
of January. 1891, baring been fixed for a joint meeting of both 
luaiulii-s of the general assembly to count and declare the votes 
and election of officers, the contestees including Hon. James E. 
Bc.vd, the Hon. T. J. Majors, republican, elected as lieutenant 
raw, and the balance of the state officers, entered their pro 
¦gltwt the legality of the joint assembly, in this, that the 
iiiiciu resolution ordering it was never presented to or 
signed by either the governor or lieutenant governor of the State. 
To settle the question of the legality of this joint convention, 
the supreme court was called upon to answer whether, when 
the governor and lieutenant governor were both contestees and. 
WK, personally interested in defeating the joint convention. 
was it necessary to ask their signatures to the resolution, to 
which the court (•?« an opinion that their signatures were neces- 


tiis derision havinjr been delivered seven days after the time 
le intended joint convention, and other complications aristlie 
contests were finally abandoned and the Hon. J. E. 
1. who had superseded Gen. John M. Thayer. delivered his 
gural address Feb. 6th, 1891. one month after the begiaateg 
le legislative session. 

As this inaugural message was the first democratic utterance 
of the kind since state organization, it was subjected to close 
si -numy and was warmly endorsed by the party and people generally, 
excepting those of his own party and others who were 
as honestly, intelligently and patriotically devoted to prohibition 
as he could be to its rejection. The characteristics of the message 
were directness, clearness and a critical examination of 
new themes and living issues. Brief in extent and breathing 
pure democracy, conciliatory in spirit and exceptional in style, 
to present it in fragments would do alike injustice to author and 
reader. But with |M»siti\e assurance that the lavishly decorated 
vestibule is worthy of the beautiful structure it adorns, the </seg>


            <seg id="p079">
179 

reader is introduced through the portal of the exordium and left 
with a desire for the unabridged message. 

Assembled here by direction of the people of this gTeat 
and growing commonwealth of Nebraska, to promote their 
interests and render obedience to their expressed will, I 
hope that in all things concerning the dignity of citizenship 
and the public weal, we may go hand in hand toward 
the faithful fulfillment of our accepted trust; guided by 
our best wisdom, ambitious in the performance of our 
labors, and at all times true to the honor and the escutcheon 
of the State. We meet here instructed by the public 
voice, you in your sphere and I in mine, different in action 
yet the same in end. As public servants, with express commands, 
we will be held to strict account by those who sent 

us here. Subterfuges and stratagems and weak expedients 
will all be swept away when we are called upon to explain 
the record made within these walls. Our principles abandoned 
and our pledges unperformed, the people disregarded 
and the State betrayed, means to-morrow, as it meant yesterday, 
swift and complete political death. In all that pertains 
to blooming fields and prosperous homes, in all that 
brings the people of the prairies in close alliance with the 
people of the towns; in the promotion of their welfare, in 
the protection of their rights, the redress of their wrongs, 
in lifting their burdens, and the speedy granting of their 
appeals, and finally in strict and even-handed justice to all, 
I herewith extend you my hearty approval in advance. 

El the 20th day of March, 
to regulate railroads, to &lt; 
imum rates to be charged 
i each of the railroads in 
se the powers and further 
sportation, and to punish 

1891, house bill No. 12, "For an 
•lassify freights, to fix reasonable 
for the transportation of freights 
the State of Nebraska, and to in 
define the duties of the board of 
violations thereof," was put upon 

its passage in the state senate. A call of the senate being ordered, 
a deadlock ensued, which lasted for three days, while 
¦ motion could not be entertained for a "suspension of further 
proceedings under the call," although one senator (Taylor, of 
I.oup county) was permanently absent. Of this state of affairs, 
after seventy-five hours of continuous session, Senator Stevens 

The public feel that such a policy is a part of the tactics 

of the railroads of the State to prevent any legislation </seg>

            <seg id="p080">
180 


regulating the charges of these common carriers. Will the 
chair unlock the entanglement and afford the senate a 
means of escape by overruling or rather correcting the 
former ruling, or shall this foolishness at the expense of 
the State go merrily on? 

Pending this obstruction to business a self-constituted committee 
of democrats and republicans, twelve in number, offered 
K&gt;mpromise to the independents who were pressing the bill, 
he first place they claimed that the railroad bill was uncon- 

Mitutional; to which it was replied, "If the railroads really 
thought it was invalid, it is strange that they should offer |5.0»i) 
apiece for senatorial votes to defeat it." They further asserted: 

In other words we favor a bill which would provide a 
reasonable rate on the following articles: wheat, flour, millet, 
flax-seed, corn, oats, barley and other grains; millstuff, 
hard and soft lumber, lath, doors, shingles, sash, 
blinds, salt, lime, cement, stucco, horses, mules, cattle, 
hogs, sheep, hard and soft coal. And also a provision 
against increasing through freight rates, and that on all 
articles not mentioned the rate shall not exceed the tariff 
in force on January 1st, 1891. 

To which sixteen Independent senators made reply 

We had rather suffer defeat at your hands when we are 
fighting the uneven battle of the people against the corporations, 
than to gain an apparent victory by passing a 
measure prepared and placed in our hands by the very corporations 
which we seek to control. A maximum rate bill 
embracing only the articles of live-stock, grain, lumber and 
coal would bring no relief to our people, for the reason 
that those articles would all be controlled by interstate 
rates. Nebraska produces no coal or lumber, and would 
be required by the roads of this State to pay local rates 
on both of these commodities, which local rates are higher 
than the present' through rates, and the revenue of the 
roads would thereby be increased rather than diminished. 
The railroad companies have already tried to frighten us 
by threatening to refuse to give Nebraska through rates 
in case the Newberry bill becomes a law, and we believe 
they would not be slow to take advantage of an opportunity 
to charge local rates on the four commodities in 
which the farmers are interested, if we should accede to 
your request. </seg>

            <seg id="p081">
181 


Eer three days of suspense and strife, the sergeant-at-arms 
% to find the absconding senator (Taylor), who had fled 
the State, Mr. Shumway, a Republican, moved that further 
jdings under the call be dispensed with, and explained his 
n as follows: 

Ample time has been given all parties interested in this 

bill to try and persuade one missing- member to return 
But he is still absent. I do not think it wise that the ac- 

tions of this body be further delayed on account of the 
absentee, therefore I make the motion. 

The motion prevailed and the bill passed. 

Eie belief that Taylor was bribed to leave the senate and the 
e, to defeat railroad legislation, produced the most intense 
tement throughout the State, and even the house chaplain, 
day after the senate deadlock was broken, emphasized the 
»ral feeling in his prayer before that body: 

We thank Thee for Nebraska, for her enlarged borders, 
for her citizens and her brotherhood, but rejoice that her 
borders are not large enough to enclose, nor her brotherhood 
sweet enough to embrace a traitor recreant to her 
interests. Help him to flee farther and yet farther from an 
outraged and indignant people, until he shall stand upon 
the brink of a moral volcano, behold the forked tongues of 
fiery flames, the seething sea of lurid lava, hear the muttured 
thunder of hidden forces, and feel the nausea of 
mental hell, until he shall awake from mental death, repent, 
believe and be saved. And what we ask for discovered treason 
and uncovered traitors, we ask for all covert treason 
and covered traitors. 

E r hen the railroad bill was presented to Governor Boyd for 
signature he returned it with a veto message, in which he 

The rate in this bill is supposed to be based on the Iowa 
rates. In Iowa the rates are fixed by a commission and are 
changed from time to time as circumstances and the course 
of trade seem to require. In that state the various roads 
are classified so that the rates are higher on the weaker 
roads and lower on the stronger ones which have a greater 
volume of business. 

The justice of such a classification is apparent. It is </seg>

            <seg id="p082">
182 

NEBRASKA STATE HISTORICAL 8OCIETY 

evident that a road doing- a large business can afford to 
carry freight at a less rate than one which has but little 
traffic. This bill places the same Iowa rate on all the roads 
in the State without regard to the volume of business carried, 
and the rate fixed by the bill is based upon the lowest 
classification in Iowa. The latter state has double the 
acreage under cultivation and almost twice the population 
of Nebraska, with only about two-thirds its extent of territory, 
and less than double its railroad mileage. The volume 
of freight transported by the railroads in Iowa is more 
than four times as great as that transported by the railroads 
of Nebraska. It is manifest injustice to apply to the 
Nebraska roads the lowest rates in force in Iowa. 

He strongly combated the idea that the railroads were mak 
ing exorbitant profits at the present time: 

In my judjjnient there is not a mile of railroad west of 
the sixth principal meridian, except the trunk lines, that 
is paying- its running- expenses today. The products of our 
State in some form are almost entirely consumed in the 
East and must be carried upon interstate rates. These 
interstate rates upon grain particularly are but very little 
above the rates from Iowa points. These rates will not 
be reduced by this proposed law, and may. and can be 
very materially advanced by the railroad companies in self 
defense and for self preservation. 

The interstate rates rcfcireJ to above are those upon traffic 
between and beyond states, under laws of Congress, and not the 
business done within individual states, and governed by thei 
local laws. The governor approved of the "rate on live stoc] 
in the eastern part of the State," and ''attributed the best inten 
tions and motives to the framers and supporters of the bill, 
and conceded '"that the railroad corporations have, in many in 
stances, exacted unjust tribute from the people," but believec 
the law lacked careful consideration, was unconstitutional, am 
would stop railroad construction, deter capital from entering 
the State for improvements, and in the reduction of wages and 
discharge from railroad services produce a dangerous competition 
in other branches of labor. On account of the condition of 
affairs in the State he also argued that the bill was inopportune: </seg>

            <seg id="p083">
183 


• 

Owing to the crop failure of last year there will be but 
meager shipments of agricultural or live stock products 
from our State until after another crop shall have matured; 
and hence the carrying 1 trade within our borders 
will be reduced to the minimum, and with such a condition 
confronting us I deem it unwise, as well as unjust, at the 
present time, to enforce such sweeping reductions as are 
provided for in this hill. 

Remembering that each party platform demanded restrictive 
legislation, and that the retiring governor's message recommended 
it and his own inaugural address made it prominent, he 
knew full well that the temporary political consequences of his 
own official act were impending. 

I am well aware that my refusal to sanction this bill will 
meet with the disapproval of many. Dissatisfaction may be 
expressed and harsh criticism will follow. Be that as it 
may. I feel that I have a plain duty to perform, a duty 
which I owe to the interests of this great State, and whatever 
censure or criticism may result, this duty I will perform 
in the consciousness that I am acting for the best 
interests of the State of Nebraska. I therefore withhold 
my approval of this bill. 

Inasmuch as the majority in each house was not large enough 
to pass the bill over the veto, it failed to become a law, and since 
the Independent party had redeemed its pledges by passing it 
they returned to their constituents vindicated, while several 

other members had voted for it under protest. 

Two other acts were passed and signed by (iovernor Boyd, 
relative to railroads, the one providing for naming stations after 
the towns in which they may be located, and the other for securing 
the safety of operatives by requiring railroads, corporations 
and companies to equip engines and cars with proper, efficient 
and safe automatic couplers and brakes, so that brakeinen shall 
not be required to go between cars, or on top of them, in the discharge 
of their duties. 

If the governor could not co-operate with the Independent 
party fully as to the details of railroad legislation, it must have 
given him pleasure to find the |ntnl recommendations ,,f his </seg>

            <seg id="p084">
184 


¦pos sun" rage su crimpletely incorporated in the secret 
ballot law. If it secures the freedom of the voter, shields the 
1 r man of talent and integrity against the competitor of mere 
wealth and assumptions, and results in purity of elections and 
6 education of manly voters, and relegate* bribes and bribery 
le rear, all concerned in its establishment will have cause to 
ice in an honored citizenship and a dignified stat&lt;\ 

tying (ailed the attention of the legislature to the fact that 
warehouse system now in vogue in the State of Nebraska 

B holly in the hands of private parties and corporations, unrolled 
bj and not responsible to any statute of the Slate, 
ive to public warehouses." the body took prompt action and 

i\.- form to a statute. The scope of the law required a license 

» keeping 8 warehouse, for reception, storage, and sale of 
i. under penalty of a $10,000 bond and a fine of from one to 
hundred dollars for every day's business transacted without 

such license, obtained from the State Hoard of Transportation. 
• &gt;\\ neis of property were to have access to the same and all the 
books and records of the warehouse; receipts were made transferable 
by endorsement: the issue of fraudulent receipts made 
punishable with imprisonment for not more than ten years in 
the i»enitentiary, in addition to all other penalties, and provis 
were made for a chief inspector, with all such safeguards 
and restrictions as the experience of other states had found 
j and practicable from absolute test and experience. 
This act was followed by another giving new duties to the Board 
of Transportation, among which was the appointment of a committee 
of appeals for each city and town in which a warehouse 
was located, the members of which were placed under bonds of 
$5,000 each, having first taken the oath of office. 

fie recommendation for cheaper school books was met by a 
allowing the district boards to purchase a supply to be 
ed to pupils of the school or sold at cost to patrons for the 
of their children. 

Saving signed a bill in aid of drouth sufferers of 1890 approting 
$100,000, before delivering his inaugural, he therein </seg>

            <seg id="p085">
185 


said. "If further aid is required. I will sanction such appropriation 
as may be necessary." and accordingly was called upon to 
sign a law for an issue of £100,000 in state bonds. Such were 
his views of the value of an adequate exhibition of Nebraska's 
products at the Columbian Exposition, it would have given 
greater pleasure to be permitted to sign a bill for fl(M,M8, 
rather than as passed for $~&gt;o.ooo. Hills also passed his inion 
;m&lt;l received his signature amending the law governing 
the Soldiers' and Sailors' Hone; admitting members of the 
Women's Relief Corps to the visiting and examining board; a 
bill for a Girls' Industrial School for juvenile delinquents; for a 
stute Board of Health; for prohibiting the sale of firearms and 
ammunition or intoxicating liquors to Indians not citizens; for 
&gt;lisliment of two experimental stations in the interests of 
agriculture; for the loaning and safe keeping of state funds; 
and for the government of cities, with numerous other acts in 
the interest of economy and progress. 

fie last recommendation of his message, though not incorpod 
in law, is receiving public attention from politicians and 
esmen, and in the progress of intelligent reform will yet be 
;ited. when presidential electors will he chosen in congreaal 
districts, and a "quartette of so-called pivotal states no 
:er monopolize the honor of electing the chief magistrate of 
entire country." 

A majority of the legislative members being farmers from the 
two old parties, banded together to resist all forms of monopoly 
and railroad extortion, having much to learn of parliamentary 
strategy, they were often embarrassed but never discouraged. 

11 addition to the local acts for Nebraska, the discussions em:ed 
many subjects of interest of national character, and aclingly 
we find the House passing instructions to the delegas 
in Congress, on the subject of the Paddock pure food bill, 
also in favor of the election of United States senators by 
people, while the United States Senate was complimented 
refusing to pass the Force Bill, "the boldest stroke of cenization 
and imperialism since the establishment of the Re* </seg>

            <seg id="p086">
186 


public." and affirming their opposition thereto, because Nebraska 
believed in "local sovereignty and federal unity and the 
secrecy of the ballot." 1 democrats voting with independents in 
affirmation of these principles caused a member to exclaim, ''The 
lion and th'e lamb have at last lain down together. Let us have 
peace." The ''free coinage of silver'' was recommended, and the 
ii.iioo appropriation for a deep water harbor at Galveston, 
Texas, was approved, a committee appointed to attend the convention 
of states, and an elaborate report received of its great 
value to the Northwest. As a matter of reciprocity and adveriient, 
the City of Galveston presented tlie Nebraska legislature 
fifteen barrels of oysters, which eventuated in a state oyster 
supper and a gastronomic bond of union. Other episodes relieved 
the monotonv of the dailv dutv, as the presentation of a 
gavel to the spea-ker, S. M. Elder, of the House, made from the 

Etrcc" that served the early emigrants as the beacon light 
MCU mariners. In reply to a speech of presentation, by 
Morris, Mr. Elder said, in conclusion: 

IJpmember that the tree from which this gavel comes 
could be seen from Buffalo Peak to Little Blue River. One 
evening' at six o'clock, together with some comrades, I was 
traveling through this section. The ground was covered 
with snow, and the storm increased. For hours we traveled 
through the storm. Wearied and worn. I remember 
I desired to lie down and sleep; my companions refused, 
and we traveled on and on until at 12 o'clock at night we 
ran against a tree: we knew it was "lone tree," and that we 
were saved. It afforded us shelter that night as it had 
many others. 1 thank ray people for this gavel. Moving 
along under this gavel, let us enact such laws as will be 
of great and lasting benefit to the great Commonwealth 
of Nebraska. 

En the last day of the session, Mr. Watson, of Otoe county 
e and addressed the speaker, complimenting him on his ad 
istration of the rules of order: 

Mr. Speaker, I desire to say further that sometime in 
your history, before the meeting of this legislature, Prov- 
Umh lias appeared to be unkind to you and deprived you 
of a useful appendage of your body, your strong arm. </seg>


            <seg id="p087">
187 

making 1 you physically incapacitated as knight and warrior. 
When it was proclaimed on Mount Sinai that man was fearfully 
and wonderfully made, your friends, wishing that you 
should be physically intact as you are mentally capable, 
herewith present you an arm, and while it is not as nature 
formed you, it is an expression of our good will and honest 
intentions of the donors who address you as brave and 
fair minded, in all the elements of man, an able, impartial, 
presiding officer, a true and trusted friend, an elegant and 
a splendid gentleman. And in conclusion let me say, that 
it is the desire of your friends and well wishers that your 
future life may be happiness, and the conclusion thereof 
peace and comfort. 

Mr. McKesson arose and said: 

Mr. Speaker, and Gentlemen of the House — As a further 
token of respect and appreciation on the part of the members 
of this House, for the fair and impartial manner in 
which you have presided over its turbulent deliberations, 
I have been requested to present, not to you, but through 
you to your esteemed wife, this beautiful crayon portrait of 
yourself. Novelists depict fancy painted pictures, poets 
sing of "Arms and of Heroes"; but it remains for the artist 
to put upon canvass, lifelike and real, living characteristics 
of man. It was said of Oliver Cromwell, England's illustrious 
Commoner, who led the mediocrity of that nation 
triumphantly against Charles the First to the throne, that 
when asked by his artist that he be allowed to remove a 
defect of nature from the face of his picture, exclaimed, 
"Paint me as I am." So we, Mr. Speaker, have painted you 
as you are, without compliment to your beauty; and as you 

go forth from the arduous duties of this chair to commoner 
walks of life, be assured we carry the reflex of your 

picture stamped in pleasant m 
your success. 

morv. with best wishes for 

The Speaker in ttspoam said 

Mr. Chairman, members of 
generally: For me to say at 
rassed would be superfluous. 

the legislature, and citizens 
this time that I am embar- 
These presents will long be 

remembered by me. I have never sought a position higher 
than I had before. I came here to do my duty as a man, and 
if I have not done my duty it was because I did not know 
how and not because I did not want to do it. I go from 
Lincoln with ill will toward none. I will never forget this </seg>

            <seg id="p088">
188 


legislature, and I am sure there are many here who will 
likewise not forget it. I will always remember you all. 
Once more, I thank you. 

I the matter of state politics, the three parties differed M 
cm many questions of prime importance that the strandis 
revealed by official documents, that both the retiring and 
ning gorenora, in several Important cases, recommended 
n upon the same identical questions, while the independresponded 
in approving legislation. 

THAYEIt 

VS. I'.OYD. 

In the L3tk day of January. 1S01. leave was granted to John 
rhayer bj the Bapreme Coart of the State of Nebraska, to 
an information against .lames K. Boyd, to establish the reiiilit 
to the office of governor of the State and to oust 
respondent therefrom. 

These pMeeedtagi were commenced five days after Boyd was 
officially declared governor of Nebraska and sworn into office. 
The information set forth the following state of facts: the election 
of John If. Thayer as governor, in November, 1888, and his 
oath requiring him to hold office "until his successor should be 
elected and qualified"; the subsequent election of November, 
in which 1214. (ton votes were cast, of which James E. Boyd 
ved 71.:i31, J. H. Powers Tn.lsT. and L. D. Richards 68,878; 
and the fact that James E. Boyd was not at the time of the 
election of 1890 a citizen of the United States, having been born 
in Ireland in 1834 and brought to the United States in 1844 by 
his father, who never went further in the matter of naturalize 
tion than to file a "declaration of intentions" (1851) prior to the 
son's becoming fifty-six years of age. The information contained 
many specifications of corroborating facts sustaining the leading 
propositions. The information closed with the demand that 
James E. Boyd be ousted from office and that John M. Thayer 
be declared entitled thereto, and that he be protected in office 
by an injunction restraining the said Boyd from interfering with 
the relator as governor of Nebraska. </seg>


            <seg id="p089">
189 

In answer, a motion to dismiss having failed, the respondtnt. 
James E. Boyd, admitted numerous allegations, put in issue 
&gt; thing tending to cloud his title to the office, on account of 
want of citizenship, and gave a full and accurate account of the 
- of his father and himself as citizens and office holders, in 
llif states of Ohio and Nebraska. But inasmuch as the facts 
will appear in the decision of the Supreme Court of the United 
Slates, they mav be omitted in this connection. A demurrer to 

respondent's answer having been argued before the Supreme 
Court of Nebraska on March 12, 1891, an opinion was announced 
on the following May 5. ousting respondent. James E. Boyd, and 
¦ ?¦instating the relator John M. Thayer. One judge of three dis 

I hereupon, Governor Boyd, giving place to General Thayer. 
ried his case to the supreme court of the United States on a 
t of error, where the Nebraska court was reversed and he 
i reinstated Feb. 1, 1892. In delivering the opinion of the 
ited States court, Chief Justice Fuller gave first attention 
he question of citizenship, and quoted the definition given it. 
Chief Justice Waite: 

Citizens are the members of the political community to 
which they belong. They are the people who compose the 
community, and who in their associated capacity, have established 
or submitted themselves to the domination of 
the government for the promotion of their general welfare, 
and the protection of their individual as well as their 
collective rights. 

The 14th amendment reads, "All persons born or naturalized 
in the United States and subject to the jurisdiction 
thereof, are citizens of the United States and of the 
state wherein they reside." The supreme court [of Nebraska] 
decided that James E. Boyd had not been for two 
years next preceding his election a citizen of the United 
States, and hence that under the constitution of the State 
he was not eligible to the office of governor; and that he 
was not a citizen of the United States because during his 
entire residence in the Territory from 1856 to 1867 and in 
the State from 1867 to November 4, 1890, the date upon 
which he was elected governor, he was a subject of Great 
Britain and Ireland. Arrival ait this conclusion involved 
the denial of a right or privilege under the constitution and </seg>

            <seg id="p090">
190 


laws of the United States, upon which the determination of 
whether Boyd was a citizen of the United States or not depended, 
and jurisdiction to review a decision against such a 
right or privilege necessarily exists in this tribunal. Missouri 
vs. Andriano, 138 U. S., 496. Each state has the power 
to prescribe the qualifications of its officers and the manner 
in which they shall be chosen, and the title to offices 
shall be tried, whether in the judicial courts or otherwise. 
But when the trial is in the courts, it is a "case," and if a 
defense is interposed under the constitution or laws of the 
United States, and is overruled, then, as in any other 
case decided by the highest courts of the State, this court 
had jurisdiction by writ of error. 

We 'In not understand the contention to involve directly 
a denial of the right of expatriation which the political departments 
of this government have always united in asserting 
(Lawrence's Wheaton, 925; Whart. Conn. Laws, sec. 5; 

8 Op. Att'y Gen., 130; 9 Op. Att'y G ;ict of Congress 
of July 27, 1868, 15 Stat. 223; K. S., sec. 1999), but that it 
that Boyd was an alien upon the ground that 

the disabilities of alienage ha 
catisr he had never been natur 

1 never been removed, bealized. 


Naturalization is the act of 
clothing him with the privileg 
relator's position is that such 
sought nor obtained by respon 
gress in that behalf. Congress 

es of a native citizen, and 
adoption has neither been 
lent under the acts of conin 
the exercise of the power 

ablish an uniform rule of naturalization has enacted 
general laws under which individuals may be naturalized, 
but the instances of collective naturalization by treaty 
or l&gt;y statute are numerous. 

Iltistrating the doctrine of collective naturalization, ninnerreferences 
were made to Indian treaties and treaties with 
'rnnients, and to organic acts when ready for admission as 


Thus, although Indians are not members of the political 
sovereignty, many classes of them have been made citizens 
in that way. 

As an instance of this process we give the following 

By the act (if March U&lt;1, l*4i, it was provided that on 
the completion of certain arrangements for the partition 
of the lands of the Stockbridge tribe of Indians, each 
and every one of them shall then be deemed to be and from 

adopting a foreigner, and </seg>

            <seg id="p091">
191 


that time forth are hereby declared to be citizens of the 
United States, to all intents and purposes, and shall be entitled 
to all the rights, privileges and immunities of such 
citizens. By the 8th article of treaty with Mexico in ISM, 
those Mexican* who remained in the territory ceded, and 
who did not declare their intentions to remain Mexican citizens, 
were to be deemed citizens of the United States. 

Treaties with France for Louisiana and that with Spain tar 
Florida were noted, and of the latter it was quoted: "This ti 
is the law of the land, and admits the inhabitants of Flori.la to 
the enjoyment of the privileges, rights and immunities of the 

itizeq* of the United States 

the twenty-seventh con. 
who had been elected a dele- 
Florida, where it was alleged 

rate from the Territory of 

that he was not a citizen 
by the house committee 

tl 

e United States, it \v;i&gt; held 

el 

ections, "It matters not hi 

whether the naturalizatioi: 

mirress, March 1, 1845, all the citizens of the former r 

any express declaration, citizens 

the United States 

raking of the admission of 
the chief justice said: 

stains of Ohio, Indiana and Illi 

The inhabitants, or people 

who were empowered to take 

part in the creation of these new political organisms and 
who continued to participate in the discharge of political 
functions, included others than those who were originally 
citizens of the United States. 

Efter numerous other citations illustrative of collective nat 
ization, the following general conclusions were announced: 

Congress having the power to deal with the people of 
the territories in view of the future states to be formed 
from them, there can be no doubt that in the admission of 
a state a collective naturalization may be effected in accordance 
with the intention of congress and the people applying 
for admission. Admission on an equal footing with 
the original states, in all respects whatever, involves the 

.At i he second session o 
ita the case of David Levy, 

be effected by act of congrt 

y treaty or adr 

w states, the provision is alikt 

iplicable." 
By the annexat 

Texas, under a joint resolution 

public became, w </seg>

            <seg id="p092">
192 


adoption as citizens of the United States of those whom 
congTess makes members of the political community, and 
who are recognized as such in the formation of the new 
state with the «onsent of congress. 

The next question in the chain of investigation was, in th«-admission 
of Nebraska, who were made "members of the polit 
ical community"; and from a thorough examination of the organic 
act, the enabling act, the state constitution and laws, tor 
with the act of congress for the State's admission, it appeared 
that in addition to citizens of the United States, all others 
who had declared intentions to become such were made members 

of the political community. On this point the opinion of the 
court is most emphatic. 

It follows from these documents that congress regarded 
as citizens of the Territory all who were already citizens of 
the United States, and all who had declared their intention 
to become such. Indeed they are referred to in section 3 of 
the enabling act as citizens and by the organic law the 
right of suffrage and of holding office had been allowed to 
them. Those whose naturalization was incomplete were 
treated as in the same category as those who were already 
citizens of the United States. What the State had power 
to do after its admission is not the question. Before congTess 
let go its hold upon the Territory, it was for congress 
to say who were members of the political community. So 
far as the original states were concerned, all those who 
were citizens of such states became upon the formation 
of the Union citizens of the United States, and upon the 
admission of Nebraska into the Union "upon an equal 
footing with the original states, in all respects whatsoever" 
the citizens of what had been the Territory became 
citizens of the United States and of the State. 

As remarked by Mr. Chief Justice Waite in Minor v. Happersett: 
"Whoever, then, was one of the people of either 
of these states when the constitution of the United States 
was adopted, became ipto facto a citizen, a member of the 
nation created by its adoption. He was one of the persons 
associating together to form the nation, and was, consequently, 
one of its original citizens. As to this there has 
never been a doubt. Dispute has arisen as to whether 
or not certain persons or certain classes of persons were 
part of the people at the time, but nerer as to their citizenship 
if they were." </seg>

            <seg id="p093">
1« 


rgued thai Jim k. |!,, v ,i had never declared 

ilioiiKh his father li.nl. and that benaw, m alleged, hi.. 

nited States, and being under the age of twenty-one 

at the time of such naturalization, and the children 

zens of the I nited States. Imni out of the limits and 

.jurisdiction of the I'nited 
citizens of the I'nited Sta 

Itatea, shall he considered as 
s." etc. 
net of April I 4th. IMC, carried 
section Mil, was: ••That the 

The fourth section of the 
nto the revised statutes a 

us duly naturalized under any of the laws 

of the I'nited States, or who. previous to the passing of anv 
law on that subject, by government of the I'nited States, 
may have become citizens of anv one of the said states, 
under the laws thereof. Iwinjr under the ape of twentv- 

one years at the time of their parents l&gt;ein(r so naturaiized 
or admitted to the rights of citizenship, shall if dwelling 
in the I'nited States. l&gt;e considered as citizens of the 
I'nited States." In Campbell v. Cordon. I (ranch. IT*, it 

v 

•tion conferred the rig-tits of citizen 
hild of a parent who had been duly 

naturalized under the act of I 

Tit:., although the child did 
nited States until she came 
net of 1s»-J was [Kissed. The 
and we perceive no reason 
children of those who had 
&gt;ur judgment the intention 
I have a pros|&gt;ecti\e opera- 

i resident of the I 

here after that, but In-fore the 
rule was to be a uniform ride 

r limiting such a rule to tin 
tii already naturalized. In 

hat the act of 1802 shoul 

By the second section of th 

act of March '.'(&gt;. ISM, if any 

alien who had complied with the terms of the act should 
ilie without having- completed his naturalization, his widow 
nnd children should be considered citizens u|m&gt;h taking the 
naths prescribed by law: anil this was carried forward into 
section 21(&gt;s of the revised statute-.. 

II 

me ;i .-itizcii of th.- tinted Stiitrs. :l l 

mcr IM not completed his nat uralization Iwfore the son 

Gained his majority, tkc latter cannot he held t&lt;&gt; conic 

thin tlie purview ,,f the acts of congress relating to the 

rritorv an&lt;l the admission of the State, so as to l»e en- 

le&lt;l to claim to have been made a citizen therein. 

Ihc act of March M, ITM, provi.le.l for the nat urali/ation 

aliens ami then that "the children of such |&gt;erson&lt; so 

lnrali/c,l. dwelHag; within the Initcl States. Ihmii^ under 

¦ age of t«eiityone years at the time of such naturaliza- 

n. shall also be considered citizens of the United States." 

I'he third section of the act of .lanuar.v M, 17M, provi.led 

liil children of persons duly naturalized, dweliinff within </seg>


            <seg id="p094">

l'.\ the first section of the met of May :.'•&gt;. Ib24. carried 
forward iato section :J1&lt;&gt;7 of the revised statutes, any alien. 
¦Wing a minor, who shall have resided in the United 8 
ihree xe;irs next preceding his arrival at majority ami continued 
to reside therein, may. upon reaching the Bfe "f 
Twenty-one years and after a residence of five years, including 
the three years of minority, be admitted a citizen 
of the I nited States, without having made during minority 
the declaration of intention required in the case of aliens. 

Tin- statutory provision* leave much to he desired, and 
the attention of congress has been called to the condition 
of the laws in reference to election of nationality: and to 
'he desirability of a clear definition of the status of minor 
children of fathers who had declared their intention to lie 

come citi/ens. but had failed to perfect their naturalization: 
and of the status grained b\ those of full aire by tht 
declaration of intention. 

Clearly minors acquire an inchoate status by the declaia 
lion of intention on the part of their parents. If they at 
tain their majority before the parent completes his natural 
i/alion. then they have an election to repudiate the status 
which they find impressed upon them, and determine that 
they will accept allegiance to some foreign potentate or 
power rather than hold fast to the citizenship which the 
acr of the parent has initiated for them. Ordinarily this 
election is determined by application on their own behalf, 
but it does not follow that an actual equivalent may not 
lie accepted in lieu of a technical compliance. 

James K. I'.ovd was born in Ireland, of Irish parents, in 
ISM, and brought to this country in 1844 by his father. 
Ip-cph ISoyd. who settled at Zanesville. Miiskingiim County. 
Ohio, and on March ."&gt;. 1S49, declared his intention to become 
a citizen of the I'nited States. In 1855 .Tames K. l'..p\d. 
who had grows up in the full belief of his father's citizenship 
and had been assured by him that he had completed 
his naturalization by taking- out his second papers ii 
voted in Ohio as a citizen. In August, lSSfi. he removed to the 
Territory of Nebraska. In 1857 he was elected and served 
as county clerk of Douglas County: in 1864 he was sworn 
into the military ser\ ice and served as a soldier of the federal 
government to defend the frontier from an attack of 
Indians; jn I860 he was elected a member of the Nebraska 
lejri.-ilature and served one session; in L8T1 he was elected 
a member of the convention to frame a state constitution 
and served as such; in IS".} he was again elected and served 
os a member of the convention which framed the present 
state constitution: in 1-&gt;M1 he was elected and acted as </seg>



            <seg id="p095">
¦ resident of the city council of Omaha; in tWl and 
i^pcctively, was elected mayor of that &lt;it\. serving- in all 
four years. From 1856 until the State was admitted, and 
from thence to this election, he had voted at every elecion. 
territorial, state, municipal and national. He had 
aken prior to the admission of the State the oath required 
&gt;y law in entering upon the duties of the offices he had 
filled, and sworn to support the constitution of the United 
states and the provisions of the organic act under which 
he Territory of Nebraska was created. For over thirty 
years prior to his election as governor, he had enjoyed all 
the rights, privileges and immunities as a citizen of the 
I'nited States and of the Territory and State. M betaf in 
law, as he was in fact, such citizen. 

When he removed to Nebraska, that Territory m to a 
large extent a wilderness and he spent years of extreme 
hardship upon the frontier, one of the pioneers of the new 
settlement and one of the inhabitants who subsequently 
formed a government for themselves. The policy which 
sought the development of the country by inviting to participation 
in all the rights, privileges and immunities of citizenship 
those who would engage in the labors and endure 
the trials of frontier life, which so vastly contributed to 
the unexampled progress of the Nation, justifies the application 
of a liberal rather than a technical rule in the solution 

of the question before us. 

We are of the opinion that .Tames E. Boyd is entitled to 
claim that if his father did not complete his naturalization 
before his son had attained majority, the son cannot be 
held to have lost the inchoate status he had acquired by the 
declaration of intention, and to have elected to become the 
subject of a foreign power, but, on the contrary, that the 
oaths he took and his action as a citizen entitled him to 
insist upon the benefit of his father's act, and placed him 
in the same category as his father would have occupied if 
he had emigrated to the Territory of Nebraska: that in 
short, he was within the intent and meaning, effect and 
operation of the acts of congress in relation to citizenship 
of the Territory, and was made a citizen of the United 
States and of the State of Nebraska under the organic and 
enabling acts and act of admission. 

(2) Another and shorter course of reasoning leads to the 
same conclusion: — 

The respondent, in his answer, after stating that his 
father, on March 5, 1849, when the respondent was about 
fourteen years of age, made before a court of the State of </seg>



            <seg id="p096">
Ohio hi* declaration of intention to become a citizen of the 
1 nited States, anil averring "that liis father for forty- two 

yean last past has an joyed and exercised all of the rights, 
ininiiiiiitifs and BrtrUagu and discharged all the duties of ¦ 
citizen of the Inited States and of the State of Ohio, and 
was in all respects and purposes ¦ eitizen of the L'nited 
States and of the State of Ohio": and particularly alleging 
his &lt;|iialifieations to lie a citizen, and his Beting as sneh for 
forty vrars. rating and holding office in the State, further 
distinctly alleges "on infortuat ion anil lielief. that 
prior to October, ls."&gt;4. liis father did in fact complete his 
naturalization in strict accordance with the acts of con 
j/rcss known as the naturalization laws so as to admit 
and constitute him a full citizen of the l'nited States thereunder, 
he having exercised the rights of citizenship herein 
descrilied, and at said time informed respondent that such 
was the fact." 

As the allegation last qttoted sets up a riffht and privilege 
claimed under the laws of the United States, this 
court must determine for itself the question of the suffi 
ciency of this allegation, and is not concluded by the view 
taken of that question by the supreme court of Nebraska. 
In the words of Mr. Justice Miller, speaking- for this court: 

"The question whether a plea sets up a sufficient defense, 
when the defense relied on arises under an act of congress, 
docs present, and that necessarily, a question of federal 
law: for the question is and must lie. Does the plea state 
fails which under the act of congress constitute ;i 
defense'.'" 

It is true that naturalization under the acts of congress 
known as the naturalization laws can lie completed before 
a court, and that the usual proof of naturalization is a 
cosy of the record of the court. Hut it is equally true 
where no record of naturalization can be produced. c&gt; idence 
that a person having the requisite qualification to 
baeaaac a citizen, did in fact and for a loag time vote ami 
hold office and exercise rights beloufrinjr to citizens, is sufficient 
to warrant a jury in inferring that he has been duly 
naturalized as a citizen. And by the constitution of Ohio 
of is.",), none but white male citizens of the I'nited States 
were entitled to Kite or hold office. 

Such beiiifr the settled law. we can have no doubt that the 
fact that the respondent's father liecame a naturalized citizen 
of the I'liited States before October. 1854, is well 
pleaded in the allegation in question, anil is therefore admitted 
by the demurrer. The allegation "that prior to October. 
Is.'i4. his father did in fact complete his nat urali/.a- </seg>


            <seg id="p097">
197 

Tin 

•laim 
willi 

t.i l&gt;i 

II. 

two v 

ited 

ion 

Cs 

rot 

tion iii strict accordance with the act of congress known 
as the naturalization laws so as to admit and constitute 
him a full citizen of the Inited States thereunder."" necessarily 
implies that he had been duly naturalized before a 
court as required by those laws. Specific allegations of 
the time and place at which, and of the court l&gt;efore which, 
he was so naturalized, or setting forth a record of his naturalization, 
would have Ween superfluous, and. in view of 

lie respondent's imperfect information, as manifest upon 
he face of the allegation, of a transaction taking place so 

•go, hardly possible 

1'nder this allegation, and the earlier allegations leading 
up lo it. if traversed, a jury would have been warranted 
in inferring that the respondent's father became a citizen of 
the Tinted States before October, 1V&gt;4. and consequent ly 

that the respondent himself 
l-'or Ihis reason, without 

was likewise a citizen. 
regard to any other question 
poudent was entitled to judg- 

argued in the case, the re 

ment upon the demurrer. 

Mr. Justice Marian. M 

Justice (I ray and Mr. Justice 
;ion of the court upon the lat- 

l!rown concur in the conclu 

ter course of reasoning only 

All of the justices, except Mr. Justice Field, unite in holding 
that this court had jurisdiction of the case, and that 
ii|)on this record. James K. ISoyd has been for two years 
next preceding his election to the office of governor, a citizen 
of the Inited States and of the State of Nebraska. 

The judgment of the supreme court of Nebraska is reversed, 
and the cause remanded to l&gt;e proceeded in according 
to law and in conformity with this opinion. 

¦ lnessiip- of (ioveinoi- Hoyd. closing liis official term, da 
uv 1:!. 1893, disclosed thorough analysis of the siluali 
evidence of practical reform. He enumerated as objt 
remedied, first : 

The last legislature great I J increased the appropriations 

but made no provision for an 
additional expense. 

increased levy to meet the 

estimated the deficiency tli 
t-ars. at $750,000. Second: 

it would result therefrom 

That, while the law explicitly 
listed for assessment at its 

states that property should 
nctual value, it is notorious 

hat this is not done. In fact it is safe to say that the pre- </seg>

            <seg id="p098">
198 


railing average of rallies a 
the actual value and there ii 

:essed is about one eighth of 
in consequence, a correspond- 

ing high rate of levy required for the raising of the necessary 
rciemic. the same being almost invariably up to the 
limit established by law. 

Third: 

That as the constitutional amendment, for the investment 
f the permanent school fund, was undoubtedly defeated by 

the heedlt— Utlg of voters it should again be submitted for 

public approval 

Fourtli, inasmuch as a laving 
administering the affairs of a ft 
argued the necessity sf allowing 
t»aperintendent*, believing thai 

of 140,000 had been secured in 

\v of ilii- state institutions, li&lt; 

governors to appoint all their 
¦their running expennes could 

lie reduced '¦'&gt;&lt;&gt; per cen&lt; over amounts heretofore eoaraaied.' 
speaking of an investigation which he had the honor to instituii 
he said: 

The investigation which followed developed such a stat&lt; 
f affairs as warranted an investigation by the grand jurv 

with the result that a number of criminal indictments wer 
found, with which the courts have yet to deal. 

Commenting on the report of the commissioner of public lands 
and buildings relative to the school fund he said: 

The report farther shows that there is now Invested in 
United States bonds, state securities and registered county 
bonds belonging to the permanent school fund the sum of 

and cash in the state treasury amounting t 

*4'.io.:;iis.:;!i. making a total of 13,016,270.74, an increase in the 
permanent school fund during- the past two years of 
The common school lands now under lease produce 
an annual rental of m,71CM. This with the annual interest 
and unpaid principal on said contracts, amounts to 
$239,170.11, which with the added interest amounting to 

:.:;i makes a fund of $33 
tioned to the school district* 
the revenue derived from the 
school fund in the state trei 

i to be annually apporof 
the State in addition to 

investment of the permanent 
¦wry. 

This is a magnificent showing for the educational advantages 
of our State and reflects grestf credit upon t hostfounders 
of our State who in the early days conserved its 
school interests. </seg>

            <seg id="p099">
199 


th, 

¦c,ual 

ud 

com 


Of (lie State University ac uttered the following 

The report of the Bound of Regents of the State Univerity 
makes a particularly gratifying- showing. The growth 
.f Mm University during- the last biennial period has been 

phenomenal. The attendance has more than doubled, the 
present enrollment being 057. This registration represents 
twenty states besides Nebraska and sixty-four Nebraska 

counties. The close connection of the University with the 
public school system is shown by the fact that :&gt;&gt;T pupils 

come from high schools and 313 from public schools. The 
advanced standing of the University and its strong- hold 
upon all who are seeking the best facilities for higher education 
is manifested by the fact that 12.". of the students 
catnc from other colleges and universities, largely within 
this State. That it is ministering in a helpful way to the 

great mass of the ]&gt;eople 
felled class is shown by 
.Tie children of- farmers v 
with a large degree of &lt; 

of the State and not to any prethe 
fact that Ml of its students 
hile the remainder are scattered 

|uality among every occupation 

known in the State 

* 

He rave the following fact 

I have the honor to report the granting by me of thirteen 

pardon*, twelve commutations and five remittances of fines 

The different sums of money received by me and paid into 

the State Treasury, as evidenced by receipts on file, amount 

$14,166.80 

Speaking of the Adjutant QetteraTi office lit- said: 
A demand was made for the return of this money ($1 

4-10. si;) which demand was complied with. 

On tlic subject of the Nebraska Relief Commission 

ltelief was afforded in about ten counties which had suffered 
from the drouth of the season of 1890. Provisions were 
supplied to an average of 8,000 families averaging five 
in a family, from four to six weeks. Great good was done, 
and many discouraged settlers were thus enabled to hold 
their homes, and have since been rewarded with good crops. 

Though the last legislature had appropriated 925,000 for 
National &lt;Juard. Oov. Bojd asked but flll.lMMi for an e 
length of time, two years; and recommended that artillery 
cavalr.v be mustered out. and "that the strength of the . 
panies be increased lo conform with the new tactics, and 
each comiiany have a maximum of 10(1 enlisted men." </seg>


            <seg id="p100">
&lt; 

I 


Of 



Mi tin- sulijcci of extortions, he stated 

I think there is a demand for the regulation of rate 
•hartred by the express ci unpanics within this State, to tli 

end that charges unreasonably 
reasonable tost. There is no jii 
at present exacted by the expr&lt; 

high may be reduced to a 
itiflcation of the hijrh rates 

companies of this Stall 

I* had iIk- following on insam 

linn iit 

I would further rail your attc 

ntion fn i he adviitabilitv of 

a law which would authorize the executive to parole convicts 
who iM-conie insane in the prison for transfer to 
an asylum, I nder existing conditions, to transfer an insane 
convict to an asylum, the governor must issue a par 
don and an insanity board must then pass upon the unfortunate 
pel-son. Should the prisoner, however, beeoaae cured 

&lt;:f his insanity, lie cannot be returned to the state prison, 
a defect in the law which should be remedied. 

rvo important recommendation* related to librari**f ami to 
St;it«' Historical Koci.-tv. 

I believe that the law relating to the establishment of 
public libraries should be amended so as to extend like privilege* 
to each school district in the Slate, as 1 think the 
establishment of free libraries in conjunction with the 
public schools would be a wise and judicious thing. 

The State Historical Society calls upon the legislature for 
an increase of the amount appropriated allotted to it. asking 
for $7..')(Ni for t lie ensuing two years. I believe this de- 

iralile and therefore recommend it. 

tmrriag to liis vi-to of a railroad freight bill in the s.ssinn 
H82, lie said: 

I a m still of the opinion that a reasonable reduction in 
freight rates should he made, but from year to year conditions 
vary so much that an inflexible rate on all schedule 
articles would l&gt;e liable to work injustice, and. in my jutlfrinent 
should not be established by statute, except. perhaps, 
upon staple eommooit ies. such as grata, live stock, coal, 
lumber, and like commodities in car-load lots. The adjustment 
of rates should. I beliexe. Ik- left to a commission 
composed of men capable of dealing Intelligently with the 
question and affording means to thoroughly inform them-rlirs 
as to the merits of each separate ease brought before 
them for adjustment. </seg>

            <seg id="p101">
201 



fail to present the stilt c's capabilities and demands, in an ;ul«-&lt;|iiate 
manner, in the World's Kail- at Chicago, an rqaal addi 
tional iippro]iriat ion was i-eroinniended. 

the warehouse bill of last session, now a law. received heart v 
liiendatioti. with sin h additions mggiwtti as would Riw ii 
Her efficiency. The new elect ion law known as the A us 
ian System, and the Michigan mode of choosing presidential 
Iocs, by congressional districts, came in for approval. M 
basis of successful U|ltlitll and needed only certain 
•i tic additions to bring them up to the governor's standard 
lemocratic excellence. 

In his official term, baring navigated a stormy sea. his n 

cellency hailed a ipiiet port with 

an honest concession 

There iire ninny itirreenble 
(iovernor's ottici'. but at ihe 
with a feeling of pleasmr ;n 
unto my ¦¦eecaaor the dntic«. 

tliinirs rniiiiei'te&lt;l with the 
~a nif time. I niiiv &gt;uy. it iil 
lejoicillfr tllilt I relini|ilish 
;l rt's i\ut\ res|&gt;i»iisit»ilit ies |&gt;er- 

taininir therett </seg>

            <seg id="p102">
202 


* 

Governor Lothmo Croente delivered his inaugural Januan 
1-".. 1893, in whk'fa In- congratulated the legislature upon star 
prosperity, as contrasted with the drouth of two years befoiv 
affirmed the fact of Xebraskans being a plain, toiling peopl&lt; 
;u &lt;¦!¦*&lt;¦ 10 "extravagance which begets extravagance"; and ex 
pressed the positive opinion that "the appropriations made b\ 
ill.- last legislature" were f 750,000 too high, and that f50.0(i 
E- could he Bared by the legislature dispensing with unneees 
employees: thai the iwajrmml of state institution 
hi he so thorough that guilty officials, if in existence 
should he exposed: that "corporations not only have no right 1&lt; 
unjustly take millions, but they should not be allowed to tak 
an unjust dollar from the people," .and yet "their property di 
¦erven the same consideration as that accorded to any other, 
and while the Populist party had control of the legislature am 
he would hare preferred one in harmony with his own vie\\&gt; 
still it was their duty "to advance the welfare and glory of th 
State in which we all have such a just pride." 

It was at this session of the legislature that Judge William 
V. Allen. Populist, was elected TJnited States Senator for a term 

of six years. 

Two years after the delivery of his inaugural, he was compelled 
to review a period of great financial depression and fail 
ure of crops in the western part of the State, causing him to revive 
the relief commission of 1891, and giving an opportunity 
of thanking the people of Oregon and others for substantial aid. 
aad the railroads for free transportation for donated supplies. 
Said he: "My idea is that the several counties should care for 
iheir own needy." He believed this would produce economy aud 

&lt;;&amp;amp;lt;&gt;\ 

1893-1895. 

Mkss.\i;k. Januaby :{. ls'.t."i </seg>


            <seg id="p103">KRXOK LORENZO CROUNSE. </seg>

            <seg id="p104">
203 

Ety in distributiou. and if the State would invest tin- |»i 
nt school fund in relief bonds of counties, it would l»-and 
cheaper than outright appropriations; besides tinindebtedness 
had reached the constitutional limit. 

FINANCES 

H»' declared the State's financial condition bad. inasmuch a&gt; 

tin-re were outstanding warrants of two classes, equal to $tinv 
538, with only |28,503 with which to pay. He found the property 
of the State f l,27."i.t;s.".."H4. assessed at less than 15 per tmmi 
of its value. He demanded better security for State funds ie 
posited with banks; and gave ample evidence of a painstaking 
and intelligent care over the investments of the permaneni 
school fund. By securing obedience to the law requiring ofti 
of state institutions to make semiannual reports of receipt! 
and disbursements, he was aMe to Me order evolved from (H 
fusion and economy made the rule rather than the exception. 
While the monthly demand for coal at the Lincoln Insane H"s 
pital under Thayer's administration for two terms was 546 tons. 
and under Boyd's 233 tons for one term, it was only 1 s I tee* 
during the term of Mr. Crounse. 

It was his good fortune to have administered his term on 
f667,0()0 less of an appropriation than the allowance for the 
previous years. 

Iy allowing an officer of a prominent institution to retain 
ition irrespective of politics, he honored the doctrine of proion 
for merit, and said in his message: "Sound legislation 
uld not be avoided for fear of the loss of some partisan ail 
tage." In cases where malfeasance and embezzlement were 
pected he promptly aided the officers of justice. In the mat 
of f 236,364 he ordered suit to be brought upon a ret tied 
isurer's bond. He was able to show a decided decline in in 

sane hospital expense* in these word 

These three hospitals, located nt Hastings. Lincoln, and 
Norfolk, under the superintendence of Drs. Johnston. Hay. 
and Little, respectively, have kaca ably managed, and T desire 
to testify to the hearty co-operation and sympathy of </seg>

            <seg id="p105">
204 




iln-f gentlemen, and the itew»rdi under them, in my efforta 
to reduce the expense* i&gt;f theae institutions to the 
minimum. A reference to the table furnished you «ill show 
thai the annual |ht capita ta\ expense wa&gt; reduced from 

I.IM ill the year ISM to HS2.U in WW at Hastings, from 

s_':.".i.7j to $193.03 at Lincoln, and from (270.34 to fZMjM ai 
Norfolk during the corresponding [mm-mmI all excellent 
Khowinga ami about equally goad considering the difference 
in population of each, which of course affects the result. 

lltKIUATIllN 

B dealing with liis immediate fellow citizens and the ostsidc 
¦ 1 In- was equally explicit and fail-: 

The fail that nearly or quite half of the lands within the 
State lie west of the line of humidity sufficient to insure 
an unbroken succession of crops, renders irrijrdtion necessary 
to protect the people against disaster in unusually dry 
wars. The partial failure from drouth in WMMrJ-'.i;:. anil 
the almost total failure of ISM, has awakened the people 
to the necessity of providing for watering the grow Ian crops 
by artiticial means. The soil of western Nebraska, where. 
to some extent, want now prevails, is as fertile as that of 

any portion of the Inited States, and in the years past hmi 
yielded abundani harwsts in response to the efforts of in 
dustrious settlers. 

ICAII.Ii'iAl'S AM. BEET S1GA1 

EMiniajcfelj impwt'd willi tlic fact of tli&lt;- State's adaptation 
m i-ultivat ion of tin- sii^ar lieet an&lt;l of tin- value of that gieat 
stIV. lie su
204 




iln-f gentlemen, and the itew»rdi under them, in my efforta 
to reduce the expense* i&gt;f theae institutions to the 
minimum. A reference to the table furnished you «ill show 
thai the annual |ht capita ta\ expense wa&gt; reduced from 

I.IM ill the year ISM to HS2.U in WW at Hastings, from 

s_':.".i.7j to $193.03 at Lincoln, and from (270.34 to fZMjM ai 
Norfolk during the corresponding [mm-mmI all excellent 
Khowinga ami about equally goad considering the difference 
in population of each, which of course affects the result. 

lltKIUATIllN 

B dealing with liis immediate fellow citizens and the ostsidc 
¦ 1 In- was equally explicit and fail-: 

The fail that nearly or quite half of the lands within the 
State lie west of the line of humidity sufficient to insure 
an unbroken succession of crops, renders irrijrdtion necessary 
to protect the people against disaster in unusually dry 
wars. The partial failure from drouth in WMMrJ-'.i;:. anil 
the almost total failure of ISM, has awakened the people 
to the necessity of providing for watering the grow Ian crops 
by artiticial means. The soil of western Nebraska, where. 
to some extent, want now prevails, is as fertile as that of 

any portion of the Inited States, and in the years past hmi 
yielded abundani harwsts in response to the efforts of in 
dustrious settlers. 

ICAII.Ii'iAl'S AM. BEET S1GA1 

EMiniajcfelj impwt'd willi tlic fact of tli&lt;- State's adaptation 
m i-ultivat ion of tin- sii^ar lieet an&lt;l of tin- value of that gieat 
stIV. lie su^&gt;;este(l a holllltv \vller&lt;' a specific price lia&lt;l lieeli 

I aid the inltivator of the beet, 
the I'nited States 
tion. He declated the court 
-lacim-v." in admitting tlie 
upon freight rates, and then 
adaptability and the financial 

Imt which should stop as soon as 
gavre the suc/ar industry protec 

decision "disappointing and un 
lonsiitut ional power to legislate 
nullifying the law for want of 
ability of the railroads, and sn^ 

(i'il an appeal to the court of last resort. I hiring his admin 
ition he had specially received and turned into the state 
sur.v *:&lt;r,..-|!i;v 

K'ith a carefully prepared and condensed niessap*. and in a 
if of kindness he made his official how. gt;;este(l a holllltv \vller&lt;' a specific price lia&lt;l lieeli 

I aid the inltivator of the beet, 
the I'nited States 
tion. He declated the court 
-lacim-v." in admitting tlie 
upon freight rates, and then 
adaptability and the financial 

Imt which should stop as soon as 
gavre the suc/ar industry protec 

decision "disappointing and un 
lonsiitut ional power to legislate 
nullifying the law for want of 
ability of the railroads, and sn^ 

(i'il an appeal to the court of last resort. I hiring his admin 
ition he had specially received and turned into the state 
sur.v *:&lt;r,..-|!i;v 

K'ith a carefully prepared and condensed niessap*. and in a 
if of kindness he made his official how. </seg>


            <seg id="p106">
205 

In rrlinquiahing ;m office which came to me in :i manner 
highly complimentary I do so with the I niMW III— H ¦¦ of having 
tried tti 1h- of service to the people of the State who 
Iwiw so freipientlv honored me. How well I have succeeded 
thev must decide. I shall carry with me pleasant recollections 
of the kindly relations which have existed between 
¦jraelf and those with whom I have associated or hail to 
deal with ill an orticial wit. 

rO.WLI Sl&lt;&gt;.\. </seg>

            <seg id="p107">
206 


GOVERNOR SILAS A. HOLOOMB 

1*9". 18&lt;*7 

lion. Silas A. Bolcomb was born in t lit- slat.- of Indiana in 

the year 1858, and is. consequently, 37 years of age, in this 1895. 
UN e«riy education was obtained in the roinmon and Normal 
id | before liis 17th year, when lie assumed the duly of 
teacher. Daring four yean of teaching he was preparing for 
i-ollege; but liis plans were seriously deranged on account of 
ill.- death of his father in 1878. One year thereafter he arrived 
in Hamilton County. Nebraska, with his mother and younger 
brother* and sisters. Thoughtful, industrious and persevering. 
In- accepted ilie tirst honorable opening for employment, work 
¦pea a farm, for one year. an&lt;l in L89§ entered the law office of 
Thiimmel iV 1'latt. at (irand Island, and came to the bar in 1882. 
In 1883 lie removed to Broken Bow. and in 1891 was elected 

Jadge of the 12th Judicial District. 

Kiougs. a populist and allied with the silver democrats, he 
elected Governor in L8M, while the State went republican 
luralit ies of from twelve to twenty-five thousand. 

I he election of Silas A. Holcomb, of the Populist party, in 
4. took place daring the 40th year of our congressional rep•ntation 
(the limit of ihese sketchesi. He has been preed 
by Burt of South Carolina. Izard of Arkansas, Richmond 
Illinois, and Black of Pennsylvania, all democratic terri 
ial governors, and Sauuders, republican, from Iowa; also by 
•ted governors of the State. Butler, Furiias. Garber. Nance, 
Thayer and ("rounse, republicans, and Boyd. democrat, 
rernor Crounse, his immediate predecessor, had been inaug 
ted by a poaalfcrt legislature, while he was inducted into 

Ee by a republican one. In the great political upheaval of 
[ the populists lost the legislature and gained the Governor, 
le the republicans, losing the Governor, gained the legisla•. 
and consequently the United States Senator, John M. </seg>

            <seg id="p108">
207 


Tlmistoii. The canvass had been one of exceeding hitterneM. 
&lt; 'li-vt'lainl democrats bad ben charged wiili beiag allies of Wall 
Street hankers. bondholders and brokers: rc]»iil&gt;lirans wiili 
beiag in the MOM boat, and pandering to capital by high pi" 
live tariffs: while populists were denounced by both af the old 
parties, as the destroyers of state credit, advocates of vap. 
.mil extremists getrally. Billy opponents fancied rhe inaugural 
of Governor Ilolcomh would giye forth sulphur, be lurid in 
war paint anil intimate scalpels and dangers. Populists, silver 
democrats and independent republicans, who had supported 
hint, had no fears of the result and were delighted with the 
effort Exceptional in taste, pure in style, and admirable in 
«cn| ,-. dealing only in living issues, the production carried its 
own vindication. Almost the tirst subject treated was 

KROl'TH BDFFERSI 

I itani the necessity demanding a careful eonsideratioi 

the actual want of a irreat niimber of our people cans. 

by Ilic drouth of last vear. Nature has bountifully blessed 

Nebraska. Her climate is unexcelled and her soil respond! 

nerously to the labor of the husbandman. For vear- 

prior to 1890 there was an uninterrupted era of gocxl crops 

Kapidly the domain of the rancher was encroached upon bv 

the farmer. From various states came an energetic cla 

f good citizens to make their homes in western Nebraska 

(ienerally they were poor and depended upon the fir- 

son's crop to supply themsi 
immediate necessities of life, 
in vain. Then came on. 
failed to fall and hot winds 
ing devastation to the fields 
there have been alternating 

•hi 1 * and families with all the 
and until 1890 they never relied 

ion when the accustomed ratal 
swept over the country, carryof 
growing grain. Since then 
good and poor crops culmiuat- 

ing- in the general drouth of 1894. 

While this drouth extended practically over the entire 
country, it was particularly disastrous in the western portion 
of the State. Distressed by combats with previous partial 
crop failures, many farmers with only moderate means 
were wholly unprepared to meet the drouth. Many had 
been unable, on account of the short time of their 1 residence, 
to store up grain sufficient to meet the exigencies of this 
extraordinary occasion. Some removed from the State, but 
the great majority, possessing the utmost faith in the country, 
remained, determined to hold on to their possessions </seg>

            <seg id="p109">
¦¦ 

11 

nil 

I 




ill the drouth-stricken district. If p;it ience and lonfr-siiffet 
inf.' ntake people dexrtlag. the barrest of I8»5 should I. 

imhimi ; -r i i r 

our gn-ai state is mbtr t.i mkv tare of its owa poor ami 
many of Hi.- , my boards haw. with commendable nier^ry. 
1 n-&lt;»x i.l.-.l «o,-k with compensation for the able-bodied needy 
in tlit-ir own counties, but there is still necessity for qaiek 
relief to Im- extended to many portions of the Stwte. so that 
all her people may l&gt;e comfortable during the present winter 
;ni(l have :m opportunity to seed ;md work their ground 
for the coming harvest. I know some claim the legislative 
body has no rijrht to make the people donale to the needy 
and that such work should be left to Individuals who are 
charitably inclined, hut every government is in duty Unnid 
to provide at public expense the necessit ies to sustain life 
to its own needy inhabitants, and es|&gt;eeially is this the case 
when the needy are without fault on their part. 

IRRIGATION 

After dwelling upon the sucres* of irrigation upon sina 
ale*. In- broached the bold and &lt;• pr* he—ire theory of N 
Ml aid: 

The |rrea( water ways in the State and on its borders 
haie heretofore in early spring run bankful of water. In 
the early summer they have joined with the waters of the 
Mississippi and Ohio, and many seasons have spread devastation 
over the fertile bottoms of Illinois. Missouri. Kentucky. 
Tennessee. Arkansas. Mississippi and Louisiana, while 
the vegetation of a port km of Nebraska was in many places 
u itheriiifr and drvinjr for want of water. The trovernment 
lias seen tit to rxpend millions of dollars in the construction 
and maintenance of (Treat levees to protect the property 
and lives of the people residing along the rivers in the 

south. Would it not conserve a double purpose and 1*» pro 
ductive of Inestimable good to both sections if the gOT' 
eminent woaM (lirei't its efforts toward* turning the vvatei&gt; 

of the western tributaries of the Mississippi Uiver into 
great reservoirs and thence into irrigation ditches for the 
development of sections of the country which now produce 
very little'.' 

A proper system of irrigation would doubtless make the 
fertile plains of Nebraska and similar states produce an 
inexhaustible supply of 1 he sweetest vegetables and l&gt;est 
cereals, and thus by spreading the water in the springtime 
would reclaim the jrreat river bottoms of our southern 
neighbors and make them kinys of corn and cotton conn- </seg>


            <seg id="p110">II. \S A. IIOUOMI </seg>

            <seg id="p111">
209 


{All 

l: 

AI&lt; 

Iiisi&lt;-;mI of denouncing railroad 

prr w, or iir^in^: government 

(¦in rol 

lie declared 

It is ;m cniini'ipiislv conceived idea, and &lt;| iiitc prevalent, 

thai the interest* .&gt;f t li*- railways and tin- pupli of the 

the inte 

I State arc inimical. In fact Ike iineceaa of each lies principally 
in Ike prosperity of tlie ntlier. 
I mb i&gt;l' i In- opinion that if ¦ constitutional amendment 
ircntiiif.' ;i board of railroad commissionera, with ample 
power in the premises, enulil l&gt;e sul&gt;initteil to the [H U[ll« 
it would receive their approval bj ¦¦ overwhelming majority, 
:iinl 1 believe this rexed question eould be nearer set 
lied sat isfaetori l.\ in that than in any other manner. 

State are inimical. In fuel the hiicopm of rach lies urinci 

n 

it her 

thiit if a constitutional amendment 

r in the premises, could !»¦ submitted to the peopl&lt; 

il receive their npproval bv an overwhelming in 

ieK t i on 

nearer set 

'i 

ill 

hiv other inann 

KI.KiTIVK lUAM'HlSK. 

1,1 

II \ I- 

II 

ANCHISt 

Km willi lini]Miiiii\ nlicf. anil |»im;iiiin! aid for irrigl 

Hut w 

ith temporary 

It inn. 

wiili fair and ample facilities for iranspnrlal ion. In- argt 

w il li t'ai 

.Illll Mlllpll' f 

for iraiiHportation, he arged in 

ii-i 

ti'llijiini economy ami i In- frees! exercise &lt;&gt;f the eleetire 

i cxt'i-risc i»f i lie elective 

fran- 

eliisc as the great ctHmenrator of hamaa fact do— : 
It i&gt; roar duty In Haeredl.v (ruanl this rifrat to \ ' fellow 
electors and to reduce to the absolute minimum anj 
infringement of it. ICspeeialh dues it seem to me that tin' 
employees of the larfrer'eorporationM should. h\ wise lejris 
lation. have sneh protecting care tin-own aaoat them that 
they ma.\ in the exercise of the right of suffrage act without 
any fear whatsoever from the displeasure of their employers, 
whose political conviction* may l&gt;e different from 
t heir ow n. 
It is undented that the Australian ballot Ian Waal needed 
reform and has done much toward purifying elections in 
Nebraska, but I am confident* it would prant a privilege 
without mischief if the law should lie amended bj you so 
that the elector can designate, where it is possible, his 
choice of candidates and at the same time express by his 
ballot his political convictions. 
I would respectfully Kiiinreal that each political party 
havinir a fair percentage of the vote in an\ district should 
have representation on the election board, and that not 
more than two judyes should be selected from any one political 
party. 
There can be no more important subject for the careful 

riirht ti 

rrdiicc to i hf absolute minimum ;in\ 

it to nit* th;it tl 

1 

hit of their em 

iion&gt; niav he different f 

nliMiii'il that the Australian l«ilh&gt;t lu\t «a»a neefled 

s done niiiih toward punfying 

lilt ;i |il'i\il 

\'OI| 

lesic 

\\ here it i^ possible, hi 
«ame time exprrtM l&gt;\ Iti 

t 

m ¦ &lt; • t fully Kii|f|pes1 that each political party 

of 

tl 

tc iii am ilistriot should 

have representation on the elevtion lionnl. ami that not 

r 

party 

llinrr III 

than the protection of tht 

on 

iilerati 

\\ maker 

t. ami 1 would most respectfully call 
nir existinfr election laws and invite a 

purity of the liall 
vour atU'iitton to </seg>

            <seg id="p112">
210 



comparison with those of other stales, to the end that 
amendments may be made rendering bribery and undue influence 
of the voter more nearly impossible and facilitating 
the more rapid and accurate countinir of votes. 

Ethe legislature ami lie himself sliall be so foituuale as to 
sure up to his standard of duty, his message two years beace 
have joyful acceptance. 

Although Ig various political beliefs we as legislators 
and executive should have but one great object in 
in discharge the duties incumbent upon us in a (rood 
businesslike manner for the eommon good of all. Each of 
vim as a legislator has been elected as the advocate of the 
principle* of some political party, but today you represent 
all the people of your district. In my capacity I shall 
earnestly endeavor to be the governor of all the people. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>