<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FOURTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE State Industrial School AT KEARNEY, NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">FOURTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE State Industrial School AT KEARNEY, NEBRASKA FOR THE TIVO YEARS ENDING NOT EMBER 30, 1908 190t* </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Kearney, Nov. 30, hHiv ] &lt;i Hit) Excellency, ( Seorge L. Sheldon, Governor ami The Honoi a lilt Board of Public Lands and Building] k Gentlemen I have the honor to submit herewith the Pour nth Biennial Report of the State Industrial School for Boy the biennium ending November :i()t h. 190V The bienniuni has seen«a steady decrease in the population of the school. On December 1st. 1906, the inmates of the school numbered 214. On .November :{&lt;) of 1908 the population is 14s A number of causes for this decrease can be given. Towns am cities are taking car*' of their dependent and delinquent ehildrei much better than ever before. This is particularly true in tht cities of Omaha and Lincoln, from which in past years a large pro portion of the inmates of this school came. The juvenile court i in these cities are remarkably well organized and effective, am are successful in saving to the homes a large number of boys who under old conditions would inevitably be sent lure. The deten - tion schools in these cities do much that otherwise would have to be done by this school. Another cause of decrease is the increas - ing habit of judges in all parts of the satte in paroling and thereby often saving boys who have broken laws for the first time. All this decrease can be reckoned as progress in the right direction in saving boys to the home and to society. Another cause of de - crease is the unusual number of irregular paroles during the month of August. 1007, just previous to the change in administration in the institution. The total number of boys received during the biennium is 202. The total number leaving the institution is 268. During the biennium the schools have been made more effect - ive. Instead of breaking into school work in order to carry on work in other lines more effectively, effort has been made to pre - serve the school work even at the expense of work in other depart - ments. If the present administration should have been con - tinued, much more effective plans would have been put into effect along this line, plans studied out during the work of the p </seg>
            <seg id="p004">234 Much less land would l&gt;e handled, much less purely manual work would l&gt;e done, much more industrial work would l&gt;e carried on nnection with the academic branches. A new course of study has been adopted and has been made a part of this report. It ■gnized that school work in an institution like this should be not only as effective as work in city schools, but more effective. It must l&gt;e recognized also, that as conditions are different in some respects, courses and methods should differ. rived are usually deficient or irregular in school work. their average stay here is two years, they seldom go to school after they leave here. The school work, therefore, consists of a series of courses grading in difficulty from the very elementary to the h one including all the essentials possible in a course of its difficulty, each one l&gt;eing two years in length. tKffort has been made to have all departments do industrial cation. In ati institution like this all the work is done by boys ler the direction of employe.-. Our effort lias been to direct ■ntion to teaching the boys how to do the work rather than to ter the effort on getting the work done. To keep this aim in it weekly meetings of all employes have been held, and the of handling the boys and accomplishing the work have I discussed. The industrial course is made part of this report. t.\ compfc in of daily reports has been invented, l'rac - llv all employes hand in every evening a report of work accoin - hed. output, material used, breakages, etc. All demerit re - handed in daily, as well as extra merit reports. These recommendations for corporal punishment are signed by the erintendent 0 Dt superintendent before being effective, ailed reports from kitchens, store rooms, dining rooms, boiler se. and stock farm are handed in daily. These reports require little time from each person, yet furnish a daily check on all id all rapplii Kffort has been made to secure employes of the highest type. aid women are required who not only know their respective occupations, but who also know how to handle boys. must l&gt;e able to so live as to furnish to the boys the right |iles of American citizenship. Political lines have been ignored by the management and higher wages have been paid in order to secure the l&gt;est possible corps of employes. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">235 Effort ha&gt; been made to pursue the agricultural work along scientific lines. An alliance has been made with the State Agri - cultural School, and improved methods have been introduced. The size of the dairy barn lias been doubled, a dairy equipped, fine stock purchased, methods of testing and weighing milk introduced and workmen of such merit employed that two of them are two a part of the st; ff at the state farm. I Effort has been made to keep a systematic record of paroled rs. A card catalog has been made and a system adopted for aining monthly reports from the persons to whom the bo\ •oled for the first year of the parole. A quarterly report i&gt; re - ired thereafter until the boy reaches the age of twenty-one, ere has been an attempt made to require good behavior of ■oled boys and to return any boy whose conduct on parole has been good. 1'ersistent efforts have also been made to appre - ld and return escapes. As a result of this policy the net loss m desertion from September 1. H&gt;()7 to September 1. IMG i than the net loss for the same months as far back as re available. Effort has been made to make all the operations of the school systematic and orderly. Transfers of boys are made in pa Hoys are kept strictly to their details. Written orders from the office are required for all irregular movements or work in the shops. All use of nicknames or epithets is forbidden, and affability is required from employes and inmates alike. Military customs in raising and lowering the Hag have been adopted-and the employes required to wear a uniform. I Effort has been made to improve the physical condition of the rtitution. Most of the work has l&gt;een done on the insides of the ildings. Plumbing has been overhauled, buildings rewired, walls d ceilings cleaned and painted, electric motors installed in p wasteful steam engines, a new engine and a new boiler have I ■ •tailed. Small wooden structures adjacent to valuable build: ve been destroyed or replaced by brick buildings. Part of the unels have been re walled, the steam pipes have been covered, a w stole room has been built and new employes' rooms furnished, fact, with the exception of the repainting of the family build: d barn, the enlarging of the dairy barn, the moving of the chicken use. the planting of two mile long rows of trees, and the aln </seg>
            <seg id="p006">236 r rebuilding «&gt;f th yards, the improvements I interior and out of sight. Effort has l&gt;een made to run the institution economically M well a&gt; effectively. The expenditure from the maintenance fund has decreased as the population decreased: the average monthly nditure for .June. July and August of l(&gt;07 was over twentv-.-ix hundred dollars, the average for the same months of 1908 wa than hundred. In numerous ways small wastefulnesses !i stopped, and there is now no danger of a deficit if ordi - rved. In the maintenance fund the averag - penditure for each month of the last six months has been Si ,680. 68 ;iains in that fund 110,045.16. This would allow an ex - ,i ure of ♦2."&gt;1 1 .29 per month from now until April 1st. with no Mo report. In the employes' wages fund the average monthly nditure for the last six months has been ill, 190. 89. There •nofigh t&lt;&gt; expend (1,567.65 per month. In the fund for :inent and general repairs the average monthly expenditure \ months has been S124.76. There remains enough forS572.0S per month. There should he no deficit in any fund from institution. pecta the hiennium has been an unfortunate and whaN D gained, has been against heavy odds. On ! before Christmas day in 1907, a boy newly received from South Omaha came down with smallpox. On Christmas iiindred thirty boys were vaccinated, and the entire school quarantine. Seventeen suited from this first .nd the school remained under quarantine two months. &lt;'&gt;m - ! with the way quarantine regulations are enforced in the sur - iing community, the regulations adopted by the school author - ities were drastic in the extreme. A hospital was established ict quarantine, every one was vaccinated, no communi- Ilowed with the city of Kearney or the surrounding eoual mallpox stamped out than diph- This was no more than the diphtheretir ly in the country around, but cultures showed the and the school authorities maintained the quarantine until this disease also was overcome. Only two In t bieanium the school and the surrounding country has I the school fared </seg>
            <seg id="p007">237 Emewhat letter than its neighbors on account of the continual ltivations. In August. 1!&gt;()7. a hot wind ruined the corn, and dueed the sugar beet crop to a half crop. The corn yielded al c bushels to the acre. In the summer of 1906 the very dry spring dueed the wheat yield to not much more than enough to pay the reshing bill. A hot wind in August reduced the corn yield and t the beet yield to a half crop. These failures affected materially e financial prosperity of the school, and if strict economy had imt en observed might have caused a deficit. The high price of feed for stock has hampered the school. With but little feed raised on the farm, and the price of corn as high a - sixty-five cents, the question of feed wa&gt; a serious one. It mil remembered also that most of our land is farmed on shares with the owner. With careful handling of stock and thorough eultivi of the land the school has been able to secure a considerable value from the agricultural operations in spite of the unfavorable y&lt; I For the past ten months the institution has been troubled with E water supply. This is gotten from shallow wells in the l'latte lley, and pumped to the stand pipe on the highest place of the iff on which the school is located. In the course of years the iter-l&gt;earing strata has become filled with clay and quicksand, so :it the water does not How to the points as rapidly as the pump (uires. The pump house has been moved twice, and sum. vice must now be adopted or more land purchased, lor t! • : months attempts have been made to secure water from 11s. but no success has yet been attained. The proper water itection has been maintained at great expenditure of coal in long urs of pumping. The situation demands the attention of experts. I At four o'clock on the morning of November 23d, fir. covered in the horse barn. When the watchman opened the Ml of the stable in the basement, he found the basement filled h dense smoke, and the horses already suffocated. With the Miing of the doors the whole building burst into flames and within rty minutes the building was destroyed. Employes were in - ntly on the scene, hose attached to the hydrants and water run - g. Efforts were concentrated on saving the ice house, which is y fifty feet from the location of the barn, and the vegetable ise. eighty feet distant. The vegetable house contained about r thousand bushels of potatoes, as well as a large amount of ins. Although the wind was blowing directly toward I </seg>
            <seg id="p008">238 luiilii th of them were saved- Twenty-four horses were lest in the barm, two earriages, two top buggies, three mad emits, ami all the h trued by the school A temporary barn was im - . improvised in the implement shed, and horses borrowed [•v. Probably no horses need he bought until I the prosperity »&gt;f the school certain things are neci t only the legislature can grant. There should be an appropri - for the purchase of a quarter section of land in the id immediately below the | ower canal. There should be amount appropriated for the erection of a modern barn. There ulil \n- a sufficient general repair appropriation to place numer - ceilings and to install commodious toilets and luiths in ily building. There should be an appropriation for equip - las departments sufficient to install modern machinery in ■ and laundry, and to install six forges in the machine p. twelve manual training benches and six lathes in the earpen - ahop. lerintendeni regards the work of the bienniuni The financial record is good, there should l&gt;e a surplus in a numltet of funds, and no deficit in any. The physical condition .■f tli. cadily improved and is now in first class cnii- The income from the farm and dairy has been large, coii - ng the effects of drought and hot wind. The morale of the ellent, the boys are in thorough discipline and ;; • le in such an institution. 'The efficiency and of the force of employes and their willingness to coo| ■ in the work of the school is probably greater now than it has The regard in which the people of the state hold the in - stitution ifactory to the management. More than any - thing else, the record of the paroled boys shows that the school has il U'neht to the boys and to soeietv. thanks are due to the governor of the state •usistent policy of requiring results without regard topoliti - - and for allowing the superintendent to appoint such ml einpl ie believed most valuable without regard ieir political affiliations 'Thanks also are due to the Board of Publi&lt; Building! and to the Hoard of Pureha.se and • lul and efficient direction of those affairs that conn iheir authority. The juvenile courts and probation </seg>
            <seg id="p009">239 ricen in the cities and the civic authorities throughout the ve also materially assisted us in our work. Thanks also are due to the office force as it is now made up, for earnestness, efficiency, and loyalty, particularly to the capable assistant superintendent, \Y. H. Myers. The force of em - ployes, as now constituted, have given to the work more in loyalty and earnestness than they have been paid for and thereby del our thanks. tlfany other persons have also made the work easier, especially State Board of Charities and Corrections and the citizt ■: arney. and therefore our thanks are extended to these pet Respectfully submitted, E. B. SHERMAN, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">FINANCIAL STATEMENT &lt;•! APPROPRIATIONS Balance Aijprtt- I.:ip-4-il Net Appro- ilwr pnation Tolal August priatioo Expendad Balance l»04&gt; 1907 1907 Available 40 1./S01 13 33.183 27 ■_'(i.«&gt;«t_ ) 47 fi. 190.80 pU December 1. HM&gt;6 to May 31, 1907 pta June 1. l'.»07 to November 90, l ( .»&lt;»7 pia December 1. 1&lt;M)7 t&lt;&gt; May 31, LOW i November m&gt;. l'.tos 1,512 77 1,503.34 1,511 .",l 2,127.52 ' receipts 16 . 24 ments December 1. 1906 to May 11, 1907... 13,214.16 merits .June 1. 1907 to November 30, 1*M)7 . IJ60.37 ursejnents December 1. 1907 to May II, 1908... 1,381.36 ursonients June 1. 190S to November 30, 1908. 1^78.93 il (lishurseiiients 4 82 Balance on hand in treasurer's office $711.42 FARM PRODVCTS FDR THE YEAR 1907 AND 1908 1907 190S bushels 3.800 3,794 el Potatoes, bushels 60 76 Oni.m- bushel* 250 114 (MbwB'wUriM tt.fi 19 OS $1(»._&gt;(KI (X) $l.i.M!t us 1767 44 $13,051 M *lo.Mis 1.' $2 Enpioyt*' wagm 4 4M 44 &gt; 304)00 00 34,484 lUtolenaiK ■■. &lt;Xl 71&lt;&gt;&lt;»l .Vt 7&lt;i _'ti 71,015 03 61,118.28 9,8 :.ir» V(NX&gt; IN) S..V&gt;5 _&gt;.N _&gt;:&lt; M 8,528 lis (».J41 ."&gt;:{ _' J . </seg>
            <seg id="p011">241 STATK IMHSTRIAl. SCHOOL, KEARNEY Table Beets, bushels Turnips, bushels 200 11 !• 110 30 Carrot*, bushels Oats, bushels Corn, bushels Alfalfa Hay. tons Wild Hay. tons Sugar Beets, tons Sweet Corn, bushels Cherries, bushels 71) :&gt;4 1 ,827 1.000 1.1. V) MM) 50 :« 176 229* ti(i 114 S Cabbage, heads Rhubarb, bushel 4.000 1.500 25 35 19 String Beans, bushels Cauliflower, bushels Salsify, bushels .1 .&gt; 20 Parsnips, bushels Strawberries, quarts Gooseberries, gallons Currants, gallons :{(t i .&gt; Ill 4 26 2(1 Lettuce, bushels Pop Corn, bushel. Radishes, bushels Asparagus, bushels Tomatoes, bushels Squash, loads 20 is 25 10 5 :«M&gt; 122 I 1 1 1 1 Pumpkins, loads Watermelons, loads Muskmelons. loads Cucumbers, bushels Milk, gallons 25 :u 10,356 1,168 9,840 020 Butter, poundf Peas, bushels s Navy Beans, bushels Dressed Beef, pounds Dressed Pork, pounds 75 1H.767 9.600 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">242 LAND ('&lt; &gt;M M1SSIO N h K S HKPORT POPULATION i&gt;er of Boys in attendance November 30, HMJ6 214 I x*r &lt;&gt;f 1 Total 416 Number of H&lt; i ml discharged during the biennium . 265 Number of Hoys present November 30, 1008 14s 3 i&gt;h HOYS PKE8ENT \XD IN FIRST VEAR OF PAROLE Nuin Xumlier '.t years of age Numlter 10 years of Nttmbar 11 years of ftg I Nuinlier 12 years of ape.. .13 XuiiiUt IS years of age.. 19 X umber 14 years of Nunil&gt;er 15 years of age 36 Numl&gt;er 15 years of ago ...36 Nuin Number '.• years of age Numl&gt;er 16 years of age 38 Number 16 years of age.. Number 10 years of Number 17 years of age 31 XuihIhm- 17 years of age 31 Nttmbar 11 years of ftg I Numl&gt;er IS years of age 30 Nuinl&gt;er IS years of age 30 Number 12 years of age.. 13 Number 19 years of age 22 Number 19 years of age 22 NuiiiUt 13 years of age.. 19 Number 20 years of age 4 Number 30 years of age 4 Number 14 years of - KOH WHICH HO\s PRESENT \ M&gt; IN FIRST VEAH &gt;K PAROLE WERE COMMITTED |uencv . .65 Mendicancy 4 Burglary Petty Larceny . 1 t&gt; Rape . l •lpbility Robbery 14 Stealing . . 9 Murder 1 NATIONALITY OF BOYS PRESENT AND IN FIRST YEAH Of PA HOLE American 131 Southerner 1 Swiss . 1 14 Negro B -' Polish 4 Danish 1 i Russian •&gt; French 2 ,"&gt; November 30, l90(j 202 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">243 Kearney, November M). 1908 K. B. Sherman. Superintendent State Industrial School: Dear Sir -Herewith 1 submit my report for two years' atten - dance at the State Industrial School. During this time we have had two epidemics, small pox and diphtheria, seventeen cases of the former, sixteen of the hitter. Results good. During the two I have made 4Ktf visits. 14 night visits. 1 .496 examinations, and have given 5(H) prescriptions. t There have l&gt;een S fractures. 8 dislocations. 1 amputation. 19 ains. SO cases minor surgery. 4t&gt; abweMes, in addition to the &lt; 'M STIKH KKUM WHH'H H&lt;i\&gt; PRKMKNT V M) IN F1B8T UAH &lt;&gt;K PAROLE WI.KK RKCKIVKD V N I&gt; VI'MHKK KHOM I.U II Counties Adam 4 Jefferson ' Banner Box Butto 1 Kearney 2 Kimball I Browa 2 Lancaster Buffalo 4 Lincoln -■ H,, f , .") Meirick Butler 1 Nance Cedar 4 Neinaha Cherry 1 Nuekolls &gt; Cheyenne :&lt; Otoe ! Coif ax 1 Pawnee 2 Platte : Custer _» Red Willow.. Da wet 1 Saline Dawson A Harpy Deuel 2 Reward ■ ! Douglas 70 Thayer • Fillmore 1 Thurston (lage ■ ■lev it Wayne 1 Webster i • i H.,l 4 York - ■ Harlan 3 Valley ■ Boh 1 PI V: SI It (■ iA.VS REPORT </seg>
            <seg id="p014">244 &lt;kness. confuting &lt;&gt;f lore throats, colds, roughs. bronchial trouble, bowel trouble, etc. There have l&gt;een 130 vac- ; revaccinnations. Then lieen two deaths due to disease, one a case of broncho-pneumonia, the other chronic Bright'a of the kidneys. One boy wan killed in an accident on a hay stacker. Kxcluding the epidemics mentioned, the health of the boys for the past two- year.- the average. -li to thank you for support and courtesies extended to me. and especially do 1 wish to thank Mrs. Sherman for the great a*ai*&lt; iek and injured boys. rt fully yours. C. V. D. Hastkx. 11. D. ESTIMATE mil 1IIK HIHNNH M BEGINNING iPBIL 1. 1909 Per Total Annum Amount \ of Mperiotcodeni II,800.00 »:i.6&lt;)0 (&gt;&lt;&gt; Salary ..; nt superintendent 1,100.00 '-'.'ion (it&gt; Salary of bookkeeper 800.00 1.600 oo Salary of chaplain and probation officers MM) (Ml 1.6(M).(M&gt; Salary of pbymcuu 6(MI (Ml 1.2(M).(M&gt; 110,200.00 CUBRENT EXPENSES 130,000.00 lice 60.IMM) (K) consisting of board, dining room and kitchen ex - l&gt;enses. fuel, electric lights, water supply, boiler house expenses, clothing, lidding, furniture, library books, periodicals, school books, station - medicine, drug supplies, telephone. telegraph. incidentals, traveling e\pei music and amusements. al repair 8,000.00 Kquipping trade department- 5,000.00 New barn 5.000.00 1108,000 (M» </seg>
            <seg id="p015">245 INDUSTRIAL EDUCATION I. MNDKV I The laundry does all the work of the institution, amount i ween two and three thousand pieces per week. The course com - sting, marking, washing, bleaching, blueing, wringing, dry - ;. Bt&amp;rchillg, dampening, flat work with the mangle, shirt waist ning, starching, ironing and shaping collars, counting, checking, anliness, neatness, quickness, system, economy of power and Aerial, action of soaps and acids, formulas for washing diffi id*, use of special machines, speed and cost of machines, effects different kinds of water, blends of starch, wages paid ndrvmen, and what constitutes a good laundryman. TAILOR &gt;HDP The tailor shop makes and repairs practically all the clothing orn by the hoys, including the gray uniforms, the khaki unit te blue shirts, "part of the overalls, as well as all of the riti nthing worn away by paroled boys. The course of instru lcludes pressing, cleaning, padding canva laking. making sleeves, making up facings, putting in p&lt; i lelping coat maker, coat making, measuring, drafting pat' ltting pants, sack coat and vest, busheling. SHOK SHOP tThe shoe shop does all the repairing of the institution ikes all the shoes worn by the hoys. The work include* ig out. pasting up, fitting insoles, fitting outsoles, lasting, nailing' tckening. finishing off. half soling, heeling, sewing up, patching, ids and qualities of leather, splitting leather, waterpn repairing, care in buying si re of tools, reliability il thoroughness of work. tThe carpenter force does all the repairing of the institution. erations, and the building of small structures, as well as the in - uction in the operations of the trade. Sawing, crosscut, rip. &gt;e. compass, filing: planing, surfacing, jointing, champhi iversing, hlocking. grinding: plowing, tongue and grooving, rahit - g, dadoing, graining, heading, moulding, nosing: nailing nd, concealed, cross-toe; morticing, round, square, double. wi ice: glueing, tennons, joints, veneers, furniture: turning, spin- CARPENTKH *HOP </seg>
            <seg id="p016">246 P Kindles, rungs, legs, newer making sashes, doors, blinds s. frames, drawer.-, stairs; shingling, flooring, lathing, fin - : the value of lumber, hardware, relative strength of mate - lirinking and warping of wood. I The boiler bouse furnishes steam for the heating lines, the ring room of the laundry, the steam cookers of the kitchen, the •enty-five hone power engine directly connected with a 220 volt namo whick furnishes electricity for lighting, running the motor the valley pump house, the motor that runs the machinery for indrv. machine shop, and printing office, and the motor that is the feed mill in the cow barn. Under the direction of the en - ieers the hoys in this department first work in the boiler room, noting attention to economical firing, cleaning boilers and flues. tching water and steam gauges, caring for valves, pump and am heating lines. Then comes the work as assistant engineers, tching. oiling and cleaning t he engines, helping the engineers in steam fitting, machine shop work and electrical work. PRINTING OFKICK The printing office prints a weekly paper and for a time a monthly magazine was issued. The office does all the institution printing and could easily do the work for other state institutions. The work includes type-setting, distributing, setting letter heads. envelo|K»s. blank reports, pamphlets, advertising bill-, making up. ■ . proof-reading, correcting, press work on cylinder and platen presses, cutting paper, stapling and sewing pamphlets, collect - ing and writing up news notes, caring for an office in a neat and workmanlike wav. ( ; k k i . n h ( &gt; i s i : tThe greenhouse is maintained for the purpose of furnishing its for the buildings, and plants for the campus and gardens well as for the instruction of the boys. The work includes ping, propagating, budding, testing seeds, potting and repotting, isplanting seedlings, preparation of plants for setting out. plant - and preparing plants for the gardens, mixing soils, fertilizing, iting and care of bulbs, methods of destroying inserts, watering, jer temperature for plants, planning flower bt&gt;d&lt;. care of the s. making up bouquets. HOILKK IUKSK. ENtJINK K&lt;&gt;&lt; &gt; M V N I) MACHINK &gt;H()1&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p017">247 KIK H KNS I The two kitchens do all the cooking for the institution. The king and steam cooking for the boya is done in t he kitchen in the &gt;p building. The cooking for t ho officers' dining room including ■ pastries is done in the kitchen in the administration building, e boys under the direction of the two cooks do the work as lows: preparation and cooking of vegetables; preparing and iking of meats; making of soups, salads, desserts, pastry; put - g up pickles and fruits; taking bread, buns, biscuits; preparing k meals; care of cold storage room; cleanliness (if utensils and 1)1 M\C IdlilM All the dining room work is done by the boys under the direct - ion! of the two managers, one for each dining room. The work includes setting tables, dishing and serving food, waiting on tables, washing and drying dishes, sweeping, dusting, can- of Boon and windows, neatness, quickness and carefulness, deftness in movements of body and handling of dishes, personal cleanliness and obligingness. HOl'SK WdHk All the buildings are taken care of by the smaller boys under the directions of the housekeepers. Attention is given to sweeping, dusting, scrubbing, washing windows, care of lamps, paratinning and polishing floors, patching and mending, making beds, easy repairs of building and furniture, neatness and carefulness, deft - of movement, personal cleanliness and obligingness, reliability. AGRICULTURE I The agricultural work consists chiefly of gardening and inten - e farming. Some corn and wheat are raised each year, but more ention is given to sugar beets, sweet corn, potatoes, beans, ions, tomatoes, and other vegetables needed for the maintenance the institution. Careful sve&lt;\ selection, thorough preparation of ■ soil, and frequent cultivations during the growing season are lght and practiced by the men in charge of the work, and a large ml&gt;er of boys receive sufficient training to make them valuable intelligent farm hands when ready to be paroled. In detail the rk is along the following lines: hot l&gt;eds. soil preparation, nsplanting. seeding, weeding, thinning, tillage, disking, iwing, harrowing, raking, crop cultivation, curing and stacking </seg>
            <seg id="p018">248 manuring, crop rotation, care and use of common farm machine:-, care of horses, breaking, driving, feeding and general LIVK KTOCK I It has Ikh-ii the policy of the institution to get rid of scrub stock id improve as fast M possible the herds of Holstein cattle and hoc Jersey swine The dairy herd now contains about a dozen entered females and a very hue male secured from the state farm Lincoln. From thirty to forty cows art' milked regularly, hut is number is l&gt;eing reduced by culling out unprofitable milkers. fast as possible these should be replaced by good grade or pure t'd Holsteins Two calves have been sold at good prices probable that all surplus stock can be disposed of t&gt; vantage. The rations fed consist of a well balanced grain mix - re of ground corn, bran and oil meal, and an abundance of alfalfa jr. During the fall beet topi and other forage are available • used to supplement the dry feed. However, no very satisfactory •li be expected from the dairy until a silo is erected in order insure a regular and adequate supply of succulent feed. I Other facilities are in quite satisfactory condition. Then i. - * ample barn room and a thoroughly equipped creamery with arator, refrigerator, milk tester, and other necessary articles. * About three hundred hogs are raised each year for the market and for the use of the institution. Nothing has been done in the matter of raising pure bred swine, but the herd presents a favorable irance as a result of continual improvement. Last year the large chicken house was moved to a better location among the other farm buildings and a good start of Plymouth Rock chickens secured. It is hoped that this will soon become a profitable branch he live stock department. The work with the live stock is popular with the inmates. I' is in charge of a graduate of the State Agricultural School, and a :d effort is made to give the boys of this detail thorough in - struction in the principles of stock raising and dairy work according to the following outline care of yards and barns: stabling. ning and feeding: care of young stock; milking: weighing and testing milk; butter making; care of milk utensils. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">249 IN GENERAL In must l»f recognized that school work in an institution like tins should Ik' not only us effective as work in city school*, but more effective. It must l&gt;e recognized also that as conditions are different in some respects, courses and methods should differ. Bo\ ceived are usually deficient or irregular in school work, their -lav here is two years, they seldom go to school after leaving here. The school work, therefore, should consist of a series of CO grading in difficulty from very elementary to advanced, each one in - cluding all of the essentials possible in a course of its difficulty one l&gt;eing two years in length. (Method is of great importance here. The class of boys we have usually not of the kind that know how to study or thai have • taste for study. The lessons should In- taught by the teacher, her than assigned by the teacher and studied by the pupil - &gt;k work should he largely for review and drill. The teachers will furnished with all possible aids and apparatus. The teachers are asked to keep up a plan book, provided for each school. In this book should be recorded the plans for i one day in advance. The books should be on the teacher's desk open for inspection at all times. I Frequent tests will In- given by the superintendent. No boys 1 be paroled who cannot l&gt;e recommended by the teacln &gt;\ving some degree of proficiency. iAll boys are required to work in schools a half of each day. her from 7 or 7 :M) A. M. to 1130 A. M.; or from 1 P. M. t. * 10 1'. M. The other half of the day is spent in some kind of in - strial work. The following departments are maintained ami are i by the boys under the direction of an overseer: printing shop, lor shop, shoe-making and repairing shop, carpenter shop, laun - f, machine shop, blacksmith shop, engine room, boiler house, chens. dining-rooms, a garden of about twenty acres, a farm of nut six hundred awes, a dairy, a stock farm, a chicken ho lenhouse, a paint shop. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">250 I'HIMAHY SCHOOL TIME TABLE The }&gt;eriod includes both study and recitation; in fact, most j&gt;eriods should lx&gt; study-recitation, that is. a period wherein the Development of the idea of form: straight, curved, broken, square, triangle, oblong, circle, prism, sphere, cylinder. The com - paring of objects in size, including one half, one third, one fourth, two thirds, etc.. to five sixths. I Measurements: inch, square inch, cubic inch. foot. yard, the t rule. pint, quart, peck, gallon, bushel, minute, hour. day. week, nth. cent. dime, ounce, pound, all taught objectively. I Reading and writing of numbers to 1000. Addition and sub - ption to and including 0 plus *t. Multiplication and division in - ding 12 time I Written work in addition and subtraction of not exceeding ?e orders, and in multiplication and division, with one digit Mu - ltiplier or divisor. READING Graded Literature Headers, one and two. Hiawatha Primer. Brook's Headers, books one and two The end to be gained is the ability to glean thought and the iig of much good and interesting literature. As much easy ble will be supplied. Kach recitation should if possible include the following five exercises. If time fails for all. numbers four and five can l&gt;est l&gt;e slighted. 1. A conversation with the pupils in order to make sure that the pupils have read the lesson intelligently. toachen help the pupil.- study. Arithmetic 30 minute.- five days a week. Reading.. SO minutes five days a week. Language . 30 minute.- five days a week. Spelling 20 minutes five days a week. Writing • _'."&gt; minutes five days a week. Hygiene 30 minutes two days a week. v Civics.. 30 minutes two days a week. akithmk i n </seg>
            <seg id="p021">251 (1. A preparation of the next lesson to make sure tliat the pupils ve in their min&lt;4s the meanings of the new words. New words l&gt;e marked, sounded, and explained. ■\. A testing in order to find out whether the lesson has been prepared as directed. 4. J\ drill in oral reading. IVn exercise in articulation. Definite detailed assignment ould l&gt;e made of each lesson. This assignment should consist questions; to l&gt;e answered or of directions as to what to do. COURSE IN PHIMAKV READING First Period Characteristic Teaching sight words and sounds separately. Time — Kight to ten weeks. Heading -Sixty to hundred words by sight. Phonetic Work Teaching the symbols, a. e. i. u. c. d. 1. in. Second Period 1 Characteristic Introducing the hook and teaching analysi words into sounds. Time — Four weeks. Reading— From the reader, both sight anil phonetic word t Phonetic work Teaching the symbols o, an, ic. ip. k, ick. r. l&gt;. br, pi. f. ch. tn. ing. ight. tr. s. ter. y; training pupils to ognize sounds in words, and to make words out of sounds whose nbols are known. Third Period Characteristic Change from script to print. Time -About four weeks. Heading — From reader, both sight and phonetic word Phonetic work- Teach symbols dr. ck. a. e. i. ly, less, ne Fourth Period Characteristic Increasing proportion of phonetic words. Time —The remainder of the first year of school. About five months. Heading From readers. Many new phonetic words. Some new sight words. Much easy reading. Phonetic Work -Much training in sounds. Much drill on old I new phonetic words. Sound symbols a. a. el </seg>
            <seg id="p022">252 L A N ( i V A ti f tervation lessons &lt;&gt;r picture study followed by oral or written npositton. Reproduction &lt;&gt;f stories and biography. Dictation KMH ill which previously studied sentences are written from tation. Language work either oral or written daily. Work as suitable from Step* in English Book 1 and from Hitch- Mgjish Composition. w 1 1 1 1 1 n c Legibility the prime essential. 20 minutes daily. 5 genera] exer - 1") individual work. Attention to position of body. The &lt;T to enforce careful writing and correct position in all written work. All written work to !*• put in the permanent hooks and kept ready for inspection. No pages are to l&gt;e torn out of the hooks. Hnuileluish System Hook I. SPELLINM Kight words daily from reading lesson. Words to be placed on the blackboard, marked diacritically. syllabified, sounded by the pupils, the meaning of each word explained and the words used in nee&gt;. l'upils to keep word lists for review every two weeks. Diacritical marks to be taught and the pupils trained to pronounce new words when marked. Studv and recitation not to exceed 25 minutes dailv. HYCilENE and talks by the teacher on how to keep well. The following subjects should l&gt;e included. Jewett's "Good Health" in the hands of the teacher. t Breathing. Pure air. Impurities. Tobacco. Drafts. Ven - ition. Cleanliness and microbes. Dust. Need of sleep. Hahits sleep. Dangers to eyesight. Dangers to hearing. Health of the r. the skin, the nose, the lungs, the teeth, the ringer nails, ting. Alcohol. HlSTom AND ilVHS I Historic anniversaries. Thanksgiving. Christmas. Washing - 's Birthday. Lincoln's Birthday. Decoration Day. Inde|&gt;endenee v. Arbor Dav. Eh. ih, i^h. th. v. so, on. ph, ful. &lt;&gt;. ou.o, &lt;&gt;. ow, u. u, w, wli. y. and a </seg>
            <seg id="p023">253 f Institutional Life: Trades and occupations —baker, earpen - inason. plumber, tailor, blacksmith, fanner, etc. Public Ser - ta Potieeman, engineer, janitor, teacher, governor, etc. His'ory of Nebraska in a simple form. See &lt; ieneral Course) ELEMENTARY SCHooi TIME TABLE period include- both study and recitation: in fact most iods should l&gt;o study recitation, that is a period wherein the teachers help the pupils study Arithmetic. . . M) minute: I Measurements taught objectively, inch, square inch, cubic ■h. foot, yard, rod. miles, pint, quart, peck, gallon, bushel, minute. at, day. week, month, cent. dime, dollar, ounce, pound, ton. Heading and writing of numbers to KM). (MM) in words or figures. I Thorough drill in addition or substraction of the digits and any tnber of two orders, also in the combination of the multiplication &gt;les including the nines. I Addition and subtraction of numbers not exceeding five orders, ultiplication by multipliers not exceeding two orders. Division ■ 10 and multiples of 10 under KM); by numbers below 60 ending 1,2,3; by other numbers not exceeding 25. Origin* problems ' pupils. All problems to be concrete and common. Addition, btraction, multiplication and division of fractions having denotni - tors less than 12. Arithmetic. . . 30 minutes five days ■ week. Reading 30 minutes five days a week. ».nguag». elling lit in *r M) minutes five days a week. JO minutes five days a week. 25 minutes five days a week graphy. . M) minutes five (lays a week. Hygiene History 30 minute* two days a week 30 minutes two days a week Civics 30 minutes one day a week. ARITHMETIC </seg>
            <seg id="p024">254 KKADIM. LBIaisdeU's Fourth Header. lieGuffey'a Fourth Reader. Bald - 's Robinson Crusoe. Around the World. Book 2. The end to l&gt;e pained is the ability to glean thought and the reading of much good and interesting literature. As much material as possible will l&gt;e supplied. Kach recitation should if possible include the following five exercises. If time fails for all numl&gt;ers four and five can Ix'st l&gt;e neglected. A conversation with the pupils in order to make sure that pupils have read the lesson intelligently. \ preparation of the next lesson to make sure that the pupils have in their minds the meanings of new words, words to l&gt;e marked, sounded, and explained. A testing in order to find out whether the lesson htt pared as directed. 4. A drill in oral reading. exercise in articulation. Definite detailed assignment &gt;uld be made of each lesson. This assignment should consist questions, to \te answered or of directions as to what to do. i.am,|- \&lt;;k -•■rvatioii followed by oral or written composition. Picture study. Reproduction of stories and biography. Dicta - tion lessons, in which previously studied- sentences are written from dictation.- Composition weekly in which corrections are made by the Correction Manual. Work from part* I and II of "Steps in Knghsh. " Special attention to letter writing. SPELLING Kight words daily from reading lesson. Words to U 1 placed on the blackboard, marked diacritic-ally, syllabified, sounded by upils. the meaning of each word explained and the word - in sentences. Pupils to keep word lists for review every two weeks. :itical marks to l&gt;e taught and the pupils trained to pronounce new words when marked. Study and recitation not to exceed 25 minutes daily. WRITING t legibility the prime essential. 20 minutes daily. 5 general '. 15 individual work. Attention to position of body. The cher to eii eful writing and correct position in all written </seg>
            <seg id="p025">255 ready for inspection. No pages are to be torn out of the books. Houdebush System Bonk 1. A study of the peoples of the earth, where each live, how to £&lt;&gt; there, how long it would take, what places would be passed, what kind of a country the people have, its size, surface, drainage. plants, natural resources, channels of communication, how ruled, what great cities, what appearance, customs, houses, occupation, language, what products we get from there. I This study should be made as much as possible from maps, pictures, etc. The peoples of the following places should • studied as type peoples: Nebraska, Illinois. Massachusetts, iloradn, Louisiana. California. Canada. Mexico. Brazil, England, aiice, Italy, Spain. Turkey. Norway and Sweden. Germany, olland. Austria, Cape Colony, Egypt, China. Japan. India, the lilippines. HIVrnKY Kggleston's Elementary United States History. The book to be in the hands of the teacher, and the subjects taught to the pupils. Heading the hook to the pupils is not enough, the pupils must be taught, the houk is for the purpose of outlining the course ami fur - nishing material. HVIIIK N E t Lessons and talks by the teacher on how to keep well. The lowing subjects should l&gt;e included. Jewett's "Good Health" the hands of ttie teacher: t Breathing. Pure air. Impurities. Tobacco. Drafts. Yenti - ion. Cleanliness and microbes. Dust. Need of sleep. Habits sleep. Dangers to eyesight. Dangers to hearing. Health of ■ hair, the skin, the nose, the lungs, the teeth, the finger nails. ting. Alcohol. CIVICS Lessons and talks by the teacher, followed by questioning the pupils, or by written lessons. Clark's "Government " in the hands of the teacher. The following subjects are to l&gt;e included: what government is: who compose the government; what things the government does; as keeping order, making laws., protection indi - vidual rights, public sehoi caring for the desti- &lt;;e&lt;x;h u'tn </seg>
            <seg id="p026">256 f I tute. the postoffiee. foreign relations, taxes, war. etc; relation &lt;&gt;: te and federal government ; how a criminal is caught am punished; bow laws arc made; how officers art 1 elected; what t he different political parties stand for. Drills in rapid addition and multiplication of small numbers, uracy being the prime requisite. t Drills in written addition and subtraction with numbers up to orders. Multiplication and division with numbers up to three ers. t Common fractions, reduction and the operations. The aim tuld t&gt;e accuracy in the solution of many problems involving all numb. Decimal fractions of three decimal periods. Decimal equiva - lents of simpler common fractioi Denominate nuinl)ers. an dry, liquid, long, square, cubic, time, avoirdupois weight. I". S. none READING (Harpers Fourth Reader. Brook's Hook Four, Pratt s Story the Karlv Colonies. Carpenter's Geography Readers. The end to l&gt;e gained is the ability to glean thought and the reading of much good and interesting literature. As much easy If OR ALB ■&lt;■ General Com- INTERMEDIATE school Arithmetic . .. :\() minutes five days ■ week. lia| 90 minutes five days a week. Language. M) minutes five days a week. ing -'&lt;• minutes five days a week. Writing 25 minutes five days a week. graphy... M) minutes five days a week. Hygiene 30 minutes two days a week. r\ M) minutes two days a week. Civics M) minutes one day a week. AKITHMKTK Reading and writing of numl&gt;ers to btUiotU, Roman numeral? M KK). </seg>
            <seg id="p027">257 material as possible will be supplied. Kach recitation should it possible include five exercises. If time fails for all numbers four and five can best be slighted. tl. A conversation with the pupils to make sure that they havt a&lt;l the lesson intelligently. 2. A preparation &lt;if the next lesson to make sure that th( pupils have in their mind." the meaning of new. wortls. New worth be marked, sounded, and explained. \ testing in order to find out whether the lesson has been prepared as directed. »4. A drill in oral reading. ."&gt;. An exercise in articulati n. Definite detailed assignment This assignment should consist should be made of each lesson, of questions to be answeretl or of lirections as to what t&lt; \\i t u. i- Almost entirely compositions, written compositions once a week, written, revised and corrected by the Correction Manual. Grammar wherever necessary to fix a usage in language; as the subject and predicate in teaching the agree men 1 of subject and predicate. Dictation lessons in which previously studied sentences are written from dictation. Work from part? '_' and :•&gt; from "Steps in Kngli h." Hook 1 PKLLl \ Kight words daily from reading lesson. Word* to be placed on the blackboard, marked diacritic-ally, syllabified, rounded by the pupils, the meaning of each word explained, and the word- used in sentences. Pupils to keep word lists for review every two weeks. Diacritical marks to be taught and the pupil." trained to pronounce onotllice new woids when marked Studv and recitation not to exceed 2o minute- dailv w II l\(. Legibility the prime essential. i'&lt;&gt; minutes daily, exercise, 15 individual work. Attention to position of body. The teacher to enforce careful writing and correct position in all written work. All written work to be put in the permanent book.- and kept ready for inspection. No pages are to be torn out of the books. Roudebush Svstem. Hook 2. Special attention to letter writin </seg>
            <seg id="p028">258 GEOGRAPHY ' ndy of the peoples of the earth, where each live, how to go . how long it would take, what placet would be passed, what kind of a country the people have, its size, surface, drainage, plant.-, natural resources, channels of communication, how ruled, what great cities, what appearance, customs, houses, occupation, language products we get from there. This study should l&gt;e made as much as possible from maps. glol&gt;es. pictures, etc. I The text. Redway's Natural Klementary Geography, should used for review and drill after the lessons are taught. The iple of the following places should Ik- studied: Northern Section the V. B., Northeastern Section. Southern Section. Plateau Sec - n. Pacific Section. Canada. Mexico. Central America. West Indies, azil. Argentina. Chile. British Isles. German Empire, Holland, rway ami Sweden. Austria-Hungary. Switzerland. Fiance. Rel - iii. Spain, Portugal. Italy. Greece, Russia. China. Japan, India. ibia, Persia. Indo-China. Northern Africa. Egypt, Central Africa, jthern Africa. Australia. Hawaii, the Philippines. HYGIENE I "iis and talks by the teacher on hygiene and elementary ysiology. The following subjects should be included. " Krohn's aded lessons in Hygiene" in the hands of the teacher: Foods. ilthful and unhealthful. Drink. Temperance. The skin and the The bones. The muscles. The blood. Breathing and the The nerves and the brain. The eyes and their care. The •e of the ear. The teeth. Disease germs and common Hm ■st aid to the injured. nisroin kKgglestons Klementarv United States History. The most ntion given to recent history. The history is to be taiiyht by teacher, by means of maps, charts, outlines, pictures and con - ations, the books to l&gt;e used for review ami drill. CIVICS Lessons and talks by the teacher, followed by questioning the pupils, or by written lessons. Clark's "Government" in the hands of the teacher. The following subjects are to lie included: what nment is; who compose the government; what things the government does, as keeping order, making laws, protecting in- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">259 dividual rights, public schools, roads and - aring for the titute. the postoHice. foreign relations, taxes, war. etc; relation of local, state, and federal government; how a criminal is caught and punished; how laws are made; how officers are elected; what the different political parties stand for. MOK M.S (See General Course) GRAMMAR SCHOOL Arithmetic... 'M) minutes five davs a week Reading 1.") minutes five days a week I Drills in rapid addition and multiplication of small numbers, uracy l&gt;eing the prime requisite. t Drills in written additions, subtraction, multiplication and ision. Accuracy to l&gt;e the prime essential. t Drill in the common measures; dry liquid, long. I'. S. in. \ weight, common fractions, addition, subtraction, multiplica - . division. Decimal fractions within the limits of four orders, imal equivalents of simpler common fractions. i Simple percentage and interest taught as a part of decimals. blems to bo confined to finding percentage or interest. Lin all the work there should be many short problems rather a few long ones. Problems should Ik- concrete and in familiar u e adi N g KSwinton's Fifth Readers. Carpenter's Geography Reader*, Master's I'. S. History. I or with Geography, History or Physiology, inguage. .. .90 minutes five days a week. ielling JO minutes five days ■ week, ritinp _'.') minutes five days ■ week. graphy.. M) minutes five days a week. Hygiene .30 minutes five days ■ week. History M) minutes four days a week. Civics ,30 minutes one day a week. AUITHMKTK Reading and writing of numhera to billions. Roman numeral: to KM). </seg>
            <seg id="p030">260 i in- end to *• gaine&lt; u le a &gt; \ 10 giean lougni ana tne reading of mucli good ;tn&lt;l interesting literature. As much rial as possible will l&gt;e supplied. Kach recitation should if : Me include the following five exercises. If time fails for all. numbers four and five can l&gt;est l&gt;e slighted. 1. A conversation with the pupils in order to make sure that • upils have read the lesson intelligently. 1\ preparation of the next lesson to make sure that the pupils ve in their minds the meaning of new words. New words to lx - irked, sounded and explained. 3. A test in order to find out whether the lesson has been pit a&gt; directed. 4. A drill in oral reading. kr&gt;. An exercise in articulation. Definite detailed assignment uld Ik- made of each lesson. This assignment should consist of stions to Ik 1 answered or of directions as to what to do. I. \\c, I \(.K Almost entirely compositions, written compositions once a written, revised and corrected by the Correction Manual. (irammar wherever necessary to fix a usage in language, as the sub - ind predicate. Dictation lessons in which previously studied sentences are written from dictation. Special attention to letter writing. Work from Hitchcock's English Composition. SI'KI.LIN(. EKight word* daily from first list in Roll of Honor Speller. Words i*&gt; placed on the blackboard, marked (Uncritically, syllabified, tided by the pupils, meaning of each word explained, and the WK1TIM. legibility the prime essential. 20 minutes daily. 5 general exer - 1.") individual work. Attention to position of body. The teacher to enforce careful writing and correct position in all written work. All written work to lx&gt; put in the permanent books ami kept ready for inspection. No pages are to l&gt;e torn out of the books. Houdebush System, Hook 2. (iEOURAPm bA study of the peoples of the earth, where each live, how to go I, how long it would take, what places would l&gt;e passed, what </seg>
            <seg id="p031">261 kind of a country the people have, its size, surface, drainage, plants, natural resources, channels of communication, how ruled, what great cities, what appearance, customs, houses, occupation, lan - guage, what products we get from there. This study should be made as much :i&gt; possible from map.-, globes, pictures, etc. The text "Natural Advanced Geography" should he used for review and drill after the lessons are taught. The people of the following places should he studied : Northern Section of t he Tinted States. Northeastern Section. Southern Section. Plateau Section. Pacific Section. Canada. Mexico. Central America. West Indies. Brazil. Argentina. Chile. British Isles. German Empire, Holland. Norway and Sweden, Austria-Hungary. Switzerland. Fiance. Bel - gium. Spain. Portugal, Italy. Greece, Russia. China. .Japan. India. Arabia. Persia. Indo-China. Northern Africa. Egypt, Central Africa. Southern Africa, Australia. Hawaii, the Philippines. The &lt; ieog - raphy may be used as a reading text. HISTOHT United States History, Me Master's. The most attention given tor ecent history. The history is to be tnu&lt;/ht by the teacher, by means of maps, charts, outlines, pictures, and conversations, the books to be used for review and drill. The history may be used as a reading text. II V(.IKNK t Lessons and talks by the teacher on hygiene and elementary ivsiology. The following subjects should be included. " Krofan's Graded Lessons in Hygiene" in the hands of the teacher: Foods, healthful and unhealthful. Drink. Temperance. The skin and the kidneys. The bones. The muscles. The blood. Breathing and the lungs. The nerves and the brain. The eyes and their care. The care of the ear. The teeth. Disease germs and common diseases. First aid to the injured. ri vi&lt; Lessons and talks by the teacher, followed by questioning the pupils, or by written lessons. Clark's "Government" in the hands of the teacher. The following subjects are to !&gt;e included: what government is; who compose the government: what things the government does, as keeping order, making laws, protecting indi - vidual rights, public schools, roads and streets, caring for the desti- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">262 Ee. the post office, foreign relations, taxes, war etc.; relation of nil federal government; bow a criminal is caught and llthed; how laws are made; how officers are elected; what the r erent parties stand for. Everything to lie put in the shape of business arithmetic I Drills in rapid addition and multiplication. Making of hills from one to eight items. These hills to include problem! in coin - &gt;n and decimal fractions and in common measurements. t Percentage and interest, confining the work principally to ing percentage and interest: insurance, taxes, commission, part of jiercentage. Making and balancing simple accounts. Application of square and cubic measures to the measuring of lumber, land, tiinlier. wood, grain in the bin. water in the tank. etc. irement of geometrical forms including triangles, circles, rect - angles, trapezoid. prism, cylinder, pyramid, and cone. HKADlMi Curry's Literary Headings, or Barnes' General History. The end to be gained is the ability to glean thought and the reading of much good and interesting literature. As much easy material as possible will lie supplied. Bach recitation should if possible include the following five exercises. If time fails for all numliers four and five can l&gt;est l&gt;e slighted. MUKA LH 'I'licial ( nui hk;h school TIMK TAH1.K Arithmetic f»0 minutes five days a week. Language 30 minutes five days a week. Spelling 20 minutes five days a week. Writing 28 minutes five days a week. Musine-- 90 minutes five days a week. General History... .30 minutes five days a week. Algebra A Geometry. 00 minutes five days a week. Reading 15 minutes five days a week. or in cornier- tion with History. ARITHMETIC </seg>
            <seg id="p033">263 1. A conversation with the pupils in order to make sure that the pupils have read t he lesson intelligently. 2. A preparation of the next lesson to make sure that the pupils have in their minds the meanings of the new words. New words to he marked sounded and explained. .'{. A testing in order to find out whether the lesson has been prepared as directed. 4. A drill in oral reading. ."&gt;. An exercise in articulation. Definite detailed assignment should be made of each lesson. This assignment should consist of ANiil a«;k Almost entirely compositions, written composition once a week, written, revised, and corrected by the Correction Manual. Grammar wherever necessary to fix a usage in language, as the subject and predicate in teaching the agreement of subject and predicate. Dictation lessons in which previously studied sentences are written from dictation. Special attention to letter writii Work from Hitchcock's Knglish Composition. WWTIM Legibility the prime essential. 20 minutes daily. "&gt; general exercise. 15 individual work. Attention to position of body. The teacher to enforce careful writing and correct position in all written work. All written work to be put in the permanent books and kept ready for inspection. No pages are to Ik&gt; torn out of the books. Houdebush System, Hook 3. pei.lixi; t Eight words daily from second list in Roll of Honor Speller, ords to Ik&gt; placed on the blackboard marked (Uncritically, syllabi - fied, sounded by the pupils, meaning of each word explained, and the words used in sentences. HISTORY McMaster's United States History or Barnes' General History. The most attention given to recent history. The history is to l&gt;e taught by the teacher, by means of maps, charts, outlines, pictures, and conversations, the books to he used for review and drill. questions t&lt;&gt; l&gt;e answered or of direction u to what to do. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">264 BUSINESS METHOD: Teller and Brown's ■First Book in Business Methods. liver's First Year Mathematics. Mill! Al.i- Sec ( ieneral ( oiiis&lt; MOliAl.S GENERAL ( or l(&gt;h The training &lt;&gt;f buys in murals is more a problem of atmotsphen example ami ideals than of course of study. llveiy action in the school should l&gt;e performed with the ac - companying intent of moral improvement. It is particularly im - portant for officers and employes to he clean in conduct and quiet and considerate in speech and manner even when administering reprimand or punishment. The following course of instruction in Is. adapted from the Illinois Course of Study for the Common School is to 1h j t might in each school. , I Cleanliness and Neatneet 1. Nature. neret&lt;sity anil udvantagi 2. They apply to body, hands, face. hail', nails, etc. 'A. T» thing, sh&lt; ■ 4. To book desks, floors, etc. ."&gt;. T&lt; •rything used or done. t Politeness 1. What it is. 2. The good ii does. •&gt;. It- relation home life. 4. Spurious politenc . ."&gt;. Helps in securing polite - r ti. Politeness at school. 7. At home. V At the table. '.I. To ■st: and visitors. 1(1. On the street. 11. In company. I Gentleness 1. An evidence of good birth or training. 2. Ap - ived by fiood people. 3. Commendable in speech and manner. Rude and boisterous conduct the opposite of it. ' ."&gt;. Patience re - ired when misjudged. (;. Docility, when instructed. IKindne-r to Others 1. What it really i-. 1. It significance character, '.i. Kindin ,ita&lt;rious. !. It helps intellectual velopnieni . 5. We should !*■ kind to all persons: a. To parents: To brothers and si To other members of the family; d. To • aged, infirm, unfortunate, to the helpless and needy. I The forms in which kindnes appears are: 1. Sympathy. 1. ference and consideration. 3. Helpfulness. -1. Charity. 5. In tdemning cruelty and injustice. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">265 Kindness t&lt;« Animals I. This, too, spring from sympathy. _'. ( )nlv fiendish persons delight in causing suffering to any creature, and cruelty to any animal is wrong. 3. We should he kind to the inimals which servo us. I. To those that do not harm us. Cruelty if killinjr birds. .V Cruelty should he avoided in the kiflinj tnimals that do us harm. (i. In kilii ti &lt;r animals for food. Love 1. A benevolent feeling. '2. It i.- the chief motive ii life, leading to unselfish service. .'!. It ennobles character "(Jod love." !. We should cherish love for parents. ."&gt;. For brothei tnd sisters, (i. For other member- of the family , ami friends. « For teachers, and all lienefactors. s. For one'.- neighbor Thou .-halt love thv neighbor as thyself." 9. For (iod. rruthfulnesf 1. It is the : faith which make- the wort fthe world possible. _'. Children naturally truthful and confiding. Lying always wicked. !. All should he truthful both in words and action- 'Without truth there can be no other virtue." ."&gt; Keeping one'.- word promise* to do wrong, ti. Distinction l&gt;&lt; teen a lie and an untruth. 7. Telling what one doe not know to true. H. Prevarication ami exaggeration. 9. The giving of a wrong impression, a form of falsehood. II). Telling falsehoods foi tun. Fidelity in Duty 1. Idea of obligation, intuitive. 2. Con- science to he obeyed. :■&gt;. How conscience is quickened. 4. We should faithfully perform our duty to parents, in assistance, com- fort, etc. ."). To brothers and sisters older to assist younger, et( fTo the poor and unfortunate Dutv to Cod. 7. To the wronged and oppressed Obedience 1. Obedience i submission to proper authority. tit is required of all. •'&gt;. Progress depends on it. 4. Real, not »iiied obedience, required. •"&gt;. It should be: a. prompt; b. cheer - ; c. implicit: d. faithful, ti. Obedience to parents. 7. To tchors and others in authority. S. To law. 9. To conscience. . To Cod. Nobility 1. Chief element in it is goodness. 2. It requires manliness. 3. Magnanimity and &lt;renerosity. 1. Self denial and self sacrifice for others. 5. Bravery in helping or saving other Confession of injury done another. Respect and Reverence 1. These imply proper estimate and treatment of others. 2. Lack of these, "a sure sign of smallii' '■&gt;. We should show proper respect and reverence for parents. 4. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">266 hers. i. For the aged. 6. For those who have done di tinquished service . 7. For those in civil authority. Gratitude and Thankfulness 1. What these are. 2.jThey show a good disposition. 3. We should cultivate these virtues. tlue to parents. 4. To all l&gt;enefactors. 5. To God, the giver of all good. • i t Forgiveness- ■ 1. All need forgiveness. 2. It is Godlike to for - e. 3. We should l&gt;e ready to forgive those who confess their It. 4. Those who have wronged us. ."&gt;. Our enemies. 6. (len - hould govern our dealings with the faults of others. Confession — 1. This means an honest acknowledgment of mistake or of wrong done another. 2. This confession is manly and noble, 3. Denial of faults, ignoble — "The denial of a fault doubles it." 4. Frankness and candor. Honesty — 1. Honesty accords justice to all. 2. A double standard of honesty, immoral. 3. Honesty is more important than wealth. 4. The right to property must be learned. 5. The toad nple. 6. Honesty required in keeping ones word. 7. liool and out of school. S. In little things. U. Cheating, ig - noble and base. 10. "Honesty is the l&gt;est policy." 11. Honesty is • (Honor 1. Honor shows a fine sense of justice. 2. Popular itimeiit of honor may l&gt;e wrong. 3. One should endeavor to if. i. e.. to l&gt;e worthy of honor. 4. To honor one's family. To honor one's friends. 6. To honor one's home. 7. To honor iuntrv. S. To honor God. Courage — 1. A chief virtue of character. 2. Moral coinage ined by health and strength. 3. Discouragement, harmful. •wardice. disgraceful. 5. True courage daring to do right and to defend the right. 6. False daring to do or to defend the wrong. 7. In l&gt;earing unjust censure or unpopularity. 8. In dan - ■i misfortune. 9. Heroism. Humility— 1. A virtue of religion. 2. An evidence of great - ness. 3. A feigned humility is pride. 4. True great ne..- not blind to one's own faults. 5. Modesty becoming to the vouiil Avoidance of pride and vanity. 7. Self-conceit, a sign of self i. True humility, not servility or time serving. tSelf Respect -1. It is a good opinion of worthy qualities in '■ self based on conscious moral worth. 2. It requires that be worthy. :•(. It is not self conceit, not inconsistent witli </seg>
            <seg id="p037">267 rmility. 4. Nut self-admiration. 5. It results in personal dignity. Distinction l&gt;etween self-love and selfishness. 7. "lie not wise in vour own conceit. I Self-Control 1. Needed for growth of character. 2. Of more lue than wealth, power, fame or pleasure. 1. It is a duty one es to self. 4. Control of temper. 5. Anger, when right. 6. oidanoe of hasty words "Think twice before you speak." 7. If restraint when tempted. 8. Self restraint under provocation Bear and forebear." 9. Kule your own spirit. Prudence 1. The moral man wishes to Ik- right: the prudent man to he safe. 2. Prudence not always wisdom. 3. A degree of prudence required in speech and action. 4. When one may l*» misunderstood. "). In respect for the opinions of others. fi. 'Judge not that ye l&gt;e not judged." I Good Name 1. Its great value. 2. How it can be obtained, (laining a good name when young. 4. Keeping a good name. Keeping good company. 6. Reputation and character. Good Manners (-In youth) — 1. Needed in association with others. 2. Promote comfort of others and advantage of sell They become a habit. 4. At home. 5. In school. 6. In company. 7. When a visitor, or a guest. S. In public assemblies. &lt;». Saluta - tion on the street. 10. Politeness to strangers. 11. Trifling in serious matters to l&gt;e avoided. Health 1. It is a condition of wholeness, a state of soundness or freedom from defect or disease. 2. Ill health hinders usefulness and happiness. 3. Duty to preserve health. 4. Habits that impair health, foolish as well as sinful. 5. The sowing of "wild oatt Ki'hat a man sows, that shall he also reap." 6. The body never gets or forgives its abuse. Temperance 1. Moderation in use of things helpful and avoid - ance of things harmful. 2. Moderation in the indulgence of appe - tite in things not harmful, -i. Total abstinence from that which is injurious. 4. Dangers in the use of alcoholic liquors. 5. Courage to resist social temptations to indulgence. 6. Injurious effects of tobaei n growing boys. 7. Cigarette smoking by boys, a serious I Evil Habits 1. Habits good and bad. 2. More easily formed n broken. 3. How to break a bad habit. 4. Habits that injure lth. 5. That destroy reputation. 6. That dishonor one </seg>
            <seg id="p038">268 ami family. 7. That waste tnoa* l'liat take away self eoo - troL It. That incur needless risks, as gambling. 10. That are offensive to others, etc. Hail Language 1. Language is vocal expression of idr thought. 2. It denotes the man. 3. Significance of borrowed language. -4. Profanity, foolish and wicked. ."&gt;. Obscenity, base and offensive. f&gt;. Defiling hook: or other things with obscene words and eharai offense. 7. The use of slatijr. vulgar and impolite. Evil Speaking 1. It is use of words either good or Wad without good pui ace of evil speaking, bad intention. :{. Law and public sentiment defective on evil speaking. !. Slander a -«&gt;rious offense. ."&gt;. Tale bearing to injure another, (i. Repeating evil which one tuu heard without knowing that it i.- true. 7. Thou ■bah not bear fals&lt;&gt; witnes- against thy neighbor." Industry 1. Great activity, not ahvays industry. 2. Industry relates to work rather than play. '-i. It works wonders. 4. Indo - shows value of it. ."&gt;. Work, not a hardship. &lt;i. Labor, a duty and a privilege. 7. Right use of time. K. Manual labor bonorabV i lf-«uppon give- manly independence. 10. Avoid - of unnecessary debt. II. When lagging i- right. 12. \u opportunity to earn a living by labor, due every one. 11. Both extravagance and parsimony wrong (iioiny is temperance in expenditure. -i. Youth need encourage - nt to !. Economy becomes a habit. "&gt;. Saving in early mean- competency and comfort in old age. ti. Duty to save a •t of one- earning. "Lay up -omething for a rainy day." 7. travagance wrong A pendthrift in youth, a poor man in 8. The hoarding of money needed for comfort or culture charity, wrong. 9. Charity "No man liveth unto himself." Patriotism 1. Always regarded as a virtue. _'. Need of pa - triotism in a republic. :*. Love of country should be taught in the • \r . A. How to develop it. ."&gt;. Reverence for our country's tor its ruler:. 7. Its defence when necessary. 8 rd for its honor and good name. Civil Dutiet 1. They are a division of social duties. 2. Gov - ary. :{. It requires law. -1. The good citizen obeys thel; to have good laws. ti. He aids the enforcement of law. 7. Fidelity in office and bribery. 8. Honor in takit jurj 9. Duty involved in the ballot, and buying and sellin, Id. Dignity and honor of citizen-hip, etc. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>