<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ELEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA, BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1910.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">ELEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home AT MILFORD. NEBRASKA BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30. 1910. The CUain Printing Co. Univenity Place, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p002">236 U\.\D COMMISSIONERS REPORT BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS Hon. Ashton ( '. Shallenberger ■ ernor Hon. Edward R Cowles Land Commisnonei Hun. Lawaon &lt;!. Brian. State Treasurer linn. George ( '. -lunkin Secretary of IIi'ii. William T. Thompson Attorney General ADVISORY BOARD BJ. P. ('. .McKesson. President ('alien Thompson, Secretary. Clara &lt; laracadden Lincoln York Mrs. Dr. Towne .Mrs. J)r. Wilcox £SI OFFICERS OF THE INSTITUTION BE. Ward Superintendeiil Phynician Sude R Wanl Matron EMPLOYES Kvelyn .Meyer Nora lien/. Enuna .Maurer . Qleisberg Secretary and Teacher Sewing Teacher s. Martin </seg>
            <seg id="p003">1*0 His Excellency. Governor Ashton C. Shallenberger, and the Honorable Board of Pablie Landfl and Buildings, Lin- Nebraska ■ Gentlemen: — I have the honor to submit for your eonnd tin- eleventh biennial report of the Nebraska Indwl .-. for ''iris. ■Twenty-one yean ago last May, the state of Nebraahi loors of this institution to her unfortunate girls, and during ■ time seven hundred ninety-three homeless, penitent girls sought the protection and care of the Home. f'or the benefit of those who may read this report and who ) understand the purpose of this institution, we feel that rd of explanation may not be amiss at this time. Y e think it is a Home for fallen girll and women, but this mistaken idea, as the Home is maintained in the int« Iie unfortunate girl. Those who are unfortunate in birth, or se parents do not realize the hundreds of pitfalls there are in world for young girls. 11 f mothers would take their little girls and give them the entary training in life's lesson, before they have the op- I unity of learning it from a perverted source, she would tieally assure herself that her daughter would be above the itations that sends so many bright, young girls to this II 1 fathers should take their young boys and explain to I purpose of life, and the souree of its existence, and the edness of all human anatomy; the proper respect due his rs and all members of the gentl and above all, make understand that vice is as vicious in man as in woman, and social sin as intolerable in the one sex as in the other. The ■ would have no farther need for an institution of this kind. the world is not ideal, and so long -s children cannot, or do have proper home training there will be these unfortunate i who must be eared for. The greatest su&lt; ss with these girls is attained by giving them the best of eare. making their lives pleasant, forgetful of the past, by showing them that although they have made a serious mistake, vet all in life is not lost, and that they may yet make </seg>
            <seg id="p004">238 I noble women. Their salvation is not in penance, suffering torture ; through constant though of their error, but rather ning their mistake and all thought of it, they grow, only as become oblivious of themselves, their weakness and frailti&gt; •«;. blossom out into self-forgetfulness and selfeffaeement. The •r this may be accomplished the better it is for them. If a man makes a mistake, society again takes him in. No matter how great the crime, even murder itself; if he can eseape the clutches of the law he is taken back at practically liis old value. But the unfortunate girl who has only those elements that were born in her. augmented by such characteristics as the environment into which she was cast and over the makiir. whieh she had no control, is turned loose to go on down to the very bottom of sin and degradation. No encouragement is given her; only a rebuff awaits her at each house she may approach. Society as such, shuns her, even the door of her own home is closed against her. The temptations that are now thrown before young girls are appalling. Society does not stop to consider her age, knowledge and ability to withstand those temptations Society offers no apology and accepts none. The thirteen year old girl, without a mother to guide her, is held equally re - sponsible with the woman of thirty. I The majority of girls who come to this Home, are between age of twelve and eighteen years. Some of course are older. ?w as old as thirty and thirty-five, but these are poor, feeble rled creatures, who are in no wise responsible for their ble and who should have been placed where they could have 1 protected and cared for. as they never have been and n be, responsible for what they do. iThe Home not only cares -for the girl, who has made this 1 mistake, but for any girl, who is not or who cannot have proper home training and who is in danger of being led into is of sin and shame, may come to this Home and receive the and protection of the Home until she is able to go out into world and make for herself, a good honest living. Krhe methods and plans of the work are all formulated in nterest of protecting and aiding the one needing it. Advice encouragement are given freely. Upon entering the Home 1 must sign an application blank, which gives a little history </seg>
            <seg id="p005">239 of her life, and whereby she agrees to remain in the Home one to abide by the rules of the Home, and to do whatever work may be assigned her. The work of the Home is divided into details of six weeks each. KITCHEN In this department there are two cook*, one who cooks meat Fruit Canned Apples, quarts 426 Ul 92 Tomatoes, quarts Total quarts ( 'rab Apples, quarts Bies and Quince, quarts kberries, quarts tries quarts 33 quarts and vegetable*; I pastry cook, who bakes the bread, pies and I, makes all deserta and prepare* hospital meals. A milk girl, ■ cares for the butter and milk and prepares the baby food. following is a tabulated statement of the work done in the kitchen aside from preparing the regular meals: M Wheat Bread 1 M Graham Bread Light Rolls 8,105 Cinnamon Rolls 1.331 Huns 2.012 Corn Bread, shirts 100 Ginger Bread, sheet* 107 Coffee Cakes 137 (irahan Gems Dumplings 311 Bakingpowder Biscuits ."&gt;,993 Doughnuts 618 tea 1,070 Tea Cakes 269 Roll Jellie Cake* 21 r and Loaf Cakes 468 1,119 Pudding* SM </seg>
            <seg id="p006">240 Preserves Ermelon. quarts ; Apple, quarts &gt;, quarts Apple and Quince, quarts h. quarts Crab Apple, quarts !l 328 Total quarts Pickles Sweet Ember, quarts t Apples quarts ;, quarts s 224 Green Tomato, quarts Total quarts Jellies Apple, quarts -cherries, quarts Krape, quart&gt;. s ti s §e and Quince.. ; &gt;nt. quarts Apple, quarts 11 151 Total quarts Jam leberriei quarts Current, quarts ti 14 Total quarts. Butter Ee, gallons tto, gallons h, gallons.. , gallons 2 (rah Apple, gallons. &lt; Total gallons.. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">241 Tliis work is divided into two details, one in the wash r (the other in the ironing room. The washing and ironii every day of the week, in the same manner it would be i in private homes, as the object in each detail is to t( girls to do the work as they will have to do it in pri es. On Monday, nursery and hospital washing is done. Tues - day, nursery and employe's washing. Wednesday, nui - girls' washing. Thursday, nursery, kitchen and table linen. Friday, nursery, bed linen and extra washing. Saturday nut- »\Ve have no regular teacher in this department, but a monitor ppointed, both in the ironing and wash room for six wi with the assistance of the matron look after the work that it is properly done. Average number of pieces laundered per week, 1,97:?. SEWING ROOM In this department we an' more fortunate, having tnt teacher who teaches the girls to do all kinds plan mending, as well as some fancy needle work, that by the time a girl is ready to leave the Home, she is if at all apt with thf needle, able to care for her own wardrobe. Number of pieces made and mended are as followea adult Aprons, with Meat Relish -up, gallons C'hillisauce. gallons Jersey Piekle, galloM (how Chow, gallons .Maniocs. gallons alilli, gallons Total gallons Mince Meat, quarts Cucumbers, in brine, gallons rkraut. gallons LAUNDRY </seg>
            <seg id="p008">242 Kte waists, adults, red waists, adults e skirts 52 Sateen skirts Gowns 108 Corset covers Sanitary belts. 113 32 Etary napkins hen aprons :s, pair : Hose supporters Dresses, infants. Skirts, infants Shirts, infants Gowns, infants.. Bands 6 I I Eing blankets iving blankets tins, nursery 762 I r s : Nursery quilts. Nursery sheets Nursery pillow cases 1 1 1 ispital gowns 12 Hospital bands Sunbonnets 6 10 Eng sheets holders i clothes.. is 58 62 72 ■ i clothes.. ; napkins dry bags 24 4 Bed pads, quilted Comforts, tied Curtains, pair Dresses scarfs. 24 : &amp; 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">243 trict school, classes ranging from third to fourth gradea to eighth ind tenth grade work. We often have eome to the lion foreign girl, who can neither read nor write. Special attention in the school work is given in such cases, thai they ma better able to go out into the world. At ."&gt;::{(*, girls" supper i ved. &lt; :.!() chapel exercise ; coll - excepi on Wednesday evening, ■se meetinga being eondu ted by the different teacher •h is Christian Endeavor, th of the girls. On Sunday w&lt; a have girls who have had and it is very gratifying to pel work. have our regular services. We lit little, if any. religious train- the interest they take in the tWhen a girl is ready to leav own to go to. or if her home ild be, she is provided with the Home, if she has no boa surroundings an- not what I a home in sonic good Christian family, where they will take an interest in her and look after her. She is also given a good wardi of clothes to last her until she &lt; &gt;be so that she will have plenty ■a earn more. As a rule, the girls make Home. Some marry and marry girls in the last four years hav good records after leaving the i tiiKcn no iiiii*sint' w Hili* in thf* Boys suits - pants, pair Boya waists §pers 12 ber nf garments mended 7 HOUSEWORK Each girl on this detail is given one Boor, which she must keep neat and elean. NURSERIES We have two Urge tmnerit* in which the babiea are for during the day. two or three girli being detailed in nurs.-ry to look after the babies, under the direct supervision of the Home nurse. Detail work beginning at seven o'clock in the morning, clos- ing at 2:1.") in the afternoon, when all j:irls go to school until five in the evening. The school work is very much like that of ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p010">244 Home ainl one upon leaving the Home went into ■ hospital in Chicago and completed her course there last spring. The other (MM studied and worked what sin- could in the hospital while in the Home and when she was ready to leave the Home a place was found for her witli a doctor, who furnished her with plenty of practical nursing, where she received from eighi to ii dollars per week. After working in this state for some - time, she went to one of the western states where she twenty and twenty-five dollars per week. Others have gone to their own homes and are doing well. Two have taken their babies with them, working as domestics, and are getting thirty dollars per month and babies cared for. A number of other - receiving from five to six dollars per week, giving splendid - faction. Some arc elerking and others are in school again. During the last two years fifteen babies have been placed in good homes, where they will be protected from the stigma which always follows an illegitimate child through life, and where they may be trained to be good Christian men and women. FARM There are thirty-seven acres of land in connection with the institution. Of this eleven acres are in pasture, four in alfalfa. three in timothy, eighi and one-half in garden, two in orchard, nine in lawn and yard. In addition to this we rented eight I tot corn. Our early garden and potatoes were almost a failure, on account of the dry weather. Farm ] Prod ducts Potatoes, bushels t Potatoes, liiisluls Onions, bushels B, liusht'ls 60 Turnips, bushels 555 Cabbage, heads i.500 Lettuce, bunches 1,040 Carrot*, bwbeb 20 Bean*, buskeli 80 Tomatoes, husllels * • !om, liushels S()iiasli. dozen </seg>
            <seg id="p011">245 We were not able to make all the repairs the p«*t two that we had hoped to. our repair fund being so small, bat by ■ fill tijmrinjr ;i"&lt;l by using some of the maintenance fund have able to sake a few of the ranch needed repairs. Ft was im - ble to get through another winter with the old boiler room, which stood just a few feet from the haek door, so this we had torn down and now have a nice new one. away from the main buildings. While it is not completed as it should he. yet we can •ret through the winter and hope we will he able to have more work done on it. out of the old appropriation. The engine was entirely worn out. this has been replaced by a new one. We have also a new deep well pump, which was badly needed. The little old wooden water tank has been replaced by a large steel tank of nearly three times the capacity of the old one. Some new hard maple lloors ha\c been laid, papering and painting have been done, twenty-four new radiators have been placed in the building! and a number of new pipes laid. REPAIRS NEEDED t\Ve have been unable to do anything with the se\\. ition for lack of funds and will have to again ask the i re for an appropriation for this, as it cannot go longer without ething being done. rhe outside walls of the two main buildings will also ha loked after, as they are in such conditions that the rain through anil in a number of rooms the inside walls ai d with mildew and the paper which has only been on a Pumpkins, dozen OZt'Il Cucumber*, bushels S, bushels . Apples, bushels Radishes, bushels K^rtrs. dozen- M ilk. gallons Hatter, pounds Hay, tons Alfalfa, tons REPAIRS </seg>
            <seg id="p012">246 1 years is ruined. The plastering in a number of rooms is in shape and will soon be falling off if not eared for. Other is need new ceilings and floors. B Storm windows should be made for each building. The lings are getting old and the windows loose so that on cold [y days it is almost impossible to keep the house comfortable. The cottage is also badly in need of repair. A great deal of papering and painting will have to be done. There will have to be some repairing around the barn and barn yard. STATISTICAL REPORT Population From December 1, 1908 to December 1 1909 Male Female Total tber inmates present at beginning of fiscal year 1 5 iber received during year _M Lber discharged and died during year '2'2 iber at end of year 14 36 2 59 4!) 71 4i ; Expenditures Current Expenses Salaries Maintenance O.VO'J 1 0 Repairs $14,964 83 Population From December 1. !!»()(» to December 1 1910. Male Female Total ■iber inmates present at begining of fiscal year _ I 4ti Number received during year 9 41 Number discharged and died during year 13 Number at end of year 10 Expenditures Current Expenses: Salaries Maintenance Repairs </seg>
            <seg id="p013">247 1 Average Per Capita Cost of Maintenance IK) 03 &gt;r semi-annual period June 1. 1 !H&lt; &gt; to Dee. 1. 1!UO Hit 12 I -,ci Average Per Capita Cost Repairs I semi-annual period Dee. 1. 1908 to .May 31, 1909 semi-annual period June 1. 1909 to Nov. :«). 1909 semi-annual period Dee. 1. 1!»d!l to May 31, 1910, semi-annu:il period June 1. 1910 to Dee. 1. 1!)1&lt;&gt; Cash Fund Cash on hand Dee. 1. 1908 t receipts from Dee. 1. 1908 to Dec. 1. 1910 expended from Dee. 1. 1908 to Dee. 1. 1910 ee on hand Dei-. 1. Illlo :UT Appropriation of 1907 Lapsed Employes wages Maintenan Repairs Appropriation 1909 Appropriated Expended 4.4(MI (Ml R semi-annual period Dec 1. 1908 to May 31, 1908 * 1"&gt;4 42 sem-annual period June 1. 1909 to Nov. 30, 1909 B1 U «'ini-anniial period Dec 1. 1909 to May 31, 1910 110 3,666 H4 Officers' Salaric Employes' wage Maintenance 4,640 00 3,700 87 17.IHMI 00 11,551 42 6.000 00 5,944 64 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">248 Estimated Appropriation for Coming Biennium Salary of Superintendent for two years Salary of .Matron for two yean Salary of Physician for two yean Employes' wages for two years 2,400 00 1.400 00 1.400 00 Maintenance for two yean Repairs for two yean 17,001 . ■ Total estiniaieil appropriation $34,28 In conclusion I wish to express my gratitude and apprecia - tion to the Governor, Board of Public Lands and Building*, Members of the Advisory Hoard. Co-workers and all friends who generously aided m in carrying on the work of the PHYSICIAN S REPORT December 13. 1!)M. To Hon. A. ( '. Shallenliersrer. Governor, and the Board of Public Lands and Buildinra of Nebraska Sirs: — I have the honor to report that the general health of the inmates of the Nebraska Industrial Home for (iirls at Mil - ford lias been exceptionally good during tin- past year. Only one death has occurred among the adult inmates. There have been no epidemics of any kind, the sanitary condition of the Home having been kept very good. This excellent showing is largely due to the competent and careful management of the Home by the superintendent. Miss Lena Ward, and the matron. 3ude Ward. It is my belief that the eoinpensat ion now paid the superin - tendent and matron is entirely inadequate, considering tli sponsibility of the positions and the hiyh degree of skill and experience required, and I would recommend that the legislature quesied to increase these salan Respectively submitted J. D. CASE. Physician. Very respectfully, LENA E. WARD. Superintenden </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>