<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FORTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1931-02-01">1931-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">FORTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA . ■ Presented to the Governor February 1, 1931 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska, approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor here - with to submit the Forty-fourth Annual Report of the Agri - cultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. W. W. Burr, February 1, 1931. Director. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, Executive Department Mr. W. W. Burr, Director Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station: Sir: I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Forty-fourth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. Charles W. Bryan, Lincoln, February 1, 1931. Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD ' • (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Frank J. Taylor, St. Paul, President Term expires January, 1933 Stanley D. Long, Cowles Terra expires January, 1933 Fred A. Marsh, Archer Term expires January, 1935 Marion A. Shaw, David City Term expires January, 1935 Earl Cline, Lincoln ■ Term expires January, 1937 Arthur C. Stokes, Omaha Term expires January, 1937 E. A. Burnett, D.Sc, Chancellor L. E. Gunderson, 1 Finance Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS W. W. Burr, B.Sc, Director W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF C. W. Ackerson, Ph.D., Assistant in Agricultural] Chemistry Arthur Anderson, 2 M.Sc, Assistant in Agronomy M. J. Blish, Ph.D., Agricultural Chemistry (Chairman) E. E. Brackett, B.Sc. in E.E., Agricultural Engineering (Chairman) E. M. BROUSE, B.Sc, Supt. Experimental Substation, Valentine W. W. Burr, B.Sc, Agronomy (Chairman) M. Ruth Clark, Ph.D., Associate in Home Economics H. P. DAVIS, M.Sc, Dairy Husbandry (Chairman) P. A. Downs, Ph.D., Associate in Dairy Husbandry H. C. Filley, A.M., Rural Economics (Chairman) R. W. Goss, Ph.D., Associate in Plant Pathology H. J. Gramlich, B.Sc, Animal Husbandry (Chairman) I. L. Hathaway, M.Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry Harold Hedges, A.M., Assistant in Rural Econoinics J. A. Holden, B.Sc, Supt. Experimental Substation, Mitchell NELSON E. Jodon, 3 B.Sc, Research Assistant in Agronomy, North Platte T. A. Kiesselbach, Ph.D., Agronomy E. B. LEWIS, B.Sc. in A.E., Assistant in Agricultural Engineering W. J. Loeffel, B.Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry W. E. Lyness, B.Sc in Agr., Assistant in Agronomy C. B. McGrath, D.V.M., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene R. F. MORGAN, M.Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry F. E. Mussehl, B.Sc, Poultry Husbandry (Chairman) J. F. Olney, D.V.M., M.S., Assistant in Animal Pathology G. L. Peltier, Ph.D., Plant Pathology (Chairman) J. O. Rankin, 2 A.M., Associate in Rural Economics 3. C. Russel, M.Sc, Associate in Agronomy Rudolph Sandstedt, M.Sc, Analyst Edna B. Snyder, M.Sc, Assistant in Home Economics W. P. Snyder, M.S., Supt. Experimental Substation, North Platte Coit A. Suneson, 3 'M.Sc, Research Assistant in 'Agronomy M. H. Swenk, A.M., Entomology (Chairman) H. M. Tysdal, 4 M.Sc, Assistant in Plant Pathology 1 By an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska, approved and in effect February 15, 1889, the State Treasurer became ez-offlcio custodian of the Experi - ment Station fund on and after July 1, 1899. • DetaUed°from Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases, United States Department of A " I DetaSed &gt; f^&gt;m h Offl t c O e n of D Fo ! r.Be Crops and Disease., United State. Department of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Fruit Breeding Experiments J 20 Orchard Culture — Union Fruit Farm 20 Vegetable Experimentation — Variety Trials and Cultural Tests.. 21 Fruit Stocks Investigations 1 21 Orchard Spraying for the Codling Moth .• 22 Home Economics: Kerosene Cooking Stoves 22 Cash Contribution of Women to Farm Income thru Dairy and Poultry Products 1 23 Washing Machine Study . 1 23 Insect Control: Investigation and Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds ; [ 23 Life History and Control of Potato Flea-Beetles in Western Ne - braska i 24 Brood Study of the Codling Moth in Southeastern Nebraska.....".... 24 The Distribution, Life History, and Control of Cutworms that Attack Corn in Nebraska 24 Livestock Feeding: Fattening Cattle J 25 Forage Crops for Hogs 1 25 Rations for Fattening Hogs.. J 26 Factors Affecting the Quality and Palatability of Meat 26 . Lamb Feeding 1 28 Milling and Baking: The Relation of Certain Chemical and Physical-Chemical Char - acteristics of Nebraska Wheat to Its Milling and Baking Quality '. 29 Preparation and Study of the Cereal Glutelinsl 30 Standardization of Methods in the Experimental Baking Pro - cedure J. 31 Nutrition : " Study. of the Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry 32 Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks 33 Plant Diseases: Spindle Tuber and Combinations of Spindle Tuber with Other Degeneration Diseases 33 Pathological and Physiological Aspects of Alfalfa Failures in Nebraska : . J 34 Scab and Fusarium Wilt of Potatoes in Relation to Infection from the Soil J 34 Fruit Disease Investigations... 35 Potatoes: Selections for Seed Purposes 35 Degeneracy in Seed Stocks 3C Poultry: Nutrition Studies of Growing Chicks 38 Turkey Production I 39 Rural Economics: Cost of Producing Farm Crops &#132;- 39 Economic Studies in Price, Volume of Production, and the Pur - chasing Power of Farm Products L 40 Market Costs , L 40 Farm Organization and Farm Costs L 41 Serum Production L 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">North Platte Substation \ Agronomy 4 * Beef Cattle ZZZZZZ. ' 42 Dairying 43 Hogs 44 Sheep ZZZZZZZZ. ' 44 Horticulture and Forestry."."""""!!!^"!""" \\ Scottsbluff Substation " .. Crop Rotations 44 Lamb Feeding 44 Dairying &lt; "ZZ ' ; 4 « Beef Calves 46 Hogs "■ 4 6 Poultry ZZZZZZZZ -' 46 Valentine Substation.. " 46 Beef Cattle 4 ' Dairy Cattle -■ 47 Poultry " ■ 4 ? Cereal Crops •— 47 Forage Crops ZZZ".Z~.Z[ ' 47 Meadow Investigations ZZ. """• ' If Changes in Staff. ' ".". 4 | Publications 48 Legislation -"ZZZZZZZZ '' 48 Additional Lands, Buildings, and Equipment *n Financial Statement... ' °: 51 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Forty-fourth Annual Report This report covers the investigations, expenditures, and publications of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1930. During the year there have been under investigation a total of seventy-four PnTTw 0^ 11 ?!, 11 WidG F . a ?£ e Of sul ?iects. For convenience in setting forth the report these projects are grouped as to subject matter. Of necessity the reports are brief. ■«J» Un E fir i; n ear covered bv this report eleven bulletins, five research bulletins, and two circulars were published by the f™ w&gt;, *" T ari ° US t ?^ m i c » 1 and Professional journals thirty - twa technical or semi-technical papers, submitted by various members of the staff, were printed. A list of the publications is shown in the latter part of this report on twf the l e&amp;T QUite sati A sfactor y Progress has been made npJ on! I C k vrog % m l . As P r °J ects h ave been completed onThoT hav^r n added&gt; the selecti °n of new projects being ?♦? £ S ° f th f most urgent need ' together with the ability of the Experiment Station to carry on the projects There is always more demand for information than the Experiment Station can supply The policy is to concentrate the investiga - tions on a few rather than many projects, and naturally the work has to be kept within the resources of the Station M^ffnT* 88 !?* demand "P° n th e Experiment Station for identification, diagnosis, and analysis of and general informa - tion concerning various kinds of plant and animal diseases is seriously interfering with the program of certain depart JS °S,h?B a " y f Ammal Pathology. This kind of werk does not contribute to the research program, nor is the Experiment ?™? f °^ anized or equipped to take caife of such requests, except at the expense of the research work Already the work along these lines is so heavy that thought|should be given to^ ward making some other arrangement for taking care of it INVESTIGATIONAL WORK The funds for carrying on the work of the Station are i*^ f^ b ° th I ed f ra l and state sources - No attempt is wwt ■ ?« h ? S ep^ rt to desi «" a te the actual projects upon S^£ d^ fi f nite S Unds W ? e ex P end e d - The financial report of the receipts and expenditures of the Experiment Station has e b nd n of P Srlport y ** B « Wt^ and is given at </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station agricultural engineering Nebraska Tractor Tests. — Work under this project is carried in accordance with the Nebraska Tractor Testing Law. During the past year eleven tests were completed and individual reports issued. Six of the tractors submitted were models of the new design, four being the general-purpose type adapted to row-crop cultivation. This seems to indicate that manufacturers expect a wide expansion of power farm - ing on diversified farms of limited size. The manufacturers as well as purchasers have shown great interest in these tests. Poultry House Ventilation and Construction. — The data obtained in these studies indicate that insulation had a bene - ficial effect on winter egg production ; that closing up a house all night during the winter season had no detrimental effect on winter egg production; and that the use of a small stove to lower humidity but not to raise. the temperature appreci - ably was of doubtful value. The use of steam heat increased egg production during December, January, and February. No correlation was found between humidity and winter egg production. The use of commercial ventilators, the use of an exhaust fan to change the air, and stirring the air by electric fan were not found beneficial. Combine Harvester Study. — This project is co-operative among several departments. Work during the past year was confined to observations on the use of windrow and pick-up equipment for the combine. These observations indicate the need for further development and improvement of this equip - ment to meet requirements of varying climatic conditions and smaller farms of eastern Nebraska. It is hoped that during the coming harvest season some draft studies will be included. A Study of Wind-driven Electric Plants for Farm Use. — It is planned to conclude observations and issue a bulletin during the coming year. Recent observations confirm the re - sults of previous studies that high investment cost, high rate of battery depreciation, and uncertainty of wind velocity and duration combine to make its unit cost high and also to limit output of current and its uses. The owner of this type of plant cannot apply the rule that increased use lowers the cost of current per unit, which usually holds on engine-driven plants and with electric service purchased from central sta - tions. . .. Pump Irrigation. — The serious shortage of rainfall in cen - tral Nebraska during the summer of 1929 greatly increased the interest of farmers in pump irrigation. It also made more apparent the need of more definite information along this line. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Forty-fourth Annual Report Previous work showed the need of an accurate means of measuring power requirements of different pumping plants. To meet this need a four-cylinder engine has been cradle - mounted and is now available as a dynamometer power unit. It is hoped that more experimental evidence can be pro - cured during the coming year and that the data already ob - tained can be analyzed and made available. Some results at North Platte with pump irrigation have been previously pub - lished as Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 227. Tractor Lug Efficiency Tests. — Due to the death of Mr. Wallace, the man in charge of the work under this project, it has been inactive during the past year. The project is being continued in the hope that it will be possible to carry it on. A Study of the Use of Electric Power on Nebraska Farms. Four phases of this project have been under study during the past year. . Adaptation of small electric motors to farm use. — Experi - mental use of a 3 H. P. motor for hay hoisting, for the con - struction and operation of the pit silo, and for feed grinding indicates that this size of motor can be utilized advantageously on many farms. Additional experimental work has been done with a 5 H. P. motor in feed cutting and grinding. Surpris - ingly satisfactory results were derived from the use of this motor on a silo filler. A circular on silo filling is being pre - pared for early publication. A 7Vfe"H. P. motor used for corn fodder grinding in co - operation with the Animal Husbandry Department has shown the power cost to be 32 cents per ton with electricity at 5 cents per kilowatt-hour. Grinding was thru a combination knife and burr mill, the fodder averaging about 35 per cent grain. Additional work on grinding and feed preparation is contemplated, probably in co-operation with the Animal Husbandry Department feeding experiments. Automatic water systems. — The results of observations and studies previously made under this subtopic have been assem - bled and presented for publication as Bulletin No. 245, en - titled "Water Supply and Sewage Disposal Systems for Ne - braska Farms." Study of small unit plants for farm use. — Bulletin No. 235, "Unit Electric Plants for Nebraska Farms," published late in the last fiscal year, has received wide distribution and very favorable comment. Additional data and observations are be - ing made on unit plants; Bulletin No. 236. entitled "Rural Electric Service Supplied from Central. Stations in Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station in 1927" was published during the present year. This phase of the project will remain active. let£ e SK?' "&amp;f at^ for farm use.— A bul - l^m enbtled The Mechanical Dairy Cooler on Nebraska Farms has been prepared and presented for publication, but ™Tv* 8l 7 e S *n dy On some of the installations is needed, and the work will be continued. The phase of the project S?« 7 &amp;S S StUd^ equipment loaned by com- STStaSSSSS* farmers has been closed and th ? data ANIMAL DISEASES r,w/-"^ ° f *!?■ Pat p-°9enidty as well as the Antigenic and Btologzc Properties of the Organisms Belonging to the Hem - orrhagic Septicemw Group.— -This project remained compar- S5SS y tff B Sfffl B d " ring the P ast y ear - principal reason nSSSn v dlffi . c M ]t y experienced in getting active virus of Sw^SSf" ? ngin&lt; - A^°i he l reason was that the demand of otiier projects required both the attention of the personnel and the use of all of the test stock. The project will be con tmued when there is opportunity for further work An Inquiry into the Part Played by the Avian Tubercle SSftfJT r S erc^°. s H° i r M ™™*s other t/^n sine -The work under this project has been completed during the vear S twAt^nn 3 °S ined P, ub ! ished as Research Bultetfa Vo, II of * h » station. The conclusions reached are as follows 1. The avian strain of Bacillus tuberculosis was determined to be a cause of tuberculous disease in cattle ueiern "nea ™w . Av J a . n , tub e r culous infection of bovine animals was found only m solitary lymphnode lesions in nearly ten per cent of the cases furnishing lesions of this type sns? j°£SK? °' avian infcctlon was iS th»'«v^ C l,r-'i? enCe . ob ? afned indicates that, infection due to of cm£usio " in the io 1 rd1.S e 8 e ba n 1 man Ot °™" t "'™ W " as a «»«Sto^- S^S'SiSeafth' 1113 ttae aM " med "S" </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Forty-fourth Annual Report ■ ■ . 7. On the other hand, the prevalence of avian tuberculosis on farms must be looked upon as a positive hazard to other livestock. This" project will be closed. An Inquiry into the Influence of Environment upon Poultry Morbidity. — The work on this project is being pursued with vigor, but owing to the nature of the technique necessarily employed, no statement can as yet be made regarding final results. It is quite apparent, however, that in some diseases the environmental factor is of predominant importance, while in others the direct-contact factor is the prevailing one. Laboratory Diagnosis and Examination of Specimens. — This project is continued to take care of the many specimens that come to the Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene for routine examination and diagnosis. During the year covered by this report 10,239 specimens of various kinds were received. The fact is that this kind of work has grown to such proportions that it seriously interferes with the re - search program of the department, and it is. hoped that some other means of handling it may be found. DAIRY HUSBANDRY A Study of the Principles of Ice Cream Making. — During the past year samples of both vanilla and strawberry ice cream were submitted by manufacturers and each was scored for flavor, body . and texture, bacterial count, and package and color. Fat-and-solids analyses were made on the vanilla ice cream. As a result of this work, there has been a decided improvement in the quality of vanilla ice cream produced thru - out the. state and it is hoped that additional work will bring about similar improvement in strawberry ice cream. Bacterial counts still indicate considerable variation, but a larger proportion of the samples have had low counts than in previous years. More complete pasteurization and better sanitary conditions undoubtedly would do much to- lower the bacterial count of the ice cream. Yeast and mold content of strawberry ice cream. — Studies were made of seventeen samples of strawberry ice cream with reference to the yeast and mold content (in the frozen pro - duct. This is of particular interest because in recent years there has been a large increase in the use of strawberries put up in a sugar syrup and then frozen and kept in a frozen con - dition until used. In the manufacturing plants it is fre - quently a custom to thaw out the strawberries too far ahead of their actual use. This allows for the development of yeasts </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station hPrr£°I dS - K The Studie ? so far that when straw- SnrtiHoi G^f en P 5° P -! r y packed and have bee " kept in good £?££?£. n? I 1 US6d ' 1* 13^ p0SS , ible to P roduce a strawberry £t a f m ° f - low yeast and mold content. The plate method for determining a yeast and mold count of strawberry ice cream can be used satisfactorily. There appearsTo be Httle *L ™ C i°, rrelat l°? b f tWeen the bacteria co ™t and the yeast and mold count in strawberry ice cream +J n th r, st "^ y . of the effect of s P eed of dasher and scraper on the quality of ice cream and sherbet, it was found : t&gt; , at the s P eed of the dasher (200 R. P M normal 1&lt;W R. P. M. low, 260 R. P..M. high) has no ap P reciab?e effect ur. on the rapidity of the freezing of ice cream, Spon the rap"d-" V *l incorporating a 100 per cent overrun, or upon the body and texture of the finished ice cream when it is made from fresh dairy products with a composition of 14 per cent fa? atine 61 " **' " P6f C6nt SUgar ' and 25 5S gf - r295R h p°M r^ fvfnv 0^^ a speed above ™™al n? 5 tL P ablt n Trm?n°ut R es P a n^^ SgBFSJSjZg*- ° Ve ™' and tende/trS^^ 200 lSf t°n P^ at i° n °i * he dasher at varying speeds (260 to 163 to idle) and m the same direction as the scraDer had practically no effect on the time requSed to f rS fee ovSn^T,? ? G time re ? uired t0 incorporate 100 per cen? tuTrfVe fee cre Sm aPPreCiable effeCt Up ° n the body and *S nf Ijn 1 " th n freezin Kof sherbets where an overrun in excess mSBm </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Forty-fourth Annual Report —The work under this project was continued by feeding milk from the different breeds to rats of uniform age and growth. The rats were reared on a vitamin A free ration composed of casein, 18 per cent, corn starch, 78 per cent, and salts, 4 per cent. One gram of dried yeast daily was fed as a source of vitamin B. The antirachitic factor was supplied by irradia - tion of the corn starch with an ultra-violet lamp. This ration was fed from weaning time until ophthalmia became incipient or there was a cessation of growth. Wjhen this point was reached the basal ration was supplemented by one, two, and three cubic centimeters of milk. Negative controls received only the vitamin A free diet and positive controls received the basal ration supplemented by one-tenth bubic centimeter of cod liver oil. The milk was taken from four typical cows of each differ - ent breed, the cows being as nearly uniform in every respect, including feed consumed, as possible. Under the conditions of these experiments the difference in the vitamin A content of milk from Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, ] and Guernsey cows was insignificant. Methods of Cooling Milk on the Farm and their Effect on Quality. — This project is co-operative between the depart - ments of Agricultural Engineering and Dairy Husbandry. It is designed to determine the effects of different methods and rates of cooling upon the quality of the milk. Milk for bacteria study is carried thru the gradient tem - peratures and the effect noted. Usual and improved methods are being studied under various temperatures, humidities, and types of dairy business. Charts and records showing temperature gradients of milk as it is cooled down by various methods are being obtained. Study of Growth in Dairy Cattle. — The taking of measure - ments and photographs of the animals in the dairy herd has been continued as in past years. During the past year an agreement has been entered into with [the jU. S. Dairy Division for careful ante-mortem and post-mortem measurements on animals that are to be discarded from the herd. This will permit a more careful study of the relationship between body organs and production. The data on the influence of preg - nancy upon gain and weight are being assembled and analyzed for publication. The project will be continued. Factors Affecting the Quality of Fluid Milk as Shown by the Fat Test, Sediment Test, and Bacteria Count. — The work under this project has been continued in] a study of butterfat content, sediment tests, bacteria counts, and a study of farm </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station conditions. Weekly reports are made to patrons on the con - dition of their milk. The bonus system for good milk has been continued. A system of deduction for poor milk has been started. There has been a steady improvement in the milk during the past six years as far as sediment content is con - cerned. The percentage of good and excellent milk has in - creased from 5.18 to 58.66 per cent, and there has been a con - siderable decline in unsatisfactory milk. The project will be continued. Methods of Practical Control and Economic Effect of Con - tagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd.— Work under this pro - ject has been continued in an effort to obtain a herd free from reactors to the agglutination test. Animals showing a positive reaction have been isolated from the rest of the herd by a double fence between lots and by entirely separate housing and watering equipment. There is, however, the contact thru visitors from the positive .and negative herds and also the fact that the same men care for the herds. This work has been going on for a number of years, and the indications are that very satisfactory progress is being made. No new re - actors have been found in the negative herd during the past nlteen months, and no abortions in that herd for a period of SSS5« IT-" . mo . nths - A bulletin. entitled "The Economic i?v I s ? f Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd" has been published as Research Bulletin No. 46. FIELD CROPS AND SOILS A Study of the Principles of Corn Improvement Thru Inbreeding and Hybridization.— Special emphasis is now be - ing placed upon the development of hybrids suitable for farm production. More than 20(A hybrids were tested for yield ™n &amp; ei: / grOn&lt; T? cha / act V s and seed of approximated 300 hybrids was taken for testing in 1930. Inbreds pro - duced in Nebraska and other cornbelt states were employed in making these hybrids. Results indicate that some of these selfed lines and hybrids have a rather wide adaptation The ordinary Hogue Yellow Dent corn, which is a stand - ard variety for this part of the state, yielded (1 9 I 9 ) It the rate of 55 bushels per acre at the Experiment Stat on In comparison, the best F, hybrid yielded 61.9 bushels which is an increase of 9.2 bushels per acre, or 17 per cent Twenty-one hybrids and ten or more standard varieties were a so grown in outlying tests in co-operation S the TC?hSh p? erVke - At E i k 3?' the best fiv * varlSeTjSeKkS 76.5 bushels, as compared with 92.5 bushels for the best five </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Forty-fourth Annual Report hybrids. This increase was 15 bushels, or 21 per cent. At Papillion, the best five varieties produced 101.1 bushels per acre, as compared with 113.8 bushels for the best five hybrids. This is a 12.7-bushel or 12-per cent increase. Under irriga - tion at Shelton, the best five varieties yielded 70.7 bushels, as compared with 82 bushels for the best five hybrids. This is an average increase of 11.3 bushels orjl6 per cent in favor of the hybrids. It has been very clearly demonstrated that many hybrids are inferior to ordinary farm-selected corn and conservatism is desirable in changing over to the use of hybrid seed. The double cross appears to be the most promising form of recombination of selfed lines available for the present. This may consist of hybridizing either two j single crosses or a single cross by a selfed line. Selected selfed lines which have been inbred for a number of years are the basis of all modern corn breeding. Various methods of making double crosses are under comparison. Three years' data indicate that it is just as feasible to cross advanced-generation hybrids in making double crosses as to cross first-generation hybrids. In this case the parent hybrid seed stocks are maintained as open-pollinated hybrids. This may simplify and cheapen the production of double-cross seed. A paper entitled "The Use of Advanced-generation Hybrids as Parents of Double Cross Seed Corn" was published in the Journal of the American Society of Agronomy, Vol. 22, No. 7, July, 1930. A Comparative Study of Corn Tillage Practices. — Work under this project continued in a study of the various methods of preparing the seed bed for corn. In the eight years, plow - ing and listing have given about equal results. Pall plowing is distinctly unfavorable. Seven-inch plowing has been superior to shallow plowing. The use of furrow openers on plowed ground has not increased the yield. In cultivation tests the data of the past year added addition - al evidence that the most important effect of cultivation is the prevention of weed growth. But other factors enter in, and preventing weed growth by scraping gave five per cent less in yield than four cultivations, jln regard to deep, shallow, close, or wide cultivation, wide latitude is permissible, provided the weeds are equally well destroyed. Fewer than three cultivations have not proved sufficient. Frequent and prolonged cultivation is of no advantage! A Comparative Study . of Various Miscellaneous Cultural Practices Involved in Growing the Corn Crop. — As a result of various studies concerning the best type I of plat for compara- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment, Station ?o \ t -?f ti " g ? f ™™ e * ies an d hybrids, a plat containing 4 rows ifr w ! n . Jen** l»s been adopted as standard wherever reliable yields are desired. Yields are based on the two middle rows and the plats are replicated five times. The corn is erhffl * e rate and thinned uniformly to three plants *W^ Study ha - s also been made as to the best grouping ?L h S ri ? S f nd varietles » the rate and date of planting, and the effect of unevenness of stand. r£* r » n ™« he !v*l *, P a P er &gt; " Field Tests with Treated Seed VoL 40, No 2, 1930 ""*' ° f A^ ricvXlura^ Research, Variety Testing Breeding, Acclimatization and CvLtural Studues with Small Grains.— Work on this project has been continued in an effort to find or develop superior stains of SMSS™ I™ 8 ? F^-J", the last fiv * years Nebraska No Turkey Red" y P6r C8nt m ° re than ori * inal t&gt;,^ e Mo aS Jn N hJ° ha f.i or two y ears « iven a higher yield ■Sf&amp;SriiBtSt stlff straw and is deddedly - nt^-dy v ,- Q^T^n n ! W f e lections of B "rt oats developed in the nursery i£q r, 10 - t0 I 5 per cent more than ordinary Kherson in 1929. During the years 1927-29 Comfort, Glabron and TreS a a rp e^ Ve + &gt; yielded 19 ' 2 ?' and 27 P er cent mor " Sn per acre than the common six-row variety. Ceres and North Dakota No. 1456.84 have yielded 24 and 37 per cent more indusKf qU1S SPriHg dUrin * the three y ears ' !927-29 nr3S? d P^^. 38 has been made in the development of new productive selections of winter wheat that are resistant to bunt or stmkmg smut when thoroly inoculated with bunt C e L fr ° m 12 *? 2 ° S .° + UrCeS - The heads have avenged less than two per cent smutty, as compared with 35 per cent for Nebraska No. 6 and Kanred when similarly treated. Nine of 1^^^ three ap p- to ** a -o?d «, Il L- da . te ? f " planting tests at Lincoln, October 1 has eiven PrioJi^theT/^f y H dd f ° r Pa3t IeVen y ears - H«S8£ - prior to the fly-safe date results, over a period of vears in SSS?/ 1^, Ear 'y P lan «ng of oats and spring £ better tatttf^' Bar - ley endu^ es late P la S Detter than either of these other spring grains. Rate-of -planting tests indicate that there may be rather a wide range in the amount of seed sown per acre without any material influence on yield witnout </seg>
            <seg id="p017">FORTY-POUKTH ANNUAL REPORT Extensive tests of planting methods were started last fall. The plan is to continue for three years. Early seed-bed prep - aration for winter wheat, to reduce volunteer grain and weed growth 1 , continued to be an important factor in high yields. Forage Crop Investigations. — Among 'the annual forage crops used for hay, cane and Sudan grass have proved most desirable. During the twelve-year period, Black Amber sorghum has yielded 4.6 tons of well-cured forage per acre, as compared with 3.12 tons for Sudan grass. The latter has yielded only 68 j per cent as much as the sorghum. As an average for the nine-year period, 1921-29,1 the somewhat later variety known as Western Orange has surpassed the Black Amber sorghum by 26 per cent in yield of forage containing 15 per cent moisture. The quality of cane forage is greatly improved by sowing at a relatively thick I rate. The common and German varieties of millet have yielded 73 and 85 per cent as much cured forage as Black Amber sorghum during this same nine-year period. In connection with alfalfa investigations, varietal produc - tivity and the interrelations of alfalfa production and sub - soil moisture depletion have been especially stressed. These phases of alfalfa work are now co-operatiye with the U. S. D. A. While the superior winterhardiness and high yield of the Grimm and Cossack varieties have been fully confirmed, it now appears in Nebraska Station Bulletin 240 that these are relatively susceptible to the alfalfa wilt disease and for this reason are less desriable than hardy northern-grown common alfalfa in those sections of the state where this disease is likely to be serious. This is especially true of bottom-land soils. An outstanding alfalfa among the numerous varieties and strains tested during the past ten years has been from a field in Dawson county and has been named Hardistan. This strain is very promising and seed from it is being increased. Another sort designated as Provence by the U. S. Department of Agriculture has given evidence of being especially resist - ant to cold and wilt. Extensive comparative plantings for the past several years have been continued. The depletion of sub - soil moisture on the table land in Nebraska causes rapid de - cline in yields after approximately five years of cropping. This is probably the reason that the greatest alfalfa-produc - ing centers are located where subsoil ! moisture is within reach of the plants. A rather intensive survey and investigation of stacking and baling procedure in relation to the quality and market value of </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019">Forty-fourth Annual Report this project that has been continued during the past year is a study of applications of nitrogen .fertilizers to wheat. Some preliminary work done in 1928 indicated, first, that under certain climatic conditions top dressings of nitrogen fertil - izers on winter wheat were profitable in southeastern Nebraska, and, second, that sodium nitrate wa3 superior to ammonium sulfate for this purpose. The work is being continued on a wider scale with a larger number of nitrogen carriers. The tests of 1929 showed pro - fitable returns for top dressings of certain nitrogen fertilizers in eastern Nebraska, but not in central Nebraska where winter wheat was adversely affected by shortage of moisture. As in 1928, sodium nitrate was superior to ammonium sulfate. Calurea, used in all tests this season, was intermediate in value. In a test of time of application, Calurea applied in April was slightly superior to that applied early in May. A Study of the Factors which Affect the Tilth of Soils. — During the year further work has been clone under this pro - ject along two lines, namely, studies of plasticity and of fric - tion. The results under the former study were presented by J. C. Russel at the Tenth Annual Meeting of the American Soil Survey Association in a paper entitled, "Observations on Plastic Flow in Soils," which was published in Bulletin 11 of the American Soil Survey Association, (pages 61-71). No satisfactory and dependable procedure was found for the determination of the rate of shear in soils. Special apparatus was developed for| the study of fric - tion. It was found that the coefficient of friction on metal is independent of velocity over the metal surface, of area of soil in contact with the metal surface, and of pressure. The soil variables studied were texture, structure, mois - ture, organic matter content, and lime content. Coefficient of friction at moisture equivalent wetness varied from 0.500 in sandy soils to over 1.000 in clay soils. Coarse granulation decreased and fine granulation increased the coefficient of friction. Within the limits of the moisture equivalent the coefficient of friction increased with the moisture content. Changes in organic matter content did not significantly affect friction in a definite direction, but increased it in some cases and decreased it in others. Additions of lime to acid soils decreased the coefficient of friction from 10 to 20 per cent. A Study of the Restoration of Organic Matter in Soils. — Studies under this project are being continued in a series of 24x24-inch frames, 9 inches deep, and set level with the ground. These frames are filled with a uniformly mixed soil </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station that contains a given amount of the organic material to be studied. The materials used are alfalfa hay, alfalfa roots, sweet clover hay, corn stalks, corn cobs, barnyard manure, and wheat straw of high, medium, and low nitrogen content. The moisture of the soil material is analyzed at intervals to determine the extent of loss. In another series of frames alfalfa, sweet clover, blue grass, wheat, and weeds are being grown to determine the loss or gain of organic matter or nitro - gen. Co-operative Fertilizer Experiments.— A. great " deal has been done on this project during the past year. Thru the co-operative arrangements of certain interested groups, 65 tons of treble superphosphate was distributed among 100 farmers, the larger proportion going into the irrigated sec - tions. Inspection of a number of fields indicates that on cer - tain soils a considerable response will be found to the applica - tion of superphosphate. The work will be continued. FRUITS AND VEGETABLES Pruning Apples, Pears, and Small Fruits. — The young apple trees which were lightly and heavily pruned at planting time are still under observation. This is their fourth growing season. The lightly pruned trees still maintain the advantage they gained the first year. The annual increase in diameter, however, has been the same regardless of severity of pruning at planting time. It must be borne in mind that these trees have had little or no subsequent pruning. The pruning work with grapes has been discontinued and the material published as Bulletin No. 237. Fruit Breeding Experiments. — A new planting of straw - berries, including all the varieties under test during the past two years and in addition the Blakemore from North Carolina, were set during the past year. A splendid stand was ob - tained. Dr. Burrill and Premier continue to be outstanding varieties. The Salway peach has a good crop here at Lincoln while other varieties have a few scattered fruits. There are no peaches in the orchard at the Union Fruit Farm. The hybrid plums, such as Sapa and Opata, are the only plums either at Lincoln or Union having a good crop in 1930. Several more Omaha seedlings are beginning to fruit. Orchard Culture, Union Fruit Farm. — Work under this pro - ject has been continued as previously outlined. Up to the present time the set of fruit has been light, and it has not been possible to measure the effect of cultural practices. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Forty-fourth Annual Report Trunk-diameter measurements have been continued. A comprehensive fertilizer test for apples has been started on the Union Fruit Farm and will be continued for several years. The fertilizer used is ammonium sulfate and is applied as a full application jn the spring, a full application in the fall, and with half the regular amount in the spring and the other half in the fall. In a comparison of mulching and cultivation in grape pro - duction the cultivation was superior to mulching both in total yield and in weight of bunches. The | highest yield was obtained by cultivation plus an application of ammonium sul - fate. The study of the soil nitrates confirms evidence of previous years ; the cultivated plats contain a higher percentage of nitrates than the mulched plats. The plat which is merely scraped averaged about as low in available nitrogen as the mulched plats. The addition of nitrate fertilizer greatly in - creased the available nitrogen in the cultivated plats, but not in the permanently mulched plats. The moisture determina - tions agree closely with those of a year ago. Applications of ammonium sulfate and sodium nitrate to Concord and Moore Early grapes at Lincoln had no effect upon the germination of the pollen. Vegetable Experimentation — Variety Trials and Cultural Tests. — Irrigation has again been demonstrated as one of the most practical means of increasing yields of nearly all vege - table crops. Straw mulching was the next most useful means. Paper mulching was found desirable in [hastening extremely early production of some crops, but for a reasonably early pro - duction date, such as August 15, or for total yield, paper mulching was found to be inferior to jcultivation, and de - cidedly inferior to straw mulching. Very shallow cultivation was generally superior to normal cultivation (about 3 inches deep) , especially in non-irrigated soils. Irrigation was of most value for soils cultivated normally, and of less value in straw-mulched plats. The addition of nitrate of soda was sometimes beneficial with straw mulching, but on the whole results do not warrant recommending it on soils that are as well supplied with fer - tility and organic mtater as is the soil used in these experi - ments. Fruit Stock Investigations. — The trees from grafts made in the spring of 1928 are not yet ready for final weights and measurements. The top-worked orchard at Lincoln and the scion-rooted orchard at Union are developing nicely, tho </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station they have few fruits on them. These trees are being kept under observation to see whether any differences show up as a result of the effect of the stock on the scion, or of scion on stock. The only differences noted so far are upon the rate of growth. Those trees on Virginia Crab stock are still the most vigorous of all. Orchard Spraying for the Codling Moth. — This project is in co-operation with Agricultural Extension. The year covered by this report was quite similar to the year previous in that there was a light crop of apples and the codling moth devel - oped slowly and in small numbers. The test of summer oils for moth control is being continued. In a test for arsenic on fruit that had received arsenical spray, the greatest amount found was slightly more than one - half of the so-called world tolerance. Under conditions such as existed it would seem that there is no danger from using these sprays. In the use of chemically treated paper bands to control codling moth, different chemicals were used. The various treatments resulted in kills ranging from 15 to 96 per cent of the worms that crawled under the bands to hide. While this one year's results are not sufficient for definite recom - mendations, they offer promise of a means of control. Spraying to control leaf spot in cherries was not found satisfactory last year, but the work is being continued. It was felt that a year ago the spraying was begun too late. This year the first spray was applied at the time of petal fall. In a test to control black rot of grapes by spraying, one application gave decidedly beneficial results. Where second and third sprayings were made there was some additional con - trol. The bunches of grapes were heavier and the loss of leaves from disease was much less on the sprayed vines. Copper dust was found about as effective in the control of black rot as the liquid Bordeaux spray. The spraying of grapes was done largely as a demonstration, and many farm - ers visiting the vineyards were convinced of its value. This part of the work will not be continued, but other phases of the project will be. HOME ECONOMICS Kerosene Cooking Stoves. — The work under this project has been completed and presented for publication as Research Bulletin No. 48. With the publication of the data the project will be closed. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Forty-fourth Annual Report Cash Contribution of Farm Homemakers to the Family In - come from Dairy and Poultry Products.- -i-The purpose of this study is. to determine the extent of the farm homemaker's activities in the care and sale of dairy and poultry products, and the net return she receives for her labor. It is proposed to compare the returns from the two activities and to dis - cover whether time can be more profitably spent in one than in the other or whether the return from both is so small that the time of the homemaker might more profitably be spent in some other way. In April, 1929, a group of farm women in various parts of Nebraska began keeping records of time spent in the care of poultry and dairy products, and of the returns received. These records were completed on March 31, 1930. The data are at present tabulated and summarized, and individual sum - maries are being returned to the women who completed the year's record keeping. A few of the completed records are not being used, but after throwing out such records as seemed inaccurate or inadequate, 160 reports remain. To complete the project the material gathered must be analyzed and the results prepared for publication. Washing Machine Study.— This project is in co-operation with the Department of Agricultural Engineering. Two each of the four different types of washing machines, namely cylinder, agitator, dolly, and vacuum types, are being used for the, study. • Samples of fabric are uniformly soiled, dried, aged, and washed by the different types of machines under uniform con - ditions of temperature, time* soap solution, and load. The washed samples are dried and tested for cleanness by meas - uring the brightness with a photometer j the new unwashed sample being used as the standard of brightness. Samples of fabric after being washed in the different types of machines are tested for breaking strength, the breaking strength being compared with that of the new sample to deter - mine wear on the fabric due to the washing machine. The machines are watched for discoloration and checked for heat retention. INSECT CONTROL Investigation and Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds.-^-TYie principal work done on this project in recent years has been with the Hessian fly. A study of the life his - tory and control of this pest was carried on in 1923, 1924, and 1925, and was then suspended because of the practical disap - pearance of the fly as a pest in. the state during 1926, 1927, </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station and 1928. In the winter wheat crop of 1929-30 the Hessian fly reappeared in injurious numbers, and a thoro survey of the extent and intensity of the injury was made from October 8 to 25, 1929, and again in May, 1930. Work on the Hessian fly has, therefore, been resumed under this project. It is expected that a bulletin covering the work done to date will be published in the near future. Studies on stored-grain pests are continuing under this project. Surveys to determine the spread of the alfalfa weevil- in the state were made under this project in June, 1930, as they were made also during June of the two preceding years. Nothing more has been done during the past year on wireworm, false wireworm, or chinch-bug investigations. The project will be continued. The Life History and Control of Potato Flea-Beetles in Western Nebraska. — Serious loss to the producers of seed potatoes in certain parts of western Nebraska because of "worm track" led to the starting of this work in 1928. The plan is to determine the life history of the potato flea-beetle, in these districts, as a basis for control recommendations. Spraying and dusting experiments are also being carried on to test out various direct methods of chemical control. The work previous to this year was done in Dawes county. This year the work was transferred to the vicinity of Morrill in Scotts Bluff county, where conditions seem more satisfactory. Very satisfactory progress is being made. A Brood Study of the Codling Moth in Southeastern Nebras - ka. — This project was originally co-operative with the De - partment of Horticulture. It was deemed best, however, to separate the more technical portions under the present pro - ject. The purpose is to determine the period of development of the broods of eggs, larvae, pupae, and moths of each gen - eration of the codling moth in southeastern Nebraska, and the yearly life cycle of the insect in this region as a basis for pro - perly timing spray applications for its control, and thus in - creasing their efficiency. The principal portion of the work under this project is being done here at Lincoln in the Agri - cultural College orchard. A report on the 1929 studies has been published in the Annual Report of the Nebraska State Horticultural Society for 1930. The project will be continued. A Study of the Distribution, Life History, and Means of Control of Cutworms Attacking Corn in Nebraska. — During the spring of 1930 cutworms were plentiful and some progress was made on this project. The phase of the work which gives keys and descriptions of the various kinds of cutworms known to attack field crops is nearing completion. The portion deal- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Forty-fourth Annual Report ing with the life history and methods of control will require considerably more work. Special attention has been given during the past two years to a species of cutworm (Euxoa detersa) that has been exceedingly destructive. The project will be continued. LIVESTOCK FEEDING - Fattening Cattle.— Two experiments were carried on dur - ing the past year. Wintering stock calves in eastern Nebraska.— During the past several years there has been an increased interest among cattle feeders in year-round feeding. A project was in - augurated to determine how stockmen might best carry their stock calves thru the winter. This will J be carried for three years. For this experiment seven lots of 14 steer calves each were procured. The calves weighed! approximately 350 pounds at the beginning and were on feed for 135 days. The results of the feeding tests indicate that it is entirely feasible tor a cornbelt farmer to carry stock calves thru the winter either for feeders or to put on grass the following year 1 he calves fed silage made greater gains and had a better general appearance than those fed ground corn fodder. The latter, however, had a somewhat higher! market value, owing to the fact that they were of lighter weight at the conclusion ot the test. One Pound of cottonseed cake fed daily was equal to three pounds of alfalfa hay as a protein supplement, with both the basic rations of silage and ground corn fodder. Short-feeding yearling heifers.— Previous work carried on at this station indicated that female cattle take on fat more rapidly than steers. Many feeders follow the practice of pur - chasing yearling heifers for a short period of intensive feed - '^•. 1 . n tnis study three lots of heifers j were fed for a period of 65 days. Large gains were obtained and the heifers were merdaU°rcSss S e U s tO Pr ° dUCe satisfactorv corn- In the test shelled corn was found to be superior to ground ear corn. Where ground ear corn was fed with one pound of cottonseed cake per head instead of alfalfa, the heifers experi - enced no digestive disorders and apparently the ration was satisfactory, altho the gain produced was not quite as great as where alfalfa hay was fed with ground ear corn. The pro - ject will be continued. Forage Crops for Hogs.— Under this project six lots of 10 pigs each were carried, five of them on Sudan-grass pasture. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station • The rations used and the gain made by the various lots are shown in the following table. ,1 Av. daily: Feed required for gain 100 lbs. gain i i i I Grain ! Tankage Lbs. j Lba. ' Lb«. Corn and tankage (dry lot) : | .587 527 : 37 Corn and tankage (pasture) I .995 380 2G Corn alone (pasture) I .795 447 Ground wheat and tankage (pasture) .| 1.160 I 389 27 Whole wheat and tankage (pasture) | .992 479 32 Ground barley and tankage (pasture) | .976 454 33 The addition of tankage to a corn ration on pasture in - creased the daily gain. Pigs receiving ground wheat made a larger gain than those receiving corn. The feeding value of ground wheat in the test was 98 per cent of that of shelled corn. Grinding the wheat increased the rate of gain and the efficiency of the feed. Ground barley was 84 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. The project will be continued. Rations for Fattening Hogs. — Under this project three lots of 10 pigs each were fed from January 1 to June 9 in an at - tempt to determine the effect of the weight of pigs on the rate and economy of gains. The various lots were fed thru self-feeders a ration of corn with a supplement mixture con - taining two parts tankage, one part cottonseed meal, and one part ground alfalfa hay. At the beginning of the tests the pigs averaged 71.6 pounds, and at the close 350 pounds per head. A careful check of the feed consumption was made when each lot averaged 100- pounds and again at 150 pounds, and thereafter at 25-pound intervals until the final weight was reached. The feed required to produce a given amount of gain increased up to 200 pounds of weight. At the next interval there seemed to be a slight decrease in the feed re - quirement per given weight, but this did not show in the final feeding period. A careful study of the quality of the meat and the growth of the various organs was made at definite intervals. The results are reported below. This project will be continued. Factors Affecting the Quality and Palatability of Meat. — Two tests were made during the past year. The first was a repetition of work done with lambs a year ago. In this test three lots of lambs were used. The first lot received a full </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Forty-fourth Annual Report feed of shelled corn and alfalfa hay for a period of 140 days. The second lot received a full feed of shelled corn and alfalfa nay for a period of 84 days, after which the ration was reduced to that required for body maintenance. The third lot was fed for a period of 56 days on ai maintenance ration of alfalfa alone, after which they were brought to a full feed of shelled corn and alfalfa for an additional period of 84 days. Three average lambs from each lot were slaughtered at 28-day intervals for carcass studies and palatability com - parison.. The lambs in Lot 1 improved from medium to choice during the period of full feeding, increasing in 1 weight from 64 to 105 pounds per head. The dressing percentage increased from 27.5 to 52. The lambs in Lot 2 made equal progress with those in Lot 1 during the first 84 days, when they were on full feed. After they were put on a maintenance ration the dressing percent - age was reduced about three per cent. No significant changes in dressing yield or yield of internal fat were noted in the lambs in Lot 3 during the maintenance period. After they were on full feed their behavior was similar to that of other lots. With increased fatness, the weight of the loin increased, due to the accumulation of kidney fat. As the fat increased, the percentage of bone in the shortracks decreased from 20 per cent in the controls to 12 per cent in the lambs full fed for 140 days. As the period of full feeding continued, the per - centage of fat in the tissues increased with a corresponding decrease in percentage of water, protein' and ash. From the results of the palatability study, it appears that the aroma of fat. roasts is more marked and more desirable. With the increase of fatness, the flavor, of fat becomes more desirable and the flavor of the lean becomes less pronounced and more desirable. The fat roasts appeared to be slightly more tender and more juicy than the leaner roasts. The second test was a study of the |effect of weight and degree of fatness of pork carcasses upon the quality and palatability of the meat. Thirty 71-pound fall pigs were self - fed shelled corn and a protein supplement, and a record was kept of the food consumption and daily gains up to the time the hogs were slaughtered. ,« T^ S ,&amp; vestigation extende d thru the first six months of 1930. The low temperatures encountered during the early part of the trial and the extreme heat of early summer doubt - less were factors in reducing gains during those portions of the trial. From the time the hogs reached 150 pounds live </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station weight, three average animals were slaughtered at every 25 - pound interval until the lots averaged 250 pounds. From this weight to the 400-pound average, slaughterings were made at 50-pound intervals. With increasing live weight, the dressing yield increased consistently from 73.2 per cent at 150 pounds to 82.7 per cent at 400 pounds. The fat cuts, such as leaf, fat, fat back, belly, clear plate, and trimmings increased with the fatness of the pigs. The lean cuts, such as loin, ham, picnic, and Boston Butt, decreased from 2 to 4 per cent as the pigs increased in live weight from 150 pounds to 400 pounds. At 150 pounds, the average thickness of back fat was found to be .60 inch, while at 400 pounds, the average thickness was 2.35 inches. Physical separations into fat, lean, bone, and skin were made of all cuts. The percentage of the bone in the carcass of a 150-pound pig was found to be 10.63 per cent. This de - creased to 6.25 per cent in the 400-pound pig. The percent - ages of mechanically separable fat and lean practically re - versed between 150 and 400 pounds of live weight. The car - casses of 150-pound pigs contained 28 per cent fat and 53 per cent lean, while those of the 400-pound pigs contained 58 per cent fat and 30 per cent lean. Chemical analyses of the edible portion of the pork loins disclosed that the percentages of water, protein, and ash de - clined with increasing fatness. The loins of the 150-pound pigs contained 45 per cent. Refractive indices of the leaf lard disclosed that all of the carcasses were hard. With in - creased fatness, the pork roast lost a higher percentage in drippings. Progressive fattening appeared to increase the amount and richness of the juice and to increase the desirabil - ity of the fat flavor. This project is being duplicated with a few minor variations at the present time. Lamb Feeding. — During the past year three sub-projects were carried under this project. The first test was a studv of the effect of the plane of nutrition, on (1) the rate and economy of gains made by the western lambs, and (2) the quality and palatability of lamb carcasses reported above under the title, "Factors Affecting the Quality and Palatabil - ity of Meat." Two lots of 75 lambs each were put on feed early in October. These were white-faced Wyoming lambs of fine - wool type, and the average initial weight was 63 pounds per head. Lot 1 received shelled corn and alfalfa hay, was brought to full feed as quickly as possible, and continued on feed for 84 days, after which 20 average lambs were selected </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Forty-fourth Annual Report for further tests and the rest marketed. Ten of the lambs selected were continued on full feed and ten were fed a limited grain ration. Those continued oh full feed made an average gain of 42.4 pounds for the 140 days. They required 19 per cent more shelled corn and 32 per cent more alfalfa hay to produce a hundred pounds of gain during the last 56 days than was required during the first 84 days of feeding. Trying to maintain the weights of ten lambs that had been on full feed for 84 days was not found [to be entirely satis - factory when a low grain ration was used. The lambs in the second lot were fed only alfalfa hay for a period of 56 days and then were gradually brought to a full feed of shelled corn. They remained thrifty during the main - tenance period but made very little gain, j The gains made for the whole period were much the same as the gains made by the lambs in Lot 1, but slightly more grain and considerably more alfalfa were required, and the practice! would not be con - sidered satisfactory. The second phase of the project was a study of the effect of the plane t)f nutrition on (1) the wool growth and (2) the body growth of sheep. Two lots of six lambs each were selected from a bunch of uniform Shropshires. Lot 1 was fed a maintenance ration of alfalfa meal. Lot 2 was on a full feed of cracked corn and alfalfa meal. Lot 1 lost weight dur - ing the feeding period, while Lot 2 made satisfactory gains in body weight. The total wool secured and the breaking strength of fibers were significantly decreased where lambs were maintained on the low plane of nutrition for a period of 196 days. The third phase of this work was a study of some of the problems involved in the production of! market lambs from aged western ewes. For the experiment] 200 broken-mouthed western ewes were procured. The results of this test showed that cutting alfalfa hay for aged pregnant ewes increased their feed consumption and gain and decreased the amount of feed required for 100 pounds of gain. Lambs fed a high-protein grain mixture before and after weaning made slightly greater gains than those on a low-pro - tein grain mixture. One-half of the ewes were bred when purchased and the other half were bred 1 at the station farm. Those bred in Colorado lambed about seven days earlier, but produced a lower percentage of lambs than those bred at the station farm. • MILLING AND BAKING The Relation of Certain Chemical and Physical-Chemical Characteristics of Nebraska Wheat to its Milling and Baking </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Quality.— The small amount of work done on this project, during the past year merely served to confirm the conclusion stated in last year's report, i.e., that protein content is the predominating quality factor in Nebraska wheats, as it is elsewhere, when one considers "quality" from the standpoint of prevailing methods used in modern flour and bread pro - duction. This does not mean that excellent bread cannot be made from wheat or flour of low gluten content. The pref - erence for higher-protein flours is due to their - relatively greater strength or "stability," which gives them a wider margin of safety when subjected to handling by modern methods of large-scale commercial bread production They are more "fool-proof." It may again- be emphasized that as compared with hard winter bread wheats produced in other localities, and on a basis of equal protein content, Nebraska wheat is m no way inferior in quality. Beliefs to the con - trary, which were formerly quite common, are disappear - ing to a noticeable degree. The most important outcome of work on this project has been the apparent establishment of a start toward a standard and generally recognized method for the ascertainment of those flour characteristics upon which "quality" estimates are based. This is the so-called "Standard American Associa - tion of CerealiChemists Experimental Baking Test," which has also been recently made a tentative method of the Asso - ciation of Official Agricultural Chemists. It is recommended that this project be closed, for reasons S j o^j in the discussi °ns of projects entitled "Preparation S^'L.j'*?' °l the Cereal Glutelins" and "Standardization of Methods m Experimental, Baking Procedure." Preparation and Study of the Cereal Glutelins.— -Work on this project was pursued thruout the year, and was confined entirely to studies of the gluten of wheat. Data were nub - lished showing conclusively that there is occasion for a thoro of the nature and identity of the wheat pro - •!, n °£_? ro l ei &lt; ns in « eneral » an d of the constitution and indi - viduality of 'glutenin" in particular. As indicated in last year s report, glutenin (as characterized by Osborne, and as customarily isolated by methods involving preliminary dis - persion m dilute alkali) is not a naturally occurring protein individual, as has been hitherto believed, but is rather a derived fraction" of a more complex entity. Furthermore, both the amount and composition of this "fraction" will vary with the strength of the alkali used for its extraction and purification. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Forty-fourth Annual Report The past year's work has involved the continued prepara - tion and study of "glutenins" by methods in which the use of or exposure to alkali was scrupulously avoided. Many in - dividual preparations have been made, in most of which the original dispersing agent was dilute acetic acid in alcohol. From dispersions of this character "glutenin fractions" may be precipitated by neutralization or by the addition of salts. It has been found by submitting all preparations to partial Van Slyke analysis that there is considerable variation, in composition as well as in amount, of | protein precipitated according to variations among factors such as pH, tempera - ture, time, kind of salt, amount of salt, and concentration of protein in solution. In some cases it I has been possible to isolate a "glutenin" of uniform and constant composition by different methods of procedure. There I is some evidence of the presence of at least two gluten proteins aside from gliadin. The problem has proved to be | -exceedingly difficult, owing on the one hand to a lack of suitable criteria for estab - lishing the individuality of proteins, arid on the other hand to the ease with which proteins frequently undergo unaccount - able and irreversible changes in their physical properties due to apparently minor variations in the technique of their pre - paration and purification. It is hoped arid expected, however, that definite conclusions will eventually be reached. Since gluten is the most important constituent of wheat flour there should be no relaxation of effort to gain reliable knowledge of its fundamental constitution and properties. The project will be actively continued. Standardization of Methods in Experimental Baking Pro - cedure. — This project is being carried |thru the assignment by the American Association of Cereal Chemists of a Research Fellow to this institution for one year, beginning September 1. The object of the fellowship is to provide facilities for systematic research on certain problems relating to the ade - quate control of certain environmental I factors operative in experimental baking tests as conducted by the tentative stand - ard A. A. C. C. method. Since considerable time and facilities will be devoted to this activity, it is recommended that the project be reopened. Within a year, a five-minute method for estimating the per - centage of moisture in flour was developed and published as follows: "A Rapid and Simple Carbide (Method for Estimat - ing Moisture in Flour," Cereal Chemistry, March, 1930. This procedure is based upon a measurement of the pressure developed when flour is intimately mixed! with calcium carbide </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station in a closed system connected with a mercury manometer, the pressure being due, of course, to acetylene gas produced when the flour moisture reacts with carbide. NUTRITION A Study of the Comparative Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry Feeding. — The method of Thomas for evaluating the biological value of proteins, modified slightly to conform to the special requirements of hens, has been employed over a period of years to study the comparative efficiency of various cereals when fed as the sole source of nitrogen. The results of these efforts have been summarized in Poultry Science, Vol. 9, No. 2, p. 112, January 1, 1930. In order to show differences in biological values, several grains were fed separately at low levels of nitrogen intake, approximately twice maintenance, one and one-third main - tenance, and two-thirds maintenance with respect to the nitro - gen requirements as previously determined. Slight variations were observed at the highest plane of nitrogen feeding. As the plane of nitrogen was successively lowered the biological values of the individual grains increased, confirming for poul - try the experience of others with different animals. Varia - tions between individual cereals also increased. The values obtained when applied as a factor to the protein (nitrogen x 6.25) content of the different grains, yielded a figure which is indicative of their "net protein value," that is, the amount of protein in a given quantity of grain which is actually used by hens. The cereals used in this study included whole corn, wheat, both whole and ground, whole oats, rye, both whole and ground, barley, both whole and ground, and ground soy beans. The utilization of the proteins of the grains tested was im - proved by grinding it finely enough to pass thru a two-milli - meter sieve. Since the formula of Thomas requires the determination of the nitrogen excretion of hens on a ration in which the nitro - gen content is reduced to the negligible amount found in starch, the effect on the depletion of the protein reserves of a nitrogen-free feeding period, following 27 days on the low planes of nitrogen intake mentioned above, was studied. Since the oviducts of hens completing such tests atrophy, the nitrogen content of the oviducts of six hens finishing such a period and the nitrogen content of the oviducts of eight pullets killed immediately after laying their first egg were compared. The atrophied oviducts of these six hens contained but 0.07 gram, while the actively functioning oviducts of the pullets at the beginning of a laying cycle average 1.45 grams of nitro- </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Forty-fourth Annual Report gen. Assuming that the difference was excreted by the hens while undergoing a test, it may be calculated that about one - third of the loss of nitrogen from the body may be accounted for by the resqrption of the oviducts and the excretion of the nitrogen contained therein. These results are also reported in the above-mentioned article. The project will be continued. Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks. — In the Journal of Agricultural Research, Vol. 40, No. 9, p. 863, May 1, 1930, a study of the sex differences in the normal growth rate of S. C. White Leghorn chicks up to nine weeks of age was reported. In this work the growth rates of 397 male and 403 female chicks were compared by means of a statistical analysis of their weights at bi-weekly intervals. It was found that differ - ences in the means of the weights of the chicks were signifi - cant at one week of age, and that the significance of the difference between the means increased thereafter. A factor for bringing experimental lots with different numbers of male and female chicks to a common basis for the purpose of com - parison is suggested. PLANT DISEASES A Study of Spindle Tuber and Cofnbinations of Spindle Tuber with Other. Degeneration Diseases. — Seed stocks affected with different virus diseases j are being propagated for further study and comparison with some of the unidenti - fied diseases occurring in Nebraska. The project will be con - tinued for the present as a minor subject. The status of the investigations at present are summarized as follows : 1. Studies of the symptoms and thej effect of environment on the symptoms of spindle tuber arid unmottled curly dwarf have been concluded and published as Research Bulletin No. 47. The experimental results of the effect of soil moisture, soil temperature, and air temperature on the development of both vine and tuber symptoms are reported and illustrated in this bulletin. The application of these results to the identifica - tion of the diseases in the field is discussed. The differential value of some 20 detailed vine symptoms and 18 tuber symp - toms are tabulated and their occurrence as current-season or. as perpetuation symptoms is noted. The relations of these diseases to abnormal sprout development, to apical domin - ance, and to the effect upon the symptoms of chemical treat - ments used to break the rest period are discussed. 2. The results of the studies of insect transmission have been published in abstract form in Phytopathology, 2(1:136, 1930. A number of insects not previously connected^ with </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural, Experiment Station spindle tuber and unmottled curly dwarf were shown to be able to transmit these diseases. 3. The results of other phases of the transmission studies and the differences between these two diseases, as determined by different infection methods, are being prepared for publi - cation. An Inquiry into the Pathological and Physiological Aspects of Alfalfa Failures in Nebraska, — Studies in the greenhouse, in the laboratory, and in the field, of four phases of the pro - ject have been carried on. 1. Etiology of alfalfa wilt (Aplanobacter insidiosum) . — A preliminary report on wilt in Nebraska has been published as Experiment Station Bulletin No. 240. Wilt was found in some fields in all sections of the state. The solution of the problem seems to be the growing of resistant varieties. Three vari - eties, Hardistan, Turkestan, and Provence, as studied from the seed stock available, appear to be tolerant of or resistant to wilt. 2. Pathological, anatomy of alfalfa wilt. — Some work has been done on a study of the pathological anatomy of alfalfa wilt. The results are now being analyzed. 3. Selections for wilt resistance. — -In a search for wilt-re - sistant strains or varieties, some work has been done. Three thousand selections have been planted and studied. The seed from the more resistant varieties was obtained and cuttings were made from apparently healthy plants found in infected fields. Some 20,000 young plants were inoculated and trans - planted to the field for observation as to their susceptibility. 4. Winter injury and hardiness studies. — Winter injury and hardiness studies have been conducted in co-operation with the United States Department of Agriculture. A large amount of data has been obtained from plants of different varieties and ages, and they are now being analyzed. In a study of twenty-five Turkestan strains a great differ - ence was shown in their resistance to artificial freezing, the most cold resistant being from the Khiva district. The hardier Turkestans appear to be more resistant to cold than does Grimm. Work is also being done on the influence of environmental factors in the hardening process in alfalfa. A Study of Potato Scab and Fusarium Wilt of the Potato in Relation to Infection from the Soil. — The results of an ex - tensive survey of the occurrence of scab in western Nebraska in relation to soil conditions and crop rotations are being sum - marized for publication. The field experiments dealing with this problem are being started this summer on the new Box Butte Experiment Farm. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Forty-fourth Annual Report Preliminary method studies have been made in the labora - tory and greenhouse. No satisfactory technique has been developed for the quantitative determination of pathogenic organisms in the soil. Promising preliminary results have been obtained in the laboratory and greenhouse, in the study of different species and strains of the organism in relation to the type of scab produced and in determining the effect of soil moisture, soil type, sterilization methods, the effect of the numbers of the pathogene in the soil, and the relation of the numbers. of com - peting organisms to the severity of infection. The major portion of the Associate! Pathologist's time is being spent on this project, with special emphasis on the effect of different cropping systems on infection and on method studies dealing with the quantitative determination of the pathogenic flora of the soil. Fruit Disease Investigations. — This project is co-operative between the Departments of Plant Pathology and Horticulture. The phase of the project now being studied is an investigation of the cherry leaf spot, a disease caused by Coccomyces hiem - alis. The work to date has consisted of the determination of the time of spore ejection in the sprpg and the effect of different spray schedules upon the disease. The disease was especially severe in the experimental orchard at Nebraska City in 1929. None of the spray methods used controlled the disease satisfactorily. This year the first spray application was made earlier, and a larger variety of schedules and spray materials is included in the tests. POTATOES Potato Selection for Seed Purposes.— During the past year 100 tuber-line strains of Triumph potatoes have been selected because of their distinctive characteristics and are being in - creased for seed stocks. Factors being considered in the study of these strains are (a) season of maturity, (b) yield, (c) tuber size, (d) tuber shape, (e) freedom from knobs and second growth, (f ) susceptibility to tuber cracking at harvest time, (g) susceptibility to scab and other diseases. The prin - cipal tests are being conducted at Alliance. Other .tests to determine the most satisfactory type of tuber line for further propagation and later dissemination are being carried on co-operatively at several southern points in the Gulf Coast states and also under irrigation in western Nebraska. At the present time there are indications that! tuber lines vary with regard to all the various factors enumerated. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station During the past winter about 8,000 tubers were indexed from lines that had been indexed for two or three years pre - viously. The indications are that the mosaic diseases of the typical mild, crinkle, rugose, and comparable types have been SS ehmin ated, not a single infected plant having been tound this past winter. During the spring of 1930 approxi - mately 30,000 bushels of seed stock, increased from tuber-S - dexed potatoes, were planted in the state. tw rt a te ! tS du 5 in£r the past year confirmed the evidence Nebrlskt potatoes can be Produced in central and eastern «,™k! fur^ e J S^ dy . 0f *, he relation of depth of planting to ?hi2 ZfTi depth ° f I 010 " 3 an d tubers, length of stolons, to &amp; ™L1 tV"? scab pre Y alen &lt;*, shallow planting seems to be more satisfactory than deep planting and high ridging. A study was made of keeping seed potatoes in cold storage and the indications are that it is desirable, the most benefit coming from cold storage after March first. Removing sprouts m early June, after the potatoes had been stored if the cellar, resulted in from 20 to 30 per cent increased yield but it was not as satisfactory as cold storage «Pn£« ng t] 1 ™. 3^ 1 ". 1 ™ 0 papers were Published as follows: • R l lat i on . °/ Time of Roguing to the Spread of Spindle Tuber ioSS l^%^'7^ Vt&lt;yp f-^ l9V ' &amp;0V " 1929, P VoTl?, U p P " n£™ tv, e i5 0 ! Y acant HiIls and of Plant Compet tion upon the Yield of Potatoes in Field Experiments," Proceed pTl09-120. ° AsSOciaticm °f December 1929, yJtJ!?"^ 1^ De Q er f r^V in Seed-Potato Stocks.— Several phases of this project have been carried on during the past &gt;,* Jil me ° f P 1^ 1 *™^ and of harvesting seed potatoes.— With healthy seed stock the importance of maturity appears to be S uli?i^ t On + t°f^ don S? nt period of the seed tSK. Re! ?£? md Tf at } he metn °d °f borage and time of planting S 1f«^ ed^ t0CkS °? VSrying ma turity (as measured from timf «Ln D - are importan t variables in such studies. In southern regions where potatoes are planted in the fall and early winter months, mature seed seems to be desirable be - cause of its more complete emergence from the dormant period, whereas in the north, where planting is dSerred™nSl fi£ w matU1 £ 8ee f , is P ?. Ssibly more desirable bemuse it win have been weakened less by excessive sprouting. Effect of soil conditions upon seed stocks.— These studies take into consideration different soil types, so 1 imffiufiSon? and straw and paper mulches. The tubers gVownbv these various methods-are checked under unifoSi cSSons </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Forty-fourth Annual Report Another phase of this problem is a study of the effect of soil fertility and size of crop upon the seed value of tubers. In comprehensive tests at Alliance, North Platte, and Scotts - bluff with healthy Triumph and Cobbler seed, no significant yield differences were found between dry-land and irrigated seed stocks. Similar results were obtained in six southern states. In a further study of the rest period of potatoes, ethylene chlorhydrin treatment (dipping method) was again found to be very effective in breaking the rest period of Triumph potatoes. The results were more pronounced with the most mature potatoes. Beneficial effects, as 'measured by prompt emergence and increase in number of stems per seed piece, were secured with the treatments thru the entire storage period. A series of studies was made with the Triumph variety of potatoes to determine (a) the effect of various practices upon wound healing, and (b) the manner in! which healing occurs in wounds of various types. Exposure of tangential cuts on immature tubers in Septem - ber to direct sunlight for six hours resulted in the desiccation of many surface cells with a significant slowing up in the suberization and cork formation processes. Cutting out some light rays by means of plain silica glass, cello glass, or red glass was beneficial in hastening the healing processes. Treating wounds with hot formaldehyde, within two days after the wounds were produced," retarded suberization and cork formation. If suberization had already begun when the wound was treated, there- was no retarding effect. Cracks and cuts in the tubers did not heal as rapidly as tangential cuts. The innermost portions of the cracks were the slowest to heal ; in fact these portions were not completely healed until about 35 days after being produced. Exposure of the cracks to sunlight during the first six hours retarded healing processes during the first 14 days. In a study of the time of treating s^eed potatoes with hot formaldehyde, various lots were treated at intervals ranging from one hour after harvesting to the day they were planted. Undesirable effects as measured by emergence, stand, and yield were apparent only with the lots given extreme treat - ments. During the year Research Bulletin No. 45 of this station was published, entitled, "Effect of Cultural Methods and Maturity upon the Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes " and a paper entitled, "Some Factors Concerning the Producti - vity of Irrigated Seed Potatoes," was published in the Journal of the Potato Association of America. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ■ • •■ POULTRY Nutrition Studies of Growing Chicks. — In some further studies of this project three phases were considered during the past year. . . 1. Irradiated ergosterol as an antirachitic for chicks. — Irradiated ergosterol has been recommended as a practical source of the antirachitic essential. This product is now be - ing offered consumers in a standardized form which has been recognized by the Council on Pharmacy and Chemistry of the American Medical Association under the name of Viosterol 100 D. Theoretically this product should have an antirachitic value one hundred times greater than that of an equal volume of standard cod liver oil. A basal ration complete for all essential factors except vitamin D was used for a series of experiments. When two per cent of a good grade of cod liver oil was added, normal growth resulted. When irradiated ergosterol in amounts theoretically equivalent to two, four, six, twenty, and fifty per cent of cod liver oil was added rickets developed consistently in all lots. Rickets was not prevented until irradiated ergos - terol theoretically equivalent to 200 per cent of cod liver oil was used. Irradiated yeast was also used as a source of the antirachitic factor. The ' inclusion of one and of three per cent of irradiated yeast did not protect the chicks against rickets. A more detailed report of these experiments is given in Poultry Science, Volume 9, No. 5, June, 1930. 2. The effect on the growth rate of yeast additions to cer - tain chick rations. — It had been observed in an earlier series of experiments that the growth rate could be appreciably in - creased by adding yeast to the ration. An investigation showed that the protein content of the yeast was 50.9 per cent. The addition of three per cent of this yeast, therefore, raised the protein level one and one-half per cent. The ques - tion of whether the increased growth rate was due to the vitamin B contribution of the yeast or to the protein was immediately presented. The yeast was autoclaved to destroy the B-l or antineuritic factor. It was found that the auto - claved yeast stimulated the growth rate just as effectively as did the original yeast. Since autoclaving for two hours at fifteen pounds pressure is known to destroy the B-l or anti - neuritic vitamin factor, the increase in the growth rate was not due to the vitamin B-l contribution. 3. Utilization of various proteins by growing chicks.— The biological values of nine of the most common protein con - centrates was compared at exactly the same protein level when </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Forty-fourth Annual Report added to the same basal ration, which was known to be com - plete for vitamin and mineral essentials. The protein con - centrates used were meat and bone meal, dried buttermilk, blood meal, linseed oil meal, cottonseed meal, gluten meal, soybean meal, fish meal, casein, and gelatin. Various com-, binations of these concentrates were also used. A more de - tailed report of these experiments is being prepared at the present time, and will be submitted as a bulletin of the Station. Turkey Production, — Two phases of this project were carried on during the past year. The first was a test of cross - breeding to determine its effect upon growth and productivity. There is a rather well established belief that cross-breeding of certain breeds causes improvement. Bronze females were mated with White Holland males and Bourbon males. The eggs from these crosses were hatched in an incubator and the poults were brooded together and received the same rations. Standard-bred Bronze poults were hatched and reared under exactly the same conditions. To eliminate the error due to unequal distribution of sexes in the respective lots the weights for females at 24 weeks were translated into the male equi - valent. These data have shown that standard-bred Bronze males averaged 1.61 times as heavy as females at the age of 24 weeks. The evidence obtained in this test does not indicate any stimulation in growth rate in turkeys as a result of the above-mentioned matings. Under the second phase of the project a study was made of the humidity factor as affecting the haichability of eggs and vigor of poults hatched artificially. For this purpose a large group of turkey eggs of apparently the same shell texture and quality, and the same size, were incubated in the same cab - inet incubator with temperature, humidity, and ventilation under control. Accurate weights were obtained oh each of the 150 eggs before they were put into the incubator and at the end of 8, 16, and 24 days of incubation respectively. The mean weight loss of all of the eggs from the first to the 24th day of incubation was 11.95 per cent of the original weight. Under the same humidity there was an individual loss from eggs of from 9 to 16.9 per cent. The poults from this hatch - ing will be grouped and their growth rate determined. The project will be continued. RURAL ECONOMICS Cost of Producing Farm Products. — In an attempt to get information on the cost of producing crops in different sec - tions of Nebraska 360 farm records were completed during the past calendar year, and a considerably larger number of </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station X*f %* bein \ ke P t durin * the current year. The records include the man, horse, and machine labor and other produc - tion costs. The land rental is figured as the share of the annual crop usually given for rent. The work is being carried HpvI^ - 1X countles m different sections of the state, and is tIThT" V° m £ l ei £ in teresting and valuable information. The date show both the efficiency of different methods and of fmES? far ™; rs in * ?, ven ar ea, and they also serve as an orn^i *"£ ° f th - e P rofita , bl eness or unprofitableness of a given crop m the various sections of the state. JWjK* 'i tvdie&amp; ';^ PHce ' Volume of Production, and the o^r luun ?9 p ower of Farm Products.— This project has been continued during the past year, and considerable date have ftf e ™ relative to the production and prices obtained loo*?! braskas - i more im P ort ant farm products during the drcular entitled 'Trice Facts and Factors-H^s" was pre^ pared for and published by the Extension Service ttJvW 0 * movement of Nebraska farm products to «PnS?' ? E f te SV ? been , coll ected and tebulated on carrot ship - ments of the principal grains and kinds, of livestock from selected shipping points in the state. Effort is being maSe £ determine the differences in the seasonal movement! of these vJSh tr -° m t} l e Various parts of the s tate, the year-to-year SXSrirrBSS^ lf PbSSible the -asonsTor 19S n SS'LH3i O ? er * ti ", ar da i a f0r 83 f armers' elevators for 1928 were added to similar date previously assembled An - alysis has given evidence of the influence of such factors as results was presented to the annual convention o? the BW </seg>
            <seg id="p041">FORTY-FOUKTH ANNUAL REPORT ers' Elevator Association and was published in the "Farmers' Elevator Guide." Farm Organization and Farm Costs. — -The data for study under this project have been obtained from the farmers' records kept in connection with other work. The interest in the work has steadily increased the number of records being kept. During the past calendar year 537 records were com - pleted and a larger number of record books were asked for during the current year. A new phase of this project is the summarization by pre - cincts of the agricultural statistics obtained by the assessors. This should give accurate information on jthe various types of farming in the different sections of the state. A portion of this work is in co-operation with the U. S. Bureau of Agricul - tural Economics. The results of one study have now been pre - pared and published as Bulletin No. 244,; "Types of Farming in Nebraska." The project will be continued. SERUM PRODUCTION Several outbreaks of cholera occurred during the months of September and October. These were local in character and did not assume epidemic proportions, which frequently obtain during periodic outbreaks. The State Serum Plant ex - perienced no difficulty in filling all orders promptly, and at all times there was in storage a liberal supply of serum. The policy of buying the serum andj manufacturing the virus has been continued. The retail price up to June first was 70 cents for blood serum and 90 cents for clear concen - trated serum per hundred cubic centimeters. On June first the prices were reduced to 60 and 75 cents respectively. The virus sold at $1.50 per hundred cubic centimeters thruout the year. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Following is a report of the serum and virus sold by months during the calendar year, together with a financial statement as of January 1, 1931. Cubic Serum on hand January 1, 1930 ] 7 403 275 Serum purchased and delivered during: 19S0/.i!"!!Z,.!™™i""! 7*8541250 Total serum handled for year.. 15 257 52=; Serum and virus sold by months: 10,267,628 Serum Virus T . c.c. c.c. January 125,425 8,510 February ;. 100,725 5,655 March ... 85,125 4,900 April 87,125 6,890 May ■ 337,425 123,290 June 1,472,300 100,650 July 747,600 46,760 August : ..;... 911,375 60,265 September 868,375 49,110 October 787,225 39,475 November 217,525 13,945 December 335,475 21.605 TT , . , 6,075,700 -381,055 Used by plant 17,625 3,500 Total 6,093.325 384,555 Tntnl I 1 " °? hand ., January 1 -' 1931 • 9,164,200 c.c. iotal gross sales from all sources .—...$44,035.95 Money collected and receipted for. 43 06447 Cash balance January 1, 1931 * $56,840.08 Value stock invoice January 1, 1931 50 000 00 Accounts payable 971 48 Total assets 1 $107 811 56 Pigs used in retesting serum and making virus.' 378 Number of orders for year t 2,406 ' NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION Agronomy.— The work of the North Platte Substation has I e 1 n o&lt;^ rried / 1 . on8r lines Previously, determined. The season of 1929 was fairly good from the standpoint of crop produc - tion. The portion of the present crop season included in this report was marked by radical variations from normal weather conditions in temperature and precipitation. On the whole the crop prospects appear quite favorable and bid fair to result in good yields. The favorable moisture conditions now prevailing tend, as they always do, to reduce differences which frequently occur in tillage practices. At the same time they bring into evidence the effects of various cropping systems and soil treatments upon soil fertility. There is a noticeable </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Forty-fourth Annual Report difference in crop growth between continuously cropped land and rotations where either barnyard manure or green manure crops have been used. This difference lias not been obvious during periods of less favorable moisture conditions. Crop-rotation and tillage-method studies in co-operation with the United States Bureau of Plant Industry, Office of Dry Land Agriculture, have been in progress for 24 years. Altho it is recognized that moisture variations are the chief cause of high and low yields of all crops, the crop results secured show that good tillage is of great importance. Early tillage to control weeds after harvest lias for the past ten years increased the average yield of winder wheat more than 30 per cent and the average yields of barley, oats, and corn, about 25 per cent. The season of 1929 completed the seventh year of crop im - provement work in co-operation with the U. S. Bureau of Plant Industry, Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases. Several promising strains of winter wheat and barley have been ad - vanced from the nursery to field trials. Among varieties that have so far given best results are Nebraska No. 60, Kanred, and Montana, among the winter wheats ; Ceres spring wheat ; Sandrel, McClymont and Trebi barleys; and Iowar and Burt oats. Progress is being made in developing grains which are resistant to smuts. During 1929, water was applied by pump irrigation to a total of 90 acres of various crops. The average increased net return from the use of water from all crops was $15.25 per acre. During the vear Circular No. 38 was published, entitled "Seed Corn Treatments at the North Platte Substation." A rather comprehensive test of the various seed corn treatments failed to reveal any benefit from their use. This is in agree - ment with data obtained at the main station at Lincoln. Beef Cattle. — The experimental work with livestock has been retarded because of the lack of a technically trained man to carry it on. For this work Mr. Marvel L. Baker has been engaged, his services beginning on July 1, 1930. Two herds of beef cattle are maintained, one of Hereford's and one of Shorthorns. In the*future the progeny of the herd will be used largely for experimental [purposes, altho out - standing individuals may be sold to farmers and ranchers for breeding purposes. During the past year there was published Bulletin No. 239 on "The Use of Alfalfa Pasture for Fattening Cattle." In the test on pastures it was found that heifers fed on alfalfa pasture and corn returned a greater profit than those fed </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station alfalfa hay and corn, even after allowing reasonable rental for the alfalfa pasture. Plans are now being made for a study of the value of wheat and rye in the fattening ration of cattle. Dairying.— The dairy herd is entirely Holsteins, and all purebred. The herd has become outstanding in production During the past year several 1,000-pound butter records have been made. A number of quite promising heifers are being developed. The splendid performance record, as well as the type of animals, is evidence of what may be accomplished thru the careful breeding, selection, and care of a dairy herd. Most of the young animals in excess of those needed in the herd have been sold to farmers within the state. A few young bulls have been sold to be used in outstanding herds in other states. On the whole the herd has had a marked influence in establishing good dairy stock in the western part of the state. Hog Production.— The station maintains a creditable herd °- f eed i ng TT S^? k - At the time of this re P°rt " con - sists^of 324 head. While some of the progeny are sold to farm - ers for breeding purposes, the majority are used in experi - mental feeding tests. 16 , past year Ex P eri ment Station Bulletin No. 243, entitled, "Pork Production at North Platte Substation," was published. Sheep Production.— A breeding flock of 65 Rambouillet ewes is maintained on a farm flock basis. Hampshire rams are be - ing used. It is expected that data on the cost of establishing and maintaining such a flock will be. secured. The feeding work being planned has for its object the study of the value of wheat and rye in the lamb-fattening ration. Horticulture and Forestry.— The growing of trees, shrubs, and flowers has been attracting more attention each year. Species of shrubs and trees are being grown quite satisfac - i i y il J£ 1S work has now been carried on for a sufficient length of time to indicate species and varieties that are hardy and worth while under the general environmental conditions of this region. SCOTTSBLUFP SUBSTATION The work at this station is in co-operation with the Office of Western Irription Agriculture of the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Most of the crops work is in definite projects planned on a long-time basis. Crop Rotations.— In all, thirty-four crop rotations, varying trom continuously cropped to seven-year plats, are carried on. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Forty-fourth Annual Report The plats are one-fourth acre in size. Results during the last year added further confirmation to the importance of soil fertility in the agriculture of this section. Rotations contain - ing a legume crop, either alfalfa or sweet clover, or receiving applications of barnyard manure gave uniformly higher yields than those not containing legumes or receiving applications of manure. The following table shows the] yields for the grow - ing season of 1929 under different methods of treatment. I Manure Sweet No and clover, Crops manure Manured Alfa if a alfalfa pastured Potatoes (bushels) .... I 152.2 320.7 315 6 I Sugar beets (tons).... 8.66 19.12 13 49 17.6 16.71 Corn (bushels) 27.0 4016 Oats (bushels) 29.2 71.0 79i9 88.5 64.6 Wheat (bushels) 11.5 22.4 ' In cropping system's where neither manure nor alfalfa has been used the yields of all crops have shown a decline, and have been less for the last five years than during the first five years of the experiment. Where applications of manure have been made or alfalfa included in the rotation, there has been an actual increase in the average yield of the past five years over the first five years. As an average for twelve years, sugar beets from unma - nured rotations yielded 10.1 tons per acre; where manure was applied, 18 tons per acre; where alfalfa 1 was included in the rotation, 16.6 tons per acre; and where both manure and alfalfa were used, 19.5 tons per acre. "V^here no manure was applied potatoes averaged 145.2 bushels; on manured land, 234.7 bushels; and in rotations where alfalfa was included, 310.3 bushels per acre. The average yield of corn was 30.1 from unmanured land and 58.5 bushels |per acre in rotations including alfalfa. Oats gave a yield of 42.4 bushels on un - manured land, 65.3 bushels on manured land, and 69.8 bushels in rotations with alfalfa. The yield of wheat was approxi - mately 50 per cent .greater following alfalfa than on unma - nured land. Other crop work is being carried on, including variety test - ing and cultural practices concerning the production of small grains, beans, alfalfa, sweet clover, sugar beets, and potatoes. During the current year work on various cultural practices </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station in the production of beets has been started in co-operation with the Office of Sugar Beet Investigations. Lamb Feeding. — Each winter the station conducts a rather extensive set of lamb-feeding experiments, which test the locally grown feeds. In these tests thirteen lots of lambs and thirteen different rations are used. The practice has been to publish the results in three-year periods. Four bulletins have previously been published. The results of the past year's tests show that the cost of 100 pounds of gain varied from $6.32 for corn, pulp, cottonseed cake, beet tops, and alfalfa, to $9.14 where corn, dry pulp, and alfalfa were fed. All lambs fed during the past year were fed at a loss, as was quite general thruout the valley. The losses ranged from 64 cents to $3.07 per head. Dairying. — During the past year the dairy herd was divided into two lots, one receiving one pound of grain for each four pounds of milk produced, and the other receiving no grain. It is too early to draw conclusions, but it is very evident that heavy-producing cows cannot maintain body weight without grain. The average production for the cows in the herd was 470 pounds of butterfat. Beef Calves. — For the past several years the station has been carrying on a test of the cost of wintering range calves on different rations, and then noting the effect of the winter feed on the gains during the following summer. The purpose is to find out whether or not it is economical to carry young range animals thru the winter on irrigated farms. The winter feeding period has averaged about 160 days, and the cost of wintering has varied from $9.93 to $12.82 per head. Figured on the cost of 100 pounds of gain, the cheapest gain has been the largest gain and has been from silage and cotton - seed cake, while the most expensive gain has been made on alfalfa alone. During the summers following the winter feed - ing the gains have been in reverse. The calves fed alfalfa hay alone have made the greatest gains and those fed silage and cottonseed cake the lowest. Hogs. — The work with hogs has been continued as in years past. Poultry. — The poultry flock is kept for demonstrational rather than experimental purposes. The White Leghorns, kept for egg production, and the turkeys showed a profit over pro - duction costs during the past year. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Forty-fourth Annual Report valentine substation Crop conditions were about normal in spite of the fact that there was an excess in annual precipitation. The United States Weather Bureau has set a new normal of 18.34 inches for Valentine, which is 4.12 inches below the former normal. Improvements in the physical plant consisted of filling in around the barn and laying some concrete. The houses and main barn were painted and a shelter belt: of trees was planted south of the buildings. Beef Cattle. — The project on supplemjental feeds for win - tering range calves was quite largely a repetition of the pre - vious two years' work and the results agree very closely. Two new phases were added. The feeding of two pounds of oats compared favorably with feeding three-fourths pound of cottonseed cake, and the replacing of (30 per cent of the prairie hay with alfalfa returned practically the same profit as feeding one pound of cottonseed cake with prairie hay. These results demonstrate the value of home-grown feeds as a supplement to prairie hay. Dairy Cattle. — The dairy herd has been reduced in size. Ten females were sold in an effort to free the herd from con - tagious abortion. The project comparing the cost of milk and fat production from purebred Holsteins and grade Short - horns has been discontinued and the latter cows sold. The following figures show a three-year average feed cost per unit of production. Holsteins — $1.00 per 100 pounds of milk, $.25 per pound of fat. Shorthorns — $1.23 per 100 pounds of milk, $.30 per pound of fat. Poultry. — In the turkey-raising project the of an early hatch was shown. Late-hatched poults sold for 10 cents per pound less and many could not be sold on account of colds. Flock-mating 40 hens with 3 has given good fertility, when the toms have been at all congenial with each other. Cereal Crops. — Small-grain yields were about average. Oats produced fewer pounds per acre than barley, emmer, or spring wheat. Comfort barley was again the I high-yielding barley variety and stood enough taller than common barley to bind" into a good bundle. Ceres spring wheat showed a slight ad - vantage in yield over Marquis. An attempt to grow some flax varieties on corn ground proved futile on account of weeds. . </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Forage Crops. — The amber sorghums produced more for - age than any other feed crop. Intertilled seedings outyielded broadcast. Meadow Investigations. — Seeding tame grasses and clover on subirrigated meadows has again demonstrated the inad - visability of seeding where it is further than three feet to water. Seeding on marginal land is often unsatisfactory be - cause of the annual fluctuation of the water table. CHANGES IN STAFF Professor 0. W. Sjogren, who had been on leave of absence for one year, resigned effective January 1, 1930, and Pro - fessor E. E. Brackett was made chairman of the Department of Agricultural Engineering, effective on the same date. Two men were detailed from the Department of Agricul - ture, Washington, D. C, as follows: Coit A. Suneson, Research Assistant in Agronomy. De - tailed from the Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases. Nelson E. Jodon,Research Assistant in Agronomy, Experi - mental Substation, ' North Platte, Nebraska. Detailed from the Office of Dry Land Agriculture. PUBLICATIONS OF THE LAST FISCAL YEAR The publications of the Station for the fiscal year covered by this report are as follows : Forty-third Annual Report, presented to the Governor, February 1, 1930. 2,000 copies. BULLETINS No. 236, Rural Electric Service Supplied from Central Stations in Nebraska in 1927. Brackett and Lewis. July, 1929. 5,000 copies. No. 237, Cane versus Spur Pruning for Grapes. C. C. Wiggans. November, 1929. 4,000 copies. No. 238, Routine and Seasonal Work of the Nebraska Farm Home - maker. M. Ruth Clark and Greta Gray. January, 1930. 3,000 copies. No. 239, The Use of Alfalfa Pasture for Fattening Cattle. W. P. Snyder. March, 1930. 5,000 copies. No. 240, Alfalfa Wilt in Nebraska. George L. Peltier and James H. Jensen. April, 1930. 6,000 copies. No. 241, Clover in the Subirrigated Meadows of the Sand Hills. E. M. Brouse. April, 1930. 3,000 copies. No. 242, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1920-1929. Brackett, Smith, Lewis, Wallace, Adams. March, 1930. 8,000 copies. No. 243, Pork Production at the North Platte Substation. W. P. Snyder. April, 1930. 5,000 copies. No. 244, Types of Farming in Nebraska. Harold Hedges and F. F. Elliott. May, 1930. 10,000 copies. No. 245, Water Supply and Sewage Disposal Systems for Farm Homes. Ivan D. Wood and E. B. Lewis. 15,000 copies. No. 246, Testing Ice Cream for Butterfat. L. K. Crowe. 5,000 copies. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Forty-fourth Annual Report '■ ■ RESEARCH BULLETINS No. 43, On the Nature and Cause of the "Walking Disease" of Northwestern Nebraska. Van Es, Cantwell, Martin, Kramer. July, 1929. 5,000 copies. No. 44, Seed Potato Treatment Tests for Control of Scab and Rhiz - octonia. R. W. Goss and H. O. Werner. . December, 1929. 3,000 copies. . • • • No. 45, Effect of Cultural Methods and Maturity upon the Seed Value of Eastern Nebraska Potatoes. H. O. Werner. December, 1929. 3,000 copies. No. 46, The Economic Aspects of Abortion! in a Dairy Herd. De - partment of Dairy Husbandry. May, 1930. 5,000 copies. No. 47, The Symptoms of Spindle Tuber and Unmottled Curly Dwarf of the Potato. R. W. Goss. May, 1930. 3,000 copies. CIRCULARS No. 38, Seed Corn Treatments at the North Platte Substation. L. L. Zook and N. E. Jodon. February, 1930. 2,000 copies. No. 39, Swine Sanitation. L. Van Es. March, 1930. 20,000 copies. TECHNICAL PAPERS Ackerson, C. W., Blish, M. J., and Mussehl, F. E. A Study of the Comparative Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry Feeding. Poultry Sci., 9:112-132. August, 1929. Ackerson, C- W., and Mussehl, F. E. Sex Differences in the Normal Growth Rate of Chicks. Jour, of Agr. Research, 40:863-866. May, 1930. Anderson, Arthur, and Kiesselbach, T. A. Cultural Tests with the Jerusalem Artichoke. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 21, No. 10. October, 1929. Blish, M. J. Reporting System for Standard Experimental Baking Test. Cereal Chem., 6:253-258. July,. 1929. | Blish, M. J. Report on Experimental Baking Test. Jour. Assoc. Off. Agr. Chem., 12:395-398. November, 1929. Blish, M. J. Report on Glutenin in Flour. Jour. Assoc. Off. Agr. Chem., 12:388-389. November, 1929. Blish, M. J., and Sandstedt, R. M. Concerning the Nature of the Protein Extracted from Wheat Flour by Hot Alcohol. Cereal Chem., 6:494-503. November, 1929. Blish, M. J., and Sandstedt, R. M. the Nature and Identity of Wheat Glutenin. Jour. Bipl. Chem., 85:195-206. December, 1929. Blish, M. J., and Hites, B. D. A Rapid and Simple Carbide Method for Estimating Moisture in Flour. Cereal Chem., 7:99-107. March, 1930. Blish, M. J. Report of Committee on Methods of Analysis. Cereal Chem., 6:423-429. September, 1929. Downs, P. A. A Survey of Present Methods of Grading Milk at Condenseries, Evaporated, and Dry Milk Plants. Jour. Dairy Sci., Vol. 12. No. 51. September, 1929. Goss, R. W. Insect Transmission of Potato Virus Diseases. Ab - stract in Phytopathology, Vol. 20, No. L January, 1929. Hays, C. H., and Van Es, L. On the Nature, Cause, and Possible Prevention of the Walking Disease Among Horses and Cattle. Bulletin published by the Nebraska State Department [of Agriculture. 1929. Hurst, W. M., and Kiesselbach, T. A. Drying Alfalfa by Forced Draft with Heated Air. Agr. Engin., Vol. 10, No. 7. July, 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Kiesselbach, T. A., Anderson, A., and Peltier, G. L. A New Variety of Alfalfa. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol." 22, No. 2. February, 1930. Kiesselbach, T. A. Field Tests with Treated Seed Corn. Jour. Agr. Research, Vol. 40, No. 2. January, 1930. Kiesselbach, T. A. What About Corn Hybrids? Twenty-first Ann. Rept. Nebr. Crop Growers' Assoc. January, 1930. Martin, H. M. A Species of Eimeria from the Muskrat. Arch. Protistenk., 70:273. 1930. Martin, H. M. Coccidiosis of Fowls. Vet. Med., 15:346. 1930. Martin, H. M. Notes on Cestode Larvae. Jour. Amer. Vet. Med. Assoc, 29:804. 1930. Mussehl, F. E., and Ackerson, C. W. Irradiated Ergosterol as an Antirachitic for Chicks. Poultry Sci., Vol. 9, No. 5, pp. 334-339. June, 1930. Mussehl, F. E., Hill, F. S., Blish, M. J., and Ackerson, C. W. Utilization of Calcium by the Growing Chick. Jour. Agr. Research, 40:191-199. January 15, 1930. Peltier, G. L. Some Aspects of the Spread of Stem Rust. Centbl. Bakt., II. Abt., 78:525-535. 1929. Russel, J. C. Observations on Plastic Flow in Soils. Report of the Tenth Annual Meeting Amer. Soil Survey Assoc. Bulletin 11, 1929. Russel, J. C. The Use of Supplemental Water. Agr. Engin., Vol. 11, No. 3. March, 1930. Russel, J. C. Drought and Its Relation to the Practice of Supple - mental Irrigation. Agr. Engin., Vol. 11, No. 3. March, 1930. Van Es, L. Undulant Fever in Man and Its Relation to Abortion Disease in Farm Livestock. Published by the Nebr. State Dept. of Agr. 1929. Werner, H. O. Relation of Time of Roguing to the Spread of Spindle Tuber • in Seed Potato Plats. Phytopathology, 19:1045-9. November, 1929. Werner, H. O., and Kiesselbach, T. A. The Effect of Vacant Hills and Plat Competition upon the Yield of Potatoes in Field Experiments. Potato Assoc. Amer. Proc, pp. 109-120. .December, 1929. Werner, H. O. Some Facts Concerning the Productivity of Irrigated Seed Potatoes. Potato Assoc. Amer. Proc, pp. 120-132. December, 1929. Yocum, W. W. The 1929 Spray Experiments at Shubert. Nebr. State Hort. Soc. Ann. Rept., pp. 47-51. LEGISLATION There was no new legislation affecting the work of the Experiment Station during the period covered by this report. ADDITIONAL LAND, BUILDINGS, AND EQUIPMENT At the North Platte Substation the feeding sheds, for beef cattle were completed, together with the necessary grading for corrals. Work was begun on a residence for the agron - omist. During the year the Experiment Station came into posses - sion of an additional tract of land consisting of 30 acres on which there is a fairly good house. This tract lies directly across from the Agronomy Farm, and is being assigned to Animal Husbandry for work iii swine production. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Forty-fourth Annual Report In accordance with the provisions made by the last legis - lature an experimental farm was established in Box Butte County in co-operation with the Board of | County Commission - ers. The County Commissioners have already on the land a barn, machine shed, dwelling house, and jwell, and the investi - gational work with crops has been started. THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF MONEY | RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT HATCH FUND " Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1930, under act of Congress approved March 2, 1887. Total $15,000.00 Expenditure* For salaries '. ...I $15,000.00 Total....: :... $15,000.00 ADAMS FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1930, under act of Congress approved March 16, 1906. Total L $15,000.00 Expenditures For salaries $15,000.00 Total $15,000.00 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska L E. GUNDERSON, Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station purnell fund Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of. the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1930, under act of Congress approved February 24, 1925. Total , :...$60,000.00 Expenditures SALARIES AND WAGES Regular employees $36,002.50 Temporary employees 7,633.01 Total - $43,635.51 SUPPLIES Office supplies $ 56.66 Laboratory supplies 2,262.69 Educational and recreational 125.33 Janitor and bam supplies 90.40 Feeding stuffs 4,344.92 Agricultural supplies ■. 504.80 Total 7,384.80 EXPENSE Office expense and postage - ...$ 85.39 Freight, express, and drayage 3.79 Water, heat, light, power, and fuel.... 22.75 Public printing, advertising, and photo supplies 1,953.59 Traveling expense 1,908.33 Rentals 44.50 Special and temporary service 2,245.32 Miscellaneous 16.99 Total 6,280.66 REPAIRS Building ...$ 104.48 Land 134.89 Equipment „. 301.13 Total.. ..'. 540.50 EQUIPMENT Furniture and fixtures $ 127.32 Apparatus, labor, and equipment 1,355.60 Machinery . 550.32 Books, magazines, and maps.... 58.09 Total 2,091.33 LAND AND BUILDINGS Land improvements $ 67.20 Total.. 67.20 GRAND TOTAL $60,000.00 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska L. E. GUNDERSON, Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Forty-fourth Annual Report financial statement Statement of expenditures for the Agricultural Experiment Station of the University of Nebraska for the year ending June 30, 1930 (ex - clusive of Federal funds), including expenditures for central station at Lincoln and substations at North Platte, Scottsbluff, Valentine, Union, and Alliance. SALARIES AND WAGES Regular employees ; $75,625.02J Temporary employees 8,218.50 Total $83,843.52 SUPPLIES Office supplies $ 1,266.24 Laboratory supplies 4,866.11 Fuel 2,207.91; Food stuffs 2,181.79 Educational and recreational 106.74 Janitor and barn supplies 358.99 Feeding stuffs 35,697.45 Agricultural supplies 6.287.2SJ Total 52,972.51 EXPENSE Office expense and postage $ 982.12 Freight, express, and drayage 2,007.81 Water, heat, light, and power 4,552.26 Public printing, advertising, and photo supplies 1,638.96 Traveling expense.... 3,786.58 Rentals 163.25 Special and temporary services 30,650.12 Miscellaneous 1,897.29 Total 45,678.39 REPAIRS Buildings $ 4,119.86 Lands 210.53 Equipment 5,429.56 Total : 9,759.95 . EQUIPMENT Furniture and fixtures : $ 1,064.27 Apparatus, labor, and equipment.... 4,323.01 Livestock 19,046.17 Machinery 6,017.93 Books, magazines, and maps 289. 4^ Total | 30,740.85 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station lands and buildings Land improvements. $ 1,014.93 Original construction 351.25 Additions and improvements 579.69 Total ■....:.. 1,945.87 GRAND TOTAL $224,941.09 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska L. E. GUNDERSON, Finance Secretary. [2M] "' . • ' .'■■'•'■''':'' </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>