<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00013.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00013.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA REPORT OF THE STATE LIBRARIAN FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1904.</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF XKHRASKA R EPORT OF THE State Librarian FOR THE Two Vkaks Ending November :$(&gt;. 19O4. EB. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Offick or State Ljbi; Lincoln, December 20, 19 To his Excellency John H. Mickey, Governor of Nebraska I have the honor to submit my official rei&gt;ort libra rian for the biennial period ending November 80, l'.»04. The number of volumes in the library Novenibei with the accessions thereto to November 80, 19 -hown us follows: Volumes on hand November 80, l'.tdi' . 17,249 Volumes purchased 1,154 Volumes received by purchase and exchang- Volumes on hand November 30, l ( .K&gt;4 ' Generally speaking the library is in good condition. Its growth has been fairly commensurate with the demands made upon it, and it is a credit to the wisdom and foresight of the members of preceding legislatures who have made the m sary appropi-iations of the public funds for its maintenan&lt; The library has outgrown its allotted space in the house. Every foot of available shelf room for books is now used, and books are necessarily being piled on the floor and in the windows. Within the next two years it is reasonable to presume that 3,500 volumes will be added to the libra i It is to be hoped that the legislature will carefully ii gate this need and provide additional room at an early d The appendix to this report contains a list of the ;i to the library alphabetically arranged and a statement of the condition of the library funds. Very respectfully H. C. IjInd- State Librarian </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">5 STATE LIBRARY. FIND FOH PIKCHASK OF BOOKS DK Amount appropriated 1901, unexpended.. Amount appropriated, 1908 7,l&gt; lt«&gt;i to whom paid vnrcHH 19, Lincoln Book Store 10"&gt;0 *16.45 1903 Jan. 28, Columbia Law Revie . 1 ()."&gt;! Jan. 28, The Lanning Co. . . 1062 Jan. 28, Nebr. State Journal 1058 Jan. 28, Lawyers Co-op. Pub. to. . ior&gt;4 Jan. 2 E. Bowman 105S Jan. 28, T. &amp; J. W. Johnson 1056 Jan. 28, Bancroft Whitney Go 1067 Jan. L'*, James D. Cockroft 1068 Jan. 28, Edward Thompson Od 1058 Jan. 28, The Mic-hie Co. ... 1080 June 10, C&amp;llaghan &amp; Co. . . . 1061 June 10, Bee Pub. Co lo*o June 10, World Pub. Co KM June 10, J. D. P. Schenk. . . 1082 June 10, Lanning Co 1088 June 10, Joel Munsells Sons .10*4 June 10, Leonard Scott ( June 10, Carswell Co June 10, Callaghan &amp; Co June 10, Cumulative Index Co June 10, Michie Co June 10, Edward Thompson Co I June 10, Central Law Journal 1091 June 10, T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1092 June 10, Boston Book Company 1098 Aug. 24, R H. Gillespie Aug. l'4. Mississippi Prese Aug. 24, State Journal &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 TO WHOM PAID. I. 24, Statf Journal Company 1&lt; 22, Murdoc-k Law Book Co 1100 West Pub. Co 1101 .T. D. P. Schenck 1102 12.00 Y T ernon Richards Co 1103 Boston Book Company 1104 84 Aug. 24, State Journal Company 109m West Pub. Co 1101 — 22, J. D. P. Schenck 1 102 22, Vernon Richards Co 1103 22, Boston Book Company 1104 341.83 A. C. IfoCtargOo 1106 4.14 V C. MeClurgCo 1106 4.14 Edward Thompson Co 1108 18.00 22, Bancroft Whitney Go 1 107 22, Cumulative Index Co 1 ion - 22, Keefe- Davidson Law Book Co 1109 22, Banks Law Pub. O ...1110 — i T. &amp; J. W. Johnson 1111 22. Federal Book Co. (Lamb) .... 1 1 12 22, Lincoln Book Co 1113 82, Bancroft Whitney Ca 1114 3-&gt; i » i &lt; tet 22, Dotld Mead &amp; Co 1115 22, Lawyers Co-op. Pub. Co ... . lllti -well Co.' Limited 1117 22, Library Bureau . . 11 \f* 22, James D. Cockcroft 1119 30, West Pub. Co . .1123 Robt. H. Gillespie .1124 30, Robt. H. Gillespie 1125 Nov. 14 G. A. Proffitt . . .. . .1128 11, Callajfhan * I 1127 Dec. 1 1 Statute Law Book Co 112m Dec. 11, Wm. F. Boogher 1 129 II, W. H. Moor. 1180 10.00 11. Frank Shepard Co 1131 Dec. 11, Frank Shepard i q .1132 1904 Jan. McClurtf &amp; Co 118Q Jan. 2, Library Bureau. . . . . 113ti Jan. 2, Dodd Mead &amp; Co 1K57 Jan. 2, John D. Morris &amp; Co 113H Jan. 2, Bancroft Whitney Co 1 139 Jan. 2, J. D. P. Schenck 1140 Jan. 2, Poors R. R. Manual Co 1141 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">VM)A TO WHOM PAID. Mar. 4, W. H. Moore 1142 - Mar. 4, Banks Law Pub. Co 1 14:5 Mar. 4, Keeff- Davidson Co 1 144 Mar. 4, T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1 147. Mar. 4, Lawyers Co-op Pub. Co 1 146 Mar. 4, Boston Book Co 1 147 Mar. 4, Neb. State Journal 1 148 Mar. 4, Canada Law Book Co 1 149 Mar. 4, A. C. McClurg &amp; Co 1150 2.40 Mar. 4, Edward Thompson Co 1 1 T&gt; 1 12.IX' Mar. 4, Michie Co 1152 Mar. 4, Carswell Co 1158 J7 .•':• t Mar. 4, L. D. Powell 0 ....1154 Mar. 4, T. E. Sedgwick 115.") Mar. 4, The Hubbell Pub. Co 1 156 Mar. 4, T. K. Jones. ( Bee&amp; Herald) .. li:&gt;7 Mar. 4. Statute Law Book Co 115* Mar. 4, T. &amp; J. W. Johnson &amp; Co. ... 1159 Mar. 4, Bancroft Whitney Co 1160 Mar. 4, American Law Book Co 1 161 Mar. 4. West Pub. Co 1162 Apr. 8, Lincoln Book Store 1 169 H Apr. 8, H. H. Wilson 1 170 h Apr. H, J. D. P. Schenck .1171 H Apr. K, Publishers Weekly. 1172 Apr. 8, Robert H. Gillespie 1 17M May 20, Miller &amp; Paine 1174 17.40 Mav 20. Columbia Law Review 1175 Mav 20, R . H . Wolcott 1 176 Mav 20, West Pub. Co 1 177 May 20, Dodd Mead &amp; Co 117m 11.20 May 20, Lawyers Coop Pub. Co. ... 1179 25.00 Mav 20. Federal Book Co 1 1*0 14. 00 May 20. Moulton Pub. Co. . .11*1 20. Callaghan &amp; Co. ... .1182 164.14 Mav 20, T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1188 Mav 20, Boston Book Co 1 1*4 Mav 20, American Law Book Co .... 1 1*5 July 12. J. D. P. Schenck 1190 24.00 Julv 12. Geo. W. Martin.. 1191 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 li»04 0 WHOM PAID. Nil July 12, Miller &amp; Paine 1 192 July 12. MichieCo .1198 July 12. Mathew Bender. . .1191 Aug. 4, Callaghan &amp; Co 1195 Aug. 4, Boston Book Co. ... , .1196 Aug. 4. Frank Shepard &lt; 1197 Aug. 4, Keefe Davidson Co 1 19* Aug. 4. Ro'-)t. H. (Jillespie 1199 Aug. 4, Bancroft Whitney Co 1200 Aug. 4, Soney &amp; Sage 1201 Aug. 4, West Pub. &lt; .1802 61.45 Aug. 4. L. D. Powell 1208 Aug. 4, R. H. Gillespie 1205 1. J. D. P.Schenck .1206 Oct. 1, Law.\ op. Pub. Co. ..1207 Oct. 1, James D. Cockcroft 1208 Oet. 1. Moulton Pub. Co 1209 Oct. 1, Scientific American 121 1 Oct. 1, W. H. Moore 1212 Oct. 1, F. H. Thomas L. B. Co 1213 Oct. 1, American Law Book Co 1214 Oct . 1 , James D . Cockcroft 121 "&gt; Oct. 1, Murdock Law Book Co 1216 Oct. 1, Banks Law Book Co 1217 Oct. 1, T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1248 Oct. 1, J. E. Cobbey 1219 1, Edward Thompson Co 1220 Nov. 28 West Pub. Co 1221 Nov. 28, Medico Legal Journal. 1222 Nov. 28, Nat! Soc. D. A. R 1223 Lapsed from appropriation of 1901 Amount of appropriation, 19(13, unexpend I I I . _' ed November 80, 1904 1 S7 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 rXIVKKSITY LIBRARY FIND FOK Priil'MASK OF HOOKS I)H ount appropriated, 1903 Sl.tX*) (HI TO WHOM PAID. '**" June !(•, Boston Book Co 10&lt;&gt;4 uBookr,, 1099 . W.»st Pub I -'i', Baker Voorhis 4 Co .1121 2-2. Boston Book Co 1 122 ;fcUN&gt; 1 1, Frank Shepard Co 1 188 •&gt;O.(MI 11, T. H. Flood 4 Co 1184 1904 March 4. Baker Voorhis Co 1 UYA arch 1. Baker Voorhis Co 1 81.15 March 4, Charles W. Seaver &amp; Son. .. 1164 arch 4, Chart r A Son...llt&gt;4 March 4, J . H. Beale Jr 1 165 arch 4, J . H. Beale Jr 1 165 arch 4. West Pub. Co 1188 March 4. West Pub. Co 1166 March 4, Edward Thompson Co 1187 arch 4, Edward Thompson Co llt&gt;7 March 4, Keefe Davidson Co 116m arch 4, Keefe Davidson Co 1 June 10, T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1 W, me 10, T. H. Flood &amp; Co 1186 June lo, West Pub. Co .1187 ine 10, West Pub. Co 11-7 June 10, Boston Book Co 1188 me 10, Boston Book Co 1 June 10, Edward Thompson Co 1 ine 10, Edward Thompson Co 1 Amount of appropriation, 1908, unexpend- Int of appropriation, 1908, unexpend - ed November 3n, lCM&gt;4 ■•Him - The following items for the purchase of books for the - library were paid under the provisions of a deficiency bill ■d by the legislature of liX»:J: TO WHOM PAID. HEK June 10, Jacob North &amp; Co 1062 June K&gt;, New Talmud Co 1CH 10.00 June 10, T. H. Flood &amp; Co KHU June 10, MichieCo 10 June 10, Geo. E. Bowman, Mayflr Des 1067 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 TO WHOM PAID. Vilt'CHKK AMOUNT No. June 10, Pub. Policy Co 1&lt;*&gt;* June 10, Pub. Policy Co 10 June 10, Funk &amp; Wagnalls 1069 June 10. Funk &amp; Wagnalls 1008 :&gt;.oo June 10, Dodd Mead &amp; Co 1070 IH.nm June in. Dodd Mead &amp; Co loTo June 10, Boston Book Co loTl 101.90 June 10, Boston Book Co loTl 391.90 June Id. Moulton Pub.Co loTii 5.00 June 10. Moulton Pub. Co 1072 5.00 June 10, John D. Morris lo7:i 47. "&gt;o June 10, John D. Morris 1073 47.50 June lo. West Pub. Co 1074 189 June 10. West Pub. Co 1074 June 10, W. H. Moore 1077) June lo. \V. H. Moore 1075 171.70 171. 7o June lo. Banks Law Pub Co lo7t&gt; June lo. Banks Law Pub Co 1078 52 . 15 15 June 10. The World Pub. Co K&gt;77 12.00 June 10. The World Pub. Co U&gt;77 12.00 June 10. H. V. &amp; H. W. Poor lo7^ 10.00 June 10. H. V. &amp; H. W. Poor 107* June lo. Neb. State Journal lo7 ; .t Total June lo. Neb. State Journal lo7:&gt; 7.:&gt;" Total $1,12 7.50 $1,123.65 STATE LIBRARY STATE LIBRARY. BOOKS. BLANKS. STATIONERY. EXPRESS. POSTAGE, TELEGRAPH, BOOKS. BLANKS. STATIONERY, EXPRESS. POSTAGE, TELEGRAPH, ETC ET&lt; Amount appropriation, 1903 fci H&gt;0 00 «&gt;unt appropriation, 190)! 12,000 09 Amount # expended to November 80, l'.H&gt;4 ■ ■ si .471 . 85 Amount # expended to November 80, l'.H&gt;4 Amount unexpended November 80, 19o4 $1,471.85 Amount unexpended November 81 &gt;. 1 9o4 . . 528 . 1 ."• 528.15 12 omi no $2ooo imi in mi SUPREME COURT SUPREME COURT. BOOKS, BLANKS. STATIONERY, EXPRESS, POSTAGE, TELEGRAPH, BOOKS, BLANKS. STATIONERY, EXPRESS, POSTAGE. TKLBQKAPH, ETC. ETC Amount appropriation, 1908 $8,500.00 &gt;unt expended to November 80, 1904 . . &gt;unt unexpended November 80, l ( .*o4 . . 117. 7t&gt; Amount appropriation, 1903 $3,500.00 &gt;unt expended to November B0, 1904. 80, 1904. -J.L'4 . &gt;unt unexpended November 117. 7t» 13,500.00 :,ihmh&gt; $3,500.00 BAR EXAM IN ATK &gt;N FUND . BAR EXAMINATION FUND Amount on hand November 30, I!*):.' sC&gt;44 . 85 Amount on hand November 80, 1902 SC&gt;44 . 85 ■ived from applicants l,ir&gt;r&gt;.oo ursements on order supreme court 9 28 Balance, November 80, 1904 L .57 51,700.85 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 SUPREME COURT REPORTS On hand Nov. 30, 1902. ... lft,71fi ■ived in volume H2 Received in volume C&gt;:5 Ijhmi Received in volume 64 l.iMMt Received in volume 65 Ijmmi Received in volume 1, Unofficial Received in volume 2, Unofficial . . Ijmmi Received in volume 3, Unofficial 1 jmm» Distributed Free as provided by law to State and Federal Courts, District Judges, County Judges, State Officers, Court and Consultation rooms, copyright, and exchange for other books 4,178 Sold Damaged books on hand . . . On hand November 80. 1!»&lt;&gt;4 I'ajur. : For the sale of 4.176 volumes of reports there has been re ceived the sum of *4.:{67.&lt;M&gt; and the said amount has been to the State Treasurer. SESSION LAWS 1!*&lt;&gt; volumes of the session laws of 1908 have been sold at fifty cents per volume, amounting to &amp;♦"&gt;.&lt; x i, which sum paid to th*&gt; State Trc </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013">vppkxdix </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015">15 ADDITIONS TO THE STATE LIBRARY FOR THF Pwo Years Ending November 30, The figures in ( ) indicate the source from which the ived, thus (1), received by purcha- lonation: (4) from officers of the state and genera nent A tt, Austin. Trial brief on the pleadings in ci\ v.l, 2. 19(&gt;4 Alabama. General acts. 1903 Official and statistical register. 190 Supreme court reports, v. 131-139 . . \laska. District court reports, v.l. 1903.. (II Albany law journal, v. 64 II) \merican annual catalogue. 1900-08. v. 1 . (1) American bankruptcy reports, r. 8-11 ( 1 ) American bar association reports, v. 25-26 American criminal reports, v. 11 ... American digest (annual), UXtfB-HXMA American digest (century ed.) v. 36-50 &lt; 1 1 American electrical cas* 1 American historical review, v. 7-8 American journal of sociology, v. 7 - (II American law register, v. 41 1 1 1 American law review, v. 36 11) American lawyer, v. 10 &lt; 1 » American negligence cases, v. 14 ( 1 ) American negligence reports, v. 12-15 ( 1 &gt; American pharmaceutical association proceedings, 1 1903 American review of reviews, t. 21, ID American state reports, v. ( 1 ) American and English corporation cases, v. 16-19 American and English encyclopedia of law. (2d ed.) v. American and English railroad cas* American and .English railroad cases. Dig' </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 rican and English railroad reports, v. 10.. (1) Anthracite ooal strike, report of president. 190 (4) Appleton's annual cyclopedia, v. 7. 1908 (1 1 24,27,28 (1) Arizona. Session lav Supreme court reports, v. l 1 Ark. orporation laws. 1904... st of election laws. 1904. .. House journal. 19o4 Laws. 1903 Senate journal. 1904 Supreme court reports, v. 70-71 ■ Mark and William. Table of federal citations. 17 - 1901. v. 1-4 Hi rton, Gertrude. Rulers of kings. 190:: ( 1 ) i tic- monthly, v. 91 .... (It Atlantic reporter, v. ,"l' ."7 . ., (1 ) - Index-digest. 1902 (1) Auerbaeh. Berthold. On tlie heights (1 ) Stories by foreign authors. 1 898 ( 1 1 ■ ralia. Statutes of Queensland. ( 1) B win. Simeon. American railroad law. 1904. .. (1) ird, Emerson. Law of real property, v. !•. 1903. ( II ine. v. •" ( ] ) flanking v. 4 &lt; 1 1 king law journal, v. 19 ( 1 ) reports, v. 9 ( 1) Wyman on public service companies. 1902 (1) ird, Win. L. Church act. 1869 .... ( 1 ) ind, John. View of the world, v. 1-5 k. Henry C. American constitutional law. 1897. (1 ) hfield, DeWitt C. Instructions to juries. 1908 ( 1 ) e, Thomas A. Fomeroys'a code remedies (4th ed.) litoi (D Boogher. Win. Fletcher. Gleaning of Virgina history. 1903 (1) Bookman, The. v. 14 1* (1) Bourne. Edward n historical criticism. 1901 ... ulenburg, E. C. Law of bankruptcy. 19". (1 1 r, James H. Law of conveyancing. 1904 (D </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Bridge, .James H. Inside history of Carnegie steel com pany. I'M);! &gt;h Columbia. Department of agriculture. Deseripi pamphlet. 1!N):&gt; Report of 5th annual convention. 1'" Report of superintendent of farmers' instit 19oi&gt; Monal papers. 1902 Statutes. 1903 .... Statutes. 19o;{-4.. . Bronson, Harrison. Law of tixtu res. 1904. ill Brown, G. Waldo. The far east and new America, v. 1-6 . Ill vn. John H. Cyclopedia of American biography . » " Hurnham. Clara L* The right princess. 1002 (1) c • ( California. Assembly journal. 1903 Blue book. 100) Code of civil procedure. 1003 til Digest of supreme court reports. 1 !•»•;; 1 1 1 California. Assembly journal. 190J Blue book. ll*i:S . . . C(Kle of civil procedure. 1903 &lt; 1 1 Digest of supreme court reports. 1 General laws. I 1 .' &lt; 1 1 General laws. 1 * &lt; 1 i Penal code. 1008 Political code. 1903 (It Senate journal. 1901 Statutes and amendments to codes, lit" ( 1 1 Supreme court reports, v. 137-142 Canada. Annual digest of reports. 2 v. 1902-1903 U&gt; Census, v. 1. 1903. Geological survey Altitudes of Canada. I" Report of. 1898 .Journal of the house of commons. Law journal, v. 38-39 U&gt; Law times, v. 28 Hi Law time*. Annual digest. 1902 Ordinance of the Northwest Territory. 1903 Proceedings and transactions of the roj v. 7-9 Railway ort of landslide at Frank All i inal papers, 2d session. 9th parliament </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 onal papers. 8d session. Mb parliament, v pts. 1-12. ... (.') Statutes. 1908. v. 1-2 (2) Supreme court reports, w. 82 . ... (l'&gt; Yearbook. 1903 .. (3) Daniel M. Progressive men of Dodge county. 1902. &gt;n, Hampton L. History of the supreme court of the United States, v. 1-2. L902 (1) r Rapids. Report of free library. 1903 (2&gt; ral law journal, v. ~&gt;f) .... ( 1 ) Index. l ( .xr2 ... (1&gt; ■ ury magazine, v. 28, 4t&gt;. :&gt;7, 68, W, 66 (1 &gt; tterton, M. D. Probate law. w. 1-2. I'.tol (1) itaucjuan, The. ( 1 &gt; ( 'hicago legal news. v. 33 . ( 1 ) Chicago university register. L992-19O2 Chitty's English statutes, supplement, v. 14. 1*95-1901 ... (1 &gt; k, Henry H. Street railway accident law. 19&lt;4 ( 1 &gt; Clarke, Edward. Law of extradition. 19o:i ( 1 &gt; ent, G. A. Pire insurance. 1908 II ► »»nt. Geo. R. Probate reports, annotated, v. 7 (1 &gt; Clinical journal, v. 20-21 ( 1 &gt; rado. Court of appeals reixM'ts. v. 15-17. i'2) Laws. 1902 (2) Proceedings of state bar association. 1!*&gt;4 ( - J&gt; Report of superintendent of public instruction. IMS ... (2) Supreme court reports, v. ... i'2) ihoun, Patrick D. Summary of Roman civil law. v. 1-4. 1*49 (1) Columbia law review, w. 2, 8 &lt; 1 ) Columbia university. Catalogue. 1902-03; 1903-04 Connecticut. Annual report historical society. 1908-04 (2) General statutes, 1902 (2) Historical society collections. 19o-_' (2) History of the tirst commander of artillery (2) History of the ninth regiment. Connecticut volun - te. (2) Hospital for insane, report of. 19&lt;&gt;3 . . House journal. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Legislative manual, v. 4. 1903-4 . . List of bills reported upon by general assembly. 1903 Message of Governor Chamberlain. 190l&gt; Monument souvenir. HXt-J Public documents. 1901, v. 1-8; 1902, v. 1-4; 1904, v. l-;} .... Report of attorney general. I!**:! Senate journal. 1901 (2) Special laws. v. 14. 1909 .■librarian. Report. 1901-02 . (2) State register and manual. 1903 I • Supreme court reports, v. 75-78 .. (2) Contemporary review. (It . Walter I. Index to bankruptcy and bills of sale re - ports, v. 1 ( 1 1 Cook. William W. Law of corporations, v. 1-8. 190 (1) Thomas M. Constitutional limitations. 1 ( .»" (1) lopolitan, The. &lt; It Crane. Herbert S. Irrigation and water right* in brask;, Critic, v. 40. 49 &lt;1&gt; Cumulative index to periodicals v. 4. 1903 (1) Current law. v. 1-2. l'.H)4 (1) Cyclopaedia of American biography v. 7. 1 lit ( ■yclopedia of evidence, v. 1-3. 1 902-04 lit Cyclopedia of law and procedure, v. 9-13. 1908-04 111 I) A S America in the China relief expedition. 1903 tli Daniel, John W. Law of negotiable instruments, v. 1-2. I9us Deitch. (iuilford A. Digest of insurant ■ v. 15-16 II) Delaware. Auditor. Report. 1 90 Hrj (J) Duke of York, records. 1646-1671 I^iws. 1908 Supreme court reports, v. I Treasurer. Report. 1901-06 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Dickson. Harris. She that hesitates. 19(&gt;4 (1&gt; Dillon, John F. Life, character and judicial services of John Marshal, v. 1-3. 190H ID Dillon, John M. Marshals constitutional decisions. 1908.. (II District of Columbia. Code of laws. 1901 (2&gt; Court of appeals reports, v. 19-28 ( 1 ) rver, Louise P. Lineage book, daughters of American revolution, v. 12-18. 1900-1901 (1) Donnell, K. Irish land reports. 1878 ( 1) E Bankruptcy law. 1908 (1 &gt; on and Gilbert. Treatise on commercial paper. 1908.. U&gt; Edinburgh review, v. 197-19* ( 1 &gt; Educational review, v. 24 2a (II Elliot. Byron K. &amp;. W. F. Law of evidence, v. I. 1SKM 111 ng. W. W. Negroes of Columbia (■ &gt; &lt; loped ia Americana, v. [-18 ( 1 &gt; Engineering news. v. 45-49 ( 1 &gt; England. Acts of general assembly, Prince Edward Island ( 1 &gt; Bankruptcy reports, v. 1&lt;&gt; 1 1 &gt; Collection of statutes, v. 1-10 ( 1 &gt; I^aw journal reports, v. 71 in 8 pts: v. 72 in 8 pts . . (II Law reports. Appeal cases. 1902,1908. 2v. (1) Chancery division. 1902. v. 1-2; 190:1 v. 12 II &gt; King's bench division. 1902. v. 12. ! v. 1 2 .... (II Probate division. L902, 1 l . H &gt;; J ( 1 &gt; Law times, v. 11 1-1 1H (1&gt; Law times repo: I ( \) Mew's annual digest. 2 v. 1902, 1901 (1&gt; Revised reports, v. 57-69 (1 &gt; Solicitor's journal and reporter, v. 4C&gt;-47 (2) Statesman's year book. 1902 Statutory rules and orders revised, v. I &gt; (II Times law reports, r. 18-19 (1&gt; kly reporter, v. 50-51 (1&gt; English criminal cases . t. -19 ( 1 » English repofts (reprint I. v. 22-44. 1 ( .)()2. (1&gt; English ruling cases. l ( .»»i2. v. 26 (II </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 - K Third Massachusetts cavalry in the war for union . 1906 F Farnham. Henry P. Law of waters and water rights 8. HWU ial reporte r . v . 1 16-132 &lt; 1 1 Digest . v . : rai statutes. Annotated, v. 1-4. 1903,1904. (1» i Columbian inuseu in. Annual report, board of t&gt; tees, l90t . . . her. William I. Annual literary index . 19 &lt;1) ■her. Win . M . Equity pleading and pr; Florida. Session laws. Supreme court reports i 12 I lightly review, r. 71-74 Forum. The. v. Ill Frank, Nathan. Bankrupt law. annotated. l»9t (1) Freund, Ernst. Police power. 1004... G Gardner, Geo. E. Law of wills. 1903 has. Louisiana; its colonial history and romance rgia. Code. v. 1-8. 1806 House journal. 1902, 1903. 2 t Laws. \Uo-2. 1908. 2 v Senate journal . 1 9&lt;&gt;2, HX &gt;3 . i' v Supplement to code. v. 4. 1901... (1) Supreme cou rt reports . v . 115-119 (iilbert. Frank Fi. Street railway reports, v 1 L904 I It (•ould. John M . 1 jaw of contracts, v. 1-8 rand Tucker. Supplement to notes on i 1904 ;ne, JamesG. .W*- York annotates v. Ill: Griffin, A 1 ' tlect books relating to the fa Gunby. A. A. Address on negro education in the south Gunckle. Patrick H. Taxation o 1904. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 H Hadley, Arthur T. Education of American citizens. I! 1 Hamlin, Arthur. Copyright 1M04 (1&gt; Hamnion. Louis L. Law of chattel mortgages. 1JH)3 (1 &gt; Harper's magazine, w. 100, 108-106 &lt;1&gt; Hartford seminary record, v. 12-18 (1 &gt; Hartford theological seminary register, l'.toi -08 ird college. Annual report of president and tn urer, L900-08..' Harvard university. Annual report, 1901-02 Catalogue. 1902-03; 1903-04. 2 v (3) iii. Laws. 1903; Special session. 1904. 2 v Report of commissioner of labor. L908 Supreme court reports, v. 14-ltt (2) Heitman. Francis B. Historical register and dictionary of V. S. army. v. 1-2. 1903 &lt;4&gt; Helliwell, Arthur L. Law of stock and stockholders. 1 '.»»»:{. (l&gt; Henderson, John G. Chancery practice. 1W4 (1 &gt; Hepburn, A. B. History of coinage and currency . Heyse, Paul. Stories by foreign authors ( 1 &gt; Historical and political science journal, v. 20 ( 1 &gt; Homiletic review, v. 44-45 (1&gt; hkiss, Law of bankruptcy. 1908 (1) Howard. James I. History of the Louisiana purchase ( 1 &gt; Hubbel), J. H. Legal directory. UKH (1&gt; Hughes, Wm. T. Law of contracts. 1908 (1 &gt; Hunt, Alva. Law of tender. 1!M)3 (1 &gt; I Idaho. Digest of supreme court reports. 1890 (1 ) r Inspector of mines. Report of mining districts. 1903 Laws. 1908 Supreme court reports, v. 2-7. Illinois. Abbott's cyclopedic digest, v. 1-14. .. (1) — Appellate court reports, v. 103 1 1"_ ( . . . . (1 &gt; Blue book, 1903 (2) - Bureau of labor statistics. 21st annual report. Catalogue state library. !!»&lt;&gt;:; Ditrest of supreme and appellate court repot </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Digest of supreme court reports, v. 12. 1902 &lt; 1 1 Historical society publications, v. 7. 19 Laws. L9O3 Supplement to statutes, v. 4-."&gt;. l'.toi' • 1 » Supreme court reports, v. 15)7-209 .... Transactions of the historical society. l'.»t&gt; 4 Indian law reports. Allahabad series, v. L'.'i 2"&gt; Bombay series. Calcutta series. Madras series, v. 24-'_'t) &lt; 1 j Indian Territory. United States court of appeals repo r.8 Indiana. Adjutant general. Report. L901-02 Appellate court reports, v. 2H-31 . Attorney general. Report, 1901-02... Auditor. Report, 1901-02 Board of tax commissioners. Report, 1902 Bureau of statistics, 1902 Custodian of public buildings. Report. 1!M)2. . Digest, supreme and appellate court reports. 1902. (1) Fish and game commissioner. Report. 1901-08. . . Laws. 1!H&gt;;5 Legislative commission on educational and ben« lent institutions. Report. 1908 Purdue university. Catalogue. 1901-02 Revised statutes, v. 1-2. li»&lt;»l ill Secretary of state. 1901-02 State bar association, v. l-t&gt;. 1902-04 State board of charities. Report. 1901-02 . State board of medical registration and examina tion. Report. 1901 State horticultural society. Report. 191 State librarian. Report. 1902 Superintendent of public instruction. Report. 1902 Supreme court reports, v. 158-161. Treasurer. Report. 1902 Inland printer, v. 2!»-31 Insurance digest . 1908. v. 1 T» Hi Insurance law journal . v. 11 ( 1 &gt; Insurance man's practical digest 1 ' Mi </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Interstate commerce reports, t. 9 &lt;1&gt; Board of control of state institutions. Report, 1901. (2) Geological survey U»i&gt;l, 1904. 2 v Laws of 1904. Official register. 19&lt;H (2) •State bar association . nth annual report. li^M •^tate bur association proceedings. 1904 Supplement to eodc. l»o-2 Supreme court reports, v . L 15- 128 Ireland . Church act, 1869 Ill Digest of reports, ITfiit 1771: [867-1877. 2 f (1&gt; I rish law times, v. 36 ... ( 1 ) Irish reports, v. 1-2,1901;t. 1-2, L903 Ill .! Johns, Edward M . American notaries . l!« 14 ( I) ■is Hopkins university studies in historical and political science . v. 21 &lt; 1 » Jones, Ijeonard A. Law of mortgages . r. 1-2. 1W4 (1» Journal of Franklin institute . r. 152-156 ( 1 ( Journal of Franklin institute . v. 152-156 &lt; 1 ( Journal of historical and political science, v. 19-80 &lt;1&gt; Journal of historical and political science, v. 19-20 &lt;1&gt; Journal of political economy . v 10, 1 1 . ( 1 &gt; e, Joseph A. Treatise on damages . r. 1-8. 1904.... (1&gt; Journal of political economy . v 10, II. ( 1 &gt; Judson, Frederick Power of taxation. 1903 ill K ■ House journal, 1896, 1897, I special session: 1901; 1908 Laws, 11*08; special session; 1903 Proceedings state bar association . I'.mU Public documen 17-98, 1899-1900, 1901-02, 3 v Report of state bar association. 1903-04 Report of state librarian. 1900-02 i-l r Senate journal, 1895, 1898-99; special session l 1901-03 U&gt; Supreme court reports, v. 64-67 rcky. Acts of the general essembly, 1887-88; 1 4v Acts of the general assembly. l!'&lt;&gt;4 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Annual reports. 1901 . . ( ivil and criminal codes, v. 1902 Court of appeals report v. 105-112 Diyt'st of supreme court reports, v. 5. Documents. \\H )•_&gt;(»:!. v. 1-9.. House journal. 1!HM. Manual. l'.KH Monthly law record, v. 1 -:j (1) Senate journal. 1!H)4 . . Statutes. 18W fll Keltie, J. Scott Stateman'syear book. 1903 U&gt; Kinkead, Edgar B. Law of t&lt;»rts. v. 1-2. Mi Kinkead, Edgar B. Law of torts, v. 1-2. Mi L 't. ('. H. Law of master and servant. l'"U (1) 't, ('. B. Law of master and servant I9W (1) Iviw journal, v. 157 " ( 1 1 Iviw journal, v. :&gt;7 " ( 1 1 Lawyers' reports annotated, v. "&gt;7f&gt;4 (It i' reports annotated, v. r&gt;7 ti4 (1 » Lewis, John Henry. The Ik » (li I jewis. John Henry. The bo&gt;- (II Library journal, v. :it&gt;. 27 1 1 ) Library journal, v. :it&gt;. 27 1 1 ) IJndau, Paul. Hanging mo— ( 1 1 Lace ) 1 1 I jndau, Paul. Hanjfin^ mosfl ( 1 1 e Hi Lindley, Curtis- H. Law relating to mines and mi l. •_'. &lt;li Lindley, Curtis- H. Law relating to mines and mi 1. •_'. &lt;D Lippincott's magBMnfl v. 47. 51-54, •&gt;'.• 71 IJppincotfs magazine, v. 47, 51-54, ti!» 71 Literary diftest v. (D literary digest, v. 24-26 (1) ary ne\' 24 (1) Literary sen 24 (D U's living as*&gt;. v. 234-240.. Ixin^sdorf, iieo. R. Current law. v. L-2. 1 ( .'(M 111 Loti, Pierre. Into Morrotvo (1) Ixrti. Pierre. Into Morrocvo ( 1 1 Louisiana. Acts. 1902, UH&gt;4. 2 v. I»uisiana. Acts. L902, 1904. 2 v Attorney general. Re])ort, 1901-02 Attorney general. Rei&gt;ort, 1901-02 — — ('ode of practice in civil 1 Ml (I ('ode of practice in civil - • ( 1 ) — — Commissioner of agriculture. Annual r»&gt;]&gt;. liMXt 'Commissioner of agriculture. Annual repi liMXi — — Digest of laws, v . 1. 1804-1840. — — House journal. 1 !•&lt;•:.&gt; Digest of laws, v. 1. 1804-1840. (li Message of Governor Heard, l'-xii'. Railroad commissioners. 2d annual report, 1901 Revised and civil code. l!H&gt;i ( 1 1 Secretary of state. Report. 1900-01 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Senate journal. 1902 (l'&gt; Supreme court reports, v. 106-1 11 Treasurer. Report. l!»»Hi-(U Ijoveland, Prank. Law and proceedings in bankruptcy. IW&gt;4 &lt;1&gt; Forms of federal practice, v. 1-2. 1903 (1&gt; Luzerne legal register, v. II ( 1 ) le, Francis. The grafters ( 1 ) M lure's magazine, v. 1h, !&lt;♦ ( i ) McKinney. Win. N. Federal statutes, annotated, v. 1908 Supplement to encyclopedia of pleading and tice. v. 1. lt+03 ,'uillin. Law of municipal ordinances. I!»o4 1 -:;. (1) piac (1) 11» supplement to encyclopedia of pleading and prac tice. v. 1. lt+03. . . 11 &gt; ,'uillin. Law of municipal ordinances. I!»o4 1 1» Maine. House bills and documents. l!»o:!. _' v Maine. House bills and documents. l!»o:!. _' v House journal, li»o:{ (2) Laws, 1MI Legislative records. 1908 House journal, 1903 - Laws, 1!K)8 1'ublic documents, v. 1-4. lHj»;i Register and legislative manual. I!»o4 Report of president of Bowdoin college, 1901-0 Revised statutes. l!»o:S Senate bills and documents, 1903 senate journal. 1908 Supreme court reports, v. 1*6-98 York deeds, v. li\ pts. 1-2 Mallory, John A. United States compiled statutes, v. 1901 (1) ■t, Hector. Romain Kalbris ( 1 ) Manitoba. Revised statutes, v. 1-l'. 1902 (1) Statutes. 1903-04. 2v ( 1 ) Manson. Edward. Bankruptcy reports, v. 9-10 U ► v land. Court of api&gt;eals re]X)iT — Law review, v. 1-2 U I Manual of general courts. 19(&gt;:S State historical society. Annual report. 1902 Supreme court reports, v. !»7 Massachusetts. Acts and resolves, v. 10-12 Colonial laws, ltitio ...Ill </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE MBUAKIAN l'.HC! 1!M»4 27 i »r and industrial chronology. 1**03 slative manual. 1901-08 &gt;nd special statutes. \^-- Private and special statutes, v. l*&lt; Public documents, v. 1 li&gt;, 11H»1 ; v. 1-12, l»02 Soldiers and sailors of the revolutionary war. v Supreme court reports, v. 180-184 Vital records of Alford to 185&lt; Arlington to 1850 . . . Bar re to 1850 Berket to 1-" Bedford to 1850 . Belli ngham to 1850 t'hilmark to 1850 Gill to 1*50 Great Barrington to 1850 Hinsdale to 1850 Holden to !-:■• Lee to 1h5u Leicester to 185O. Lexington to 1850 Maiden to 1850.. .. Manchester to 1850 Marbtehead to I860. . Medtield to 1850 Medfiekl to I860 Middleton to I860 Middleton to I860 Milbury to I860.. Milbury to 1860. . New Braintree to l^r»(&gt; . . New Braintree to l*r&gt;0 . . Peru to 1 861 Peru to 1850 Petersham to I860 Petersham to 1850 Princeton to l s ."&gt;0 Princeton to I860 Shrewsbury to 1850 Shrewsbury to I860 Southborough to 1850 Southborough to I860 Sudbury to Sudbury to Topstield to 1 86&lt; I Tyringham to 1-r Upton to 1850. Walpoleto 1850.. . Waltham to Washington to </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 West borough to l*r&gt;o Maupassant. Guy de. The odd number. VMV, (1) tlower descendant. The. v. 4-5 Medical news. v. •'I Itcdico T irgwl journal, v. 18-20 Mexico, [jaws. 1908 '-' Michelson. Miriam. The bishop's carriage &lt;1&gt; Mic-hie. Thomas J. Municipal corporation cues. v. lit.. (1) If ichie. Thomas J. Municipal corporation cases, v. lit.. (1) igan. Academy of science. 4th annual report Michigan. Academy of science. 4th annual report Adjutant general. Report, 1901-02 &lt;-&gt; Asylums, reformatories and state institutions. 1908... '-' Attorney gem ral. Report. 1902 ( - &gt; Auditor general. Reports, 1908-1904. Ji (2) Auditors. Report state board of, 1902 (2) — Building and lain associations. 1!&gt;&lt;&gt;-J. 1908 (2) - Bureau of labor. Annual reports. UMrJ. 1908 (2) Commissioners of banking. Reports. 1902,1903 (2) Commissioners of insurance. Report. 1902... Commissioners of railroads. Report, VMti Dairy and food commissioners. Report. 1 !♦&lt;&gt;_&gt;, 190B Dairymen's association. Report, 1902, I' 1 (2) Adjutant general. Report, 1901-02 Asylums, reformatories and state institutions. 1903. Attorney gem ml. Report. 1902 Auditor general. Reports. 1902-1904. 3 v Auditors. Report state board of, l'.Mii 2) 2 (2) Bureau of labor. Annual reports. 1902, 1908 Commissioners of insurance. Report. 1902 .... Commissioners of railroads. Report, V*r2 (2) Dairy and food commissioners. Report, 1 !♦&lt;&gt;•_&gt; (2) Forestry commission. Report, 1901 Geological survey. Reports of. I'.mhi. L9O2 History of township libraries. 1835-1901 ■ • (2) House journal. \W&gt; '"' House and senate journal. 2d extra session 1!HM). Inaugural message of Governor Bliss. 1 '•&lt;•:! Inspector of illuminating oils. Report. 1W4 Insurance report, 1902 Journal of 25th annual encampment. 1903 Land office. Commissioner's report, l'.nrj Legislative manual, 1WI5 Library commissioners. Reports, 1901, 1908 1904. Local acts. 1903 Official manual. 1901-IW2, 1 ' </seg>
            <seg id="p029">STATE I.IBKAKIAN l!«&gt;i]-l!H)4 29 Railroad commissioners. Annual reports, 1902, 1908. Registration report, 1900 Report of proceedings of advisor; board. 1904.. &lt;■_') Senate journal, v. 1 ;{. !!•&lt;■• State board of agriculture. Report. 1900 d'l State board of education. Reports, 1902- \i* tt (2) State board of health. Reports. 1902-1904 State treasurer. Kejxjrt, 1902 Statistical abstract of insane, deaf, dumb and blind. 11MI4 (2) Superintendent of poor. Report. 1!«&gt;1. 1902.. . (2) Superintendent of public instruction. Repoi 1901, l!»o-_» Supreme court reports, v. 127-181 Tax commissioners and state board of Report. 1902 Miller, Elizabeth. Theyok.- (H Mills. Charles H. New York criminal • 16 Mining reports, v. 18-19 (1) Minnesota. Digest of supreme court report! tit General laws, extra session, 1902. Laws of 1903 Supreme court reports, v. 85-90. Minor, John B. Institutes of common law and statu 4 v. 1893 Hi \u000dr. Report, \Shr.\ Court of appeals reports, v. 92-103 Digest of supreme court reports, v. ft, 1903 Laws. 1908 Official manual. 19O1-02; 1903-04. (2) Supreme court reports, v. 1H0-17'.' (2) University. Rejjort of, l ( .K);j-ti( hell, John Ames. The villa claudia . (1) iipll, Jolin (i. Conne&lt;'ticut citations. 1902 (H Montana. Attorney general. Reports. r.HH». 1903 Bureau of agriculture, labor and industry, annual report. 190 Digest of supreme court reports. 1898 Tnsnector of mil fienort of l'lui </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Secretary of state. Report, 1901 02 &lt;•_'&gt; .•documents. 1901-02 ... (2) Supreme court reports, v. 26-28 Morley, John. Life of William v. K3. 1903 Ewart Gladstone. (I) Moore, Avery E. Digest of revenue laws. 1903 (2) ■&gt; very E. Digest of revenue laws. 1901 &lt; _&gt; Morrison, R. S. Mining reports, v. 17 ( 1 ) -e, Jedidiah. Universal geography, v. 1-2 Morrison, R. S. Mining reports, v. 17 ( 1 ) se, Jedidiah. Universal geography, v. 1-2 Moulton, Charles \V. Library of literary criticism. v. r,-tt (1) Moulton. Charles \V. Library of literary criticism. w. 5-6 (1) Muller, Max. Memories ( 1 &gt; Muller, Max. Memories ( I) Municipal corporation i 11 ( 1 ) Municipal corporation i 11 ( 1 ) X &gt;n. The v. 57-59, 74-76 (I) &gt;n. The v. 57-69, 74-7C ( I ) &gt;nal c-ori&gt;oration reporter, v. 26-27 ( 1 &gt; Nebraska. Attorney general. Reports. 1901-02. (4) — Banking department. Report of, 1904 I4&gt; Briefs in cases tiled in supreme court. :ij v (1 ) Brie fs in cases filed in supreme court (unofficial) Supreme court reports, v. 2tt {-) Brunswick. Statutes, v. 1, 2. 1908 &lt;U England magazine, v. : ( 1 ) Hampshire. Annual reports, v. 1-3. 1901-02,1904.. Author list of state library, v. 1. 1908 Manual and state register. ltf v (1) Dairymen's association. Report of, 1908 Geological survey. Report of, 1 !♦* &gt;8 House journal, 19OH s Laws. 1908 (4) = Legislative album. 19015 Public documents, w. 1-4, 1899-1900; v.1-4. 1901-02 Senate journal. 1908 State bar association proceedings . 2 v. 1902. 19o:; Statutes (annotated), w. 1-2, 1908 Statutes, (compiled), l'.t' Supreme court reports, v. 68-66 8 Supreme court reports (unofficial), v. 1-8 (4) S T evada. . Laws, 1903 (2) </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 Miinual for constitution. 190J Manual for general courts. 1903 Senate and house journal. l'.Mi:; . . . ■ librarian. Report, l ( .M»l-(t2 . Supreme court reports, v. 71 ... international encyclopaedia, v. TJ-14 (1) Jersey. Archives, v. 22 Equity reports. I library of Newark. Report, 1902. Law reix&gt;rts. v. t'.7-i Laws. 1903, 1!»()4.. . Legislative documents, 1901, v. !-."&gt;: 1902, v. 1-5 Legislative manual, 1903, l!»i&gt;4 Proceedings of the genera] assembly. 1903 Senate journal, 1!M&gt;:{ .. Xf\v York. Abbott's annual digest, 1902, 190-1 d&gt; Annotated eases, v. 12 (It Appellate division of supreme court reports 71-84 nibly documents, 124th session. 1901. v. 1-20, Assembly documents, lii'ith session. 1902. v. 1 Calendar of bills of assembly, liJ.'th session. 1" Calendar of bills of senate. 125th session, 1902 Civil procedure reports, v. Ill Council of ap]K)intment, military record Court of appeals report, v. 171 177 Criminal reports, w. 16-17 &lt;1&gt; Cyclopedic digest, v. 1-14 (ll Ecclesiastical records, v :{-4 F'orest, tish and game commissioners. Report, !!♦&lt; &gt;•_&gt;.(&gt;:{ Laws. v. 1-2, 1903 (2) Legislative manual. 1903, 1!«&gt;4... Miscellaneous reports, v. 33 H (1) Report of de])artment of parks, I' 1 School of journalism. 1902-1903 Senate documents, 124th session, 1'.»&lt;&gt;1. v. 1 " Senate journal, li'.'ith session, v. 1-2. 1!H»2 State jreolojiist. Annual reports. • ■ librarian. Bulletin. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 State museum. Bulletin. !!•»►. S til te museum. Report of regents. I J •&lt; i2 . Supplement, v. 77-88 &lt; 1 1 Supplement, v. 77-88 Digest, v. :i-4. 1903 (1) Digest, v. :i-4. 1903 (1) Supplement to general laws. 1902 ... ... (It Supplement to general laws, l'.tou ... u&gt; Supreme court rejxjrts. Appellate division, v. '.«&gt; Supreme court rejxjrts. Appellate division, v. 90 Tree planting on streets and highways. iyo:&gt; .... Tree planting on streets and highways. iyo:&gt; .... University. High school department. 10th annual University. High school department, 10th annual report, v. 1 -•_'. 1 !»• &gt;i' (2) k report v. l -•_&gt;. 1902 (2) Home education department. l!»oo. 1902. &lt;:i&gt; Library school. Bulletin No. 78 Ili) Public^papers of George Clinton, first governor — — Regent's bulletins. Nos. 54, 50. 1902 ... State librarian. Report, v. 1-2. 1902.... (2) State museum. Bulletin No. 44-66 State museum. Report. 1!H&gt;4 South Wales. Constitution bill; speeches in legiala tive council. 1902 Department of labor and industry. Report, 1902. (2) Home education department. 1!hh». !:«)•_' Library school. Bulletin No. 7k Public^papers of George Clinton, tirst governor Regent "s bulletins. Nos. 54, 59. 1902 State librarian. Report, v. 1-2. 1902.... State museum. Bulletin No. 44-M State museum. Report. 1!H&gt;4 South Wales. Constitution bill; speeches in legisla tive council. 1902 Department of lands. •_'. v. 1!«K) Department of mines. Annual report, 1'.mm&gt; Minister of public instruction. Report, I!HM&gt;. Postmaster general. Report, 1!»&lt;*» (2) Railway commissioners. Report. l'.'Oii (2) Record of debates of Australasian conven tion. 8 v &lt; i' ) Reports of commissioners on sites for seat of gov ernment. r. 1-2. 19&lt;X&gt; Reports of the seven colonies of Australa - 1!H&gt;1-Cr2 Royal commission on Chinese gambling. Report. VMH) C2) Royal commission on strikes. Report. 1890 (2) State reports, v. ::. 1908 (1&gt; Statistical register. 1hh!)-1!»o1 Statutes, mtl-03 Wealth and progress of. 1902 Zealand. I^aw reports, v. 19-22 ( 1 &gt; colonies. 1 '.♦&lt;••_' . </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 Niblack, Win. c. The Torrens plexity Nicolas. Sir Harris. Proceedings and ordinances of the privy council. England, v. 1-7 Nineteenth century. The. v. 52-54 .... h American review. The. v. 174 17' Ml North Carolina. Bureau of labor and printing. Hith annual report. !!«»•_'. Private laws. 1868-69. (1) Private laws. 1'." Public laws. 1908 Report of deaf, dumb and blind institutions. Supreme court reports, v. 131-131 North Dakota. L^iws. 1903 Legislative manual, I'M)'.', Supreme court reports, v. 1&lt;&gt; -tern reporter, v. 84-70 Digest. 1903.. . ill n reporter, v. 91-99 tutes. 1903. 1904. 2 v. (1) Suj)reine court reports, v. ::." (11 () Odgen, G. W. Tennessee Todd Ohio. Adjutant general. Reports. 1901, l!»o-_'.. Athens state hospital. Reix&gt;rt.s. 1902,1904. Attorney general. Report. 1904. . . Auditor of state. Reports. 1903, 1904. Ballot election laws. 1903 Boys' industrial school. Report, 1902 Building &amp; Loan associations. Reports. 1901-03. Bureau of labor. Report. 1!H&gt;3. ... Calendar of general docket. 1!H&gt;4 Canal commission. Report, 1902-03... Chief inspector of mines. Report. 1903 Chief inspector of nurseries and orchards. Rep 1908 Cleveland state hospital. Report. 190 Columbus state hospital. Report. I' 1 Til '^ 1 f\ T1 0 T^ i l Tj* 1 1 T^^\rf r^ tj* j w t </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Dairy and fcxxl commission. Report. l ( .»0'2 &lt; Dayton state hospital. Report, 1902, 1003 Decisions, v. 12-13 &lt; 1 &gt; tion law. 1JMM Election statistics. ISM&gt;3 Executive documents. l'.MH, pts. 1-3; 1902, pts. 1 ■• Federal, county, township and municipal officers. 1904 . . . - and compensations, county officers. Geological survey. 4th series, bulletin 1. Girls' industrial home, Report, 1902. Harrison school code, The. 1903 Hospital for epileptics. Report, 11H&gt;-J House journal, extra session. 1902 Index digest of supreme court reports. 1899... &lt;1&gt; Institution for deaf and dumb. Report, 1904 Institution for feebleminded youth. 1903 Insurance laws. l!tt&gt;4 Insurance reports, tire. 1902, l!»u Insurance reports, life, l ( .t&lt;&gt;"2. 1903.. Journal of 32d national encampment G. A. R Labor statistics. 1901, 1902 Laws. 1902 (2) Laws, extra session. 1902, 1904. 2 v Live stock commissioners. Reports, 1903, 1904. Massillon state hospital. Report. 1902-03 Miami university report. 1904... Official bulletin of recognized schools, 1903 (2) Premiums and regulations, ."&gt;4th annual state fair. 1904 Pure food laws. 1903-04 Railway reports. 1901, 1902 School commission. Reports of, 1901, 1903 etary of state. Rei&gt;ort, 1903 Senate journal. 19O2 ite journal. 1902, extra session Soldiers and sailors home. Reports. 1902, 1!" •board of agriculture. Reports, 1901, \U&gt; State board of arbitration. Reports. 1902, 1'" State board of charities. Report. 1 " ■ th. Report, 1904 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 State board of public- works. Report, 1903 State tire marshal. Repo e inspector of oils. Report , r.«&lt; State penitentiary. Report, 1902-03 State reformatory. Report, litni' State school for blind. Report, 11*02 treasurer. Report. 11HI4. State university. Reports. 1903, 190-J Supervisor of public printing. Report Supreme court reports, v. liti i&gt;:i Tax laws. l!t&lt;»4 Toledo state hospital. Reports. 1902, lit" Trustees of state university. Report, P.mil 1 Work shop, factories and buildings. Report, I Oklahoma. Digest. 1902 Revised statutes, v. 1 i\ Session laws. v. 1 Supreme court reports, v. li Omaha daily bee. 1901, v. 14: 19O2, \. 1-4; 1903, v. M; 1904, v. l-i&gt; Illustrated Inf. !!»(&gt;. iio. Digest of case law. v. -1- \. Law reports, v. 4 -•&gt; Statutes. 1904 u r on (Jeneral laws. 1903 l^iiws. speci Statutes, v. l-i\ l!t()^. . Supreme court reports Outlook, v. 70-74. .. i], 1' itic reporter, v. 70-78 Pall Mall. v. 27-30, 32 &gt;ns. Frank. Treatise on law of banks and bankinK 1, ± 1903 isylvania county court rep&lt; i 1 1 1 Dauphin county report- Delaware count; History -*7th (Pa.) voluni House journal. 1903. v. 1-2.. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Laws, 1!K)8 legislative handbook and manual 1908 . — Legislative manual. 1904 Montgomery county law reporter, v. 18, 19 (1 ) Northampton county reporter \ - (1) Official documents. 1900, v. 1 11: 19&lt;&gt;1, v. 1 In. L902. v. 1-10 (2) Senate journal, v. 1-2 1'." (2) ■ librarian. Reports. 1902-03 — Statutes at large. 177o-l77t&gt;. v. 8 Statutes at large. 177H-177!' v. '.» Story of 111th and lltith regiment volunteers. 2 v. Superior court reports, v. "Jo-iM (2) Supreme court reports, v. 202-208 University catalogue. l!HXM»l Pettingill's newspaper directory . l'.lo;! ( \\ Philadelphia free library. Report, L902 Phillips, David G. The cost ( 1 1 Pidgin, Charles. The climax. 1 !♦&lt;&gt;:?. (1) Political science quarterly, v. 17 ( 1 &gt; Poor. H. V. &amp; H. \V. Manual of railroads, v. 85.. ( 1) Porto Rico, Laws. 1900-01, 11H»3 Laws and code of civil procedure. 1W4. (2) Revised statutes .and codes. 1901 Prince Edwards Island. Acts of general assembly. !!»&lt;&gt;:&gt;. . (1 ) Statutes (3 Edward VII.) 1903. . . Princeton university catalogue. 1903-04 Probate reports., annotated, v. 7-8 ( 1 1 Public libraries, v. 5-7 ( 1) Public opinion, v. 30-84 (1) Public policy, v. 6-8 . (1) Publications of American economical association v. 3 ( 1 1 hological review, v. H-lo (1) Q Quebec. Official law report*. ?. 21-24... (1) Official law reports. Kings bench, v. 11-12 &lt;1&gt; Statutes. 1908, 1904 2 1 (II Queensland. Law journal, v. 11 U ) </seg>
            <seg id="p037">STATE UBKAK1AN litO-M'MU 37 rvatory and allied stations n Stati Supreme court reports. \. l &gt;'. K Railway and canal cases, v. 11 l*i-(lh'«'l(l. Robert Law and practice of surrog its in New York, 1 !'&lt;&gt;:; Reed, Thomas I?. Modern eloquence. After dinner lies. v. 1-15. hard. Geo-L. Law of agency. 14*02 ■. Conrad. Employers liability acts. ]:• •w of reviews, v. 27, _• &lt; i&gt; le Island. Acts and resolves. 1902, 190 Adjutant general. Report I* Auditor. Rfix&gt;rt, l'.MC' Commissioners of dams and reservoirs. Annual Ke]x&gt;rt. IW1 Commissioners of dams and reservoirs. Annual Report lmrj Board of polio" commissioners. Annual report. 1902 Board of police commissioners. Annual report. 1902 Hoii id of labor statistics. Report 1902 Board of labor statistics. Report 1902 Commissioners of inland nahe Ith aim report. L902. Commissioners of inland fishe Ith aim report. 1902. Commissioner of statistics. 15th annual Commissioner of statistics. 1 5th annual &gt;• Comptroller. Report l'.«»4.. Comptroller. Report. l'.»&lt;»4 Condition of state banks. 1906. . . Condition of state banks. 1903 Factory inspector. 10th annual report, 1908 Factory inspector. 10th annual report, 1903 General assembly reports. 1900-1J* General assembly reports. 1900-191 Harbor commissioi • th annual report 18 Barbor commission) h annual report Ifl Industrial school. Annual reixirts. 1903, 1904. Insurance commission* nual re: 1904. slative manual. 1!«»4. . Life and accident insurance re: Manual. 1901, 1903. 2 v Public laws. 1902-1904 Public papers of Governor Black, 1897-9fl Registration report. !'.»&lt;»■_» nks and savings institutions. I. \nnual report. \'" \nnual reixjrt I 1 ' </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 REPORT OF THE Supreme court reports, v. '23 -2\ Vital records. 1 636- 1 850. v. 12 (2) Rodkinson, Michael. Babylonian talmud. v. 14-16 ( 1 ) Michael. History of the talmud Rood, John R. Law of wills. IW4 1 1 &gt; Walter M. Digest of United States report*, v. 1-8, 1MB (li Notes on United States reports. v. 12-13. 1J«&gt;1 &lt;1&gt; -«'ger. Peter. The God seeker. L90I ( 1 &gt; ■11 A Winslow. Syllabus digest of United State-; reports, r. 4. 1908 ( 1 &gt; v. Williams. Pleadings in parliament (1) S Sally. A. S. Marriage records of South Carolina. 17: J VMM (1) Schwab, JohnC. Confederate States of America, 1HH itific American, v. (1 &gt; itific American supplement. I &lt;1&gt; and. Law times, v. 10. 11 (1&gt; !;tnd. Lkw times, v. 10. II (1&gt; Public general statutes for 17o7-lSXU: L90&amp; ». 1-3. (1) Scots statutes revised, v. 10 .... (1&gt; Scots statutes revised, v. 10 (1&gt; s. house of lords, v. 5 (1) ouseof lords, v.5 (1) • . James B. Cases on international law. I!&gt;(&gt;"2 ( 1 &gt; ish law reporter, v. 8B-40 ( 1 &gt; ish law review, v. IS* ( 1 &gt; \ James B. Cases on international law. I!&gt;(&gt;"2 (1&gt; 'ish law reixjrter. v. :S ( .) 4o ( 1 ► ish law review, v. IS* ( 1 &gt; Scribner's magazine, v. 81-88 ( I &gt; ight, Thomas B. History of the national road. 1906. Scribner's magazine, v. 81-88 ( I &gt; ight, Thomas B. History of the national road. 1906. Shepard, Prank. Federal reporter citations. 1 !«&gt;•_' (I) Illinois appellate court citations. 1908 . . ( 1 &gt; Illinois supreme and appellate court citations. 190-2 (1) Illinois supreme court citations. UHK) ( l &gt; Illinois appellate court citations. 1903 . . ( 1 &gt; Illinois supreme and appellate court citations. mr2 &lt;n N'ebraska citations. 1908 &lt; 1 &gt; Northwestern reporter citations. 1908 ( 1 &gt; United States supreme court citations. I!H»i» (l &gt; Smith, F. Hopkihson. The under dog ( 1 &gt; Smith, John W. Law of municipal corpi 1-2. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 Selection of leading cases, v. 1,2. 1 ( .H&gt;: (li Snyder, Wilson I. Mines and mining- 1902. v. 1 ■•_' (1) South Australia. Acts of parliament. l'.Hi-J. !.■■ th Carolina. Acts. L9O4. . House journal. 1908, 1904 Laws, UMKi Marriage records, 1732-1801 Reports and resolutions. 1903,1904... Senate journal. 1903, 1904. . . &lt;:.') Supreme court reports, v. 63-66 South Dakota- Laws. 1903 &lt;-• Legislative manual. 1966.... (2) Historical collection. 19o-_&gt;. House journal. 19o:-{. . . Public documents. 19o:-{. v. 1 -:; Revised codes. 1903 Senate journal, 19o:i Supreme court reports, v. 11-15 Southeastern reporter, v. 4:2 47 » 1 ) Southern law review, v. 1 .... II) Southern reporter, v. 32-36 . . &lt; 1) Southwestern reporter, v. 69-81 &lt;1&gt; Digest, v. 6. 1904 Ill Spelling, T. Carl. Manual of corporate management. 1904 &lt; 1 &gt; ring, Thomas. New trial and appellate practice, v. 1 •2. iaO8 Stanley, Caroline A. Order No. 11. 1!HM . (1) .'journal (daily) 1901-1904 (1) rns. Arthur A. Law of suretyship, li" (1) hens, Henry J. Principles of pleading. 19»&gt;1 (1) Sutherland, J. G. Law of damages, v. 1-4. 1903,1904.... (1) « rerland, William A. Notes on the I -nstitution. 1904 T Taikington, Booth. Cherry... (1) Acts of parliament, v. 17. 1903 Statutes, v. 2. 1902 John N. Law of landlord and tenant v. 11 l l .M&gt;4 ID Tenness' </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Api&gt;endix to legislative journals, bouse and senate, L908 . ... Chancery appeal reports, v. 1 (1&gt; House journal. 1' Senate journal, Supreme court reports, v. [07-110 Civil appeals reports v. i'."&gt; ;;i Criminal reports. v. li' 4 4 flouse journal, !!«»;{ . . (2) ite journal. 11H&gt;:'. supreme court reports, v. 95-9(1 Edward B. Negligence, rules, decisions and opinions, v. 1-2. 1004 (1&gt; John L. Non-mailable matter; law of lotteries, fraud and obscenity in mails. [903 &lt; t &gt; mpson. Seymour D. Cotnmenteries on the law cA licence, v. 4. 1 V+4 &gt;4 •l.v. Francis B. Law of principal and agent. 1902 tli TiflFany. Herbert T. I real property, v. !-•_'. r Alaskan boundary. Atlas, counter i 1908 (4) Tribunal argument. 190 Tribunal count. &lt;4&gt; Azimuths of celestial bodies, v. 120 (4&gt; Boundary lines between United States and M- ... (4&gt; Commercial relations of the T'nit. « with forei^m countries, v. 12. 1908 &lt;4&gt; Circuit court of appeals reports, v. ~&gt;-2-fr2 &lt; 1 &gt; ions supplementary to Rose's notes on I'nited - reports. 19 Civil mission. Report, v. 19. 1&gt; 2 Compile" iwl &lt;n piled statutes, supplement, v. 4. 1903 (1) 52d congress, lsi n, 1F91-92. House miscella n* ' 1 1 K i)t. 1 (41 i l*t ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 r congress, 2d session, 1 17 inents. v. 7fl t congress, I'd session (lex 1 901-O2. D« inents. v. 1. 3-7, 10, 11. 17. I tcong I. House journal. Mth. ports 54th congress, 2d session, 1896-97, Hows.- docu i6th congress, LHH9-1901. Document indi fi congress, 1st session, 1-:- (x-unient. v 7. 16, 47 ill &lt;•&lt;&gt;: non, liMMi-oi. i ients. v. 2, ::. 4. li'. i:;. k m. 20,22, - 111. 112, 113, 114. 18, 120, 121, 124, 126, 127, 133, 134, 135, 137. 1 congress, 2d session, 1900-01. Sena* lents. v. 2,7, 8, 12, 17. 18, I 1 .'. 21, 22 &gt;7th congress, li on, 1901-02. H&lt; its. v. 1. 2, 4-40, 44 1l&gt;.{. 127, Ii9-131 &gt;7th congress, 1st session, 1901-02. ports.* v. l-'.» '■Ttli congress, 1st session, 1901-02. Senate meat*, v. 1-5, 7-20, 22 '»7th congress. Is* ,&gt;n. litOlm journal, v. :;-." '•t.iiKit'ss. 1st session. L 901-01 Mtli con^ivss. a n, 1901 0 directory ■&gt;7tli com. I session, 1902-03. CkM . pt 1 r»7tli congress, 2d session. 1902-03. B ■enta n, 17, 19-21, I 91-98, 98, 100, 101-104, 108, 107, 118, 116, ! »7th conf n, 1901-02. House joui 57th congress, 2d session, 1901-02. Senat. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 53th congress. Id session, 1903-04. Congressional record, v. 88, pts. 1 -(&gt; i congress, I'd session, 1903-01. House journal v. 7-lo j^tli congress, special we —ion, &lt; ongressional record, v. '61 Court of claims reports, v. 87-86 Department of agriculture. Bureau of ani mal industry, v &gt;,62 Bureau of chemistry. \. 09, pt. 4. 81- Bureau of forestry-, v. 4.V."&gt;&lt;&gt;. ."&gt;:&gt; Bureau of plant industry. Bulletin, v. " 61-68, 65, 67, 70 " Bureau of plant industry. Experiment tion record, v. 15 — Bureau of plant industry. Office of experi- ment station, v. 144 Bureau of soils. Report. \. *"!'.'• Bureau of statistics, v. 27-29 Division of entomology, v. 44, 4t&gt;, 4i» Division of foreign markets, v. lo. 84, " — — Farmers bulletin. v. 152, 177. 198-195, 197-248 — — Index to experiment station reports Investigation of irrigation in Utah Office of experiment station, v. 142-148, 15 pts. 8-12, 706-718, 728 ::: Department of commerce and labor. Annual re port of commissioners. 1MB. v. 17. Bureau of labor bulletin. No. 54 Discussion of vital statistics. 12th census. v. 12 Electrical tire alarm and police patrol stem. v. 1 1 1 — Estimates of population in large cit . 1901-08 v. 7 Executive civil 1!*»4 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 Monthly summary of tinar.&lt; Negroes, v. 8 Organization and law of Philippine island- rod annual report of civil service commission Philippine islands. Auditor's \&lt; Bulletin 1-8 Census of the Philippine islands, 1!H&gt;::. bulletin 1-JS Tide Ubles. 190 Birtrnent of interior. 12t'i i.il port Commissioner of pensions. Annual re port, 190 4 . . Decisions relating to public lands, v. :!1 Geological sur\- Report of commissioner of education, v. 1-2. l'.H)-_&gt;, 1903. I Report of commissioiiei or. v. 1 Specifications and drawings of paten I 361-374 irtment of state. Exports declared lor 19 Division of statistics. 14th annual report of rail - way statistics Historical papers, society of colonial wars, li 1903 rrical register and directory 12. l!HKi Industrial commissioner. Keport. v. 1-5, 13 1 Interstate commerce commission. 16th annual Port Interstate commerce reports, v. 15 Bnthly summary of commerce and finance. !■ 804. . department. Naval mobilization Naval observatory publicat Naval reserve, training and material ■ xiation of state librarians. 1!H»4 Nautical almanac l'.'^'l !!•&lt;•;! ( &gt;fticial i v. 1 .... </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 ions of attorn*" tal tfuide. 1903 (1) Proceedings of the Bunker Hill monument associ - ation nid international American conference. lUm 1 . Smitlisonian institution. Board of regents' rep. L9O2-O4 Contributions to knowledge, v. :!:! . . . National museum proceedings, v. 24-27 &lt; J&gt; tistical atlas, 12th census, 1903 Statutes at large. 1901-03. v. 32, pte. I 2 Structures used on irrigation canals . &lt;4&gt; Supreme court reportei 24 (1 &gt; Supreme court reports, t. 177-194 . &lt;1&gt; (L. Ed.) v. 46-48 ill Digest, v. 3-4. 1908 (I) Surgeon general's library. Index catalogue, v. Survi memorial South California. Mexico and Texas, v. Treasury department. Abstract of V us. l'HHt in • and geodetic survey. List of pub lications. 1903 Coast and geodetic survey. Reports, 19055 1!»O4 Commissioner general of immigration Annual report, I'.**:.' iptrollei ions. v. 9-10. . . Comptroller's decisions. Digest &lt;4&gt; Director of the mint. Report of. 1901.. Life saving service. Annual rei&gt;orts. 1902 War department. Drill regulations &lt;4) •etary's report. 1899-19 House journal. 1 ' Laws. 1903 ,te journal. 190! </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 V Van Dyne, Frederick. Citizenship of the United 1904 Hi Van Wyck. P. International revenue record, v. 1 ;•■ ID Zile, Philip. Equity pleading and practice. l'«&gt;4 (li ler, Van Ve€hter, Legal masterp Ml Vermont. lk&gt;ard of agriculture. 22d Board of railroad port. 1WJ Fish and game warden. 16th L9O2 Historical society proceedings. House journal, 1902.. . Insurance report. 1902 Laws. IW2, l» annual report. 1902 ii'i commissioners, bienniai d'l biennial report 1901, (2) l!' (l _ Board of railroad commissioners, biennial port. 1WJ Fish and game warden. 16th biennial report 1901, 1902 Historical society proceedings, l!*^ House journal, 1902 Insurance report. I!*"'.' Laws. IW2, 1908 — Legislative manual. l'.Hd' Library commissioners. 4th biennial report 1 Legislative manual. l'.Hd' Library commissioners. 4th biennial report. 1901 - !!»(»•_&gt; 1902 Senate journal. 1902. .. Senate journal. 1902 Supreme court reports, v. 74 7.". Supreme court rejxn'ts. v. 74 7." (2) State geologist. Rej&gt;ort. 1902 (2) State geologist. Report, 1!N ••_&gt;... (2) State highway commissioners, id biennial report, 1902 State highway commissioners. 2d biennial report, 1902 State officers. Reiwrts. 1901-1902 State Su]&gt;erintendent. Report of schools. 1902 Victorian law reports, r. 28 (1) statutes. T. 1-9 (1) Victorian law reports, r, 28 (1) statutes, v. lit (1) Virginia. Acts of assembly. 1*1C&gt;... ID Acta of assembly, 1902, 1904. Decisions, un reported, v 1-l'. \'M)-2 (1) House journal and documents. [901,1904. •&gt; v .. Virginia. Acts of assembly. 1816 ID Acts of assembly. 1902, 1!M&gt;4 (l'» Decisions, unrej)orted. v 1-l'. I'M)'! (1) House journal and documents. 1904 House journal and documents, extra session. 1902 - 04 Journals and documents of constitutional conven - tion Railroad commissioner's repoi Senate journal and documents. 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 &gt;n commission. Report, 1908 Supplement to digest of supreme court reports I. 1908 (1) Supreme court reports, v. loo, lol &gt;. 1\ Measure of damages and persona] In - juries. L90S W Win. H. r^aw and practice, v. .".. I'.mi:; &lt;i&gt; ibaugh. Eugene. Littleton's tenures. 1902 (1) lington. Digest. Supremecourt reports. 1908 (1&gt; cutive documents. HX&gt;"2. v. 1 1 (4) House journal, l'.'ir:; (L'» Opinions of the attorney general, l'.»o;i .... Senate journal. 1908 (2) Supreme court reports, v. 27-34 Daniel. Works of. v. 1-6. K&gt;1 U&gt; Life of John Trunibull. 1!«&gt;1 man. Francis L. Art of cross examination. U&gt;oJ. &lt;1&gt; •Australia. Law reports, v. 1-5. (1&gt; ates. v. 1 :! and index. 1896 U&gt; t&gt;rn medical review, v. 7 (II review, v. 157-159 ( 1 1 t Virginia. Digest of supreme court reports, v. 2-3.. &lt;1&gt; Uiv - Supreme court of appeals, v. 51-52 \\liite. Frank. Law of corporations, 1908 (1) s wlio. HJO4 (1) 's who in America. l ( .to4 . . . . . ( 1 1 rs. Bors idy of Uni' I corpora - tion. 1901 onsin. Blue book. !!»&lt;•:! (2) ■ historical society collections. 1849-1864. v. 1,2 I — State historical society proceedings. 1901-190 Digest, supreme court reports. 1902. v. i (1) Law- S </seg>
            <seg id="p047">LIBRARIAN Words and phrases judicially defined. 1904 World almanac. 1903 World-Herald, Omaha. 1901, 3 v.; l'.ini 1 4 V Wyoming. Supreme coart reports, v. 10, 11 Y Yale review, v. 11 sity. Report of librarian. 19: Report of president, 1903-04. 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">• </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>