<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00085.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0085.0003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1937-1938</title>
               <date value="1938-12-31">1938-12-31</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Adjutant General OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1937 - 1938 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA " ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 31, 1938 From: The Adjutant General of Nebraska. ■ V■- To : His Excellency. Roy L. Cochran, Governor of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. Subject: Biennial Report for 1937 and 1938. 1. In compliance with requirements of Sections 1 to 5, Chapter 55, Article 1, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska 1929, thc following Biennial Re - port for the calendar years 1937 and 1938 is respectfully submitted. The Nebraska National Guard occupies an enviable position in its standing in the National- Guard of the United States and that steady improvement which has so richly rewarded thc efforts of its personnel for years has never been more potent than during the period covered by this report. Each year training has materially improveel in a logical and progressive manner, and notwithstanding the fact that many states allot much more money for use of the National Guartl, I sincerely believe there is not a better organization in any State in the Union than has Nebraska-at this time. 2. Annual armory inspections are made by officers of the United States Army detailed for that purpose. The results of our last armory in - spection evidenced the closest conformity to prescribed schedules and found our organizations as a whole very satisfactory. 3. As previously reported, the most discouraging proposition with which the units of the Xcbraska National Guard have to contend is the rental of armories. It is almost impossible to rent suitable buildings and tbe government officials arc becoming more exacting constantly as to the care and protection of government equipment. This is particularly true with reference to ordnance, as there have been a number of thefts in the East of the 45 automatics and also of machine guns and we are compelled to pay the penalty, notwithstanding the fact we have had no losses of this kind. Government inspectors have already peremptorily ordered a number of changes maele in our armories, which entails considerable expense and which results in either an increased rental or the State defraying the ex - penses of thc additional security demanded. Within the last two years it </seg>
            <seg id="p006">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL has been necessary to construct steel vaults for storage of arms and am - munition and even at this time with this improvement made, the Regular Army Inspectors claim tlie-y do not conic up to standard. It is, therefore, recommentlcd that our Legislature give very serious consideration to mak - ing provisions for an Armory Building Program which will undoubtedly be - much cheaper in thc long run. 4. Inasmuch as the government is requiring the State to accept mor . and more motor vehicle's lor which we are required to provide housing and pay rental, the National Guard appropriation should be increased at Last $5,000 over and above what was reepiested in my budget. In conclusion, 1 wish to express my appreciation to the- officers and enlisted men of the Xcbraska National Guard and to the dozens of Cham - bers of Commerce and to our Commander-iu-Cliicf and the thousands of loyal citizens who have so heartily cooperated with us in their work, energy and moral support, thereby assisting in bringing the Xcbraska National Guard to its present high stale- of efficiency and making same a bigger and better organization. H. J. PAUL, Brigadier General, Tbe Adjutant General, Nebraska. FNAINCIAL STATEMENT NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD Appropriation Balance from biennium July 1. 1938, te&gt; July 1, 1937. as of January 1. 1937 $ 40,744.52 Biennium July 1. 1937. to July 1. 1939 150.000.00 5190.744.52 Expenditures — January 1, 1937, to December 31, 1938 Office Salaries 12.190.00 Office Maintenance 4,171.84 National Guard Maintenance 12,109.18 Rifle Range Maintenance 35.988.72 Arsenal Expense 2,470.47 Armory and Garage Rentals 40.219.06 Enlisted Men's Pay— Two Camps 47,532.71 154,681.98 Balance December 31, 1938 $ 36.062,54 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GEXERAL STRENGTH BY COMPANY AND DETACHMENT AS OF DECEMBER 31, 1938 Enl. War. Officers Men Off. State Staff and State Detachment 7 18 35th Division Detachment, Hq. Staff ..: 4 69th Brigade Headquarters 4 134th Infantry I feadquarters : 6 Med. Dept. Det : 5 29 Headquarters Co 2 62 Service Co 4 88 1 Howitzer Co 3 62 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co.. Ist Bn 3 24 Company A ; 3 64 Company B 2 64 Company C 3 64 Company D 3 64 Hq. &amp; Hq. Co.. 2nd Bn 3 23 Company E 3 63 Company I" 3 60 Company G 3 64 Company II 3 64 Hq. &amp; 11. |. Co.. 3rd Bn 3 25 Company I 3 64 Company K 3 64 Company L '. 3 64 Company M 3 63 110th Medical Regiment Headquarters 6 Service Co 3 65 1 Veterinary Co 2 38 Company C 1 62 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Company D 2 47 Company F 2 46 Company I 6 63 110th Quartermaster Regiment Headquarters 4 Headquarters Co 3 31 Med. Dept. Det 2 !1 Hq., Ist Bn 2 Company A 2 44 Company B 2 44 Hq., 2nd Bn '. 2 Company C 2 45 Company D 2 45 Company E ~ 2 31 Total , 124 1.665 2 ROSTER OF NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD December 31, 1938 H.J. Paul. Brigadier General. The Adjutant General. State Capitol. Lincoln State Staff O'Connell, Frank 8.. Major AGD, Stale Capitol, Lincoln Clark, Clarence 1... Capt., JAGD, 4!n Richards Blk., Lincoln McConnaughey, \V. 1"... Major, QMC, State' Capitol, Lincoln Stein, 11. C, Major. (.'MC. State Capi:ol. Lincoln Yoder, Byron E.. Capt, QMC. 3551 Davenport St.. Omaha Gillaspie, Trev. E., Major. Ord. Dept.. 400 Woodmen Accident B'.dg., Lincoln Evansi Carroll D.. Jr , Capt.. MC. 2502;:. 13th St., Columbus 35th Division Detach. Hq. Staff Thornton. Thos. Q.. Lt. Col., Inf:, 1408 W'.OAV. Bldg.. Omaha Ellis, Harry H., Lt. Col., QMC. 322 Federal Bldg.. Wichita, Kansas Stout. Richard F., Lt. Col.. JAGD, 722 Stuart Bldg., Lincoln Young, A. Farley, Capt., Court House, Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 69th Brigade Headquarters Thomas. Amos, Brig. Gen., Inf., 824 Omaha Nat'l Bank Bldg., Omaha L'tterback, Wm. G., Major, Inf., Nebraska City Dudley. Henry 11., Capt.. Inf., 1743 So. 23rd St.. Lincoln Xicholls, Harold C, Ist Lt. Inf., 1906 Douglas St., Omaha 134th Infantry Headquarters McCormick. Clyde E.. Col.. Inf., 824 Omaha Nat. Bank Bldg., Omaha Stoll. Fred H., Major, Inf., 915 No. 12th St., Beatrice Collier. Harold L., Capt., Inf., 430 No. 16th St., Beatrice Turner. Howard R., Capt., Inf., 2112 Harrison Ave., Lincoln He-atou. Lee \Y., Major. Chaplain, 815 W. Ist St., Grand Island Thoinscn. Alfred, Capt., Inf.. Rt. 2, Florence Sta., Omaha Med. Dept. Det. En=ar, Rolland R., Majtir, MC, 406 Aquila Court. Omaha Attwood, Norman 11.. (apt.. MC, 813 Med. Arts Bldg., Omaha Paynter, Floyd L., Capt . DC. 340 Med. Arts Bldg., Omaha Hughes, Leo \\. Ist Lt.. MC, Douglas Co. Hospital, Omaha Millett. Clinton C, Ist Lt.. MC, 5607 Leavenworth St., Omaha Headquarters Cc. McGill, Albert L.. Capt.. Inf.. 2316 Xo. 65th St.. Omaha Adamson, llolton R.. 2nd Lt.. Inf.. 2722 Xo. 65th Ave., Omaha Service Co. Beckicy, Harry A.. Cap!.. Inf., 624 Lincoln Ave., York Anderson. Raymond J.. Ist Lt., Inf., County Treas. Office, York Maurer, Arnold 1., 2nd Lt.. Inf.. 616 W. 7th St., York Valentine, Clarke E., 2nd Lt., Inf., Rm. 5, Cain Bldg., York McCall. George A.. War. Off., Band. P.O. Box 78, York Howitzer Cc. Allison. J. Ned, Capt., Inf., 1327 10th St., Gering Laugblin, Leslie J., Ist Lt., Inf.. 815 P St., Gering Wood, Warren C, 2nd Lt., Inf., Courier Bldg., Gering </seg>
            <seg id="p010">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Hq. Ist Bn. Miltonberger, Butler 8., Major, Inf.. 2244 O St.. Apt 1, Lincoln Hq. Co., Ist Bn. Yager, Leslie, Jr., Ist Lt., Inf., 713 Park Ave., Xcbraska City Pitzcr, John M.. 2nd Lt., Inf.. 115 So. Bth St.. Xcbraska City Co. A Thurman. Ray A., Capt., Inf., Court House. Xcbraska City Morton. Thos. S„ Ist Lt.. Inf.. 823 2nd Ave., Xcbraska City Wilson. Robert R.. 2nd Lt.. Inf., 1918 Ist Ave.. Xcbraska City Co. B Myers, Mervctl F., Capt.. Inf.. 1..20 Stone St.. Falls City Smith. Leo L.. Ist Lt.. Inf.. 1821 Towlc St.. Falls City Co. C j Coonley, Dean E„ Capt., Int.. Court House, Beatrice Boatsman, Alford C. Ist Lt.. Inf.. 1818 E. Court St., Beatrice Scott, Harrison !•".. 2nd Lt.. Inf.. 709 Xo. 9th St.. Beatrice- Co. D Petersen. Fred C. Capt., Inf., 1018 W. 3rd St., Xorth Platte Wilson. Denver W.. Ist Lt., Inf.. 17 So. Elm St.. Xorth Platte Godwin. Dale M., 2nd Lt.. Int.. 611 E. 9th St.. Xorth Platte Hq. 2nd Bn. Eby, Louis R.. Major. Inf.. Hartington Hq. Co., 2nd Bn. Bradley, James A., Ist Lt.. Inf.. 5232 Poppleton St.. Omaha Palmer, Thurston J.. 2nd Lt.. Inf., 4355 Hamilton St.. Omaha Co. E Eatwcll. Ora A., Capt., Inf., 2120 D Ave., Scottsbluff </seg>
            <seg id="p011">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Runyon, Harold M., Ist Lt., Inf., 1806 Bth Ave.. Scottsbluff Ecktand, Kenneth E., 2nd Lt., Inf., 1616 14th Ave.. Scottsbluff Co. F Hardy, Lloyd R.. Capt.. Int., Post Office. Hartington Stejskal, Julius, Ist Lt., Inf., P.O. Box 184, Hartington Carstcns, Walter W., 2nd Lt., Inf., Hartington Co. G Vaii Fleet] Robert J.. Capt.. Inf.. Fire Dept.. Hastings Jacobs. Paul 11.. Ist Lt.. Inf.. 804 Xo. Burlington Ave., Hastings Butler. Albert M.. 2nd Lt., Inf.. P.O. Box 293. Hastings Co. H Barratt. I-Idgar. Capt.. Inf.. Rm. 28, Hedde Bldg. Grand Island McElroy, Francis E., Ist Lt.. Inf., 211 So. Tilden St., Grand Island Xewell. Paul 8.. 2nd Lt.. Inf.. 1118 W. Kith St., Grand Island Hq. 3rd Bn. Geesen. Edward J., Major, Inf., 641 Seward St.. Seward Hq. Co., 3rd Bn. Dier. Clifford L., Ist Lt.. Inf., 1811 Garfield St., Lincoln Turner, Keith K.. 2nd Lt.. Inf., 419 Fed. See. Bldg., Lincoln Co. I Van Kirk. Rolla C, Capt.. Inf.. 802 First Nat. Bank Bldg., Lincoln Stewart. Clarence J.. Ist Lt.,' Inf., 1025 Elmwood, Lincoln Weyand, Foster H., 2nd Lt.. Inf., 600 L St., Lincoln Co. K Gatz. Edwin C, Capt.. Inf., 504 U. P. Bldg., Omaha Jacobscn, Harry 8., 2nd Lt.. Inf., 6204 No. 31st Ave., Omaha Wagner. Emil C, 2nd Lt.. Inf., 3528 No. 40th St., Omaha Co. L Kelso, F-arl H., Capt., Inf., 2224 Emmet St., Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p012">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Hall, Wallace 8.. Ist Lt., Inf., 1531 So. 29th St.. Omaha Osborne, Albert 8., 2nd Lt., Inf., 4506, No. 65th Ave., Omaha Co. M Jones. Erwin A., Capt., Inf., Court House, Seward Hauck, Paul C, Ist Lt., Inf., 509 So. Columbia Ave., Seward Firnhaber. Harold J., 2nd Lt., Inf., 128 No. sth St., Seward 110th Medical Regiment Headquarters Hilton. David C. Col., MC, 305 Richards Blk., Lincoln - Bartholomew. P. H., Et. Col., MC, State Capitol. Lincoln Evans, J. North. Major, MC, P.O. Box 156, Columbus Brooks, Earl 8.. Major, MC, 939 Stuart Bldg., Lincoln Bennett, John R.. Major. DC. 917 Stuart Bldg., Lincoln Deppen. Earl X.. Capt., MC, Security Mutual Bldg.. Lincoln Service Co. Ball. Harry R.. Capt.. MAC, 304 Stuart Bldg.. Lincoln Stearns. Harry A. Capt.. MAC. Post Office, Lincoln Strickland, Henry H.. Capt.. MAC. 4332 L St., Lincoln Welch. I.yle A.. War. Off., Band. 3725 M St.. Lincoln Veterinary Co. Alford. S. W., Capt.. VC. 1311 Xo. 37th St., Lincoln Skidmorc. Louis V., Ist Lt.. \'C, 3859 Dudley St.. Lincoln Co. C, Ist Bn. Anderson. Ronald C, Capt., MC, 2513 13th St.. Columbus Co. D, 2nd Bn. Ainlay. George W., Capt., MC, Fairbury Clinic. Fairbury Banks, Miles S.. Ist Lt., MAC, A22'A 4th St., Fairbury Co. F, 2nd Bn. Swanson, Leonard A., Capt., MC, 600 No. Hastings Avp., Hastings </seg>
            <seg id="p013">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GEXERAL Wiegman, Richard A.. 2nd Lt., MAC, 610 Xo. California Ave., 1 Eastings Cc. I, 3rd Bn. Johnson. Rodney K.. Capt., MC, 413 Pine St.. Friend Johnston, Leonard R.. Capt.. DC. 916 Stuart Bldg., Lincoln Anderson. James 8., Capt.. MC. 1119 Fed. Sec, Bldg., Lincoln Merid.tli. John A.. Capt.. MC. 914 Fed. Sec. Bldg., Lincoln Thomas. Dwigbt P.. Capt.. MAC. 2917 Xo. 52nd St., Lincoln I-luber, Paul J., Ist Lt.. MC, Box 83 Exeter 110th QM Regiment Headquarters P., Het. Marcus L„ Col., QMC. 704 First Nat Bank Bldg.. Lincoln Henninger. Guy X., Lt. Col., QMC. Pratt Bldg. Kearney Haycock. Willis F.. Capt.. QMC, Callaway Kpupal, Richard V.. Ist Lt., QMC, 1320 X St., Lincoln Headquarters Co. Browne. Win. 11., Capt.. QMC. 2701 Everett St., Lincoln Pel/. Harold G., Ist Lt.. QMC. 800 So. 16th St.. Apt. 409, Lincoln Gish. Herb. D.. Ist Lt.. QMC. 2020 South St.. Lincoln Med. Dept. Det. Rose. Wallace E.. Major, MC. 2215J/' Central Ave., Kearney Hansen, Henry C Capt., MC. Olson Bldg., Kearney I * Hq. Ist Bn. Leffler, Dclbert C. Major, QMC, 920 West. Ave., Holdrege Black. Walter 1., Ist Lt.. QMC, 234 Aquila Court, Omaha Co. A, Ist Bn. Gillette, Edward, Capt.; QMC, Court House, Holdrege Winqucst, Harold L.. 2nd Lt., QMC. 724 West Ave., Holdrege Co. B, Ist Bn. Olson. Xels A.. Capt., QMC, S37y. No. Broad St., Fremont </seg>
            <seg id="p014">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Hammond, Egbert E, 2nd Lt., QMC. Fremont Daily Tribune. Fre - mont Hq. 2nd Bn. Atkinson. W. J., Major QMC, 927 W. 28th St.. Kearney Zumwinkcl, Otto H.. Ist Lt., QMC. 414 Insurance Bldg., Lincoln Co. C, 2nd Bn." Kiffin. Monte R.. Capt.. QMC, 1600 No Lincoln St.. Lexington Smith. Elbert H., 2nd Lt.. QMC. Court House, Lexington Co. D, 2nd Bn. ■ Mattspn, Herman G.. Capt.. QMC, Post Office. Kearney Beaver, George R.. 2nd Lt., QMC. 2721 Avenue D. Kearney Co. E, 3rd Bn. ' Peterson, Vaughn. Capt., QMC. 234 W. Military Ave, Fremont Walther, Norris F... 2nd|Lt., QMC. 6307 No. 33rd Ave.. Omaha STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1. 1937 General Orders No. 1 1. The current season for indoor Range Practice is hereby desig - nated to extend from January 1 .1937. to May 1, 1937. and from September 1, 1937, to December 31, 1937. 2. The current season for outdoor Range Practice is hereby desig nated to extend from April 1, 1937, to August 31, 1937. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL OFFICIAL: 11. C. STEIX. Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 8, 1937 General Orelers No. .2 1. Annual Federal Armory Inspection. In accordance with tbe provisions of National Guard Regulations 48, Annual Federal Armory Inspection of Xcbraska National Guard Units will be made by Regular Army Officers as follows: Lt. Col. .A. E. Sawkins. Inf., Inspector Organization Station Date Hi.. 134th Int Omaha April 16 Hq. 69th Brig Omaha April 17 Med. Dept. Det.. 134 Inf : Omaha April 19 Co. K. 134th Inf Omaha , April 20 Hq. Co., 2nd Bn.. 134th Inf Omaha April 21 Co. I-. 134th Inf Omaha April 22 Hq. Co.. 134th Inf Omaha April 23 Hq., '3sth Div. Lincoln April 24 Co. I. 134th Inf Lincoln April 26 State Staff &amp; State Det., and State Arsenal: Hq. Co.. 3rd Bn.. &amp; Hq. Ist Bn., 134th Inf Lincoln April 27 Capt. M. R. Finney, Inf., Inspector Hq.. 2nd Bn.. 134th Inf Hartington April 19 Co. F. 134th Inf Hartington April 19 Co. A. 134th Inf Nebraska City April 20 Hq. Co.. Ist Bn.. 134th Inf Xcbraska City April 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Co. B. 134th Inf Falls City April 22 Co. C. 134th Inf Beatrice April 23 Hq., 3rd Bn., &amp; Co. M, 134th Inf Seward ... April 26 Service Co., 134th Inf _ York April 27 Co. G, 134th Inf Hastings April 28 Co. H. 134th Inf Grand Island \pri! 29 Co. D, 134th Inf _ Xortb Platte April 30 Hbwitzcr Co., 134th Inf Gering .'. May 3 Co. E, 134th Inf Scottsbluff May 4 Major E. L. Titus. MC, Inspector Co. C. 110th Med Regt Columbus April 19 Co. F, 110th Meel. Regt Hastings .._ April 20 Co. I. &amp; Vet. Co., 110th Med. Regt. .. Lincoln April 21 Hq.. &amp; Service Co.. 110th Med. Regt.. Lincoln April 22 Co. D, 110th Med. Regt Fairbury April 23 2. Brigade, regimental and separate organization Commanders will direct membrs of their respective Field and Staff, who are stationed at points other than the headquarters of the organization, to report to the designated Inspector at the- most convenient point. 3. Absentees. Xo authority will be granted absentees to stand in - spection with units other than their own. except as provided in paragraph 2 above. 4. All Federal property will be displayed so as to be ready lor in spection. Serviceable property will be separated from the unserviceable 5. All records, including morning reports, retained pay rolls. Forms Xo. 100. enlistment contracts and property re-cords, will be made available for inspection. Field desks will be arranged in accordance with previous instructions. 6. Blank forms for the Federal inspection will be furnished to thc unit commanders by thc Inspector. Responsible officers will study the forms carefully and be prepared to give full and accurate information on any point desired. 7. Unit commanders, first sergeants, supply sergeants, caretakers and company clerks should so arrange their affairs as to enable them to be a» the disposal of the Inspector for such time as he may require. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 8. Inspection of companies and similar units will be divided into two phases, i.e., the administrative inspection and thc inspection in formation. Thc formeT will be conducted during the day and the latter in the evening. Only the personnel mentioned under paragraph 7 above need be present for the administrative inspection. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General, " Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 13, 1937 General Orders No. 3 1. From May 1. 1937. until October 1, 1937, the prescribed uniform for the enlisted men of the National Guard of Nebraska will be as follows: Hats, service, with hat cords Shirts, woolen, Q. D. Breeches, cotton Leggins, spiral Shoes, service 2. On and after October 1, 1937, thc uniform prescribed in General Order Xo. 5, dated September 21, 1935, will again be in effect. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, Thc Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 26, 193'/ General Orders ': No. 4 1. Annual Federal Armory Inspection. In accordance with the provisions of National Guard Regulations 48, the Annual Federal Armory Inspection of the units of the 110th Quarter - master Regiment will be made by Major Julian 11. George (Inf.), QMC. Inspector, as follows: Hq. Ist Bn Holdrege May 11 Co. A ...' Holdrege May 11 Co. C Lexington May 12 Hq. 2nd Bn Kearney May 13 Co. D Kearney May 13 Med. Dept. Det Kearney May 14 CoJ B - _ Fremont May 17 Co.. E Fremont ■. May 18 Hq and Hq. Co Lincoln May 19 2. Regimental and separate organization commander- will direct members of their respective Field and Staff, who are stationed at points other than thc headquarters of the organization, to report to the designated Inspector at the most convenient point. 3. No authority will be granted absentees to stand iun.-pcction \.ii'' units other than their own. except as provided in paragraph 2 above. 4. All Federal property will be displayed so as to be ready tor in - spection. Serviceable property will be separated from the unserviceable. 5. AH records, including morning reports, retained pay rolls. Forms No. 100, enlistment contracts and property records, will be made •wailable for inspection. Field desks will be arranged in accordance v ill - , previous instructions. 6.' Blank forms for the Federal inspection will be furnished to the unit commanders by tbe Inspector. Responsible officers will study the- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL forms carefully and be prepared to give full and accurate information on any point desired. 7. Unit commanders, first sergeants, supply sergeants, caretakers and company clerks should so arrange their affairs as to enable them to be at the disposal of the Inspector for such time as he may require. 8. Inspection of companies and similar units will be divided into two phases, i.e.. the administrative inspection and thc inspection in formation. The former will be conducted during the day and the latter in tbe evening. Only the personnel mentionetl under paragraph 7 above need be present for the administrative inspection. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 10, 1937 General Orilers No. 5 1. In recognition of Memorial Day. Sunday, May 30, 1937, con - secrated to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the American Republic, thc National Flag will, in accordance with paragraph 2, sub - paragraph 11. AR 260-10, be displayed on all armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half-staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist Veteran organizations in the observance of the day, Com - manding Officers of National Guard organizations will place their respec - tive commands at the: disposal of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic. 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 17. 1937 General Orders No. 6 1. Pursuant to authority contained in Training Authority Xo. 43-1, File NGB 354.1 Nebr;-29, June 25, 1937. the following organizations will attend thc Fourth Army Maneuvers. Fort Riley phase at Camp Whitside, Kansas, August 15 to August 29, 1937. inclusive, under command of Major General Herbert J. Paul, Commanding General 35th Division, and upon completion of this tour of duty will return to their home stataions. Atten - tion is invited to paragraph 37. XGR 45. State Staff and State Detachment Det. Hq. 35th Division Det. Hq. 69th Infantry Brigade 134th Infantry 110th Medical Regiment 110th Quartermaster Regiment 2. Advance detachments will report as earlv as possible on \ugust 13, 1937, as follows: State Staff and Slate Detachment, consisting of 1 Major. QMC. 1 Major Ordnance Department, 1 Captain, QMC (Commissary)] and 16 enlisted men. Service Detachment, Service Co.. 134th Inf., consisting of 1 First Lieutenant and 14 enlisted men, and 1 Captain S O 134th Inf. Service Detachment, Service Company, 110th Med. Re-gt.. con - sisting of 1 Captain, 5.0., and 12 enlisted men. Service Detachment, 110th QM Regt.. consisting of 1 First Lieu- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL tenant and 10 enlisted men from Headquarters Company. They will form an advance detachment for the purpose of preparing the camp site and establishing camp for thc reception of troops and will report to Major W. E. McConnaughey, State Staff, August 13, 1937. The Commanding Officer of the 110th Medical Regiment will designate 1 Cap - tain, MC, to accompany the advance detachment of his regiment and will sec that he is provided with thc necessary medical equipment to establish a camp infirmary. 3. Upon arrival in camp August 13, 1937, thc Commanding Officer, Service Detachment, 110th Medical Regiment, will establish mess for all members of the Advance Detachments. The officers in charge of the 134th Infantry and the 110th Medical Regiment Advance Detachments will see that at least one cook is included in their detachments. Commanding of - ficers of the 134th Infantry, 110th Medical Regiment and 110th QM Regi - ment will see that equipment necessary for establishing commissaries is forwarded with advance detachments. 4. A rear detachment consisting of 1 Major, QMC, 1 Major, Ord - nance Department, and 1 Captain, QMC (Commissary), of the State Staff, 1 Captain, MC, 110th Medical Regiment, and 16 enlisted men of the State Detachment will remain in camp August 30, 1937. for the purpose of necessary detail incident to the departure of troops from camp. 5. Details as to transportation, supplies, equipment, etc., will be handled by circular letters from this office. 6. Regimental and Detachment Commanders will see that all of - ficers arc physically examined in accordance with paragraph 4, NGR 27. All enlisted men will be physically examined prior to their arrival in camp and after arrival in camp in accordance with letter from the Division Sur - geon, subject, "Vaccinations, Inoculations, Physical Examination," etc., June 17. 1937. 7. The travel directed is necessary in the military service of the State. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 5, 1937 General Orders No. 7 1. Pursuant lo authority contained in paragraph 3, XGR 62. a Medical Board on Hospitalization is appointed, to consist of th following members: Lt. Col. Philip 11. Bartholomew, MC Major R. R. Elisor. MC Major Earl B. Brooks. MC The Board on Hospitalization will recommend to their Headquarters dis - position of all cases of disease or injury coming under the provisions of NGR 62. before the close of camp. • By order of Governor Cochran; H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. ST FIX. Assistant Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 21. 1937 General Orders No. 8 1. Pursuant to the requirements of paragraph 5, C-2, dated Septem - ber 7, 1935. NGR 75-11. the Annual Inventory of Property pertaining te ' thc organizations of tbe Nebraska National Guard herein mentioned will be made on the following dates: </seg>
            <seg id="p023">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Hq. Co., Ist Bn.. 134th Inf Nebraska City Oct. 12, 1937 Co. A, 134th Inf. Nebraska City Oct. 13, 1937 Co. B. 134th Inf Falls City Oct. 14, 1937 Co. F, 134th Inf „. Hartington Oct. 16, 1937 Co. C, 134th Inf Beatrice Oct. 18, 1937 Co. D, 110th Med Regt Fairbury Oct. 19, 1937 Co. 1, l.Hth Inf Lincoln Oct. 21, 1937 Hq. Co.. 3rd Bn., 134th Inf Lincoln Oct. 22, 1937 Co. E. 134th Inf Scottsbluff Oct. 25, 1937 How. Co., 134th Inf Gering Oct. 26, 1937 Co. D. 134th Inf North Platte Oct. 28, 1937 Hq. Co., 110th QM Regt Lincoln Nov. 1, 1937 Vet. Co.. 110th Med. Regt Lincoln Nov. 2, 1937 Co. B. 110th QM Regt _ Fremont _ _ Nov. 3. 1937 Co. E, 110th QM Regt Fremont Nov. 4, 1937 Service Co.. 110th Med. Regt. Lincoln Nov. 8, 1937 Co. I. 110th Med. Regt Lincoln Nov. 9, 1937 Co. G, 134th Inf _ Hastings Nov. 15. 1937 Co. F. 110th Med. Regt Hastings -.. Nov. 16. 1937 Co. 11. 134th Inf Grand Island Nov. 17, 1937 Service Co., 134th Inf York Nov. 18, 1937 Co. M. 134th :Inf Seward Nov. 19, 1937 Co. A. 110th QM Regt Holdrege Nov. 29, 1937 Co. C. 110th QM Regt Lexington Nov. 30, 1937 Co. D. 110th QM Regt Kearney Dec. 1, 1937 Med. Dept Det., 110th QM Regt Kearney Dec. 2, 1937 Co. C. 110th Med. Regt Columbus Dec. 3, 1937 Hq. Co.. 134th Inf Omaha Dec. 6, 1937 Hq. Co., 2nd Bn., 134th Inf Omaha Dec. 7, 1937 Co. K. 134th Inf Omaha Dec. 8, 1937 Co. L. 134th Inf Omaha Dec. 9, 1937 Med. Dept. Det.. 134th Ini Omaha Dec. 10, 1937 2. All property will be arranged so that it may be counted with the least possible delay. Individual equipment records WD MB Form No. 30 will be posted to date and an abstract of items shown thereon will be made up so that same may be considered in thc inventory. 3. Attention is invited to the provisions of NGR 75-3, dated Novem - ber 17, 1933, which requires that all property be kept in the armory. 4. Responsible Officer, with Armory Caretaker and two (2) assist - ants, will be present to assist in the inventory on the date set. By order of Governor Cochran: </seg>
            <seg id="p024">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. OFFICIAL: Nebraska. H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 28, 1937 General Orders No. 9 • 1 1 - 1 . I Ar " ,is ' icc Da - V ' Thursday. November 11. 1937. will be observed as a holiday in honor of those who served their country in tbe World War. The National Flag will be displayed on all National Guard Armories with,,, the State at half-staff from sunrise until noon, when it will b raised to full-staff, remaining there until sunset. A " National Guard organizations are hereby authorized to parade on the basis of an armory drill, when requested to do so by patriotic societies. By order of Governor Cochran: . H. J. PALL, The Adjutant General, OFFICIAL: Nebraska. H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN General Orders November 6, 1937 No. 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. Under tbe provisions of paragraph 78e, NGR 20, dated February 25, 1935, Major General Herbert J. Paul, Commanding General, 35th Divi - sion, having attained the age of sixty-four years, is retired from active serv - ice in the National Guard of the United States, effective this date. 2. In accordance with an act of the Legislature, 1935, being H.R. No. 290. Herbert J. Paul, Brigadier General, Nebraska National Guard, will continue in office as Adjutant General, State of Nebraska, as provided therein. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 1, 1938 General Orders No. 1 1. The current season for indoor Range Practice is hereby desig - nated to extend from January 1, 1938, to May 1, 1938, and from September 1. 1938. to December 31. 1938. 2. Tbe current season for outdoor Range Practice is hereby desig - nated to extend from April 1, 1938, to August 31, 1938. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Assistant Atljutant General Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 11. 1938 General Orders No. 2 1. Annual Federal Armory Inspection. In accordance with the provisions of National Guard Regulations 48, Annual Federal Armory Inspection of Nebraska National Guard Units will be made by Regular Army Officers as follows: Major B. M. Crenshaw, Inf., Inspector Organization Station Date Hq., 2nd Bn., 134th Inf .... Hartington April 8 Co. F. 134th Inf Hartington April 8 Hq. Co.. Ist Bn., 134th Inf Xerasl.a City ....' April 1 1 Co. A. 134th Inf Nebraska City April 12 Co. B, 134th Inf. Falls City April 13 Co. C. 134th Inf Beatrice April 14 Hq. 3rd Bn., 134th Inf Seward April 15 Co. M. 134th Inf _ _„ Seward April 15 Service Co.. 134th Inf York \ pr j&lt; is Co. G, 134th Inf Hastings April 1" Co. H. 134th Inf Grand Island April 20 Howitzer Co., 134th Inf Gering April 21 Co. E. 134th Inf Scottsbluff April 22 Co. D, 134th Inf North Platte April 25 Col. B. F. Ristine, Inf.. Inspector Hq., 134th Inf Omaha .\ ]lr j| is Hq. 69th Inf. Brig Omaha April lo Med. Dept. Det., 134th Inf Omaha April 18 Co. K. 134th Inf Omaha April 19 Hq. Co . 2nd Bn., 134th Inf. Omaha April 20 Co. L, 134th Inf „ Omaha April 21 Hq. Co., 134th Inf Omaha April 22 Hq., 35th Div _ Lincoln April 23 Co. I, 134th Inf. _ Lincoln April 25 State Staff &amp; State Detach Lincoln April 26 State Arsenal Lincoln April 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Hq. Co., 3rd Bn., 134th Inf Lincoln April 26 Hq., Ist Bn.. 134th Inf Lincoln April 26 Lt. Col. John R. Hall, MC, Inspector Co. C. 110th Med Regt Columbus April 11 Co. F.. 110th Med Regt Hastings April 12 Co. I, 110th Med. Regt .'. Lincoln April 13 Vet. Co.. 110th Med Regt Lincoln April 13 11(1.. 110th Med Regt _ Lincoln April 14 Service Co., 110th Med. Regt Lincoln April 14 Co. D. 110th Med. Regt _.. Fairbury April 15 Majeir Clarence Longacre, QMC, Inspector Hq. 2nd Bn.. 110th QM Regt Kearney :. May 2 Co. D. 110th QM Regt _ Kearney _ May 2 Med. Dept. Det.. 110th QM Regt. . Kearney May 3 Hq., Ist Bn., 110th QM Regt _ Holdrege May 4 Co. A. 1 10th QM Regt Holdrege May 4 Co. C, 110th QM Regt Lexington May S Hq. 110th QM Regt Lincoln May 6 11. 1. Co.. 110th QM Regt Lincoln May 6 Co. B. 110th QM Regt Fremont May 9 Co. E, 110th QM Regt Fremont May 10 2. Brigade, regimental and separate organization Commanders will direct members of their respective Field and Staff, who are stationed at points other than the headquarters of the organization, to report to the designated Inspector at the most convenient point. 3. Absentees. Xo authority will be granted absentees to stand in - spection with units oilu-r than their own, except as provided in paragraph 2 above. 4. All Federal property will be displayed so as to be ready for in - spection. Serviceable property will be separate-el from the unserviceable. 5. All records, including morning reports, retained pay rolls. Forms No.. 100, enlistment contracts and property records, will be made available for inspection. Field desks will be arrangeel in accordance with previous instructions. (i. Blank forms for thc Federal inspection will be furnished to the unit commanders by the Inspector. Responsible officers will study the </seg>
            <seg id="p028">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL forms carefully and be prepared to give full and accurate information on any point desired. 7. Unit commanders, first sergeants, supply sergeants, caretakers and company clerks should so arrange their affairs as to enable them to be at the disposal of the Inspector for such time as he may require. 8. Inspection of companies and similar units will be divided into two phases, i.e., the administrative inspection and the inspection in forma - tion. The former will be conducted during the day and the latter in the evening. Only the personnel mentioned under paragraph 7 above need be present for the administrative inspection. 9. Thc provisions of G.O. 3, dated April 13. 1937, are rescinded in - sofar as Federal Armory Inspection is concerned. Troops are- authorized to wear serge and elastique. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 10. 1938 General Orders No. 3 1. In recognition of Memorial Day, Monday, May 30, 1938. con - secrated to the brave soldiers who sacrificed their lives for the American Republic, the National Flag will, in accordance with paragraph 2, sub - paragraph 11, AR 260-10, be displayed on all armories and all stations of the Nebraska National Guard at half-staff from sunrise until noon on that day. To assist Veteran organizations in the observance of the day, Com - manding Officers of National Guard organizations will place their respec - tive commands at the disposal of local representatives of the Grand Army of the Republic. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. Owing to the fact that credit for drill will be given for these exercises, no other report will be necessary. By order of Governor Cochran : H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 11, 1938 General Orders No. 4 1. From May 15, 1938, until October 1, 1938, the prescribed uniform for the enlisted men of the National Guard of Nebraska will tie as follows: Hats, service, with hat cords Shirts, woolen, O. D. Breeches, cotton Leggins, spiral Shoes, service 2. Companies and detachments arc authorized to wear cotton trousers and shirts, provided the wearing of same is uniform within each unit. 3. Companies and detachments equipped with caps, field, are auth - orized to wear same. 4. On and after October 1, 1938, thc uniform prescribed in General Order Xo. 5. daled September 21, 1935, will again be in effect. By order of Governor Cochran: H. I. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 23. 1938 General Orders No. 5 1. Pursuant to authority contained in Training Authority No. 43-1, File NGB 354.1 Nebr.-30, April 19, 1938. the following organizations will go into Camp of Instruction at the Government Rifle Range, Ashland, Nebraska, August 8 to 22, 1938, inclusive, under the command of Brigadier General Herbert J. Paul, and upon completion of this tour of duty will return to their home stations. Attention is invited to paragraph 37. NGR 45. State Staff and State Detachment 134th Infantry ! 1 10th Medical Regiment 1 10th Quartermaster Regiment Det. Hq.. 35th Division (1 off.) (in lieu of training with Hq., 35th Division) 2. An advance detachment, consisting of the following, will report as early as possible on August 5, 1938: State Staff and State Detachiiient, consisting of 1 Major, QMC. 1 Captain, QMC (commissary), and 18 enlisted men. Service Detachment, Service Co., 134th Inf., consisting of 1 First Lieutenant, 14 enlisted men. and 1 Captain (S. O.). 134th Inf. Communications Detachment', Hq. Co., 134th Inf. consisting of 3 enlisted men (installation of camp telephones). Service Detachment, Service Co., 110th Med. Regt.. consisting of 1 Captain (S. O.). and 12 enlisted men. Company I, 110th Med. Regt.. consisting of 1 Captain. MC. The Commanding Officer, 110th Med. Regt., will see that this Cap - tain is provided with the necessary equipment to establish a camp infirmary. Service Detachment, Hq. Company, 110th QM Regt., consist - ing of 1 First Lieutenant (S. O.), and 10 enlisted men. This advance detachment is for the purpose of ctsablishing Camp for thc reception of troops. 4. Upon arrival in Camp, August 5, 1938, the Commanding Of - ficer, Service Detachment, 134th Inf., will establish mess for his Detach- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ment and the Detachment, Hq. Company, 134th Inf. The Commanding Officer. Service Detachment. 110th Med. Regt.. will establish mess for his Detachment. Service Detachment, 110th QM Regt., and the State De - tachment. The officers in charge should sec that at least one regular cook is included for each of these messes. Commanding Officers of thc 134th Inf., 110th Med. Regt.. and 110th QM Regt. will sec that tbe necessary equipment for establishing commissaries is forwarded with thc advance detachment. The Commanding Officer, Hq. Company, 134th Inf., will see that the detachment from his company is supplied with sufficient equip - ment for the installation of camp telephones. 5. The following enlisted men will draw one additional day's pay, August 7. 1938: Service Co.. 110th Med. Regt. 2 Noncommissioned officers (Sgts.) &gt;. 18 Enlisted men — truck drivers Co. I, 110th Med. Regt. 2 Noncommissioned officers (Sgts.) 18 Enlisted men — truck drivers Co. A. 110th QM Regt. 2 Noncommissioned officers (Sgts.) 24 Enlisted men — truck drivers Co. B, 110th QM Regt. 2 Noncommissioned officers (Sgts.) 28 Enlisted men— truck drivers Co. E. 110th QM Regt. 1 Noncommissioned officer (Sgt.) 16 Enlisted men — truck drivers A list of the enlisted personnel by grades will be furnished immediately upon arrival in Camp so that special orders may be published for payment of travel rations, not to exceed 40 cents per meal. 6. A rear detachment consisting of 1 Major, QMC, 1 Captain, QMC (Commissary), and 18 enlisted men of the State Staff and State Detach - ment and 1 Captain, MC. Co. I. 110th Med. Regt., will remain in Camp August 23. 1935, for the purpose of necessary detail incident to the de - parture of troops from Camp. 7. Details as to transportation, supplies, equipment, etc., will be handled by circular letters from this office. S. All enlisted men will be physically examined on the day of their arrival "is Camp. Thc annuel physical examination of officer-; i.nd warrant </seg>
            <seg id="p032">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL officers will be had either before or during the period of Camp of Instruc - tion (paragraph 4, NGR 27). 9. Pursuant to authority contained in Training Authority No. 43-2, File NGB 354.1-30, April 19, 1938, as amended by Change No. 1, NGB, April 26, 1938, the following organization will report at Camp Clark, Mis - souri, August 14 to 28, 1938. inclusive: Det. Hq., 35th Division. 10. Pursuant to authority contained in Training Authority No. 43-3, April 19, 1938, the follov.:ng organization will report at Fort Riley. Kan - sas: Det. Hq., 69th Inf. Brig. i 1. Leavs of absence or furloughs, except in special cases anet for very urgent reasons, will not be granted during the camp period. 12. Thc travel directed is necc-isary in the military service of thc State. By order of Governor Cochran: ;The Adjutant General, Nebraska. H. J. PAUL. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General Nebraska. |; ' • ."■■'■■ </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 15, 1938 General Orders No. 6 1. It is with profound sorrow that the Commander-in-Chief announces the death of Capt. Henry Howard Marsden, Chaplain, 110th Med. Regt., Nebraska National Guard and National Guard of the United States, on September 8, 1938. 2. Henry Howard Marsden was born in Lawrence, Massa - chusetts, March 5, 1883. The following is a statement of his mili - tary service: Commissioned Ist Lt., Chaplain, Maryland NG, July 18, 1917; Chaplain 3 D. C. Inf.; Chaplain 148 FA, October 9, 1917. Served overseas from January 22, 1918, to June 14, 1919. En - gagements in which he took part were Chateau-Thierry Sec - tor: Clianipagnc-Marne; Aisne-Marne; Vcsle Sector; St. Mi - hiel; Meusc Argonnc. Honorably discharged July 15, 1919. Joined the Nebraska National Guard November 13, 1934, and was commissioned Capt., Chaplain, and assigned to the Hq. 110th Med. Regt. Commissioned Capt.. Chaplain, NGUS, February 19, 1935. 3. Captain Marsden. through his cheerful and kindly disposi - tion, endeared himself not only to the members of the 110th Medi - cal Regiment, but to the members of thc entire Nebraska National Guard. It was a pleasure tei visit with him and one felt better for having bad the opportunity of eloing so. His untimely death was a shock to all who knew and loved him and he will be missed more and more as time goes on. The entire National Guard of Nebraska and Governor Cochran, its Coiiimaiider-in-Chicf, ex - tend their sincere sympathy to bis family in this, their hour of sorrow. By order of Governor Cochran: Thc Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. J. PAUL, H. C. STEIN, Assistant Adjutant General, . ' Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 25. 1938 General Orders No. 7 1. Armistice Day. Friday, November 11. 1938, will be observed as a holiday in honor of those who served their country in the World War. The National Flag will be displayed on all National Guard Armories within the State at half-staff from sunrise until noon, when it will he - raised to full staff, remaining there until sunset. All National Guard organizations are hereby authorized to parade on thc basis of an armory drill, when requested to do so by patriotic societies. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Assistant Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 4, 1937 Circular Letter No. 1 Subject: Requests for Publications. To: All Officers of the Nebraska National Guard. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned. This should be brought most forcibly to the attention of all junior officers, as they seem to be the main offenders. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL "1. Many requests for training regulations and other military pub - lications are being received in the National Guard Bureau from junior of - ficers. Practically all such requests are sent direct to the Bureau or reach the Bureau through Representatives in Congress. 2. Due to the necessity of keeping within thc funds made available, the number of such pamphlets printed by the War Departrafent is limited. They are distributed in bulk through the respective state headquarters. 3. In checking over the lists of some of the applicants, it is found that many of the publications requested arc obsolete and have been super - seded by more recent issues. Also many contain requests for publica - tions that are not applicable to the duties of the officer concerned. Had the requests been forwarded through tbe proper military channels, doubt - less the discrepancies mentioned would have been noted and corrected. Also many of the publications could be furnished by company, battalion or regiment headquarters if the proper channels of communication had been observed. 4. The Bureau is very anxious that all National Guard officers have access to the training regulations which they need in the prosecution of their military duties. Also every effort is being made to train young of - ficers in thc proper use of military channels. Your cooperation is especial - ly requested with the hope that this office may be relieved of embarrass - ment and unnecessary work and that the junior officers may be instructed as to the proper military procedure in obtaining such pamphlets as arc available and necessary. (Signed) Albert H. Blanding, Major General, Chief, National Guard Bureau." By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 12, 1937 Circular Letter No. 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Subject: Head Pads and Frame Assemblies for Steel Helmets. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Commanding General, Seventh Corps Area, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. Information has been received from Rock Island Arsenal, Illinois, that only a limited number of Helmet Head Pads and Frame Assemblies are being manufactured, covering which a priority list has been established by the Chief of Ordnance. 2. It is the policy of this heade[uarters that during the annual in - spection of Ordnance material, the Ordnance inspector will report to this, headquarters thc number of Helmets, Steel, on hand in each organization requiring replacement of unserviceable head pads. The organization com - mander then receives from this headquarters written instructions to place the number of head pads reported by thc inspector as unserviceable on Inventory and Inspection Report or Report of Survey, to be elisposed ol locally in accordance with existing regulations, and to submit a requisition for the quantity so disposed of. 3. It is requested that all officers who ititiatc Inventory and In - spection Reports or Survey Reports, and all officers appointed to act there - on be instructed thai in the absence o'. wrifen instructions from this head - quarters, no helmet bead paels be disposed of on Inventory and Inspection Report or Survey Report. For thc Commanding General: (Signed) JAMES TOTTHN. Colonel. A.G.D.. Adjutant General." By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p037">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL April 21, 1937 Circular Letter No. 3 Subject: Preliminary and Record Firing of Rifle, Auto Rifle, Machine Gun and Howitzer Company Weapons, 1937. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, NNG. 1. All preliminary and record firing during 1937 will be conducted at home stations or ranges previously used for preliminary firing and must be completed prior to August 1. 2. Prescribed courses: Rifle Course D, Basic Field Manual Vol 111, Part 1, Chap. 1. All enlisted men of Rifle Companies are authorized and required to fire except those who have qualified as marksmen or better during one of the two preceding target seasons. All other en - listed men armed with the rifle are authorized to fire with the same exception as given above. Auto Rifle Course C, Basic Field Manual Vol. 111, Part 1, Chap. 2. No enlisted man is authorized to fire the auto rifle unless he has qualified with the Cal. .30 rifle. 3. Company Commanders must bear in mind that the Cal. .30 am - munition that will be shipped from the State Arsenal is to cover both pre - liminary and record fire as no additional is available for issue. 4. Machine Gun companies will conduct preliminary and record fire with the Cal. .22 Machine Gun. Howitzer Company will fire record fire with the 37 mm and trench mortars to the fullest extent that ammunition issued will permit. 5. Officers having charge of Record Fire are as follows: Hq. Co. and Hq. Co., 2nd Bn.. 134th Inf. Capt. E. B. Peterson Service Co.. 134th Inf Capt. Harry A. Beckley How. Co. and Co. E, 134th Inf Capt. J. Ned Allison Hq. Co., Ist Bn., and Co. A, 134th Inf Major W. G. Utterback Co. B, 134th Inf Capt. M. F. Myers Co. C, 134th Inf Capt. H. C. Collier Co. D, 134th Inf Capt. F. C. Petersen Co. F, 134th Inf Major L. R. Eby </seg>
            <seg id="p038">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ?• S : Capt - r - c - ™*y Ho ?„ ,H P. -,-,7,-77'- Capt. Edgar Barratt ? q ' . ,7 f_ \ ,"" 34th Inf 2nd Lt ' F ' H ' Weyand r°" 1 iV" f ; - lst Lt ' CL. Dier E°" 5* *"? , C °- h 134th Inf Lt ' Col. B. C. Grasborg Co. M, 134th Inf Major E j G g I Co. A, 110th QM Reg, Ma / or D £ £gg Co. B. 110th QM Regt Capt . w&lt; H Vak , s e h Co. C and Co. D. 110th QM Regt Major W. J. Atkinson 6. Officers having charge of Record Firing will familiarize them - selves with existing regulations pertaining to the conduct of Record Fire - before firing is started and will sign all individual score cards immediately upon completion of each stage of firing. 7. Staff officers having charge of firing may claim Armor, Drill credit for same. By order of the Governor: H . J. PAUL. The Adjutant General, Nebraska I STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April ;:i. 1&lt;)37 Circular Letter No. 4 Subject: Mothers' Day. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, NNG. The second Sunday in May having been dedicated to the mo'hers of our country as the day on which we should express the love and reverence we owe them, you are directed to bring to the attention of the members of your organizat.on who may be separated from their mothers on May 9 the duty they can fulfill and the pleasure they can give by writing home on Mothers Day. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, Thc Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA -' ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 16, 1937 Circular Letter No. 5 Subject: Annual Physical Examination; 1937. To: All Officers and Warrant Officers, NNG. There is inclosed NGB Form No. 63, "Report of Physical Examina - tion of Officers and Warrant Officers,'' for your annual 1937 examination, requesting that, if possible, same be submitted to this office not later than August 10. 1937. This also applies to enlisted men holding commission in NGUS. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN. Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 25, 1937 Circular Letter No. 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Subject: Allotment of Strength. To: AH Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with letter NGB, 325.4-Nebr.-4, Subject, Strength Allotment, dated May 3, 1937, thc maximum enlisted strength of the Ne - braska National Guard will be as follows: F-nlisted Men State Detachment lg 134th Infantry Med. Dept. Det 32 Hq. Co 64 Service Co. (Less Band) 55 Service Co. (Band) 34 How. Co 64 Bn. Hq. Companies „ 25 Rifle and M.G. Companies 04 110th Medical Regiment Serv. Co. (Less Band) 42 Serv. Co. (Band) 25 Vet. Co 38 Co. C 63 Co. D 47 Co. F 47 Co. I 63 110th QM Regiment Hq. Co 31 Med. Dept. Det \\ Co. A 45 Co. B 45 Co. C 45 Co D ] 45 Co. E ; 31 2. Where there has been a change in the apportionment in some of the companies a sufficient number will immediately be discharged so as to some within these figures. This allowance must not be exceeded until authority is granted by this office. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. The companies or detachments affected by the change will reduce noncommissioned officers and specialists within the number authorized by Tables of Organization for the strength set out above. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 8, 1937 Circular Letter ■ No. 7 Confidential Military Information. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PALTL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 20, 1937 Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1937, Fourth Army Maneuvers, Camp Whiteside, Kansas. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. Tbe dates of the annual encampment, 1937, having been set, i.e., </seg>
            <seg id="p042">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL August 15 to August 29, inclusive. 1937, no organization will be excused from =";»d&gt;n^except when they do not comply with the provisions of Section 111. NGR 45. At this point you are cautioned as to tbe absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted section and citations contained therein, as non-compliance therewith will cause forfeiture of pay of company officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the USP &amp; DO as to truck movements, train schedules and purchase of travel rations for enlisted men. 3. Travel Discipline. The senior /ine officer will assume command of the men of the convoy or train (par. 94, NGR 71). and see that travel discipline ,s maintained. The officers or noncommissioned officers in charge of motor transportation are held responsible for condition and equipment of trucks and for speed of convoy. Officers in charge of troops will not infringe upon this prerogative. 4. Travel Uniform. Enlisted men will wear woolen O.D shirt&lt; cot - ton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewed on. issue leggins and is - sue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Company commanders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian clothing to camp as they will not be permitted to wear same on leave or otherwise dur - ing the fifteen day training period. 5. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Traininß Rcgtt - ations 50-80 and 50-90. except steel helmets, pistols, bayonets and scab - bards, service caps. Extra blankets, cloth-ng. raincoats, shoes, toilet ar - ticles, etc.. and the bed sack and mosquito bars will be taken bv each in - dividual as personal baggage in the barrack bag. Companv commanders should check each enlisted man to sec that be provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth brush, tooth paste, hand soap, etc and that he has extra issue clothing, i.e., cotton breeches and OD shirts (Slacks and cotton shirts may be worn after retreat or when not on duty.) Trunk lockers arc not authorized for enlisted men. Each officer (below field grade) 1 bed roll 1 clothing roll or hand bag .*- Each field officer 1 trunk locker in addition to that authorized above for officers I </seg>
            <seg id="p043">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 6. Additional Equipment, Only the following equipment pertain - ing to the organization will be brought to camp: a. Field ranges No. 1 with contents, and bags water sterilizing. b. Rifles and automatic rifles, with arms racks sufficient for same, and only in the amounts necessary to properlv equip the men of your company. Four (4) cal. .30 M.G. with mounts for each M G company and ammunition and water boxes only in the amount that can be carried on the mounts. Two (2) 37 mm guns and two (2) 3-inch trench mortars by the Howitzer Company. c. Only sufficient quartermaster, medical and engineer property necessary to carry out the trainning program of the organization. d. Records. Field desks A and B, with thc necessary personnel and property records. e. All signal equipment now in possession of troops participating in thc maneuvers will be taken with them, extra wire tvpe W-110 (Par. 9. Annex 7, Mvr Memo. No. 8, 1937. 7th CA, Signal equip - ment.) f. Lengths of pipes or rods to improvise a grate over incinerator for heating water must be provided. (Par. 9. Annex No 1 Mvr Memo. No. 8. 1937, 7th CA.) g. Gas masks will be carried to concentration area for all organiza - tions, for training purposes only. Masks will be used during actual field exercises as ordered. (Par. 3, Annex No. 5 Mvr Memo. No. 8, 1937, 7th CA.) h. No ammunition of any type whatsoever, either ball or blank, will be taken to maneuvers either by organizations or individuals. Organization commanders will make thorough inspections to in - sure compliance, and will be held strictly responsible therefor. (Par. 1, Annex No. 2, Mvr. Memo. No. 8, 1937, 7th CA.) i. Repair chests and spare parts, cleaning and preserving material (Par. 4. Annex No. 2, Mvr. Memo. No. 8. 1937, 7th CA.) j. Tentage with poles and pins, G.I. cans and milk cans will be is - sued to each company and detachment upon arrival at camp. 7. A complete list, in quadruplicate, of all officers and men will be turned in immediately by regiments or separate detachments to the 35th Division adjutant upon your arrival at camp, with a notation opposite the name of the absentee showing the reason for such absence. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 8. Messes. All company officers and reserve officers attached will mess with their organization. Every effort should be made to secure the best possible cooks and mess sergeants, as a good mess is one of the most important things toward contentment and good morale of an organization. Thc commanding General, 69th Infantry Brigade, will arrange an of - ficers' mess for his brigade headquarters and the field and staff of the 134th Infantry. The Commanding Officers of the 110th Medical Regi - ment and the 110th Quartermaster Regiment will arrange with the Head - quarters Commandant for the mess of their respective field and staff of - ficers. The State Staff will arrange for their mess with the Headquarters Commandant. Regimental commanders will receive their assignment for quarters and messes in accordance with Annex No. 1, Mvr. Memo. No. 2, 1937, Headquarters 35th Division. 9. Field and Staff officers' cars and one car per company or detach - ment will be permitted. No privately owned motorcycles will be per - mitted. No mileage is authorized nor will gasoline be available for pur - chase at Camp Whiteside or Ft. Riley. Owners will register their cars with the Provost Marshal, 35th Division. Cars brought to camp will be at owner's risk and expense. Commanding officers of companies :.nd de - tachments must travel with their organization. 10. The attention of all unit commanders is called to thc necessity of determining to the best of their knowledge and belief that their men are physically fit before taking them to camp, as the number of major opera - tions in camp must be reduced and the only operative cases that will be taken care of during camp will be for conditions that have not previously existed and have been brought about during camp and in line of duty. 11. Unit commanders will, by physical inspection, make sure that they arc not bringing any venereal cases to camp, and in case any are found upon physical examination made upon entering camp, such men will be returned to their home station at their own expense, without pay or al - lowance, as they will not be permitted in camp. 12. Water for drinking purposes will be entirely from reliable public utilities sources. 13. Unit and sub-unit commanders will read this letter- to their com mand at every armory drill between the time of its receipt and the time of entrucking or entraining for camp. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, . Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 22, 1937 Circular Letter No. 9 Subject: Instructions in Connection with Troop Movements, Fourth Army Maneuvers, Ft. Riley Phase, Camp Whiteside, Kansas. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. The following concerning troop movements are extracts taken from letters of instructions, Fourth Army, Seventh Corps Area and National' Guard Bureau: 1. Troop Movement Table (rail) : See Annex No. 1 attached. Field and Staff Officers will travel with troops from home station, either by rail or motor. 2. Railroad Equipment: Railroad equipment necessary for the move - ment will be arranged for by Fourth Army Headquarters and will be placed prior to tlcparturc as indicated in the schedule. 3. .Inspection of Railroad Equipment: a. Car inspection at entrain - ing and detraining points and all entraining and detraining will be super - vised by all company and detachment commanders insofar as they have occupied any of the railroad equipment. b. In order to obviate claims and correspondence in connection with the troop movement, tbe provisions of paragraphs 4 and 15, AR 30-945, as amended by Changes No. 3, and paragraph 94-j, NGR 71, relative to thc inspection of, damage to, or loss of equipment, should be carefully studied by all. concerned and complied with in all respects. 4. Transportation Requests and Bills of Lading: a. Transportation requests and bills of lading covering National Guard movement will be issued by tbe United. States Property and Disbursing Officer. Use rate table, Annex No. 3, for per capita fare one way and for freight rates. b. It may be impossible to arrange, with all the carriers concerned, to secure travel by presentation of transportation requests in lieu of tick- </seg>
            <seg id="p046">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ets. or to have a ticket aboard the train to issue tickets in exchange for the transportation request after the exact number of tickets needed is known. This will necessitate the issuance of transportation requests which, in some cases, will show the number of passengers to be more than the actual number that travel. This necessitates return of surplus tickets and a careful check on the part of the Officer in Charge of Troop Move - ments to see that the Government is charged only for the actual i.umber ot troops transported. C The Officer in Charge of Troop Movement must turn the trans - portation request over to the ticket agent prior to boarding train in ex - change for railroad tickets. Care should be taken that sufficient individual tickets arc secured to take care of any shortage in personnel. Should the count show the number of passengers to be less than the number called for by the transportation request, a proper notation as to the actual num - ber of persons transported should be made on the back of the transporta - tion request and signed by the officer. Under certain circumstances it may be impossible for the officer to make this notation without holding i.p the departure of the train, in which case this notation may be omitted. Upon verification of thc actual number of tickets to be used, the unused tickets should be returned at once to the United States Propertv and Disbursing Officer, with a statement showing the designation of the unit the Main number of the train, thc number of troops actuallv transported, and the number of unused tickets returned for the adjusting of accounts with the carriers. d. In addition to the copies of transportation request: and bills of lading now required by regulations, in each instance the issuing officer Z\, P /?!- rC a " d fUrn ' Sh a " CXtra COpy of each transportation request and bill of lading to G-4, Fourth Army, Headquarters Fourth Army Presidio of San Francisco. California, and one to G-4. Seventh Corps A.-a Head - quarters, Omaha, Nebraska. These extra copies of transportation request will have to be made on plain paper, and it is essential for purposes of ac - counting that they be accurate copies of the original request, containing full information as to the number of officers and men covered by the transportation request, starting point, organization, routing and transporta - tion request number. (See sub-paragraph i, below.) e. Each United States Property and Disbursing Officer will be ad - vised in orders issued by Commanding General, Fourth Armv as to the number of troops to be transported by rail, as well as the amount of equipage and impedimenta authorized for shipment. In no case will the number of troops or amount of equipage or impedimenta authorized be in - creased without specific authority from this headquarters. The United States Property and Disbursing Officer will be held strictly responsible for any obligations in excess of these authorizations. Number of troops and im - pedimenta authorized — see Annex No. 4 attached. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL f. Attention is invited to the fact that transportation requests will be issued for each journey, going and returning: * * * i. In order that the Fourth Army and Seventh Corps may have prompt information of the number of officers and men transported, copy ot transportation request for these headquarters as indicated in paragraph d. above, will be furnished the officer receiving the transportation request, with an addressed envelope to G-4, Fourth Army, Headquarters Fourth Army. Presidio of San Fransicso, California, and G-4, Seventh Corps Area. Omaha. Nebraska, with instructions to complete it in the same manner as for the original transportation request at hour of departure, and to mail it at once. The same procedure will be followed with respect to the extra copy of bill of lading to be furnished these headquarters. j. As a further check on the actual number of troops transported and costs involved, arrangements have been made with thc carriers tc secure an extra copy of the Conductor's report. This Conductor's report, which is used as a basis for the settlement of accounts, will be made in triplicate by thc Conductor for each unit of the train. This report is made out after the number of fares have been verified by both the Conductor and the Officer in Charge of the Troop Movement and is signed by both. The original Conductor's report is retained by the Conductor. The two copies retained by the Officer in Charge of Troop Movement will be disposed of as follows: U. S. Property and Disbursing Officer, Nebraska— for the incoming movement at Camp Whiteside, Kansas, and for the return move - ment they will be mailed to Lincoln, Nebraska. k. For the return movement from concentration area to home sta - tion the number of troops to be transported should be accurately known within a very small variation, and transportation requests should,' as far as possible, show the exact number for which tickets are needed; however, the same instructions in regard to the Conductor's report remain in effect. I. It is requested that the United States Property and Disbursing Officer furnish one copy of these instructions to each Officer in Charge of Troop Movements, and include a card with a memorandum showing the Main number of the train, the number of tickets secured, thc actual num - ber of tickets used, and the number of tickets returned, for the signature of the USP&amp;DO. This card when completed will be mailed to G-4, Fourci Army, in the same envelope with copy of the transportation request re - quired by paragraph 4 i. m. NGR 71 will be carried out with respect to the preparation and </seg>
            <seg id="p048">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL listing of property for shipment. Pick up and delivery service by railroads at points of origin will be used whenever available in connection with shipments on bills of lading if a saving in net cost will result. No drayage is authorized. No switching charges are authorized. n. Attention is invited to pargraphs 72, 73, 74, 75 and 76, NGR 71, which will be complied with, in addition to the above instructions, where applicable. o. Freight shipments will be consolidated wherever possible to take advantage of carload rates. p. Precautions will be taken to insure that all checkable baggage is shipped as such and not placed on bills of lading as impedimenta. q. Freight shipments of impedimenta pertaining to troops moving by motor will not be accepted by the carriers under the impedimenta rates. Care will be taken to insure that such shipments are so handled as to se - cure thc lowest obtainable rates in each case. 5. Meals on Train: Baggage cars for use as kitchen cars have not been prescribed due to the fact that in most cases it is believed that same were not desired, organizations preferring to subsist to and from the camp by use of cooked rations or lunch. 6. Command of Trains: The senior line officer will assume com - mand of the men of the convoy or train. The officer so designated will be responsible for the control, discipline and orderly conduct of all the troops on the train or convoy. In all movements by rail officers in charge of trains will be held responsible that all cars are filled to the capacity limit, regardless of whether or not two or more organizations are assigned to the same coach. Such officers, prior to any rail movement from an en - training point, will request railroad authorities to remove unnecessary or empty cars from tbe train. In case an unnecessary car was not removed a report will be made to the Corps Area Quartermaster giving all circum - stances regarding the same. 7. Motorized companies will follow out truck schedule, Annex No. 2, as outlined, transporting troops other than their own companies as in - dicated in the schedule. Where thc truck schedule indicates trucks to be furnished advance and rear detachments, drivers will not be furnished with these trucks. Convoys are to maintain an average speed of between 20 and 25 miles per hour. Intervals between vehicles is to be not less than 200 yards as per instructions in letter from Headquarters, Seventh Corps Area, dated </seg>
            <seg id="p049">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL July 16, 1937. In all motor movements convoy regulations as given in War Depart - ment publications must be observed, with the exception of intervals be - tween vehicles. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, QMC, NGUS, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. 4 Incls. Annex No. 1 to 4, incl. ( </seg>
            <seg id="p050">NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD TO FORT RILEY 1 r TYPE OP DEPARTURE ARRIVAL CARS REMARKS AMI J _\ ENTRAINING DETRAINING KOUTJNG £ KK UNITS f* M a POINTS Date Hour POINTS Wats Hour Main :J _\ •&gt; Time used is Central 2 Ao. ol a a Standard Time unless 28' .-j" '3 otherwise noted. 1 2433 2 lln Hq 110 (JM Kegt 2 Kearney 8-15 12:3U A.M. Camp Whitrs.de 8-15 ,'.30 A.M. Un Pac Co D III) &lt;JM Regt 47 t 1 Kearney Med Det 110 (JM Kegt 17 1 Kearney Co II 134th Int 67 1 1 Grand Island 1 :55 A.M. to G 134th Inf 67 1 1 Hastings 3:00 A.M. .! 2434 Serv Co 13411. In. .03 2 . York M» 3:27 A.M. 8.5 ,„:45 A.M. CB&amp;Q Lincoln; Un Co M 134th Jul 67 1 1 Seward 4 :0o A.M. Hq 3'Bu 134th inl 28 1 Lincoln 5 :3C A.M. -• 1..c. UnPac Co 1 134th Int 67 1 1 Lincoln Hq 110 Med Kegt is Union! Hq 110 (JM Kegt + Lincoln Vet Co 110 Med Regt 42 I Lincoln Co C 134 Inl 66 1 1 Beatrice 6:55 AM. u lt ,m \ m .. k.li i -4= \ M Mo l*ac Kans City; 3 2435 ,|„ Co Tlln 134 Inl 28 1 Nebraska City »-" &gt; :40 A.M. »-l» 1.45 A.M. »° •„'o A 134 Inl 67 1 1 Wlwaska City Co .1 134 Inl 67 1 1 KaMs City 3:20 A.M. Annex No. I— Movement Tables Fourth Army Maneuvers, 1937. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD TO FORT RILEY 2 — ; \ 3 | j [ 5 | 6 I / 8 I » I 10 ' | I. | H » \\ I'KOl' DEI'ARIURE ARRIVAL CAK S I REMARKS AND 0 RR UNIls 2 v: a ENTRAINING DETRAINING KOUTJNG z Main baa POINTS JJate Hour POINTS JJatc "our Tim( . uie d- is Central 2; No. S y a Standard Time unless 3 a &lt; S olherwisc noted. 2 '■« -J — 4 2430 Hq &amp; Det 69 Brig 4 Omaha 3-Ji 8:00 AM Camp Whiteside 815 4:30 I'M Un I'ac Hq 134 inl / Omaha " Regt Hq to lit Inl 66 1 Oiiaha ? Hq 2 Un 134 Int 28 1 Omaha " Co K 134 Inl 6/1 I Omaha " Co L 134 Inl 6/11 Omaha " Med Uep Det 37 1 Omaha Co C 110 Med Kegt 65 1 1 Columbus 6:30 AM b MJ; How to .34 hit 67 1 I Gering tM •&lt; '30 .'M " 8-16 9:3" AM Un Tac to D 134 lru 67 1 1 Norm l'latte 10 :W i*M Co C 110 _M Reg, 4/ I I Lc»in„ton 8-15 1.1:40 I'M to E 134 Inl «7 1 1 Scottsiiluti 4.4/ IM t Str.M&amp;O Omaha; 6 /.(38 Co r" 134 Int 6/ 1 I Hartmgton 8:;5 AM S!6 1:45 AM M oFac Ku . Un J*ac „, , " 71 , n ii NOTE: Gering and ScottsbluH— Mountain June. Annex No. 1— Movement Tables Fourth Army Maneuvers, 1937. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD TO HOME STATION 3 \~] 2 3 4 | 5 | 6 7 8 | !&gt; 10 | 1.1 12 13 TWBO* UKI'ARTURK ARRIVAL CARS REMARKS AWD 0 KK UNJTS 2 ;/) M KM RAINING DETRAINING ROUTING Main b a J I'OINTS IJate Hour I'UINTS JJa, &lt;- Hour Time used is central 2 No ' a U 3 Standard June unless 5 r 5 i; . otherwise noted. ■ : r 1 2523 Co C llli (JM Rest 4/ : 1 "Kort Riley 8-2t&gt; 2:30 I'M Lexington 8-29 4:011 AM Un l"ac. entrain at Co I) 134 Hit bi 1 1 North J'lalte u.:0ll AM Camp Whiteside How to 134 int 67 1 1 " tieiing 10:55 AM ;„ k ij4 Int W 1 1 " Scottublulf 8:55 AM Un Tao Grand Js - land; CllciO. ■ &#132; &#132; Un I'ac. 'Entrain at 2 2524 „„ s Ue , 69 , lriß 4 -. ":.0..M ,„„,,,.-, &#132;.» AM Camp , v hlt „ lde Hq 134 Int 7 " Omaha Regt ll«; to IJ4 Inl 6'! 1 ' Omaha Hq 2 lln 134 Inl 2a l " Omaha Co K 134 inl 07 1I '■ • Omaha Co L 134 Int 67 1 1 " Omaha Med Det 37 1 1 " Omaiia Co C 110 Men Kegt 6s 1 . 1 " Columbus 10:35 AM 3 2525 Co U 134 Int 6/ 1 1 ' 8-2'J 12:01 AM Hasting* 7:15 AM Un Tac. 'Entrain at to II 134 Inl 67 1 1 • •■ Grand Island 8:20 AM Camp Wh.teside 2'lln H&lt;i 110 o.it Rtßt 2 " Kearney 10:00 AM Co U 110 Uj.M R.ui ■»? 1 • " Kearney Med Det 111) ■ (JM Kegt 1/ 1 " Kearney Annex No. 1 — Movement Tables Fourth Army Maneuvers, 1937. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD TO HOME STATION 4 1 j 2 j 1 5 | 6 7 ~~| b II 1U 11 U \ 13 TVl'EOr DKI'AKTUKJS AKRIXAL CARS KEMAKKS ANJJ ~ &#132;„ - XJUXINU g "'&lt; UNITS /3 M KNTRAININU IIKTRAININU Main 3 y S I'Ot.VIS "»'« Hour POINTS Ua,c Hcur Time used is Cential 5 No 5 y a Standard Time unless. D5 &lt; '-3 otherwise noted. 4 2526 Co C 134 Inl 66 1 I * I-oi t Riley U-29 .2:31' AM Beatrice »•» 3 :3U AM Un I'.ie. -lintriin at Hq 3'Hn 134 lr.l 2s 1 " Lincoln '**?.** Camp Wnlteiio. Co 1 134 Inl C7 1 1 Lincoln Hq 110 .Med Krci S Lincoln Hq 110 Mil Kegt 4 Lincoln Vet Co 110 Med Kegt 42 1 I incoln Co M 134 int 67 11 " Sl , ward „ :0:, AM Serv Co 134 Inl 103 . 1 York U;&lt;4AM 5 2527 Co 11 134 int £7 t 1 " 2 :00 AM Fa „, City 11 : uy AM l „ I'ac Kansas City; Hq Co .' Bn 13! in. U 1 " Nebraska City '*•'» *■ M ° **" "f^S Co A 134 in. 67 11 ' Nebraska City &#132; i'o v ill i«i 6/11 ' &#132; ■ . II !'« JM Ln I'ac Aansas City, Lo * 134 ln ' 6/ Hart.ngton Mo ,, ac Unmiun CStI'M&amp;U Annex No. 1 — Movement Tables Fourth Army Maneuvers, 1937. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 23, 1937 Circular Letter No. 10 Subject: Extracts. Maneuver Memorandums, 1937, Headquarters Sev - enth Corps Area, Fourth Army Maneuvers, Camp Whiteside. Kansas. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers. NNG. The following e-xlracts are- taken from Maneuver Memorandums, Sev - enth Corps Area, and will be read and explained to members of your com - mand. Annex No. 1, Maneuver Memorandum No. 7. * * * * "6. UMPIRE FLAG SIGNAL CODE.— a. WHITE FLAG . vertical and stationary . . . CEASE FIRING OR TIME OUT FOR UMPIRE DECISION. Personnel of both of the opposing forces with - in 500 yards of the Hag location will cease firing immediately and re - main in position until further movement is authorized. This signal will be used by Contact or Area Umpires to temporarily suspend the opera - tions in a particular locality. b. RED FLAG .. . vertical and stationary. RED or GREEN has fire superiority anel can advance in proper formation. BLUE CANNOT ADVANCE. c. BLUE FLAG . . . vertical and stationary. BLUE lias lire su - periority and can advance in proper formation. RED or GPEEN CAN - NOT ADVANCE. d. RED FLAG WITH WHITE CENTER . . . vertical and sta - tionary. The area within 100 yards of (his signal is covered by artillery fire. Units in or passing through the area will receive casualties. e. YELLOW FLAG . . . Fire from .30 caliber MG's. f. BLACK FLAG . . . Fire from .50 caliber MG's and 37-mm guns. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 7. IDENTIFICATIONS.— a. Personnel and material carrying the identifying marks as shown below will be allowed free access be - tween the contesting forces: VII CORPS STAFF — Blue and white arm bands, blue uppermost — (AR 600-35). UMPIRES PERSONNEL— White hat and arm bands. OBSERVERS— YeIIow arm bands. PRESS REPRESENTATIVES— White arm bands with black "C." MILITARY POLICE— BIue arm bands with white "MP." UMPIRE PLANES— White streamers. NEUTRAL VEHICLES— White sticker, 3"x 6", lower hight hand corner of windshield. OFF LIMIT AREAS — Signs and orange streamers. b. Identifying marks for contending forces will be as shown be - low: GREENS AND REDS— Red arm bands for all troops. BLUES — No distinguishing mark. GREEN AND RED OBSERVATION PLANES— Red streamer BLUE OBSERVATION PLANES— No distinguishing mark. ISLUE MOTOR VEHICLES— BIue sticker, 3"x6", lower right hand corner of windshield. GREEN AND RED MOTOR VEHICLES— Red sticker. 3"x6", . lower right hand corner of windshield." * * * * Section 11. Annex No. 8, Maneuver Memorandum No. 8. * * * ♦ "7e. In the interest of the United Slates and the property and rights of land owners, the following instructions will be read and carefully explained to all officers and enlisted men taking part in the maneuvers prior to departure from home stations, again immedi - ately upon arrival in the initial areas and from time to time thereafter as determined by commanders concerned: </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (1) Officers and enlisted men will avoid entering private build - ings in the concentration and maneuver area which have not been rent - ed bythe Rents and Claims Officer. (2) Cultivated lands or field containing growing crops or recenth seeded crops will not be molested. (3) Pilfering fruits and vegetables by troops is strictly prohibited. (4) Thc breaking or cutting or otherwise injuring of trcer will be scrupulously avoided. (5) Especial care will be taken tt&gt; prevent the escape of livestock from enclosures or their transfer to another enclosure. Should animals escape from enclosures, maneuvering troops will return them to their enclosures. (6) Whenever practicable, gates will be used by troops and ve hiclcs. Umpires will not penalize troops who may expose themselves to assumed hostile fire through following these instructions. (7) Gates will ALWAYS be closed and secured after passage through them. (8) Fences may be cut ONLY where gates are not available for the passage of vehicles or animals. In any case, only gaps large enough to admit vehicles in column will be opened. Woven wire fences will not be cut. (9) When fences arc cut, they will be- repaired by tbe ui.it con - cerned IMMEDIATELY after the passage of the vehicles or animals. Field (communications) wire on such fences will not be cut but will be removed from fences and laid flat on thc ground. (10) Troops passing through or over fences will take particular care to avoid damaging fence posts and breaking wire. (11) When on private property, established roads and trails will be used as far as practicable. (12) Poultry, pigs, and other farm animals, garden and orchard produce, will NOT be molested. Troops will avoid trespassing upon gardens, lawns or any other portions of premises in the immediate vicinity of houses and buildings. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (13) No ditches or trenches will be dug on private lands. This applies particularly to ditching of tents and field fortifications. Pits for latrines and kitchens are authorized where required, but will be filled and covered with clean dirt before departure of troops. Tin cans, bot - tles and other indestructible material will, after burning, be placed in pits on land not likely to be subsequently plowed or excavated, and will be covered with clean soil. (14) Pollution of water in streams, lakes, wells and other sources is prohibited. (15) SMOKING and the building of FIRES in thc vicinity of stables, barns, straw and haystacks and other areas which may con - stitute hazard are PROHIBITED. (16) Whenever damages cannot be repaired by troops on the spot, they will be promptly reported to the representative of the Rents and Claims Section in the area by any officer or umpire having knowl - edge thereof. Notation on map of ' definite location, and the names of two competent available witnesses as to the damage will be furnished with tbe report. (17) Umpires will watch for and direct the correction of damages insofar as practicable. (18) In the event of damage to private property of any nature, the landowners or tenants will be informed that the Rents and Claims Section will investigate thc matter and make a satisfactory atljustment for such damage. Under no circumstances will any officer or enlisted man make any promise of reimbursement to such landowner or tenant. ( 19) Camp and bivouac areas will be thoroughly policed by units on departure therefrom. (20) Hunting of any character is prohibited. (21 ) The use of live ammunition of any caliber in the maneuver area is PROHIBITED. (22) Any fishing done will be strictly in compliance with the Fish and Game Laws of the respective states. A State License MUST be secured. (23) Past experience in other maneuvers has indicated that most of the claims for damages developed from disregard of troops for the administrative instructions issued by higher headquarters. Had these </seg>
            <seg id="p058">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL instructions been complied with, practically all claims would have been eliminated. (24) (a) The drinking of water from any source except such as may be specifically designated and approved by a medical officer is pro - hibited. The local streams in the non-restricted area may be used for bathing and washing by the personnel and for the watering of animals. (b) In this connection, the responsible commanders will take the necessary measures to insure that bathing and washing in streams is authorized only below places prescribed for watering of animals." * * * * By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The- Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 2-1. 1937 Circular Letter No. 11 Subject: Nebraska National Guardsmen on WPA Payrolls. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following letter from D. I-'. Fclton. State Administrator, Works Progress Administration, Union Terminal Warehouse' Bldg., Lin - coln, Nebr.. is herewith reproduced for the- information and guidance of all concerned: "I wonder if it would be possible for someone in your office to pre - pare a list of the members of the National Guard who you expect, or they expect, to be in camp this summer. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Someone front your office requested that these people be allowed to attend this camp lor their summer activities and not be- released from the WPA payrolls on account of attending the camp meeting. I have taken this up with the Chicago office and I find that I will be able- to do this providing I can know who these men are and where- they arc front, in order to instruct the- foremen on the- project what action to take. Any information will be appreciated. Yours very truly, (Signed) D. F. Fclton, State Administrator." 2. In case- any members of the Nebraska National Guard are on WI'A payrolls, it is essential that Mr. Fclton be advised at once and Unit and Sub-unit Commanders are requested to communicate with him direct. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. -t STATIC OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 24, 1937 Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Visits to Canada in Uniform. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. Your attention is especially invited to the provisions and re - quirements of AR 605-115. AR 015-275 and AR 30-905 as changed by Cir - cular No. 20. W. D. March 9. 1937. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. Since requests for permission to visit Canada in uniform must be passed upon by the Department of State, it is absolutely essential that they reach the office of The Adjutant General at least fifteen days in ad - vance of the date it is desired to enter Canada. 3. In event that any requests are received which fail to meet the requirements as to time, they will be accorded neither approval nor a reply. For the Chief, National Guard Bureau: . (Signed) William E. Persons, Colonel, NGB., Executive." By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 26, 1937 Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Travel Ration to Fourth Army Maneuvers, Camp Whiteside, Kansas, 1937. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with par. 13, NGB Circular No. 23 A-13, December 2, 1936, responsible officers of companies or detachments arc authorized to purchase the necessary subsistence for enlisted men at not to exceed 30 cents per meal per man for the time involved in assembly, travel and arrival at camp, and will be computed as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p061">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL The ration day begins at midnight. Assembly at Armory Arrival at Camp Entitled to Before 7:00 AM Before 11:00 AM Morning meal After 11:00 AM Morning &amp; noon meals After 4:00 PM Morning, noon &amp; evening meals Between 7 AM. and noonßefore 11:00 AM Nothing After 11:00 AM Noon meal After 4:00 PM Noon &amp; evening meals Between noon &amp; 4:30 PM Before 4:00 PM Nothing After 4:00 PM Evening meal Balance of meals for first day will be furnished by 35th Div. Quartermaster. 2. Public voucher is inclosed for stating amount due and should be completed insofar as possible. After the articles have been listed indicate thereunder across the face of the voucher, 'Travel Rations, Co. , Regt.. (so many) enlisted men. (1 or 2) meals," as tbe case may be. Where two companies or detachments mess together show the organizations and the number of men separately. 3. Tbe attached report must be completed and accompany the voucher. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major. QMC, NGUS, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL In els. 2 1. Vouchers 2. Report TRAVEL RATION REPORT | 1937 Company Home Station Show date and hour of assembly Show date and hour of arrival at camp Enlisted strength attending camp (Name — signed by CO.") Rank and Branch This report must accompany the Travel Ration Voucher. (Inch to Nebraska Circular Letter No. 13, 1937.) ■ STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 26, 1937 Circular Letter No. 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Subject: Government Transportation Requests, Annual Encampment, 1937, Fourth Army Maneuvers, Camp Whiteside. Kansas. To: All Responsible Officers and for thc Information of All Field and Staff Officers. 1. In accordrice with par. 73 c, NGR 71. Government Transportation Request No. WQ is inclosed, to cover railroad transportation (tick - ets) for your company and any field and staff officers of the NNG residing at your station, to Camp Whiteside, Kansas, which should be completed in accordance with Check List "B" attached in duplicate. Transportation re - quest for return movement will be furnished at Camp Whiteside. 2. The responsible officer in this case is acting as transportation of - ficer and as train quartermaster and any accommodations in excess of those- authorized by regulations will be charged against the responsible officer. 3. Exchange transportation requests for tickets with your local agent. Read carefully NGR 70 and 71, with changes. 4. Report of Transportation NNG Fourth Army Maneuvers and Conductor's Re-port are inclosed and should be completed as required by paragraph 4 1 and j, Nebraska Circular Letter No. 9, 1937. 5. Tin- duplicate and triplicate T/R should be completed and mailed to the- G-4s, Army and Corps, as required in paragraph 4 i, Nebraska Cir - cular Letter No. 9, 1937. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, V Nebraska. OFFICIAL: H. C. STEIN, Major, QMC, NGUS, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. 5 Incls. 1. Original T/R and 2 memos. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. Check List "B," in dup. 3. Post Card WD MB 36. 4. Conductor's Reports as required. 5. Report of Transportation NNG. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 26, 1937 Circular Letter No. 15 Subject: Government Bill of Lading, Annual Encampment, 1937, Fourth Army Maneuvers, Camp Whiteside, Kansas. To: All Responsible Officers and for the Information of All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. Government Bill of Lading, WQ is inclosed for freight (not checkable baggage) involved in movement of your company to Camp Whiteside, Kansas. Bill of Lading for the return movement will be fur - nished while at camp. These Bills of Lading should be completed in ac - cordance with Check List "C" attached in duplicate. 2. Company Commanders will detail sufficient personnel to handle baggage at thc detraining point. 3. Read carefully NGR 71 and 72, with changes. Circular Letter By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: .. H. C. STEIN, Major, QMC, NGUS, USP&amp;DO, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3 Incls. ' 1. Original B/L with 5 memos and S.O. 2. Check List "C," in dup. 3. Property List, in quint. CHECK LIST "C"— BILLS OF LADING — 1937 Company Regiment Date The- following items should be checked and the original Check List turned in with thc different reports required. (Check here) 1. Opposite "Est. Cost $ ," upper right hand corner, insert the total actual cost. See Annex No. 3, Nebraska Circular Let - ter No. 9, 1937. 2. Insert number of packages under column "Number and Kind of packages" (see par. 40-b (7) NGR 71), and the total weight under column "Weights." Pick-up service at origin should be corrected and in thc case of going to Camp Whiteside it "was not" by the Government. On the return movement it will be "was" by the Government. This certificate should be signed by the consignor. 3. Insert length of car furnished, the date, initials and car num - ber. 4. Original B/ L and five memos to be signed by your local agent. The original B/L, properly executed under the con - signee's certificate of delivery, and two memos as indicated thereon to be turned in to the USP&amp;DO at Camp Whiteside, and two memos marked for G-4 of Army and Corps to be malted in the inclosctl envelopes. Also under thc consignee's certificate of delivery be sure to correct thc statement with reference to delivery service. On thc incoming movement it will b "was"' by tbe Government and on thc return move - ment it will be "was not." On the return movement the orig - inal B/L is to be surrendered to your local agent and two memos mailed immediately to the USP&amp;DO, Lincoln, Ne- </seg>
            <seg id="p066">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL braska, and the same procedure as outlined above for the remaining memos. 5. Shipping Order to be signed by you and surrendered to agent of railroad concerned. 6. Retain one memo for company files. 7. Property List, MB Form No. 34 (supply inclosed), as required by par. 30, NGR 71, will be prepared in quinttiplicate and one copy attached to each memorandum Bill of Lading. 8. Only federal property may be shipped on this Bill of Lading and you cannot exceed the weights authorized in Annex No. 4. Nebraska Circular Letter No. 9. 1937. Checkable baggage is not to be included on these Bills of Lading. (Name— signed by CO.) Rank and Branch STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 28. 1037 Circular Letter No. 16 Subject: National Matches. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. Inasmuch as the National Matches this year comes at a time that would necessitate those chosen as members of our team losing one full week of the Fourth Army Maneuvers and that it would be impossible to, take either field or staff officers or company commanders away from their </seg>
            <seg id="p067">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL organizations to accompany the Rifle Team, it has been decided that the Nebraska National Guard will not be represented by a Rifle Team at the National Matches this year. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 28, 1937 Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: Proper Mail Address to be used during Fourth Army Man - euvers. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders. NNG. The following letter from the Commanding General, 7th Corps Area, pertaining to the above subject is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. A copy of this should be posted on bulletin boards of the respective units. * * * * "NOTICE FOR ORGANIZATION BULLETIN BOARDS 1. Tho efficiency of the Postal Service during Maneuvers will de - pend upon the' extent to which correspondents are informed as to the correct address of individual officers and soldiers. 2. Each individual should inform his correspondents of the follow - ing instructions: a. All mail must bear the full name of addressee, his rank, his company, battery or troop, his regiment and his division. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL /-&gt;«• t'- , CamP „ R ' plcy Goncent ration mail will be addressed c/o Post Office, Little Falls. Minn. I„ no case will mail be addressed to SwanviHe! Off % A » Fort Riley Concentration mail will be addressed c/o Post Office, Fort Riley, Kansas. ' d. All mail must bear a return address in the upper left hand cor - ner of the envelope. e. Handwriting must be legible. f. All correspondents must be informed of tin- above as well as cautioned to reduce correspondence to a minimum. g. COD mail cannot be delivered. 3. a. The distribution of mail follows routine- militarv channels and individuals should not attempt to secure mail outside of routine channels. b. Collection of mail follows the prescribed routine channels The Postmasters concerned have requested that these channels be observed. (Sample of Address) RETURN TO— JANE DOE. ADDRESS 122 "A" STREET, PORTLAND, OREGON. PVT. JOHN DOE, COMPANY B. 367th INFANTRY 100th DIVISION, either c/o Post Office — FORT RILEY, KANS-\S or c/o Post Office— LlTTLE FALLS, MINNESOTA. By Command of Major General FORD - (Signed) JAMES TOTTEN. Colonel, A.G.D.. Adjutant General." </seg>
            <seg id="p069">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 6, 1937 Circular Letter No. 18 Subject: Amendment Nebraska Circular Letter No. 8, July 20, 1937. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. Paragraph 5 of the above cited letter is amended as follows: No field caps or pistol holsters will be taken. Fatigue clothing will be included in the equipment. 2. Checkable personal baggage, par. 44, NGR 70, not military im - pedimenta, must be transported by the company or detachment as the railroads have not provided pick-up service for this class of property. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN \ . </seg>
            <seg id="p070">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL August 6, 1937 Circular Letter No. 19 Subject: Mustering of Field Training Pay Rolls, 1937, Camp White - side, Kansas. To: All Responsible Officers. NNG. 1. The following instructions have been received from Headquarters, VII Corps Area, with reference to mustering the Field Training Pay Rolls of thc Nebraska National Guard. * * * * NATIONAL GUARD BULLETIN No. 16, VII Corps Area. Aug. 3. 1937 "1." DESIGNATION OF MUSTERING OFFICERS: Officers assigned as instructors of National Guard units for the duration of the- Field Training period arc designated as mustering officers for the units to which assigned (ref. Par. 25. NGR 58). * * * * SPECIAL ORDER No. 197. Headquarters VII Corps Area. July. 26, 1937. "19." Each of the following named officers (lutsr NG). will proceed at the proper time- to Fort Riley. Kansas, reporting upon arrival to thc Commanding General. VII Corps, for temporary duty as Instructor and Umpire of the organizations indicated, during the National Guard Field Training Camp, August 15 to 29, 1937. and upon completion of this duty will return to his proper station: ' * * * * Major HARVEY SH ELTON. Infantry. Conway. Arkansas. Hq. Staff, 35th Div. NNG. * * * * Major ROY T. ROUSE, Infantry. St. Joseph, Mo. Major BERT S. WAMPLER, Infantry, Cape Girardeau, Mo., SS &amp; SD; Hq. 69th Brig. &amp; 134th Inf., Nebr. NG. * ♦ * » Major GEORGE W. WEST. QMC, Lincoln, Nebr., QM Regt., Nebr.. NG. * * * » </seg>
            <seg id="p071">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL SPECIAL ORDER No. 192, Headquarters VII Corps Area, July 21, 1937. "19." Lt. Colonel WALTER P. DAVENPORT, MC. Lincoln, Ne - braska, 110th Med. Regt., Nebr., NG. • * * * 2. All Companies and Detachments must be mustered at Reveille August 21, 1957. and the pay rolls are to be submitted to the USP&amp;DO Nebraska not later than Noon of thc same day. No enlisted man will be excused from camp without prior written authority from the Headquarters, 35th Div.. and any enlisted men so excused for cause will be directed by his Company Commander to report to the mustering officer for muster be - fore departure. Unless this is complied with, no enlisted man or officer can be paid. 3. Thc following officers of the NNG are designated as mustering officers for tbe State Pay Rolls: Major FRED H. STOLL, Aux. Bn. Major BUTLER B. MILTONBERGER, Ist Bn. Major LOUIS R. EBY. 2nd Bn. Major EDWARD J. GEESEN. 3rd Bn. Lt. Col. P. H. BARRTHOLOMEW. 110th Med. Regt. Lt. Col. GUY N. HENNINGER, 110th QM Regt., SS &amp; SD. 4. Muster of State Pay Rolls will be accomplished after August 21, but all rolls will be completed and turned in to the office of the USP&amp;DO Nebraska not later than Noon, August 25, 1937. 5. Pay Roll forms will be secured from the USP&amp;DO Nebraska at thc time when you turn in reports on Transportation Requests and Bills of Lading. These rolls must be prenaretl during thc first week. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 10, 1937 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Circular Letter No. 20 Subject: Claims for Damages in Connection with thc Fourth Army Maneuvers. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following Utter is published for the information and guidance of all concerned and will be read to each Unit and Sub-unit and the ad - visability of adhering thereto will be impressed upon all concerned: "1. Due to the very limited funds available for the payment of claims for damages arising as a result of participation in the Fourth Army Maneuvers, it is of vital importance that all concerned cooperate in an en - deavor to entirely eliminate the necessity of paying any claims of any nature whatsoever. 2. Past experience has demonstrated that claims for damages to private property can be entirely eliminated if the troops participating in the maneuvers are' properly instructed and supervised. Such claims for damages are in every case a result of cither carelessness or a lack of proper instruction in the organization concerned. Damages to private property committed by troops of an organization are a direct indication of the state of discipline existing in that organization. 3. In connection with possible- claims for damages, attention is in - vited to the fact that claims for damages of any nature arising from par - ticipation in the maneuvers (except claims concerning damages committed by troops of the regular army that may be disposed of under the 105th Article of War) must be referred to this headquarters for necessary action by thc Rent &amp; Claims Section. The following are examples of claims that may be submitted and require such action: a. Damages arising from motor accidents, either in the maneuver area or in connection with the movement of troops and supplies between the maneuver area and home stations. b. Damages to crops, livestock, fences, buildings, trees, electric light or telephone lines, poles, etc. c. Damages to roads, walks, culverts, bridges, etc., on the public highway. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 4. It is desired that this matter be given careful attention and that the specific instructions contained in Annex No. 8 to Maneuver Memoran - dum No. 8, Rent &amp; Claims Plan, be strictly complied with. For thc Commanding General: (Signed) JAMES TOTTEN, Colonel, A.G.D., • Adjutant General." By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN September 7, 1937 Circular Letter No. 21 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, National Guard, Fiscal Year 1938. r° : All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned: "The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the number of Federal pay armory drills to be held by the National Guard during the Fiscal Year, 1938, be as follows: (a) A total of 48 during thc year. (b) Not more than 8 during any one month. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (c) A minimum of 10 per quarter during the second, third and fourth quarters. (Signed) ALBERT H. BLANDING, Major General, Chief, National Guard Bureau." By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, Thc Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT ! LINCOLN September 22. 1937 Circular Letter No. 22 Subject: Storage 10 Gallon Milk Cans. To: All Responsible Officers, NNG. The 10 gallon milk cans now in possession of your cotrpany or de - tachment shoulel be stored upside down without the lid on and raised slightly under one edge to allow air to circulate, thereby eliminating mois - ture which would cause these cans to rust. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 15, 1937 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Circular Letter No. 23 Subject: West Point Preliminary Competitive Examination, 1937, for the Nebraska National Guard. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The annual preliminary examination for thc selection of one en - listed man of the Nebraska National Guard to take the competitive exam - ination for appointment to the United States Military Academy will take place at the Adjutant General's Office, beginning Wednesday, November 3. 1937. at 9:00 A.M.. and continuing through Thursday and Friday, No - vember 4 and 5. 2. To l»- eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an ap - plicant must be an enlisted man of a unit recognized by the Federal Gov - ernment. He- must, on the dale of admission, July 1, 1938, have served as an enlisted man not less than one year, must be between the ages of 19 and 22 years and must not be less than 5 ft. 4 in. in height. The age ana service requirements' arc statutory and cannot be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, therefore former service in the Guard may be counted in determining an applicant's eligibility. 3. The candidate selected will be authorized by the War Departmcni to report for tbe regular entrance examination, which is scheduled to be held beginning on March 1, 1938, and the appointment available on July 1, 1938. will be awarded to the qualified candidate in order of merit estah lished at the examination, which is competitive among all National Guard candidates. 4. Previously applicants have presented themselves to take this examination who were in no way qualified and could not hope to pass the rigid examination given. It has been demonstrated that an applicant should have had at least one year in college, in addition to a high school educa - tion. The examination will be written and will consist of an exhaustive examination in the following subjects: Elementary Algebra, to and includ - ing Quadratics, Plane Geometry, English Grammar, United States and General History and English Literature, and Composition. 5. No state funds are available for the payment of any part of the expenses of applicants taking this examination. 6. A blank form to be used in making application to participate in </seg>
            <seg id="p076">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL the examination is inclosed. A West Point pamphlet will be sent upon re - quest. By direction of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Incl. Appl. blank (Town) Date In accordance with instructions contained in Circular Letter No. 23, AGO Nebraska. October 15. 1937, I request that I be authorized to par - ticipate in the West Point Preliminary Examination to be held at the Ad - jutant General's Office. State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska, beginning No - vember 3, 1937. 1. Name: (Last) (Middle) (First) 2. Residence: (Street Address) (City) (State) 3. Date of Birth: : (Day) (Month) (Year) (Place) 4. Date of Enlistment: 5. Schools or Colleges Attended: From to Grad. — Yes, No „ _ From to Grad.— Yes, No From to Grad. — Yes, No </seg>
            <seg id="p077">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL From to Grad. — Yes, No (Signature) (Company) (Regiment) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 27, 1937 Circular Letter No. 24 Subject: Allotment of Strength. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with letter NGB, 325.44-Nebr.-11, dated October 18, 1937. Subject. Reduction in Allotted Enlisted Strength, the maximum enlisted strength of the Nebraska National Guard will be as follows: Enlisted Men . State Detachment 18 134th Infantry Med. Dept. Det 29 Hq. Co 64 Serv. Co. (Less Band) 55 Serv. Co. (Band) t 34 How. Co 64 Bn. Hq. Co.s 25 Rifle and M.G. Co.s 64 110th Medical Regiment Serv. Co. (Less Band) 42 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Serv. Co. (Band) 25 Vet. Co 38 Co. C , 63 Co. D 47 Co. F 47 Co. I 63 HCth QM Regiment Hq. Co :... 31 Med. Dept. Det 11 Co. A 45 Co. B _ 45 Co. C 45 Co. D 45 Co. E 31 2. Where there is a change in apportionment a sufficient number of enlisted men will immediately be elischarged to bring the strength within these figures. This allowance must not be exceeded until authority i= granted by this office. 3. The organizations affected by the change will reduce noncom - missioned officers and specialists within the number authorized by Tables of Organization for the strength set out above. 4. Circular Letter No. 24. dated Oct. 27, 1937, is to be shown in certificate of strength on Form 100 beginning with the month of November. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERALS DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 18. 1937 Circular Letter No. 25 Subject: Re-enlistment and Pay Pending Naturalization. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is pub - lished for the in formation and guidance of all concerned: "1. A provision in the Army Appropriation Bill, fiscal year 1938, with regard to the prohibition against the employment of persons who are not citizens of the United States was published in letter from this office dated July 6. 1937. The following Act, Public No. 317, 75th Congress, ap - proved August 19, 1937, supplementing the provision referred to, is pub - lished tor the information and guidance of all conc;rned: "Be it enacted I&gt;y the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, That, notwith - standing thc language contained in the second proviso on page 6 of thc Act of July 1. 1937 (Public. Numbered 176, Seventy-fifth Congress, first session), or any other Act, during the three-year period following the enactment of this Act, enlisted personnel of the Army who have legally declared their intention to become citizens, or who do so dur - ing their current enlistment, or who have been discharged from the Army since July 1, 1937, and who also agree to complete expeditiously their naturalization and become citizens of the United States may be re-enlisted and receive the pay to which, except for the aforesaid pro - viso, they would otherwise be legally entitled: Provided, That Fili - pinos who were serving in the Army on July 1, 1937, may be re - enlisted without regard to their citizenship status, and receive the pay to which otherwise legally entitled." 2. The term "Army" is used in its broadest sense in Public Act. No. 317 from which thc foregoing is quoted, and the Act therefore includes in its provisions the enlisted personnel of thc National Guard of the United States. For the Chief, National Guard Bureau: (Signed) THEODORE K. SPENCER, Colonel, N.G.8., Assistant." By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">v REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN , December 8, 1937 Circular Letter No. 26 Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers, NNG. 1. Inclosed are WD MB Forms No. 67 to be used in making the an - nual Efficiency Reports for the year ending December 31. 1937. The re - ports are to be ma !e in accordance with instructions contained in para - graph 64, NGR 20, dated February 25, 1935. 2. Reports are to be forwarded by the reporting officer to the next military superior within ten days of the close of the period covered in the report, exclusive of Sundays and holidays, and are to reach this office by the end of the month. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. Incl. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 29, 1937 Circular Letter No. 27 Subject: Audit of Company Council Books, 1937. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: All Officers Responsible for Same. 1. Company Council Books will be closed on December 31, 1937, in accordance with the following instructions: a. Tbe account will be based on the calendar year and will be posted only under "Other Funds" and in accordance with para - graphs 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6 of the instructions. (See also the model.) b. Number all vouchers consecutively for the calendar year, re - gardless of whether receipts or expenditures. c. Certificates for receipts and itemized invoices for expenditures are required for all transactions during the current year. d. 1 n case the full page of the account will not carry the year's transactions, cut off bottom of page above words "Total re - ceipts and expenditures" and thc top of the next page "In Ac - count with Fund," etc., under the word "year" and above "month,'' and paste these pages together. e. Funds subject to check will require the bank statement of De - cember 31, 1937. 2. In cases where the Council Book has been filled and the last cer - tificate has not been signed, it will be necessary to send in the old and the new book. However, these books should be used until they are completely filled and they are good for a period of from five to ten years. 3. These Council Books with vouchers will be sent to the Adjutant General's office for audit. By direction of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL, Thc Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 24, 1938 Circular Letter No. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Subject: National Defense Week. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief. National Guard Bureau, is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned: "1. Thc Reserve Officers' Association of the United States has ac - cepted thc sponsorship of National Denfensc Week during the period February 12-22, 1938. 2. It is hoped that the same cordial support and active cooperation of National Guard units that has been extended in the past will again be contributed this important activity. 3. It is therefore requested that the matter be brought to the at - tention of all unit commanders and that they be encouraged to contact local chapters of the Reserve Officers' Association. (Signed) ALBERT H. BLANDING. Major General. Chief, National Guard Bureau." By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 3. 1938 Circular Letter No. 2 Subject: Notation of Ordnance Inspection. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following dates for the 1938 Ordnance Inspection Schedule are published for the information of all concerned: 134th Infantry 1938 Nebraska City — Hq. Co., Ist Bn March 16 Nebraska City .... Company A March 16 Falls City Company B March 17 Beatrice Company C March 18 Fairbury Company D, 110th Med. Regt March 18 Lincoln Hq. Co., 110th QM Regt March 19-22 Lincoln _ Hq. Co., 3rd Bn., 134th Inf March 19-22 Lincoln Company I. 134th Inf _ March 19-22 Lincoln Serv. Co., 110th Med. Regt March 19-22 Lincoln Co. I, 110th Med. Regt March 19-22 Lincoln State Storehouse March 19-22 134th Infantry Seward Company M March 23 York Service Company March 24 Grand Island Company H March 25 Hastings Company G March 26 i Hastings Company F, 110th Med. Regt March 26 110th QM Regiment Holdrcge Company A March 27-28 Kearney Med. Dept. Det , March 29 Kearney Company D March 29 134th Infantry North Platte Company D March 30 Gering Howitzer Company March 31 Scottsbluff Company E April- 1 Hartington Company F _ April 8-9 Columbus Company C, 110th Med. Regt _ April 9 Fremont Company B, 1 10th QM Regt April 10-11 Fremont Company E, 110th QM Regt April 10-11 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 134th Infantry Omaha Med. Dept. Det April 12-14 Omaha Headquarters Company _ April 12-14 Omaha Hq. Co., 2nd Bn _ April 12-14 Omaha Company K April 12-14 Omaha , Company L April 12-14 2. The dates shown arc approximate, depending upon the condition of ordnance equipment and character of modifications necessary. This may cause some slight alteration of the schedule, in which case, organizations will be notified in advance by the Inspector, if the change is more than one day. 3. It is directed that attention of thc Ordnance Representative be called to all matters of faulty weapons and equipment, cases where clean - ing or repair has been difficult, and all other ordnance troubles encountered. Your attention is invited to the fact that it is desired to make these in - spections helpful rather than critical. 4. Cosmolincd arms, other than those in original arsenal cosmoline. or arms which have been cosmolincd by representatives of the Ordnance Office, Hq. 7th Corps Area, must have the cosmoline removed from the entire rifle and the bores oiled with light nil so they can be readily wiped dry just prior to the inspection. By order of Governor Cochran: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 26, 1938 Circular Letter No. 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Subject: Mothers' Day. To: All Unit and Sub-Unit Commanders, NNG. Thc second Sunday in May having been dedicated to the mothers of our country as the day on which we should express the love and reverence we owe them, you are directed to bring to thc attention of the members of your organization who may be separated from their mothers on May 8, the duty they can fulfill and the pleasure they can give by writing home on Mothers' Day. By order of thc Governor: H. J. PAUL, Thc Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN ' May 12, 1938 Circular Letter No. 4 Subject:- Preliminary and Record Firing of Rifles, Auto Rifles, Machine Gun and Howitzer Company Weapons, 1938. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders concerned, NNG. 1. The following course will be fired during thc current target prac - tice season: a. RIFLE. Due to limited range and other facilities, the course to be fired will be the "abbreviated small bore course — range 50 feet," as given in paragraph 7c, Training Circular No. 3, 0.C.N.G.8., April 1, 1936. b. MACHINE GUN. The course to be fired in Machine Gun Marksmanship Course A, prescribed in paragraph 77, Basic Field Manual, Vol. 111, Part Three, Chapter 2 (1938 edition), modified as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p086">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL "The Caliber .22 machine gun. as issued, will be used instead of the Browning machine gun, Caliber .30, M1917. The course will be fired at 500 inches instead of 1000 inches. The targets will be those prescribed in paragraph 92, BFM, Vol. 111, Part Three, so reduced in size as to conform to the re - duction in range. c. AUTOMATIC RIFLE. No firing authorized. d. 37 MM GUN AND 3-INCH TRENCH MORTAR. No firing required or authorized. For qualification, the tests outlined in Section V and VI, BFM. Vol. 111. Part Four, Chapter 2. are prescribed. e. PISTOL. No firing authorized. 2. For further details as to qualifications, etc.. attention is invited to the following: Training Circular No. 3. OCNGB. April 1, 1936. Training Circular No. 3. OCNGB. February 10, 1938. 3. The above applies only to those organizations which have not completed firing in accordance with current Regimental Armorv Training Programs. 4. Firing of Cal. .311 ball ammunition is prohibited. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN ~. . T . June 6, 193S Circular Letter No. 5 Subject: Issue of Shoes to the National Guard. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. Thc following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is pub - lished for thc information and guidance of all concerned: "1. Shoes issued an enlisted man of the National Guard and worn by him in the military service for such time as to cause them to lose their original shape in conforming to the foot of the wearer, are not suitable for re-issue, and when returned to the storeroom by reason of the soldier's separation from the service, or other cause, will not be is - sued to another soldier. 2. Shoes accumulated in an organization by reason of the above directive, will be surveyed periodically under thc provisions of NGR 75-7. (Signed) ALBERT H. BLANDING, Major General, Chief, National Guard Bureau." By order of thc Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 27, 1938 Circular Letter No. 6 Subject: Athletic Program. To.: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following Athletic Program, which may be changed slightly if circumstances require, is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 2. Each unit and sub-unit commander will give this program his personal attention and will cooperate with the Camp Athletic Officer in all particulars to the end that the program may be most interesting, enter - taining, instructive and beneficial to the enlisted men and officers. 3. PROGRAM. a. FIELD MEET. Saturday, August 20, after 9:30 A.M., is re - served as Athletic Field Day. (1) All entries in' athletic events scheduled for that period will be released from all other military duties and the athletic field will be cleared of troops prior to the above designat - ed hour. (2) Track. All track events will be put on as in previous years and medals awarded for Ist, 2nd and 3rd in each event. b. SWIMMING. (1) Swimming events will 'be put on as in previous years and medals awarded lor Ist, ,2nd, and 3rd in each event. (2) The swimming pool may be used only when life guards are present and on duty at the pool. c BOXING. (1) There will be competition in each weight division and a medal awarded to thc winner in each weight. d. MASS ATHLETICS. (1) AH enlisted men not engaged in other regularly scheduled training between the hours of 1:15 P.M. and 3:00 P.M.. daily, Monday, August 8, and Saturdays and Sundays ex I - cepted. will be assembled in their company streets at 1:15 P.M., and marched, under a permanently designated leader, to the athletic field and reported to the camp ath - letic officer for physical training, athletics, recreational '. games, sports and training for athletics. (2) The period from 1:15 P.M. to 2:00 P.M., will be devoted to mass athletics, group games and similar events. The remainder of the time allotted will be devoted to base- </seg>
            <seg id="p089">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ball, swimming, track and similar activities. 4. GENERAL PROVISIONS. a. Each regimental and separate battalion commander will im - mediately upon arrival at camp appoint a regimental and bat - talion athletic officer who will immedately report to the camp athletic officer as his assistant in the supervision of the rec - reational and athletic activities of the camp (Training Direc - tive 1938). b. Tlu- commanding officer of each company or like unit will detail one noncommissioned officer or selected private to act as athletic representative of the unit. Individuals so detailed will report to the camp athletic officer as assistants from 1:15 P.M. lo 3:00 P.M. on days when physical training is sched - uled, and they will also report promptly at 9:00 A.M., for one hour's attendance at any conference or school scheduled by the Cam]) Athletic Officer. c. All officers detailed as above and all others assigned as camp athletic instructors will be under the orders of the camp ath - letic officer and will report to him for duty during thc periods herein provided. d. EACH COMPANY AND DETACHMENT COMMAND - • ER WILL, PRIOR TO LEAVING HIS HOME STATION HAVE ALL MEN WHO WILL BE ENTERED IN THE BOXING CONTESTS ACCURATELY WEIGHED AND IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL AT CAMP DELIV - ER TO THE CAMP ATHLETIC OFFICER A LIST OF ENTRIES TOGETHER WITH A STATEMENT OF THEIR ACCURATE WEIGHTS. e. EACH COMPANY AND DETACHMENT COMMAND - ER WILL, PRIOR TO LEAVING HIS HOME STA - TION. PREPARE LISTS OF ENTRIES IN THE FIELD, TRACK AND SWIMMING EVENTS AND IMMEDI - ATELY UPON ARRIVAL AT CAMP DELIVER SAID LISTS TO THE CAMP ATHLETIC OFFICER. 5. GENERAL'S TROPHY. a. Adjutant General Paul is again offering a cup to the company showing the greatest activity and efficiency in athletics. b. Points will be awarded to the various companies upon the fol - lowing basis: </seg>
            <seg id="p090">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (1) Boxing. Owing to the difficulty that has been experienced in ar - ranging a card for the second evening of camp (Tuesday), it has been decided to award a greater number of points to the companies having entries in the boxing bouts that evening. Therefore, upon the first Tuesday evening, 25 points will be awarded for each entry at the ringside in condition to box, and 15 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. Upon all other evenings points will be awarded as follows: 10 points will be awarded for each entry appearing at the ringside in condition to box. 10 points will be awarded for each round that the bout goes. An additional 15 points will be awarded to the win - ing entry in each bout. 25 points will be awarded to each entry who enters the semi-finals. 50 points will be awarded to the champion in each weight division. If a knock-out loccurs, the winner will be entitled to credit for three rounds. (2) Swimming 50 points will be awarded for each Ist. 35 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 25 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (3) Track. 50 points will be awarded for each Ist. 35 points will be awarded for each 2nd. 25 points will be awarded for each 3rd. (4) Kitten Ball. 75 points will be awarded to the company rating Ist place. 50 points will be awarded to the company rating 2nd place. 25 points will be awarded to the company rating 3rd place. (5) Mass Athletics. 350 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. 250 points will be awarded to the company evidencing the second greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. 150 points will be awarded to the company evidencing thc third greatest activity and efficiency in mass athletics. By order of the Governor: 90 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 16, 1938 Circular Letter No. 7 Subject: Medical Plan. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders and Med. Dept. Officers, NNG. 1. Thc following Medical Plan is published for the information and guidance of all concerned. 2. Each unit and sub-unit commander will give this his personal attention and will cooperate with the Camp Medical Department in all particulars to the end that the health of the command may be conserved and troop training in matters of their physical welfare advanced. 3. CLOSING OF RECRUITMENT FOR CAMP, VACCINA - TIONS. INOCULATIONS, AND ANNUAL PHYSICAL EXAMINA - TIONS OF OFFICERS. (See Advance Camp Order No. 2, dated Aug - ust 8, 1938.) 4. SUPPLY. a. Medical units will bring with them sufficient medical supplies for thc encampment. No medical Supply Depot will be established. b. Items of Medical equipment necessary for physical examina - tions, such as sphygmomanometers, that are not in thc table of allowances, will be made available for the during of camp by the regimental and sepa - rate unit surgeons for examinations within their respective commands. c. Chlorine tubes for the purification of water in the field, fly </seg>
            <seg id="p092">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL swatters, fly paper and ribbons, fly dope and sprayers, are Quartermaster issue. Supplies of this character on hand in organizations will be brought to camp. 5. EVACUATION AND HOSPITALIZATION. a. Men. .'. ■ (1) General provision of medical attendance for National Guard troops in excess of that available at camp will be governed by authority contained in NGR 62 (Medical Attendance). (2) Enroute. (a) Casualties requiring evacuation while enroute to or from camp will be sent to the nearest Government hospital. If no Govern - ment hospital is reasonably available, then these casualties will be sent to the nearest civilian hospital. (b) All officers authorizing hospitalization in civilian in - stitutions will report at once to the Camp Commander, giving the name of the patient, the proper identification, the diagnosis if known, the name of the institution to which sent, and the name of the doctor in charge. (3) Camp and Field. (a) The Division (Camp) Surgeon is responsible for the supervision and coordination of all Medical Department activities. He will make necessary inspections and prepare recommendations for the employ - ment of the Camp Medical Service. As technical Medical Department ad - visor to the Camp Commander, he is responsible for all plans and policies pertaining to the evacuation and actual care of sick and injured personnel. (b) The normal echelons of evacuation will be operated in the evacuation of casualties. The normal echelons of evacuation in semi - permanent camp are Dispensary-Hospital Station; and in the field, Bat - talion or Regimental Aid Station — Collecting Station — Hospital Station. (c) Within regimental and separate unit areas Medical service will be rendered by the unit medical detachments, both at the semi - permanent camp and in the field through the operation of dispensaries and aid stations. (d) The 110th Medical Regiment will extend its evacuation service as far forward as dispensaries and aid stations and rearward to the Hospital Station and to a fixed hospital. (e) The collecting stataions will gain contact and maintain </seg>
            <seg id="p093">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL liaison with aid stations in the field and evacuate their casualties. (f) The ambulance service will establish and operate load - ing posts in the field in advance of the collecting stations, as far forward as the battalion aid stations, the situation permitting. It will evacuate casualties through thc collecting stations to the Hospital Station and to a fixed hospital. It will establish, maintain, and operate a Camp Ambulance Station in the vicinity of the Hospital Station. (g) The Hospital Stataion will receive casualties from camp and field operating as thc second echelon of evacuation in semi-per - manent camp, and as the third and fourth mobile echelons in the field (Hospital Station and Evacuation Hospital). b. Animals. (1)' None. 6. TRAINS. a. Medical Detachments. (1) Battalion and regimental Medical detachments will move into the field on service and training missions with their organizations. They will cooperate to thc fullest extent in assisting the collecting station to make and to maintain liaison with their aid stations. Organization com - manders moving troops fnto field exercises on independent missions will notify the commanding officer of the 110th Medical Regiment of their de - tailed plan in ample time for support of a division Medical service to evacuate aid stations of their organizations. b. Provision al Medical Battalion. (1) The 110th Medical Regiment will move into the field as a provisional Medical battalion on independent training missions. It will provide evacuation and hospitalization for casualties received from the first echelon of evacuation when troops are on field exercises. 7. PHYSICAL INSPECTIONS OF TROOPS. (See Advance Camp Order No. 2, dated August 8, 1938.) 8. LINE OF DUTY BOARD: MEDICAL ATTENDANCE. (See Advance Camp Order No. 2, dated August 8, 1938.) 9. SANITATION. a. Reference, Camp G.0., No. 3, 1938 — Sanitation. </seg>
            <seg id="p094">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ~ 10. REQORDS; REPORTS, RETURNS. a. Medical Department records, reports, and returns for the dura - tion of Camp, including also "Board Reports," will be accomplished and disposed of according to pertinent regulations and as follows: (1) Report of Physical Examination of Troops on Arrival. (a) These reports will be compiled by the Assistant Medi - cal Inspector for the Camp Surgeon, August 8. Cases of contagion and suspects, cases of venereal disease or other infections, cases of injury cases of hernia and all other cases inimical to the health of troops or in - capacitated for full military duty from any cause will be reported. (2) Surgeon's Morning Report. (a) Each morning the Surgeon of every command will prepare a report of the sick of the command on WD MD Form No 71 The day covered by the report will be the 24 hour period ending the pre - ceding midnight— the first morning report will be sent forward on the morning of August 9 and exhibit entries made from midnight August 7-8 to midnight, August 8-9. (b) The morning report will be prepared as per instruc - tions in paragraph 6, AR 40-1005. (c) "The sick of the command" include only those ad - mitted to the sick report (quarters or hospital). A case will not be admit - ted to sick report that will not be off duty at least 24 hours, and no case wdl be retained on duty status "under observation of the Medical Officer" for more than 24 consecutive hours without being admitted to sick report. (3) The Sick Blotter. (a) The sick blotter is the Surgeon's basic Medical record at dispensary or station for sick and injured. AH patients admitted to sick - report, and all cases "for record only," and all treatments given and sup - plies-] furnished, whatsoever and to whomsoever, will be entered and initialed by thc Medical officer. It constitutes a register of patients and other important cases observed and of professional work done. (4) The Company Sick Book. (a) The sick book is the basic Medical record of a com - mand, other than a hospital, for cases admitted to sick report. The entry of each case will be properly made and initialed by the Surgeon at sick call. (b) In emergency cases requiring admission to sick re - port, the Medical officer will immediately call for the company sick book </seg>
            <seg id="p095">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL and make proper entry of the patient thereon, and also on the EMT. (c) Circumstances that require entries into the company sick book: (i) Admission to sick report. (ii) Transfer of patient. (iii) Completion of case by duty or death. (iv) "For record only" (important case on duty status). (v) "For transfer only" (case admitted to sick report and transferred to other place of treatment the same day — not held in his organization 24 hours). (vi) Accidental death. (5) The Emergency Medical Tag. (a) As a sick and wounded record, the Emergency Medical Tag (WD MD Form No. 52-b) will be properly accomplished and at - tached to the clothing of all persons excused from any part of their mili - tary duties on account of sickness or injury and in case of death. It will be prepared as per AR 40-1055. (b) "In the field" it will be made out by the first member of the Medical Department who treats the case prior to admission to a hospital and he will attach the original of the tag to the patient's clothing near the breast. Thc carbon copy will be turned in promptly to the Surgeon of the organization to which the patient belongs. (c) At the dispensary or aid station it will be made out invariably and attached to each patient formally transferred to the hospital (hospital station). (d) Only one EMT will be attached to any patient; and all notes concerning treatment, disposition, etc., will be on the one tag. A new EMT will be made out for each admission to sick report, except at hospital. (e) The Surgeon of a command will pick up the EMTs of all cases completed by "return to duty" or by "death," and at the end of the camp period he will forward them with the Report Sheet (WD MD Form No. 51) as a part of the "sick and wounded report" of his command. (f) The collecting station and the hospital station will not remove the EMTs from patients which they do not formally admit and treat, and which they return directly back to the aid station or dispensary. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ;. c ' r (gr) The ' carbon co P ie s of EMTs will be collected daily by the burgeon of a command to prepare the daily casualty list as of mid - night just past, for thc organization commander. k u, j (I^, At the end of the cam P P eriod all carbon copies will be assembled and forwarded with "the sick and wounded report" by the Surgeon of each command. y (6) Alcohol and Narcotic Register. (a) Officers responsible for alcohol and narcotics will when prescribing same, enter into a manifolding book, such as is furnished in Chest No. 1 of battalion dispensary equipment, the place of issue, date name o mdivdual for whom prescribed, name of preparation and quantity and will sign the entry. ■ l , x.™ } J h ' S registcr win be Prepared and disposed as per paragraph 1, NGR 75-6, and will be open at all times for inspection. (7) Records and Reports of Venereal Diseases. (a) The provisions of AR 40-235 as changed by Changes J, applying to this camp period will be strictly complied with. (b &gt; A record tForm MD 77) will be kept of each pro - phylaxis. ' (c) On each Saturday morning and on the day of depar - ture for home station, regimental and separate unit Surgeons will render an informal written report to the Camp Commander (through the Camp Surgeon) stating the number of individuals among the members of each company or corresponding unit of the command who have developed venereal disease during the week or period covered. (d) At the end of Camp, regimental and separate unit commanders will render to thc Camp Commander, a "Venereal Disease- Report on each company or corresponding unit of the command for thc camp period. This report will be in form as on page 4. AR 40-235 with captions changed as required. (8) Hospital Station: Sick and Wounded Administration, (a) Receiving Department. _ . . „. (*) ° n formally admitting a patient for treatment, the Receiving officer will accomplish and dispose of records as follows: „„ .t. tr^-r. r ( . X) N ° te the ! fact and day and hour of admission on the EMT found attached to the clothing of the patient. </seg>
            <seg id="p097">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL (y) Enter the patient on the "Receiving Log" in - cluding data as follows : day and hour, name, grade, organization, diagnosis, line of duty, ATS, disposition, remarks (if any). (z) Initiate a FMR (WD MD Forms 52-c and 52-d — Field Medical Card and Field Medical Jacket), and remove the EMT from the patient and deposit it in the jacket as a part of the sick and wounded report. (b) "Treatment Departments. (i) The Medical Officer administering professional treatment will note on the FMR, diagnosis, complications, treatments, or death, and transcribe same to his sick blotter. Each patient will be entered into the sick blotter with appropriate remarks. (c) Evacuation Department. (i) The evacuation officer upon evacuation of a pa - tient who has passed the Treatment Departments will proceed and ac - complish records as follows: (w) Check up and insure the adequacy of entries on thc FMR and then add his own entry. Pick up FMRs of cases com - pleted by return to duty or by death and retain a duplicate FMR of cases transferred to a fixed hospital. (x) Accomplish and file a "Nominal Index Regis - ter Card" (WD MD Form 52-a) in the nominal index register of the hos - pital station for each patient. Enter on the card all personal identifying data, all changes of status incident to MD administration of patient, dis - position and date and hour of admission to and evacuation from the hos - pital station. (y) Transcribe all narcotic data from FMRs into thc "Narcotic Register" and have each entry properly signed. (z) Enter each patient in the "Evacuation Log" which will be in similar form to the receiving log. (ii) The Evacuation officer will coordinate with the police in handling cases not formally received and treated in the hospital station and with the quartermaster with reference to the disposition of the dead. (9) Veterinary Reports. (a) There being no animals in this division the Meat and Milk Inspector will render the regulation report, Veterinary Inspection </seg>
            <seg id="p098">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL of Food Products, daily and for the period of the camp. (10) Annual Physical Examinations. (a) Regimental and separate unit Surgeons will make an - nual physical examinations of National Guard Officers of their organiza - tions and assigned officers accomplishing N.G.B. Form No. 63, as per NGR No. 28 (Physical Examination) in thc cases of officers who have not had a regulation physical examination during the calendar year. Urin - alyses may be had at the hospital station. Reports should be in the hands of the Camp Surgeon by August 17. (11) The Statistical Report. (a) The Statistical Report (WD MD Form No. 86 a 6) will be rcndcTed weekly and at the end of camp, in duplicate, be regimental and separate unit Surgeons for their organizations. AR 40-1080 and the instructions on the back of the form will be complied with. (b) The initial Statistical Report will be for the week ending with the morning report of August 14. The' original will be for - warded to the Camp Surgeon's office by noon of thc due date. (12) The Report Sheet; Sick and Wounded Report. (a) "The Sick and Wounded Report" will be rendered by regimental and separate unit Surgeons for their organizations at the end of camp. (b) It consists of two parts: (1) The Report Sheet (WD MD Form No. 51). (2) The Emergency Medical Tags (WD MD Form No. 52-b) of all persons excused from any part of their military duties, of all cases "for record only." and for all accidental deaths, by all places other than hospitals. (c) The hospital station operating in some respects as a mobile hospital in the field, will assemble and forward with the report sheet (Form 51), the Field Medical Records (WD MD Forms 52-c and 52-d), as the second part of the sick and wounded report as provided in paragraph 8-b, AR 40-1025, with the EMTs previously deposited in the jacket. Wires and strings will be removed. (d) The Report Sheet will be accomplished in duplicate conformably with AR 40-1025. (e) The original of the Report Sheet, the assembled EMTs </seg>
            <seg id="p099">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL and FMRs as the case may be, and the carbon copies of the EMTs con - stituting the complete Sick and Wounded Report, will be delivered to thc Camp Surgeon's office immediately after sick call, August 22. _ ( f ) 0n August 20, Surgeons will review their assembled EMTs and FMRs and proposed entries on the Report Sheet, at the Camp Surgeon's office, by appointment. (13) Numerical Report of Casualties. (a) Aid Stations and Collecting Stations. (i) The clerk keeps a numerical record of all patients received at the aid station and at the collecting station, classified as indi - cated on the report form below. This report is submitted through the message center to battalion headquarters at such intervals as may be directed by the regimental commander, usually every 4, 6, or 12 hours depending on the situation. \ „ (aid station ) lronl (Collecting station) at (place) To ; „ . , ( - A M) ( AM) ! Pcr,od &lt; PM &gt; (d^) to ( PM) (day) (mo.) year &lt;-i -c *• ~— Adjacent[Prison-| Classification Officers* Enlisted divisions ers Others Aggregate Seriously wounded Slightly wounded Gassed Sick Died at station Returned to organization _ _ Total 'Name, rank, and organization of officers to be listed below. (b) Ambulance Stations.— The clerk keeps the "log" which </seg>
            <seg id="p100">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL forms the basis of the periodical operation reports to the battalion com - mander, in which are recorded the number of patients transported as fol - lows: (i) Number of lying and sitting patients (ii) Number of ambulance (iii) Name of driver (iv) Hour ambulance checks in at station enroute to and from hospital station. (c) Hospital Stations. (i) Receiving. — A noncommissioned officer keeps a record of all incoming patients. Thc necessary information is obtained by questioning the patient or from the emergency medical tag. In case a patient arrives without an emergency tag, one is made out here and at - tached to the patient as prescribed in AR 40-1055. At stated intervals, record sheets are sent to the' hospital station office. The following sample form is suggested as a suitable one for the hospital record. ADMISSION RECORD G.S.W. Gunshot wound Hospital station B.W. Bayonet wound Date Sick Location ... Ga. Gassed: Admitted (M) Mustard Ev. Evacuated (P) Phosgene Remaining '. SI. Slight Died S. Severe R..T.F. Returned to front L. Litter A. Ambulant ■ Consolidated 1 list of sick and wounded Army Grade andl | |Admission|Disposition Name Serial Organiza-lDiagnosisl Litter or | date and I date, hour, Number tion ] J Ambulant hour | hospital </seg>
            <seg id="p101">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 101 'Strike out if not consolidated. (ii) Evacuating. A noncommissioned officer keeps a record showing the disposition of all patients whether by death, evacua - tion or return to duty. These lists are sent at intervals to the hospital office tent for consolidation. Each case is given a final inspection by the evacuation officer who makes sure that the emergency medical tag is at - tached. Thc following sample form is suggested for the evacuation record. EVACUATION RECORD L. Litter Hospital A. Ambulance Location M.P. to military police | Army Name Serial Disposition L. or A., Hour Number etc. . (iii) Hospital Station Office. — This section operates as a distinct entity and keeps those records pertaining exclusively to pa - tients. From the lists of admissions and dispositions received at intervals from the admission and evacuation tents, a consolidated report is made periodically and sent to the surgeon of the main force to which the regi - ment pertains through battalion headquarters. Names are not shown on the consolidated report until final disposition is effected. Thc form used for the admission report can be used for the consolidated report. In addi - tion to the consolidated report a condensed report of casualties is required for the information of the battalion commander and the Surgeon of the main force. These reports arc furnished at regular intervals or on request. A suggested form follows: HOSPITAL STATION _ At -_ Date To - </seg>
            <seg id="p102">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL REPORT OF CASUALTIES DURING PERIOD p.m. ££". „ Litter Sitting REMAINING IN SECTION AT LAST REPORT ADMISSION DURING PERIOD: Wounded _ Gassed „ Sick „ TOTAL EVACUATED DURING PERIOD J REMAINING j (d) Veterinary Stations. (i) In a theater of operations. (y) Emergency Veterinary Tags. — E.V.T (WD MD Form No. 115-b).— The original tag will be attached to the animal's halter in accordance with instructions on the tag and remain theTc until the animal is disposed of by return to duty, death, or separation from the service, when it may be removed and destroyed. The duplicate tag will be placed in an envelope and turned over to the senior noncommissioned officer of thc unit evacuating the animal, after entry of this fact has been made on reverse side of the tag. The triplicate tag will be retained for reference purposes. When final disposition of the animal has been made or when the animal reaches the zone of the interior by transfer from a theater of operations, the duplicate tag will be completed and signed by the responsible officer and forwarded with the next report of sick and wounded. The officer in charge of each evacuation unit will check the tag on each animal handled by his organization, and should he find one missing or illegible he will retag thc animal, using the information obtained from the duplicate. (z) Based on the Emergency Veterinary Tags used in tagging animal casualties "a report of animal casualties treated and evacuated" is prepared, and sent through the Veterinarian to the Surgeon. NOTE: The routine in the military service requires a report of sick and wounded to be rendered monthly from every military station and separate command which is attended by a medical officer or civilian </seg>
            <seg id="p103">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL physician, and forwarded before the fifth day of the month next succeeding. NOTE: The monthly report of sick and wounded in a theater of opera - tions in time of war for all aid stations, collection stations, ambu - lance stations, hospital stations, dispensaries, and places of treat - ment other than hospitals consists of: (1) The report sheet (MD Form 51 and MD Form 102, (V)), (2) The emergency medical tag, EMT (MD Form 52-b) for all persons excused from any part of their military duties on ac - count of sickness or injury, and for all that are wounded in action whose cases are completed by death or by return to duty without admission to hospital. The carbon copies of the EMTs of persons killed in action who have been tagged by any member of the Medi - cal Department will be included. EVT (Form 115-b (V.)), will be accomplished for animal casualties. NOTE: The forward mobile "hospital" echelon is the Evacuation Hos - pitals. In this camp the "hospital station" serves partly as an evacuation hospital. Reference Subpar. 10-a (8). By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN n . , T , June 30, 1938 Circular Letter No. 8 Subject: Annual Encampment, Nebraska National Guard, 1938. To: All Unit Commanders and all Field and Staff Officers, NNG. </seg>
            <seg id="p104">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 1. Thc dates of the annual encampment, 1938, having been set, i.e., August 8 to August 22, inclusive, 1938, no organization will be excused from attending except when they do not comply with the provisions of Section 111, NGR 45. At this point you arc cautioned as to the absolute necessity of making yourselves conversant with the above quoted section and citations contained therein, as non-compliance therewith will cause forfeiture of pay of company officers. 2. All units will be notified direct by the USP&amp;DO as to truck movements, train schedules and purchase of travel rations for enlisted men. 3. Travel Discipline. The senior line officer will assume command of the men of thc convoy or train and see that travel discipline is main - tained. The officers or noncommissioned officers in charge of motor trans - portation are held responsible for condition and equipment of trucks and for speed of convoy. Officers in charge of troops will not infringe upon this prerogative. 4. Uniforms. Enlisted men will wear woolen O.D. shirts, cotton breeches, service hats with hat cords sewed on, issue leggins and issue shoes. Officers will wear the uniform prescribed for them. Company com - manders will not permit enlisted men to bring civilian clothing to camp as they will not be permitted to wear same on leave or otherwise during the fifteen day training period. Slacks may be worn after retreat. 5. Equipment. Enlisted men will carry prescribed individual and special equipment and the contents of the pack as shown in Basic Field Manual Vol. I. Chap. 3. Kquipment and Clothing. Extra blanket, clothing, shoes, toilet articles, etc., and the bed sack and mosquito bar will be taken by each individual as personal baggage in the barrack bag. Company com - manders should check each enlisted man to see that he provides himself with extra underwear, socks, towels, tooth brush, tooth paste, hand soap, etc., and that he has extra issue clothing, i.e., cotton breeches and O.D. shirts. If foot lockers are brought to camp same will be transported via commercial truck and payment made from funds other than State or Federal. 6. Additional Equipment. Only the following equipment pertaining to thc organization will be brought to camp: a. Cooking utensils, bags water sterilizing. b. All tentagc and G.l. cans at home station, and hereafter these articles will not be taken from ramp, j </seg>
            <seg id="p105">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL c. All Cal. .30 ball ammunition and all empty cartridge cases (brass) in packing boxes. d. Rifles, bayonets, automatic rifles and pistols, with arms racks sufficient for same, and only in the amounts necessary to properly equip the men of your company. e. All .22 caliber rifles with magazines. f. Only sufficient quartermaster, signal; medical and engineer property necessary to carry out the training program of the organization. g. All gas masks issue. h. Records. Field desks A and B, with the necessary personnel and property records. 7. A complete list, in quadruplicate, of all officers and men will be turned in immediately to the camp adjutant upon your arrival at camp with a notation opposite the name of the absentee showing the reason for such absence. 8. Messes. a. All company officers will mess with their organization. Every effort should be made to secure the. best possible cooks and mess sergeants, as a good mess is one of the most important things toward contentment and good morale of an organiza - tion. Thc Commanding Officer, 134th Infantry, and the Com - manding Officer, 110th Medical Regiment, with thc Com - manding Officer, 110th Quartermaster Regiment, will estab - lish officers' messes for thc Field and Staff Officers of their own organizations and such Officers of the State Staff and Instructors as may be assigned thereto for mess purposes. Messes are to be operating so as to serve lunch at noon, August 8, 1938. b. Commanding Officers of regiments will assign companies or detachments, not operating messes, to some other company for mess. 9. Transportation. a. All company offices arc permitted to bring their private cars to camp, but in case of troops transported by truck the com - -1 any commander must accompany the convoy, whether driv - </seg>
            <seg id="p106">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ■.'■■-.'■' 1/ ■■ ■■■ ing his own car or not. Private cars for enlisted men are - authorized on the basis of one car for each 10 men, i.e., a company of 64 men would be entitled to 6 cars, a company of 52 men would be entitled to 5 cars, etc. No mileage allowance will be authorized for any individuals. b. In case of companies traveling by rail the company com - mander must accompany his organization, but he may detail one enlisted man to drive his car to camp. And furthermore, in the case of companies traveling via rail, not to exceed 10 per cent of the company may travel via private transportation. c. The regimental adjutants will make a written report to thc camp adjutant not later than 5:00 p.m., August 9, of the num - i ber of cars in their organization, giving make, type and county registration number. 10. The attention of all unit commanders is called to the necessity of determining to the best of their knowledge and belief that their men are physically fit before taking them to camp, as the number of major op - erations in our camp must be reduced and the only operative cases that will be taken care of during camp will be for conditions that have not previously existed and have been brought about during camp and in line of duty. 11. Unit commanders will make sure that they do not bring any venereal cases to camp, and in case any are found upon physical examina - tion made' upon entering camp, such men will be returned to their home station at their own expense, without pay or allowance, as they will not be permitted in camp. 12. a. Company Commanders operating messes, so desiring, may send to camp, on Sunday, August 7, by private transportation and at no cost to thc State or Federal Government, an ad - vance detachment consisting of Mess Sergeant and two en - listed men, for thc purpose of receiving rations and condi - tioning kitchens. b. The Mess Sergeant must bring with him written authority from the Company Commander authorizing him to enter the kitchen and mess hal! of that particular unit. c. These details are to report to the Camp Quartermaster im - mediately upon arrival in camp. After receiving the keys to their respective kitchens they will then be under thc super - vision of their respective Regimental Supply Officers. i ■'•■." ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p107">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL d. Private car used by this detail will be counted as one of the cars authorized in Paragraph 9-a above. 13. Rations Remaining on Hand. In accordance with instructions from the National Guard Bureau any subsistence remaining on hand at termination of field training which cannot be consumed during period of travel to home stations will be turned in by the companies or detachments to their respective supply officers,, who in turn will turn in same to the Camp Quartermaster. This provision must be strictly complied with. (C-l, March 19, 1938, to Circular No. 14 B-1937 NGB Nov. 1, 1937.) 14. Unit and sub-unit commanders will read this letter to their com - mand at every armory drill between the time of its receipt and the time of entrucking or entraining for camp. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 2, 1938 Circular Letter No. 9 Subject: Officers' Tent Houses. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. There is a surplus of twenty-three officers' tent houses at Camp Ashland which cost $26.00 each. For the purpose of disposing of these tent bouses, which were built in 1936, we are offering them for $15.00 each. 2. We must have an immediate answer with reference to the above tioned tent houses as they must be moved in the very near future on ac - count of outlets on new officers' light lines. </seg>
            <seg id="p108">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. In case one of these is desired by any officer, a check or draft must accompany request for same ! H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 5, 1938 Circular Letter No. 10 Subject: Instructions Pertaing to Movement of Troops by Truck. To: All Unit and Tub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The attached schedules for incoming and return movement of troops via motor trucks will be strictly adhered to by all concerned. 2. The number of trucks allotcd to each company or detachment has been computed on the basis of one for baggage and the balance for men, twelve (12) men with barrack bags to the truck. The only exception to this is in the case of Company H and Company M, which have been allotted two trucks for baggage. 3. Company Commanders assigned motor transportation, who will be responsible for thc successful carrying out of the troops' movement, will study carefully the attached schedules, paying particular attention to the time each company or detachment is scheduled to move and to thc condition of their trucks. A fresh driver will be proyided for each vehicle after the completion of each trip. 4. While federel pay is not authorized for officers on this move - ment, it is the desire of this office that an officer accompany each convoy on the incoming movement. On the return movement, it is directed that an officer accompany each convoy. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 5. Officers and noncommissioned officers in charge of convoys, and also truck drivers and assistants, must understand that they are in charge of the truck and equipment pertaining thereto and are responsible that none of the truck equipment is removed. They are also responsible for the speed at which the convoy travels and the route to be traveled. 6. Officers of companies or detachments being transported will have their organization ready to move as per the attached schedule and will not give orders to the truck drivers or individuals in charge of trucks regarding truck equipment or operation of convoy. If necessary to halt the convoy, they should confer with the officer or noncommissioner officer in charge. 7. Immediately after the completion of the movement of troops into camp, all motor vehicles will be turned in to the Camp Transportation Officers for use in the camp motor pool. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">ANNEX NO. 1, F.O. No. 1. A.G.O. NEBR., July S, 1938 TROOP MOVEMENT TO CAMP ASHLAND, NEBRASKA Advance Detachments . Page 1 Transport Unit Leave Home Miles to Arrive at Leave Arrive at Unit Miles Total and No. of Trucks Station JiF JiF KF JJF Transported JSl' to DF Miles Co. I, 110th Med Kegt. 6:00 I'M 33 8:30 FM 4:30 AM 8:30 AM Del. Serv. Co. 85 140 3 IJ4 T Trucks 4 Aug 4 Aug 5 Aug 5 Aug 134' Inl. rork (15) Serv. Co., 110th Med. Kegt. 7:00 AM 30 There 7:00 AM 8:30 AM Det. Serv. Cc. 30 30 3 IJ4 T Trucks 5 Aug 3 Aug 5 Aug 111) - Med. Kegt. Lincoln (15) Serv. Co., 110th Med. Kegt 7:00 AM 30 Ihere 7:00 AM 8:30 AM Del. SS&amp;SD 30 30 4 V/, T Trucks 5 Aug 5 Aug 5 Aug Det. Hq. Co. 110 (JM Lincoln (27) Serv. Co., 110th Med. Kegt. Leave uamp Ash- 30 . 11:00 AM 12.00 AM "1:30 FM Det. Hq. Co. 134 Int. 30 60 1 Keconn Car land 9:30 AM 3 Aug 5 Aug 3 Aug Omaha (3) 1 \y, T Truck 5 Aug Rear Detachments Transport Unit Leave .Miles to Arrive at Unit and No. of Trucks Camp Ashland Itl DP Transported .Serv. Co., 110th Med. Kegt. 1:00 FM 30 2:30 FM .SS&amp; SD 1 Keconn Car -'3 Aug ?3 Aug 3 \y, T Trucks </seg>
            <seg id="p111">INCOMING TROOP MOVEMENT Page 2 ; 1 1 j Transport Unit Leave Home Miles to Arn\c at Leave Arrive at Unit Miles Total and No. of Trucks Station KF F.l' h.F 111' Transported JiF to DP Miles Co. A, 110th CJM Kegt. .&lt;:00 I'M 40 &lt;' :45 I'M 12:01 AM ":43 AM Co. C. 110' (JM Kegt. 205 243 11) 5 Is4 T Trucks 7 Aug / Aug 8 Aug S Aug Lexington (45) (2) 7 \'/j T trucks 8:00 FM 40 9:45 FM 12:01 AM 8:15 AM Co. 1), Med. Dept. Oct. 170 210 110' (JM Kegt. Kearney (56) XT) 2 Keconn Can 1 \'A T Truck 12:01 AM There 1 here 12:01 AM 9:15 AM Det. Co. A, 110 (JM 190 190 (Attached trom Co. 1, 8 Aug Kegt. Holdregc (12) 110th Med. Kegt.) (4) 6 IJ-S T Trucks Leave Camp . 30 10:45 AM 11:45 AM 1:30 FM Co. 1, 134th Int. 30 60 From (2) '':15 AM Lincoln (64) (5) 7 IJS T Trucks 10:43 AM 30 12:15 FM 1:15 I'M 2:45 FM Hq Co 3'Bn, 134 Inl. 30 60 From (1). (2), (3) Vet Co, 110 Med Kegt Lincoln (63) Co. B, 110th (JM Kegt. 3.00 FM 120 8:00 FM 12:01 AM 5:30 AM Co. 11, 134th Int. 130 250 (1) 7 IJ4 T 1 rucks 7 Aug 7 Aug 8 Aug 8 Aug Grand Isluid (64) TJ) 5 I '/, T Trucks 1 154 T Truck 3:00 FM 145 9:00 FM 12:01 AM 5:30 AM Co. (i, 134th Inl. 130 275 (Attached trom Co. 1, Hastings (64) 110th Med. Kegt.) '• ' </seg>
            <seg id="p112">INCOMING TROOP MOVEMENT Page 3 Transport Unit Leave Home Miles to Arrive at | Leave Arrive at Unit Miles to Total and No. of Trucks Station JiF JiF Jit' UP Transported jiF to DP Miles Leave Camp (3) 6 \y, T Trucks 7:00 AM /5 '0:00 AM 11:01; AM 2:00 FM Co. C, !34th Int. 75 150 F'rom (1) 8 Aug 8 Aug Beatrice (64) (4) 1 iy 2 T Truck Fr (1) 7:00 AM 60 9:30 AM 10:30 AM 1 :titl I'M Co. M, 134th int. 60 120 6 V/i T Trucks Fr (2) Seward (64) Co. E, 110th (JM Kegt. 3.00 FM 110 7:30 I'M 12:01 AM 8:00 AM Co. F, 134th Int. 160 2/U .(1) 6 I}4 T Trucks 7 Aug / Aug 8 Aug 8 Aug Darlington (64) (2) 2 \y, T Trucks 12:01 AM There There 12:01 AM 2:00 AM Uet. Co. K, 110th (JM 50 50 8 Aug Kegt.. Fremont (15) (3) 2 I}4 T Trucks Leave Camp 50 5:00 AM 6.00 AM 8:00 AM Det. Co. B, lluth UM 50 1(11: 3:00 AM 8 Aug Kegt. Fremont (13) (4) 6 V/i T Trucks Leave Camp 30 10:00 AM ll.:10 AM ,2:00 Noon Del. Co, I, 110th Med. 30 60 From (1) 9:00 AM a /iug .S Aug 8 Aug Kegt. Lincoln Co. D, 110th Med Kegt. (1) 1 Keconn Truck 5:00 AM There i here 5:00 AM 9:00 AM Co. 11, 110th Med. ■a y, I IJJ T Truck 8 Aug . 8 Aug 8 Aug Kegt. Fairbury (47) 4 Ambulances (Fr Co. F, 110th Med. Kegt.) </seg>
            <seg id="p113">INCOMING TROOP MOVEMENT Page 4 Transport Unit Leave Home .Miles to Arrive at Leave Arrive at Unit Miles Total and No. of Trucks .Station EP &amp;P li'F 111* Transported hf to 111* Allies Arr. I' anbury ~~ to. !•'. 110th Alcd. Kept. 12:01 AM 100 I AM .8 Aug. IUU1 UU (1) 1:1*4 T Truck 6 Aug (Attached Co. 11, on arrival) (21 1 Kcconn Truck 12:01 AM There There ,2:01 AM 5:15 AM to. F, 110th Med. 130 130 6 Ambulances S Aug 8 Aug Kent. Hastings (45) I \&lt;/. T Truck (3) 1 \y t T Truck 6-30 AM ' 30 7:45 AM ,5:45 AM 10:00 AM Service Co. 110th Med. V, 60 Ambulances 8 Aug 8 Aug 8 Aug 8 Aug Kegt. \'/i T Truck Irom Co. K, 110th *JM Kegt Co. I. 110th Med. Kegt. 6:JO I'M 110 10:30 FM 12:01 AM 6:00 AM Co. B, 134th lnt 140 250 (1) 6 \'/i T trucks / Aug 8 Aug 8 Aug 8 Aug (2) 6 IJS T Trucks Leave Camp 80 10:30 AM 11:30 AM 2:45 FM Co. C, 110th Med. 80 160 From (1) /:15 AM I Aug 8 Aug 8 Aug Kegt- Columbus (63) .Service Co., 110th Med. b:00 1M 50 8:00 FM 12:01 AM 3:30 AM Service Co. 134th Int. 85 135 Kegt. (1) 9 1J4..T Trucks 7 Aug 7 Aug 8 Aug 8 Aug Vork (74) </seg>
            <seg id="p114">INCOMING TROOP MOVEMENT Page 5 Transport Unit Leave Home Miles to Arrive at Leave Arrive »t Unit Miles Total anil No. of Trucks Station EP iil J *.!' "f transported t£V to UP Miles (2) 2 IJS T trucks 12:01 AM There 1 lieie 12-U1 AM 1-30 AM Hq, (Jo., HOth UM 30 30 jj aub Keßt- Lincoln US) C.i) 9 I} 4 T lrucks Leave Lamp Sll 7:45 AM «:45 AM 12:00 .\oon Hq. Ist tin.— Co. A, 80 160 From (1) 1:30 AM 8 Aue 134 th Int ji Aui{ • Nebraska City (89; Note: Movement of Omaha Units by Scry. Co. 17th Inf. (Sec \ppcnoix A) </seg>
            <seg id="p115">RETURN TROOP MOVEMENT Page C Transport Unit Leave H.V at .Miles to Arrive at Unit Leave Arrive at Allies lotal and No. ot irucks lamp Asliland Ul' Uf transported Ut tr .Jl' 10 fcf Miles Co. A. 110 th UM Xegt. 6:30 fM 140 12:30 AM Co. H, 134 th Int. 1:30 AM 7:30 AM ho 28»"&gt; (1) 6 I'/, T Irucks 21 Aug 22 Aug lulls City (64) 22 Aug 22 Aug (2) 1 Keconn Truck 7:00 JKM J3O 12:30 AM fa G, 134 th In!. 1:30 AM 7:00 AM 13U 2tO 6 \y, T Trucks 21 Aug 22 Aug llasiitißs (64) 22 Aug 22 Aug (3) 1 Keconn truck 8:30 AM -'IS 5:45 iM C.,. ( , iioth !JM Kegt. 6:45 I'M Arrive .Home 4u 24i 5 \y, T Trucks 22 Aug 22 Aug Lexington 145) Ma. 8:3" I'M From (1) (4) 1 Keconn Truck 8:30 AM 1/U 4:30 Co. U, Mcd iJcpt. 5:30 I'M Arrive Home 40 210 7 V/, '1' Trucks l)ct. 110 th UM Kegt. Sla. 7:l£ I'M From (1) &amp; (2) Kearney (56) Co. U. 110 th UM. Kegt. 7-00 I'M IJO 12:3(1 AM Co. 11, 134 th ml. 1:30 AM 7:00 AM uo 2bo (1) 7 iy, T Trucka 21 Aug 22 Aug (irand Island (64) 22 Aug 22 Aug (2) 5 ly, T Trucks 5:00 AM SO S:3U AM Co. C, 110 th Med. 9:30 AM 1:00 FM 80 160 1 lyi T Truck 22 Aug 22 Aug Ki-Rt. Columbm (67) (Attached dom Co. £, 110 th UM Kegt.) </seg>
            <seg id="p116">RETURN TROOP MOVEMENT Page 7 Transport unit Leave KF at Miles to Arrive at Unit Leave Arrive it Miles Total and Wo. ol Trucks Camp Ashland Ul' IJF Transported OV tLf Jl'tofcF Miles &lt;3) 6 V/i T I'rucki S:00 AJU &gt;6U 3:30 FM Co. 1\ 134 th Int. 4:311 I'M Arrive Home 110 270 From (1) Hartington (64) Sta. 10:00 I'M (4) 4 \'/j T Trucks 2:00 r"M JU 3:30 I:3U1 :3U FM 6:00 I'M 30 80 From v 2) »&lt;1- 10 -. "0"' U*» Kfgt, IJncoln (30) (5) 6 IJS T I'rucks 7:00 I'M 5u Arrive Home lift. Co. UK. l'Uth 50 from (2) &amp; 14) Ma. ":U0 I'M OM Kept Kremoni (28) Co. li. 110 th CJM Krgt S:00 AM &lt;&gt;U /:iu AM i ... M, 134 th Int. S:3O AM 11:00 VM 60 120 (1) 7 \'/, V Irucks il Aug 22 Aug Srward (64) -'2 Aug 22 Aug (2) 6 IVS T Irucks U :00 iNoon 3D 1:311 I'M ( ". I. 134 th Int. .':3 d i"M Arrive Home 50 110 From (1) Lincoln (64) bta. 6:00 MA. I &lt;&gt;. 1) ,110 th Med. Kegt. 8:00 AM '&gt;b Arrine Home Co. I), i 10th Mert. I li I ltuck Arrive Home 93 (1) 1 Kcconn Truck 22 .\n« Station 12:00 Kairbury (47) 'Aticlin tr Co Ma. 3:00 FM 4 Ambulances Voon, 22 Aug X, 1 1U Mcd) 1 m T Iruck i At- I:(JO I'M Inched Ir Co c, 110' Mcd) </seg>
            <seg id="p117">RETURN TROOP MOVEMENT Page 8 Transport Unit Leave n.l' at .Miles to Arrive at Unit Leave Arrive at .Miles Total and No. ol trucks La'np Ashland UP UP Transported UP h.P DP to EP Milef Co. K. 110th Med. Kegt. 8:00 AM 130 Arrive Home Co: K, 110th Med Kegt 130 (1) 1 Kcconn Truck 22 Aug St*. 2:15 I'M Hastings (47) 6 Ambulances 22 Aug 1 IJ4 T Truck to. 1, MOth Med. Kegt. 10:00 I'M 80 1:30 AM Hq Co, V Bn; Co A 2:30 AM 6:00 AM 80 160 (1) 9 IJ4 T Trucks 21 Aug 22 Aug I J4th Inf. 22 Aug 22 Aug Nebraska City (89) (2) 9 IJ4 T Trucks 7:00 AM £5 10:30 AM Serv. Co., 134th int. 11:30 AM 3:00 FM 85 170 From (1) 22 Aug Vork (89) (3) 9 tyi T Trucks 4:00 I'M 30 Arrive Home Hq Co. 3' Bn 134' Int. From (2) 22 Aug Sta. 5:30 FM Co. 1, HO 1 Med. (88) Service Co., 110th Med. 5:00 AM 70 8:00 AM Co. C, 134th Inf. 9:00 AM 12:00 Noon 70 140 (1) 6 \yi T Trucks 22 Aug 22 Aug Beatrice (64) 22 Aug 22 Aug L [ </seg>
            <seg id="p118">RETURN TROOP MOVEMENT Page 9 Transport Unit Leave Jii at .Miles to Arrive at Unit Leave Arrive at Miles Total and No. ot Trucks Lamp Ashland DH Uf Transported DF fcf DP to Kl' Miles (2) 2 \Y, T Trucki 6:00 AM 190 2:45 FM Dot. Co. A. 110 th QM 3:45 PM Arrive Home 160 ,i£o Reßt. lloldrcß.- (12) Sta. 10:30 PM (.1) 2 Rcconn Truclci 1 : nn TM 30 Arrive Home Scry. (.'o.. Vet Co., 9 \y, T Trucks St... 2:30 PMjlMth Mcd Rt K t. I Lincoln (80) Note: Moyomcnt of Omaha Units by Scry. Co. 17th Inf. (See Appendix A&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p119">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL INCOMING TRUCK SCHEDULE Omaha companies to be transported by trucks furnished by Corps Area Motor Pool, Fort Omaha. Units to be transported— Hq. Co.-Co. K— Co. L-Hq. Co., 2nd Bn — Med. Dept. Det., 134th Infantry. Baggage trucks will be required as follows: Hq. Co f Each of tbe other organizations 1 Baggage detail to be transported in two (2) trucks will be furnished by each company as follows: Hq. Co ; 6 Co. K 6 Co. 1 6 Hq. Co. 2nd Bn 4 Med. Dept. Det 4 Baggage trucks and trucks transporting baggage personnel to leave the Armory at Omaha not later than 7:00 A.M., August 8. As soon as trucks arc unloaded at Camp Ashland, return to thc Armory at Omaha for the purpose of transporting personnel of the above units. As soon as per - sonnel of all units have been transported to Camp, trucks will then be released and report back to Corps Area Motor Pool, Fort Omaha. RETURNING TRUCK SCHEDULE The same amount of baggage trucks and baggage detail will be necessary on thc return movement from Camp Ashland to Omaha. Trucks to leave Camp Ashland at 8:00 A.M. on August 22. After unloading bag - gage at the Armory in Omaha, trucks will return to Camp Ashland for the purpose of transporting the personnel of these units back to the Armory at Omaha. After all personnel has been returned to Omaha, trucks will be released and will report back to Corps Area Motor Pool, Fort Omaha. APPENDIX "A" TRAVEL RATION REPORT The following report must be completed by each company or detach - ment and accompany thc voucher. </seg>
            <seg id="p120">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Company Home Station Show date and hour of assembly 1 Show date and hour of arrival at camp .: _ Enlisted strength _. attending camp (Name) (Signed by CO.) (Rank and Branch) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 6, 1938 Circular Letter No. 11 Subject: Travel Rations to Annual Encampment, 1938. To: All Company and Detachment Commanders, NNG. 1. In accordance with par. 13. NGB Circular No. 14 B. November 1, 1937, responsible officers for companies or detachments are authorized to purchase the necessary subsistence for enlisted men at not to exceed 30 cents per meal per man for the time involved in assembling, travel and arrival at camp, meals to be computed as follows: The day will be considered as beginning at midnight. Hour of assembly at armory or Entitled to travel ration arrival at camp allowance provided for Assembly prior to 7 A.M. Morning meal Assembly after 7 A.M. and before noon Noon meal Assembly after 12 noon and before 4:30 P.M. Evening meal Arrival at camp after 11 A.M. Noon meal Arrival at camp after 4 P.M. Evening meal </seg>
            <seg id="p121">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Balance of meals for the first day will be the Garrison Ration. 2. Public voucher is inclosed for stating amount due and should be completed insofar as possible. After the articles have been listed indicate thereunder across the face of the voucher, "Travel Rations, Co , Regt., (so many) enlisted men, (1 or 2) meals," as the case may be*. Where two companies or detachments mess together show the organizations and the number of men separately. 3. The attached report must be completed and accompany the voucher. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Incls. 2 1. Vouchers 2. Report STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 14, 1938 Circular Letter No. 12 Subject: Limitation of Armory Drills, National Guard, Fiscal Year 1939. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. The following letter from the Chief, National Guard Bureau, is pub - lished for the information and guidance of all concerned: "The Secretary of War directs that you be informed that the number of Federal pay armory drills to be held by the National Guard during the </seg>
            <seg id="p122">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Fiscal Year 1939, be as follows: . (a) A total of 48 during the year. (b) Not more than 8 dining any one month. (c) A minimum of 10 per quarter during the second, third and fourth quarters. (Signed) ALBERT H. BLANDING, Major General. Chief, National Guard Bureau." By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, . The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN .Inly 16, 1938 Circular Letter No. 13 Subject: Nebraska Circular Letter No. 8. June 30. 1938. is Amended. To: All Unit Commanders and All Field and Staff Officers. NNG. Paragraph 4, of the above mentioned letter is amended by adding the following, "Officers and enlisted men will be permitted to wear khaki shirts with slacks or cotton breeches after retreat." By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p123">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 23, 1938 Circular Letter No. 14 Subject: Train Schedule To and Return From Annual Encampment, 1938. Ashland. Nebraska. . To: All Company Commanders, Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. In accordance with General Order No. 5, AGO Nebraska, May 23. 1938. tbe following train schedule is prescribed for movement to camp: Move- ! Organiza- T „__,• I Approx. Bag. c . . . tnents tions Location [ No- Pass Ca r Schedule No. 1 How Co Gering 64 1 l-v. Gerihg Tn No. 54, UP (x) 3:10 I'M, 8-7-38 Fremont Co D No. Platte 64 1 Ly. No. Platte Tn. No. CB&amp;Q (x) 12. 2:15 AM, 8-8-38 Ashland Ar. Fremont, 6:55 AM, 8-8-38 I.v. Fremont, Q Spec 7:25 AM Ar. Ashland. Q Spec . BilO AM No. 2 I.v. Scottsbluff Tn No. CB&amp;Q Co E Scotts- 64 I 1 -*2. 5:18 PM, 8-7-38 Ashland bluff (x) Ar - Ashland Tn No. 24, 11:10 AM, 8-8-38 (x) Tourist cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering) and Co. E (Scottsbluff). coaches for Co. D (North Platte) 2. TICKETS Government Transportation Requests on the carrier concerned will be exchanged for ROUND TRIP TICKETS at the local ticket office. Requests for berths will be exchanged with thc Pullman conductor for </seg>
            <seg id="p124">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL accommodations actually furnished. 3. RAILROAD EQUIPMENT Baggage cars will be set the day preceding the movement to permit loading baggage and installation of field ranges, where it is necessary. Tourist cars or coaches will be loaded in a quiet and orderly manner in ample time to permit carriers to leave at designated time. I 4. BAGGAGE 150 pounds of personnel baggage will be transported free for each passenger, consisting of trunks, barracg bags, bedding rolls, hand bag - gage, fiield desks, dispensaries, typewriters, etc., (par. 28, NGR 71). Each, piece will be marked or tagged with name of owner. Checkable baggage will not be included on Bill of Lading. Excess baggage, consisting of property other than checkable baggage, will be handled in baggage cars but is paid for by the Government on Government Bill of Lading, cover - ing such impedimenta forwarded from each station, at freight rates. 5. The following train schedule is prescribed for thc return move - ment. Move- Organiza- T ■■ Approx. Bag. Schedule ments tions Location No p ass Car bcheoulc No. 3 Co E ScottS- 64 1 Lv. Ashland Tn No. 17, CB&amp;Q bluff *••« J?**. 8-21-38 (x) D est v ' Ar. Scottsbluff Tn No. 31. 6:1(1 AM. 8-22-33 No. 4 Co D No. Platte 64 1 »• Ashland Tn No. 16, CB&amp;Q (X) 2:15 I'M. 8-21-38 Fremont *' v - Fremont Tn No. IS, UP 5:25 I'M, 8-21-38 Dest Ar. No. Platte Tn No. 15. 12:01 AM, 8-22-38 How Co Gering 64 1 Ar: Gering Tn No. 53, (x) 10:55 AM, 8-22-38 (x) Tourist cars will be required for Howitzer Company (Gering; and Co. E (Scottsbluff), coaches for Co. D (North Platte). 6. Postal Card Report WD MB No." 36 will be mailed to the USP &amp; DO as soon as possible after arrival at home Station, with any unused tickets and "Conductor's Report of Troops Carried." </seg>
            <seg id="p125">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 7. Two memorandum copies of Bill of Lading must be given to the USP&amp;DO properly signed by the local agent prior to departure. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 25, 1938 Circular Letter No. 15 Subject: Cans. Milk, 10 Gallon. To: All Unit Commanders and Field and Staff Officers. NNG. All cans. milk. JO gal., will be brought to Camp for the overnight bivouac. These cans are to be left in thc mess halls and upon departure from Camp they should have tbe lids removed and be turned upside down and slightly tilted so that air may circulate in same. (See Nebraska Cir - cular Letter No. 22. September 22, 1937.) By order of Ibe Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 26, 1938 Circular Letter </seg>
            <seg id="p126">REPORT OF. THE ADJUTANT GENERAL No. 16 Subject: Additional Certificate on Payrolls, Pay Vouchers or Pay Claims. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. The following Act of June 11. 1938, is quoted for your information: "*** Provided further, That no part of this or any other appropria - tion contained in this Act shall be available for the pay of any per - son, civil or military, not a citizen of the United States, unless in the employ of the Government or in a pay status on July 1. 1937, under appropriations for the War Department, nor for the pay of any such person beyond the period of enlistment or termination of employ - ment, but nothing herein shall be construed as applying to instructors of foreign languages at the Military Academy, or to Filipinos in the Army Transport Service, or to persons employed outside of the con - tinental limits of the United States except enlisted men of the Regular Army, other than Philippine Scouts, upon expiration of enlistment and this provision shall be subject to the provisions of the Act en - titled 'An Act for the protection of certain enlisted men of the Army, approved August 19, 1937." 2. lii view of the above Act. the following certificate will be re - quired on all payrolls, pay vouchers or pay claims as the case may be: "1 further certify that employment of the persons named on the within. (Payroll, pay voucher, or pay claim, as the case may be) is not prohibited by the so-called 'Citizenship' provi - sions of the Act of June 11. 1938 (Public 590— 75th Congress), limit - ing thc availability of thc appropriation from which their salaries arc - to be paid." By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 29, 1938 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Circular Letter No. 17 Subject: West Point Preliminary Competitive Examination, 1938, for the Nebraska National Guard. To: All Unit and Sub-unit Commanders, NNG. 1. Tbe annual preliminary examination for the selection of one-en - listed man of the Nebraska National Guard to take the competitive exam - ination for appointment to the United States Military Academy will take place at the Adjutant General's Office, beginning Tuesday, November 8, 1938. at 9:00 A.M.. and continuing through Wednesday and Thursday, November 9 and 10. ' 2. To be eligible for appointment from the National Guard, an ap - plicant must be an enlisted man in a federally recognized unit and must, on the date of admission, July 1, 1939, be between thc ages of nineteen and twenty-two years, not less than five feet four inches in height, and have served as an enlisted man in an active status in the National Guard not less than one year. Thc age and service requirements arc statutory and cannot be waived or modified, but it is not essential that the service be continuous, so that former service in the Guard may be counted in de - termining an applicant's eligibility. 3. The candidate selected will be authorized by the War Depart - ment to report for the regular entrance examination, which is scheduled to be held beginning on March 7. 1939. and the appointment available on July 1. 1939, will be awarded to the qualified condidate in order of merit established at thc examination, which is competitive among all National Guard candidates. 4. Previously applicants have presented themselves to take this ex - amination who were in no way qualified and could not hope to pass the rigid examination given. It has been demonstrated that an applicant should have had at least one year in college, in addition to a high school educa - tion. The examination will be written and will consist of an exhaustive examination in the following subjects: Elementary Algebra, to and in - cluding Quadratics, Plane Geometry, English Grammar, United States and General History and English Literature and Composition. 5. No state funds are available for the payment of any part of the expenses of applicants taking this examination. </seg>
            <seg id="p128">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 6. A blank form to be used in making application to participate in the examination is inclosed. A 1938 West Point pamphlet will be sent upon request. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Incl. Appl. blank. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 18. 1938 Circular Letter No. 18 Subject: Command and General Staff School for National Guard Officers. Fort Crook. Nebraska. To: All Unit Commanders and Field and Staff Officers, NNG. 1. The following National Guard Bulletin, Hq. 7th Corps Area, is quoted for your information : * * * "COMMAND AND STAFF SCHOOL FOR NATIONAL GUARD OFFICERS 1. A Command and Staff School for selected National Guard officers will be conducted in this corps area, under the supervision of this head - quarters. 2. Course. Thc course will consist of three subcourses, one sub - course of two weeks duration to be held each of the three years. This course has been prepared by thc Command and General Staff School at Fort Leavenworth. </seg>
            <seg id="p129">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 3. Place and date. This year the school will be held in the CCC buildings at Fort Crook. Nebraska, during the period April 16-29, 1939. 4. Instructors. There will be five instructors who will be detailed from the instructors on duty with thc National Guard of this Corps area. 5. Students. a. There will be ** * students alloted to states as follows: ** » * Nebraska 2 ** * * b. Graduates of the Special Course, Command and General Staff School are ineligible. Tbe completion of Subcourse 1, Part I, Command and General Staff Extension Course, will be a prerequisite for attendance. c. Applications for attendance and selections, should be made from groups in the following priority: ( 1 ) Brigade and division staff officers of field grade and commanders down to include battalions, who have been prevented from attending any service school. (2) Brigade and division staff officers of field grade and commanders down to include battalions who are graduates of a special service school. (3) Captains whose mobilization assignment carries promo - tion to the grade of field officers. (4) Specially selected staff officers below field grade. d. State Adjutants General are requested to submit their list of selected students to this headquarters not later than January 1, 1939. In making his report the priority class to which each proposed student be - longs should be shown. Especial care should be given to selecting officers who will attend all three years. Each state may submit the names of alternates if so desired from which this headquarters may select students to fill vacancies caused by failure of some state to fill its allotment. Each selected student should be required to submit his application on the form provided by this headquarters. 6. Future Subcourses. To be eligible for thc second and third sub - courses to be held in 1940 and 1941, an officer must have completed the preceding subcourse, either by attendance at the corps area school, or at a school operated at state expense, under supervision of the corps area </seg>
            <seg id="p130">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL commander and using the texts and school materials supplied by the Com - mand and General Staff School for the regular corps area schools. 7. Attendance at this school is supplementary training and will net make an officer ineligible for annual field training. Students will receive pay and allowances under the provisions of NCR 58. 8. Seventh Corps Area instructions! National Guard Bulletin No 7 March 12, 1937. ' ' By command of Major General FORD: JOHN F. FRANKLIN, Colonel, G. S. C, Chief of Staff. OFFICIAL: (Signed) W. T. MACMILLAN. Colonel. A. G. D., Adjutant General." * * * 2 Applications may be secured front this office and must be sub - nutted by November 30. 1938. By order of the Governor: H. J. PAUL. The Adjutant General. Nebraska. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Circular Letter December 6, 1938 No. 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Subject: Efficiency Reports. To: All Reporting Officers, NNG. 1. Inclosed are WD MB Forms No. 67 to be used in making the annual Efficiency Reports for the year ending December 31, 1938. Thc reports arc to lie made in accordance with instructions contained in para - graph 51. XGR 20, dated July 8, 1938. 2. Reports are to be forwarded by the reporting officer to the next military superior within fifteen days of the close of the period covered by the report and are to reach this office by the end of thc month. By order of the Governor: I H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. End. SPANISH-AMERICAN WAR FUND The following is a list of unpaid claims due soldiers who participated in the service of thc Spanish-American War in the First. Second and Third Nebraska Volunteer Regiments and Troop K, Third Volunteer Cavalry : COMPANY A— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Bye, Joseph G $3.20 Pvt. Gelvin. Robert N $3.20 Pvt. Allen, Roller C 3.20 Pvt. Kremer, Cochran A 4.00 Pvt. Kelly. Charles R 3.20 Pvt. Sommcrs. Ncls J 3.20 Pvt. Morgenstern, Henry A. 3.20 Pvt. Turner, Robert W 3.20 Pvt. Shivery, Bion .3.20 Pvt. Womplcr. Elmer B 3.20 Pvt. Freeman. Charlie 0 3.20 COMPANY B— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Garinger, Albert 80 Pvt. Killhom, Perry A 4.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p132">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Black, John „. 4.00 Pvt. Ressekuie, Herbert L. .. 4.0C Pvt Grainger, Louis I _ 1.60 COMPANY C— FIRST REGIMENT i Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Duf Pvt. Johnson. Hans 3.20 Pvt. Dringman, Will F 3.20 COMPANY D— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Alley, John S 4.00 Pvt. Kosharek, John 4.01 Pvt. Bergcr, Harry A 4.00 Pvt. Bloom, John J 4.00 Pvt. Fitchie. Sanuel B 4.00 COMPANY E— FIRST REGIMENT I Rank Name - Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Land. Noah B 1.60 Pvt. Lisk. Jack G 3.20 Pvt. Blackburn. Wm. C 3.20 Pvt. Pecinovsky, Jos. W 3.20 Pvt. Bliss. Henry 3.20 Pvt. Bays. Wm 80 Pvt. Dunning, Benj. F 3.20 Pvt. Moffet. Jesse C. 3.20 Pvt. Duvall, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Scott, Sampel G 3.20 Pvt. Gilham, Wm. H 1.60 Pvt. Thomas, Harry H 3.20 COMPANY F— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Gallagher. Joseph P. ..:. 3.20 Pvt. Gilbert, Alvin W. 3.20 Cpl. Sims, Arthur C 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E 3.20 Cpl. Marsh, Pierce D 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua 3.20 Cpl. Fell, Joseph G 3.20 Pvt. Kesney, John D 3.20 Pvt. Brown, Lewis 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Dennis E 3.20 Pvt. Curas, Frederick L 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F 3.20 Pvt. Davidson, Houston 3.20 Pvt. Webb, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY G— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Burlington, John 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Guy C 3.20 Pvt. Dowis. Jonathan E 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Wm. P 3.20 Pvt. Underwood, Henry C. .. 3.20 COMPANY H— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Andrews, Ernest H 3.20 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C 4.00 Pvt. Dawson, Eugene M 4.C0 Pvt. Robbtns, Rces 4.00 Pvt. Hunt, Geo. W 1.60 Pvt. Smith, George J 4.00 Pvt. Downing, Edward S. .. 4.00 Pvt. Sutton, Roy 0 1.60 Pvt. Mansker, James F 3.20 Pvt Secley, F. Homer 2.40 Pvt. Mcngier, Frank 80 Pvt. Winagel, Anthony J 2.40 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L 3.20 COMPANY I— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Mus. Hotsel, Leon Y 4.00 Pvt. Jones. Oliver J _ 4.00 Pvt. Fricke, Albert W. 4.00 Pvt. McFry, Albert 4.00 Pvt. Gregg, Edwin F 4.00 Pvt. Miller, Wm. D 4.00 Pvt. Jeon, John M 4.00 Pvt. Passmore, Lewis D 4.00 COMPANY K— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. DeLong, Herbert B 3.20 Pvt. Swanson, August 4.00 Pvt. Crittenden, David L 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Chas. F 3.20 Pvt. Schmeider, Wm. G 4.00 Pvt. Witsch, Max N 3.20 COMPANY L— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Pvt. Downs, James W 3.20 Pvt. Legg, Marvin 0 3.20 Pvt. Green, Fred L 3.20 Pvt. Taylor, Fred 3.20 Pvt. Humphrey, Mortimer B. 3.20 Pvt. Whitaker, Robert H. .. 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p134">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY M— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Spence, Monroe W 3.20 Pvt. Coxson, Alvin A 3.20 Cpl. Rucker, Winifred L 3.20 Pvt. Jack. Cecil B 3.20 Pvt. Coons. Chas. J 3.20 FIELD AND STAFF— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due P.M. Brown, Robert S 4.00 Mes. Murnhouse. F. Edd. .. 4.00 COMPANY A— SECOND REGIMENT - ... . -j Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Cupernell, Ernest H. .. 3.20 Art. Devinncy, Harry M 3.21 : Cpl. Pain. Lewis A 3.20 Pvt. Miller. Ned K 3.20 Pvt. Carman. Chas. : S 3.20 Pvt. Mott, Mathew 3.20 Pvt." Charles. Alfred W 3.20 Pvt. Packwood, Arthur T. _ 3.20 Pvt. Cornell, George S 3.20 Pvt. Tuffs, Frank 3,20 Pvt. Dwyer, Patrick 3.20 Pvt. White, Wm. A 3.20 Pvt. Forman, David A 3.20 Pvt. Walker. Ollie :... 320 Pvt; Harrold. Harry 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Alfred 3.20 Pvt. Kearney, William 3.20 Pvt. Woodruff, Charles 3.20 COMPANY B— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Whitmer. James K. 3.20 Pvt. Briggs, Ernest G. Wag. Crow, Wallace H 3.20 (Died in service) 3.20 Pvt. Minnich, Herbert J 3.20 Pvt. Williams. Frank 3.20 Pvt. Smith. Frank A 3.20 Pvt. Wilson. Eli A: ;.. 3.20 Art. Grossctt. Chas. E 3.^0 COMPANY C— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Miles, George 3.20 Pvt. Clark. Win. B 3.20 Pvt. Burnham, Irwin C. 3.20 Pvt. l-fadley, Wm. B 1.60 Pvt. Kjellidin, Larch A 3.20 Pvt. Kinic. David 1.60 Pvt. Lee. Ira E 3.20 Pvt. Mcl.ain, Clarence E. .. 1.60 Pvt. Leon, Victor C 1.60 Pvt. Roddy, John H 3.20 Pvt. Cristianson. Edw. R 3.20 Pvt. Shanklin. Sylvester 1.6U Pvt. Church, John H 1.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY D— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt Due Rank Name Amt Due Pvt. Allen, Chas. A. 4.00 Pvt. Lloyd, Wm. T 4.00 Pvt. French, John C 3.20 Pvt. Mager, Clarence E 4.00 Pvt. Anderson, Albert R. .... 4.00 Pvt. Pickens, Walter R 4.00 Pvt. Hastings, Bert 4.00 Pvt. Semmcbroth, Emil M... 4.00 Pvt. Ludwick, George L 4.00 COMPANY E— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Andrews, Nick 3.20 Pvt. Keen, Robert J 3.20 Art. Wiese, Herman 2.40 Pvt. Krajicck, John 3.20 Pvt. Alexander, Chas. W. .. 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Thomas 3.20 Pvt. Dahiem, Henry W 3.20 Pvt. Osterhout. John H 3.20 Pvt. Frame. George W 3.20 Pvt. Stroud. Ivan E 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Edward J 3.20 COMPANY F— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Grofton. George 3.20 Pvt. Hall. James H 3.20 Pvt. Goodwill, Louis M. ...... 3.20 Pvt. Mitchell, Harry D 4.80 COMPANY G— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt Due Rank Name Amt. Due 2nd Lt. Hodgins, Eli .... 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Martin T 80 Cpl. Hays. Robert A 3.20 Pvt. Hugh, Harry 80 Cpl. Morrison, Max 3.20 Pvt. Lininger, Wilbur S 80 Cpl. Turcot, Eugene 3.20 Pvt. McFarland, Sm'l F 80 Pvt. Blenkiron, Harry V. 80 Pvt. Neucomb, Frank S 3.20 Pvt. Deverall, Ralph H 80 Pvt. Newton, William 3.20 Pvt. Drake, Henry L 80 Pvt. Packard, Hugh M 3.20 Pvt. Fisher, Leo 80 Pvt. Quimby, Lucien E 80 Pvt. Gainey, John H .80 Pvt. Ritter, David .30 Pvt. Horn, George L., Jr. .. 3.20 Pvt. Thompson, Eddie D. .. .80 </seg>
            <seg id="p136">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY H— SECOND REGIMENT * Rank Name Amt Due Rank Name Amt Due Cpl. Borland. John A 4.00 Pvt. Johnston. George II 400 Art. Niell, John W 4.00 Pvt. Logan, Alvab 400 Pvt. Bowers. Henry H 4.00 Pvt. Mcitner, Joseph 400 Pvt. Boyd, Wm. J 4.00 Pvt. Nelson, John 400 Pvt. Davis, Harry E 4.00 Pvt. Perry, Herbert N 400 Pvt. Ditzler. Al 4.C0 Pvt. Scrensen, Olc C. 400 Pvt. Gillespie, David E 4.00 Pvt. Tucker. Harry O 400 Pvt. Hershev, Will L 4.00 Pvt. Whitney, John A 4. W COMPANY I— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due QM Sgt. Rairiey. Jacob A 4.00 Pvt. Schuelke. Herman A 400 Pvt. Evans. Fletcher 4.00 Pvt. Thompson, Theodore 400 Pvt. Hammill, Oscar 4.00 Pvt. Walker. Joseph H. 400 Pvt. Penland. John W 80 Pvt. Way. Rueben D. 400 Pvt. Schooler, John H 4.00 COMPANY K— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Pvt. Erickson, Francis T. .. 3.20 Pvt. West. Charles 3"i Cpl. Hill, John T. 3.20 COMPANY L— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Cottr'ell, Eugene W. 3'o Cpl. Jack, Charles H : 2.40 Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Clarenden. Alvin T 4.00 Pvt. Johnson, John 3?0 Cpl. Kohout, Frank W 4.00 Pvt. Leonard. Wm C 80 «,' ■T ge ' J ° hn M 3 ' 20 J ' vt - Powell, Joseph A. ..3 20 Wag. Bauman, John P 4.00 Pvt. Rainey, Wm N 3 Pvt. Abel, Louis , 3.20 Pvt. Smith, George W 160 Pvt. Anderson, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Thomas B 1.60 COMPANY M— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt Due Rank Name Amt Du. Wag. Alfreds, Frank H 5.60 Pvt. Schwart, Wm. 560 Pvt. Londlodge, Henry W. 5.60 Pvt. Steele, Duncan C. . ."" 560 Pvt. Payne, Wesley R 6.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL FIELD STAFF AND BAND— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due RB Mus. Henderson, Roy .. 9.60 RB Mus. Wells, Richard L. ..12.00 COMPANY A— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due UM Sgt. Bridenthal, C. W. 32.55 Pvt. Gray. Burton E 2.40 Cpl. Ford. John J 5.60 Pvt. Hinckley, John S 1.60 Cpl. Steinbach, George 1272 Pvt. Hurst, Arthur J 1.60 Cpl. Ross. Mathew 1.60 Pvt. Koontz, Edmund J 2.40 Pvt. Marksbury. Thos. N. ..' 1.60 Pvt. Lee, Leonard 4.80 Pvt. Michael, Wm 14.61 Pvt. O'Leary, John J 2.40 Pvt, Rader, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Pace, Pcrle R 2.40 Mu&gt;. Miller, Wilson N 2.40 Pvt. Philpott, Tyra A 1.60 Mus. Lenker, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Reynolds, John A 1.60 Art. Ball, Wm. A 18.39 Pvt. Schneider, Wm 2.40 Pvt. Allen. Thomas 4.80 Pvt. Smith, John J 1.60 Pvt. Avery, John S 1.60 Pvt. Taylor, James J 2.40 Pvt. Bliss, Gottle 1.60 Pvt. Trtrnibly .Warden, A. F. 18.39 Pvt. Collins. John H 1.60 Pvt. Zarbock, Herman, Jr. .. 2.40 COMPANY B— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt Due Rank Name Amt. Due Wag. Palmer, James H 32.69 Pvt. Keanes. James N 80 Pvt. Bowers, Leslie L 3.20 Pvt. Line, Jno. M. 17.59 Pvt. Bradford, George H 80 Pvt. Whales, Edwin F 3.20 Pvt. Clancy. Thomas 80 Pvt. Mungoran. Peter 3.20 Pvt. Custer, Elisha 80 Pvt. McGrew, Frank 80 Pvt. Francisco, John H 80 Pvt. McMillan, Daniel W. ..33.64 Pvt. ("asser, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Peterson, Paul H 33.64 Pvt. Greenlee, William 3.20 Pvt. Rickenburg, Gust 33.64 Pvt. Gross, William 3.20 Pvt. Roop, Scott D 80 Pvt. Habbick, George W 1.60 Pvt. Swanson, Albert N 80 Pvt. Jarvis. Chas. T 80 Pvt. Ward, William R 80 COMPANY C— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt Due Rank Name Amt Due Cpl. Bailey, Frank C 22.74 Pvt. Paul, Henry C 2.40 Cpl. Dillion. Samuel H 27.46 Pvt. Breechwald, Philip 2.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p138">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Sydow, Emil 27.46 Pvt. Collins, Bernard P 8.58 Cpl. Miller. Wm. E 27.46 Pvt. Dobbins, Albert 2.40 Cpl. Burket, Harry B 2.40 Pvt. Henske, Fred .80 Wag. Clayberg, Elmer 27.46 Pvt. Henry, William 2.40 Mus. Eberhart, Chas. E 2.40 Pvt. Seek, John A 2.40 Art. Freeman, Nathan W. ..27.46 Pvt. Strupp, Henry F 2.40 Pvt. Hileman, Robert E 27.46 Pvt. Swanson. Oscar 2.40 Pvt. Howell. Harry H 22.74 Pvt. Taylor, Edward 4.00 Pvt. Keliher, John F 4.50 Pvt. Vernon, George A 12.36 Pvt. Long. Wilbur W 5.75 Pvt. Wahlstrom. Albin F. .. 2.40 Pvt. Mitchell. Edward F 2.40 Pvt.. Zurubsky, James 7.64 COMPANY D— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Reynolds, Walter D 4.80 Pvt. Landsbury, Harry 1.60 Sgt. Dennett, Albert G 29.57 Pvt. Lundell, Ernest 4.86 Cpl. Abernathy, Fred B 26.74 Pvt. Allwein, John C. 1.60 Cpl. Christensen, Pvt. Anderson, Edward .. 4.06 Christian A 36.18 Pvt. Anderson. Andrew 3.20 Cpl. Asbough, Albert L 3.20 Pvt. Bandy. John W 1. .0 Mus. Howell. Edward 3.20 Pvt. Flor. Sigurd 8.80 Pvt. Hamilton. James 3.20 Pvt. Nelson, Chas. M 8.0!) Pvt. Jansen, Nels P 23.91 Pvt. Nelson. Ivan G 8.00 Pvt. Juul, John M 30.52 Pvt. Pollock, Mak 2.40 Pvt. Jones, Lewis C .80 Pvt. Robie, Ernest 4.80 COMPANY E— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Siddell, Bert E 13.01 Pvt. Rcinbolt, Fred 80 Pvt. Anderson, Claude 4.00 Pvt. Smith. Fred S 22.45 Pvt. Hays, John S 28.12 Pvt. Van Epps. Bert L 80 Pvt. Lewin, Samuel C 80 COMPANY F— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Baughman, Chas 2.40 Pvt. Olson, Chris 80 Pvt. Elm, William 36.69 Pvt. Head, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Gage, Elmer 6.40 Pvt. Houdek, Charles 1.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Hayes, John C 8.80 Pvt. Hudec, Wm 3.20 Pvt. Knient, Joe 1.60 Pvt. Karges, John 36.65 Pvt. Knott. Fred 80 Pvt. Sarre, Alfred H 80 Pvt. Manzel, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Sramek, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Miller. Thomas J 1.60 Pvt. Underhill, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Nicholson. James 1.60 Pvt. Whyte, Wm. M 80 COMPANY G— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Duo Cpl. Larson. Felix G 29.72 Pvt. Forsman. Oscar 29 72 Cpl. Collins. Wilkc S 29.72 Pvt. Fuller. Guy W 1.60 Pvt. Berg. Axel 1.60 Pvt. Howard. Edward 29.72 Pvt. Brower, Bertie M 29.72 Pvt. Jones, Frank 27.72 !'\t. Ferguson, Isaac 60 Pvt. Larson, Axel W 29.72 Pvt. Burke. Frank J 29.72 Pvt. Meade, Frank ...29!r2 Pvt Carter, Wm. H 29.72 Pvt. O'Connor, William .... 4^oo Pvt. Conner, Clement T 29.72 Pvt. Pickard, Harry M 29.72 Pvt. Durham, Miller L. ......29.72 Pvt. Reap. Warren A 29.72 COMPANY H— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Headwell, Axel 3109 Pvt. Robinson, Kdward 3.20 Pvt. Jackmaii. Wm. N 6.55 Pvt. Thomas, James T 3.Z0 Pvt. Uichty. John 6.55 Pvt. Matson, Albert 500 I'\t. Williams, Kdgar T 31.09 COMPANY I— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Dericnger. Ceorge 36.61 Pvt. Brown. Frank H 4.00 Sgt. Waterman, Harry D. S. 37.56 Pvt. Carrol, John W ' 400 Cpl. Dickenson. John W U.\)7 Pvt. Center, Albert """ 480 Cpl. Felts. William B 6.40 Pvt. Dinsmore, Claude R. a24 Cpl. Jensen. Chris M .4.00 Pvt. Dubee. Alexander 320 Cpl. Meyer. Otto 4.00 Pvt Fairchild. Homer 160 Wag. Brett. Zinc H 22.45 Pvt. Guthercole, Fred A. 400 Pvt. Houghs, Chas. L 4.00 Pvt. Hackler, David D 160 Pvt. Jones. Lloyd 0 4.00 Pvt. Hanks, Harry E. 160 Pvt. Miller. Fred S 9.24 Pvt. Potter, Forrest A. 924 </seg>
            <seg id="p140">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Morris, Benjamin F 9.24 Pvt. Palmer. Archibald G. .. 5/.0 Pvt. Padol. Adam 80 Pvt. Roberts. James W 9.24 Pvt. Perry, Chas. E 11.12 Pvt. Starky, Cyrus &#132; 37.56 Art. Shcpardson. Bcnj. W. ..23.40 Pvt. Stohe. John G 400 Pvt. Aitkeu. George F 37.56 Pvt. Swan, Richard B. SO Pvt. Baird. Francis H 4.80 Pvt. Vandyke, John T. 6.40 Pvt. Bcrsley, Wm. G 31.89 Pvt. Warrington. Albert J. .. 2.40 COMPANY K— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Ist Sgt. Jacobscn. Carl L 34.29 Pvt. 'Mines, Janus S. ..: ■. 1.60 Cpl. Fountain. Francis N 34.29 Pvt. Painter, Wm. C 2.40 Pvt. Arnold. Otto II 80 Pvt. Porterricld, James A. 34.2') Pvt. Cofield. Chester A 11.64 Pvt. Reardon. Patrick J 2.40 Pvt. Hightower. Harry A 2.40 Pvt. RofT. John I ...29.57 Pvt. Kennedy, George H 7.20 Pvt. Snider. Charles 3.20 Pvt. Kankright. Clinton D. 27/8 |Yt. Stamp. Samuel 1.60 Pvt. Krugcr. Win SO Pvt. Van Sickle, Cyrus 1.60 Pvt. Mathews. Stanley 30.52' Pvt. Williams. Wm. M 1.60 Pvt. McCaultcy, Wm. G 1.60 COMPANY L-THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Nicholson, Chas. J 4.00 Pvt. Kcllcy. Rolxrt S 6.40 Cpl. Taft. Charles C 21.01 Pvt. McColl. John 14.1.0 Wag. Stockton. Andrew .32.34 Pvti McCornn'ck. Bcnj. D 8.110 Pvt. Kritsch, Herman 6.40 Pvt. Miller. August 4.80 Pvt. Laflin, Gilbert B 8.80 Pvt. Pcndarvis, George 11. .. 5.60 Pvt. Lee, Justivin E 1.60 Pvt. Bradshaw, Thomas H. .. 5.60 Pvt. Lehmus, Lewis A 21.01 Pvt. Burns. James E 3.20 Pvt. Mardock. John E 1.60 Pvt. Cbisolm. Ralph 0 5.60 Wag. Brott, Zina H 22.45 Pvt. Redfield, Cyrus R. ...... 4.80 Art. Watson, Grant 24.79 Pvt. Rundus. Frank 32.34 Pvt. Athos, Andrew G 1.27.62 Pvt. Slurry, John W 5.60 Pvt. Black. Wm 2.40 Pvt. Swanson, Ncls 32.34 Pvt. Fox. Ernest S 24.79 Pvt. Turner, Carlton B 5.60 Pvt. Grove, George W 5.60 Pvt. Walker, Chas 27.62 Pvt. Jensen, Hans 27.62 Mus. Woerhide, Charles E. .. 6.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p141">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY M— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due S^t. Lord, George E 35.38 Pvt. Hensel, Win. A 2.40 Pvt. Foster, John E 4.00 Pvt. Kleinsmith, Morris 35.38 Pvt. Bennett. Niks 21.22 Pvt. Leonard, Harry H. ; ....17.44 Pvt. Biegler, George 34.44 Pvt. Maddan, Chas 35.3S Pvt. Brewick, Andrew T 3.20 Pvt. Maxwell, Joseph E 11.78 Pvt. Cantello. John 10.84 Pvt. Ratckin, "janson L 80 Pvt. Carigan, Robert J 35.38 Pvt. Timmons, Alfred D 34.44 Pvt. Custard, Marshall 1.60 Pvt. Wiesman, Jacob 2.40 Pvt. Drustrup, Ncls 3.20 Cpl. Forrester, Herbert A. 13.60 Pvt. Heisler, Robert D 80 Pvt. Alley. Franc 2.40 Pvt. . Poster. Frederick W 17.44 Pvt. Beardsley, Wm. S 80 Pvt. Graham, Alonzo 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, John D 13.60 Pvt. Griggs, Bert 2.40 TROOP K— THIRD CAVALRY Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. McLaughlin, Walter .... 2.40 Pvt. Robinson, Fred 2.40 Pvt! Mossbarger, Claude G. 2.40 It is recommended that this list be given a circulation in the news - papers of the State with a view to locating such of these men as possible. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>