<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  SOY BEANS AND COWPEAS.</title>
               <date value="1915">1915</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Voi.umk XXVII, Article VII. SOY BEANS AND COWPEAS. By T. A. Kifk.ski.bach. Distributed April 6, 1915. A SHOCK OF SDV HKAXN. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY I HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, President. Valley. HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL. Lincoln. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR O. LYFORD, Falls City. HONORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN, Dav.y. HONORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln. THE STATION OFFICERS. ■CL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. ;URNETT, B. S&lt;\, Director; Animal Husbandry. 'UGSLEY, B. Sc. Din; tor of Exit iision Service. ALES, M. Ph., Financial Bccretaru. PRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF. E. Mkm&gt; Wiuox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. \V. Li'sdx, Ph. D.. Agricultural Chemittru. L. W. Chase. M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. *R. K. Bliss, B. S. A., Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Fkamiskn. M. S. A., Dairy Husbamlr.u. Lawrence Bui nkr, B. So., Entomology. T. A. Kiksski h.m ii, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. H. C. Fillky, A. M., Farm Management. W. J. MoRRii.i.. M. Foil, Forestry. •R. A. Emerson, D. Sc, Horticulture. R. F. HowAitu, A. M., Horticulture. G. A. Lovei.ami, A. M.. Met' moloijii. W. P. S.nydkr, M. S., Supt. of Experimental Substation. North Platte. C. B. Lee, A. M., Axxociute in Animal Husbandry. Howard J. Gisamuch, B. Sc, Associate in Animal Husbandry. M. H. Swenk, A. M-, 4 HOC In fr in Entomology. George K. K. Link, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Kotanii. H. A. McComh, B. Sc, Horticulturist of Experimental Substation. North Platte. L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Assistant in Dry Land Agriculture, U. 8. Department of Agriculture, North Platte. J. W. Calyix, B. Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Chei:iistrii P. B. Barker, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). ■BWM Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). J. A. Ratcukk, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy L. B. Stlrdeyast, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. E. G. Woodward, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. J. R. Cooper, B. Sc, Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, B. Sc., Assistant m Experimental Agronomy. Fi.iikkmk A. McCormiok, Ph. D., Assistant in Agricultural ISotauy. H. E. Vasey, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. ■ Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Kxorh, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. H. L. Nye, Foreman DawamttTWtiOM Farm. Culbertson. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Introduction - Habits of growth - Adaptation and uses for Nebraska conditions 7 Composition and feediag value § Yields in other States n 11 Varieties tested and yields at Nebraska Kxperinieiit Station. . 12 Sov beam and eowpeaa for hay 17 Sov lieans and eowpeaa for tillage IS field compared with grain crnpa at Nebraska Experiment Station |() Boj lie.ms and cowpeaa as mi] baproferi 20 rlace in the rotation 22 aiieties and seed •&gt;•&gt; ■&gt;■) • to Inoculation •&gt;.» Time, rate, and manner of planting 2;t . &lt; 'ult iv.it ion 20 Harvesting ■»(! L'C, Thresh i 11 g and storing 28 Farmers" jests with soy beans 28 Summary 2!) </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">SOY BEANS AND COWPEAS. IIY T. A. K1ESSKI.H.UII. INTRODUCTION. EIu recent years considerable interest has been manifest in ■braska concerning soy Ikmiis ami cowpeaa; and numerous iu - irics regarding them have come to the Experiment Station. The BDWpea is regarded as a profitable crop chictly in the cotton Slates, but lias some importance as far north as Missouri. Illinois. Indiana, and Ohio. On the oilier hand, the soy Mil is adapted primarily to the Northern States between ihe NgioM l&gt;est suited for eowpeaa in the Soulh an&lt;l Canada h'eld peas in the North. Tile Central States in which they are most commonly grown are Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, and Michigan, and they have I wen recom mended for Kansas and Missouri. Much has been said of than crops in the States in which they are es|teciall.y adapted, and the interest in them has spread to Nebraska. Somewhat extensive experimental tests were made at the Ne - braska Agricultural Experiment Station by Dr. T. L. Lyon, BOW of Cornell I'niversity. Included in these tests were nine varieties of soy beans for which yields were determined during the years In 1909 this Station secured lead of eight representative va - rieties of soy beans from Mr. C. V. l'iper of the United Stales De - partment of Agriculture. At that time Professor K. &lt;S. Mont - gomery. now of Cornell Tniversity, again took up the testing of soy beans, which has l&gt;een continued since lltll by the writer, thus giving a continuous record of six years" work in recent years. Co - operative tests also have been made, during the past three years, with farmers of the State. Tuo our tests with COWfeaa have not l&gt;een extensive, this crop seems much less deserving of trial than soy beans. HABITS OF GROWTH. The soy ltean is an upright, branching, annual legume varying in height, under normal conditions, from 1)4 to 4 feet. It pro - duces a small pod (very similar to the garden |&gt;ea) which eon- BUL 1.10. AGR. EXP. STATION OF SEBR VOL XXVII. ART. VII. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Soy licaiis iiml Cotcpma. Efmm two in four seeds. Tile stein usuallv has live or six lii-iiiu'lus. u|i&lt; &gt;n wliicli m Itunic tlie leaves ami chisleis at hmIs. All tliesee&lt;l matures at pi act ieallv the same time. Fig. 2. — A typical cowpea plant. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Soy livunx and Cowpcm%. 7 On the other hand, the cowpea has pods varying in hagth, from 5 t&lt;» 15 inches, according to variety and seasonal conditions. I'ods of varieties commonly grown in this State average about i&gt; inches in length. Under normal conditions the plants continue to bloom and set seed thniont the fall until frost. The most promising varieties suitable for growing in this Slate have I growth habit somewhat similar to that of the soy liean but are more prostrate and viny. The seeds of each crop differ greatly in size, shape, and color, according to variety. The (lowers are usually self-fertilized, and it is not at all necessary for insects to carry the jiollen. Figures 1 and '2 are typical soy l&gt;ean and cow l»ea plants, respectively. Being leguminous plants, they possess nodules with nitrogen - gathering bacteria on their routs just as do clover and alfalfa, when the proper bacteria are present in the soil. Soy l&gt;eans and cow|&gt;eas. in general, require nearly the same length of growing season as corn in eastern Nebraska, altho most varieties are somewhat later in maturing. Of the eight varieties of soy beans, which represent a wide variation in tjM tested during the past six years, the earliest ripeacd Septenil&gt;er IK on an average and the latest. October 11*. ADAPTATION AND USES FOR NEBRASKA CONDITIONS. I' uses to which these crops are [nit in various parts of the are: ill Food for man: ill i food for live stock, in the form in, hay, pasture, and silage: and (3) as soil restorers. In in. soy bean oil is being used in the manufacture of paint. r lubricants. The latter iudustrv promises to develop more ively. Experience indicates that at the present time in Nebraska their chief value is as a protein concentrate and as hay for cattle, hogs, and sheep, and possibly for soil improvement. They deserve more extensive trial as food for man. Eieatious are that cowpeas never will W a practical crop in ate. The yield of seed is relatively very low. and in forage tion cow|K'as are not sujierior to soy beUMk The lack of lit 1 v early varieties also limits the growing of COwpeM t" Nebraska. Soy Iteans are the most practicable of any of the annual legumes. They are one of the most drouth resistant crops we have. However, more experience is required to grow a crop of soy l&gt;eans successfnllv than is the cast- with our common Held crops. Varieties of so\ beans are available that are sufficiently early to mature anywhere in Nebraska except in the northwestern por- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Hoy Beans and Cotcpeas. 8 Eof the State. They may prove of considerable value in central southwestern Nebraska where drouth resistance is a very ini ant quality. Eeveral acres of soy beans must usually be planted where jack its and grasshoppers are numerous in order to harvest a crop make a satisfactory test, because these j&gt;ests are very fond of &gt;eans. and frequently destroy smaller areas. The soy bean has not proved to be a socially profitable crop, hut will at least approach oats, acre for acre, in feeding value. Fifteen bushels of seed to the acre, or \y 2 tons of cured hay, is an average crop in eastern Nebraska under normal conditions. The yield will be somewhat lower farther west because of more limited rainfall. Bui on the other hand, the assurance of securing a stand is greater than with leguminous crops having small seeds, siidi as alfalfa or sweel clover. If the surface soil is too dry for ger - mination, the seed may be plaited "2 or .'! inches deep, thus reach - ing moist soil. COMPOSITION AND FEEDING VALUE. I composition and feeding value, the seed of the soy bean very high and is much superior to that of the BOW pea. It is centrated protein feed, being in this res|&gt;ect practically to oil meal. Its fat content is also very high. The soy U-an niitains 3.7 times as much digestible protein and '.i.i times ch digestible fat as corn, pound for pound. In) pared with the commonly used protein concentrate, oil according to percentages given in Table 2, 1 ton, or 33 1-3 Is, of soy beans contains 5N2 pounds of digestible protein. I as much as is contained in 1,927 pounds of aid process oil A ton also contains 2!&gt;2 pounds of digestible fat, which is ch as is contained in 4.2X1! pounds of old process oil meal. Ethis Station, during the six years 1!M)9 to 1914, eight varie - if soy beans have averaged a yield of 14 bushels }&gt;er acre. At rate of production, the seed from an acre of soy beans con ; as much digestible protein as 872 pounds of oil meal, and uch digestible fat as 1.777 pounds of oil meal. Ie United States Department of Agriculture has estimated when used as a supplementary protein feed for live stock, shel of sov lM-ans is at least twice as valuable for feed as a 1 of corn." (See T'. S. Farmers' Bulletin 372, p. 25.) Data licking to make an accurate comparative estimate of the lg value of a carbohydrate concentrate, as corn, and a pro - oucentrate. as soy beans, under conditions where the protein I ant ■ 11 * * .1 • L-al 1 - •! &gt; f i.in as alfalfa </seg>
            <seg id="p009">I r. '— j* *o -r -r ci i &gt;• n x '. ai ««t* ri re i ri ?i ri o 4 I I I a I hi 2 c g ™ «. T T ="■ - '- t = •- =« . - « t = • - J 1 a • «5jflxixns-f;:rix:ii.;x °i ; «fidi-i-xxi.-r--txic;-i[; fc — M "I ~1 n ~l y 8^ a 'Z I C X ® ■* ■ m — »' &gt;n •" «5 w e in i» x : s&gt; ac : ■*' ?i ~i ci I r - . — ■* C ~ — O i c: l- I-' — C: '"r 3B ri^det 1 : I : : : j \'}\ \ : j \ • ; : '. \ •3.S : : : -i^li : f : &amp;- : Sc2 ■ — = _T3 f = ? b^i ' &gt;?j* 5. ' .5 &gt; 1. \ </seg>
            <seg id="p010">0 : " " i ■a i ■ i &lt; S « '-C c i- &gt;: r» »c t'- x h- gc r^ r- ot we so »r ■ 0! &gt;- — — ~ c; in c -h -h « — c s =' c o e = = (5 Si I i v. I 1 * 4 H I It! si 1 ]}. a a. 5 •S ~ s S * s I 2 I £ •5 /. d 1 2. X 41 Si i v s — « « '?; o c: -r = s; m r: x a m « a; i- 6 — ; -r d — -o fg «:' «' r^ — -^ c; -^ -■ c: c ° « — oi ?i i- cs "5 w cc o =■- 1» eej •« *&gt; I *gt&lt;pi*ao**a6e — i u-i ib ~ d i-' c r&gt;i ?i -« — i : : ; : : :^-i| i ::;:::: liSl£iilijrf-flii -jet ??SSr£-B.»:=|.cP. 1 ! I 1 — \ - I I i </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 clover, iiml sweet clover hay anil pasture. In a feeding ration in which alfalfa or clover is fed liberally, there is little to l&gt;e gained liy feeding; soy beans in addition. After a sufficient amount of protein has Ikhmi supplied to ha'ance the ration, any additional amount of protein fed replaces merely part (if the carbohydrate. When protein serves merely to replace a carbohydrate, the actual feeding value pound for pound is slightly lower than that of the carbohydrate. Tables 1 and - have been compiled from Henry's I'rcrix uml Fccil'uuj. IMS, to show the coinjMisitiou of soy beans and cowjieas as compared with other feeds. Henry is regarded as a standard authority on the coni]tosition of various feeds. YIELDS IN OTHER STATES. OHIO KXI'KItl.MKNT STATION. Dwiag the three years 1909*19] 1, 1(1 varieties of soy beans gave an average yield of 'S-&gt;X&gt;'2 bushels per acre, while the total weight of the crop harvested, including the entire plant, was :!.."&gt;L's ]M&gt;unds. 1 Miring the same period, three varieties of cowj)eas pro duced an average yield of ."i.S:'&gt; bushels of seed, and •_'.&lt;&gt;&lt;»!• pounds total weight of crop, including the entire plant. The average farm Ktion in Ohio is IS bushels of soy beans \h'V acre lOhio I till. In Ohio Circular 1:11'. !t2 cooperative tests during l!»12, in - g yields varying from § to ."ill bushels per acre, are reported. Kl average soy Itcau production at the Indiana Agricultural iinent Station during the V2 yean 1903-1913 was 1S.S s of seed ]ier acre, while the yield of hay was 'l.'.\ tons per Cooperative tests by farmers during 1906-1912 in northern la showed an average soy bean yield of lit bushels of wet] re. When cut for hay the yield was 1.5 tons. Cowjieascut ■d yielded 12.5 bushels, and cut for hay the yield was 1.7 er acre. Similar cooperative soy l&gt;ean seed and hay tests in ■rii Indiana yielded respectively 15.4 bushels of Bed and is of hay per acre. I hid. Hul. 172. 1 KANSAS KX1-KKIMKNT STATION. Elicaiis and cowpeas produced on an average during l'.Mi:! .45 and 11.55 bushels of seed per acre resjiectively. When hay. the yields were respectively 1.71 tons and 2.1!» tons . i Kans. Hul. 1 •_»(&gt;. i INDIANA KXI'KItl.MKNT STATION. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Soy livanx and Coir/iaix. ARKANSAS EXPERIMENT STATION. Kiii}; the years 1S!I!»1!H)1 eowpeas yielded 22.U bushels of i- acre. When cut for liav, the yield was 1.5 tons. (Ark. ) KENTUCKY EXPERIMENT STATION. I' average yield of soy beans for three years. l!t()!»-l!ll 1, in a Uniting test was 10.fi bushels. It is mentioned that these are much lower than should have been expected had more iowii concerning the culture of this crop. Frequeut reports wived at the Kentucky Agricultural Exjierimeut Station irmers who produced 20 to 80 bushels of soy lM-ans j»er acre. VARIETIES TESTED AT THE NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION. Nine varieties were tested in unduplicated plats, one-tenth acre in size, during each of two years, 190:5 and IMA. The rows were 32 inches apart and cultivated. The results are given in Table 3. that variation from vear to abu : .—A I rcriK/r yield of nin&lt; \ rhraxku tJxprrinir &lt;■ ranc\ nt Stat (&lt;■« of m on. 190.' iti/ beans tm i ■■/ DO',. nt Variety Date planted Date ripe Xo. days required to mature Yield of beans per Early Yellow American Coffee Herry Karly Black Wisconsin Black Medium Early Yellow Medium Early Brown Medium Early Black Medium Green May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 May 30 Sept. 20 Sept. 20 Sept. 20 Sept . 20 Sept. a Sept. 23 Sept. 23 Sept. a Oct. 4 112 112 112 112 115 US 115 1 ir&gt; 124 12.44 Average all varieties §ther tt-st injj was discontinued ■ sov lwans rapnmtfaag ■ rataa I fi-oin Mr. a V. Piper of the 1 Slates Department of Agriei fni- six yeai-s, l!t(t!t-l!H4. and the ntil 190! r wide i 9 when eight varie- range of type were of Plant Industry, These have been B given in detail for ulturv. data art </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 During (lie first three years, the l&gt;eaus were tested in single culti - vated rows 42 inches apart, and duplicated three times, with a few exceptions as indicated in the tables. During the last three years they have been grown in 4-row plats approximately one-fourteenth and one-seventeenth acre in size, according to space between rows. The entire series has been duplicated four times. They were tested iu rows both 28 inches and 35 inches apart — the same amount of seed being sown per row regardless of the distance between rows. This makes the equiva - lent of two rates of planting — each rate being duplicated. In the years 1969-1911 they were planted with a 1-row garden drill. In 1912 and 1913 a BmpeHar drain Drill was used with all rls closed except those which would properly space the rows. 1914 they were planted with an edge-drop corn planter. Each year the seeder was so adjusted as to space the seed about 2 inches apart in the row. Tn rows 35 inches apart, this required approximately 30 pounds per acre with varieties having small seed and 40 pounds with varieties having larger seed. kin the variety and rate planting tests, the seed has been in - ulated each year with artificial culture furnished by the United ates Department of Agriculture. The eight varieties from the Government included in these total are as follows: Habaro. S. P. I. No. 20,405: Shingto, 8, P. I. No. 21,079; Chernie, B. P. I. No. 18.227; Haberlandt, B. P. I. No. 17,271; Nuttall, S. P. I. No. 17,253; Cloud, S. P. I. No. 16,790; Amherst, 8. P. I. No. 17.27.-.: and Merer, S. P. I. No. 17,582. OnrpaM and an additional variety of soy lteans. the Early Yellow, were tested in 1913 and 1914. Tablk 4. — Variety Irxt of my beaux. 1909. Variety Date planted Date ripe No day* required to mature No of luplica- tions Yield »f beans per acre (b— hull) Haberlandt Nuttall Cloud June -i June 3 June 3 June I June 3 June 3 June :i June 3 Sept. 16 Sept. 24 Sept 29 Sept. 28 Sept. 29 Oct. I Oct. 14 Oet 14 l()t&gt; 114 119 us 119 l:&gt;.-&gt; 134 134 •_&gt; I 2 I 4 4 I 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 i; \ il 10 11 v 3 :~ The varieties tested during 1909-1914. All but the Early Yellow soy bean and the cowpeas were tested six years Reading from left to right, upper row: Cowpeas— 1, New Era; 2, Whippoor - will. Soy Beans — 3, Meyer; 4, Araherst; 5, Cloud. Lower row 6 -Nuttall; 7, Haberlandt; 8, Chernie; 9, Shingto; 10, Habaro; 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">*«.&lt;/ Beans and Co ii/hiix. 15 Table 5. — Vt rietp text of .f. iij biiinx. 1919. Variety DUb planted Date ripe No. ifatyi required to mature No. of duplica- tions Yield of beans per m Huharo Shingto Chernie Haberlandt Nuttall Cloud Amherst Meyer May 25 May 28 May 2o May 25 May 25 May 25' May 25, May 25 Sept. 17 Sept. 2A Sept. 24 Sept. 2!t Sept . M) Oct. 5 Oct. I Oct. § 115 121 122 127 12s 133 133 136 :{ :{ :s :{ I :{ 'ABLE ti. — lie U ■xt Of xi) bill us. '9 I. Variety Date planted Date ripe N*o. days required to mat lire No. or duplica- tions Yield of beans per acre (Itushclsi Haberlandt Nuttall May 25 May 25 May 2f) May 25 May 25 May 25 May 25 May 25 Sept. 20 Sept . :{0 Sept :i0 Sept. 38 s&lt;-pt. :m Oct. ti Oct. 7 ( M . 7 lis 128 12s 126 12s 134 135 135 I 3 a :! :&lt;, 3 :{ :! ■&gt;■&gt; j j 'ABLE 7. — ne .'/ ea ill *&lt;i Itraits. Variety Date planted Date ripe No days required to mature No of duplica- tions Yield of bean- |mt acre Average of 2 rates (buaheb&gt;) Habaro .... Shinto Chernie Haberlandt Nut tall May 21 May 21 Mav _'l May 21 Miy 21 May 21 May 21 May 21 Sept. l(i Sept. M Sept. l»i Oet. o Oct. ") ( M . •') Oct. ") Oct. :&gt; us 118 US i:i7 \M 137 i:i7 137 i 4 I i 1 4 t 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 New Era June 2 Sept. 14 KM 4 2.00 Whippoorwill* | June 2 4 0 4 0 *The Whippoorwill variety set practically no sped pods. New Era . May 20 Sept. 15 US 4 4.t&gt; Whippoorwill' | May 201 | | 4 [ 0 •The Whippoorwill cow)&gt;eax produced no seed pods. 'ahle 8. — ariety text of top bill int. Variety Date plante&lt;l Date ripe No. days required to mature No. of duplica- tions Yield of beans per acre. Average of 2 rates i bushels) C'hernie Meyer June 2 June 2 June 2 June 2 June 2 June 2 June 2 June I June 3 Sept. 11 Sept. 20 Sept. 13 Sept. 2.5 Sept. 29 Ot 11 Oct. 11 Oct. 11 Sept. 7 101 110 103 116 119 131 131 131 M t 4 4 i 4 1 4 I 4 2.63 5.09 6.60 Cowpemt. 'AlfLE !). riety t ■at a xo conn. ). Date planted Date ripe No days No. of required duplica- to mature tions Yield of beans [xt acre. Average of 2 rater (bushels i Variety May 20 May 20 May 30 May 20 May 20 May 20 Mav 20 May 20 May 20 Sept. IS Sept ■ Sept. 28 Oct I Oct. I Oct. 10 Oct. 10 Oct 17 Sept. 12 IIS 131 1*1 138 13K 143 143 150 115 4 t 4 4 I 4 t 4 4 16.78 15.78 16.54 21.49 Co* r/JCUH. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Tahi.e 10. — Showing six ycurx' mirage performative of eight soy bean nuii-ticx. 1909-191 J h lu 1912 and 1!)13 both soy beauts and cowpeas were drilled in rows 8 inches apart, for hay and seed. Under these conditions the crop could not be cultivated and was overcome by weeds each year. This has not proved a practical way for planting in eastern Nebraska, altho it might prove satisfactory in the western part of the Slate where weeds are not so troublesome because of lower rainfall. Several duplicate plats were planted in 1912 and 1914 in rows 28 inches apart which were cultivated and harvested for hay, the results from which are given in Table 12. Judging from the general appearance of the plant, the Cloud variety would make a better quality of hay than the other varieties tented. Variety Average date planted Average date ripe Average no. days required to mature Total no . phil- averaged Yield of beans per acre (bushels) Chernie Haborlandt Nuttall Cloud Amherst Meyer May 28 May 25 May 25 May 35 May 25 May 28 May 25 May 28 Sept. 16 Sept. 23 Sept. 23 Sept. 30 Oct 1 Oct. 7 Oct. 9 Oct. 10 114 121 121 12S 129 135 137 138 20 a 20 23 22 22 22 ■&gt;•&gt; 13.62 13.67 13.69 15.56 14.21 13.39 15.87 14.75 Taui.k 11. — Siimmanj nf variety tests with soy h 1909-191',. •&lt;in* 'or six y &lt;&lt;t rx. Air-dry yieli i per icro — bi ushels. 1909 1910 1911 1912 1913 1914 6-year average Average | 10. 2S Bus. 20 .30 20.00 20.10 19.70 24.30 22.30 29.90 26.10 22.84 Bun. 15.26 15.81 14.88 22.71 22.14 18.79 21.96 21 .03 Bus 12.90 12!t.-&gt; 12.85 11.95 9.39 8.69 8.93 9.70 10.92 But. 7.82 8.12 9.38 5.95 6.04 3.85 2.62 5.09 But. 16.78 15.78 lti..-&gt;4 21.49 16.29 14.29 17.39 16.24 Bus 13.62 13.67 13.69 15.56 14.21 13.39 15.87 14.75 19.07 6.11 16.85 14.35 IAN D CO PEA R HAY </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 excellent forage for cattle. hogs, and sheep. Its feediag value is practically aqwU to alfalfa ami clover. Befog less productive, however, and more difticull to grow when cultivation is necessary to keep down weeds, they are not so protitable as either alfalfa or clover in those parti of the State where the latter two thrive. Three tons of alfalfa hay per acre were produced at the Ne Inaska Agricultural Experiment Station in those years when s&lt;&gt;\ beans and cowpeas yielded not quite 1 V2 t&lt;&gt;lls °f ' l!l . v - '" ln ' s »■&lt;•"'■ parisun t lit* alfalfa tield was several years old. and the soy BMM and cow]&gt;eas were planted in cnttirated rows 2S inches apart. I cause of their forage value these crops seed seldom be con d a total failure. Their hay value is very iin|«n-l;ml \vl&gt; &lt;\ te a variety is planted to mature satisfactorily, or if for any reason the seed yield promises to 1k&gt; very small, as the field hen lx' harvested for hay. SOY BEANS AND COWPEAS FOR SILAGE. I some States both soy beans and camjptm are r&lt; commended lage as a mixture with corn. I'sed alone they are not suit 'or silage. They may be planted: (1) As a mixture in the row with corn; 1 1* 1 in rows In'twcen widely spaced corn as is common in the South ; or (S) the beans or peas and the inav be grown in separate fields and mixed as they are placed ! si'lo. I the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, corn yields average about cS tons of silage jkt acre. Those varieties of ■ans and cowpeas making the maximum amount of vegetative h yield at the rate of about (&gt; tons of silage, or three-fourths ich as corn. As a general farm practice we consider it far practicable in this State to make silage of corn alone and to alfalfa hay for the protein needed to balance the ration. In 1!I14 soy beaus of the Cloud variety were planted in the rows of corn for mixed silage. The results follow : Alll.E '2. — Kit hi ma ry of hail !/ic&gt; 'dx in I 'UJ and 1911,. Crop Yield of cured hay per acre Yield of eared haj per acre Whippoorwill amwjmm Amherst soy beans Whippoorwill row-peas. . . Pounds 2,729 2,866 2,&gt;KX) Tons 1.37 1.4:i 1.4.5 The liiiv from either i»f these crops whea properly &lt;-m rwl inakt-s </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 xihtf/t'. /.*'/ '/. ' Yield |&gt;cr acre of Per cent water when harvested September .") Yield per acre moist ure free Cri&gt;l) tnm siiaxi' substance Tons '.I.S4 Per cr.nt E Corn alone 75.4 747 Corn ami sov beMM mixed We were unsuccessful in Kcariag a satisfactory distribution l»v mixing the ('Din ami beans in the planter box. The In-ans lend to work tn the bottoa and Iced mil faster tlian the com. In the above trial, the corn was drilled 14 indies apart in the row, and the rows were then fjeM over ■gala with tile planter, drilling the lieans altonl (i inches apart. kSonie fanners have reported growing cowpeas and corn to ler in the row for silage and found difticnltv in harvesting the us jiroperlv with the corn harvester. This method of culture ol recommended. PLATIVE YIELDS OF SOY BEANS AND PRINCIPAL GRAIN CROPS AT NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION. Moisture conditions at the Kxperinient Station have I wen coin parativelv unfavni aide for corn and Buy l&gt;caus during the past six veais in which these coiiipai isons are made. This is shown by the faci that corn has produced ll-i Imsl'cls |kt acre less at the Station during the past six veais than during the previous seven vears. Since sov Iteans occupv the same part of the growing season as corn, the.vield from them mav be assumed to have beea reduced in s iinewhat the same inaiiiier. Win at and oats have yielded practi - cally the same during the last six years as during the preceding In TaMe 14 the grain yields are re|M&gt;rted from our standard. beat adapted va:ietiis. Since the Ilalierlandt variety of soy beam seems West adapted to conditions at the Experiment Station, the yield of this variety makes a better comparison with the other grains than does the average yield from the eight varieties. In Table 1"&gt; theae crop yields are calculated in terms of available nutrients. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 0of Bran.* ami Cowptmt. B14. — Summary showing coini&gt;arativc fUUt of corn, wheat. t8, and soy beans at \ehnixka Experiment Station for the tt six nears. 190!U!&gt;l&gt;,. may pay to plow under an entire crop. In this way an amount of nitrogen will be added to the soil equivalent to that of an equal quantity of clover. According to Dr. Cyril G. Hopkins of the Illinois Agricultural Experiment Station (in Soil Fertility and Permanent Aijrirulture) the stubble and roots of a ton of air-dry soy bean forage contain only about 6 pounds of nitrogen while the stubble and roots of a ton of air-dry clover hay contaiu L'O pounds of nitrogen. Accordingly an average yield of red clover cut for hay in eastern Nebraska will leave four times as much nitrogen in its roots and stuhble as an acre of soy beans cut for seed. Clover lias probably about the same superiority over cowpeas. It has sometimes been suggested that these crops be used as gpm manure crops to be planted in the stubble after the wheat or oats harvest and plowed under late in the fall. It has lteen our experience that, in Nebraska, success with this practice is very uncertain because of limited rainfall. Only a small total growth is made so late in the year, and the iuereased fertility would usually scarcely repay the cost of seed and labor. Furthermore, to grow such a catch crop for green manuring uses soil moisture at the expense of the following year's crop, as much of this moisture might otherwise l»e stored in the soil for the next crop. In Ne - braska where moisture is often the limiting factor in crop produc - tion, the situation is different from that in the more humid States to the east ami southeast, where catch crops are profitably used Yield per acn Crop Avcrai 6y&lt; K e for MM 1909 1910 1911 1912 1913 1914 But.l But. But. Bu». But. But. But. Lb». Hogue's Yellow Dent Turkey Red wheat . . . Kherson oats Average of 8 soy bean Haberlandt soy beans 41 27 67 m 4S 42 43 51 38 4S 9 37 I 50 m 53 34 M 42 36.5 49.5 2,352 2,16(] 9 11.5 23 20 19 23 11 12 6 17 21.5 14 16 M 96( SOY BEANS AND COWPEAS AS SO IL IMPROVERS. For the purpose of increasing the soil I crops is much inferior to clover or alfalfa Fertility, aimer of thw« . On verv poor soil i </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 • • ! 1||3 E" 1 - iSsqisxo cxncioOH H &gt; o s 1 1 &amp; 1 j 3 'I * JS .5 I c . O — r 55 p."c "5 '•: x M in X c l^ r*** l* L-t 5fli&gt; ■- — l- /. B _B r a 3 ■ Q S O tt --C f N ll 5 "-« &lt;N « S5 t-; e « oe OJ m «a 5 n t&gt; t» N e: |iCtl&gt;N- a 1 II tils 'S "S ". '- " n . t as a ; i I S I 1 ! I I i 1 1 s .= l|1 s^ a? 3 I 3 ■» s = t =. .S 2 .37 • N . -I- c IN E 0 • ■ : : I i i ; i I [ • Ml i ilfli 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Ill |Mirli«nis of I lu- Slide where the earlier varieties mature in time, soy Ih'.mis ami rwwpeaH may sometimes Ik' followed to good advantage with winter wheai. These crops Wave the gromd in such a loose and ojieii comlition that a satisfactory seed bed for wheat can often be secured by simply disking rather than by plow - ing the land. It is probable, however, that in ordinary farm practice it mav not always be possible io char the land in time for wheat, as abnormal conditions may cai.se the crop to ripen late or rains may delay removing it from the land. Any spring Kl farm trap may successfully follow these legumes. I'tider ka conditions either soy l&lt; ans oi- cowpeaa should be grown ith the expectation thai they will consume the entire sea - t will, therefore. U' necessary to grow them in place of. tit sm in addition to. some other crop in any one season. VARIETIES AND SEED. For sotillieaMci n Nebiaska we consider the Ualierlandt va - riety U'st. For the northern, rent ml, and western portions of the Stale, the llaba'.o. Cheinie. Hhingio. and KaHy Yellow are most writable. It is prol a!ile that of these early va'-ieti&lt;s Karly Yellow i Ito San i is the only nne commercially available. Seed houses may not handle the 1 1 si' ■«•] lainli variety, in which case the .Medium Ycilow may be used as a substitute. This is a medium early com - mercial variety hut a irinV late for all except the southeastern counties in ihis Stale. The:e would doubtless be an opportunity for a few farmers in the Stale to Riuw seed of well -adapted varie - liis lo supply the home Hale. !■'( d ;si;ally sells for from 92.541 In s:',.r&gt;ll per in shel. Bthe cow pea varieties, the New Kra seems lo Im- one of the radical lo grow in this Siaie. Beed of both soy beans and cowpeas usually deterioiaus in };er - minative power when mole than one or twoyeaisold. INOCULATION. Hoy beans and cowpeas, being leguminous plants, are more productive when nodules develop upon the roots and are less draining apoa the nitrogea content of the soil. These nodules are merely the home of iiinuineiable uitrogen -gathering bacteria or geraw, which lake Ihis element directly from the air. These nodule-forming bacteria are found on no Held crop plants except lliose betonging to the legume family. The soy bean possesses its own particular kind of Iricteri'i "ind ciunot l&gt;e inocul'ittHl with </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 |MM from any oilier species. On the oilier hand, soy bean bac - teria will inoculate no oilier plant. The i-owjH-a likewise jMHwesses its o« ii [K-fiiliar bacteria. Ei soils where nodules fail to develop, inoculation may be ed by scattering MOO or 400 pounds of soil per acre frimi some upon which the same crop has previously been pMn. Since g sunlight is injurious to tlie liacteria, this soil should ta - rred on a cool, cloudy day ami be harrowed in immediately. A common, lint more uncertain, method of inoculation is to apply to the seed a prepared culture made for the particular crop. Inoculating cultures may usually be secured free of charge from the Tinted States Department of Agriculture. Washington. I). ('.. upon request, liy agreeing to leave a portion of the tield untreated and reporting results. Cultures may also he purchased from manufacturers and seed dealers. .Methods for inoculating these crops are the same as have often Ikhmi described for alfalfa. I'nless the soil is known bj experience to contain the necessary liacteria, it is a wise plan to inoculate before Heeding. A ntiiiiiter of fanners in the Stale have reported benelicial effects from in oculating tile seed, altho the majority have observed no benefit. The soils at the Nebraska Agricultural V,x peri men t Station ap - pear to possess the soy U-an bacteria, as inoculation by both the culture and the soil method failed to increase the yield materially, as is shown in the following table: iug to seasonal conditions. May 15 to May 30 may Ik- considered as the U-st range of planting dates for Nebraska. Karlier planting will usually not hasten maturity, and may result in a poor stand. 1 1 is iniiMii'tant that the irround be thorolv warm at idaiitiu (r time T.viii.k Hi. — Hffrrt of innniht ti ikj sot/ beaux. Yield per I icre Crop Size of plat No. of duplica- tions Soil Culture inocula- inocula- ted ted No inordla- 1 ion 1-6 1-10 Bus. But. 15.7 16.4 3.8 i :&gt; But. PAmherst soy hems. Ainlicrsl &gt;ov boMM. 2 ■ &gt; Avoranc for 2 years &lt;).S 10.4 '.,:, TIME, RATE. AND M [ANNER OF PLANTING. BIk'.iiis and GOWptM sli&lt;i Uniting lime. Varyiag ■ •U be planted immediately after miewliai in different vt-ars accord- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 The seed bed should l&gt;e prepared the same as for corn. Our experience at the Exi&gt;eriineiit Station has been onl.v with plowing and surface planting. This is I he method also rommoulv cm ployed in other States. There are a few advocates of listing. In western Nebraska listing in probably a good practice, but the method has not been sufficiently tried for general reeomnienda- I During the last three years of the variety test at this Station. 12-1914, each variety was planted in plats witli rows 28 and ■iH •lies apart. With both spacing, the seeds were drop|&gt;ed ;i]p Pig. 4. — A typical field of soy beans planted in rows 35 inches apart and cultivated. proximately 2 inches apart in the row. This required about 40 pounds of seed per acre with the large seeded varieties and 30 pounds with the small seeded varieties in rows 35 inches apart. During the three years, the average yield of the four earliest va - rieties, with September 23 as an average ripening date, was 1 bushel more per acre when the rows were 28 inches apart; while the four latest maturing varieties, ripening on an average October 7, yielded 1 bushel less when the rows were 28 inches apart. The later varieties made the largest vegetative growth and fully oc - riiiiipd thp ivrAnnil of fh*» thinner rat** i»f i&gt;l*uitiiiu while this was </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Soy Hcmtx and Cowpeas. 25 not true of the smaller, earlier varieties. The results of this test are given in Table 17. Tablk 17. — Shoving the effect of distance between rotes and ratr of planting my beans. seed. The drill may be easily adjusted if this does not give the proper spacing. A corn planter fitted with bean plates may also be used quite successfully. Plates regularly accompanying corn planters can usually be adjusted or altered so as to space the seed properly. The machine to be used should be tested and adjusted in advance so as to space the seed between 2 and 3 inches apart. Pie rows should not be closer than 28 inches because of increasing e difficulty of cultivation. Where seed is drilled from every drill spout in rows 7 inches apart for forage or green manuring, 6 pecks per acre should be used. It must be rememlM'i-ed that weeds are likely to l&gt;ecoine bad [1 llllflllll\tll " 1 IltrHIo. 1912 1 1913 1914 Average Variety Diat ,nce b&lt; it ween rows S« in. 2Sin. K in. 2Xin. 35 in. 28 in. 35 in. 28 i.. But. Habaro 12:50 Shinuto I3J0 Chernie 14. 25 Haberlandt 11.45 Nuttall 10.15 Cloud 7 'JO Amherst 10.05 Meyer 11.00 Bui 13.50 12.40 11.25 12.45 8.60 9.45 7.80 8.40 Bus. 7.25 7.58 7.67 5.54 sja 3.30 2.81 5.70 Bui. 8.39 8.66 10.23 6.37 till 4.00 2.43 4.48 But. 15.72 14.42 14.25 21.82 IS 42 15.83 17.18 16.15 Bui. 17.85 17.12 18.84 21.15 14.17 12.7.5 17.61 16.32 Bus. 11.76 11.83 12.06 12.94 11.52 9.01 10.01 10.95 ss 12.73 13.44 13.32 9.63 8.73 9.28 9 73 Average all varieties. 11.33 1048 5.73 6.33 16.72 16.98 11.26 11.26 Bxperience at other A grim believe that cowpeas slio soy beans in rows 35 inche n ordinary grain drill, wil ■r width between the rows e different types of force 1 that in forcing out the set ves at different speeds. 1 i and does good work. Tl and set between '.» and 12 i iltural Experiment Stations leads mid be planted somewhat thinner ?s apart. th part of the feeds closed to give , is the best machine for planting, feed in drills, one kind has a disk imI for various rates of planting it rbis type does not crack the seed tie oats side of the drill should be Decks per acre, according to size of </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 It is recommended llial the laid be disked ;uid harrowed just prior to settling in order to check the weed growth as nnich as possible. A weeder may be run over the fraud just before the Iteans come li|&gt; and agaia before the lieans are larjfe eaangh to elil - livale. The weeder should lie used only during the warmer ]&gt;or - linii of the day. as the plant* are inclined to lie brittle and lireak in the morning. Three or four cultivations are reqaited. It has been mil- exjierience that ordinarily at lc;;st one boring alonjr the Fig. 5. — Cowpeas ready to harvest K leu the plants are small will We necesxary. One man can mt an acre a dav. The labor connected with growing the crop makes it a rather I r substitute for oats so far as the management of farm labor is concerned. If soy iN-ans were grows extensively, the acreage of corn would necessarily he reduced, since both require cultivation at the same time. HARVESTING. Sov beam and eewpaan may he harvested with a mower or a specially made bean harvester. We have also found it practicable io harvest sov beans for seed with a binder Some varieties are </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Iiiii short iinil others too vinv to harvest in this manner. In cast - it mower is Mai, it is well to have a side delivery attachment in order that the horses will not need to tramp on the cut swath of Ix-ans. This trapping is likely In shatter many of the beans. In general, the proper stage to cut soy lieans for seed is when the pods have tilled brown or blackish according to variety, and alxiut two-thirds of the leaves have fallen. During this stage of development, they ramfre close attention, because if cutting is delayed, considerable loss of seed will lie sustained from shatter Fig. (&gt;.-— Soy beans ready to harvest for seed ing. This is especially true in case of frost. If the U-ans are per - mitted to stand until thoi-oly ripe, much loss of seed may be ex ported from this source. Inexperienced growers are likely to sutler serious loss from shattering of the seed thru impro|&gt;er handling. After curing in the windrow for a day or two, the lieans should be placed in shocks. When thoroly cured it is best to thresh them immediately. In case this cannot be done, they should be slacked to avoid unnecessary exposure and consequent shattering in the shuck. Soy beans, when stacked, should be covered with canvas </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Soy liiii us ami Cittrprma. Cowpeas differ greatly from soy Ik'siiis in their manner of ripening seed. Under normal conditions they continue to bloom and set pods thruout the fall until frost. As a grain crop, they should be harvested when, in the judgment of the grower, the maximum amount of seed is ripe. B»r hay the crop should be- harvested when the pods are well id. At this stage most of the leaves arc still on, and the have not become coarse and woody. After curing in the i a day or two, they may be raked and cocked. Cowpeas dry slowly than soy beans. It may take a week or 10 days of drying weather before either crop can be stacked. This is a is handicap. THRESHING AND STORING. These crops may lie threshed with an ordinary threshing ma - chine by reducing the sjieed of the cylinder and replacing all or part of the concaves by blank concaves. The best adjustment of the thresher is by the use of sj&gt;ecial pulleys which reduce the speed of the cylinder without reducing that of ilie rest of the working parts of the machine. Many of the seeds are likely to be broken in threshing, but this does not reduce their feeding vahie. Bl l&gt;eans or peas should lie watched carefully after threshing d heating and molding. When thoroly dry. there is no such . Unless very dry it may Im- necessary to spread them out thin for a time. FARMERS' TESTS WITH SOY BEANS. E-ing the years 1!)12, 1913, and 1!U4 the Experiment Station d a number of farmers with soy l&gt;ean seed, together with ions relative to planting, cultivating, and harvesting the In all cases the soy l&gt;eans were planted in rows and culti- The farmers either were supplied with both inoculated inoculated seed for comparison, or were furnished inotulat - ture from the United States Department of Agriculture. ■ 1!»12 three farmers in southeastern Nebraska tested Am - soy l&gt;eans for seed with rather encouraging results. Their were respectively 18, 20, and 20 bushels j&gt;er acre. From &gt; three acres were grown by each man. TESTS IN 1913. Ten rejxirts were received from farmers growing soy iN-ans in TESTS IN 1912. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">dog Km us mid t'otepeaa. 29 men harvested their crop for seed, with yields of B, 8, aud 15 ImslielB, res[K'&lt;:tively. Owing to the extreme drouth, and in some instances to inex]&gt;erience either in planting or harvesting, the others did not thresh their crap. The beans were pastured in two cases with satisfactory results. Two cooperators cut their crop for hay. which yielded at the rate of iy 2 tons per acre, and re - ported thai the stock to which it was fed — milch cows and sheep Bd it fully as well as choice alfalfa hay. It should be noted n these cases the crops were not promising for seed on ac - either of drouth or danger from frost. Six of these fanners found it necessary to hoe the soy heanR at least once. Cultivation proved more ililticult and weeds harder to subdue than in the case of corn planted with a planter. There was no noticeable superiority in development due to the use of inoculation culture in eight of tlrese ten lesls. Four of these farmers intended planting soy lieans again the following year, and only one reported having seed for sale. Opin - ion as to the utility of ihis crop was quite evenly divided, but in a comparative way the soy l»ean was ranked as inferior to our siandanl crops in nearly all cases. TESTS IN 1914 K etna farmers reported results of their trials with MJ The areas plated were in most cases from 1 to .1 acres in aud the yield was from :i to 30 bushels per acre. The • The average yield of seven farmers reporting the yield wa» 14 bushels per acre. ata may be summarized as in the follow! g tablt Taki.e 18. — Farmers' tests irith so i bran*. I'.fl',.' Question No. of replies yes No. of replies no Doubtful Were they harder to cultivate than corn? Was it harder to keep weeds down? Do they need hoeinK? Are they a practical crop? Will you grow them again?. Did inoculation prove favorable? Does this crop mature? Have you seed to sell? Does yield compare favorably with other crops'. Do they ripen in time to follow with winter wheat? 10 id I l 4 I I 1 I I 1 1 1 I ti ti 1 s ti ■1 1 1 T </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 The relatively small iiuiiiImt of replies Ul the qaulioaa as shown in the talile is due either to the fact that many of the co - operator! replied only to a part (»f the mhUmi asked, or their crops were discar&lt;leil owing in poor stands or damage. Bides lading tliis crop harder to handle than most of our rops. and less profitable, ineiitiou ni made of damage ng from jack rabbits, drouth, hail. wind. rain, frost, and ing. B considering the reports for 1913 it must lie borne in mind hat season was an unusually dry one in southeastern Ne - i. where most of these trials were made, and that for this i less trouble was caused by the growth of weeds than would case in years of average rainfall. K&lt;en as a whole, these icpoits from our cooperato:s are un - ble to soy beam as a general unrpoae ciop in Nebraska, but mid not underestinia'e the tact that inexperience in grow - s crop is an important advci se factor. SUMMARY. t'l'lic climatic adaptatitm of soy art— to Nebraska condi - n a whole is much belter than tliat of cowpoaa. Varietfe* x' had which will matuie Icfoie fn st in all pans of the except perhaps in the northwest. (&gt;■ the other hand. COW - hoiilil. at least for the presi nt. Ik- contined to llic southern iiilhrastein portions of this Stale. BSoy beans do not show the effect* of drouth as quickly as and reductions in yield due to dr&gt;uth are relatively less d. However, soy btans aie by no means entirely drouth int. and the amount and distribution of rainfall are im - ii cmtrolltag factors. :!. Neither soy ln-ans nor eowpeaa are gfwwa extensively in Nebraska. They have been tried in an expt'riiuental way for 1") years, but have nowhere come into common use. tin those States where these crops have come into favor with s. they are used for grata, hay. silage, pasture, and soil im - nent. In Nebraska their chief value is, doubtless, as a grata o provide a proiein concentrate for live slock. The low yields of cowpeas make them impractical, therefore, in this Soy heaaa merit more extensive trial as human food. •"&gt;. Inder Nebraska conditions, alfalfa and led clover yield more forage with lower labor cost and are much more effective in soil improvement than are cow pt as or soy beans. It must be re ntcinltet'ed however that evcelit in* r in vallevs and olherw ise -..JUI, 111.11. ■ All (Mill,. Ill &gt;.IMt_&gt;. .HIM 'MIIIOIIM </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 favored locations, red clover is satisfactory only in tin- eastern third, and alfalfa only in the eastern two-thirds, of the State. li. Ordinarily, cowpeaa and soy beans should be planted in rows from ."'(I to :&gt;."&gt; inches apart with the seed spaced from 2 to •"&gt; inches in the row. Planted in this manner, at least three eultiva lions and usually one baefag are necessary to keep down the BThe average yield of soy beans daring eight years at the ska Agricultural Kxperiuient Station has been 14. S bushels re. In feeding value per acre this is less than was obtained pats, and the cost of production was higher. v Since soy bean grain must be used for feed in the same man ner as oil meal and is eapal in value as a concentrate, the cost of the oil meal may Ik- used as a standard to measure the acre value of soy beans. It must be remembered, however, that the protein nci'dexl to accompany corn aud balance the ration can usually l&gt;e much more cheaply supplied in the form of alfalfa hay and alfalfa pasture, the latter being especially good for hogs. E Since soy beans require cultivation in a manner similar to and at about the same time, they should be compared with in jMiint of practical utility. The soy bean is one of those which look promising and inviting but which nevertheless &lt;&gt;t quite sufficiently meritorious to take a place among oar ard crops under existing conditions. </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>