<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A House for the Farm Poultry Flock</title>
               <date value="1919-01">1919-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Extension Bulletin 53 January, 1919 A House for the Farm Poultry Flock F. E. Mussehl and H. M. Wells THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE LINCOLN U. S. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE COOPERATING </seg>
            <seg id="p002">University of Nebraska College of Agriculture THE EXTENSION SERVICE THE GOVERNING BOARD (The Regents of the University) Honorable E. P. Brown, President, Davey Honorable J. E. Miller, Vice President, Lincoln Honorable Frank L. Haller, Omaha Honorable Victor G. Lyford, Falls City Honorable Philip L. Hall, Lincoln Honorable Harry D. Landis, Seward THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor E. A. BURNETT, D. Sc, Dean, College of Agriculture; Director, Erpc vieni Station J. S. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF E. A. Burnett, D. Sc, Acting Director R. E. Holland, B. Sc, County Agent Leader Lew T. Skinner, B. Sc, Secretary Mrs. Emma Reed Davisson, Home Demount rat, on Leaner C. A. Lewis, B. Sc, Agricultural Editor C. W. Watson, A. M., Junior Extension Leader THE EXTENSION COUNCIL E. A. Burnett, D. Sc, Dean Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry H. C. Filley, A. M Rural Economics *L. W. Chase, M.E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering Alice M. Loomis, A. M., Home Economics W. W. Burr. B. Sc, Agronomy R. F. Howard, A. M. Horticulture H. J. Gramlich, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry L. Van Es, M. D., V. S., G. A. Loveland, A. M Meteorology E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Plant Pathology Animal Pathology and Hygiene J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology F. E. Mussehl, B. Sc Poultry Husbandry J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry H. E. Bradford, A. M. Principal, School of Agriculture •Absent on leave, </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A HOUSE FOR THE FARM POULTRY FLOCK F. E. Mussehl and H. M Wells One of the important essentials for high egg production in the poultry flock is that the hens be kept comfortable. To maintain a "high morale" in the poultry flock, especially in the winter months, is, therefore, the special function of the poultry house. From the hens' standpoint, the house that is dry, wind - proof, light, bright and clean is most satisfactory. The importance of having the poultry house dry at all times is emphasized when it is noted that the respiratory system of the bird consists not alone of lungs and windpipe but also of a rather complicated system of air sacs which reach into every part of the body cavity. The hen is not equipped with sweat glands as are other farm animals, but equalizes its body temperature and purifies the blood by a movement of air thru these air sacs as well as thru the lungs. It is extremely difficult for birds to be comfortable in a damp poultry house, — dryness is the first essential. To insure absolute dryness the poultry house should be located on porous, well-drained soil on a slope, preferably to the south or southeast. The ventilation system and the floor should be planned with an appreciation of the importance of dryness in making hens comfortable. THE POULTRY HOUSE FLOOR A concrete floor is especially practical for a permanent poultry house. If a concrete floor is used the precaution which needs to be taken is that plenty of coarse crushed rock or cind - ers are used as filler so that the capillary soil moisture is pre - vented from coming up thru the floor. An 8 or 10-inch layer of coarse crushed rock or cinders is usually enough to break up capillarity. Next should come a coarse coat of concrete about 3 inches thick and finally a finishing coat of rich cement mixture (three parts of sand and one part cement) about 2 inches thick. The concrete floor is not cold if it is kept covered with 10 or 12 inches of straw or cut up corn fodder. DRYNESS IS THE FIRST ESSENTIAL </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Extension Service 4 n ■ I ji I i J 5 ! !! \ i; ■! [i :i I i! ■I -it 1 ii * ii | i 1 r i' ~- ii II - 5 : 5 —^_ 4 tt i: a f- N— * i! t " v v^ I I I I I j Will "i 9~ t — j I i ( 1 I, i s 1 :: ! I'il I -.•-.« — I i -»•/. '*/• I- &gt;* -»A </seg>
            <seg id="p005">A Farm Poultry House 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Extension Service THE VENTILATION SYSTEM Chickens need more fresh air per thousand pounds of live weight than any other common farm animal. King in dis - cussing ventilation, estimates the cubic feet of air needed by common farm animals per thousand pounds of live weight as follows : Cow, 2,804 ; horse, 3,401 ; hen, 8,278. These comparisons emphasize the special importance of a good practical ventilation system in the poultry house Of several systems equally efficient the one which is most automatic is most satisfactory. The shutter system has this particular advantage, tho it is recommended, of course, that additional ventilation by opening the windows and doors be provided when needed during the summer months. The shut ters placed at the top of the south side of the house should however, never be closed even in below-zero weather A cer' tarn amount of moving fresh air is always needed in the poul - try house, altho not as much is needed during the winter time as during the summer months. SUNLIGHT Dryden notes that "Sunshine is a germ destroyer and a £od e s r " e *F S° dU tT % &amp; l re t PePPer ° r Other condimentai foods. Fortunately Nebraska poultry raisers are favored with an abundant supply of this good germicide and the best possible use should surely be made of it The poultry house should face toward the south or south - east and most of the window openings should be placed in hese sides, so as to catch the greatest amount of winter sun - light. The windows should be placed so that they can be lT±Sr^^.^i\^. v _ er Z easily, and thus" providS more ventilation during the summer months when "his add? tional ventilation is needed. SIZE OF THE POULTRY HOUSE From 3 to 4 square feet of floor space should be provided for each hen under average farm conditions. A unit 20 by 20 feet square should comfortably take care of from 100 to 125 birds. The double unit house 20 by 20 feet will comfortably house from 200 to 250 birds. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 A Farm Poultry House LABOR SAVING EQUIPMENT The first consideration in poultry house building is that the hens be made comfortable but of almost equal importance is that of convenience for the caretaker. The Nebraska poul - try house has been especially planned to save labor in caring for the flock. The ventilation system is as automatic as is practically possible, the wide end doors permit of easy clean - ing and additional equipment of nests, roosts, dry mash hopper, water stand and dropping boards are planned to save labor. As the fixtures are planned, it will be noted that all equipment is raised up off the floor at least 18 inches. Every inch of floor space is, therefore, available for scratching purposes during the winter months. Dropping Boards — The space under the roosts can be made available for scratching and exercising when dropping boards are used. Their use on the other hand, necessitates more frequent cleaning than a good many farm poultry keepers find time for. Where labor is so scarce as not to permit clean - ing of the dropping boards at least once a week during the winter months, this equipment should be disposed with. A practical arrangement which has been used on some farms is that of using dropping boards only during the winter months when more labor is available and when the exercising space is especially needed. During spring and summer when the birds can range around outside and when they do not need the exercising space in the house so badly the dropping boards are not used. When dropping boards are used they should be placed about 30 inches above the floor with the roosts 6 inches higher. When dropping boards are not used, an 8 or 1 0-inch board should be placed across the floor in front of the roosts to keep the litter from being mixed with the droppings. Roosts — The roosts should be placed on a level at the back of the house and from 7 to 10 inches of space per bird should be allowed. Rounded poles about 3 inches in diameter or 2 by 4's which are rounded off on one side make very satisfactory roosts. Nests — A nest for every six hens should be provided. Where trapnests are used, a nest for every four hens will be needed. The bottom dimensions of a good practical nest should be about 14 by 14 inches. Dry Mash Hopper — From the labor saving standpoint the dry mash hopper is almost entitled to first place in our list of equipment. More economical and more practical feeding is </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Extension Service possible when a dry mash hopper is used. A practical dry mash hopper for a flock of 100 hens should hold from one lo two hundred pounds of feed and should be constructed so that the birds cannot waste any of the feed by throwing it out with their beaks when searching for a choice morsel. BUILDING MATERIALS Either lumber or tile blocks may be used for constructing the poultry house described in this bulletin. Cost of construc - tion may be somewhat less when lumber is used but advan - tages claimed for the tile block are greater permanence and smaller maintenance expense. A comparison of local prices of the two building materials will help decide which had best be used under your conditions. CARE OF THE HOUSE With well-planned labor-saving equipment, the work of keeping the poultry house clean and sanitary will be very easy, but always very important. The floor of the poultry house should be kept well-littered with clean straw, cut up corn fodder, or sorghum fodder. The last mentioned litter mater - ials do not break up so readily as does the straw and are, therefore, especially practical. A coat of white wash or cold water white paint put on the inside walls of the house will make the house lighter and brighter during the winter months. The use of a coal tar dis - infectant for spraying the roost and dropping boards about cnce a month is especially recommendable. An occasional spraying with kerosene emulsion will aid materially in the destruction of parasites. The kerosene emulsion may be made as follows : Dissolve about one-quarter of a pound of common laundry soap in one gallon of soft water by boiling. When the soap has all dissolved and the solution is still hot, pour into it two gallons of kerosene, and stir mixture vigorously. Of the resulting creamy solution one part is added to eight or ten parts of warm soft water. This can be used as a spray or ap - plied by means of a stiff fibered brush. The authors wish to acknowledge the co-operation of the Department of Agri - cultural Engineering in preparing tbe plans shown in this circular. Distributed in furtherance of co-operative agricultural extension work. Acts of May 8 and June 30, 1914. Extension Service of The fniversity of Nebraska College of Agriculture and U. 8. Department of Agriculture co-operating. E. A. Burnett, Acting Director. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>