<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00002.00010">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00002.00010</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE NORFOLK HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE TO THE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1890. NORFOLK, DECEMBER 1, 1890. OMAHA, NEB,: HENRY GIBSON, STATE PRINTER, 1890.</title>
               <date value="1890">1890</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-29</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item> 
         </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2007-03-20</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>Thomas J. Wattenbarger</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item> 
         </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
¦ .^ i * iii fi.i *&gt; ia1j i\ r j i * ' i\ -i 


r h fc 

:1 ERINTENDENT 

t 

Norfolk Hospital for the Insane 

nit 

OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS 

BOARD 

FOR 

THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1890. 

RFOLK. l'h'AEMBEE 1. 1690 

UMAUA, SKI! 
Hh\||\ GIBSON, PTATK PUKTEI </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
\i:i&gt; iiF CONTROL 

\ 

BLIC LANDS ANH BUILDINGS 

O111. Public Lands and Bldgs President. 
•ery, Secretary of State. Secretary. 

Pharmacist 

ind Supervisor Dept. for Males 
Night Watch Dept. for Males 

w 

Xi,»,ht Watch for Females 

Ban 

Seamstress 

I II P \ 1 I KK- 
I kRRI W -I' '1 
I. I!. Prerso 

Engineer 

Laundryman 

Chief Cook 

R. \NhKl 

Carpenter 


• 


ff 

I 

n 

i 

r- 

•^1 </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
I 'KIM NTKNDKXT'S IJKI'OIJT. 

Board of Public Lands and Buildings: 

The second biennial report ot the Norfolk 
the Insane is respectfully submitted herewith. 

wo yean last ]&gt;ast have been very successful ones 

history of this hospital No serious accidents or calami\ 
e befallen u^. We have had no epidemics of disease 

1 

MECHANICAL RESTRAINTS 

Mechanical restraints are never, under any circumstances, 
with "Ui- patients, and we are more than ever convinced 

h means are not necessary, but are harmful in their 
N*u instance of damage or injury of maiming or sui- 

»&gt; resulted from the non-restraint system. Our anbelieved 
the insane to be possessed of the devil and 

I them up like wild beasts or drove them out to live or 

»ng the tombs. Less than two thousand years ago the 
of such people was reported as casting out devils by 

. Tin- ilavs of miracles are past, superstitions are 
way, and with the more enlightened views on the 
&gt;f insanity will come the more humane system of 

and personal care. To get best results from the nonraint 
system, or. in fact, from any system, there should be 
increased number of attendants. Our hospital now em- 

tun- attendant to eleven patients. This number should 
reased so thai die attendant should care for only three 
r patients. 

Eiis would enable the attendant to give his personal care 
to each patient, and amuse or instruct them and thus 
te their recovery. </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
We have uniformly insisted upon exercis 
of every patieni physicallj able to walk. I 
only be obtained by taking .1 walk once ortw i 
pany of their attendants. Better results would 1 
obtained if we could exercis&lt; their minds ai 
same time l&gt;j giving them lighi and pleasai 
• 'ii a lawn, garden or farm. Also light and 
chanical work would gladlj Lx performed bj m&lt; 
tients. We have no means •¦' furnishing 
Provision should be made to supply this 
women patients, when the} an physicalh 
the habit of helping to care for their room and 1 i 
also do sewing mending and ironing 
eagerlj sough 1 after and en 

The aged and feebl&lt; 1 

relief from the monotony 
inn with the more u We 
number of attendant 
duty it should tx 
walks or sitting in 1 lie sha&lt; 
permits, and by reading 
pleasantly a&gt; possible, li 
experience that the emp 
occupation with pleasan 
curative effi 


An injurious custom thi 
criminate visiting in insane hospitals. N 
visitors now come to gratifj a morbid curiosit} I 
objectionable in many ways. The popular opinion i 
boundary of insanity is a well-marked and definit&lt; line O 
one side is sanity with all the faculties of reason, right) 
sensibilities of humanity. &lt; &gt;n the other side is insan 
out reason, rights or sensibilities. 

This is far as possible from the truth. In almost all cas&lt; 
of true insanity the person s sane in almost all things, ai 

208 </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
&lt; 

Ire ni"iv acute than in health. They do not 
In gazed at and criticised and gossiped 
hi we we mill. To be made a show of twice a 
injurious. The public has a right to know 
tutiona air conducted, and relatives and friends 

ksiov how their people are treated. That 
i concealment, every hospital should be 
H. - to thorough inspection by representatives of 
te and county officers: the clergy, the medical 
ad all friends and relatives of patients, and to all 
far as it is consistent with the welfare of the 
But the visits of the mere sight-seer and the morrious 
who are looking for something shocking or 
should be discouraged. 

ADDITIONAL ROOM. 

nee to the statistical table you will see that we 
rolls of this hospital 123 male patients. In the 
its our numbers have increased 44 patients. The 
increase for the next two years will give us 198 
nt-. witli room for but 101. I would therefore recomadditional 
wing, or a separate building, as the 
lecide, should be built to accommodate the addi¦ 
r. The cost of the additional room should not 

135.000, including the steam-fitting, tunneling, etc.. 
attach it to the power-plant now used. The 
ha • will supply the new building with water, heat 


LAND8CAPIXU. 

i- been very little accomplished here in the way 
It seems absolutely necessary that pleasant 
surroundings lie about a hospital. This we have not now and 
cannot have without expending money for it. The sandy soil 
r\ unfavorable for landscaping. We cannot have a 
intil the soil is made. It will cost the sum of flO.OOOto 
prepare the ground for a shaded lawn, which would make a 
.mi retreat for the patients in a hot day. This approiriation 
is greatly needed. 

209 </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
TERRITORY. 

Since the last report the Board of Public Lands 
ings have increased the Norfolk Hospital district, i 
comprises the following, to-wit: All of the counti 
north of the Platte River, except Douglas. Barp 
and Hall, and including Dawson, Lincoln and Keit 
which the Platte runs, making very much inure fch 
the state in territory, and which i~- rapidly tillin; 
settlers. 

.1 

wh 

e 

\ 

rKASSFER OK PATIENTS 

I On August 12. 1889, a transfer was mad.- from 
folk, via Union Pacific Railway, of 37 patients. 96 
»males. from the increased territory set aside bj 
'ublic Lands and Buildings. The transfer wa 

1 

safety and comfortably by l&gt;r. Hay, assistant bu] 
of the Nebraska Hospital for Insane, ably assisted 
of attendants. November 12, 1889. the hospital I 
Insane having openni for th&lt;- reception of patieni 
was made by order of the Board of Public Lands ai 
of 23 patients, 15 males and 8 females, from Nbrf 
for Insane by Dr. Hasson. assistant superintend* 
mont, Elkhorn &amp; Missouri Valley Railroad, whic 
without accident and in safety. Reference U 

B follow will show the m 
ast report. 

HOAKD AN 

THI 

S The $40,000 appropriated -in 1889 will last us t ii r. 
ably until April 1, 1891. with perhaps a very sma 
average number of patients for these two year 
average is 06. The same proportionate 
the next two years will giro us an increase i 
ed to the number we now have will make 301 pi 
iverage of 252 patients. This is an increase of th 
ndance of 44 per cent.: 44 per dent, added 
&gt;unts to $57,600. 

I 

It 

It It'll 

ivera 

$4O.(Hh 

r his amount includes the board of emploves an 

I att 

210 </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
r, under the present system, will not be 
hi. Therefore, we think it possible to 

itienta on $54,000. This does not take 
'eased juice of articles of consumption, 

U per cent. There is no economy or hu 
be patients. 

EMPLOYEfl WAGES 

touni appropriated in 1889 was $80,000. By most 
m\ and denying ourselves much help we should 

will succeed in keeping our expenses in this 
r appropriation. This has been done some times 

•ii—.- of lowering the grade of service, and at other 
jot mi without help that was greatly needed. 

I 

ed some more attendants to care for the increased 
patients. Without any desire to be extravagant 
$84,000. 

I (HI. AND LICiHTS. 

nut appropriated for fuel and lights in 1888 was 
the most careful and economical management by 

1 

gineer and the providential help of mild 

hope to come through without any deficiency. If 

winter proves to be a severe one we will be forced 

i 

ficiency in this fund, which we will greatly de- 

ire aoi able to run our institution as cheaply in 

\ 

¦it ;i~ we would like, because our coal, for some 
t explained, costs us more than it does at other instibere 
the same coals are used. The increased num- 

,v 

ient^ will correspondingly increase the amount of 

t 

red t&lt;i give us heat, light and water. The amount 

§20,000. seems the smallest sum we can possibly 


MKNITIRE AND BKDDIXH. 

We a 

sk for $1,000, which will be sufficient to replace 
iine&gt; useless by wear and accident. 

•vhat be&lt; 

211 </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
Ife have never been supplied with curtains ai 
d. Some of the carpets an 1 worn and tiseles 
replaced. 

This seems an indefinite t 

her of things that will not be classified oi 
they will be paid for properly from this tin 

VEHICLES ANH FARM IMPLEMENT 

These are obviously required and Deed ii" explai 

TEN COM s 

We find that the quantity of milk is not equal t&lt; 
inand. and it is cheaper to have our own cows than 

! 

212 

CARPETS AND &lt; CKTAIN&gt; 

Ml SI. AND AM1SKMK.1TS. BOOKS, STATIONERY, lie? 

FRAMES, PAINTS. OILS \M&gt; 1'JIMIN 

These arc all bo obviously necessan that 

sary to allude to them. The amounts are pla 

think it advisable to place them for the good i 

REPAIRS \n 

Iii 1889 |1 000 '¦ 

initially in i 

Farm mac) 

thai liae 

roofs ol our ¦ 

tinualh 

. 

needed fund 

y with &gt;;r 

rELEGRAPH, I BLEPHi &gt;NK 

These are obviouslj 

I N ' &lt; 1 I ' I 


nt\ of pasture for the cows and help to </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
ttions asked for are as follows 

ICE-HOUSE. 

we have is not "f a satisfactory character 

lown at any time I would therefore ask 

1.000 be i^iven us for that purpose, 

V IM. AND LANDSCAPE GARDENING. 

tnd-hill on which this hospital is located has 
pleasures without work being done to make 
¦en. This is an important part of the treat- 

ii. 1 |10,000 would he well expended for this 

Been by this report then- is liable to be about 
Imitted &gt;&gt;r seeking admission to this hospital 

onof the next two years. We surely owe 
tlii — . state to provide for their care. This 

here because we have an abundant supply 
•r -plant which is ample for heating, lightwater. 
We ask $35,000 for the purpoc 
building and tunneling and laying pipes 

E-HOUSE, ROOT- HO USE AND MOR(iL*E. 

\ 

able place to keep vegetables for a store- 

.Hi-. All these things are very much needed, 
p combined for the sum of $1,500, which we 

r 

u 


KIKE PROTECTION. 

Ens hospital i^ entirely without protection in case of fire. 
ater supply to the building comes from tanks placed in 
wen. If hose should be connected with pipes in use it 
be almost useless for fighting fire, because the force 
not be sufficient. What we should have is a main laid 
the building with hydrants placed conveniently and an 

213 
ADDITIONAL HooM. </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
Kidant supply of hose ready to attach. The ma 
mnected with the pumps so we could put on &lt; 1 i r 
in case of tire This fire protection would c 
X), and the appropriation is earnestly asked for. 

1 

¦ ie Honorable Hoard of Public Lands and Buildii 
tF.NTi.KMKN : — Estimated appropriations necessary 
years beginning April 1, 1891, is respectfully su 

herewith. 

¦aployea' wages 
mrd and clothin 
el and lights. 

For drugs, instrument* ami appi 
For furniture and bedding 

rat i 

For carpeta and curtains 
For niUHic and amusements 
For hooks, stationery, picture 
For repairs and improvement 
For paints, oils and paintings 
For telephone, telegraph and 
For expenwe returning patient 
For incidentals 

K hides and farm implemi 
n cows 

For ice 

For superintendent's «alar\ 
For asmstam superintendent' 

liar 

sl'K 

A I 

For ice-house 

For new machinery 

For grading, fencing and land 
For new wing . 

ape gardt 

For furnishing wing 


For store- house, root-houHe and 
For fire protection 

niorgut 

NI.IHI 


I'EH CAl'lTA &lt;¦( 

sT OF MAINTENANCE 

K he actual per capita cost of maintenance, hast 
ge number of 164 patients, and calculated upon 
priated, which will very nearly correspond 

214 </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
sd "ii tin 
the sum- 
with tli. 


\ 

xpended, for employes' wages, board and clothing. 

and officers' salaries, amounts to $5.86 

Without including officers, salaries the per capita 

unite a reduction from the previous re- 

1 

v ill very naturally be still further reduced 
itients shall increase. 

ii 

daily number under treatment during the 
tr&gt; has U-en 164. 

of recoveries based upon the total number under 
io-:,&gt;) per cent 

ii i lie aim of the institution to always receive 
ace the acuteand violent insane, even when crowded 

tind room for them. 

IMPROVEMENTS. 

Improvements made since the last report have been 
antial and necessary. Among these are, first, a frame 
barn with stone basement that will accommodate twenty - 

sows, sixty (60) tons of hay and five hundred (500) 
f urain. the cost of which has been about $1,500. 

\ pasture for horses has been made at a cost of $62.75 for 
necessary to fence forty (40) acres. To this pasture and 

pipe has been laid from the pump-house and tanks 
1 a cost of 8174.50. 
iaira on house, barn, roof ? chapel, kitchen, laundry. 
Dinting windows in main building, repainting roof and 
building oven have been made at a cost of about $1,450. 
Last spring then- was planted on the north line of the hos- 

K grounds and north of the hospital five (5) acres of trees, 
&lt;nu£ of maple, box-elder and ash, about eight thousand 

Ei in all, it being an exceptionally dry summer; about oneot 
them failed to grow. In a few years a good windpron 
will 1).- the result. In all of this work a saving has 

I effected by the use of our own employes and what few 
llts that Collld lie used. 

ADDITIONAL WATER SUPPLY. 

Ene last legislature appropriated $3,500 for additional 
. The Board of Public Lands and Buildings contracted 

215</seg> 

            <seg id="p014">
Efoseph Burns, of Lincoln, who made a n&lt;\\ well 125 t 
placed therein a Dew pump, erected an elevated tank 
undred (500) barrel capacity, and made the n&lt; 
etions, etc., at a cost of $3,450.50. 

ITMl-Hi H -V 

Che machinery, pomp and -team pipe- wer 

¦built without cover. A new brick pump-house w 
•der of the Hoard of Public Lands and Buildin 
,f |5l * '. 

\&lt; k V 

I desire to very cordialh 

ink 

John II. Thayer, and each membei ind 

honorable Board of Public Land- and Buildines for 

form kindness to us at this hospital, and for theii 

as to management and finances, wrhicl 

value and have been appreciat 

I also desire to express our very greal obligation to tfa 

people of Norfolk and Madison county for th.ir many tokei 

of favors and good will which they have extended to tli 

people at this hospital, both in business ami social relation 
I also desire to express our thanks to all the new-paper- i 

Norfolk and many others of our state papers for favors -how 

to us and substantial benefit- conferred 

216 </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
LA.\"I&gt;S( WINc, ami GRADING. 

Aii appropriation of $1,000 made for landscai 

nn^ was expended to the besi advantage during 

mer of 188i». 

Since then .Mir own help have expended about 

work. It will take years of patieni ami mi. 

labor to make a decent lawn .,| 

Fll 

Fire-escapes have been 

ings for use of the patient* 

the appropriation being madi 

purpose. 


I 

in. and returned to Rev. J. W. Jennings, 
irk. t and Dean W. T. Witmarsh for voluntarily 
uslv conducting religious services in our chapel 
asi 5 ear. 

II 

I 

i 

! 

-, attendants and employes I desire to espem\ 
great obligations for their uniform attention 
kindly cooperation with me in promoting the 

hospital and the welfare of the inmates. 

ENGINEER -S RKl'OKT. 

power-plant of this institution consists of five boilers. 

three pumps and two electric dynamos with 
fixtures for same, all of which are in perfect 

I 

Dhree boilers art- used exclusively for steam- 

i 

wo ari' required to furnish steam for cooking:, 

iting water and running electric dynamos for 

ry and all other machinery connected with the 

i 

We are supplied with two tubular wells 125 feet 

furnish an inexhaustible supply of water and 

th.se wells and landed in a 500-barrel 

k li\ two deep-well lifting pumps, taken from 

\ fi irce-pump and forced into three iron tanks of 

itv, each situated in the towers of the main 

tanks we obtain a fair circulation of 

In entire building. While we have water 
i an titles it is of very poor quality, coiitain- 

• f solid matter in 1,000 by chemical analy- 

very bad quality of water for laundry 

IK 

poses. It requires constant care and vigilance 

dlers in safe and economical working condition. 
imp i-- of ample size and power to furnish water 

ressure in case of fire were arrangements made 

M I... used in this way. To do this would require the 
of ,i few hydrant-- on the grounds and several hose 

in the building furnished with proper hose. 

tloll 

fthis addition to our water system we would have as 
a fire protection as could he asked for as regards water. 

With this a 

\^ it is now. we have no protection whatever of this nature, 

217 </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
218 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPOR1 

and in case &lt;&gt;f tire could do nothing except wh 

accomplished by using the ordinary buckets, wl 

h u 

aiiiount, practically, to nothing in a building of tin 

km 

Being advised by tin- officers of this institut 

meaner appropriation for fuel ami li^-h 

11 

been the watchword of this department. Slack 

us here from (8.50 to $4.50 per ton, it has been i 

u- to make careful test of the qualities of coa 

mines and select that which suit 

mr (nirpi 

the credit of the superintendent and &gt;t&lt;\\;i 

that they have urged an. I aide 

r\ 

reduce the expenses of thi- department m 

900 patients than i1 was when this buildii 

patients, and the ••vin^s incon id uno 

ai 

•Mil 

n r 

truly say thai thi </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
1AHLK No. 1. 

December 1. /ss \ to November •.'", .' 

December 1. 1888 

I 

v 

IIP 10 21) 

1 1 

i:«) 77 207 
12"&gt; 70 19o 

Sorember 30, is*). 

W« 65 1 .. 1M 

Will I.ATIoN. 

Male Ki'inai.-. Total, 
SI 59 140 

219 </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
Male, nmli 
H7 r,4 121 
M -11 37 
lti S _M 
137 s2 -219 
•-'04 13K :H0 
M 3- r &gt; 74 
7 ,4 

10, 1890 


Cheyenm 

m 


Garfield 

ssr 

Keys Pa ha 

Kimhall. 

Lincoln 
Madison 


Sheridan 

Stanton. 
Sherman. 

Scott's Bluffs 

Thureton 
Valley 

1 

Washington. 
Wayne 

13 

1 

Wheeler 

r" 

l 

State at large 

1 

Total. 


•i 

220 


TABLE No. -2. 

Reitirfence of t hour Admitted and Remain 

I :. - n i. i n -. of those vi 
tlllttcd &gt;iii... in., 'i M 
i i '( STIKS tx i ~^« to No 
VelutH 

M:l • 

Sffiir 

Box Bum- 
Banner 
Cumins 

I 
! 
t </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
TABLE No. 3. 

l'nite&lt;! States. 

Mai. Female. Total. 

1 .. 1 

1 1 

1 1 

11 7 18 

5 4 9 

8 8 1« 

1 1 

1 . 1 

1 2 S 

4 2 « 

1 .. 1 

1 1 

3 3ft 

5 . . &amp; 

1 

9 8 17 
9 10 19 
8 2 10 

1 X 

;u 

A 

7 

r 

81 59 140 

IIKl AIMTll.ATION. 

L'nited States 

81 5» 140 
56 23 79 

Born 

T.,tal 


221 </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
Foreign Born 

Austria 

Bohemia 
Canada 
Denmark 
England 
Frailer 

(iermain 
Ireland . 

Holland 
Nor\va\ 
Prussia 
B— in 
Scotland 
Sweden 

Bwitzerlam 
Unknown 

' 

1 

222 </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
\I!LK No. 4. 

Decanter 1 . 1 8S8, to .Vot-ember 30, 

Male. K- male. Total. 

1 

1 

&gt; 

¦_&gt; 

1 

: 

i 
i 
i 

! 

1 1 

1 
Til 

1 


25 . 
46 4« 

3 

:? 

1 

1 

1H 

1« 

¦2 

¦&gt; 

-&gt; 

¦&gt; 

1 

1 

1 1 2 

i 4 

-2 

¦&gt; 

i 
i 
&lt;2 

\ 

¦ &gt; 

¦• 

i 

: 

i 

i 



223 </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
TABLE \. . 5. 

ig 

&lt; 

I - M 

Under* 
From 10 to 
From 2"&gt; to 
From BO to 

136 to 40 
4(1 In IB 
¦ 

From BO to 
From Be to 

From rid 

From 85 to 70 

From 70 to 
From 75 to 
From HO to 
rnknown. 

Total 

in 

224 </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
K So. 6. 

llmm Admitted. 

Mil I.- l-.-li 

1 1 

¦1 

II ti is 

II 1 U| 
1-. Id 1&gt; 

¦ ; ¦: 

¦&gt; 

r &gt; 

14 1 Ii 


•&gt; 

12 

12 

:i 

S 

I 1 :? 

¦• 

-&gt; 

¦&gt; 

:« 2t&gt; tvi 

l:&lt;7 m' -21» 

225 </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
TABLE N'. 7. 


of Ditram r,,,h ¦ f 

'¦•¦mb' • 


HIM \ - I 

¦ nlia 

u primar 


•¦ p« 

d senile 

\\ i t h l 

Hystero • 


¦ i .1.11',. 

I* acute r. 


&lt;/ chron 

r hyster 



/ puerperal 


!! with ep 

Megalomania 


Melancholia 

a acute 

'&lt; chronic 

&lt;• witli epileps&gt; 

Not insane 

iholic mania 

Total 


226 </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
« 

TABLE No. 8. 


Mali I •••iikiI.- rotal 


i a 

i&lt; 

n 

8 '.' S 12 I IK 


8 2 7 

1 5 7 2-2 

il 3 14 

1 


I 

in 

1 1 


-' 5 7 



1 

• 


•i 7 13 

¦ 8 '_' 

¦ &gt; 

2 2 4 

1 1 


1 1 


-1 88 HH 137 M SI* 

227 </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
tted siiirr / )t fitjiht-r /. /.S\V.S', to Xttretn- 

¦'". / S!HI. 

El 4 8 11) ¦ l!l 
'• '¦ •&gt; 1"&gt; 7 22 
l 1 IS :! lti 

B r -' 4 I !l 16 _&gt;4 
• '• 11 1l' IS J"&gt; 
7 8 13 4s 17 iv&gt; 
¦ '&lt; 7 10 -J •") 7 

TABLE So. '.'. 

S hi Xumber 'tinl Condition of (fro* D 

18S8,to Norembei 

A* unimproved 

Died 

At borne 'Hi tin!'. u. 

i

Peritonitis 

Acute I'hthi-i-l'MU-MUM 

ExhauHtion 

( 'erebral hemorrhage 

Pneomonia with manim 
Pnlmonary apoplex) 

Bterii- tuber 
's disease 

Epileptifome convulsions

228 </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
Bci\ llVll 
.roved 
mi&gt;r&lt; i vt-ci 


229 </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
,,. 

11. 

i .\rnaj .^ ' ' . 

¦ / thote I'nrfr 
to Sovember ¦• 

r Treatment *ince December 1, 

'". /.v&lt;". 

~-z ||| -| 

-Kit. 

I? 

g£ I 

I 

£ * 

% .-;.-' i 

3 

3 
z 

i-i ii 
H S £ H 

8 : 
i . • j _¦ 
- ¦ j :. 
1 1 I 
!.¦ "¦ 17 
• 
¦ ! ' .' 1 1 
1 I 1 ¦_' 
I 
: i ~ 2 7 
• 
I I 
I 
1 1 
I 

1 

I 

I 

! 

1 

i 

! 

- 

I- 

1 

1 

i 

i 

' 

1 

i 

. 

I 

1 

i 
1 
1 
l 

! 

: 

1 .: 

1 

-• 

in 

- 

i 

•i 

u 



MI i-'l SU 

rber l, balance on hand 
ber M, sold 2,mr, lbs. In 

1 

Aug. K 

I 

April ¦_&gt;:!. sold 2,221 
AogOal S, sold trail 
August IT. sold MO 
August 17. solil \Mi, 

t 

till;; up t 

November ). 

February l* 
April 8, sold 

November 11. -old 


E&gt; 90, paid ('ran.- Brothers Mi 
y ;M). paid John &lt; &gt;Banion for 
y .'JO. paid F. H. Greenwald t. 
y 30, ]&gt;aid for sundries mere 

in 

ing 

March 30, paid for returning patients 
March 30, paid for sundries telegrap 

express 

April 27, paid J. J. Johnson for vet 

mi. i 

October 30. paid for 1,406 lbs. hog 

Is 


Balance on hand Decenili- 

r l 


230 


STK WARDS REPORT 

For Norfolk Hospital for Innatu from Decevibi 

&lt; &gt;i-tol»'i- I . cash reeei \ i 

¦j .;. paid ( Fal 
y 11. paid S. M; 
5 30, paid Neb 

telephone 

lanuar&gt; 30, paid II. Wim. </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
Xl'KNIM TURKS 

I 

\M-il 1 

arm implements 
luill 

in iny and landscape 

ntendenfs salar\ 

Win 

I 

119,350.00 

I of I'liUir Larrds and Buildings: 
nditures for the Norfolk Hospital for 

1889. to November 30,189o. is respect- 

119,3-iO.O.l 

231 </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
light* t 12,294. HI 
traces.. 24.779.2H 
I clothing . W.449.14 
.t rumenta and apparatus 864.38 
and bedding 8,638.21 
id curtains . '!41.:{1 
I amusements 775.90 
itionerj' and pictures t!H».44 
nd improvements. i.ooo.ho 
I- and paintings . . . 64S.:» 
graph and postage 536.17 
¦eturning patients t&gt;^i.29 
440. lil 

tttT supph 

salar\ 


ED IN -K\VIN(,-| 

&gt;v 

Kheets. single, 
llet'ts, double 
illow-cases. 


bath towels 


tea towels 

comforts, doublt 

H4 

comforts, singlt 


chemise 


ladies' draw ers 

m&gt; 

men's drawers 

(Ires 

&gt; ) 

irting 
k m i u 

Is 

dr. 


men's shirts 
skirls. Hani] 

1 

1; 

skirts, skirting 
skirls, cotton t] 

ladies' waist 
tra\ coven*, 
coffee sacks 
tea sacks. 

in 

&gt; 

l« 

1 

chair cushion, 
roller towels, 
shrouds. 

»2 

•&gt; 

12 

bed-spreads, 
table scarfs. 

4 

232 
&lt;;&amp;amp;lt;&gt;&lt;&gt;!&gt;&gt; MAXIKAi 

7(i»&gt; pillow -cases 
9M napkins. 

10 dresses, flanne 
li'tf dresses, irint;li; 
80 ilrrsM's. calico 

table-olol 

»ili|c-i-(i\ ers 
rewHing-ffo 

15 clothes sacks. 
198 curtains, windo 
61 aprons. 
•Jo ticks, single. 
15 ticks, doable. 
fiO iron-holders. 
16 bonnets. </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
Eshew. blacking 
Bhes, counter 
Bhes, hair </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
Brushes, feather 
Brushes, scrub 
Brushes, shaving 
Brushes, wall 

Bed-spreads. 

Brooms, whiap 

Ei. brussels. yards 
i, ingrain, \ arcls 
¦tretcben 


Chairs, arm 

K barber 
willow 

Chairs, upholstered 
Chairs, dining 

Chairs, cane 

Chairs, rocking 

Chambers, earthen 
Chambers, fiber 


Etbles, double 
ibles. single 
es 

Cups, tin 

R shaving 
rs 

Ewers and basins 

Graduate medicine glasses 
Mattress, double hair 

Mattress, single hair 
Mattress, felt, double 
Mirrors 

M 

Mops. . 
Organ. 

1 

Pans, dust 
Pianos 

« 

Pails 


Pillows, felt 


Pillows, feather 
Pillow-slips 


234 </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
INSAKK HOSPIT \ I.. X( &gt;RK&lt; I K 

235 </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
K, breakfast 
. dinner 

Plates, pi.. 

Soup tureens 
howls. 
Deep dishes 
Butter dishes 
Pickle dishes. 
&lt; lomporta 

Sugar bowls 


Syrup joga 

Platters, 14-inch 
Platters. 10-inch 
• iravy dishes 
Spoon holders 
Thermometers 
Pitchers, l-quart 
Pitchers. ¦_' quart 
Tumblers 

Lanterns 
Sad irons. 
Kkk cup« 

( 'elerv dishes 
Mustard caps 
Carring set 
Trays, large 
Tra\s. small 

Eble cutter 
e cutter , 
tone, sma'1 

236 

i roles 
&lt; ll|». cciffi 
&lt; Ups. ten 
&lt; "reamers </seg>
         </p>

		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>