<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00001">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00001</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1901-1902, ANNUAL REPORT NEBRASKA State Board of Agriculture FOR THE YEAR 1901</title>
		             <date value="1902">1902</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-08</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
rBLIO DOCUMENTS 
OP NEBRASKA 

19O1-O2 

Vol.. Ill 

K. Il.tilLLKBHIG 

'. ¦ &gt; IIICI 

l.ivml.s. mil </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
TV KEV. YORK 
PUBLIC LIBRARY 
512281B 
A9T0B. LSNOI AND 
TIUtKN IW NDATIOIW 
« 1H49 L </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
i 

¦&gt; 

IJ 

4 

i 


CONTENTS. 

Annual Report of the State Board of Agriculture, 1901-02. 

Fifteenth and Sixteenth Annual Reports Experimental 
Station of Nebraska. 

Bulletins 71-80, inclusive, Nebraska Experimental Station 

rs Bulletins. Nos. lti, 17. 18, Nebraska Experimental 
Station. 

Annual Report of the State Board of Horticulture. </seg>


            <seg id="p005">/ 


State Board of Agriculture 

FOK THE YEAE 1901. 


PREPARED BT 

ROBT. W. FURNAS, Secretary. 



LINCOLN, NEB : 

STATE JOURNAL COUPANT, PRINTERS. 

'" \ 

/ 


/ 


¦*1 


I </seg>


            <seg id="p007">

Bbownviixe, Neb., January 31. 1902, 

Hi* Exttllency, K. P. Satmje, Governor of Xebraska: 

EIn compliance with the law in this case made and provided, 
transmit the annual report of the Nebraska State Board 
Iture for the year 1901. 

Very respectfully. 

ROBERT W. K( UNAS. 8ecnfr% 



I 

' </seg>









            <seg id="p009">
PROCEEDINGS. 

There was no semi-annual meeting of the Board held in the year 1901. 

AJSNUAL MEETING. 

Lincoln, Neb., January 21, 1902. 

In compliance with the provisions of law in this case provided, the 
Nebraska State Board of Agriculture this day convened in the New 
Chapel Hall of the University of Nebraska, and at 4 o'clock p. m. was 
called to order by the President. 

ROLL CALL. 

(&gt;n roll being called there were found to be present: 

OFFICERS. 

E. L. Vance, President 

J. R. Cantlin, 1st Vice-President. 
W. E. Ewing, 2d Vice-President. 
Ed. Mclntyre, Treasurer. 

Robert W. Fnrnas, Secretary. 

MEMBERS OF THE BOABD. 

S. C. Bassett, Gibbon, Buffalo County. 
E. L. Vance, Pawnee City, Pawnee County. 
Charles Mann, Chadron, Dawes County. 
J. R. Cantlin, Webster, Dodge County. 
E. Mclntyre, Seward, Seward County. 
\V. K. Mellor, Loup City, Sherman County. 
N. Withrow, Central City, Merrick County. 
L. Morse, Benkelman, Dundy County. 
T. A. McKay, Aurora, Hamilton County. 
Peter Youngers, Jr., Geneva, Fillmore County. 
J. C. Seacrest, Lincoln, Lancaster County. 

W. C. Hervey, Omaha, Douglas County. 
J. B. Dinsmore, Sutton, Clay County. 

Robt. W. Furnas, Brownville, Nemaha County. 
L. D. Stilson, York, York County. </seg>


            <seg id="p010">
6 


E- M. Searle, Ogallala, Keith County. 
L. B. Fletcher, Bancroft, Cuniing County. 
('. M. Lewelling. Reaver City, Kurnas County. 
Elijah Filley, Beatrice. (iagc County. 

W. A. Poynter, Albion, Boone County. 
O. A. Strand. Mind&lt;n, Kearney County. 
II. L. Cook, St. Paul. Howard County. 
W. E. Ewing, Franklin, Franklin County. 
YV. H. Barger, Hebron. Th:i\cr County. 
H. C. Lydick, Decat\ir, Burt County. 

¦loriiin being present, the Board was declared, by the president, in 
to transact business. 

cllor Andrews then delivered the following- address of welcome: 

CHANCELLOR ANDKEWS* AMU 

B,l and UnttUvicn nf At IM llnnnl nf iiiriciiltmt : 1 am very 
bliged to you for the prl»llege 1 have of standing before you. I 
TV if I was just a little late. This is the fourth engagement 
of my regular work that I have to fill today. I am not going 
,k at great length. I wish to bid you all welcome to the prinall 
of the principal seat of learning in this city. You are more 
¦•elcoine here. We are glad to ha\e you come here. We feel 
il with people, citizens and taxpayer! and church members who 
labor in here and train in this university: we feel honored by having 
the likes of you to come up and stay with us for a few hours a clay 
for a day or so. I believe there is no other university in this country 
or in the world where the representative men of the constituency 
i in this way' in so large numbers to hold counsel with those who 
t work nt the university as in'the stale • &gt; f Nebraska. It eli 
1 have been a teacher for i great many years, but I 
remember in many of the places where 1 have had the privilege of 
ling and tramping about, tramping month after month and year 
after fear, and you would hardly see anybody but your instructors and 
and it literally seems that nobody cares for us, or our souls. 
• ins good to see those come here anil sit with us in our halls to look 
ogr work and shake us by the hand: on the other hand it very 
likely does not do you any harm to come here. This is your work. If 
re doing anything good iu this university, in any department in 
it. it -e of the co-operation ¦ ance that we get from 
and from the likes of you. We shnul I .ease immediately if it 
was not for your help, and I assure you that we wish to be as worthy 
as we can of the continuance of this rapport, for the cause is one. 

kthe agricultural interests of this great state have two or three 
e problems l&gt;efore them, more vital, perhaps, than any other 
the I'nion. One nf thru aination &lt;&gt;f scientific methods 
culture, by which 1 don't niei.n. and who have </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
7 



fancy agriculture, the agriculture of the city man; I mean by scientific 
agriculture those principles of agriculture that will actually make the 
fields pay more, that will actually make the agriculturist a richer, and 
whole a better man from year to year. That Is one of the problems, 
ng them, and more or less separate, is the problem of forestration 
of those parts of the state that ought to be forestried as our secretary 
has briefly set forth in his report. Now this is a necessity that is no 
going to care for itself. You find almost all of the farmers qui 
E»tic. There has got to be evangelical work right soon. Governo 
s, you have been one of them. There is not a farmer today wh 
better off because of the agitation by the governor. We hav 
got to tell the people who live in these various localities to 1&gt; 
themselves. It is not necessary that our crops should be burned down 
and blown down frequently as they hnve been in the past. By prope 
forestration of places and parts of sections here and there, a grea 
deal of that can be overcome, can be made an impossibility in tim 
to come, and when this splendid result has been achieved then it w 
be that all parts of this country will l ¦ the rose summer aft 
summer. 

There is one other great necessity. Anil how delighted I was when I 
took up the President's message to find that he had treated this subject 
so kindly; so great was it that the President of this Republic saw 
fit to devote to it a very considerable part of his recent message. 
I mention the necessity of conserving all the waters, to provide for 
the times when they will be most needed. We have water enough in 
the arid parts of this country. I believe, and no doubt most of you 
believe, because I have talked with scientific irrigationists on the subject, 
that there is a way by which enough of that water can be saved 
and stored up to make all that part of the country now spoken of as 
:irid or semi-arid most luxurious, and prolific in providing the things 
that are a necessity for the life of man and beast. Here is another 
-sity that will not take care of itself. In many parts of this 
country there are those who have such a deep interest in Nebraska 
that I think this board ought to be up and adoing. Our voices should 
1m&gt; heard and known. Many of yon live in parts of the state which 
arc known as well worth having, that ought to let every good voice 
that can be, lifted up in the propagation of this great cause and in 
endeavoring to store it rightly so that it will not get into the hands of 
jobbers; so that it will accomplish what all good citizens wish. There 
are gentlemen here who go east and who have business and various 
relations with men in this Republic who have never been further west 
than Chicago. I know a great many of such men. They are good 
men; they vant to do the best for the Republic. Many of them are 
church members, but they are simply ignorant about the immensity of 
this country. I have a brother who for fifteen years was chief justice </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
8 


nf the state of Connecticut. 1 am told by the lawyers that he is one 
of the best lawyers in the country; a life-long republican and always 
deeply interested in the Republic. In the ciTil war he would have been 
the first to enlist if radical disability had not prevented him from 
becoming a soldier, so he sent all of his brothers to war and he stayed 
at home and organized companies to go out and help them. I am 
hound to say that he has no more conception than an infant in the 
cradle of the necessities of this part of the world where we live, and 
he and the likes of him, when you speak about the great necessity of 
the government helping to irrigate these millions of square miles, 
naturally inquire whether it is for the best. Those people need to be 
labored with. We should take a map of the United States with us arid 
point out how much is taken up "by Nebraska and by this great arid 
and semi-arid tract. 

Again welcoming you, Mr. President, to the precincts of the Univerand 
begging of you to stay as long as you can and look over 
our plant just as completely as von can, I bid you- good afternoon. 
[Applause.] 

Evident: Some little time ago, in conversation with Governor 
f, he assured me that at this meeting he would be here and stay 
is all through the meeting. I find that the Ciovernor is not here; 
am happy to say that, in his stead, an acting Governor with full 
, we have our friend who has always been a mutual friend of 
rricultural interests of the state. 

I have the pleasure now of introducing to you Hon. C. F. Steele, 
Governor of Nebraska. [Applause.] 

ADDRESS BY ACTING GOVERNOR STEELE 

Honorable President, and Gentlemen of the State Agricultural Society: I 
want to say to you that while it is pleasant for me to be here with you 
this year, it is yet a disappointment thai Governor Savage could not 
be here. I think that the Governor really had something to say. If 
I knew what it was I would say it; but nevertheless on my own behalf 
I would like to say this, that I do feel an interest in the agricultural 
interests of the state. I think that there is nothing that is of greater 
interest to us, it being strictly an agricultural state. I want to speak 
of the exhibit at Buffalo. I had the pleasure of seeing the Nebraska 
exhibit as compared with others, and I felt proud of it. I felt proud to 
be a citizen of Nebraska with the exhibit that we had there and the 
interest taken in that exhibit both in agriculture and horticulture. I 
think that the horticultural display was grand; yet there was none that 
1 thought that was, I say, equal to it. I don't expect to detain you. This 
is election time and it is getting time perhaps that you should be at 
business, and I know that while I cannot say anything that will entertain 
you, yet I want to say one word, and it is that we welcome you </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
1 


to the State Capital of Nebraska in behalf of the state, and furthermore 
I think that we should hare an interest in this Louisiana Exposition. 
I think that the state of Nebraska, being centrally located 
in the territory as it is, I believe that we ought to have a very deep 
interest, and work to our utmost in that respect. And as for our own 
agricultural society, as for the fair grounds, I want to say to you that 
the three terms that I was in the legislature I didn't cast a vote that I 
felt the deep interest in that I did in casting that vote for the purchase 
of the fair grounds. I felt an interest in this way, knowing our state 
fit is, an agricultural state, and needing the assistance of the state 
for one, did what I could, and I did it with just lots of pleasure. 

V;men, I thank you for this honor of being called here. I was 
here by the chairman, and we appreciate the invitation and 
glad to meet you thus and hope to in the future. [Applause.] 

President: We will now have a word from Secretary Furnas 

ADDRESS OF R. W. FUHXAS. 

Mr. Chancellor: In behalf of the State Board of Agriculture, I thank 
vou for the cordial and hearty welcome you extend. We fully realize 
that the close and friendly relations which have for years existed between 
the University of Nebraska and this Board, are for the betterment 
of all concerned — the whole state, in that higher agriculture is 
secured. I trust that these relations may ever exist, desired results 
increase and compound from year to year in the future. ¦ 

t never come to Lincoln and in sight of these university buildings 
what I feel a happier and a better man. Now let me tell you why. 
i principally from an agricultural standpoint. 

When I was elected Secretary of this State Board of Agriculture 
•gainst my will, as Mr. Mclntyre and others know at the time, I found 
that there was something lacking in order to make this board and its 
work as useful as it ought to be and might be. I thought that if the 
scientific agriculturists or scientific workers in this work and our 
State Board of Agriculture could work hand in hand that better 
results must follow. There was no kind of standing between this 
State Board and the agricultural college, or the university or anything 
of that kind; each seemed to be working along their own line and 
from their own standpoint. There was no coming together of the 
practical experimenters of this state and the scientific men, who could 
tell you how the greatest possible yields could be obtained with the 
least expenditure and toil. We didn't seem to understand that, as 
practical farmers. To use an expression of the Mayor of Richmond, 
Virginia, when extending an address of welcome to the American 
Pomological Society some years ago: 

Bi was when Philosophy marched along the highway of earth, 
1 in lordly pride, which disdained all association with labor, 
it deigned to cast even a look across the hedge that divided </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
10 


L'arden and the field, it was .rn on tl 
and less intelligent brain, there ei Prom this two great evils reagriculture 
and every other form of fruitful labor 
the important aid of philosophy condlv, philosophy tbai 
powerful stimulus which profit lend* to every development Of li &gt; 
t. But within our memories all this has changed. The white hand 
i's the brown; the teeming brain has grasped the plow, pruning 1 
i and sickle, and tl • agencies for the betterment of our 
whom God hath joined, are no longer by man to be sundered -• 
pnd with what glorious resuli 

That idea took possession of me and I devoted myself to bring the 
I'niversity of Nebraska and this State Board of Agriculture In m 
and harmony in this work, and I think I was L, not al&lt;&gt;i 
He, but I think I first started it, and when a movement starts it 
always find help. And let me say, while this is probably not the 
time, yet I will say that the annual agricultural reports of the Neka 
State Board of Agriculture stand today higher than any other 
- in the I'nion. 

1 have been asked, why do you not fret out a large book annually, 
and quarterly Bulletin, such as Secretary Cobern of Kansas. My answer 
has been, and is. llr. Cobern is justly and well furnished by the 
with means to publish, and he get* out a model report. This Boar.: 
never had a penny provided for this work, and yet, I do not fear to 
our annual report brought in comparison with any other 
ultural report in the United States. This worth is attributable 
ly, if not wholly, to rateable contributions of our corps of scien- 
It is claimed the services of these men are too expensive. Your 
physician charges you five dollars for a ten minutes' visit. Why? 
Because, with years of education and qualification, lie is prepared, and 
has the ability, to meet the demand and emergency. So with I 
I repeat, I am always glad when we come up here and come 
'iitact with these people of the university. [Applause.] 

PRESIDENTS ANNUAL ADD 

En of the State Buard of AfriCliUmre: It has been the i 
of roar President, at the annual meeting of your body in 
to make a report of his doings during the year he has beM 
make such recommendations. a&gt; h« may see fit, for the 
re of the best interests of agriculture in Nebraska. 

find ourselves in a much better condition today than we wi 
ago. Then we had no home, so to speak, but the location of 
without means to buy. The question as to how we could M 
the means was fully discussed at our last annual meeting, and it *.vas 
finally decided to ask the legislature, which was then in session, for 
|ipropriation to buy grounds, and erect suitable buildings for the 
use of state fairs. A bill was drafted by the agriculture and horticulture 
society and presented to tin' ilt $35,000 
was appropriated for this puip </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
11 


distance of the city, with many good buildings and improvements that 
can be added to as necessity requires. 

During the year many improvements were made under the supervision 
of Messrs. Basset t a nl Budge of our Roard, with power to act, superintend 
improvements and O. K. bills being given them by the B 
Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings. 

The appropriation was all expended and more too, as will be shown 
in the reports of our Beeretarjr a irer. 

Our last fair wax a n ¦ dibit and finance, on account of 
the individual interest of those who were in any way connected with 
tli.- work. s 

It was not my privilege to be here very much during the summer 
and aid in the work, as I should like to have done. I?ut I was by no 
means Idle, ;i&gt; at tli" Pan-American Imposition in Buffalo, with the aid 
of others. I was advertising the n-reat state of Nebraska, and in more 
than one way our sister states fi.uud a worthy competitor in agriculture. 
We won a gold in thai alone should make our agrieult- 

K society feel proud. In coin we 
ms with our r 

were second, in sugar beets first. 

need not fear failure in making 

w 

our state fair better each su&lt; 

ar. I would suggest that night 

entertainments be considered by th 

in-coming board, as I learn from 
1hat last year they found it quite 

the secretary of the Iowa state fair 

profitable, and it was their first at 
It is with much pride I speak i 

nipt 

f the Horticultural Society, and I 
-ult of their showing at the 
permission the I Mr. ,1. H. 
isplay, and I will say I do not think 
or more competent man for the 
d will bear me out, since our 
that were our competitors. 

desire to bring before the board 

l'an-American Exposition. With my 

ihev eould have selected a bet 

place, and the 14 medals he captor 

i uf exposition to be held at St. Louis 
Iture l istanee possible 
in charge, to aid and assist them 
hey may not be handicapped at the 

uiterial with which to make 

a •howing 

State fairs and exposition! 

urce of education to all class 

people, for in them we see diversified exhibits for all products grown 
nnd manufaeiured. To this end ltt us all work for what we think l&gt;est 
for the uplifting and building of our next annual fair to be held A 
September. 5, inclusive. 

In compliance with law. the President had, l&gt;efore this Board coni. 
appointed an auditing committee, consisting of C. If. Ru 
chairman. T. A. M'Kay. 1. It. (aiitlin. Mr. Bodge being absent, 1' 

Hadkinson to take charge of their 

&gt;l*M)iiip by haying to rustle to pi 

¦ new compared with many others 
I would niffgest that in the cumin 

n HlO.i. the Stat&lt;- Bo«H of Agrk-iil 

o the vomniissioncrs who have it 

n the collecting of exhibits, that tl </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
12 



referred the accounts and reports of the Secretary and Treasurer. 

REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON CREDENTIALS. 

Your committee on credentials find the following named counties 

represented by the persons whose names follow: Franklin County, W. 

H. Arnold; Frontier, L. H. Cheney; Seward, F. Unitt; Harlan, W. H. 

Lewis; Hamilton, T. A. M'Kay; Merrick, D. J. Clark; Washington, A. C. 

s; York, R. B. Price; Kearney, T. B. Keele; Polk, L. A. Lawson; 

Pawnee, John R. Gosson; Sherman, W. R. Mellor; Hitchcock, C. O. 

is; Red Willow, J. W. Dutcher; Dawes, Charles Mann; Custer, J. J. 

Wilson; Lancaster, S. R. Hull; Jefferson, Joseph Helvey; Boone, H. C. 

Kruster; Clay, W. T. Johnson; Douglas, Smith Brown; Butler, C W. 

Derby; Saline, J. J. Burke; Merrick, R. M. Wolcott; Madison, Mark 

Richardson. H. L. Cook, 

W. A. Potster, 

L. Morse, 

Committee. 

Mr. Dinsmore moved that the report of the Committee on Credentials 

be received and permission be granted to add to as the delegates may 

report. Adopted. 

TREASURER'S ANNUAL REPORT, 1901 

Treasurer Edmund McTntyre submitted his annual report as follows: 

Annual Statement of E. Mclntyre, Treasurer of the Nebraska State Board of 

Agriculture. 

1901, Jan. 18. Dr. 

To balance on hand as shown by Auditor's report $391 73 

To bonus for printing premium list 50 00 

Money borrowed 500 00 

State appropriation, $3,000, premium on warrant, $15.00 3,015 00 

hs, 2,063 05 

Admission tickets, 25,045 at 50 cents 12,522 50 

Amphitheatre, 8,786 at 25 cents 2,196 50 

Dray permits 54 00 

Camping permits 29 00 

Quarter stretch receipts 119 50 

e cards 100 00 

s and pens 723 55 

Wagon permits 80 00 

Speed department 1,046 45 

t&amp; M. R. R. coupons, 11,396 at 50 cents; half coupons, 204 
at 25 cents 5,749 00 

Old typewriter sold 20 00 

Lincoln Traction Co 50 24 

Old lumber sold 117 36 </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
13 


Refunded by C, St. P., M. A. O. R. R $11 44 

Refunded by W. U. Tel. Co 3 87 

Kindling wood sold 16 20 

Old shafting sold 37 00 

Rebate on freight on premium lists 9 98 

1 1 penalties collected 56 05 

Total liabilities $28,962 36 

Credit by warrants paid, series of 1901 $26,146 27 

Credit by warrants paid, series 1897 262 83 

Credit by warrants paid, series 1900 5 00 

Cash to balance 2,548 26 

Total $28,962 36 $28,862 36 

Respectfully submitted this 

January 21, 1892, 

Edmund McIntyre, Treasurer. 

SECRETARY'S ANNUAL REPORT. 

The Secretary submitted his annual report as follows: 

To thr Xcbraska State Board of Agriculture — Sirs: In compliance with 

the law governing my official transactions as Secretary of the State 

Board of Agriculture, I hereby submit the annual report for the year 

ending December 31, 1901. 

The Treasurer's report shows in detail all itemized receipts of the 

Board for the year indicated. The Secretary's report presents, itemized. 

each warrant drawn, its date, to whom issued, and for what purpose. 

The following epitomized presentation shows more briefly the finan- 

cial expenditures of the Board to date: 

The total receipts and resources of the Board, including state aid 

$3,015, was $28,962.36. Of this sum there was expended in payment of 

premiums $10,903.71; for all other expenses, $15,380.72; leaving a bal- 

ance on hand of $2,677.93. 

The several heads of expenditures were: 

Labor preparing Fair Grounds $1,387 09 

Expense on Fair Grounds, material, etc 1,702 80 

Advertising Fair 1,090 50 

Miscellaneous 1,188 80 

Salaries 3,518 10 

Police expense on grounds : . . . 762 20 

Printing 1,094 75 

Paid superintendents, judges and experts 1,181 59 

Insurance 505 46 

Attractions 535 00 

Ice 175 49 

Expense of gates 266 70 


( 'lerk hire •• 409 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
14 


Treasurer's pay roll * $183 00 

Hotel bills, members' board, guests, etc 423 75 

Livery 12 00 

Horticultural Society, annual appropriation 500 00 

Kailroad switching 24 00 

freight, telegraph, and express 147 07 

$15,380 72 

CROPS FOB THE YEAR 1901. 

From the fact that annual reports from county societies are not 
due until this date, it is impossible for me to present the Board with 
compiled data at this meeting. Therefore, only estimates can be used 
to-day. 

Iie season of 1901, for a term of nearly six weeks in July and August, 
particularly characterized for the longest and most Intense 
ited term" known in the history of the state, thus affecting most 
&gt;usly our staple crop, corn. It is safe to say, however, considering 
corn belt of the state proper, with irrigated portions added, there 
¦ar an average half crop. In this connection it may be stated that 
price of corn renders the aggregate corn crop of 1901 of more value 
really than perhaps ever before. 

Small grain crops for the year, more especially fall wheat, were 
seldom better. The fall wheat crop was never better, both as to yield 
and quality. Spring wheat suffered. Prices of all crops were good. 
Thus, considering an aggregate, all crops in Nebraska, for the year 
1901, there is nothing to discourage persistent tillers of the soil. 

NEBRASKA STATE FAIR. 

The Nebraska State Fair, 1901, all things considered, was the most 
auspicious, encouraging and gratifying of any of its predecessors. 

From its first existence, until that year, it was but a sojourner; 
nomad; wanderer; on wheels; periodically placed upon the auction 
block, and knocked off to the highest bidder. Under these adverse environments, 
and risking fickle elements in addition, the law compelled 
the Board to hold annual fairs, improvising its own support. With 
these handicaps the Board, true to duty, has held annual fairs, thus 
serving the best interests of the state agriculturally. 

Thanks to the liberally exercised wisdom of the last Nebraska legislature, 
it now, for the first time in its history, is provided with a 
permanent abiding place. The management can now, with confidence 
and head erect, invite exhibitors and patrons to join in the work of 
placing resources and productions of the state before the people. 

In this connection it is warrantable, and a pleasure, to further say 
that, in my opinion, there has never been a more judicious and economical 
expenditure of a public appropriation than was made by the Board 
of Public Lands and Buildings with the $35,000 appropriated for this 
purpose. The improvements on the land purchased were really of more </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
15 


intrinsic value than the sum appropriated. Few fair grounds in the 
I'nited States are better equipped and more advantageously located 

Pit mistakes have at times been made in the management of Nea 
State Fairs and Expositions, none will deny. They are inevitable 
1 organizations. That our Fairs stand as models in essential 
cts, is the best evidence that as few errors, to say the least, occur 
us as with other like organizations in the United States. 

COUNTY AGRICULTURAL BOCIETIE8. 

County agricultural organizations, or societies, are most valuable 
coadjutors in the efforts of this State Board of Agriculture, more 
ially in its fair work. Beside holding their own local fairs, they 
have been near the sole presenters of agricultural products at State 
Fairs. Possibly there have been instances of abuse of the aid and 
support given by county authorities, as occurs not infrequently in 
similar matters. The great aim and results of county societies have 
been in the right direction, and results most beneficial. Hence the 
action of the last legislature was most unfortunate; in fact, was 
r:t to a death-blow to county agricultural societies, as organizations, 
Nebraska. 

ANNUAL VOLUME BEt&gt;ORT FOR 1900. 

Early in the last season, copy for this volume was promptly prepared, 
and placed in the hands of the' printer selected by the State Board of 
Printing. The work is not yet completed. Neither your Secretary nor 
the State Board of Agriculture have control or management of this 
work, hence should not be held responsible for tardiness or delay In 
printing. This statement is made that responsibility may rest where 
it belongs. 

Heretofore we have distributed 2,000 copies on the Fair Grounds during 
the State Fair, which saved us $180 postage. They have been called 
for to be used at Farmers' Institutes during the current season and 
sessions of these organizations more largely than ever before. For 
reasons above given I have not been able to supply. 

THE 8T. LOUIS EXPOSITION. 

Bring to the great "Louisiana Purchase Exposition," to be held 
ouis in the year 1903, permit digression, and individual expresy 
saying that, in my opinion, there has never been an exposition 
the United States more important," calling for the attention and 
ace of Nebraska. The Louisiana Purchase, as President Rooseappropriately 
said in his late message to Congress on this subject, 
"is one of three or four great landmarks In our history, — the 
great turning points in our development." Nebraska has become a 
most prominent factor in the territory embraced in this purchase, by 
reason of her unprecedented rapid and permanent illustrative development 
of her worth as one of the states of the Union. </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
16 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE. 

This is not the time nor the place to present more detailed reasons 
or arguments in favor of Nebraska being represented at this comingexposition. 
Governor Savage has wisely undertaken the task to this 
end. He, with the commissioners he has appointed, will acquaint the 
le of the state in all details. My purpose in referring to this 
enterprise is simply to call attention and urge our people to action, 
-hould be represented, and that in no penurious manner, but one 
commensurate with our standing and development in all things tending 
to a prosperous and promising commonwealth. 

FORESTRY AND IRRIGATION. 

E twin-kindred, inseparable developing factors, upon which the 
portion of Nebraska is so much interested and dependent for 
ural worth and standing, I am pleased to announce are well to 
,t. 

The older members of this Board will call to mind the expenditures 
by this organization, in both cash and time, for experimenting in planting 
trees in the Sand Hills, locating irrigating -experiment stations, and, 
in all ways possible, urging the attention of the General Government 
to the performance of a duty it owes to the people who have paid 
their money for lands represented to be of agricultural value, but 
found to be worthless, without irrigation and protection from sweeping 

K efforts have borne fruit to the extent that now the President of 
ted States, in his late message, urges the attention of Congress 
s important matters, in these words: 

"The wise administration of the forest reserves will be not less helpful 
to the interests which depend on water than to those who depend 
on wood and grass. The water supply itself depends upon the forest. 
In the arid regions it is water, not land, which measures productions. 
The western half of the United States would sustain a population 
greater than that of our whole country to-day, if the waters that now 
run to waste were saved and used for irrigation. The forest and water 
problems are, perhaps, the most vital internal questions of the United 

The Secretary of the Interior, before President Roosevelt gave these 
utterances, had brought the subjects before Congress. 

E Secretary of Agriculture, the past summer, put in the field an 
&gt;rps of investigators, who canvassed portions of Nebraska, anil 
¦d favorably as to the feasibility of tree planting and irrigation 
latic conservators. 

It is a pleasure to me, as one who has given years of thought and 
work in this direction, to know and report what is being done to render 
of agricultural value portions of our domain which has always been 
considered as the Great American Desert, if such ever existed. 

The outlook for Nebraska in these respects is encouraging, in that 
large sections of our lands may be reclaimed and utilized for agricultural 
purposes. Hence this paragraph in my report. </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
17 

REPOBT OK MEETING. 

Robt. W. Fumas, Secretary, in account irifh Nebnukm Mat* Board of 
Agriculture. 
Dk. 

aid and premium thereon $3,015 00 

• hs 2,063 05 

Speed l,04« 45 

Stalls and pens 563 55 

Borrowed money 500 00 

Old lumber sold from Fair Grounds 133 56 

1 card privilege 100 40 

Wagon permits 80 00 

Dray license 54 00 

Speed collections and penalties 56 05 

Lincoln Traction supplies 50 24 

Old shafting and pulleys sold from Fair Grounds 37 00 

Printing of premium lists 50 00 

Typewriter sold 20 00 

Rebate, C, St. P.. M. &amp; 0. R. R 11 44 

Rebate, freight on premium lists 9 98 

Rebate. \V. V. Telegraph 3 87 

$7,794 13 

Cs. 

By Treasurer, receipts $7,794 13 

StniS CHAIKiKI) TO THE TREASURER FOR THE TEAR 1901 

Ed. Mclntyre. Trewturn; tn State Board of Agriculture. 
Dr. 

hs $2,063 05 

Balance on hand 391 73 

i ved from the state 3,015 00 

Cash borrowed 500 00 

B. &lt;fe M. R. R. coupons 5,749 00 

&lt; General admission tickets 12,521 50 

Amphitheatre 2,196 50 

Drays 54 00 

(amp permits 29 00 

Quarter-stretch 119 50 

Wagon permits 80 00 

• cards 100 00 

Old typewriter sold 20 00 

Received Lincoln Tract ion Co 50 24 

Old 1-imber sold 117 3« 

Refund, C, St. P., M. &amp; O. R. R 11 44 

Ref und, W. U. Telegraph 3 87 

Kindlings sold 1* 20 

Old shafting sold 37 00 

». </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
18 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE. 

1 $l,04« 45 

Stalls and pens 723 55 

Bonus printing 1 premium lists 50 00 

Rebate, freight on premium lists 9 92 

Speed penalties collected 56 05 

Total receipts $28,962 36 

Warrants drawn to date 26,284 43 

$2,677 93 

WARRANTS ISSUED BY THE SI 

:CHETAI5Y FOR THE YEAR 1901: 

DATE, NUMBER. AMOUNT, TO WHOM ISSUED AND FOB WHAT 
PURPOSE. 

Date. To Whom Issued. No. For What Purpose. Prem. 

March 

14 Phillip Potter 

1 Bond, Secretary $12 50 

16 Robt. W. Pumas. 
16 Kobt. W. Furnas. 
16 Robt. W. Furnas. 

2 Salary, Jan., 1901 166 65 

3 Salary, Feb., 1901 166 65 

4 Office rent, fuel, lights, 
typewriting, clerical 

work for Jan., 1901.. 50 00 

16 Robt. W. Furnas. 

5 Office rent, fuel, lights, 
typewriting, clerical 

work for Feb., 1901. . 50 00 


1 Robt. W. Furnas 6 Salary, March, 1901... 166 65 

1 Robt. W. Furnas. 

7 Office rent, fuel, lights, 
typewriting, clerical 

work. March, 1901... 50 00 

t Phillip Potter 
r 

8 Bond, Treasurer 25 00 

1 Robt. W. Furnas. 
1 Robt. W. Furnas. 

9 Salary, April, 1901 166 65 

10 Office rent, fuel, lights, 
typewriting, clerical 

work, April, 1901 50 00 

1 E. E. Cole 11 Postage, April, 1901... 21 79 


1 Robt. W. Furnas. 
1 Robt. W. Furnas. 

12 Salary, May, 1901 16« 64 

13 Office rent, fuel, lights, 
typewriting, clerical 

work for May, 1901. . 50 00 


1 Robt. W. Furnas 14 Salary for June, 1901. . 166 65 

1 Robt. W. Furnas. 

15 Office rent, fuel, lights, 

typewriting, clerical 

work, June, 1901 . . </seg>



            <seg id="p023">
19 

Date. To Whom Issued. For What Purpose. Prem. Mise. 


B. Cole 16 Postage, June, 1901... $101 39 

15 C. H. Rudge 17 Borrowed money 500 00 

II. Rudge 18 Int. on $500 advanced 

for labor 5 83 

F. Fassett 19 Printing 9 50 

Am. Trot'g Ass'n 20 -Annual dues, 1901 35 00 

August 

B. Cole 21 Postage, July, 1901.... 29 94 

1 Kobt. W. Furnaa 22 vSalary, July, 1901 $166 AS 


1 Robt. W. Furnas 23 Office rent, fuel, lights. 

typewriting, clerical 

work, July, 1901 50 00 

1 J. B. Lewis 24 Frt.. Tel. and Ex., July, 

1901 30 23 

2 \V. M. Oilmore 25 Int. on time warrant 

No. 151, Mockett A 

Polk 3 71 

17 A. E. Moeller 26 Posting hangers 4 30 

September 

1 E. E. Cole 27 Postage 47 79 

2 Frank Peterson 28 Refund B. R. tickets.. 14 88 

2 J. R. Cantlin 29 Canvassing 32 50 

2 Clif. Calkins 30 Messenger 7 00 

3 J. B. Lewis 31 Frt., Tel. and Ex 32 17 

3 W. S. Russell 32 Poultry Judge 40 00 

4 Lafe Burnett 33 Canvassing 45 40 

4 Lafe Burnett 34 Canvassing 15 00 

4 W. V. Hyder 35 York Running Team.. $125 00 

4 Jack Ney 36 100-yd. foot race 5 00 

5 W. H. Barger 37 Canvassing 18 00 

;;. 

5 Robt. W. Furnas 38 Salary, Aug., 1901 166 AS 

5 Robt. W. Furnas 39 Office rent, fuel, lights. 

typewriting, clerical 

work for Aug., 1901. . 50 00 

5 0. S. West 40 Swine Judge 25 00 

5 W. Z. Swallow 41 Swine Judge 21 75 

I W. H. Stowell 42 Printing 107 75 

5 Omaha Camp No. 120 M.W.A. 43 First Prize 75 00 

5 So. Omaha Camp No. 1095 M 

W. A 44 Second Prize 50 00 

5 G. W. Overmier 4j Part police pay roll. . . 100 00 

5 Capital City Camp No. 190, 

M. W. A 46 Third prize 25 00 </seg>


            <seg id="p024">
20 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AORICULTI'RB. 

Date. To \\ horn Issued. 
September 

No. For What Purpose. Prem. Misc. 

6 C. N. Moody... 
6LW. Leonard. 
6 L. R. Fletcher. 

48 Premiums $50 00 

49 Supt Class C $35 40 

50 Supt. Corn 18 72 

6 E. Reynolds &amp; Son. 
6 W. H. Barger 

51 Premiums 75 00 

52 Supt. Class B 26 39 

6 H. L. Cook 

53 Supt. Class M 35 32 

6 G..R. Williams. 
6 T. A. McKay... 
6 Jno. Barr 

54 Supt. Amphitheatre... 15 00 

55 Supt. Class A 38 20 

56 Judge Class A 20 00 

57 Ass't Class 22 20 

BRuthford . 
. Eggart... 
. Eggart . . . 
. Lydick... 
. Waite 
. Overmier. 
orse 

58 Premiums 50 00 

59 Labor 6 00 

60 Supt. Class 17 91 

61 Clerk at gate 3 00 

62 Ap. police roll 200 00 

63 Supt. Class F 12 00 

BDinsmore 
McClanahan. 
. Kennedy 

64 Supt. Class B 32 00 

65 Ass't Supt. Class B 19 55 

66 Judge Class B 50 00 

67 Premiums 60 00 

6 Lewis Bros 

68 Premiums 10 00 

6 Peter Johnson 
6 M. V. Perkins. 
• L. A. Kent.... 

69 Premiums, Dundy Co.. 60 00 

70 Clerk Farm Products, 12 00 

KGeo. McKerrow &amp; Sons 
Win. Foster 

71 Premiums 75 00 

72 Pay Roll 148 00 

« J. E. Miller 

73 Premiums 50 00 

« J. H. McAllister. 
6 Robt. Taylor ... 

74 Premiums 10 00 

75 Premiums 50 00 

EK. M. Mclntyre... 
Mrs. W. A. Wooley 
D. W. Evans 

7G Treas. pay roll 183 00 

77 Ass't Supt. Class I 24 00 

78 Ice attendant 16 00 

79 Stenographer to Bd 24 00 

6 Emily A. Cook.. 
M. Searle, Jr. 
6 S. B. Moflett 
6 W. S. Harlan.... 

80 Gate keeper roll 150 00 

81 Clerk to Secretary 36 00 

82 Clerk to Secretary 24 00 

7 J. S. Pedlar. 
7 O. M. Keats. 

83 Judge speed 12 00 

84 Jumping horse 35 00 

R. Searle, Jr. 
. Overmier.. 
. Odell 

85 Salary and pay roll... 116 70 

86 Balance police 418 20 

87 Meals to workmen 7 10 

Ker Reade . 
:. Ewing.. 
reenmeyre 
. McComb. 

88 Meals for firemen 11 44 

89 Judge Class 0 19 80 

90 Judge Class 0 6 00 

91 Judge Class F 12 00 
</seg>

            <seg id="p025">
21 

September 


Rf. Pearin.. 
E. McBride 
i Adams . . 
i M. Vance 

92 Judge Class F *-'O 00 

93 Expert Textile Dept.. 20 00 

94 Ass't Supt. Text. Dept. 18 10 

95 Work Textile Dept.... 16 00 

7 Mrs. M. M. Presson. 
7 Cbas. Mann 

96 Supt. Textile Dept 36 00 

97 Supt. Forage M 53 

7 Mrs. H. L. Worker. 
7 H. G. Ekman 

98 Labor 7 50 

99 Messenger to Presid't, 16 00 

100 Tickets received 5 00 

7 ( . E. Hayme. 

101 Speed $60 00 

3 Bradenburg &amp; Stall. 
4 C. C. Owen 

102 Speed 20 00 

4 J. H. Milez 

103 Speed 10 00 

4 W. H. Plourd. 
5 W. H. Plourd 
5 F. C. Owen... 
5 G. A. Curry.. 
5 E. C. Holland 
5 O. M. Keatz.. 
5 H. A. Willis.. 
5 C. D. Bell.... 

104 Speed 55 00 

105 Speed 20 00 

106 Speed 10 00 

107 Speed 135 00 

108 Speed 60 00 

109 Speed 60 00 

110 Speed 30 00 

Ill Speed 30 00 

5 F. St. Brown 
5 M. J. Brown 
5 J. T. Wright 
5 C. H. Roby 
5 C. H. Roby 
6 J. K. Strohm 
6 J. N. Patterson. 
5 J. N. Patterson . . 
5 Fred Woodcock 
5 Fred Woodcock 
5 J. B. Davis 

112 Speed 180 00 

113 Speed 135 00 

114 Speed 135 00 

115 Speed \ 15 00 

116 Speed 135 00 

117 Speed 40 00 

118 Speed 16 00 

119 Speed 119 00 

120 Speed 65 00 

121 Speed 125 00 

122 Speed 30 00 

5 Wm. Wallace ... 
S Wm. Wallace . . . 
5 W. H. Crow 
5 W. H. Crow 
5 D. H. Cool 
."j Win. Spohn 
5 Wm. Spohn 
5 J. P. Elmore 
5 J. P. Elraore.... 
5 W. H. Plourd... 
I W. H. Plourd 
6 H. K. Patterson. 

123 Speed 25 00 

124 Speed 50 00 

125 Speed 33 00 

126 Speed 147 00 

127 Speed 40 00 

128 Speed 60 00 

129 Speed 5 00 

130 Speed 70 00 

131 Speed 15 00 

132 Speed 20 00 

133 Speed 5 00 

134 Speed 50 00 

135 Speed 90 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
22 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AOR1 

Date. To Whom Issued. 

No. For What Purpose. Prem. Misc. 

September 

Fred Woodcock . . 
\V. Y. Johnson 
W. Y. Johnson 
F. A. Smith 
O. M. Keats 
F. A. Reynolds 
Q. W. Augubright. 
C. A. Wallace 

136 Speed $40 00 

137 Speed 8 00 

138 Speed 12 00 

139 Speed 135 00 

140 Speed 60 00 

141 Speed 30 00 

142 Speed 10 00 

143 Speed 7 50 

tj. H. Miles. 
J. H. Miles. 

144 Speed 9 00 

145 Speed 6 00 

6 Geo. F. Dickman. 
7 C. E. Pierce 

146 Speed Clerk $40 00 

147 Clerk to Secretary 52 00 

7 Ed. Ewan 

148 Clerk to Secretary 15 00 

KFordyce ... 
A. Itoyce 
S. C. Wilson. 
Humphrey . 
Stilson 

149 Supt. Class 24 00 

150 Clerk to Secretary 84 00 

151 Clerk to Secretary 7 00 

152 Clerk to Secretary 2 00 

153 Supt. Class 24 00 

7 \V. H. Plourd.... 
\V. Shamtnon. 
J. Ronin 

154 Speed 41 25 

155 Speed Timer 8 00 

156 Speed Judge 9 00 

7 \V. H. Green. 

157 Wall paper 6 10 

Planing Mill. 
7 H. M. Shaefter.... 

158 Sawdust 25 

159 Ass't Secretary 56 00 

7 J. R. Cantlin.. 
7 A. P. Job 
7 Aaron Sullivan 
7 O. U. Loch ... 

160 Supt. Ag. Hall 46 30 

161 Ass't Supt 18 85 

162 Messenger 6 00 

163 Clerk to President. ... 27 00 

K. Le welling. 
Journal . . 

164 Supt. Class E 36 10 

165 Supplies and printing 

for 1900 82 30 

K Journal . . 
Ass'n Fairs. 
G. Furnas. . 
. Druse 

166 Advertising for 1900. . . 2 25 

167 Dues 25 00 

168 Account Concessions. . 215 10 

169 Master Transportat'n, 75 00 

7 Pawnee City Band. 
7 W. A. Howard 

170 Music 500 00 

171 Ass't Class G 18 00 

7 F. A. Graham. 
Mclntyre . . 
\rnold .... 

172 Horse and buggy 10 00 

173 Treasurer 210 00 

174 Judge Class 0 9 00 

¦P. McCreary. 
Clark 

175 Starting Judge 40 00 

176 Scott's Bluff County, 
Premiums 50 00 

7 J. H. Masters. 

177 Judge Class K 1 50 </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
REPORT OF ANNUAL MEETING. 

23 

Datp. w\ iioxn Issued. 
September 

No. For What Purpose. Prem. Misc. 

7 J. J. Ingram. 
7H. Jeger .... 

178 Fixing water tank $1 55 

179 Judge Class P 9 00 

7 E. L. Vance 
7 G. S. Leininger. 
7 W. A. Hauers.. 
7 F. M. Crow 

180 Salary and expense... 308 30 

181 Clerk to Board 33 00 

182 Judge Class J 3 00 

183 Ass't Class M 28 45 

7 E. L. Vance. 

184 Special police 40 00 

7 Clark &amp; McDonald.... 
7 Neb. Exposition Ass'n. 
7 Dr. R. E. Giffen 

185 Insurance 75 97 

186 Insurance 245 45 

187 Prof, serrice 5 00 

7 Mrs. F. M. Hall. 
7 J. B. Lewis 

188 Supt. Class H 30 00 

189 Frt., Tel. and Express, 

Dec, 1901 7 11 

7 J. B. Lewis 
7 J. B. Lewis 

190 Ex. for Jan., 1901 1 90 

191 Frt., Ex. and Tele., 

Feb., 1901 5 07 

7 J. B. Lewis. 

192 Frt., Ex. and Tel- 

March, 1901 7 83 

7 J. B. Lewis. 

193 Frt., Ex. and Tel., 

April, 1901 6 07 

7 J. B. Lewis. 

194 Frt., Ex. and Tel- 

May, 1901 6 80 

7 J. B. Lewis. 

195 Frt., Ex. and Tel.. 

June, 1901 20 45 

7 J. B. Lewis... 
7E. E. Cole.... 
7C. J.Tracy... 
7 K. W. Furnas. 

196 Ex. for July, 1901 1 00 

197 Postage, May, 1901 21 53 

198 Police 4 00 

199 Money paid out during 

Fair 20 85 

7 Mrs. S. C. Langworthy. 
7 P. F. Youngers, Jr 

200 Judge 9 00 

201 Salary 200 00 

7 a C. Bassett 
7 a C. Bassett 
7E. Filler ••• 

202 Salary 200 00 

203 Postage and Tel 7 55 

204 Salary 200 00 

7 State Journal 
7 Void 

205 Supplies 405 70 

206 Void 

7 W. E. Mellor. 

207 Tickets, Tel., Postage, 5 03 

7 Budge A Guenzel 

208 Part payment on h'd 

bill 150 00 

7 Auburn Post 

209 Cut for Bulletin No. 1, 4 00 

7 O'Flying Printing Co. 
7 Hotel Lindell 

210 Stickers 10 00 

211 Managers' bd. bill 423 75 

7 C. H. Rudge. 
7 E. L. Vance. 

212 Salary 200 00 

213 Exo. to Des Moines... 12 50 </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
24 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGBICUI.Tl BE. 

Date. To Whom Issued. 
September 

No. For What Purpose. Prem. Misc. 

7 W. R. Mellor. 

214 Salary $^00 00 

7 Lincoln Tent &amp; Awn'g Co 
7 .7. ('. Seacrest 

215 Rent of tents 165 00 

216 Supt. Mer. Hall 24 00 

¦Hort. Society. 
s. Scully 

217 April App'n 500 00 

218 Salary. July, Aug. and 

September 62 49 

Tent A Awning Co.. 
7 Dierks Lumber Co 

219 Rent of tent 85 00 

220 Rent building 85 00 

KBushnell .. 
A Guenzel. 

221 Write up St. Fair 35 00 

222 Fish globes 7 20 

Kerald Dry Goods Co 
In Ice Co 

223 Merchandise 21 60 

224 Ice 175 49 

7 F. G. Odell. 

225 Labor 229 38 

F\m. Trotting Ass'n. 
Lincoln Drug Co 

226 Speed supension col... 35 30 

227 Supplies 6 00 

10 Nat. Manufacturing Co.. 
10 Harry Porter 

228 Supplies 4 20 

229 Pencils 2 95 

10 Western Supply Co. 
10 B. O. Koster 

230 Merchandise 14 78 

231 Glass, etc 7 80 

10 T. L. Lyon . . 
10 E. Whitcomb 

232 St. Ini. Ex 133 43 

233 Supt. Class K 24 00 

10 Odell Construction Co. 
13 Geo. B. Simpkins 

234 Signs 7 50 

235 App'n Fish Exhibit.. 240 50 

14 Lincoln Traction Co. 
16 C. H. Rudge 

236 Cartage 3 00 

237 Pay roll 50 76 

16 Robt. W. Furnas. 
16 Robt. W. Furnas. 
16 Billboard 

238 Cartage, 1900 9 80 

239 Phone service 9 60 

240 Advertising 1 80 

16 O. C. Williams . 
16 W. H. Kearney. 
16 Fred Pahl 

241 Canvassing 36 75 

242 Canvassing 33 00 

243 Canvassing '. . 33 00 

16 D. L. Allen 
16 Muhahill Co. .. 
16 Miller &amp; Paine. 
16 E. H. Wilke 
16 Neb. Tel. Co 

244 Canvassing 57 00 

245 Canvassing 6 00 

246 Supplies 12 00 

247 Service Class E 15 00 

248 Telephones 25 50 

16 Hunter-Woodruff Co 
16 Rees Printing Co 
16 Independent 

249 Printing 34 25 

250 Hangers and tickets. . 249 00 

251 Advertising 25 00 

16 Neb. Farmer . 
16 Farmer's Voice 

252 Advertising 20 00 

253 Advertising 10 00 

16 Spirit of the West. 
:6 Iowa Homestead . . 
IS Farmer &amp; Breeder. 

254 Advertising 10 00 

255 Advertising 10 00 

256 Advertising 10 00 </seg>


            <seg id="p029">
25 

Date. To Whom Issued. 
September 

No. For What Purpose. Prem. Misc. 

18 Nat. Printing Co 
18 Prairie Farmer 
16 Kan. &amp; Neb. Farmer. 
16 Breeders Gazette 

257 Advertising $:jn 00 

258 Advertising 10 00 

259 Ad vertising 10 00 

260 Advertising 9 60 

16 World Herald 
16 Omaha Bee . . 

261 Advertising 75 00 

262 Advertising 75 00 

16 State Journal Co 
16 Swine Breeder 
16 Zehrung, Bill Poster. 
16 S. E. Upton 

263 Advertising 200 00 

264 Advertising 50 00 

265 Posting bills 3 00 

266 Labor 18 00 

16 a E. Upton 
16 A. O. Greenlee . . . 
16 B. W. Richards... 
16 Folsom Bros. Co. 
16 City of Lincoln... 
16 Palace Stable 

267 Police 4 00 

268 Ass't Supt., Class H.. 16 00 

269 Insurance 95 04 

270 Insurance 89 00 

271 Men Water Dept 33 00 

272 Livery 1 00 

16 Wm. Foster 

273 General Supt 36 00 

16 Faruth Printing Co. 
16 H. Clement 

274 Printing 23 00 

275 Fire Dept 25 28 

16 Telegraph Co 

276 Messages 3 87 

eR'y Guide Co. 
W. Furnas.. 
W. Furnas.. 

277 Nat. R. R. Guide 5 0* 

278 Salary for Sept., 1901, 166 61 

279 Office rent, fuel, lights, 
typewriting, clerical 

work for Sept., 1901, 50 01 

(Htolx'r 

3 G. H. Ross. 

280 Saline County Coll. 

3 N. Withrow 

3 Blodgett Bros. . 
3 J. O. Hallerman. 

284 Void 

3 O. P. Dovel. 

285 Nemaha Co. Coll. Ex.. 152 
286 Brown Co. Coll. Ex... 95 

f.s 

¦ H. Baldwin. 
Clark 

S4 

287 Scotfs Bluff Co. Coll 

Exhibit 30 00 

;i V. Peterson . 
3 M. W. Smith. 

288 Cuming Co. Coll. Ex.. 168 

r&gt;2 

289 Washington Co. Coll 

Exhibit 240 00 

3 H. Schickedantz 
3 A. P. Job 

290 Howard Co. Coll. Ex.. 80 
291 Burt County Coll. Ex. 127 
292 York County Coll. Ex. 126 

00 

.-,6 

3 L. D. Stilson. 
3 W. Z. Taylor. 
3 C. C. Wright.. 

04 

293 Hitchcock Co. Coll. Ex. 80 

00 

294 Thomas Co. Coll. Ex.. 4 

« 

Exhibit $161 28 
281 Merrick Co. Coll. Ex.. 84 68 
282 Gage Co. Coll. Ex 124 64 
283 Cheyenne Co. Coll. Ex. 80 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
26 


Date. To Whom Issued. 
October 

No. For What Purpose. Prem. Misc. 

3 L. Morse . 
3 E. E. Cole. 

293 Dun&lt;iy Co. Coll. Ex 986 88 

296 Postage for Sept $6 18 

3 Jno. B. Lewis. 

297 Frt., Tel., etc., for 

Sept., 1901 12 8« 

. Class &amp; Paint Co. 
28 W. U. Tel. Co 

298 Supplies 21 30 

299 Service 4 57 

28 Mrs. F. Hall. 
September 

300 Supt. salary 3 00 

20 E. H. Andrews. 
20 Seth Abbott ... 

301 Premium 9 60 

302 Premium 2 00 

Arriga 

303 Premium 5 00 

rMrs. M. M. Allen. 
Alfred Ableman . 
20 E. F. Black 

304 Premium 4 00 

305 Premium 1 00 

306 Premium 43 20 

20 Bobt. Black . . 
20 I. E. Baldwin . . 
20 J. H. Blodgett. 
20 C. C. Blodgett. 

307 Premium 51 00 

308 Premium 9 60 

309 Premium 46 40 

310 Premium 50 

311 Premium 14 40 

BBriggs &amp; Son. 
an A Fitch 
. Blodgett 

312 Premium 13 60 

313 Premium 27 20 

314 Premium 21 60 

20 Blodgett Bros. 
20 C. H. Ballinger. 

315 Premium 25 00 

316 Premium 128 80 

¦i. Lucy J. Barger. 
E. Bowman 

317 Premium 11 10 

318 Premium 9 60 

20 B. L. Ball. 

319 Premium 1 50 

20 Mrs. C. A. Blanchard. 
20 Mrs. Jennie Birdsall.. 
20 F. H. Brown 

320 Premium 12 00 

321 Premium 16 80 

322 Premium 2 40 

20 F. M. Booth. 

323 Premium 3 50 

20 J. H. C. Brewer. 
20 J. H. Ballard 
20 C. F. Boyd 

324 Premium 4 80 

325 Premium 18 20 

326 Premium 1 50 

20 W. H. Baldwin. 
20 N. D. Blood.... 
20 L. Butts 

327 Premium 7 40 

328 Premium 5 00 

329 Premium 1 00 

20 S. Brollier . 
20 Otto Berger 

330 Premium 1 00 

331 Premium 1 00 

20 Mrs. S. B. Butler. 
20 M. Bitters 

332 Premium 1 00 

333 Premium 6 70 

20 Mrs. E. C. Barr. . . . 
*0H. H. Bagg 
20 Mrs. H. M. Brock. 

334 Premium 1 00 

335 Premium 8 50 

336 Premium 14 2S </seg>


            <seg id="p031">
27 

Ufttc l o u hnm Issued. 
September 

No. For What Purpose. 


BMrs. Ida Bennett. 
C. R. Blood 

337 Premium $10 25 

338 Premium 50 

20 Beatrice Cr'y Co. . 
20 Mrs. A. L. Brown. 
20 Helen S. Bacon... 
20 Alice Blanchard . . 
20 Mark M. Coad 
20 I. W. Chappell 

339 Premium 4 40 

340 Premium 8 00 

341 Premium 3 00 

342 Premium 2 00 

343 Premium 69 60 

344 Premium 8 00 

ECottrell Bros 
Wm. Clark 
20 H. W. Cranzler 
20 E. M. Coffin &amp; Son. 
20 A. C. Clark 

345 Premium I 57 60 \ 

346 Premium 12 00 

347 Premium 92 00 

348 Premium 3 90 

349 Premium 9 60 

20 Cottle Bros. . . 
20 Arthur Clark . 
20 Paul E. Cook. 
20 J. J. Cooper . . 
20 U. Cochelin . . . 

350 Premium 2 40 

351 Premium 3 50 

352 Premium 50 

353 Premium 5 40 

354 Premium 20 70 

20 J. L. Cone. 

355 Premium 2 00 

20 Murray Cameron 
20 J. E. L. Carey... 

356 Premium 1 50 

357 Premium 1 50 

20 M. Clark 

358 Premium 2 40 

20 A. R. Carruth . 
20 R. W. Cates. . . . 
20 C. W. Conkling. 
20 Edw. Cochelin . 
20 I. Cecha 

359 Premium 1 50 

360 Premium 1 00 

361 Premium 2 00 

362 Premium 1 00 

363 Premium 1 00 

20 Mrs. W. H. Cotton... 
20 Mary Hope Cabell... 
20 Mrs. A. Cooper 
20 Mrs. A. E. Converse. 
20 Mrs. H. J. Crawford. 
20 Mrs. N. Cherrout... 
20 C. H. Collins 

364 Premium 2 00 

365 Premium 1 00 

366 Premium 4 00 

367 Premium 2 00 

368 Premium 7 00 

369 Premium 1 00 

370 Premium 2 40 

20 Earl Cline 
20 J. B. Davis 
20 N. a Donner 
20 J. C. Doubt 
20 P. A C. DawBon. 
20 J. C. Day A Son. 
20 Casper Dice 

371 Premium 2 00 

372 Premium 8 00 

373 Premium 13 60 

374 Premium 76 00 

375 Premium 25 60 

376 Premium 8 50 

377 Premium 40 80 

20 Mrs. F. W. Doyle. 
80 F. B. Dury 

378 Premium 12 00 

379 Premium 3 90 

20 H. M. Davenport. 

380 Premium 1 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
28 



r*o. For \» hat Purpose 


1*. Dovel 

381 Premium $23 60 

20 A. H. Dingee 
I). Davis 
T. Dresler 
&gt;. (). M. Druse. 

382 Premium 1 50 

383 Premium 8 70 

384 Premium 2 00 

385 Premium 1 00 

L'ii Mrs. A. Dewett... 
rtha Denman . 

386 Premium 2 50 

387 Premium 1 00 

.'0 Mrs. C. P. Dybra. 
Danwalter 

388 Premium 1 50 

389 Premium 2 50 

20 Klizabelh Dalan . 
20 Mrs. W. R. Davey 
"_'O Aup. C. Duvidson. 
20 J. C. Edwards 
20 L. E. Emerson . . . 
20 E. H. Eggert 

390 Premium 7 25 

391 Premium 1 00 

392 Premium 28 80 

393 Premium 20 00 

394 Premium 8 00 

395 Premium 64 90 

20 E. H. Egbert. 
20 D. W. Evans... 
20 Swan Elmund 

396 Premium 10 00 

397 Premium 15 60 

398 Premium 1 00 

399 Premium 1 50 

EL M. Easterday 
C. Emberson 
Bryant 

400 Premium 1 00 

401 Premium 2 40 

~sie Erford 
20 \V. II. Eppers. 
20 Void 

402 Premium 50 

403 Premium 2 50 

404 Void 

E Albert Emberson 
Alex Francke . . . 

405 Premium 12 80 

406 Premium 2 40 

20 F. Frekll.y . . 
1). Fraley . 
20 Sam'l Forest 
U Freeman 
20 J. B. Finnicy. 

407 Premium 12 00 

408 Premium 5 40 

409 Premium 5 00 

410 Premium 8 00 

411 Premium 1 00 

20 Mrs. S. E. Furnas. 
20 M. Filkins 

412 Premium 7 90 

413 Premium 1 00 

rt. A. Frisehett. 
s. C. E. Finch.. 
20 Anna Fulk 

414 Premium 50 

415 Premium 2 40 

416 Premium 2 00 

20 F. Ferris 

417 Premium 3 00 

20 Dora Frankfurter 
G. Fordyce... 
aude Fordyce . 
L. Glinm 

418 Premium 2 00 

419 Premium 3 20 

420 Premium 3 20 

421 Premium 16 00 

K. Glissman, Jr. 
. Grau 

422 Premium 8 00 

423 Premium 5 60 

H. Green. 

424 Premium 6 30 </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
29 



September 

Pio. t or iV h&amp;t r urpoM. 

f Goldsburg 

425 Premium $2 50 

20 Mrs. A. D. Gilmore. 
20 Mrs. G. H. Grassner. 
M Mrs. M. Glenn 

426 Premium 8 00 

427 Premium 4 50 

428 Premium 1 00 

429 Premium 5 50 

430 Premium 12 00 

431 Premium 9 00 

432 Premium 3 50 

433 Premium 7 25 

434 Premium 1 50 

435 Premium 1 00 

436 Premium 50 

¦jo Mrs. A. Greenameyer. 
20 Mrs. G. G. Grinm 

437 Premium 3 00 

438 Premium 1 00 

K.Mrs. H. Goodell. 
J. Holin 

439 Premium 4 00 

440 Premium 3 20 

¦JO K. C. Holland . . 
20 J. E. Hess '. 
BL. Hunter.. 
H. Hamilton. 
F. Hollum.. 
s. S. S. Hall.. 
; Hilter 

441 Premium 8 00 

442 Premium 27 20 

443 Premium 149 60 

444 Premium 24 00 

445 Premium 1 50 

.446 Premium 1 50 

447 Premium 5 40 

448 Premium 5 40 

B. Hal len back. 
Huntington. 
offmeister . . . 
Alice Uiatt.. 
Healea 

449 Premium 4 80 

. 450 Premium 8 20 

451 Premium 3 90 

452 Premium 4 90 

rank Hamilton 
20 Jas. Hall 

453 Premium 2 40 

454 Premium 3 00 

455 Premium 11 00 

20 Mrs. E. Harrington, 
i una Hudelson 

456 Premium 50 

457 Premium 4 50 

458 Premium 50 

M Mrs. L. A. Hall 
20 Mr». C. L. Hooper 
:!0 .Mrs. Lola Hetrick 
ss Ethelyn Hooper. 
20 Anna Haas 

459 Premium 2 00 

460 Premium '2 00 

461 Premium 2 00 

462 Premium 7 50 

20 Mrs. Estelle Hayden. 
L H. Hunter 

463 Premium 4 00 

464 Premium 50 

465 Premium 50 

466 Premium 10 80 

467 Premium 1120 

Ks Holmes 
ew Hansen 

468 Premium 10 20 

IWm. Gallop 
Greer 
Clara Gallop... 
L. S. Grule 
A. G. Greenlee. 
M. Graffe 
Gaskill 
ardner 

D. Harris. 

20 Lily E. Harris. 
20 J. Hess </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
32 


September 

No. For What Purpose. 


20 C. G. Nootz. 

557 Premium $16 00 

20 Nixon &amp; McLaughlin. 
20 M. E. Newborn 

558 Premium 89 60 

559 Premium 184 00 

20 T. L. Norval 
20 Nebr. Rabbitry 
20 Mrs. C. Nelson. 
20 Mrs. C. Nelson.. 
SO Mrs. O. Nelson. 
&lt;lw. Orr 

560 Premium 25 70 

561 Premium 1 50 

562 Premium 1 70 

563 Premium 30 

564 Premium 2 00 

565 Premium 4 00 

E. J. G. Odell. 
&gt;ie Owens ... 
t C. Owens . . . 
20 Otto J. May 

566 Premium 7 40 

567 Premium 2 00 

568 Premium 4 00 

569 Premium 6 40 

20 J. Edw. Parrish. 
20 L. T. Paugh 
20 M. E. Plank 

570 Premium 4 80 

571 Premium 8 00 

572 Premium 4 00 

20 T. Phelan 

573 Premium 8 80 

20 Ithiel Payne . . . 
20 X. J. Peterson... 
20 Anton Prote . . . 
20 M. V. Perkins... 
20 Frank Peterson 
20 .1. \V. Patterson. 
L. Parsons... 
20 A. M. Patterson. 
SO Jes. Pike 

574 Premium 7 80 

575 Premium 2 40 

576 Premium 4 00 

577 Premium 6 50 

578 Premium 51 70 

579 Premium 6 90 

580 Premium 1 50 

581 Premium 1 50 

582 Premium 3 00 

¦E. Peterson 
V. Persons. 

583 Premium 3 00 

584 Premium 2 00 

20 Pound &amp; Slaughter. 
20 Mrs. Eli Plummer... 
20 Mrs. Anna Pettitt . . . 
20 Mrs. L. M. Pratt 
20 Ann Parks 

585 Premium 2 00 

586 Premium 2 40 

587 Premium 1 50 

588 Premium 1 00 

589 Premium 4 20 

20 Mrs. H. Presson. 
20 Gay Palmer 

590 Premium 2 00 

591 Premium 6 00 

20 Mrs. M. J. Phillips. 
20 A. J. Paulson 

592 Premium 3 00 

593 Premium 10 20 

20 Mrs. M. J. H. Pinkerton 
20 F. W. Retzloff 

. 594 Premium 2 00 

595 Premium 24 00 

PN. Rogers. 
N. Rogers. 

596 Premium 12 00 

597 Premium 53 60 

20 Ed. Reynolds &amp; Son. 
Rowland &amp; Son.. 
20 A. Rowland &lt;fe Son. . 

598 Premium 90 60 

599 Premium 10 00 

600 Premium 89 20 </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
33 


Date. To Whom Issued. 
September 

No. 

For What Purpose. 

Prem. Misc. 

20 Geo. S. Root. 
80 Win. Reim ... 

601 Premium $4 00 

602 Premium 4 00 

20 J. A. Rudge. 

603 Premium 37 70 

20 Ridgway Poultry Yds 
20 Ridgway Belgian Hare Co 
20 G. H. Ross 

604 Premium 3 20 

605 Premium 3 SO 

606 Premium 28 80 

23 F. W. Rinecar 
23 G. W. Retzloff. 

607 Premium 2 40 

608 Premium 2 00 

23 Mrs. W. J. Robinson. 
23 Mrs. K. Randolph 
23 Mrs. E.. Raphael. ...... 

609 Premium 13 90 

610 Premium 4 00 

611 Premium 14 40 

23 L. A. Reeder.. 
23 Kate Randolph 

612 Premium .... 7 40 

613 Premium 100 

23 Fannie M. Richardson. 
23 Maud C. Rugh 

614 Premium 3190 

615 Premium 1 00 

23 Mrs. J. W. Rees... 
23 Mrs. A. Randolph. 
23 C. H. Rockwell 
23 Ella A. Royce 
23 Sanford Shirley . . 
23 E. M. Shumbarger. 
23 A. L. Sullivan 

616 Premium 4 40 

617 Premium 4 00 

618 Premium 2 00 

619 Premium 1 00 

620 Premium 9 60 

621 Premium 8 80 

622 Premium 29 60 

23 F. A. Smith... 
»3 W. M. Stewart 

623 Premium 20 00 

624 Premium 4 00 

23 G. P. Schwab &amp; Son 
23 Stanton Breed'g Farm. 
23 D. N. Syford 

625 Premium 8 00 

626 Premium 140 00 

627 Premium 92 00 

23 J. B. Smith . . . 
23 H. G. Sims . . . 
KE. O. Spencer 
C. H. Searle.. 

628 Premium 58 40 

629 Premium 4 00 

630 Premium 7 80 

631 Premium 10 40 

23 Sure Hatch Poultry Co. 
23 A. R. Smith 

632 Premium 170 30 

633 Premium 3. 00 

23 W. B. Swisher. 
23 R. Stryker . . . 

634 Premium 1 50 

635 Premium 23 70 

23 E. F. Smith.. 
23 Larry Scully 
23 Aug. Schmidt 
23 Lee Smith . . . 
23 M. H. Smith . 
23 Harry Seltz . 
23 W. P. Scott.. 
23 I.. T). Stilson. 

636 Premium 8 40 

637 Premium 1 00 

638 Premium 2 40 

639 Premium 37 90 

640 Premium *25 50 

641 Premium 4 80 

642 Premium 2 40 

643 Premium 23 00 

23 Henry S. Stilson. 

644 Premium 5 60 

3 </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
34 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD. OF AGRICULTURE. 

September 

No. For What Purpose. 


23 L. Spellman 

645 Premium $5 90 

EJ. Schwindhelm 
F. J. Steen 

646 Premium 1 50 

647 Premium 2 40 

23 Lou Sweet 

648 Premium 2 00 

KPaul Milling Co. 
. J. A. Shore 
'. Seymore 

649 Premium 2 00 

650 Premium 2 00 

651 Premium 2 00 

S3 Mrs. J. D. Slade. 

652 Premium 3 00 

23 Mrs. S. C. Safford 653 Premium 2 40 

Irs. S. C. Sherman. 
23 J. Shuin 

654 Premium 1 00 

655 Premium 1 00 

23 Jas. Steger 
23 C. Seimiller 
23 E. M. Smith 
rs. C. Spears. . . 
Era. C. I. Smith. 
Schonlan 

656 Premium 2 40 

657 Premium 1 50 

658 Premium 1 00 

659 Premium 2 40 

660 Premium 4 00 

661 Premium I 00 

23 Bertha Spooner 
SMary C. Swihart 
E. Sanzelin 

662 Premium * 2 00 

663 Premium 50 

664 Premium 1100 

23 Geo. A. Smith. 
¦Si W. W. Towle.. 
23 R. Taylor 

665 Premium 19 45 

666 Premium 6 40 

667 Premium 4 00 

K. Tomson &amp; Son 
H. Thurman 

668 Premium 139 20 

669 Premium 64 00 

23 G. W. Trone A Son. 
23 W. H. Taylor 

670 Premium 143 20 

671 Premium 23 20 

3 Robt. Taylor 
3 W. Z. Taylor 
I A. Talcott. ...'... 
Irs. C. R. Tefft 
3 H. H. Tuttle 
3 Miss E. Tychen 
inma Grigg 
rs. M. K. Towle... 
Ira. H. A. Tebbetts. 
; rester Supply Oo. . . 
3 A. J. Unlund 

672 Premium 66 80 

673 Premium 8 70 

674 Premium 2 40 

675 Premium 2 00 

676 Premium 11 00 

677 Premium 3 50 

678 Premium 50 

679 Premium 1 00 

680 Premium 6 00 

681 Premium 21 30 

682 Premium 100 

23 Van Darslie Bros. 
Van Patter 
K. Valentine. 
23 Mrs. S. Vandolah. 
23 Ottie Voderberg . . 

683 Premium 44 00 

684 Premium 45 60 

685 Premium 7 00 

686 Premium 1 00 

687 PremiHm 5 00 

23 Watson, Wood Bros. 4 Kelly, 688 Premium 99 20 </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
35 


No. For What Purpose. Prem. Misc. 

September 

23 R. M. Wolcott 
I no. F. Wright 
M. Woods 
23 G. M. Woneland 
\alnut Urove Farm. 
&gt;r. H. .1. Winnett... 
23 E. M. Westerrelt.... 
. S. Warren 

689 Premium $203 20 

690 Premium 9 80 

691 Premium 6 40 

692 Premium 16 00 

693 Premium 20 00 

694 Premium 8 00 

695 Premium 4 00 

696 Premium 8 80 

23 J. A. Wheeler. 
23 F. E. Wheeler. 
23 .T. Weiberg . . . 

697 Premium 8 70 

098 Premium 4 80 

699 Premium 2 40 

23 N. Withrow . . 
23 Sam'l Warrick 
23 C. C. Wright.. 
23 F. L. Wright.. 
23 J. M. Wild.... 

700 Premium 2 40 

701 Premium 6 90 

702 Premium 14 00 

703 Premium 5 00 

704 Premium 1 00 

23 Mrs. S. C. Wilson. 
23 Mrs. O. L. Ward... 
23 Mrs. L. Williams.. 
23 Martha Witte 

705 Premium 10 50 

706 Premium 2 00 

707 Premium 8 40 

708 Premium 1 00 

is. Witter 

709 Premium 6 50 

23 Mr«. P. .1. Wohlenberg. 
23 Mrs. O. S. Wolcott 

710 Premium 4 00 

711 Premium 1 00 

SClaista Wolcott 
Mabel Wolcott 
23 L. C. Waggoner 
23 Earl Wilson ... 

712 Premium 1 00 

713 Premium 1 00 

714 Premium 2 25 
715 Premium 2 00 

23 Mrs. E. Whitcomb. 
23 G. M. Whitf ord . . . 

716 Premium 3 40 

717 Premium 3 40 

23 H. C. Young. 

718 Premium 74 30 

23 York Roller Mills. 
23 Mrs. F. G. Yule... 
23 Karl Zimmerman 
23 Jno. Zwonaschek . 

719 Premium 2 00 

720 Premium 3 40 

721 Premium 1 00 

722 Premium 1 50 

23 Zwonachek &amp; Aksamit. 
23 E. Zimmerman 

723 Premium 3 00 

724 Premium 75 

725 Premium 2 00 

26 J. H. Honeywell. 
October 

728 Typewriter 85 00 

26 Robt. W. Furnas. 
mber 

727 Premium 215 20 

1 M. E. Moore. 

728 Salary, Oct., 1901 166 65 

1 Robt. W. Furnas. 
1 Robt. W. Furnas. 

729 Office rent, fuel, lights, 
typewriting, clerical </seg>


            <seg id="p040">
36 


Date. To Whom Issued. 
November 

No. For What Purpose. Prem. Misc. 

1 E. E. Cole. 
October 

730 Postage Oct., 1901 H M 

I Hutton Bros . 
3 Palace Stables 

801 Peed 6 20 

802 Livery 1 00 

:; Pierks Lumber Co. 
3 Dunn A Lynn 

803 Lumber 285 86 

804 Lumber 144 31 

3 E. A. Burnett. 

805 Judge Sheep 5 00 

3 Odell Construction Co. 
3 W. H. Dorgan 

808 Signs 9 00 

807 Judge Speed 12 00 

3 F.. E. &amp; M. V. R. R. 
3 W. News Co 

808 Switching 12 00 

809 Advertising 35 00 

3 B. 4 M. II. K 
3 M. Print Co.. 

810 Switching 12 00 

811 Slips 2 00 

I Kerc-hner &amp; Broadwater 
3 Harry Porter 

812 Implement C50 

813 Mch'd'g 17 50 

II. Budge, 
nber 

814 Pay roll 421 62 

4 J. B. Lewis 

815 Tel., Ex., and Pr't for 

Oct., 1901 2 10 

5 R. W. Lowery 
5 Void 

816 Premium 30 00 

817 Void 

7 M. E. Moore. 

818 Premium 20 00 

BO. B. Simpkins. 
V. Arnold 

819 Supt. Fish 25 00 

820 R. R. Fare, Fair 1901 . . 2 70 

W. Furnas 
2« W. H. Stowell... 
26 State Journal Co. 
26 J. C. Ish 

821 Postage 8 50 

822 Supplies 5 25 

823 Advertising 17 80 

824 R. R. fare 1 65 

26 A. H. Farrens. 

825 Fair Circuit fee 30 00 

26 T. A. Mann or Order. 
29 A. T. Peters 

826 Planting trees 6 90 

827 Special vet'y services 

for Fair, 1901 50 00 

30 R. W. Furnas. 
30 R. W. Furnas 

828 Salary for Nov., 1901.. 166 65 

829 Office rent, fuel, lights, 
typewriting, clerical 

December 

work, Nov., 1901 50 00 

tE. E. Cole.. 
J. C. Doubt 

830 Postage, Nov., 1901 10 63 

831 Premium 16 00 

26 S. D. Childs &amp; Co... 
26 S. P. Typewriter Co. 
30 J. H. Hadkinson 
31 Robt. W. Furnas 
31 Robt. W. Furnas 

832 Medals 76 00 

833 Two ribbons 2 00 

834 Grading 75 00 

835 Salary for Dec, 1901.. 166 65 

836 Office rent, lights fuel, 
typewriting, clerical 

work, Dec. 1901 .... 50 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
37 

REPORT OF ANNI'AI. MEETING. 

REPORT OF THE BOARD OF MANAGEBR 

Ejur last annual meeting, when the present Board of Managers 
appointed, the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture was in the 
i tof a struggle for a permanent home. 

Mr. Lane, a representative to the state legislature from Lancaster 
county, had introduced House Roll No. "!«. asking for an appropriation 
of $50,000 for the purpose of purchasing the present Fair (Irounds as 
• site for the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture. In due course of 
time this bill passed the House carrying an appropriation of $35,000, 
and was sent to the Senate, in which body it lay the subject for one 
of the hardest fights for that honorable body until the last hour of 
the last day of the session, when it was placed on its final passage, 
which resulted favorably. When Governor Dietrich attached his signature 
it was a great relief to every person interested in the perpetuity 
of the furthering of the. interests of agriculture, and holding of 
state fairs in Nebraska. The provisions of the bill made it incumbent 
S'ie State Board of Public Lands and Buildings to purchase the rite. 
among other lands offered was our present site, at a purchase 
of $22,300 exclusive of the ten-acre tract owned by the Lancaster 
ty Agricultural Society. 

¦final offer of the State Board of Public Lands and Buildings for 
&gt;perty wu $18,000 and the deeding of the ten acres by the Lan- 
County Agricultural Society. 

When it became evident that neither grantor nor grantee would 
recede or advance from their respective amounts so named, and at a 
date when the time was becoming extremely limited for the accomplishment 
of the work necessary to be performed, the patriotic and 
public-spirited citizens of Lincoln came to our support in furnishing 
by subscription the $4,300 difference needed, and the securing from the 
Lancaster County Agricultural Society of the ten-acre tract held by 

.•ording to the provisions of the law, our Board of Managers then 
submitted to the Board of Pubic Lands and Buildings plans and specifications 
for such improvements as were thought necessary, and the 

)at«. To Whom Issued. No. For What Purpose. Prem. Misc. 

December 

S. E. Cole 837 Postage, Dec., 1901... $11 85 
pens &amp; Sharp 838 Painting buildings on 
Fair Grounds 300 00 

II J. C. Campbell 389 Express 1 S6 
II W. H. Stowell 840 Supplies 12 00 
II .Tno. B. Lewis Ml Frt.. Tel., Express 2 85 

Total Premium* » $10,903 71 

Total Miscellaneous W. 3 * 0 ** 

Ormnd Total $26,284 43 </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
38 


cost of which might come within the balance of the appropriation, aa 
follows: 

Wiilir Bftttm. In the new water system were laid 1,225 feet of 6-inch 
pipe; 600 feet of 4-inch pipe; 225 feet of 2-inch pipe; 1,950 feet of 1-inch 
pipe; 880 feet of ?4-inch pipe; 290 feet of pipe; 2 new fire 
hydrants; at a total cost of $2,083. 

Pi nee. — The entire grounds were enclosed with wire fence. 2,325 
t along south side being 78 inches high, and 5,525 feet 58 inches 
h, all of which is surmounted by three barb .wires firmly stapled 
pood red cedar posts. 

The approximate expense of this fence, not including posts, which 
were taken from the old fence and former cattle sheds, was about 
$550 outside of the KO0 feet sold to the Street Car Company. 

The following buildings have been erected, viz. 

Hwxe Ham*. — Three horse barns. 34x114 feet, and each containing 
38 stalls, at an expense of $2,850. 

r'altli Hams. — Five cattle barns, each 30x120 feet, and each containing 
double stalls, at a cost of $2,550. 

Xirim mill Shee/i &gt;WI fli swine and sheep barns, each 26x108 feet, 
and each containing- :is pens, at a cost of $2,400. 

Horticultural Hall. — Horticultural Hall was moved from its old position 
near the center of the grounds to its present position on Dunham 
Avenue, at an expense for moving and grading of about $200, and a new 
wing 30x50 feet was built on the north to replace the one blown off 
sfieral years ago, at a cost of $500. 

tMtrmntilr Hull. — To Mercantile Hall was required and added a lew 
of at a cost of $880. 

IHitnil Stand*. — Two band stands, each 24x24 feet, were erected, one of 
hich was located near judge's stand at race track, and the other in 
ie court south of Agricultural Hall, at a total cost of $250. 

Toilet Rooms. — One extra large toilet room was erected east of the 
large grand stand, and one south of Fisheries Building, at a total cost 
for the two of $300. 

Grand Stand. — It was deemed necessary to place new sills along the 
front of the large grand stand, which, together with other repairs 
required, cost $150. 

t Painting, — During the past year the amount expended for painting 
is been $2,075, with $316 yet to pay when the second coat is finished 
i buildings contracted to be painted since the fair. 

Labor and Material. — The amount paid out for labor out of the state 
appropriation was $2,672.56, and by this Board for additional labor and 
material a further sum of $3,089.89, making a total expenditure in this 
department of $5,762.45. 

Insurance. — The ownership of the grounds brings the added responsibility 
of maintaining insurance on the buildings, and we are now carry- </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
40 


On motion of Mr. Parker that the report be received and published 
in the annual report, same was adopted. 

KEPORT OF SUPERINTENDENT CLASS F. 

The President and Members, Slate Board of Agriculture: As Superintendent 
of Class F, I hereby submit report as required in your by-laws. 

Owing to business engagements beyond my control 1 could not report 
for duty until the second day of the fair, but with the assistance as 
expert judges L. A. Kent on flour, Superintendent State Farm on 
grain and vegetables, who brought with them experience and an untiring 
energy, the work was well completed. 

I would recommend that alfalfa sheaves should be cut from same 
root for the three cuttings and the fourth cutting stricken out, as only 
three mature cuttings can be obtained at date of fair, and all sheaf 
exhibits be not less than six inches in diameter; and four best table 
watermelons be added. 

lilwff County produced sixty-four pounds hard spring wheat, 
Hitchcock County took first premium on spring wheat flour, showing 
the soil anil climate of Western Nebraska are specially adapted to 
wheat growing; and I think it will well come within the province of 
this Association to take suitable action in sustaining our senators and 
representatives in congress in their efforts to obtain government aid 
in conserving water for irrigation of the thousands of acres in Western 
Nebraska of the best wheat lands on earth. 

1.. Morse, Superintendent. 

The chairman of Committee on Revision of Premium List asked 
further time to report in full, which was given, and the committee 
directed to make its final report to ; the incoming Board of Managers, 
who were empowered to approve and accept. 

IN MEMOKIAM 

The following preambles and resolutions were adopted by the Board 
of Managers. State Board of Agriculture, at a meeting May 22, 1902, 
and ordered published in the Annual Report. 

WiiekkAs. .). Sterling Morton, one of the original and charter members 
of the Nebraska State Hoard of Agriculture, long a continuous 
and useful member, and for two terms its President; ever with pen, 
and by word an upbuilder in all lines of agriculture and horticulture; 
one of the earliest pioneers of Nebraska: one of its most beloved and 
Bed citizens, whose impress for good is to be seen in every part 
I state; secretary of the territory of Nebraska, a portion of the 
acting governor; author of Arbor Day; for four years, as presal 
cabinet officer, one of the select counselors of the nation; 
en down by death, in the zenith of his manhood and usefulness: 
fore; 

Bemdced, That we extend most sincere and heartfelt sympathy and </seg>


            <seg id="p047">
JULIUS STERLINC MORTON. 
Born in Adams, Jefferson County, New York, 
April 22, 1832. 
Died in Chicago, Illinois, April 27, I9O2. 

" Mens sibi conscia recti.' </seg>


            <seg id="p048">
41 

&amp;KPOKT OF ANNl AL M EetiI N l*. 

condolence to the surviving family; that we bow in humble submission 
to the decree of Him who doeth all things for His ever wise purposes. 

Rnu&gt;lrrti. That these proceedings be spread in full on our records; 
that a memorial page with portrait lw set apart and published in the 
next Annual Report of the State Board: that a copy of this action be 
furnished each of the surviving sons, and sister of the deceased. 

Whereas. J. D. Macfarlaml was long an active devoted member of 
the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture; that to him, more than to 
any other one person, is the Board indebted for the present permanent 
Fair Grounds, home and equipments, it now enjoys. He was indomitable 
and self-sacrificing to this end. Death has severed his relation 
with us, and summoned him to appear in the great hereafter: There- 
ReKolerd, That we mourn his loss, and sympathize with the bereaved 
family. It is but meet and proper we thus recognize and acknowledge 
his worth. 

Rnolred, That this Board make record of our appreciation of his 
valued and long to be remembered good words and deeds in support 
of our cause, and his merits as a most worthy citizen, as well. 

Rf&amp;otcrd. That these preambles and resolutions be spread at large 
in our record of proceedings; that a memorial page- in our Annual 
Report, together with a likeness of him, be set apart to that end; 
That the Secretary be and is hereby directed to furnish the surviving 
widow and family with an engrossed copy of these proceedings. 

Whereas. Samuel M. Barker was for years a prominent and zealous 
member of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture; for three M» 
sive terms its worthy President, and recognized throughout the state 
as a meritorious citizen; 

Whereas. That great Reaper, who, without distinction, garners from 
all ranks of homes alike, has taken from us our friend and associate; 
Therefore, 

Renolitd, That we. in this public manner, express our recognition 
of his worth in the cause of agriculture in Nebraska: that we sympathise 
with the afflicted family: that the action of this Board be spread 
at length on our records; that a memorial page with his likeness be 
set apart and published in the Anntril Report of this Board, and that 
the Secretary be directed to furnish the family with an engrossed copy 
of these proceedings. 

REPORT OF THE AUDITING COMMITTEE. 

Your Auditing Committee, duly appointed by the President of this 

¦Society, in compliance with said requirements have examined the 1901 

vouchers and warrants, and find the same to agree and to he con 
All payments ha^e Ix-en made by your Treasurer oti warrants regu- 

larly drawn by your Secretary, same being based on the order of the 
Board, or the order of your President and vouchers approved 

l&gt;\ the Board of Managers. 

To balance in hand of Treasurer July 18, 1901 $391 75 

Receipts during 1901 28,570 61 

Total receipts $28,962 36 </seg>

            <seg id="p049">
42 


Warrants paid Treasurer $26,414 10 

Balance on hand January 21, 1902 » 12,548 26 

Respectfully submitted this 21st day of January, 1902, 

T. A. McKay, 

J. R. Canton, 

Peter Youngers. 

On motion the report of the Auditing Committee was adopted. 

Secretary Furnas: 1 would like, before we adjourn for the evening 
meeting, to offer # a resolution. 

RESOLUTION. 

\\ hlufas. There will be held at the city of St. Louis, Missouri, during 
the year 11*03, an International Exposition commemorating what 
is known in history of the United States as the "Louisiana Purchase" 
of territory from France in the year 1803; and 

Whereas, The now state of Nebraska is a prominent factor embraced 
in said domain, and 

Whereas: It is deemed fitting and proper that Nebraska should be 
represented at said Exposition, with a showing of her products, resources 
and possibilities: Therefore 

Resolved, That this Board endorse and approve the efforts now being 
made by Governor Savage to the end indicated in the foregoing preambles. 


Krxolrcd, That the Secretary of this Board be and is hereby directed 
furnish Governor Savage with a certified copy of these preambles 
I resolutions. 

Mr. Dinsmore moved its adoption. Carried. 

President Vance: I have a little matter that I desire to speak of. 
It has been the custom in years past, that whenever the condition 
of the finances of this board would permit, that the board bill of this 
Board be paid, and we can congratulate ourselves that we have money 
at this time, and I would suggest lhat the board of this Board be paid 
at this meeting. 

Mr. Basset t offered the following 

RESOLUTION. 

Rrmhed. That the hotel bills of members and delegates in attendance 
at this meeting 1 , for not exceeding two days, be paid by this 
Board, and that a committee of one be appointed by the President, 
who shall hare power to audit said bills: also that a warrant be drawn 
in favor of the President in such an amount as shall be necessary to 
pay said hotel bills. 

Mr. Bassett: I move its adoption. 

Mr. J. K. Cantlin: It seems to me this Is not quite fair of them. 
He says for two days' service. Xow this committee has been brought 
here by the call of the Board of Managers to work for this State 
Association, and we have been busy since yesterday hard as we could 
work and then didn't get through until after 12 o'clock to-day, and 
such members of this body cannot get over two days' pay; now will </seg>


            <seg id="p050">
43 

you ask these men to oome here and pay their extra hotel bills and do 
this work gratis? 

t President Vance: I will say in answer to you that wherever it has 
¦en necessary to employ any one, as you speak of, to do this work, 
it is expected that they will be paid, and there will be arrangements 
made by which you will get your hotel bills paid for the service you 
have rendered. I haven't talked with Mr. Bassett, the introducer of 
this resolution, but I think it was merely to determine what amount 
it would be, and possibly people might want to stay here three or 
four days; but I will ask Mr. Bassett if that is not the object in view, 
in placing it in a manner so we can have something to work to. 

Mr. Bassett: Yes, that is the object. The commit tc* appointed to do 
work is an outside matter. 

Mr. Mclntyre: I didn't understand the resolution. Will you be land 
enough to read it again? 

Mr. Bassett read the resolution again. 

Mr. Mclntyre: I move the adoption of the resolution. 

Mr. Bassett: In order to save a multitude of bills each member will 
receive his money and sign a pay-roll, and it will save trouble. Each 
member will settle his own hotel bills and come to the person appointed 
by the president and be paid by him. Carried. 

President: I will appoint Mr. J. R. Cantlin as a committee to look 
after that. What te your further pleasure? 

P Bassett: I have a resolution I would like to introduce in regard 
e beautifying of the Fair Grounds. We now have grounds, and 
uildings are repainted and 'there are some trees already set out, 
.here is need of some work being done to beautify the grounds, 
t ought to be done according to some systematic plan; some genplans 
should be outlined. 1 might say in this connection that 
Professor Stout, of the University, in order to drill the children under 
him in civil engineering, is preparing — and I think he calls it a topographical 
elevation of the ground — and when that is complete, that 
being done without any expense to the Board, it will be our property 
tn finished, and by preserving that, whoever has that matter in 
ge of beautifying the grounds, can doubtless use that. Now havthis 
in view, I offer the following 

RESOLUTION. 

Pi, That for the purpose of preparing a systematic and wellplan 
for the planting of trees, shrubs, etc., on the state fair 
.Mr. J. H. Hadkinson be and is hereby appointed landscape 
to the State Board of Agriculture, the compensation for his 
to be determined by the Board of Managers. 

I move the adoption of this resolution. Seconded by Mr. Dinsmore. 

Mr. Filley offered the following </seg>

            <seg id="p051">
44 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AURHTI .1 IRK. 

UWLITION. 

Rrsolied, That that part of article 2 of by-laws relating to the corps 
of scientists be stricken out, and the following by-law be enacted: 

"That the Board of Managers are hereby empowered to hire and fix 
the compensation of such corps of scientists, each year, as may in 
their judgment seem necessary." 

Mr. Mellor: The present law 1 suppose is not understood by all present. 
The part of our by-laws there as it states that the corps of scientists 
are employed by this Board and are named — I think there are 
eight of them — and states that their powers and duties toward this 
Board may be continued during their mutual pleasure and the pleasure 
of this Board. I understand that we have eight scientists to whom 
this Board several years ago pledged $100 per annum each, making a 
total of $800 per annum that we should pay these scientists under that 
resolution. During the past four years, according to our records, 1 
don't find that they have been paid. Last night this Board took action 
and paid them for this year's labor just passed, that is by warrants. 
The duties of these scientists are to write an article to be 
placed in the annual report filed by Governor Furnas, and the idea of 
this resolution that Mr. Filley has introduced, 1 think, is for the pur- 
Eof repealing that section and placing it in the hands of the 
of Managers to hire the scientists. It may be Governor Furnas 
&gt;me light to throw on this subject. 

Secretary Furnas: Mr. President, and gentlemen of the Board, I do 
want to be heard in this matter, from a standpoint of vital interest 
and the cause of agriculture in Nebraska. 1 am sorry to disagree with 
my friend Mr. Filley. I spoke a while ago of the work of these scientists, 
and I wish I had the power of language to impart to you how 
important I consider this matter, and how little we will seemingly have 
to do if you dispense with these scientists, and if this resolution is 
passed the present Board of Managers will, I feel sure, dispense with 

iw, this is the point I want to repeat, what I said a while ago, that 
I have striven for years, and because 1 got this thing in the shape it 
ia, where 1 think the people and agricultural interests of this state 
will be best served by the co-operative work of the scientists. In fact 
1 need not tell any farmer who is here to-day that it requires the 
strictest and most rigid economy and scientific modes if we make life 
a success, and it is more applicable to the farming interests, because 
their margins are small and they must do what they do now from a 
paying standpoint, or they are not going to make farming pay. We 
have a gentleman now in this meeting who I regard as one of the best 
illustrations of what an educated farmer can do over a man who 
Iv depends upon his manual labor. The ox and horse have a 
manual labor force beyond that of any man, but unless it is guided 
by the intelligent lirain of the man it don't amount to a row of pins. </seg>

            <seg id="p052">
45 


I tell you if you withdraw from this Board this feature, thin factor of 
its work, you are going to injure the work of the State Board and the 
interests of agriculture in this state. 

You cannot do anything now in the old methods of farming; it will 
not keep the family, to say nothing about paying. Now I think I 
have made myself understood on this. You are robbing the Board, 
when you do that, of all that it has got to go- before the world with 
of what you are doing. The fair is a great work and fills its place, 
but it comes and goes and there is no record that the people get of 
it except what they see. It is a great object lesson — one of the very 
best in the world for agricultural interests, but I tell you, you take 
the work of the scientists away from this Board and you have nothing 
to show what this Board is doing. These reports of ours are used in 
nearly all of the schools of this state as text-books, and I have had 
applications from eastern states for these books because of the seientine 
papers in them. We have had over thirty applications for these 
reports since I came to this town, and it is done because they are full 
of scientific matter that will enable the farmer to do better. We have 
been talking about this matter, and I say I know how the Board of 
Managers stand on this question. I know that we have not been paying 
these scientists and I think we ought to have done it, or at least 
done it in that same proportion as these evidences of indebtedness. 
We have got a whole iot of things we are behind in — $700 for medals. 
We will have to change them from silver to bronze medals. But I 
beg you, gentlemen to have at heart and in consideration the best interests 
of this Board, and not deprive it of one of its best mediums 
by which it is going to accomplish good work in this state and elsewhere. 
While I am not a member of the Board of Managers, I think 
it is so plain, 1 would like to have the matter remain where it is till 
we get more time to see what can be done; nothing is going to spoil 
for another year. We fixed the pay for them, they didn't do it. If 
you let this matter rest and go over until another year I will hare a 
personal conference with every member of the scientist board and 
see if the thing cannot be brought down a little lower. Now to this 
end I move that this resolution be postponed for further consideration, 
if I can meet with a second. 

Mr. Poynter: I would like to know what use this State Board of 
Agriculture is. We meet annually and elect a Board of Managers and 
our President,- and that Board of Managers haven't anything to do 
in their own case except to hold only a great big state fair. It seems 
to me that it is lowering the influence of the State Board. The State 
Board has something else to do besides simply to hold the state fair 
annually. While that is a great thing to educate our people, and while 
¦ splendid thing to advertise our state, yet it does not give the 
f education which our reports should give. One of the best 
of education for the farmers of this country and this state is </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
46 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE. 

the annual reports that are made, the scientific research that is embodied 
in these reports. I am absolutely opposed to the cutting' off 
of this scientific board from this State Board of Agriculture. It seems 
to me we should rather enlarge it than diminish it. 1 am in favor of 
the putting into the annual reports the work uf these men of science. 
It is the one thing that gives our reports a standing and us a standing 
as an agricultural state. I am in favor of maintaining this and 
BtrougM than in the past. We see we have not been paying the scienin 
the times past, because we have been in hard lines. We have 
now a home of our own. We are going to be more successful in the 
future than in the past. The question of finances will not bother us 
after. These scientists are Nebraskans and they are in favor of 
the upbuilding of the state, and from this time on these things will 
¦pear, and for this reason, if nothing else, I am in favor of continuing 
this same corps of scientists, or if need be to enlarge it. 

Mr. Filley: It is a mistaken idea if you think the State Board of 
Managers want to cut off these scientists. We want to pay them just 
what they are worth as near as we can; as it is now, we pay each one 
so much. We don't want to squander the money; we want them to 
their money and we are willing to pay them. We don't want to 
shut them out. We don't want to pay a man here $100 for doing 50 
' worth of work. You leave it with the State Board of Managers 
and these men will be worked and will be paid for their work; but as 
it is now they come in and want their money when they haven't done 
anything — that is, some of them. They are good workers and good 
and I want to uphold them as much as any man. 

P. Dinsmore: 1 wish to speak to the motion to postpone the conation 
of this resolution for the time being. I object to the adopof 
that for this reason, that the trial of this matter rests with 
Board of Management to do, notwithstanding the article that 
brother Filley proposes to amend. If the Board of Management, by 
resolution, when in session, shall say to their Secretary that he is not 
to employ the scientists for this year or for any year, I apprehend 
that there is not any man who has the honor to stand and serve us 
as Secretary, that will not obey that resolution, and for that reason 
I wish that this matter may be continued for another year. I know 
that these articles are sought for among people that we never hear 
from other than those who come in contact with them. It is within 
the last ten days that men, who I don't suppose there is a single member 
of the Board has an acquaintance with, have applied for these and 
wanted those scientific articles. They tell me they are worth more 
to them than any other articles on agriculture they have come across. 
I believe they are worth every dollar they have cost us. There can 
be no harm come to anybody to leave this matter to the incoming 
Board of Management to act upon it next year. </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
47 


31 1* EjiVIXI^ m IS IX SO ill 1 SS 1 1 ) H* TOr UB TO l^KC 11 p A Tici CIlftuKv dUV 8 *0T I Oil 
of oar by-laws and act upon it immediately? 

President: Yes, this full Board can. 

Mr. Ewing: It seems just at present this association is financially 
in pretty good shape. It does not seem to occur to Mr. Poynter that 
we might be financially embarrassed in the future. We had a successful 
fair last year, and that accounts for the financial standing of the 
association today. We are not guaranteed a successful fair and the 
receipts ample on this year or any other year that will justify the 
Board of Management in paying out any expenditure we may adopt 
now. I would like to call attention to the fact that we had better be 
C pared in any emergency in a financial way that we may meet in 
future. 

President: I will aay it takes a two-thirds vote of the members 
present to alter or change the by-laws. 

Mr. Ewing: And it is not required to lny on the table? 

President: No, sir. 

Secretary: My motion was to postpone this resolution until the next 

Mr. Basset t: I don't want it to be understood that I am not in favor 
of the work, but the Board of Management occupy a position that is 
not just the same as some other members of the Board. Into their 
hands is placed the financial part of the Board: it is under their management 
that we receive the fees of the state fair. We owed, until we 
Sthe warrants yesterday, the scientists of this board $3,200, but 
haven't been paid for several years. I don't know how it was 
he other members, I never felt more humiliated when we were uno 
pay these scientists in full. 

Two years ago we got out the annual report with a debt of $4,000, 
and nothing to pay it with. While I am in favor of the work that is 
being done, I still have in mind whether we can meet the expense. 
The income of this Board is at the peril of the weather, whether we 
have two days of good weather at the fair. And this is one of the reasons 
this matter was brought up, to make some preparation in regard 
to it. It means $800 a year if we continue to pay it, and that is just 
as much due as any other debt. The labor is well performed: the 
question is whether we are to continue it or not. It was a resolution 
that was adopted by the Board at its annual meeting-; not a resolution 
the Board of Managers had anything to do with. I don't wish to 
any reflections as between the work of the scientists: some of 
them are more capable than others, yet we are bound to pay each one 
$100 if he is working for the Board. It seems not a just way of arranging 
the matter. 

One thing further. That arrangement was made when this - 
Board of Agriculture was carrying a balance of $13,000 or $14,000 each 
year, which we have not been doing for a number of years. That was </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
48 

W— *mr&gt; STATE BOARD OT AGRICULTUWL 

before mv time; but you will bear in mind that for the last seven or 
eight years the balance has been the other way. You are well aware 
that we hare reduced the expenses of the Board in great many high 
premium list compensations, and this was one of the questions that 
we thought best to bring up at the annual meeting, and have it understood, 
then if the members of the Board see fit to continue it, then 
it is a legitimate debt. The compensation comes from the Board of 
Managers; we have the management of the State Board, and if we 
Enot pay the debts of the Board it reflects upon the management, 
sonally, we might favor that; as a Board of Management we could 
favor it. 

Secretary Purnas: I don't want to be considered as ugly or stubborn 
about this matter. Mr. Bassett misrepresents the matter when he 
says that they are opposed to it. I think every member of this State 
Board would like to have this thing continued, but I am quite sure that 
the expressions of the present Board of Managers is to discontinue 
under the circumstances. There has been no ugly disposition 
about this — simply a difference of opinion, but I cannot help but feel 
and express myself with earnestness and feeling in regard to it when 
I know what has been accomplished. I think possibly the expense 
uld be reduced somewhat. I think I could take the premium list 
today and take out from there what we can better afford to lose than 
this. 1. too. would like to keep the premium list up as high as we 
could get it, but I think I could cut out something in that premium 
list to the extent of $800, if that be necessary. This is all I have to 
say. I feel that after I have labored for years to bring about the 
condition of affairs as they exist, and knowing that there is so much 
good grows out of it to agriculture, I feel like I want to say all I can 
to keep it from being wiped out of existence. 

Mr. Mclntyre; As Mr. Bassett has well said, when we started in on 
this work we were carrying over large balances. As my memory serves 
me, in years gone by, with the view to seeing what we could do in 
showing up the grasses, we called in Professor Bessey, and he went 
out and worked a week. Ue named them np and in our generosity 
we gave him $50. A year or two later we gave him for his work $100, 
and that is the way we run the thing until we have run this up to 
$800. I thing the thing that this Board wants to determine— and I 
think there is a great deal of meat in the nut that Mr. Filley cracked 
— pay these fellows what they are worth. This matter was under discussion 
a while ago when 1 happened to be present, and one, who has 
had some experience in matters of this kind along his line, said he had 
always got what he wanted by asking for it. I am not in favor of 
cutting this out entirely, but I am in favor of pruning it. Which is 
the best way to do I would not say. I was surprised when I found there 
were four years that they had not received their compensation for </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
49 

BBPOKT or ANNUAL MEBTINU. 

Mr. Mellor: We said that they were hired under the auspices of the 
Hoard for the past year, and we gave them their $100 due them for 
their last year's services. 

Mr. Mclntyre: A while ago I heard there was a move afoot to compromise 
the matter and settle the whole matter up. I would like to 
know if that was true. How is it with you, Mr. Basset t? 

BBassett: That is the most disagreeable task I ever had, when 
appointed by the Board of Management to see if we could not 
&gt;mise with these gentlemen for $100 each. After I considered it 
ent, that they are some of the most eminent men in the state, 
they had given us this service, and then for us to go and ask that 
they take $100. Prof. Bruner said that he had expended $300 of his own 
money in cuts, in illustrating, the cuts that he had made for the Board. 

Mr Mclntyre: Solely? 

Mr. Bassett: Yes, and others had expressed themselves in the same 
respect, only not to so great an amonnt. They had expended of their 
own money from *100 to $300 in order to prepare the reports that 
they had furnished us for publication, and I simply stopped right 
there, and I said I could not do anything further or more of that 
kind, and I suggested to the Board that we withdraw that proposition; 
that we pay them $100 this year and let the future take care of itself. 
We could not pay what we owed them. We had a balance of $3,500, 
and we have a balance now of $1,500. Therefore we paid them $100 
and left the balance to the future. That is why I was anxious to have 
the matter come up and for the State Board of Agriculture to under'1 
the matter. I should vote for the proposition personally to 
postpone. I am not in favor of doing away with the scientists as indi- 

Mr. Mclntyre: I don't understand any one is in favor of that. 

Mr. Filley: Neither am I. 1 want it understood, if one scientist 
conies in here and does $50 worth of work he will be paid that, and 
if one does $25 worth of work he will be paid $25. We will pay for 
uhnt we get. 

Mr. Mclntyre: 1 think it very fortunate, and I am glad they brought 
this matter up. It is a need that ought to be corrected here. I assume 
that a great many members of the Board were in the dark about it, 
like myself. The more we discuss these things and get acquainted 
with the facts the better we will understand them. I would like Mr. 
Filley's consent to defer the further consideration of this matter until 
tomorrow: 

Mr. Filley: I will do that with great pleasure. I want every member 
to understand just where we are at. 

Mr. Mann: Can anybody state the exact amount that is due; what 
is the number and what is the aggregate amount that lb*» Board 
owes? 

4 </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
50 


Mr. Mcllor: We tried to look that up. We figured in 1901 we owed 
eight of them for four years' services; we paid them $800. As business 
men we ought to pay our debts; that is the way we felt about it. I 
think Mr. Dinsmore stated that it would lie with the Board of Managers 
whether they took away the power from the Secretary to hire 
¦ men or not. I don't think so. As long as the pleasure of the 
Board need the services of scientists, it has made it possible to 
keep this up. I think this discussion is for the good of this organization, 
and that is the reason the Board of Managers brought this before 
this body. 1 don't think there is one of the Board of Managers that 
would like to lose the services of these gentlemen, but when we are 
up against the proposition like the last two years it makes people 
think about these things. Two or three years ago we started in here 
in debt, in addition to what we owed the scientists and medals. — some 
of those medals dated about 1892 or 1893 as I understand it. some were 
silver and some bronze. Now this State Board of Agriculture should 
pay its debts just like a private individual, and they should not run in 
debt any more than necessary until they get this debt paid. We prefer 
that you gentlemen would take action upon this matter and leave 
the Board of Managers out: not to increase its load more than necesto 
carry. We have done the best we could, and in a fair way we 
linve had success in the last two fairs and have about $1,200 that is not 
hypothecated at the present time. There is $316 to be furnished or 
drawn out of this $1,500. so that will leave us about $1,200. and the 
board bill of $200. leaving $1,000. and the Secretary's salary will take 
up that in the next six months. We are trying to run this Board on 
principles in the last two years, as far as we could, and we 
want the assistance of every member of this Board to do it. 

Erfnnn: I think this is a very plain proposition, and this claim 
e Board has made on the State Board certainly should be recog- 
Mr. Filley's proposition is very plain and just as plain for this 
to adopt. 

¦Bassett: The two years in which we held no fair the reports 
furnished by the scientists the same. This is why the amount 
en increased perhaps more than it otherwise would. 

¦ oungers: I move you this question (resolution) be laid on the 
ntil tomorrow forenoon's session at 9:30 o'clock. Seconded. 

Mr. IMn8more: I move you that a committee of five be appointed 
on nominations, and that we proceed to nominate parties to fill vacancies 
that occur on the Board at this time. Carried. 

NOMINATIONS. 

R oungers, W. R. Mellor, W. G. Hervey, E. Mclntyre, T. A. McKay, 
Volcott, W. Foster, S. C. Bassett, N. Withrow, J. R. Cantlin, Chas. 
J. X. Van Duzen, L. Morse, E. L. Vance. V. Arnold, J. C. Seacrest, </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
REPORT OF ANNUAL MEETING. 

51 

Thus. Mortimer. M. B. Hoffman, W. W. Cole, G. W. Wykoff, E. A. Barnes, 
M. L. Coad, Robt. Taylor, J. C. Anderson, P. Jansen, W. V. Allen. 

President: I will appoint as the commit tee on Humiliations, J. B. 
Dinsmore, S. R. Hull, J. J. Burke, E. L. Searles, W. H. Arnold. 

Mr. Bassett read the following- 

KKl'OKT OF THE COMMITTEE OX THE TEACHING OF AQRH ILT 
URE IN THE PUBLIC SCHOOLS. 

Mr. PrtHident: Your committee, to whom was referred the matter of 
legislation necessary to secure the teaching of agriculture in the rural 
and high schools of the state, begs leave to submit the following report: 


Doubtless most of those present recall that at the annual meeting 
of this Board for the year 1900, we discussed for one entire session the 
subject of teaching agriculture in the public schools of the state, and 
the conclusion finally reached was, that before the pupils in our schools 
could be thus taught, the teachers themselves must be fitted to give 
such instruction; and to secure the latter result it would be necessary 
to amend the law relating to teachers' certificates, to include "The Elements 
of Agriculture" among the branches in which persons are required 
to pass a satisfactory examination, in order to secure certificates 
of the first and second grades. 

With this object in view, the proposed amendment to the school 
laws relating to teachers' certificates was prepared in words as follows: 
"The elements of agriculture, including a fair knowledge of 
the structure and habits of the common plants, insects, birds and 
quadrupeds," and with this proviso: "Provided, that the part of this 
section relating to the elements of agriculture, to-wit: the elements 
of agriculture, including a fair knowledge of the structure and habit* 
tthe common plants, insects, birds and quadrupeds, shall not be in 
M until on and after July 1st, 1903." 

The words of this amendment, here quoted, are now a part of the 
school laws of the state. While not certain your committee is still 
qu'iie sure that Nebraska is the first state to make this requirement of 
teachers in the public schools. 

Having secured the enactment of this law, the next step is to make 
it useful and effective. Diligent inquiry, on the part of those most 
interested, has shown that there are no text-books published, relating 
to this subject, suitable for use in our rural and high schools. Being 
pioneers in the enactment of such a law, it becomes accessary for those 
charged with its enforcement to become pioneers in providing textbooks 
necessary for its teaching. It was at once realized that it would 
not do to attempt too much in the beginning; that text-books for use 
iu the rural schools must be quite elementary in character and that 
the requirements, on the part of the state and county superintendents, </seg>

            <seg id="p059">
52 


tthe teachers, must not be such as to discourage the latter and make 
&gt; new branch of study unpopular. 

Happily the wisdom, tact and energy of Superintendent W. K. Fowler 
in this matter has been such as to secure the co-operation of county 
superintendents, teachers and the press, and also to provide the textbooks 
necessary for the successful introduction of this study into our 
public schools. 

Supt. Fowler has given this measure his hearty support since its first 
inception, and, as showing what has been and is being done under his 
direction, I quote from an interview lately had with him on this subject 
in which he said: 

Pe proposition to include a knowledge of the elements of agriculuiong 
the subjects commonly taught in the public schools of the 
has met with great favor generally from its people. Superintendents 
and teachers generally are taking it up with great rim and preparing 
themselves for examination and instruction in the subject. The 
Nebraska Teachers' Reading Circle, including about five thousand 
teachers in the state, has adopted as one of its texts for the current 
year 'The Principles of Agriculture,' a most excellent book written by 
that eminent author, Prof. L. H. Bailey, of Cornell University, Ithica, N. 
V., and published by The Macmillan Co. Many of the institutes the 
coming season will have one instructor who can teach the subject and 
assist the teachers in preparing for the examination in that branch one 
year later. All the institutions in the state that are authorized to 
grant state certificates, the University of Nebraska, the State Normal 
School at Peru, the Nebraska Wesleyan University, and the Fremont 
Normal School, have included the subject of agriculture among the 
branches taught there. The matter has received very favorable consideration 
from the press of the state on account of its practical value 
and usefulness. Prof. Chas. E. Bessey, of the University of Nebraska, 
the state botanist, and Prof. Lawrence Bruner, also of the University, 
and state entomologist, both men who love Nebraska as they love 
their homes, and whom Nebraska loves to honor, but also men of 
national reputation, are now engaged in preparing manuscript for a 
publication which will be known as 'Elementary Agriculture: a Text- 
Book for the Schools of Nebraska.' This is a book that may be used 
in almost any schoolroom in Nebraska, but more particularly in the 
grammar grades or the higher grades of the rural schools. No men 
are more familiar with the needs of the state and of the schools in 
this important subject than they. The introduction for the book will 
be written by the State Superintendent, giving his official endorsement. 
He is in receipt of the following letter from the Hon. James Wilson, 
Secretary of Agriculture: </seg>

            <seg id="p060">
53 

REPORT OF ANNUAL MEETING. 

'Department or Aobicultube, Office of the Secretary, 

" 'Washington, D. C, November 15, 1901. 

" 'Mr. W. K. Fowler, State Superintendent of Public Instruction, Lincoln, 
Aeftra#ku— My Dear Sib: Reply to your letter of the 6th, I have to 
say that your proposition to have a book written along the lines of 
elementary agriculture for the use of the school teachers of Nebraska 
is well timed. It will meet a want that has been very pressing. If we 
could have school teachers informed along these lines it would be a 
great pleasure to them and a great benefit to their pupils, and would 
train young people in the direction of the studies that will control 
their life work. There should be a universal demand for such a publication. 
The gentlemen who are to write it are well known to the educators 
and scientists of the country, and stand high in their respective 
specialties. I bespeak a very cordial reception for the publication when 
it is issued. Very truly yours. 

" '(Signed) James Wilson, Secretary.' " 

Cr committee begs to be pardoned for quoting, in this connection, 
the address of the president of this Board, on the occasion of 
inual meeting for the year 1900, under the heading. 

"AQaiCULTCBAL EDUCATION. 

Bere is no question of more vital importance to the people of this 
to-day, than the question of agricultural education; and at this 
lg of the parent agricultural organization of the state, it is 
Dtly proper that, the question be not only presented but that 
time be spent in its discussion and consideration, and let me say 
to you in all candor that if at this meeting you shall come to a thorough 
understanding of this important matter, shall correctly understand 
the conditions as they exist at this time, shall so assist that this 
cause shall take root and grow, flourish and bear fruit, in every county 
and school district in the state, you will have done an hundred times 
more for the cause of agriculture and for the development of our agricultural 
resources than though you had assisted to hold a fair in the 
year 1899 and we had today in our treasury a balance of $10,000." 

It gives me great pleasure, as your committee, to report that the seed 
in this great cause has been planted; that it has germinated and taken 
root. That it will grow and nourish, spreading even beyond the borders 
of our own state, and in the end bear fruit of great value to all the 
people, only time is needed to demonstrate and determine. 

Your committee feels to congratulate the members of this Board that 
they were permitted the privilege to take the initiative, as it were, in 
the development of this new plant; to assist in the preparation of the 
soil and the planting of the seed. 

In the years to come the harvest gathered from this planting will be 
of incalculable benefit to the cause of agriculture and add to the welfare 
and happiness of all the people. 

(Signed) S. C Bassett, Committee. 

President: You have heard this report. What is your pleasure? 

Mr. Dinsmore: I move that the report be received, and time be set 
apart some time tomorrow for its discussion. </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
54 


Mr. Basset t: I prepared this resolution in connection therewith, 
for fear I might not be here. I would like to offer the resolution now: 

Resolred, That the thanks of this Hoard be and are hereby extended 
to State Superintendent of Public Instruction \V. K. Fowler, for his 
earnest efforts in making all necessary provision for the teaching of 
the elements of agriculture in the public schools of the state, and that 
we most heartily approve the plan of having prepared, for use in the 
&gt;ls. a text-book on the elements of agriculture by those eminent 
scientists, Prof. Charles E. Bessey and Prof. Lawrence Bruner." 

I would like to offer that to be acted upon with the other. 

Mr. Mel lor: 1 move that the resolution be laid on the table until 
after the discussion. Seconded. Carried. 

Mr. Cantlin: I desire to offer the following resolution: 

I Resolved; that we are in favor of such legislation by the National 
ingress as will protect the legitimate dairy interests of the nation 
ainst the fraudulent sale and use of oleomargarine as and for butter, 
id to this end we favor the passage by congress of the so called 
rout bill" or a bill of like nature, and most respectfully request our 
nators and members of congress to support such a measure; also 
:it the Secretary be requested to send a copy of this resolution to 
eh senator and member of congress from this state. 

I move the adoption of the resolution. Seconded. Carried. 

tMr. Dinsmore: I move that we do now adjourn until 9 o'clock in the 
orning. Carried. 

Chapel Hall, University of Nebraska, January 22, 1902. 

On roll-call all were found present except the following: Mr. Bassett 
and Mr. Mellor. 

President: Is the committee on nominations ready to report? 

I Mr. Dinsmore: Gentlemen, your committee has a query which it 
ants to shy into the ring this morning: 

"Your committee on nominations, are confronted with the question 
in the assignment of names to fill the vacancies on the Board with the 
question whether by the -reason of the present residence of W. A. Poynter 
in Lancaster county has not removed his membership from this 
Board from Boone county to Lancaster county. If such be the sense 
of this Board then Lancaster county would have two representatives 
whose terms of office expire in 1903, and under the unwritten law 
governing this Board they would be entitled to consideration in recommending 
names at this time." 

The committee submit this as a query. The information which the 
committee now has is that Governor Poynter is now a resident of the 
county. If so, does not his residence in Boone county still hold or 
does it not change his residence to this county, or is it vacant in 
Boone county? 

Mr. Cantlin: It seems that question can best be answered by Mr. 
Poynter himself — whether he is a resident of Lancaster county or </seg>

            <seg id="p062">
REPORT OF ANNIAI. SIEETIMj. 

55 

Boone county. If he is a resident of Lancaster county it seems that 
it makes a vacancy in Boone county, if he is now a resident of this 
count v. 

Blent: The question now is whether he should be a delegate 
is county or Boone county, or whether it becomes vacant; that 
ay I understand il. Now have we any legal authority or light 
subject? 

KDinsmore: I would ask Mr. Mclntyre and Mr. Furnas a question, 
emember the question on more than one occasion where parties 
from one county to another, their position has been declared 
from the county from which they moved. Can any one throw 
rht on that? 

Mr. Mclntyre: Two or three years ago in the case of Saunders county, 
when he moved from Saunders to another county and subsequently 
came here he responded to his call and participated in the meeting, but 
the question was raised. Pierson was his name. I believe. He moved 
from Saunders county into Seward county. He came in at a subsequent 
meeting two years ago and the question was not raised, and I 
think his term expired since then. I can't remember that the rule 
WU formally considered by this Board. As far as I know I don't recall 
that this Board has ever put this on record on that point, or either of 
the others involved here. 

retary Furnas: 1 was going to narrate the same circnnistane 
which Mr. Mclntyre refers to. 1 can't now recall to mind any instance 
where the membership has l&gt;een declared vacant by reason of removing 
from one county to another, because there is no law governing that. 
I don't think there is any rule that there should be a real resident 
from the county from which they are named, but it has been the 
• in of this Board when it meets as it does now, under these circumstances, 
and where the same condition of affairs confronts, as the 
chairman of the committee on credentials or nominations of new 
members .refers to, that they could not hold after that. If their terms 
had expired they were not replaced for the new place or from the old 
one from which they came from. I repeat, there is no law upon that 
subject at all. A man may live in Lincoln and be a representative of 
Boone county on this Board, but it has not been the custom and it has 
not been recognized when it comes to representing a county. 

Mr. Dinsmore: This question was brought up by myself. One reason 
is we found" with the convening of this session that there are at least 
two members who are not living in the territory where they have been 
elected. They have sold out and moved to other counties. I wish to 
present a possible contingency. It never has arisen but it may arise 
in the future. We may find instead of having two members in Lancaster 
county when convened that the members have moved from the 
Knties from which they were elected, until we have six or eight 
nbers here, and it seems to me that the time has come that ire </seg>

            <seg id="p063">
56 

NKBKASKA STATK BOARI&gt; OF IKE. 

ill in ike a ruling- and take a stand that will determine this question. 
Because otherwise you will fiml these men moving from one 
;v to another: some other counties over-represented, and some 
•Mat are entitled to representation as much as theirs that have 
no representation by reason of the selling and moving out of the membership 
of this Board. and it seems to me it is an important thing, we 
id take it up at this point and make some ruling upon that ques- 

President : I would say, as far as my knowledge goes, to get this 
matter fairly before this body I would say: Mr. Poynter, as I remember, 
was re-elected last year, having one year at the present time to 
serve. We have two members here from Lancaster county, and one of 
these gentlemen's terms expires at this meeting, so there is where 
Estion comes in. whether they will be entitled to the re-election 
her member now. or whether Mr. Poynter coming from Boone 
will take the place of that expired term. This is as I undert. 


Mr. Mellor: I think if we have no precedent we should fix one. I 
• think it would be justice to Mr. Poynter to declare him not a 
member of this Board. His term expires next year, and 1 don't think it 
would be justice to I^ancasfer county to have to take another member 
that comes to this place to reside as its member. I think Lancaster 
county should say who its members should lie, and if Mr. Poynter 
would have removed from the state he would have lost his membership 
&lt;&gt;n this Board actually. But in the condition that this case is in, 
that Lancaster county should have the right to name its own members 
ame as any other county in the state. It is possible that five or 
six members of this Board may move to Lancaster and other counties 
nc\er get a representation on this Board. 

¦Kwing: Can evei-v county in this state have a representation 
s Board? 

lent: No. sir; it is entitled to but twenty-nine members. 

Kwing: It strikes me the proper way to get at this is to district 
te. 

Bdent: Our rules and by-laws make it plain that no county, 
he exception of Lancaster and Dou-jlas counties, shall be ento 
more than one member, and it is limited to twenty-nine. I 
to get at this matter, better make a motion for or against some 
in. 

Bassett: As I understand we are members of the State Board of 
culture. The law does not provide that we shall represent any 
county. It is not by counties or districts, and if the Board in its wisdom 
should select them all in Lancaster county, the law would be 
:lied with. It is a ruTing that this Board has made not the law 
of the state. I think that (iovernor Poynter is a member of this 
Board. In our plan he represents Boone county, — represents that part </seg>


            <seg id="p064">
57 

* 3" M^j\»* Ki\. tl lil^! v (* 111 111 I I T 1 FT I il K 1 n 1 II f ) 1 1 \ I H &lt;l 1 1 0 H rt 
with that object in view. This committee has selected members from 
the state as a whole. I think it is the province of the president to rule 
on that question, and in my opinion Mr. Poynter still continues as a 
member of this State Board. In one sense he represents Boone county, 
and that if Lancaster county has been in the past entitled to two n 
bers and still entitled to two, it should still have them. 

Secretary Furnas: Governor Poynter is a resident of Boone county 
and a member at large of the state. 

Mr. Bassett: He is a member of the State Board of Agriculture. 

Mr. Morse: Perhaps twenty-four years ago the Board had its annual 
meeting 1 . Some counties had two or three or more represent:) • 
upon the Board; other counties had none, and at that time we adopted 
the rule of distributing the membership over the state with the view 
of getting a larger representation and influence among the agricultur"f 
the state, and at that time they adopted the rule that Lancaster 
and Douglas counties, owing to their size and population, v&gt; 
be entitled to two members each, and that has never been deviated 
from. The committee in distributing membership, so far as my observation 
has gone. — I have served on that committee more than once.— 
is, that they take into consideration the location of the members who 
hold over in distributing those new members who come on, with the 
view of getting the largest representation in the redistribution that 
is possible among those sections that are strictly agricultural in the 
broad sense of that term. 

Mr. Barger: Does not that rule there say that no other county shall 
have more than one member other than Done 'as and Lancaster cotin- 

EMr. Mellor: I am not certain there is a writ'en rule upon the ques&gt;n. 
I think not. How is that. Governor? It provides that not more 
an one member of the Board of Managers shall act. 

I move you that a committee of three to draw a rule for the action 
of this Board to cover this point be appointed. Carried. 

The chair will appoint on that committee, W. R. Mellor, S. C. Bassett, 
T. A. McKay. 

I Secretary Furnas: Mr. Stilson Jias drawn up this preamble and resotion 
and asked me to read it: s 

&gt; 

Whereas, the Agricultural Society is a family without a building; 
Therefore, be it 

Rrxolretl. that in the near future we ask of our legislators that a 
sufficient sum of money be appropriated to build at Lincoln a suitable 
home for the agricultural and kindred societies of our state. 

Secretary Furnas: I will say in connection with this matter that 
both the Horticultural Society and the State- Historical Society first 
had taken this matter up, finding that they had no room over in the 
other building for anything further, that they had taken occasion to </seg>

            <seg id="p065">
58 


ssk for an appropriation oi $75,000 to erect a building expressly for 
the State Historical Society, and the State Board of Agriculture and 
Horticultural Society. Resolutions have been passed by both of those 
organizations substantially to the same effect of this resolution. 

Pnave just had handed me a notice that the Live Stock Breeders' 
¦ciation are now in session at University Hall, first floor. If there 
any who desire to attend they can do so. 

Mr. Mclntyre: I move to substitute the word "building" instead of 
home. Carried. 

Er. Stilson: I move as an amendment that the sum of $35,000 be 
pd for. Not carried. 

On vote being taken on the resolution the same was carried. 

En t : I think about this time yesterday we agreed to take up 
resolution offered by Mr. Filley relating to the corps of scientists; 
was laid over from yesterday until at this time. 

¦tarv Furnas: And the motion was, when it was laid over, that 
sideration of that be postponeil until the next meeting of this 
That was the resolution pending. 

Mr. Killey: I have no desire to rush this matter through any further, 
but to look after the interests of these scientists. There is an expenditure 
of $S00 that has been carried on from year to year by this Asson; 
whether they were needed or not we have had to meet that 
$800. I want to get it in that shape that your Board of Managers can 
use these people whenever they want them and pay them for their 
serwres. We don't want to dispense with these people, — far from it. 
but we want to pay them for what they do, and it seems to me that 
there is nothing embodied in this resolution that would hurt their inita 
or the interests of this Association, and I should like to see 
this resolution adopted. 

rotary Furnas: I'nder the circumstances. I said yesterday all I 
! to say. and have nothing to take back, but there are some rea»vhy 
I understand the Board of Managers would like to handle 
this matter, and if (he disposition is not to dispense with their services 
entirely — and I had heard nothing akM but their disposition was to 
Mapenae with the services — and with the understanding that that rule 
Tiot mean to dispense with their services. — under all the eircum&gt;hat 
I said yesterday created some feeling, and we have a 
perfect right without calling in question any other person's motives 
in this matter, to express our opinion in regard to that — I repeat, 
while I have nothing to take bark from what I said yesterday as relates 
to the value of the services of these scientists, not because of stubbornness, 
I would withdraw my motion to postpone the further consideration 
of this resolution. Let me say however, in connection with this, 
and I don't call that is question as far as action at present is concerned. 

You cannot change the by-laws without a two-thirds vote, but in order </seg>

            <seg id="p066">
59 


to place myself right before the Board of Managers, I withdraw my 
motion and let it be acted upon. 

R Williams: I believe that that resolution is just and right. There 
&gt;ne as well able to judge as to the value and the necessity as to 
ard of scientists as they are. I have my doubts whether a resolu- 
F that kind is just what' this association needs, and I believe that 
that by-law should be annulled and that this work should be put in the 
hands of the Board of Managers, and I have the faith to believe that 
the Board of Managers, whoever they are, will engage such scientific 
expert men as they need and pay them Tor it. Now I understand it, 
we have been running under a by-law that has been running us in debt 
when the fair was not held. 

Secretary Furnas: Their work was performed just the same every 
year whether the fair was held or not. It is in the compilation of this 
volume. 

Mr. Williams: I don't understand that part of it. However, I am in 
favor of this resolution and hope it will carry. 

Mr. Stilson: I seconded the motion yesterday to postpone the action 
on this resolution. T wanted a little time. In going over Nebraska I 
have repeatedly run across these volumes as text-books and books of 
reference in the schools of the state of Nebraska, and I believe they 
have been of too much value to dispense with the services of these men, 
but in talking with the Board of Managers I find that it is not their 
intention to do away with the work. I would cheerfully like to see 
the vote taken at this time on this. I believe they should be retained, 
but at a compensation which is just and right to all. 

Pilent: I believe as a precautionary measure I will ask all those 
building that are delegates or representatives of this Board to 
stand, please rise to your feet to be counted. The count 
35. 

Mr. Mellor: It might be well to ask if there is any here who represent 
the State Board and are delegates. 

President: We will take a vote on this resolution. As many as favor 
this resolution will please rise to your feet. The count shows 30 in 
favor. The' resolution is adopted. 

Mr. Mellor: Your committee is now ready to report 

REPORT OF COMMITTEE. 

I That a removal of a member of the Nebraska State Board of Ag-riilture 
from the county from which he is selected to another county 
this state does not thereby transfer his representation on this Board 
om the county from which he was elected. That no county be alwed 
more than one representative except the counties of Lancaster 
id Douglas, which may have not to exceed two. 

W. R. Meixob. 

B. C. Basmtt. </seg>


            <seg id="p067">
60 


I move its adoption. Adopted. 

Mr. Dinsmore: Your committee on nominations is ready to report 

REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON NOMINATIONS 

Bour Committee on Nominations, would respectfully submit this 
ort and recommendations thereunder. 

¦the members of the Board for the term commencing with the 
t session: 

V. Arnold, Verdon, Richardson count}'. 
S. C. Baasett. Gibbon, Buffalo county. 

J. K. Cantlin, Blair, Washing-ton county. 
E. U Vance, Pawnee City, Pawnee county. 

Charles Mann, Chadron, Dawes county. 
K. Mclntyre, Seward, Seward county. 

W. K. Mellor, Loup City, Sherman county. 
N. Withrow, Central City. Merrick county 

L. Morse, Benkelman, Ihindv county. 
T. A. McKay, Aurora, Hamilton county. 
Peter Youngers, Geneva, Fillmore county. 
\V. ('. Hervey, Omaha. Douglas county. 
\V. \V. Cole, Neligh, Antelope county. 
\V. Foster, Lincoln, Lancaster county. 

(Signed) J. B. Dinsmore. 

E. M. Searle. 

W. H. Arnold. 

S. R. Hall. 

J. R. Cantlin. 

I move the adoption of the report. Adopted. 

Mr. Mellor: I would like to make a report of the Committee on Revision 
of Premium Lists. 

REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON PREMIUM LISTS. 

We, your Committee on Revision of Premium Lists, report progress 
and ask that the unfinished portion of said revision be referred to the 
incoming Board of Managers with power to act. Report adopted. 

Mr. Mclntyre: Now, so far as the premium list is concerned, that 
part of it I am not tenacious about, and I am not tenaciously opposed 
to the resolution excepting in this sense. I believe that we ought to 
take time by the forelock and have our Secretary to read the constitution 
and by-laws at least, and the rules and regulations that we are 
running under. Now if that had been done in later years we would 
all understand the condition that exists in relation to this liability. 
I confess I awoke up to the realizing fact that part of that liability had 
been carried and been running two years l&gt;efore I knew that the rule 
stood there. We created a liability of $simi a year. Now, I am not op- </seg>

            <seg id="p068">
61 


like to have ua all listen to the rules and by-laws that the Board of 
Managers govern their actions by. So far as this, premium list is concerned, 
I would like to see that discussed a little in open meeting with 
the view of getting at the sense of the Board. I have not discussed 
this matter with the Committee on Premium Lists. I know, as far as 
tarn concerned, I feel that we ought to do something. I am not preired 
to say what, but it would be along this line: To be brief, I would 
vote now to make the appropriation $1,500, to be distributed in the 
discretion of this Committee on Premium Lists, to magnify the cattle 
and horse industry of this state by putting up premiums in addition 
to those that have been. I don't wish to be understood as being in 
favor of keeping these entries open to the world as we express it. 
Now so far as the premiums we have been offering — but I believe in 
reaching further than that in some way whereby we will put up something 
like $1,500 for premiums that shall be confined to exhibitors 
confined within the limits of our own state. There is a certain kind 
of difference that some of our^jeople feel about coming in here. They 
say they are not fitted up to that buying point of presentation; that 
the professional exhibitor has his horses in and they don't like to go 
up against them. Now I would like a way open. I haven't anything 
firmly in my own mind that I wish to press or have this Board apply, 
but I am only speaking for one in this direction; it is no new thought, 
but I have kept silent. While I am not opposed to the spirit of the 
resolution, but I think the Committee on Premium Lists — I would like 
an expression of this Board as to whether or not we had better or not 
— we can improve these fairs by cutting down the premium lists. We 
cannot afford to do that. On the other hand I would regret to find 
myself favoring anything like extravagance in the premiums, but the 
stock industry is the thing that we all live on, to say the least, and I 
believe that we would like to see something accomplished along this 
line, and, as I say, I don't wish to arbitrarily oppose the passing of the 
resolution, but I would like to see this matter opened up and spend a 
little time with familiarizing ourselves in regard to this matter. I 
would like to hear from others. 

Mr. Hervey: I think that is very important, as Mr. Mclntyre has 
suggested, in regard to the greater encouragement of the live-stock 
in the state of Nebraska as it relates to the exhibition at the Nebraska 
State Fair. I think Mr. Mclntyre didn't get this matter entirely presented 
as it should be. I think our present classification in the premium 
lists should be confined to the state of Nebraska. I think our 
Nebraska breeders get more encouragement with an additional $1,500 
given to a free-for-all classification which will encourage outside 
breeders, I mean those men that have shown horses that are in adjoining 
states and make a business of traveling around state fair circuits 
for advertising business. I think it is wrong to compel our state </seg>

            <seg id="p069">
62 

NEBBASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE. 

breeders — we have got fully 1,500 breeders of thoroughbred stock — it is 
wrong to force those men to conie up in competition against these 
old rounders that have mime \. It is an imposition on the encouragement 
nf the live-stock industry of Nebraska. The result is that our 
breeders feel as though as if they cannot meet that competition, and 
they stay at home. Any one who has had experience in exhibition of 
live-stock understands that when you start out on the fair circuit you 
expect to get some premiums, enough premium to justify you for the 
effort, and your advertising is above that. That is the rule among 
exhibitors. We must have home protection for our home breeders. I 
don't believe it is right to shut out competition entirely from the state 
fair in Nebraska, but 1 believe we must have that protection and have 
$1,500 as an outside inducement for a free-for-all classification; that 
gives the incentive for encouraging these parties (boards?) who are on 
the state circuits and would shut them out; they will come here anyway 
to advertise themselves. If you can furnish them some money 
inducement and in connection with that with other association premiums 
which can very easily be worked up by the various breeders of 
other classifications of stock, there is no question but what a great 
improvements can be made in the live-stock exhibition of the state of 
Nebraska. 

Mr. Dinsmore: I find myself fully in accord with the gist of the remarks 
of both of the gentlemen who have just sat down — in the encouragement 
of the exhibitor at home. I also find myself emphatically 
of the opinion that we have not shut any door that we have now open 
to the exhibitor abroad. With the experience I have had with the exhibitors 
I know that $1,500 would bring out an exhibit of cattle here 
that would not only make the Superintendent tired- before he got 
through with it, but the members of the State Board of Agriculture; 
but you would have the exhibit to bring the people and make an enthusiasm, 
and it would result in good to our own people. 

Biecember, when 1 was at the stock meeting in Chicago, several 
I was asked what became of the representatives of Nebraska; 
on't they come here and ask for money for us to come there; 
they looking after their live-stock interests? There was no one 
who was authorized to say a word, and then at that time there 
have been no trouble to have got $2,000, $3,000 or $4,000 as special 
premiums, if there had been any one there to represent this Stat« 
Board; and with this much money from outside of the state, in addition 
to what we have in the state, you would have had an exhibit of 
ettle that all would be proud of and would have filled all their pockets 
th money. 

Mr. Mellor: I think it is wisdom for this State Board to grow in their 
exhibit, but we last year had an exhibit that overtaxed our capacity. 
It cost us a great amount of money to provide for that exhibit. When 
we should come to award the exhibits at this coming meeting we </seg>

            <seg id="p070">
63 

REPORT 01 

would not have room on the ground for our lire-stock, and we are not 
prepared at the present time to take advantage of thin opportunity 
that Mr. Dinsmore has stated. If we were prepared in buildings and 
capacity to handle, we would have done this. Imt we felt it our duty 
to handle these. If this Board thinks we pan handle them it is for the 
Board to say now so that the incoming Board may take charge of thig. 
My reason for introducing the resolution was that just this morning 
the State Poultry Association has handed tup a list of what they ask 
in the premium list. We have been busy here ever since, and we have 
had no time to pass upon this, and one or two other departments have 
not presented us with their requests. It seems to me it would be eminently 
proper for the Board of Managers, or somebody, to look after 
this matter. It is ver.v nice to say what might be dune, but we have 
got to consider what can be done. We want to do all we can. Each 
member of this State Board of Agriculture has the ffood at heart of 
the State Board of Agriculture, but we have got to go to a certain 
limit befoxe we can go any further. 

Mr. Barger: I don't know as I can say anything in particular to 
what has been said, but I want to add my influence to this line of 
work. I believe we should agitate this question, if we cannot do anything 
this year. In the sheep department, of which 1 had the pleasure 
of presiding over at the fair, I found that nearly all the money paid 
in premiums on sheep went out of the state: I believe it goes too 
largely, for the reason that those fellows are brought more for show 
than anything else, and it seems to me that the sheep industry of this 
state has not been what it ought to have been, and what it would beif 
we encourged it more through the state fair. The number of breeders 
from outside of the state that made exhibits at the state fair were 
more than those from the state of Nebraska. I have tried to think and 
formulate son ething in regard to that at the time, lint I have not come 
to any conclusion as to what changes ought to be made, but I do think 
there should be some word of encouragement to f«4 out ami owl livestock 
fellows and not leave everything to the outside 

Mr. Cantlin: I had an idea when we were called to order here that we 
were strictly an agricultural association and for a strictly agricultural 
meeting here to-day; but it seems we are live-stock men on the ttoor 
of this house that have conducted this matter so far. As I have had 
hold of the plow-handle for thirty years in this state I feel a great 
interest in the argricultural interests of this state and. I desire now 
to speak for the interest of the plowman and the fellow that follows 
the plow and the product that conies from the soil. I heartily agree 
with the gentleman who has preceded me, and especially Mr. Mclntyre, 
because I have repeatedly urged that we give this matter more time and 
give the premiums a thorough revision. I have had the honor of being 
Superintendent of Class F for three years, and we found there were 
many inaccuracies there existing and injuries done to our exhibitors </seg>

            <seg id="p071">
64 

NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD Or AQB1 

in that line, because the premium list does not provide for it. I have 
recommended four times in my annual reports a revision, and I will 
say now to the incoming Board of Managers, who will revise this 
matter, I have recommended $3,000 for county collective exhibits which 
actually made our state fair exhibit in the hall; but I will change that 
recommendation. I will recommend $3,000 now, and to do it and make 
the division of the amount this way: Take $1,000 of the amount, make 
two premiums of that, the first $600, the second $400. the other $2,000 
to divide in premiums according to the score of the exhibitors right 
through. While you gentlemen may think it is a small matter, it is 
work to do it. It will take a man a whole summer to do this work, 
and the amount of premiums that he gets out of it does not compensate 
him for his time. While we had a good exhibit for last year for 
the season, and was up in good shape, we can far improve it in that 
matter, and I would suggest to that committee, whoever they may 
be, that there be no 20 per cent reductions in the premiums. I made a 
fight on the floor of the house to make our premiums alone $1,200, and 
we had a strong fight. Mr. Mclntyre knows that, and we didn't follow 
his suggestion. It was understood then there would be no reduction of 
20 per cent in the amounts. 1 am glad to see these gentlemen on the 
floor of this house advocating the stock interests, because it follows 
the advancement, the progress of the agricultural state as it is to-day. 
If it was not for the agricultural ability of the whole of this state we 
would not have the stock interests we have got to-day,- and for that 
reason we must not look sidewise at the agricultural interest of this 
state. You can see from the increase of sales that have been made 
and advancement of lands in this state, and the thousands that are 
coming from the eastern states to settle here. Now we are almost 
in the lead of anything in the United States — superior in some things. 
No state touches us. I would like to see this matter up and the revision 
of the premiums well looked after. I feel that this matter should have 
been in the hands of two or three men qualified to handle the livestock 
interests of the state and agricultural interests. Let them come 
here and spend a week, if necessary, and pay them for their time and 
have their report, and we would all go home and knowing- intelligently 
what had been done. There are omissions in our premium lists, that 
while we are getting that out at the time of the state fair, we are so 
busy that we don't make a thorough record of it, and consequently it 
is not known, and where the revisions of the committee are not 
familiar, all of them, with the premium fist, to be revised. The books 
of the revision of the premium list should be revised thoroughly, for 
there is where we find losses. Where men can send for and get new 
samples of corn, it is not named on our premium list, and it is optional 
whether they get a premium list or not. 

I Mr. Morse: The by-laws require the superintendent to make a report, 
lat report is never looked at until next year. Whatever recommenda- </seg>


            <seg id="p072">
65 

tions any class superintendent may make will not be looked at until 
next year. If we could have these superintendents come in and give 
their notes verbally and discussed before that committee at each 
annual meeting, we would get this matter better before the committee 
and in time to be acted on. Now they go over till another year and 
are never looked at. 

Secretary Furnas: As a member of the premium committee, we have 
had much more per cent of attendance, who desired a change in the 
premium list, in presenting a by-law than ever before. Mr. Mellor is 
chairman of that committee, and it is still under consideration. 

!Ma.nn: I think, Mr. Mclntyre, if our committee and Board of 
era suggest keeping our premium list entire as it is, and if our 
nakes special premiums for our own state, that we, as the state 
iraska. are "proud to have our advertising placards go out to the 
Our men who exhibit are proud to compete with the men from 
Missouri or Illinois, but with men in the circuit and travelling 
ne fair to another, it is hard for our men to compete with them. 

Mr. Morse: They like to compete, and it is to our interests as a 
state, to compete with the stock of the other states. But still where 
our exhibitors are in their infancy, as Mr. Mclntyre says, they have 
$1,500 applied to our state herds, they can still compete in the champion 
premium. This money should be for our state here. It would stimulate 
our own state stock, for it would compete in the original where it 
is open for all states, and then as a state compete one as against 
another. It would bar them of the circuit out. Of course you gentlemen 
connected with the stock circuit know that they are trained for 
this special purpose. For us as a Board of Agriculture to cut down, I 
think it would be best to have it opened for the world. 

Mr. Bassett: There are some peculiar things in fair work. You think 
increased premiums. Last year they said if we would offer not less 
than $5,000 as our premiums they would duplicate the amount. We 
increased the amount over $80 in the shorthorn class so that whole 
amount offered was $500, and the Shorthorn Breeders' Association took 
$500 more. 

I Mr. Dlnsmore: So far as I am aware there is not a single thing from 
e shorthorn breeders' last year special premium. There was not an 
itry made in the book. 

Mr. Bassett: We offered no sweepstakes. This provision of cash in 
this lot I made and made the requirements of the American Shorthorn 
Association. 

Mr. Oinsmore: That we put in there two years ago, but there was 
nothing in that book to show that the shorthorn breeders made an 
offer. • 


Mr. Bassett: Did they make the offer? 

Mr. Dinsmore: They made the offer, but it was never printed. The 
Shorthorn Breeders' Association will not duplicate the premium* in 

5 </seg>

            <seg id="p073">
66 


it in the premium list in time. The Shorthorn Breeders' Association 
about that time, when that correspondence was going on, the secretary 
suddenly died, and the office was turned into confusion and for nearly 
tfcree months they were practically without any head of the office 
force, and 1 presume that is where the trouble grew out. 

¦etary Fnnias: I think we printed some slips afterwards. I 
the money was paid by the American Association. I furnished 
certified list of the rules and he paid the premiums himself. 

BHnsmore: I sent for the book. There was no entry of special 
in made in the book at that time. This is true that if the 
is taken up to-day the $500 can be gotten for this state and the 
gotten from the Herefords. I am satisfied it can be gotten from 
ers. 

Eretnry Kuriiiis: In regard to that shorthorn premium. They 
made the same offers for some other years. Last year they did 
»nd in their proposition until after the premium list was printed 
&gt;ut, and then the secretary said that upon my certificate they 
I be paid, and they were paid. 

Mr. Massett: The offer is here in the premium list; eighty more than 
in the shorthorn out of any other list. Yet their exhibit at our fair 
last year was poor. The point 1 want to make is this: that by increasing 
the amount of money does not always increase the exhibit to that 
extent. I think that is true; the increasing of the amount of premiums 
not always increase the attendance. The premiums offered in the 
nine classes of cattle aggregated about $4,000 or $3,500. Now if we 
were to increase as proposed here, by making special premiums for 
Nebraska horses, if you did that in cattle you must pay for any horses 
if you did that in cattle you must pay for any horses shipped; that 
would make a considerable increase. In making up these premium 
lists two things are to be considered; one thing, the amount of the 
premiums offered to induce the people to come to the fair, and the 
other thing the gate receipts to pay these. These things the Board 
of Managers have considered. The gate receipts should pay the 
premiums. Whether it would be wise that we would not pay $3,500 
for the cattle exhibit at our fair, open to the world, that we reduce 
that amount and divide it and make it $1,500, whether it would be a 
thing to do, it is a question. We arc in line with other state fairs, 
only the premiums offered by our Board are less than in some other 
states. The premiums offered for agricultural products, I have not 
seen that any other state offers as much as Nebraska. I never seen at 
any state fair such an exhibit of agriculture as will be seen at ours, and 
it may be true we omit here and there some things. The committee 
asked the Poultry Association yesterday to revise the schedule for the 
poultry list. I don't know that I will serve on that committee for the 
ensuing year, hut it has always been niv wish to consider the recom- </seg>

            <seg id="p074">
67 


mendation of the Superintendent as to what should go into the premium 
list. I don't see how we can well increase the rates at the state fair. 
Thus a certain number of people will go to the state fair. I understand 
the Burlington railroad use* every coach they have got to bring 
the people. If this is true, and more people are to come, they must 
provide more equipment. If you increase the attraction you are going 
to increase the number of people to come. 

Ensmore: I simply give a word along the line of what a sister 
s done in increasing its cash receipts through the increasing of 
is in the live-stock. The city of Minneapolis two years ago, in 
December last, was met with the proposition from the Hereford 
Breeders' Association that they would make an exhibit and sale at 
the coming Minnesota State Fair, and put up $2,000 for special premiums 
for that breed of cattle, provided the state board would do the same 
thing. The shorthorn people came back at them, saying, if you do 
that with the Hereford people you must do it with the shorthorn people, 
and we will put up the same money. The board took it up by telegraph 
with the boards in St. Paul and Minneapolis and they advised 
them to go ahead and accept the oltier. They did so. The increased 
attendance by reason of that show a year ago last fall at Hainlin was 
probably better- than 40 per cent of what it had been before. A gentleman 
residing in this city who was present at the last state fair at 
Hamlin tells me, and the secretary of the board carries it out, that 
their attendance in one day, actual cash attendance, was 82,000 during 
the days when the stock exhibit was at its height and the sales -were 
going on. Their attendance has increased year by year by reason of 
the increased premiums offering the extra inducement given to people 
to come out and see the cuttle. Quite a number of the Board of 
Directors with whom I talked in December were in favor of making an 
offer to this Board, not as much money, but a similar amount, increasing 
the amount offered here. If we would do something to encourage 
them, and with the experience in the matter of bringing out 
people in the expositions ut Chicago and Omaha, I saw that whenever 
the live-stock came on exhibition the increased attendance was noticeable. 
The stock day drew an increased attendance of people. 

President: I was at Chicago this winter — I will make a report after 
a while at the meeting of the fair associations to set the dates and 
consult together — and 1 overheard to quite an extent this matter 
talked about, especially from Minnesota. I heard the secretary himself 
say, as Mr. Dinsmore says, that their attendance was something 
like 82,000 on one day. As I remember it now, the president sa \ 
what do you attribute your large attendance? He says that is a 
question I can't answer. He says, we tried to treat the people well 
and paid our premiums and we threw the gates wide open. Some one 
asked how many free admissions there were that day. He says any </seg>

            <seg id="p075">
68 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AflEICULTlRE. 

hard matter, in fact I know it is &amp; hard matter. I say there is nobody 
that can attribute the attendance or success of any state fair to one 
feature of it; you have to take them all into consideration. 

Mr. Seacrest: On the day that they had 82,000 there they had Mr. 
Roosevelt. They said they were centrally located between Minneapolis 
and St. Paul, they are right close by there, and the weather was nice. 
I remember of that being spoken of too. For that reason we cannot 
be governed by things of that nature. We have to take these matters 
up and consider them. We are not as wealthy as they are, and we 
have to be guided along the line of what we think is right. I know 
they have always extended an invitation to those interested along the 
line of correcting the premium list. 

Mr. Cantlin: 1 will say for Minnesota, they have got a very large 
tract of country to be occupied that is not occupied now, and they 
desire it occupied, and for that reason they give their live-stock a 
hearty support. A few years ago I was there, and Mr. Bassett was 
there also. I was requested to attend their state fair while there, and 
to pay particular attention to the agricultural interests there, to see 
if I could improve on our exhibits. I became acquainted with the 
State Board of Agriculture and was there nearly all day, and I can 
say to you while they paid fair premiums, they didn't begin to pay 
what we pay here. What was the success of our fair? We felt our 
buildings could hardly hold them. I could take any three counties in 
our fair exhibits and put up a better exhibit of agriculture than they 
had In Minnesota that year. Since the rulings of our supreme court 
and the feelings and sentiments of our present President of the United 
States, and the majority of the memberR of congress, we are going to 
open a large area of land in the western part of our state that is not 
producing anything now. In the early days it was not wise to break up 
the western part of our state, but it has been done, and with the improvements 
in the next few years we will develop the lands. I will ask 
Mr. Bassett to say if an increase of premiums will not bring a better 
exhibit or attendance to the fair. I contend it will, and these men 
in the western part of Nebraska want to be recognized. In the '60's I 
was there myself and I know what they have to contend with. We 
want to give them support, and make it so it will be advisable to put 
up good premiums. A man who gets $200 on his premium, it does not 
pay him. I believe if you would put up more for agricultural interests 
that it would fully pay us for our labor. 

Mr. Bassett: There is one thing. My friend. Cantlin and I hardly ever 
agree. He says that the whole aggregate at the Minnesota state fair 
wasn't as much as one county that we had in this state. Now that is 

Secretary Furnas: How many western states can do better than 
Nebraska? 

Mr. Mclntyre: They are aptly situated. Hamlin is midway between </seg>

            <seg id="p076">
69 


PMid Minneapolis of 400.000; it only costs you a nickel to go 
rr of these places to the grounds. They are a wealthy people. 
Dt situated as the state of Minnesota is in that way. That is 
5 conceptions of .Tim Hill. He says, move it down into llamlin 
¦ St. Paul and Minneapolis there. They will quit quarreling 
location, and you will get these people to support your fair. 
b special days for St. Paul and Minneapolis. 

Mr. Bassett: Yes, that is true, they get up a consideration. I don't 
wish to be understood as saying that the magnitude of the exhibit was 
not affected by the amount of money offered, but it is not true when 
you offer more money that you get more exhibi 

Mr. Dinsmore: In 1897 I was at Hamlin. Had they barred out the 
Manitoba exhibit which was there and afterwards came to our state, 
the smallest county that we had in 1897 would have put up a better 
agricultural exhibit than they had on the Minnesota state fair grounds. 
Barring out the Manitoba exhibit, the smallest county exhibit on our 
grounds would have exceeded the agricultural products of the soil on 
the Minnesota grounds that year. In the last twenty years I have 
attended the Iowa state fair at least twelve years. I have never yet 
seen an exhibit there from the state of Iowa that was equal to the 
exhibit that I have seen from Custer, Douglas or Washington counties 
in certain years of this state. 

Blent: This discussion came up over the report of the Revision 
tee. 

Upon the motion being made to aeeefM the report it was carried. 

Er. Mann: I would like to bring up for consideration at this 
ual meeting, and have a committee appointed, including our S. 
', and whoever this Board think best, to treat with our railroads 
and the passenger traffic, to have a reduction in the tickets for the 
long distance run. In Omaha, when we had the fair there, we got a 
run there for the Board of $6, and our gate receipts for our fair. 
Our gate receipts are of vital interest to render this fair a success, 
and if we could get the same reduction like at Omaha and a $5 or $6 
rate for the long run. — when they come within 100 or 150 miles they 
come on the regular rate. — to have the usual rate from the western 
part of the state we can get them from the western part of the state. 
With the Omaha rate there were people who came from Chadron; and 
my resolution, if I put it in the form of a resolution, would be that our 
Secretary and a committee wait upon Mr. Holdrege in regard to this 
matter. One of those tickets carries a coupon for our fair, and I 
would like to submit this qvesttoa so it would get in shape; we could 
then get people from the western part of the state. Of course the 
Sion arises with our state fair, to render it successful it must be 
with care by the Board of Management and our President and 
itary for this reason, if anything should come to us next year 
ave got a home. I am glad we have got it. But suppose now </seg>

            <seg id="p077">
70 


first time in five years that M ha\e eoMM to our annual meeting- with 
little money in our treasury at about $1,500, and it conies up that we 
seem to have some obligations that we have pot to meet. I l&gt;elieve 
rt if we have a eonimitti-e to wait upon Mr. Iloldrege and Mr. BMweU 
lay this matter l&gt;efore them it will brtaaj us in gate receipts the 
same as it did at Omaha, ft pets the people in the west interested in 
our state fair. 

Mr. Wallace: Being from the western part of the state, and the 
reason that the western part of the state has not taken the interest 
in the state fair that it should is simply berause we are barred out 
on the rate for one thing. Our resources out there are in one sense 
hardly equal to any part of the state, but when we have to pay from 
$10, $12 and $15 fare, and then pay our hotel bills, we can't afford to 
come; that is, enough cannot afford to come to keep up the representa- 
El of the western part of the state. As he says. 1 think, it would 
well to have this Boaril to ha\e an understanding in some way with 
railroads to get a better rate for the western part of the state. 

E-. Mclntyre: 1 think at Omaha they had a blanket rate of $5 for 
round trip. I think, however, if this is taken up in time it can be 
nged. 

Mr. L.vdick: I would like tt. say. while the gentlemen from the 
western part of the state are asking for rates, 1 would like to ask 
for rates for the eastern |Kirt of the slate. I got my receipt at Tekamah, 
expecting to get some rebate. When I faH back to Omaha I presented 
my receipt and they said there was no arrangement made. I have got 
¦ two receipts now. and while the western part of the state is 
making for something to be done in the way of railroad rates, I would 
like to have something done in the eastern. 

President: In my connection with the State Board for the past 
few years, mv experience is we ha\e gone to the railroad people, and 
we hare taken up the matter of passenger and freight rates, and we 
have thought that the roads have l&gt;een very fair with the State Board. 
Now they have rules that we can talk about, but when we go up 
against them we are helpless. Of course, as Mr. Lydick says, you are 
unfortunate; you are on the wrong road. We have had a whole lot 
of trouble from that section of the country. We never have our friend 
up there. Mr. Peterson: he never conies down here but what we have 
trouble, not with him particularly, but the railroad people don't think 
M he thinks they ought to, and as other roads do to a certain extent. 
Now will any one make a motion 1 .' 

E-. Lewelling: I am glad this Matter was sprung right here. I 
'rom the western part of the state. Knrnns county, and 1 want to 
that the way the excursions have lmt.li run to the state fair, they 
been against the people of Furnas county. We had a fiat rate 
i for the round trip, which was cheap enough, but they started the </seg>

            <seg id="p078">
71 


people in r urnas county and got them here in the evening of Thursday 
and they could only go into the fair on Friday. They complained to 
me there, and said, why don't you change it and have the excursion 
start on Tuesday, and we would fret some Iwnefit of it. and contribute 
something to the support of the fair and come away satisfied. When 
they start in the morning they get here in the evening- and it is too 
late to go into the state fair and have to go in Friday. You must let 
them exhibit until 4 o'clock in the evening the last day. If this matter 
could be taken up with the railroads and start on Tuesday instead of 
Thursday, you can get the people to come. 

Mr. Bassett: We are talking of holding the fair in the evening, and 
that will take care of the matter. 

Rlent: I will report that I am named as a delegate to attend 
vention at CUeagD, called the Western Fair A Exposition Assoand 
the time set for holding our State Fair was August 29 to 
September 5 inclusive; the other state fairs come about the same time 
as usual, Iowa just preceding ours, and then Minnesota. Ohio and ours 
is the same week. This is nut exact, but that is about the rotation of 
them. This Board, at course, has power to change that if they see 
fit; we did that once. We arc in a kind of rotation or circuit. It waa 
the week we wanted and we were fortunate in getting it, and I 
tsunie a motion to either confirm that now, or a new plan, would 
in order. 

Mr. Dinsmore: I move you that the time assigned to Nebraska for 
holding its fair at the meeting of the National Association of Fair 
Managers lw accepted and adopted. Carried. 

(Mr. Cantlin here takes the chair.) 

ELECTION- OF OFFICERS. 

Chairman: There is a motion l&gt;efore the house that we proceed to 
elect officers. Are you ready for the question? Motion carried. 

The Chairman appointed the following as tellers: Mr. Ewing, Mr. 

Chairman: The first thing in order is the nominations for President. 
Mr. Mellor: I rise to nominate our present President, Mr. E. L. Vance. 

Bi'illinnis: I rise to nominate one of our oldest members in the 
tion for President, that is Mr. Dinsniore. believing that he is 
inipped as I do. and 1 don't believe there is a member present 
II disagree as to Mr. Dinsmore's ability. 

Ballot being taken, resulted as follows: Vor Mr. Vance, 18; for Mr. 
Dinsmore. 

Eirman: Mr. Vance h;is It votes, and Mr. Dinsmore 25 votes. By 
ballots you have elected Mr. Dinsiuore as your President for the 
vear. 

(Mr. Vance resumes the chair.) 

President: Next thiny in order will be the election of the First Vice- 
Pr.-si.lent. </seg>

            <seg id="p079">
72 

NEBRASKA STATE BOAKi 

Mr. Mclntyre: I place Mr. McKay, of Hamilton county, in nomination. 

Mr. Dinsmore: I hope I may be permitted to ask that Mr. McKay be 
"ted for. 

Mr. Hervey: I place in nomination Mr. Williams, of Omaha. 
Mr. Williams: I respectfully decline the nomination. 
Mr. Cantlin: I nominate Mr. E. P. Job. T move you that the Secre- 

tary cast the ballot of this society for Mr. Job. Carried. 

Secretary Furnas: The unanimous vote of the society is cast for 
Mr. Job, as First Vice-President. 

Mr. Vance: I nominate for Second Vice-President Mr. W. E. Ewing. 

Mr. Mellor: I desire to place in nomination for Secretary for the en¦ring 
year. R. W. Furnas. 

Mr. Dinsmore: I would move that the President be instructed to cast 
the ballot of this association if there is no other nomination. Carried. 

mMmU: The vote is so cast, and by that you have elected (Jovernor 
Furnas to succeed himself as secretary. 

P Dinsmore: I desire to place in nomination for Treasurer our 
Treasurer, and if there be no other nominations, that the Secbe 
instructed to. cast the ballot of the association for his elee- 

President: Do I hear any other nominations. The Secretary is so 
instructed to cast the vote. Carried. 

Secretary Furnas: The vote is so cast. 

President Vance: Gentlemen, I have the pleasure of introducing to 
your old friend as well as mine, and it is with pleasure that I 
introduce him now to you as your President. 

I |«n the invitation of President Vance. Mr. Dinsmore, the newly 
elected President, took the platform and spoke as follows: 

ADDRESS OF PRESIDENT DINSMORE 

iilimrn of the State Board of Agriculture: This is an honor that vmi 
have conferred upon me that I appreciate most highly, yet it is not 
such an honor that I have not had before, because I was President of 
this Board in 1884-1885, and it is a renewed expression of the confidence 
have in me and an appreciation of .the work that I have done in 
the advancement of the agricultural interests of this state during the 
twenty-five years that closes with this meeting since I was first elected 
a member of your Board. When some asked me if I would serve if I 
was elected I said I had had all the honor there was in it, and siwne 
of the hard work, and I never shrank from the duties placed upon me 
by the State Board of Agriculture. 

I can promise you only one thing, that I will bring 1 to your service 
the best that I have. If I make mistakes they will be of the head and 
not of the heart; I will do everything I can to advance the interests of </seg>

            <seg id="p080">
73 


the Board, and so when we come together next year we will make ma 
I a report as possible. 

What is your pleasure? 

Mr. Basset t: I submitted a report here last evening that I am 
greatly interested in, — not because it is my report, — and in connection 
\vith that report I submitted a resolution. If permissible at this time 
1 would like to have the resolution acted upon. The report, as I understand, 
is laid over for discussion. It is too late for discussion at this 
time, but I hope it may be acted upon now. As I stated in the«report, 
that Supt. W. K. Fowler had been most active and earnest to make an 
arrangement for the teaching of agriculture in the schools, and Professors 
Bessey and Bruner were to prepare a text-book. The resolution 
is as follows: 

Resolved. That we are in favor of such legislation by the national 
congress as will protect the legitimate dairy interests of the nation 
against the fraudulent sale and use of oleomargarine as and for butter, 
and to this end we favor the passage by congress of the so-called 
•(irout Bill" or a bill of like nature, and most respectfully request our 
senators and members of congress to support such a measure; also 
that the Secretary be requested to send a copy of this resolution to 
each senator- and member of congress from this state. 

President Dinsmore: You have heard the resolution, what is your 
pleasure? Carried. 

t President Dinsmore: If I may be permitted to make a report that 
ould have been made before coming here I will do so. and briefly 
ate my reasons for it. 

REPORT OF SUPERINTENDENT OK CLASS B (CATTLE). 

Tn The Xebraska State Board of Agriculture : Your Superintendent of 
- B (Cattle) would respectfully report that the exhibit in this 
class was fairly satisfactory as to number although falling short of the 
exhibit of some prior years. 

Bit was deficient in some lots as to merit, showing lack of preparation 
id care. 

Et is the opinion of your superintendent that premiums could be 
rhtlv advanced to the credit of the Board and the satisfaction of 
libitors. 

(Your superintendent would rec6mmend that a class be provided 
nong beef breeds for cattle owned in the state of Nebraska, leaving 
M classification as it now is open to animals coming from whatever 
puree they may. It being my firm conviction that this would result 
in bringing out a large exhibit of animals from the herds of the state 
that have hitherto failed to make an exhibit. 

1 would recommend that a rule be added which shall place it within 
the discretion of the superintendent to bar from the show ring animals 
that are not properly broken to halter and whose general appear- </seg>

            <seg id="p081">
74 


ance indicate* a lack of care in preparation, whose condition is such as 
to show that they are not representative animals of the breed in their 
then present condition. 

It is my firm conviction that each year the Board is paying out 
money in the way of premiums awarded to animals that are not a 
credit to the breed, that are a disgTace to the Board offering the premiums 
and a disgrace to the exhibitors, the exhibition of which should 
be discouraged in every way possible, to the end that exhibitors will 
properly train their animals and put them in such condition to be 
shown as they should be in if offered for sale at home. Respectfully 
submitted, J. B. Dinsmobe. Superintendent. 

This was forced upon my mind last year by finding- animals offered 
upon the grounds for exhibition that from their appearance had never 
been halter-broken. They had the appearance of never having had a 
hair straightened on them except what their mother did, what she did 
in her affection in petting them. They were not in good condition 
even at home. Brother Filley will bear me out in that. That has not 
only been this year but every year that I have had the honor of this 
Board of representing, the superintendent of that class. The superintendent 
of Iowa said the sooner you stop paying premiums on such 
Eimals and say to your men that they must have them broken and 
tc their hair straightened out the better work you are doing for 
ur breeder, better service lo your Board and state and all concerned. 

Mr. Mellor: I move that the recommendation be referred to the 
Committee -on Revision. Seconded. Carried. 

Mr. Cantlin: I will say, as long as I have been appointed on that 
bread-and-butter committee, I have had but very few reports of these 
fellows that have been eating the bread and butter, and it is very important 
if they want any money that they hand in their hotel bills, 
because I am going to get out of here pretty soon and this will have to 
be attended to. We are somewhat in the dark; we are not sure who 
will pay these bills. 

B'sident : If you will permit, as I understood the resolution last 
ng there was to be a pay-roll that would show the number of 
ms here who are representing them either as members of the 
i or presidents of county societies, that they pay their hotel bills 
you pay them the amount not to exceed $ . The Board will 
get you the money. 

Mr. Williams: I move as an amendment that the amount be set at 
$4 for each member for his expense account instead of an indefinite 
amount. 

Mr. Ewing: I move to amend and make it $3 

President reads the resolution as follows: 

Retnlwd, That the hofel bills of the members and delegates of this 
meeting not exceeding $3 be paid by this Board, and that a committee </seg>

            <seg id="p082">
75 

Kr*POItX OF AN N I Al. M EET1 N (i. 

of one be appointed by the president, who shall have power to pay 

Mr. Bassett: I move you that the adoption of it be reconsidered, that 
is the resolution just read. Carried. 

Kill i;i m&gt;: I now move you that $4 be appropriated to each memient 
as expense account. 

¦lent: Allow me ti make a suggestion. There are certain memre 
whtr have been on a committee who came in here early. If 
lid amend so as to include others than those. 

Mr. Williams: I accept that as amended, and the President will 
please read it. 

Kient: The motion i.s that the members other than those on 
tee work be allowed $4 expense; and that the committee be 
the rate of $2 a day for additional time. Carried. 

Eiident: The question has been asked me whether or not we would 
this room this afternoon. So far as I know the business is pracover. 


I am not at present ready to name my Board of Managers, but would 
be perhaps at 2 o'clock. The law requires them to be confirmed by the 
Board. 

Kellor: It has been moved and seconded that the president name 
•d of Managers, and when named the same be confirmed by this 
.s having been done at the time. Carried. 

Mr. Cantlin: I would ask that the Secretary furnish me a list according 
to the vote, and I will be at the Lindell Hotel in the lobby 
there at 2 o'clock this afternoon. 

(Mr. Bassett reads the Board of Managers' rules.) 

The Board of Managers has been in peculiar relation to the State 
Board. Some of the business which they do may get into court. There 
have been such things in the past and there might be in the future. I 
think it would be wiser for this Board to adjourn to the Lindell Hotel 
at 2 o'clock and approve of the appointment of the Board of Managers. 
Therefore, I move when we adjourn we adjourn to meet at the Lindell 
Hotel at 2 o'clock. 

Mr. Mellor: I move to reconsider the motion, the vote just taken, to 
approve of the Board of Managers. Motion to reconsider adopted. 

CLr. Bassett: I move that we now take a recess to 2 o'clock at the 
dell Hotel. Carried. 

After recess, the Board, with a quorum, convened at Hotel Lindell. 

President Dinsmore appointed as Board of Managers: C. H. Rudge, 
Chairman; W. R. Mellor, Peter Youngers, Jr., A. R, Williams, T. A. 
McKay. The nominations were confirmed by the Board. 

There being no further business, the Board adjourned *ime die. 

J. B. Dinsmobe, PrttUmt. </seg>




            <seg id="p084">
BY HUGH F. M'INTOSH, EDITOR NEBRASKA FARMER. 

On a memorial stone erected on the lawn at "Arbor Lodge" ia thi* 
inscription: "The beginning of this home was made by J. Sterling Morton 
and Caroline Joy Morton in June, 1855." Old prints show that the 
beginning was a log cabin with log "lean-to's" on two aides, and the 
present mansion house, which looms up in stately magnificence through 
the trees which have made the founder of "Arbor Lodge" famous, is 
the fourth residence which has crowned the beautiful swell of rolling 
prairie which constitutes the site of the Morton home. 

In November, 1854, J. Sterling Morton, of Detroit, Mich., a young 
college graduate of Union College in New York state, accompanied by 
his wife, reached Nebraska. Their journey to the frontier trading 
post of Bellevue, Neb., was a bridal tour. But Nebraska City was at 
that time the gateway to the trans-Missouri country. It was also the 
pioneer "townsite" for booming purposes. Its attractions soon drew 
the Mortons away from the quiet Indian trading post of Bellevue. and 
early in the year 1855 J. Sterling Morton became actively identified 
with the business interests of Nebraska City, throwing into the booming 
and building up of the town all of his tremendous energy and persistence. 


West of the Missouri River in 1855 the only thing which had no value 
was land. It was nearly all "open," and the few settlers had pick and 
choice. Mr. Morton, upon identifying himself with the town aa the 
publisher of its newspaper, had secured a liberal allowance of town 
lots. But the love of nature which was always a predominant note 
in his character led Mr. Morton to select a farm — a picturesque tract 
of land adjoining the city on the west — for his home, in preference to 
the narrow confines of a town lot. Hence, the foundation of the 
famous "Arbor Lodge," as chronicled in the beginning of this narrative. 

The Morton farm was a roughly undulating stretch of timber and 
prairie. A small creek which winds its way eastward to the river cuts 
through the south side of the farm, and a draw from the northwest 
breaks up the eastern portion of it. The creek banks and draw are 
heavily timbered, the latter now constituting beautiful "Morton Park," 
which was donated to the town by Mr. Morton, and constitutes one 
of the attractions of Nebraska City. A meandering drive through this 
grassy, well kept park leads to the broad gate of Arbor Lodge. 

At this point it may be proper to suggest that the public have come 
to entertain a wholly erroneous notion in regard to Mr. MortoD&gt; tree </seg>


            <seg id="p085">
78 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGBICULTUM. 

planting'. It is quite generally thought that Mr. Morton planted trees 
for economic (timber) purposes. This is not true. Mr. Morton's land 
had on it an abundance of native timber. This has been preserved and 
carefully husbanded. His tree planting has been exclusively for ornamental 
and educational purposes, except where orchards were planted. 
At this time the Morton farm is essentially an apple orchard. It is not 
and never has been a timber plantation. The timber on the farm is, in 
fact, of but little economic value, consisting as it does of elm, soft 
maple, burr oak, etc. — the usual collection found near the Missouri 
River, and such planted-in species as make it a valuable educational 
collection. It is not unfair, either, to suggest that since Mr. Morton 
was not a farmer, "Arbor Lodge" has not been conducted as an agricultural 
enterprise. Corn, alfalfa, etc., are produced on the farm, and 
pigs, poultry and some cattle stock are maintained, as well as the farm 
family horses. But the inspiration of "Arbor Lodge" was not 
agriculture, just as it was not arboriculture. This magnificent example 
of art applied to agriculture is the result of making a "home." "Arbor 
Lodge" is a home. The gross sense of building a temporary shelter 
while wringing money out of the soil to buy more land to make more 
money to go into town to spend one's declining years never poisoned 
the poetic spring out of which flowed the sweet water of rural associations 
in Mr. Morton's heart. The farm was to him cool shade and fresh 
breezes, the songs of birds and the soft soughing of the wind in the 
. bright bloom and the odor of flowers, rest and the sweet intimacy 
of loved ones. 

Mr. Morton's life was not the life of a farmer, though his chief pleasand 
his honors came of his agricultural associations. His nature 
was intensely aggressive, and while he must have succeeded, in a business 
sense, had he devoted his energy to agriculture, men so endowed 
-e rather to pass their lives in the crowded avenues of business. 
Therefore it was that Mr. Morton loved the editorial desk, commercial 
enterprises and the intensity of political contest. 

It was both the rich endowment and the fault of Mr. Morton that 
he was a man of convictions, for in his aggressive nature a conclusion 
once arrived at became a passion, and from its grip Mr. Morton could 
not himself swerve, even in immaterial things, nor could he tolerate 
in others a different conclusion, even if reached by equally conscientious 
reasoning from a different point of view. This characteristic had 
the virtue of making Mr. Morton's life simple and secure, if not serene. 

Mr. Morton's youth and young manhood embraced the ante-bellum 
period of states rights and anti-slavery agitation, and low tariff in the 
political life of the nation. And since he was always a student of books 
of history and political economy, his reading inclined him to the 
theory of national organization and conduct of government which has 
become known as Jacksonian Democracy, and his early associations and 
conservative instincts wedded him to that party. None of the national </seg>

            <seg id="p086">
79 

TRIBUTE TO THE MEMORY OF .1. STKRI.IXG MORTON. 

Pthe last half century served to change those early «wodl-1 
when Mr. Morton was called to administer one of the deof 
government, in IM-T, as Secretary of Agriculture under 
Cleveland, he enjoyed a coveted opportunity to demonstrate 
Dusness of his lifetime conviction that the limit of utility 
lent is reached when it secures opportunity to the individual. 

In pursuance of this principle, Mr. Morton, as Secretary of Agrieulture, 
unsparingly cut off the multitude of "nephews" and "nieces" 
"I ncle" Jerry Rusk and his predecessors in the office had made places 
for and paid salaries to for only trifling service in the Department, 
and cut out the glaring abuse of vacation and travel privilege which 
absorbed the funds of the Department. He fought ( impress for four 
years to get rid of the free seed distribution humbug, and failing in 
this applied business methods to the seed distribution, with the result 
that two packages of seeds were sent out for what was formerly the 
of one. He discontinued a multitude of special experiments 
which he found had reached the point of demonstration, and ceased 
to spend public money on them. He spent money to perfect the 
meat inspection system so our meat products would stand the 
test in every market of the world. He spent money to perfect 
the crop reporting system, extending the work so as to cover 
practically all competing grain growing countries. He spent money 
to conserve and develop the timber resources of the nation, and to 
ascertain the adaptability of soils to special crops. He spent money 
to try to make the weather service a science from which agriculture 
could derive economic advantage. But Mr. Morton did not expend all 
the money Congress appropriated for his Deportment. It was to him 
the crowning achievement of administration that he conducted the 
Department of Agriculture with unmistakable efficiency while at the 
same time returning to the treasury, as saved to the people, in the four 
years of his administration, $2,066,661.19 — about 28 per cent of the entire 
sum appropriated. This would have been regarded a princely sum 
in any period of the government prior to this age of unbridled extravagance 
in national expenditure, and would have been conceded to be a 
noble achievement. But this virtue of economy in conducting the office 
was seized upon by the barnacles and grafters who fatten on the maladministration 
of government at Washington, and the Secretary's work 
fel systematically and designedly discredited in the minds of the peowho 
are made to believe that it is weak to save and wisdom to 
spend all and more than Congress provides for the Department. N 
before was saving 1 the people's money accounted a sin! And now that 
the mantle of death has hidden the great Secretary from the enemies 
his uprightness in office made, will historians fairly record his invaluable 
services to agriculture? 

Korton's love for the forum would have made him 3 romm 
i any state. And in the formative period of a state, such ma </seg>

            <seg id="p087">
80 


Nebraska was when Mr. Morton was a young; man, so rugged a per- 
Inality could not but achieve prominence. And had Mr. Morton's 
nvictions been less intense and his will less inflexible he might have 
joyed every honor his state can bestow. Bnt endowed as he was, Mr. 
»rton merely achieved the distinction of being 1 for a full generation 
e storm center of Nebraska's political life. In the infancy of the 
ite Mr. Morton missed election to the position of governor of the 
ite and afterwards United States senator, by one of the accidents of 
litical life which historians will ever find it impossible to explain or 
ree upon. Such defeat might have embittered and crushed a less 
rdy nature. It may, indeed, have embittered Mr. Morton's life, for 
opponents ever found him a relentless, uncompromising antagonist. 
t political defeat never crushed him. In the most hopeless hour of 
his party's history Mr. Morton was willing to lead the forlorn hope. 
Twice in recent times he was the candidate of his party for governor, 
and without hope of success his campaigns were made with vigor, persistence 
and the enthusiasm impossible except to a man intensely convinced 
of the righteousness of the cause he represents. In the moment 
of political controversy and under the heat of party passion men mock 
at this devotion to conviction. But may we not seriously ask ourselves, 
would not Nebraska as a community have honored herself by accepting 
the services of a man of such conviction, integrity, and inflexibility of 
purpose? The political history of Nebraska forbids the belief that 
the state has not "killed some of her prophets and stoned those who 
were sent." 

It was impossible for a man actively interested in public affairs, 
whose lot was cast in Nebraska in territorial days, not to come much in 
contact with government contracting, railroad and townsite promoting, 
and the one and sundry things which shake a man's faith in the honesty 
of the few and the business judgment of the many. Mr. Morton 
undoubtedly suffered from the latter, however the observation of the 
former may have influenced him. Very few men who have been prominent 
in public life evinced so little faith in the judgment of the common 
people, nor regarded masses so indifferently if not contemptuously. 
Those who have read Mr. Morton's political and economic writings in 
recent years must have gotten the impression that those who are not 
"thrifty" are to be regarded »s weaklings or unsafe persons. He was 
insistent that the strong hand of government should not be held out 
to help even the most deserving of her citizens, and that if men did 
not choose to create wealth by industrial pursuits they should neither 
share in the fruits of industry nor presume to a voice in directing public 
affairs. The spirit of his writing and speech was as if to say, "The 
earth and the fullness thereof belongs- to him who can take it. If you 
have no taste for looting the sooner you get out of the scramble the 
better. Ood loves those who get." He made money out of railroad 
investments, and his sons were pushed into railroad service or advanced </seg>

            <seg id="p088">
S 
u^ 

J 

: I 

r *ri 

! 

u 

' 

s 

i 

«? 

&gt; 

%Vl 

! 

TvC 

! 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p089">
TRIBUTE TO THE MEMORY OF J. ST! 

81 

in business by railroad favoritism till they are what are known aa 
"captains of industry" (chief captains). Yet Mr. Morton never tired 
of denouncing- the people who voted bonds in aid of railroads and other 
public service corporations. Neither did he tire of denouncing those 
who invoke government aid in business enterprises, either directly or indirectly. 
Almost his last public appearances were made in laboring 
to thwart the dairy interests in their efforts to secure, through the 
i. rout bill, government aid to protect the dairy industry from unfair 
petition by the packing industry. And by what scorns to be "the 
irony of fate" that bill was given final passage by Congress when the 
mortal remains of Mr. Morton were awaiting interment. But having 
mentioned this partiality of Mr. Morton for those who succeed in busifor 
the Ranctity of property and accumulated wealth, we are 
mindful that those who have come very near to Mr. Morton in private 
life insist that any view of his life which reflects the opinion that he 
waa a hard and unsympathetic man does him great wrong. They point 
rather to his well known devotion to his family, his constancy in 
friendship, and the enthusiasm for the beautiful and refined in nature 
as the true indices of Mr. Morton's character. It is certainly true that 
no busy man has given more of his life to promote a love for those 
things which give comfort and beauty to the home life. And where 
the bitterness of political controversy has not entered into the estimation 
of the man. Mr. Morton will be known rather as the poetic spirit 
which in January, 1872. gave the world a thought which crystallized into 
a nearly universal "Arbor Day" than as a political controversaliinflexible 
resolution and implacable animosity. 

Looking out from the ample porches of "Arbor Lodge," in every direction 
the work of the tree planter is in evidence. The long avenue 
leading through Morton Park to the city is embowered in planted trees 
showing a great variety of both conifer and deciduous species; on each 
the ample orchards. Then, beyond the forest bordered stream 
on a gentle slope, rising almost to the horizon's rim. is a continuous 
apple orchard. Every row is planted with mathematical exactness, and 
each tree is pruned and nurtured as if enjoying the special favor of the 
master. It is a matter of extreme interest to note that in his orcharding, 
while Mr. Morton in early plantings had entertained the current 
¦ rn notion of close planting and no pruning, in the younger orchards 
tfce trees are planted 33x33 feet, and are kept very carefully 
pruned. The old orchard has in recent years been most severely pruned 
also, and while the trees are scarred and greatly damaged by so much 
cutting, the results evidently justify the system, as the apple crop of 
Arl&gt;or Lodge was sold on the trees last year for M.7M, 

Eatest planting of interest at Arbor Lodge is the jungle of white 
i block of two acres on the northwest of the house, planted to 
miniature forest background to the "Lodge." This plantation 
lently referred to as evidence of the possibility of growing this 

« </seg>

            <seg id="p090">
82 

V STATE BOARD OF A(iRICl'I,Tl'RK. 

valuable of the pines in Nebraska on an economic scale, if given 
forest conditions. 

Mr. Morton was a successful business man. though he has rather 
pushed his sons into business opportunity than pursued those opportunities 
himself. Thus the manufacturing- industries of Nebraska City, 
the salt business in Chicago, the glucose factories in Peoria and the 
Burlington and Santa Fe railroads, with which the family interests 
¦ re identified, have become the work of the sons rather than of J. 
trling Morton. But along with each son went the counsel, and cour, 
and indomitable energy of the sire to win suci ¦ 

On the last day of April, when the narcissus and tulips, which border 
the long driveway into Arbor Lodge, filled the air of an exquisite spring 
afternoon with their heavy odor, and the whispering pines tossed languidly 
their branches in the breezr; when the apple trees were pink 
with bursting bloom and all nature was full of newness of life, the 
Sage of Arbor Lodge was borne out on loving hands from the "home" 
which had been the ideal and the inspiration of a stormy life. There 
came to do him reverence a multitude such as rarely meets around the 
bier of a private citizen. They represented every walk and calling in 
life, and those who had come nearest Mr. Morton's heart, whether as 
servants or as companions, bore evidence in their gTief of the strength 
of character and sincerity of the Sage of Arbor Lodge. </seg>


            <seg id="p091">
Of lands, improved and unimproved, live stock, crop returns, assessed 
valuations of property, state levy, assessments charged to counties for 
the year 1900, officially rendered by the several county clerks in the 
state of Nebraska. </seg>


            <seg id="p092">
NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AOHiri'LTl'M. 

|fi||5||M!iiii!iiiiiiiililiiiiiM^ 8 ni;iiM 
I ii iiiili i in i i i i If if ii i Mi ii ! i i i|gs i ii ||i I i 
1,1* i S i;il M 18 ! M M 1 ji i 1 1 M s i g N M f s !!«P i 

MIPIPI « H 111 II 1 lj&gt; 

¦iS ! I I I I f I I 1 i i ! i i : :• i i i i )• i I i 1 I i ! !¦ I I If = 1 ¦• i i 
li i i i i 1 1 i i i I i i I i i il : i i i il ! i 1 1 1 1 i Q| i I 1 1 i i is i I 
-S • • • • ! t • : i •••••••-¦••• IS ::•••••¦:¦••• i •¦ i 

1 il I j ii i 1 1 j 1 1 1 Mi 1 M ! I ! i I to 1 1 1 1 1 1 M 1 1 1 ! i 
*5 I ! i 1 i I ! I I I : : : : : : : : : : : i** 1 : : : ::::::: i : : 
£ j j i j j I j j j j i j I i j j j j j j j j j I j I j j I j j ¦ j j j I I j ' 

1 i i ! i 1 j i F ! i i i I i£ M I i j i I i I i ! 
* ijiuijji Mini \ MijjijjjiiiiiijiijjjH 

- 

s I It ! ! is i i : Ms ! ! &gt; hi ! 
&lt; Mi; j i j ; ; I j I j : ! I M ! i I I I I I i I I i I j i 111 

\ 
I 
El. 

I |5|j«l|jM Ms III Ms nil; 

j |! IN j|g;iijj|ijHi }!h| Mill 

;iii 

iTTjijj 

a 1 1 1 1 i j I ! ii ! I i i i I i ! i 1 1 1 ! I i 1 1 1 i i i i i i I i i j j j j j 
c I ! !; I I hi H iilii hi 1 
::::::::: ::::::::::::::::::::::::;:::t:; 

| 

| pjij j|Hj! 1 1 f ill IFMII 
S : : : :::::::::: 

I SjipTTSSi j|:i;ijniLiii;mwjH»jM! 
* ! ; ! • i ¦ ; ; ; ; i I ; • ; I ; ; ; ! ; ¦ ¦ I j j 

lllII|i g |ll§Ii||l|I|lll|Ili§Jillll8 g l|lllIl 

e !|| III i 1 II 1 i i 1 il ]J I ! il if p 
I j25 :|* j jig M* j* i j I* i*|6 j 

I i W I 

I 

!5i iti I ! ill i 1 1 1 li is 1 1 !e [ess i i | iEss i la iy I 
i ! 1 1 ! 1 1 1 1 1 I Hi ! I 

! I ! : i : : &gt; : &gt; I I ! ! l : ! i : ! ! I ! ! I i i I I I ! 1 I ! I I I I I I 
hi i! I j i !| j mm i i 
I I Mji I J il I I il! !| Mijiy 
ifiii^jiJ^dii^iidikiiiitlUiJiiu </seg>

            <seg id="p093">
¦ 

: ' j ; t : i ¦ : : I : : : 

Hi lip I M| i 18 ii i| I II I ii iilii 1 1 Mis I m nil 

1*111 Mil ! Ml 111 I !| Hi Ml Ml M [| M l|| |l| I us I 

¦ || ] ; :o« ! I I f i ! :• ! ! I ! i M ! ! ¦¦ : n i I i 1 i i ss = 
1 1 i :g I I I i I i ii 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 i •¦ ! i • ! i I ii i i ; si 
| i i !¦ i i 4 1 1 1 1 Illllifii i 1 1 i 1 1 1 1 f i i i - i = = I 
• : : ¦ : ¦ I ¦ ¦ ¦ i = : • • : ¦ i ¦ : ¦ ¦ •:¦;¦;¦::•:: M : 

: : : 

E I m i i i I I i I m I i i i i I I i m M I i i i j j i i ji j i i ii 
N I ill jiillii j i i I j 1 1 1 II i ! i ! H 1 !i ! I hi 
I I I i I I I ; I ; I j j i I j I I I j I i I I I i ; i I j I j i = Mil ;; I 

¦ : ¦ : : I • i •• • : :g ¦:::•: I I ! j ! I I* j I I I I I I ? 
i 1 1 1 i 1 1 f j I i fiiiiliiiilillliiilllil 1 1 1 i ! I ! i H 

: :^ i i I I t i =m llliliiililtiiililSiiliili III! *« *• ¦ : |« 
1 1* i i i 1 1 1 is 1 1 i 1 1 1 1 1 1 i S i II M 1 1 1 i i ! 1 1 ! 1 1 i 3 i i IS '¦ &lt; &gt;ll 
N ! I i i i ! ! i ! | I I I SI 

¦ I i53» i |c I j! il i MiiMaiMflMBMi s 
MM M li I illlilllii Mi Ml t ir I i Mri 

M|?|i j|s»jj|JH| Ms Ml Ms !j || ji jq ||i ||s i| | 

i i !• i i 1 1 i« i ! I I I i I ! IS i I ! 1 i i i 1 i I I I i *¦ l\ I '« * &gt;* ' I I 1 Mfe 
! HI i ! i ; ;| j i 1 1 i 1 1 i 1 1 ! i 1 1 i i 1 1 i j i ! I •* i ! i ia ! !I i 
Mi HIM M M i 1 1 M II M i I i M i 1 1 i M MM II fill In 

Nil! !iP!ili|i[l!]!]iii!|l!|!i!!liiN!il! 
I j 1 1 1 i I II II I till III1I III III M ; I 

Mi«ii Mgai |)9 Ms is jj j|| )|i Mi || || |a |i Mnr i{|| 
j i i i i ¦ j j i I i i j : i ••••¦•:•: ; ; -I 

Pi Ibis ! !• j || il it ! is Hi 1 ;S = i i S 
j isl 8 I jl j p jl jl 1 18 1 p j |3 1 1 18 i g ill ; i*Is2 jl 

I 

j «|| i j Ms 1 1| ! ii i§ [| I jl ] |8 } jl I ! jg jl ;ia ] ;iii2 ;SI| 

1 

»&gt;; iiiMiin; 

Q444A0 (3 d O •© •&lt;&gt; O O*O O-O O -O O •© &lt;? &lt;S •© a O * O O-O 0 O O ¦* O-O Q&lt;A-Q « Q A ¦« A A Q4 
uiu Uiuli ill i I 
iMiiiiiliiiiiiiil 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p094">
86 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE. 

| &gt; .|«a8»*asS»Sg«SSR5S88528a«l88588t8IIS88«SKK!:«8 
Hl ll l i iilIlifff«rsili s Plll6iltpi i i!Pi 

1 

i|rv9rapniiff i wpwiinN i sip 

SS3S888S8S8«Z&amp;8oS8^S8S!l8S&amp;89 

:&amp;KSS ;S8J jS 

1 

| PP!ptt8isp?|=pi*isiil 

sir sp ? 

I 

I !ll&gt;SpliB«H!ip|t|*|Hii{|ir»r pp ;:&gt; 
- ; a¥8S5¥SlS«R5Sga88¥laS8SSS5S59gl8^K8lS« 

iifnwpip 

! 

! 

&gt; 

i 

d t8«*S«s»2SES|S!8"IEi2S*B«SS3SB«fi«fi*S«MS 

a5asISS3g'£aSgS88SSSS38&lt;i88!SS8EaS8SSf:28?=2!!S 

3 

I 

&gt; 

ssssiSgssissoS8si3sss8s2f saSEassssfSSif ses 

&gt; 
&lt; 

"^BgS2S5Sl8lS8«fl2S8SSS88S38S8=SSg8BSS8S»Sa 

1 

i 

Si!f8iIiSSiiS=ii3i£Ii?SiSi?iSSiifii«8S8i8 

i 

iiiZNl«piSi!|Sii!EiliiiSiil!liIli!»!lH 

¦I 

E 1 1 i { M i i ) 1 i N 1 1 H H M ! M i i N H I ! I M 1 1 i 1 1 1 
! iilli II i i| i ii Ml I Ml 
1 1 1 1 1 1 if I i i hi I i if ! 
! j I { : j I It j ! I j I ! } | | | I I | I j j { I j I | j j | i 
i|is^jgiJsN^lli|ii«f|g|iiIlliy^|J||s| 
libMIiilJiilsifiillllifllillllllllllili </seg>


            <seg id="p095">
87 

slIliIl|5p3|s|i*H|i5i|i|g|ii|i?3ip|||p|fp||ft| 
7 8 t8i$ s l r -A^!; s ss''&amp;&amp;§Ssr: s 93£s3iSssssls3lSf-§ais3sg ( 
|5|1IiPiIll?IllIIII|i|SilPis|ipilil!p!!ilii||| 

i i» J I i i*j i 1 1 i i ¦ is I 
iiiiiliiiilili^l </seg>

            <seg id="p096">
88 


is 

888Sg8g838888SSS38S83888S8888Sg£83383Sg IS 
IpIppllIipIIlillliliilliliiiPPilii 

&lt; 

1 

ssssssssss is issss isss ! is i issasssasaasatsss 
ex saaa"" is i*"y Is— i i- i ig-^-s-ss-^-sa" 0 — 
iP 2 IIIIp jl jlili jllil |B j j|iIlIlIIi s iIIP^ 
illiiiilpir(llirjii# rji j" ipiinpf«i|ipi 
: : : : 

¦S 

i 
s 

I 

I 

I 8S88SR JSSI-O-38S25SS38 !s??a?3SS838 IfeSfeSSgf;: 
f g-* -•• !•• « ¦ — — 10 ¦;«—*¦ 

1 
I 

I 

&gt; * 3 

pi 11 
I 

\ I ; 

I S2SS-58SBS j ; fattS ! ;SSSRSS = S6 iSSSPfrS ;SS8S¥^ 
I* iii! ii i 
&lt; I : : : : : : : 

¦ 
s 
s 

I 
4 

TTlpilipiTmip 
•5?* »«3 : :&lt;e« 

i ! iiiilHlH lipil jgSf JSJI 

| $88858 ISSSSSSSS JSSSSS J3SSgS88&amp;j;83SS!SS8aC9 jfc 
s 8 " i ! " ! s ~ m - r 

x o-m &lt;x&gt; \ — S Mi — -r ac ¦* : fc c» -*¦ c Z -3 xSS b * -r do tf SwoSv j S 

I P 1 ! 1 plhirii jBxifl jPlIfflSIIisPBH |! 

MM jj Mjjf ill f iif fij jl j MM i </seg>


            <seg id="p097">
89 

S33SS3 38SSS3SSSSSS8883g8883888838888S88888388S8! 81 
1*1111 !Miis»pHi!iii]||iisii|qii!|i&gt;i9iii&gt;i i 

Pis )IM1!|H9| ilMiiMiigai jay |ppliim i IFi | 

38S3S3 [ iSSSBSSRS38RSSSSSSaSS3S.ta3558S5SS!SXS?5S |S 8 
a = KSZS ! !$Sg3SS| ! 'S33SSeSSS2S i »3a58SS?SSSii33g.- 1 -SS IS 8 

m5S5liii*|iSi|5a5|S|||||6|SaiS8SS=8|gSg If 

ss j ; ass 1 s-Ssla'^^aSsl-s r e 3-" f S s S28S J ! 
i : i 

¦SS5332S !£3II38§S ;gf?S3 = 82 JSSS ;8 ;33?JSS3 :S j : = S8 
" ~ m 1 •"•" — I i | r "" |" 1 1 — 

s 

¦Mill liiiiii UPPii |P I jipiii j i lip 

538S ;S1 S5^S3 i'iS^iSS ; S3! 9 82I iBS8 :S :*s*?s* " ; S M&amp;8S 
|lli jllilill iiSiglil ipiisl 1 ! slis I iiilli I i ill 
" ! "1 i I I i I 11 

SSSffSS ! ISaSS^SS I8SSS3S jSS822S3SSS8S2!8S2;i8g8B3S it 

s 

rl -llW§ |iipi§ lisilgsilPjlPiriif || if 
I i i " i r 

II M M N ! ! ij I ! ! 1 1 ! i I M Uj 1 1 ! y M ! I j I !! fg I N I ! 
iiliiiiliilillliilliJiiji </seg>

            <seg id="p098">
90 

NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE. 

SCORES OF COl'XTY COLLECTIVE EXHIBITS, NEBRASKA STATB 

Name or 
COOBTT. 

s ! 1 1 1 

Wmliinirton ; W Wli 87 M 

Cheyenne I 80 

Sett's Bluff | 71 , 81 
Bitch ock ..!-! 8B ¦ 87 ¦ 85 ' &amp; 70 

Ibaau... .'.".'!_ J M 

The Vcftro«fc« Farmer, commenting on thin exhibit. Bays: 

"In agricultural hall of the state fair there were fifteen county 
lollertive exhibits, besides the Lancaster county exhibit and that of 
the Nebraska Experiment Station. These latter two each occupied a 
winfc of the agricultural hall, leaving the fifteen counties to crowd 
into the space of the remaining four wings of the building. This 
necessarily crowded the exhibits, yet they were put up in a most attractive 
style and afforded one of the interesting features of the fair. 
A careful study of the accompanying table showing the score of each 
article in each of the county exhibits will be found instructive. There 
were sixteen groupR of products taken into consideration in scoring in 
the counties, and a perfect score in each product would give 100 points, 
»o that 1,600 points is a perfect total score. In the table the highest 
t on corn, 99 points, is given to Washington county, and the next, 
88, to Nemaha. both Missouri river counties. Nemaha and Howard 
counties were awarded 100 on wheat, the latter a centrally located 
This is high honors for Howard, as she has been supposed to 
b* above the north line of the winter wheat district, and the score 
was on the winter wheat. 

"Burt and Nemaha counties have the highest scores, 98, on oats. 

beat display of native grasses. Thomas county, west of Central 
Nebraska, scored 100; while Washington county was 98 on- tame grasses. 

"The potato exhibit for an "oft*" year was very good. Washington 
county scoring 9&amp; and Burt $8. Scott's Bluff county in the extreme 
ten part of the state, led all others by ten points on cabbage and 
beats, ret other irrigated counties were in the cont. 

Herri, k ; W S6 
Howti 7i M 

II. 

I * i it 1 It 
illllilillAl 
*1 »5 98 » { ttH!H 96 M9B87 l^M 
75 H I »1 97 | 94 91 I SI 98 88 97 M 1107 
&gt;R X7 US 7» f.8 i» Si !i| HT »1 9* I I3»l 
70 60 86 71 68 *» m vt 9J 100 V* 1UI 
at»n«H«!S«i7t 
61 I 70 HO 88 :t » » Ml 75 ¦* HU \£A 
M 63 H 77 7.i 88 86 7h SO m7 77 m» 
(t I tM S6 «4 t« 87 « 7 M llfl 
(8 80 »7 «5 ! 86 70 8" n M till 
... 60 TO 8^ 67 »• ' 87 6.4 &lt;W 87 «1 "06 
•7 «2 50 47 ¦ I _ 78 72 48 91 ¦ S 10!B 
*t 6t 17 »¦• *7 87 6-J 112 H SO 82 H&gt;» 
... 65 83 95 96 10U 68 87 B2 7« 7l! 1'"'- 
... t7 70 ... 61 I 68 ' 71 M M 7t 70 961 
... KM 56 90 97 90 « 57 4i »&gt; 

[-liming tt ¦.« KM US 
hliDc H ¦ - (Pj 8s 
Sernnha !&gt;• 
Kurt M i ¦» 
Vork K 8« 
:i*«e I »2 W 8« 7:! 7S 
Br. wn , s» 9^ B '» M 
thi dy 87 M 48 ft-&gt; « </seg>


            <seg id="p099">
91 

"Nemaha county led all others for taste in display and arrangement, 
scoring 100 points; and she was certainly entitled to it. The large 
map of Nemaha county, made in various grains, showed each precinct, 
creek, railroad and village, together with agricultural statistics of the 
county, and there were many other interesting features in this exhibit. 

Pvill afford interesting matter to study the score of awards. 
I herewith, with a county map of Nebraska in hand. There are 
who express an opinion that the agricultural show was not 
representative of what Nebraska is producing because each county 
is not represented. But, if each county in the state were competing 
the same objection could be made. One might insist that each farm 
in the state must be represented by an exhibit at the state fair! The 
list of counties includes Gage and Saline from the south central district, 
where the droug-ht has been most severe; north central; the far 
west, where population is sparse and such agricultural operations as 
are on hand are of a pioneer sort; the Elkhorn Valley counties, where 
"all goes right and nothing goes wrong'; and the Missouri river 
counties. The sections not represented were southwestern Nebraska, 
and the extreme northern part of the state. The southwestern part 
of the state was on exhibition in the cattle barns with winning herds 
of Herefords and Shorthorns. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>