<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  GROUND WHEAT VERSUS WHOLE WHEAT FOR FATTENING PIGS.</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 144. The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OP THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXVII, Article I. GROUND WHEAT VERSUS WHOLE WHEAT FOR FATTENING PIGS. By R. K. Bliss and C. B. Lie. Distributed August 10, 1914. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. (iHE IKOCNTS OF THE UNIVf»bl'*' EORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. ORABLE GEORGE COIPLAND, Elgin. ORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, Prcsidt nt, Lincoln. ORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE. Valley HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMl'EL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D.. Chancellor, ex offlcio. E. A. BI'RNETT, B. S&lt; ., Director. C. W. PUOSLKY, B Sf. Director of Extension Scrrice. I. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Si er, tnrii. FRANK C. DEAN, A B.. Bulletin Editrr THE WORKING STAFF. K. Mkad Wn.cox, Ph. D., Agricultural Bntanii. F. W. Upsox, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. U W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricuttmrmi F.ngincering. R. K. Bliss, B. S. A., Animal Husbandry. §Gaix. M. D. C, Animal Patholoay. runan, H S. A., Daim gmfcViutry. knce Bri-ner. B. St., Entomolony. KMBlin, A. M., Experimental Agritmimu. Fii.i.ev, A. M., Farm Hanaqement. K. MfHjRiu., M. Foi!., Forestry. A. Emerson, D. So., Horticultun . I^ovei.and, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. Snydrr. M. S., Ruperintentletit of Experimental Substation, North Platte. C. B. Lee. A. M., Associate in Animal Husbandry M. H. Swenk, A. M., Associate in Kntnmology. (Jeokge K. K. Link, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. .]. W. Cai.vin, b. S&lt;., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. P. B. Bakkek, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). Erwin Hopt, B. S&lt;\, Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). .). A. Ratci.ifk, B. S&lt; ., Assistant in Erp&lt; rimpntal Agronomy. Howard J. Ouaun, B. 8c, Assistant in Animal Husbandry (Horses). L. B. Sti hdi-.vant, A. M. M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. E. G. Woodward, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. J. R. Cooper, B. St., Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, B. Sr.. Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Fritz Knorr, B. St., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. * S. W. Peris, Farm Superintendent. H. L. Nte, Foreman Demonstration Farm. Culbertson. • Resigned. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">GROUND WHEAT VERSUS WHOLE WHEAT FOR FATTENING PIGS. During the suiniiitM- and fall of 1913 the College of Agriculture received a large Mmhef of inquiries t'oncerning the value of wheat as ■ feed fur fattening pigs. Information was especially desired iipnu the relative feeding values of whole wheat and ground wheat and upon the relative feeding values of corn and wheat. I These inquiries were prompted by the fact that many farmers an abundance of wheat and little or no corn. Since this MM - DS often prevails in certain localities in the State of Nebraska. Department of Animal Husbandry inaugurated an experiment determine the relative feeding values of whole wheat and und wheat when fed to fattening pigs. It was not considered issary to compare wheat with corn in this experiment owing (he fact that other Kx|K&gt;rinient 'Stations have found ground ■at about 10 per cent more efficient than shelled corn when to fattening pigs. The economic advantage of ground wheat r corn as a feed for pigs is largely offset by the additional ex - se incurred in irrinding and feeding the wheat. I Forty spring pigs were used in the experiment. These pigs •e divided into four lots of ten each. In making the division. e was taken to get the lots as nearly equal as possible both as ards size and thrift. The following rations were fed : Lot 1.— Soaked wholewheat. Lot 2.-— Soaked whole wheat 1!» parts, tankage* 1 part. Lot .'{. — Soaked ground wheat Lot 1. —Soaked ground wheat !!♦ parts, tankage* 1 part The pigs were accustomed to eating wheat before the begin - ning of the test. They were fed at 7:30 a. in. and 5 p. in. each day during the test. The wheat was soaked from one feeding jK-riod to the next. The lots were weighed each week during the experiment, the weights lieing taken at $ o'clock in the morning. * Commonly referred to as 5 per cent of tankage. BUL 144 AGR EXP. STATIOV OF NKRR VOL. XXVII, ART. I. I»Y R. K. Itl.ISS AMI C. B. I.KK. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 The daily ration fed amounted to approximately 3 per cent of the live weight of the pigs. In establishing prices for feeds used, it was the intention to make them correspond as nearly as possible to the prices that prevailed on Nebraska farms during the time that the test waB in progress. Whole wheat was valued at 75 cents per bushel and tankage at #2.50 per hundredweight. A charge of -1 cents per bushel was made for grinding the wheat, which brought the price of ground wheat up to 70 cents per bushel. RATE OF GAIN In rate of gain the pigs in Lot 3, fed soaked ground wheat averaged 1.19 pounds daily fo.- each pig. while the pigs in Lot 1 Fhe experiment was begun C s later. January 10. 1914. ' in connection with the ex] i,- etobcr :!7. 1913, and closed twelve rhe following table gives the ni:iin wriamt: Shoiriiifi coinfunatir' period o) i' rallies of ration* for the entire ' 12 iceeks. Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 J~ Number of pigs in lot 10 9* Soaked whole wheat 19 part*, tankage 1 part 84 1,245 2,070 825 138 230 91.6 1.09 10 19 parts. 1 ,0170 2,503 1 1 I |v Rations fed Soaked whole wheat Soaked ground wheat Number of days on feed Weight of lot at beginning Weight of lot at close Total gain by lots Average first weight per pig, lbs. . Average last weight per pig, lbs. . Total gain per pig, lbs Average daily gain per pig, lbs. . . . Total feed consumed— Wheat Tankage Feed required for 100 lbs. gain- Wheat Tankage Co»t of 100 lbs. gain I 84 1,360 2,065 705 136 206 70.5 0.84 84 1,370 2,370 1,000 137 237 100 1.19 4,166.4 4,007.5 197.5 4,429.6 •« 591 485.8 23.9 $6.67 443 1 'as ellml $7 39 $5.83 BOne pig in Lot 2 died at the c number in Lot 2 to nine. The d as nearly as possible from tta lose of thi previous le experin ? second week, thus record of this pig v lent. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">™* /*^&gt;*i * j l/r 1 \»1r + \/n * '11/ M *yo 5 K soaked whole wheat, averaged 0.84 pounds daily for each pig. 3, fed soaked ground wheat, made gains 42 per cent faster i Lot I. fed soaked whole wheat. I Mt 4, fed a mixture of 19 parts soaked ground wheat and 1 tankage, made an average gain of 1.32 pounds daily for each Lot 2, fed a mixture of 19 parts soaked whole wheat and 1 tankage, made an average gain of 1.09 pounds daily for each Lot 4, fed soaked ground wheat and tankage, made gains 21 cent faster than Lot 2. fed soaked whole wheat and tankage. IDhe taukage proved relatively much more effective in increas - the rate of gain when fed with soaked whole wheat than when with soaked ground wheat. Lot 2, fed soaked whole wheat and iage. made gains 30 per cent faster than Lot 1, fed soaked ile wheat only ; while Lot 4, fed soaked ground wheat and tank - niiide gains 11 per cent faster than Lot 3, fed ground wheat ". Ah regards rate of gain, the addition of tankage to a wheat on proved 19 per cent more efficient in the case of the whole at than in the case of the ground wheat. I Lot 3. fed ground wheat only, made gains 9 per cent faster n Lot 2, fed soaked whole wheat and tankage. Ground wheat alone proved more efficient in rate of gain than did whole •at nnd tankage. FEED REQUIRED FOR 100 POUNDS OF GAIN I Lot 3, fed soaked ground wheat, consumed 443 pounds of 'at for 100 pounds of gain, while Lot 1, fed soaked whole &gt;at, consumed 591 pounds of wheat for 100 pounds of gain. It uired 118 more pounds of soaked whole wheat to produce 100 inds of gain than it did of soaked ground wheat. On a per - tage basis it required 33.4 per cent or one-third more soaked ile wheat to produce 100 pounds of gain than it did of soaked und wheat. Stated in another way, 3 pounds of ground wheat vvjz-tfj /"CUR /oo lbs gain. MMMU ***** I ar om/yoirtc Fig. 1. — Showing the relative efficiency of ground wheat and whole wheat when fed alone to fattening pigs. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 fed as much gain when fed to fattening pigs as did 4 potindR ile wheat. &lt;ir(inii(l wlicat al $1 per bushel proved M t as whole wlieal at 7."i cents per bushel. Grinding th&lt; - resulted in a saving of 25 cents per bushel less 4 cents per grinding, or a net saving of 21 cents per bushel. Lot 4. fed a mixture of 19 part* ground wheat and 1 pan tankage, consumed 121 JS pounds of wheat and 2(1.7 poiunls of tankage for everv 100 pounds of jrain: while Lot 2. fed a mixture of 19 parts whole wheat and 1 part tankage, consumed 18CL8 pounds of wheat and 23.9 pounds of tankage for each lflfl pound* of gain. Sixtv-four and three-tenths more wheat a'&gt;d -"f.2 pounds more tankage were rc&lt;piircd to produce 1M pounds of gain when the wheat was fed whole than when the wheat was fed ground. On a percentage basis 18 per cent more wheat and IS pi r cent more tankage were required to produce 1(1(1 pounds of gain with whole wheat than with irronnd wheat, (iround wheat :it M cents pet liushel. when fed with lankage. proved as efficient as whole wheat at 75 cents per bushel when fed with tankajre. Griadiag the wheat resulted in a saving of 11 cents per bushel less -1 cents pn liushel for jrrindin;;. or a net stiving of 7 rents per bushel. omouno mtmr /rmrrA *o.j lbs or rmnKtze fO* /oo lbi cai/v. 3.1 LBS. r/fn/rmce &amp;f c*i rvo/r*c* ■ 2. — Showing the relative efficiency of ground wheat and whole wheat when fed with tankage to fattening pigs. II -i it I 1 , fed a mixture of 1't parti whole wheat and 1 part tank . produced 100 pounds of jrain with 105 pounds less wheat I not siderinsj tankage) than Tx&gt;t 1 ; while hot 4. fed a mixture of parts ground wheat and 1 part tankage, produced 100 pounds rain with 22 pounds less wheat i not considering tankage i than •\. The addition of 5 per cent of tankage proved much MR ient in redlining the pounds of wheat required to produce 100 inds of gain when fed with whole wheat than it did when fed h ground wheat. Lot ■"{. fed soaked ground wheat, produced 100 pounds of gain </seg>
            <seg id="p007">OfOHtld W'hrnt is. Whiilr Whi'it for I'ntli iiiiitl I'iilx ■ ti I !-'{ pounds of wheat: while Lot -. M a mixture of 19 part* lc wheat and 1 part tankage, required 485J pounds of wheat -'■'M pounds of tankage to produce 100 pounds of gain. In case, grinding the wheat effected a saving of 42.8 dwnda of it and '_'•!. !i pounds of tankage for every 10(1 pounds of gain luced. I Lot 1' consunied 4S."&gt;.s (mmiihIk of whole wlieat and li:t *&gt; pounds lankage for even Kill pounds of jiain. while Lot 1. fed whole •at only, consunied 591 pounds of wlieat far every 1(10 pounds rain, or 106 more pounds of wheat than Lot -. In this case the ling of ii::.!l pounds of tankage saved HI." pounds of wheat on ry Hill pounds of gain. The addition o"f tankage to a ration ioaked whole wlieat proved very profitable. Considerable whole wlieat passed An the pins in Lots 1 and '2. Apparently the pigs swallowed the grain* without chew inir them. This in a large measure accounts for the greater effi - ciency of the ground wheat. The pips receiving whole wheat and tankage apparently passed less wheat than the pigs receiving wliole wheat alone. From this it would appear that the tankage aided in digesting the whole wheat. COST OF GAIN. I Lot •'{. fed soaked ground wheat, produced 100 pounds of gain i cost of f&amp;88; while Lot I. fed soaked wliole wheat, produced pounds of gain at a cost of $7.39. The saving effected by iding the wheat amounted to $1.56 per 100 pounds gain. Th,' t of producing 100 pounds of gain was reduced 21 per cent ba - lding the wheat. I Lot 4. fed soaked ground wheat and tankage, produced 100 mds of gain at a cost of $6.07 per hundredweight, while Lot 2, soaked whole wheat and tankage, produced 100 pounds of gain a cost of ffi.67 per hundredweight. The saving realized by nding the wheat amounts to 60 cents j»er hundredweight. The t of producing 100 pounds of gain was reduced 0 per cent by iding the wheat. E4. fed ground wheat and tankage, made the largest daily mid were better finished than the other lots, altho Lot 3. )nnd wheat alone, made gains 24 cents per hundredweight r during the entire 12-week period. The cont of gains in increased rapidly during the last two weeks of the experi - which can probably be accounted for on the basis of their reached a point in weight and condition where gains are it a higher cost per ]&gt;ound. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Ground Whmt t*. Whole Wheat for Fattening Pigs The following table {jives the results of the experiment at the close of the 1 0-week period : an advantage over Lot 3 of 10 cents per hundred. This would mean that Lot 3 gained 34 cents per hundredweight on Lot 4 in economy of production during the last two weeks of the experi - ment, which indicates that Lot 4 was fed past the time when the moot profitable gains are made. It is also of interest to note that the amount of feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain was less in Lots 2 and 3 at the end of the 12- week period than at the end of the 10-week period. The following table shows the gains made at the close of the S-week period: 'ABLE 2.—S hotnng eompara ice v&lt;ilues o\ 'eks. id ions at e ei IM i^&gt;t i Lot 2 Lot 3 Number of pigs in lot 10 9 Soaked whole wheat 19 parts, tankage 1 part 70 138 211 73 1.04 10 ground 19 parts, tankage K ati °" s f «&gt; Soaked whole wheat Soaked ground wheat Number of days on feed Average fir I weight per pig, lbs Average last weight per pig, lbs Total gain per pig, lbs Average daily gain per pig, lbs Feed required for 100 lbs. gain- Wheat Tankage Co«t of 100 lbs. gain 70 130 193 57 0.K1 70 137 213 7ti 1.09 5H6.S 494.5 24.5 $6 79 457.7 m $7 34 $6.03 I This table shows that at the end of the first ten weeki soaked ground wheat and tankage, had made both the [ most economical gains of any lot. As compared witt ich had an advantage of 24 cents per hundred at the i exiieriment, Lot 4, at the close of the 10-week peri [■is? close or iod. had </seg>
            <seg id="p009">pound of gain is very materially increased, and this in all ibility explains the increased cost of producing a pound of on Lot 4 during the last two weeks of the experiment. IV comparison of the feed required to produce 100 pounds of i during the first eight weeks and during the entire period of !ve weeks shows that Lots 1, 2. and 3 required less feed to luce 100 pounds of gain during the last four weeks than they during the first eight weeks. A study of Lot 4 shows that a e more feed was required to produce 100 pounds of gain ing the first eight weeks than during the first ten weeks, h lot of pigs evidently made the most economical gains when pigs averaged from 175 to 210 pounds in weight. 'able 3. — Shotting cowparativt I values •eks. &gt;f rations at end of eight m Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 Number of pigs in lot 10 9 Soaked whole wheat 19 parts, tankage 1 part 56 138 195 56.7 1.01 10 U |':.rw. Rations fed \ Soaked whole wheat Soaked ground wheat Number of days on feed Average first weight per pig, lbs Average last weight per pig, lbs Total gain per pig, lbs Average daily gain per pig, lbs Feed required for 100 lbs. gain — Wheat Tankage Cost of 100 lbs. gain 56 136 178 42 0.75 56 137 193.5 56.5 1.01 616.1 486.7 241 S6.69 472.7 m $770 ' $6.22 I Had the experiment been iod, Lot 4 would have showi hundredweight less than L&lt; e the pigs in T-ot 4 average&lt; v true that after a pig th; ches a weight of from 225 t closed ai n a cost &lt; ot 3. the i 207 poi: at has b ;o 250 poi t the en of produ next lov inds per een well unds, thi id of the 8-week iction of 27 rents rest lot. At this pig. Tt is prob- l fed from birth e cost of produc- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">or efficient toward the STMMARY. When wheat romprixix the entire feeti for fatteniiiq pigs — B. Three pounds of soaked ground wheat produced as much as 4 pounds of soaked whole wheat. 2. Ground wheat at |1 per bushel proved as economical as whole wheat at 75 cents ]&gt;er bushel. At a cost of 4 cents per bushel for jrrindinfr. the net profit due to grinding amounts to 21 cents per bushel. E Ground wheat produced gains 42 |&gt;er cent faster than whole t. 4. A noticeable amount of whole wheat passed thru the pips undigested. When a nii.itnre of 19 part* irlieut tint} 7 part tankaffi onn pHtei the entire feed for fattening pi(/x — 1. Six pounds of ground wheat produced practically as much gain as seven pounds of whole wheat. 2. Ground wheat at Sfi cents ]»er bushel proved as economical as whole wheat at 75 cents per bushel when both were fed with tankage. At a cost of 4 cents per bushel for grinding, the net saving due to grinding amounted to 7 cents per bushel. K Ground wheat produced gains 21 per cent faster than whole t when both were fed with tankage. wheat ration did not jrrow less palatable or » end of a feeding period of 12 weeks duration. ii (ivoimil Whint m. Whole Wheat for Fnttniimi Pr F. — ffhoirinfi the ntotive cost of gainx during th&lt; and 1 2-ireek periods. Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 it urns fill f Soaked whole wheat Soaked whole wheut 19 parts, tankage 1 part Soaked ground wheat ground 19 parts tankage of 100 lbs. of gain— pnd of H-week |&gt;criod End of 10- week period . End of 12-week ]Kriod ■ $7 70 7.:U 7.:W 6.79 6.67 M 23 6.02 5.83 E'liis table is interesting in lliat it w HfT the last fottr weeks of the feedi 8 in both lots receiving wheat onl ilinws ;i marked deerease ■g period in the coat of y. Evidently the whole </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 1. The whok wheat was apparently letter digested wlien fed with tankage than when fed without tankage. Ground wheat proved more profitable than whole wheat for fattening pigs, either when fed with or without tankage. CONCLUSIONS. BV peat saving can be effected hv grinding the wheat for fiiinir pigs. ■ Pig! can be fattened and marketed on a shorter feed with und wheat than with whole wheat. Owing to the faster gains made ami file letter finish obtained. a small amount of tankage can be profitably fed with ground I In ease conditions are such that grinding the wheat in not cticable. a small amount of tankage fed with whole wheat will teriallx increase the rate of gain and. on the basis of prices :'n in this bulletin, will materially increase the profit obtained. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Ground Wheat vs. Whole Wheat for Fattening Pigs UNPUBLISHED DATA FROM THE NORTH PLATTE STATION. IFhe following data from the North Platte Station furnish itional proof to that already given in this bulletin as to the lomic advantage of ground wheat over whole wheat as a feed fattening pigs : r.E 5. — Wheat and corn for fattening pigs. Wheat compared with corn; whole wheat compared with ground wheat; soaked wheat compared taith unsoaked wheat. •On the basis of the following prices: Shelled corn 66 cents per bushel, whole wheat 75 cents per bushel, ground wheat 79 cents per bushel, and alfalfa $10 per ton. FEED REQUIRED FOR 100 POUNDS OF GAIN.* I The pigs receiving soaked ground wheat consumed 413 pounds nheat for 100 pounds of gain ; while the pigs receiving soaked jle wheat consumed 504 pounds of wheat for 100 pounds of n. It required 91 more pounds of soaked whole wheat than of ked ground wheat to produce 100 pounds of gain. On a per * The small amount of alfalfa eaten was not considered. BY W. P. SN'YDER. r-age of days. f two tests. October 21. 1913, to Januar There were nine pigs in each lot, 90 p 7 27, 1914 igs in all. ' I Ground wheat moist- ened &gt;tion . Shelled corn dry Whole wheat dry Whole wheat soaked 3 Iige first weight per pig, lbs. ige last weight per pig, lbs. jge gain per pig, lbs. ...&gt;... ige daily gain per pig, lbs. . grain for 100 lbs. gain ... alfalfa for 100 lbs. gain . . I lbs. feed for 100 lbs. eain . L of feed for 100 lbs, gain. . 108.8 217.9 109.1 1.11 468 11 479 »5.48 109.0 209.1 100.1 1.02 510 9 519 86 42 107.5 210.4 102.9 1.05 504 10 514 86.35 108.8 242.7 133.9 1.36 426 7 433 85.64 ! </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Ground Wheat vs. W hoi, \\ heat for Fattening Pigs 13 oentage basis it required 22 per cent more soaked whole wheat than of soaked ground wheat to produce 100 pounds of gain. Ground wheat at 91 cents per bushel proved as economical as whole wheat at 75 cents per bushel. It required 13 pounds more moistened ground wheat than soaked ground wheat to produce 100 pounds of gain. It re - quired 6 pounds more whole dry wheat than whole soaked wheat to produce 100 pounds of gain. In each case a small saving was effected by soaking the wheat. I The pigs receiving shelled corn consumed 468 pounds of corn 100 pounds of gain; while the pigs receiving soaked ground ?at consumed 413 pounds of wheat for 100 pounds of gain. It nired 55 more pounds of shelled corn than of soaked ground ?at to produce 100 pounds of gain, or 11 per cent more shelled n than soaked ground wheat to produce 100 pounds of gain. ! difference in favor of soaked ground wheat as compared with lied corn is largely offset by the additional expense due to nding and soaking the wheat. </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>