<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Commercial Application of LACTOBACILLUS ACIDOPHILUS MILK</title>
               <date value="1928-10">1928-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN C226^ * OCTOBER 1928 The Commercial Application of LACTOBACILLUS ACIDOPHILUS M I LK </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction . „ 3 Review of literature pertaining to Lactobacilliis aeidophilus 3 Studies of the characteristics of LactobacUlus aeidophilus 6 Isolation studies , . 6 Results 7 Method used • 8 Effect of L. addophilus milk feeding on rats having an intestinal flora practically devoid of Gram-positive organisms 8 Results '. 8 ' Media studies ; ; g. The use of carbon dioxide in the growth of L. acidophilus on agar plates ; 9 Viability studies „. 10 The commercial manufacture of acidophilus milk 11 Method of manufacturing ;; 12 Equipment .. 12 Materials needed .: 12 Mother cultures 13 Preparation of bulk milk : 13 Marketing 14 Uses of acidophilus milk '. „ 14 General directions for the use of acidophilus milk 15 Literature cited 17 Additional bibliography lg </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Commercial Application of jLactobacillus Acidophilus Milk E. L. REICHART AND H. P. DAVIS Milk is not only man's most perfect food ; it is his first and remains his staple article of diet thruout life. Milk has been varied in many ways to make it more palatable, to increase its digestibility, and to adapt it to various fancies of man. Soured milks of various kinds have been popular since Biblical times. Egypt's " leben raib," koumiss, kefir, yoghurt, and even our commercial buttermilk of today are variations of this nature. Bulgarian buttermilk, ! a product of the Balkan peninsula, is probably the most famous of these soured milks. Metchnikoff (1) and his followers strongly advocated the use of milk containing LactobaciUus bulgaricus and even went so far as to attribute the longevity of the Bulgarian peasant to the continual use of | soured-milk drinks. It has been only very recently that interest in sour milk therapy has been revived. The development and subsequent commercialization of acidophilus milk is largely responsible for the renewed interest. Preventive rather than curative methods in public health matters have been advocated to a considerable extent and acidophilus therapy follows that general trend. LactobaciUus acidophilus, the active and result-producing organism in acidophilus milk, lends itself especially well to propagation and use in a milk medium and for that reason acidophilus therapy becomes of interest to the dairy industry. Dairy products and health have long been associated and it is with just pride that the dairy industry welcomes acidophilus milk as the newest member of an old and firmly established family of dairy products. REVIEW OF LITERATURE PERTAINING TO LACTOBACILLUS ACIDOPHILUS Metchnikoff (1) believed that L. bulgaricus had the prop - erty of implanting itself in the intestines of man and thus of establishing an aciduric flora which was detrimental to putrefaction and beneficial to the well-being of man Moro (2), writing in 1900, described an organism similar to L bulgaricus which he called L. acidophilus. This organism is described as a strong Gram-positive rod, 1.5 to 2 microns long, 0.6 to 0.9 microns wide, and with slightly tapering ends Finkelstein (3) and Tissier confirmed the findings of Moro </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 228 the same year, while Rettger (4) and his associates mentioned the organism in a comparative study of L. acidophUus and L. bulgaricus. \ The first work bearing on the therapeutic value of L acidophUus wds published by Rettger and Cheplin (5) in 1921. The distinguishing difference between two closely related organisms appears to be in the fermentation of one sugar, maltose, and the ability of L. acidophUus to implant itself in the intestine. Differences due to surface tension have been reported by Albus and Holm (6) and Kopeloff and Beerman (7). The ability of an organism to implant itself in the human intestine is of vital importance in sour milk therapy. That L. acidophilus is capable of such implantation has been shown by Rettger and Cheplin (5, 23) and Cheplin, Fullmer, and Barney (19) as possible either by the use of lactose feeding or by the oral administration of L. acidophUus cultures. They demonstrated that the daily oral administra - tion of 2 c.c. of L. acidophUus without the addition of lactose to the diet leads to a profound change in the character of the intestinal flora of white rats and an implantation of L acidophtlus to the extent of between 90 and 99 per cent of the total flora. They state: "The simple character of the flora is affected as long as one or the other of the above - mentioned diets is continued but reverts gradually to the normal or usual mixed type within five or six days after a return to the basal diet. L. bulgaricus, which is not an in - testinal organism, is unable under any circumstances to estab - lish itself in the alimentary canal of the albino rat. Even daily administration of 5 c.c. of the bulgaricus suspension exerts no influence on the bacterial population of the in - testine. In accounting for the influence of lactose on the intestinal flora, Rettger (5) states: "There appears to be a definite relation between the rate of absorption or digestion in the alimentary canal of the utilizable carbohydrate and its tendency to effect a transformation. Only those carbohydrates which reach the cecum and colon unchanged have a trans - forming influence. The results with human subjects closely follow those shown in rats, namely, the transformation by the use of L. acidophUus, lactose, or dextrin, singly, or in combination." Cheplin's (20, 21) later work seems to indi - cate similar results. Kopeloff (8) later enlarged on Rettger 's work, giving more attention to clinical data. Briefly, Kopeloff 's work, which covered a large enough number of cases to eliminate unusual or exceptional ones, seems to have established the following - 1. L. bulgaricus was not recovered during the feeding </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Commercial Application op Acidophilus Milk period from the feces of patients, indicating that it can rarely, if ever, be implanted in the human intestine. 2. L. acidophilus was recovered during the feeding period from the feces of all patients ingesting large numbers of this organism. 3. Constipation appeared to be markedly alleviated by the administration of L. acidophilus milk containing 200 million viable organisms per c.c. In non-constipated cases there was a tendency to increase the number of j normal defecations daily. The benefits of L. acidophilus persisted after the treatment and in all but one case the condition after treatment was better than before. Patients who had previously aver - aged only one normal defecation weekly j had normal defeca - tions daily. The feeding of lactose proved valuable in pro - longing the beneficial effects of L. acidophilus milk feeding after the administration of L. acidophilus organisms was dis - continued. 4. The action of L. acidophilus is not a physical phenom - enon due to the action of milk ingested, since patients receiv - ing sterile milk were not relieved. 5. The action of L. acidophilus is jnot chemical, since patients receiving pasteurized milk with |the organisms killed were not relieved. 6. Filtered milk also proved valueless in combating con - stipation, so it appears that L. acidophilus therapy is essen - tially a bacteriologic phenomenon. 7. It was found that L. acidophilus milk may be kept satisfactorily for only 3 or 4 days. 8. Eleven cases of severe diarrhea were successfully treated by oral administration of L. acidophilus milk, aug - mented when necessary by rectal administration. 9. " From a practical standpoint it has been shown that constipation, diarrhea, and other intestinal disorders may be satisfactorily treated by L. addophilus\ Such treatment is simple and works no hardship on the patient. The use of L. acidophilus should for the present b6 limited to prepara - tions from scientific laboratories rather [than extended to the unsatisfactory products being exploited commercially. Before L. acidophilus can be used successfully | to any extent there must be an ample supply easily obtainable and at a reasonable price." L. acidophilus is at the present time marketed in the form of milk cultures (acidophilus milk), blroth cultures, agar cubes, and pills. James (9) recently investigated these various products on the market supposedly capable of being used in acidophilus therapy. He summarized his findings as follows : " 1. Milk cultures showed the highest average count, whey the next highest, and solid cultures the lowest. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 228 "• 2 'jA} 1 sam P les of one type from any one producer ex - amined before the expiration date were more or less similar inequality regardless of age. • " 3. Liquid and solid preparations marketed by the same producer were somewhat similar in quality. " 4 -. Contaminating organisms were more common in solid than in broth or milk cultures. "5. Of thirty-three strains of organisms isolated from a culture claimed to be Bacillus acidophilus, nineteen showed a possibility and fourteen did not, and of .fifteen claimed to be L. bulgancus, ten showed a possibility and five did not. Of one hundred samples examined thirteen produced the species claimed on the label in reasonably pure form and satisfactory numbers. Of the remainder fifteen had possible value, the rest being worthless." It is readily apparent, therefore, that before L. acidophilus therapy gains in popularity and certainty of producing de - sired results, the supply must be of better quality, more easily obtainable, and more strictly supervised. STUDIES OF THE CHARACTERISTICS OF LACTOBACILLUS ACIDOPHILUS To manufacture acidophilus milk successfully requires a thoro familiarity with the characteristics of the organism and its behavior under commercial conditions, and the ability to make qualitative as well as quantitative determinations on the marketed product. In addition there must be a practical method of obtaining fresh cultures. The manufacture of acidophilus milk begins with the isolation of the organism, continues with its being grown in a milk culture in large enough numbers to be of therapeutic value, and is ended by keeping this culture under such conditions as to injure least any of its constituent organisms during the marketing process. : ISOLATION STUDIES L. acidophihcs, being of intestinal origin, must necessarily be isolated from that source. Rettger (5) used white rats dogs, and human beings, while Orcutt (10) isolated the organism from calves. Rettger (5) also demonstrated that carbohydrate feeding produces a prolific aciduric flora in the intestines in which L. acidophilus largely predominates. In our isolation studies the following procedure was used : Normal full-grown white rats were placed on a basal diet which was 25 per cent lactose, and in addition were given all the whole milk they would drink. The rats were kept on this diet for from 10 to 14 days, when samples of fresh feces </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Commercial Application . of Acidophilus Milk were taken and plated after dilutions in saline solution (0.9 per cent NaCl) were made. The medium employed was that recommended by Rettger (5) and iyas prepared as fol - lows: Two hundred grams of finely granulated commercial casein was dissolved in 2 liters of 1 per cent sodium carbonate solution. The latter was heated to boiling and the casein was added a little at a time and well stirred until completely dis - solved. The solution was then cooled to about 40° C, and 10 c.c. of a water solution containing 3 grams of fresh " Fair - child's Trypsin " added. After thoro mixing and the addition of 25 c.c. of chloroform as a preservative, the mixture was introduced into a flask and incubated at 37° C. for 48 hours. It was then neutralized to litmus with HC1, heated in a double boiler to drive off all chloroform, and then filtered. Using this casein digest as a base, media were made up as follows: Casein digest 100 c.c. Commercial meat extract (Liebig's)J 3 grams Agar, to make the desired consistency..about 1 per cent Galactose...:... , }..... 10 grams Water to make... L..1000 c.c. Sixteen mature albino rats, divided into three groups, 6, 6, and 4, were placed in individual metal cages with removable bottoms that were covered with filter paper to collect the feces. Samples of f eces were taken at the beginning of the period and smears made to determine the bacterial flora. A basal ration was fed to all rats. 1 Three trials containing 6, 6, and 4 rats respectively were run. The animals were fed lactose and whole milk in addition to the basal rations, while an equal number of rats in each trial wei[e given meat scraps with the basal diet. Smears were made daily from each group for 14 days. Results.— The fecal smears showed a flora at the beginning of the experiment ranging from 70 to 90 per cent Gram negative, indicating that the flora was not very prolific in Gram-positive organisms. The rats receiving the lactose and milk in addition to the basal ration showed a rapid change in the bacterial flora from day to day until at the end of two weeks the flora was decidedly Gram-positive, indicating the prevalence of aciduric types of organisms. The flora of the rats composing the meat scrap group I showed a gradual change until at the end of the two-weeks period it was almost entirely Gram-negative. This experiment seems to show that lactose feeding has a rather decided effect on the fecal flora 1 Basal ration consisted of : Wheat 2900 gr. Peas 152 str. Cod liver oil.. . . 300 re Cbrn, yellow 2800 i-r. Alfalfa flour 500 cr. ! CaCOj 150 er° Oats 760 gr. Meat scraps 1000 gr. I NaCl, .'.". 160 gr' </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station,, Bulletin 228 of rats, causing an increase in the percentage of Gram-positive organisms present and in that manner furnishing a convenient source of L. acidophilus. . Method used in isolation of Lactobacillus acidophilus. — Feces of the rats on the lactose diet were collected and dilu - tions in saline solutions were made which were then inoculated into " Heymanns " (11) acid broth and plated on galactose agar made from casein digest. Colonies having the character - istic appearance of L. acidophilus were then picked and in - oculated into litmus milk. After curdling had occurred they were replated and reisolated and reinpculated until the culture obtained was pure and vigorous. EFFECT OF LACTOBACILLUS ACIDOPHILUS MILK FEEDING ON RATS HAVING AN INTESTINAL FLORA PRACTICALLY DEVOID OF GRAM-POSITIVE ORGANISMS A group of rats was fed the basal ration with the addition of all the meat scraps they would eat until an extreme con - dition of intestinal putrefaction was produced, as indicated by the absence of Gram-positive organisms and the physical condition of the feces. Meat scraps were then discontinued and 5 c.c. of acidophilus milk was fed daily with the basal ration. Changes in the intestinal flora were observed. Results. — The results indicated that acidophilus milk feed - ing will change a Gram-negative to a Gram-positive flora. Rettger (5) has obtained similar results with rats, while Kopeloff's (8) work, done mostly with human beings, has also shown similar results. The work of Kopeloff (16) in particular seems to demonstrate the therapeutic value of L. addophUus milk for human beings. As all the work on acidophilus feeding has demonstrated it to be a bacteriologic function, it becomes apparent that the number of organisms in a specific quantity are of the utmost importance in determining the therapeutic value of the product. For instance, a culture containing 200 million organisms would be 10 times as valuable therapeutically as a culture containing 20 million organisms per c.c. The development of a method of determining the bacterial content of acidophilus milk at the time of marketing is there - fore necessary, as all milk used for therapeutic purposes should be tested to insure a maximum of viable organisms. Ordinary bacterial analysis is not satisfactory, as L. acidophilus does not grow satisfactorily in ordinary media. MEDIA STUDIES Several recommended media were tried, including tryptic digest of casein (22), tryptic digest of skim milk powder (13), Farr's whey agar (13), and whey galactose peptone </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Commercial Application of Acidophilus Milk agar (12). Of these the last mentioned proved the most satisfactory when made according to the following directions. Skimmed milk is heated to 85"-90° C. Sufficient acetic acid is added to precipitate the casein. The whey is then heated to complete the precipitation and filtered) thru several thick - nesses of cheesecloth. It is then adjusted to p.H. 8 and auto - claved at 15 pounds for 15 minutes. The precipitate is then allowed to settle and the supernatent whey is filtered thru paper and adjusted to p.H. 6.8. To 1000 c.c. of whey 5 grams of peptone, 10 grams- of agar, and 10 grams of galactose are then added. The mixture is autoclaved to dissolve the agar, filtered, flasked, and sterilized at 12 pounds pressure for 30 minutes. After sterilization the p.H. value should be 6.3-6.4. THE USE OF CARBON DIOXIDE IN THE GROWTH OF LACTOBACIIXUS ' ACIDOPHILUS ON AGAR PLATES Continued work with whey peptone galactose in making routine counts showed occasional variations, especially when different strains were used, and counts were often entirely too low considering the behavior of the organisms in the cultures. Later work of Kulp (15) seejmed to explain these difficulties. He noted similar occurrences, especially with certain strains, and found that carbon dioxide was necessary for the prolific growth of L. acidophilud^ of certain strains in quantities larger than the ordinary atmosphere contained (about .03 per cent). Valley and Rettger (14) have shown that carbon dioxide is necessary for bacterial development and that while many bacterial species will grow and multiply normally in the presence of the ordinary atmospheric carbon dioxide, others are accelerated in their growth when they are provided with an atmosphere which is 1 to 10 per j cent carbon dioxide. L. acidophilus apparently belongs to this group. To check the efficiency of carbon dioxide in increasing the plate counts of certain strains of acidophilus, whey-peptone - galactose plates were incubated in thej presence of varying percentages of carbon dioxide gas. Carbon dioxide was in - troduced from a cylinder of compressed! carbon dioxide into a flask full of water until water, to the same volume as carbon dioxide was required, had been expelled) from bottle. A hose connection was then made to a water tap while another hose was attached to the bottle containing the measured CO- and the petri plate container. Water was then introduced into the bottle until all the CO 2 had been forced into the petri plate container. It was then incubated as usual. ■ . ■ '■■■■■■••.■■ : .' ' ■ ■■■ ■ . ■ :. </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 228 tising has been published relative to the health-maintaining and therapeutic value of acidophilus milk. All these factors have tended to create quite a general demand on the part of the public for this product. The manufacture of acidophilus milk that is to be used for its therapeutic effect is an intricate process and requires the utmost care. Laboratory facilities are essential for the proper control of the product if it ia to meet a high standard of medical usefulness. The average milk. plant, not having at its disposal the services of a trained bacteriologist, is not in a position to produce the product satisfactorily. However, if a bacteriological laboratory is available and the personnel of the plant is such as to provide for proper control, acidophilus milk can be made satisfac - torily as one of the products of a milk plant. METHOD OF MANUFACTURING As has been emphasized, the manufacture of acidophilus milk requires the greatest care at every stage of the process if a satisfactory product is to be made. The methods de - scribed are based on the experience of others (8, 17, 18, 26) and have been modified by our experiments and experience. Equipment. — The equipment necessary for the manufacture • of acidophilus milk depends somewhat upon the quantity of the product to be made. Equipment usually found in dairy plants, such as bottles, thermometers, a steam supply, and the like, are of course essential in all cases. Where only a small quantity of milk is made, it may be sterilized in quart bottles in an ordinary autoclave and incubated in bacteriological in - cubators, agitated by hand, and bottled by hand. Where larger quantities are made, a pressure sterilizer-and-incubator is used. Such a vat is glass lined to facilitate keeping it clean and is equipped with a tight cover so that milk in it can be heated under 10 to 15 pounds of steam pressure per square inch. It is also well enough insulated so that the milk can be incubated at 99.5" F. (37.5° C.) for 12 to 18 hours without having outside temperatures affect the temperature of the milk being held. A motor-driven propeller serves as an agi - tator, and the milk is usually pumped directly into the bottler after being thoroly agitated. Materials needed.— The raw milk from which acidophilus milk is to be made should be as clean bacteriologically as possible. It may be skim, part-skim, or whole milk. Gen - erally, part-skim or whole milk is, used, as it makes a little more palatable and a smoother product. Unless the milk is to be sterilized, great care should be taken in producing and handling it to prevent introduction of bacteria, especially heat-resisting spore-formers that might survive the heating process and later contaminate the finished product. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Commercial Application op Actdophilus Milk Mother cultures. — Mother cultures should be carried daily to keep the organisms vigorous and increasing rapidly as well as to prevent contaminating organisms from gaining any headway. Mother cultures should be made from milk sterilized in an autoclave at a pressure of 20 pounds for 30 minutes to insure the purity of the culture. Usually Jone-liter or two-liter flasks are used for mother culture bottles and several are carried at all times to guard against loss or accidents. The milk is sterilized as indicated above, cooled to 99.5° F. (37.5° C.) and inoculated with 2 to 5 per cent of recently isolated culture and incubated at 99.5° F. (37.5° C.) for 12 to 18 hours or until a slight whey line 1 is apparent on the surface of the curd. The cultures are then kept at room temperatures until used or repropagated. Preparation of bvlk milk. — The milk should be as free from bacteria as possible. It is standardized to the desired fat content, and heated either by the intermittent method of pasteurization or under pressures destroying all organisms present. The intermittent method of pasteurization consists of heating the milk to 190° to 200° F., (holding at that tem - erature for 30 minutes, cooling to 85° to 90° F., holding at that temperature for 3 to 5 hours, and reheating at 190° to 200° F. and holding again for 30 minutes. It is then cooled to the incubating temperature. This metihod is rather tedious and the results somewhat uncertain, as organisms may resist the temperatures used. The heating under pressure has been found more practical and is in greater use today. The milk is heated under a pressure of 12 to 15 pounds at a temperature of about 245° F. to 250° F. for one-half hour and cooled to incubating temperature. This process, as can readily be seen, is more rapid and reliable. The milk is also slightly caramel - ized during sterilization, which gives it a distinctive color and flavor. The milk is cooled to 98° F., inoculated with 1 to 4 per cent of mother cultures (usually about 2 per cent), and held at that temperature for 18 to 20 hours or until the curd shows a small quantity of whey on the surface. | The acidity at this time is usually 1 to 1.5 per cent, calculated as lactic acid, and the product should show a count of 300 fco 400 million organ - isms per cubic centimeter as determined by the plate method previously discussed. In this work it has been found that by cooling the milk before agitating to a temperature of approx - imately 60° F., " wheying off " of the product during storage is largely prevented. The curd is then thoroly agitated and is ready for bottling and consumption. There are several steps that should be discussed at this time. The incubation period is of vital importance to the </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 228 number of organisms found in the product at time of delivery nnZ nSUm f Ptl ° n - - K mUSt be long en ° u * h to allow a SiS mum fl n ™ ber n of organisms to develop; but care must be taken to avoid allowing too much time, as too great an increase in the th?£ t l ? ely S° cau *l t0 ° hi *h • rite of mo?Sll?y durinl the marketing time Thus the actual incubation period can be determined only by practical trial. The matter of cooline ™^ Vei l Whe &amp; n S ° ff + aIs0 nec&lt; *sitates the use of good Tud? ment, as the milk must not be cooled too low, as that is likefy to have a detrimental influence on the bacterial flora as was buEn" Viabllity StUdiGS in an earlier «5iS' of This MARKETING fl n^ C S° PhilU % mi l. k S - hould be mar keted as quickly as possible and the manufacturing process should be so timed that the f™ d h U&lt; ? WlH be T dy^ r deliver y at th e completion of the onv? £?* Pe n I0d - The opportunities for the sale of acidophilus milk are practically unlimited. When property made and handled, the product should find a ready marke? Ro^lrf ° ?£ Care "f.^"^ in the Process of manufacturing it would not be practical to make it in a plant not havimr an opportunity to market a quantity sufficiently large to abforb onfv°1n S?r? t^^f d " T^ da * 6 aci do P hifuf 3k isfound Sf™. °, ur relatively larger cities, where consumption is large enough to warrant the necessary expense on the manS turer's part to make and handle the product properly? USES OF ACIDOPHILUS MILK Rettger and Cheplin (5) have used acidophilus in a series of pathologic cases, including 20 cases of chronic : diarrhS ma«S n % p" f of bacillary dysentery, 3 cases of der- ES % + CaSCS ? f , c ? lltls ' and 2 cases of sprue. Altho de - sss? t'wwsasK 1^ are ""-^issssss Chephn, Post, and Wiseman (21) have reported favorahlP treatment with L. acidophihis milk in 9 Se of gastroin testinal disorders, but their reports contain no quaSatiJe' laboratory data Kopeloff (8) has found acidophilus Sifk to weU asT a ld rT ble Va - 1Ue in th - e of consSpaSon as 71 2? 97 l£ 'T msummm e UP Published results (5, 8, «7m v.-i ' 28) -, 1 and .° ur own experience it seems probable that acidophilus milk will prove valuable in the treatment of any intestinal disorder caused by a change of the bacterial flora from a natural one to an unnatural one </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Commercial Application op Acidophilus Milk GENERAL DIRECTIONS FOR THE USE OF ACIDOPHILUS MILK The manufacturer of acidophilus milk is continually be - sieged with questions regarding its iise, and it is in order to facilitate his answers and to avoid the unethical exploitation of the product that the following general directions are given. Acidophilus milk treatment being primarily a bacterial phenomenon, the number of organisms present in a given quantity would naturally have a decided effect on the results obtained with a given dosage. Variations in individuals as well as the general condition of the patient would also affect the dosage. In general the average daily dose should be th&lt;! equivalent of 1000 c.c. of a culture containing 200 million viable L. acidophilus organisms per c.c. I In mild cases of constipation this dose may soon be reduced, while in severe cases it may have to be increased. Since acidophilus when first ingested is likely to cause considerable gas production, Kopeloff recommends 500 c.c. the first day, 750 c.c. the sec - ond, and 1000 c.c. the third. In the treatment of constipation, lactose is generally added to the milk or ingested at the same time. Fifty to three hundred . grams is | usually used with 1000 c.c. of milk, depending on the reaction of the patient. The milk" has a flavor objectionable to some people and may be flavored with chocolate or fruit juice to suit the individual without injuring its action. As the patient's condition is gradually improved the dosage is reduced until in some cases a weekly or biweekly ingestion may be sufficient to maintain the prevalence of the organism in the. patient's body. Where the above dosage does not produce the desired results it may be increased to where the patient receives as much as 1500 c.c. of culture and 400 grams of lactose. One thousand c.c. of culture may be thinned with warm water and used as an enema in particularly obstinate cases. According to Kopeloff, such a procedure is of particular value in diarrhea cases. Acidophilus milk should be of particular value in the treat - ment of children's intestinal disorders. According to Kope - loff there is every reason to believe that acidophilus milk should be particularly advantageous in the treatment of sum - mer diarrhea, which is ordinarily so difficult to combat. The proposed use of acidophilus milk usually raises the question of diet. Altho it is desirable to reduce animal pro - tein in the diet as much as possible, no other changes are necessary. The use of large quantities of acidophilus milk and lactose naturally reduces the appetite of the patient and he will consume less of other foods. Acidophilus milk should be taken in. three equal doses as nearly midway between meals as possible.] To assure success of treatments the cultures should be obtained from a reput- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 228 able firm and the viability of the organisms checked frequently enough to assure high-count cultures. In conclusion it might be well to state that altho acidophilus milk has been success - fully used in the treatment of constipation, diarrhea, sprue, and intestinal toxemia, there are exceptional cases where it has failed to produce the above-mentioned results, and to con - sider it a cure-all, if only for a group of ailments, is ridiculous. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Commercial Application of Acidophilus Milk literature cited 1. Metchnikoff, E.: The prolongation of life; G. P. Putnam's Sons, N. Y., 1908. 2. Moro, E.: Morphologische und Biologische Untersuchungen uber die Darmbacterien des Sauglings; Jahrb. f. Kinderheilkunde, 61, 1905, 687-734, 870-899. 3. Firikelstein, H.: Ueber Saureliebende Bacillcn im Sauglingsstuhl; Deut. Med. Wchnschr. 26, 1900, 263. 4. Kulp, W. L., and Rettger, L. F. : A comparative study of Lacto - bacillus acidophilus (Moro) and Lactobacillus bulgaricus (Mas - sol) ; Journal Bact. IX 1924, 357-396. 5. Rettger, L. F., and Cheplin, H. A.: Treatise on the transformation of the intestinal flora with special reference to the implantation of Bacillus acidophilus; Yale University Press, 1921. 6. Albus, W. R., and Holm, G. E.: The effect of surface tension on the growth of Lactobacillu8 acidophilus; Proc.J Soc. for Exp. Bio. and Med., 22, 1925, 337. 7. Kopeloff, N., and Bcerman, P.: Surface tension studies with L. ■ acidophilus and L. bulgaricus; Psychiatric Quarterly, July, 1927. 8. Kopeloff, N.: Lactobacillus acidophilus; The Williams and Wilkins Company, Baltimore, 1926. ' 9. James, L. H.: The determination of viable Lactobacillus acidophilus; Science, Sept. 24, 1926, Vol. LXIV, No. 1656, pp. 304-306. 10. Orcutt, M. L. : A study of Bacillus acidophilus from the digestive tract of calves; Jour. Bact. 11, 1926, No. 2. 11. Heymanns, Bruno: 1898, cited by Finkelstein (3). 12. Rettger, L. F., and Kulp, W. L. : A note on the choice of culture media for the study of Lactobacillus acidophilus with special reference to the carbohydrate employed; Abstracts of Bact., 1922 - 6, 24. 13. Farr, S. M.: Correspondence. 14. Valley, G., and' Rettger, L. F.: The influence of carbon dioxide on bacteria; Journal of Bact., Vol. XIV, No. 2 p. 101. 15. Kulp, W. L. : The determination of viable Lactobacillus acidophilus; Science, Sept. 24, 1926, Vol. LXIV, No. 1656, pp. 304-306. 16. Kopeloff, N., and Cheney, C. O.: Studies on the therapeutic effect of Bacillus acidophilus milk and lactose; Bact. Abst. 178, 1923. 17. Bass, C. C: Transformation of the intestinal flora; Am. Clin. Med. 1, 1922, 25-32. 18. Hughens, H. V. : A simple procedure for preparing Bacillus acido - philus milk; Naval Med. Bui., Washington,] D. C, 1924, 21, 548-549. 19. Cheplin, H. A., Fullmer, H. C, Barney, C. O.: Studies on the therapeutic application of Bacillus acidophilus milk with report of cases; J.A.M.A., 1923, 80, 1896. 20. Cheplin, H. A.: Further studies on the therapeutic application of LactobacUlus acidophilus; Bact. Abst. 246, 1923. 21. Cheplin, H. A., Post, C. D., and Wiseman, J. R.: Bacillus acido - philus milk, and its therapeutic effects; Boston Med. Surg. Jour., 189, 1923, 405-410. 22. Kulp, W. L.: Casein digest media for growing Lactobacillus acido - philus and Lactobacillus bulgaricus: Bact; Abst. 25, 1923. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 228 23. Rettger, L F., and Cheplin, H. A.: Bacillus acidophUua and its therapeutic application; Arch. Int. Med. 29, 1922, 357-367? 24. Slanetz, C. A.: Thermal death points of Bacillus acidophilus and Streptococcus lacticus; Abstracts Bact. 7, 1923, 353. 25. Prucha, M. J and Brannon, J. M.: Acidophilus milk credited with correcting ailments; 40th Annual Report. Illinois AgrTExp. Sta 26. Prucha, M. J., and Brannon, J. M.: Manufacture of lactobacillus acidophilus milk; 30th Annual Report, Illinois Agr'l Exp. Sta. 27. Morris, W..H.: The use of bacillus acidophilus milk in a tubercu - losis sanatorium; J.A.M.A., 1923, 81, 93. 28. Rahe, A. H.: A. study of the so-called implantation of the Bacillus bulgancus; Jour. Inf. Dis. 16, 1915, 210-220. ADDITIONAL BIBLIOGRAPHY Ba vi!ue fn'in a t n es\4 U l tZ &lt;iis J ord^s; f atf^s^S * T* Ber^oF^ZTl^T2Ar teTiOlOey; The WiUiamS and Wilkins Ca DT'29; IMI.'SmK* ° f di6t °" the int6Stinal fl ° ra: J ° Urnal In£ - Council on Pharmacy and Chemistry of J.A.M.A., July 17 1926- The Spy. StStUS ° f BaCiUU " acid °P hilu8 »"d Balaiul hZlgartcZ Courtney, R H., and Reddish, G:: Lactobacillus addophUus in the Dre vention of parathyroprivic tetany in dogs; Abst. of Bact. 61 1924 Dragstedt, L. R., Camon, P. R., and Dragstedt, C. A.: Factors con - trolling the intestinal bacteria; Journal Inf. Dis. 31, 1922 209 Gompertz, L. M., and Vorhaus, M. G.: Bacteriologic and clinical ex penence with Bacillus acidophilus; J.A.M.A. 80, 1923,90-9™ Hull, T. G., and. Rettger, L. F.: The influence of milk and carbohydrate if, i914? n 219^29 teStinal fl ° ra ° f White rStS: CentbL f B^ I Ori Hunter, Charles A. : A preliminary report of the media for the cultiva - tion of the Lactobanllus group; Correspondence. Hunter, C. A.: A preliminary report of media for the cultivation of the Lactobactllus group; Abst. of Bact. 8, 1924. 0I lne J6tt h n n ;,ib " W tY . Ve ?e. leichend ,e Untersuchungen zwischen dem Vaginal- Dar^es; MflTyg^l, 1% f&amp; U f M °***' *'* SaU^ S 880 "' ** X^ P " 265 ' BacUlu * "*°- Ken 8t 11 No A -^Ma I r n c t h1 i 3 " a i9 i 2 n 6 t . 0leranCe of carboh y drat «; J-A-M.A. Vol. Kopeloff, N., and Beerman, P.: A modified Gram stain for differentiat - ing B. actdophilus; Abst. Bact. 1344, 1925. K °^bsf'66 r "l923 d Be^ rman&gt; P " Bacillus acidophilus therapy; Bact. Kul « P f'n^" L f +2 d 5 ettger ! L : F - : A Preliminary report of a comparative study of the fermentative action of Lactobacillus bulgaricus and L,actobaculu8 actdopkxlus; Bact. Abst. 37, 1923. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Commercial Application op Acidophilus Milk Mereshkowsky : Zur Frage uber die Rolle der Mikroorganismen im Darmkanal; Cent. Bkt. 39, 1905, 380, Robinson, C. S.: The hydrogen ion concentration of human feces; Ab - stracts of Bact. 6, 1922, 157. Rodella, A.: Ueber die sogenannten Saureliebenden Bacillen im SSuglingsstuhle; Centbl. f. Bakt. I Orig. 29, 1901, 717. Sierakowski, S., and Zajdel, R. : Sur les bacteries proviquant la carie dentaire; Compt. Rend. Soc. Biol. 91, 1924, 961. Spohr, K. P.: Acidophilus milk as a dietary factor; Sudd. Molk. Ztg. 1926, 19. Torrey, J. C, and Kahn, M. C. : The inhibition of putrefactive spore bearing anaerobes by Bacterium acidophilus; Jour. Inf. Des. 33, . 1923, 482-497. Torrey, J. C: Simple selected methods for the bacterial analysis of material from the intestinal tract; Abst. Bact. 85, 1925. tSM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>