<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Effect of Variation in the Calcium-to-Phosphorus Ratio on the Utilization of Nitrogen, Calcium, and Phosphorus by the Growing Chick</title>
               <date value="1936-05">1936-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE, UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 83 The Effect of Variation in the Calcium - to-Phosphorus Ratio on the Utiliza - tion of Nitrogen, Calcium, and Phosphorus by the Growing Chick C. W. Ackerson, M. J. Blish, and F. E. Mussehl 1 ■ « ' '■'■ '■ ■■■■.■■: '-'.' ■ ! LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MAY, 1936 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY 1. Three groups totaling 123 chicks were fed accurately known amounts of rations containing 0.9, 1.5, and 2.3 per cent of calcium with liberal provision of the anti - rachitic factor so that conditions for assimilation and deposition were favorable. 2. By means of the comparative slaughter test the retention of ingested nitrogen was found to be about 37 per cent, and that of phosphorus about 28 per cent m the three lots. 3. With 0.9 per cent calcium m the ration, 35 per cent of that ingested was retained; at a level of 1.5 per cent calcium, 24 per cent was retained, while with 2.3 per cent of calcium ingested but 13 per cent was retained. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Effect of Variations m the Calcium-to- Phosphorus Ratio on the Utilization of Nitrogen, Calcium, and Phos - phorus by the Growing Chick C. W. ACKERSON, M. J. BUSH, AND F. E. MUSSEHL Various phases of the interrelationships between calcium, phosphorus, vitamin D, and radiant energy are being studied by an ever-increasing number of nutrition workers. In consequence, a general literature review cannot be attempted m this paper. A recent review which furnishes an extensive bibliography is that of Schmidt and Greenberg (1). The primary purpose of the experiment to be reported m this paper was to observe the effect on the utilization of nitrogen, calcium, and phos - phorus of changing the calcium-to-phosphorus ratio of the ration of grow - ing chicks. The method of feeding employed was the same as that used m previous work (2). Conclusions were drawn from food intake, body growth, and carcass analysis at slaughter for nitrogen, calcium, and phos - phorus. The percentage retention of these elements was determined by comparative slaughter tests, comparisons being made between newly hatched chicks and chicks which had been fed for. several weeks. The chicks were brooded m electrically heated battery brooders equipped with one-half-inch-mesh wire bottoms. They were hand-fed their pelleted feed, so that quantitative food intakes were assured. PREPARATION OF THE RATIONS The rations fed were based on the formula used m previous experi - ments (2) by taking 96 parts of the base and making up to 100 with additions of either starch or calcium carbonate, or both. The rations were mixed as follows: Ingredients Ration 1 Ration 2 Ration 3 Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Yellow cornmeal 34.56 34.56 34.56 Shorts 19.20 19.20 19.20 Bran , v 9.60 9.60 9.60 Pulverized oats 9.60 9.60 9.60 Meat meal 9.60 9.60 9.60 Alfalfa meal 7.68 7.68 7.68 Dried buttermilk 4.80 4.80 4.80 Sodium chloride 0.96 0.96 0.96 Starch 4.00 2.00 0.00 Calcium carbonate {precipitated) 0.00 2.00 4.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 83 The ingredients of the ration were mixed in a mechanical agitator, and then pelleted, using a 5/32-inch die. Analysis of samples at intervals during the feeding trial showed that the feed as pelleted was of uniform composition. Cod-liver oil was fed by pipette in amounts sufficient to prevent rickets. The protein plane was the &amp;ame in all lots, while the calcium carbonate additions constituted the expeiimental variable, but the energy content of the three modifications varied slightly because of the substitution of calcium carbonate for starch in Lots 2 and 3. Superimposing the salt on the base would have changed both the protein and starch levels, so the method used appeared to be the ratic nal choice, inasmuch as only the calorific value of the feed was changed i ANALYTICAL METHODS The rations were subjected to the usual fodder analysis according to the methods of the A. O. A. C. Calcium and phosphorus were deter - mined after ashing, the form:r volumetrically after precipitation as the oxalate, and the latter gravimeirically, according to the methods of the A. O. A. C. Table 1. — Analysis of the rations. Ration , I Nitro- . | Phm- l Crude Crude . XilniR'n- i Ratio fell.. , " 31cr Ash Kt-n '- lk: T 1 I'hi.rus , f.it (il.cr l ' r """ 1 free exincl' Oi:l' .". ct. P. &lt;•/. /'. a. . p. a. P. a. l'. a. P. a. P. a. P. a. Lot I 7.1 6.3 3.07 0.881 0.798 3.6 6.0 19.2 57.8 1.10 Lot 2 7.1 7.2 3.07 1.-165 0.S00 2.7 6.2 19.2 57.6 1,83 Lot 3 6.9 8.5 3.07 2.277 0.803 2.6 6.4 19.2 V,A 2.84 The chicks were handled i a the manner given in detail in an earlier paper (2). However, analyses of individual chicks were not made, two or more chicks being compojsited by disintegration with concentrated hydrochloric acid after removal of the contents of the digestive tract, to form one sample. Nitrogen was determined on suitable portions of the hydrochloric acid digest of the chicks. Calcium and phosphorus were deter - mined after digestion of an aliquot with nitric acid. Phosphorus was also determined following digestionj with sulfuric acid. It may be noted here that the preparation of the sample for calcium and phosphorus analysis is at present carried out by digestion with nitric and perchloric acids, fol - lowing the suggestions of Gerritz (3, 4), Gieseking, Snider, and Getz (5), and Smith (6). Nitric acid destroys the readily oxidizable organic matter, after which the perchloric acild readily oxidizes the remaining organic matter. This procedure effects a great saving of time, and produces a solution in which all the organic matter has been destroyed. I ■ ■ ■ ■■ RESULTS FROM THE EXPERIMENTAL FEEDING The chicks used were newly! hatched White Rocks, chosen in a weight range of 37±2 grams. They ■ivere leg banded at random and assigned to lots which were to receive Rations 1, 2, and 3 respectively. Seventeen </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Effect of Variation in Ca:P Ratio chicks were started in each lot, but as a result o£ casualties during the first week, because of hand feeding, the. survivors numbered 14, 13, and 12 in Lots 1, 2, and 3. The chicks were not segregated by lots, but were mixed indiscriminately in two sections of a battery brooder. Each chick was hand-fed the pelleted ration from individual diet bottles so its feed intake was known. In addition to Lots 1, 2, and 3, fed Rations 1, 2, and 3, two other lots were fed at later dates. Lot 1-a was fed Ration 1, but the food record was kept for the lot, and not by individuals. Lot 2-a was fed Ration 2, and handled in the same manner as Lots 1, 2, and 3, making the lots comparable. Lots 1, 2, and 3 were fed simultaneously. At the conclusion of the feeding trials the chicks were killed after a 16-hour fast without loss of blood, and analyzed in groups after removal of the contents of the digestive tract. The sex of each chick was noted during this operation. With the exception of Lot 1-a, records were kept of the initial weight, final live weight, net body weight, and food intake of each chick. The pertinent figures involved, namely the gain in body weight, dry - matter intake, and the nitrogen intake, together with the derived values, percentage rate of gain and gain per gram nitrogen fed, are recorded for each chick in Table 2, and summarized in Table 3. The nitrogen found in the provcntriculus and gizzard was deducted from the total amount fed to give the figure for nitrogen intake. The gain in weight was the net body weight minus the initial weight. The average "fill" of the chicks at slaughter was found to be 5.5 per cent of their net body weight. Lots 1, 2, and 3 were started May 18 and fed until July 5, or 48 days. Lot 1-a was fed from January 4 to February 11, or 39 days. Lot 2-a was fed from July 18 to September 15, or 59 days. Forty-nine of the 58 chicks in Lots 1, 2, 2-a, and 3 showed a dry-matter intake range of only 26 grams, from 682 to 708 grams. The data secured from the feeding records and the analysis of the chicks are given in Table 4. The composition of the chicks was found by analysis, and these values, expressed in percentage of the net body weight, are shown in Table 5. From these figures and the average com- , position of newly hatched chicks, as given in Table 1 of an earlier report (2), the composition of the gain was calculated. The values are expressed in per cent of the gain in Table 5, and by weights for each analytical group in Table 6. The actual intakes of nitrogen, calcium, and phos - phorus were found by consulting the individual food-intake records and the analytical data on the rations. These figures, together with the calculated percentage retentions of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus, are also pre - sented in Table 6. A summary is presented in Table 7. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 83 Table 2. — Ind ' victual data on chic\s. Chick Cain" J^ I Ra.c of Nitrogen ££$£,. w "S ht imakc I g Jln i"»l« g™n""d No. Grams Grams P. ct. Grams Grams LCT 1— MALES 1 296 688 43.0 22.75 13 0 5 300 684 43.8 22.60 13.3 8 356 661 38.8 21.83 117 10 217 543 40.0 17.96 12.1 12 283 694 40.8 22.93 12.3 14.... 288 687 41.9 22.72 12.7 LOT 1— FEMALES 3 234 694 33.7 22.94 10.2 •4 256 642 39.8 21.21 12 1 7 275 697 39.4 23.03 11.9 13 263 686 38.3 22.66 116 15 262 692 37.9 22.87 115 16 271 682 39.7 22.53 12 0 17 284 697 40.7 23.03 12.3 18 236 689 34.2 ' 22.78 10.4 LOT 2— MALES 24 256 695 36.8 22.96 112 26 355 828 42.9 27.35 13.0 29 266 690 38.6 22.81 11.7 LOT 2— FEMALES 19 281 685 41.0 22.63 12.4 21 275 688 40.0 22.75 12 1 25 293 695 42.2 22.96 12.8 27 280 696 40.2 22.99 12.2 28 266 697 38.2 23.03 11.6 30 228 556 41.0 18.36 12.4 31 311 689 45.1 22.78 13.7 32 256 661 38.7 21.86 11.7 33 269 695 38.7 22.96 11.7 34 197 557 35.4 18.42 10.7 LOT 2-a— MALES 1-- 280 708 39.5 23.39 12.0 2 300 697 43.0 . 23.03 13.0 7 , 271 708 38.3 23.39 11.6 10 281 708 39.5 23.39 12.0 16 289 708 40.8 23.39 12.4 17 308 708 43.5 23.39 13.2 27 301 708 42.5 23.39 12.9 28 302 I 708 42.7 23.39 12 9 35 293 i 688 42.6 22.75 12.9 LOT !-a— FEMALES 5 2M 708 40.1 23.39 12.1 11 263 691 38.1 22.84 11.5 14 298 689 43.3 22.78 13.1 19... 267 697 38.3 23.03 11.6 22 276 708 39.0 23.39 11.8 23 269 . 697 38.6 23.03 11.7 25 290 I 708 41.0 23.39 12.5 26 269 697 38.6 23.03 11.7 33 324 708 45.8 23.39 13.9 36.... 284 708 40.1 23.39 12.1 LO-T 3— MALES 36 290 I 696 41.7 22.99 12.6 39 281 | 695 40.4 22.96 12.2 46 205 552 37.1 18.23 11.3 48 283 697 40.6 23.03 12.3 49 265 695 38.1 22.96 11.5 51 266 694 38.3 22.93 11.6 LOT 3 — FEMALES 37 282 695 40.6 22.96 12.3 38 248 622 39.9 20.54 12.1 41 265 693 38.2 22.90 11.6 42 249 695 35.8 22.96 10.8 43 233 695 33.5 22.96 10.2 47 245 691 ' 35.5 22.84 10.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">I Effect of Variation in Ca:P Ratio Table 3. — Summary of data in Table 2. Group Gain in j Rate of Nitrog(:n C*n per , w "B ht | intake g»i° inuke "^"n fed Gram/ Gramj p. c t. Grams Crams LOT 1 J** 1 , &lt;6) •■•• 273 660 41.4 21.80 12.5 Females (8) 260 685 38.0 22.63 11.5 LOT 2 " al " &lt;3) 292 738 39.6 24.38 12.0 VmaXa &lt; 10 266 662 40.2 21.89 12.2 LOT 2-a If'" W "; 292 705 41.4 23.27 12.6 Females (10) 283 701 40.4 23.18 12.2 LOT 3 "*'" (6) 265 671 39.5 22.19 11.9 Female. (6) 2S4 682 3? 2 125J M 3 Table 4. — Weight data on composited chicly and summary of lots. I A I %££• r? n g;ri »£■? 1 S^S" " Crams Grams Grams Percent Grams LOT 1-a 11.683 9,242 22,914 40.3 12 1 LOT 1 !' "••• 563 «2 1.332 36.9 11.2 ?' "' IS 935 820 .2.083 39.4 11.9 7 :•:;•" 566 190 1,354 36.2 n.o ; 5 ' : - xm '•° 96 2 - 612 42 ° 12.7 "• "• '••••: 935 822 2,055 40.0 12.1 LOT 2 l°- 31 ' 27 817 706 1,809 39.0 118 ,„ " 390 355 828 42.9 13.0 5 29 « 22 547 1,375 39.8 12.1 „ "••" 35 ° 311 689 45.1 13.7 f. 1 2 4 8 ' H 938 «28 2,087 39.7 12.0 21 - 24 ' 32 901 787 2,045 38.5 11.7 LOT 2-a }■ 2l 5&gt; 7 1.285 1,135 3.124 36 3 110 £"•:£" '' 278 •'»« 3,095 36.5 U "' '•?,'?„ l '*» &gt;•'» 3,1.3 36.0 10.9 I 5 ' It'll' ll313 U62 3 - 120 37 - 2 "J 33 ' 35 ' 36 1.0M 901 2,329 38.7 11.7 LOT 3 39 / %• ** 921 809 2,083 38.8 11.8 %%•?, 95 ° 837 2M &lt;™ 12-2 I 3 ' 49&gt; 51 878 764 2,084 36.7 11.1 3 J- * 2 571 497 1,316 37.8 114 46 240 205 552 37.1 113 Summary Lor j 4.247 3,720 9,436 39.4 H.9 LOTS 2 AND 2-a 10.176 8,983 23,613 38.0 11.5 LOT 3 ' 3.560 3,112 8.127 38.3 11.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">! ■ -■ . Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 83 Table 5. — Percentage composition data on composited chic\s and summary _ of lots. Chick Composition of chicks Rat j 0 I Composition of gain Rat ; o E|hcr N Ca P t Ca:I&gt; I N Ca P Ca:P extract •Vim. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. LOT la 2.98 0.77 0.55 1.4 3.08 0.86 0.62 1.4 5.6 LOT 1 4, 18 3.24 0.73 0.55 1.4 3.34 0.77 0.59 1.3 3.5 7. 12, 15 3.16 0.74 O.sl 1.4 3.24 0.79 0.57 1.4 5.8 3,8 3.28 0.77 0.56 1.4 3.39 0.83 0.60 1.4 6.6 1, 5. 10, 17.. 3.08 0.76 0.5f. 1.4 3.14 0.81 0.60 1.4 6.3 13, 14. 16 3.07' 0.68 0.52 1.3 3.13 0.72 0.55 1.3 6.6 LOT 2 27,30.34.... 3.02 0.75 0.61 1.3 3.08 0.80 0.64 1.3 6.1 26 2.99 0.80 0.511 1.4 3.02 0.84 0.60 1.4 7.6 19, 29 3.08 0.85 0.59 1.4 3.15 0.92 0.63 1.5 6.5 31 3.06 0.76 0.5" 1.3 3.12 0.81 0.61 1.3 7,3 25, 28. 33 .... 3.16 0.79 0.5. i 1.4 3.24 0.84 0.60 1.4 4.8 21, 24, 32.... 3.21 0.83 0.5' 1.5 3.30 0.89 0/&gt;fl 1.5 5.0 LOT 2-a 1, 2. 5, 7 3.18 0.99 O.fif 1.5 3.25 1.07 0.69 1.6 4.4 10. II, 14, 16 3.13 0.97 0.6 1.5 3.22 1.04 0.68 1.5 3.4 17, 19, 22, 23 3.18 1.03 0.6B 1.6 3.26 1.12 0.71 1.6 6.1 25, 26, 27, 28 3.07 0.98 0.6-1 1.6 3.13 1.05 0.68 1.5 4.8 33,35,36... 3.02 0.93 0.6:: 1.5 3.07 1.00 0.67 1.5 3.2 LOT 3 39, 47, 48... 3.15 0.82 0.5ii .1.5 3.22 n.88 0.66 1.5 5.7 36,37,41.... 3.02 0.76 0.53 1.4 3.08 0.81 0.56 1.5 6.8 43, 49. 51 .... 3.11 0.86 0.55 1.6 3.17 0.93 0.59 1.6 5.0 38, 42 3.22 0.71 0.5 1.4 3.31 0.76 0.54 1.4 5.5 46 3.02 0.81 0.5: 1.4 3.09 0.87 0.61 1.4 2.8 Summary .LOT 1 3.14 0.73 0.55 ' 1.3 3.22 0.78 0.58 1.3 6.2 LOTS 2 AM) 2-a ..... 3.11 0.91 0.62 1.5 3.18 0.98 0.66 1.5 5.0 I LOT 3 3.11 0.80 0.54 1.5 3.18 0.85 0.58 1.5 5.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Effect of Variation in Ca:P Ratio Table 6. — Retention of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus. Nitrogen Calcium I'hosphoruT chlck Intake In gain I Retained Intake In gain Retained Intake I In Rain Retained No! - Crams Grams P. it. Grams Grams V. ct. Grams Grams P. ct. LOT I -a 756.34 284.86 37.7 217.05 79.72 36.7 197.32 57.63 29.2 LOT 1 4.18 43.94 16.42 37.4 12.61 3.79 30.0 11.46 2.88 25.1 7 - n - 15. ■■• 68.76 26.53 38.6 19.73 6.45 32.7 17.94 4.71 26.2 3 - 8 44.71 16.60 37.1 12.83 4.(16 31.7 11.66 2.96 25.4 1, 5. 10. 17.. 86.25 34.45 39.9 j 24.75 8.88 35.9 22.50 6.63 29.5 13. 14, 16... 67.85 25.76 38.0 19.47 5.92 30.4 17.70 4.48 25.3 LOT 2 27,30.34... 59.70 21.78 36.5 2H.52 5.64 19.8 15.58 4.54 29.2 26 27.53 10.73 39.3 13.05 2.99 22.9 7.13 2.14 30.0 19. 29 45.19 17.21 38.6 21.68 5.02 23.2 11.84 3.47 29.3 31 22.77 9.69 42.6 10.87 2.53 23.3 5.94 1.89 31.9 25, 28, 33... 68.89 26.84 39.0 32.90 6.93 21.1 17.97 4.92 27.4 21, 24,32... 67.51 25.92 38.4 32.25 0.99 21.7 17.61 4.77 2~!l LOT 2a 1 I. 2, 5. 7... 103.17 36.93 35.8 49.27 12.11 24.6 26.90 7.86 29.2 10, II, 14, 16 102.19 36.21 35.5 48.81 11.73 24.1 26.66 7.64 28.7 17, 19. 22. 23 102.85 36.47 35.5 49.(19 12.50 25.5 26.81 7.98 29.8 25. 26. 27. 28 103.04 36.34 35.3 49.20 12.26 24.9 26.86 7.95 29.6 33. 35. 36 ... 76.91 27.65 36.0 36.73 9.01 24.5 20.06 6.00 29^9 LOT 3 39,47,48... 68.77 26.06 37.9 51.05 7.11 13.9 17.94 4.M 27.0 36, 37, 41 ... 68.80 25.80 37.5 51.07 6.82 13.4 17.94 4.70 26.2 43, 49. 51 ... 68.81 24.24 35.2 51.07 7.08 13.9 17.94 4.50 25J 38, 42 43.47 16.47 37.9 32.27 3.75 11.6 11.34 2.70 23^8 46 18.21 6.34 34.8 13.53 1.79 13.2 4.75 1.26 26.5 Summary LOT 1 — ■ 311.51 119.75 38.4 89.38 29.11 32.6 81.26 21.65 26.7 LOTS 2 AND 2-a 779.75 285.79 36.7 372.37 87.72 23.6 203.35 59.17 29.1 LOT 3 268.06 98.91 36.9 198.99 26.54 13.3 69.91 18.00 25.8 DISCUSSION Inspection of the tabular data shows that changing the calcium content of the ration fed to newly hatched chicks produced a marked effect on the percentage retention of calcium. It did not affect the composition of either the chicks or the gain, nor did it affect the retention of the nitrogen and phosphorus. The data on Lots 1, 2, and 3 are susceptible to an analysis of variance according to methods outlined by Snedecor (7). Such an an - alysis revealed highly significant differences in calcium retention between treatments, that is, variances in the calcium content of Rations 1, 2, and 3. With a calcium content of 0.9 per cent, 35 per cent of the ingested calcium was retained, but with 2.3 per cent in the ration, but 13 per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agr. Exf. Sta. Research Bulletin 83 was retained. The data of Speirs and Sherman (8) in similar work with rats show the tendency o£ the calcium utilization factor to decrease as the percentage of calcium in the diet is increased. The differences found between lots with respect to the percentage re - tention of nitrogen and phosphorus, percentage of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus in the net weight, percentage rate of gain, and gain per gram of nitrogen fed were not statistically significant under the conditions of the experiment. It may be that at lower levels of calcium feeding an effect might be noticed. Sherman and Campbell (9) found that increasing the calcium content of a certain ration for rats from 0.2 to 0.35 per cent was followed by a more efficient utilization of the food, but in their work calcium was designedly one of the limiting factors. It is interesting to note that their rats made the same gain per gram of nitrogen fed as did our chicks. Table 7. — Summary of data by lots. , i Lot 1. I Lot la. I Lot 2, i Lot 2-a, j Lot 3. ™™ I 14 chicks I 65 chicks I 13 chicks I 19 chicks | 12 chicks Nitrogen in chicks (p. ct.) 3.14 2.98 3.11 3.12 3.11 Calcium in chicks {p. ct.) 0.73 0.77 0.80 0.98 0.80 Phosphorus in chicks (p. ct.) 0.55 0.55 0.58 0.64 0.54 Ratio. Ca:P in chicks lj 1.4 1.4 1.5 1.5 Nitrogen in gain (p. rt.) 3.22 3.08 3.17 3.19 3.18 Calcium in gain (p. rt.) 0.78 0.86 0.85 1.06 0.85 Phosphorus in gain (p. rt.) 0.58 0.62 0.62 0.69 0.58 Ratio, Ca:P in gain 1.3 1.4 1.4 1.5 1.5 Rate of gain (p. rt.) 39.4 40.3 40.0 36.7. 38.3 Gain per gm. nitrogen fed (gm.)... 11.9' 12.2 12.1 11.1 11.6 Nitrogen retained (p. rt.) 38.4 37.7 38.5 35.4 36.9 Calcium retained (p. rt.) 32.6 36.7 21.6 24.8 133 Phosphorus retained (p. rt.) 26.7 29.2 28.6 29.5 25.8 Ether extract (p. rt.) 6.2 5.6 5.9 4.4 5.6 CONCLUSIONS Under the conditions of the experiment and with the ration fed it is evident that increasing the amount of calcium in the ration of growing chicks produced: 1. A decreased retention of the ingested calcium. 2. No significant change in the retention of ingested nitrogen and phos - phorus. 3. No significant change in the percentage composition of the chicks or of the gains made by them. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Effect of Variation in Ca:P Ratio literature cited 1. Schmidt, C. L. A., and Grecnbcrg, D. M. 1935. Physiol. Rev. 15:297-434. 2. Ackcrson, C. W., Blish, M. J., and Musschl, F. E. 1935. Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Res. Bui. 80. 3. Gcrritz, H, W. 1935. Ind. and Eng. Chcm., Anal. Ed. 7:116-18. 4. Gcrritz, H. W. 1935. Ind. and Eng. Chcm., Anal. Ed. 7:167-68. 5. Gicscking, J. E., Snider, H. J., and Get/., C. A. 1935. Ind. and Eng. Chcm., Anal. Ed. 7:185-86. 6. Smith, G. Frederick. 1935. Mixed Perchloric, Sulfuric and Phosphoric Acids and Their Applica - tion in Analysis. The G. Frederick Smith Chemical Co., Columbus, Ohio. 1st cd., 70 pp. 7. Snedccor, G. W. 1934. Calculation and Interpretation of Analysis of Variance and Covari - ance. Collegiate Press, Inc., Ames, Iowa, 105 pp. 8. Spcirs, Mary, and Sherman, H. C. 1936. Jour. Nutrition 11:211-18. 9. Sherman, H. C, and Campbell, H. L. 1935. Jour. Nutrition 10:363-71. I3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>