<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nineteenth Biennial Report OF THE Nebraska School for the Blind TO THE GOVERNOR For the Years 1911 and 1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Nineteenth Biennial Report OF THE Nebraska School for the Blind TO THE GOVERNOR For the Years 1911 and 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Nebraska School for the Blind, Nebraska City, Nebraska, November 30, 1912. Honorable Chestfr H. Aldrich, Governor: ESm: In compliance with section 12, chapter 26, of the ion Laws of 1896, the Board of Trustees of the Nebraska &gt;ol for the Blind have the honor to transmit herewith the nineteenth biennial report for that school upon the work ac - complished during the period ending November 30, 1912. Respectfully, H. H. Hands, President D. O. Dwyer, Vice President Viola J. Cameron, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Administrative Department Per Annum $1,800.00 tKiNG, Superintendent R. C. King, Matron ;rine Bosworth, Clerk Literary Department Per Month E. C. Cook, History and Mathematics Jennie E. Johnson, Primary 50.00 Mary French Morton, Literature and Geography 50.00 Catherine Bosworth, American History and Typewriting 20.00 Music Department Marjorie White, Organ and Advanced Piano Alice Whitaker, Voice and Piano Nora Martin, Violin and Beginners' Piano Industrial Department Clark Bruce, Piano tuning, Orchestra, Broom making 90.00 Effie Campbell, Domestic Science 50.00 Health Department EWm. Edmonds, Physician ennie Erb, Girls' Nurse. Aird, Boys' Nurse Employees Mike Carmody, Engineer S. J. Yowell, Farmer 50.00 Frantz Gamboni, Watchman 40.00 Susan Wilson, Laundress </seg>
            <seg id="p004">328 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT tNE TOLIVER, Cook 30.00 RS. E. BELCHER, Assistant Laundress 20.00 Jessie Pierce, Assistant Cook 20.00 Rita Peterson, Head Domestic 20.00 Rebecca Fields, Domestic 17.00 Mary Wehrs, Domestic 17.00 Bell Rakes, Domestic 17.00 Mrs. Dora Cook, Domestic 17.00 Olga Lindahl, Domestic 17.00 REPORT OF THE TRUSTEES Nebraska School for the Blind, Nebraska City, Nebraska, November 30, 1912. To the Governor: The Board of Trustees for the Nebraska School for the Blind have the honor to submit the following report: On January 7, 1911, Mr. R. C. King appeared before the board with proper credentials from yourself as superintendent, and immediately assumed the duties of office. Some enforced changes were made in the faculty soon after his entrance, but matters soon adjusted themselves, making his term a successful one in every particular. The personnel of the board has changed since the report of two years ago, Mr. H. H. Hanks being elected president to fill the vacancy caused by the retirement of Chas. R. Sherman, Mrs. Viola J. Cameron as secretary, but still retaining the Hon. D. O. Dwyer as the third member on the board. rThe report of the superintendent, giving in detail the affairs statistics of the school, is made a part of this report. Respectfully submitted, H. H. Hanks, President D. O. Dwyer, Vice President Viola J. Cameron, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p005">329 SUPERINTENDENTS REPORT Nebraska City, Nebraska, December 1, 1912. To the Board of Trustees, Nebraska School for the Blind: Gentlemen: I herewith present the nineteenth biennial report of the affairs of the school. Graduates In the past two years there have been seven graduates from the school, three from the literary department, one from the domestic science and four from the industrial department in L Li II lllg£» I mprovements rPhe following improvements have been made during the two years: 1. Five cement porches replace the old frame porches on the building, and the whole is painted a grey stone color which adds greatly to its general appearance. 2. An entirely new heating plant was installed, rendering it comfortable in all parts of the building in the severest weather 3. A tubular fire escape, and new underwriters hose with extension for the interior of the building adds much to our safety against fire. bi. Steel ceilings have been put on all rooms, plastering papering done when needed, the halls throughout the main ling have been repainted. 5. New carpets purchased for teachers and reception room. 6. Entire new plumbing and fixtures replace the old un - sanitary system. B. A new Troy laundry machine and other minor improve - i have been made in the laundry. EThe replacing of steel ceilings rendered it a most op - e time for rewiring the building, which has been done, much to the appearance as well as material safety. 9. A new wagonette replaces the old, also a new wagon box for use at the stables. / </seg>
            <seg id="p006">330 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Three Schools Three schools — literary, musical, industrial — have been maintained as formerly with excellent results. Literary Department The literary department uses, as far as is practical, the course of study adopted for public school work, the advanced classes are under the supervision of Prof. E. C. Cook and Miss Mary Morton, teachers of wide experience in this class of work, with Miss Jennie Johnson doing most efficient work in the grammar grades. Musical Department The courses of study prescribed for this department are identical with those of our best schools of music and most com - mendable work is being done in this department of the school. Industrial Department The girls are taught domestic science in all its branches, both in theory and practice, while the boys do all sorts of shop work, piano tuning, chair caning, broom making, carpet weaving and netting. A cobblers outfit was added to the equipment this last year, which branch is proving very practical. Acknowledgement In conclusion let me express my thanks to the governor for his support, and the the board, teachers and employees my heartiest appreciation for their co-operation during the time Respectfully submitted, R. C. King, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">331 PHYSICIAN'S REPORT Nebraska City, Nebraska, December 1, 1912. To the Superintendent of the Nebraska School for the Blind: Sir: Since my appointment, January 1911, as physician to the school, the only sickness has been of a minor nature. ■rhe building is in excellent sanitary condition, entire new bing having been installed through the building, which is exceptionally clean. Respectfully submitted, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">6HM T— &lt; \»^ Sv' Uaf *A»&gt; '•'•' l.~ b « i ii ii •w a &lt;N CO • &lt;M »H p4 ' H 51 H ■ ■ { « II l11k«l ; g 2«!ffl &gt;pQOffiKCL,Qii&lt;: o £ clooOoooo - r Lti«Btititi9it&gt;0 .Ci JJ— OOOwOOOOOOOO j«H pqOO&lt;OCOC!OOOC Z' « :::::::::::: OOOOOOOOOOOOOOQOOSOiOl • a i— ii— ii— 1»— ii— (i— 1&gt;— ii— ii— i i— (i-h «^J "be^ ooooxoowooooooooosoios — »»Z 1-H»-|1— If-ll-Hi— (I— 1»— ll-H»-ll— I»-H 2O5 O riNHlSiaOUHStHHt- c/) :;•;•::;'.:;: mi : ; i : | : • : : : : : | S3 § M I M I J I 8 i : - '■ I 1 llU|lll1!l| </seg>
            <seg id="p009">333 OFFICERS AND TEACHERS NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND Hon. Chester H. Aldrich Governor Board of Trustees Hon. H. H. Hanks President Mrs. Viola J. Cameron D. O. Dwyer Secretary Vice President Officers tKlNG (Northern Indiana University) Superintendent R. C. King (Wesleyan University, Lincoln) Matron Im. Edmonds (Jefferson Medical School, Philadelphia TEACHERS Literary Department E. C. Cook (Nebraska School for the Blind) History and Mathematics Jennie Johnson (Nebraska School for the Blind) Primary Mary French Morton (Monroe Collegiate Seminary) Literature and Geography CATHERINE BOSWORTH American History and Typewriting Music Department Marjorie White (Oberlin Conservatory, Ohio) Organ and Advanced Piano ALICE WHITAKER (Wesleyan Conservatory) .... Voice and Piano Nora Martin (Nebraska School for the Blind, Fremont Conservatory) Violin and Piano Industrial Department Clark Bruce (Ohio Institute for the Blind) Piano Tuning, Orchestra, Weaving Effie Campbell (Illinois Institute for Blind) Domestic Science, Bead Work M. Jennie Erb Xurse, girls Jean Aird Nurse, boys </seg>
            <seg id="p010">334 TEACHERS L— Denotes Teachers in Literary Department. M — In Music. I — In Industrial. T — In Typewriting. Mary E. Bishop L 1875-1877 Jacob Niermeyer M 1875-1880 Lucretia Hotchkiss M 1877- 1887 Martha Langford M 1877 1878 Mary McGinnis M 1880-1886 Lillie Chadsey M 1880-1884 M. G. Parmalee M 1884 1892 C. M. Scott I 1884-1886 Blanch Bedell M 1886-1889 M. L. Nichol L 1887-1891 Clark Bruce ■ . .1 1887 1891 Clara Delong M 1887-1891 Jessie Sinclair L 1889-1891 D. R. Collins L 1889 1891 Walter Alexander L 1891-1893 Mary F. Morton L 1891-1893 1908 Clara M. Noble L 1891-1893 Mrs. H. Brinkmeyer L 1891-1893 W. W. Campbell L 1891-1893 Effie Campbell M 1891-1893 1903 Julia Noble M 1891-1893 J. M. C. Manager M 1891-1893 F. 0. Taylor I 1891-1893 Olive Grant L 1893-1895 Minnie Trask L 1893-1895 Carrie McClurken M 1893-1895 Blanch Smith M 1893-1895 Ivy Hoffine L 1893-1895 H. Blake L 1894-1896 Carl D. Beghtol L 1894 1896 E. C. Cook L 1894-1896 1899 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">335 M. E. Dawes . ...M 1895 1897 Annie Sidwell L 1895-1906 W. H. Wright L 1895 1896 Gertrude Souseley M 1895 1906 M. N. S. Conner M 1896 1898 Almeda Adams M 1896 1898 X. C. Abbott L 1896 1898 C. L. Mansfield W. B. Woods L 1897-1899 Mrs. W. B. Woods L 1897 1899 Frances Tibbetts L 1897-1898 Jennie Holland Alice Baker. . M M 1898-1899 1898 1900 R. M. Volke M 1898 A. McTaggart. L 1898 1899 Mrs. C. McTaggart L 1898 1899 Allie Truesdale M 1898 1902 R. A. Lymon L 1899 1900 Mrs. R. A. Lyman L 1899-1900 A. Loeb M 1899 1912 Flora Bullock L 1899 1902 Mrs. J. H. Marnell I 1899 1901 Jennie Johnson . . L 1900 Lois Burruss M 1902 1905 H. W. Newton T 1902-1905 W. A. Dull T 1903 1904 Jacob Voeglei H. L. Boge . T 1904-1905 T 1905 1905 J. W. High T 1905 1905 M. F. Clary ,T 1905 1906 Jessie Dea Emerick M 1905 1912 Winfred Bortis L 1906-1908 Thomas L. Drake T 1906-1907 Elizabeth Hemler M 1906-1907 Otis F. Hunter T 1907 1908 Maud Wolfe . M 1907 1911 Marie Miller T 1908-1908 C. J. Hammer T 1908 1909 Vera Towner M 1908-1908 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Wlademer Veitemeir T 1909 -1909 Edward R. Walther T 1909 1911 Chas. Zadiba M 1909-1909 Ethel Denton M 1911-1911 Pearl Fodrea M 1911-1912 Catherine Bosworth L, T 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">ENROLLMENT FOR THE BIENNIUM DECEMBER 1, 1910 TO NOVEMBER 30, 1912 f PUPILS Aubrecht, Elsie P. O. ADDRESS NATIVITY DATE OF ADM. South Omaha Nebraska. . Oct. 5, 1908 ■ Alexander, Dorothy Adams, Maurice. . . . Milford Nebraska. Sept. 17, 1907 Council Bluffs. Nebraska. Sept. 11, 1912 Dakota City Nebraska. Sept. 11, 1912 ■ Baker, William Brinson, Nellie Cozad, Albert. Cozad, George Carnth, .Elsie . . Dunbar Indiana Jan. 2, 1907 Lincoln Nebraska. Sept. 10, 1902 Lincoln Nebraska. Sept. 10, 1902 Cairo Nebraska. Sept. 13, 1911 Nebraska City . Nebraska. Jan. 23, 1910 ■ Cunningham, Millard Davis, Grace Franklin Illinois Mar. 27, 1907 IDevorak, Joseph . Dakin, Mary T . Fedaler, Frank Fleming, Kenith Foutch, Glen Madison Bohemia Mar. 27, 1912 Omaha Nebraska. . Sept. 11, 1912 Havelock Nebraska. Sept. 2, 1896 Kearney Nebraska. . Sept. 19, 1906 Box Elder Nebraska. Feb. 22, 1912 I Griffith, Irene Gordon, Bessie Gireau, Henry Hardin, Oscar Huit, Grace Huit, Nola. . . Burn, Kansas Nebraska. Sept. 16, 1907 Sutton Nebraska. Feb. 14, 1890 WeWala, S. D. Nebraska. Sept. 19, 1902 So. Sioux City.. Nebraska. . Sept. 11, 1912 South Omaha .. Nebraska. Sept. 7,1911 South Omaha Nebraska. Sept. 20, 1902 18 Hill, Ethel South Omaha Nebraska. Nou. 27, 1906 Omaha Nebraska. Feb. 27, 1908 IHendricks, Delia Holderman, Clara Hawley, Leo Gary, S. D Nebraska. Oct. 1, 1911 Arcadia Nebraska. Oct. 10, 1906 22 Harris, Lyle Beaver City Nebraska. Sept. 11, 1906 ■ Journey, Wallace. . Jones, Walter Dale Koch, Wm Arapahoe Nebraska. . Oct. 12, 1908 Torrington.Wyo. Nebraska. . Sept. 1, 1909 Sutton Nebraska. Sept. 20, 1905 14 Kerst, Mark Lincoln Nebraska. Sept. 2, 1909 IKirkpatrick, Iona. . . Laurence, Lula May. Omaha Nebraska.. Sept. 11, 1911 Pierce Nebraska. . Sept. 11, 1912 Elm Creek Nebraska. Sept. 16, 1907 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">338 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT P. O. ADDRESS NATIVITY ■ Leonard, Elizabeth Lillie, Rena May Munford, Henry. . Mogis, Robert. . . Plattsmouth . . Missouri. . . . Mar. 3, 1902 Reynolds Nebraska. . Sept. 16, 1907 Ashland Nebraska. . . Sept. 10, 1901 Nebraska City . Nebraska. . . Oct. 11, 1910 53 Myers, John Nebraska City . Germany . . Aug. 3, 1909 17 McCune, Walter. 30 Martin, Nora 11 Misner, Harley. 18 Neilson, Einar 17 Phillips, Cecile . . . 22 Phillips, Lela. . . . 39 Preston, George. . 22 Rothery, George 19 Roemick, Tillie . . 15 Russell, Laura. . . 22 Reed, Minnie. . . . 17 Sawyer, Bessie. . . 10 Sarratt, Laurence 18 Sheridan, Ruby. . 10 Snyder, Mary Omaha Iowa Sept. 18, 1904 Schuyler Nebraska. Oct. 14, 1911 Aurora Nebraska. Dec. 30, 1909 Hastings Texas Sept. 16,- 1910 Uni. Place Nebraska. Jan. 26, 1909 Uni. Place Nebraska.. Nov. 10, 1908 Springfield. . . . Nebraska. . Apr. 1, 1910 Omaha Nebraska. Sept. 16, 1905 Sutton Nebraska. . . Sept. 18, 1908 Verdon Nebraska. . . Sept. 15, 1910 Wymore Missouri. . . . Sept. 10, 1902 Fairbury Nebraska. . . Sept. 13, 1904 Nebraska City . Nebraska. . . Mar. 6, 1910 McCook Nebraska.. Oct. 1, 1912 Dodge Nebraska. . . Sept. 28, 1907 51 Snow, Zeno Auburn Missouri. . . . Nov. 1, 1910 14 Sheckler, Harry Nebraska City Nebraska. . Oct. 24, 1904 I Stevenson, Harry. Stevenson, Orval . Smith, Lena Vista Smith, Walter . ... Lincoln Nebraska.. Aug. 31, 1911 Lincoln Nebraska.. Aug. 31, 1912 Craig Nebraska. . . Sept. 13, 1904 Craig Nebraska. . . Sept. 21, 1908 22 Vak, Joe Florence Nebraska. . . Feb. 6, 1910 ■ Walton, Charlotte Wadell, May Sioux City Iowa Nov. 3, 1905 So. Dakota Sept. 20, 1906 14 Wilson, Clee . . 48 Walker, W. M. 11 Yoder, Edwin Plattsmouth . Nebraska. Apr. 20, 1911 Omaha Scotland.. . Sept. 20, 1911 Hagie Wyoming.. Aug. 5, 1911 Malcolm Nebraska. Sept. 13, 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">339 GRADUATES OF THE NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND L — Literary depatment. B — Broom making. V -Violin. P Piano. T — Piano tuning. C — Clarionet. O — Industrial NAME GRADUATED IN YEAR Self P. O. ADDRESS Sustaining Aaberg, Albert L Brazil, Nebraska Deceased 1886 Adams, Nellie L 1890 Nebraska City, Nebraska. Yes Bail, James B&amp;C 1898 Tecumseh, Nebraska Baker, Alice (Muck) P,T,V 1898 College View, Nebraska ... Yes Bebout, Isabella L 1894 Nebraska City, Nebraska. Yes Bell, Bertram V 1897 Jacksonville, Illinois Beuter, Harry B 1897 Omaha, Nebraska Botsford, Anna L 1898 Lawrence, Kansas Bruce, Clark L 1886 Nebraska City, Nebraska. Brown, Gertrude L 1S90 Madrid, Nebraska Burns, James T 1896 Kenesaw, Nebraska. Deceased Bush, S. J T&amp;B 1900 Marquette, Nebraska Yes Campbell, Lucy L 1886 Graf, Nebraska Clark, Roy L&amp;P 1899 Seattle, Washington Yes Cozad, Harry L&amp;T,T L895 Lincoln, Nebraska Cozad, Sara L 1894 Long Island, Kansas Coryell, Levi L 1888 Brock, Nebraska Crim, Emma. . .• L 1886 Nemaha, Nebraska Yes Crowder, William B 1S9* Lincoln, Nebraska Curtis, Fred'k L 1894 Lincoln, Nebraska DeLong, Clara L 1886 Alexandria, Nebraska Dreanleau, Remi P,T 1899 Rapid City, So. Dakota Yes Duncan, Sylvia L 1899 Stella, Nebraska Louisville, Nebraska Yes Dueholm, Christiana L 1888 Blair, Nebraska Gillette, L. B T 1907 Gish, Clarence L &amp; I 1907 . . Nelson, Nebraska . Yes Gregg, Wm L 1896. Chicago, Illinois Yes Buffalo Gap, So. Dakota . Yes Harmon, Mary L 1S86 1903. Omaha, Nebraska Yes Haynes, Frank P Hegel, Paul T 1899 Hexthousen, Hans . L,T,P,B 1901 . . Omaha, Nebraska Yes Holdeman, Clara I,L 1908 Gary, South Dakota Yes Nebraska City, Nebraska. Yes Hollabaugh, Wm T,B 1902 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">340 NAME GRADUATED IN YEAR P. 0. ADDRESS SELF SUSTAINING Hollingsworth, Nora L. .1899 Diller, Nebraska Yes Husa, Rosa L,I . . 1908 Chico, California Johnson, Ingwald B . . 1896 Genoa, Nebraska Johnson, Jennie E L,B .1899 Nebraska City, Nebraska. Yes Jones, Clarence T,L,L. .1898 Jones, Francis L..1896 Jones, Josephine L..1894 Knapp, Anna L,P. 1901 Wilber, Nebraska Yes Koontz, Edna L,I,P . . 1908 Lincoln, Nebraska Lanham, Alma L .1896 Cozad, Nebraska Yes Red Cloud, Nebraska Yes Lewis, Clarence B . 1897 Lewis, Glen L,I,T..19O8 Beatrice, Nebraska Yes L,I 1906 Seattle, Washington Linstrom, Anna Linstrom, Christine L,l .1906 Hershey, Nebraska . . . Partially Long, Delia (Mathers) . . L,I . . 1904 Burr, Nebraska Ludwick, Lewis P,T. 1910 . McCook, Nebraska . . . Partially Mathews, Golda L..1896 South Omaha, Nebraska . . . Yes McCauley, Mary (Cook).L,P. .1898. Nebraska City, Nebraska. Miller, E. J L..1894 Madison, Nebraska Yes Miller, Stella L..1896. . Nebraska City, Nebr . Deceased Martin, Nora L,P,V,D,S1901-1912 . Nebraska City, Nebraska . . Yes L,P. 1899 Guide Rock, Nebraska Yes Moore, E. C Mullins, Julia L..1886. Salem, Nebraska Noble, Bell L..1894 Grant, Nebraska Oleson, Ida L..1901 . Stromsburg, Nebraska Owens, Clara P,L. . 1898 Burress, Nebraska Yes Page, Adelbert P,T,L. 1899 Omaha, Nebraska Yes Beatrice, Nebraska Yes Parrish.Mer L,T .1896 Quandt, Gustav L..1886 Grand Island, Nebraska. . . Yes Regelin, Minnie L..1896 Rowe, John L,T,B,V . . 1902 Los Angeles, California Schneider, Henry T,I. .1910 McCook, Nebraska Yes L,I . . 1906 Severson w Anna Wolbach, Nebraska Yes Simpson, Arthur B . . 1900 Peru, Nebraska Yes Schneider, Henry T,I. .1910 McCook, Nebraska Yes L,I . . 1906 Severso, Anna Wolbach, Nebraska Yes B . . 1900 Simpson, Arthur Peru, Nebraska Yes </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NAME GRADUATED IN YEAR P. 0. ADDRESS SELF SUSTAINING Stinger, May . Tarwater, May Warrick, Maud L. 1899 Gering, Nebraska No Nebraska City, Nebr. Deceased L 1894 Deceased L. 1890 Omaha, Nebraska Yes West, Mona (Clary) White, Owen L,P,I. 1906 L,P 1904 Albion, Nebraska Yes Wilson, Austin . Zadina, Chas. . Journey, Wallace Jennings, Leona Rothery, Geo . L 1894 Battle Creek, Nebraska Yes L,P,C 1906 T,L 1912 P.L..1911 Omaha, Nebraska Yes Arapahoe, Nebraska Yes Lincoln, Nebraska No T 1912 T 1912 Omaha, Nebraska No Gireau, Henry Wewala, South Dakota No </seg>
            <seg id="p018">342 Table Showing Balance of Appropriations for 1909-1910, With Amounts Lapsed and Appropriations for 1911- 1912, Amounts Expended, Balance December 1, 1911-1912, Amounts Expended, Balance December 1, 1912 Balance Dec. 1, '10 Appro- Balance Appro- priation Total Expended Dec. 1, priation of 1911 1912 of 1908 Superintendent's salary $600.00 $3,600.00 $4,200.00 $3,600,001 $600.00 General repairs Heating plant 12,000.00 12,000.00 11,990.12 9.88 Totals $9,274.96 $75,160.00 $82,374.96 $69,485.48 $11,592.92 latron salary . 'eachers' salaries Imployees' wages laintenance reneral repairs 166.67 1,200.00 1,366.67 1,000.00 2,675.27 12,000.00 12,675.27 10,000.00 1,668.29 8,500.00 10,168.29 7,430.76 4,132.07 19,800.00 23,932.07 17,542.37 32.661 18,000.00 18,032.66 17,922.23 200.00 3,010.50 2,108.03 5,454.08 110.43 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">343 TABLE SHOWING CLASSIFICATION OF ALL EXPENDITURES First Year Second Y Salaries and wages ! I 511,754.05 $1 11,985.98 Groceries 1,329.67 1,451.61 Bread and bread stuffs 285.44 248.38 Meat 802.37 Ice 116.66 Chickens 93.00 73.00 Eggs Dishes 25.00 50.00 32.50 Canned goods Bran and screenings 180.00 80.85 102.30 Oats and wheat 152.50 171.14 Hay 298.18 185.00 Brooms and broom materials 355.16 250.75 Cord 57.00 32.75 Electrical supplies 35.00 Rewiring 166.07 Kitchen range repairs Corn, ear and shell Cattle and hogs 8.72 99.86 182.20 Coal 1,859.95 2,454.92 Beads, wire, raffia and needles Violin repairs 72.35 . Piano Expenses of board members 14.91 Books and magazines 310.00 Carpets 215.00 Dry goods and bedding 65.45 Drugs and prescriptions Printing of notices, programs, etc 136.70 55.86 85.98 Stationery 70.65 Toilet paper 36.00 Bath room repairs (carpentering) Plumbing and supplies Steel ceilings Repairing chimneys and chapel roof Heating plant, architects' fees, etc 78.25 245.97 1,912.50 181.00 7,701.90 10,174.36 238.03 _ ,000.0 L </seg>
            <seg id="p020">344 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Interior painting, halls, etc 231.00 Water and light 633.40 572.53 Furniture 22.47 New dining room floor 370.00 Papering and plastering 243.35 120.30 Floor dressing and oils 25.00 25.00 Laundry soap and starch 40.35 184.94 New Troy laundry machine 55.00 Medical attendance 225.00 225.00 New fiber tubes 15.00 New wagonette and wagon box 268.00 14.25 Musical supplies 109.19 24.50 Gymnasium supplies 6.60 Watchmans clock 65.00 Typewriters and duplicator 87.80 195.55 Fire hose, nozzle and extension 57.50 Fire escape, tubular 950.00 Veterinary services 35.00 4.00 Harness supplies 20.00 21.50 Blacksmith ing and horseshoeing 31.40 49.00 Fresh fruit 180.98 60.00 Rental of lots 7.50 3.75 Glass, putty, storm windows and screens 7.50 75.18 Point and type paper 37.10 38.00 Cobblers supplies 19.86 Stereotyper and supplies 27.79 Painting exterior of building 1,000.28 Postage 50.00 50.00 Cleaning carpets 12.36 New library case 20.60 Addition to boiler house 1,070.00 Miscellaneous 345.00 125.73 Total $46,550.25 $27,751.41 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">345 INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND rABLE SHOWING CLASSIFIED RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES OF CASH Receipts Balance on hand, December 1, 1910 Miss Campbell (beads, beadwork, etc., sold) $131.40 - Mike Carmody (scales, cinders) 15.60 Old iron 279.20 Potatoes sold 83.16 Tuition from State of Wyoming (2 students) 600.00 Stock sold 377.80 Brooms sold 478.32 Chairs caned 3.05 Carpet weaving 3.63 Slates sold . . 8.40 Hammocks sold 80.39 Edward R. Walther (merchandise sold) 40.91 R. C. King (merchandise sold) 80.40 Catherine Bosworth (merchandise sold) 55.08 2,241.34 Total Total expenditure for two years $2,835.17 2,245.74 * Balance, December 1, 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">346 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Expenditures — First Year Dec. For butter, broom materials, magazine sub - scriptions $284.48 Jan. For tinners and freight bills 63.12 March For music 49.20 May For laundry machine 55.00 June For freight, express and labor 6.62 July For freight bills 9.37 Aug. For freight bills and express 9.03 Sept. For watchmans clock and carpets cleaned 95.55 Nov. For music, industrial materials, typewriters 310.27 Total expenditures, first year $882.64 Second Year Feb. For books and point music copied $226.11 March For broom materials, gym, supplies, magazine subscriptions 63.30 April For architects' fees, new chapel roof and labor. . 245.50 May For Underwood duplicator, carpenters, tinners . . 285.82 June For drinking fountaines, hay and labor 134.82 July For freight bills, interior painting, cow 98.14 Aug. For electrical supplies, freight bills, labor 39.32 Sept. For violins repaired, magazines, stereotyper, cow. 194.39 Oct. For pigs bought 28.00 Nor. For pigs bought 47.70 Total of expenditures during second year $1,363.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">347 Estimates for the Biennium Ending March 31, 1915 Salaries For Year Biennium Superintendent $1,800.00 $3,600.00 Matron 600.00 1,200.00 Teachers 6,000.00 12,000.00 Employees' wages 4,250.00 8,500.00 Total $12,650.00 $25,300.00 Maintenance 19,800.00 General repairs 10,000.00 Total $55,100.00 The above estimate is $20,000.00 less than that of previous biennium. During the past two years pupils have been instructed in the various subjects and trades as follows: Reading, New York point 40 Reading, line letter None Writing, New York point 43 Typewriting 20 Language 4:5 Grammar 40 Arithmetic 25 Geography 30 United States history 9 English history v Ancient history t Mediaeval and modern history 8 Rhetoric 14 Physics None American literature ' 8 Physiology .9 Algebra .8 Elocution 15 C oomotrv 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">348 Pipe organ 8 Violin 14 Cornet 5 Other band instruments 10 Voice culture 6 Chorus singing 35 Theory 9 Point music 15 Piano tuning 10 Broom making 35 Carpet weaving 3 Hammock netting 36 Cane seating 6 Sewing 20 Sewing by machine 10 Knitting 6 Crocheting 10 Raffia 10 Bead work 48 Domestic science 10 ARTICLES MADE BY PUPILS DURING THE BIENNIUM Domestic Science 1 dress, 9 aprons, 2 skirts, 4 laundry bags, 1 shoe bag, 1 tablecloth,* 4 pieces underwear, 16 towels, 51 dish cloths, 62 wash cloths, 2 rugs, 12 lifters, 6 sets of mats, 2 sets of collars and cuffs, 7 pairs bootees, 2 belts, 2 ties, 3 jackets, 9 bags, 8 caps, 8 yards lace, 4 pairs slippers, 3 fascinators, 4 shawls, 11 pieces raffia, 335 pieces bead work; also mending and darning. 200 dozen brooms, 8 dozen whiskbrooms, 30 hammock nets, 20 yards carpet. In addition to this a number of chairs </seg>
            <seg id="p025">349 PROGRAM Bacon Memorial Service Sunday Afternoon, June Eleventh, Three O'clock Hymn— "Lead, Kindly Light" Prayer Scripture Reading Dr. F. M. Sisson Address — "A Hero in the Strife" Jennie E. Johnson Quarteet — "Crossing the Bar" Messrs. Ludwick, Fedaler, Laird and Bruce Mr. Bacon as an Educator Reminiscenses E. C. Cook Effie Campbell Dr. F. M. Sisson Eulogy Hymn 'Abide With Me" Benediction </seg>
            <seg id="p026">350 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT PROGRAM Grand Concert Monday Evening, June Twelfth, Eight O'clock Selection from "Bohemian Girl" Balfe Orchestra Song— "My Heart Is Singing" Gertrude Sans Souci Frank Fedaler Pioan — Polonaise, op. 9, No. 5 Paderewski Henry Gierau Duet for Clarionet and Violin — "Somnambula" Bellini Wm. Koch and A. Loeb Cornet— "Spring Song" Mendelssohn Lewis Ludwick Violin— "Night of Joy" J. C. Macy Lewis Ludwick and Frank Fedaler Quartette— "March Militaire" Schubert H. Gierau, A. Loeb, Jessie Dea Emerick, Ethel Denton Organ— "Festival March" Ralph Kinder Leona Jennings Quartette— " Breezes of the Night" Lamothe Messrs. Ludwick, Fedaler, Laird and Bruce Two Pianos — (a) Le Martin Chaminade (b) Turkish March , Beethoven Leona I. Jennings and Ethel Denton Pilgrims Chorus Wagner Orchestra </seg>
            <seg id="p027">351 INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND PROGRAM ■Friday Evening, June 7, 1913, Eight O'clock piel Overture 1 Keler Bela Orchestra Clarionet— "Tenth Air Varie' Wm. Koch Song— "By the Fountain" Adams Frank Fedalar (a) Spanish Dance No. 1 Mozkowsky N. S. Quintette Quartette — "Overture Rosamunde" Sdmtori H. Gierau, Geo. Cozad, Geo. Rothery, C. Laird Song— "The Carnival" In Molloy Cecile Phillips Violin— " Faust Fantasia" Singelee Henry Gierau Organ— March Moderne, op. 2 Edwin Lenare Nora Martin (a) Serenade Schubert b) Traumerei Schumann N. S. B. Quintette Concertstiick, op. 39 Pieme Nora Martin Orchestral parts on second piano by Miss Fodrea Marche Militaire Seh Orchestra </seg>
            <seg id="p028">352 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT COMMENCEMENT EXERCISES Monday, June 10, 1912, Eight O'clock Tannhausser March Wagner Orchestra Theme — "The Maker of Home Nora Martin Piano— "Rigoletto Fantasia" George Rothery Theme— "The Tempered Scale" Wallace Mandron Tourney Piano— "Valse Brilliant," op. 34 Chopin Clyde Laird Theme— "A Writer of Action" George Rothery Organ— "In the Morning"— Peer Ghynt Suite &lt; Nora Martin Theme — "German Speech and Thought" Theme — Le Grande Monarque" Henry Gierau Song— "The Nightingale's Song" \ Cecile Phillips Presentation of Diplomas HON. H. H. Hanks, President Board of Trustees l'iano Duet—" Marche Slav " Tschaikoirski Nora Martin and Henry Gierai Rev. Frank Lyons Lel Phillips '' Longing for Home" Jungmann N. S. B. Quintette </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>