<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SIXTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE COMMISSIONER OF Public Lands and Buildings TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA DECEMBER 1, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE COMMISSIONER OF Public Lands and Buildings TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA DECEMBER 1, 1908 HENRY M. EATON Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings 190b THE WOODRUFF-COLLINS PRESS Lincoln. Neb.. U. S. A - </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Hhnky If. Eaton, Fremont Com miss JoeiAH M. Shivkly, Fremont Deputy John I. yon. Aurora.... Chief Clerk Robert Hahvey, St. Paul Surveyor, and Draughts Fkank \V. Holungwobth, Oak Bookki Pblham A. Babrows, Albion Bookki Susie C. Eaton, Fremont .Contract clerk Berth v May Bbown, Lincoln gnment • Myrtle Keeuan, Lincoln Assignmeni I Helen Howland. Lincoln Delinquent Clerk Bbbmici Clabke, Pairfield. - ipher </seg>
            <seg id="p004">I.KTTER OF TRANSMITTAL Office uf CommiMumer of Public Lands ami Buildii Lincoln, Nebr., December 1, l'.tov illencv, George L. Sheldon, Governor of Nebra Rl — In compliance with Section 22 of Article 5 of the Cm i of the State of Nebraska, I have the honor to .submit I the sixteenth biennial report of the office of Pilliillli— iiiim c Lands and Buildings for the two years ending November 30, 1 ( .K)S. together with the reports of the several state institutions under the general control and management of the Hoard of Public &lt;1 Buildings. Very respectfully. H. M. Eaton. Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">COMMISSIONERS &lt; &gt;K PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDING NEBRASKA F M. Davis 1877 A. (i. Kendall lssi ■h Scott John Steen A. H. Himphkey 1891 H. ('. RUMSLL J. V. Wolfe L897 1900 CiEORGE D. Foi.l.MKK 1901 11M&gt;4 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">IHST MUNDU IN EACH MONTH H).\in M. Eaton. Commissioner l'uhlic Lands ami Buildings It nkin. Secretary' "1 State State Treasurer \Y nil \m T. Thompson BOARD •»! EDUCATIONAL LANDS AM) FUNDS ■» ■ c IN 1) I I l.~I) \ ■» IN EACH- MONTH * Chairman Seen ■ie I.wvsun Sheldon, Governor M. Eaton, Commissioner Slate Tic; Secretary of - BOAKI) OF PURCHASE AND SUPPLIES HOT WORKING I)V* IN .I\NI \H\. M'Kll.. JTL1 \NI&gt; ' " TOBEK Lawhon Sheldon. Governor Chairman Ht mm M. Eaton, Commissionei Seen ('. J I" NKIN Secretary &lt;it State Trey W ii. i.i wi T. Thompson li(&gt;Al!l) •»! l'HAH.MACV JDAY IN rE»BDABT t jMAV, \li,l-l \ N l&gt; MBEK Edwin M. Beakle, Jb., Auditor (Imiinian "i II. Eaton, Commiauioner Seen William T. Thompson Attorney G&lt; -on (i. Bui \ n State Til-:,- 'lent Secre &lt;&gt;. Brian Attorney &lt; lei Bin &lt;;. Brian . i c. J un kin wi T. Tiidm !•-&lt; &gt;\ Attorney &lt; lei SON &lt;i. BhlAN Attorney &lt; i&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p007">HUM) 11 K.SIM1 IN .1 \ N I IKY, VIMill. kc;e I.kwsiix Sheldon. Governor ('hail Chaii Jahper L. McBrien, State Superintendent By If. Katox, ( 'iiininir &gt; inner Public Lands ami uildii Joel A. Pipeh Chief BOAIil) OF IRRIGATION MEKTS KIKST WEDXES \ "i l\ \ 1*14 1 I . \\H SEPTEMBER La who n Sheldon. Governor... Chai BOARD OF \ssi:ss.Mi:.\ 1 AMI EQUALIZATION MEET8 lol; \»K&gt;&gt;MI\I Filial MONDAY IN M \ 1 MEETS KUK EQUALIZATION THIRD MONDAY l\ Mil oe Lawuon Sheldon. Governor &lt;h Chaii ('. .Il \ KIN hirv cit' - I. w\&gt;&lt;&gt;\ ( i. Brian State T Edwin M. Searlb, -I a Henry If. Eaton, Commissioner Public Lands and BuildingB B^ M. Eaton, Commissioner Public I. uildii Bwi T. Thompson Attorney &lt; ■&gt; Dobson </seg>
            <seg id="p008">C. Shallenbergeh Govi M. R. Hope well Lieutenant Governor 1 1 skin .Secretary of State &lt;i. Bkian State Treasurer Si i. \&gt; H. BabTOM ' State Auditor WilliamJT. Thompson Attorney uiD H. Cowles .Land Commissioner Bishop State Superintendent Schools H. J. Wiwkti .Railway Commissioner H. T. Ci.akkk. .1 i Railway Commissioner William H. I I Kailu -ioner </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NAME AND LOCATION OF STATE INSTITUTIONS AND SUPERINTENDENTS IN CHARGE NEBRASKA HOSPITAL K&lt;il&lt; THE INSANE -LINCOLN I)H. .!. T. HAY NEBRASKA 8TATE HOSPITAL K()l&lt; THE INSANE HASTINGS DR. \\. B. KERN INSANE ASYLUM NORFOLK DR. (I. A. YOUNG NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AM) BAILORS' HOME GRAND ISLAND I). \V. HOVT SOLDIERS' VM) SAILORS' HOME MILFORO J. H. PRESSOX HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS LINCOLN MRS. KM MA JOHNSTON STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL KEARNEY GIRLS INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL GENEVA MISS I.VDA J. MCMAHON NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME MI I.K&lt; &gt; K 1&gt; MISS LENA WARD STATE PENITENTIAR1 LINCOLN A. I). BEEMER NEBRASKA INSTITUTE KOK FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH BEATRICE 1&gt;H. F. E. OSBORNK HOSPITAL FOR (KII'PLKD CHILDREN LINCOLN UR. J. P. LORI) INSTITUTE FUR THK DEAF AND DIMII — (IMUIA C. E. WHITE 1 HE BLIND — NEBRASKA I I' \fi ll)l*\ f E. H. SHKHMAN </seg>
            <seg id="p010">GINNING AI'HIL 1. 1909 AND ENDING |{&gt; OFFICE COMMISSIONS if ( '(llllIllissilllHT uf Deputy 5,400 00 2,000 00 2,01 &gt; i Chief Clerk 1 Surveyor ■I Two Bookkee &lt;f Contract Clerk if Delinquent Clerk nment Clerk if Stenographer Furniture and Repairs phone and Telegraph . &gt; - i . ( .. . 25Q mi Bind uther expenst mi! Expei Total S_N SMI mi IKIU1II OF ITlll.li LANDS \ \ I) HI II. DIM. &gt; trie Klevator ■ iinplete wiring building E Light and Engine House Expense ovements. Repairs of Capitol Building and ( iniunds entals ring roof ceilings Total $42,10 HOAKI) OK EDUCATIONAL LANDS KM) FUND for serving notices, holding auctions and sup - lilies to county treasurers $2,000.00 3,000 imi ■ praising school land Total $5,000 imi HOAKI) OF PURCHASE \NI&gt; SUPPLIES ihlishing notices, printing and p' $150 01) </seg>
            <seg id="p011">KST1MATK1) APPROPRIATION'S For the purpose of paying salaries and meeting the ex pen the land department f&lt; &gt;r the coming two years, I have a.-kc an appropriation of $28.K80. The work of the department tn date in every respect; reappraisements have been ma nearly all of the counties in the state; the lessees are paying interests in the main yearly, instead of semi-annually as beret i : these reasons 1 have omitted the salary of on&lt; clerk who has been receiving $1,000 per annum, and if the wo late surveyor doe- not increase, the work' of one other could he added to that of the second bookkeeper without n ially affecting the efficiency of the department. The amount I have asked for to meet the office expen this department is sufficient although slightly reduced, idderable amount has lapsed to the state each biennium for tin eighi years. I have also asked for an appropriation to place an elevati ipitol building. Phi 1 helieve to l&gt;e necessary from the ill of the rooms on the second and third Boors are now &gt;v depart incuts which have been created from time e legislature. I have recommended that an appropriation of s:&gt;.."&gt;uu U in order to complete the wiring ami to furnish fixtures in that all of the department- in the state house may Ik- light' electric lights from the plant at the state penitentiary. I ially recommend that this appropriation be made at ODi an emergency, as it will save the state nearly half the cost of the wiring and fixtures during the time the legislutare is in ave the lighting plant at the penitentiary completed, the line iding from the penitentiary to the state house finished with the main conduits and considerable other wiring in the state I in place, so that the work of lighting the entire Capitol can l&gt;e com - pleted in a very short period of time and without very much turhance or inconvenience. It will be necessary to appropriate 10 to meet the fuel, light and engine house expense. This i&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 - in the Capitol building including the senate chamber which necessarily ini 'tie ainuunt of fuel to be used. I added to this amount sufficient to pay the costs of fuel and light during t in of the legislature as 1 can see no reason why each legislature should have charged to its incidental exp&gt; of furnishing fuel to heat the entire building. I have : for an lucre— e in the appropriation for employe* 'he amount appropriated heretofore has not been sut- Qi to meet the payments of those who take care of the Capitol building and the amount asked for does not either increase the ry of any employee nor the number employed. tAll other appropriations asked for speak for themaelvet the work is to be carried on properly, I l&gt;elieve that the amounts ked for will \te none too lartjf FINANCIAL STATEMENT In submitting a statement of the expenditures of the Land . rtment and of the various Boards, of which 1 am Secretary. I would say that I have endeavored to expend the public funds entrusted to my care in an economical manner and to pan only such material a- t-ssary to properly conduct the business of tl </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 APPROPRIATIONS 1907 P. Mis MISSIONER OF PUBLIC I. A \ I&gt;S AND li I 1 1.1)1 M.- Office expenses, furniture, repair; telephone Biph and postage .led 12,100.00 1,528.06 On hand November 30, 1908 MASK \\D SUPPLIES printing, post- Expenses for publishing notices $150 (til age, etc nded 6 25 On hand November 30, .1908 BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FINDS Brving school land notices, reviewing hool lands, supplies to county treasurers, ate surveyor's supplies, etc (4,000.00 Expended 3,473.02 On hand November HO. 1908 Reappraising school lands 13,000 00 Expended 2,760.60 On hand November 30, 1906 ' 40 Bud November :&lt;(&gt;. l'tos ing expeaaM ded $500. 00 172 25 HOARD OK I'lld </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Kb provided by an Act of the Legislature l'.t(W the following fees are charged by this department for service performed as follows: recording lease or contract of sale. ."&gt;&lt;) cents. Kor copy of any instrument, paper or record. 10 cents fn ords. For certificate and seal. 2't cents. Er filing and recording assignment of lease, or contract of BOO word- 50 eenti and 10 cents for each KM) words ss of ! • For notice of forfeiture of lease or sale contract, 50 cents. For reinstatement of lease or sale contract. .")(! cents. For recording order of forfeiture. ."&gt;&lt;) cents for each tract of 4&lt;&gt; :es of naps or plats. 4&lt;&gt; cents per hour for time required for ing or preparation. Ke have collected from all source.- the sum of *71_'s • ; certified copies of field notes and other records, for r&lt; ignments and contracts and for registered notices, forfeiture ment. making surveys, and sale of old material. This has l&gt;een turned into the state treasury and we hold tin for same. TABLE SHOWINC KK AI'l'H USKMKN I &lt;&gt;l SCHOOL LANDS I'NDBH ty \. Old Value New Value Inc. Value Inc. Rental 411 1st IKI !."&gt; 41 J T-l 121.609 is 44.124 ::• 4.". 1 T.I &gt; LEASE CONTK.U T HI iirit- I • ri .~&gt;1 IS INI n •i7) .-)•_' l.i.UM i.:: v1.':i 7."&gt; ld.s.V. :-!7 I7J 4ii _"Ui7l 4&lt;i - HlutT (,.:,_'•_&gt; 72 2^.743 4 4 17.' 74 711. Hii(» M r.i.iH.c iki ji;.")ii7 ."^&gt; 126.311 tu 53.151 (Nl 4!i.4:i."&gt; :i«t lMi.l'L'1 lit 73.431) ini J 7&lt;i 'u (Ml 76.1a 10,677 ::t..(M (it ■ i :&gt;i 54.82 98.841 -N 411 ".' i IMI S14.:«i7 .'&gt;1 12,453 (Kt 19.531 fKt 51.21 :U.S(N) IK) .'7 . 1 H 12.423 (HI ."&gt;4.4.')t 7.' 65.489 15 23.:MS ii7 39.613 11 :;_'.( i.s-_&gt; 12 11"). 47 1 04 1.171 90 :i.()7-i n| _' 1 1 v l.i. 1.1 2.37 l.fti i.l* </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Kree thousand dollars wen appropriated by the \a for the purpose of reappraising lands for lease pun the two years the following-counties have been reappn Klaine. Box Butte, Brown, Chase. Da wee, Deuel. Hayex. Huh. Perkins, Hock. Scotte HlutT. Sheridan and Wheeler. I he appraisement of Perkins County made by the county issioners was rejected by the Hoard of Educational Land - inds. and as provided by law the said Hoard appointed three to reappraise the school lands in this county, which seinent was approved. She reappraisement of lands was commenced by my j Honorable George I). Follmer. and the work has l&gt;eei by myself. All counties have been reappraised except the ing: ■aimer. (*herr\ . Grant, Hooker. Keya I'aha. Kimhall, I McPherson, Sioux and Thomas. ■ wins to the increase in value of lands in' Nebraska, the school in all counties reappraised in 1905 and 1904 should be n 1 during the next biennium. INDKMNITY LANDS E&gt;n October _'s. 1907, the Department of the Interior appn ions of ten hundred sixty five and twelve hundredth)! I KHi." of land in Cherry County, given to the state in lieu of lai rithin Indian Reservations and fractional townships. This lands was approved by tin 1 Hoard of Educational Lands - December :i. llt()7. and the lands are now under lease. HOVD COUNTY C'OXTKST KNDE1J Ki my last report I stated that the settlers living upon the ted lands of Boyd County had acknowledged that th&lt; se lands rested in the state, ami that I hoped to hav&lt; versv closed in a short time. Ke Supreme Court decided that the lea • d by th nt upon a part of this land were not made according to law dared them null and void. This gave the who »n these Und I right t- by actin, </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 law passed by the last legislature. All the parties living upon lands made application to purchase. Appraisement was made by the full county board of supervisors by request of the Board of cation*] Lands and Funds. After this valuation had handed in. the Hoard of Educational Lands and Funds, acting upon the recommendation of this department, decided that the prii • d by the county board was not a sufficient amount to warrant pass title. Biime an agreement was readied and entered into by I parties in which they were to pay an amount &lt; 1 1 nt. and the lands were sold for a total value of O6,4£ LEASES ANNULLED BY SUPKKMK COURT The following leases were declared null and void by dc of the Supreme Court of the state: Che above named &gt;aid their money to the state in | and same should be refunded to them as they received no benefit from the lands thev leased. CONTI ■ D LANDS SOLD \cres Bold for i. l -:« ll Uallur.1 $1,364.00 13 M) Tiler IxwdbiMg ltKI John A. Sinclair. Maries Kricksnn i s\v I :&lt;4 ll ltiO Jolin T. Brimmer. . . . S-_' K\ *! 7 :&lt;4 Id ](*) S. \V. Tanner . »&gt; (M\^ (Ui s\\ U It-ll tflO Thomo \ McC'right.. 2,8 ■ ;i li n 1 rank J. liednar ll :&lt;4 ll Kitl Solomon JnhiiMiii M s\v n ;*4 n Id Cliarlcs J. Nelson. M600 NT n "■«"!! N\\ ;&lt; :&lt;4 li 16O William H. Lapratli 100 Harry J. Sinclair 1«&gt; A. H. Blair s\\ IKS4-40 lti») Albert Anderson 160 Johann Hedlund s 2,118. W $36,- ,. ■t 11 Acre* 160 M. P. Meholin tental paid 13-34 11 11-34-11 19-34-10 160 M. P. Meholin 64() Charles S. McDonald. 160 W. H. (iricv.- ■ TOUT 1,120 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 STATK LANDS SOLD STATK LANDS SOLD Euring this biennium 77365.46 acres of land have lands were Bold under the laws as existed at the time the were leased, the law of 1907 authorizing the sale of las i lessees and settlers and the Saline law of IWt l!veiy tract of land so sold has been personally examine If or deputy. 1 am pleased to report that in many com the local appraisers are valuing lands at near their real \ ver. many of the lands were appraised at a very low price and it was my duty to so report to the Board of Educational I and Funds, and these applications to purchase were rejected. Et has been my practice to advise the Hoard as to the of the lands appraised and t ho applicants were given ige of purchasing at such prices, or to ask that the- Ian raised by freeholders of the county. Appraisements * Beholders in most instances have been as high or hip t he value placed on the lands by this department. (&gt;n the question of appraisement of lands for sale pur] I quote from my report of 1906: "Under the law prior to July '.'. was given the right to make application to pure and the law further provided that the lands should l&gt;e appi at its full value. The applicant to purchase should not ol&gt;j&lt; : appraisement and the appraisers ought to keep the law in mind when so acting. They should not consider the length of time the man has lived on the land, the amount of rental he hai for the use of it. nor the amount paid for the lease, if pure! from another, neither should they appraise it at what it was « five or ten years ago. nor what it may l&gt;e worth ten years in the future, hut what it is worth at the date of application to pun So much of the state land has l&gt;een sold at seven dollars and eight dollars per acre that it seems quite difficult to have school lands valued at a fair price compared with like lands close by. "The legislature has very generously given the holder of I ited prior to July 9, 1897, the right to release for an addii period of 2."&gt; years without competition, so if the appraiser will follow the law. the state school fund will not suffer, and the !• may buy, if 1 or when his lease expires, secure a.n </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Iii connection with the sale of land.- 1 desire to call bj t ion i&lt;i a decision of our Supreme Court in the ease entitled rel Rutledge against Baton, Commissioner. The right of the Hoard of Educational Lands and Funds to m appraisements of lands for sale purposes had been d and that right is now fully established in the opinion of our Delilah Rutledf i an eighty acre tract of land ■ in County, which land was subject to sale, made applica - to purchase the same. The land was apprai 11,400.00. ! wing the practice, the land was examined by this department Bade that f 1,400. 00 was much less than the full ■ the hmd. and the application to purchase was I'd by the Hoard of Educational Lands and Funds. Khe lessee commenced an action in the Supreme Court, asking writ of mandamus requiring the land commissioner to -ell id at 11,400.00. Evidence a. to the value of the land The &lt; oiirt in passing on t hi. "The rule i: fundamental that a writ of mandamus will n&lt; rd unless the right of the relator thereto i. clear. State v. _'l Neb., 572, 32 N.W. 589; State \. Bowman, \. \V. T2'.i. ami where it appear! that the provisioi the" law on which the relator bases his right to the writ. hav&lt; tantially complied with, the writ will be denied. "There is. however, another and more cogent reason why i he .Id not U- allowed. It is contended on the part of the indent that the Board of Educational Lands and Funds has a right . and it is its duty, to exert : onable discretion to pro - • hat it can disapprove of an appi and require the respondent to refrain from entering into the when it is shown that the appraisement is grossly below .I value of the lands sought to be purchased. Sec. 1. of Art. S of the Constitution, define- the power, and duties of t he lucational Lands and Funds as follow "The (iovernor. Secretary of State. Trea. urer. Attorney ( leneral loner of Public Lands and Buildings shall, under the ion of ' titute a Hoard of Commissioners for the sale. It pni of all lands and funds </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 STATE LANDS sol. I) ;p;irt for educational purposes, an funds in such manner ;is may Ik* prescribed l&gt;y law. "By an act passed for that purpose, the legislature ha scribed the manner in which such powers and duties shall be • The power thus conferred upon the hoard carrier wi a duty to exercise a reasonable discretion in executing \he with which it stand- charged. It will hardly lie contended the appraisement appears to inadequate a- to an constructive fraud, that the Hoard would have no disci - and could not refuse to authorize the rale of the lamb sought to Ik* purchased thereunder. The mere statement of that question is vn solution and while we are not prepared to say that the appraisement in the case at bar is so low as to 1m- fraudulent clear that such appraisement is from four hundred I hundred doll. than the actual value of the land, which i •nably be regarded by the board in the exercise of a reasonable being the result of a mistake. This of itself 1 ficient to require the hoard to exercise its discretionary powei ■ the appraisement. In State v. Scot! is Neb. 600, it " The Hoard of Educational Land* and I'unds is a ti ile and l&lt; f the land, set apart for the support tional institution:, and to justify the int. of a court I must lie an abuse of the trust. This question was hefore t hi. i ite v. Scott. 17 Neb., 888, and it was held thai a writ would not be granted against the hoard unless there wa: an aim cretion, which, in our view, there was not in thi duty of the board to sell or lease the educational lands of the for the highest price possible to he obtained, ami increase and by all honoiahle means, the funds for the support of t he e tional institutions, and so long as the hoard is faithfully performing its duty in that regard, this court will refuse to interfi "In State v. Scott. I. Neb.. 6N6. it was held that: B Where mandamus i- Bought to compel the Hoard of Public and Buildings to accept the highest bid for the least school lands, the writ will Ik 1 denied, unless it is clear that s an abuse of discretion, and that the sum hid is tbi value of the land 'The rule thus applicable to the present the evidence it appears that the land is worth, at 1- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 than the value fixed by the appraisements. ;in&lt;l thi- • ■••in to require the board to reject the appraisements and 1 justify the respondent in refusing to execute the contra Mb. "For the foregoing reasons the writ should 1m&gt; denied. ' Thus lias l**en definitely determined the right of the that appraisements are the reasonable value of lands sought to t&gt;e purchased, and if this policy is continued as it has Iteen during the last two administrations, many thousands of dollars will l&gt;e saved to the school funds of this - LANDS sol.l) County County Appniaedfor S&lt;&gt;1&lt;1 for i ii snuMi no fu/ I II | Ml IKI $11, 19.000 (Hi U id 19,000 (Ml "O titXI (Ml 1.1 I IX) liMI (Ml |,4 . 1.4441 I.I) 80 UO i .4441 UO 60 (K) 1,1 SO 31 53,732 7(i 7!i mv 15 !■• (I (Hi 50,74 I 00 .'. 6o Caw 4(1 (Ml :{.4&lt;MI (Ml :{. 1. 4(1 (H) :{.4OO 00 :{.l. 1.0*1 00 _'4.:&lt;(&gt;0 (HI :{•_' 7 4(1 :(L(i (M) :{.u in 4(1 :(lo (M) :{.ii ihi SMI (Ml (t..".-ll IMI 15.34 SMI (HI &lt;&gt;.:&gt;-{) IKI 15.34 4(1 00 000 (HI 4(1 00 000 (HI 4.". I :&lt;.o^.') oo ••I 1.0 112,117 50 120,317 00 79 1.196 in 1,94 r -i ui 112,117 .V) 1L'().:{17 (id la Tt 1.196 4(1 |,94 Ml 00 720 (M) Ml 00 720 (HI • J (.7 39.558 )'.i.^ U) 1.520 00 :{.i&gt; •J (.7 :«(.. ').".- 4'.i- 00 1.520 00 :{.i&gt; Divu 40 ihi 1,000 iai l.i Ill (Ml I.(MM) IMI I.I IMI 560 (Ml I .!.( i mi 500 (HI l.i.i - :«&gt;."&gt; 00 til. 7 1 :U&gt;.". (Ml til. 7 I (HI til. 117 (Ml til'. 7 I (HI 81,117 (Ml til'. 7 U iki :i.!.44(l (HI 500 ihi S.IHHI (HI Hd .'ill 1,971 03 cl&lt;l 201 l,»71 03 920 (Ml 19.410 (Ml 23.4( 920 (HI 1(1.410 (HI 23,4( 4.1I.NI (HI M) (HI 4.1I.N) (Hi 10 (HI 55,600 (HI H;ill ;,7 :{4l 1,146 (HI 1.14'i ihi M I.I4ti (HI |.l . H irian !i7.') 10 17.."):^ m 19,47 Ki 5,672.25 KJ (Hi :U) 00 2.00 :$T) (Ml 4.()l.'4 70 56 05 42,0 1,439 11 17.044 10 l.52i 25.37; l\no\ s - | - j. . </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 LANDS SOLD VlT( ( olllltV Nil (Nl _'.-NX) INI 250 (Ml '5 (Hi 125 ini JIN) (Nl J.L'IK) ( 0 .':« M :; 77(1 IH) 5,150 IHI Red Willow Kicli;ircls(iii I.IHIL' 20 .w.827 '-'•"&gt; til. si ;J6»» ini i:!.INNMMI JMI (HI _&gt;.MHI (HI lid (HI 1.620 mi ; . Ml , „ , I. HNi INI l.MNI INI 14.1IH) IN) I.S.UII IHI 4U IH) 1.4IN) (Nl 1.7IN) INI Slicrniiiii Sioux 1,470 :&gt;i 16.564 ti7 19.87 4IHI INI l(I.IHN) IN) I1.INHI INI St. llllOtl Thayer Ml IHI I. (MM) IN) ! t &gt;i H ' I'll 1.037 _':&lt; 23.066 7li 28.8J (Mill (Ml lli.7(i() IH) 16.760 ini ;,trt..n ter 4."&gt; !C) 919 INI ■J.-.»(N) (N) HI INI .'&gt; IHI York JIM) (H) 'JUKI IHI '.I. (IHI (HI Total 7,365 4(, $1.1. Biennium 1906-1900 Mini 1«N)7-1(K),S Total 155,982 59 $2 I in 294 vv [NTEREST AND RENTAL COLLECTED EACH YEAH 1908 \|i|&gt;r.iix-(l far Sold f&lt; r 401. ,042 IKI li.'.iT) 7»&gt; 75.243 :i7 4MI IM) 1 1.120 (H) I 1.1. :!.Vl 85 l.:&lt;77 (Mi Ml (X) .",.4(HI 1,11 ."&gt;.4tl(l INI Pierce I'lattc l&gt;i.lk HI INI Til INI I .800 (HI _'."&gt;.7(H) IK) HI IKI 360 (mi 5,660 INI 6,200 ini Bluff NO (HI ."&gt;_1' (Ml Ts.iilT 13 t.oflrf 31 $1.- 77. .«».', 4&lt;i 1.126.728.57 1.324,022 91 1897 Interest •290,443.71 312314.00 198,380.38 255,336.32 178,285.56 158,282.84 154,442 -'.") 143,378 Rental |] 1 »;..-)»■&gt;- 92,51 97400 76 1 22 U7M I 125,083 141.41-* 4(1 165,228 71 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 s I 1 V I v 116370.22 122,600. 13 158,232 :&lt;4 175.829 53 SEMI AN MA I APPORTIONMENTS OF TEMPORARY SCHonl. FIND 1897 lvts i.m)I Tax 1313.981 612,257 71 209.141 72 344.16: ■ii Sale Contract Rental on Lease Contract 'ii Blinds and Warrants Total \niount in Suspended Hank $1,471,11 1899 MHMl 1S99 1900 ,.»ul Tax 29,381 31 I.3M 39 ■ ii Sale Contracts il on Lease Cootractt on Sale Contract* 453,69£ Reatal on Ltame Coatraeti 220,085 7.", faterast &lt;&gt;n Bonds and WarranU 328,712 ')1 lines, etc 1,271 \y2 Total 11,333,147 27 tl on Bonds and Warrant •&lt;•- Fines, etc Total $1.333. 147 27 1901-1902 Him 1902 1 1 Tax. n,429 25 ,429 -':, Eon Sale Contracts ntal on Lease Contract Iim-ic-t on Sale Contracts 336,568 40 'al on I ntracta 242,428 56 Interest on Bonds and Wan Interest on Bonds and Warrant :$&lt;)4.&lt;i4 Total $1,321,468 29 1908 1904 loo! Tax ,:.V24.:iO J97.S20.63 306.643 11 378,699.39 Bt on Sale Contract! on Lease Contract rest on Bonds and Warrant on Bonds, etc 10.644.49 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">l'.M S^t on Sale &lt; ontm i on Lease Contn &lt;t on Bonds and Warrai I)i: count on Bonds, etc i ota I '.Ml Matt- hchool 1 a: ■ ai on Lease I ontrai Interest on Bond- and Warran Discount on Bonds, etc I otai I lie i.anil l oiniiussioiit Bial on common school an the l T nivereity, Agriculti but to slmw the large dec c total principal due on ■ he end oi each menmur KJ i;v&gt; i -i uecemoer i. isyn December 1. 1900 December 1. 1902 December 1. l!i()4 December 1. 1906 December 1. l'.io.s ii ii: i m. i --.) VIZ I I ■)llv 71 O or 1899 on initicinal It will be noticed that the December 1. 1896 at six per cei it 1909 baaed on principal due all 1h&gt; hut 1136,459.08. The u lltt'VCS it was £279,127.38 while int. December 1. mils at five md saline lands under lease con - 72 for 1897 and 1898toS334.061.87 Hental on common school ; raci has increased from 1209,141, &gt;r 1!&gt;()7 and IOCS, although thousands of acres of the besi land cen sold. This Urge increase in rental is due to two n he i' aken by the Commissioner of Public Lands -&gt;Chool la .hi sale ( ontrac &gt;-.i: ■&gt; i &gt; ■Ml Jv npaid interesl oow due I I insignificant, i . i </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 i) commissioner's report •oikI: Keappraisement (if the land Cor lease pur - poses which has greatly increased the valuation of the land. A* sold the valuation for rental purposes decreases &lt;■ ■ unsold lands increase in value and are reappraised. TK.MI'ORARY SCHOOL FIND Bhe temporary school fund is derived from the following Interest on |&gt;ennanent school funds, rental on lands under interest on balance due on lands sold, bonus received as mi to secure lease contracts, interest on delinquent rental terest and money received for licenses, fines, fees. etc. KM temporary school fund is apportioned twice a year to erent counties in the state for the support of the public PERMANENT SCHOOL FIND The permanent school funds are derived from the sale of edu - nal lands, escheated estates and five per cent of the purchase of public lands sold within the state, and are invested in inter - tig United States bonds, registered county bonds and t« warrants. The several amounts invested in these funds are as follows mon school $7,513,624 44 University 189,022 Hi Bltuial College 1 Kiidownient 497,93! 77.N1H 13 Total S8.27N.4u. Principal due m sale cunt tacts 2,729,381 74 ' valuation of lease contracts 2,989,331 EDUCATIONAL LANDS i numlier of acres acquired 2,977,309 4_' I number of acres deeded MMO Acres remaining 2.&lt;&gt;2N.«l« Number i ile cunt </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 COLLECTIONS AS SHOWN BY RECEIPTS RECEIVED DTK Number of acres tinder lease contract i.7t;:;.'.it;s 05 N'umlier of acres vacant 2,991 -'-'i Number of acres mippoeed right of way Number of acres paid for and not deeded NumlxM 1 of' acres in riven i Number of acres in model farms 1,280 00 f umber of acres in city lots umber of acres Lincoln Hospital : Total acres now held bv the state 2,028.99 ING THE Ml EN JNIUM Total rental on lease contracts S5.371 86 Total interest on sale contracts 280,831 Total bonus and added inten Total principal on sale contracts Total fees £52,707 16 Total collections for the bienniuin tl .584.385 01 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 I DABLE EDUCATIONAL I.VNDi ■ &lt; ii. •res Tui il Hem I'm ,1 . • l&lt;-&lt;l under tale underlease cull' eontrart I'ii- Vaeanl eliuwified \ htssil 2o.4mi mi |6&gt;M i"i 2.440 t M &gt; 1,'iOO (Ml S" :il-HHMHi II. Ml (Hi tv7&gt;m ihi I2.7»&gt;o&lt;hi ■ i _'ti.S.stl (HI ;n a:, ■ ik) 2.V4."&gt;o -i.'i 12.801 82 K.02U '.« 3.036 .V2 il l&lt;. ul ■ji (Mi 722 mi lii.2:is iki ■ 2 72 1.269 :i"' 3.3X8 11 I7.W.'&gt; _'C 10,998 '.hi M 4(1 SO (H) 10,892 "&gt;o ■. 92 7,481 M i .'■_'.')_' 27 17.4S7 ss 15.654 91 1,452 !»7 230 (Hi (3)160 (Hi 21.687 in 20.521 !•&lt;) 640 (Hi ."&gt;.'.") 20 I'.i 7 537 7il 130 (H) in (HI ■■&gt; IHI 1.729 (Hi t^ 42 (Kl 31.654 52 245.169 21 52 156 !•-&lt; Jr-'.(i7ii 71 2,610 (Hi • i 02 510 &lt;Mi 2.04&lt;l (Hi 103.702 96 . 21.240 IHI |s.7sl Ii2 2,03 420 (H) 14.4.V.I (i!l 1 2.508 s't 1,831 114 VA MI.II44 70 15.879 70 3,125 (HI -HI 00 92.017 us ti.4O7 (HI 16.485 (HI 69,125 Us 7.1t&gt;:{ 19 1.827 55 1.027 07 971 71 I o (HI 492 »:&lt; s&lt;i (Hi »s.7(&gt;7 '&gt;7 36,105 15 14..V2."&gt; (HI S..VT2 07 13,038 08 ■7 M 123 4!t 1,305 52 K1.13H 20 11 2,138 13 1.111 :t.') 198 31 I7.:&lt;14 $) 1,167 68 9,160 23 8,167 7'.io 99 181 ."&gt;4 &lt;f&lt; 20.05 ■7 01 241 (HI iioo (Ni 32,416 ill 20 '.is 51 IM.K44I ihi ."il 20.471 85; 7 'in 7,766 36 • i ihi 26,198 (Hi 13,271 (Kl 24.637 ol 23.437 si MO (HI 214 SO 20,480 (HI sM 58 19.598 4:* • i IX) S.242 ihi 3,798 (Hi 4.MHI (HI 2&lt;t.(HHI (HI 29.000 (HI 20.475 :«l 4.606 63 :..s4() (H) 9.948 67 (8) so 00 19,507 71 I l-'i 17 '».'&gt; 2.230 50 :i.»KMt 26 20,487 56 19,720 (HI 7(i(l (H) 7 56 20,400 69 'i.."&gt;12 10 5.191 5,691 7-1 ki (Hi 193 31 1,144.59 24,262 10 7 1,635 62 144 80 2:{.714 65 2,921 ."i7 5.320 (Hi 79,135 03 vi 120 Otr 26.038 •'&gt;!• I si4 14 7.127 6.054 os (9) l'&gt; 08 i 20.484 os 16,207 2:&lt; 3,227 7o 1,049 15 13.440 ini 12.076 67 1.INHI (H) .lt»a 33 11.424 14 •t (••) ] U | 2 1 7&lt; t * ~i S V 1 ) i </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 PABLE {EDUCATIONAL LAND.H COMMON school Total aerea Total acres Total acrea Total acres ' I'oImI :tcn-s Total acres Total acres Total acres acquired deeded under nate under lease Vacant el I L'ountiM acquired deeded under Bale under lease Vacant elaiwil contract contract 101 Kimball 36.618 88 80 00 - s 12,893.81 16,470.62 7.744 (Mi 18.439.13 (11 -I" 31,236 &gt;-4 27.607 ■'■ »HI s44 !."&gt; (IS Lincoln St7.892.89 8,134.24 10.181 tiN 79.540.97 (13 It. ihi _&lt;o 4n(I im. 20,480 tKl '0 393 28 680 »H) 7(&gt;o (Hi 18,953 .ii 24.B39 13 18.442 14 3.757 29 -'.440 ihi rsc.n . 56.320 (Hi 20 00 - k 14 976 -'I 8.906 14 :;.1»HI W _'ll.4sll (HI McPhern 56.320 (Ml 969 59 Neman 11.802 34 10.85:1.49 ' (Ml (HI 149 lit to IN 21.049 10 17.740 10 -'.7s(t (HI 520 .20 (Hi 21.992.44 20.172 14 1.550 00 260.00 I" ihi it'll) IH) 20.a &lt; M 85 1 7&lt;M 85 1.160 (HI HO IHI Ml (H) IVrk. 31,523 7.'&gt; 10 (Hi 31.51 IVrkin- 31,523 7.'&gt; 10 (HI 1.51 20.228.60 13.586.50 5.002 10 I.64O.O0 j.002 Id 1,640 (Hi 20.228 mi 13.586 "&gt;(i _tl4MI(HI 11,240 (Ml -'.4MI (HI D.76O Oil 20.480 (Hi 1 1,240 (Hi 4M) (HI 6,760 (Hi 23.655 4s 30,131 03 -'._':?:. 35 1.289 in 23.655 4S 20,131 03 16.787 tis 14.387 IS 1.302 40 1,097 80 16.787 68 1 I..*" I 1 - 1.302 Id 1.097 mi Willow.. J.V4.S.-. :«i 4.835.00 5.931 I 14.71 4N.') :{o 4.s:C) m 5.931 IK! 1 4 719 :«) A illow ,, n 10.400 (Hi 8,790.00 1.(140 (H. .'&gt;,.! (Hi .J 40 HKI 00 280 (Ml 39.792 4(1 20 4^0 (HI [9,360 (HI 1.IHHI (HI 120 (HI 8.988 27 7.835 (i!i i 70 284 &gt;70 (Hi Hi(li.irds( 10.4110 (10 8.790 (HI (140 (Hi 40,232.40 MM) (HI .'SO (HI :;!i.7'.U 40 120 (H» 1 .0(10 (Ml Mi7 70 i,.,- 26,390 99 Jl.lf.7 04 40.&lt;Ml ts Bluff.'. 25,467 481 11 I. til 20 23.835 34 HI I 20.M0 (Hi 18.806 36 1.673 64 NO (HI I(i7 65 4M 11 l.tll -'(I - 20.560 (Hi IS.806 so (Hi Sheridan 94.627 74 367 -'(HI (HI SM.049 s7 5 (hi man 20 477 20 5.894 38 6.072 "&gt;1 S.510 :!1 80.972.22 100 4(HI (Hi 80,492.22 IHI Sheridan Sherman 80.972 •-'-' i.n 15,360 (HI 10.836 09 1.083 91 440 (Hi i. . L'0.47-' ••!.-&gt; 16,609 04 3,445 :il 41s (HI 2.-..H00 (Hi 25.280 (Hi 320 (Hi - rhainas Valley 20,474.88 9.298 79 ti..".44 !H 4,631 18 shington 13,851 86 11,606 &lt;Hi 655 65 1,512 35 nijion 15,360 tHI 14.040 (Id 1.320 &lt;HI 20.480.00 11.561 do 8,227 41 633.89 'I s 20.480 (Hi YA 00 I (HI 19,957 00 York 20.480 ihi 17 v -!'i 61 I 68(1 (Hi </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 LAND COMMISSIONER'S KKI'ORT Total acres Total acres i IV under sile under lease I'ncla acquired contract contract Kiiov Madison Ntickolls AGRICULTURAL COLLXQB Total acres Total acres County Total acres under sale under le ise I nelassified acijuired deeded contract contract (21 12 23 10 :!4 140 21 70.029 ihi i ti."&gt; 3,202 99 s \ 1.1 S K Lancaster 15,594 24 25.3S2 74 3,242 ."&gt;0 1.865 16 (23) 15,1 Ml KM A I. Lancaster 12304 so 11351 20 60 mi ihi PI. 16 01 acres supposed right of way. Omaha. \iol&gt; ek Hills Railway. 2. 12 27 urea ("ninn Pacific right of way. 240 acres paid out hut not deeded. 1,000 &lt;M( 1.165 4."&gt; 154 .V) _&gt;so (Ml n (HI 1,530 (HI BO (Ml .!-'&lt;&gt; (HI 320 00 160 (Hi 160 IK) i.4U (Hi 440 (&gt;0 200 (Ml 8,322 ID 1,720 (HI L'.l«2 10 4.440 (HI 4.4SU (Hi 2,160.00 1,380.00 1 .040 (Hi J.JM) (HI 1.4IHI (HI »&gt;MI (H) 16(1 (HI 4!l!(i (is 2,888 16 1,876 4_' ■."&gt;-' 10 .{.I'.tT tiT 2,718 U 479 36 4s 11.256 .'&gt;&lt;l ."&gt;.04:i ."&gt;.' 1.4!ll 41 12 05 4.". W.i &lt;Xi li.").4_&gt;S J_ 1_M1."&gt; 95 7.ss:{ ."&gt;1 I&gt;4O (H) MO (Ht .'."). 4(1.". 47 l!t.!«&gt;4 48 4. •&lt;."&gt;:( iis 1,087 91 980 (hi 900 (Hi »i4tl (X) 003 !)-' _&gt;._&gt;4O (HI J.O71 77 l.Vi (Ml :s:f.4'tl 20 22,566 21 9,483 99 1.439 (Hi 10.114 «1 K 1.4! t&gt;4() (Kl i:&gt;.t&gt;4N MS 15,158 64 4S(l (H) </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 4. :«6.M iii Missouri River. 5. 130 acret paid out but not deeded. 12.31 acres right &lt;&gt;t \v;iv. Chicago. St. Paul. Minneapolis A Omaha Railway. 54 23. 15,103.84 acres of saline land were Bet aside by the lature us follows: State University and City Lots 320 acres; Lin - coln Hospital for Insane. 699.04 acres; Model Farm. 1280 Normal School. 12 Ml! 81 in Kiver. n (&gt;. 20 . 05 acres supposed right of way, Union Pacific Railway. 7. 85 acres paid out but not deeded. 8. BO acres paid out but not deeded. 9. 45.03 acres in river. h(). 307.76 acres paid out l&gt;ut not deeded. I. 240 acres paid out but not deeded. 12. 9.52 acres paid out but nut deeded. 13. 16 acres supposed right of way. 14. 113.20 acres in river. l."i. 10 acres paid out but not deeded. lti. ."&gt; acres paid out but not deeded. 17. 76.90 acres in river. Pv 17 70 acres supposed right of way. &lt;'. H. t v (}. R. R. 10 paid out but not deeded. 19. HO acres paid out but not deeded. 20. 12.05 acres supposed right of way. ('. B. iV IJ. R. R. 21. 12.23 acres supposed right of way. ('. St. Paul, M. A' O. 22. 10.34 acres supposed right of way. ('. St. Paul, II. A 0. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 TABLE 8HOWING WORK OF THE BIENNIUM COMMON scHt ml \ 1 1 1 ■&gt; if) ihi $15,71! 4,1 IK, » _\(KHI IK " "" *?•?£! IKI IHI IHI | '4(1 (XI 1 44O l«l 1.131 I"l -' "" ' ''40 (Ml 1,1211 IKI -' IHI ' . ' ''411 (HI 88 S 4 "it» 94 71 _•:«; :t7 -'h.os.-, 4.-. U [Ml 4O9.V4:, 4'.l (14 i;:t .'_' :ils '.HI 4 i.iao it ... 4.09."&gt;"4.i H H3 22 si: 7i, 4u 33.99. SJ 7 attU II .'INI INI IMI 9.634 9.634 — . - , mi ISI 74 M 4.064 IHI 421 4(i iki J4(i (*l mi 4n iki INI '»n Utl l_1i HI 22.744 74 4(1 IKI ,i i in ami &lt;hi i «i7 ,.&gt;ii 14,476 -liv ..41' IKI II 2*7 1.4IKI IKI « '^ 300 (»i 1.700 i»i 7.1M 310 «i -* 113 W ,.,, ... 113 411 2.158 -:* L-4II IKI J4II IKI 5fo !! - 4.--, n -,9 I8.17J J1.747 40 H7II I" \tjil IHI i 41 H' IHI .117, -11 IHI V--! ?a 7MB is is (KI , ,,.ti .-I (IJll IKI hi 1.017 S • '■!'-- IKI I 7-11 i - 4IKI IKI IKI . _ ■ ■ iki 6,905 iSnM W5 10 673H . ,k, !.k :S«m ijnn '"•' l^ _ T 1 Mil (KI IKI 'I IKI 12 Mil in, 12.090 .--II 72 3.731 I-' HIM »i mi 1 7 1 ' -17 -4 1 .fSMt , ,, ill 14.98 4191)0 4^ : tr las is 419 (ki . ■, -2' • .11 in IHI ■•• .i.M»4 Jll IKI - ■ (KI I "* till 17,44(1 ,44 uu 906 17 44O , 1 4l. :i..Vi(i 71 4«. .-,.", 44 14 _'7.i.".l mi 49.091 KJ .-,.", 44 323 14 .'7. el l"i 49.1)91 _mi 4.171 S7 -..91-' IK) 11.524 J1S 640 (Ki 3.4A1 47 10 00 7CKI IKI 91-1 IKI . .y^it in»i" i - 4 , _ 4 liOlU </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 TABLE SHOWING WORK OF THE BIENNIUM Continued COMMON SCHOOL COMMON .-(IK Mil — — — '■ ~z T ~ T 2- DOU.NTIEH 5 I 'Ss'-f ~ I 11 "-^= 17: Coin tiks - S"5 a i - :(_• 10 (Ki II) IKI III I'll ."&gt;2O I M I 711 III Ml IKI I Mill IKI ' '"- i'iiiiiiihi 411 I"' ■1.1KII 41 L'.tWfi 91 IHT 14 7 21 I 111,. 13 lit -'1. 'oik s41 I lot&gt; I ■ II 17.". :tl •_&gt;ii iki (1 4:i - J 17 12.1 iki I.t9 7ii su iki r,7!&lt; 1 1 7i. '..Si&gt;4 iki :)4 .':&gt; 8 40 1,512 iki 4(1 (Ml is:, 211 12 47 r.,61fl 8 41 I2.i;j4 (Ml Inn iki 411 IKI 1 (HI I [20 111 I 4 7 72(1 iki ill' ls7 17 S4 »l S9 4 41 Ml IMI 411 IM 1 . 120 W I 15 1! I I I 47(1 .'.I 7-'(l IM' I 9JU IK) 7 3»&gt;7 -- -'47 .Mi . 4111 (Ml 1 IKI ". 4117 7n 9.17 -•:! I.IO7 -'( J4n in 9.17 Si ' 2411 iki :,.|H4 44 1.44(1 IKI I.30U III 1.44(1 IN) _' 1 1 1 SS .; 7;, '». 1. mi _'in K&gt; -ki mi 'i 47 'i 7'vii 47 II Ml IMI l.~. . i,4i 1,411 mi 1.043 us 4ii I t 1111 I.4H I 41 H I I II I I 1 1 « i INI 4.1Hi 4.1 lii v7 4(1(1 HI Mi ,.rk 7*14 Jim (Kl 4H mi I &gt;7 1 Jn &gt;i4 Jim (Kl 4(1 mi 1.S74 HI 71N :ss rvivKKsi rv "HI IKI I 1(1 SX rvivKH n v Aiitelui 'HI ' ■ *M&gt; .(&gt;( IMI l.lii Ml 1 :&gt; 1 A 744 (Ml I..".4S 9(1 28 74 4sii 744 (XI I..VI8 9(1 2S 74 ■| .-,1 II I RM.i 24 29 - iKI .II l.fiM-i J4 M - IM) is 1,354 &lt;KI :{"■ Mi I.70S iki 12 1 :&gt;2 2, mis s7 IH7 17 9.533 22 [IL'J 111 J4I1 (Ml 's AGRICULTURAL COLL1 AGRICUI.Tri M. COI.I.KCI Hurt :(■-&gt;», :!9 lo.fl &gt;1 ,,ll I UN mi :i27 :i:&gt; 17 1,512 iki Knox 7211 (HP 1.355 08 12.(174 H2 l« III. 1 S9 i n \! </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 f5.»l( Imii- 161 17 |i Total M H $J.:..Vi 30 K..IS-' in *14H 47 tH.WJ 14 COMMENTS In my report i&gt;f HMHi I suggested the advisability nf sub - tnitting to the voters an amendmeni to the constitution, providing for the investment of the permanent school fund. Such pro| amendment was submitted and the tax payers of this state are to U&gt; congratulated on the adoption of the same. Under the constitution of 1875 moneys belonging to the several permanent educational funds could 1*&gt; invested only in I'nited in&lt;l registered county bonds of this state. The amendment recently adopted permits the Board of Educa - tional Lands and Funds to purchase registered school district bonds of this state, thus giving a wider held for the safe investment of school money and at the same time affording the school districts nf Nebraska a ready market for bonds issued for educational pur- ()n page 32 of my report of 1906 will l&gt;e found a recommenda - tion that interest on principal due on lands sold be reduced from I had a bill prepared and presented to the last legis - lature providing that all moneys due on sale contracts thereafter made draw 5' ; annual interest, and that all moneys due on con - tracts issued prior thereto draw ,V , interest on and after January 1, 1908. This bill was passed and approved. It is well known that some years ago our permanent educa - tional funds suffered the extent of 1325,587.50 and these losses have not been supplied as provided by our constitution. &lt; &gt;n page 32 of my last report, referern ade to tin's matter and at I \ 1 &gt; 1 . 1 i^Ili 'U I.Mi \»*»I\ is. v »r 1 III'. l&gt; 1 1'-.N JN I i .M &lt; *( it 1HIH*&lt; 1 NdliMAI. *&lt;*i (M i $7H7 7fl fc&lt; .".7 $.'&gt;^1 M.1X.' ID $149 47 tH.Wl 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 II desire again to call your attention to the matter &lt;&gt;t &lt; the institutions under control of the Board of Public l.andr- Buildings Prior to the enact men 1 of a law by the lasi legislature, m ,(■(1 by these institution expended for th&lt; The law passed in 1907 provides that all money red from the sale of property belonging to the state shall be dep&lt; with the state treasurer to the credit of such institutions. II am of the opinion that all moneys received and belong! e state should he deposited with I be appropriated by each legislature to the use of the tion depositing the same and that all moneys so deposited be awn only upon voucher approved by the Hoard n\ I'uhlic I and Building it will tie n«&gt;1 iced I hat 121 Bv an examination of th' supposed railroad right oi ie made for the purchi the same. acres of the state land an If this he true, provision should 1 ime by the companies occupying At the last session of the legi lature, I had prepared and pre - :tatutes relative to right &lt;&gt;' -ented hill, repealing the present late lands and providing that all eompanie- desiring to struct a line of road over state lands lie permitted to purchase right of way. and that all lands now occupied by any compan right of way purposes he sold and deeded to the said company. I believe such a law should he enacted as it would lie onl to the state, the railroad companies and the sale or lease con DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING The recent installation of electric lights in the vault whe stored the records of Government surveys in Nebraska i improvement over the former gas illumination which had iorating effect on the leather binding of field note recoi The routine office work of th&lt; urveyor and draughi i supplying the office with such data from i- Robert H ihvet, State Surveyor </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 l&gt;e required, examination of abstracts, making i and mapfl for office use. copying field notes and pi: iiment surveys for the use of county and local surveyor Others who may apply for the same, answering corresponded g to surveys and such other work as may l&gt;e required by the ioner. All fees for work done by this department are turned, accord - ing to law. into the General Fund of the State Treasury. After 111 correspondence relating to survc ed to this de - &gt;nt. During the .hienniuin 818 letters have ban written large number of personal and telephone calls by wrv&lt; hers interested in surveys have been received and the desired ation furnished them. When the archives of the Surveyor General's office were do - ! by the Government to the State and a place provided for their safe keeping, they were dumped promiscuously into the State House; the contents of the boxes were covered with dust and the ■deuce and other loose papers not hound or securely tied packages were scattered about, many of them finding their into different receptacles, some into the storage rooms in the tnent and a few into the scrap pile. In the winter of 1903 as draughtsman in this office. I the labor of collecting these valuable pap&lt; tting and arrang - ording to their subjects. This department has con - tinued the work and during the biennium has placed upon the shelves eight large volumes of the correspondence of the Commis - r of the General Land Office. During the progress of the work. evident re in the l&gt;eginning of the surveys g of the fee hook lor the last hienniuin there was rec&lt; [he following towit : I surveying 1138.00 : opies of field notes, etc 14 (M) Total - 1152 (Ml ived for surveying during the hienniuni (795.00 ivetl for copies of field notes, plats, etc. 1,307.25 Total 2,102 _'.-. Total receipt- $2,"2."&gt;-4 '_'."&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 &lt;it Nebraska in 18M were missing as well as a few at the eonipk irveya in 1888. After considerable correspondence with the Honorable Commissioner of the General Land Office, in an i tain copies, the Commissioner replied thai since Kansas i part of the surveying district, the correspondence pertaining to each territory was not kept in separate records, and it would be difficult to sort out the correspondence wanted and with a lii office force he could not comply with the request of this office. 1 accordingly obtained a leave of absence for -W days ami to Washington, 1). ('.. in February last and spent a number of in searching out and e piling an index or digest ot all letters and excerpts of letters pertaining to Nebraska surveys from the I the Act creating the new surveying district, until Se] consisting of 4tt letters, for the completion of the first vol and 3 letters at the dosing of the Surveyor General's office and the receipt for the Archives by Commissioner John Steen. for the pletion of the tenth and last volume. Certified copies of letters have been received and '.lie two volumes are now in the bindery. The work of collecting and arranging the correspondence of the Deputy Surveyors with the Surveyor (ieneral has been going i time could be spared. This correspondence consists ol explana - tions and information regarding progress of surveys, repori character of the country, climatic conditions, dangers eneounfc Indian battles and depredations, sickness and deaths, etc.. and are compiled alphabetically and chronologically, indexed with classified, and a list of the names of the deputy survev. three volumes; these are nearly ready for the bindery, and placed upon the shelves will prove an invaluable storehouse -ting information to the surveyors of the state as well i &gt;rian. There are still other records which need like attention. In my last report 1 gave a brief account of the fii in Nebraska territory in ls:!7 (certified in ISIS) by the McCoy, a Baptist Indian missionary, and of the efforts made during preceding years to find the field notes of said survey, and the final discovery of a folio sheet of letter paper which cont what appeared to !*• a general report or advanced statemei survey, signed by Mr. McCoy. During my visit to the &lt;i&lt; Land Office last spring, above alluded to. 1 made search for lid </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT findi! i which ' also ilif grutifn of finding a duplicate of the folio sheel of notes signed by Mr. M tifioil copy of this survey (if the Half Breed Indian Reservation ived from the General Land Office and has been bound with the notes of .hi tu I.. Coiad's retracement and Alexander OUphanf ihlishment of McCoy's line according to the \ June 12, I s - ireh i now being made for the notes of the original survey of the Omaha Indian Reservation by Wallace lin in 1S5"). The invoice of records do not show that they ived by the Surveyor General of Nebraska from the 8ur - ieial of Kansas and- Nebraska when the Surveyor General's :l)lished at Plattsmouth in 1887. neither are they to be i in the General I-and Office or in the Bureau of Indian Affairs in Washington, I). ('. Man\ yean ago the Missouri River cut a new channel aci ■ w neck of land in Neinaha County, throwing the land in the l&gt;end thus cut off to the east side of the new channel. This ue known at ' McKi. ick's Island." On account of its new &gt;m with reference to the stream, the state of Missouri claimed iiction over the tract. The residents resisted and suit wtm l&gt;egun in the Federal Court to determine the boundary line \n-&lt; • ■ the river changed its channel by avulsion and not by gradual process of erosion, the court held the boundary line in the center of the former river bed. A survey of this line uttered, and the report of the Commission appointed to super - irvey with the field notes and map of the surve duly filed in the office of the Attorney General. Certified ve bean filed in this office, as a part of the re braska surveys and are bound with the notes of survey of the boundary line in the Missouri River between Union County. South Dakota and Dakota County. Nebraska, as adopted by the ■ f the two states in 1905 and approved by Conj During the biennium there lias been an unusual demand for tield notes; to meet this demand assistance was nect ils have been made from time to time from the regular could l&gt;e spared from the regular routine of office work, luring the next biennium, a numb </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 Inch will in inanenl an tanre to meet this increasing demand. IIKI.I) WIII1K Complaints arising from disputes between land owm ml surveyors, or between . urvevor.-. filed with the I ioner of Public Land.- and Buildings arc r» ■ the I)i of Surveying for adjustment. Many of those referred 1 by telephone, telegraph and corn the panic- interested and with the County Surveyor •na and advice. Those requiring the personal exaniii and a Burvey by the State Surveyor on file to date, are tal&gt;u according to date of execution of survey, giving the na: applicant, location, time required, and. per diem charged and the office of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buil&lt; e turned into the (leneral Fund of the state, towit: of Survey Amount K. 33 Stale of Nebraska Sec. Mi T. :i:; N. R. 7 . .54 \\ . A. Havens, Loretto, BooneCounty, I ! da\ . :C&gt; Village of St. Edward, Boone County, 6 day: K. :?o Tboe. Dutcher, Greelej \ County. •"&gt;. No. 1&lt; Geo. W. Reiter, Spaulding. Greeley County No. 17 reinstated and completed. 4 day li. No. 3( David Hoe. St. Paul. Howard County. :&gt; day. I- B&gt;. :5s W. A. Bower. Hampton. Hamilton County, co nued, :{ days 8. Xo. :«&gt; Wesley T. Hainan el al. Keith County, coin pleted. 31J daya 1 VI MO 9. No. 39 A. K. Shefflerand A K. Stow, Nuckolls ( oiint v : V • _' I I H &gt; 10. No. 40 Joseph Toman. St. Paul. Howard County. \ day K. 41 John Nuernberger, \\ isner. Cuming County 21 00 K. 42 M. N. Holcomb, Maxwell. Lincoln County, 11 13. No. 43 J. \N . Cox and W . Stickler. Keith Comity. ) day 14. No. 44 H. ('. Anderson and ('. F. Harmon. Ogalalla. Keith County, by their Attorneys. 17 da l ( </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 ttj T. Wight man. Lincoln County, &gt; day 17. No. 47 Wm. Dei t rich. Lincoln County, 11 days is Frank McFadden, Pax ton, Keith County .' 12 (Mi Bo. 49 A. D. Coy, el al, Braden, McPbi unty, 14 &lt;»tal. 132] day* S4 (Kl I hich per diem was cha COMPLAINTS ON KII.K A W A III \ c . ACTION 1. E. I), tiipuld, Wolbach, Graeley County. _'. Kini! Wegner, Grand Island, Hall County. (. I*. Murphy. Graeley, Greeley County. 4. John Frederickaen, t)enmark, Lincoln County. "&gt;. Joseph Roschynialslri, Rockville, Sherman County. - H. Hicks, et al, Callawav. Cii :ci County. 7. Iran/. Bey I, Ellwood, Gosper County. H. Kli/a M. Beardsley. Clarks, Merrick County. 9. E. K. DeVoe, Lebanon, Rcl Willow County l(t. Geo. Beveridge, Paxt-on, Keith County. 11. Fred Quadour, Indianola, l?e«l Willow Count) 13. F. D. Arnot. Mcniinan. Cherry County. 13. Thos. V&lt; m«l H. I*. Sorrensen. Denmark. Lincoln 14. Lincoln Land Company. Lincoln, by C. H. Morrill. President. 15. D. A. Hancock. Wood Lake Cherry County. 16. C. A. Lapham, Hendley, Furnai County. E own-hip M N. ElangB 7 W. ii within the limits of the old Indian Reservation and wai urveyed by John Clop and according to said survey Section Hi. contained EAll that portion of the township situated in the Ponca &lt; ■ uri River Valley was. in July 1871, resurveyed by Oj h. I . S. ! of Dakota Territory, and subdivided eighty aei i ke the Indians to make their allotments according to said sur on 18 was found to contain only r the Indian title to the unallotted lands had been exlin - ior ruled that Sections 16 ai </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 ■ ling u&gt; Mai li e survey tl tions had all l&gt;een swe by th&lt;- Missouri (excepting the 0.94 acres) indemnity lands ted in lieu thereof. The amount of land in place in Section 16 being so email, the iinient did not think it worth the while to charge off the amount and the title remained in the state. The matter being milted, the Department ruled that inasmuch a • ( i r i t had taken of the 0.94 acres although indemnity had been allowe ntire section, the fraction still belonged to the state. Having ascertained that an accretion had attached to the ion. I was instructed by the Commissioner to make of the fraction and accretion to ascertain the amount of land for the purpose of leasing the same. Accordingly in the latter part of 1(107. 1 made a survey and found about 4(1 acres of tine valley land which had not l&gt;een encroached upon by the river still in place in the Southwest quarter of the section, and about |H&lt;&gt; of accretion covered with brush and valuable cotton 1 The matter was again submitted and the Depart! its former ruling and decided that the State bavin. I indemnity for the loss of the section, the State was di\ • of its title and the land !&gt;elonged to the Public Domain. The ■ ion after admitted to homestead entry at the local land &lt; I was absent from the office six days. My personal expen ■ making the survey have been refunded but no per diem ha - received for the time spent. In 1903 a complaint was filed alleging that in the resurvi T. 30 N. H. '.U \Y. Cherry County, in 1900, over KM) acres of valuable land had been surveyed out of section ."W u an adverse claim, ami the claimant had possession of the same, although the section had leased to another party who was paying rental on the entire &gt;n. The lessee desired the state to resurvey the section original government coiners. The matter was referred to the Honorable Commissioner of the General Land Office at Washington, 1). ('.. who after considerable correspondence conceded the conten - tion of the state and promised to have a resurvey made ol section, with others, conditioned, that the State Surveyor should -•'tit the state in : aid surveys. On April 17. 1907, I went to Valentine, Cherry County, to meet Mr. X. B. Sweitzer, I*. S. Examiner of Surveys, who had been de - i by the Department to make said stirv. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 land commissioner's report . 30 \. R. 32 W. if nil Boardman k about fifty miles from Valentine. The weather was and the survey was attended with many inconvenu ami I Five original corners were found and the remainder ding to the Special Instruct ioi 1 l&gt;y the i Office. The field i: i map of said survey have d liy the proper Government Official and copie in t li i ~ nil if T. 2.'{ and 24 S. H al«&gt; to lie re lake country southeast of Alliam Evey of T. 23 X. K. 4&lt; YV. in 1901 an adverse clai 14(1 valuable bay land had been surveyed out ol of tl u. although it had lx-en leaped, and the state ing rental on the entire section. In .cciioi! '■',(&gt; T. 2-1 N. R. !i \Y. ;■ t range condition existed. A itry had been fil«&gt;(l on the 1.-2 SI ion 35 i id to another, a homestead entry on the \\ -2 S' :{| T. 2-1 N. R. -Hi \V. The entry i wtion 35 claimed tin The ent rv man. or w&lt; lion :il claimed the S. \V. comer of -aid section to !&gt;&lt;■ one mile iie corner claimed by the former perron. The result of ntirely elimii ange part in this ntryman in section ■';" |uently pure! 'ion 'A\ . and claimed to Us that there wen one a mile east of hi* S. K. corner of -ecti&lt; 'her. the corner claimed to be the 8. \\ . corner of secti iinan entry man, or the corner claimed by the first entry - i I., con, tion 35. The re.-uh \\a. that thi lay aloi ich other with a common dividing line be1 ■ction MS was by tin manipulation compli .•d. Kie District Court at Alliance had. a lew years previously. 1 that the true township corner was in the sand hills as I by the entryman in section 35. According to this c nd by measurement that R. -Hi W. would !&gt;&lt;• approxin and 8 chains in width. ■ of investigations of line- and corners in Ha: I -47. we concluded that the origii in such i </seg>
            <seg id="p041">SUR V E VI NG 41 &gt;n. The matter is now under process of investigation. ■ was absent from the office :io days excluding Sundaj ier was unusually stormy during the entire trip; thi the long distances traveled over land, caused the lot* of i Bly personal expenses were paid by the (lovernment, o charge to the state. I "lie history of complaints filed, and the fact:- gathi examinations and surveys, emphaatw the conclusion previous reports thai the principal cause of dispute f the original (iovernment corners, and by the failui surveyors to make an intelligent, thorough and exhau i to discover the evidence necessary to secure the proof. Many county purveyors deem it sufficient, if the corner be readily found, to measure off the distance stated in the field note: a the absolute length of the line and erect a c&lt; without connecting the line with other original corners, igi (hat remeasurement: seldom agree with the original ~ur- This may he illustrated by reference to in vey No. 19 of the ; 'ins list, during the month of October last. The 5th ' Meridian or line between Range? K) and 41 W. wa hip 17. Is and 19 X. in ticPheraon County. The line run in 1872 and the length of each mile as stated in the field m Ml MO chains, or a total of 1440 chains. There were AT or coiners on the line: of these :U were recovered and the length of each half mile measured; 13 miles were found to be less than 8 chains. 5 miles to be over 80.00 chains, and none to 1h&gt; ju. t sit nil chains according to my chaining. The length of T. 17 X found to lx&gt; 47s 91) chains; T. 19 X. 47X71 chain, and T. l'&gt; X. '1 chains; total 1437.53) chains, a difference of 2.48) c! It is needless to comment on the result to property owners living in the last mile of T. '20 X. had no corners been found and an u lute lengt h of NO .00 chains been given to each mile. Kail cases in making retraeementa to settle disputes, the t effort is put forth to recover the original survey as l&gt;eing y medium of insuring satisfactory results. 1 have heard of no appeal to the courts from my decision in any of the findings in any of tin ribed, nor in </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 LAND COMMISSIONER'S KKI'ORT ding the amount of office work required &lt;&gt;f the Surveyor, a great deal of time (luring the surveying » 'o making examinations and surveys for applicants and ■ ring the necessary Held notes and maps for record. N I is made to encourage filing of complaint.-, yet the increasing numlier of applications on file awaiting action thereon, a-- shown by the above list, together with the urgent appeals made to this i- an indication of the favor with which the E Attorneys inform me that the most unsatisfactory and e\ &gt;f civil (:; suits over boundary lines, and the favor with 1 the law creating the Department of Surveying is looked upon lat prod more direct, quicker and less expeo od of settling such di-pu strong argument in favor of ding for additional surveying force, in order that the increi &gt;er of applicant! may receive early attention and secure bjm HOARD OK 1TBLIC LANDS AND BULDIXCS The Board of Public Lands anil Building have made the following di position of the several appropriations made by the «gislature for the use of the various institutions under control of this board. 120,000 was appropriated for the construction of a le barn at tl fair grounds, plans and Bpeci to l&gt;e approved by this board with authority to advert] let contract and appoint superintendent of construction. After due advertisement, the board awarded contract for construc - tion on August 22, 1907. to A. ]■'.. Stephens in the amount of *!'■ and appointed &lt;!. A. Berlinghof superintendent of construction. E\n appropriation of 91,200 was made for the purpose of equip - the Capitol building with fire protection. Specifications red and bids called for. On May 11. I'M)? the board awarded let to Charles Burns in the sum of 11,189.50, leaving a bal - of $10.50 unexpended. $2,500 was appropriated for the erection of a brick addition to the main building for the Home for the Friendleas. After ad - vertising for bids, the board awarded contract to Debit) and H; 1 " * f \ m on a bast- intendn action of same. $24' </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 AIM'KOPKIATION.-- \pended ami ilic state has a good, substantial addition i &lt;■ with a balance of $1 .43 unexpended. E'he Board also purchased Lota 1. 2. 'A. »&gt;. 7 in Block 1. &gt; addition to Lincoln according to the appropriation &lt;&gt;i S2 I. (i and 7 being purchased &lt;&gt;n May 24, 1 ( .»()7. Lots ti ami 7 ind Lot 1 at 11000. On April 4. 1908 Lots _' and 3 w, 1 for *HMM). titles to same having been approved !&gt;\ nev General. An appropriation of StiO.(MM) was made for the erectioi it al building for women. 12,000 for a cottage for male pal 16,000 for store room ami employees' dormitory at the Ho for the Insane at Norfolk. After advertising for l&gt;ids. the con let to \Y. &lt;i. Merton to build all of the above mentioned build - for S77&gt;72 no on November 19, HM)7 and on December ! tine year, contract for wiring buildings was awarded to F. H. ■ ler for t2.046.0O. These buildings will not be finished I ■ the first of the coming July. The legislature made an appropriation of 115,000 to build and equip a new family cottage at the State Industrial School at Kea The Hoard directed that plan- and .specification be made and duly advertised and received bids for construction, but as bids exc&lt; the appropriation, all bids were rejected and new plans on prepared. Bids were called for under the new plan but upon reeom - atioii of Superintendent K. B. Sherman, the board d&lt; &lt; under existing conditions, it would l&gt;e justified in not consi ing the building. Mr. Sherman stated that inasmuch as then 214 inmates on December 1. 1906 and 148 on December 1. 1908. con - traction of space would be better than expansion. The B taking the same view, all bids were rejected and returned to bidders without opening. 'Ml was appropriated for t he construction of an addition (o the brick Hospital at the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home at G Inland. Nebraska. After quieting title to the land upon which, the Home is built as demanded by the legislature, the board advei for bids for the construction of a Hospital and the contraci awarded on June 2A. 1908 to John ('. Marxem in the sum of $[ ami on April 18, 1908 the L. W. I'omerene Company were aw the contract for plumbing and heating same for SI.KM). whik era Electrical Company were on April 24th awarded the trie wiring for </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 An appropriation oi S15.000 and uttir Aii appropriation oi SI.). iniii a building for office ami officers and to enlarge the laundry at the sufficient amoun Supi for a boiler a te Industrial School. Kearn ; mount of $924 and an ( i( te Penitentiary foi ■ 4.000 fro t.(MM) made for this purpi During the season of I'.mi C\ I'll and conn i to \V. S. Assenmacher. In I • n Mr. Assenniacher to fix the roof ami walls of advantage and to have the porch in of the building painted to pn ; all lpol v. This no doubt will reach 19,000. The Legislature of 1907 provided that the Home Governor's Mansion and Capitol B '&lt; sctrieity furnished from the plant ai the l'eniu and appropriated $2,000 for this purpose. Aft i built, it was found that it would it the Penitentiary, and from the various fund, appro) titution, and the Hoard of Public band i entire new system has been constructed and tlu for the Friendless, Orthopedic Hospital, Governor's M ortion of the Capitol Building are now lightei by the legislature. The Hoard awarded a contract on July 13 iv for SI. 5-!'. i ; into a contract with the Sutherland Ho v for a new engine, boiler and dynamo for s7.4o ( .t. and from Fairbanks, Morse and ( for $810. and duplicated the engine already furnished by the Brs' and Saili.i- ' H Milford, and on April 24. I ft wtm awarded to K. Rohlfs for 110.631.32 to con I &gt;n »] u*rt\ ivided by the legislature. The Sutherland Mm- Riumlry and store room at I he &lt; iirls' [ndu I rial School ai ( lei : roved the engine i id badly racked The Board &lt;&lt;i Public Land: and Buildii t ion. thought rmanent new lau iiiji with room? above sufficient to house the male empl&lt; ■ institution. Accordingly plane and specifications w Fairbanks, Morse and Compa Slltli. ffW %^ 7'"» til nt irwr i. ,1,1 fi»m tlir - • *, i «.«7 . mi ui iin ' in*; j ),i i &lt; i i i i &gt; n l lilt </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 REMARKS AND RECOMMENDATION'S appropriation for general repairs and the amounts received ill' of the old material. In order to properly take care of the patient* in the II" rippled. Ruptered and Deformed Children, an appropri: made by the legislature for thie purpose. &lt; &gt;n A ml the amounts receive* I ale of the old material. In order to properly take can the patients in I he II Childre 10 \\ a made bv t lie leeisla l' for tllir nil: J_\ 1907 a contract war awarded to Shaul and Asaenniacher i .m a ba iperintending said tmprovem* -. I'.'Oi a contract war awarded i let w [tending sa ed into with varii ling of the Hospital. On Dec. 2, 1907 a contraci was awn Elevator Company in supply this institution \\ . Elevator Compi ,n electric elevator for the sum of $3,700. The buildi im). Tin h- elevator lor tlu in splendid condition t" be used as a hospital. REMARKS AND RECOMMENDATIONS OMMKNDATIONS In the last three biennial reports &lt;&gt;f this depart mi called to the work that has been done by the Boa in called to tlu* work th &gt;en done liv the lioa ■( Public Lands and Buildings which is composed of iheComi iblic Land.- and Buildings. Secretary of H t Lands and Buildi lie Land.- and Buildi &gt;f the( mi ■ retarv and Attorney General. Each of the is. undt the head of a distinct department which nee! e officers is. undi v. the head of a distinct denai i entire attention of the officer for the conduct of his official bus I ddition to this, each legislature i a new board and im- conduct of hi u re a Idition to this, each legislature u new hoard am neone of tin- i. It imeone of the me thai tlu- coming legislature should find some w, e thai the coming lep this bu inducted without taking the entire time i of the department- for board work. INSTITUTION CASH FUNDS business conducted with &gt;ut taking the entire time e depart men 1 wort :ll SSTITUTK \ \sll FINDS Th. The last legislature passed a law relative to the cash fun egislature pa iw relative to the cash fur the different state institutions. While this law is an iniprovi the different state institutions. While this law is an improve! nvcr the old one. it should be so amended or changed as to i old one. it should Ik i mended or changed as to afl ample protection and the fullest publicity in its distribution. publicity in its distribution riBS kx \ i Fllih h Al'h There are a numl&gt;er of the state institutions that are not pro- The re are a number of the th adequate fire eecapet should Ik 1 made to place &gt;f the institutions of the ate institutions that are not vided with adequate fire • ny opinion that an ;&lt;: my opinion that an a] ne or more cylindrical fin pnation tate where needed. STATE H&lt;»l K BASEMENT The crowded condition of the Capitol building makes it i ary to use the basement of the state house for storage purp </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 I . \ N I ) f O M M I ***S M ) \ r. i{ ** lir.l I)K1 Ee rooms should Ik- cemented and the various rooms plasti :he dirt floors in the ; &gt;\ ays should lie paved with brick the stairs leading into the basement should We replaced with In appropriation should l&gt;e made to the Adjutant General suf - for him to rent a building for storage purposes which will him to properly take care of the material entrusted to his ithout monopolising the entire basement with this material idangering the property itself. WIKIM. CAPITOL I would recommend that an immediate appropriation of ficient amount to finish wiring the Capitol building lie mat: that the entire building may receive its lights from the plant at the |&gt;onitentiarv. It i.- my opinion that the cost of the wiring will not greatly exceed the cost of gas during the present m the legislature. LIGHTS FOH THE UROUNDS The Board of Public Lands and Buildings made application ty of Lincoln for a right to run a pole line from the city limits to the state house agreeing to present to the coming lature a recommendation that the state house grounds be lighted from tin- plant at the penitentiary and taken care of at the exi of the state. I l&gt;elieve t hat this should be done and would recoin - i that an adequate lighting system In- devised similar to th( I the government square, attention to be paid to the capacity of the plant at the penitentiary. I KKINU in HdVD COUNTY LESSEES I would recommend that the legislature appropriate th&gt; of $352 to be returned to the lessees of Boyd County lands v lease- ledarad null and void by the Supreme Court. This ■ v was paid into the school fund but the lessees never en into possession of the land and received no l&gt;enefit therefrom. CITT LOTS BELONGING To THE SCHOOL KIM) USED HV THE BIK- HAILKOAD HIT MIT I'AII) Kllli HV THEM Everal years ago t he Burlington Railroad Company appropri- I and 12 in Block SO, Lots ti and 7 in Block 190, in Block itS, Lot 6 in Block 170. Lots 5 and 6 in Bloet and 2 in Block 283 and Lot 6 in Block 284 by condemnation and have t&gt;een using same without making settlement </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 to '1 had this matter up several times with thi of the Burlington Railroad and they have been willing tu payment to the state for these lots ai soon as the state d&lt; the proper place to make the payment. As the law has Ween cha : ially from time to time since these proceedings of eonde tion were had, I t&gt;elieve that a law should he pawed design that the payment be made to the county treasurer as in ea sale of other school lands. I would also call attention to Lot 12. Block 32. A law should I giving the Governor through this department the to pass title to the proper person, as there is evidence on our I of a legal exchange for other lots, hut no proper order of trai been recorded. The legislature has from time to time created commi or departments for conducting state business and have desigi that the Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings should furnish with offices in the state house. The amendment to the state stitution in which four additional jud| dded to our Su] Court has earned and this amendment demands that the j become residents of the city of Lincoln, hence rooms must be i for them. How this can l&gt;e done under the present ci: a mystery yet to he solved. Appropriation can he made for finishing t he hasement for offices or by renting a huilding outside of the Capitol for so: the departments or by pasting a law doing away with some of the commissions. I l&gt;elieve that if the proper steps were taken. 0 the floors in the new historical huilding can l&gt;e given over to the department of justice and to the state library. This would fu the library with a good home in a fire proof huilding and at the time would give the space now occupied by these department the use of other departments and would furnish ample room for everyone. STATK INSTITUTIONS Cie various state institutions which are under charge of the of Public Lands and Buildings are in splendid condition. It t be necessary during the next hiennium for a large appropri - ation for improvements and repairs from the fact that it hat t policy of the present hoard in making improvements to make i of a permanent character as far as possible. OFFICE ROOMS IN CAPITOL Hl"ll.l&gt;l\&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 ort that there will I*- few deficiencies \ of the stale institutions, li baa been the intention of the Mperintendeatfl and the hoard to properly conduct the institutions without exceeding the appropriations u made by the legislature. Iv express my appreciation of the many court* ?ceived from time to time from the superintendents and other ! of the various state institution and thank each and them for their hearty co-operation in conducting the bu which has been entrusted to them. Ely thank.- to my associate -late off eir uniform kindness and courteous treatment, and I that my acquaintance with them both in a business anil social ill lx" remembered among the many plea-ant recollection icial life. Bo my deputy. Mr. .1. M. Shivelv. 1 owe a del&gt;i of gratitude for nseientious devotion to all business with which he ha - ted, and for the very able manner in which he has performed duty required of him. 1 can heartily commend him to the of the state for able and efficient service. ED wish t&lt; - my heartfelt thank&gt; to the office : idually and collectively, for their uniform courtesy toward me for the efficient manner in which they have performed their ■ in attending to the work that has been given them 1.' [K" that their future life may l&gt;e as plea, ant :i. our relations l&gt;een during the time we have been associated together, and trd mav lie theirs as they so richlv deserve. I^"itli this I close eight years of service in this department, l which time much effort has I tern put forth to adopt proper and to systematize the work of the department, and it me pleasure to report to the people of the state that prog ■en made in the manner of attending to state busine tainly would l&gt;e ungrateful did I not express my apprecia - to (he people in general for the many kind words I have re - ■1 and help they have given me while conducting the but h devolves upon this department under the law. Very respectfully. H. M. Eaton, ' iblic Lands and Buildi • Ll'SION </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>