<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00057.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00057.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1923-1924 VOLUME 4</title>
               <date value="1923-1924">1923-1924</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1923-1924 VOLUME 4 .:•:: :^V-. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY 857566 A ASTOR. LENOX AND TILDEN FOUNDATIONS R 1936 L </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS VOLUME 4 1. Board of Control, Biennial Report, 1920-1923. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">STATE OF NEBRASKA Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Girls' Training School GENEVA, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions For the Period Ending June 30, 1923 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">♦ </seg>
            <seg id="p006">3 FOREWORD To His Excellency, the Governor : The Board of Control herewith transmits the Fifth Biennial Report of the State Institutions of Nebraska for the period ending June 30, 1923. The biennium formerly ended on November 30 of each even-numbered year, but this date was changed by an act of the legislature, so that this report really covers a period of thirty-one months from December 1, 1920, to June 30, 1923. During the period, no change has occurred in the personnel of the Board, but several changes have been made in the chief officers of institutions. Dr. Beverly A. Finkle, superintendent of the Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska, resigned to enter private practice, and was succeeded on August 23, 1921, by Dr. J. H. Matthai. Miss Amy V. Stevens, who had been superintendent of the Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Nebraska, for a number of years, resigned on July 5, 1922, being succeeded by her sister, Miss Nellie Stevens. The latter served until February 19, 1923, when her resignation was received, and Miss Lena Driever was appointed to the position. We call attention with pride and pleasure to the fact that the report shows the institutions to have gone through the bien - nium without incurring any deficiencies; although the cost of living, and consequently the cost of supporting the state's depen - dents, has certainly not decreased since the appropriations were made for the biennium. Some improvements of a pcrmament character have been made at the various institutions during the period covered by this report. A hospital building, bakery and scullery have been erected at the Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded, Beatrice, Nebraska ; a cottage for girls at the Girls' Training School, Geneva, Nebraska; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">4 Nebraska ; a gymnasium building at the State Industrial School, Kearney, Nebraska; a hospital building at the Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney, Nebraska ; a farm house and a barn at the Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a warehouse at the State Penitentiary, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska; a kitchen building at the Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk, Nebraska ; a main building at the State Reformatory for Women, York, Nebraska. These buildings were badly needed, and they will have to be -followed by others in the very near 'future if our wards are to be properly, efficiently and economically cared for. The legislature just past made provision for two or three buildings, but failed to see the necessity for several others that were urgently requested. Brief mention was made in the last report of the establishment of the Reformatory for Men at Lincoln, but the importance of the institution calls, we believe, for rather more extended notice. This institution was established as a result, primarily, of a wide recognition of the need of segregating young first-term offenders from more mature criminals. The legislature of 1921 authorized the establishment, therefore, of such an institution, making an initial approproation of $300,000. Of this sum the Board ex - pended $37,500 for 10 acres and a brick building known as the Hayward Military Academy, later buying about 152 acres of contiguous land for the sum of $49,531.25. This land is used for farming, stock raising, dairying, and intensive gardening. Various trades are taught such as tailoring, shoe repairing, carpentry and joinery, brick laying, electricity, automobile repairing, launder - ing, engineering, firing, and barbering. The manual labor about the institution is, of course, performed by the inmates, of which there are at this date 189. Mr. A. W. Miller, the superintendent, is doing much constructive work with the young men committed to his charge, and we believe the institution is amply justifying itself. The difficulty of employing the penitentiary inmates at suitable labor that does not conflict too much with the prerogatives of the free workers of our state, has been pretty well overcome. The state still operates the fibre furniture factory which has been at the prison for some years, and has also established relations with the Oberman Company by which shirts are made and disposed of with a minimum of competition with free labor. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">5 INMATE POPULATION There are seventeen institutions under the control of the Board, and at this time (July 1, l°-23) the inmate population is 5917, as compared with an average of 4980 for the biennium ending in 1921, and 4907 for the biennium just prior to that. The following table will be found of interest as showing the population of the different institutions during the past two biennia : Av. pop. Av. pop. Largest biennium biennium number Institutions ending ending at any one (With "Key" Letters) June 30, June 30, time past 1921 1923 two years A— Institution for Feeble-Mindcd 607 725 756 B— Girls' Training School 106 173 189 C— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 409 353 412 D— Hastings State Hospital 1152 1193 1219 E— State Industrial School 217 214 241 F— Hospital for Tuberculous 78 102 106 G— Lincoln State Hospital 837 971 995 H— Orthopedic Hospital 64 . 88 102 J — State Penitentiary 363 586 596 K— Nebraska Industrial Home...' 73 86 99 L— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 148 162 195 M— School for the Blind (a) 47 53 57 N— Norfolk State Hospital 646 733 768 P— School for the Deaf (a) 171 178 187 R— State Reformatory for Women 9 18 28 S — Home for Dependent Children 53 91 107 T — State Reformatory for Men (b) '. Not open 150 192 Total 4980 5876 6249 (a) 19 months (1921, 9 months school; 1922, 10 months school.) (b) Open only 21 months; started October 1, 1921. EXPENDITURES The following table reveals the expenditures at the various institutions for the past biennium, the item of salaries and wages being included under Maintenance in all instances excepting the first. Capital outlay represents permanent improvements to the realty and equipment. Board of Control, Lincoln- Maintenance $ 5,151.87 Salaries and Wages 42,529.53 $ 47,681.40 Institution for Feeble- Minded, Beatrice — Maintenance 253,843.43 Cash - 27,524.49 Capital Outlay 93,899.95 375,267.87 Girls' Training School, Geneva — Maintenance 111,808.47 Cash 4,964.20 Capital Outlay _ 42,000.00 158,772.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">6 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett— Maintenance 176,14828 Cash 67,846.61 Capital Outlay 115,000.00 358,994.89 Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside — Maintenance 501,184.46 Cash _ 99,853.78 Capital Outlay 38,850.25 639,888.49 State Industrial School, Kearney — Maintenance 161,200.06 Cash 26,345.72 Capital Outlay 43,440.24 230,986.02 Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney — Maintenance 106,076.45 Cash 30,794.13 Capital Outlay 117,826.18 254,696.76 Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 375,095,50 Cash 89,072.43 Capital Outlay 74,803.84 538,971.77 Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 122,286.28 Cash _ _ : 25,627.53 Capital Outlay 4,490,17 152,403.98 State Penitentiary, Lincoln — Maintenance 229,205.92 Cash 161,633.02 Capital Outlay 390,838.94 Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford — Maintenance 61 ,306.38 Cash 2,578.26 Capital Outlay _ 63,884,64 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford — Maintenance 94,406.99 Cash _ _ 29,700.29 Capital Outlay 15,934.10 140,041.38 School for the Blind, Nebraska City — Maintenance 57,82522 Cash 3,989.06 Capital Outlay...- 3,952.01 65.76629 Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk- Maintenance 321.060.71 Cash 50,535.76 Capital Outlay _ 59,999.01 431,595.48 School for the Deaf, Omaha — Maintenance „ 137,695.55 Cash _ 16,819.16 Capital Outlay. 4,500.00 159,014.71 State Reformatory for Women, York — Maintenance 28,489.38 Cash 2,733.39 Capital Outlay 46,996.15 78218.92 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">7 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln — Grand Total. 4,538,783.65 At its various institutions the state owns something over 4000 acres of land, of which in excess of 3500 are in farm and garden. About 800 acres are rented in addition. Details of operation are given in the reports from the several superintendents which are appended hereto. The health of the inmate population has been generally good during the past biennium. We are pleased to be able to report that no epidemic has broken out at any of the institutions, and our medical men have been able to cope with such sporadic cases of contagious disease as have appeared. In conclusion we wish to express our appreciation of the efforts of the officers and employees of the various institutions in striving to bring about a betterment of the living conditions of the wards under their care. We wish also to thank the Governor for his manifestations of interest and for his assistance in the work of this department, and we trust that he will continue his efforts to help us provide better means of caring for the wards of the state. Board of Control, KATHERINE F. WORLEY, Chairman, A. E. ALLYN, L. C. OBERLIES. Attest : E. B. FAIRFIELD, Secretary. Maintenance Cash : Capital Outlay 65,026.59 7,584.94 72,611.53 itate Reformatory for Men, Lincoln — Maintenance Cash Capital Outlay 72,188.46 6,959.45 300,000.00 379,147.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">8 AVERAGE DAILY POPULATION STATE INSTITUTIONS OF TOTAL POPULATION 5,876 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">9 EXPENDITURES FOR 1921-1922 SALARIES and WAGES I£M2 .276.94 OPERATION and MAINTENANCE FURNITURE and EQUIPMENT NEW BUILDINGS LAND 2,Z72,H65.H6 I96.093.9M 2,Z72,H65.H6 NEW BUILDINGS 6O3.6H9.60 LAND H8.7M8.O8 FIXED CHARGES and STATE AID 6,848.53 PERMANENT IMP TO BUILDINGS and GROUNDS 1 1 1 ,02570 TOTAL 4,491,102.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">10 INCOME FOR 1921-1922 STATE FUNOS CASH FUNDS FEDERAL FUNDS TRUST FUNDS 3,841,318.13 598,304.90 66,960.00 48,100.56 4,554,713.59 TOTAL • unexpended balance of cash , federal and trust fund (clothing fund,institute. for feebleminded) rehppropriateo </seg>
            <seg id="p014">11 (a) Opened October I, 1921. 21 months. [TURKS, STA' PE INSTITUTIONS July 1, 1 11 to June 30, I 1 &gt;23 Salaries and Wages Operation and Maintenance Furniture and Equipment Permanent Improvements to Bldgs. and Grounds New Buildings Land Fixed and State Aid Charges Total for Biennium Per Cent institution for Feeble-Minded. ... jirls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett..... Hastings State Hospital state Industrial School hospital for Tuberculous -incoln State Hospital Drthopedic Hospital . State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home. soldiers' Home, Milford school for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital school for the Deaf state Reformatory for Women.... jlome for Dependent Children. state Reformatory for Men (a) I 89,737.78 31,660.01 77,410,19 226,534.52 60,739.65 4528120 178,107.10 56,464.88 93,39320 19,294.61 35,009.08 32,444.05 137^4138 77242.53 9,137.15 19,53925 52,439.86 $ 186,411.64 82,797.68 155,198.27 351,306.24 120,474.65 87,490.63 269,172.04 89,805.58 288,86020 42,879,03 88,144.78 28,007.41 229,413.66 74,549.12 19,058.85 49,977.47 108,91821 $ 25,232.79 9,782.66 8,110.35 15,447.16 10,56822 16,452.47 16.898.41 4,786.04 4,309.18 520.59 5,468.85 676.87 38,443.00 7223.06 3,470.00 1,003.35 27,700.94 $236.00 16.08 150.50 8,557.31 10.72 2,124.19 28,624.45 1,347.48 3,776.36 1,165.66 10,552.41 685.95 3,634.66 $72,778.39 34,512.84 118,115.58 37,872.07 39,192.78 103,348.27 45,077.86 ........ ..--..........„„.,_. $ 871,27 3.40 10.00 171.19 i;09L91 "" 500.00 24.75 19.00 3,952.01 200.00 $ 375,267,87 158,772.67 358,994.89 639,888.49 230,986.02 254,696.76 538,971.77 152,403.98 390,838,94 63384.64 140,041.38 65,76629 431,595.48 139,01471 78,218.92 72,611.53 379,147.91 8.3 3.5 8.0 14.2 5.1 5.7 12.0 3.4 8.7 1.4 3.1 1.4 10.0 3.5 1.7 1.6 8.4 84726 ' '22,06228"" 7,500.00 2,091.46 50,552.47 39i052;92" _ '90i789i35"" 48,747"08 ' Total $1,242276.94 $2272,465.46 $196,093.94 $121,025.70 $603,649.60 $48,747.08 $6,843.53 $4,491,102.25 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">12 POPULATION AND PER CAPITA REPORT OF STATS INSTITUTIONS July 1, 1921, to June 30, 1923 Number of Inmates June 30, 1923 Average number Inmates during Biennium Number of employees June 30, 1923. Average number employees during Biennium Average number Inmates to each employee Average per Capita Cost for Biennium Average per Capita Cost per month Average amount Pay Roll per month Institution for Feeble-Minded Girls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home _... Soldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the Blind (a).. Norfolk State Hospital Nebraska School for the Deaf (a)- State Reformatory for Women. Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men (b) 747 183 301 1200 207 103 981 93 579 63 154 53 767 187 25 87 187 725 173 353 1,193 214 102 971 88 586 86 162 53 733 178 18 91 150 66 20 72 160 40 36 132 49 55 11 32 24 90 49 7 14 26 61 19 62 158 38 35 131 48 53 11 31 24 88 48 6 13 25 12 9 6 7 5 3 7 2 1! 8 S 2 8 4 3 7 6 $ 380.89 661.60 659.00 48427 846.80 1,301.68 460.63 1,662.16 652.31 722.95 76020 1,140.59 501.03 852.76 1,566.44 763.92 1,075.72 $ 15.87 27.57 27.46 20.18 3528 5423 19.19 6925 27.18 30.12 31.67 47.52 20.87 35.53 65.27 31.83 51.22 $ 3,562.47 1,319.17 3,225.42 9,438.94 2,530.82 1,886.72 7,421.13 2,352.70 3,891.47 803.94 1,458.71 1,351.84 5,743.41 3,218.44 380.01 814.14 2,497.13 Total 5,917 5376 — ■*•. ...... 851 $ 598.15 $24.92 $51,896.46 (a) Average during school year. (b) Opem :d October 1, 1921—21 months. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">13 AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOB FIRST TIME 'eri( Endin; June 30, 1923 Under 5 years 5 to 9 yrs. inc. 10 to 14 yrs. inc. 15 to 17 yrs, inc. 18 to 24 yrs. inc. 25 to 34 yrs, inc. 35 to 44 yrs. inc. 45 to 49 yrs. inc. 50 to 59 yrs. inc. 60 to 69 yrs, inc. 70 to 79 yrs. inc. 80 to 90 yrs. inc. Over 90 years Unascer- tained Total institution for Feeble-Minded... jirls' Training School _ Soldiers' Home, Burkett -Jastings State Hospital.................... State Industrial School hospital for Tuberculous Jncoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital.... _ state Penitentiary.. _... .... Nebraska Industrial Home. Soldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the Blind. Norfolk State Hospital „ Nebraska School for the Deaf State Reformatory for Women iome for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men 15 6 67 67 17 9 ido 70 28 65 14 89 2 38 134 13 204 18 17 57 13 59 33 33 41 60 54 41 37 31 11 112 63 185 17 223 6 80 28 135 10 61 6 i 36 16 50 3 18 ! 9 59 12 70 14 16 58 8 43 3 79 61 31 30 15 2 3 1 1 — 246 472 333 229 586 384 369 92 125 21 344 35 62 238 241 7 7 1 4 3 12 2 8 6 15 4 27 1 39 "'" 3 6 ■■■ 66 "»" 4 ... 2 26 80 74 36 41 38 34 i 121 67 44 6 5 3 i 180 46 ... Total.. 211 293 324 599 581 743 399 172 212 181 271 76 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">14 T &lt; OP1 CHOSE ADI FIRST TIME Bie: iinium Rndin; June 30. 1ft I. S^ Girt.' tlntng School Soldiers tad Skuas' Hob* Barkett HMtin«» State H(MpiUl State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers and Sailors' Home Mllford Nebraska School tor the Blind Norfolk State Hospital Nebraska School (or the Deaf Reformatory lor Women Home for Dependent Children Reformatory (or Men Total AHRIUI Austria Bohemia Bulgaria Canada I China . Ciecho-Slovakia Denmark , Fjicland Finland France Germany Greece Holland Hungary Ireland .. .......... ™..- Italy „ japan ................. - Macedonia ... Mexico Moravia ........ Nebraska Netherlands Norway Poland Russia « - -« Saxony - Scotland _ Seria Servia .._. _ Sic ili a „. „ Spain : Sweden - . Switzerland ... Turkey _ _ U. S. other than Nebraska. Unknown Other Countries __ _.. _.„__ "~2 „. ~~2~ ___... _.. . „ 3 • -5 2 ~7 1 7 6 1 19 1 _. ■ ... ~1 "' 1 1 "i _ ....._.._. 1 1 _ _. . '4 1 -i i _ ■ 1 1 119 1 7 12 17 8 6 2 """32" 1 n ~ 4 3 i ... """" i - - I 2 ' 2 1 3 2 1 3 1 i 11 ........................ I, 1 2 I • i 2 i 2 i .... i 14 ' V 3 4 5 1 2 27 _ i 3 2 ' i" i ~~ , 1 " i i 2 "i i 7 20 12 3 28 1 18 24 28 3 5 95 7 1 4 21 4 6 1 22 1 1929 1 4 14 30 8 1 2 1 2 44 a i 1564 124 30 209 ■"" 98 ' ~T1 Ts7" 1$ 26T 339 74 66 i' 12 103 26 30 232 72 2 3 8 1 2 1 3 10 2 1 2 1 2 5 1 "' i 4 I _ _ . I T _. « 2 i " I _ - 1 _ n i i •••- — _ 2 9 2 13 2 T i l '. i~3 1 _ _ i _ 256 5 _ _ 32 56 4 119 205 26 137 " 76 209 42 4 42 " '" 20 1 116 8 129" 9 "29"" s 1 — ■ 116 45 _ .... 472 333 229 384 360 " 92 21 .' 26 34T 62 238 4074 135 586 125 35 241 Total 246 162 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">15 CLASSIFICATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIKST TIME Biennium Ending June 30, 1923. County Minded QirU' Training School Soldiers' andSailora' Horn* Burkett Hut— fs State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital far Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic State Hospital Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldier*' and Sailors' Home Ifilford Nebraska School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital Nebraska School for the Deaf Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children Reformatory tor lien Total 8 1 I I 10 « 5 1 8 3 1 9 3 2 2 I- 1 5 97 35 1 2 2 26 20 27 19 85 Jl 38 46 38 14 19 51 3k 19 2C 74 23 26 46 8 13 58 810 9 36 27 14 27 110 7 9 5 1 12 112 39 22 4 18 31 5 22 29 11 30 14 8 12 29 726 46 3 37 7 19 1 29 21 43 33 49 20 16 22 20 40 12 39 68 8 38 11 39 44 53 28 27 17 32 16 25 1 43 19 16 19 A __ a 2 '." 20 L Arthur Banner fflawtf Box Batte _ZZ__1_! Boyd Brown Buffalo Burt — — Butler ~ Cass Cesar 1 n : ... h™ " ... i Z _ _..... „ ■■ i .". 3 2 4 1 5 3 7 4 2 1 1 4 1 " 1 ... 4 3 4 1 3 5 6 1 4 1 6 9 2 1 2 1 6 2 6 1 2 13 125 ~""i i " 1 8 1 7 12 3 9 3 4 I t-L .. 1 12 1 i Z 9 3 2 1 1 . 1 3 1 5 2 1 1 2 3 1 2 1 3 i " l i i 1 2 " 9 _, "3 2 _ 4" _ 2 «—- 1 25 ■•"- 5—L 4 - ,,. » 1 ." 3 i i i 2 1 1 S 2 2 S 10 7 2 2 3 1 2 1 6 1 _ _ 16 1 6 1 4 " 4 i i Cherry 2 4 2 2 1 16 2 4 2 „ 1 r --- 9 16 4" 3 2 1 2 i I 4 2 i ".. 6 2 ". - • .. ColLx Canine Cutter Dakota Dawes Dawson Deuel Dixon Dodge Douglas . . ii . Dundy Fillmore Franklin _.~ Frontier Furnas Gage Garden Garfield Gosper Grant Greeley _™ Hall Hamilton Harlan _J Hayes &lt; Hitchcock ..._. Hoh - Howard .._..._._»..._...._ Jefferson Johnson . , Kearney , Keith Keya Paha Kimball Knox ,,, n , Lancaster X_ linCOlU ■ ■■^■■^■■■■■■■■■■■T-T-TrTT- - ifBfaon ' McPherson Nebraska industrial Home Morrill . Nance •..._._._ Nemaha Nuckolls Otoe _ Pawnee ~. - Perkins Phelps Pierce ~ Platte PoUc Red Willow - Richardson Saline 3Z_____T_-_-____._ Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff Sheridan Sherman Siota Stanton Thayer Thomas Thurston .................................. Unknown — . . .«— Valley Washington Wayne Webster Wheeler Other States York 1 2 2 4 — — _ . 2 1 14 3 4 __ 4 '"" 6 is ".. i 2 l l i' .... __ . 3 3 ~ 1 " ' 4 2 2 4 1 2 12 3 2 5 __ . ™ i6 4 i i 10 1 2 32 "2 44 2 1 . 2" - 6 . 5 4 17 13 5 9 7 109 1 2 .. 4 68 'is 211 2 2 6 1 3 5 2 1 8 8 1 - 27 " i 5 5 1 76 i l 7 i "9 1 6 68 4 ' 3 rr 1 1 2 2 5 1 1 1 1 3 i 3 ~ '. 1 -' 2 " " 1 'I 1 2 7 1 2 h— ' 1 4 i" "2 1 1 2 i - 12 "3 i 1 „ "~2 - 56 1 1 1 1 2 8 2 4 3 1 4 ■ _ . ._ i f — . _ .. . r : . L L „ . ' ~" """ r • 3 1 2 2 1 ' it 1 . I. .. 32 ■■■■■ 5 S 25 12 10 2 5 6 3 3 . .... 5 2 2 . ■ 3 ' 3 11 5 1 1 3 5 i l „_____ 8 3 1 . „.. i , 2 1 " 3 « 2 8 2 4 1 2 2 1 ■ ~ L _ "'" ' _____ 1 " • . L I 3 '. 1 . 1 3 1 4 1 2 ~ '. : r .. 1 1 3 2 ... ■ ■■ • 18 I "" "8 11 1 3 2 2 2 . 1 '.'. 2 ! 1 " I 2 1 2 1 1 1 1 62 3 2 4 1 1 3 6 ! 2 1 i" " . . i 2 ~ T"I I— 1 ; if 4 7 ■ - i ■ r ■ 1 1 4 24 5 2 ' 1 L 1 2 1 ! ~" 2~ 2 3 25 3 I " 145" 1 1 1 214 1 3 1 12 14 1 1 16 2 1 • • - 38 ' 1 "~ ' 2 ""i"6 2 2~ i ! is ■ io2 ; 1 '"" 14 9 49" 3 3 4 1 • i ... 2 4 1 3 ! 1 1 2 3 4 3 4 2 r. " 2 . 4 L • •h- . : i" 3 3 1 2 - ~~ i [ T L .. A 8 ■ I "i _ _ i ■-■ . — - 7™ 1 ■■ ■•■ ■ :. i -••• ■ ■ - 4 3 2 7 1 6 1 4 1 7 3 1 2 2 1 _ .._ i 6 i "• i 2 8 2 3 _. . . _ . — i 20 1 1 2 1 3 1 5 1 4 3 1 1 15 18 9 1 1 1 6 1 i i i 2 i . ; ' 5" . " L ... t 3 „ 8 .. 2 1 2 1 ; i i 2 2 ; i '. 2 2 ri 1 _ , : U FT -" 1 i'd 10 ■ ■■■■" __, i ™" 3 12 _l 1 9 14 1 _ „ .. "■■■ 2 5 1 5 "T 6 3 l 1 B 4 3 2 5 2 ____ .' i ■ H ■ ~ J 5 15 1 1 1 "3 __ ...._ „ I 3 i 17 6 19 ' "4 .. 2 ; ~ i .. i i » :; i •- . _ _. "tTl I "~ 3 " 3""" 5 _ _. .... .„ " i a 1 3 3 1 4 1 7 1 4 6 1 7 3 2 4 . 2 1 2 ". s 3 1 ~ ■ 6 11 7 8 5 1 2 1 2 _. „ ._....„ 6 '. 8 _ . _ I " 2 16" _ 2 ... 2 2 .. I 6 _ _._ I i 4 i 2 2 " i i 3 2 1 .'. "2 1 — — .. 2 1 _. _j| 2 6 _ i " ; * ~ 2 2 4 * " I j __ I ii~ i ... _______ ±f±r u 1 ~ _ 7 ""2 2 S I 2 2 1 1 1 _ ... J _ " i " i i 2 v&lt; 2. ' 2 ... 2 " I * ... 2 ~ 5 10 . L r T" 1 1 1 _ 11 . .. 1 13 ..... .. I .. i " .. i ~ '"'" ■ ~ ______ "a .... " 1 -•-"ig—- "I i ""I .. _ ,_i „. 55 ... I Total 162 135 472 229 384 125 35 241 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">• </seg>
            <seg id="p020">17 GIRLS' TRAINING SCHOOL Geneva, Nebraska MISS LENA E. WARD MISS SUDE B. WARD MRS. OLIVE JOHNSTON J. BIXBY Miscellaneous Statement Girls' and Bovs" Industrial School Founded 1879-1891 Established a's Girls' Industrial School 1891 Number of Employees June 30, 1923... 20 Number of Inmates June 30, 1923 183 Highest Number of Inmates during Biennium 189 Per Capita Cost per month $ 27.57 Number of Acres 70 Number of Acres under cultivation 62 Value of Land and Buildings $ 257,000.00 Principal Industries — dairy, gardening, canning of fruits and vegetables and sewing. Visiting Days — Every day except Sundays and Holidays, 8 :30 A. M. to 11 :30 A. M.. and 1 :30 P. M. to 4:30 P. M. Admission to the school is by commitment by court of compe - tent jurisdiction, and girls are required to remain until they are 21 years old, unless sooner released by parole or otherwise. </seg>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022">19 To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska : It is with no small degree of pleasure that we review the work of the past two years. Although we have been somewhat handi - capped on account of insufficient means and lack of room, yet a great deal has been accomplished and these have been years of prosperity and progress. One of the things for which we feel most grateful and which we know is a step in the right direction is the beginning of the Cottage System. Nebraska was one of the few states whose school was on the old congregate plan, but we now have almost completed our first modern cottage. This cottage is of the old colonial type with plenty of windows, a large living room, with fire place and built-in book cases. This room is furnished with everything to give it the appearance and atmosphere of a real home. There is also a sewing-room, laundry, dining-room and well equipped kitchen. Each girl has her own room, provided with a good bed, rocker and dresser. To many it is the first taste of real comforts and home life. The occupants of this cottage will be chosen from our best girls, who have mani - fested a real desire to make the most of the opportunities which the state is giving them. They chose the name of Fanny Crosby for this cottage and they will be known as Crosby girls. Before entering this cottage a girl must read the life of Fanny Crosby and learn for what she stood, and take the following pledge: "I pledge my loyalty to the Girls' Training School. I promise to be worthy of the honor and responsibility given me in electing me a Crosby sister. I will perform my duties to the best of my ability. I promise to do all in my power to uphold the Ideals for which the School stands." The day will begin and close by singing one of Fanny Crosby's hymns. Could the tax payers of Nebraska realize the interest and appreciation the girls have manifested in this cottage, they would feel well repaid for the money spent. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">20 Religious Training Sifnday mornings at eight o'clock the girls pass to the audi - torium where one hour is spent in the study of the International Sunday School lesson. At three in the afternoon one of the minis - ters from Geneva speaks to the girls, and at seven Christian Endeavor meetings are held in the different families. A leader is chosen from the girls and some very interesting meetings are held. The girls all take an active part. Last winter Professor Hendrickson of McPherson, Kansas, offered an illustrated copy of the Sermon on the Mount to every girl who would learn the entire Sermon, and one hundred eighty - rive girls signified their desire to do so. Of this number one hundred thirty-three learned it so well they could give it almost without mistake. Professor Hendrickson was so pleased with this that he gave each girl a copy of the Xew Testament. This is highly prized by each girl who received one. School Work One teacher was added to our force last year. This was a great help as she handled the lower grades, giving the other two teachers the sixth, seventh and eighth grades. In these grades we had one hundred girls, forty-eight being in the eighth grade, and not one in this grade failed to pass the county examination. One girl tied with the highest grade made in the county. Next year we hope to add another teacher, which will enable us to do some ninth and tenth grade work. The grades of the girls on parole attending school averaged from 92.5 to 97. Music We have an instructor who teaches piano and voice. There is no influence so effective in uniting the spirit of the girls as music. As they unite in song so they unite in thought. Three nights out of each week the girls gather in the auditorium and one hour is spent in singing good songs. Each night, after roll call, and the diffi - culties of the day have been straightened out, fifteen minutes are spent in singing in the different families before they retire. It is our aim never to put a girl to bed in an unhappy spirit, and nothing will take the place of singing in inducing the right frame of mind. Industrial Training We keep before us constantly the fact that in a very few years many of these girls will be in homes of their own and become </seg>
            <seg id="p024">21 mothers of the coming generation. With this thought uppermost in our minds, we endeavor to train them for this responsibility. Everything that goes to make a well equipped house-keeper and home-maker is taught. The girls not only get the theory of all this work, hut the actual experience of planning and doing the work. Large quantities of fruit and vegetables are canned each year. The girls are always enthusiastic over this work. It never seems to grow old and each year they try to excel the class of the year before. Their best single day's work last year was canning 1234 cans of corn. The State University Extension Department has been a help to us. They send a representative to give us lectures and demonstrations whenever it is possible to do so. Work and Recreation All the outside work is done by the girls. They prepare the seed beds, and do the planting, cultivating and harvesting of all the crops. We have the reputation of having the fewest weeds and the best-kept barn lots in the neighborhood. During the past year, we have been able to do considerable fencing which has added a great deal to the appearance of the grounds, and has made it possible for us to better care for our poultry and stock. The girls helped with the building of the fences, digging the post holes and helping to set the posts. We have been fortunate in having a splendid woman to supervise such work. The school has a herd of Holstein cows, a fine drove of Hampshire hogs, and a flock of chickens, turkeys, ducks, geese and guineas. Raising and caring for all' these is a real pleasure for the girls. It is not "ail work and no play" at the school. There is a time for work and a time for play. Special picnics, wienie roasts, watermelon feeds, ball games and all kinds of races and games are enthusiastically entered into by the girls. The observance of all holidays is an established custom. Needs Our greatest need at this time is a parole officer, — someone who could devote her time to looking after the girls on parole Almost every girl leaving the school goes with higher ideals in life and fully determined to make good, but unless she has a proper place to go, with good environment and someone to advise and </seg>
            <seg id="p025">22 4 encourage her, she often drifts back into her former life. If we had a good woman, someone with experience in dealing with the unprivileged girl and who understands her and her problems, we feel sure that very few girls would fail to make good. In conclusion, to all who have in any way contributed to the success of our work, we desire to express our appreciation. To my co-workers, who have been loyal and faithful and have labored so willingly, I am most grateful. And to the members of the Board, I desire to express my deepest gratitude for kindness, wise counsel and loyal support at all times. Respectfully submitted, LENA E. WARD, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p026">23 Total 162 TABLE IV— CAUSE FOR ADMISSION Delinquent Unclassified Immoral Incorrigible Forgery Dependent and neglected _. Stealing 0 126 8 9 3 14 2 Total _ 162 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Ten and under twelve 2 13 Twelve ;:nd under fourteen 24 1 25 Fourteen and under sixteen , 82 5 87 Sixteen and under eighteen i 42 5 47 Total 150 12 162 TABLE III— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED Third grade I 0 Fourth grade 8 Fifth grade 14 Sixth grade _ 25 Seventh grade 25 Eighth grade 43 Ninth grade 17 Tenth grade 21 Eleventh grade 6 Twelfth grade 3 Present at beginning of period.. Absent on parok Admitted for first time I 143 28 162 Total 333 Discharged Absent on parole Present at clo.^e of period 84 59 190 Total 333 TABLE II— AGE AND COLOR OF THOSE ADMITTED Age \Y. C, T. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">24 TABLE V— PAROLE STATISTICS Number on parole July 1, 1921 28 Number paroled from July 1, 1921-22 ! 46 Number paroled from July 1, 1922-23 j 58 Number discharged 64 Number returned i 9 Number on parole July 1, 1923 j 59 TABLE VI— AGE AT DEATH OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED Age at death of father : Under ten years ; 5 Ten and under fifteen : 13 Fifteen and over j 11 Unknown 4 Age at death of mother : Under ten years J 17 Ten and under fifteen 7 Fifteen and over 2 Unknown 4 Total I 63 TABLE VII— COUNTIES FROM WHICH GIRLS WERE ADMITTED TABLE VIII— NATIVITY OP THOSE ADMITTED Nebraska I 98 Other States than Nebraska ' 56 Foreign 4 Unknown '. 4 Total 162 Adams Antelope Buffalo Boyd Burt Cedar Cass Cheyenne Dodge Douglas Uundy Furnas Fillmorc Gage Hall Hamilton Kearney Kimball 6 3 1 2 2 4 1 2 44 2 3 1 1 1 1 1 1 Keya Paha Lancaster Lincoln Morrill Phelps Platte Richardson Red Willow Scotts Bluff Stanton Thayer Thomas Valley Webster Washington York 2 A') 3 1 1 1 fi 3 6 1 1 4 2 1 2 1 Totals 162 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">25 TABLE IX— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED United States' both parents I 131 Foreign botli parents 12 Mixed 10 Unknown 9 Total 162 TABLE X— PARENTAL CONDITIONS OF THOSE ADMITTED Both parents dead | 35 Father dead 30 Mother dead 22 Parents living together 44 Parents living separate 29 Unknown •. I 2 Total | 162 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">26 n 8.8.3.3.3.33. j$ ;?; I "■ g 18" M ■ &gt; « 7 § I •ft|S JFJf&lt;a I** K Si | || £|# ! M ? : I 51 * * i ; i i II 5 r^H f ' ig !g t i li ir :7 o^«5C is !•«■ 'i : SffiSSinSSr^n 9 S &gt; fs lr i O M H K » g I li^« r&gt;» rs. r4 io rvi r^u-. InWi i i i Q O Q i in 133 3 st a .1 mi i Z— : : : *"O i O"« ii iisiisiir </seg>
            <seg id="p030">27 9 9 n i: 1*4 £ -* #? s I £ » H r I Us« fe I = ||l|i | 111 B I 5 my. 9 * « S 3 I P 5 r-H 1 1 r i i § £ ■'£ 1 1 r. 's •2 » i = S2 I ■y. U ■g E Ns ?o2 H it •2 SH fa &lt;HOh 5 jB "3 I 8S ! cic? i s- 1^ ! I (A; Q a tft J^ iff II 1 1 \*A I %« % a i|| i </seg>
            <seg id="p031">28 GARDEN PRODUCTS Produced Vegetables Measure Value Beans, string. bushels 604 $1,138.37 Beans, dry...—™ L , , bushels 1 so 48,00 Beets . bushels 162 162.00 198.00 Cabbage bushels 1,700 Carrots bushels 119 158.00 Corn _ _ bushels 335 373.00 Cucumbers _ bushels 40 35,10 Onions, green dozens 356 32.50 Onions, dry pounds 1,208 118.73 117,00 40.00 1,610.80 Peas quarts 1,138 40.00 7425 809.00 50.00 Lettuce pounds 707 89.70 Plums , bushels 35 105.00 Strawberries _ quarts 10 1.00 Total $5,160.45 'eppers bushels 'otatocs _ bushels tadishes dozens 'omatoes bushels 'urnips bushels 1,654 1,279 800 50 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>