<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00008">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00008</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL STATION EXPERIMENT OF NEBRASKA</title>
			            <date value="1902">1902</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
The University of Nebraska 

BULLETIN 

or the 

AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

or 

NEBRASKA 

VOL. XIV. Article III. 

Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 

Br T. L. Lton and A. T. Wiancko 

Distributed Mat 8, 1MB 

BAND-HOEING SUGAR BEETS AT AMES. NEBB. 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA 
TT ft A </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

OF 

NEBRASKA 

THE GOVERNING BOARD 

E. v. FORELL, President, Kearney 
GEO. F. KENOWER, YVisner 

tN C. RICH, Omaha 
L. TEETERS, Lincoln 
CALKINS, Kearney 
ERNST, Lincoln 

THE STATION OFFICERS 

E. A. BURNETT. B. Sc., Director and Animal HuMbandman 
T. L. LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist 
J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Srcretary 

WM W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk 

THE WORKING STAFF 

(Peters, D. V. M , Animal Pathologist 
iles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist 
k&gt;n H. Nicholson, M. A., Chemist 
Haeckeb. B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman 
kence Brunek, B. Sc., Entomologist 
in H. Barbouk, Ph. D., Otologist 
. Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulturist 
. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineer 
. Swezey, M. A.. Meteorologist 

A. T. Wiancko, B. S. A., Assistant Agriculturist 
H. R. Smith, B. Sc., Assistant Animal Husbandman 
J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist 
Henry B. Slaue, B. A.. Assistant Chemist 
H. \V. Perin, Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm 

(th. or M „«,»...,„¦ </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
Ui A . i-d. AjYON AJTD A* A . W LAJiUltO. 

* 

INTRODUCTION 

The experimental work in the culture of sugar beets upon 
the farm of the Standard Cattle Company at Ames, Nebr., during 
the season of 1901 followed plans similar to those of some 
years past and consisted in the main of tests of varieties, tests 
of fertilizers, different times and different distances of planting, 
and various methods of cultivation. In conjunction with 
these experiments an extended examination of the moisture 
content of soils under different conditions was conducted 
throughout the greater part of the growing season. Experi- 
Eents in the production of sugar beet seed were continued, and 
nong other matters the treatment of diseases and insect ennies 
affecting the sugar beet was given some attention. 

Through the liberality of the Cattle Company and the large 
amount of land devoted to experimental work it was possible 
to conduct most of these experiments upon a scale so large 
that the results should be of especial value to the beet sugar 
industry. Aside from the purely experimental work, over 
2,000 acres of sugar beets growing under various conditions 
were kept under constant observation, and the results referred 
to, though they cannot be taken as conclusive evidence, are at 
least interesting and suggestive. 

As was explained in Bulletin 60 of this Station, the land upon 
which the experiments were conducted is representative of the 
large region of country watered by the Platte and Elkhorn 
rivers and varies from a sandy loam to what is commonly 
known as gumbo, incidentally giving excellent opportunities 
for testing the relative merits of light and heavy soils^for the 
production of sugar beets^for factory purposes. 

Ehe rather low yields per acre obtained may be attributed to 
severe drought which lasted the greater part of two'months, 
inning with the second week in July. Under normal weather 

BULL. 73, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XIV., ART. III. </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
4 


conditions the tonnage would probably have been fully twenty 
per cent higher. On the whole, the season's experience 
showed to a remarkable extent the drought-resistant qualities 
of sugar beets in comparison with other field crops. They 
were found superior in this respect to anything upon the farm 
except alfalfa. " 

CHARACTER OF THE SEASON 

There was no lack of moisture at the beginning of the season 
as the soil was well filled with water when spring cultivation 
began and there was an abundance of rain up to the first week 
in July, as will be seen in the record of rainfall given below. 
After the rain of July 4 the weather suddenly became hot and 
dry, accompanied by a hot south wind which lasted over two 
weeks, so that the soil rapidly dried out and in many instances 
baked and cracked open to a depth of two to three feet. Extremely 
hot weather continued for some time and the drought 
remained practically unbroken until the end of the first week 
in September. The average temperature for the month of 
July was 84.5 degrees Fahrenheit. 

FAs an abundance of seed was at hand, two fields were se:ted 
for this experiment, the one a sandy loam and the other 
medium gumbo nil, comprising about fifty and sixty-five 
acres respectively. The same varieties were planted upon both 
fields and were given the same treatment as the other beet 
fields upon the farm. The former field is known as the "North 
Hairer" and the latter M "Division D". 

E1899 the North Hager produced a crop of sugar beets and 
X) a crop of corn which received a liberal dressing of barnmanure, 
while Division D was in corn and sorghum dur- 
MM two vi;i]&gt; and l.a&gt; never been manured. The latter 

Record of Samfall at Ann* 

a 

A 

April 1.14 inclie 
May 1.95 •• 
June 4.76 
July 2.06 •• 

AiiRiist 52 

Septmatarr 5 24 '¦ 
Octobar 1.84 •• 

Noveml)er 55 " 

TESTS OF VARIETIES OF SUGAR BEETS </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
5 

was prepared for sugar beets by deep plowing in the fall of 
1900 with the exception of a few strips where sorghum stacks 
were standing, which were plowed in the spring. The North 
Hager was plowed early in the spring, about a month before 
planting. 

Immediately before planting, the ground was thoroughly 
"double disked", rolled, and dragged with a light harrow attached 
behind the roller. 

Planting was begun on both fields on April 25 and continued 
uninterruptedly until completed. For the sake of convenience 
only one drill was kept at work on each field. Planting upon 
the North Hager was completed on May 1 and on Division D 
on May 4. The North Hager was in excellent tilth throughout, 
but the spring-plowed portions of Division D were quite hard 
and lumpy so that it was impossible to properly cover much of 
the seed. A spell of hot, dry weather retarded germination 
to a considerable extent, especially on Division D, where the 
first appearance of plants was very scattering. A heavy 
shower on May 8 melted down the lumps and by a timely use 
of the roller and harrow a good, even stand of plants was eventually 
secured. 

tThe plats on Division D consisted of two acres each, while 
the North Hager they varied from one to two acres owing 
an uneven length of the rows. 

Horse cultivation was begun on the North Hager on May 16, 
and on Division D on May 20. Both fields were treated in 
every respect as ordinary fields would have been. The North 
Hager received somewhat more hand labor than Division D 
owing to its being very weedy. It was hand-hoed about the 
middle of June and afterwards gone over twice to pull the 
large weeds, while Division D, being exceptionally clean, received 
only horse cultivation. 

ethe plats were carefully examined from time to time but 
ierence could be detected between any of the varieties in 
:t to growth or outward appearance. 

It^will be noticed in the table below that the plats on a considerable 
portion of Division D gave very light yields. This 
was^due to the fact that here the necessary cultivation was not 
given'soon enough after the last heavy rain of the season, 
July 4, to put the ground into good condition before the severe </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 

Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska. 

drought set in and consequently much of the field became very 
hard and the beets^suffered considerably, becoming quite yellow 
in appearance. Later, another attempt to 'cultivate the 
field was made but without effect as the ground had become 
so hard that the cultivator could not be forced to enter to the 
desired depth and even" where this was^possible the ground 
broke up^intolumps^too large to form an effective mulch.'JJ^* ' 

In comparing the* varieties as to yield the results on the 
North Hager may be considered fairly reliable as the soil conditions 
were quite uniform. The yields as given in the table 
below represent topped beets and are computed from the factory 
tared weights. Both fields were harvested during the 
latter part of October. The sugar content of the North Hager 
plats was probably somewhat affected by the presence of some 
"leaf spot", which affected the whole of the field. 

Sugar tests were begun on August 22 and were made at intervals 
of one week for seven weeks. The two fields were 
sampled on two consecutive days and the samples consisted of 
five beets each. The figures in the table below are the averages 
01 ine seve wasis. </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska. 

Table I. — Results of variety tests. 

Division D» Nobth Hagek* 

Yield Sogar Purity 

Yield Sugar Purity 

VARIETIES in tons ! Id juice of juice I In ton* ! In juice of jolce 

per acre per cent per cent 

per acre per cent per cent 

1. Dieckmann 15.72 15.07 M.I 

10.70 12.11 79.1 
10.56 12.36 79.5 
11.17 11.89 76.9 
11.01 12 16 78.4 
9.94 1256 79.4 
12.14 12.56 I 80.8 

2. Maurus Deutsch ! 13 46 15.66 ! 88.8 

8. Kommer I 15.85 16.00 i 80.0 

4. Aderstedt 15.46 14 86 

5. Braune | 13. 7» 15.14 85 8 

6. Strandes 18.59 14.74 86.6 

7. Licht 12.91 14.78 85.4 ! 11.14 18.14 I 80.6 

8. Russian Vilmorin. ...: 10.80 15 44 12.25 12.24 81.6 

9. Simon Legrande 8.59 14.77 85.0 11.62 13.11 

10. Janasz 8 02 15.96 86.2 12.81 18.16 80.1 

11. Ziemann 6.87 16 08 86.2 18.81 12.21 78.8 

12. Fouquier d'Hercuel.. 6.57 15.24 86.7 I 18.78 j 12.40 

18 Original K. W 6.15 15.88 86.9 j 14.51 I 14.51 84.7 

rBlary Mulliez 6 00 15.04 86.8 i 12.65 10.77 7t.» 
Eloir 6.72 15.29 87.7 ' 12.88 11.66 T7 1 

16. Schreiber 8.51 15.71 85.5 j 11.92 11.84 77.1 

17. Wohanka'sZ. R i 9 58 14 94 86.8 11.14 11.69 77.8 

18 Wohanka'sE R j 9.20 14.87 86.5 ;: 12.99 j 11.40 76.7 

rBoerning 9.48 14.90 86.5 ! 12.64 14.77 85.8 
DippesK. W 9.68 15.71 86.2 9.54 11.94 78.7 

21. Pioneer K. W 6.62 16.01 86.9 ... .... 

22. Peaz 5.94 15.04 86.6 18.10 12.49 78.0 

28. Hennion Faumont. . . 5.68 15.28 87.0 i 12.16 11.87 77.1 

24. Klein et Soukoffsky. . 6.12 15.88 87.1 13.99 : 12.94 81.1 

26. Sachs 6.64 15.21 86.7 ¦] 12.56 I 12.76 80.8 

86. Dubois 7 41 15.81 86 8 j 18 - 47 la *° \ ™- 7 

87. Drumez Elite 7.26 15.44 86.2 | 12.64 11.90 7».7 

88. Ladislas Mayzel 6.64 15.41 | 87.4 12 98 10.91 78.6 

29 Dernocour 6.26 14.61 86.4 14.16 11.64 76.7 

80. Knauer's Mangold... j 8.89 16.20 88.1 j 18.70 11.29 77.0 

81. Baumeier 10.61 16.89 88.4 : 12.68 11.24 

82. Count Stadnicky .... 12.91 15.14 84.7 1210. 78.8 

M. Utah-grown seed.... .... 15.54 11.90 77.« 

84. Vilmorin's V. R .... 11.80 i 12.49 81.8 

SB. Friedrichswerther... . .. .... ! 18.26 18.31 88.7 

86. Imperial .... 12.68 81. t 

87. Mangold .... 12.54 81.8 

'Medium gumbo soil. 
'Sandy loam soil. </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebrcuka 

E study of the above table will show that on the heavy soil 
sugar content and purity were higher throughout and 
¦e the ground was kept in good condition the yields were 
considerably higher. These results as to sugar content of 
i on light and heavy soils were borne out by the results 
the farm as a whole but the average yields were slightly 
vor of the lighter soils. 

The varieties show considerable differences in sugar and 
tonnage under approximately the same conditions. A comparison 
upon the basis of total sugar per acre on the North 
Hager plats shows a variation from 2280 pounds for the lowest 
to 4205 pounds for the highest, a very considerable difference. 
But to make close comparisons between the varieties with only 
one year's test would hardly be just and might be quite mis- 

EXPERIMENTS WITH FERTILIZERS 

The object of this experiment was to determine the effects 
upon sugar beets of various complete fertilizers, single fertilizing 
constituents and combinations of the latter. The single 
fertilizers were in each case applied in two different quantities 
with a view to getting at the relative value of light and heavy 
dressings. The mixtures were made up of equal weights of 
the constituents. The accompanying diagram of the field, 
which also contained the planting and cultivation experiments, 
represents the arrangement of the plats. </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
¦ 

Experiments in the 

!(ure o. 

lu^ar 

lee, 

in 

4 

~ 

I 
M 
] 
X 
s 
£ 
¦S 
I 
I 
¦ 
4 
i 
I 
| 
¦ 
B 
i 

i 
I 
i 
e 
1 

s 
_o 
&gt; 
1 
I 
5 
I 

¦ 
1 
I 
I 
j 
o 
c 
I 

a 
1 
i 
1 
¦ 
i 

j 
be 
| 
c 
I 
1 
EL 
I 

9, 
-5 

i 
S | | 
8-3 - &amp; &amp; 
Hill 
j i "• 8 i 
i i 1 ! I 
i i 1 1 i 
* 09 c 3 3 
J f Mil 
1 1 1 ! i 1 1 
= a a ja o O Jr 
_ ¦&lt; &lt; sl. o, a- s 

I . 
8. g g 8 - I 
i \ 3 | I | 
I s. I. i si j 
a i I "Sal 
nun s 
3- Z Z £ 3 SU -y. &lt; 

I 
s 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 

10 

Each of the fertilizer plats consisted of one-tenth acre having 
twelve rows of beets. A thirteenth row was planted with 
each plat to separate it from its neighbor and for convenience 
in harvesting. 

Pe previous [cropping and manuring of the ground was 
ame as that of the North Hager variety field, of^whichTt 
originally a part, being now separated by a deep drainage 
ditch. The field was prepared for sugar beets Jby deep plowing 
early in April. The fertilizers were carefully broadcasted 
upon the plats a few days before planting, which was done on 
May 11. The preparation of the seed bed and the planting 
were conducted as in the case of the variety fields. The ground 
was in excellent condition. 

Unfortunately a flock of chickens from a neighboring barnyard 
destroyed portions of the first four plats soon after the 
beets came up and it was found impossible to secure an even 
stand by replanting, though two attempts were made. However, 
enough of the original planting of each plat was saved to 
provide samples for the sugar tests. 

The following table gives the yields per acre of tared beets, 
together with the sugar content and purity of the juice. The 
sugar tests were made at intervals of one week for five weeks 
beginning August 26. The figures represent the averages of 
the five tests. </seg>


            <seg id="p011">
11 

Table II.— 

MttmMa 

of fertilizer 

texts 

*,JSW1?, Yield 
grmms ln toos 

Sugar Purity 
in juice of juice 
per cent per cent 

Kind and quantity of fertilizer 

1. Barnyard manure, 10 tons per 
acre 279 

12.7 BM 
129 NJ 

2. Lime, 10 tons per acre 806 

8. Armour &amp; Company's fertilizer, 
500 lbs. per acre 290 

¦wift &amp; Company's fertilizer, 
500 lbs. per acre 840 

5. Phosphate, potash and nitrate, 

820 lbs. per acre 856 18.19 

6. Unfertilized 880 11.86 
7. Potash and nitrate, 820 lbs. 

834 11.62 

per acre 
8. Nitrate of soda, 160 lbs. per 

acre 818 10.64 

9. Nitrate of soda, 830 lbs. per 

acre 346 ! 12.00 

10. Phosphate and nitrate, 320 lbs. 

per acre 846 ! 11.80 

11. Unfertilized 894 10.45 

18. Potassium sulphate, 160 lbs. 

per it ere 877 HJI 

18. Potassium sulphate, 320 lbs. 

per acre 888 10 08 

14. Phosphate and potash. 320 lbs. 

per acre 896 11.16 

15. Acid phosphate, 160 lbs. per 

acre . 426 10.81 

16. Acid phosphate, 320 lbs. per 

acre 478 10.30 

17. Unfertilized 472 10 42 

The much greater average weight of the beets on the last 
two plats, 16 and 17, may be accounted for by the shelter derived 
from a strip of sorghum along the south side of the plats. 
The yield per acre was not heavier because on each of these 
plats parts of two rows were missed by the planter. 

Ei examination of the above table, while showing small 
itions such as might be expected on equal-sized plats in 
field, shows, upon the whole, a slight increase upon the 
lized plats. The results, however, do not point to any 
trial advantage in the use of fertilizers upon this land. 

Leaving out of consideration Plats 1, 2, 3, 4, 16, and 17, and 
calculating the average results for the fertilized and unfertilized 
plats, we get the following : </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 


Table III. — Averages of fertilized and unfertilized plats. 

wJuntfUt Yleld S"*" Parity 
In tons peroent percent 

Fertilized plats 865 11.4 12.7 8"i.8 

Unfertili/ed plats '.'.""I"'...'.. 387 ll!l 12^6 81^8 

To show the effect of each class of fertilizer used, by calcu- 

lating the average results from all plats where the fertilizer 

was used ana tabulating the figures obtained we get the 

following 

Table IV. — Effect of each class of fertilizers. 

wJiVhfZt Yleld 8n «» r Pnrit » 
T2£\? : E'«!!r i^i?. -y-2 

Fertilizers 

j£££ in tons peroent peroent 

Plats having potash 870 11.6 12.7 81.4 

Plats having nitrate 840 11.7 18.0 81.8 

Plats having phosphate 880 11.7 12.7 11.1 
Plats not fertilized 8*7 11.1 12.6 81.8 

3*7 11.1 12.6 81.8 

By referring to Bulletin 60 and the Fourteenth Annual Re- 

port of this Station it will be seen that similar fertilizer exper- 

iments conducted in 1898 and 1899 showed a slight increase in 

yield of beets from the use of fertilizers but no difference in 

the sugar content and purity of the juice. 

METHODS OF CULTIVATION 

The object of this experiment was to determine the effects 

of various systems of cultivation upon the yield and sugar con- 

tent. The different systems tested are shown in the diagram 

of the experimental field. 

All the plats were treated in the ordinary way [up to the 

time of the second cultivation. The hand-noeing, given after 

the third cultivation, was the same for all plats and was simply 


sufficient to cleaT the ground of weeds. "All plats were horse- 

cultivated five times."~ ~ 

The ''ordinary" cultivation was that practiced on other por- 

tions of the farm, consisting'in^a' gradual deepening of the 

cultivated area with each successive cultivation until at the </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
13 

end of tbe season a depth of about four to five inches is 
reached. On the first plat a depth of about six inches was 
reached. On the second plat cultivation was begun at a depth 
of five inches and gradually made shallower as the season advanced, 
but this was found difficult owing to the looseness of 
the ground. The fourth plat was cultivated five inches deep 
throughout the season. The last plat was cultivated two to 
three inches deep throughout, but it was found that the mulch 
produced was not sufficient to protect the soil beneath during 
the drought and as a consequence it became rather more compact 
and dry than the other plats. 

Kmparison between shallow and deep cultivation was atd 
upon a large field but the extremely dry weather made 
issible to satisfactorily carry out the experiment. 

K Fable V., below, the sugar content and purity of the juice 
jent the averages of five tests made at intervals of one 
beginning August 26. 

Table V. — Results of cultivation atperiments. 

Yield Sagar Purity 
per acre in juice of juice 
tons percent percent 

Method or cultivation 

Although there does not seem to be any satisfactory explanation 
why the results on the first plat should be so low, a 
study of the above table seems to indicate that moderately 
deep cultivation should be practiced. It must always be remembered 
that very deep cultivation will, late in the season, 
interfere considerably with the fine lateral roots of the beets, 
but in this climate of hot, dry summers with high winds the soil 
mulch in order to be effective must be three or four inches 

Pi conjunction/with the cultivation experiments, soil moisture 
rminations were made upon the deep and shallow cultid 
plats to see the effect of the depth of cultivation 'upon 
moisture content of the soil. As has already been ex- 

' 

! 

Shallow to deep 
Deep to shallow 
Ordinary 
Deep throughout (5 inches) 
Shallow throughout rii inches) 

12.09 
12.74 
1800 
18.02 
12.51 

12.4 
13.0 
14.8 
134 
14.0 </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 


plained the deep cultivation was five inches, while the shallow 
cultivation was two to three inches deep throughout the 

Table VI. — Showing percentage moisture content of deep and 
shallow cultivated plats. 

was found at a 

Average.. 11.90 9.52 10.46 12 68 9.59 10. T2 depth ot 7.» feet 
f under these plats 

It will be seen from the above table that the shallow cultivated 
plat at first contained more moisture in the surface foot, 
which was probably due to the smaller proportion of loose, dry 
soil upon the surface, but later in the season the moisture in 
this plat decreased more rapidly than in the case of the deep 
cultivated plat, which seems to indicate that the deeper mulch 
was more effective in checking evaporation and consequently 
that cultivation in this country in order to be as effective as 
possible in conserving soil moisture should be fairly deep. 

DISTANCE OF PLANTING 

Pi one plat in this experiment an attempt was made to get 
lany rows per acre as possible without increasing the difty 
of horse cultivation. The rows were placed 15 inches 
apart with every fourth space 18 inches. The idea was to use 
a one-horse, four-row cultivator and let the horse walk in the 
18-inch space. The plants were thinned to eight inches apart 
in all the rows. In order to increase the ease of cultivation 
without reducing the number of plants per acre, a second plat, 
21 inches between the rows and six to seven inches beeen 
the plants in the rows, was planted. These two plats 
were compared with one having 18 inches between rows and 
8 inches between plants in the rows. This plat was that des- 

¦ 6-INCH CULTIVATION 2i-INCH CULTIVATION 
or i j i i 

8AM PLING '"I* 1*-M S&lt;-» 1-M •*-»• »«-•&gt; 
Inches lncne* Inches inches Inches Inches 

l»at« or 
SAMPLING 11* 
Inebes 

12-M 24-«S 1-12 
Inchef Inches inches 

12-24 
Inches 

24*, REMARKS 
Inches 

incoes 
uly20.. 13.29 
nly 29. ... 12.72 
Lugust 6.. 10.86 ! 
Lugast 18. 10.75 

incnep incnes incaes 
16.72 
11.67 11.21 18.14 
8.63 9.94 11.40 
8.86 10.28 10.27 

incnes 
11.88 
9.19 
8.20 

incnes 
The ground on 
the shallow cultl - 
Vo aj »»ted plat was 
**?* found to be much 
1U.UO firmer than on 
10 00 the deep cultivat- 
ed plat. 

Standing water </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Ntbraika. 

15 

ignated "ordinary" in the cultivation experiment. All plats 
were cultivated alike. 

The results as recorded in tne table below are in every respect 
in favor of the 18-inch rows. In the case of [the 15-inch 
rows more or less difficulty was experienced in the'cultivation. 
Owing to the difficulty of securing an even stand "of plants 
in the row it does not seem to be advisable to plant so far apart 
as 21 inches. Experience upon the large fields on the farm 
shows that with a little care at the beginning a horse or mule 
will soon learn to walk in a comparatively narrow space. 

TABLE VII. — Results of distance of planting experiments. 

Yield Sugar Purity 
per acre In juice of juice 

Distance of plantinc 

ton* 1 per cent per cent 

Rows 18 inches apart 18.00 14.8 »4.5 

Rows 15 inches apart with 4th row 18 inches.. 11. UN 14.0 84.1 

Rows 21 inches apart I 10.70 12.5 HJ 

TIME OF PLANTING 

This experiment was rather unsatisfactory owing to^the fact 
that it was found impracticable to plant early upon the ground 
chosen for the experiment, and the last planting was a com 
plete failure because of adverse weather conditions at the 
time the plants came up. 

The first plat was planted on May 11, a second on May 
and'a third on June 13. The interval between the second and 
third plantings was longer than that between the first and 
second, on account of wet weather. A heavy rain, followed by 
a scorching sun just as the plants were coming up, almost totally 
destroyed the stand. 

As the season advanced there seemed to be an increasing 
difference in the growth of the two plats planted May^ll and 
May 22, and about the end of July there appeared to^be'almost 
a month difference between the two. The following table 
shows the results: </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 

Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebratka. 

Table VIII. — Besults of time of planting experiments. 

Yield Sugar Purtty 
per acre in juice »l Juice 

Date or planting 

tons per cent per cent 

May 11 18.60 14.8 84 5 
May 22 9.06 10.6 77.8 
June 18 Failure 

Failure 

Although this experiment shows such a decided difference in 
favor of the earlier planting, the results are not borne out by 
the results obtained upon the farm as a whole. A 38-acre field 
planted about June 15 gave a yield of 13.5 tons per acre with 
an average sugar content of about 15 per cent. On another 
large field about half of which was planted about May 5 and 
the rest about three weeks later, the later planting besides giving 
a slightly heavier yield gave about 1 per cent more sugar 
than did the earlier planted portion. But these results may 
possibly be accounted for by the peculiarity of the season. The 
late planted beets did not receive the same check by the extreme 
drought which suddenly set in. The early planted beets 
had, during the rather wet weather which preceded, developed 
an unusually large proportion of leaves, which, when the 
drought came, the roots were unable to support, while the later 
planted beets seemed to somewhat adapt themselves to the 

On the whole, however, the season's experience indicates 
that, while good results may be obtained from late planting 
under favorable conditions, the chances of success are in favor 
of early planting. The difficulty of securing^. a good stand^of 
sugar beets increases very materially as the'season advances 
past the third week in May. A small field planted on AprilJJIS 
gave a yield of 17 tons per acre,*and two large fields planted 
about April 25 gave yields of 14.7 and'l 4.1 T.tons'per^acre"'respectively, 
but in all these instances the sugar content was low, 
•which may be accounted for by the presence of some "leaf 
spot" and by a greater "second growth" during the rainy 
weather of September. 
</seg>

            <seg id="p017">
17 

EFFECTS OF LATE CULTIVATION ON SUGAR BEETS 

In general field practice, sugar beets are "laid by" when the 
leaves are large enough to cover the space between the rows, 
further cultivation being thereby made difficult. On several 
fields cultivation was attempted after this stage had been 
reached, as the ground had become compacted by heavy rains 
early in July. The passage of the horse and cultivator broke 
and tore off many leaves and more or less bruised the crowns 
of the beets, so that it was considered advisable to determine 
the effect upon the sugar content later in the season. Several 
pieces of rows that had been badly bruised were marked, as 
well as pieces of adjoining rows that were left untouched. During 
the end of September and beginning of October several 
samples from each were taken to the laboratory and tested, 
with the. following results: 

Table IX. — Showing effect of bruising upon sugar beets. 

Bruised 

Umsuissu 

ATermge At. wt. - . piirit. Average At. wt. *„.. PnritT 
wt. with without £",«" E^iL *t. with without ,„£** F.^iL 
crowns crowns l^"™, £r^.?t crowns crowns i! _*£!?. £f- Ju i~, 
grmms grams P« &lt;*nt ¦ per eent percent per.tnl 

It will be observed that while the sugar content and purity 
of the bruised beets were somewhat lower the loss is more than 
made up by the gain in the average weight of the beets. 
While the test was too limited to be considered conclusive it 
indicates that rather late cultivation may be found beneficial 
where the ground has become unduly compacted. The harm 
done by leaf pruning may be more than counterbalanced by the 
more vigorous growth of the beets, especially when very dry 
weather follows. If the cultivating be done during the middle 
of the day when the leaves are more "or less wilted, few will be 
broken off. 

¦order to determine more fully to what extent the late cultin 
of sugar beets may be beneficial, soil moisture determi- 

Test No. 1 

576 
468 
¦m 

387 
W 
302 

12.9 
12.8 
12.8 

80.6 
79.2 
80 8 

•Vi7 
426 
356 

H.H7 
HI 

180 
12 5 
18. » 

51 

I !" 

! 

— 

478 i 

:«7 

12.8 

800 

449 

440 

:«ii 

m 

18.1 

181 

». 
</seg>
            <seg id="p018">
Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraika. 

18 

Rns were made on August 15 upon adjoining portions of a 
1 field half of which was laid by about the 1st of July and 
emainder cultivated about the 10th and again about the 
of July. The soil was a medium loam and, at the time of 
sampling, the former portion was quite hard upon the surface 
as a result of the heavy rain of July 4, while the latter portion 
was found to be quite loose and the soil moist to within two or 
three inches of the surface, representing an almost ideal condition. 
Carefully made duplicate determinations showed 17.3 
and 14.4 per cent of moisture in the first and second foot respectively 
of the late cultivated portion of the field, while that 
laid by about July 1 contained only 9.4 and 8.5 per cent in 
the first two feet. Similarly marked differences were found in 
more extensive examinations of cornfields similarly treated. 

EFFECT OF WEEDY VS. CLEAN GROUND UPON SUGAR CONTENT 

On the assumption that the growth of weeds in sugar beet 
fields, aside from lessening the yields, may have a deleterious 
effect upon the sugar content of the beets, it \ras determined to 
make some tests with a view to ascertaining the extent of the 
injury. 

Adjoining portions in two different fields were selected for 
the experiment. In each field a plat was allowed to run to 
weeds about the end of July and the beets from these were 
compared with samples taken from the adjoining clean ground, 
with the results recorded in the table below. The tests were 
made during the first and second weeks of October and the 
figures in the table represent the averages of the samples from 
both fields. The samples consisted of five average sized beets 

Owing to the fact that both plats received the same treatment 
and were kept equally clean until late in the cultivation season, 
it may be assumed that the difference in the results obtained 
was not so marked as might otherwise have been the case. 
Nevertheless, the test plainly indicates that where weeds are 
allowed to'flourish they may very materially reduce the value 
of the beets produced. </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebratka. 

19 

Table X. — Effect of xoeeds upon sugar content. 

Weedy plats Clean plats 

Sugar Purity Sugar Puritv 
In juice of juice in juice of jumper 
cent percent percent percent 

EFFECTS OF WET WEATHER AND "SECOND GROWTH" UPON 

* SUGAR BEETS 

That the sugar content and purity of the juice of sugar beets 
are more or less reduced in cases where wet weather sets in at 
the time when the beets should be ripening is a fact that has 
long been recognized, and the common belief seems to be that 
this reduction takes place very rapidly. 

In order to determine to what extent this is true, an extended 
comparison was made, as the weather conditions from the first 
week in September to the middle of October were particularly 
favorable for such an investigation. Owing to the dry weather 
preceding this period, the beets ripened very early and the 
sugar content and purity were unusually high. Soon after 
the first rain the beets freshened up and began a vigorous 
growth which continued up to the time of harvesting, so that 
their foliage then was more luxuriant than at any period in 
their growth. 

In the table below, the figures represent the averages of 250 
beets in each test. 

Test No. 1 
Test No. 2 
Tnt Mo. 4! '.'.'.'.'.'.'.. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. '.".'.'.'.'.'. 

13.0 
12.0 
9-8 
9.3 

77.9 
74.8 
71.9 

18 2 
II :» 
110 
10 7 

I 

11.0 

77.1 

11 9 

i i-ragf 

7H5 </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
20 

Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska. 

Table XL— Aovfaf the fjfect of xoet weather upon sur/tn 

purity. 

in gn!mi P« «"' «"" &lt;*" 

Average of 50 samples tested Sept. 4 and 5 j 294 II 8 
Average of 50 samples tested Sept. 11 and 1-2.. 812 14.1 

Average of 50 samples tested Sept. 18 and 19.. 384 13 S xh s 

Av- rage of 50 samples tested Sept. M and M.. 18.5 

Average of 50 samples tested Oct. 2 and 3 380 12.7 81.7 

It will be observed that the drop in the percentage of sugar 
was quite rapid during the first week, but a study of all the 
figures will show that the drop was more apparent than real 
and can be fully accounted for by the increase in the weight of 
the beets, which was probably wholly due to the water taken 
up. The fact that the purity of^the juice fell so little bears 
out this view. Now allowing, for the purpose of a fuller comgarison, 
25,000 beets per acre and'calculating the yield of sugar 
from the data at hand, we have in the first instance a total of 
2412 pounds of sugar per acre with a purity of 84.8 per cent. 
In the second instance the result would be 2428 pounds of sugar 
having a purity of 84.1 per cent. In the latter instance, a month 
after'the fresh growth and the drop in sugar began, the result 
would be 2515 pounds of sugar per acre having a purity of 81.7 
per cent. These figures indicate that while the drop in the 
percentage of sugar is very considerable the damage is not so 
great as is generally supposed and the ultimate results go to 
show that it is the manufacturer and not the farmer who is the 

It was observed during the experiment that the increase in 
the weight of the beets was due to a natural, healthy arrowth 
and buds did not appear on the crowns of the beets until near 
the end of the period. Had the beets been quite mature when 
tht&gt; wet weather began, the fresh growth would probably have 
appeared in the form of buds and there would have been little 
or no increase in the weight of the beets to compensate for the 
loss of sugar. It is well known that buds grow at the expense 
of the sugar in the beet and where such are observed harvesting 
should not be delayed. Even if the weather should turn </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
Experintnt* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska. 

21 

dry a rise in sugar content can hardly be looked for. The buds 
once started will keep on growing. 

DISEASES OP SUGAR BEETS 

kA few experiments were made in the treatment of "leaf spot" 
ercon/Him Mtota) and a form of root rot, which appeared to 
a species of Rhizoctonia. 

The root rot made its first appearance about the 15th of June 
and affected patches in several fields. The disease was recognized 
as the Rhizoctonia described by Dr. Duggar in Bulletin 
163 of the Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station. 
About a week later it was found to be spreading quite rapidly 
upon a corner of a large field that had been laid by. Knowing 
that Rhizoctonia had been found to grow particularly well in 
acid media, an examination of the soil was made and it was 
found by the litmus test to give a decidedly acid reaction. It 
was, therefore, determined to try the effect upon the disease of 
a liberal application of fresh, powdered lime on and around the 
affected portions of the field. All diseased matter was carefully 
collected and carried from the field. The lime was then 
liberally scattered on the remaining plants and around the affected 
areas. Later examinations showed that the liming was 
quite effective in stopping the spread of the disease, in some 
cases even curing slightly infected plants, while on other untreated 
portions of the field the disease continued to spread for 
some time. A later experiment showed that the liming had no 
apparent effect where the diseased matter was not first removed. 
The lime, although quite fresh, seemed to have no injurious 
effect upon the green foliage, which was in many instances completely 
covered. 

While not considered conclusive, the results were very satisfactory 
and indicate that removing the diseased portions of 
plants and liberally applying fresh, powdered lime may do much 
to check the spread of this particular fungus. ' In cases of 
underground rot the application of lime upon the surface 
seemed to have no effect. 

Ba popular article on beet diseases in The Beet Sugar Gazette, Vol. 3, 
September, 1901. where Mr. Geo. G. Hedgcnck, of the U. B. Department 
icultare, refers to this experiment and suggests the treatment her* </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
22 


To determine the effect of liming the soil upon the root-rot 
fungus (P/iyl/osticta), ten acres of a field that had borne sugar 
beets the previous year, and where they had rotted considerably, 
were given a dressing of fifteen to twenty tons per acre 
of the refuse lime from the factory together with some cinders. 
The lime and cinders were plowed under and the beets planted 
on May 14. Not a trace of rot was found upon the beets when 
harvested. While the result of a single experiment of this kind 
does not furnish sufficient evidence upon which to base a conclusion, 
it indicates that heavy applications of lime may produce 
conditions unfavorable to the development of certain 

R "leaf spot" disease did not develop to any serious ex\o 
that there was not a good opportunity to test the effecss 
of methods of treatment. 

Bly in the season more or less trouble from both insects 
af spot was anticipated, and a spraying machine was seby 
means of which it would be possible to spray thirty 
ty acres of sugar beets in a day. 

This machine consisted of a one-horse cart upon which was 
set a hundred-gallon tank fitted with a double-acting pump 
which was geared to the wheels of the cart. The piping was 
specially designed for the purpose in view and consisted of a 
main cross-pipe covering eight rows and having a short branch 
pipe with a fine nozzle at the end for each row. The piping 
was so arranged that it could be tilted up or down to suit the 
height of the beets and to avoid trouble from the blowing of 
the spray by the wind. The working of the machine was in 
every respect satisfactory. No difficulty was experienced in 
evenly covering the leaves with the solution without its forming 
into drops and running off the smooth surface of the leaf, 
which is so often a source of trouble in properly spraying 
sugar beets. 

On July 27 slight traces of "leaf spot" were noticed upon 
several of the beet fields and a strip upon one of these was 
sprayed with Bordeaux mixture. The following day a light 
rain washed off some of the poison and the treatment was repeated 
on August 1 and again on the 10th. Later, portions of 
other fields were treated twice. On September 27 a careful ex- </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 

23 

amination for the effects of the spraying was made. On the 
fields where portions had been twice sprayed with the Bordeaux 
mixture there was no apparent difference between the sprayed 
and the unsprayed portions. All were affected more or leas 
with the disease. But where the beets had been sprayed three 
times there was quite a noticeable difference, the foliage of the 
sprayed beets having a fresher green color and less ' 'leaf 
spot." The indications seem to be that if the Bordeaux mixture 
be applied as soon as the first traces of "leaf spot" appear 
and the applications repeated at intervals, the disease may be 
considerably checked, but where it has once secured a good 
foothold there seems to be little use in applying this fungicide. 

8:h Paris green and lead arsenate were successfully used as 
;icides for the striped blister beetle and grasshoppers, in 
nction with the Bordeaux mixture. These insects both 
id to be easily driven off the field but the grasshoppers 
led after the poison had somewhat dissipated. 

A very significant observation in connection with the prevalence 
of "leaf spot" was that in every case the disease made 
the greatest progress upon the earliest planted fields. In no 
case did leaf spot appear upon beets planted after the 1st of 
June. A partial explanation of this phenomenon may be found 
in the fact that the earlier planted fields all received a more 
severe check when the drought set in than did those of later 
planting. In the case of the late plantings, although the growth 
was slowjit^was steady all through the dry period. But very 
much thejsams observation seams to have been made in'JprevT 
ous years and it may be that where "leaf spot" is troublesome 
rather late planting would be advisable. In all cases there 
was more "leaf spot" upon the beets on the lighter soils] than 
upon those on the heavier, but this again may have been due to 
the^faot that all of the lighter soils were earlier planted. * 

In continuation "of jthe observations ba»un in 1899, and 
recorded in the Fourteenth Annual Report of this Station, the 
following jtable is designed to show thejcondition under which 
the beets ware grown where "leaf spot" appeared. It may be 
that the appearance of the) disease is ' connected with more or 
less'ja voidable '^conditions and these "observations if carried 
through a nutnbar of years may point tham out. 

« Njbr.no 3tv/ioa Bille:ia 6), Fjarte)V,h Ainuil R)p&gt;-U </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebra$ka. 

¦ !? ; i i j 1 t .3 2 § 
I |5 I I a I I I * 3 1 
J * I » t n I i • « • j 
£ 5- * ** If 5 ¦ * I ] 
ilia W, = " 
p|** tee !£•-••¦ 
fe M : a 
i ¦. " * 
1 1 Ik I * I I =* - I 
|l~~* i «-, » ! i 
I i rs&gt; 1 S * » I r . . 5 
I « ? |s S 6 * I |. ri B 2 1 
I t s ?i I • 1 « * 
1 1 ! II i i i i \ \ 

I 

I 

'. I I I . I I I I I I I I 
Eii^ilSffi-!'*-: 
S*.Hi-*5c E Si • g - K 
ii^uii-iMill 
1 iiiniiinHHuu 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Xehratka 

25 

SELECTION OF MOTHER BEETS AND SEED PRODUCTION 

tThe production of sugar beet seed is an important branch of 
e experimental work at Ames, and gratifying progress has 
en made. 

For the purpose of next year's work some four thousand 
mother beets were selected and placed in sand silos over winter. 
The method of selection employed was that known as the 
"Pellet cold aqueous diffusion process", which is fully described 
in Bulletin 60 of this Station. It was intended to try the new 
method worked out by R. S. Hiltner and R. W. Thatcher, and 
described' in the Fourteenth Annual Report of this Station, 1 
but as the necessary apparatus wa» not at hand in time it had 
to be abandoned for this year. 

The mother beets selected were classified according to sugar 
content into three classes: 14 to 16 per cent, 16 to 18 per cent, 
and 18 per cent and over, and kept separate in the silos. 
These beets will be planted next spring. 

In the spring of 1901 about 7,000 mother beets were planted 
three feet apart each way and cultivated as is usual in the case 
of corn. The result was about a ton of clean seed of excellent 
quality. The best of this seed will be planted this year for 
beets from which commercial seed is to be produced the follow- 

Es believed that by careful selection good seed for factory 
jses can be produced at home and a large part of the cost 
iportation done away with. It is hoped, too, that this 
will be better adapted to home conditions and that more 
rm results may be secured. 

COST OP PRODUCING SUGAR BEETS 

The cost of producing sugar beets varies with a number of 
conditions: such as, kind and condition of soil, season, and 
price of labor. A little reflection will show how these condition* 
may affect the cost. 

:i i-n .liiiirna) of the American L'!ieiuK:»l &gt;ooieiv, Vol. XXIII. No </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
26 


The following table is taken from the books of the Standard 
Cattle Company, where a careful account has been kept of every 
item of expense. 

These figures are necessarily higher than they need be upon 
the average farm, where only a comparatively few acres are 
grown and much of the work may be done without the hiring 
of extra labor. On the Cattle Company's farm every hand's 
turn must be covered by a cash outlay and at the highest price, 
while the average farmer with his family can do the work much 
cheaper and earn a great part or all of the money represented, 
and correspondingly increase his yearly income. 

The cost of cultivation beyond a certain point will depend 
largely upon the extent of weed growth, and the cost of harvesting 
will be considerably affected by the distance the beets 
have to be hauled. 

SUMMAEY AND CONCLUSIONS 

A test of thirty-seven varieties of sugar beets under similar 
conditions showed a wide variation in the total amount of sugar 
produced per acre. 

A comparison of light and heavy soils for sugar beet production 
showed a considerably higher sugar content in the 
beets grown upon the heavy soil. 

Slight increases in the yield, sugar content, and purity of 
beets were produced by the use of commercial fertilizers, but 
their use does not seem to be profitable upon the land where 
the tests were conducted. 

Cable XIII.— &lt; 

Cost per acre of producing sugar bt 

ucnii/ sugar 

kaeCt, 1893-1901 

Wto, 1 893- 1901 

Yiak Manuring 

Seed Pre^ration Cu '* l « , ™, al l £ 
and Siding tlon L V l0 * "» i 

f»rvest Total 

" 

MM 
1884 $2.20 
1805 
IKSKi 2.66 
1897 8 56 
1808 3.74 
1899 .-»-. 
1900 .77 
1901 .78 

M.M $7.90 $31.15 141. »0 
2.00 3.89 ».O7 H 1« 
111 S.M 15.08 28 74 
3.33 4.08 14.09 24.17 
I.M 4.18 1H.32 29 88 
3.83 2.36 i 15.'iV 3A.0S 
1.78 7 14 n.W 32 12 
2.46 4.65 12.3m W.M 
2.68 4.37 18.44 M.I7 

$12.75 $54.06 
8.13 
18.19 86-08 
1302 
S .94 
11.80 87.88 
16.99 m.\\ 
15.47 
12.95 89.22 

. I 
i 

.Terage •1.66 

$280 14.90 118.80 •38.W 

$12.58 $40.74 

I I 

! I </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
Experiment! in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 

n 

A comparison of the different classes of commercial fertilizers 
was slightly in favor of the phosphate . 

A comparison of different methods of cultivation was in 
every respect in favor of three to four inch cultivation, which 
seems to be necessary in this region to produce an effective 
mulch. 

The most satisfactory distance of planting was found to be 
eighteen inches between rows and eight inches between plants 
in the rows. 

Late cultivation of sugar beets, after the leaves are full 
grown, may, by tearing off leaves, reduce the sugar content, 
but the extra growth induced this year more than counterbalanced 
the loss in sugar. 

The presence of weeds in sugar beet fields may very materially 
affect the sugar content of the beets. 

Fresh growth induced by wet weather in autumn when the 
beets should be ripening may rapidly reduce the percentage 
sugar content of the beets, but unless the fresh growth is 
accompanied by buds upon the crown there seems to be no 
real loss of sugar — the beets increase in size and weight while 
the sugar remains at a standstill. 

Surface applications of lime may be effective in checking 
the Rhizoctonia rot of sugar beets. 

Repeated spraying with "Bordeaux mixture" may act as a 
preventive of "leaf spot" but will not cure infected leaves. 

ACKNOWLEDGEMENT 

For the material of this bulletin our thanks are due the 
Standard Cattle Company, who bore the expense of the work 
recorded, and to Mr. R. M. Allen, its general manager, whose 
enthusiastic interest in sugar beet experimentation has done 
much to advance the beet sugar industry of this country. 

Accepted for publication March 14, 1902. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>