<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>An Inquiry Into the Cause of the Increase of Tuberculosis of Swince</title>
               <date value="1925-02">1925-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 30 An Inquiry Into the Cause of the Increase of Tuberculosis of Swine By L. VAN ES AND H. M. MARTIN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA February, 1925 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">An Inquiry Into the Cause of the Increase of Tuberculosis of Swine By L. VAN ES AND H. M. MARTIN Tuberculosis of swine has, as a rule, been looked upon as being transmitted from cattle either thru the feeding of milk products or thru the agency of the manure of feeding yards occupied by both hogs and cattle. This has been the accepted theory of the origin of swine tuberculosis and no doubt it was based upon substantial experimental evidence at the time of its conception and for a considerable period after that. While it was known for some years that swine were occa - sionally found to contract tuberculosis thru direct or indirect contact with tuberculous poultry, such occurrences, at least in this country, were looked upon as more or less infrequent incidences and even as late as 1923 Mohler (46) reported that: "It is believed that the area eradication work among cattle will eventually eliminate tuberculosis from swine as the greatest source of infection in swine is known to be through following diseased cattle or drinking unpasteurized skim milk from creameries." In the face of a lack of any volume of evidence contrary to this view it was generally shared by animal pathologists and livestock sanitarians of this country, and the elimination of swine tuberculosis became a very important, altho somewhat secondary objective of the efforts looking forward to the eradication of the bovine disease. The meat inspection returns for a number of years, how - ever, pointed strongly to the possibility that some factor or factors other than bovine infection operating in the recog - nized manner may play an etiologic part in the production of swine tuberculosis. Not only do those data fail to show any degree of parallelism between the incidence of bovine and swine tuberculosis, but they present the picture of a very wide divergence for the two types of the disease which were thought to be so closely correlated. As shown by the graphs represented in Figs. 1 and 2 which were projected from the data submitted in Tables 1 and 2, the curve representing the total retentions on account of tuberculosis in cattle, gently declining or inclining remains, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 on the whole, close to a horizontal position and during no one year does the number of retentions amount to much more than 27 per thousand animals slaughtered. The curve show - ing the number of animals condemned, even more closely ad - hering to a certain level, on the whole follows the curve rep - resenting the retentions. In the graph, based upon the tuberculosis data pertaining to swine, the curve representing the number of condemnations per thousand animals slaughtered is even more level and Taihjc 1. — Number of cattle slaughtered during period 1907-19SS&amp; mid number of animal* retained &lt;m&lt;I condenviwd. (Table prepared from data published in Yearbook of I . • v&gt; . Depart - ment »f Agriculture for l-'/JJ. p. 217.) 'Covers 9 months from October 1, 1996, to June 30, 1907. stable during the period studied than the same curve dealing with cattle tuberculosis, practically ranging only between one and two per thousand. On the other hand the curve per - taining to swine retained for tuberculosis shows a marked rise from the beginning of the period to the last, with the exception of the slight decline for the year 1919. The num - ber of retentions of swine on account of tuberculosis per thousand animals slaughtered rose from 13.83 in 1907 to 163.87 in 1922. Thus there apparently took place in the period, 1907-1922, an increase of close to 150 per 1,000 hogs Year Year I Slaughtered Retained Condemned i No. PeriOOO No. Per 1000 1907 1 1908 1909 1910 1911 1912 1913 1914 1915 1916 1917 1918 1919 1920 1921 1922 5,867,642 7,116,275 7,325,337 7,962,189 7,781,030 7,532,005 7,155,816 6,724,117 6,964,402 7,404,288 9,299,489 10,938,287 11,241,991 9,709,819 8,179,572 7,871,457 24,876 4.23 68,395 9.61 100,650 13.74 123,501 15.51 133,551 17.16 160,122 I 21.27 152,560 21.31 143,699 21.36 158,239 22.72 190,991 25.79 218,928 23.53 222,787 20.38 205,698 18.31 200,917 20.70 173,658 21.35 212,978 27.05 17,117 2.91 24,371 3.42 24,525 3.34 27,638 3.47 27,186 3.49 35,273 4.68 33,001 4.61 29,738 4.42 32,644 4.68 37,085 5.00 46,351 4.98 40,692 3.90 37,600 3.35 37,762 3.99 33,328 4.19 38,804 4.93 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 1 slaughtered, of a type of tuberculosis not sufficiently pro - gressive to lead to the condemnation of the carcasses. No doubt improvements in the technique of meat inspec - tion may be responsible for a greater number of retentions, but under a system of meat inspection operating under the same general rules and supervision, marked differences in their relative number for cattle and swine can not reasonably be expected if a greater proficiency of inspectors were the only factor to be considered in this problem. 'Covers 9 months from October 1, 1906, to June 30, 1907. While during the period under consideration the rate of cattle retentions as compared with condemnations increased 3.7 times, those in swine multiplied 10.8 times under the same meat inspection practices. This great increase in the number of swine found to be tuberculous presented a problem, the solution of which ap - peared to be desirable before adequate control measures could be devised or recommended. In the hope that a solution of the problem may be found this station undertook an in - vestigation and attempted by experimental inquiry to deter- aiu.k % 2. — X umber of xiriiie slaughter mill number &lt;&gt;f animah iwAbmm prepared from data published in Department of Agriculture for I, mi (hiniu/ period 1907-1962 I und condemned. (Table )'&lt; mbook of United states MB, /&gt;. 217.) Yew- Slaughtered | Retaii Condemned — i -i- 907 1 908 909 910 911 912 913. 914. 915. 916 917. . 918 919. . 920 921 922 26,189,026 35,113,077 35,427,931 27,656,021 29,916,363 34,966,378 32,287,538 33,289,705 36,247,958 40,482,799 40,210,847 35,449,247 44,398,389 . 38,981,914 37,702,866 34,416,439 No. 362,445 719,279 860,425 792,176 j 1,117,789 1,643,100 1,809,751 ! 2,201,005 S 2,774,835 ! 3,687,817 3,978,168 3,494,587 4,103,376 4,262,719 4,693,305 5,640,061 Per 1,000 13.83 20.48 24.28 28.64 37.36 47.00 56.05 66.11 76.55 91.09 98.93 98.58 92.42 109.35 124.48 163.87 No. 48,544 77,554 45,113 28,880 31,517 42,267 47,632 48,252 66,023 74,109 76,807 59,740 65,837 65,609 64,830 70,304 PerlfiOO 1.85 2.20 1.27 1.04 1.08 1.21 1.47 1.44 1.82 1.83 1.91 1.68 1.48 1.68 1.71 2.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 mine the infection type of the tuberculosis associated with the animals which constituted the bulk of the retentions. In view of the apparent increased incidence and spread of tuberculosis among poultry in a large hog raising section, of which Nebraska forms a part, the experimental project men - tioned was to a large extent so directed as to prove or dis - prove the hypothesis that avian infection may at least in part be held accountable for the great morbidity rate for tubercu- FlG. 1. — Retentions and condemnations, on account of tuberculosis, per 1000 head of swine slaughtered between 1907 and 1922. losis among swine and its marked increase during the last fifteen years. Evidence that avian infection may cause tuberculosis in swine and that the pathogenicity of the avian type of the tubercle bacillus is not strictly confined to birds has grown in volume since 1904 when Weber and Bofinger (53) demon - strated for the first time the presence of avian tubercle bacilli in the caseous lymphnodes of a three-months-old pig which was otherwise entirely free from tuberculosis. Much of the early work, such as that by Gilbert and Roger (28), Cadiot, Gilbert and Roger (11), Courmont and Dor </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine (17), Maffucci (42), Vignal (51), Kossel, Weber and Heuss (39), and Rabinowitch (47), as well as some of a later date by Koch and Rabinowitch (38), Bang (3), Zwick (54), De Haan (9), Bang (4), Arloing (1), De Jong (22-23), Carl (13), and Zwick and Zeller (55) pertain largely to the re - lation of the avian to the mammalian type of infection and vice versa, and helped to establish a definite technique of differentiation between the two types. As practically all the Fig. 2. — Retentions and condemnations, on account of tuberculosis, per 1000 head of cattle slaughtered between 1907 and 1922 observations made concerned the smaller laboratory animals and fowls they did not disclose the fact that avian infection, aside from poultry, was to be considered as a source of in - fection to other farm animals. The susceptibility of swine to avian tuberculosis was first shown by De Jong (20) in 1905, who 5 years later (21) re - ported a case of spontaneous infection which had produced a generalized tuberculosis necessitating the condemnation of the carcass. He concluded from his observations and experi - ments that swine belong to a category of mammals susceptible </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 to both mammalian and avian tuberculosis. Titze (49) and Kersten and Ungermann (37) on the other hand either failed to transmit avian tuberculosis to swine or could not demon - strate its presence in the tuberculous hogs examined. Weber (54) did not care to exclude the possibility of avian infec - tion in swine, but like Eber (27) did not appear to attach much importance to it. Mohler and Washburn (44-45) of this country demon - strated the susceptibility of swine to poultry tuberculosis and reported an outbreak in Oregon where apparently a spon - taneous transmission had taken place. In 1911 the British Royal Commission on tuberculosis (48) reported that of 59 cases of tuberculosis of swine of which the type of infection was definitely determined, 5 cases showed avian infection, while in another the avian as well as the bovine bacillus were jointly associated with the lesions. Bang (5-6) found evidence indicating the transmission of tuberculosis to swine from an infected flock of poultry and observed further that infected swine gave a stronger reaction to avian tuberculin than to a tuberculin prepared with bacilli of the human type. According to this author avian tubercu - losis is accountable for a part of the swine tuberculosis en - countered in Denmark. This opinion found ample support in the work of Christiansen (14-15) who typed the bacilli found in 118 hogs and demonstrated the presence of avian infection in 86 animals, of the bovine type in 28 animals, while those found in the remaining 4 were classified as atypical. The importance of an avian source of infection in dealing with tuberculosis in swine in Denmark is further emphasized by Bang and Holm (7), Brieg (8-9-10), and others. Eastwood and Griffith (26) found avian infection in 9 of the 34 animals comprising one group examined and in 17 of another group of 59 tuberculous swine. The importance of the avian type of tubercle bacillus as a cause of hog tuberculosis is further emphasized by Junack (35-36), Joest (33), Douma (25), Day (18), De Jong (24), and Helm (30). The various observations and experiments reported fully justified in our local problem serious consideration of a pos - sible avian source. To that end the writers endeavored above all to ascertain the bacillary types found to be present in the lesions examined and to employ such a method that, if avian bacilli were pres- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 9 ent, the fact would hot escape attention. While it was as - sumed that if mammalian types were found, they would be of bovine origin, the scheme of investigation provided for their further typing in case they were found frequently enough to be regarded as factors in the increase of the in - cidence of swine tuberculosis. The results of the inquiry, however, were such as to render the further typing of the mammalian bacilli quite unnecessary. The typing was entirely accomplished by the use of animal inoculations. Altho a number of strains were isolated and brought under cultivation, preference was given to the use of cavias and fowls in order to bring to light the different pathogenic characters of the organisms present in the material studied. This material consisted almost entirely of the cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes of swine affected with the more or less non-progressive forms of tuberculosis, which are the preponderating causes for retentions at abattoirs and which group is more than any other responsible for the increased incidence of swine tuberculosis since 1907. The lymphnodes were secured through the courteous and efficient co-operation of the inspectors in charge of the Fed - eral Meat Inspection Stations of Omaha, Nebraska ; Nebraska City, Nebraska; Sioux City, Iowa, and St. Joseph, Missouri, who also indicated the origin of the swine from which the material was obtained. All the material used in the ex - periment was obtained from Nebraska swine with the ex - ception of one consignment which came from a South Dakota shipment. The latter detail was deemed advisable in order to secure, if possible, surveys of the livestock on the farms of origin. Unfortunately this proved to be possible in only a very few instances. As soon as practicable after the arrival of the material the caseous material of the lymphnodes was removed, examined for bacilli, and brought in suspension for inoculation pur - poses. Two or more cavias were injected subcutaneously in the inner face of the thigh, while two or more fowls were injected intravenously with the same suspension. In ad - dition, the fowls were permitted to eat a quantity of what was left of the lymphnodes after the removal of the caseous material. At times trouble was encountered on account of the presence of septic organisms in the lymphnodes which resulted in the premature deaths of the cavias and very rarely also of </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 11 the fowls. Treatment with very weak solutions of antiform - in was always successful in the prevention of such accidents. In a number of instances a repetition of the inoculation ex - periments became necessary on account of the occurrence of fatal disease among the guinea pigs. Looking forward to such contingencies, a part of the original infective material, kept in cold storage, was always held available until termin - ation of each experiment. The fowls used as test animals were nearly all obtained from the station flock in which no tuberculosis had occurred for at least 6 years. As an additional precaution against the presence of spontaneous disease, all birds entering into the experiment were tested with avian tuberculin. No chickens were procured in the open market and the few not supplied by the station were purchased out of private flocks. The inoculated animals were permitted to live for approxi - mately 3 months, unless any of those infected with the same material died earlier and showed unmistakable evidence of tuberculous infection. In such a case the remaining cavias and fowls would be killed and examined, provided that not less than 8 weeks had passed since the inoculation. No ani - mals were killed and their condition accepted as experimental evidence after a shorter period. The autopsy results enabled the writers to distinguish cer - tain definite groups among the material examined which in their opinion justified the following classifications: Group I: Negative results. In the experiments ranged under this division, tuberculosis was not produced in any of the animals inoculated. In all probability the bacilli of the original lesions had died or were present only in such small numbers as to be incapable of producing disease. Group II: Infection due to a mammalian type of tubercle bacilli. As the base for classification under this group served the fact that the guinea pigs as a result of the inoculation de - veloped a marked, generalized, progressive tuberculosis, while the fowls inoculated with the same material remained entirely free from tuberculous lesions or the latter consisted only of one or two strictly localized, small, non-progressive, indurated, or caseous nodules. Group III: Infection caused by the avian type of Bacillus tuberculosis. If the inoculation caused a manifest, marked, or extensive tuberculosis in the fowls and failed to produce either any lesions at all in the cavias, or such as were so en- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 12 tirely localized, non-progressive, and small as to cause no disturbance in the animal's health or well-being, the results were accepted as evidence of infection by the avian type of bacillus and of a transmission of tuberculosis from poultry to swine. Group IV: Infection of probable avian origin. In a small number of the cases the inoculation experiments resulted in the production of one or two small, isolated, non-progressive nodules in the fowls, while no lesions of any kind could be demonstrated in the cavias. The writers regard such lesions as being due to avian infection, but on account of the possi - bility that a similar lesion could readily have been missed in the cavia, it was thought wise to include this type of results in a separate group. Group V: Infection resulting in the development of tu - berculosis in both cavias and fowls. Results of this nature were classified as due to a mixture of mammalian and avian types of bacilli. The term "mixed types" is used largely because it is convenient. There is, however, no reason to doubt the existence of ambivirulent strains of tubercle bacilli entirely capable of producing tuberculoses of identical sever - ity and type in guinea pigs as well as fowls. In the experi - ments reported at this time, no attempt was made to pur - sue this question any further and hence this group may in - clude infection results by the simultaneous action of avian and mammalian types of bacilli, by the action of mammalian types also capable of producing a marked tuberculosis in fowls, or by the action of avian types endowed also with path - ogenic qualities toward cavias. Here follow statements pertaining to each lymphnode con - signment received and examined, to the inoculation results observed, and to the classification of the infection type of each shipment of swine from which the material was obtained : No. S188. A shipment of 56 hogs by F. M., Platte County. Tu - berculosis in 21 animals. Lesions in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Both fowls developed small lesions in liver and spleen in which bacilli were found to be present. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 13 .No. 3189. A shipment of 59 hogs by A. F., Custer County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Caviaa Fowls Negative A marked tuberculosis of liver and spleen in one fowl and a less extensive infection in the other. In the lesions of the former, bacilli were plentiful but very scarce in those of the latter. No. 3199. A shipment of 66 hogs by J. R. K., Stanton County. Tuberculosis in 5 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli present in lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative or doubtful Classification of infection type — Undetermined. No. 3266. A shipment of 57 hogs by L. B. M., Holt County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lymphnode lesions only. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Developed marked or extensive tu- berculosis of liver and spleen in which bacilli were numerous. No. 3279. A shipment of 68 hogs by D. O'S., South Dakota. Tu - berculosis in 46 animals. Lesions in cervical and mesenteric lymph - nodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Slight tuberculous lesions de- veloped in liver and spleen in which bacilli were present. No. 3422. A shipment of 71 hogs by A. L., Cuming County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lymphnode lesions only in which bacilli were found to be present. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative . Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 3445. A shipment of 51 hogs by E. N., Dodge County. Tuber - culosis in 28 animals. Lesions in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in which bacilli were found to be present. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Slight lesions in one fowl only. Bacilli present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Probably avian. No. 3477. A shipment of 83 hogs by T. E. K., Holt County. Tuber - culosis in 15 animals. Bacilli found to be present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of the liver and spleen of one fowl. Bacilli present in the lesions, but not numerous. The other fowl showed no evidence of disease. Classification of infection type Avian. No. H99. A shipment of 82 hogs by R. A. G., Buffalo County. Tu - berculosis in 16 animals. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative In one fowl no lesions could be found. The other one showed one tuberculous nodule in the spleen in which bacilli could be shown Classification of infection type = Probably avian. No. 3500. A shipment of 65 hogs by F. S., Holt County. Tuber - culosis in 13 animals. Bacilli could be shown in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative In one fowl lesions could not be found, while in the other liver and spleen showed a marked tuberculosis with an abundance of bacilli present in the lesions. No. 3533. A shipment of 55 hogs by T. B. B., Boone County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Slight lesions of cervical lymphnodes in which bacilli could not be found. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 15 No. 3553. A shipment of 60 hogs by G. R., Cuming County. Tu - berculosis in 37 animals. Lesions of cervical and mesenteric lymph - nodes. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked or extensive tuberculosis of liver and spleen. Bacilli very numerous in the lesions. No. 3610. A shipment of 13 hogs by G. R., Nemaha County. Tu - berculosis in three animals. Slight calcareous lesions in cervical lymph - nodes in which bacilli were present. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of spleens and livers. Bacilli were present in the le- .V". 3611. A shipment of 11 hogs by W. H. K., Nemaha County. Tuberculosis in 3 animals. Slight caseo-calcareous lesions of cervical lymphnodes in which bacilli were present. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens in which enormous masses of bacilli could be shown. No. 3912. A shipment of 3 hogs by A. M., Nemaha County. Tu - berculosis in one animal. Slight caseo-calcareous lesions in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative One fowl showed no lesions and the other one only one small nod- ule in the spleen in which bacilli were numerous. Classification of infection type = Probably Avian. No. 3613. A shipment of 10 hogs by J. F. C, Nemaha County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Slight lesions in the cervical and well marked caseo-calcareous lesions in the mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens. A moderate number of bacilli were found to be present in the Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 3614. A shipment of 10 hogs by H. C. S., Otoe County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Slight lesions in the cervical lymphnodes and well marked or extensive caseo-calcareous lesions of the mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Slight tuberculous lesions of spleen and liver in which bacilli were No. S615. A shipment of 5 hogs by P. B., Otoe County. Tuber - culosis in 2 animals. Slight lesions of the cervical lymphnodes and well marked or extensive caseo-calcareous lesions of the mesenteric lymph - nodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens. Bacilli were plentiful in the le- sions. Classification of infection type — Avian. No. 3616. A shipment of 7 hogs by H. H., Johnson County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Slight caseo-calcareous lesions of cervical lymphnodes in which bacilli were found to be present. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens. Bacilli were plentiful in the lesions. No. S617. A shipment of 17 hogs by F. M., Otoe County. Tuber - culosis in 3 animals. Slight and extensive lesions in cervical, bronchial, portal, and mesenteric lymphnodes and in lungs, liver and spleen. Bacilli were found to be present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative One fowl showed no lesions and the other one a slight tuberculosis of the liver, in the lesions of which bacilli were present in No. 3618. A shipment of 15 hogs by R. K., Nemaha County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Slight lesions of the mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens. Bacilli were present in the le- present. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. abundance. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 17 No. S619. A shipment of 7 hogs by P. F. N., Otoe County. Tuber - culosis in 3 animals. Slight or slightly caseo-calcareous lesions in liver and in cervical, bronchial, portal, and mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavia8 Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of spleens and livers in the lesions of which bacilli were present. No. 3629. A shipment of 62 hogs by G. J., Thurston County. Tu - berculosis in 19 animals, cervical lymphnodes affected in 14 and mes - enteric lymphnodes in 5 animals. All lesions were old and calcareous and bacilli could scarcely be found in them. ' Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative in one fowl while the other showed 3 small tuberculous nodules in which bacilli could not be found. No. 3701. A shipment of 65 hogs by J. L., Stanton County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Slight lesions of cervical and mesenteric lymph - nodes in which bacilli could be found. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked and extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens. Bacilli could be shown in the lesions. No. 3732. A shipment of 63 hogs by N. V. P., Burt County. Tu - berculosis in 26 animals; cervical lesions shown in 15 and mesenteric lesions in 11 animals. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens. Bacilli present in the lesions. No. 3909. A shipment of 56 hogs by F. M. A., Holt County. Tu - berculosis in 23 animals. Lesions of cervical and mesenteric lymph - nodes. Bacilli were abundant in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined, Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Probably Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 18 No. 3931. A shipment of 45 hogs by C. F. F., Madison County. Tu - berculosis in 34 animals. Bacilli present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Extensive, generalized and pro- Negative gressive tuberculosis in both cavias. Material contained but few bacilli. Classification of infection type = Mammalian. No. 3999. Tuberculous mesenteric lymphnodes from a hog affected with hog cholera examined for C. W. M., Cass County. Bacilli present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of spleens and livers. Bacilli were present in the le- No. 4006. Tuberculous mesenteric lymphnodes of a hog affected with hog-cholera submitted by W. D., Cass County. Bacilli were abun - dant in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers in the lesions of which bacilli were present. No. J032. A shipment of 61 hogs by P. C. A., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 17 animals: 11, cervical lymphnodes; 5, mesenteric lymph - nodes; one, cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were found to be plentiful in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens with bacilli present in the le- No. +126. A shipment of 81 hogs by F. W. S., Saunders County. Tuberculosis in 18 animals. Lesions in cervical and mesenteric lymph - nodes. Bacilli were abundant in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 19 No. 1,133. A shipment of 48 hogs by C. C, Buffalo County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Slight lesions of the cervical lymphnodes in which bacilli were present. Inoculation Results Cai-ias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, lungs, and cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. U1US. A shipment of 4 hogs by J. G., Nemaha County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Extensive lesions of liver, and lungs, and cer - vical, bronchial, portal, and mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were pres - ent in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Tuberculosis in all 4 cavias, but Negative only in one was the disease gen - eralized and progressive Classification of infection type = Mammalian No. U1UU- A shipment of 25 hogs by D. E. W., Richardson County. Tuberculosis in 13 animals. Slight lesions of cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes. The lesions contained many bacilli. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens with bacilli present in the le- No. UU5. A shipment of 5 hogs by A. F. D., Otoe County. Tuber - culosis of one animal. Slight lesions of cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined No. AH.6. A shipment of 29 hogs by F. P., Otoe County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Slight lesions in cervical lymphnodes and in one case also extensive lesions of mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were abundant in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of spleens and livers. Bacilli were present in the le- Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 4147. A shipment of 4 hogs by L. E., Nemaha County. Tu - berculosis in one animal. Slight lesions of cervical lymphnodes in which bacilli were present. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. 4.H8. A shipment of 22 hogs by L. A., Nemaha County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in lungs and liver and in cervical, bronchial, portal, and mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Generalized, progressive tubercu - losis in 3 cavias, while the fourth presented no lesions. One fowl presented an isolated nodule in the spleen while the other showed marked tubercu - losis of the liver, several nod - ules in the spleen, and a few in the intestine. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mixed. No. iU9. A shipment of 8 hogs by F. H., Otoe County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Slight lesions of cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli could not be found in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. 4150. A shipment of 6 hogs by C. W., Nemaha County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Slight lesions of cervical lymphnodes. Ba - cilli were not found in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Bacilli present in the lesions. No. 4151. A shipment of 10 hogs by H. M., Nemaha County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Slight lesions of cervical lymphnodes. Ba - cilli could not be found in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 21 No. 4152. A shipment of 11 hogs by W. G., Otoe County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Slight lesions of cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of spleens and livers of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. -Vo. A15S. A shipment of 15 hogs by A. L., Otoe County. Tu - berculosis of 4 animals. Lesions of cervical and mesenteric lymph - nodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavia8 Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in liver, spleen, kidneys, and lungs. Bacilli plentiful in the lesions. No. 4163. A shipment of 79 hogs by E. H. W., Otoe County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. 4193. Lesions from 3 hogs which had reacted to a tuberculin test. The lesions were slight and bacilli were scarce in them. Hogs owned by G. H., Buffalo County. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls^ Negative A slight tuberculosis of the liver and spleen of one fowl and ex- tensive tuberculous lesions in those of the other fowl. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 4366. Shipment of 150 hogs by O. C, Saline County. Tu - berculosis in 24 animals. Lesions of lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens. Bacilli present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. J,388. A shipment of 68 hogs by F. U-, Madison County. Tu - berculosis in 13 animals. Slight lesions of cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes. Bacilli were found to be numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in liver, spleen, lungs, and mesentery. Bacilli were very numerous in the No. U09. A shipment of 9 hogs by W. M. M., Otoe County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in which bacilli were numerous. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in spleen, liver, lungs, gall bladder, and mesen- tery. Bacilli numerous in the No. iiH. A shipment of 56 hogs by E. H., Cuming County. Tu - berculosis in 10 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one animal. A few bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Slight tuberculosis of the livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. H16. A shipment of 70 hogs by M. J., Boyd County. Tubercu - losis in 26 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes, 15; in mesenteric lymphnodes, 7; and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes, 4. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias . Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, lungs, and mesentery. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 23 No. U17. A shipment of 75 hogs by J. R. M., Holt County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 7 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, lungs, kidneys, and mesentery. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. No. W8. A shipment of 64 hogs by P. S., Boone County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers of both and the spleen of one fowl. Bacilli were plentiful in the No. 448S. A shipment of 71 hogs by G. H. S., Dodge County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 4, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were very numerous in the No. UH- A shipment of 72 hogs by H. E. R., Nance County. Tu - berculosis of 17 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 10, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 4, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 3. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis in both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. HS5. A shipment of 50 hogs by H. J. N., Dodge County. Tu - berculosis in 10 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Generalized, progressive tubercu - losis in 2 cavias and a more localized form of the disease in one. A moderate degree of tuberculosis in both fowls. Bacilli were nu - merous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mixed. Classification of infection type = Avian. material. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. HS7. A shipment of 68 hogs by W. S., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 23 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 21, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli numerous in the lesions. Caseous lymphadenitis near inocu - lation point. Bacilli present in the material. No tuberculous lesions in any other part. No. W8. A shipment of 82 hogs by E. S., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 29 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 15, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 12, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and mesentery. Bacilli were very numerous in the material. No. UUU6. A shipment of 73 hogs by W. P., Hamilton County. Tu - berculosis in 7 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Slight degree of tuberculosis of the livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the le- No. H56. A shipment of 61 hogs by J. C. C, Platte County. Tu - berculosis in 26 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 17, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 7, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls, with bacilli very numerous in the No. WU- A shipment of 64 hogs by F. F. P., Burt County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli rather numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined, Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 25 No. 4476. A shipment of 76 hogs by P. X. P., Burt County. Tu - berculosis in 16 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 7. Bacilli numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli were numer- ous in the lesions. No. 448S. A shipment of 74 hogs by E. S., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Slight lesions in cervical lymphnodes in which bacilli were numerous. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Slight tuberculous lesions in both fowls. A number of nodules in livers of both and spleen of one. Bacilli were plentiful in the le- No. 4506. A shipment of 58 hogs by S. P., Gage County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Slight lesions in cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Negative Marked or extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and peritoneum. Bacilli were present in the lesions. So. 4516. A shipment of 73 hogs by E. F., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one, and cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were numerous in the le- No. 4525. A shipment of 55 hogs by H. P., Platte County. Tu - berculosis in 41 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 34, in mes - enteric lymphnodes 3, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes 4. Bacilli were plentiful in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Cavias Fowls Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 4534. A shipment of 60 hogs by H. S., Gage County. Tu - berculosis in 10 animals. Slight lesions in the cervical lymphnodes of 9 and in the mesenteric lymphnodes of one. Bacilli were present in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. No. 45S6. A shipment of 76 hogs by J. S., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 23 head. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes in 20 and of mes - enteric lymphnodes in 3. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls One cavia developed extensive tu - berculosis of liver and spleen and lymphnodes. Another showed a nonprogressive or arrested tuberculosis and a third was found to be free of lesions. Tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens with an abundance of bacilli. Classification of infection type Mixed. No. 454S. A shipment of 63 hogs by H. G. L., Platte County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes in 3, and of mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were plentiful in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Two small nodules in the spleen of one fowl. Bacilli present but scarce in the lesions. The other fowl presented no le- No. 4550. A shipment of 62 hogs by A. A., Polk County. Tubercu - losis in 39 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 16, in mesenteric lymphnodes in 15, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 8. Ba - cilli were numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli were very numer- ous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Probably Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 27 No. 4565. Some tuberculous lymphnodes of a hog slaughtered by I. W. P., Saunders County. Bacilli were very scarce in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Extensive, generalized, progres- Negative sive tuberculosis of all 4 cavias. Bacilli present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mammalian. No. 4619. A shipment of 69 hogs by J. W. K., Boone County. Tu - berculosis in 16 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 10. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis in livers and spleens of both fowls, with ba- cilli numerous in the lesions. No. 4626. A shipment of 58 hogs by E. O., Lancaster County. Tu - berculosis in 19 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes in 12, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 6, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of both fowls. Le- sions in spleens and livers. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. 4627. A shipment of 65 hogs by C. W. J., Boone County. Tu - berculosis in 14 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes in 7, and of mesenteric lymphnodes in 7. Bacilli were present in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Generalized, progressive tubercu - losis in 2 cavias. Localized, non - progressive tuberculosis in one cavia. Bacilli were present in all lesions. Tuberculosis in both fowls. Le - sions in spleens and livers. Ba - cilli were numerous in the le - sions. Classification of infection type = Mixed. No. 4643. A shipment of 71 hogs by J. B. P., Burt County. Tu - berculosis in 10 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 7, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Marked, progressive, generalized Slight tuberculosis of livers and tuberculosis in all cavias. spleens of both fowls, with ba - cilli present in the lesions either numerously or in moderate num - bers. Classification of infection type = Mixed. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 28 No. 4658. A shipment of 60 hogs by A. V., Colfax County. Tu - berculosis in 40 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 22, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 12, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 6. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were numerous. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 4659. A shipment of 64 hogs by F. P., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 10 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 8, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked and extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli very nu- merous in the lesions. No. 4668. A shipment of 60 hogs by W. B., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 28 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 23, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 3, in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one, and generalized tuberculosis in one. Bacilli were numerous in the le - sions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens. and lungs. Bacilli present in the No. 4669. A shipment of 63 hogs by E. H., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 12 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 11, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative in one cavia. Very ex - tensive, progressive tuberculosis in the other. Bacilli were nu - merous in the spleen lesions. One fowl presented lesions which were probably tuberculous in character, but in which bacilli could not be found. The other fowl showed a mod - erate degree of tuberculosis, probably of a non-progressive type. Bacilli were numerous in some of the lesions. Classification of infection type Mixed. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 29 No. 4670. A shipment of 60 hogs by P. N. P., Buffalo County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Fowls Cavias Of the 3 cavias one showed a caseated lymphnode containing bacilli. No other lesions were found in those animals. Marked or extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 4671. A shipment of 60 hogs by E. F., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 38 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 29, in raes - enteric lymphnodes in 4, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were pres - ent in the lesions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 4687. A shipment of 68 hogs by L. B. B., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 35 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 29, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 6. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were found to be present. No. 4688. A shipment of 66 hogs by A. S. W., Cuming County. Tu - berculosis in 7 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavt'as Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined No. 4689. A shipment of 63 hogs by E. H., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes in 3, of mes - enteric lymphnodes in 3, and of cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions of spleens and livers with bacilli present. Classification of infection type -■= Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. A690. A shipment of 55 hogs by C. S., Burt County. Tubercu - losis in 11 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes in 4, of mesenteric lymphnodes in 5, and of cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Ba - cilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls with bacilli present in the No. 4697. A shipment of 46 hogs by L. W. C, Thurston County. Tuberculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 2, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 4. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli were plenti- ful in the lesions. No. 4711. A shipment of 61 hogs by R. B., Hamilton County. Tu - berculosis in 15 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 10, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were very numerous in the ma - terial. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative - A moderate degree of tuberculosis of the spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. 4712. A shipment of 54 hogs by H. W. M., Dodge County. Tu - berculosis in 7 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5, and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were present in the le- No. 4713* A shipment of 63 hogs by G. W., Cuming County. Tu - berculosis in 30 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes in 10, of mes - enteric lymphnodes in 12, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 8. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of the livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 31 No. 4718. A shipment of 60 hogs by H. A. K., Platte County. Tu - berculosis in 15 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 12, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 2, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 4723. A shipment of 58 hogs by J. J. B., Saunders County. Tu - berculosis in 16 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 12, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 4. Bacilli were very numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were present in the le- No. 47 9i. Tuberculous cervical lymphnodes from hogs shipped by J. S., Hitchcock County. Very slight lesions in which bacilli were ex - ceedingly scarce. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. 4767. A shipment of 63 hogs by R. P., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 24 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 14, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 7, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes 3. Bacilli were found to be present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were very numerous in the No. 4768. A shipment of 60 hogs by A. B., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 19 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 16, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one. One animal sterilized. Bacilli found to be present in the ma - terial. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative, with exception of some non-progressive lesions in the spleen of one of the 4 cavias. Very extensive tuberculosis of the livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were found to be present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 32 No. W69. A shipment of 65 hogs by A. F., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 56 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 42, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 2, in mesenteric and cervical lymphnodes 4. Animals sterilized 4 and animals condemned 4. Bacilli were present in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Foivls Marked or extensive, generalized, Negative and progressive tuberculosis in the 4 cavias. Bacilli were found to be present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mammalian. No. U770. A shipment of 60 hogs by B. F. M., Antelope County. Tuberculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 3 and in the mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were found to be present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Very slight tuberculous lesions in the livers of both fowls. Only in one fowl could bacilli be found to be present in moderate num - bers. Negative with the exception of a small necrotic area in the liver of one of the cavias. In this le - sion one bacillus only could be found. Classification of infection type = Probably Avian. No. i771. A shipment of 60 hogs by W. C. P., Antelope County. Tuberculosis in 7 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. The presence of bacilli in this material was very doubtful. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. U772. A shipment of 77 hogs by F L., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were probably present in the material, but very scarce and difficult to be recognized as such. Inoculation Results Cavias Foiols Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined No. U77S. A shipment of 63 hogs by S. H., Dakota County. Tu - berculosis in 14 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were found to be numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli were numer- ous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 33 No. 4789. Tuberculous lymphnodes of swine shipped by G. B., Hitchcock County. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavxas Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. No. 4792. A shipment of 62 hogs by H. R. N., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 24 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 20, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 4. Bacilli were found to be numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Caviaa Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and mesentery. Bacilli were abund- ant in the lesions. No. 4793. A shipment of 74 hogs by H. M., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 28 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 16, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 6, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 6. Bacilli were very numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative with the exception of a small necrotic focus in the liver of one cavia in which bacilli could be found. A localized, non - progressive lesion. Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba - cilli were numerous in the le - sions. No. 4794. A shipment of 65 hogs by C. T., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 17 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 11, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 5, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Marked and extensive, general- Negative ized, progressive tuberculosis of both cavias. Bacilli were pres - ent in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mammalian. No. 4795. A shipment of 63 hogs by R. L., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 61 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 50, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 9, one animal sterilized and one condemned. Ba - cilli were found to be present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Extensive, generalized, progressive Negative tuberculosis of both cavias. Classification of infection type = Mammalian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 4796. A shipment of 76 hogs by J. L., Knox County. Tubercu - losis in 4 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A slight tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were found to be present in the No. 4797. A shipment of 64 hogs by C. M. M., Antelope County. Tuberculosis in 13 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 4, in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 7. Bacilli were found to be very numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 4807. A shipment of 67 hogs by J. H., Knox County. Tubercu - losis in 15 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 13 and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were found to be very numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive and marked tu- berculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were found to be present in the No. 4808. A shipment of 43 hogs by S. N. D., Kearney County. Tu - berculosis in 10 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 8 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were very numerous in this ma - terial. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of both fowls. Le- sions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 4809. A shipment of 64 hogs by W. E. F., Cedar County. Le - sions of cervical lymphnodes only. Number of animals retained not known. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Caviaa Fowls Negative A slight tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were found to be present in the lesions. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">INCREASE IN TUBERCULOSIS OF SWINE 35 No. 4815. A shipment of 51 hogs by H. J. H., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in one animal. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were found to be pres- ent in the lesions. No. 4816. A shipment of 62 hogs by E. B., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. The presence of bacilli in this material was doubtful. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined, No. 4817. A shipment of 69 hogs by H. S., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Lesions in mesenteric lymphnodes only. Ba - cilli were scarce in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined, No. 4818. A shipment of 66 hogs by A. S., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. The pres - ence of bacilli in this material was doubtful. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined, No. 4829. A shipment of 70 hogs by A. J. E., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 28 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 16, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 7, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of the spleen and livers of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 4830. A shipment of 69 hogs by C. A. J., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis of 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavia.8 Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and intestine. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. No. 4835. A shipment of 67 hogs by W. R., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis of 14 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 7 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 7. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavia8 Fowls Negative Negative in one fowl while in the other one a nodule was found in the liver in which bacilli were present. Classification of infection type = Probably Avian. No. 48S6. A shipment of 25 hogs by D. H., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 17 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 4 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 13. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavia.8 Fowls Negative Marked or extensive tuberculosis of the livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. No. 4837. A shipment of 53 hogs by G. A. J., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 20 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 13 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 7. Bacilli were present in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in spleens and livers. Bacilli were present in the No. 4861. A shipment of 71 hogs by O. E. M., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were found to be Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. present. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 37 No. 4862. A shipment of 72 hogs by C. C. B., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls A marked tuberculosis of both cavias, but apparently the dis - ease was not progressive. Ba - cilli could not be found in the lesions. Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Legions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mixed. No. 1,863. A shipment of 37 hogs by A. S., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. As the lesions were of an extremely doubtful character and no bacilli could be found this material was discarded. No. 4864. A shipment of 61 hogs by T. S., Dakota County. Tu - berculosis in 21 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were very numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis of the livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the le- No. 4865. A shipment of 81 hogs by A. B., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 7 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were very numerous in the ma - terial. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. 4866. A shipment of 71 hogs by G. H., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 10 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were found to be present in the lesions. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. U867. A shipment of 60 hogs by M. B., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 28 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 26 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked and very extensive tu- berculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. No. JfSGS. A shipment of 30 hogs by E. N., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 7 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions of livers and spleens. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. No. J,869. A shipment of 66 hogs by C. A. B., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli could not be found in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined No. A870. A shipment of 68 hogs by L. F. S., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli present in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Extensive, progressive, general - ized tuberculosis in all 3 cavias. Bacilli scarce in the lesions. A moderate degree of tuberculosis in livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mixed. No. A871. A shipment of 66 hogs by C. E. E., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions only in cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Both cavias died with marked tu - berculosis after one month fol - lowing inoculation. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Both fowls developed small, local lesions in about 10 weeks tims. Bacilli were extremely rare in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mammalian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 39 No. 4872. A shipment of 73 hogs by N. F. T., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Doubtful lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli could not be found in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined, No. 4881. A shipment of 66 hogs by A. G., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli were very numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and one spleen. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 4882. A shipment of 42 hogs for B. B., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis in livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba - cilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 4883. A shipment of 53 hogs by R. H. T., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were present in the le- No. 4909. A shipment of 69 hogs by F. T., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli could not be found in this ma - terial. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. ±910. A shipment of 39 hogs by W. P., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 17 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9, in portal lymphnodes in one, and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 7. Bacilli were found to be present in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Marked, generalized, progressive tuberculosis in the cavia. Ba - cilli were present in moderate numbers. One fowl showed slight tubercu - lous lesions of the spleen in which bacilli were extremely rare. The other fowl presented no lesions. Classification of infection type Mammalian. No. 4911. A shipment of 67 hogs by W. G., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 19 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 14 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were present in the le - sions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 4912. A shipment of 75 hogs by A. A. S., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 19 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 11 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 8. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative ■ Very extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions of livers, spleens, lungs-, and peritoneum. Bacilli were abundant in the lesions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 4913. A shipment of 70 hogs by C. J. E., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 7 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 4. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative in one fowl and a moder- ate degree of tuberculosis in the other. Lesions in liver and spleen in which bacilli were present. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 41 No. A921. A shipment of 77 hogs by C. S., Antelope County. Tu - berculosis in 16 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavia8 Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were numerous in the No. 4922. A shipment of 71 hogs by S. &amp; N., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 14 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 13 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Slight tuberculosis in the livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. 4923. A shipment of 70 hogs by W. Bros., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were very scarce in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined No. 4924. A shipment of 60 hogs by A. W. M., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 18 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 12 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 6. Bacilli were very numerous in the ma - terial. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, lungs, and kidneys. Bacilli were numerous in the material. No. 4925. A shipment of 72 hogs by F. W., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 21 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 19 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both -fowls. Ba- cilli were numerous in the le- lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 4926. A shipment of 66 hogs by C. T., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 3. Bacilli were very numerous in this ma - terial. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of both fowls. Le- sions in liver and spleens. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. 4930. A shipment of 34 hogs by A. P., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in one animal. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the material, but very scarce. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined No. 4938. Tuberculous lesions of hogs shipped by E. E. C, Clay County. Bacilli were very numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the le- No. 4948. A shipment of 60 hogs by E. E., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. The pres - ence of bacilli in the lesions was quite doubtful. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined No. 4949. A shipment of 65 hogs by F. R., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 18 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 17 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A slight tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were present in the le- Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Increase in Tuberculosis op Swine 43 No. 4950. A shipment of 65 hogs by F. E. H., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were very numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked or extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 4951. A shipment of 58 hogs by W. L., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the No. 4964. A shipment of 70 hogs by O. O., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 23 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 15 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 8. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavia8 Fowls Negative One fowl died prematurely of sepsis, showing no evidence of tuberculosis. The other one de- veloped extensive tuberculosis of liver and spleen. Bacilli wen- present in the lesions. No. 4965. A shipment of 71 hogs by L. H., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 24 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 17 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 7. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavia8 Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of liver and spleen of one fowl and a slight degree of tuberculosis in the same organs of the other one. Bacilli were present in the le- lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 44 No. 4966. A shipment of 71 hogs by B. W. R., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 22 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 21 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were very numerous in this ma - terial. Inoculation Results Caviag Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis in both fowls, Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were present in the le- No. 1967. A shipment of 59 hogs by F. W., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 6. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative in one fowl, and in the other there was a moderate de- gree of tuberculosis of liver and spleen. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type-— Avian. No. 4968. A shipment of 54 hogs by W. F. B., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 10 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of the livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were numerous in the No. 4969. A shipment of 46 hogs by O. L., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls One cavia died prematurely and Exten showed a caseous lymphnode and near inoculation point. The cilli other cavia died with an ex - tensive tuberculosis of liver, spleen, and precrural lymph - nodes. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Classification of infection type = Mixed. Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba - cilli were present in the lesions. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 45 No. 4970. A shipment of 72 hogs by J. J., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in the cervical lymphnodes only. Ba - cilli were very numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba - cilli were numerous in the le - sions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 4971. A shipment of 31 hogs by O. L., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 3 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 3. Bacilli were very numerous in this ma - terial. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked or extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and mesentery. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 4972. A shipment of 56 hogs by T. W., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 4 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were very numerous in this ma - terial. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative One fowl died prematurely and showed no tuberculosis, and the other developed slight tubercu- lous lesions of the liver in which bacilli were numerous. No. 4973. A shipment of 56 hogs by J. Mel., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 4974. A shipment of 70 hogs by V. J., Dixon County. Tubercu - losis in one animal. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 4975. A shipment of 45 hogs by C. B., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in one animal. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions but were atypical in form. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. 5002. Tuberculous lymphnodes of hogs shipped by A. Bros., Kearney County. The presence of bacilli was questionable. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. SOU. A shipment of 42 hogs by M. O. N., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba - cilli were numerous in the le - sions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 5015. A shipment of 73 hogs by C. L., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 10 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 50S6. A shipment of 66 hogs by P. D., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 17 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 10 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 7. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Increase in Tuberculosis op Swine 47 No. 5027. A shipment of 69 hogs by E. C. A., Holt County. Tu - berculosis in 16 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 14 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 5028. A shipment of 75 hogs by G. F., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 15 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 13 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in moderate numbers in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowl* Extensive, generalized, progres- Marked tuberculosis of both fowls, sive tuberculosis in both cavias. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were present in the le- Bacilli were found to be present sions. in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mixed. No. 5029. A shipment of 61 hogs by W. B., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis of 12 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the le- No. 5030. A shipment of 72 hogs by F. S., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 2 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 4. Bacilli were present in the lesions but very scarce. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. 5031. A shipment of 61 hogs by F. W., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in moderate numbers in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls, with bacilli numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 5032. A shipment of 65 hogs by S. K. L., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Slight tuberculosis in liver and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 5033. A shipment of 44 hogs by L. A., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis of 2 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias . Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were numerous in the le- No. 5QSU- A shipment of 56 hogs by W. T., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked or extensive tuberculosis in all 3 fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were found to be present. No. 5035. A shipment of 60 hogs by C. J. D., Dakota County. Tu - berculosis in one animal. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. This material was so unpromising that it was discarded. No. 5052. Tuberculous material obtained from a shipment of 127 hogs by B. S., Richardson County. Bacilli were present in this ma - terial in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Both cavias developed a non-pro - gressive, localized type of tu - berculosis. Bacilli were present in the lesions. The cavias were killed in 3 months after inocu - lation and were at that time quite fat and in excellent physi - cal condition. A moderate or slight degree of tu - berculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were found to be present. Classification of infection type = Mixed. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 49 No. 5094. Tuberculous material obtained from a shipment of 62 hogs by J. S., Saline County. Bacilli were very numerous in this ma - terial. Inoculation Results Carina Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of the liver and spleen of both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. 5095. A shipment of 64 hogs by J. L. L., Antelope County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavia8 Fowls Negative Marked or extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 5096. A shipment of 54 hogs by J. R., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 3 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias FowU Both cavias, when killed, showed a number of small abscesses of the spleen, which were probably of tuberculous origin since in one organisms were found which to all appearances were poorly stained tubercle bacilli. Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 5097. A shipment of 75 hogs by J. F., Knox County. Tubercu - losis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 7 and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the material in mod - erate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias . Fowls Negative One died prematurely without showing evidence of tuberculosis. The other showed one small tu- berculous nodule in the spleen in which a few bacilli could be Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. found. Classification of infection type = Probably Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 5098. A shipment of 62 hogs by H. A. P., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions in mod - erate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were No. 5099. A shipment of 47 hogs by W. S., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5 and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 3. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls with bacilli pres- ent in the lesions. Classification of infection type — Avian. No. 5100. A shipment of 71 hogs by R. N., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 12 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls One cavia died with very exten- Negative sive, generalized, progressive tu - berculosis. Bacilli were numer - ous in the lesions. The other cavia, killed, in an extremely emaciated condition, revealed not the slightest evidence of tu - berculosis. Classification of infection type = Mammalian. No. 5101. A shipment of 57 hogs by L. N., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 13 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative All 3 fowls developed a moderate degree of tuberculosis. Lesions in spleen and livers in which ba- cilli were plentiful. numerous. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 51 No. 5102. A shipment of hogs by G. S., Knox County. Tuberculosis in 12 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 6. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. No. 5103. A shipment of 67 hogs by J. R., Knox County. Tubercu - losis in 14 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive or marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 5104. A shipment of 22 hogs by W. B., Thurston County. Tu - berculosis in 14 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis in both fowla. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were plentiful. No. 5120. Tuberculous lymphnodes obtained from a shipment of 64 hogs by L. D. C, Hitchcock County. Bacilli were scarce in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were found to be present in the le- No. 5140. A shipment of 33 hogs by W. V., Dakota County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked or extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 5141. A shipment of 62 hogs by R. G. R., Antelope County. Tuberculosis in 2 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in one and in the mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were No. 5142. A shipment of 68 hogs by P. J. B., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 7 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 4 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 3. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. 514S. A shipment of 77 hogs by A. O., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were found to be numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli could be found to be pres- No. 5167. A shipment of 49 hogs by K. E., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 7 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were found to be present in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were present. No. 5168. A shipment of 77 hogs by P. A., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 3. Bacilli were found to occur in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked or extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and mesentery. Bacilli were present in the lesions. present. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. ent. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Increase in Tuberculosis op Swine 53 No. 5169. A shipment of 65 hogs by L. K., Knox County. Tubercu - losis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 2 and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very . extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the le- No. 5170. A shipment of 65 hogs by E. A. K., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 2 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis in both fowls. Le- sions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were present. No. 5182. A shipment of 66 hogs by H. B. Z., Buffalo County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Slight cervical lesions only, in which bacilli were present. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A marked or moderate degree of tuberculosis in both fowls. Le- sions in livers and spleens. Ba- cilli were present in the ma- No. 5183. A shipment of 58 hogs by A. D., Hamilton County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions of cervical lymphnodes in 4 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. 5190. A shipment of 66 hogs by F. E. Co., Platte County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Slight lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 2 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive or marked tubercu- losis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type= Avian. terial. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 5191. A shipment of 65 hogs by J. C. F., Madison County. Tu - berculosis in 15 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 8 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 7. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were to be found in the lesions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 5192. A shipment of 62 hogs by W. O., Platte County. Tu - berculosis in 20 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 14 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 6. Bacilli were present in lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type Avian. No. 5193. A shipment of 69 hogs by J. C. F., Madison County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Slight lesions in cervical lypmhnodes in 8 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were No. 519b. A shipment of 64 hogs by H. &amp; O., Nance County. Tu - berculosis in 13 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 9 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 4. Bacilli numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. Wo. 5195. A shipment of 58 hogs by F. J. N., Antelope County. Tuberculosis in 12 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 7 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. present. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 55 No. 5198. A shipment of 60 hogs by F. J. L., Boyd County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 8 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A slight tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 5201. A shipment of 79 hogs by W. F. L., Wayne County. Mesenteric lesions only. Bacilli were very numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 5202. Tuberculous lymphnodes obtained from a shipment of 47 hogs by H. B., Cedar County. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. No. 5203. Tuberculous lymphnodes obtained from a shipment of 73 hogs by A. S., Wayne County. Bacilli were very numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and in- testine in which bacilli were No. 5207. A shipment of 76 hogs by G. M. R., Nance County. Tu - berculosis in 12 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 7 and mes - enteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis in both fowls, ex- tensive lesions in livers and spleens of one fowl and slight lesions in the liver of the other one. Bacilli were present in the Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. present. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 56 No. 5208. A shipment of 70 hogs by A. K., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis of 35 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 12, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 11, and cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive and marked tubercu- losis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. No. 5213. A shipment of 60 hogs by S. C, Antelope County. Tu - berculosis in 6 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. 5214. A shipment of 75 hogs by F. G., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 15 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 13 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in this material, but very scarce. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined. No. 5215. A shipment of 74 hogs by R. H., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 25 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 15 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 10. Bacilli were numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined No. 5216. A shipment of 72 hogs by G. W. C, Greeley County. Tu - berculosis in 19 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 11 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 8. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative One fowl showed no lesions while the other developed a marked tu- berculosis of liver and spleen in the lesions of which bacilli were Classification of infection type = Avian. present. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 57 No. 5219. A shipment of 56 hogs by H. K., Platte County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 3. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis in both fowls. Le- sions in livers and spleens. Ba- cilli were present in the lesions. No. 5220. A shipment of 67 hogs by H. &amp; L., Howard County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 4 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 4. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias &lt; Fowls « Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. - No. 5224. A shipment of 78 hogs by J. V., Dodge County. Tu - berculosis in 17 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 11. Bacilli numerous in this material. Inoculation Results A 11 W Ulill 1 1V11 -l.«C«OU UlLl Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli present in the lesions. No. 5225. A shipment of 73 hogs by U. G. B., Burt County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative with the exception of one small nodule in the liver of one in which a few bacilli could be found. Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the le - sions in enormous numbers. No. 5226. A shipment of 79 hogs by C. C, Howard County. Tu - berculosis in 7 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 1. Bacilli were present in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Marked tuberculosis of livers, spleens, lungs, and lymphnodes of both cavias. Apparently dis - ease was a non-progressive type. Both cavias were in good phys - ical condition, about 11 weeks after inoculation. Bacilli were present in the lesions in mod - erate numbers. Very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mixed. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 58 No. 5227. A shipment of 60 hogs by W. W. S., Antelope County. Tuberculosis in 7 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in one and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 6. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis in both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli very numerous in the material. No. 5231. A shipment of 70 hogs by S. S., Fillmore County. Tu - berculosis in 7 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative with the exception of caseous lymphnodes near point of inoculation. A moderate degree of tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 5237. A shipment of 66 hogs by E. P., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 17 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 12, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 4, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative in one cavia, in the other very extensive tuberculosis of liver and spleen. Extensive tu - berculosis of lungs and inguinal lymphnodes. Bacilli were pres - ent in the spleen but very scarce. Very extensive tuberculosis in liver and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mixed. No. 5239. A shipment of 68 hogs by K. &amp; B., Nance County. Tu - berculosis in 10 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 8, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 59 No. 5255. A shipment of 45 hogs by F. E. P., Dodge County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 2 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Extensive tuberculosis of livers, spleens, and lungs. Marked caseation of inguinal lymph - nodes. Bacilli were exceedingly scarce in the lesions. Negative in one fowl and few small, non-progressive lesions of liver and spleen of the other. Bacilli were present in those lesions. Classification of infection type = Mammalian. No. 5256. A shipment of 56 hogs by H. S., Cuming County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative in one fowl and many tuberculous nodes in the spleen of the other. In those lesions bacilli were very numerous. No. 5261. A shipment of 52 hogs by G. R., Cedar County. Tubercu - losis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were present. No. 5262. A shipment of 26 hogs by W. K., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 8 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A marked tuberculosis of liver and spleen of one fowl and more moderate tuberculous lesions of the same organs in the other. Bacilli were present in all le- Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 5264. A shipment of 53 hogs by F. S. A., Boone County. Tu - berculosis in seven animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 3 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 4. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extremely marked miliary tu- berculosis of both fowls. Lesions of livers, spleens, lungs, kidneys, and peritonea. Lesions literally packed with bacilli. No. 5272. A shipment of 87 hogs by N. &amp; V., Colfax County. Tu - berculosis in 17 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 5, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 7, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Very extensive tuberculosis in livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. No. 5273. A shipment of 37 hogs by J. N., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 3 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias ■ Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. No. 5281. A shipment of 90 hogs by J. D., Madison County. Tu - berculosis in 11 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 5. Bacilli present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Foivls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, and lungs. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 61 No. 5282. A shipment of 63 hogs by J. V., Dodge County. Tubercu - losis in 16 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 11, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 3, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative, with the exception of caseous lesions of lymphnode near inoculation point. Bacilli were present in this material. Extensive or marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 5286. A shipment of 83 hogs by P. B., Stanton County. Tu - berculosis in 19 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 18 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were found to be present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A few small nodules in the liver and spleen of one fowl and ex- tensive tuberculosis of those organs in the other. Bacilli were present in all lesions. No. 5287. A shipment of 92 hogs by H. &amp; B., Seward County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 2 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A few small tubercles in the livers and spleens of both fowls. In only one of the spleens could ba- cilli be found. No. 5291. A shipment of 42 hogs by J. P. Z., Wheeler County. Tu - berculosis in 8 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were very numerous in the Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. j Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 5292. A shipment of 69 hogs by H. &amp; S., Buffalo County. Tu - berculosis in 5 animals. Lesions only in cervical lymphnodes. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. No. 5296. A shipment of 36 hogs by L. E. P., Madison County. Tu - berculosis in 7 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 6 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens in which bacilli were No. 5297. A shipment of 48 hogs by J. W. C, Boone County. Tu - berculosis in 22 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 20 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. Classification of infection type — Avian. No. 5298. A shipment of 52 hogs by A. S., Pierce County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in one, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one, and in portal lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extremely marked acute miliary tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the material. No. 5S07. A shipment of 57 hogs by F. &amp; T., Colfax County. Tu - berculosis in 25 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 11, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 12, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were very numerous in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers, spleens, lungs, and mesentery. Bacilli were very numerous in the le- Classification of infection type = Avian. present. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 63 No. 5308. A shipment of 56 hogs by O. P., Cuming County. Tu - berculosis in 28 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 18, in mes - enteric lymphnodes in 8, and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in 2. Bacilli were very numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were mi- merous in the lesions. No. 5311. A shipment of 49 hogs by A. R., Dodge County. Tubercu - losis in 9 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions in livers and spleens. Bacilli were numerous in the le- No. 5312. A shipment of 28 hogs by R. E. G., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 2 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in one and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Negative Classification of infection type = Undetermined, No. 5313. A shipment of 38 hogs by W. R., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 3 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 2 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. No. 5316. A shipment of 65 hogs by R. H. S., Antelope County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 8 and in mes - enteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Ba- cilli were numerous in the le- Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 5317. A shipment of 52 hogs by J. P., Knox County. Tubercu - losis in 12 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 11 and in cervical and mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were present in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A slight degree of tuberculosis of the livers of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the material. No. 5818. A shipment of 57 hogs by C. K., Cedar County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 8 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli were to be found in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were pres- ent in the lesions. No. 5319. Two shipments of 53 and 51 hogs by H. W. H., Cedar County. Tuberculosis in 27 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 24 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 3. Bacilli were present in this material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Marked tuberculosis of livers, Negative spleens and lymphnodes of both cavias. Appearance of lesions indicate a non-progressive type of disease. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Mammalian. No. 5320. A shipment of 59 hogs by H. C. H., Knox County. Tu - berculosis in 4 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes only. Bacilli present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 5321. A shipment of 42 hogs by G. J., Dixon County. Tu - berculosis in 9 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 8 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in one. Bacilli present in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative ■ Extensive tuberculosis of both fowls. Lesions of livers, spleens, kidneys, and lungs. Bacilli numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Increase in Tuberculosis op Swine 65 No. 5322. A shipment of 71 hogs by S. S., Wayne County. Tu - berculosis in 26 animals. Lesions in cervical lymphnodes in 14 and in mesenteric lymphnodes in 12. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavia8 Fowls Negative Tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. SUMMARY OF RESULTS From the details recorded above it will be observed that in the inquiry, material obtained from 250 Nebraska ship - ments of swine 1 originating in 41 counties was used. Those shipments represented a total of more than 14,299 swine of which not less than 2,781 or 19.5 per cent were retained on account of tuberculosis. Of the 250 lymphnode consignments 2 were discarded, 31 gave negative results (Group I) and 8 yielded results which made avian origin of the infection highly probable (Group IV). The number of consignments which yielded results per - mitting a definite interpretation thus was 209. The results obtained with this number are as follows : Infection Type No. Per cent FIELD SURVEY In the original schedule of the inquiry provision was made for a survey on the farms on which the shipments of tubercu - lous swine originated with a view of ascertaining the presence of tuberculosis among the cattle and poultry from which the swine might have contracted their infection. This part of the investigation was regarded as a valuable control of such laboratory results as may be obtained and as a means of either strengthening the final conclusions or of revealing whatever unknown factor of error might enter in the solu - tion of the problem. 1 Including one shipment from So. Dakota. Classification of infection type = Avian. Mammalian (Group II) Avian (Group III) Mixed (Group V) I Total I 11 185 13 209 88.51 6.22 99.94 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 The inspector in charge of the field force of the U. S. Bureau of Animal Industry, operating in the state in connec - tion with the co-operative tuberculosis eradication campaign, was appealed to for assistance and he undertook to make the surveys required so far as this could be done in conjunction with the work in hand. Unfortunately, the withdrawal of a part of the available inspectors for urgent duties in other states necessitated the abandonment of the surveys shortly after they were begun. A small number of surveys were, however, completed and their results coincided with those of the inoculation tests to such an extent that they materially contributed to the success of the investigation. As those surveys were made during the earlier phase of the inquiry they likewise inspired confidence in the method adopted in its pursuit. The surveys were made with thoroness on the part of the inspectors, and with the consent of the owners, tuberculin tests were made of the cattle and poultry present on the farms, while in a number of cases swine were also included in the field investigation. When some tuberculous swine originated from the farms concerned, the testing of those not shipped was not an urgent matter. However, by using in the testing an avian tuberculin as well as a mammalian tuberculin simultaneously, a different tuberculin on each ear of the animals tested, an interesting side light on the diagnosis of swine tuberculosis was obtained as some of the following data will show : No. S188. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 23 Reactors 0. Swine tested 12 Reactors 2. Chickens tested 20 Reactors 9. In testing the swine use was made of both avian and mammalian tu - berculin. In no case did the latter produce a reaction. The diagnosis of tuberculosis of the poultry was confirmed by autopsy. No. 3189. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 12 Reactors 0. Swine tested 28 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 149 Reactors 4. The reacting fowls were killed. Three proved to be generalized cases of tuberculosis and the fourth one showed slight liver lesions. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 67 No. S266. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 85 Reactors 0. Swine tested 58 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 407 Reactors 19. The diagnosis of tuberculosis of poultry was confirmed by autopsy. No. SU99. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. This shipment was composed of swine originating from three farms. Here follow the survey results for each No. 1 Cattle tested 3 Reactors 0. Swine tested 11 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 46 Reactors 0. No. 2 Cattle tested 19 Reactors 0. Swine tested 11 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 86 Reactors 0. No. 3 Cattle tested 12 Reactors 0. Swine tested 17 Reactors 8. Chickens tested 77 Reactors 20. The swine were tested with both avian and mammalian tuberculin. They reacted only to the avian tuberculin. The diagnosis of tuberculosis of the poultry was confirmed by autopsy. No. S500. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 15 Reactors 0. Swine tested 31 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 89 Reactors 4. The reacting fowls were examined by autopsy and found to be tu- berculous. No. sell. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 18 Reactors 0, Swine tested 5 Reactors 4. Fowls were not tested on this farm but the existence of tubercu&lt; losis among the poultry was determined by autopsy. No. 3612. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 11 , Reactors 0. Swine tested 7 Reactors 5. Chickens tested 124 Reactors 26. The swine were tested with both avian and mammalian tuberculin. In no case were reactors obtained with the mammalian tuberculin. Diag- nosis of tuberculosis in poultry confirmed by autopsy. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Nebraska Age. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. S61S. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 11 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 40 Reactors 7. The diagnosis of tuberculosis in the chickens was confirmed by autopsy. No. 361b- Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 8 Reactors 0. Swine tested 6 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 32 Reactors 13. The diagnosis of tuberculosis in the poultry flock was confirmed by autopsy. No. S615. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian, Field Survey Results Cattle tested 3 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 20 Reactors 4. Autopsies of the 4 reacting fowls confirmed the tuberculin test re- suits. No. S617. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Evidence of the existence of poultry tuberculosis was discovered on this farm, but no definite proof of this was secured. No. 3618. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 9 Reactors 0. Swine tested 5 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 66 Reactors 14. The diagnosis of tuberculosis in the poultry flock was confirmed by autopsy. No. 3629. Infection type determined by inoculation = Probably Avian Field Survey Results Cattle tested 10 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 50 Reactors 23. The diagnosis of tuberculosis among the poultry was confirmed by autopsy. No. 3701. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 5 Reactors 0. Chickens tested 50 Reactors 5. The diagnosis of tuberculosis in the poultry flock was confirmed by autopsy. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">Increase in Tuberculosis op Swine 69 No. 3? 'SS. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 10 Reactors 4. Swine tested 36 Reactors 7. Chickens tested 13 Reactors 4. The swine were tested with both avian and mammalian tuberculin. Four of the reactors only reacted to the avian tuberculin. The diagnosis of tuberculosis in the poultry flock was confirmed by autopsy. No. 4032. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 4 Reactors 0. Swine tested 3 Reactors 3. Chickens tested 150 Reactors 10. In the testing of the swine both avian and mammalian tuberculin were used. The bovine tuberculin resulted in a slight reaction in one, but the other two reacted to the avian tuberculin only. At a later period all the swine on this farm were tuberculin tested, showing 11 reactors in the 52 swine tested. All reactions were caused by the avian tuberculin and none by the mammalian tuberculin. No. 4388. Infection type determined by inoculation = Avian. Field Survey Results Information by owner that his cattle had been tuberculin tested locally, without positive reactions, but that he suspected his chickens to be tuberculous. No. 4565. Infection type determined by inoculation = Mammalian. Field Survey Results Cattle tested 4 Reactors 2. Swine tested 65 Reactors 54. Chickens tested 88 Reactors 0. Turkeys tested 4 _ Reactors 0. Cats tested Reactors 0. Both avian and mammalian tuberculin were used in the testing of the swine. All reactions were constant against the mammalian tubercu- lin and only a part of the swine reacted to the avian tuberculin also. It will be observed that 18 field surveys were made of which 16 were complete and of value in comparing their re- sults with those obtained in the laboratory. The results of this comparison are summarized in Table 3. They show a practically perfect agreement in the in- dications furnished by the surveys and those yielded by the inoculation tests. They scarcely leave any doubt in regard to the trustworthiness of information secured thru the simul- </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 — ,- — .- -)- 1 ■*©»©) | I + I I I I + I I I ! est-no " I I + I + I I! | -^- I I + ; i I + a.o. i + I . I + 5 a S.E g| cow-as *3— + i i + ♦ , n rotc — ;; ; Is |2 £2 + i J I I ; i + ; y ! „_ ♦ + J?~ : 1 _i j i i j •a &gt;. I i J5.c 3^5 cciooo ■S.S D5t»OSO5 I ti ii I i I I i i I ! + + i I I 4- + -r *s OSO15C5C Ii + -r + + •-. — /./ - 1 !. si 11 it B* .9 : 1 1 h H .S : 1 : S&gt; : a . 5 : m : c . "3 5l II ii •Si I. "3 c II a v. I ; I ; 1:1: I : I : m-M- 3§ 3§ •Si "Bi S.1 p I a </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 71 taneous use of cavias and fowls in the typing of the tubercle bacilli found in swine. The fact that in those cases where swine could be tested, positive reactions were more constant to avian than to mam - malian tuberculin, is also pregnant with interest. While this detail lies somewhat outside the field and object of this in - quiry, there are practical reasons for its consideration. THE TYPING OF THE BACILLI ASSOCIATED WITH TUBERCU - LOUS LYMPHNODES OF SWINE ORIGINATING IN HILLSDALE COUNTY, MICHIGAN Shortly after the first results of the inquiry regarding the origin of tuberculosis among Nebraska swine became avail - able, this department was made acquainted with the fact that swine originating in the bovine tuberculosis accredited area of Hillsdale County, Michigan, furnished upon slaughter many retentions on account of tuberculosis. Thru the courtesy of Mr. H. R. Smith, Livestock Com - missioner, National Livestock Exchange, and of Dr. P. B. Wende, Inspector in Charge, Buffalo, N. Y., the tuberculous lymphnodes of 14 consignments of Hillsdale County swine were secured and used in inoculation tests similar to those undertaken with Nebraska material. The following are the results obtained in the examination of each lot of lymphnodes: No. 4359. Tuberculous lymphnodes of 5 hogs originating in Hills - dale County, Michigan and shipped to Buffalo, N. Y., collected 12-18-23. Bacilli were plentiful in the material. Inoculation Results Caviaa Fowls Negative One of the fowls failed to present any evidence of tuberculosis when examined by autopsy 3 months after inoculation, while the other presented a moderate number of tuberculous nodules in the liver and spleen. Bacilli were rather numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 4363. Tuberculous lymphnodes of 7 hogs originating from ac - credited area (Hillsdale County, Michigan) and shipped to Buffalo, N. Y. Collected 12-19-23. Establishment 383. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Developed rather extensive tu- The autopsy of both fowls killed berculosis. Bacilli very scarce in the material. 3 months after inoculation re - vealed slight tuberculous lesions in spleen and liver in which ba - cilli were extremely scarce. Classification of infection type = Mammalian and avian mixed. As it seemed advisable to ascertain the type of mammalian infection, its determination was undertaken by inoculation with material from one of the cavias into cavias, rabbits, and fowls. Here follow the results: Cavias Rabbits Fowls Tuberculosis; general- Tuberculosis; general- Negative ized, extensive, and ized, extensive, and progressive. progressive. Note: The results indicate that in the passage thru the cavia of the original material the avian infection was entirely eliminated. Final classification of infection type = Bovine and avian mixed. No. 4384. Tuberculous lymphnodes of swine originating in Hills - dale County, Michigan. One node was taken from each hog. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Both fowls developed tuberculosis of liver and spleen. In one, ba- cilli were numerous in the le- sions and in the other they were present in more moderate num- No. 4397. Tuberculous lymphnodes of swine originating in Hills - dale County, Michigan. Shipped either by Hillsdale Co-operative Asso - ciation or by W. H. Croose, Hillsdale County, Michigan. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Both fowls developed an extensive tuberculosis. Bacilli were nu- merous in all lesions. No. 4398. Tuberculous lymphnodes of swine originating in Hills - dale County, Michigan. Shipped either by Hillsdale Co-operative Asso- bers. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 73 ciation or by W. H. Croose, Hillsdale County, Michigan. Bacilli were plentiful in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Both fowls developed a moderate degree of tuberculosis of liver and spleen. Bacilli numerous in all lesions. No. 4410. Tuberculous lymphnodes of swine shipped by Rowe and Adams, Camden, Michigan. Bacilli were present in the material in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Both fowls developed an extensive tuberculosis of liver and spleen. In the lesions of one, bacilli were present in moderate num- bers and in those of the other they were numerous. Classification of infection type — Avian. No. 4411. Tuberculous lymphnodes of swine shipped by Osseo Co - operative Association, Osseo, Michigan. Bacilli were present in the material in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A moderate degree of tuberculosis of liver and spleen developed in both fowls. Bacilli were present in the lesions. No. 4439. Tuberculous lymphnodes obtained from 290 certified hogs slaughtered at Buffalo, New York, and pertaining to the following ship - ments : 74 hogs by Richfield Co-operative Shippers Association, Richfield, Michigan. 84 hogs by Pittsford Co-operative Association, Pittsford, Michigan. 132 hogs by Reading Co-operative Commerce Company, Reading, Michigan. 53 head retained, slaughtered 1-14-24. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Both fowls developed extensive tu- berculosis of liver and spleen. Bacilli were numerous in the le- •. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type= Avian. sions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 No. 4443. Tuberculous lymphnodes from several retained hogs from a lot of 118 swine originating in accredited area of Hillsdale County, Michigan. Shipped by Prattville Co-operative Association. Slaughtered at Buffalo, New York, 1-12-24. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Both fowls presented an extensive tuberculosis of liver and spleen and isolated nodules in the lungs. Bacilli were numerous in the No. HH- Tuberculous lymphnodes of several retained swine of a lot of 182 hogs originating in accredited area in Hillsdale County, Michi - gan. Shipped by Associated Farmers Co., Jonesville. Michigan. Slaugh - tered, Buffalo, New York, 1-12-24. Bacilli were present in the lesions. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Both fowls developed tuberculosis of liver and spleen. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. No. 4447. Tuberculous lymphnodes of several hogs from a lot of 240 swine shipped from Hillsdale County, Michigan, by the Reading Co-operative Commerce Co. Slaughtered, Buffalo, New York, 1-16-21. The material contained bacilli in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens of both fowls. Bacilli were numerous in the lesions. No. 4448. Tuberculous lymphnodes of 93 retained hogs of a lot of 611 swine shipped from Hillsdale County, Michigan. Bacilli were pres - ent in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavia8 Fowls Negative Both fowls developed extensive tu- berculosis of livers and spleens. Bacilli were numerous in all No. 4463. Tuberculous lymphnodes of 12 hogs retained from a lot of 59 swine shipped by Allen Co-operative Association, Hillsdale County, material. Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. lesions. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 75 Michigan. Killed, Buffalo, New York, 1-9-24. Bacilli were present in the lesions in moderate numbers. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative A very extensive tuberculosis of livers and spleens developed in both fowls. The lesions con- tained many bacilli. So. 4471. Tuberculous lymphnodes of 99 retained swine from a lot of 553 hogs originating in Hillsdale County, Michigan. Slaughtered, Buffalo, New York, 1-21-24. Bacilli were numerous in the material. Inoculation Results Cavias Fowls Negative Both fowls developed a marked tuberculosis of livers and spleens. Bacilli were numerous in all lesions. In the Hillsdale County series 14 consignments of tubercu - lous lymphnodes of swine were thus examined. In 13 of this number bacilli of the avian type only could be demonstrated. In the remaining consignment avian bacilli were also present, but they occurred in association with bacilli of the bovine type. CONCLUSIONS 1. The type of swine tuberculosis which is responsible for the increased retentions of carcasses and the condemnation of parts is for the greater part due to infection of avian origin. 2. In the eradication and control of swine tuberculosis success can only then be attained when the two chief fountain heads of infection, namely, the tuberculous cattle herd and the tuberculous poultry flock be regarded as equally import - ant. 3. There are indications that the steady increase in the in - cidence of swine tuberculosis as shown by abattoir statistics reflects a similar increase in the spread of avian tuberculosis in a large area of the United States. 4. In the intradermal tuberculin test of swine in which a mammalian tuberculin is used a considerable number of cases Classification of infection type = Avian. Classification of infection type = Avian. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 of tuberculosis will escape detection. For dependable results, avian tuberculin must also be used. 5. In the bacteriologic diagnosis of tuberculosis of swine by animal inoculation tests, the results will, for a large pro - portion of the cases, remain inconclusive when only cavias are used for the purpose. In the case of swine, at least, some laboratory animals susceptible to avian tuberculosis also or susceptible to both avian and mammalian tuberculosis should be included in the experiment. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The writers are deeply indebted to Drs. H. Busman, D. R. Gillies, G. E. Kay and T. A. Shipley, Inspectors in Charge of Meat Inspection Stations at Omaha, Nebraska, St. Joseph, Missouri, Nebraska City, Ne - braska, and Sioux City, Iowa, and to their associates for the collection and shipment of materials used in the investigation, as well as for the identification of the various consignments of swine from which the material was obtained; to Dr. C. H. Hays, Inspector in Charge of Bovine Tuberculosis Eradication, Lincoln, Nebraska, and to members of his field force for surveys made on farms; to H. R. Smith, Livestock Com - missioner, Chicago, Illinois and to Dr. B. P. Wende, Inspector in Charge, Buffalo, N. Y., for the collection, shipment, and identification of the Michigan material used in the inquiry. By their good will and their courteous and efficient cooperation the gentlemen named made substantial contributions toward making the inquiry possible as well as toward its successful conclusion. [6M1 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Increase in Tuberculosis of Swine 77 BIBLIOGRAPHY 1. Arloing. Rap. 9me Congres int. de Med. Vet. LaHaye, T. 1 (1909). 2. Baby. Rev. Zootechnica. Buenos Aires, V. 4. p. 339 (1913). 3. Bang. Centralbl. f. Bakt. u.s.w. 1 ste Abt. Originate Bnd. U6, p. i6. (1908). 4. Bang. Rep. 9th Int. Congress of Vet. Med. The Hague, Vol. 1, 1909. 5. Bang. Zeitschrift f. Inf. Krankh. u.s.w. der Haustiere, Bnd. 13, p. 215, (1913). 6. Bang. Maanedsskrift f. Dyrlaeger, Bind 34, p. 641. (1923). 7. Bang and Holm. 88de Beretning fra Forsgslab. Ref. Z. f. Fleisch u. Milchhygiene, 28, Jahrg. p. 85. (1917). 8, 9, 10. Brieg. Maanedsskrift f. Dyrlaeger. Bnd. 34, pp. 441, 546, 550, 1922-1923. 11. Cadiot, Gilbert et Roger. C. R. d. 1. Soc. Biol. T. 3, Serie 9, p. 87. (1891). 12. Calmette. L'Infection Bacillaire et la Tuberculose. p. p. 327-329 - 338-339-340, Paris (1922). 13. Carl. Virchow's Archiv. Bnd. 207, p. 140 (1912). 14. Christiansen. Zeitschrift f. Inf. Krankh. u.s.w. der Haustiere. Bnd. 14, p. 323 (1913). 15. Christiansen. Zeitschrift f. Inf. Krankh. u.s.w. der Haustiere. Bnd. 16, p. 264 (1914). 16. Cobbett. The Causes of Tuberculosis, Cambridge (1917). 17. Courmont et Dor. C. R. et Mem. Congres p. 1'etude de la Tu - berculose 1891, p. 119, Paris (1892). 18. Day. Journal Am. Vet. Med. Assn. Ind. Vol. 5, p. 92, (1919). 19. De Haan. Deutsche Med. Wochenschrift 1908, p. 1386 (1908) 20. De Jong. C. R. du VUIe Congres Int. de Med. Vet. Budapest. T. 2 (1905). 21. De Jong. An. de l'Inst. Pasteur. T. 24, p. 895 (1910). 22. De Jong. Rep. International Veterinary Congress, Vol. 2. London (1914). 23. De Jong. Tijdschrift y. vergel Geneeskunde, Deel 1, p. 45 (1915). 24. De Jong. Tuberkelbacillen van Mensch en Dier, The Hague, 1922. 25. Douma. Tijdschrift v. vergel, Geneeskunde, Deel 2, p. 237 (1917). 26. Eastwood and Griffith. Reports to the local Government Board, New Series No. 91, London (1914). 27. Eber. Zeitschrift f. Fleisch-und Milchhygiene, 20 Jahrg. p. 321 (1910). 28. Gilbert et Roger. C. R. de la Soc. de Biologie. T. 3., s. 9, p. 81 (1891). 29. Glasser. Die Krankheiten des Schweines. Hanover (1922). 30. Helm. Zeitschrift f. Fleisch-und Milchhygiene, 33 Jahrg. p. 23 (1922). 31. Hoefnagel. Zeitschrift f. Fleisch-und Milchhygiene, 30 Jahrg. p. 179 (1920). 32. Hutyra u. Marek. Spez. Path. u. Therapie de Haustiere. Bnd. 1. Jena (1922). 33. Joest. Zeitschrift f. Fleisch-und Milchhygiene, 24 Jahrg. p. 293 (1914). 34. Junack. Zeitschrift f. Fleisch-und Milchhygiene, 21 Jahrg. p. 312 (1911). </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 30 35. Junack. Zeitschrift f. Fleisch-und Milchhygiene, 23 Jahrg. p. 457 (1913). 36. Junack. Zeitschrift f. Fleisch-und Milchhygiene. 24 Jahrg. p. 272 (1914). 37. Kersten und Ungermann. Tb. Arbeiten a. d. Kaiserl. Gesundheits - amte H. 11, p. 171 (1912). 38. Koch und Rabinowitch. Virchow's Archiv. Bnd. 190, Beiheft p. 246 (1907). 39. Kossel, Weber und Heuss. Tb. Arbeiten a. d. Kaiserl. Gesund - heitsamte, Heft 1, p. 1 (1904). 40. Lipschutz. Arch. f. Dermatologie u.s.w. Bnd. 120, p. 387 (1914). 41. Ldwenstein. Wiener Klin. Wochenschrift 1913, p. 785 (1913). 42. Maffucci. Zeitschrift f. Hygiene u. Infek. Krankh. Bnd. 11, p. 445 (1892). 43. Mohler and Washburn. Am. Vet. Review, Vol. 32, p. 176 (1907). 44. Mohler and Washburn. 25th An. Rep. Bureau of Animal Industry, 1908, p. 165 (1910). 45. Mohler and Washburn. Rep. 9th Int. Congress of Vet. Med. The Hague. Vol. 1 (1909). 46. Mohler. An. Report of the Dept. of Agriculture for the year ended June, 1923, p. 236, Washington (1924). 47. Rabinowitch. Deutsche Med. Wochenschrift. Bnd. 30, prt. 2, p. 1675 (1904). 48. . Royal Commission on Tuberculosis. (Final Report.) (1911). 49. Titze. Tb. Arbeiten a. d. Kaiserl. Gesundheitsamte. H. 6. p. 215 (1907). 50. Vallee et Panisset. Les Tuberculoses Animates, p. 146-148. Paris (1920). 51. Vagnal. C. R. et Mem. Congres p. l'etude de la Tuberculose, 1891, p. 63 (1892). 52. Weber. Tb. Arbeiten a. d. Kaiserl. Gesundheitsamte, H. 6, p. 1 (1907). 53. Weber und Bofinger. Tb. Arbeiten a. d. Kaiserl. Gesundheitsamte, H. 1, p. 83 (1907). 54. Zwick. Zeitschrift f. Infekts. Krankh. u. s. w. der Haustiere. Bnd. 4, p. 161 (1908). 55. Zwick und Zeller. Arb. a. d. Kaiserl. Gesundheitsamte. Bnd. 47 p. 164 (1914). </seg>
            <seg id="p079">PLATES Liver Lesions Produced in Chickens Inoculated with Tuberculous Material from Hogs Used in the Ex - periment. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">PLATE 1 [S189-c&gt;i M7J1 1 3500 eh. 4043 j |3S53 eh. 4O13J D «t . '^j3 HL fl |S619 eh 459T] |3tl6 ch. 4Jll1 H I 3816 ch- *614j B K133 et. 986^ 14146 ch 4804.I •*^-^^k. |41M eh. B69.| |414B eh. 6690| [«150 ch. 4S12.| </seg>
            <seg id="p081">PLATE 2</seg>
            <seg id="p082">PLATE 3 14410 ch7«824| _ . L — ! J4416 eh.52^TJ 14417 eh 59291 I««1T ch.7173,| |4416 eh. 5646.1 J441B oh .482371 H418 oh. 5260. | l**» 7 °h.5937]] [4438 eh.48sTT1 |««39 oh 484?Tl 14439 eli.48Sn 14443 eh .4850. | </seg>
            <seg id="p083">PLATE 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">PLATE 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">PLATE 6 ""• W3^l 4718 oh. SOSD J471B et.SOtO] »* ♦ 14767 eh 8798.J ;47E3 eh. 3M5T] : 47ti oh tJWJ, H^l%^. V I &gt;773 eh.4P6rjj 4768 eh. 41141 eh 41OSJ m* •*£ JM y 4773 &lt;:h.678O| 4793 eh. 4108.1 '4793 ch. 4115^^^ T« T »a ""■ 4106] -^ _ I .^. -.A. ■ J4789 ch. 41 03.] f4792 'chT^roT] I* 71 ' ""• «°*^ ' H [4TM eh. 3i»5. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">PLATE 7</seg>
            <seg id="p087">PLATE 8</seg>
            <seg id="p088">PLATE 9 B»^^^F V 9 14921 ch.6tT3j ■ »" cb.5363, |4912 ch.53^1. 4912 ch.5394. j6±^^^±. k 1 I V 4921 ch.6783j . . r492* ch.5664j I I493B ch.£96B.| 91 nH :492s ch.40tT. 4925 ch.4005T . 4964 ch. 7104.1 |4938 ch. 4016.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">PLATE 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">11 le* 5245.1 . I"" °"- t5 * 1 -' 15031 eh. 5396 i W -. A L ia. ■*■ til W^f^^^ 15034 ch.4710i . . 1503* ch.5534j . , 1508* eh.470n ' |5033 ch. 5840^1 |5094 eh. 50 93^ [5095 ch.««.l ' 5M5 Ch -« m -l 15098 eh .52141 k . , |509t.oh.580n 15096 eh.SZTlTl </seg>
            <seg id="p091">PLATE 12 . i L. . J mm m^^m mk^m |noi e^ Mxj I P 65651 j*!*,,. £&amp;•* 15103 5j.6t4ll JT 5696.1 15103 St. 66781 _ 15104 ell. 6689 J |5lao eh.*li?!l P1«O oh.47oT] Wr^^r^ 1 -i r — I5H0 eh. 4559. 1 15142 oh. 53teT1 4 ft /■ |514£ oh .4600^1 IS143 ct.5634j 15167 eh.4014j </seg>
            <seg id="p092">13 V^F 15170 eh &lt;147| I |5168 eh .5497! 15168 oh.5«04~3 V WF |518t ah 897T1 15169 eh 55814 15169 eh 5581 J 15191 ch. 5Z9tJ 15191 ch. 8591 J [5U0 oh.«12S-| . IS169 ch.5«»n I .Si 15190 oh. 5458 J V Bf |si9t ch.soen 15194 ch. 5285.1 15192 eh. 5279 J </seg>
            <seg id="p093">PLATE 14 |519 5 eh.StilJ IStOl eh. 4153.1 15195 ch. 52014 iszoi eh.atioj B^^ |5203 eh.5iin .^ **S B^^ I J5219 ch. 1148.1 |5tO7 eh.E63Tl |520« eh. 5485^ ch.SOglJ |5224 eh. 4140^] A I52Z4 cb.4148l V |S2Z5 ch.tlSl'J </seg>
            <seg id="p094">PLATE 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">PLATE IS </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>