<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Home Vegetable Gardening</title>
               <date value="1918-04-01">1918-04-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BXTCMMOM BULLETIN NO, M BULLETIN OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE HOME VEGETABLE GARDENING My G, W. II IICIKIMI IM. \l kll I, I'.llH LINCOLN, NBBRANKA, V, f. A ftlttrlbuUd In rtirth«r«n«« of tho Vurptmm of lh« Oo*y«r&gt;tlr« AjrUiultural B«ton»l»» Work I'ifrvi4«d for la tb« A«t of OotgroM of Mir I, 1*14, Utlvtrdtr of MovrMk* AirK-nlfiiml KxUrsdM «orrl«« •■4 th« Uiito4 ftfttoi DoHrtmMt of Agr l*uHur: Cooforfttlag, 0. W, KUOiLBY, Hhnlnt nf l'.*lrinnm S*nHir </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Unfwifty of N .bruit* ColUg • of Agriculture THE EXTENSION SERVICE TMK OOVKKXINU IM»Altl» (Tha ll«««nU «f tha t Jr»i v-r«nr &gt; Ho*. E. P. HaowN, /'resident, D«vcy Ho* J, E. Miixm, Kfc/ I'rnldmi, Ho*. Vitro* G. Lvrono, I'tllt City 1 1«« J'Hiur L. Haul, Lincoln How, lUuv L&gt;. Lamm*, S«w»rd Lincoln Ho*. Fmnk L Hauii, Omtht THK IKIVKIMITY ol I l&lt; I Us •Samvu. Avmv, Ph. D., LL. D., Chanctllor W. G. HaCTINOS, A. I)., /(f/l«(/ Chanctllor E. A. Bui««tt, D. Sc,, /?*««, Colltgt of Ayrlculturt; Dinctor, Exftrimtnl Station J. S. Dau», M. Ph., financial Sterttary KXTKNMION KXW'l'TIVK NTAW C. A. Lkwik, li. Sc, Agricultural Editor C. W. Watiom, A. M , Junior Siction THK KXTK.NHIO.%- (Or.Nril, &lt;ll,ni1» of Department*) E. A. Buinktt, D. Sc., Dean C. W, Pucmx v, B. Sc., Dinctor P. W. UfMN, Ph. D., H. C. Fiu.«v, A. M., Farm Management *Aucc M. Loouif, A. M , //0m/ EconomUi Agricultural Chimiitry L. W. Cham, M, E., A. E Jl-lia Vamcc, A. B., B. Sc llomt EconomUi Agricultural Engineering W. W. Bum, B. Sc., R. P. Howam, A. M., Horticulture G. A. LovcLAifo, A. M., Meteorology E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Plant Pathology Animal Pathology F. E. MuttEHL, B. Sc., Poultry Husbandry J. H. PlANMEN, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry H. E. Biad'oid, A. M , LAWtCNCE BlUMEB, B. Sc., EnttmtUgy Principal, School of Agricultun * AbMM on leave C. W. Puoiucy, B. 8c., Dinctor C. E. CVMMtLt, B. SC., County Agtnt Siction Maud Mathu Wilion, li. S&lt; llomt Economics Siclion Lew. T. Skinnu, B. Sc, Assistant to thi Director Agronomy H. I. GtAMLICH, B. St., Animal Husbandry J. H. Gain, M. D. C, </seg>
            <seg id="p003">HOME VEGETABLE GARDENING* The e»»cntinl fiii'turN in every garden are: Kirat, it »oil *uii - hIiIi- for the grow ing of plant*, that In, one which U abundantly HU|i|ilii-i| with i&gt;lmii food wi'oiul, n Niinii-iciii. &lt;nip|»ly of water in urilrr !&lt;» dlaaolve the plum food mid make it available lor plniit uiov*ili, third, it «'»»&lt;! locution, which will provhl* plenty of Muuithiiif ; uiid fourtii, 11 »|&gt;ot thnt iw well dntin&lt;*d. llit«n«iv« cultivation of tilt* moII i«t I'utM'iiiinl in order to produce t &gt;•&lt;• uniii Mt yield from u muni I Npact, MKI/MTINIi TMK (IIOI' The selection of proper veKetahleit for tlie dome yanlcn i&lt;* important, The lint should include tho«e plant* which produce the greatest amount of fond Do not plant a great xpnee to mjch M'KctuliIcK un lettuce and nidixhe* The follow Iiik lixtit may aid in the aclection. Home plant* neceHMarily overlap, 1. Ouickly maturing vi-(jHnl»lc», which are planted in th« early NpriiiK mid late mimmcr IMtuea Turnip* Kaihwtt t Hiring basno Kndlvn MplDMh Onion m&gt;u 2. Veitetiililcw wllicll flt'C planted in the early Mprititf and when eNtahliMhcd will witliNtHiid hot wcuthcr I'ar.nlp A»p«r»Kii» CurrolN llhiilmrli Onion M-cd Mrtty I'arcUr Hwl»» rhard 3. V'eitctablcM which me planted in the late spring and early aiimmer and ui"» thru the hot weather. weather ruriniit»&lt;T I'umpkin Kgfplant M4|uwth Muck melon ffw««t corn f'«pp«r Mw««t potato WaUr melon Tomato •ThU bullatln contain* In brl&gt;f furm tb* ••••ntlal* «.f h«m» »»««iabU Kardcnlnit Hunic va-ictanlx* whlith hav* prov«4 &lt;Jl(B&lt;uli fur lh« amal*ur lo jtri-w »urr«-»»fully hava b»n purponoly umlttvd. tMhould nut if planted until rt«n*»r ut »»v&gt;r« fr«*t* In over Ky G, W. Hih,i, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Bulletin No. 50, College of Agriculture BEAN* String beans are grown early and dwarf varieties are usually recommended. After danger of frost is past the seed should bo planted in a well-prepared seed bed. The rows should be spaced from 18 inches to 24 inches apart and the beans sown about 2 inches apart in the rows. The beans mature from 6 to 10 week's after the seed is sown. The pods should be picked while they are young and tender. The plants should be cultivated fre - quently. It i.s not generally recommended either to cultivate or gather the beans when the plants are wet because they have u tendency to spread disease should there be any present. The Stringless Oreen-pod and the Red Valentine are two good grera - podded varieties while the Golden wax and White wax are good wax-podded varieties. Dried beans are a very fine con - centrated food and are easily grown. The most common varieties are the navy, pinto and red kidney. These beans are planted and cultivated in the same manner as the string beans, but are allowed to ripen on the plants and are then shelled out when dry. BEET The beet is a crop grown principally for its root. It in hardy and of easy culture. The garden beets are mostly red or mottled in appearance and are either round or cone-shaped. The round turnip-shaped beets require a short season for their growth, and the long cone-shaped types require the whole season to develop. The soil for the beet should be rich, sandy and loose, ko that a smooth regular root can develop. The beet is usually planted in rows 12 to 18 inches apart. When the plants are 2 or 3 inches high, they should be thinned to stand 4 or 5 inches apart in the rows. The beet seed should be sown early and as soon in the spring as the ground can be worked. The beet requires from 40 to 75 days to mature, according to varieties. Three or four sow - ings can be made at intervals of two or three weeks. The De - troit Dark Red, the Dark Stinson and Improved Blood are three good varieties. CABBAGK The cabbage head varies in shape from a pointed, rather cone-shaped head, to round and flat head. The pointed head types are usually grown for the early cabbage, while the flat and round heads are more popular as fall and winter types. There are usually two types of cabbage grown in every locality, the early and late cabbage. The plants for the early cabbage </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Home Vegetable Gardening 6 arc started in hotbed*, seed for which should be planted early in March. The seedlings should be transplanted when they have developed the second leaf. When the plants have attained a height of 5 or tt inches they should be set in the field. The time for planting the early cabbage in the garden varies, but usually ranges from April 15 to May 1. Late cabbage is a difficult crop and uncertain without irrigation and not generally recommended for the amateur. There are several diseases and insects found on the cabbage. One way to avoid disease is by selecting good healthy plants free from disease. Rotation of the crops and thoro sanitation will also aid in keeping the plants healthy. Spraying is not very satisfactory. Two of the principal insects of the cabbage are the cabbage worm and the plant louse. The cabbage worms are controlled by either spraying or dusting the plants. Arsenate of lead, made by dissolving one-half pound in 5 gallons of water and adding a mi i ail piece of soap to serve as a sticker, is a satis - factory spray. Dusting the plants with 1 ounce of Paris green thoroly mixed with 1 pound of road dust or air-slaked lime is also very good. This material can be dusted on the plants by putting it in a sack made of thin cloth and shaking the sack over each plant. When the plant lice are troublesome, they can be controlled by spraying the plants with Black Leaf 40 at the rate of one-eighth pint to 15 gallons of water. The varieties which give the most satisfactory returns for early cabbage are the Copenhagen Market, and the Large Wake - field. The varieties best suited for fall are the Surehead and Flat Dutch, while the Danish Ballhead is best for winter, and excellent for storing. OOBM (MWKKT) Sweet corn is a tender vegetable and must not be planted until danger of frost is over. The ears should be picked when the kernels are plump and well filled, and it should be cooked as soon as it is taken from the stock. Sweet corn requires warm light soil for its rapid development. A sandy loam soil which warms up quickly is excellent, altho it will do well on heavier soils. The soil should be enriched by liberal application of ma - nure. A sunny exposure gives the best corn. A larger number of ears of sweet corn can be produced if the seed is planted in drills, provided there is a sufficient amount of moisture. If the drill method is used, plant the seeds 12 to 15 inches apart in the rows and the rows 24 to 36 inches apart </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Extension Bulletin No. 50, College of Agriculture according to variety. If the hill method is used, plant the seed 24 to 36 inches apart in checks. Usually three or four kernels are placed in each hill and two or three healthy plants are allowed to develop. The small-growing early varieties are planted closer together than the tall late-growing varieties. The seed should be planted an inch and a half to two inches in depth. Frequent cultivation of the soil is essential. Sweet corn will mature in from 55 to 100 days, according to variety. The early varieties which seem to give the best satis - faction are the Cory and Golden Bantam, for the medium early the Howling Mob, and late the Evergreen. The Howling Mob is an excellent variety and the most satisfactory when only one variety is planted. CUCUMBER The cucumber must not be planted until all danger of frost is over. It will grow well on a variety of soils, altho a sandy loam with plenty of organic matter in it is preferable. The soil should be cultivated until the vines cover the ground. If the hill method of planting is used plant 8 to 10 seeds in the hill and piece the hills 4 to 5 feet apart. When the plants are about 6 inches high they should be thinned out to two or four in a hill. If the drill method is used, two or three seeds should be planted every 12 inches in the row and the rows spaced 6 feet apart. When the plants begin to vine, they should be thinned out to one in a place. The seed should be sown from three-fourths to one inch in depth. The cucumber seed can be sown in the gar - den from the middle of May until the early part of July. Several diseases will be found troublesome. By spraying the vines every week or ten days with Bordeaux mixture, good re - sults are usually secured. The insect pests also are sometimes very destructive. Chief among these is the striped cucumber beetle. This insect can be controlled only by persistence in apply - ing materials which are objectionable to the insect. Dusting the plant with air-slaked lime seems to give some relief. The plant lice are also troublesome at times. Spraying the plants with Black Leaf 40 will control this insect. The varieties of cucumber which usually do the best are Davis Perfect, White Spine and the Boston Pickling. The last is a variety used for small pickles. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Home Vegetable Gardening 7 ENDIVK The endive is a salad plant. It is hardy to frost and may be sown early in the spring or late in the fall. It does not do well in hot weather. It is most important as a fall crop and can be used to follow early potatoes, cabbage and many other medium - season crops. The fall crop should be sown about the first of August and the seedlings either transplanted or thinned out. The plants should stand about 15 inches in the rows and the rows 18 inches apart. The endive should be blanched beginning about the middle of September and a few plants tied up every week until about the last of October. This will give a constant supply for the table. The usual method is to draw the leaves around the plant and tie the tops together. It requires from 10 to 20 days to blanch the leaves. The Giant Fringed and Green Curled are two good varieties. LETTICK There are two common forms of lettuce which are usually grown, leaf lettuce and head lettuce. To produce large heads of good quality, lettuce must be transplanted. The leaf types should be set six inches apart in the rows and the heading variety should be transplanted a foot apart in the rows. The rows for both types should be 12 to 14 inches apart. Soil for lettuce should be well drained and fertile. A sandy loam is preferable but good plants can be grown on a variety of soils. The seed for the early crop can be sown either in the hotbed and the seedlings transplanted to the open when the weather permits, or sown in the open as soon as conditions are favorable. Let - tuce requires 35 to 50 days to mature, according to variety. The crop should be picked when needed, and cutting the entire head is preferable to gathering a few leaves. The harvesting should be done early in the morning when the plants are crisp and ten - der. The loose-leaf varieties which are usually grown are the Black Seeded Simpson and the Morse. Of the head lettuce the Burpee- Way-Ahead and Iceberg are good varieties. MUSKMELON The muskmelon is a warm season plant and must not be planted until danger of frost is past. Muskmelons are not gen - erally satisfactory for beginners in the eastern section of the State but do very well in the western part. The muskmelon requires a light warm sandy soil. Many other soils will grow </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Extension Bulletin No. 50, College of Agriculture 8 iiiuskiiicloiis profitably, but the quality is oftentimes not so good. The soil should be well enriched by placing a shovelful of com - post in each hill if grown in the eastern part. Cultivate the soil frequently until the vines cover the ground. Later pull out all weeds by hand. The musktnelon is usually planted in hills. The distance between hills varies according to the soil and the variety. A good standard distance to plant the seed is 6 feet in the row s and the rows 6 to 7 feet apart. Plant eight or ten seeds in a hill and us the plants become too crowded, thin them out to two or three in a place. The seed should be covered to a depth of about one inch and should not be planted until dan - ger of frost is past. The muskmelon requires from sixty to eighty-five days to Mature. The melons should be picked as soon as they arc ripe. The degree of ripeness may be known by press - ing the end of the melon with the finger. When soft it is ready to pick, (lood varieties arc Rocky Ford and liurrell (Jem. The inscctN and diseases hit the miiiiic iin those found on the cucum - lier in nl the mime remedies lire used for their control. UNION The oniiin is grown cither from the need or from small bulbs called MU. It is very hardy and is u cool season crop and ona of the first crops to be planted in the garden. Where the small green onions arc desired, it is usually advisable to plant the onion sets us early in the spring as the mound can be worked. If the lut'Kc mature bulbs are wonted for fall and winter use, they should be started by planting the need early in the spring. The seed lied for the onions should be made very fine, be - cause the onion seed is slow to uermimiie and the young plants are small and delicate, It is well to plant a few radish seed with the oiiIoiin to innrl&lt; the row until the onions com* up. Almost nny soil will grow oiiIoiin, but they prefer a loose friable soil The onion sets ace usually plunted aliotit two inches apart In the rows and the rows VI to 14 inches apart.. The onion seed Is tmiinlly mwn in row* either by hand or with a seed drill. The plants are then thinned out to stand three or four Inehes apart In the run », dcpetidliiK upon the variety. The rows are usually spaced I'J to 14 Inehes apart, Where tin- largo mature bulb* am yrown, constant and frequent cultivation Is necessary, Hand weeding must be done ami the first Heeding should be given at the lime of thinning, The onion is harvested when the tops turn yellow, either in August or Mepieinber, Where the tops fail to ripen evenly, It </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Home Vegetable Gardening 9 is often desirable to break over the remaining tops with a rake or gome other implement which make* the entire crop mature at one time. Onionx should be pulled up and laid in windrowtt to dry for several dayt«. If the huh ih very hot it in uitually ad - visable to place them in crates to protect them from the sun in order to prevent sun scald. The varieties which are selected depend upon the way in which the crop is to be used. For early fall use some of the white varieties arc desirable. For the main crop and winter uk the Yellow (llobc, Australian Brown, Ked (llobe, and the I'rizetaker are usually planted. I'AIIHMI- The parsnip is u long season crop which occtipicM the ground from early npriug until late full. It is started from seed which ia planted as early in the npring as the ground can be worked. The roots arc hurdy to front and their quality is thought to be improved after they urc fronted. The purmiip require* a deep well-prepared seed bed. The soil for the parsnip should be loose, friable and preferably a sandy loam. The need should be mowii from one-half to one inch deep and the rown should be spaced 18 to 24 inches apart. When the seedling* come up they should be thinned out to stand '.\ to 4 inches apart in the row*. Culti - vate the Noil frequently and keep it loom* and fine. The roots may be duu early In the fall an needed or allowed to remain in the ground over winter and lined in the early spring. Two good varieties are the Hollow Crown and llucrnney, ii \ The pea 1m one of the earliest vegetable**, and niiecennhc •owing* of tli* 1 seed can be made vwrv ten days up until about the middle of May. The pea In divided Into three cIiinncn, the dwarf, the half-dwarf, and the tall varieties. The dwarf and the hftlf-dtvarf varieties usually need no support while the tall varieties iiiimt be supported with wire or brimh, The dwarf tiean are the e client to mature while the tall peas me the latest For early planting the nmooth (tea should be lined, because the wrinkled pens are liable to rot If planted too early, The pea will do well on a variety of soil* but It given qulckent remiltn on dandy loam, It In usually not advUablc to manure the ground th* •mm year the pea* ore planted but rather manure the ground the yenr previous The bent qualify of seed should bo purchased and th« »&lt;ed should be wwn from one to three itiehiw ri««p If </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Kxttnulim Bullutln No. 00, Culltyt of Aurlriillnn 10 thr Mill In Im'ii\,v, two liH'hi'N 1m |ii'rliu|m deep niiiuitli, Tin- m«(1n «it i'HIiit |iiiinii'i| In n double row or n »lnnlc mw, If the double row imi'IIiimI U imcil, t hi&lt; mwi mi 1 Mpni'i'il (I liii'lii'N tptli mid the ■ecuinl double row Npnced |M to 2 ( InotMM from I lie Ami doiihlo row, Tin 1 pen kIiiiiiIiI I if (jlvpll nIiiiIIum I'liltlviitloii III order not to ii ijii i •■ I lir root*, The |H'ii letUM In WHMtlMMI IroubltMHM »nd run lie I'ontrollfil by NprnyliiK t Ii •• plum with Ithick l,enf 40 At tlii&gt; rnte of one -eighth pint to ITi uuIIoiin of witter The vuriitUM which M'i'iii to yield tlu&lt; bMt me Kinly t'llot, Mcxi Kxtn Knrly mid Kmi'I.v I'l'olllh' of the ilwnrf vmli'llcn, Mhlle the Ahli'iniitn iitul Ti'li'phone ure twit |(ooi| (nil miiIciIc* The Kverlienrliitf ami NottH Ktu'dhtlor nee kooiI medium enrly vitrletleM, I'MI'I'MII Tim pepper In it wnrm NeitNoii plum him! ki'own urn II it U killed liy froNi The pepper prefurN it witriii lltfht Mill which In fertile iind eohtiilliN plenty of liilitiilN, A well prepured •nil ttiid A llhernl mipttly of witter nld itreitlly lit produclnu peppein of kooU i|iiuliiv The Need for the pepper oiimt omiully lie nturlcl In t ho liothed iiikI the plnni* m-l III tin- ui I ufler nil dMMtfer of frimt In pitNt which In iiNiinlly ulioiit •lime I, The plum* nIioiiUI he Mt •hoilt In to i\ liiclieN npiirl hi the rowN mid the row* about 2 to !l feet ii purl nccurdlnif to the vnrlety, The plmitN nIiouI4 l»« wiiiiTi-d ii iicr I hey urc Net In order to hei-oiue well enluhlUhad. The popper eitn he ImrveNted from 110 to 120 liityw after the m«4 In nuvui TIii* liiNectN mid dUeiiNeN lire Ni-itreely ever troiihlenoma, Home good varietleN tire the Unity Kinu, the ('IiIiu'm- (Hunt, the Oolden I)»wn, and the Mweet I'prlght. POTATO* The potuto In grown either ah an early or late crop. In thU fttate the eaNtern one-third In not well milted to growing late potatoe* altho in the w extern Heetion the late potato In the prin - cipal crop. The Noil for the potato nhould preferably he a good mindy loam altho the potato will do fairly well on a greut variety of Noilx. The Nnil Hhould he Npaded or plowed deeply, he well drained and moderately fertile. It should not he manured the name year an the potatoeH are planted, Devalue of the danger of iufeution from potato bcbI&gt;. Medium-Hized and uniform tubera should be delected for planting. All diiease-infented tuber* nhould be deittroyed. When planting, the potato In usually cut •Fuller Information regarding potato cultivation If contained In Ex - tendon Bulletin No. II, "Growing Potato*!." </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Homa Vtgatabl* Oardtning 11 liiio xuiiiilih' nl/t'd »eed iiltTcn Iwemmc it In umiiilly loo &lt;'«pi&lt;iiMl\« to | • I «• 1 1 f whole tulier* Till* iiion! dcnlndilc n\/v for eneli Mtd piece U iiliiiut UN Incite iin n Iicii'n «gg Mild If nIidiiIiI cunliilh OtM or two I'yi'N Kvi'i'x Mtd pfawfl imml contain mi *y« or it will Hot KI'OW, 'rill' weil pot II toe* for (lie ciinIciii third of Ilie Htnte should Itnve liecn grown I he pri'vloim wiinoii, either In (lie north ecu oldli'N or III till' liiithliiinl* of Nelii'iialtn Kecelit ti'fttft H»IH In llidli'iite I hut the Mentecn t\vy Imul \mUt\n I* nnll»fiietor,v tut' ■Md 'I'lie potfttn weil nIhiiiIiI lie I rented liefore It In |ilnnt«'d TLi* UNilllI liiflhnd In to |tlnee till* |»ntMtoe«» III 1(111111/ NIH'kN mill Illl inerw llii'in III ii wnni'I eontMlliilitf "UK oillii'M of eorrimlvn Nilli' Illillile III eluhl uiiIIiiIin of HttllT, The lioliilneo NllOllId lie HlloWfd to reinnlii in )IiIn dilution from one to two Iioiii'n, nfter Hided they Nlionld lie litken mil, dried, PUi Hlld |»lunlei| Timi.rl pntiitniN nIhmiIiI lie ki&lt;|il unity from children him) Ntnelt 'I he einl&gt; pOtHtofN NllOllId I"' |il»Mled III the NlM'llltf M Mimi iin diiliuer of rree/lnu In |iiinI The lule cro|i U |ilinile.| dlll'ilIK the lute MpHlIU liecoi'dlllU I" the Inciilll.v The *Vt&gt;ll |iiecc* kliollld lie k|inced from \'l to '24 Ilielien »|ilill ill tll« niK Mild tll« l'«»» from M) to i'i (lichen u|mrt, df|*«&lt;ndiiiu upon tlio lnl»'imlvmii'»» ut the nielhild of ellltivAtion, the Vttl'iely, the fertility of the null mid tilt* hiiiInIiiic The clow &lt;i )»l tt ii&lt;&gt;- will rei|iiire hmid eiiltivu Hull while with u renter diNlllllieN liume ellllivttlioli IMHy he liwd The potato Nlioiild lie plumed from I to 4 indu'N in depth, 'I In - pottttO iIiicn tilt) henl ill II eool llloiNt lltlllimpiiere Illld I lien- fun - eiirly plttiitiiiK In de«ir«lile in H hot, dry wet ion. l'rei ( iieni nIihI - low ciiliivttlioii of the noII In deuimlile iii order In nmiiiliiin u dn»t mulch mid kttep the noII loom* mid frlulile The potato |iIiiiiIh are itffecteil with wverul diNOttN«N. It \n therefore itdvimihle to Npruy the plantM with a 4 - 4 - f»&lt; » lionlemi\ mixture two or three iIuicn during the NeaNou, TIiIn treatment Herven an h preventive mid uIno NtimulateH plant growth, The motit injurious iiiNeet In the potato beetle. Ah hooii an thene in - sects are Keen, the plant nhould lie sprayed with antenate of lead at the rate of one pound of lead to ten gallon* of water. ttul&gt; - ■equent sprayings should be given if the insects become trouble - some. The common varieties of potatoes which are grown are the Early Ohio for the east half and Early Ohio, Pearl and Triumph for the western part of the State. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Extennion Bulletin So. SO, College of Agriculture HAIUNH Tim riidUli In ii nIhm'I ni'iimoii, cool weather crop, It U divided into MpHiiK, Niniiinei' mid winter vnrletleit. The mill for the rndlah -ImiiiIiI he liulil, wnriii nml &lt; | ■ i i i ■ k . It nIioiiIiI he Npnded deeply mid pulverised 1 1tntoly, The Need should he town to n depth of nhoiit line lull!' Inch In the ■pHt1|f. Stmill HlieePMtlve now Inn* of the NprliiK i'ihIInIicn cum he iiiimIc nt InterviiU of every ten dn.vi, until nhont »)tttn&gt; I, The Miminer nml winter indUlie* nre imunlly niiwii ii Im &gt;u 1 Miiy nml occupy the tf round the entire ni'mnou, while the NprliiK miMm inntiire In HO to Oil i|ii,vn. The HprliiK nidUhe* ■dinuld he phiuted In POWI from M to VI Inches niinrt while thn xiiiiiiner nml winter rudlfthe* lire imiuilly pliinled I '2 to |M Inehen Mpntt The plnntn nIioiiIiI he thinned froin '1 lo 4 Inehen neeord' Iiim til Ihi' l,V|ie MI/MII^V The miUlh, oi' o^Mer plmit, In ki'iimm for I&lt;n root The »«l ■•ll'.v reipilren n loiitf neimou mid therefore the need fthoiihl he wih ii eniU III Nprllitf, The pliinl U lined ,v lo frimt mid the root* i'NM lie Ii II In the ueomid nil wilder the imne nn |mi «ul|i«» The toll 'ei|ulieiiient« nre mIimIImI' lo flume of the pnoidp The Meed thmild he •mmii lo n depth of one to mie mid one hnlf Ini'lie*. In wwi lit lo If) liiehen itttft, mil- time hefore M»y I ft, The |iIhiiIn ••lii.idd he lldnned lo xIiiimI 'i ur II Imhen npnet in Ihe eown Tim mioU i km \w duu up mid nioeed In urnid In n eonl eell«r for win lee u«e NI'I»4I'M The •pIlHM'h U M plmd yiiiMii fol' IU leuve* Hlileli Hl'i&gt; imed ii« Ml'wiift ll U « •hurt M'MDon, I'ool Hniilhei ero|i ( mid nhoidd Illlt he illicit III Ihe middle nt nummei 1 1 )&lt;• neiinlllvi In lunl Hint •hiiiild hi' plmded ii» (Hi »'Mil| Npl'llitf ill 1 n hite f»|| eciHi The will for Ihe *plnneh «honld lie Ihnrol* piepmed Mild n llh • inl iipplh'iilloii uf well rolled iiiminre nhuiild he worked into I In mm The need «hnuld he wiwll Ihluly In row* \'l Inelum iilniel Mild Id H di'jilh nt mie lord Afl&lt; i the plmiU me up, thill Iliem mil lo nlmid ii eouple of inehen Mpnil ill Ihe r/iW» The eciip In lutmwled h&gt; |nekiii|| I lie leiive* n» needed If Ihe plmil him N lendeM'y lo un to »«ed, eiit the eullie plmil I'Vooi I wo Id I lire* ph'kiliun Him \mn\ly menivKil from e»eli nowIiim </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Home Vegetable Gardening 13 HQfAHH The »&lt;|inii|i In divided Into mirntiier and winter type*. Tlio Ntitntner M|iin*h In rlthrr of n ImimIi or » \iiiin« type, while the winter ni|iiiinIi In n vImIiik tytie. Hi|iihnIi immt not lie planted until diiii«er nf cold wenther U piint. The mill Nhould lie wnrni, mellow nnd well dmlned. Two or three atwYtlfttk of well - rotted Ilinillire pinned III Mfltl Illll ulvPN excellent remilU The noil Nliiiuld lie eiiltlviiled until the vIiipn rover the ground The need nliiiiild lie no Mil to n depth of Oil* 1 til fine nnd one hnlr Ineliex. from Mliy If) to JuiM I The «i|iiimh In mindly fffWfl In IdlU nnd the dUtiinee the hill* ore Npneed U delerndned Inruely li\ vnrletleN, mill rnn«PN from 4 to 7 fppt npnrt, TIip Mtfflffler \iirletlet. hip plnnled liMM'h elimer thnii the winter uiclellt^ I tniilly II or m N&lt;&lt;ed» nre plmitcd In n hill nnd "hen the plnnt« me well e^liilillnhed, they lire Ihlimwl mil to Ihiee irr fltUf lit the ntriiiitfenl plnillN III M Illll. The unmmer W|IIHnh N hnfve»tei| hi-forc rlpi", lint the winter vni'lftlcM Hfp not ImiM^ted until mn turf. The winter ni|iihmIi Nhonhl not lie frowteii hefore It In Ion veNteii When liHrvmtliiif winter »i|nn«h, do not In'enb the «imh fiom the f Mill , lieennie Ilil. liMNteiiN demy Tlie HoIiIimmI M|UN«h In tiie heNl winter vhcIH^, while the IIiinIi m|MHnIi nnd Hiimnier ' 'mull need lire i|e«lndile NUIMMier «n|ini*h Miirpee'n l^ord llooli In mii e«cii||enl m|UMnIi for liolh Niimmi'i' «n»l nlnter n*e wwnwr I'tnurn The NWeet poliiln In nvimu from •llp» Inken riom lh»&lt; WmHh which liMve lieeii urnwn In h mild hut lied TI117 ihonld lie put ihrtNed from MM Mperleiicwl tfl'owi'l' The NprmilN wliiidl HI'oh from Ihe foot* Mi'e then net in Ihe field (ifler ilnimef nf fhrnl )• piiNl The (Hill nhindd lie Inime, id h mid WHl'm up i|iili&lt;Mj&lt; ll •honhl he *\mi\i&lt;i\ eitfhl In ten In. he* ileep »nd nil InmpN lnol-» ■&gt; up Well cot ted (iimiiiim' worded into the will «lve» »&lt;»i'i&lt;l|eiil f$ niiIIn A Nlltfhl I'ldlie In iiniihII^ prefened for if rim Inn Ihe »w*el liniiiiii The pliinu nIiiimI'1 lie ncI hIioiiI |N ini'h«&gt;» Mpurl lit tin ruWH «nd die cown II In 4 feel iipmi The i'int\* nhonld he &lt;lny N« Noon «n (he vine* tun lunched wlih fi'iwl After dltfiflnn, wllimr the piitiiliiex Id 1(17 III (lie nidi fur n dii* und then ii»el» Die rmrt* In dry nmimI nnd plnee I hem in » wnrm &lt;\vy room Wrwppln^ the iiniMioeN In piiper mid pneklnif Ihem In nimeN UNiully ftv*« Kooo r*NllllM The Vellnw .ferNey In perhnpN Ihe liml vnrttif </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 N,rlrn*l»t1 Hulhlltt No, nO.Cnllrur nf Agrifiultur* TOMATO nu»i'K&lt;m In iffitwitm IkiiimIiim iI#'|ioimU mum mciii'Iiim tttnA li'itllliy jiIiimN, iifpffi'ttuiy »(mim1mh1 vmiIcIIch Mini iiiH (tin iiWMff II'M VMI'I*!)** Til* IhiiihI'i |iImiiI* mc iniinllf hImiIkiI III III* li/rt- IimiI Cue Dili kiiiI^ kpii|», Tli* »»*&lt;1 nImmiIiI Ii* miwii fl »« 10 wmIi« Miic* Hi* Unix I'lifiiM In n*I Hi* |iImiiI III III* mnhiwI, *lileli U iIhI'IHM MmI'kIi Til* »**&lt;l •InillM I IK MIWII III M l|*|llll ##f Illl* llHlf liM'll iiii'I III* mih« *|imk*iI hIiiiIII '1 IiikIiih ii i i/mI When (li* (1ml Illl* I*NV*« »|»ll*«l' ( ll'«im|il«lll III* M'*i|IIiim« 'J ill 1 II llM'liK* MJIMH iiii'li hm* ( kIMiki Iii m hIikIoh lux »(f III III* IkiIIikiI WkIm' Nllll hIiNiI* III* |ll«lll» IW M f*W llNJf* Illllll III*)' l»lt* l'(ll(t Tli* iiImiiIw &lt;tln(iil/l iii Iimi'iI*ii*'I UvUir* III*^ ttn&gt; »*l In III* riii(|(ii IIiimIkiiIiiu ** r III* •ki&lt;/|I|iik« U linn* lijf uiimIiiiiII^ *«|iii» im III* iiliinit Ik Mi* iiii »iiti| nun (in 1 iiImihi mi Any* nr 'i wfckn l» k flic* «*Hiiitf IIikih mil A C&lt;'H «1m^« liKf(d'K li'MimiiliuilliiM, ♦♦Illi linlil hkIki mill 1*1 ill* Mill di» mil Mini Jn»t licfmi' ImMhm M|i III* Illlllll^ Hllll'llijK MIMb III* Mill Illlldll III* I'dKl » A OHIIlijf Will U i|k»ImM* fill' *M*ljK fiiill*, lull N Iikhv* will |flv*« ln^d*)' jpl*M» Til* IkIMHIk diiM III* l'*ftl "II MI'llllllll lllMl llMM !»**!! IIINIIIlM ill* |ii'*vliiii« ftwti' Tli* ilUlHiii'K III* |iImiiI« Ml'* »*( Iii III* kmmIkii il*|i*lld« H|imi III* VnH*Ijk iiii'I iMi'flind nf IimIiiIiiu If III* |iImiiI« I'llll*!' IIIHIIKll Hill' »lMl«K(| |||*Jf Illiml III' «Kl i f**l N|INI'I Midi wh* If lli*&gt; Ml'* |»nni»'i| iiml dImI«ki| 'i f**l m|ini'I *mcIi *ll* II (|I»K» |ll*llljK llf »|IMI'K TkIIIIIIk lllllllU HI'* »(||||*I |IIIIIM'l| Id mi*, Ihii ni 1 Illl'** dli'tii* I'liiiiiiitf In mi* hIkki iiii'im* iIihI Mil III* »Ii|k I(|'hiik|ik« IIinI i'iiIiiu I»kI»kkii III* Ikhvk* mill «l*m Hi" "ill iitl, IciivIiik imljK linn iiiiiIii lil'MIM'li In i/niM I'i lining III Ihii III 1 Illl'** *r*lll* IHKMII1 HlHl Ihii ill' Illl'** lll'HIIl'IlM Ml'* iilliiM'Kil Iii w'"H Mini iill hIiIk Iii'hiii'Ii** hic i'*innv*i| Mum m#*i iini»l li* kIvxii In llnm* (ilimU wlili'li mi 1 * hIIiiwi'iI In dutrnnU i»'» id' Mil'** «|*m« WIikii III* |iIhiiU mi' |ii'Mti*i| IIikjc wlnnilil n« •inl'cd Mini Illl* ulnnilil In 1 ilmii' mm •ikiii h« III*^ mn&lt; **l III III* yinlllnl Tile iiliinU nIhhiIiI Ik ||i&lt;i| id Ili« nii|iiiii|'Ih mm III*!' Hnm A »nfl i&gt;nii{ ui 1 «lil|i nl immllii ('(in In' iiHi'tl In He Kir |iImiiI* In III* »ImI»k TIi*^ Mf* m*»*mI i(I«*mmk« llnil HllMi'k III* Imnnln Huh* &lt;l'iiiNll,r III* l»'»if IiIImIiI Id II'iiiiIiIhriiiii* TIiU In it*l*H*il lijr hiiimII lii'iiwM niiiiln ii|i|ii&lt;niiiiM mi iIik Ii'hvm Tli* •iii'Mjrliitf nf Hi* iiImiiU t»llli 4 4ml Mhn|*mim inUliii'K U KHlUfMi'lnijc In &lt;&lt;mil pulling (liln iIImmm* Tli*f* f« iiaiiMlljf mi I'Nil.r «ml h ImI* i'cn|i nf (iifiiHlnM |iiimImi&lt;h| 'IIk IOiiiIIiiiiii, MikII-'.' l",i(ilr -l(»il, Mini Mninir M*Ml »i»- «nnil MirU ii''l t'MI'lKllM hIiII*' III* Mmiii*, I'ii«|(mII» Mini ihihii Mm*p mc* Htttttl iiif-iiliiin Mini ImI* *mcI*»I*&lt;i Tli* ilnlm Mm** l« </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Hom§ VtgttabU Oardtning 15 iinunIIx i't,n*U\*vm\ Mi'omi nnr\y, follimlng III* KnHImiim and Wnnnt MeM Tlix iMwx I'liik mid I'ondxfuM nrx vmIiinIiI* |»lnl&lt; VI'MNIP TIm immiI|&gt; '/in li* iilnnlxd #-» t *•*-#' hi Mix xai'lj' »jii'Iiih oc mIiomi Aii*ii»I I fltf lull nil' IWIjC mmliitf of need foe llie •|»ilHK m-np U lixcxiwiir;* If M""&lt;1 "i'il"» «»■«' denlieil Tlie IimiiI|i will mil i|ii •♦nil In licit) «if^ nliiHild Miif lie itrnwu lii tlic ImiI |»mt »ir (In* •Miniiifi Tin mill •ImhiIiI In* lltflil, tm\ mii'I Hcli ll hIikhI'I li« »|i»(l»'il • Hi 10 |iM'lii'« i|»'i«|i mim! iiih/Ix v^f* (Im«&lt; ColllvMl&lt;&lt; Mix Mill fcwiiM'iiil^ mikI l»"'|i m dui) imili'li ii/i ili» MtrfHw fhn m&gt;m] dliMidd I" 1 tnHii hum linlf In mi' 1 in' li 'l"|i '|'|i»' &lt;"»• »li»»uld lie »\mi'm\ \'i llM'IlM M|IMI), Hill) HlX HKI'd "»&lt;IHII HIII»l'«l»llllH(«&lt;U I III' ll »P»H III III" f'llH* 'I'llC |ll»lll« nI|III|I/| III' tflflllixd &lt;ll|» 1*1 klMIld iS nt i In- In ■• ii|inil III Mil' I'll** hIicii Ilix^ III'* if »(' If Ilii'llM ImII 'Hi* l»IMll|l Cfffl «lll)lllll| llX |H'lH*l'IW| fl'IKII III 1^ VIliH Hull III Mid ill I'lllllllHllim lllW'I'IH Klld lIUxKKM M^flMM, o^ IHMM'rN *%M IW»M»MM Wllli'iiil I'ni'fjitliin, n^fi'f/ |iIniiI III Mi* n«i'd*n In lufxKlnl mi WHIIX Illlll' Hllll I'lilll'l' M dlM'JIW III 1 MM lll»('l'l Wlllll^llIM ll IIHHI'O »«l&gt; 'llM'llIM »»llll" I'Mll 111 III*' tfl'imlllM DXMWIM VtftfPlNllIx lll»("'l» MM lIKI'I'd Illlll »ll"MllM Mild TlllllIM r«ff'f#IM Tll»' •IK'Mllll lll«')'.f» •Midi m* lli« I'IiiiiI lice mii&lt; It mil Ilic Juice n( Ilic |il«nU, Hiu\ HI* (tilled li* »|il'Ht'lllt( (Ik- dudf "f (li»&lt; limi"'l nllli ii n/ilulluu hIiIcIi will Mil II 'I In- IMiml «*fWWWW1 •|'lll»« UlV OlU ''IlKMI ##f limci'ln *»'», Mlic r l» l'*'i«f 40/ Nli'iifiimx, nii'iiiiif «iih|i miliilliiii mid Ui'in M'llf HIIHllnlllll TJll' Illlllltf llllM'I'U. NIM'll MM Illl' lllltMllI Illlll* Hlll\ f)»» ll»&lt;«'ll»'»t, I'll I Mil' fllllHIfK III' fl'lli) Hlll'll lllKCI'U MCI' Itldcil I'*' Mlfl'NjflliM Hi'' liliinN wllli m |iiiIwiii mi Mini hIipm Mil* |iim*«'I mi I* llm |iliinl II In IiIIIcI The l»c&lt;ti |iulmin« nt Mil* i'Inm mix Mi»- MI'MliMlc til lend mid I'mi'U mci'kii Tlii'ii'fi'ie, In dHtxciiilniim Me iiiMli'ilnl In lim' fill' «|il'H^lllMi "&lt;"' "HJ«I 'll'Ml ItliiiH' Mix i&lt;Um hi Iiimu'I «llli hIiIcIi Iix Id riMlliitf Tlic i\\wnw&lt;n nf |iliinl« nix cmiiw'd d,» |iiiiM«llli' |iImiiU tfi'imliiK mi Hie »c«clnlil»' /itnl M|i|illi|l Mix life mil (if ll Oiix iiiiimI mivm' Mix |il»inl hMIi m ihmImImI Wllll'll Mill I'lllll'l Mil III*' dl«MI«l&gt; III' lll'I'VMll il ffHW MllKI'lll* lllC |il»n( MmdcMiK iiiNliiic I* Ilic ihiirI kiIiimIiIc n|imu tut 'll« xt»x« fiiiind mi Mix iiihJ»»HI|' »f ♦x||X««lilx* </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 NtfrfiHiiH tliillfliu Nn /Uht'iilh'iimf A Hi If nil it 1 1 ftt'HMft 4*1* MM W M4MM fMKM 1'iiimihH Hilt lil'llhn IM»N"M *iminih I I ""I 4 1 'limit "I lii Ml ml, 1 V I" *i ' " f ** \il "i i i &gt;;; i wr f/i/li in Mil ///Hi i Mr ni/lf Cm ( i,, t KMMMhlM '" mil in itu mini him mi IhlUI I'liimtM Will III (♦/Ml IK&gt;»W''M !•!.&lt;. I •/' I" il a tlHlU ,IHl HI 10 H HI", t /l|/(*ll/l( Wl))l I'llHulAllHtlll fill Illllllll III HlillUlll IIIHlll hull , linilf i,l Ihf )lim\ Hint In m \n hi iWilliii HII MltllllH I'ltiuititiH 0. 'i P'J" I III Illl 0HMH llllll filll jlll ill * t\im\ iii[*W\\ "LJT"r' III* nhnuliili I nf lln * ni ' i it ma! liittiiliih II ttf hiiilin* * in It ihiiinii *ltin1nA km Hump fun I'l I lllfh*»h, html* hi,. ¥i-inii \ &amp; 'fit III Ht- 1 HiililiHH* HifltlH-, Itltmlm Iht HiVHH MUl liliHh in alii Iih\\ Ihl f«i&lt;l MHA tlHill*m »h'&gt; 'I" I'l"' nliil mill In lln iilhii hull ul Ilii hhIh 'jll"[iilt hu[IhIi i\i&lt; l*n Hilithnim him Liiiif 1 1, hi, I,,*, II,, i l&lt; iA.mih T)hitHl4 hi llHtfl mllfU HUH 111 I HUH II lIlllllnlHli t Hlhtll HllllWlA I, HIM nut xK!t ! XB fi turn m Rlfli'i """*""' UW. IMfft"""" Mr* I nfltlt I HltlullHll- lit HtlWIlIt^ I* I </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>