<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fattening Yearling Heifers on Alfalfa Pasture</title>
               <date value="1933-05">1933-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 281 May 1933 Fattening Yearling Heifers on Alfalfa Pasture MARVEL L. BAKER Bulletin 35 of the North Platte Experiment Substation W. P. Snyder, Superintendent Heifers on alfalfa pasture at the North Platte Substation THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Bueb, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY In three different trials short-yearling heifers were first brought to a full feed of shelled corn and alfalfa hay, and then half the group were full-fed shelled corn on alfalfa pasture for from 112 to 120 days and finished m dry lot on shelled corn and alfalfa hay for from 20 to 28 days, while the other half were full-fed shelled corn and alfalfa hay m a dry lot for the entire period, or 132 to 140 days. The heifers fed on pasture made slightly greater gains while on pasture and slightly smaller gains after they were moved to the dry lot than the heifers fed m the dry lot for the entire period. The heifers fed on pasture made an average daily gain per head of 2.64 pounds for the entire period, compared with an average daily gain of 2.60 pounds for the heifers fed m dry lot. Each year the heifers were sold by lots at the same price per hundred pounds. The heifers fed on pasture ate an average of 36% bushels of shelled corn per head during the feeding period. During the grazing period they ate the estimated equivalent of 926 pounds of alfalfa hay and during the dry-lot finishing period they ate 126 pounds of hay. The heifers fed m dry lot ate an average of 37% bushels of shelled corn and 826 pounds of alfalfa hay per head. The heifers fed on pasture ate 29 pounds less corn but required 49 pounds more alfalfa for each 100 pounds of gain than the heifers fed m the dry lot. Each ton of alfalfa (reduced to its alfalfa-hay equivalent) eaten as pasture replaced four-fifths of a ton of alfalfa hay ar.d from 3% to 4 bushels of shelled corn m the production of gains. Different fields of alfalfa were pastured each year and, as far as could be observed, the stand was not injured. No bloating occurred among the heifers on pasture. No attempt was made to estimate the difference m labor required to feed cattle under the two methods considered. Feeding heifers shelled com on alfalfa pasture after they were on full feed proved to be a satisfactory and practical method of beef pro - duction under conditions at the North Platte Substation. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Fattening Yearling Heifers on Alfalfa Pasture MARVEL L. BAKER Considerable interest has been shown by feeders m western and southwestern Nebraska m the practice of full-feeding cattle on alfalfa pasture. The three tests reported m this publication were conducted m an effort to obtain data oh this method m comparison with the usual practice of feeding shelled corn and alfalfa hay m a dry lot. The periods covered by the three tests were from June 11 to October 29. J1929; from June 15 to October 25, 1931 ; and from June 9to October 27, 1932. PLAN OF EXPERIMENTS Twenty yearling heifers were obtained each year about the middle of May. These cattle were started on ground ear corn and alfalfa hay m 1929 and on shelled corn and alfalfa hay m the other two years. They were brought to a full feed of shelled corn and alfalfa hay as rapidly as possible. This re - quired 19 days for the first trial and 26 for each of the 1 other two trials. They were then divided into two lots as nearly equal m weight, finish, and quality as possible. One lot, re - ferred to as Lot 1, was put on alfalfa pasture and continued on a full feed of shelled corn. The other group of heifers, called Lot 2, was continued on a full feed of shelled corn and alfalfa hay m a dry lot. Salt and water were before the 1 cattle at all times. After being on pasture for from 112 to 120 days, Lot 1 was removed to a dry iot and fed shelled cotn and alfalfa hay for from 20 to 28 days. Initial and final weights are the averages of weights taken on three consecutive' days. Weights were also taken at the end of each 29-day period and at the close of the pasture period each year. The data presented do not include those for the preliminary feeding periods during which the cattle were being brought to a full feed of grain. The heifers made an average! daily gain per head during this preliminary period of approximately 2.2 pounds. CATTLE USED High-grade Hereford yearling heifers were used m each test. The heifers used m the 1929 and the 1932 tests were from the herd of Henry P. Hansen m Lincoln county. I Colo - rado-bred heifers which had been wintered m Lincoln county were used m 1931. In each case the heifers had been wintered on carbonaceous roughages without supplemental feed and were quite thin when brought to the experiment station! For the three years respectively the heifers averaged approxi - mately 375, 390, and 450 pounds when bought. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 281 FEEDS USED Shelled yellow corn, which graded No. 2 or better, and bright, leafy, second and third cutting alfalfa hay were used. ALFALFA PASTURE Each year the heifers were given pastures of from three to four acres in size on which the stand of alfalfa was old and beginning to deteriorate. The cover-page photograph shows the pasture near the close of the 1932 pasture season. The first cutting of alfalfa was cut before the heifers were placed on the pasture. , The season of 1931 was unusually dry. Only 6.31 inches of rain fell from May 1 to October 1. After August 10, even where not grazed, the alfalfa did not make sufficient growth to justify cutting and the heifers were removed to dry lot eight days earlier than had been planned. In 1932 heavy rains fell during June and July and the pasture was succulent during this period. The latter part of the summer was dry. Because of the dry weather and damage from a severe hail storm which occurred August 5, additional pasture had to be provided. Practically no hay was cut from the pastures after the heifers were turned on them during 1931 and 1932. On the other hand, the heifers were charged with pasture which would not have made a profitable hay crop during the last two months of the 1931 season. In estimating the amount of alfalfa eaten as pasture, the yield of hay from ungrazed check plots was compared with that from the pastures. The alfalfa eaten as pasture has been converted into its alfalfa hay equivalent for ease in making comparisons and is reported on that basis. HEALTH OF ANIMALS In the 1929 trial, one heifer from Lot 1 became sick and was removed August 17. There was no evidence to indicate that the pasture had any part in the sickness and the heifer recovered. In 1932 one heifer from Lot 1 died on October 6, eight days after the cattle had been removed from the pasture to the dry lot. The cause of death was pronounced acute pneumonia by the local veterinarian. In each case of the re - moval of a heifer from the experiment, her weight at the be - ginning of the experiment and one-tenth of the feed eaten by the lot prior to the date of her removal were eliminated from the data. There was no bloating among the heifers on pasture. discussion of results No extended discussion of the data presented in Tables 1 and 2 is necessary. Table 1 gives the data secured from the three trials and a weighted average of these data. Table 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Fattening Yearling Heifers on Alfalfa Pasture gives a weighted average of the data obtained from the: three pasture periods, from the three dry-lot finishing periods, and from the three trials considered as a whole. In all three trials the cattle in Lot 1, fed on alfalfa pasture, ate slightly less corn and more alfalfa than the cattle in Lot 2, which were fed in dry lot. This was not only true for each trial when considered as a whole but was also true for both the pasture periods and the dry-lot periods, with two exceo - tions. In the 1931 trial there was no difference in the average daily consumption of shelled corn between the two lots during the period when Lot 1 was on pasture ; and during the finish - ing period of the 1932 trial the heifers in Lot 1 ate slightly more corn than the heifers in Lot 2. In every case the heifers in Lot 1 required somewhat less grain and somewhatj more alfalfa for each 100 pounds of gain. As an average of the three trials this amounted to 29 pounds of shelled corn and 49 pounds of alfalfa. The heifers fed on pasture gained slightly more than thc heifers fed in dry lot in the three trials, averaged together. It will be noted that in the first trial the heifers in Lot 1 made an average daily gain of 0.14 pound per head more than those in Lot 2. In the other two trials the average daily gains were more nearly equal and were slightly in favor of the heifers in Lot 2. It appears from the data in Table 1 that the heifers fed on pasture ate relatively more alfalfa in the 1929 trial than in either of the other two trials. This may explain the slight advantage held by Lot 1 in average daily gains for that year. It is admitted that the method of estimating the amount of alfalfa eaten as pasture is subject to rather large errors. It is also apparent that the alfalfa pasture may vary greatly at different times during the season and from year to year and for this reason affect the results secured in trials of this kind. It is believed that Table 2 presents a fair picture of results which may be expected from feeding cattle under thej condi - tions of these tests. There was very little difference in the gains made by the two lots. In Lot 1 10 bushels of corn and 291 pounds of alfalfa were consumed for each 100 pounds of gain. In Lot 2 slightly more than 10*4 bushels of corn and 242 pounds of alfalfa hay were required for the same amount of gain. Of the 291 pounds of alfalfa eaten by Lot 1 fdr each 100 pounds of gain, 256 pounds (reduced to its equivalent cf alfalfa hay) were eaten as pasture and 35 pounds as alfalfa hay. In other words, if the entire feeding period is con - sidered, 256 pounds of alfalfa (reduced to its equivalent of alfalfa hay) eaten as pasture replaced 207 pounds of alfalfa hay and 29 pounds of shelled corn in the production of 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 281 pounds of gain. If only the pasture season, as shown by Table 2, is considered, 300 pounds of alfalfa eaten as pasture replaced 238 pounds of alfalfa hay and 29 pounds of shelled corn. Or for the entire feeding period, one ton of alfalfa hay eaten as pasture replaced 1,617 pounds of alfalfa hay and slightly more than 4 bushels of shelled corn. For the pasture period alone, the same amount of pasture replaced 1,587 pounds of alfalfa hay and approximately 3V_ bushels of shelled corn. It seems reasonable then to assume that under conditions similar to those of these tests the equivalent of one ton of alfalfa hay eaten as pasture has a replacement value of approximately four-fifths of a ton of alfalfa hay and from 3% to 4 bushels of shelled corn in the production of beef. It is doubtful practice to measure results in terms of "acres of alfalfa" because an acre of alfalfa is an extremely variable quantity. Under the conditions of these tests, however, after the first cutting of alfalfa had been removed, each acre used as pasture replaced approximately lVfc tons of alfalfa hay and 6 bushels of shelled corn in the production of beef. The labor of cutting, stacking, hauling, and feeding the hay was avoided and then, too, the fields were old, the stands poor, and the seasons unfavorable. SLAUGHTER AND SALE Slaughter data for the three years respectively were ob - tained through the courtesy of the Cudahy, Swift, and Armour packing companies at Omaha. It will be noted that in each case the shrink in shipment was greater for the heifers in Lot 1 than for those in Lot 2 although the difference was nor great. In all cases the cattle made acceptable carcasses, but carcass grades were not obtained for the two lots separately. The heifers used in the first two trials were sold in the auction sales of fat cattle held in conjunction with the Ak-Sar-Ben livestock show at Omaha. In 1932 the cattle were sold on the open market. Each year the cattle were sold by lots at the same price and, as far as could be observed, there was no difference in the finish or quality shown by the heifers fed on pasture and those fed in dry lot. EFFECT OF PASTURING ON ALFALFA In these tests the heifers were pastured on different fields of alfalfa each year. These were old fields in which the stands were thin. As far as could be observed the stands were not thinned out any more rapidly as a result of pastur - ing than is usually the case where the alfalfa is cut. It is possible that if the fields were abused through overgrazing, late fall grazing, or grazing over a series of years, the results would be harmful to the alfalfa stand. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Fattening Yearling Heifers on Alfalfa Pasture i Table 1.— Comparison of shelled corn and alfalfa pasture with shelled corn and alfalfa hay for fattening cattle June 11 to June 15 to June 9 to Weistited av Oct. 29. 1929 Oct. 25, 1931 Oct. 27. 1932 8 y«Jv daVa Lot ** L °t ~ Lot 1» Lot 2« Lot 1' Lot 2° j Lot l\ Lot 2 IS^EeTT- £ _ _ sir i* »«» y 882 863 363 868 860 Hi Hi ' _li Av^^gain 2.73 2.59 2.67 2.72 2.50 2.il l.\ i 2„ Av. daily ration: — — — Shelled corn 14.22 14.91 14.04 14.40 16.32 16.90 14.86 I 16.42 — — g— — 8-10 T 5.66 7.83' 6.86 7.07' 6 49 7.67'l 6 29 Feed required for 100 ' ' — ' lbs. sain: AllfXf!! C ° rn III. 5 76 B25 B30 662 674 663 592 Alfalfa 297' 215 293' 258 282' 259 291'! 242 Shrink in shipment \ __\3 : 0 if- ct -&gt; 6.6 5.5 3.1 I 2.9 6.1 4:fr Selling price per 100 lbs. ! (dollars) „ 16.25 15.25 9.25 | 9.25 6.25 6.25 i •IheSed „™. B _Wfs £ 'hly P iro t r y s 120 "^ *** "™ a " d *** 2 ° ! d ° y8 - 'ihellcd S£ IU ___. C t Ys e 2 1 d-aVs day8: *"*"* ""* ™* MMa *** 2 °l dayS - •iheUed SS a'nd alfalfa SF5t days^ *"* MM * hay 28 j daya - reported Sn* °_„ *bMis. Pn " tUre has b * en red &lt;"«l to its alfalfa-hay equivalent and Table 2. — Comparison of shelled corn and alfalfa pasture with shelled com and alfalfa hay for fattening cattle - weighted average of the data for three pasture periods, for three dry lot finishing periods, and for the three total periods | Pasture periods I Dry-lot periods [ Total ; periods Lot l 1 Lot 2» Lot 1» Lot 2« Lot 1° Lot 2° ?* ? f .u^ £ers ,-;r: 28 so 28 so 28 so Av. initial weight„ 466 457 764 760 456 i 467 Av. final weight 764 760 817 814 817 ' 814 * y - 5 a, „ n •••••: 308 303 6S bi 861 367 Av. daily gain. „ 2.69 ) 2.65 2.34 2.37 2.64 j 2.60 Av. daily ration: j 1 Shelled corn 14.60 15.12 16.12 16.93 14.85 I 15.42 Alfalfa 8.08' I 6.30 5.59 6.24 7.67' .6.29 Feed required for 100 lbs. gain: I "' " Shelled corn 642 J 671 687 713 663 i 692 Alfalfa „ „ „ 800' 1 238 288 263 291'! 242 1 Shelled corn and alfalfa pasture 120. 112. and 112 days. 'Shelled corn and alfalfa hay in dry lot 120, 112, and 112 days. ' Shelled corn and alfalfa hay 20, 20, and 28 days. 4 Shelled corn and alfalfa hay 20, 20, and 28 days. » Shelled corn and alfalfa pasture 120, 112, and 112 days ; shelled corn and alfalfa hay 20, 20, and 28 days. ' Shelled corn and alfalfa hny 140, 132, and 140 days. 'The alfalfa eaten as pasture has been reduced to its alfalfa-hay equivalent and reported on that basis. : [sm] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>