<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00033">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00033</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Co-Operative Laws</title>
               <date value="1920-01">1920-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA ■ DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE BUREAU OF MARKETS AND MARKETING LINCOLN BULLETIN NO. 102 CO-OPERATIVE LAWS CO-OPERATIVE CREDIT ASSOCIATIONS CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS CO-OPERATIVE COMPANIES COMPILED January 1920 LEO STUHR SECRETARY OF AGRICULTURE GEO. A. WILLIAMS, Chief of Bureau </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">(» Ol'EKATlVK LAWS ARTICLE XV R. S. 1913 CO-OPERATIVE COMPANIES SECTION SECTION 733 "Co-operative company* de- 736 Powers vested without being fined. mentioned. 734 How incorporated. 737 incorporation tee*. 735 Corporate powers. 733 Sec. 185. "Co-operative company" denned — For the purpose of this article, the words "cooperative company, corporation or association" are defined to mean a company, corporation or association which authorizes the distribution of its earnings in part or wholly on the basis of or in proportions to, the amount of property bought from or sold to member, or members and other patrons, or of labor performed or other services rendered to the corporation : Provided, nothing in this article shall be construed ,as in any way conflicting with or re - pealing any law relating to building and loan associations or installment investment companies. (1919 p. 161 A - mend.) 734 Sec. 186. How incorporated. — Any number of persons, not less than twenty-five, may be associated and incorporated for the cooperative transaction of any law - ful business, including the construction of canals, rail - ways, irrigation ditches, bridges, and other works of in - ternal improvements. (1911 p. 196; Ann. 4272; Comp. 2241b) 735 Sec. 187. Corporate powers — Every co-oper - .•itive corporation as such has power: First — To have succession by its corporate name: </seg>
            <seg id="p004">DEPARTMENT OK AGRICULTURE 4 Second — To sue and to be sued, to complain and de - fend in courts of law and equity : Third — To make and to use a common seal, and alter same at pleasure: Fourth — To hold personal estate, and all such real estate as may be necessary for the legitimate business of the corporation : Fifth — To regulate and limit the right of stockhold - ers to transfer their stock : Sixth — To appoint such subordinate officers and agents as the business of the corporation shall require, and to allow them suitable compensation therefor: Seventh — To make by-laws for the management of its affairs, and to provide therein the terms and limitations of stock ownership, and for the distribution of its earn - ings. Eighth — To purchase, hold, sell, assign or transfer the shares of the capital stock of other co-operative cor - porations organized under this article, and while owner of such stock, to exercise all the rights, powers and privil - eges of ownership, including the right to vote thereon. (1919 p. 162 Amend.) 736 Sec. 188. Powers vested without being men - tioned. — The powers enumerated in the preceding section shall vest in every co-operative corporation in this state, whether the same be formed without, or by legislative en - actment, although they may not be specified in its charter or in its articles of association. (1911 p. 196 ; Ann. 4274 ; Comp. 2241d.) 737 Sec. 189 Incorporation fees — The fees of the incorporation of co-op«rative corporations or associations shall be the same amounts as those provided for like </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CO-OPERATIVE LAWS 5 capitalization of general corporations in the State of Ne - braska, as provided by law: PROVIDED, any co-opera - tive corporation or association, being such under the de - finition given in section 185 of this chapter is hereby au - thorized to file with the secretary of state a declaration, signed by its president and secretary, stating that it is a co-operative corporation or association as above defined, and from and after filing of such declaration with the Secretary of State, it shall be entitled to the same legal re - cognition as though its articles of incorporation had been originally filed under this article; and the fee for filing such declaration shall be two dollars; subject however to the general incorporation laws of the state, except as herein modified or changed. (1911 p. 197; Ann. 4275; Comp. 2241e) </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE CHAPTER 197 Session Laws 1919 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS Sec. 1. Co-operative associations — defined — Co- operative associations, for purposes of this act, shall in - clude organizations organized by producers or consumers, or jointly by producers and consumers, for the purpose of collective bargaining, marketing and purchasing or other co-operative business activity, where the net profits of the association after paying the cost of operation and capital charge, shall be distributed to the membership, not on a basis of capital investment, but on a basis of patronage. Section 2. Same — limited partnerships — Co-opera - tive associations, as hereby defined, shall for all purposes of general law constitute limited partnerships and shall not be deemed corporations. Sec. 3. Articles of association— contents* — Any number of persons, not less than twenty-five, may organ - ize themselves into a co-operative association. Such or - ganization shall be effected by the adoption of articles of the association. The articles of the association shall specify : SE ECTION SECTION 1 Co-operative associations — de- 7 Membership — how determinec fined. 8 Maximum return on capital t( 2 Same — limited partnerships. be fixed — division of surplu 1 Articles of association — con- earnings. tents. 9 Limitation of individual liabil- Powers. ity. , Board of Managers and Officers 10 Real estate — conveyance of. Votes for Managers — proxies 11 Blue sky law — application. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">CO-OPERATIVE LAWS (1) The field of co-operative endeavor to be under- taken ; (2) The name of the association ; (3) The principal place of business of the associa- tion (4) The conditions of memberships; (5) The maximum earnings of capital furnished by members of the association ; (6) The number to constitute the Board of Mana- gers; (7) The basis of apportioning the net profits or losses among the members ; (8) The maximum liability of the members for the obligations of- the association ; (9) The names of the Board of Managers to serve until a Board shall have been chosen after the organiza - tion has been perfected. Sec. 4 Powers — A co-operative association shall have the power to adopt and use a common seal ; to com - plain and defend as an association in all courts of law or equity ; to hold personal estate, and all such real estate as may be necessary for the legitimate business of the as - sociation ; to make by-laws for the management of its af - fairs ; to provide by its articles of association that its mem - bers shall not be liable for any obligation of the associa - tion beyond the actual capital furnished the association by the individual member. Sec. 5. Board of managers— officers — The pruden- tial affairs of the co-operative association shall be vested in a Board of Managers, not Ie3s than five, the number to </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 DEPARTMENT OF AGI.I-U-T c. be determined by the articles of the association. The Board of Managers shall be chosen from the members of the association and upon their election they shall elect, from their own number, a president, vice-president, sec - retary and treasurer, and such other officers, managers, or assistants as shall be determined upon from time to time by the members or managers. Sec. 6. Votes for managers — proxies — In the selec - tion of the Board of Managers, each member of the as - sociation shall have an equal voice represented by one vote; such vote may be exercised in person or by proxy, and if represented by proxy, the proxy shall be in writing and filed with the secretary of the association. Sec. 7. Membership — how determined — A co-op - erative association may by its articles of association deter - mine the conditions of membership in the association. The membership shall not be assignable by any member ex - cept with the consent of the association under rules and conditions to be fixed by the association, in its articles of association or by-laws. Sec. 8. Maximum return on capital to be fixed - division of surplus earnings — The articles of association shall specify the maximum return on capital furnished the association by the members. After paying operating ex - penses and the capital charge as determined by the artic - les of association and setting aside such reserve as may be determined upon from time to time by the association, all surplus earnings shall be divided among and distributed to the membership on a basis of the patronage of the member with the association and not otherwise. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">CO OPERATIVE LAWS 9 Sec. 9. Limitation of individual liability — When by its articles of association the cooperative association shall have limited the liability of its members for obliga - tions of the association to the amount of capital furnished by the members of the association, no person shall have any claim against the members or any of them for recov - ery on account of any obligation of the association. Sec. 10. Real estate— conveyance of — Any real estate held by a co-operative association may be convey - ed in the name of the association by the president of the Board of Managers. Sec. 11. Blue sky law-application — The soliciting of membership and the contribution of membership fees shall be subject to the provisions of the "Blue Sky Law" and under the supervision of whatever department of gov - ernment is charged with the administration of said "Blue Sky Law." Approved, April 3, 1919. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 10 CHAPTER 198 Session Laws 1919 CO-OPERATIVE CREDIT ASSOCIATIONS Sec. 1. Terms defined — In this act, unless the con - text otherwise requires, ''Stock association" means an association having capital stock formed under this act. Words used import the singular or the plural as the case may demand. Sec. 2. Duties of state banking board — It shall be the duty of the State Banking Board to provide such printed information and such blank forms .as may be nec - essary in regard to co-operative credit associations ; at least once each year, and oftener if deemed advisable, to make a thorough examination of each association, either in person or through an assistant; and to perform such other duties as may be required for the carrying out of the purpose of this act. Sec. 3. Articles of association — Fifteen or more cit - izens resident in any one locality in this state may organ- 1 Terms defined 2 Duties of state banking board 3 Articles of association 13 Dividends 14 Liability of members 15 Expulsion of members 4 By-laws — required contents 5 Conditions precedent to trans- action of business. 6 Amendment of by-laws 7 First meeting — election of of- ficers. 16 Fiscal year 17 Annual and special meetings 18 Specific duties of directors 19 Credit committee duties — ap- plication for loans, etc. 8 Powers of association. 9 Loans to members — rules. 10 Unlawful loans by and to of- ficers — penalty. 20 Supervisory committee — duties 21 Annual report to state banking board— penalty for failure tc make. 11 No commissions for securing members or for sale of stock 12 Guaranty fund. 22 Access of state banking loard for examination. 23 Dissolution — how accomplished </seg>
            <seg id="p011">CO-OPERATIVE LAWS 11 ize a co-operative credit association, by subscribing to articles of association, in duplicate, upon a form provided by the State Banking Board. Said articles of association shall be acknowledged by at least fifteen of the persons uniting to form the association, and shall state — (1) The name of the association, which shall in - clude the words "Co-operative credit association;" (2) The purpose of the association ; (3) The principal place of business of the associa - tion, which shall be a place within this state ; (4) The term for which the association is to exist; (5) The par value of the shares, which shall be not less than $10 each; (6) The names and addresses of the persons who are to act as directors until the first meeting of the as - sociation. Hereafter, unless expressly authorized by law, no individual or partnership, nor any corporation or associa - tion formed in this state otherwise than as provided in this act, shall adopt or use the words "co-operative credit association," or any abbreviation or derivative thereof, as a part of the name or designation under which such individual, partnership, corporation, or association shall do business in this state. Sec. 4. By-laws — required contents — The persons uniting to form an association shall adopt, subscribe to, and submit to the State Banking Board with articles of association, a set of by-laws, in duplicate, upon a form approved by said Board. Said by-laws shall be acknow - ledged by at least fifteen of the persons uniting to form the associations, and shall state — (1) The name of the association; </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE (2) The qualifications for membership; the con - ditions under which membership may be granted and terminated ; and the rules governing the exercise of the privileges of membership and the issue and cancellation of stock certificates or membership certificates ; (3) The date of the annual meeting, which must be in the month of January; the method of notifying mem - bers of meetings ; the manner of conducting meetings ; and the number of members which shall constitute a quorum ; (4) The number of directors, to be not less than five, their terms of office, the time and manner of their election, their powers and duties, and the number, not less than a majority, necessary to constitute a quorum of the board of directors; (5) The officers to be elected by the board of di - rectors, their terms of office, the time and manner of their election, and their powers and duties. (6) The number of members on the credit com - mittee, to be not less than three, their terms of office, the time and manner of their election, and their powers and duties; (7) The number of members on the supervisory committee to be not less than three, their term of office, the time and manner of their election, and their powers and duties ; (8) The conditions upon which shares may be paid for and transferred ; (9) The conditions under which the association may borrow money ; (10) The manner of fixing and collecting fees, fines, and other charges, to be paid by the members of the association; </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 CO-OPERATIVE LAWS (11) The manner in which the funds of the assoc - iation may be employed or invested; (12) The conditions upon which loans may be made to members and the manner in which such loans may be repaid ; (13) The maximum rate of interest which may be charged upon loans; (14) The method of receipting for money received on account of shares, or loans; (15) The manner in which the guaranty fund shall be accumulated subject to the provisions of section 12; (16) The manner in which dividends shall be de - termined and paid; (17) The extent of the liability of each member for the debts and obligations of the association ; (18) Any other provisions proper and necessary to carry on the business of the association. Sec. 5. Conditions precedent to transaction of business — Within thirty days after the articles of assoc - iation and the by-laws, duly subscribed to and acknow - ledged, are received by the State Banking Board, it shall approve the same in writing if it is satisfied that they are in conformity with this act and that the conditions are favorable for the success of the association, and, retaining the original on file in its office, shall return the duplicate to the temporary board of directors, who shall within ten days file the articles of the association, together with the written approval of the State Banking Board in the of - fice of the county clerk in the county in which is located the principal place of business of the association. The association shall then have power to transact business,, as authorized by this act. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Sec. 6. Amendment of by-laws — The by-laws of an association may be amended by a three-fourths vote of the members present at a meeting, not less than a 'quorum attending, the notice of which meeting shall have stated the substance of the proposed amendment and the intention to bring it up for consideration. Such amend - ment shall not become effective until it has been ap - proved in writing by the State Banking Board and filed. Sec. 7. First meeting— election of officers — With- in thirty days after the filing of the copy of the articles of association in the office of the county clerk, as pre - scribed in section 5 of this act, a call, signed by not less than a majority of the temporary directors shall be is - sued for a meeting of the members of the association. At such meeting or an adjourned session thereof, the mem - bers shall elect from their number a board of directors, a credit committee, and a supervisory committee, who shall hold office until the next annual meeting and until their successors are elected and have qualified. At each annual meeting a board of directors, a credit committee, and a supervisory committee shall be similarly elected. No director shall be a member of either the credit committee or the supervisory committee, nor shall the same person be a member of both committees. Within ten days after their election, the board of directors shall hold a meeting and elect from their own number a president, a vice-president, a secretary, and a treasurer. The secretary and the treasurer may be the same person. Directors, members of committees, and officers shall hold office until their successors are elected and have •qualified. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">CO-OPERATIVE LAWS 15 Sec. 8. Powers of Association — Upon filing the articles of association and the by-laws, as prescribed in section 5 of this act, the association shall have power, within the limitations of this act — (1) To adopt and use a common seal and to alter it at pleasure ; (2) To have succession for the term prescribed in its articles of association, unless sooner dissolved by op - eration of law or under the provisions of this act ; (3) To make contracts necessary in the conduct of its business; (4) To purchase, lease, or receive by gift, bequest, or devise, and to hold, personal and real property nec - essary in the conduct of its business, and to dispose of the same ; (5) To sue and be sued by the name specified in its articles of association, as fully as natural persons ; (6) To issue shares to persons qualified for mem - bership and to receive payment therefore, and to limit the number of shares which may be owned by one member; (7) To borrow money; (8) To make loans to its members; (9) To deposit its funds in national banks in the state, or in state banks or trust companies organized un - der the laws of the state; (TO) To invest such of its funds as may not be re - quired for loans to members or for other immediate use, in bonds of federal, state, local and municipal govern - ments, in bonds issued under the federal farm loan act, or in other securities approved by the State Banking Board ; (11) To charge a reasonable fee for the transfer of shares: </seg>
            <seg id="p016">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 16 (12) To impose fines upon members for failure to meet promptly their financial obligations to the associa - tion; (13) To expel members, as provided in section 15; (14) To impress a lien upon the shares and divid - ends of any member to the extent of any loans made to him for any fees, fines, or other charges payable by him; (15) To cancel the shares of any member who with - draws or is expelled, subject to the provisions of sections 15 and 16; (16) To exercise such incidental powers as shall be necessary for the conduct of its business. Sec. 9. Loans to members — iules — Any loan in excess of $50 made by the association to a member shall be secured. The indorsement of two solvent members may be accepted as a security. No member shall re - ceive any loan without first pledging his stock to the as - sociation and transferring to it the certificate therefor. Sec. 10. Unlawful loans by and to officers — pen- alty. — No officer, director, or committee member shall be permitted to borrow from the association, or to be - come surety for one borrowing from the association, ex - cept with the approval of a majority of the members present at a meeting, not less than a quorum attending, the notice of which meeting shall have stated that such loans or suretyships were to be considered. Except in the exercise of the powers of the associa - tion to make deposits and investments as provided in sub - divisions 10 and 11 of section 8, any officer, director, or committee member who knowingly permits a loan to be made to a non-member shall be guilty of a misdemeanor </seg>
            <seg id="p017">A AvV and upon conviction thereof shall be fined not more than one hundred dollars or imprisoned in the county jail for 90 days and shall be personally liable to the association for the amount thus illegally loaned; but the illegality of the loan shall be no defense in an action by the assoc - iation to recover from the borrower. Sec. 11. No commissions for securing members or for sale of stock — No association shall pay any commis - sion or compensation for securing members or for the sale of its stock. Sec. 12. Guaranty fund — Every association shall create a guaranty fund, to be held as a reserve to meet contingencies and losses during the life of the associa - tion. All fees and fines, shall, after the payment of or - ganization expenses, be added at once to the guaranty fund. At least 25 percent of the net earnings shall be set aside to this fund at the close of each fiscal year until the fund shall equal the amount of outstanding capital stock. Upon the recommendation of the board of directors, the members of the association, at the annual meeting, may increase, or if the guaranty fund equals or exceeds the amount of the outstanding capital stock, may de - crease the proportion of net earnings to be thus set aside. Sec. 13. Dividends — At the end of any fiscal year, the association may declare a dividend from the income remaining after the deduction of all expenses, losses, and interest paid or accrued, and the amount required to be set aside to the guaranty fund. Such dividend shall not exceed the rate of interest charged on the major part of the money lent during the year. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 18 Sec. 14. Liability of members — No member shall be liable for the debts and obligations of the association in any amount in excess of twice the par value of stock held by said member. Sec. 15 Expulsion of members — Any member who has wilfully failed to fulfill his financial obligations to the association, who wilfully fails to comply with the by-laws, who wilfully neglects to pay his debts, who be - comes insolvent or bankrupt, or who is convicted of a criminal offense involving mortal (moral) terpitude, may be expelled by the board of directors; upon the recom - mendation of two-thirds of the board of directors, any member who is habitually intemperate may be expelled by the members of the association at any meeting; but no member shall be expelled until he has been informed in writing of the charges against him and has had oppor - tunity, after reasonable notice, to be heard thereon. The amounts paid in on shares by members who have been expelled, less the amounts due from such members to the association, shall be paid to them, in the order of their expulsion, but only as funds become available there - for. Such expulsion shall not operate to relieve the ex - pelled member from any existing liability to the associa - tion or to the creditors thereof. Sec. 16. Fiscal year — The fiscal year of all as - sociations organized under this act shall close on the last business day in December. Sec. 17. Annual and special meetings — The annual meeting of the association shall be held in January as provided by the by-laws. Special meetings may be call - ed by the board of directors upon their own initiative, </seg>
            <seg id="p019">CO-OPERATIVE LAWS 19 and shall be called by them at the request of the sup - ervisory committee, or upon the written petition of not less than 15 percent of the members. Sec. 18. Specific duties of directors — The board of directors shall have general management of the affairs, funds, and records of the association. Unless the by-laws shall expressly reserve any or all of the following duties to the membership of the as - sociation, it shall be the special duty of the board of di - rectors — (1) To act upon applications for membership; (2) To fix the amount of the surety bond of each officer having responsibility for the custody of funds oi* property ; (3) To fix the maximum amount which may be lent to any one member; (4) To determine from time to time the rate of in - terest, not to exceed the legal rate, which shall be charged on loans and the rate which shall be paid on deposits; (5) To direct the employment or investment of the funds of the association, other than those lent to mem - bers; (6) To fill any vacancies in offices, in the credit committee, or in their own number; (7) To perform such other duties as the member - ship may from time to time authorize. If at any time the board of directors shall deem any loan unsafe, they may require additional security; and </seg>
            <seg id="p020">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 20 if such additional security is not furnished, they may de - clare the loan due and take action to collect it. Sec. 19. Credit committee duties — application for loans, etc. The credit committee shall meet as often as necessary, to pass upon applications for loans. Such ap - plications shall be in writing, upon a form approved by the State Banking Board, and shall state the purpose for which the loan is desired and the security offered. No loan shall be made unless the application shall have been considered at a meeting of not less than a majority of the committee and shall have received the unanimous ap - proval of the members present, except that an appli - cant may appeal from the decision of the committee of the board of directors. Sec. 20. Supervisory committee— duties — The sup - ervisory committe shall inspect the securities, cash, ac - counts, and loans of the association from time to time, at least once in every three months, and supervise the acts of its officers, directors, and credit committee. At the close of each year they shall audit the books and records of the association, and make a full report upon its affairs for the year to the board of directors, which report shall be read at the annual meeting of the association, and then filed with the State Banking Board. This committee shall have power, by unanimous vote of the entire com - mittee at a meeting called for that purpose, to suspend any officer, any or all of the directors, or any or all of the members of the credit committee; or, by a majority vote, to call a meeting of the association to consider any violation of the by-laws or any practices of which they do not approve. Within seven days after the suspension of any officer, director, or member of the credit committee, </seg>
            <seg id="p021">CO-OPERATIVE LAWS 21 the supervisory committee shall lay the matter before a special meeting of the association for such action a3 it may decide upon. In case of a suspension, whenever the sup - ervisory committee deems necessary, they or one or more of their members designated by them, shall exercise the authority and perform the duties of the person or per - sons suspended until the association acts thereon. The supervisory committee shall fill vacancies in their own number. Sec. 21. Annual report to state banking board — penalty for fa : lure to make — On or before the 1st day of February in each year every association shall file with the State Banking Board, upon a form provided by it, a detailed report of its conditions at the close of the last fiscal year, attested under oath by the president, the secretary, or secretary-treasurer, and a majority of the supervisory committee, and such other reports, as said State Banking Board may from time to time require. For failure to make the annual report to the satisfaction of the State Banking Board and file the same within the time limit fixed by this act, an association shall pay to the State Banking Board five dollars ($5) for each day such failure shall continue, unless the State Banking Board shall extend the time for filing such report. Sec. 22. Access of state banking board for exami - nation — Each association and all of its officers and agents are required to give the State Banking Board, or exami - ners appointed by it, free access to all books, papers, se - curities, and other sources of information relative to said association under their control, and for the purpose of said examination the State Banking Board shall have </seg>
            <seg id="p022">DEPARTMENT UK AOK1CULTUKE power, personally or by deputy, to subpoena witness - es, administer oaths, compel the giving of testimony, and require the submission of documents. If it shall appear from any examination of reports, or otherwise, that an association is insolvent, that it has violated any of the provisions of this act or any other law of the state, or that it is conducting its business in an un - safe manner, the State Banking Board may, after a hear - ing or an opportunity for a hearing given to said associa - tion, take possession of the property and business of such association and retain possession thereof until such time :ts it may determine either to permit it to resume business or to order its dissolution in conformity with law. The State Banking Board may, in its discretion, order the as - sociation to discontinue any illegal or unsafe practices and grant such association not to exceed sixty days with - in which to comply with such order. Sec. 23 Dissolution — how accomplished — Upon the unanimous recommendation of the Board of direct - id's, the members may, at a meeting especially called for the purpose, order a dissolution of the association, by a vote of two-thirds of the entire membership. A commit - tee of three shall thereupon be elected to liquidate the assets of the association under the direction of the State Banking Board. The net assets shall be distributed to the stockholders in proportion to the amount of stock held ; ; .f it has not capital stock, the net assets shall be distri - buted equally among the members. Approved, April 19, 1919. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>