<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA, Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">SUGAR BEET SCRIES NO. XI BULLETIN NO. 73 The University of Nebraska BULLETIN or the AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION or NEBRASKA VOL. XIV. Article III. Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska Br T. L. Lyox and A. T. Wiancko LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. Distributed Mat «, 190£ HAND-HOEI XEBB. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD E. v. FORELL, President, Kearney GEO. F. KENOWER, WisDer EDSON C. RICH, Omaha JOHN L. TEETERS, Lincoln E. C. CALKINS, Kearney C. J. ERNST, Lincoln THE STATION OFFICERS fA BURNETT, B. Sc., Director and Animal Husbandman L. LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist J. S. DALES. M. Ph., Financial Secretary WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF A. T. Peters, D. V. M., Animal Pathologist Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist Hudson H. Nicholson, M. A., Chemist A. L. Haecker, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman Lawrence Bkcnek, B. Sc, Entomologist Erwin H. Hakbouk. Ph. D., Geologist R. A. Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulturist O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineer G. D. Swezet, M. A., Meteorologist A. T. Wiancko, B. S. A., Assistant Agriculturist H. R. Smith, B. Sc, Assistant Animal Husbandman J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist Hknky B. Slade, B. A.. Assistant Chemist (thi n.ot.T. grm umviniTt) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">By T. L. Lyon and A. T. Wiancko. INTRODUCTION The experimental work in the culture of sugar beets 'upon the farm of the Standard Cattle Company at Ames, Nebr., dur - ing the season of 1901 followed plan9 similar to those of some years past and consisted in the main of tests of varieties, testa of fertilizers, different times and different distances of plant - ing, and various methods of cultivation. In conjunction with these experiments an extended examination of the moisture content of soils under different conditions was conducted throughout the greater part of the growing season. Experi - ments in the production of sugar beet seed were continued, and among other matters the treatment of diseases and insect en - emies affecting the sugar beet was given some attention. Through the liberality of the Cattle Company and the large amount of land devoted to experimental work it was possible to conduct most of these experiments upon a scale so large that the results should be of especial value to the beet sugar industry. Aside from the purely experimental work, over 2,000 acres of sugar beets growing under various conditions were kept under constant observation, and the results referred to, though they cannot be taken as conclusive evidence, are at least interesting and suggesth l was explained in Bulletin 60 of this Station, the land upon which the experiments were conducted is representative of the large region of country watered by the Platte and Elkhorn ra and varies from a sandy loam to what is commonly known as gumbo, incidentally giving excellent opportunities for testing the relative merits of light and heavy soils for the production of sugar beet - rtory purp( i Ei rather low yields per acre obtained may be attributed to vere drought which lasted the greater part of two months, ning with the second week in July. Under normal weather 73, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XIV., ART. III. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 conditions the tonnage would probably have been fully twenty per cent higher. On the whole, the season's experience showed to a remarkable extent the drought-resistant qualities of sugar beets in comparison with other field crops. They were found superior in this respect to anything upon the farm except alfalfa. CHARACTER OF THE SEASON There w;is no lack of moisture at the beginning of the season as the soil was well filled with water when spring cultivation began and there was an abundance of rain up to the first week in July, as will be seen in the record of rainfall given below. After the rain of July 4 the weather suddenly became hot and dry, accompanied by a hot south wind which lasted over two weeks, so that the soil rapidly dried out and in many instn baked and cracked open to a depth of two to three feet. Ex tremely hot weather continued for some time and the drought remained practically unbroken until the end of the first week in September. The average temperature for the month of July was 84.5 degrees Fahrenheit. d for this experiment, the one a sandy loam and the other a medium gumbo soil, comprising about fifty and sixty-five acre- lively. The same vari&gt; re planted upon both fields and were given the same treatment ;is the other fields upon the farm. The former field is known as the "North r" and the latter ;is 'Division D". In 1899 the Noith Hager produced a crop of sugar beets and in 1900 a crop of corn which received a liberal dressing of barn - yard mai :iile Division D was in corn and BOrghom dur - beeii manured, lhe I Beoord of Rainfall at Ai I April 1.14 inei l.M • (June 4.76 " July •.« •• August ."&gt;•„» u-mHer ."&gt; -J4 October 1.64 ■ Xovc mlwr .m TESTS OF VARIETIES OF SUGAR BEETS s an abundance of seed was at hund, two fields wer </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska. 5 was prepared for sugar beets by deep plowing in the fall of 1900 with the exception of a few strips where sorghum stacks were standing, which were plowed in the spring. The North Hager was plowed early in the spring, about a month before planting. Immediately before planting, the ground was thoroughly "double disked", rolled, and dragged with ;i light harrow at - tached behind the roller. Planting was begun on both fields on April 25 and continued uninterruptedly until completed. For tbe sake of convenience only one drill was kept at work on each field. Planting upon the North Hager was completed on May 1 and on Division D on May 4. The North Hager was in excellent tilth throughout, but the spring-plowed portions of Division D were quite hard and lumpy so that it was impossible to properly cover much of the seed. A spell of hot, dry weather retarded germination to a considerable extent, especially on Division D, where the first appearance of plants was very scattering. A heavy shower on May 8 melted down the lumps and by a timely use of the roller and harrow a good, even stand of plants was event - ually secured. The plats on Division D consisted of two acres each, while on the North Hager they varied from one to two acres owing to an uneven length of the rows. Horse cultivation was begun on the North Hager on May 16, and on Division D on May 20. Both fields were treated in every respect as ordinary fields would have been. The North Hager received somewhat more hand labor than Division D owing to its being very weedy. It was hand-hoed about the middle of June and afterwards gone over twice to pull the large weeds, while Division D, being exceptionally clean, re - ceived only horse cultivation. All the plats were carefully examined from time to time but no difference could be detected between any of the varieties in respect to growth or outward appearance. Ewill be noticed in the table below that the plats on a con - •able portion of Division D gave very light yields. This due to the fact that here the necessary cultivation was not a soon enough after the last heavy rain of the season, </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 6 drought set in and consequently much of the field became very - hard and the beets suffered considerably, becoming quite yel - low in appearance. Later, another attempt to cultivate the field was made but without effect as the ground had become so hard that the cultivator could not be forced to enter to the desired depth and even where this was possible the ground broke up into lumps too large to form an effective mulch. I comparing the varieties as to yield the results on the l Hager may be considered fairly reliable as the soil con - is were quite uniform. The yields as given in the table i represent topped beets and are computed from the fac - tared weights. Both fields were harvested during the part of October. The sugar content of the North Hager was probably somewhat affected by the presence of some spot", which affected the whole of the field. Iigar tests were begun on August 22 and were made at in - als of one week for seven weeks. The two fields were pled on two consecutive days and the samples consisted of beets each. The figures in the table below are the aver - &gt; of the seven te- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 7 Table I. — l Division L&gt;' NOKTH Hi Sugar Pur in juice per cent Yield Varietie in juice of juice in tons in ions per acre per cent per cent j per acre 1. Dieekiuann 1.Y07 10.70 11.17 13.11 Maurus Deutsch 18.4 ft. Koium.T 15.08 11. 8U I.TStedt 14 36 11.01 12 IK 5. Braune 12.79 1.V14 DM randes 18.59 14 74 1-2.14 Licht 12.91 14.78 11.14 13.14 s. Russian Vilmorin. . . . 10.8 12.84 !» Simon Legrand*. .. 14 77 11.62 13.11 10. Jan:isz 8 08 13.16 12.21 11. Ziemann 12. Fouquier d'Hercuel.. 8.57 L6.94 12.40 14.51 18 Original K. W 16.81 M6.9 14. BlaryMulliez 6 00 15. Eloir 8.71 16.88 ll.tWi lireiber s "&gt;1 15.71 11.92 11 H4 K WohankasZ. R.... 14 W4 11.14 U.M 1* Wohanka's E R 8.S8 14. *7 19.88 11.40 14. T? 19. Hoerning 9.48 14 90 211. Dippe'l LW 11.4*4 21. Pioneer K. \V 16.01 22. Peaz 1"&gt; 04 18.10 Hennion Faumont. . . •"&gt; 68 I 18. 19 Klein et Soukoffsk 13.99 u-hs 6.64 88. Dubois 7 41 15.81 18.47 12 90 11. SH) ,'7 Drumez Elite 1"&gt;44 10.91 •it*. Ladislas Mayzel &lt;i fW 1.Y41 87.4 12 9H 86.4 14.16 29 Dernocour.! 6.86 14,61 11 154 80. Knauer's Mangold. 13.70 11.2'J 11. -M 31. Baumeier ■ nut Stadnii-kv 12 91 15.14 I Utah -grown Vilmorin'i V. K. . Fri»*&lt;lrichswerther Imperial Mangold 11 90 11.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">A study of the above table will show that on the heavy soil the sugar content and purity were higher throughout and where the ground was kept in good condition the yields were also considerably higher. These results as to sugar content of beets on light and heavy soils were borne out by the results upon the farm as a whole but the average yields were slightly in favor of the lighter soils. 13 varieties show considerable differences in sugar and ,ge under approximately the same conditions. A com - on upon the basis of total sugar per acre on the North r plats shows a variation from 2280 pounds for the lowest &gt;5 pounds for the highest, a very considerable difference. o make close comparisons between the varieties with only ear's test would hardly be just and might be quite mis - i&lt; r EXPERIMENTS WITH FERTILIZERS Ee object of this experiment was to determine the effects sugar beets of various complete fertilizers, single ferti - j constituents and combinations of the latter. The single izers were in each case applied in two different quantities a view to getting at the relative value of light and heavy lings. The mixtures were made up of equal weights of constituents. The accompanying diagram of the field, a also contained the planting and cultivation experiments, ssents the arrangement of the plats. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 ■ ■ X z * u. C r x / a X r - r t. ■ S 3 r 05 — I ■ « 3 i « s: » &gt;a i n. 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Xebrcuka 10 Bch of the fertilizer plats consisted of one-tenth acre) welve rows of beets. A thirteenth row was planted with plat to separate it from its neighbor and for conveni. ing. The previous 'cropping and manuring of the 'ground *ame as that of the North Hager variety field, of J.which'Tt was originally a part, being now separated by a deep drainage dit&lt;-h. The field was prepared for sugar beets by deep plow - early in April. The fertilizers were carefully broado upon the plats a few days before planting, which was don 11. The preparation of the seed bed and the planting conducted as in the case of the variety fields. The ground was in excellent condition. Unfortunately a flock of chickens from a neighboring barn - yard destroyed portions of the first four plats soon aftt-r the me up and it was found impossible to secure an even 1 by replanting, though two attempts were made. How - enough of the original planting of each plat was sa\. provide samples for the sugar t. The following table gives the yields per acre of tared b&gt; together with the sugar content and purity of the juice. The suga vere made at intervals of one week for five w oning Aogtu ni the average the ti </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Experimen ts in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 11 Iie much greater average weight of the beets on the last plats, 16 and 17, may be accounted for by the shelter de - i from a strip of sorghum along the south side of the plats, yield per acre was not heavier because on each of these 3 parts of two rows were missed by the planter. Ii examination of the above table, whilo showing small itions such as might be expected on equal-sized plat field, shows, upon the whole, a slight increase upon the lized plats. The results, however, do not point to any jrial advantage in the use of fertilizers upon this land. Leaving out of consideration Pla' ;, 4, 16, and 17, and calculating the average results for the fertilized and unferti - lized plats, we get the following : Table II.— /, E Average ijl ANT1TY &lt;JF FF.KTIL1ZEK 'be^ls'ln' grai; Yield per acre In tons -■ar ! in juice percent w 1. Barnyard manure, 10 tons per acre . .ime, 10 tons per acre 8. Armour A Company's ferti- lizer. 500 lbs. per acre npany"s fertilizer, 500 1 bs. i&gt;er acre 5. Phosphate, potash and nitrate, 8M lbs. per acre • i Unfertilized 7. Potash and nitrate, 820 lbs. 18.11 11.66 12.7 12 9 1S.I per acre 334 ■ f soda, UK) lbs. per acre Nitrate of soda. 320 lbs. per acre 10 Phosphate and nitrate, 820 lbs. per acre 1 1 Unfertilized 12 Potassium sulphate, IN 18. Polonium sulphate, 320 lbs. ll.M 10.154 12.00 11.30 10.45 13.1 13.1 12.7 12 4 »per acre hosphate and potash, 320 lbs. per acre cid phosphate, 160 lbs. per 11. If, : »acre cid phosphate. 320 lbs. per acre nfertilized... 471 10.31 10 42 11 9 9 8 ; </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska. Table III. — Averages of fertilised and unfertilvttd plats. weilht^f Yleld Sn «» r *""» T«Suta Per acre in Juice of juice grains ln tons Percent percent i zed plats 11.4 12 7 rtilized plats 11.1 12. ti To show the efEect of each class of fertilizer used, by calcu- lating the average results from all plats where the fertilizer was used ana tabulating the figures obtained we get the following Table IV. — Effect oj weteht*of Yield Su « ar P"*" TeeteiS P« "re in juice ofjui.e wccw 1U in Innu tu,« AAn* nA r /want Fertilizers grams ln t0Q8 recent Percent Plau having potash 170 11.6 IB.7 Plate having nitrate WO 11.7 13.0 Plata having phosphate 11.7 12.7 Pl»te not fertilized 11.1 18.6 By referring to Bulletin 60 and the Fourteenth Annual Re- port of this Station it will be seen that similar fertilizer exper- iments conducted in 1898 and 1899 showed a slight increase in yield of beets from ihe use of fertilizers but no difference in the sugar content and purity of the juice. METHODS OF CULTIVATION The object of this experiment was to determine the eff&gt; of various systems of cultivation upon the yield and sugar con- tent. The different systems tested are shown in the diagram of the experimental field. All the plats were treated in the ordinary way [up to the time of the second cultivation. The hand- hoeing, given after the third cultivation, was the same for all plats and was simply sufficient to clear the ground of weeds. "All plats were horse- cultivated five times."^ The "ordinary" cultivation was that practiced on other por- tion's of the farm, consisting in [[ a' gradual deepening of the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska. 13 end of the season a depth of about four to five inches is reached. On the first plat a depth of about six inches was reached. On the second plat cultivation was begun at a depth of five inches and gradually made shallower as the season ad - vanced, but this was found difficult owing to the looseness of the ground. The fourth plat was cultivated five inches deep throughout the season. The last plat was cultivated two to three inches deep throughout, but it was found that the mulch produced was not sufficient to protect the soil beneath during the drought and as a consequence it became rather more com - pact and dry than the other plats. ■comparison between shallow and deep cultivation was at - »ted upon a large field but the extremely dry weather made possible to satisfactorily carry out the experiment. K Table V., below, the sugar content and purity of the juice ssent the averages of five tests made at intervals of one beginning August 26. Yield Sntrsr PurHj per acre ' in juice of Juice Method of cultivation tons per cent per cent Although there does not seem to be any satisfactory expla - nation why the results on the first plat should be so low, a study of the above table seems to indicate that moderately deep cultivation should be practiced. It must always be re - membered that very deep cultivation will, late in the season, interfere considerably with the fine lateral roots of the beets, but in this climate of hot, dry summers with high winds the soil mulch in order to be effective must be three or four inches ErojunctionVith the cultivation experiments, soil moisture linations were made upon the deep and shallow culti - plats to see the effect of the depth of cultivation isture content of the soil. As has already been ex- Table V. — Results I Shallow to deep Deep to shallow Ordinary Deep throughout (5 inches) Shallow throughout (2i inches) 1-&gt;.O9 1:2. 74 18 00 18.02 12.51 13.0 14.1 13.4 14.0 li </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Ed the deep cultivation was five inches, while the shallow ation was two to three inches deep throughout the i. Table VI. — Showing percentag I will be seen from the above table that the shallow culti - d plat at first contained more moisture in the surface foot, :h was probably due to the smaller proportion of loose, dry upon the surface, but later in the season the moisture in plat decreased more rapidly than in the case of the deep vated plat, which seems to indicate that the deeper mulch more effective in checking evaporation and consequently cultivation in this country in order to be as effective as ible in conserving soil moisture should be fairly deep. DISTANCE OF PLANTING On one plat in this experiment an attempt was made to get as many rows per acre as possible without increasing the dif - ficulty of horse cultivation. The rows were placed 15 inches apart with every fourth space 18 inches. The idea was to use a one-horse, four-row cultivator and let the horse walk in the ch space. The plants were thinned to eight inches apart in all the rows. In order to increase the ease of cultivation without reducing the number of plants per acre, a second plat, having 21 inches between the rows and six to seven inches be - tween the plants in the rows, was planted. These two plats were compared with one having 18 inches between rows and m hu 'me eu /'■ fl B &lt; I LT1\ All 2i-INl II &lt; t 1. 1 I \ A1 1 1 . N BAMTLOra 1-12 12 -M 24-M inches inches inches .-. 2 .2-24 j ».» KKMAKK. incbes inches inches 1 : st 18. 13.2a 11.67 11.11 B.M 10.75 8.*&gt; 1i 11.90 I.M 10.46 The ground on the shallow cultl- .?i« &lt;VVa found to be much 11.40 9.19 10.06 firmer than on 10.27 8.90 10.00 the deep oultivat ed plat. I i Standing water was found at a 12.68 9.5&lt;J 10.72 depth of 7.5 feet under these plats </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 15 ignated "ordinary" in the cultivation experiment. All plats were cultivated alike. The results as recorded in tne table below are in every re - t in favor of the 18-inch rows. In the case of the 15-inch I more or less difficulty was • ■xperienced in the cultivation. Owing to the difficulty of securing an even stand of plants in the row it does not seem to be advisable to plant so far apart I 1 inches. Experience upon the large fields on the farm shows that with a little care at the beginning a horse or mule will soon learn to walk in a comparatively narrow Table VII. Yield _»r Punty per acre In Juice of juice tons percent per 1800 14 8 - 13 inches apart with 4th row \H inches. . 1 1 14.0 Rows 21 inches apart 10 TO TIME OF PLANTING I is experiment was rather unsatisfactory owing to the fact it was found impracticable to plant early upon the ground in for the experiment, and the last planting was a « failure because of adverse weather conditions at the the plants came up. The first plat was planted on May 11, a second on May and a third on June 13. The interval between the second and third plantings was longer than that between the first and nd, on account of wet weather. A heavy rain, followed by jrching sun just as the plants were coming up, almo. - tally destroyed the stand. tthe season advanced there seemed to be an increasing ence in the growth of the two plats planted May "11 and 22, and about the end of July there appeared to be alu ■nth difference between the two. The following table s the results : Di- i iuiid Rows 1H inches apart </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Table VIII. — / time of planting ea?- Yield Sugar Purity per acre In juice af Juice Date of i-laxtim; tons percent i percent Although this experiment shows such a decided differen&lt; favor of the earlier planting, the results are not borne out by the results obtained upon the farm as a whole. A 38-acre field planted about June 15 gave a yield of 13.5 tons per acre with an average sugar content of about 15 per cent. On another large held about half of which was planted about May 5 and the rest about three weeks later, the later planting besides giv - ing a slightly heavier yield gave about 1 per cent more su^ar than did the earlier planted portion. But these results may possibly be accounted for by the peculiarity of the season. The late planted beets did not receive the same check by the ex - treme drought which suddenly set in. The early planted beets had, during the rather wet weather which preceded, developed an unusually large proportion of leaves, which, when the drought came, the roots were unable to support, while the later planted beets seemed to somewFat adapt themselves to the conditions. On the whole, however, the season's experience indicates that, while good results may be obtained from late planting under favorable conditions, the chances of success are in favor of early planting. The difficulty of securing* a good stand'of sugar beets increases very materially as the*season advances past the third week in May. A small field planted~bn~April£13 gave a yield of 17 tons per acre.^and two large fields planted about April 25 gave yields of 14.7 and' 14.1 7Jtons; per* acre're - spectively, but in all these instances the sugar content was low, which may be accounted for by the presence of some "leaf spot" and by a greater "second growth" during the rainy weather of September. fa..::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::- 18 18.60 14.8 9.06 10.6 Failure </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 EFFECTS OF LATE CULTIVATION ON SUGAR BEETS In general field practice, sugar beets are "laid by" when the leaves are large enough to cover the space between the rows, further cultivation being thereby made difficult. On sev fields cultivation was attempted after this stage had been reached, as the ground had become compacted by heavy rains early in July. The passage of the horse and cultivator broke and tore off many leaves and more or less bruised the crowns of the beets, so that it was considered advisable to determine the effect upon the sugar content later in the season. Several pieces of rows that had been badly bruised were marked, as well as pieces of adjoining rows that were left untouched. Dur - ing the end of September and beginning of October sev samples from each were taken to the laboratory and tested, with the following results : Table IX. — Bruised Ukbbuised Arerage At. wt. «*„„.,. p..rft» Average At. wt. e nff - r Pm-itv wt. with without £ u £" ?.£&amp; wt witL »l«l»out in iS?L „, crowns crowns i£ r )u J?t ~, J ~?t crowns crowns )U J.V grams grams P"** 01 Percent, perce.. ■o.l 13 0 80S o.-&gt; 891 1».« T'.t.J U 0.8 BM 18 W 0 44it 18 Average. 478 I will be observed that while the sugar content and purity e bruised beets were somewhat lower the loss is more than i up by the gain in the average weight of the b&lt; le the test was too limited to be considered conclusive it sates that rather late cultivation may be found beneficial :e the ground has become unduly compacted. The harm by leaf pruning may be more than counterbalanced by the 5 vigorous growth of the beets, especially when very dry her follows. If the cultivating be done during the middle ie day when the leaves are more'or less wilted, few will be en off. In order to determine more fully to what extent the late culti- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska. were made on August 15 upon adjoining portions of a small field half of which was laid by about the 1st of July and remainder cultivate about the 10th and again about the 24th of July. The soil was a medium loam and, at the time of sampling, the former portion was quite hard upon the surface as a result of the heavy rain of July 4, while the latter portion was found to be quite loose and the soil moist to within two or three inches of the surface, representing an almost ideal dition. Carefully made duplicate determinations showed 17.3 and 14.4 per cent of moisture in the first and second foci tively of the late cultivated portion of the field, while that laid by about July 1 contained only 9.4 and 8.5 per cent in the first two feet. Similarly marked differences were found in more extensive examinations of cornfields similarly treated. i;CT OF WEEDY VS. CLEAN GROUND UPON SUGAR CONTEXT &lt; )n the assumption that the growth of weeds in sugar beet fields, aside from lessening the yields, may have a deleterious t upon the sugar content of the beets, it v;as determined to - with a view to ascertaining the extent, of the Adjoining portions in two different fields w "ted for riment. In each field a plat was allowed to run to weeds about the end of July and the beets from these were pared with samples taken from the adjoining clean ground, with the results recorded in the table below. The were made during the first and second weeks of October and the figures in the table represent the averages of the samples from both fields. The samples consisted of five average sized I Eving to the fact that both plats received the same treatment were kept equally clean until late in the cultivation ay be assumed that the difference in the results obtained not so marked as might otherwise have been the c ertheless. the test plainly indicates that where weeds are ved to flourish they may very materially reduce the value le beets produced. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 VlIDl PI CLl Su K »r Purity Sufar in juice of juice in juice of juin - percent percent percent percent EFFECTS OF WET WEATHER AND "SECOND GROWTH" I SUGAR BEETS I, at the sugar content and purity of the juice of sugar b&gt; nore or less reduced in cases where wet weatbt n at iiiif when the beets should be ripening is a fact that has been recognized, and the common belief seems to be that reduction takes place very rapidly. In order to determine to what extent this is true, an ei comparison was made, as the weather conditions from the l in September to the middle of October were particularly favorable for such an investigation. Owing to the dry weather ■ding this period, the beets ripened very early and the r content and purity were unusually high. Soon the tirst rain the beets freshened up and began a vig&lt;&gt; growth which continued up to the time of harvesting. th&lt;-ir foliage then was more luxuriant than at any period in their growth. In the table below, the figures represent the averages of h test. Table X. — I ■ &gt;. 1 lo. a V-t No. g JO 4 13.0 71 9 11 0 -"' 11 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 TABLE XI. — Showing the effect ut wet weather upon &gt;&lt; purity. Average of 50 samples teste.l Oct. 2 and 3 l-&gt; 7 It will be observed that the drop in the percentage of sugar was quite rapid during the first week, but a study of all the figures will show that the drop was more apparent than real and can be fully accounted for by the increase in the weight of the beets, which was probably wholly due to the water taken up. The fact that the purity of^the juice fell so little I out this view. Now allowing, for the purpose of a fuller -on, 25,000 beets per acre and^calculating the yield of sugar from the data at hand, we have in the first instance a total of pounds of sugar per acre with a purity of 84.8 per cent. In the second instance the result would be 2428 pounds of sugar having a purity of 84.1 per cent. In the latter instance, a month after'the fresh growth and the drop in sugar began, the result would be 2515 pounds of sugar per acre having a purity of 81.7 per cent. These figures indicate that while the drop in the percentage of sugar is very considerable the damage is not so r as is generally supposed and the ultimate results go to show that it is the manufacturer and not the farmer who is the Swas observed during the experiment that the increase in weight of the beets was due to a natural, healthy srrowth buds did not appear on the crowns of the beets until near end of the period. Had the beets been quite mature when wet weather began, the fresh growth would probably have jared in the form of buds and there would have been little o increase in the weight of the beets to compensate for the of sugar. It is well known that buds grow at the expense le sugar in the beet and where such are observed har should not be delayed. Even if the w- should turn nerSt S»«r Purit, verage of 50 samples tested Sept. 4 ami verage of 50 san pt. 11 and 12.. verage of -V pt. 1* ami lit . v« rage of 50 san pt. 25 ami 26 si a is a 14.1 18 S 1 B. ."&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 dry a rise in sugar content can hardly be looked for. The buds once started will keep on growing. DISEASES OF SUGAR BEETS 5 few experiments were made in the treatment of "leaf spot" '/) and a form of root rot, which appeared to species of Rhizoctonia. The root rot made its first appearance about the loth of June and affected patches in several fields. The disease was recog - nized as the Rhizoctonia described by Dr. Duggar in Bui if the Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station. About a week later it was found to be spreading quit« rapidly upon a corner of a large field that had been laid by. Knowing that Rhizoctonia had been found to grow particularly well in media, an examination of the soil was made and it was found by the litmus test to give a decidedly acid reaction. It Therefore, determined to try the effect upon the disease of a liberal application of fresh, powdered lime on and around the affected portions of the field. All diseased matter was careful - ly collected and carried from the field. The lime was then liberally scattered on the remaining plants and around the af - fected areas. Later examinations showed that the liming was quite effective in stopping the spread of the disease, in some cases even curing slightly infected plants, while on other un - ed portions of the field the disease continued to spread for some time. A later experiment showed that the liming had no apparent effect where the diseased matter was not first removed. The lime, although quite fresh, seemed to have no injuriuus effect upon the green foliage, which was in many instances com - pletely covered. While not considered conclusive, the results were very satis - fy and indicate that removing the diseased portions of plants and liberally applying fresh, powdered lime may do much to check the spread of this particular fungus. ' In cas« underground rot the application of lime upon the surface ned to have no effect. •See a popular article on beet diseases in The Beet Sugar Gasetti rricultore, ient ami sunci"*:- the treatneal September, 1901, where Mr. (ieo. &lt;;. 1! of the U. S. 1&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Experiment! in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 22 To determine the effect of liming the soil upon the root rot fungus (Phi/ . ten acres of a field that had borne i s the previous year, and where they had rotted consider - ably, were given a dressing of fifteen to twenty tons per acre of the refuse lime from the factory together with some cin. The lime and cinders were plowed under and the beets planted on May 14. Not a trace of rot was found upon the beets when harvested. While the result of a single experiment of this kind not furnish sufficient evidence upon which to base a con - clusion, it indicates that heavy applications of lime may pro - duce conditions unfavorable to the development of certain root-rot fungi. K} "leaf spot" disease did not develop to any serious so that there was not a good opportunity to test the effec - jss of methods of treatment. Eirly in the season more or less trouble from both in&gt; leaf spot was anticipated, and a spraying machine wa - d, by means of which it would be possible to spray thirty •rty acres of sugar beets in a day. This machine consisted of a one-horse cart upon which hundred-gallon tank fitted with a double-acting pump h was geared to the wheels of the cart. The piping was ally designed for the purpose in view and consisted of a main cross-pipe covering eight rows and having a short branch pipe with a fine nozzle at the end for each row. The piping arranged that it could be tilted up or down to suit the height of tli and to avoid trouble from the blowing of the spray by the wind. The working of the machine was in ■spect satisfactory. No difficulty was experienced in ly covering the leaves with the solution without its form nto drops and running off the smooth surface of the leaf, often a source of trouble in properly spraying KJuly 27 slight traces of "leaf spot" were noticed upon ral of the beet fields and a strip upon one of these fed with Bordeaux mixture. The following day a light washed off some of the poison and the treatment \va&gt; id on August 1 and again on the 10th. Later, portions of ■ fields were twice. On September 27 a carefu </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 ttion for the efEects of the spraying was made. On the where portions had been twice sprayed with the Bordeaux re there was no apparent difference between the sprayed te unsprayed portions. All were affected more 01 he disease. But where the beets had been sprayed three there was quite a noticeable difference, the foliage of the 3d beets having a fresher green color and less "'leaf 1 The indications seem to be that if the Bordeaux mix - e applied as soon as the first traces of "leaf spot" appear le applications repeated at intervals, the disease may be lerably checked, but where it has once secured a good ild there seems to be little use in applying this fungicide. Both Paris green and lead arsenate were successfully used as insecticides for the striped blister beetle and grasshoppers, in conjunction with the Bordeaux mixture. These insects both seemed to be easily driven off the field but the grasshoppers returned after the poison had somewhat dissipated. A very significant observation in connection with the prev - alence of "leaf spot" was that in every case the disease made the greatest progress upon the earliest planted fields. In no ci.se did leaf spot appear upon beets planted after the 1st of June. A partial explanation of this phenomenon may be found in tne fact that the earlier planted fields all received a more severe check when the drought set in than did those of later planting. In the case of the late plantings, although the growth ■was slow it was steady all through the dry period. But very much the same observation seems to have been made in previ - ous years and it may be that where "leaf spot" is troublesome rather late planting would be advisable. In all cases there was more "leaf spot" upon the beets on the lighter soils than upon those on the heavier, but this again may have been due to the fact that all of the lighter soils were earlier planted. In continuation of the observations begun in 1899, and recorded in the Fourteenth Annual Report of this Station, the following table is designed to show the condition under which the beets were grown where ' 'leaf spot" appeared. It may be that the appearance of the 'disease is]'connected with more or less* avoidable' conditions and these observations if carried through a*number of years may point them out. 1 Nebraska Station Bulletin 60, Fourteenth Annual R </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska « ! u T. u x 3» • i: I- i S ji : 2 o, u 00 &lt;! !• &amp; -. • 1 H r. x ? I i - Cfa £ ► 1^ t - I- -T (- — d 5 u be «^- _ s ~ e j i • *r «. — 5* '&lt; z I- g , - i \a i JJ a a 5 a. - . - &lt; I a | s i = E = i J 5 ' I &amp; • c .- i I I i i j ri^iLilil i |i a ; « | ; it i| I ; g L- i j | j I iJiSlfil! | ifilf! </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 SELECTION OF MOTHER BEETS AND SEED PRODUCTION I he production of sugar beet seed is an important branch of experimental work at Ames, and gratifying progress has 1 made. For the purpose of next year's work some four thousand mother beets were selected and placed in sand silos uver winter. The method of selection employed was that known as the Illpt cold aqueous diffusion process", which is fully d&lt; lulletin 60 of this Station. It was intended to try the new hod worked out by R. S. Hiltner and R. W. Thatcher, and :ri bed in the Fourteenth Annual Report of this Station,' as the necessary apparatus was not at hand in time it had e abandoned for this year. The mother beets selected were classified according to sugar • nt into three classes: 14 to 16 per cent, 16 to 18 per and 18 per cent and over, and kept separate in the i These beets will be planted next spring. Ii the spring of 1901 about 7,000 mother beets were planted •e feet apart each way and cultivated as is usual in the case orn. The result was about a ton of clean seed of excellent lity. The best of this seed will be planted this year for s from which commercial seed is to be produced the follow - season. tlieved that by careful selection good seed for factory I can be produced at home and a large part of the cost lportation done away with. It is hoped, too, that this will be better adapted to home conditions and that n rm results may be secured. COST OF PRODUCING SUGAR BEETS The cost of producing sugar beets varies with a number of conditions: such as, kind and condition of soil, season, and of labor. A little reflection will show how these condi - tions may affect the cost. Journal I. No </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 The following table is taken from the books of the Standard Cattle Company, where a careful account has been kept of every item of expense. Table XIII. — I These figures are necessarily higher than they need be upon the average farm, where only a comparatively few acres are grown and much of the work may be done without the hiring of extra labor. On the Cattle Company's farm every hand's turn must be covered by a cash outlay and at the highest price, while the average farmer with his family can do the work much cheaper and earn a great part or all of the money represented, and correspondingly increase his yearly income. Ie cost of cultivation beyond a certain point will depend ly upon the extent of weed growth, and the cost of har - ng will be considerably affected by the distance the bi to be hauled. SUMMARY AND CONCLUSIONS ■test of thirty-seven varieties of sugar beets under similar itions showed a wide variation in the total amount of sugar uced per aci I comparison of light and heavy soils for sugar beet pro - ion showed a considerably higher sugar content in the 3 grown upon the heavy soil. Slight increases in the yield, sugar content, and purity of beets were produced by the use of commercial fertilizers, but their use does not seem to be profitable upon the land where Ybak Manuring Pr-paration - illDK Cultiva tiOD I'oial to Laying by "Bl". t I I I I'*-' 2.66 8.74 us 3.33 -• 4H $7.!»il 4.00 4. is 7 14 4.37 $31 15 22 07 15. OH 14 IKt 1M 44 $41 tl9. 8 13 13. lit 13 08 11.80 15.47 IS.0S L*erm«e S166 «2S0 14.90 *1».S&lt;) $2H.1« SIS </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska 27 ■comparison of the different classes of "commercial ferti - 9 was slightly in favor of the phosphate. K comparison of different methods of cultivation was in respect in favor of three to four inch cultivation, which &gt; to be necessary in this region to produce an effective The most satisfactory distance of planting was found to be eighteen inches between rows and eight inches between plants in the rows. Late cultivation of sugar beets, after the leaves are full grown, may, by tearing off leaves, reduce the sugar content, but the extra growth induced this year more than counter - balanced the loss in sugar. The presence of weeds in sugar beet fields may very ma - terially affect the sugar content of the beets. Iesh growth induced by wet weather in autumn when the i should be ripening may rapidly, reduce the percentage r content of the beets, but unless the fresh growth is mpanied by buds upon the crown there seems to be no loss of sugar — the beets increase in size and weight while sugar remains at a standstill. ■urface applications of lime may be effective in checking Rhizoctonia rot of sugar beets. Repeated spraying with "Bordeaux mixture" may act as a preventive of "leaf spot" but will not cure infected leaves. ACKNOWLEDGEMENT For the material of this bulletin our thanks are due the Standard Cattle Company, who bore the expense of the work recorded, and to Mr. R. M. Allen, its general manager, whose enthusiastic interest in sugar beet experimentation has done much to advance the beet sugar industry of this country. Annartii^r\ for nnVilir^atinTi \farpV» 1*1 1 QO"^ </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>