<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  EXPERIMENTS IN THE CULTURE OF THE SUGAR BEET IN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1903">1903</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">IN K BEET SERIES NO. XII. BULLETIN No. 81. The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN or the AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OK NEBRASKA. Volume XVI, Article II. EXPERlMhNTS IN THE CULTURE OF 1 HE SUGAR BEET NEBRASKA. By T. L. Lyon and A. T. Wiancko. DISTRIBUTED SEPT. 1, 1908. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, SPRATIMU SUGAR BEETS </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD i F. KENOWER . Wisner I'dliKLL Aurora KC. RICH, Omaha TEETERS, Lincoln .LKINS. Kearnev NST. Omaha THE STATION OFFICERS THE WORKING STAFF Iker, B. Sc. A.. Dairy Hut liRfMEK. B. &lt;tilft I H. Barbour, Ph. D.. ' Emerson. B. - swezky. U. A ■logitt (tmc riqinti or the uoivintiTv) KXKTT, B. B .1. S. DALKS. M. \'H., I \V. MARSHALL, Ex, KERS. I). V. M. Ph. D.. ll»t. . 1'H. D., ' </seg>
            <seg id="p003">NEBRASKA. BY T. L. LVON AND A. T. WIANCKO. The cooperative sugar beei experimental work upon the farm of the Standard Cattle Company at Ames, Nebraska, dur - ing the season of 1902, was in part a continuation of previous work where conclusive results had not been obtained, and in part a test of methods of culture and combating disease that had not previously been under investigation. All the work was laid out with a view to solving problems in which the farmer or beet grower was particularly interested. As in previous years, the liberality of the Cattle Company made it possible to carry on the work on an extensive scale, and over 200 acres of selected land was used for the experiments. Most of the work was conducted upon what would commonly be termed a deep, friable loam, very uniform in physical character and fertility. This almost absolute uniformity of the soil upon the fields made it possible to use very much larger plats than would ordinarily be admissible without danger of varying the conditions. I he season, on the whole, was rather favorable to the develop - t of the sugar beet. At no time was there a lack of sture. On the contrary, the middle of July was rather this condition was probably responsible for the unusual 'alence of the "leaf spot" disease later in the season. As to perature, the season was somewhat below normal and did present the frequent extremes of heat of other years. TESTS OF VARIETIES OF SUGAR BEETS. In this test twenty-eight varieties of sugar beets were used, including three lots of home-grown seed from the 1901 crop. The field used was a medium loam soil which had been deeply fall plowed after a crop of oats. The ground was disked early in the spring with a view to saving moisture. The seed-bed was prepared just ahead of the planter by thorough "double - disking" followed by a straight-toothed harrow, which in turn was followed by a roller having a light harrow attached to slightly roughen the surface. In this way a fine moist seed-bed was secured. BULL. 8l, AGR. FXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XVI, ART. II. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Mapmntmtmt* in tl&lt;&gt; C'ttltur* &lt;\t the Sugar lift in hebraska 4 I aating was begun on May i, using two four-row planters, :ontinued for three djys without interruption. On May 4 jwer prevented further operation until May 7, when the s. was again taken up and all was completed on May 10. the plats were 160 rods long and consisted of forty-eight 1 eighteen inches apart, with the exception of Plats 27 and rhich, owing to lack of seed, consisted of thirty-one rows two rows respectively. A fairly uniform stand was secured on all plats except Nos. 26 and 27 which were rather thin. Plat 28 was exceptionally ttrick and vigorous, due apparently to the quality of the seed. This seed was of the same stock as No. 24, but subjected to a special form of treatment and styled by the producers "peeled and disinfected." The process of treatment, so far as could be learned, consisted of rubbing off the outer hull or husk and subsequent treatment of the seed with a weak solution of sulphuric acid. All through the season this plat was noticeably more vigorous than any other and remained practically free from "leaf spot," while all other plats were slightly affected. I ire was taken to give all plats the same treatment through - the season. The operations of cultivation, thinning and l-hoeing were conducted in such a way that there never more than a week between the first and last plats. This c was in all cases begun on that side of the field that had 1 planted fir3t so that all parts were cultivated during prac - ly the same stage of development. The yields as given in the table below represent topped beets and are computed from the factory tared weights. The weights are calculated in each case from the total yield of the plat. Plats 1 to 26 were 4.36 acres in extent, while Plats 27 and 28 con - tained 2.82 acres and .18 acre respectively. The sugar content and purity of the juice are averages of twelve tests in each case for Nos. 1 to 27, and three tests for No. 28. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Yield per I Sugar in I Purity of Variety acre. juice. juice. Tons. Per cent. Per cent ISchreiber &lt;90 12.4 -«&gt; ;\ 11.7 TH.ti 3. Knauer's Mangold ... 11.9 Knauer"s Mangold 11.9 4. Sachs ■&lt; 88 11.7 Sachs - 88 11.7 Licht 12.1 79 2 Licht - 12.1 '. iemann Ziemann 7*2 Baumeier 12 4 Baumeier 12 4 riedrichswerther Elite 9 (&gt;7 12 4 Friedrichswerther Elite • VI 12 4 Maurus Deutsch In Maurus Deutsoh M Vilmorin 11.3 Vilmorin j II 11.3 11. Dieokmann I 110 Diwkmann 11 0 -Umon Legrande Simon Legrande.. 13. Count Stadnicky .. 11.42 117 Count Stadnicky .. 11.42 117 Eloir U 10.4 14. Kloir U 10.4 \mts No. 1 inath' M 17 12.7 Ames No. 1 I nativ. \nifs No. 2 inative).. 12.0 •*» 0 Ames No. 2 i nativ. 12.0 80 0 \mes No. 3 (native).. 11.9 Ames No. :5 (native).. 11.9 18. Benneoke 11.4 Benneoke 11.4 Maximal Elite 10.9 Maximal Elite i »ri(final K. \V 11.9 Original K. \V 11.9 21. Pioneer K. \V 11.5 Pioneer K. W 11.5 Old Tyi&gt;e K. W 11 H Dippe's K. W M 14 11 s 24. ... 10.7 : 10.7 Dippe's Z. R 11.1 26. Vilmorin (old 8.28 11.1 I'tah-jjrown seed.. - 10.7 28. Aderstedt "peeled"... 11.7 DESCRIPTION OF THE MAIN EXPERIMENT FIELD. The main experiment field consisted of about forty-eight acres and included the fertilizer tests, time of planting, and methods of cultivation experiments. The soil may be described as a deep medium loam, in excel- condition, almost perfectly level and quite uniform in every respect, giving ideal conditions for the use of large plats. The field had been in corn during 1900 and 1901 and was prepared for the sugar beet crop by deep plowing in the fall of 1901. — a r j 1 t o s Early in March of 1902 it was carefully disked to preserve moisture. All through the spring the conditions were such that a good seed-bed might be prepared at any moment. In all cases the ground was prepared for planting by thorough "double-disking," harrowing and rolling. A light harrow was attached behind the roller to slightly roughen the surface, and the planter immediately followed. The ordinary four-row, two- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Experiment* in the Culture of the Sugar /irrt in Nebraska. 6 11 jrse planter was used. All plats were planted in rows eighteen inches apari, using about twenty pounds of seed per acre. Liter the plants were thinned to eight inches apart in the rows. EXPERIMENTS WITH FERTILIZERS. II several yeare' experiments had shown that there was :ically no use in applying commercial fertilizers to sugar i upon the land at Ames, the regular test was discontinued, as, however, thought desirable to get some further data the effect of extra heavy applications of farmyard manure, cularly upon the quality of the beets and their suscepti - to disease if such should appear. With similar objects in , lime and salt were also used. Tnis experiment, therefore, isted of four plats: one receiving farmyard manure, one and one salt, with one unfertilized plat for comparison. Iiortly before planting, four plats consisting of one acre each : laid off. To the first, 600 pounds of common salt was ed; to the second, 20 tons of well-rotted farmyard manure; e third, 10 tons of refuse lime from the sugar factory; while ourth plat was left unfertilized. All applied materials were ly disked into the ground. All plats were planted on May 7, and a fairly uniform stand of beets was secured. All plats were carefully tended, and all re - reived the same treatment throughout the season and always on In the table below, the tonnage represents the total yield of tared beets on each plat. The sugar and purity were calculated from lists of samples taken in the ordinary way out of every third load as delivered at the factory. All plats were harvested on No - vember 10 Table II. — Result. - Yield per j Supar in ' Pur Fertilizer An examination of the above table will show that the different treatments had little effect upon the yields, the result being in favor of the unfertilized plat. As was experienced in previous jui' juice Tom Farm manure. 9.50 12.1. 11.5 11.4 11.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 vay, and so far as these experiments go it would seem that heavy applications of farm manure may not always have a dele - lerious effect upon the sugar content or purity of the juice. The salt, however, shows a decided effect upon the sugar con - tent, giving 1.4 per cent more than the average of the other plats. But this effect of salt was not observed in another experiment con - ducted for the purpose of determining its effect upon beet diseas - es. Examinations throughout the season showed no differences rxcept in the case of the salt, where the surface of the ground presented a decidedly alkaline appearance and formed a very much harder crust after rains. E August 14 an examination was made as to the effects of ent treatments upon "leaf spot" but no differences could be All plats were diseased to the extent of about 75 per cent, all amount of root-rot was observed on all plats. TIME OF PLANTING EXPERIMENT. Ei object of this experiment was to determine the effect of and late planting upon yield, quality and susceptibility to e. It had been observed in the general field crops of previous years that the early planted beets generally gave heavier yields but were almost invariably more injured by disease than were the later planted fields. In order to get more accurate data upon this question it was determined to make a thorough test under the same soil conditions. With this object in view, five three-acre strips on the described experiment field were laid off and planted at intervals of three weeks. The first plat was planted on March 26, the second on April 16, the third on May 7, the fourth on May 28, .ind the fifth on June 23. In each case the ground was in ideal condition for planting and the stands secured were all that could be desired. It may be observed that while the planting of March 26 was considered very early, some I which were planted on March 14 excellent results. Throughout this experiment the various operations of cultivation, thinning and hoeing were performed at approximately the same stage of growth. The season was a particularly favorable one for work of this kind and no difficulty was experienced, except in the case of the last planting, which came up under rather unfavorable conditions but a fair stand was eventually secured. Owing to cool weather, the first planting took almost three </seg>
            <seg id="p008">KxperimetUt in ttit Culture of the Sugar But in Nebraska. 8 Its to come up and the second planting was ready for thinning e same time. The plantings of May 28 and June 23 were slow in developing although they came up quickly. On 4 it was observed that the planting of May 28 was consid - ly more than three weeks behind the planting of May 7 in of development. All plats were treated as the ordinary field crop and were harvested on November 10. Owing to a mistake the total yield of the first planting was not secured and the tonnage given in the table below was estimated from a small area. In all other cases the tonnage was calculated from the total yield of the pl.it. The sugar tests were made as described in the fertilizer experi- Table III. — Results of time of planting experiment. Yield per j Sugar in Purity of acre. iui. iu ;■ Date of planting. juice. Tons. I Percent. Percent. •Estimated It will be seen that the results of this experiment were very decidedly in favor of early planting. The differences in yields w«re very marked and there seemed to be no ground for attributing the results to any other cause than the time at which the beets were planted. In view of the fact that the sugar beet is naturally very hardy and well adapted to early planting, thr above results may well be worthy of consideration in determin - ing the best time to plant in an ordinary season. Such early planting had not generally been practiced in the locality, and the first week in May was considered a good time to plant the bulk of the crop. In most cases it will be an advantage to practice at least some early planting so as to distribute the work of tending the crop. The considerably higher sugar content of the last planting may be attributed to the very small average size of the beets and the almost entire absence of "leaf spot." On the first plant - ing, traces of "leaf spot" were observed as earlv as July 4. On August 14 the first three plantings showed about 75 per cent of "leaf spot," while the planting of May 28 began to show trares M •14.84 13 i&gt;4 11.6 11.6 11. « 11.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in Nebraska. 9 and that of June 23 was entirely free and practically remained so to the end of the season. METHODS OF CULTIVATION. This experiment was designed to determine the effects upon the beet crop of various methods of treatment throughout the growing season. 'l*he different methods of treatment were as follows: Plat 1. Three-inch cultivation throughout the season, — three Plat 2. Six-inch cultivation throughout the season, — three Kat 3. Ordinary cultivation, consisting of a gradual deepen - &gt;f the horse-cultivation to four or five inches at the end of eason, — three acres. Bai 4. Ordinary cultivation without hand-hoeing, — two and thirds acres. Plat 5. Ordinary cultivation without hand-hoeing or weeding after thinning, — one-third of an acre. Plat 6. Ordinary cultivation with a deep and thorough hand - hoeing when the beets reached a height of four to five inches, — three acres. Eat 7. Six-inch cultivation at the beginning of the season, ually decreasing in depth to three inches at the end of the m. — three acres. lat 8. Three-inch cultivation at the beginning of the season, lually increasing in depth to six inches at the end of the sea - —three acres. Plat 9. Ordinary cultivation continued late into the season, — one acre. ■ lat 10. Ordinary cultivation followed by stripping off half leaves at the time of "laying by," — one-third of an acre. Plat 11. Ordinary cultivation, same as Plat 3, — three acres. 11 plats, except 4, 5 and 6, received the ordinary shallow l-hoeing shortly after thinning. Ehe ground used was a part of the described experiment field, plats were planted in the ordinary way on May 2, and an optionally uniform stand was secured. No difficulty was ?rienced in applying to each plat the treatment designed t. Khe first cultivation was, in all cases, shallow. For the deep vation a broad "goose-foot" shovel made by the farm black - h worked excellently. All of the plais, except that designed </seg>
            <seg id="p010">for late cultivation, were "laid by" about ten days earlier than usual, owing to a wet period during which cultivation could not be practiced. Bui each plat had received five horse-cultiva - tions. The plat designed to go without hand-weeding grew very rank and was gone over with a scythe late in July to cut off the tops of the weeds to prevent seeding. The plat designed for late cultivation received two extra horse-cultivations, one about three weeks after the other plats had been "laid by," and another five weeks later, on September 3. The plat designated "bruised" in the table below was stripped of h;ilf of its leaves when they had reached their full size, on July 8. The work was done by hand, breaking off the outer half of the leaves. In August 14 all plats were carefully examined for "leaf " and it was found that all were affected with the disease to extent of about 50 per cent, except the plat from which half leaves had been stripped, which showed only about 30 per of disease. I the table below, the tonnage represents the average yield e whole plat in each case, as determined by the factory tared hts. The sugar content was determined by testing a sam - ■om every third load of beets and making an average of the ts. All plats were harvested on November 10. Tabu: IV. /. Treatment. ■ 3- loch cultivation throughout 1 cultivation throughout iiltivation Bl cultivation without hand - hoeing ■ Ordinary cultivation without hand - hoeing or weeding ■ Ordinary cultivation with one K comparison of the results of some of the different methods :atment shows how very easily the development of the sugar may be affected. It will be seen that deep cultivation ed preferable to shallow cultivation so far as yield is con- ■ ent. Yield per Sugar in Purit a&lt; 4 re. juk jui. T&lt;m*. Per cent. I Per cent. I3JW 12.2 1 ... 1 4 11.1 16.43 U.1 13.H1 12.1 hand-hoeing ution iltivation m continued late Mrui- cultivation &lt; )rdinai-v cultivation n.flo lH.im li^.04 17.90 15.21 11.x 12.4 H.9 lo.; 11.4 11.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 ccrned, while the shallow cultivation had the advantage of s somewhat higher sugar content, but this may be accounted for by the smaller average size of the beets. As regards the prac - tice of hand-hoeing, it will be seen that the deep hoeing increased the yield over two tons per acre above that secured from the ordinary hoeing and almost four tons per acre above that secured without hand-hoeing, although the latter yielded a somewhat higher sugar content owing, probably, to the considerably smaller average size of the beets. The results on the weedy, unhoed plat clearly show the harm that may result from careless treatment. Both sugar content and tonnage were seriously affected. The result of gradually deepening the cultivation was somewhat better than that secured from the reverse practice. The plat which received the late cultivation showed a very decided gain in tonnage, yielding nearly four tons more per acre than the plats receiving the ordinary treatment. The lower sugar con - tent may be accounted for by considerably larger average size of the beets. If the greater yield was due to the two extra cul - tivations, as seemed to be the case, it shows that the practice may greatly increase the profits. The cost of each such cultivation need not exceed forty cents per acre, and the increase in yield would need to be but slight to make the extra labor a paying investment. As regards the practice of breaking off the outer leaves, it would seem that good may result, since the yield secured was over two and a half tons more per acre than the average of the ordinarily treated plats. It has been argued that breaking off leaves or otherwise bruising the beet may result in permanent injury but it was observed in this case that aside from the larger growth of roots the leaves were considerably healthier later in the season, being less affected by "leaf spot" than were the plats on either side. It is well known that the older leaves are always tirst attacked by "leaf spot," and it may be that removing them has the effect of deferring the appearance of the disease. While breaking off the leaves, as was practiced in this case, would h/irdlv be practicable in general field practice, the result of the experiment indicates that the objection most strongly urged against cultivation after the spaces between the rows have been closed in by leaves mav not be well founded. The result of the experiment in late cultivation also contradicts the general sup - position. The limited experiment in 1901, recorded in Bulletin 73 of this Station, also indicates that leaf pruning and late culti - vation mav be profitable. It mav be suggested that leaf pruning </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Jitet in Nebraska. may be most beneficial in dry seasons when the partly devel - oped roots are unable to gather sufficient moisture to properly support a large leaf growth which was made while there was an abundance of moisture. EXPERIMENTS IN SUGAR BEET SEED PRODUCTION. The work in sugar beet seed production was a continuation of what had been done in former years and partly recorded in earlier bulletins. The beets which had been tested and saved for mothers in the fall of 1901 were divided into two lots and planted in the spring of 1^02. Lot 1 consisted of 1153 beets testing above 16 per cent of sugar, and Lot 2 of 2773 beets testing between 14 and 16 per cent. The two lots were planted far enough apart so that no intermingling of pollen between high and low beets could take place. The seed was harvested on Juh 29. About 150 pounds of well-selected seed from Lot 1 was saved for further propagation. From Lot 2 about 300 pounds of seed was saved to be used for the factory crop. Eom the best of the seed produced in 1901 a five-acre plat planted, to provide mothers for a commercial seed crop in The plat was planted in rows 18 inches apart and the s thinned to 4 inches apart in the rows. From this plat al thousand beets were selected upon the basis of their ical appearance and siloed for use for a commercial seed in 1903. I he regular chemical mother-beet test was conducted during last week of October, 1902. Before beginning this test it been decided to breed from single individuals so far as pos - ■, and, by keeping the progeny of each separate and select - only from those individuals which showed themselves super - n quality and prepotency, to t fleet a more rapid improve - t in sugar content and general adaptability. With this ct in view all beets testing over 15 per cent of sugar were separate, and each individual was provided with a tag rding its sugar content. These tags were rolled up and ed in the holes made bv the rasp in securing a sample of for testing. About 200 beets thus selected and separately led were placed in the silo for use in 1903. ithis mother beet test, the new method worked out by R. S. er and R. W. Thatcher, referred to in Bulletin 73, was used n the whole gave excellent satisfaction. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 I a test of twenty-odd varieties of sugar beets, the results home-grown seed compared very favorably with those the imported seed, which showed quite wide variations, difference in this, as well as in former tests, seems to indi - that the quality of the seed is more important than the Ei application of farmyard manure of 22 tons per acre ed to have no effect upon the quality of the sugar beets, pon the yield per acre, but in the latter respect this year's ts differ from those of previous years. Bie use of salt as a fertilizer, if it had any effect, improved uality of the beets produced but had no effect upon the sus - bility to disease. A comparison of early and late planting of sugar beets was decidedly in favor of early planting. — j — j s o - A comparison of different depths of horse-cultivation of sugar beets was in favor of rather deep cultivation. It should be remembered, however, that the season of 1902 was much wetter and cooler than normal. Experiments in previous years favored cultivation about three inches deep. The yield of sugar beets was very considerably increased by deep hand-hoeing when the beets were four to five inches high. The presence of weeds in sugar beet fields very materially decreased the yield and sugar content of the beets. Breaking off a part of the leaves of sugar beets at "laying by" time did not injuriously affect the yield or quality of the crop. Beets treated in this way were less affected by "leaf spot" disease than those not so treated. Continuing the cultivation of sugar beets after the leaves were full grown considerably increased the yield per acre. ACKNOWLEDGMENT. Our thanks are due Mr. R. M. Allen and the Standard Cattle Company for the very liberal appropriations of land and labor for the experiments recorded in this bulletin, and to Dr. Samuel A. very and the Agricultural Chemical Department for assistance in conducting the mother beet test. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>