<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00020.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00020.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Commission</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">Omaha. Novt To Hi&gt; Kxc-llfiu-y, (ieor.u - ■Icn. QoTemor cf N Complying with the requirement of the law, I have the hom i nt herewith the report of the Secretary of the Public Library C of the Commission and on the library sion. on the ind progress in Nebraska for the two years endii Very respectful i\ F I. HAI.l.KK </seg>
            <seg id="p003">4 The Commission. LAt the annual meeting of the Commission, held April 12. I 1 Hailer, cf Omaha, was re-elected president and Miss Templeton ■ m ppointed secretary. Miss Hunp! uy's title was charged fi 0111 that of Pnant-secretary to that of librarian. The same officers were r ted at the annual meeting of 1*08 The secretary has represented the Ccn.missk n at the meetin Lake Minnetcnka in 1908. and at tie m&lt; ;'ting of the League of Library C'ommisgioBs held in Chicago in January. Utos. The president also at «1 tho Lake Minnetonka meeting of the A. L. A Public Libraries. A number of new libraries have been established during Ii. At Aurora, Chadron. Genoa. Madison, North Bend and Randolph 's have been started by library associatiens and are maintained the public. Subscription libraries have been started at Hardy. I&gt;e - and Nelson. At Plainview a free public library was established levy made for its support. The business men of Bloomfield main - free public reading room equipped with all the best papers and nits. The libraries at Sutton Louisville. Norfolk Pawnee City, library associations, have all been by a tewn tax. shelton and Superior, established by iee public libraries supported The growth of the public library movement is encouraging. The are new only five towns in Nebraska with a population cf ov. which are without public libraries. These are Auburn. Alliance. North however, having an excellent Y. M ('. A. library. There are twenty r towns with a population of under 1000 which have public librai The administration of the libraries is improving all the time. Tht to be gaining ground that the library is net a charitab mien to provide a living for some incompetent person, who is no able to do any thing else, but th it is an educational institution 10 be administered by the person best qualified to do the work. Tht iard of qualifications is constantly being raised. Ten years pcrhapa three librarians in the state who had had technical train A'e now have fifteen librariars who are graduates of library sehoo and thirteen who have taken summer school courses, while ti laken the correspondence course given by the Commission. Many libraries have availed themselves of the services of the Com mission in organizing according to the best methods. The new libraries at Aurora, Geneva, and Sutton were organized by the Commission be- fore they were open to the public. At Ashland. Columbus. Fairbury Holdrege. Humboldt, and Wc« d R1t&lt; ice has been given in class e American Library Association at Asheville N. ('., in 1907. and at Schuyler, and Wahoo. Nrrth Platte is not without library faoi </seg>
            <seg id="p004">&gt;in K an it a ring l.3( 5 made by it. iry n forty-two of the libraries of the s^ate for the purpose cf finding for the purpose cf flnilii the library conditions and of giving help to the librarians. A great many tve been written as 10 the best methods of organizing and ing en the affairs of the library. Advice has also bees given in the ip to the librarians. A great many r have been written as to tt best methods of organizing anc J o airying en the affairs of the library AdTlce has also I n in tht matter of library archil' : of library archin. J archhects' plans criticized. archiiects' plans criticized Buildings. Buildings. Kis has been a parted of um Daring the biennium tht This has been a parted of unusual activity in the building of li- ual activity in the building of li s have been completed haii': braries. Daring the biennium th«-re hav. builiings in Albion. DeWitt. H.velo k. Helrtrfge, McCook. Pawnee builiings in Albion, DeWitt. Hue k. Hcldrege, McCook, Panne. and Tecumseh. and buiidin^s are under construction In Fairbury. Lii r construction in Fairbury, Lincoln and Tecumseh, and buildings an- und Norfolk, and Superior. These are all the gift of Mr. Andrew Cai Norfolk, and Superior. These are all the gift of Mr. Andrew Cat and represent a total cost of f ■ In addition, he has g and represent a total cost of |83.n 10.00. In addition, he has given ?_ to H ullege for a library and science hall. Adding the ;ings College for a library and science hall. Adding the gift cf the past two years to the gtfts of former years, we find ourselv. to Mr. Carnegie for buildings valued at $:: ■ Correspondence Course for Librarians. It occurred to us that the easiest and cheapest way of b f the past two years to the gifts of former years, we find ourst ; 1 to Mr. Carnegie for buildings valued at i Correspondence Course for Librarians. u and cheapest way of i ing the administration in the small library might be in the form of a l|ll»dwni couim Although our library friends told us that li - methods could not be taught except by personal instruction willing' to try it, and arranged twenty lessons covering th li points of librEr&gt; y, adapted to the needs of the small ing the administration in all library might be in the form of a -iiondf Although our library friends told us that li not be taught except by personal instruction, w willin ntial points of library adapted to the need's nf t li - library. With each lesson assignments are made, the work to be jrary. With each lesson assignments are made, the work to !•■ in to our office for revision. There is, of course, no fee, and the coat iiplies. which is small, is the only expense to the librarian. The in to our office for revision. There is, of course, no fee, and the coi le only expense to the librarian. Th plan works admirably; the librarians are doing the work very intelli- I . and library administration is being much improved under our m. bat with slight expenditure of time and energy on our part. plan works admirably rrarians are doing the work very intell being much improved under our ion, but with slight expenditure of time and energy on our part Periodical Periodical Exchange. Exchange The Commission maintains a periodical exchange for the public li Libraries and individuals send in magazines » The Conn lo not want. Th d and are sent free to libraries to f laps in their files During the biennium we have sent out 174 compl lunu-s and number Traveling Libraries. During the biennium we ha^e added seven libraries of forty volumt »ach to our collection of traveling libraries, making U3 library ;ether. These have been senl out 432 times to 196 different places. The nap appended will show how widely these are distributed o. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I ■ fc *v*ii^iiii^*iio iji 1 11 1^ oldl" »3 1\ trU llifli OOOKS 111 lilt 1 le might be added to the traveling library system. The limited funds of the Commission made it impossible to grant their request an 1 for themselves. They raised enoug about Ton volumes which they wen reserved fcr a referenet ate. Part of the Iwtion and have been well used nt cf the State Tniveisuy y the student! in the Bohemian dt Of the rest, twenty-cne traveling 1 thirty volumes each and the deman for these has already exhausted the supply. The great pc - wish that cur German and Swedish citizen might be served in the same way Special Loans, ary is convinced m and more, as udies the coi ditions which cbtain in Nebraska, that one of the best 1 Commission is in reference work. Outside of Omaha and Line ■most no book collections for the spi ;ial student and it will be many years before his needs can be met by local libraries. Ther ■i an agricultural state like Nebraska, towns are small an. and most people do not have even a small local library to drav Where is the student to turn for material on a subject on which -lies information? It seems ih natural place is a 1 by the state for the use cf all its itizens, and we h^ve assumed irk. Requests come in to us with increasing frequency fros ib women high school debaters and in all liai with little effcri, develop this work tremendously and pert reference librarian constantly busy with it alone. As it is. we hav volumes to 388 places in the past two years; more thar double our record for the last biennium. Our own collection of boo ■inadequate for this work, but the other libraries cf I. y lend us their books to be used in this way. No wor ■i , the doipg than this for hers and it is a field capable re meeting the definite i of indefinite extension. School Libraries. It has always been the policy hcols since there is no other of the Commission to work throuni channel through which we can reac arly all the people of the state. Many of cur traveling libraries I rural schools; advice is often given by the commission concerning -election and care of books in school libraries; and talks have given to the teachers at county institutes, junior normals, and teach - iatiens. During the last summer definite instruction was given in book selection and the care of books in six different county institutes ■tohemians tcnk up the matter by subscription to purchas ■vere made up. consisting of th popula </seg>
            <seg id="p006">When the last legislature passed a school library law providing 1 ■ ain amount annually for books other than text books, but making no provision for their selection, it seemed wise that the Commission should print at its expense a stigg- of books for the school library in order to guide the purchase as nm. ■Me in right directions. An dition of 10,000 was printed at a "inn and oopk ave been freely distributed to tht )f the state. There is idence that considerable buying has sen done from the list, but unfortunately there is also eviden. unwise and extravagant buying. Definil «m should made by law for the selection of books for the school library and ar mpilation and printing of a list to be used for Nebraska Library Association During the biennium there have been three meetings of the State brary Association owing to a change in the time of meeting from (ember to October. In December. 190«, a meeting was held in I.in- oln; in Oc a joint r with the Iowa Ubrar) Id at Omaha. South Omaha, and Council Bluffs; in Octoh. the meeting was held at Hastings. In no other way is the growth of the library movement more evident than in the attendance at the ai State Association. At Hastings twenty-five libraries w traveling from all parts of the state to at ■nd. The interest in these meetings is keen; new and better mi Df work are eagerly sought, and the enthusiasm displayed is boundles When one considers that the librarians of the stale get almost nothing n the way of sala y come to the meetings at an e.\ jften equal to a month's salary, in order that they may still better admin - ster the affairs of the libraries to which they are practically giving their one conies to realize something of the meaning of the oft Itioted term "library spirit" which seems synonomous with disinter. and devoted Lincoln Library Club. In the fall of 1907 a club was organized to bring together all tht ngaged in library work in and about the city of Lincoln, for a closer acquaintance and a wider knowledge of each others' fields. The lub now has a membership of about thirty, representing eight libraries }f widely different character. .Meetings are held once a month and topi&lt; Df professional interest are di&gt; Library Legislation Needed in Nebraska. Higher Maximum Tax for Public Libraries ire just coming to realize the place which the public library hould have in our educational system and to see that it should have </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Esame sen cf support which the public school does. The two null which is now the maximum library levy is not enough in our OWBI to support a library which will fulfill all the rci, 8 of the modern library. Other states have found this same thin* and our neighboring states, with conditions similar to ours, 1 it necessary to raise the levy for small towns. Iowa in 11" w allowing cities or towns with a population of fiOO.) or 1«~ mills on the dollar Kan&gt; und it necessary to ■ llowing a :! mill levy in citie: for the support of the public library raise the limit and in 1908 pi of the third and second Selection of Book for School Lihrarie Mention hns already been m M hoo: library law. This provide! ie of tlii unsatisfactory that every district shall Bel aside an ■lually for t'.ie purchase of bocks other than text baoks, a sum made up at the rate cf ten cents tor every child of school age in the dh The law is all right as far as it goes, but it should go farther and i fy hew these bcotu are to be selected. All other states having school . y lawi make seme such provision. As it is now che selection is left to tht directors, who know nothing of children's books and trill of the business side of beck buying. They are at the mercy of the book : — and this scrt of book buying is the most unsatisfactory an.: ve method known — or they order by title from the catalog of a mail order iicut-e, getting cheap binding, poor paper and mutilated I a found but one satisfactory method and that is h d by law compelling the districts to buy from an authn • arefully compiled by someone who knows, not only children. - .thing cf the subject of book buying, and who is in i-iiien to get advantageous prices for the schools. In some states this I printed annually by the state superintendent of public instruc - tion, and in some is compiled by the state library commission. The ICB a law are, of course, obvious: it gives the school the benefit pert knowledge of books, and insures them of getting the best return. - for the money expended. Country Extension of Library Privilege What we need more than anything elae in library legislation is law which will permit the extension of library privileges to par - living beyond town limits; a law which will allow contracts to be made between town, township or county officers and library boards • by. for a consideration agreed upon, the residents of the town. township, or county are given full privileges of the library. Several of our western states have passed such laws recently. The Minnesota law is particularly good, reading as follows: "And the board of direc - in the chapter provided for. shall have the power to admit to </seg>
            <seg id="p008">persons not residing within the eorporat village under such regulation! and conditloni as commissioners of the county in which the library or governing body of any with the v jwn city, or village, to loan agreed upon in such contract upon out of the Wl A la to levy annually :'. mills on ;Ii&gt; brary Provision made in the school library law for I ion of an authorized lis t board n coatrmcl with «hp lmar.l of red to nnke com: • aits with district *iliool boards 1 havf allowing a lilirary rivileg </seg>
            <seg id="p009">10 Summary of Statistics. Nov. 30, 1936- Ncv. 30, 1908. - added in biennium By gift By purcha ■ number of hot ks accessioned mini! ks withdraws to dau to date. in library ling librark Kntsli.-h Bohemian Tt till r of traveling libraries sent cut in bienniuni Number of volumes sent out in bienniuni Number of places to which hoc W4 ange Number of complete volume: in out in bienniuni Number of single numbers sen Din Expenditures, Nov. 30 1906- Nov. 30, 1908. t 1 "1 Dumber of v&lt; lumea now • r of places to which libraries were st-nt ul lean </seg>
            <seg id="p010">ii / z J£ *u ::^ i ri r. r i / i ■ --• 5 , ?' Z ! -♦ i - -* r- x" X C C ~' r- i I Ti C C -*■ C • So5 a *- r "I 5 i X ■?'■?:£ l C * xSx«3 - i 1 -* I ■•■ ? 5 5 S3 r r i -«- i I 5x5. S x S 5 S 5 5 5 5 ??.?.??. 5- : z 3 = £5 )lll! tt /■ / ,-- - 5 5 "J !;J» 5 2 X 5 S3 » '- 8 SB 3 / a !* 0 S - I e * 3 - ¥ 3E 7 ?: - .-: — r-. s *ti- :i rj — - -. - :. Sin — - - - _ in * 3 « ~ i " * S I! it ?j - ri ~ =' -f .T Ik §r- S3 7H3 § B 3 5 i S 3 « 3 3 § — ri — x r: -* — - I\ § I r- 5 8 m 3.a s §i a n it = 2 I S 5 S 5. 5. 5 / . . : : . . ■ * : -■'■£&lt;- . 2 &gt;. - S O 9 r&gt; S .._*-' — </seg>
            <seg id="p011">12 X &gt; • r r X rr-^ j; r. •x B fflX2^W&gt; r. x / / -: /. T IB ■ / ■ /" S ■ ii 2 « a « r r. &lt; S I£ 1^ --: X 1 r~ r- x I 1 X 1 1- ri -M * :' n TJ &gt;mi is — isx 11- - 5xS?St xfi i 7 i x x i x r i z i x c -t . ■* i : ;ic?X5S?;:«og i i-tt:!^-:!;.;-/ rr i- i X QC 3S 2 i — i J£ &lt; J*S gJi *5 ■ j. x ■ Ill bt 5^z :;: i S « • • • ♦ Z *,jj:e»*s5sc; * -r. x 1 1 x - -= £ J- V =5 . .Z j ; = = T _ Z / Ci, Si- 51, L. Q rt c S &lt; S 5 — r - = — - — « 0 '% z c -=r t " 7 1 I - I I s I u| 3883 f2S ii i 3 If SS8i £?i 3 S i g l[: "i i w » s_ ! , 8 8 ii r i.?c?,5 888 ! • = 3S8S38388S ; ri so c R8SS §§ 88 38 r- r— i - — 1SS8 R88 t.t I™ r- t~ C Tl " i" — ; RS2S8 S S 8J ~r i- ri — •^ Sa us S . pra 8 - 5 i I 885 3^2 S 'e ■ I --8 ■ -^ i | ■ , m 88 8 S 8 8 5 Si 8 ; SSS8 a _ '^ S 5 ;2 S t&gt; '^ '- '£ T S S i &gt; - £2 1% 5 5 5 5c </seg>
            <seg id="p012">1 * « &gt; --. --. r. i ri v ■ir»ci JSS3 Z be t: / SB X i - r - f X MS i * 2 * -fii ¥ X X -r x -r i- iri * J r a 7 J£ 7! iHi^^i^S * '■ t </seg>
            <seg id="p013">r» # :« i I &gt;1 •5* 1 a o a PS .7 • 1* «. V 5 C5 *••.. ■ &lt; r ", I* 5* z 1 v % u 2 I w* U a w z •^ Li 4 • •r N IS &gt;- &lt; \ » I - \ \ • s •I K X I 1 F 'j &lt; &gt; K IX ft j 3 O • - •- • • *! V ! z o \ v K *l /! I X z 0 c 0 _l J I * J &amp; \( c •■ O O I z C e a i&gt; X a 5 o o z :• i = I rf • 4 - X a I a m Z ■ ■ a. c o t- w j o X 3 O \ a u I - O S 5 * . • v • •••:. 3 0 ■ a z z 3 •3 s £* </seg>
            <seg id="p014">2 T. *. 7 W o a* "4 &lt; a. fe a o r : M t r .. •••, % ■3 i— S Pv 5^ {•2 a. n 8 V o x I*. K a- fi 3» &lt; r o m i^ I n &lt; \ X X '\ &lt; a \ *&lt;* 5 ./ N 5 R &gt; a J o / 0. \ \ 3 z i 3 • 3 &amp; ■ • z &lt; Z o o _; 2 * if \ Ml z O in = i a i • A- M w &gt; I ' - • * o o t - : X a D X «r z M X Q. o O — X u X o I 3 m O * s I Vi *"«. o *-J fl </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>