<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Seventeenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE State Industrial School KEARNEY, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">, i 1 !f &lt; ! ■ ).J A &gt;« . cc r : 8 I ; i § I i • c/) 3 &gt; fe r , O 5 r </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Seventeenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE State Industrial School KEARNEY, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30. 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">140 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : Honored am I with the privilege of submitting to you the seventeenth biennial report of the State Industrial School for boys for the period ending November 30, 1914. The enrollment of our school has increased from 173, December 1, 1912, to 203, December 1, 1914. This increase is attributed not to increased delinquency or incorrigibility throughout our commonwealth, but to the greater freedom with which judges of the courts, having become acquainted with our school, commit boys to this institution, also to the extreme vigilance which this administration has ex - erted in preventing escapes, the kindly interest we have ever taken in the boys, and the generosity with which we have provided them good, nourishing, plain food and neat clothing. More than that, we have been fair and just in paroling boys promptly when that privilege was earned and not till then, thus showing favoritism to none. The boys themselves have appreciated this and have responded accordingly. The management is proud of but six escapes without return during this entire administration. A special effort has been made to insist upon each and every boy being in school for his advancement in the common school branches one-half of each of the five school days in each week from fall until spring. This has been enforced often at the expense of detailed institution work but always with the belief that the institution was planned and organized by our State and its law-makers first of all for the good of the boys, the inmates themselves, and that this benefit can best be imposed by giving to the youth those rudiments of an education so essential to material prosperity in commercial life which is a struggle with an </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 141 education, much more of a struggle without an education. Consistent with this belief we have insisted upon school work first, detail work second. Endeavor has been made to increase the efficiency of the schools by grading them, as city schools are graded, and by increasing the number of instructors that each teacher may not be responsible for too many pupils, too many classes, or too many sub - jects. The schools are now managed with efficiency for our boys, with economy for the Nebraska tax payer and with justice to the instructor. The discipline of the industrial school throughout is a source of pride to all connected therewith. As "Eternal vigilance" has been said to be "the price of liberty" so do we believe it to be the price of good discipline. While the boys are orderly and well behaved, it is not a strained de - portment, neither does it prevent them from plunging heartily and with enthusiasm into the modern sports. The system of demerits in vogue at the commencement of this biennium placed a boy 6000 points in the hole at the beginning of his sojourn in the school with the under - standing that he must unpack this burden before he could gain his parole. In place of this plan of overwhelming in - debtedness burdening the boy at his very beginning in the school, the Board of Commissioners with the Superin - tendent has instituted a system whereby each boy starts with a clean record and is urged to gain his parole earn - ing a stated number of credits. This, naturally, appeals to a boy, as it would to a man, with much more favor just as it is more inspiring to build up a fortune than to over - come a debt. The boys earn these credits at the rate of thirty per day by being studious in their school assign - ments, industrious in their detail work and gentlemanly in their conduct, and are thereby entitled to parole in twelve to seventeen months. The especially good and industrious boy may by earning extra credits shorten the period sev - eral months; while others by poor work and careless in - difference may retard materially their parolement. Spacious, attractive porches have been constructed on the fronts of four cottages, B. C. D and E, adding much of beauty to the general appearance of the buildings and </seg>
            <seg id="p005">142 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF institution grounds. Material is now contracted for to place new front and rear porches on the main building. New, convenient, modern offices have been made out of the old, untidy ones. The cracked and broken plaster with many thicknesses of paper has been removed, a nice hard finish neatly and tastily painted has been substituted, making with the new woodwork Of oak a complete renova - tion. North of the Trades Buildintr a neat, one-story, frame paint shop has been erected. Just south of the brick barn a neat, commodious, up - to-date building thirty feet by sixteen feet has been erec - ted to house and protect the farm machinery, wagons and buggies belonging to the State. This is a valuable struc - ture, consisting of one story and a large, commodious base - ment, curtailing materially the destruction that has prev - iously shortened the life of valuable farm machinery. A grand, valuable, cement silo with a steel frame now stands just south of the dairy barn, improving and modern - izing the State's farm, at the same time furnishing most valuable ensilage for our large dairy herd, of which we are justly proud. A modern oven of the Middleby-Marshall type has taken the place, in the bakery, of the old, dilapidated cast iron oven formerly used to bake the bread for the boys. Through the generosity and big-heartedness of Gov - ernor Morehead it has been possible to install a first class, new, Powers 6 A moving picture machine. By placing this in a newly constructed booth on the north of the gym - nasium the boys have been permitted the pleasure of a moving picture show of their own each Saturday afternoon at 1 :30, not only furnishing them with much pleasure and amusement, but giving the opportunity to several of our boys of learning to manipulate an up-to-date moving pic - ture machine of the latest model. Much improvement has been made in the old Trades Building. It has a new roof of tin and shingles. The approach to the main entrance has been renewed with cement. The halls throughout have been relieved of the old unsanitary wainscoating and crumbling plaster. This </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 143 has been replaced with plaster of hard finish, neatly tinted, giving the halls not only neatness in appearance but real cleanliness. The boys' kitchen has been remodeled, re - plastered, refinished, and neatly painted. Perhaps the greatest improvement of all is that in the boys' dining room. It has a new hard wood floor and a modern steel ceiling. Large radiators furnish the heat in place of the old iron pipings. Out of the plain, un - attractive place, where the boys congregated for meals three times a day, a cheerful, neat, beautiful dining room has been realized which is a pride to the officers and em - ployees as well as a pride and comfort to the boys. The bed rooms of many of the employees are in the Trades Building. All of these have been repaired, re - plastered in part and painted, making comfortable and at - tractive apartments for the employees. The old carpenter shop has been abandoned and the new carpenter shop dis - placed the shoe shop. The shoe department is now in a neat room on the first floor just to the left of the main entrance. This room was replastered, refinished, painted and provided with a new century motor to furnish power for the machinery. The tailoring room was replastered, refinished, repiped for heat, and neatly painted. It was also supplied through - out with nice large, new tables, five in number. Electric irons were installed for use in pressing clothes. A par - tition was placed across the shop at the eastern extremity to form a hallway just east of the shop to permit employees to pass to their rooms without entering the tailor shop. The laundry has been renovated, old plaster and wood - work removed then replastered, refinished and refloored. Formerly an old, rat-infested department, it is now neat, clean and sanitary. The printing office has been replastered and repaired. New type has been purchased. An electric motor has been installed to run the repaired press, reducing the expense for electricity to run the large motor in the engine room unnecessarily. For this office the carpenters have made nice cupboards and cases to store and protect the paper stock. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">144 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF The large elevator which runs from the basement to the attic of the Trades Building has been, after years of idleness, repaired and placed in working order. The entire north wall of the Administration Building was deemed unsafe by the Board of Commissioners, was torn down and rebuilt. The Chapel on the third floor and the Sunday School Room on the second floor have been re - plastered. Both the main hallways have been partially replastered and one of them papered, the other painted. The Superintendent's parlor, dining room, kitchen and bed rooms on the second floor have been cleaned of old paper and plastered and have been neatly papered and painted. The officers' dining room on the first floor, the assist - ant superintendent's apartments, the steward's apartments and the stenographer's room have been refinished and decorated. In the basement of this building is the of - ficers' kitchen, which has been thoroughly cleaned, replas - tered and refinished with new wood work. It is now both sanitary and neat. New, modern steel ceilings have been placed in the large play rooms of cottages B, D, and E, while these and other rooms of these cottages have been replastered and refinished, adding greatly to the appearance and sanita - tion of the homes for the boys. Thus, these striking improvements and multitudinous repairs have been made much to the advancement of our institution, the benefit of the boys therein and to the satis - faction of the taxpayers whose money, amounting to $29,600.86, as shown in financial statement, has been eco - nomically expended. Approximately eleven thousand dollars of the above amount was invested by the Board of Commissioners in a new conduit system which permits the abandonment of the old, unsafe tunnels and the disintegrating pipe lines therein. This system furnishes the entire institution with the most efficient and most modern large heating system in the State. Its installment has been made at a minimum cost due to the extreme care of the management and the interested dexterity of the institution's engineer. The institution is proud of a good clear water supply. </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 145 The large triplex pump is overtaxed because of the ex - treme height to which the water must be lifted, straining the pump and requiring an excessive use of electric power. Consequently the engineering department is now busy ex - cavating under the pump, lowering the pump and, with the aid of practical pump men, drilling two more wells to in - crease the water volume. This is being done to save the machinery and reduce the monthly expense for electricity as power is now purchased from the Kearney Water and Electric Power Co. at a monthly expense, with electricity used for lighting and other motors, ranging from $180.00 to $280.00. Our herd of cattle has increased in number from fifty to sixty-six. It is far more nearly Holstein throughout. In the near future we hope to have it pure bred Holstein. Of nothing connected with the dairy are we more proud than our present success in making butter. During the month of October alone our dairy produced 189 pounds of butter. This has for the time more than supplied our needs. In our large brick barn, besides one old horse, we have twenty-three good horses well taken care of and in good condition. The institution possesses three hundred brown leghorn chickens. Hogs have been one of the largest sources of revenue. During the biennium we have sold them to the amount of $3,131.12. We now have in our yards two hundred fifty pure bred Duroc Jersey Reds. RECREATIONS The boys have been encouraged in all kinds of manly sports, such as foot ball, base ball, basket ball and ice skat - ing. To encourage the boys in these games new foot ball suits were purchased, basket balls, base balls, bats and skates have been cheerfully supplied. The State Legislature of 1913 is to be praised for ap - propriating $40,000.00 for the purchase of land for the State Industrial School for boys. Governor Morehead dis - played his remarkable business ability in the purchase </seg>
            <seg id="p010">146 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF made. Two hundred eighty-two acres of choice bottom land, all under irrigation, for $38,993.79 constituted the purchase. Land just east of this is held at $200.00 an acre. Governor Morehead paid less than $139.00 per acre. The purchase was an excellent bargain for the State, as the crop statistics on another page will prove. The boys enjoy the good books they borrow weekly from our library, which is large and neat, located in the western wing of the administration building on the main floor. The books are selected by the State Library Com - mission, giving the boys an excellent opportunity to cul - tivate a taste for good literature at the same time furnish - ing them information and pleasure. CHANGES OF WHICH WE ARE PROUD MAY BE SUMMED UP AS FOLLOWS A night watch has been placed in each dormitory to prevent escapes, to preserve order and to prevent vulgar practices. The credit system has been substituted for the de - merit system. The schools have been strengthened. The plan of permitting only boys in the band who will remain one year or more after entering. New speakers each Sunday in Chapel rather than one permanent Chaplain. Establishment of telephone reports by each inside night-watchman hourly to the outside night-watchman, thus guaranteeing vigilance. MY ESTIMATE OF THE SCHOOL'S NEEDS FOLLOWS Hospital, that boys who have contracted infectious or contagious diseases may be isolated. Gymnasium of the modern kind thoroughly equipped. Hog house. Ice house. Lathes, tools and supplies for manual training in the carpenter shop. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 147 Library books and cases. With gratitude I report the fact that there has been no death among the many boys cared for during the entire biennium. I regard the work of the biennium a success. The finances are sound, there being no deficit. Credit is hereby given my excellent assistants in the office, judges of the courts, probation officers and all civic authorities through - out the State. In closing this letter I thank you, Governor More - head, for all the encouragement and assistance you have ever willingly offered and freely given. I thank you, gen - tlemen, the members of the Board of Commissioners, for your conscientious aid in reducing the cost of purchased supplies and your sound judgment freely given when I have been doubtful as to the proper course to pursue in dealing with some of my boys. Sincerely yours R. V. Clark, Superintendent. Kearney, Nebraska, November 30, 191A. INDUSTRIES Carpentering Truly this department has been one of most practical benefit to the boys therein because the carpenters have been busy in various departments throughout the institution and now have much work planned in advance. They have repaired chairs and other furniture, refloored and refin - ished rooms, made fancy cupboards and pedestals, repaired the barns, sheds and buildings, reshingled the Trades Build - ing, built new porches, and constructed an excellent build - ing for the machinery. One master carpenter has charge of the boys in the department. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">148 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF Shoe Making Department Here are made all the shoes for all the boys of the institution, both every day shoes and Sunday shoes. All shoe repairing, all the repairing of harness and leather in general is done by the boys of this detail under the direc - tion of one expert shoemaker. The department has been a busy and successful one both from the standpoint of the boys employed and the State. Several boys paroled from this detail are capable of making a first class pair of shoes in one day's time. Laundry In the laundry the boys are taught practical laundry work. To do the washing and ironing for two hundred boys and forty employees, as do the boys of this detail, furnishes ample material for practice and real experience. The boys handle all kinds of garments from plain blankets to fancy waists. Painting All the buildings have been painted white on the ex - terior and very much interior decorating has wonderfully improved the appearance of the institution. Much more painting is to be done. Engineering Some of the most successful paroled boys gained their training in this department. Here the boys learn to handle the large boilers, to clean flues, watch water and steam gauges, care for valves, pumps, and steam lines, oil and clean engines, to help in steam fitting and machine shop work in general. All this is under the direction of the chief engineer and his assistant. Tailoring An experienced first class tailor has charge of this branch of the school where practically all the clothing worn by the boys is made and repaired. Gray uniforms, daily work clothes, shirts, overalls, mittens and citizen's suits for paroled boys leaving the school, are here made, keeping the tailor and his apprentices busy during all the working </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 149 hours. Boys who apply themselves leave this department thoroughly qualified to gain remunerative employment in the cities from which many of them came. Kitchens and Bakery The officers' kitchen under an able and practical lady instructor and the boys' kitchen with bakery managed by a cook and baker who is an expert in both lines, furnish wonderful facilities for the boys who are anxious to ad - vance in these trades. Boys who were formerly in these departments are now earning good salaries and there is no necessity for their ever being without work. Dining Rooms The dining room work is done by boys under the di - rection of two ladies, one for each dining room. The boys are encouraged to be neat, alert, quiet, careful, cleanly and obliging in performing their numerous duties, which in - clude sweeping, dusting, setting tables, washing dishes, drying them and serving meals. Cottage Work The boys' cottages and other buildings are cared for by the smaller boys under the direction of lady house-keep - ers. The duties here are scrubbing, washing windows, dust - ing, sweeping, paraffining and polishing floors, cleaning lamp globes, making beds, mending and patching. Green Home Four good reasons demand a green house for our school. It furnishes plants for the campus and grounds, flowers for the buildings, enables us to gain an early start with garden plants and furnishes instruction in plant life for the boy. While we have not raised many beautiful flowers we have benefited wonderfully by the early start given tomato plants, permitting us to enjoy the early mar - ket with its higher prices, bringing to us revenues and fur - nishing the dining rooms with early ripened tomatoes for table use. Egg plant, peppers and cabbage also benefit by the early start in the greenhouse. Boys are given a real relish for gardening under these conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 150 Band An excellent band of forty-three pieces is in training under the direction of an experienced and very competent instructor. This furnishes, with the orchestra and choir, an enviable opportunity to our boys to develop a taste for high grade music and to train themselves in skillfully handling an instrument so that they may go into bands or orchestras to secure remunerative assistance upon their departure from the school. We have been, indeed, proud of our band during the past summer because we sincerely felt that we had the best permanently organized band in the State of Nebraska. Printing With difficulty can too much praise be given this de - partment. It furnishes the boys not only a trade, but broadens and informs them along many lines while they are paining the mechanical side of the work. No branch of labor furnishes better and quicker facilities for gaininor employment out in the big world than does the printer's art. Our office publishes a weekly paper called the "In - dustrial School Times," in which the printers and boys in general take a deep interest, sending it to their parents as regularly as it comes from the press. Many boys through - out the State hold paying positions for which they were qualified in the printing office of the Nebraska State In - dustrial School. Agriculture It is with pride that I present the following statement of farm products during the biennium because they are the best and most profitable the school ever raised, regard - less of the fact that both seasons were dry ones and that fewer acres were under cultivation than in some previous years. A greater number of boys participate in the agri - cultural work than in any other work. They cannot but be impressed with its importance after helping to produce the following results. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 151 Our Farm Products for 1913 were: Potatoes, 2400 bushels Corn, 300 bushels... Oats, 2000 bushels Rye, 250 bushels Beets, 532 tons..._ Alfalfa, 250 tons Onions, 150 bushels.. Supar corn, 10 acres Corn fodder, 70 tons Other crops Total Our Farm Products for 1914 Sujrar beets, 613 tons were: $ 5065.00 4000.00 Potatoes, 5400 bushels Oats, 1600 bushels Wheat, 430 bushels Com, 500 bushels 640.00 344.13 300.00 Onions, 300 bushels 300.00 Tomatoes, 1000 bushel Turnips, 200 bushels 603.00 100.00 200.00 600.00 2000.00 160.00 165.60 Sweet corn Other vegetables Alfalfa, 250 tons Bailed oats straw, 32 tons Sweet potatoes, 92 bushels Pop corn. 25 bushels 45.00 Total $12519.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">152 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF PHYSICIAN'S REPORT R. V. Clark, Superintendent, State Industrial School, Kear ney, Nebraska. Dear Sir: I have been the Physician and Surgeon at the State Industrial School for the past two years. For the work done I submit my report. During the period mentioned I have made 435 calls to the school, 1740 examinations, prescribed and prepared medicine for all cases that required it. We have had to treat cases of pneumonia, many cases of bronchitis, ton - silitis, sore throat, coughs and colds, scarlet fever, an epidemic of mumps of a severe type, acute and chronic in - digestion, enteris colitis, appendicitis, cystitus, nephritis and most any of the diseases of this locality, venereal di - seases that some of the boys had contracted before they were admitted to the school. Surgery : fracture of the hum - erus radius ulna, both bones of the forearm, dislocations, hernia, sprains and other injuries. The sanitary condition of the school is excellent. I have no death to report. Pardon a little pride when I add that I have now served over eight years as physician and surgeon and during that time had only one death to report. I thank you for the assistance rendered. J. L. Bennett, M. D. Kearney, Nebraska, November 30, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 153 SUPERINTENDENTS ESTIMATE OF NEEDED APPROPRIATIONS FOR BIENNIUM APRIL 1, 1915, TO APRIL 1, 1917. Superintendent _ $3600.00 Assistant Superintendent 2200.00 Steward _ _ 1600.00 Chaplain _ _ _ 600.00 Physician „ _ _ 1200.00 Matron _ 600.00 Wages of Employees _ 34000.00 Maintenance _ _ 63000.00 Permanent and general repairs _ _ 30000.00 Equipment of Trades Department _ 2000.00 Machinery and Farm Equipment 1200.00 Band and Orchestra Instruments and Music _ 800.00 Total _ _ $140800.00 TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Year For Year Total ending ending for Nov. 30, Nov. 30, Biennium 1913 1914 Total Total Total Male Male Male Male Male Present at beginning of period i 173 150 173 Admitted: For first time 64 116 180 Readmitted Transferred from other institu- tions '. 3 3 Returned from parole granted be- fore commencement of period.... 17 9 26 Return from escape made before comencement of period : 3 1 4 Totals 257 279 386 Discharged: Expiration of fixed term 1 : 1 Reached majority •. 2 13 1 Reached majority Transferred to other institutions Released to parents of friends Died Paroled and not returned during period I 97 73 170 Escaped and not returned during period 7 2 9 Totals 107 76 183 Remaining at end of period 150 203 203 Average number under car*. I 156 178 188 Absent on parole or escape at com- mencement of or during period and later discharged without re- turning to school I 7 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">154 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE II. AGES AND COLOR OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year Total ending ending for Nov. 30, Nov. 30, Biennium AGE 1913 1914 WCT WCT WCT Under 10 3 .... 3 5 16 8 19 10 and under 12 9 .... 9 17 1 18 26 1 27 12 and under 14 15 .... 15 32 3 35 47 3 50 14 and under 16 18 2 20 ' 34 2 36 52 4 56 16 and under 18 16 1 17, 21 2 23 37 3 40 18 and under 21 I 1 .... 1 1 .... 1 Totals I 61 3 64 110 9 119 171 12 183 TABLE III. EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year I For Year Total ending ending for EDUCATION Nov. 30, I Nov. 30, Biennium 1913 1914 None - 5 5 Below 3d Grade '. 18 34 52 4th Grade 13 22 35 5th Grade 10 24 34 6th Grade 11 13 24 7th Grade 7 11 18 8th Grade 5 8 13 High School 2 2 College Totals 64 119 183 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 155 TABLE IV. NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED f For Year For Year Total ending ending for f For Year For Year Total ending ending for Nov. 30, Nov. 30, Biennium 1913 1914 NATIVITY NATIVITY Nov. 30, Nov. 30, Biennium 1913 1914 Nebraska Nebraska United States other than Nebraska Total native born United States other than Nebraska Total native born Austria 1 1 Denmark _... 1 1 France 1 1 Germany 1 1 Ireland 1 1 Poland 1 1 Roumania 1 1 Russia : 2 2 Total foreign born 3 6 9 Unknown 6 7 13 Totals ; «4 119 183 TABLE V. NATIVITY OF FATHER OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year Total ending ending for Nov. 30, Nov. 30, Biennium 1913 1914 For Year i For Year Total ending ending for NATIVITY OF FATHER NATIVITY OF FATHER Nov. 30, Nov. 30, Biennium 1913 1914 United States: United States: White 19 38 57 Colored 3 9 12 Austria j 1 1 Bohemia I 2 1 1 Denmark I 1 2 3 England 3 6 9 France 5 5 Germany 10 10 20 Holland '. | 13 4 Ireland 10 20 30 Italy 1 2 3 Jew i. 4 4 Poland j 4 J 5 Roumania ..._ 1 ' ' 1 Scotland ] 1 ' Sweden 2 2 Switzerland 1 1 Unknown 10 12 22 Totals 64 119 183 81 24 59 47 90 71 55 106 lt)l </seg>
            <seg id="p021">156 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VI. PARENTAL CONDITIONS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year Total ending ending for Nov. 30, Nov. 30, Biennium loth parents dead •"ather dead ilother dead 'arents living together J arents separated 'arents divorced las stepfather las stepmother Jnknown _... 3 11 4 29 12 3 3 2 3 16 17 19 36 11 17 21 10 2 1H 2s 2:i 65 23 20 24 12 I Totals 70 70 149 149 219 219 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 157 TABLE VII. COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For Year For Year Total All Re - endiriR ending 1 for maining Nov. 30, Nov. 30, Bienni'm Nov. 30, COUNTY 1913 1914 1914 Adams Boone 2 13 3 112 1 Box Butte Buffalo 4 4 5 3 7 10 9 Cass 5 3 8 4 Cedar ■&gt; Cheyenne Coif ax 3 3 3 2 13 2 Custer Dawes Dawson Dodge 12 3 3 112 2 ■A 2 9 9 Douglas Fillmore Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage 19 48 67 76 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 2 13 4 5 Greeley Hall 1 1 1 5 4 9 Hamilton Harlan . 111 12 3 3 Jefferson Kimball Lancaster Lincoln ... 3 3 4 1 5 8 13 16 4 4 6 1 Loup McPherson Merrick .. 1 1 1 1 Nemaha Otoe 1 - i 1 2 Pawnee Pierce Platte 1 1 112 1 3 14 4 Richardson Saline 1 1 1 5 1 1 2 Sarpy 2 2 1 Saunders Scotts Bluff Seward 1 1 1 11 2 2 Sheridan Sherman Thayer . Thomas Thurston Valley ... 1 .... 1 2 1 1 2 1 1 _... 1 1 1 2 2 1 1 Wayne 1 1 1 Webster York .... 12 3 5 Total* - 64 119 183 203 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">158 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VIII. CAUSES FOR ADMISSION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Total ending for Nov. 30, Biennium 1914 1 1 69 110 1 1 1 1 1 1 4 IS 1^ 1 1 1 4 2 1 2 »5 * 10 ri 10 10 3 3 1 1 2 Transferred from Nebraska Insti - tution for Feeble-Minded Youth Transferred from Penitentiary Stealing 1 2 2 1 2 2 182 Total delinquents «4 118 Grand Total M 119 183 CAUSE FOR ADMISSION For Year ending Nov. 30, 1913 •ependency or Neglect delinquency: Unclassified Assault Attempt to kill Attempted Murder Breaking and Entering. Burglary Felony _ Forgery Grand Larceny Hog Stealing Horse Stealing Incorrigible Larceny _ Mendicancy Petit Larceny Rape Robbery 41 ._.„ 6 1 3 1 1 ■1 ._.„ 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 159 TABLE IX. STATISTICS OF PAROLED PUPILS Paroled during: biennium Returned from parole: 214 For cause 55 Without fault 12 Escaped from parole and not retaken Discharged from parole 6 1 203 Totals »ied while on parole in parole November 30, 1914 li 133 TABLE X. DIVISION OF LABOR OF ALL PUPILS NOV. 30, 1914 Bakers Band Barn Boiler House Carpenter Cooks Dairy Force Green House House Boys Laundry Paint Shop Printing Office ... Shoe Shop Tailor Shop 3 43 8 2 4 16 7 32 3 40 10 9 11 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p025"/>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>