<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00074.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION of FIRE PREVENTION Twenty-third Annual Report 1931</title>
               <date value="1932-01-01">1932-01-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION of Fire Prevention Twenty-third Annual Report 1931 U J. BUTCHER...:. -...Assistant State Fire Marshal SIGRID WILLIAMS _ _ _ _ Secretary H. F. REQUARTTE _ .Deputy State Fire Marshal L. J. HENNING - _ Deputy State Fire Marshal H. N. DOWNING. _ _ Deputy State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL REPORT of the STATE FIRE MARSHAL LETTER of TRANSMITTAL To his Excellency, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of the State of Nebraska. Your Excellency: In compliance with the law governing this department, which pro - vides that a report of all business transacted, orders issued, and acts performed by the State Fire Marshal, his deputies and others constitut - ing the department be made to you annually, I take pleasure in sub - mitting to you, this the Twenty-third Annual Report, covering the act - tlvities of this department which you have seen fit to continue under my direction as acting head, and I wish to thank you for this honor and confidence you have placed in me. We appreciate the advice and coun - cil you have given us during the past year. The department has been operated well within the funds at its disposal, and whatever measure of success has been obtained has been due to the courteous, loyal and united efforts of everyone connected with the department, the volunteer fire department organizations, and the public. M. H. Mockenhaupt, Lincoln; Harry A. Requartette, York; Louis J. Henning, Kearney; Howard N. Downing, Fullerton; deputies, and our secretary Sigrid Williams, have worked earnestly and consistently in an effort to reduce fire hazards, and I am pleased to report that their efforts in this direction have been rewarded in a very gratifying manner. Respectfully submitted, L. J. BUTCHER, First Assistant State Fire Marshal. Lincoln, Nebraska, January 1, 1032. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL REPORT of the STATE FIRE MARSHAL LETTER of TRANSMITTAL To his Excellency, Charles W. Bryan, ■ Governor of the State of Nebraska. . Your Excellency: In compliance with the law governing this department, which pro - vides that a report of all business transacted, orders issued, and acts performed by the State Fire Marshal, his deputies and others constitut - ing the department be made to you annually, I take pleasure in sub - mitting to you, this the Twenty-third Annual Report, covering the act - tivities of this department which you have seen fit to continue under my direction as acting head, and I wish to thank you for this honor and confidence you have placed in me. We appreciate the advice and coun - cil you have given us during the past year. The department has been operated well within the funds at its disposal, and whatever measure of success has been obtained has been due to the courteous, loyal and united efforts of everyone connected with the department, the volunteer fire department organizations, and the public. M. H. Mockenhaupt, Lincoln; Harry A. Requartette, York; Louis J. Hennlng, Kearney; Howard N. Downing, Fullerton; deputies, and our secretary Sigrid Williams, have worked earnestly and consistently in an effort to reduce fire hazards, and I am pleased to report that their efforts in this direction have been rewarded in a very gratifying manner. Respectfully submitted, L. J. BUTCHER, First. Assistant State Fire Marshal. Lincoln, Nebraska, January 1, 1032. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Fire Prevention Week Proclamation In accordance with established custom and the request of a number of our citizens I am glad, as Governor of Nebraska, to do what I can to give impetus to the movement to educate all of us in the causes and means of prevention of fires. It is only necessary to consider for a moment the tremendous annual losses of lives and property and con - sider the misery and business loss that must have attended them to make us realize the need for action in this direction. In 1930 there were in our Country more than 35,000 deaths and severe injuries caused by fires and the property loss was nearly $500, - 000,000 an increase of $40,000,000 over 1929. In Nebraska alone 34 died and 113 were injured in 1930 and there was a property loss of $2,641,425 as a result of fires, a great percentage of which were pre - ventable. It is interesting to note that the campaign for fire preven - tion is bearing fruit in Nebraska, for the property losses were' 10% lighter here in 1930 than in 1929 and the number of deaths and injuries correspondingly reduced. Much, however, still can be and must be done. Wherefore, I, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Nebraska, do hereby designate the week of October 4th to 10th as fire prevention week and request that it be so observed throughout the state with such public meetings and such time given to the matter in the schools as will, with the attention generously given to it by the press and various organiza - tions help in this important movement. In witness whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and caused this seal of the Governor to be affixed. Done at Lincoln Nebraska, this 30th day of September, 1931. CHARLES W. BRYAN, - Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 1931 TAX Aetna Fire Insurance Company $688.07 Agricultural Insurance Company 97.45 Allemania Fire Insurance Company ;... 2.11 Alliance Insurance Company \ ; 29.93 American Alliance Insurance Company. 31.42 American Auto Fire Insurance Company 7.10 American Central Insurance Company 48.86 American Constitution Fire Assurance Company 22.86 American Druggists Fire Insurance Company 9.50 American Eagle Insurance Company 61.45 American Equitable Insurance Company......! 43.14 American Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company :. :. .51 American Foreign Insurance Company 14.09 American Home Fire Assurance Company....- 15.24 American Merchants Marine Insurance' Company 2.67 American Insurance Company of Newark 274.99 American Union Insurance Company J 1.25 Anchor Insurance Company 5.54 Atlas Assurance Company 28.81 Automobile Insurance Company of Hartford..! '. .'. 49.62 Bankers &amp; Shippers Insurance Company 4.10 Belt Fire Insurance Company .45 Boston Insurance Company 34.90 British America Insurance Company 4.74 Bronx Fire Insurance Company.. 2.73 Brooklyn Fire Insurance Company.: 10.79 Buffalo Insurance Company _ 26.56 Caledonian of Scotland 59.93 California Insurance Company .' 1.00 Camden Fire Insurance Association : '. 57.86 Carolina Insurance Company '. ; 14.30 Central Manufacturers' Insurance Company 15.84 Chicago Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 6.31 Citizens of New Jersey.. '. 21.01 City of New York Insurance Company 38.50 Columbia Insurance Company ;. 7.54 Commerce Insurance Company... 11.02 Commercial Union Assurance „ 80.97 Commercial Union Fire Insurance Company 3.58 Commonwealth Insurance Company , 101.21 Concordla Fire Insurance Company 76.54 Connecticut Fire Insurance Company. 511.41 Continental Insurance Company 358.23 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">; STATE OF NEBRASKA . County Fire of Philadelphia. _ 8.61 Detroit Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 3.61 Druggists Mutual Insurance Company. 21.32 Dubuque Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 81.97 Eagle Fire Insurance Company: ; 2.27 Eagle Star &amp; British Dominions 22.58 East &amp; West Insurance Company ... 12.31 Empire State Insurance Company 8.84 Employers Fire Insurance Company 126.64 Equitable Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 21.69 Eureka Security Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company. 1.74 Export Insurance Indemnity Company 28.02 Farmers Fire Insurance (Mutual) 13.51 Farmers National Co-op. Elevator Mutual Ins. Ass'n 10.45 Federal Insurance Company. 7.18 Federal Union Fire Insurance Company 19.67 Fidelity &amp; Guaranty Fire Corporation. : 18.31 Fidelity-Pheonix Insurance Company 345.35 Fire Association of Philadelphia. .-. 55.41 Firemen's Insurance Company. - • 270.98 Firemen's Fund Insurance Company 102.04 First American Insurance Company 13.00 First National Insurance Company of America. 38.56 Fitchburg Mutual Fire Insurance Company ; 8.76 Franklin Fire Insurance Company....: 147.38 Franklin National Insurance Company 4.71 Fulton Fire Insurance Company .38 General Exchange Insurance Corporation. '. 198.02 General Insurance Company of America.. 90.17 Glrard Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company. 62.17 Glens Falls Insurance Company. 209.82 Globe &amp; Rutgers Insurance Company 1,041.39 Grain Dealers National Mutual Insurance Company. 254.30 Granite State Fire Insurance Company. 41.07 Great American Insurance Company... ■. 375.80 Great Lakes Insurance Company. _ 6.77 Guaranty Fire Insurance Company..... 25.15 Hanover Fire Insurance Company .'. 117.78 Hardware Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 152.89 Harmonia Fire Insurance Company. 118.21 Hartford Fire Insurance Company 687.71 Home Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company _ _ 10.99 Home Insurance Company. : 964.21 Homestead Fire Insurance Company .-. 7.13 Hudson Insurance Company...... _ _ 41.19 Imperial Assurance Company , 9.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Implement Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 26.15 Importers &amp; -Exporters Insurance Company. 28.11 Independence Fire Insurance Company 5.66 Indiana Lumberman's Mutual Insurance Company 3.45 Insurance Company of North America 614.44 Insurance Company of State of Pa. 42.06 Inter-Ocean Reinsurance Company 20.15 International Insurance Company 274.12 LaSalle Fire Insurance Company 5.85 Law Union &amp; Rock Insurance Company Ltd 40.24 Lion Fire Insurance Company 2.96 Liverpool, London &amp; Globe Insurance Company 323.83 London Assurance Corporation '. 29.81 London &amp; Lancashire Insurance Company i 97.46 London &amp; Scottish Assurance Corporation Ltd 1.15 Lumbermen's Mutual Fire Insurance Company 11.21 Manhattan Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 1.96 Maryland Insurance Company 18.75 Massachusetts Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 7.10 Mechanics Insurance Company 73.39 Mechanics &amp; Traders Insurance Company... 3.37 Mercantile Insurance Company 275.50 Merchants &amp; Manufactures Fire Insurance Company 19.84 Merchants Fire Assurance Corp 128.43 Merchants Fire Insurance Company 20.77 Merchants Insurance Company 36.21 Mercury Insurance Company.. ....... „. i 42.78 Michigan Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 24.32 Michigan Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company....'. 54.28 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Association. 41.32 Millers Mutual Insurance Company 16.74 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company : 9.48 Millers National Insurance Company 58.97 Mill Owners Mutual Insurance Company 91.37 Milwaukee Mechanics Insurance Company 143.00 Minnesota Implement Mutual Insurance Company 67.66 Monarch Fire Insurance Company .-. 5.10 National American Insurance Company 408.63 National Ben Franklin Fire Insurance Company 90.47 National Fire Insurance Company 2,152.88 National Implement Mutual Insurance Company 6.35 National Jewelers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 5.83 National Liberty Fire Insurance Company 90.49 National Reserve Insurance Company .'. 28.67 National Retailers Mutual Insurance Company. 46.34 National Security Fire Insurance „... 346.93 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">' STATE OF NEBRASKA National Union Fire Insurance Company 436.33 Netherlands Insurance Company : 5.15 Newark Fire Insurance Company. ■. 70.68 New Brunswick Fire Insurance Company 87.71 New England Fire Insurance Company 19.66 New Hampshire Fire Insurance Company '. 118.93 New York Underwriters Insurance Company...-. 225.80 New York Fire Insurance Company. 13.81 Niagara Fire Insurance Company 48.12 North British &amp; Mercantile Insurance Company 205.67 North Carolina Home Insurance Company. 8.11 Northern Assurance Company Ltd....: 38.09 North River Insurance Company 96.77 Northern Insurance of New York 25.09 Northwestern Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 57.33 Northwestern Mutual Fire Association ; 271.59 Northwestern National Insurance Company 128.82 Norwich Union Fire Insurance Company 32.33 Occidental Insurance Company 2 99 Ohio Hardware Mutual Insurance Company '. " 61.92 Ohio Millers Mutual Insurance Company 3.76 Old Colony Insurance Company '. 8.87 Orient Insurance Company _ ; ; 157.00 Palatine Insurance Company Ltd 15.46 Patriotic Insurance Company.. ; ..... 5.89 Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Company 139.42 Pennsylvania Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 17.10 Philadelphia Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company. - 92.75 Phoenix Assurance Company Ltd. of London 48.91 Phoenix Insurance Company ; 395 jq Potomac Insurance Company 35.98 Preferred Risk Fire Insurance Company 8.11 Providence Washington Insurance Company 103.80 Prudential of Great Britian...... 28.33 Queen Insurance Company 150.79 Reinsurance Company Salamandra 13 06 Reliance Insurance Company .'. 5.55 Republic Fire Insurance Company. 8.04 Retail Hardware Mutual Insurance Company 119.27 Rhode .Island Insurance Company. _ 77.55 Rochester American Insurance Company '. 8.11 Rocky Mountain Insurance Company 4.95 Royal Exchange Assurance Company 50.84 Royal Insurance Company. _ 256.01 Safeguard Insurance Company ,. 9.65, Scottish Union &amp; National Insurance Company. 83.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Seaboard Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company. _ 3.23 Security Insurance Company 144.10 Security Mutual Fire Insurance Company 11.97 Sentinel Fire Insurance Company 19.66 Southern Fire Insurance of New York ; 15.81 Springfield Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 598.71 Standard Fire Insurance Company 4.04 Star Insurance Company _ 57.99 State Assurance Company' Ltd '. 8.44 State Farm Mutual Auto Insurance Company...... 113.13 St. Paul Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 597.04 Stuyvesant Insurance Company of New York 33&lt;6T Sun Insurance Office 1*5.64 Sun Underwriters Insurance Company 1.68 Superior Fire Insurance Company 5.72 Svea Fire &amp; Life Insurance Company Ltd 37.22 Sylvania Insurance Company 19.22 Transcontinental Insurance Company 1.70 Transportation Insurance Company .47 Travelers Insurance Company. 170.36 Twin City Insurance Company 21.41 Union Assurance Society Ltd..... 5.53 Union Automobile Insurance Company 34.68 Union Fire Insurance Company of Paris 14.20 Union Insurance Society of Canton Ltd .20 United Firemen's Insurance Company. 10.67 United Mutual Fire Insurance Company. 52.02 United States Fire Insurance Company 194.98 United States Merchants &amp; Shippers Insurance Company 5.61 Universal Insurance Company , 23.34 Victory Insurance Company...: _ 5.40 Virginia Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company. 19.60 Westchester Fire Insurance Company „ 185.56 Western Assurance Company 24.64 Western Fire Insurance Company 9.82 Western Grain Dealers Mutual Insurance Company 48.4P Western Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company. 31.38 Wisconsin Auto Insurance Company. _.. 4.44 World Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company. 13.51 Yorkshire Insurance Company. ., ... 18.45 TOTAL _ „ .... $31,024.31 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">STATE OF NEBRASKA The above figures show the amount of tax money on hand to cover the expenditures for the year 1931. These expenditures were as fol - lows: SALARIES $10,194.84 $10,194.84 Printing ; 215.81 Stamps 150.00 Supplies . 58.25 Tel. &amp; Tel 1 _ 163.34 Investigation expenses r 133.28 Miscellaneous 51.91 TOTAL, $ 772.59 $ 772.59 INSPECTORS' EXPENSES (TRAVELING) Railroad Transportation 219.28 Hotel Expenses .; 3,225.65 Auto Expenses, Taxi and carfare 2,577.73 Miscellaneous _ 113.09 TOTAL ..; 6,135.75 6,135.75 FIRE REPORT FEES Paid to fire chiefs for reporting 1931 fires.... 963.00 963.00 TOTAL EXPENDITURES FQR 1931 18,066.18 18,066.18 SUMMARY OF ACTIVITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT Inspections made _ .13,751 Orders Issued „ 16,359 Orders complied with while inspectors were in town. : 3,910 Orders complied with thru communications with office... 1,722 Buildings orders repaired by this department 207 Buildings demolished by order of this department 30 Orders issued on buildings to be demolished. ; 35 Public buildings changing doors to swing outward (churches, hotels schools, hospitals, lodge halls, dance halls and theatres) ■ . 56 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION New fire escapes installed: Schools 2 Apartment house, dance halls, lodge halls and theatres 3 Iron fire escapes on schools lowered to floor level and doors placed as exit to escape in place of windows 7 Schools extensively repaired 22 Moving picture theatres extensively repaired 21 Moving picture theatres closed on second floor (2) on first •floor (7) — total 9 Public buildings receiving extensive electrical repairs 93 Panic bar locks installed on public buildings 6 Kerosene tanks removed from store buildings 168 Fires Investigated „ ; 195 Persons arrested for arson 25 Persons convicted of arson and confessing 11 Persons tried and acquitted ; 6 Persons bound over for trial 4 Persons dismissed 4 Persons fugitives from justice on arson charges 2 CAUSES OF FIRES AS REPORTED BY THE FIRE CHIEFS OF THE STATE DURING 1931 Omaha Lincoln Bal- Total ance of State Unknown causes 212 39 253 504 Sparks from chimney on roof 156 27 134 314 Gasoline and kerosene stoves 18 3 59 80 Defective electric wires and accessories 19 6 77 102 Cigarettes, cigars and pipes :: 93 3 61 157 Defective chimney 20 2 69 91 Bonfires and burning grass .16 2 35 63 Overheated stoves and furnaces 26 5 46 77 Communicated 33 0 62 95 Children and matches 33 2 25 60 Spontaneous combustion.... 11 2 62 75 Incendiary 7 1 61 69 Inflammables too near stoves and stove pipes 12 3 18 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016">STATE OF NEBRASKA Brooders and incubators and stoves 5 2 21 28 Rubbish in basement ignited by sparks 30 5 12 47 Careless use of matches 10 1 10 21 Hot ashes against wood 10 4 12 24 Gasoline explosion ;. 2 0 26 28 Short in auto wires 2 5 28 35 Lightning 16 2 22 40 Motor back fires, auto &amp; tractors ... 0 11 2 Oil burners J [ 12 1 10 23 Eaectric curling and flatirons 13 0 6 19 Oily rags, paint rags, and mops.. 2 1 9 12 Thawing out water pipes 10 2 3 Oils and greases on stoves 15 0 14 29 Oil lamps, lanterns &amp; candles 6 18 15 Rubbish and dust in hot air registers. 1 113 Blow torch and acteylene 6 0 2 8 Sparks from engines . ; 0 0 10 10 Belt friction ;.. 10 1 2 Starting fires with kerosene &amp; gasoline 0 0 1 1 Motion picture films ignited 1 0 9 10 Mice and matches 10 0 5 15 Gas stoves &amp; heater explosions 9 3 12 24 Washing clothes with gasoline....: 9 0 8 17 Fireworks : 0 0 2 2 Stills overheating and exploding 5 0 0 5 Fumigating 1 2 0 2 Fire-place g 2 0 10 Live coals on floor. . 10 5 6 Electric lamps and heaters 4 1 0 5 Miscellaneous ..'_„'_, 8 0 16 24 Total number of fires 834 126 1220 2180 Less communicated fires....'. : 33 0 62 95 801 126 1158 2085 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION FIRE LOSSES BY COUNTIES County - Value Insurance Damage Adams. Building $ 225,043.00 $ 174.347.00 $ 27,882.00 Contents 251,785.00 176,155.00 32,873.00 Antelope :....Bullding 101,500.00 55,400.00 25,370.00 Contents 28,150.00 17,550.00 12,780.00 Boone..... .....Building 57,650.00 40,550.00 31,190.00 Contents.. 24,050.00 14,300.00 8,880.00 Box Butte Building 127,200.00 92,400.00 5,752.00 Contents 76,000.00 44,658.00 5,563.00 Boyd Building 29,370.00 21,275.00 6,415.00 Contents 13,400.00 7,225,00 4,050.00 Buffalo Building 240,206.00 140,900.00 33,796.00 Contents.! 104,591.00 68,850.00 27,470.00 Burt Building 13,600.00 10,375.00 3,087.00 Contents.. 4,620.00 2,500.00 1,375.00 Butler Building 40,000.00 20,500.00 5,112.00 Contents 16,000,00 9,100.00 2,688.00 Cass Building 81,040.00 47,600.00 22,052.00 Contents 31,430.00 16,638.00 8,022.00 Cedar /.Building 112,215,00 78,250.00 42,301.00 Contents _ 107,965.00 59,725.00 43,572.00 Cherry Building 8,000.00 4,000.00 3,825.00 ■ Contents 1,600.00 1,000.00 430.00 Cheyenne Building 18,900.00 18,500.00 4,175.00 Contents 3,750.00 3,000.00 725.00 Clay Building 36,825.00 24,225.00 7,810.00 Contents 17,660.00 6,850.00 5,609.00 Colfax Building 45,395.00 35,950.00 20,583.00 Contents:.. 72,888.00 55,450.00 29,775.00 Cuming. ..Building 55,175.00 31,625.00 6,957.00 Contents 18,800.00 8,598.00 3,890.00 Custer Building 45,400.00 33,600.00 11,567.00 Contents 24,875.00 15,300.00 6,735.00 Dakota Building 131,400.00 33,325.00 96,640.00 Contents 27,450.00 18,100.00 7,385.00 Dawes Building 36,475.00 29,283.00 10,705.00 Contents 21,000.00 12,100.00 2,742.00 Dawson Building 253,000.00 183,200.00 81,810.00 Building..... , 227,340.00 178,150.00 77.849.00 Deuel ..Contents 18,600.00 11,200.00 2,000.00 Contents 9,650.00 4,500.00 1,775.00 Dlxon Building 61,600.00 . 46.460.00 15,738.00 Contents 29,625.00 15,375.00 4,091.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">STATE OF NEBRASKA Dodge Building 249,850.00 179,150.00 36,967.00 Contents _ 131,757.00 82,341.00 56,910.00 Douglas Building 19,025.00 14,900.00 8,250.00 Om U a^i d ) e ° f Contents 14,975,00 7,750.00 10,475.00 Dundy ....Building 5,150.00 450.00 2,400.00 Contents 2,950.00 1,700.00 550.00 Fillmore Building 12,400.00 7,200.00 335.00 Contents 10,500.00 5,800.00 300.00 Franklin Building. 48,800.00 36,350.00 4,467.00 Contents 17,805.00 11,840.00 805.00 Frontier Building 800.00 500.00 800.00 Contents.... 500.00 2,500.00 500.00 Furnas Building 26,600.00 19,250.00 7,230.00 Contents 18,625.00 15,000.00 . 6,644:00 Gage Building. 327,900.00 253,100.00 104,681.00 Contents „ 143,345.00 93,750.00 22,645.00 Garfield Building. 1,000.00 500.00 100.00 Contents 1,500.00 800.00 500.00 Gosper Building 20,000.00 3,000.00 1,500.00 Contents 8,050.00 6,500.00 2,025.00 Greeley Building 86,625.00 82,075.00 12,496.00 Contents.. 29,750.00 20,350.00 7,810.00 Hall .....Building. 643,183.00 603,638.00 55,866.00 Contents 1,545,303.00 1,425,567.00 150,900.00 Hamilton Building. _ 41,673.00 28,825.00 7,178.00 Contents 11,125.00 6,400.00 4,950.00 Harlan Building. &gt; 30,175.00 16,250.00 11,715.00 Contents 8,910.00 5,400.00 3,455.00 Hayes. :.Building 800.00 500.00 800.00 Contents none none none Hitchock Building 10,050.00 6,800.00 2,750.00 Contents 6,000.00 2,300.00 3,700.00 Holt Building 97,800.00 61,650.00 35,705.00 Contents 90,155.00 - 50,300.00 48,165.00 Hooker Building 6,500.00 3,750.00 210.00 Contents...-. 4,000.00 800.00 307.00 Howard..: Building 51,262.00 23,700.00 11,663.00 Contents 18,050.00 9,350.00 6,313.00 Jefferson Building 110,425.00 102,800.00 7,969.00 Contents _ 55,400.00 45,800.00 6,096.00 Johnson Building....; 22,700.00 14,850.00 3,685.00 Contents 9,925.00 6,350.00 1,715.00 Kearney. Building 31,635.00 18,100.00 6,622.00 Contents „ 7,393.00 5,800.00 2,796.00 Keith. .Building 52,700.00 25,200.00 7,659.00. Contents 19,650.00 18,650.00 8,696.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">. DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Kimball .....Building 11,600.00 2,850.00 1,212.00 Contents 4,700.00 600.00 1,500.00 Knox Building 64,050.00 44,575.00 34,135.00 Contents 62,386.00 186,000.00 41,619.00 Lancaster. Building.... '... 900.00 350.00 270.00 L°nwin) ° f Contents 1,300.00 1,000.00 700.00 Lincoln Building 77,400.00 47,700.00 26,905.00 Contents 53,050.00 32,250.00 14,145.00 Madison/. Building 287,920.00 118,525.00 28,877.00 Contents 277,980.00 178,500.00 26,607.00 Merrick Building 35,565.00 21,100.00 7,000.00 Contents 11,142.00 6,350.00 1,099.00 Morrill -.Building .-. 13,500.00 11,200.00 725.00 Contents 7,650.00 7,300.00 515.00 Nemaha — Building 30,850.00 18,950.00 5,471.00 Contents 24,456.00 13,924.00 4,242.00 Nance Building 24,650.00 17,600.00 3,703.00 Contents 23,205.00 13,000.00 2,255.00 Nuckolls .Building 80,945.00 46,150.00 23,090.00 Contents ; 38,865.00 23,572.00 21,500.00 otoe Building 62,775.00 47,400.00 30,107.00 Contents .. 39,433.00 23,500.00 16,351.00 Pawnee .Building 32,735.00 18,950.00 8,920.00 Contents 28,130.00 22,150.00 7,330.00 Perkins ......Building 7,500.00 none 800.00 Contents 7,550.00 5,000.00 3,637.00 Pnel P s Building 83,325.00 68,000.00 1,516.00 Contents 20,735.00 14,800.00 500.00 Platte... Building 296,325.00 207,125.00 31,274.00 Contents 169,362.00 104,490.00 26,874.00 Pierce... Building....,: 47,750.00 33,275.00 6,048.00 Contents 47,665.00 35,080.00 5,344.00 Polk....... Building 10,400.00 5,600.00 260.00 Contents 3,560.00 1,600.00 65.00 Red Willow Building 442,225.00 317,000.00 20,604.00 Contents 171,475.00 147,275.00 11,898.00 Richardson Building 73,460.00 58,400.00 15,382.00 Contents 46,559.00 28,100.00 10,859.00 Hock Building 2,500.00 1,500.00 50.00 Contents 800.00 500.00 none Saline 1 .Building. 37,850.00 27,100.00. 21,167.00 Contents 31,825.00 21,000.00 22,721.00 Sarpy .-. Building 40,000.00 29,600.00 8,400.00 Contents 18,570.00 16,600.00 3,550.00 Saunders Building... 121,800.00 85,740.00 33,533.00 Contents 38,400.00 22,990.00 14,746.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">• STATE OF NEBRASKA Scottsbluff Building .'.. 60,225.00 34,650.00 6,985.00 Contents..... 20,380.00 8,200.00 6,285.00 Seward Building. 23,350.00 13,800.00 4.674.00 Contents 30,600.00 21,750.00 23,278.00 Sheridan Building 71,888.00 51,688.00 14,605.00 Contents..... 21,850.00 14,500.00 6,975.00 Sherman. ...Building. 7,200.00 4,600.00 3,300.00 Contents : 1,200.00 250.00 160.00 Sioux. Building....... 250.00 none . 75.00 Contents 100.00 none 25.00 Stanton .Building 21,000.00 13,000.00 17,400.00 Contents .'. 5,000.00 hone 5,000.00 Thayer. -.Building 28,801.00 12,530.00 14,766.00 Contents „_ 31,155.00 23,750.00 19,070.00 Thurston Building..... 41,450.00 31,800.00 7,051.00 Contents 15,300.00 7,900.00 5,025.00 Valley. Building. 5,625.00 3,600.00 2,065.00 Contents.! 5,750.00 2,800.00 1,790.00 Washington....Building. 13,350.00 10,300.00 8,705.00 Contents 8,500.00 4,750.00 4,600.00 Wayne.. Building. 126,900.00 76,900.00 20,773.00 Contents 63,550.00 27,900.00 16,580.00 Webster. Building 9,350.00 • 6,900.00 1,050.00 Contents 2,300.00 1,300.00 100.00 Wheeler. -...Building. 30,300.00 18,000.00 9,310.00 Contents 7,000.00 4,480.00 2,700.00 York Building. 422,440.00 297,950.00 37,249.00 Contents 58,235.00 45,050.00 11,573.00 FIRE LOSS FOR 1931, VALUE, INSURANCE AND LOSS AS REPORTED BY COUNTD3S Value Insurance Damage Out-State Buildings $6,383,801.00 $4,439,911.00 $1,253,272.00 Contents — . 4,678,015.00 3,628,383.00 975,754.00 Lincoln Buildings 1,078,920.00 802,000.00 109,905.00 Contents 456,490.00 390,450.00 107,001.00 Omaha. Buildings 20,064,911.00 15,500,833.00 ' 364,919.00 Contents 2,933,434.00 2,416,881.00 295,782.00 -' ■ ■ ■ ■■ ■ - Grand Total...Buildings 27,527,632.00 20,742,744.00 1,728,096.00 Contents _. 8.067,939.00 6,435,714.00 1,378,537.00 Total '. ......35,595,571.00 27,178,458.00 3,106,633.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION INCREASE IN 1931 FERE LOSSES OVER 1930 Outstate _ $278,260.00 Lincoln , .". 83;661.00 Omaha _ ,.-. 103,278.00 TOTAL : $465,208.00 No. Per Capita Per Capita Town Population Fires Loss Loss 1931 Loss 1930 1— Seward. 2,737 4 660.00 .24 4.67 2— Gering 2,531 2 700.00 .2% .09 4— Crete .'. 2,791 1 950.00 .34 3.10 3— Blair 2,865 3 1,179.00 .41 .13 5— North Platte... 12,061 8 .. 6,075.00 .50 .32 6— Holdrege 3,263 6 1,866.00 .57 4.17 7— Nebraska City. 7,230 7 5,904.00 .82 3.55 8— Falls City. 5,787 23 5,755.00 .98 30.72 9— Scottsbluff....... 8,465 5 9,350.00 1.10 2.37 10— Alliance 6,669 8 7,842.00 1.17 .11 11 — Aurora ....... 2,715 11 3,418.00 1.19 1.05 12 — Fairbury. 6,192 35 7,930.00 1.27 6.12 13— Superior. 3,044 11 5,980.00 1.30 1.28 14— Sidney 3,306 5 4,800.00 1.45 1.41 15— Broken Bow 2,715 7 3,950.00 1.46 2.62 16 — McCook 6,688 21 10,652.00 1.59 1.90 17— Wymore :... 2,680 14 5,479.00 2.04 11.23 18— York 5,712 13 12,122.00 2.12 3.63 19— Hastings....". 15,490 39 33,415.00 2.15 1.88 20— So. Sioux City.. 3,927 15 9,175.00 2.34 3.35 21 — Plattamouth...;. 3,793 15 8,989.00 2.37 3.92 22— Chadron 4,606 10 11,630.00 2.52 1.64 23 — Auburn. 3,068 12 8,194.00 2.67 4.78 24— Norfolk! 10,717 20 38,639.00 3.60 10.23 25— Wahoo 5,712 3 10,636.00 3.96 3.56 26— Columbus 6,886 38 27,491.00 3.99 1.46 27— Kearney 8,575 34 39,891.00 4.65 1.44 28— Fremont. 11,407 65 92,495.00 8.10 4.36 29— Beatrice 10,297 36 109,332.00 10.61 5.06 30— Grand Island... 18,041 213 205,563.00 11.39 7.88 31 — Schuyler....!...... 2,588 10 30,402.00 11.74 .67 32— Lexington 6,192 13 70,920.00 23.94 5.24 TOTAL LOSS.... 791,384.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">- STATE OF NEBRASKA This loss represents nearly two-fifths of the out-state loss — in thir - ty-two towns — population 2,500 or more; Three of these towns had one fire each that ruined their record: Grand Island Lumber Yard Fire $154,000.00 Beatrice ; ..Christian Church 86,964.00 Fremont ...Lumber Yard Fire 52,000.00 Lexington had three disastrous fires: Presbyterian Church , $20,000.00 Lumber Yard Fire : 27,000.00 Mill and Elevator ' 18,000.00 Total '. $65,000.00 1 I- ■ RURAL FIRES Following is the farm fire loss, reported by fire chiefs in the dif - ferent towns of our state. These fire losses are included in the total fire loss as reported by counties. You will see by these figures that the loss is greater in the country than in the towns. Country fires invariably result in total losses, due to the fact that the rural communities are not equipped and organized for fighting fires, and, therefore, every precaution should be taken about the home and farm buildings in the eradication of all 'fire hazards. A few of the rural communities have organized and purchased equipment for fighting farm fires. This is not a complete list of all farm fires, as only those where fire departments have been called to participate were reported to this office. We hope that in the near future this department will be able to assist the rural communities in dispensing with the fire hazards that now exist, but up to the present time this has been impossible, as the force of men now employed can cover only the cities and villages of our state. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION FARM LOSSES Value Buildings $210190 00 Value Contents 94,215.00 Total - -; $304,405.00 Insurance on Buildings $115,665.00 Insurance on Contents......... 44,788 00 Total • i - - $160,453.00 Loss on Buildings : ; $153,061 00 Loss on Contents 65,285.00 Total ■ ■ • ...5218,346.00 FIRE LOSSES FOR NEBRASKA As Reported by the Fire Chiefs from 1910 to 1931; Also News - paper Clippings and Chiefs' Reports on Deaths and Injuries. Total Loss No. Fires Bldg. and Cont. Reported Deaths and Injuries 1810 ■ $2,181,058.00 1,222 No Record 1911 1,788,123,00 1,348 No Record 1812 2,251,774.00 1,234 No Record 1813 - — 1,715,676.00 1,265 No Record 1914 1,873,071.00 1,325 No Record 1915 1,789,269.00 1,341 No Record 1816 1,908,297.00 1,348 47 100 1817.... 2,895,935.00 1,649 57 110 1918 2,158,204.00 1,313 21 56 1818 .'. 1,422,943.00 959 11 0 1820 2,679,029.00 1,193 10 68 1821 2,164,042.00 1,481 29 24 1822 2,140,081.00 1,874 28 102 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">STATE OF NEBRASKA 1923 4,569,357.00 1,476 4 11 1924 1,880,870.00 1,665 34 59 1925 2,230,715.00 1,636 49 56 1926 : 2,878,677.00 1,744 29 71 1927 2,461,245.00 2,102 45 105 1928 2,061,853.00 1,365 ' 79 143 1929 2,945,866.00 2,001 48 172 1930 : 2.641,425.00 2,102 .34 113 1931 3,106,633.00 2,085 61 214 STOP — LOOK — AMD LISTEN. Who has not seen these words be - fore and know they refer usually to the danger of crossing over rail - roads and street car tracks. Very impressive words. Should be followed to the letter by every one of us. Let's use them for another terrible danger for a few minutes, and what is that danger? THE FIRE DE - MON. Stop. Let us turn to the pages of this booklet where causes of over 2000 fires for 1931 are listed. Look. And you will see the many causes given as to what started these fires, you will also realize of your own knowledge that more than half of these causes could easily have been eliminated by being careful. Listen. And I'll try to explain to you these causes so that you will realize that nearly every one of them could have been eliminated by every one using their brains to prevent fire from happening. 1. We will start with the first cause given, UNKNOWN, which represents nearly one-fourth of all causes. Of course the real cause of these fires was some of those given or others not mentioned but prac - tically all preventable. But I honestly believe that a large percent of those reported unknown are incendiary set in order to collect the insur - ance. During' a depression the. fire losses always increase. There is very little reason in reporting a fire as unknown origin unless' the parties are wishing to hide the carelessness of their act which might have been accidental or intentional on their part. Ninety-nine out of every one hundred people who has a fire know' in their own mind what caused it, but because it would show carelessness on their part, they report it as unknown cause. 2. Sparks from ' chimneys on roof. Absolutely preventable. Do away with the wooden shingle hazard. Cover roof with new up-to-date fire resisting roofing and if you are delayed in doing this at once, be sure to clean out the chimney, stove and furnace pipes of all soot. Be - cause it is these hardened pieces of soot that catch on fire and comes whirling up out of the chimney, lighting on the shingles or in the cracks between t&gt;"»T", and in these cracks is the small quantities of fine pulpy substances washed off from the shingles and. Just waiting for this burn- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION ing soot to light. The wind blows on the spark and it eats, into this ready made fuse, setting it on fire, and it in turn the entire roof and the whole house, if not discovered in time. You owe it to yourself and family and to your neighbors to make your roof safe from sparks and flying brands. Then try and persuade your neighbors to do the same for their roofs. 3. Defective electric wiring and accessories. This is an absolutely preventable, cause. Have your wiring Installed according to the National Electrical Code, by a competent electrician, and buy only electrical de - vices approved by the National Board of Fire Underwriters Laboratories. Your electric fuses serve exactly the same purpose as the safety valve on a steam boiler. The ordinary branch lighting circuit should be pro - tected by a not to exceed fifteen ampere fuse. If this will not carry the load, you need another circuit. The practice of "jumping fuses" or the use of pennies and other makeshift devices is extremely dangerous and has caused many fires. Before renewing blown fuses be sure to remedy the cause of the blowout. When you are in electrical difficulty the safest course to pursue is get a good electrician. Don't attempt to do it your - self. 4. Cigarettes, cigars and pipe smoking. Absolutely preventable. Quit the use of them, or if you do use them be sure to put out the fire in them before you throw them away, and do not smoke in any place that you know you should not, and try and observe all NO SMOKING SIGNS. They are put up for safety measures. "The Baltimore fire was caused by a careless smoker who destroyed eighty city blocks, with a loss of approximately $40,000,000. A record of 392 clothing factory fires shows that 173 were caused by careless smokers. The terrible fire at the Triangle shirtwaist factory in New York, in which 145 girls lost their lives, was started by a careless smoker, who ignited scrap material on the floor. A cigarette fire at Pittsburgh killed fifteen girls in the Union Paper Box factory. In 1914 there were about sixteen billion cigarettes consumed in the United States. In 1918 the amount had grown to forty - six billion and is still increasing." 5. Communicated (those set on fire from other fires). These are partly preventable. In commercial buildings try and build them fire proof or fire resistive, with fire doors and windows and good fire walls. Dwell - ings and other out buildings have roofs covered with asbestos shingles or rubberoid roofing to protect from sparks and fire brands. Have handy some means for fighting fires, garden hose and fire extinguishers. 6. Defective Chimneys. Absolutely preventable. The combination of. a dirty chimney and an old wooden shingle roof is responsible for </seg>
            <seg id="p026">STATE OF NEBRASKA many unnecessary runs by the fire department Even though the roof is of fire resistive material, and the chimney is well built from the ground and lined with fire tile, sparks may be carried to adjoining combustible property. Have your chimneys cleaned every fall, and then about every two weeks it is a good plan to burn several handsful of coarse salt in your stove or furnace. The chemical reaction will assist in keeping your chimneys clean. Inspect your chimneys occasionally for possible cracks which may result in a fire. 7. Gasoline and kerosene stove fires. Preventable to a great ex - tent. Be careful in handling them. Never allow them to get out of repair. Must be kept clean and in working order at all times or they may ex - plode and cause serious injury or death besides burning up your home. Never fill tank while stove is lighted or other open blaze in the same room. Read list of deaths and injuries for this year. 8. Overheated stoves, and furnaces. This is a preventable cause, you will alL agree. It just calls on you to remember that you have a fire in the stove or furnace and must watch the drafts and regulate it. It is up to you also not to put in too much fuel at one time. Train your mind to remember. 9. Spontaneous combustion. This cause is at least 90 percent pre - ventable is we will only use due precaution. Certain substances, because of their affinity for oxygen, are particularly susceptible to spontaneous ignition, as for example rags or Utter saturated with fish oils, Unseed oil, soya bean oil, or cotton seed pressings. Practically all vegetable and animal oils or fats have a tendency to oxidize and heat. So watch your oily rags, dust mops, paint rags, rubbish piles in basement and garret, damp or green. hay, alfalfa and grains, sawdust and wet coal. Read up on the Chemistry of FIRE and you will be weU paid for your trouble. 10. Incendiary (meaning deliberately set by some one). So this is a preventable cause. I am satisfied in my own mind that probably 50 percent of the. unknown fires and a goodly number of the other fires Hated as some known cause, in reaUty should be listed under this cause. To set a fire to buildings or other property is a crime called arson. (See incendiary fires, page 56. . 11. Children and matches. With proper teaching, and eternal vigi - lance to keep them out of reach of them, this is a preventable cause. 12. Bonfires and burning grass. Preventable cause, absolutely. If you must burn your rubbish and trash, do it when there is no wind and </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION have It far enough away to be safe. Then never leave it alone until every spark of fire is out. Make sure of It by pouring water on the ashes. Use your good judgment. 13. Rubbish In basement. Ignited by sparks from furnaces, matches, etc. Absolutely preventable. Just criminal carelessness and poor house keeping. Rubbish has no business to be there. Clean base - ments and attics seldom have a fire. 14. Lightning. The man with lightning rods properly installed on his buildings can feel sure that he is practically safe from fire from this cause. 15. Short In auto wires. This is nearly wholly preventable by hav - ing a competent auto electrical mechanic look your wiring over two or three times a year, and if wiring shows wear, have it replaced. Also carry a quart size fire extinguisher in car and have it handy. 16. Inflammables too near stoves and stove pipes. Absolutely preventable. Use your own good judgment and you won't be silly enough to have a fire from this cause. Live fire prevention every day and talk it to your friends when you notice their carelessness. 17. Gasoline explosion. Preventable to a great extent if extreme caution is used. Gasoline, benzine and naphtha are extremely dangerous to use as a cleaning fluid due to their tremendous explosive force wheu mixed with air. Their ignition point is low, and they vaporize rapidly into highly inflammable gases. The explosive energy of a gallon of gasoline properly vaporized equals that of ; some eighty- three sticks of 40 percent dynamite. Static electricity induced by friction may cause the ignition of clothing being cleaned. In one year nearly 800 women lost their lives in the United States through indifference to this principle. Gasoline has been known to explode many feet from an open flame. If spots are to be removed use carbon tetrachloride, for it serves excellently, and is also a fire retardent. Under proper conditions a quart of gasoline will move an automobile about four miles. Improperly used In the home the same quantity will move two fire trucks, two ambulances, and two hearses about the same distance. 18. Brooders and incubator stoves. Fires preventable, ninety-nine cases out of one hundred if proper attention is given to see that the stoves are in good order and that inflammable material is protected from catching on fire from them. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">STATE OF NEBRASKA 19. Oils and greases on stoves. This is a preventable cause if due caution is used, but stay on the job and don't leave it a second. Of course explosive oils should never be put on or around an open flame. Heat a bucket of hot water and place your container with oil in that. 20. Gas stoves and heater explosions. This is also a preventable cause in most cases if due diligence is exerecised. Be sure to keep them in perfect condition, and then use caution in lighting them and be sure they are completely turned off. Natural and artificial gas as a fire hazard causes property destruction amounting to almost $3,000,000 each year, much of the damage being due to leaking pipe connections, and exposure of gas to vagrant sparks or to the open flame of a match or candle while searching for gas leaks. This fire hazard may be rendered considerably less important by proper care, by the tightening of all loose connections, and by applying to the suspected parts an application of soap suds, the bubbling of which will reveal the defect. 21. Hot ashes against wood. This cause is absolutely preventable. Do not put ashes in wooden or pasteboard containers, as ashes will hold fire for two weeks, use only metal containers. Never throw them up against wooden partitions or supports in the basement or against the house or other out buildings. Empty them out in an open lot where the wind will not blow the coals up against or into something that will catch on fire. Think fire prevention. 22. Oil burners. This is a fire hazard that needs plenty of watch - ing, but by using only furnaces and oil burners that are approved by the National Board of Fire Underwriters Laboratories, you will be fairly safe, if you do your part. 23. Careless use of matches. This stands in the front rank as to causes, and is preventable with each one of you if you are careful. Re - member the match has a head but no brains. It is up to you to use your brains. 24. Electric curling and flatirons cause fires. Absolutely prevent - able if the lady would only remember to turn off the switch when she leaves the iron. Every electric iron should have a red pilot light to indi - cate when the current is on, and all irons should have a metal stand two inches high. 25. Washing clothes and woodwork with gasoline, benzine and naphtha. Causes fires and explosions resulting in injuries and deaths. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Absolutely preventable in the home. Women should not use any of these explosive oils for cleaning purposes; they are playing with dynamite. (Re-read cause 17.) 26. Oil lamps, lanterns and candles. Cause fires, preventable to a great extent. Do not use candles, very seldom necessary, as every one these days can easily have safe lamps and lanterns. Use metal lamps with solid heavy bases, not glass ones. Use only the best quality of oil; be sure that the wick fits snugly; keep burner clean, boil occasionally with soda and lye, or strong soap solution. Keep wick trimmed evenly. Fill lamp or lantern by day light only. Lots better to have flash lights to carry around barns and in house basements, attics and closets. Never use a lamp or open flame light. 27. Mice and matches cause fires. This is preventable to a great extent. Keep your matches in metal or glass receptacles with cover. Keep watch that no matches are left in pockets of clothing stored away in closets or attic. ■ ' 28: Oily rags, paint rags and oily mops. Absolutely preventable cause. Burn up all paint and oily rags after using them and keep your dust mops outside on .porch, never in closets or under stairs. (See cause No. 9.) . 29. Sparks from engines. Preventable if screen is used on smoke stack. 30. Motion picture film fires. Preventable to a great extent if the law covering motion picture booths are rigidly complied with. 31. Fire place fires. Absolutely preventable if proper precautions are taken in building the fire place and keeping it in good shape and using a screen before the fire to catch -the sparks and be careful always. 32. Blow and acetylene torch fires. These are all preventable if proper use is made of them and one is careful to protect them from all inflammables. Do not use them to thaw frozen pipes, take paint off houses, warm up frozen carburaetors, because that is just criminal care - lessness. 33. Starting fires with kerosene and gasoline. Absolutely pre - ventable and any one that will do this is flirting with death, not only for himself but his or her loved ones and also the danger of destroying all their earthly belongings, also their neighbor's property. There should </seg>
            <seg id="p030">STATE OF NEBRASKA be a law passed that any one using explosive oils in tW" manner, should be prosecuted for criminal carelessness. 34. Live coals on wooden floor fires. Absolutely preventable. Put tin under stoves and have it extend eighteen inches or more out in front of stove. 35. Electric lamps and heater fires. Preventable if one uses cau - tion in installing them, must have heavy approved cords running from lamp or heater to wall socket, and be very careful to have no inflam - mables close to the heaters. 36. Stills over heating. Very much preventable. Against the law to have one. Enough said. 37. Rubbish and dust In hot air registers and pipes. Preventable always. Keep registers and pipes clean at all times. 1 38. Thawing out frozen water pipes. Fires from this cause are ab - solutely preventable. Do not use an open flame from anything to thaw a frozen pipe. Use only hot water or steam. 39. Motor back fire from auto and tractor. Partly preventable. Adjust motor for this trouble as soon as it develops and remember to keep watch that no fire develops after you hear the motor backfiring. 40. Belt' friction and hot bearings. This cause arises where there is machinery running and it requires careful and thorough inspection every little while by the operator to be sure that no belts are rubbing against wood or that bearings aren't getting hot because of lack of oil or other cause. So you see this is a preventable cause. 41. Fire works. An entirely preventable cause if you leave them alone. If you do play with them, extreme carefullness must be used. 42. Fumigating. Causes fire often. This is a preventable cause, just use common sense. 43. Miscellaneous causes. And there are many of them not listed here, all of them preventable, if you will only think and practice fire prevention, all the time, not just one day or one week, but 365 days in the year, and every year you live. Also convert your family and friends into being fire preventionists. Remember any fool can start a fire, but it takes a careful person to prevent one. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">. DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Fire Safety Resolutions But few, if any, New Tear's resolutions offer better dividends in the protection of both life and property than the following: I will not leave the matches where small children can get them. I will not use kerosene or gasoline for starting or quickning fires. . I will not use gasoline or naptha for cleaning indoors. I will keep gasoline and naptha in safety cans, painted vermllllon red. I will destroy oily waste or oily rags after use, or keep them In a covered metal waste can. I will keep my premises clean and closets, attics, basements and yards free from combustible rubbish. I will not place ashes in cardboard or any wooden containers nor in contact with wood. I will not go into dark closets with lighted matches or candles. I will use a metal stove board under all stoves. I will protect all woodwork near stoves or smokepipes with metal over asbestos. I will have all chimneys and smokepipes cleaned at least once each year. I will see that smokepipes are sound, well connected, and firmly wired or riveted. I will put a double, ventilated, metal thimble and asbestos board around smoke pipes in partitions. I will provide a good screen for my fireplace. I will inspect the heating apparatus before retiring. I will not tamper with the electric wiring but will have a good electrician make all needed changes. . I will use only proper electric fuses, no substitutes. I will turn off the current when through using an electric iron or appliance. </seg>
            <seg id="p032"/>
            <seg id="p033"/>
            <seg id="p034">STATE OF NEBRASKA I will connect gas stoves and plates with iron pipes, not rubber hose. I will not install swinging gas brackets, nor any gas brackets near windows. I will not hunt for gas leaks with a match or open light, but will use a flashlite. I will not use benzine stove polish on a hot stove. I will not thaw out frozen water pipes with a torch, flame or fire. I will not hang clothes of fabrics near a stove, smokepipe or an open fire. I will not use cotton, paper or other combustible decorations. I will not throw away a lighted match, cigar or cigarette. I will think of the injury and- fire damage my careless acts might cause "my brother". The above suggestions are very timely and come from the Fire Pre - vention Division of the Industrial Commission of Wisconsin. ■ TOTAL DEATHS FROM FIRES Men. a „ j : 29 Women .' '. 14 Children 18 Total 61 CAUSES OF DEATHS Kerosene explosions 7 Starting fires with kerosene . 8 Gasoline explosions 7 Clothing caught fire from stoves 1 Cleaning clothes with gasoline _ : :. 3 Bon fires ,.....'. 1 Playing with matches 3 Electricity 1 Automobiles I 7 Miscellaneous 23 Total - '. 61 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION TOTAL INJURIES FROM FIRES Men .. 101 Women. 38 Children : ;. 32 Firemen injured ~ 43 Total..... . f 214 CAUSES OF INJURIES Cleaning clothes with gasoline 7 Kerosene explosions '. 17 Gasoline explosions „ 66 Fire works 14 Automobiles : „ 18 Firemen fighting fires ..— 43 Electricity 2 Filling kerosene lamps and stoves .'. 5 Heating oils ~ _ 10 Playing, with matches » _ 2 Miscellaneous . : 30 Total ~ 214 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">STATE OF NEBRASKA Injuries from Fires ABIE — Otto Vidlak received two badly burned hands when a gasoline stove exploded. ANGORA — Dale and John Thompson, brothers, 22 and 10 years old, suffered serious burns in an explosion caused by lighting a match while emptying the gas tank of the auto. ANSLEY — H. D. Reed was burned badly about the head, shoulders and arms as gas exploded when he lit a match to examine a cesspool. ANSLEY — Mr. and Mrs. John Marion, and an elderly man who resides with them, were burned in an endeavor to save some of the house - hold effects when the house in which they lived caught on fire. ALLIANCE — Myra Lou Mahoney, 2, was burned painfully by the flash of flame from a celluloid comb that she touched to a hot stove. ALLIANCE — Myer Reising, 21, received severe burns trying to extricate his companion from the burning auto. (See deaths.) ALLIANCE — Amanda Schfeld, when attempting to start the oven blaze, the blaze puffed out and burned her badly. ALLIANCE — Claude Farrow, farmer, was burned severely about the hands, arms and face when a can of gasoline exploded. ALLIANCE — Connie Kilian, 17, narrowly escaped being burned to death when he dropped a match into a gasoline filled manhole, causing a terrific explosion. ALLIANCE— A. E. Fisher was burned severely about the hands and arms when he attempted to extinguish a fire in hia automobile. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVKNTION ALLIANCE — When a can of gasoline which he was pouring into the tank of his auto exploded in his hands, Glen Shelter was severely burned. . . . ALLIANCE — Jacob Henserman, 40, was severely burned about the face, hands an feet, in an attempt to extricate his sedan from a prairie fire. ASHLAND — Glenn Hall was burned when a piece of fire works ex - . ploded. AURORA — Miss Thompson was burned on the arm when varnish ex - ploded, that was being heated on the stove. BEATRICE — Raymond Calkins sustained severe bums on his right hand when a cannon cracker exploded. BEATRICE — Charles Taylor was severely burned about the face and arms from an explosion which occurred when he was cleaning a gas burner with gaBoline. BEATRICE — While extinguishing a fire in a car, caused by a short cir - cuit, T. E. Benty was burned on the face and on one arm. BEATRICE — In dropping a lighted match into the mouth of an appar - ently empty cartridge, Delbert Hevelone, 18, suffered a maimed hand, an abdominal wound and severe burns about the face, from the explosion that followed. BELLWOOD— Mrs. Conrad Melster was badly burned when gasoline, which she was heating on a stove, exploded. BENNINGTON — A skyrocket blew off two fingers and a thumb from Pete Bunz'B hand. BLOOMFIELD — Mrs. John Fritz was burned when their car upset and burned. (See deaths.) BROKEN BOW — L. D. George 'fainted while carrying a basket of hot ashes out of the basement. The hot ashes fell on him and Ignited his clothing, causing burns on bis body. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">STATE OF NEBRASKA BUTTE — Loraine Horst, 7, was severely burned on the left side of her body when a gasoline can exploded throwing the burning liquid over her. CHADRON — Mrs. Louis E. Lecher suffered severe burns on the hands when the gasoline stove exploded. CLAY CENTER — Oscar W. Nelson was severely burned when a gasoline air pressure stove exploded. CRAIG — C. E. Cram was quite badly burned on the face, hands and chest by a kerosene explosion while starting a fire. CRETE — The left hand of Mrs. Fred Meyer was blown off when a laun - dry stove exploded. DE WITT — Edward Heller and Milo Garrison were burned slightly, and Earl Suiter was burned painfully when gasoline exploded, with which they were working. DOUGLAS — Mrs. Greeders Hofker was" burned when wax boiled over and caught on fire. EAGLE — Joseph Schmader was badly burned about the face and hands while starting a fire in the stove of his garage. Gasoline fumes igniting caused the explosion. FALLS CITY — Harry Pecht, operator, escaped with minor burns when ignited film filled the projection booth with flames. FRANKLIN — Winfred Winz received severe burns when blazing gaso - line was spilled upon him. FREMONT — Donald Peterson, 2, was throwing rubbish on a bonfire. He fell into the fire, receiving painful burns. FREMONT — Claude and George Howard received burns on the hands and their hair was singed when pouring gasoline on hot coals in the stove. FREMONT — Firemen injured: Clarence Johnson, hand injury; Joe Brunk, burns on body; Raymond Bently, blisters on hand; Sherman Leister, blisters on hand; Troy Cain, fell, hurt back and hip; Albert Sheldon, eye injury; Ed Warner, burned on legs and face; Joe Warner, feet burned while fighting the lumberyard fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION GERING — Freda Guettler, 18; Leo Douglas, 19; Kenneth Ferguson, re - ceived burns when their cars crashed and caught fire. GRAND ISLAND — Mrs. Wm. Carter was burned about the hands and arms when kerosene exploded with which she was building a fire. GRAND ISLAND— Harold Henne, 12, in attempting to open a dynamite cap with a nail and hammer, the cap exploded, tearing off his index finger, part of his thumb and burning bis entire hand severely. GRANT— While attempting to light a blow torch, the valve blew off, spraying burning gas over Mr. Petty, of the Petty Hardware Store. GREENWOOD — A stick of dynamite, used in blasting driftwood, ex - ploded prematurely in the hand of Archie Hohenschell, 65, blowing his hand away and seriously burning his face. He may lose his eye - sight in both eyes, and his nose was left barely hanging to his face. HARTINGTON — Ralph Morten was badly burned about the hands and face when gasoline, with which he was cleaning the sink, exploded. HARTINGTON — Miss Mildred Nelson, teacher, received burns on her hands and limbs when a match set fire to the bed clothing. HARTINGTON — B. Morten, 35, suffered serious burns when his truck crashed into a ditch. HASTINGS — Mrs. Jacob Frisch was severely burned when the stove exploded, presumably from a dynamite cap being in the coal. HASTINGS — Mrs. Dalsey Rutherford was burned about the face when she opened the oven door, the flames leaped out burning her hair, face and eyes. HASTINGS— W. H. Brach suffered burns when gas exploded in the furnace. HASTINGS — Endeavoring to rekindle the furnace fire with kerosene, Mrs. Francis Pigeon was painfully burned by the explosion. HASTINGS — Hulbert Malich sustained burns, caused by pulling an electric switch while unloading gasoline from an oil car. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATE OF NEBRASKA - HAVELOCK— A salesman suffered severe burns to both hands while endeavoring to extinguish the flames In his car. HEMINGPORD— Donald Wax was burned on the hands and face when hot grease caught on fire. HICKMAN — Mrs. Ivan Brendle was burned painfully when kerosene, with which she was starting a fire, ignited her clothing. HOLBROOK — Mr. P. C. Childera was severely burned when he tried to get his car out of the burning garage. • HYANNIS — Mrs. Roscoe Bray sustained burns in a kerosene explosion, when she tried to hasten the kitchen fire. *' INDIANOLA— Ed Jones was badly burned when the gasoline stove ex - ploded, while he was filling the tank. KEARNEY— C. L. Johnson was burned about the face, arms and one shoulder in getting his truck out of the burning building. KIMBALL— Dr. RoyO. Warde Is near death as result of burns suffered when a cigarette set fire to the couch and rug on which he was sleeping. KIMBALL — Mrs. George Anderson suffered severely burned limbs, and her husband was painfully burned about the face and hands, when a pan of gasoline, in which they were cleaning clothes, exploded. LEWISTON— Mrs. Wm. Myers was burned In an explosion when she attempted to rekindle a fire with kerosene. LINCOLN— Mr. Wm. Petty, 41, lost his right hand when a piece of fire - works he was holding exploded. LINCOLN— Tom Green was burned slightly about his hands In attempt - ing to combat a blaze that resulted when a heating stove exploded. LINCOLN— Chet Taylor, 32, electrician, suffered a badly burned right hand when lightning flashed across one set of copper bus bars to another. LINCOLN— Edward Scoonover, 25, was severely burned about the face and hands when natural gas exploded. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">DIVISION OF FlRE PREVENTION LINCOLN — Static electricity was responsible for blaze while gang was working in excavation installing valve in natural gas main, result - ing in painful injuries to Paul Brandt, 23, and E. B. White, 45, and serious injuries to Arthur Schaldecker, 23, and H. R. Allison, 43. LINCOLN — Winnett Jacobs, 8, suffered a badly burned arm while at - tempting to carry a flaming pan of gasoline. LINCOLN — Margaret Lewis was burned slightly in making her escape from flames which damaged her home. LINCOLN — Martha Thomsen received severe burns when a can of var - nish exploded in the warming oven of the kitchen range. LINCOLN — Fred Bushee was rescued from his burning room by his nephew, C. A. Bushee. Both men were slightly burned. LINCOLN — Bob Vorhees suffered a burned arm when an oil burner • exploded. LINCOLN — Betty Ann Schaus, 6, was injured when a fragment of a large bomb exploded, embedding itself in her right leg. LINCOLN — Mrs. Sophie Mueller, 77, suffered serious burns to her face, chest and arms when the gasoline oven exploded. LINCOLN— Russell Willard, state chemist, was badly burned in an ex - plosion at the chemical laboratories at the state house. LINCOLN — L. F. Bishop was severely burned about the face, neck and . one arm in a gas explosion. LINCOLN — A vat of molten lead boiled over, spraying Leon Hunt and Harry H. Dreith, burning them very severely. LINCOLN — Dave Lee, 11, colored, received minor burns about the face 'when powder he and a playmate had extracted from a shotgun shell, exploded. LINCOLN — Mr. A. J. Hoelk, 39, sustained severe burns on both legs, hands, arms, head, face and neck, while examining a gasoline leak between storage tanks. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">STATE OF NEBRASKA . LINCOLN — Bob Dyer was burned on his hands while tearing off his wife's burning clothing that caught fire when the gasoline oven ex - ploded. LINCOLN— George W. Morris, clerk of the district court, had deep burns inflicted on his forehead, ears and nose and right hand, and part of his hair was burned off, as the green celluloid eyeshade became a blazing wreath about his head. While lighting a match for his pipe, a spark set fire to the eyeshade. LINCOLN— Kirk Marshall, 24, was burned severely about his face and hands when a brooder stove exploded. LINDSAY— Herman Belcher was badly burned in an endeavor to get the horses out of the burning barn. LYONS— Caps for a toy pistol, in the pocket of Bobby Henderson, 6, ignited, burning him severely. MC COOL— Ernest Newcomb was burned following an explosion of a gasoline stove. MADISON— Robs Adcock, 10, poured coal oil in a furnace fire receiving severe burns about the hands and face. MULLEN— Ben Kemp was burned considerably when his brooder house caught fire. NEWMAN GROVE— Theodore Thorson suffered burns on. his hands and legs when a pan of gasoline exploded. NORTH PLATTE— Leslie J. Plaugher, 44, suffered burns on his face and abdomen when a gasoline storage tank exploded. NORTH PLATTE— Dell, Theodore, Howard and Roland Phillips were burned when a kerosene lamp used to warm a cement mixer, over which they were huddled, exploded. NORTH PLATTE-^r. M. Wooater Was cleaning the upholstering of his car with gasoline, inside the building, when a spark of static elec - tricity ignited the gas vapor. The explosion threw Mr. Wooster out of the car, but he was only slightly singed by the blast </seg>
            <seg id="p043">. DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION OMAHA — Mrs. Ed Easley was burned severely on the hands and arms in aiding to extinguish the flames that enveloped her husband. (See deaths.) OMAHA — Mrs. Kate Parr, 57, was reported in a critical condition as a result of burns suffered from a kerosene stove which ignited her apron. OMAHA — O. L. Dyer suffered burns on his left hand when he carried a burning chair out of the house. OMAHA — Paul Mowrey, 14, was seriously burned about the legs and body when a can of blazing gasoline was thrown from a cave; the flaming liquid enveloped him. OMAHA — Mary Frances Kane, 13, may .be burned fatally as a result of her clothing catching on fire while preparing lunch. OMAHA — In an endeavor to stamp out a fire in a pile of burning papers, Mary Johanne Bliss, 5, was probably fatally burned. OMAHA — Mrs. Frank Miller received a painfully burned hand when the gasoline stove exploded. OMAHA — A pot of boiling tar exploded, burning both of Mrs. Helen Gabel's ankles. OMAHA — Rosella Sherman, 7, was burned seriously, when her clothing caught fire while playing with matches. OMAHA — Exploding into flames, a pan of gasoline set fire to clothing of Mrs. Fred Stein, 26, burning her severely on the legs, arms, chest and face. Marvin Hayden, 19, was burned as he aided Mrs. Stein in throwing the pan out of the window. OMAHA — Mrs. Ray Plummer suffered serious burns when pulled from the cab of a burning truck containing gasoline and kerosene. Mr. - Plummer. was also burned. OMAHA — Jack Bullock, 9, was burned slightly when the home caught on fire. OMAHA — Louis Galvin was slightly burned attempting to rescue little 'Ida Ortiz. (See deaths.) </seg>
            <seg id="p044">STATE OF NEBRASKA OMAHA-Joe Hoftetter, 15; Louis Prchall, 14; William Hoban, 16 and James Vocelka, 15. were burned when flashlight powder exploded. OMAHA-Pollce Captain Charles J. Payne was burned seriously when gasoline fumes became ignited from a pilot light on a gas stove. OMAHA-O. S. Walker, fireman, was injured severely while aiding in extinguishing a fire. He was struck by a falling timber as the roof c&amp;vgq in. OMV S^f tt^,° n « C^f DaQ ° 1Colmor ' ™s Painfully burned about the head while fighting the blaze of the Omar theatre fire. OMAHA-Six firemen were burned slightly as they searched thru the ruins of a two story structure that burned down within a few mln - °M^rf^men. In3Ured ta Termlnal warehouse fire: Chief Cogan; PatrfCk Dem P fle y: Chief Theodore Bernhardt; Captain James P. Jensen; Ed J. Clausen; August Kud - la*z; Harry Walsh; Williams Huston; W. T. Me WiUlans inspector Clarence Urban; Harry Shropshire; Chiefs Driver Ed Cullianane- James Matcha; Joseph Fitzgerald; Steve Howard; Albert Newton^ Ora S. Walker; Battalion Chief Patrick McEligott; Captain E W S°w™ PtaIn ir d GUlan: WUUam Ryan: Otto Gternandt; Ehner Urban; William Christian; Leo Kelly; Fjed Tonach. OTOE-AUen Paap, Herman Lange. Rev. Charles P. Lange. Louis Paap were injured when removing goods from the drug store that burned to the ground. PALISADE-Mrs. Mary Benge received severe burns when the gasoline Iron exploded. ■ PAWNEE CITY-Mrs. Fred Dunn. 35, suffered severe burns when her clothing caught fire from the kitchen stove. PAXTON-Mr. and Mrs. Hoffman, tourists, had an oil heater in their PCte GUy WaS TCVerel y burned wh 0e starting a fire </seg>
            <seg id="p045">, ■ DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION SEWARD — Mrs. Lawrence Ihde received burns on ber back, shoulders, head and hands when an electric spark set fire to her dress. SHELTON — Bud Bly was seriously burned on both legs and one arm while cleaning the car bearings with gasoline. . SHELTON — James McMullen, 12, was badly burned when he dropped a lighted candle into a box of blasting powder, causing an explosion. Wayne Hogg, 10, was also batlly' burned. SHELTON — D. D. McKee, 55, was burned severely when he poured kero - ' sene on live coals in the kitchen range, causing an explosion. SIDNEY — L. J. Chemelka was painfully burned when a kerosene stove exploded. SIDNEY — Mrs. Herman Florke was badly burned while lighting the fire with kerosene. Her husband received burns in trying to tear her garments off. SPENCER — O. L. Johnson was burned about the chest and face when gasoline exploded with which he was cleaning clothes. SPENCER — Mra. Wm. Lalintone was burned slightly when the gas stove leaked and caught on fire. SPENCER — Ollie Johnson is recovering from severe burns sustained when gasoline with which he was cleaning clothes exploded, show - ering him with the flaming fluid. Lee Strange ran to aid Johnson and was badly burned about his hands and arms. ST ANTON — Mrs.. Albert Dreger was severely burned in a brooder ex - plosion. ST. EDWARD — Don Armes mistook gasoline for kerosene when start - ing the furnace fire. The flames singed his hair and eyebrows and burned his face. ST. EDWARD — Joe Baustert was seriously burned when a gasoline lan - tern exploded, throwing flaming gas over Wm. SUPERIOR — Charles Beemer received burns when he endeavored to get his car out -of the garage that was on fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">STATE OF NEBRASKA TABLE ROCK — Mr. Grimm, father of Clarence Grimm, was burned on both hands in an endeavor to tear the burning clothes off his son's body. (See deaths.) TECUMSEH — Mrs. Emmett Taylor was severely burned in an endeavor to save her son, whose clothing was a mass of flames, caused when the stove exploded. TECUMSEH — Hariand Morrissey, 8, and Robert Tucker, 6, found an old gasoline blow torch. They Ignited it, an explosion followed, throw - ing gasoline over both boys. They were both badly burned. TEKAMAH — John Ackerman was painfully burned when he proceeded to draw some gasoline from a barrel by the aid of a lighted lantern. An explosion followed. TECUMSEH — Feme Smith, 3, received burns which may cause her death, when her sister set fire to a pile of wall paper trimmings. The girls were a mass of flames when found by the father. THURSTON — John Stuckenschmidt was quite badly burned about the face and hands when some tractor oil exploded. ULYSSES — Ted Cordes suffered severe burns on both of his hands when he lit a match a few minutes after washing his hands with gasoline. VALPARAISO — C. C. Conger, editor of the Visitor, received badly burned hands when gasoline exploded with which he was heating a linotype. VERDON — Dean Crouch and Keith Cook, 12, suffered burns when a skyrocket ran wild. WAHOO — Mrs. Harry A. Schmidt mistook gasoline for kerosene when she tried to hasten the fire. She was severely burned. WAKEFIELD — Mrs. Crulckshon suffered burns on hands and limbs In an explosion of the gasoline stove. WAYNE — Gas escaping from a main exploded, burning J. C. Froelich, Everett Day and C. B. Kelrchy, who were working on the pipe. WILBER — Mrs. Fred Meyer was painfully injured when a laundry stove exploded. Her left arm was so badly mangled that It was necessary to amputate the member below the elbow. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">j • DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION WYMORE — Quincy Bridsley, 24, nearly lost his right eye in an explosion of gasoline soaked rags. The right side of his face was badly burned. YORK — Shirley Rogers, 12, suffered severe burns when the gas stove ex - ploded. YORK — Edward Shrigley was seriously burned when the oil heater ex - ploded. YORK — Miss Jane Mulr suffered serious burns about her face and hands when she dropped a blazing piece of paper on the pilot of a jet gas burner in the furnace. YORK — William Stafford, fireman, was burned about the face while fighting a fire. GERING — A. J. Ryan and his daughter, Jeanette, were both badly burned when gasoline exploded, with which she was cleaning clothes. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">STATE OF NEBRASKA Deaths from Fires ALLIANCE— Andres Glines. 23. was burned to death when the auto he was driving burst Into flames, after It hit the ditch. (See Injured.) AUBURN— Eugene Keedy, 3, died from burns received when a flaming can of gasoline thrown by his father struck him. BEATRICE— Florence Plainer, 13, died as a result of severe burns sus - tained when using kerosene to start a fire. (See injured.) BLOOMFIELD-^rohn Fritz, 75, died when their car upset and burned (See Injured.) BRIDGEPORT— Burns suffered when he poured gasoline on live coals, caused the death of Dan Murphy. BROKEN BOW— Trapped In his burning auto, which overturned, Oscar Martin, 57, was burned to death. BROKEN BOW— Adeline ChelewsM, 3, suffered burns that resulted in her death. BRUNO-^Jacob Stava was fatally burned. It Is thought he lighted his pipe ari3 the burning match f ell In his pocket, Igniting his clothing. BUSHNELL— Adeline Fox, 21, poured gasoline Into the kitchen range to kindle the fire. An explosion followed, causing her death. CAMPBELL— Burns proved fatal to Adam Melnger. 57. when a motor exploded. CEDAR BLUFF— Young Knutzen, 4, waa burned to death while playing with matches In the barn. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION CHAMBERS — Charles Brown was fatally burned when his clothing caught fire while burning rubbish. CHAMBERS — Mrs. Rudolf Horacek, 64, was burned to death when a can of kerosene, with which she was starting a fire, exploded. ELGIN — Elmer Christianson received burns from which he died when an incubator he was filling, exploded. ELWOOD — Merna Hall, 15, was burned to death when starting a fire. FALLS CITY — Harve Kimmel was burned to death when his auto caught fire. FALLS CITY — Donna Lee Frieese, 5, died from burns suffered when she and her 6 year old brother attempted to prepare supper and sur - prise their parents. FALLS CITY — Raymond Conover, 19, was burned to death in a fire that destroyed the home. FREMONT — Mrs. Ida Williams, 45, died as a result of burns received in an explosion from a cleaning fluid. GUIDE ROCK — Fire that destroyed a large barn, caused the death of Ralph McCallum, 50. It is thought the lantern set fire to the hay. GORDON — Darlene Cornett, 17, died of burns suffered when a stove, in which she was starting a fire, exploded. HASTINGS— Harry E. Geaghler, 53, was burned to death in his garage. HASTINGS — Harley Mullen, 46, fireman, died while fighting a fire at the Ingleside State Hospital. It is believed he was electrocuted by a fallen power line wire. LEWELLEN — Burns received, when a kerosene lamp exploded, re - sulted in the deaths of Joseph Rosas, 39, his wife, 36, and Victor Conzales, 32. HYANNIS — Mrs. John Kaschube died of burns from a gasoline explosion while she was trying to start a fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">STATE OF NEBRASKA -__^ LINCOLN — Flames In the basement of the home caused the death of Wayne Mischnick, 3. LTTCHFIELD— Mrs. Charles Wolford and her two months' old son were burned to death in a fire which, destroyed a chicken house at their home. - - LYONS — Frank Talbot died of burns received falling asleep smoking his pipe. MEADOW GROVE — Nona Joyce Lewis, 6, picked up a match, lighted it, and set fire to her dress, and before bystanders could catch her, I she was burned from neck to knees, causing her death. NEBRASKA CITY— Lee Abernathy, 30, was fatally burned when his clothing, saturated with gasoline, ignited. NORTH PLATTE— Burdette Leypoldt, 22, died as a result of burns received in a gas explosion. His father, Dorcey M. Leypoldt, died in a vain attempt to save his son. Skin was taken from the father for grafting on the son, resulting in infection, which caused his death. OMAHA— While trying to hasten a kitchen fire, kerosene exploded, causing the death of Mrs. Edna Devers, 36. OMAHA — Mrs. Fannie Matson, .72, was burned to death when her cloth - ing caught fire in an unknown manner. OMAHA — John Miroslavic, 60, died from effects of burns received when a kerosene lamp fell from a table, setting the bed on fire, upon which he was sleeping. OMAHA. — Ed Easley, 43, died of burns suffered when a gasoline stove exploded. (See injured.) OMAHA — Burns proved fatal to Nicholas Damato, 24, when he set a fire. OMAHA — Ignition of a religious shrine, set up near the crib Of five months old Ida Ortiz, caused her death when a lighted candle set fire to the flimsy decorations. OMAHA — V. E. Hammond, 64, was burned to death by falling asleep while smoking his pipe. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION OMAHA — Jean Bullock, 7, succumbed following a fire in the home. Simon Bowser, 73, the great grandfather, died enroute to the hos - pital. (See injured.) OSHKOSH— Mrs. Clifford Snell, 19, died when Jumping from a blazing motor truck. PALISADE — Mrs. May Benge, 60, received burns causing her death, when gasoline, with which she was cleaning clothes, exploded. PAXTON — Little baby Hoffman was burned to death in a car when a can of gasoline became ignited. (See injured.) RED CLOUD — Shirley Louise Harris, 6, died of burns received while trying to light a match. Her dress caught on fire. RESCUE — Mr. Joseph Kahout, farmer, was found burned to death in the debris of a bonfire. SHELTON — Wayne Hogg and James McCullin lost their lives when they dropped a lighted match in a can of blasting powder. SOUTH SIOUX CITY— Mrs. Ella Nelson, 71, died from burns suffered when a gasoline stove exploded, STAPLETON— Mrs. Olive Fuller, 29, died from burns received when starting fire with kerosene. ST. PAUL— Lockjaw developed, from burns, after a fire cracker was thrown at Florence Todd, causing her death. TABLE ROCK — Clarence Grimm, 14, was fatally burned when he lit a match to see if his father had the car tank filled. (See injured.) TECUMSEH — Raymond Cecil Taylor, 15, was burned to death when a v brooder house stove exploded. (See injured.) TECUMSEH — Verna Smith, 5, set fire to a pile of wall paper trimmings. Her dress caught on fire and she was burned to death. (See injured.) VALLEY — Jacob Chris tens en, 80, was burned to death in a fire that destroyed his home. WAHOO— Harold Knutzen, 4, lost his life in a fire that burned the barn to the ground. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">STATE OF NEBRASKA WAU^- 3 f rS \ Bernhard Johnson &lt;"ed as a result of burns received while cleaning clothes In gasoline. «&lt;.«vea WINSroE-Mrs Ludwlg Sonnenberg, 85, died as a result of burns suf - fered In an oil stove explosion. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">. DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION . ■ j Investigations of Suspicious Fires . . . During 1931 the Fire Marshal's office made investigations of 195 suspicious fires. Of this number investigated it was believed that 116 of these fires were, without doubt, of incendiary origin. Twenty-five persons were arrested and charged wth arson; 11 confessed, were tried, con - victed and sentenced; 6 others were tried and acquitted, and 4 bound over for trial in 1932; 4 persons were dismissed and two are fugitives from arrest. Of the remaining cases, up to date, no charges have been preferred, as the collecting of evidence still continues. Fifty-five of the fires in - vestigated proved not to be of incendiary origin, but in most cases care - lessness on the part of the occupant in allowing fire hazards to exist. The other twenty-four were listed as unknown or doubtful. In the investigation of these fires the utmost care was taken to avoid publicity and reflections being cast on any innocent party or par - ties. It is a greater satisfaction to the investigator to be able to exon - erate the suspected ones than it is to bring charges of arson against them. . LINCOLN — January 29, 1931, attempted arson. Grocery store. George Mumby. Convicted in Muny Court of the crime and fined $200.00. MINDEN — February 8-11, 1931. Arson. Bowling alley. Cyrus E. Ab - bott, owner. Fred Taylor, employe", and two others, Oalf Crooker and Nels Nelson. All of them arrested and confessed to conspiracy to burn the bowling alley equipment. Abbot hiring them. Abott sentenced to pen for three years; Taylor for two years; Crooker and Nelson sentenced to reformatory for one year each. NEAR FALLS CITY — February 22, 1931. Arson. Barn on a farm. Mrs. Lavina Micheal, owner; 72 years old and crippled. Tried for hiring her half-brother to burn barn, but jury acquitted her. Yock Micheal, her half-brother, confessed that she offered him $50 to burn it, so he hired </seg>
            <seg id="p054">STATE OF NEBRASKA Artie Booth, a three time convict, to help him for $10.00. Booth was tried and convicted and sentenced to ten years In pen, and Yock Mlcheal was given three years. NEAR CLEARWATER— February 3, 1931. Burning of truck. Arson. E. Rushall arrested and bound over to district court for trial. $1,000 bond. Tried and acquitted November 3. ASHTON— February 25, 1931. Dwelling, partly burned. Arson. H. W. Moore, arrested and bound over to district court in $1,000 bond, March 10. Tried September 21, 1931, and acquitted. OMAHA — March 4, 1931. Dwelling, burned. Arson. August Pe - kleser arrested and charged with having burned it for his brother-in-law. Bound over to district court. No report of trial yet. CURTIS — March 29, 1931. Tire and battery shop and service station. Arson. Lester D. Kemp ton, occupant, arrested April 11 and charged with arson. Bound over to the district court. Jury later acquitted him. KEARNEY— March 30, 1931. Dwelling set. Arson. J. Spooner, owner, confessed to haying set the fire to collect the insurance. Turned over to district court for sentence. BEATRICE — April 25, 1931. Dwelling set on fire. Arson. David Colby, occupant, suspected and warrant issued and read to Wm He de - nied the charge and asked to be allowed to go home that night and would appear the next morning with a bondsman but it was" found the next morning that he immediately got his brother to drive him to Omaha, and he is now. a fugitive from Justice. WYMORE— May 27, 1931. Dwelling burned. Arson. Mrs. Emma D. Moore arrested and charged with burning it. Preliminary hearing held June 4 and she was bound over to district court under $1,000. On June 10 she decided to plead guilty and was sentenced to one year in state pen. SOUTH SIOUX CITY— June 21, 1931. Dan Lee (colored) arrested for attempting to burn his house. Fire had been set in five places with kerosene. Was bound over in $500 bond for preliminary hearing, which was not held until December 18, 1931,. and charges dismissed. House cost $1,700; was Insured for $4,000. Household goods worth $300; was insured for $800. ' • </seg>
            <seg id="p055">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION CRAWFORD— July 5-6, 1931. Dwelling set three different times. Arson. Sam Holloway, a bootlegger, and the occupant of this house, is without doubt guilty, and a warrant issued for his arrest, as soon as he comes back into state. He ran out on us. COMSTOCK — July 8, 1931. Dwelling partly burned. Arson. Earl H. Howland, the owner, was arrested and charged with burning same on July 11. Preliminary hearing July 27, bound over to district court under $1,000 bond. Not yet tried. NEAR SIMEON — July 25, 1931. Hay stacks and prairie fire. Paul Nollett, 18 years old, arrested and confessed. Was paroled to bis parents for two years and ordered to report to the court at stated intervals. RULO — August 19, 1931. Garage burned. Arson and robbery. Dick Miller ex-convict, suspected. Was taken before an insanity board and found insane. Sent to the Lincoln State Insane Hospital. EDISON — September 3, 1931. Dwelling burned. Arson. John Geis arrested and charged with burning. He was badly burfied and is in hos - pital until he can be taken to jail at Beaver City. Later dismissed. NEAR NORTH PLATTE — August 10, 1931. Auto burned. Arson. Herman Moore, owner, arrested and charged with arson. September 19, bound over to district court in $1,000 bond. Tried November 2, 1931, and acquitted. CEDAR RAPIDS — August 29, 1931. Two story garage burned. Ar - son. J. A. Divis, Adolph Dolezal and Jerry Mullen arrested October 5 and charged with arson and conspiring to burn the building for the insurance to the contents. They nave confessed to conspiring to burn, but deny having set it. Dolezal tried December 16 and jury acquitted him, so the county attorney dismissed the charges against Divis and Mullen. PAXTON — July 6-27, August 4, 1931. Eight fires; one dwelling, three attempts at an opera house, one church and three lumberyards. Five of these in the village of Paxton. The lumberyard fires same night, July 27, at Lexington, Cozad and Gothenburg. Losses amounted to ap - proximately $150,000. All of these were set by Dr. H. J. O'Donnel, M. D., who lived in Paxton. He confessed first to the Paxton fires and later to the others. He was ready to plead guilty to arson, but his brother pro - tested, so both district judges. Nicely and Toul, refused to accept his </seg>
            <seg id="p056"/>
            <seg id="p057"/>
            <seg id="p058">STATE OF NEBRASKA plea of guilty, and he must stand trial before a jury, as to his sanity. Was tried on November 17, 1931. Jury out two days and nights, dis - agreed. To be tried again. OMAHA — October 2, 1931. Dwelling fired. Arson. Denny Powers, an 18 year old boy, rather simple minded, was seen to set it on fire and also two or three other buildings in this same neighborhood, but neigh - bors were afraid to report it, as the boy is a brother-in-law to one of the city firemen. He lives in a rough section of the city. Denny is un - doubtedly a pyromaniac. He was turned over to the Juvenile Court to take action on October 10. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">■ DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION ■ Over Insurance Cause of Incendiary Fires Our experience In the investigation of fires has proven beyond a doubt that over insurance is the predominant cause of arson. Fully 90 percent of the incendiary fires are set for the purpose of collecting the insurance money. It is very easy for anyone to obtain insurance on household goods or stocks of merchandise in excess of their real value. We have had cases that have come to our department for Investigation where dishonest persons have obtained $2,500 insurance on goods actu - ally worth but $150.00. One can readily see the incentive for arson in a case of this kind. When an insurance agent writes a policy for a man with a written assurance that in case of fire his company will pay in spot cash $2,500 for goods that are not worth more than $150.00, there is every reason to believe that the stock will be burned up before the insurance expires. So easy is it to obtain insurance for three, four or even eight or ten times what the Insured property Is worth that in sev - eral large cities gangs of crooks have organized themselves into what are called "arson trusts" who make it a business to go into a town, rent a house, furnish it with a table and chair and proceed to obtain "insur - ance" on it. It has proven a most remunerative business to them, they plan their work so well they have all the time for deliberation and oper - ation that they require, they can choose the most Convenient time in which to set the fire, and they use the utmost care to burn every trace of the origin of the fire with the fire itself so that it is almost impossible for police officials, detectives or state officals to fnd anything but cir - cumstantial evidence against them. Hence very few arson criminals ever pay the penalty of their crimes; in fact they nearly always attain their purpose and collect their insurance. It seems the only way to abolish the crime of arson is to prevent over insurance; then there will be no incentive for it as few cases are committed through spite or revenge. We know insurance companies do not want to write risks for more than they are worth; it is the local agent who is at fault and how best to deal with him is a problem yet unsolved. We know it is a hardship to ask that every risk be personally inspected; the commissions paid the local agent do not warrant him to spend his time in doing this; how - ever, it would not be impossible for each assured to give the local' agent a sworn statement of his household goods and their value and while of </seg>
            <seg id="p060">STATE OF NEBRASKA course the agent and company might even be taken advantage of then, yet it would have a tendency to hold even the dishonest applicant within reasonable bounds, for the agent could give him the impressions that as soon as he had time he would go and look over the property and com - pare it with the statement. Of course, we realize that unless all com - panies agreed to do this it would not be practicable, for the assured would take out his Insurance from a company that did not make this requirement. In time we feel some such method will be adopted uni - versally by all companies.. Even now insurance companies can have some understanding with their agents to the effect that they will not stand for the fragrant writing of risks and that wherever possible and con - venient the risk must be inspected. Cases have come to our notice where agents have insured property to the point of criminality, and yet the company in no way blamed the agent. At Sidney, on December 15, 1915, we investigated a case where a lot of newspapers and rubbish were gathered together in the basement and saturated with coal oil and evidently set on fire. The investigation brought out the fact that this party bought the stock contained In the store for $175.00 and obtained insurance on it amounting to $1,400. The stock was bought In June and burned up in December. Both the man and his wife were away at the time the fire started (3 a. m.) and had been away from the house since 7 o'clock the night before and were able to prove an alibi. No one was seen around the place and of course this department could have no one arrested for the crime. There is no doubt but that the fire was set by a slow fuse, but the evidence was destroyed by the fire. : "To prove the carelessness of the insurance agents, Fire Marshal Stevens of Oregon has made public the result of a test he recently made. A fireman's helmet and a grand jury subpoena were placed In an empty flat. The fire marshal then sent a deputy to get the furniture Insured. As a result the deputy secured policies from twenty. companies, each insuring the furniture for $500. In a frame shack in another part of the city, a fireman's helmet, a subpoena and a tin cup resulted In the obtaining of almost a score more of policies for $1,000 each. "Fire Marshal Stevens says that in the deputy's round of the agen - cies no effort was made by the agents to have the goods inspected be - fore issuing the policies nor did they ask for a list of the goods. Of course, the deputy who asked for the insurance deviated from the truth "somewhat" when he asked for insurance on furniture, but so would a dishonest person who wanted excess insurance in order that he might burn out and collect same." </seg>
            <seg id="p061">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION We realize of course, that companies writing city business meet more frequently with the person who wants excess insurance than do farm mutual companies who write only on farm property, but our office has also had cases where the farmer has evidently had horses, cattle, household goods, etc., over Insured and the company has insurance, but those who have had experience in settling losses know only too well how often suspicion is well founded. It is departments like ours and the members that become suspicious of him when they go out to settle the loss. Often the remains. of about four hours es have been found when the insured insisted that he had lost seven or ten horses in the fire. Often the fact that household goods have been removed from the insured property just before a fire has been proven. We would not have com - panies and agents look with suspicion on every one who takes out In - surance with them. The average • layman has no idea of the number of dishonest losses that the insurance companies have to pay. As the prin - ciple that the proper way to control the fire hazard Is to study causes of fires, and from each experience devise remedies to prevent a recur - rnce of such loss, so we ought therefore to turn our attention to reducing incendiary fires as well as minimizing the loss from careless causes. This article was taken from the Eighth Annual Report of State Fire Marshal W. S. Ridgell, for the year 1916. Conditions found at that time are still existing today, and, there - fore, calls for vigilance on the part of the agent </seg>
            <seg id="p062">STATE OF NEBRASKA Incendiary Fires Bulletin for Fire Departments It Is desired to call the attention of the members of the fire de - partments throughout the State of Nebraska to the ever increasing number of fires of suspicious origin. Some officials are on record as making a positive statement that more than 30 percent of the fire loss is incendiary. This is undoubtedly an extravagant statement, but it Is conservatively estimated that 10 percent of the fires show evidence of incendiarism. It occurs to me that by co-operating together and thor - oughly Investigating every fire of suspicious origin we may materially decrease the fire waste In this state and make the crime of arson so unprofitable and so unpopular that it will be seldom attempted. Arson has always been considered one of the most serious crimes and has been classed with murder and treason, and in some states, even now, a conviction of arson carries with It the death penalty. Incendiary fires can, for ordinary purposes, be separated into five classes, according to motive: 1. — Desire to defraud the insurer. 2. — Malice or revenge. 8. — Malicious mischief. 4. — To conceal evidence of some other crime. S. — Pyromanla or some other form of Insanity. Every fire Is presumed to be of accidental origin, and as the fire - men are the first to reach the scene of the fire, it is usually within the province of these men to overcome the presumption of accident and to discover evidence to show that the fire was incendiary. One of the first and most important steps In an arson trial Is to prove what the lawyers call the "Corpus Delecti," or the body of the crime. In other words, before evidence of a motive, or even a confession, can be Introduced In </seg>
            <seg id="p063">■ DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION a criminal trial it must first be proven that the specific crime charged has been committed. In a case or arson the specific charge is the burn - ing of a building or other property. In the investigation of a fire care should always be taken to as - certain the character of it, in what part of the building it originated, how it burned, and other facts and circumstances which may be sug - gestive of the nature of the fire under investigation. The incendiary origin of a fire is sometimes shown by direct and positive evidence, such as the saturation of the premises with kerosene or some other explosive compound. It may be shown by the fact that there are two or three separate fires, one having no connection with another. It some - times manifests itself to the firemen by trie manner in which it burns, or by the presence of dense smoke, indicating the use of oil. ■ The appearance of the interior of a building frequently shows whether a fire is the result of accident or design. The articles of fur - niture may be so placed as to retard the work of the firemen, or there may be evidence that a considerable part of the furniture, fixtures, or stock had been removed previous to the fire. The Supreme Court, of a western state, in commenting on an arson case, said: "Where the same person has a series of fires and collects insurance it furnishes a basis for an inference of more or less strength that the fires are not accidental." In the investigation of a supposed incendiary fire it is frequently thought important to eliminate insofar as is possible all the accidental causes which might possibly be put forward as the probable cause for the fire. It is highly important to Inspect the heating and the electrical equipment of the building, to see whether such equipment could possibly have been the cause of the fire. It is thus important to know that the electrical equipment is intact or that there is no electric wire near the origin of the fire, as some of these things will undoubtedly be advanced by the defense as the probable cause. Any of these things and many others not here mentioned, may tend to excite the suspicion of the firemen that the fire was not accidental, and in such a case a thorough investigation as to its cause should be immediately made. If any physical evidence of incendiarism is found it should be immediately taken possession of by the officer in charge and held for the Fire Marshal or his deputy. It frequently happens that the remains of a "plant" arranged by someone to start or accelerate the fire is found in the building after </seg>
            <seg id="p064">STATE OF NEBRASKA the fire is extinguished. It is highly important, in the event candles, or oily bottles, or things of that character are discovered, that they be left exactly as found until they can be photographed. If the candle is to be picked up, lift it by the wick and turn it over to the Fire Marshal's office, for examination for fingerprints. The same care should be exercised in handling any other articles which were plainly used by the incendiary, for their examination for fingerprints. All cases of suspicious fires should be immediately referred to the State Fire Marshal for further investigation, but the members of the fire department should bear in mind that, being the first at the scene of the fire, it is their duty, if the fire' is incendiary, to collect and develop the evidence to support this fact. Of course, it is impossible to properly investigate the cause of a fire during its progress, but where the 'circumstances are suspicious, as soon as the fire is extinguished a watchman should be placed in charge of the building until such time as proper investigation can be made. (Signed) L. J. BUTCHER, Assistant State Fire Marshal. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Standard Equipment of Fire Departments The hose couplings of all fire departments in this state should be brought to a standard. The standard for hose couplings established by the National Board of Fire Underwriters is known as seven and one - half threads to the inch, National Standard. It is essential that this standard should be adopted by all cities, towns and villages, so that in case of a big fire occurring, and a call for help being sent out, other fire companies responding to the call can couple on the fire hydrants wherever and whenever necessary. At the Baltimore fire, Washington and Philadelphia sent their equipment to assist, but their equipment was useless for they could not connect onto the fire hydrants. The fire loss was forty million dollars. This might have been greatly reduced had all equipment been standard. (Anderson Company, Omaha, Nebraska, has standard dyes changing hose couplings to standard.) </seg>
            <seg id="p066">STATE OF NEBRASKA 1 What Pressure Should Be Maintained on the Pumping Engine? These Suggestions Will Help You to Solve this Problem PUMPING ENGINE PRESSURES It Is evident that a short method which will enable an operator of a pumping engine to determine the pressure suitable under various ordin - ary conditions would be quite welcome, and with that in mind the fol - lowing has been prepared as a guide. It should always be borne In mind that a few pounds variance either way makes but little difference in the amount of water that reaches the fire. There is an old saying that any stream that does not make a black spot where It hits is of little, If any, value. A good stream Is one that will enter through a window with force, and at this point not lose con - tinuity of the stream by dividing into a shower or spray, and should appear to shoot 90 percent of the whole body of water inside a 15-inch circle, and 75 percent of it through a 10-inch circle. It Is generally considered that an effective nozzle pressure Is ap - proximately as shown In the following- table which also shows the dis - charge in gallons per minute at such pressure: Size of Pressure Nozzle at Nozzle . Discharge %-inch 50 lbs „ 120 G. P. M. %-inch. 50 lbs 160 O. P. M - 1 -Inch. 50 lbs .209 G. P. M. 1%-inch. 50 lbs 265 G. P. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION ■ 1%-inch 50 lbs 326 G. P. M. 1%-inch 60 lbs 434 G. P. M. 1%-inch.... : ...60 lbs . 515 G. P. M. 1%-inch...] ...........60 lbs _ .....600 G. P. M. 1%-inch...: 60 lbs 700 G. P. M. 2 -inch 65 lbs .'. 960 G. P. M. A nozzle of any certain size is not suitable in all cases. For example, a %-inch or a %-Inch tip is best suited for small fires; 1-inch and 1% - inch tips are effective on fires of ordinary magnitude; 1%-inch tips should be used on single lines directed upon large fires; larger sizes are used in connection with large stream appliances, such as deluge sets, deck pipes, .monitors, turret pipes and ladder nozzles. The following methods may be used to roughly and quickly calcu - late the pressure at which to operate the pumper, remembering that one or two pounds either way make no noticeable difference. These formulas are based upon the assumption that there is little or no difference in ground elevation between the fire and the location of the pumper. Where there is a difference, add 5 pounds to pump pressure for each 10 feet the pumper is lower than the fire and subtract 5 pounds for each 10 feet the fire is lower than the pumper. Also, add 5 pounds to pump pres - sure for each story the nozzle is used above ground. The pressure added for each 100 feet of hose in the line is equivalent to the approximate pressure lost due to friction in the hose with the. amount of water flow - ing that would result with the given size of nozzle and the pressure at the tip as indicated in the table. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">STATE OF NEBRASKA ■ 1 ' i ' ■ . ■ ■ " Formulas s (1) '/4-INCH NOZZLE: SINGLE LINE: Pump pressure equals 50 pounds plus 5 pounds for each 100 feet of 2%-inch hose in the line. Example: 300-foot line would require 50 plus 5 plus 5 plus 5 equal 65 pounds pump pressure. (2) '/,-INCH NOZZLE: SINGLE LINE: Pump pressure equals 50 pounds plus 7 pounds for each 100 feet of 2% -inch hose In line. (S) 1-INCH NOZZLE: SINGLE LINE: Pump pressure equals 50 pounds plus 10 pounds for each 100 feet of 2%-inch hose in the line. (4) 1% -INCH NOZZLE: SINGLE LINE: Pump pressure equals 50 pounds plus 17 pounds each 100 feet of 2%-inch hose in the line. (5) 11/4 -INCH NOZZLE: SINGLE LINE: Pump equals 50 pounds plus 25 pounds for each 100 feet of 2-inch hose in the line. (6) 1%-INCH NOZZLE: 2 LINES OF 2&lt;/ 2 -INCH HOSE OF EQUAL LENGTH, SIAMESED: Pump pressure equals 60 pounds plus 10 pounds for each 100 feet in one line. (7) l»/,-INCH NOZZLE: 2 LINES OF 2J4-INCH HOSE OF EQUAL LENGTH, SIAMESED: Pump pressure equals 60 pounds plus 20 pounds for each 100 feet in one line. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION (8) 134-INCH NOZZLE: S ONES OF 2'/ 2 -INCH HOSE OF EQUAL LENGTH, SIAMESED: Piimp pressure equals 60 pounds, plus IS pounds for each 100 feet in one line. (9) 2-INCH NOZZLE: S LINES OF 2&lt;/i-INCH HOSE OF EQUAL LENGTH, SIAMESED: Pump pressure equals 65 pounds plus 25 pounds for each 100 feet in one line. These pressures give good average streams but are not the maxi - mum nozzle pressure permissible. Under certain conditions higher or lower pressures may be more desirable and the officer in command will give instructions .to the pump operator. Care should be taken that the layout will not require the pump to operate at a greater capacity or pressure than that for which it is designed. Published by the KANSAS INSPECTION BUREAU. W. C. HODGES, Manager. • B. J. STEWART, Chief Engineer. Topeka, Kansas. Permission was given this department to print this in our Annual for the benefit of all fire departments. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">STATE OF NEBRASKA Nebraska Editors, City Councils and Town Boards, Chambers of Commerce, Boy Scouts and Camp Fire Girls and all Other Organizations We take this opportunity to thank you, one and all, for your splen - did co-operation given us In fire prevention lines, and we ask you to make a resolution of vigilant fire carefulness, so that 1932 may be a year of concerted effort in fire prevention throughout the country, to aid the return of economic prosperity. Fire loss figures for 1931, in the State of Nebraska, show an increase of one-half million over the preceding year — per capita loss, $2.25. This loss was felt severely, especially during this depression. '. • ■ Fires in Nebraska will never be very much reduced unless we, as individuals, decide to remove the causes, of which there are many. Most of the causes are absolutely preventable, and the fires can be avoided if proper precautions are taken. Carelessness and indifference will never stop or prevent fires. Study the r nes of those more or less seriously burned, and the reasons given for these tragic affairs by those reporting them, and then determine to practice every safety move that will tend to prevent a like occurrence on your premises — either home or business place. We must prevent every such happening, by removing fire hazards, screening open fires, handling explosive liquids in a safe manner, as the dangers in handling gasoline improperly is becoming very alarming, and by using all precautions possible, that would tend to safeguard both life and prop - erty. It will take the help and co-operation of every citizen of this state, if we are to have a fire waste reduction in 1932, or to keep it from in - creasing during the year; for strange as it may seem, property burns much easier when times are hard than when business is flourishing. Your co-operation will tend to reduce the fire waste for 1932 to a very small figure. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">■ DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Fire Department and Fire Alarm Tax "Section 4469. Compiled Statutes for 1922. FIRE DEPARTMENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX. All cities of the metropolitan, first or sec - ond class or village, organized under the laws of the State of Nebraska, shall have power and authority to levy a special tax of not more than one and one-half (1%) mills each year upon all taxable property in said city. Such special levy shall be made by the same officers or board and shall be levied in the same manner as in the case of general city taxes. Revenue raised by such special tax may be used only for the purposes of purchasing equipment for a fire department of such city or for installing and equipping a fire alarm Bsytem, or in payment of bonds as herein - after authorized, (Note: Sections 5820 and 5910, C. S. Neb. 1922, now fix levy at 20 percent of one and one-half mills actual valuation.) "Section 4470. BONDS— AUTHORIZED. Any city or village hav - ing levied a tax as herein authorized may anticipate the collection of such tax so levied, and for that purpose may issue bonds with interest coupons attached, in a sum amounting to 90 percent of the tax so levied. Such bonds may run for a period of not more than five years, and may bear interest at a rate not to exceed 5 percent per annum Bonds so issued shall be secured by such tax so levied, and shall be payable only out of the funds derived from such tax. In any case in which bonds are issued as herein authorized, it shall be the duty of such city, on receipt of such tax, to hold the same as a separate fund to the amount of the bonds, so issued, and the interest thereon, for the purpose of paying or redeeming such bonds." </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>