<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ELEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska State Hospital AT INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1910</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">OF THE Nebraska State Hospital AT INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER. 30. 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE BOARD OF CONTROL Hon. E. B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Hon. George C. Junkin Lands and Buildings, Chairman Secretary of State K. L. O. Brian . Arthur Mullen Treasurer of State Attorney General RESIDENT OFFICERS Superintendent Steward STAFF Superintendent First Assistant Physiei;ui Second Assistant Physician Third Assistant Physician Fourth Assistant Phy 1W. Baxter, M. D. le Gidley MEDICAL M. W. Baxter, M. D J. W. Meehan, M. D \V. Y. Thompson, M. D _ S. C. Doran, M. D A. J. Pricke, Ph. G. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">To His Excellency, Aahton C. Shallenberger, Governor of braska : Dear Sir: — I have the honor to submit this, the Eleventh Biennial Report of the Nebraska State Hospital. Ingleside, Xebr., covering the biennial period eonmeneinfj December 1, IJMtS, and ending November 30, 1910. At the beginning of the biennial period. December 1. 1908, there were ten hundred and forty-five patients in the Hospital of whom six-hundred and eighty-two M ere males and three hundred and sixty-three (363) females. During the period, four hundreci fourteen (414 1 patients have been received, of whom two hundred and sixty-one (96] rid one hundred and fifty-three (153) females. During this period there wer&lt; hundred and forty-five cJ4-"&gt; paroled; out of this number one hundred and seventy-eight (178) were discharged and sixty - seven (67) were returned from parole. Of the one hundred and seventy-eight (ITS; discharged, fifty-thr eighty-three (83) improved and forty-two 1 42 no change. At the present time there are fifty-one (51) on parol. twent males and twenty-five (2~&gt; &gt; females and four (4 escaped. We had two hundred and five (805) deaths, leaving ten him and sixty-one (10151 i patients in the Hospital. November 30, 1910, isting of six hundred and ninety-three malm ml three hundred and sixty-eight (368) females. We have maintained a daily average of ten hundred and sixty-one and one-third patients at a daily average cost per capita of 31 1-10 cent an annual per capita of $113.53. Realizing that the successful management of an Institution of this kind greatly depends upon employing men and women •aed of a high sense of duty toward those who may be placed in their care, it has been my constant endeavor to obtain such help as would assist in raising the standard of efficien. compare favorably with any Institution of this kind. I have visited several Institutions, both in the east and the west, during the past two years and, after giving due consideration to their methods of treatment and management. I feel safe in saying Till I n T 1 111 f^ Wl T l I I f^ t k TH T 1 * I l*i^ i^tt T t ?*H ill T 1 T w\ W^ 4~\^2 ■ tf^fc^T T w^ TT1 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">312 I^M) COMMISSIONER'S RKI'OKT IMPROVEMENTS II take jrreat pleasure in calling attention to a tew of the important improvements which have been made during my rintendemy. General Kitchen: The floor of the general kitchen was found to be in a verv unsanitary condition. This was entirely removed and replaced by a solid six inch cement floor. The ste.iin pipes which heretofore had been placed under the floor. &gt;sitatin^ the taking up of the floor in case of repairs, were changed M that in future it will not be necessary to disturb the floor when repairs are found to be needed. I Boiler Room: The annual coal hill was found to be a very &gt;us item in the maintenance account, and after inquiring and onally investigating several different methods of tiring as ial saver, we finally decided upon giving the Jones anto - ic stoker a trial. The old style prates were removed and e of the automatic stokers installed. After giving the old new style a competent and thorough test, we were able to irt a little over IS per cent saving in coal. We have also i enabled during the cold weather to keep not only a greater but also a much more even one throughout the who buildings. t Power House: All the expensive machinery has been over - ed and repainted. The walls of the power house have been led. painted and a brick Hoor replaces that of the dirt one • before. tA further saving of coal I nught mention was made by in - inur a 4."&gt; II. P. motor to run the ice machine instead of the in engine which had heretofore been in use. This enabled us ut out one steam line and use the surplus electricity which iously had not been utilized. Cold Storage: The cold storage tu next given attention, as the wooden rs sings and mineral wool used for insulation had become mouldy and saturated, thereby throwing off an unwhole - some odor. This we realized to be a source of grave danger. The whole of the interior was torn out and entirely remodeled providing separate rooms lor meat and poultry, milk, butter, lard, vegetables and fruit, waking one of the most sanitary. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, LNGLKSIDE 313 useful and ap to date cold storages in the state. The material used was powdered cork, cement and lime. I Wards: Everything lias been done to make the wards erful and pleasant. .Most of them have been repainted orated, new furniture and rugs have been supplied when y. and careful attention has been given to sanitary eoa - on*. The result lias been that I ,im able to report there been an outbreak of any contagious disease. Food: It has been my constant endeavor to provide and wholesome food and of sufficient quantity, not only to the patients but also to those who are employed in the Hospital this has 1 n greatly appreciated by all concerned. AMUSEMENTS I Amusements both indoors and out have been amply supplied. ong a few of the most important that I may mention baseball park, provided with a covered stand for the women seats for the men. Several interesting g.tnies have been wit - led during the season, which were greatly enjoyed. Open air certs were given during the summer months. A band stand has n erected near the main building, which gives those patients &gt; are unable to leave their wards an opportunity of hearing the :ic. Dancing during the winter months has also been provid- Iand greatly enjoyed by those patients who care to take part. lay also mention that a moving picture show is held once reek. DAIRY &lt; Special attention lias been given to the dairy cows inasmuch i- I large number. 85 per cent, were found to be infected with tuberculosis. These animals were shipped to South Omaha and old subject to inspection and slaughtered under the supervision »f the state veterinarian. Many of the carcasses were wholly •ondemned as unfit for consumption, others partially remainder being passed. The healthy cows were segregi their offspring and other younger animals having replaced I lisposed of. Believing that too elose housing was one of the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">314 given to better ventilation in the barn and to keeping the animals out in the open air whenever the weather permitted. HOGS IThe raising of hogs lias proven to be very successful and we at the present time about three hundred and twenty (390 . a a fine healthy condition. FARM AND GARDEN IAYe have had excellent results both from the farm and en during the past summer. The Institution is well supplied all kinds of vegetable! at the present time. NEW BUILDING tA new Srproof building which will tceomodate 120 patients been provided at a cost of $50,000 and will be ready for ipaney in a short time. The building in itself is the must tantial one of those erected on these grounds, and will be id of great benefit to relieve the congestion now existing in Institution. RECOMMENDATIONS Prevention of Insanity EAny action looking toward the prevention of insanity in opinion has been too long neglected. Cnlcss some check is ed upon existing conditions this matter will become a serious ilem for future generations. I To bring the matter before the present legislature. I shall ition only one case out of many, that have come to my knowl - e during the time I have had charge of this hospital. Mr. was sent to the hospital suffering from syphilitic dementia. After a time he made a slight improvement and was taken home by his wife and other friends. After spending a year or more at home it was found necessary to return him to the hospital: he being in a violent condition at that time, and dying a few weeks later without making any recovery. 1 am especial - ly prompted in bringing the matter before the legislature on the grounds that during the twelve (12i months this man was at </seg>
            <seg id="p007">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. INGLESIDE 315 home, and three (3) months prior to his death, a child was horn to them; and I feel under such circumstances that I am justified in asking that some action he taken. tWhat I would suggest for consideration is a state law pro - ng for the sterilization of chronic insane patients lx&gt;th male female. I would also favor such a law applying in the case riminal rape, etc. I wish to say that in making thi - , I am advocating an operation (vasectomyi that would take away a man or woman's usefulness, hut on the contrary. Id he a factor in assisting to restore the patient to his or ber normal condition hoth mentally and physically. NEEDS OF THE INSTITUTION EThe present requirements, which I shall take the liberty of ng to your special attention are as follows: The laundry is ted in an old building. In the same building are the bakes Enter shop and paint shop. Should a fire, once gel started in r one of these shops it would mean the destructoin of the p building. The loss of the laundry would mean a terrible ter to an institution of this kind. II would suggest that sufficient money be provided to letatched. fireproof and modern equipped laundry. I would D suggest that a subway he built, commencing at the general chen and connecting the same with all the different buildings, should be sufficiently large for carrying food from the ki' the several wards. It would also be used for carrying all ies. hot and cold water, etc.. so that in the event of any leakage bursting they could be reached at once. This would do away h present conditions, which mean a constant digging and ring up of lawns and sidewalks when necessary to repair | It gives me great pleasure to thank and fully acknow the very important services rendered hy our able steward and competent corps of assistant physicians, and the other officers and employes of the hospital, in constantly and intelligently perform - ing their several duties. Their co-operation in this great work B the means of bringing this biennial period to a KM ful conclusion. The responsibilities resting upon one and all of 1*1 s f*nT\Yif\f Vif* ful 1 v r^iil i7p(i r)v the? cssiifll onlooker* 'w ho \i\ a v </seg>
            <seg id="p008">&gt; at liberty to criticise without any realization of the fjrav responsibilities and attention to duties, that are required of thot who work among the insane. To His Excellency, the Governor, and &lt; lag the Hoard of Public Lands and Building! my sincere thanks for the courtesy, raluabh selfish support which I have received at your time both individually and as an official 1 you I have at all times fully appreciated place this Institution upon the highest plane :entleinen constitut I desire to expres: assistance and un hands from time t&lt; &gt;«ly. I can assur. your endeavors v if efficiency. Respectfully submitted, M. \Y </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">SEWING ROOM REPORT Made in the Sewing Room the Biennial Ending November 30, 1910. Aprons Rurial squares I5i(l ticks _.&lt; I! (*■» Bandages Bibb* Eball suits in}/ cloths ■in 14 1 Eain straps ets covers osolcs 6 &lt; 'licmise 531 S Comforts &lt; 'andy bags 884 tss linings wers (men) wers (womf rarfs &gt;r covers 4ti 1 121 824 u 440 •&gt; Jumpers Kimonas •5 Laundry sacks Mail pouch 101 1 •Matrcss pad Napkins 9 500 Neckties 675 Night gowns Night shirts : </seg>
            <seg id="p011">319 Pillow ca Bow shams o\v ticks illow tops Ktraint sheets ks of mending rts i Shirt waists Sheeta 6 K.iuva.s •uds _ 6 4:. Bgical gowns i pillowi S s Kid covers le cloths i 1 Talilc pads Towel*, roller Tciwels. hand I'nderwaist Underkirti .. as Miscellaneona </seg>
            <seg id="p012">320 LAM) COMMISSIONER'S REPORT rM AND GARDEN PRODUCTS RAISED AND CONSUMED DURING THE BIENNIAL PERIOD BEGINNING DE- CEMBER 1. 1908, AND ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1910. Products — Asparagus . 43 dozen Beam 4-i'J bushels 427 bushels ( labbage 15,378 heads Carrots . 100 bushels Cauliflower 640 heads Cucumbers 444 bushels Kali-rabi 1- bushels Lettuce : *44 bushels .Mushrooms 1 ' a dozen .Musk melons 300 bushels Onions 2 " bushels Onions, green 465 dozen Parsnips 961 bushels 255 bushels potatoes 6,178 bushels Potatoes, sweel 24.") bushels • Pumkins 1,240 only Radishes 7,63] dozen i Rhubarb 1J12 dozen ,\ 25 bushels »rkraut aeh 150 gallons ."),S4 bushels 638 only Squash t corn . 375 bushels Tomatoes 680 bushels Turnips 750 bushels Watermelons 960 only Milk 109,980 gallons Pork 19,938 pounds Poultry 3,429 pounds ■) • 5 Veal 12.4415 pounds Alfalfa 243 tons (Judo *^ ' tons </seg>
            <seg id="p013">HOSPITAL FOR IXSAXE, INOLI 321 Corn fothler Millet Oats Prairie hay FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCTS ON HAND DECEMBER 1, DISBURSEMENTS Dec 1 S. BUckenbiller, auto kin 8 Geo. Springer, veterinary wrriec 8 Edgar J. Tanner, hone feed and auto 8 Hastings Fuel Co., 230 Hi. B. S eo*l 14 J. I'iekens &amp; Sons 17 Ilanseii Lumber Co.. voucher 6 17 C. K. Lawson. Hardware Co.. voucher 7 17 Ferrens &amp; Xeinieyer. voucher s 17 Stein Bros., voucher !• 17 A. If. Clark, voucher 10 17 A. M. Clark, voucher 11 17 II. J. Penfold Co., voucher 12 17 Mrs. \V. 0. Clark. 47 II.. thick 1!) J. II. McQrmtk Hdw. Co.. for hardware 1!» lini. H. Isaiuan &amp; Co.. lantern burners 1 4.. 14 13 70 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">322 UAND CO.MMISSIONKR'S REPORT •&gt;•) J. II. .Mc(Jratli lldw. Co., ti bushel baskets 2 10 2:5 Mrs. W. O. Clark. 27';. lbs. dressed duck .'{(» Ilayiics Bros., sundries B 4n 1909 deposited with State Treasurer 28] 92 Balance carried forward 117 16 Total 1909 2 F. J. Thorp Co., 2 stamping pads s 2 W. B. Kern. P. M.. postage stamps 5 J. II. Hoagland, cartage 2 00 5 Blackman &amp; Fuller. 2 1-3 boxes scouring 5 Blackmail &amp; Fuller. 2 1-3 boxes scouring p 4 00 :s soap ti II. E. Shumate, extra labor 4 77 t; II. E. Shumate, extra labor 13 Ilolstein Frit-sen Association, fee for transfer 50 13 Holstein Friesen Association, fee for transfer Baker Bros. Engraving Co., voucher 14 Sharpc &amp; Smith voucliers 15 50 16 Baker Bros. Engraving Co., voucher 14 18 69 16 18 69 Sharpe &amp; Smith ( vouchers 15 17 14 i&lt;; 17 14 16 A. M. Clark, voucher 16 22 45 22 4.'. 16 A. M. Clark, voucher 17 27 65 Ki ('. K. Lawaoo Hdw. Co., voucher 18 lti If. 0. Bishop, voucher Id 4.") nu 16 P. R. Reiner, voucher 2o :&gt;4 on lit ]!• W. B. Kearn. picture! for Cyrus King 2 00 W. B. Kearn. pietnres for Cyras King Dr. Geo. Springer, veterinary serviees A. L. Underland, repairs for barbers chair 2:{ Dr. (3eo. Springer, veterinary services 7 50 23 S3 A. I,. [Tnderltnd, repairs for l&gt;arbers chair •{'• O. C. Zinn. repair work M() P. A. Feist, upholstering 2 couches 13 (m&gt; P. A. Feist, upholstering 2 couches 13 imi 30 Deposited with State Trcaurer 2i" Balance carried forward 121 95 30 Deposited with State Treaurer Balance carried forward 200 33 Total $ fi] Total 1 W. B. Kern. P. M. voucher 24 1 1 W. B. Kern. P. M. voucher 24 Standard Oil Co., vouch. A. M. Clark, voucher 26 « 1 Standard Oil Co., voucher 2."&gt; 7 63 1 A. M. Clark, voucher 26 :{."&gt; oo 35 00 1 Bert Scobey. voucher 28 2.1 do 1 Bert Scobey. voucher 2!) 15 (Ml Bert Scobey. voucher 2!l Hastings Fuel Co.. voucher :{o c. B. &amp; Q. R. R.. voucher 23 E. M other 22 (J. W James voucher 33 1 Hastings Fuel Co.. voucher 30 1 i </seg>
            <seg id="p015">323 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE 18 II. Kidder, drngi is A. Pickens &amp; Son 18 G. H. Ilanty &amp; Co. 18 0. C. Zinn 1 Deposited with State Treasurer Balance carried forward 9:] 20 Total - {2 16 50 27 J. W. Ilaney Co. 27 Wallen &amp; Allen 27 Hastings Fuel Co. 27 Quake Cornelius 2!) Oliver Lumber Co 2!l J. W. Crissinan 1 or, 10 4.'. :{ 20 2!) Stein Bro 30 American Express ( \ :il Deposited with State Treasurer 2 15 Balance carried forward I Total Is K. J. Tanner 18 Blackman &amp; Fuller 18 Geo. Kist.r 120 T. J. Throp Co. 20 E. I'. Burnap &amp; &lt; . 1 Deposited with ! 10 Ilaynrs Bros., voucher 27 10 A. M. Clark, voucher 31... II) Woodruff Collins Printing Co., voucher 1 ,]. \V. Hoaeland J. B. Cornelius ti Jesse Gidley 11 J. B. Thompson Caranation ' 20 ■]. M. Anson 22 .1. X. Dean 2:5 Nebraska Hardware ( 27 II. Lehman 27 C. W. Jacob 27 Geo. Kester.... r&gt;4 31 Stein Bro; :il Stein Bm </seg>
            <seg id="p016">324 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 1. Jesse Qidley, voucher -'54 $ 37 14 1 Rudpe &amp; Ouenxel, voucher •!•"&gt; 1 50 1 II. If. Alexander, voucher 3&lt;i 4 00 1 Bates Manufacturing Co.. voucher 37 10 90 1 Jesse Qidley, Steward 38 82 64 1 T*. S. Supply Co.. 1 enamel fountain. 9 00 6 American Express Co. 1 20 I. W. Pepper, 150 clarinet solos 1 50 i 10 American Express Co. 19 American Express Co. 26 Stein Bros.. 3 dozen glasses 3 90 29 Stein Bros.. 2 dozen pencils 1 00 29 Benederup Hardware Co.. 1 lock 40 29 Haynes Bros., gold and silver paint 30 29 II. M. Cohn. repairing sterilizer m 3(1 Singer Sewing Machine Co. repairs 3 85 30 Haynes Bros., for jrlass 3 45 30 John Cornalis. to 30 dozen esr^'s at 1 * » cents 4 80 Retained from cash to balance account 2!&gt; 30 30 Deposited with state Treasurer 639 B5 Balance carried forward 200 (|(l Total ft 1,036 7^ ■ 1 Austin Hyan. paper for 10 rooms ft 5ii 00 s 1 (iastoii .Music Co. 1.") ] Jesse Gidley, K. R. fare to Lincoln and return 4 S3 T. F. Mennin Co.. ' .. dozen billard cues 4 00 ) 15 B. &amp; M. Co.. 1.000 mile hook. Dr. Baxter 20 00 18 J. T. Shumate. Tti dozen eKira 14 09 2(i J. A. Craneer, 1 dozen pictures 13 50 19 Stein Bros.. 1 toilet set 7 90 20 S. Blankenbiller, auto service to pastun 21 Stein Bros.. 1 rujr. 1 carpet and latches 2, !&gt;:i 22 H. G. Meyers. .") lhs. butter, bill of January 1 25 26 Lewis B. Maleeki. sheet music 6 43 26 Stein Bros., balance on gilkolim 27 Karl Wiseman, fi loads cobs 4 7."&gt; 31 C. &amp; \. \V. 1.0(10 mil,, book. Jesse Qidley 20 00 &lt;] Stein Bros., key rings </seg>
            <seg id="p017">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGI.I ■]\ Retained from eash to balan ml 300 "7 Total 2 1 pair lineman's pliers •&gt; 1 pair lineman's pliers Freight on clothing 3 Freight on clothing. 5 Express charts Express charge Express charge •&gt; 5 Express charges •fin Bros., Linoleum, earpet, et« 40 75 .} 8 Stein Bros.. Linoleum, car E. J. Ilearn. services hook 40 ::. 10 E. J. Ilearn, services bookkeeper's office 5 &lt; *&lt; • 1(1 14 Express charge! 71 14 17 Stein Bros., dishes, razor strop 12 2&gt; 17 Stein Bros., dishes, razor Wolbach &amp; Brach. 2 carp strop 17 Wolbaeh &amp; Braeh, 2 carpets 17 ts 17 Express chargei 17 Express charges 18 Stein Bros., supplies 1") 41 Stein Bros., supplies 18 19 W. II. Mansfield, 280 ft. picture molding -rein Bros., crockery IS 80 19 W. II. Mansfield. 280 ft. picture molding 21 Stein Bros., crockerv IS 80 21 C. E. Ilarritt, stove casting 21 C. E. Ilarritt, stove casting 22 D. M. Judkins, baby carriage, etc. 2 10 T). M. Judkins, baby carriage, etc. 8 10 22 J. P. Rafter, expense Lincoln and return J. P. Rafter, expense Lincoln and return 22 W. Hall Crutcher. freight on pool table 2-1 Hastings Tribune, advertising 1 80 23 A. II. Mansfield, 2 gallon* varnish 4 50 A. II. Mansfield. 2 gallons varnish 4 50 24 Wolbaeh &amp; Braeh, 100 Ib cotton batting 12 50 24 Wolbach &amp; Brach, 100 11. cotton hatting 12 50 2.") Stein Bros.. 2 rolls crepe pap t 15 2.") Stein Bros.. 2 rolls crepe paper 15 86 Stein Bros.. 1 pair scissors. 100 ft. rope 1 00 26 Stein Bros.. 1 pair scissors. 100 ft. rope 1 00 26 Swartzebild &amp; Solxberger, by error in bill 2 4&gt; 26 Swartzchild &amp; Sulzberger. by error in hill 2 4:{ 28 Stein Bros.. 1 box toilet paper 5 75 28 Stein Bros.. 1 box toilet paper ('. B. &amp; Q. R. R. freight char 28 C. B. i Q. K. B. freight eharges 28 28 ('. B. &amp; Q. K. H. freight charges 12 4(i ('. B. &amp; Q. R. R. freight eh 12 4.. are 28 C. B. &amp; Q. R. B 28 Hastingi Light &amp; Heat Co.. i^bbl coal tar 2 Deposited with State Treasurer Balance carried forward 200 00 Total I 1-' Hastings Light &amp; Heat Co Deposited with State Trea •) urer Total July 1 Western Supply Co.. 1 barbers lavatorj fi ExDresa Expn Stein Bros., water cooler ; i "&lt;• r i Exprcs s Id Freight charge &gt;•&gt; )•) </seg>
            <seg id="p018">LAND COMMISSIONER'S EPORT 326 1!) l:{ Express ehai 15 Stein Bros., hay fork, rop&lt; Robert Dressier, repairing SchmiU &amp; Headriek, d 17 mirror 17 Carl Fischer, sheel music Frank Holt on Co., 2 drum IT 17 heads, cymbal 17 Bristol Co., 500 steam charts John Hopkins, press subscription, Am. Journal Frank S. Betz Co., surgical supplies Evening News. Lincoln, hack subscription..... Xve Schneider Co., 200 ft. molding, ."&gt; sks. IS 1!) 19 1!» lit cement City of Hastings, tapping water main and 19 attaching pipe 19 W. B. &amp; S. Co., 2 sacks fir. W. T. Cornelius &amp; Co., gn Ilaynes Bros., 1 gal sheila Stein Bros., •! yds. eambri II. S. Brown &amp; Co., 1 lamp ( '. W. Jacobs, lawn mower lav 1!) ri&lt; lit 1!) 20 )\\1 20 repair II. M. Cohn. 2 iamp shades and holder Schmitz &amp; Headriek, 1 &lt;it. ink •2o 20 "• 20 Stein Bros.. 2."» rolls toilet paper Deposited with State Treasurer Balance carried forward ■&gt; l:{."» 04 200 00 Tot hI 536 95 S 2 C. S. Palmef, 122 His. lmtt.-r (" 2 nts 24 4o 2 Exuress eharses 1" Express charges 3 Geo. Anfdenkamp, 118 lbs. butter (a 20 eta 2:{ 60 :{ Mrs. L. C. O'Neill, 34 lbs. hutter (a 20 cents :{ E. A. Philleo. 4 bu. apples (a 7a cents '.\ 00 4 Win. Grothaus. fifli.. lh.s butter (a 20 cents V-i 90 Stein Bros. Co., crockery 1 94 •) Wm. Huston, 120&gt; 4 lbs. butter (q 20 ceir 24 05 i decorations and fireworks 17 K. A. W«tkins, printing matron's reporti 17 Stein Bros.. :! hunches hanan is. 2 boxes lemons 2 C. B. &amp; &lt;l R. I?. mUeage hook. 1.0(»0 miles 20 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLES1DE 327 0 0 12 1 1 1 1 1 &gt;] 21 &gt; '( &gt; i &gt; &gt; ;ii i •&gt; H - I A. II. Stuart, 12 bu. apples (a 7.~&gt; cents Wolbach &amp;. Braeh, *7 yils. earpei and paper Sears. Roebuck &amp; ('&lt;&gt;.. 4 eots II. W. Baxter, cash advanced for 82'/. H butter Schmitz &amp; Headrick, stationery State Journal Co., subscription New York Press •I. T. Shumate, ins doz. eggs, 8f) lbs chicken nts s ;■; Ed. Philleo, l:!i L , bu. apples II. Sehriner, express charges L H. Seudder, 130^ ll.s. ,-lii Geo. Anfdenkamp, sin., ll.s M. W. Baxter, cash adv. in r (I I.I cents 19 return of escaped I). Tot a Cushing Grocery CJo., '-1 rolls wrapping paper ('. B. &amp; Q. R. R. (ticket book) 1,000 miles Rutherford Bros., water guages 7n ij." Hastings Electric Supply Co., lamp shade Singer Sewing machine Co., repairs repairs Eric Johnson. li.Ml ]bs. butter (a 2" cent Louis B. Maleeki. hand music 1~&gt; cent 17 &lt;'. IF. I &gt;a vies, expense in return of patient Fk. Quade, 38 lbs. butter, 44':. .loz Wm. Huston. 26»/ 2 lbs. butter (&lt;i 20 cents II. Schiner, express charges M. W. Baxter, easfc adv. for 10 bu. apple Fk. Quade, 20 lbs. butter, 2n doz patients elothi km Ui 15 cents butter patient •sited with State Treasure! Sept. 1 Wm. Orotham, • &gt;(&gt; lbs. butter Ui 20 eeni 2 Pk. Qoade, 15 lbs. batter Ui 20 eente, 18 dot 10 (M'llts 1 E. A. Philleo, 25*4 bu. apples (a 75 :{ Ruthi'i'foni Bros., water gnage glasses boiler 4 Cushinir Grocery ('&lt;&gt;.. -i rolls wmppins paper </seg>
            <seg id="p020">LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 328 9 Chris. Eggers, 21 bu. apph Johnson Blec. Co., 6 ox. ma Win. Houston, 21 His. lmtt( •J. T. Shumate. ls:{i.. ]| ls . s Ul 50 cents mei wire Ki 4:: 11 13 18 4(i doz. eggs Ui 20 cent; Kastijra Glasti &amp; Paint Co. •I. A. Rom &amp; Co.. glass cuti J. H. Ilaniy &amp; Co., sirai Stein Bros., 2 doz. sauce di 7 90 i:» 1 Ch. Brush r attachment : it; 16 is 18 ('. II. Davies. cash advanced for 8 bu. applet* •J. T. Simulate. 17 1 -. doz. chickens. 1'.. doz. 18 21 M. W. Baxter, cash advance 48 lbs. butter Ui 22 cents. :)2 doz. egga Ui 21 cents 7 50 30 Stein Bros., kitchen utensils and crepe paper 30 Stein Bros.. 2 gross buttons 11 40 30 Hastings Furniture Co.. 1 wardrobe, 1 mat- 23 00 233 52 tress 1 Deposited with State Treasurer Total 584 38 1 1 •r ((I 20 cents chickens and 224 eggs ('. S. Palmer. !i2 lhs. butter (n 20 cents 15 Pk. Qoade, 15% His. butter (§ 2o cents. 24 lies. 1&gt; linkers eggi Stein Bros.. 1 dos. tailors' tap» 21 Stein Bros.. 1 butcher's steel 2:{ Fk. Quade, 16 His. butter (a 20 &lt;-.-nts. 15 ( | ( .z e«r&lt;rs (a 2h cents ii '2&lt;&gt; 2."&gt; Win. (initlmus. 1 ."&gt; 1 lbs. butter (a 2&lt;) cents 10 :!&lt;&gt; 2."&gt; E.I. I'hilleo. 28 !iu. applet 17 00 27 Stoin Bros., kitchen utensils and merchandise 13 45 2!t .Mrs. C. E. Palmer. iV/ 2 ll.s. 1. utter, and 4 iliiz. eggs !• 15 2'.) ('. Sclmltz. auto service to pasture and return &lt;&gt; on :{() M. W. Baxter, cash advance 48 lbs. butter (a 30 Wolhach &amp; Hr.ich 15% ft. linoleum ;{o Wolhach ft Braeh, 7 ft. fi in. linoleum. 'M\ W'olliacli &amp; Brach, 7' L . dot table napkins 3d Stein Bros., kitchen utensils and crepe pap &lt;•&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p021">HOSPITAL FOR IN 329 1 Freight hill on (tempers from Chicago 2 in lbs. chicks (a I") cents. 14' ._. lbs. butter (a 2~&gt; cents, 4 dozen eggs (5 22 cents K&gt; :{•&gt; in 36 2 6 months subscription Rocky Mountain News ■fin Bros., 1 day honk -■"&gt; 2 ii months subscription \i 2 Stein Bros., 1 dav hook 4 Star l'rein Co.. 12 pictures fur ward itein Bros., :i do/, tumblers, 1 water pitcher, 1 do/, trays 4 51 4 :.l 4 Hastingg Vulcanizing Co.. repairing water bags 7.") 4 Hastings Vulcanizing ( repairing water 4 Hanson Lumber &lt;'".. 24 It. molding- 4 II. S. Brown, 1 :Ui^rht 15. I?, ehandelier. 4 L. Carroll. :! bu. sweel potatoes :$ 7."&gt; • fin Bros., as per invoice 5 4^5 •liniitz &amp; Headriek, 1 letter book 1 2"&gt; 3 i.t Stein Bros., as per invoice ."&gt; 4^5 Schmitz &amp; lleadrick, 1 letter hook 1 2.~&gt; t; ti I*. -\. Robinson, easli advance •!■"&gt; dozen eggs 7 70 P. -\. Robinson, cash advance 35 dozen eggs 7 ii&gt; ti 7 Ed. l'liilleo. 26 bu. apples 12 no Ed. Philleo, 26 bu. apples 12 00 ' 7 Fk. Quade, 2:! Ib. butter. 24 do*, eggs lo 33 Fk. Quade, 2:! Ib. butter, 24 doz. eggs !•• 33 !l -I. 15. Cornelius, .'ii'., doz. eggs (a 22 cents 11 :U 11 .1. Adeeamp, 91 lbs. butter Ut 20 cents, 42 lbs. butter (a 2.") cents, 4 doz. e^rtrs (a 22 ets. 29 58 .1. Adeeamp, 9] lhs. butter Ui 20 cents, 42 lbs. butter (3 25 cents, 4 doz. e&lt;r&lt;:s ui 22 ets. 29 58 12 Express charges on samples from Lincoln 7"&gt; 5 Express charges on samples from Lincoln 14 Electric lijdit and frame for library 12 7-~&gt; Electric lijrht and frame for library 12 7-~&gt; 14 If. W. Baxter, cash adv. for 24 doz. eggs ('/ 2:: cents. :{2 lbs. butter Ui 2.") cents . S. Palmer, 31^ lt&gt;s. butter ui 25 cents. :. doz. eggs (a 22 cents M. W. Baxter, cash adv. for 24 doz. eggs u/ 23 cents. :{2 lhs. batter (a 2.") eents 16 C. S. Palmer, 31^ lt&gt;s. butter (g 2."&gt; cents. :. doz. eggs (a 22 cents Id I. ]!. Sen, Ider. 2P -. lbs. butter (a 25 cents, .")' 4 doz. et:i. r s ('/ 22 cents. 4:{ lbs. chickens Ui 1.") cents 12 !»'.» •ein Bros., goods as per invoice 16 I. ]!. Scudder. 21 1-. lbs. butter (a 25 eents, 5% doz. et.'i. r s (a 22 cents. 4:{ lhs. chickens (1 15 cents 12 !»'.&gt; Stein Bros., goods as per invoice ■ l!i L. Carroll. 10 bu. sweet potatoes 12 50 L. Carroll. 10 bu. sweet potatoes 12 50 l'J A. S. Bos, 80 lbs. chickens u, 12 cents 13 00 r. S. Boz, 80 lbs. chickens (a 12 eents 13 ini 20 Wolbach &amp; Brach, for ward 1 1" 11 20 Wolbach «i: Brach, for ward 11 11 90 &gt;n 21 c. II. Da vies, repairing drug scales ■ C. II. Davit's, repairing drug scales 21 Wolbach &amp; Braeh, 1 rag 12 50 Wolbach &amp; Brach. 1 rag 12 50 21 Wolbach &amp; Braeh, clothes for baby Wolbach &amp; Brach, clothes for baby 22 K. T. Bowers, \cterinary services •&gt; (l(l 22 One mileage book 1,000 miles . If. \\". B ter </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Kov 22 29 24 C. S. Palmer, -'M- His. batter (a 25 cents 27 Kk. Qaade, :! invoices batter and eggs ft (i: 14 54 2 Subscription to Ilolstein Frieseo World Balance carried forward 1 00 ll:{ 99 406 51 Total .1. S. ]{(&gt;/. 180 His. chickens (a 9 cents ('. II. Dabies, return of patient and R. B. fare 4 (i Stein Bros.. 1 Neulife, 7 s ll»s. chickens (a 12 Win. GrothauK, 1 &lt;() His. j •lesse (ii.lley. 20 2 -l{ 1)11. Geo. Kister. blacksmith Tlieo. Sims, repairing s| Stein Bros., :&gt; pairing reese (n 12" .'. cents 21 2."&gt; 8 Id Id 10 ipples Ui 1.0(1 21 (Jti work 1 2o tacli's for patients 95 turner 10 McUratli Hdw. ( !o., 3 lanterns 18 84 ;::- 12 Schmitz &amp; lieadrick, typewriter ribbon 1 rug !Jil7.."&gt;0, Iti yds carpet (a 12.00. sewiu 12 1 lbs. butter Ui 30 25 cents cents. :i.") do/, eggs (a Emma Cole. Repairs on Express charges on pati&lt; Jesse Gidley, emery wht 13 tewing machine nts clothi s 1.'! 16 el and frame 2:5 Wm. Orothaus, butter and . 16 20 2 96 bread knives, 2 mat tresses 8 -I. H. Cornelius, 1"&gt; doz. (••r^s (a '22 cent- nts 13 ."&gt;(&gt; knives. 1 pancake 10 Stein Bros., dishes for officers &lt;linhi&lt;r room in Denver Post, (i months subscription. Hi Rutherford Bros., plumbing repairs 11 FU. Quade, is ]hs. butter (a 2."&gt; easts, Hi 1 - lbs. butter (a :&gt;&lt;&gt; cents. (J dox. eggi (a 2") cents. Id &lt;l(iz. c&lt;.'j.'s (S 28 cents 1:{ T."&gt; 12 Wm. P. IIiif,'D. slicct musk. 11 00 12 Stein lJnis.. balance &lt;&gt;n buttons 1 27 80 cents 12 Subscription Alienist and Neurologist 12 U. W. Baxter, cash adv. :il lbs. buttei ts. Palmer, :si lbs. batter ui 30 eents, 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">MO8PTTAI. FOR INSANE, [NOLESIDE 19 1!) li &gt; '( &gt; i ;( !(&gt; 1 s &gt; i i 1 17 &gt;•) 51 'ITS I'liiidi meal market. 12 lbs. pork loin. Pickens &amp; Sons. 8 yils. flannel (a 15 cents. •) yds. outing flannel (5 in cent Wolbach &amp; Brach, 9 yds. carpet ('. II. BeNight, 80 lbs. tnrk. Arthur Kilev. violin how h ('. S. Palmer, 2si._, lbs. butt Cashing Groeery Co., 2 pk M. O'Meara, repairs farm A. R. ( !ole, cash adv. 16 ll&gt;s. City of Hastings, 7 100-W. A. M. Clark. 2 pkgs. fish fi in •r (a 30 cent paper sacks cliinerv in; ill cents. s pat lent 7, Austin Ryan, 40 ft. plate and dado rail B. &amp; M. R. 1{. freight eharces Wm. Grothaus, 32^ Iba. batter "/ 25 i 28 lbs. &lt;a 25 cents Kk. Qaade 49y 2 lb. batter Ui 30 cents. 27 (I. Aut'denkainp. •)2' : . His butter (a 25 cents 34 lbs. (a .in cents. :{i:. doz. esrira II 15 Wolbach &amp; Brach, 24% yds. carpel 15 Sehmitz k Headriek, stationery 21 «»4 Stein Bros., kitchen utensils 1G J. IS. Cornelius, 2U 1 -. doz. 2ti cent supplies for 17 Freight charges mi :i c 1!) Wolbach &amp; Brach, 9 yds. carpet 2&lt;&gt; John Iloagland, dray charges 2&lt;&gt; ('. II. BeNight, 80 li.s. turkey (a 20 eeni batter (a 30 cents Tungesten lamps 11 20 od buttons irricil forward ss ■ (J. \\ . Lchr. express char clothe* - cent hS E&lt;J. Hoefer, 47i U lbs. batter - (I Anfcleiikamn. 521X Hi* l.ntt.-r (it ' A. B. Cole, cash adv. 4.i lhs. chicks (q 1.~&gt; eti 15 L. B. Xorris. return of patient and R. R. far ") do/ ~ ceni Brunswick-Blake ( 'ollendcr pool table •mi .Music &lt; f rnitar </seg>
            <seg id="p024">I-AXD COMMISSIONER'S REPORT I 17 A. Beck, harness repairs 2 05 18 Mrs. \V. 0. Clark. 21 lbs. butter ui 30 cent*, .Vt lhs. dllcks (a 10 cents Mrs. W. (&gt;. dark, 21 lbs. butter (a 30 cents. .")4 lhs. ducks (a 10 cents M. W. Baxter, cash adv. 1,000 mile R. R. hook Win. Grothaus, 129 lbs. batter (« 30 eeni .Mrs. K. A. Karr. *4 Iba. ducks Ui 10 cents Hoefer, 56% !"*■ butter (a 30 cents II. II. .Mansfield, picture molding 11 70 I - M. W. Baxter, cash adv. 1,000 mile R. R. hook 20 (&gt;(i 1* 18 18 Wm. Grothaus, 129 Iba. butter (a 30 cents 38 70 B .Mrs. K. A. Karr. *4 Iba. ducks (a 1(1 cents 8 40 22 Geo. Hoefer. 56^ lb«. butter (g 30 eenta 16 95 22 23 II. II. Mansfield, picture molding 14 13 23 z-&gt; 23 ('. S. Palmer, 73 lbs. batter (a 30 cents ('. S. Palmer. 73 lbs. butter (5 30 cents A. Pickens. patters and game 21 90 23 28 A. Pickens. pattern and game 28 85 19 Wm. (irothaus. 24% Iba. batter (§ 30 cents 4 do*, eggs (" 30 cents 29 S 55 2!) Proffitt &amp; Lovell, Christinas trees 2 (to 29 Stein Bros., Christmas decorations. $14.30 Stein Bros., Christmas decorations. $14.30, :{ bolts ribbon $2.4:5. ."&gt; boxes buttons $1.10 17 83 5 00 Dr. J. P. Kiddle, one pair glasses, patient's Fk. Quade, :!7 lbs. butter (a :50 cents. ."&gt; do/.. 29 29 15 40 gg ui :{() cents, lo (c; 28 cents C. K. Hoefer. 39 lbs. butter at 30 cents Balanee carried forward 11 70 :il 94 23 4.").") 80 Total 1910. Jesse Gidley, fare to Lincoln and return $ L. W. Wolworth, 9 dot pens, 2 rubbers 3 88 «n. 2 6 65 daters 1 50 Schmitf &amp; Ileadrick. 2 inkwells Sewing machine fixtures 6 95 58 50 Mrs. Grothen, 195 lbs. butter (a 30 eenta Fk. Q\iade. 16% lbs. butter «i 30 cents. 11 i H 8 25 2 00 doz. eggs Ui 30 cents 11 P. J. Robinson, mushroom spawn n Eric Johnson, 23% lbs. batter (a 30 cents, 15 lbs. butter (a 25 cents, 18 lbs. butter :!0 cents 13 85 5 00 12 G. O. Spillman, return of patient Palmer, M2 lbs. butt i doz. eggs (a 30 cent- 1.-5 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">13 IT. Hammerand, steam whistle for kitchen 14 Win. Qrothara, .~&gt;1 lbs. butter (a 30 cen1 loz. effffs (a -ill 14 Tina Wright, 37% lbs. butter (a 30 eetna 14 Fk. Quade, 8 lbs. butter Ui 30 cents. 8 doi li Gastoo Music ('o.. 1 piano aeraf for ward 4 2i) M. W. Baxter, cash adv. 41 lbs. butt. 41 lbs. butter 11 d (I :{d cents 20 Vuleanizinz Co.. washer for extractor 2(i Subscription Ila.stintrs Tribun.- ion Hastings Tribune 21 Fk. Quade, !i lbs. butter a :5d cents. !) do*. &lt;: butter (a :{o cents friction tape $1.75, 2 lb. solder 70 cent 22 (I. Hoefer, :&lt;Si .', lbs. butt r (a :in cents 1 1 .V&gt; 22 Mo. Pacific express, paekagi 2") Wolbach &amp; Brach, earpet unsewed 86 Jess Oidley, 1,000 mileage book 26 Dr. Cruteher, fare to Omaha 28 Robt. Wright, cash by Dr. Baxter, butter and 25 72 20 IN) 1 Balance carried forwai 13 J. J. Convghy, expna charges 1!&gt; 14 J. Hoefer, .")."&gt; lbs. butter (a 30 ct'iits 14 Mrs. Orothen, 47% ll&gt;s. hutt (loz. effffS Ul 30 rents egirs (a 30 17 Stein Bros., 2 hooks units $6.50, queenswu $11.24 17 McGrath Hdw. Co.. 1 thermometer 17 Hastings Furn. Co., 1 sanitary cot and mot- nts 12 (ii'o. Aiifilcnkamp. :{:{ U&gt; 12 II. S. Brown Co., 5 lbs. 29 Win. Grothaus. cash by Dr. Baxter, butter 29 Mme. H. Stuart-Riehings, Dr. Baxter | en- tertain I </seg>
            <seg id="p026">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 334 1 W. II. Cruther, Billard markers and hook W. II. Cruther, Billard markers and lion! L. X. Goody, 1 stack si raw 1 35 1 L. X. Goody, 1 stack si raw 5 00 I ('. X. Schmitz, stationery 2 85 4 Tina Wright, 13 His. butter (a 30 rents. 5»4 doz. et'trs (a :{O cents. 10 lt)s. butter Ui 30 Tina Wright. 13 His. butter fa 30 cents. .")' doz. egjre (a 30 cents. 10 lbs. butter fa :{() rent* cents 5 Hastings Furniture Co., 1 mirror Hastings Furniture Co., 1 mirror 3 50 .) 5 W. II. Palmer, II 1 - doz. egg* (&lt;&gt; 30 rents W. II. Palmer, II 1 - doi. eggs fa 30 cents Glem Qidley, 14 bo. applet fa 11.10 J. Aufdenkamp. 30^4 His. butter fa 30 cents 3 45 o 5 Glem Qidley, 14 bu. applet (a |1.10 15 40 n 5 J. Aufdenkainp. 30^4 lbs. butter (a M) cents. IT 1 - doz. (",:',:&gt;• (&lt;i 30 rents ■) 5 Wm. Grothaua 22', lbs. butter Ui 30 rents. 8 doz. e&gt;_'&lt;rs (g :id 8 doz. eggs (2 30 9 i '7 7 C. Hoeffer, Hi lbs. butter ui M) cents. 2 doz. eggs (fi 30 cents 1 eggi fa 30 cents 7 M. W. Baxter, 1.000 mile book (C. B. &amp; Q. M. W. Baxter, 1.000 mile book (C. B. &amp; Q. i r8. Palmer, 41 lbs. butter (a 30 eeiita, 18 Palmer, 41 lbs. butter (3 30 eents, 18 - doz. ejrjrs fr' 2.") cent- doz. eggs fi 2.") cents 16 80 9 C. B. &amp; Q. H. H.. freight 1)111- 9 C. B. &amp; Q. R. K.. freight bills 16 14 9 Eric Johnson. 60U 11). butter (a 30 cents. 7'^ 9 Eric Johnson. 60% lb. butter (a 30 eeata, 7% doz. egga ff/ 2(1 cents doz. i 20 cents 19 65 9 A. M. Clark. 2 nipples I A. M. Clark. 2 nipples 30 9 A. Pirkeiis &amp; Son 2 doz. thimbles 9 A. Pickens &amp; Son 2 doz. thimbles ro 9 Singer Sewing Machine Co.. repairs 9 Singer Sewing Machine Co., repairs 1 "&gt;0 II J. Aufdenkainp. 31 His. butter (a :i&lt;l cents. 2.')'., doz. eggs ('/ 2.") rents. ."&gt; doz. egga 30 rents 11 J. Aufdenkamp, 31 lbs. butter (a 30 cent 2.') 1 -. doz. eggs (5 25 cents. 5 doz. i_ (a 30 Renti 17 18 (a 30 cents 11 Mrs. Grothen. 186 lbs. butter Ui 30 cents. 12 11 Mrs. Grothen. 186 lbs. butter (a 30 rents. 12 doz. eggs Ul 30 rents. 18 do/., eejrs (r; 2o eenta 2o cents 12 C. B. &amp; Q. R .H.. 3 freight bills 3 18 12 C. B. &amp; Q. R .K.. :i freight bills 12 Win. Braeh, grill for library 12 20 12 Wm. Brach. grill for library 12 O. C. Zinn. clock for engine room 4 80 12 0. C. Zinn. clock for engine room 17 W. F. Shay. 17' 2 lbs. butter (a 30 eeati 17 W. P. Shay. 17% lbs. butter (a 30 cents o K i J.i 18 Robt. Wright, 22 lbs. butter (5 30 cents. 12 18 Bobt. Wright. 22 lbs. butter Ui 30 cents. 12 doz 5 2U rents. !l doz. e-zgs Ui 25 cents 11 -•» 25 cents 19 Hastings Elec. Light Co., 1 pendant switch 19 Hastings Klec. Light Co.. 1 pendant switch 19 Wm. Grothaus. :W lbs. butter Ui :5n eenta, 8 19 Wm. Grothaus. :W lbs. butter (a 30 eeni doz. e^rgs (a 2."&gt; cents, 8 do </seg>
            <seg id="p027">•* Uof I 1 A Lt r Urt 1 b,\.N t», 1 LjEjSI I ) fc. 335 .M 24 Stein Hros.. 1 pair overalls and ehilds elothea 2 50 24 I. Iloeffer. 82 lbs. butter (a 30 cents. 13 doz. (i 20 cents 27 20 24 ('. \V. Schmitz. 1 typewriter ribbon 26 N. Vilmur. balance pasture bill 10o!i 10 00 26 .1. H. Ilaney &amp; Co., leather triniininKs and rep handcuffs 43 00 Total 1 Ilattie Cole. 21 ' g doz. ej 1 0. Hoefer, 24 lbs. butter rs (a 20 cents a :50 cents. 24 doz. eg nt 2 Lee Pearl and Bogert, entertainment '■i Jesse Gidley, expenses l&gt;ill to Kearney 1 by irria 4 J. Aufdenkanip. 13% lbs. butter (&lt;i 30 cents 4 Julius Kinspart. 18 lbs. butter (a 30 ecu 4 Will F. Shea, 18 lbs. buti enta 5 Singer Sewing Machine c. repain 1-i C. s. Palmer, 24^ lbs. butter (a 30 eents, 27 ilnz. eg»s @ 2d criits 12 75 24 •). Autdenkamp, 4&lt;J lbs. butter (a 30 cents. 24 1 - doz. eggs (a 20 cents 18 70 85 Mrs. Grothen, 92 lbs. butter (a 90 cents. 42 doz. eggs (a 2d ct-nts 36 00 26 Geo. Anfdenkamp, 21 lbs. batter (a :{n cents. 531/2 «l«)z. eggs (a 2(i 17 00 26 Wni. Brach, 3 carpet nreepen, 2 rugi ward ■&gt;■) J. M. Cornelius, 44 ll&gt;s. butter (n 30 cuts rll doz. eggS ((I 20 rrllts 88 P. X. Addleman, exprem shaft 1 Balance carried forward I eggs ui 2u cents Fk. Quade, 22 :! 4 lbs. butter (a 30 eeni 4 -I. II. Hoajrland. drayage 4 If. O'Meara, expense bill with tean to Kearney </seg>
            <seg id="p028">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 336 5 Mrs. L. O'Neill. SOyu doz. eggs (a 20 cents 6 10 5 J. B. Scudder. 150 lbs. chicks (a 12^. cents, 75 lbs. butter (q 28 cents 40 87 5 Wm. Grothaus. 30 lbs. butter (n 30 cents, 8 doz. @ 20 cents 13 30 7 Cushing Grocery Co., 1 roll Manilla paper 1 15 7 W. H. Palmer, 4 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 5y 2 doz. eggs (a 20 cents 2 10 7 A. Pickens &amp; Son. 1 pattern _ 15 7 Gaston Music Co.. 1 orchestration 65 8 H. S. Brown Co.. electrical supplies 4 75 9 Fk. Quade. 18 lbs. butter (a 30 cents. 6 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 100 doz. eggs cents 26 90 9 Wm. F. Hugo. Italian strings 3 00 9 D. Fulton. 50 lb. hens (a 13 cents. 58 lb, n&gt;' 11 cents, 9 lb. rooster (a 6 eta. 13 42 9 C. A. Avery. entertainment in 00 10 J. Aufdenkamp. :i~&gt; lbs. butter Ui 2'&lt; 42] L. doz. eggs (&lt;i 20 cents rents. 17 2") 10 Wm. Brach. 1 rug $10. 2 yards percale L2%c !&lt;• 2-~&gt; 10 Schmitz &amp; Deines. pencils and library paste 10 Stein Bros.. 6 lbs. mimeograph ink. telephone and expres- 17 90 10 Stein Bros.. 6 lbs. mimeograph ink. telephone and expn-Nv 17 90 11 H. S. Brown &amp; Co.. 1 chandelier for sewinjr room 11 H. S. Brown &amp; Co., 1 chandelier for sewin room 12 Mrs. R. A. Karr. 12 doz. eggs Ui 2(&gt; cent 2 40 12 Mrs. R. A. Karr. 12 doz. eggs Ui 2(&gt; cent 12 T. Shattuck. 4 lbs. butter (a 2.~&gt; cents. 10 2 4(i 12 T. Shattuck. 4 lbs. butter (&lt;■/ 25 cents, lu doz. eggs (a 2(&gt; rents 12 C. S. Palmer. 13 lbs. butter (a 30 rents. 13 12 C. S. Palmer. 13 lbs. butter (a 30 cents. 13 lbs. butter (a 25 cents. 27 1 -. doz. eggs lbs. butter (a 25 cents. 27 1 - doz. eggl 20 cents 12 65 14 C. W. Schmitz. 2 cans pine tar 20 2(i 14 A. Pickens &amp; Son. 15 yds. linoleum for post offic&gt; 11 2;") Id 30 J6 P. J. Robinson, ."il I L . dozen egga «i 20 cents 17 Mrs. .1. Einsphar. 141bs. butter (S 25 cents. 8 &lt;loz. eggs (a 2(ic 18 Express charges </seg>
            <seg id="p029">337 18 rrs. Grothen, 47 y 2 lbs. butter @ 30 cents, 89 lbs. butter (a: 27 cents. 50 dozen eggs (a) 20 cents 4* 2* 18 rbt. Wright. 28y 2 lbs. butter @ 30 cents, 25^£ lbs. butter (7/ 25 cents, 59 doz. eggs (a) 20 cents 26 74 40 95 16 lbs. butter (a ■nts. 34 lbs. butter (a 2.") cents 26 40 19 Mrs. R. A. Karr. 41bs. butter (a 2.~&gt; cents. 20 cents 13 1 -. (l(IZ. I'!.'- 19 Wm. Grothaus. 44 lbs. doc egtr- chicks (fi 12' .. cents 12 (■•» 2i cents 25 Erie Johnson, 50 H»s. butt in eents : 26 Eolbach &amp; Brach, 30 1-3 yds. carpet. 1st Asst. office \V. Schmitz, stationery B. Cornelius. 65^ dox. epgs (a 20 cents. butter {a 2~&gt; cents, 2(i cento, 14L. lbs. Eattie Cole, 4:{ doc. i 20 rents 8 60 . Shattuck. 30H lbs. butter «, 2."&gt; ecnta, 12 doz. ep^'s (a 2' i cents 10 03 r. H. Palmer. 2:i doz. egga g 2n cents 4 60 . Hoefer. 74 lhs. butter (a 2."&gt; cents. ."&gt;4 doz. eggs c/ 20 cents F. Augustine, :!1' L . lt&gt;s. butter (n 2."&gt; cents 21 doz. eggs (a 2o centa 24 Fk. Qnade, 16 Ib*. batter fn 25 cents, 79 tloz eggs fi 2(i eentt 25 G. Aufdenkamp. 5 lhs. butter (a -'in ceni lbs. butter (' nts, 12-"&gt;i., &lt;loz. eggs ii 2t&gt; cents 2") Mrs. Grothen, i:i lbs. butt (loZ. f''L'S ((I 2&lt;&gt; l-t'Ilts lbs. butter (a 2~&gt; ■ ••■nts Hatti.- Cole, 23 doz. -&lt;» centi - Palmer. 14 1 - His. liutter Ui _ 20i : z ,ioz. t •_ nta Th..s Shattu.-k. 15 di </seg>
            <seg id="p030">338 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 26 J. Aufdenkamp, 12K lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 47 doz. eggs @ 20 cents 12 53 5 88 26 Julius Einspahr. 2:V ■. lbs. butter (a 25 cents 26 Voucher issued for repayment warrant to balance account Total $ Julius Einspahr, 32% lbs. butter (a 25 cents ,$ Singer Sewing Machine Co., mach. needles D. L. Alexander, bus hire _ 656 65 1 8 12 1 1 25 1 Tena Wright. 40% lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 22 doz. eggs (a 20 cents 14 95 1 Jennie Wilcox, chickens 12 80 12 80 2 II. B. Steele, 3 bbla. apples 12 50 12 50 2 W. H. Palmer. 8% do*, eggl fa 20 cents 1 70 \V. II. Palmer. 8% doz. eggs (a 20 cents J. A. Finnigsmier. 28 lbs. butter @ 22 cents B. &amp; If. R. K. Co.. freight on beds 2 J. A. Finnigsmier. 28 lbs. butter @ 22 cents 6 16 2 2 B. &amp; If. R. K. Co., freight on beds 2 Wm. Grothaus, 61% lbs. butter fa 85 cents, 30 doz. eggs fa 20 cents 21 38 5 Jesse Gidley. R. R. ticket to Omaha 3 04 6 Hotel bill, Omaha 1 50 7 Mrs. F. ('. Johnson. 11 doz. eggs fa IS cents. 1 98 Mrs. F. ('. Johnson. 11 dot eggs (a 18 cents. J. Cornelius. 33 doz. eggs Ui 20 cents Geo. Aufdenkamp, 27 lbs. butter (a 22 cents 8 J. Cornelius, '.i'.i doz. eggl f " 20 cents * Geo. Aufdenk&amp;mp, 27 lbs. batter fa 22 cents 25 dozen cif^rs (r/ 18 cents 10 44 s 25 dozen I'ggs 0/ 18 cent ID 44 8 Fk. Quade. 14% lbs. butter (a 2."&gt; cents. 21 ' L . lbs. butter (o 22 cents. 74 dozen egg! ff/ U cents.. 21 69 8 Fk. Qoade, 14% lbs. butter (&lt;t 25 cents. 21% lbs. butter (a 22 cents. 74 dozen eggs (a 18 cents 12 2 B. &amp; M. R. R. Co., 1,000 mile book (M. W. Baxten 20 00 B. &amp; M. R. R. Co.. 1,000 mile book (M. W Baxter | 20 00 5 30 12 2 Sehmitz &amp; Deines. stationery 5 '-i0 Schmitz &amp; Deines. stationery 13 3 Geo. Aufdenkamp. 16 lbs. butter (fi 22 cents 18 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 6 76 Geo. Aufdenkamp. 16 lbs. butter (d 22 cents 18 doz. eggs Ui is cents Ill V.i 3 Jesse Gidley. 3% bu. apples (a 3 85 Jesse Gidley. 3% bu. apples Ui $1.10 Mrs. Grothen. 128% lbs. butter (a 27 cents, 16 6 Mrs. Grothen. 128% lbs. butter (a 27 cents, 17 doz. eggs (a 20 cents. 60 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 4- 85 16 G. Hoeffer, 22% lbs. butter (&lt;i 25 cents. 47 U lbs. butter (a 22 cents. 10% doz. eggs (a. 18 cents </seg>
            <seg id="p031">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. INGLESIDE 339 16 is G. W. Dunn, for entertainment id no Mrs. W. O. Clark. H lbs. butter (a 25 cento, 21 doz. 8fgi Ui IS cents 2d Eric Johnson. .-&gt;7U lbs. butter (a 22 cents. 441. _. lb.s. butter (a 2.") cento 19 A. Beal. Jr.. n2 doz. egg* onto P. ('. Johnson, 14 doz I s cent F. Quad.-, is lbs. butter (a 22 cent*, 25 lbs 11 16 •)•) •)•) 26 Stein Bros., uueenswan American Express Co., C. ft X. W.*B. H. Co. 26 27 26 Baxter 26 C. ft X. W. H. H. Co York t*i'&lt;*iiriit on t PITS 1 1'niii 13 1 1 I I Eric Johnson. K4 1 ■&gt; lbs. butter Ui 25 eento, 12 doz. eggs (&lt;i 18 eento 25 79 6 00 J. Aufdenkamp. 4:^;. lbs. butter «i 22 cents. LID lbs. butter (a 25 cuts. 77 d«.z eggs Z/? 1 1 ft nfl _i 1 butter (a 25 ct.s. 83 doz. eggs (q 18 II. \V. Fogel, horse shoeing. harges on shabbery mileage book I Dr. 26 Sehmiti &amp; Deinem, stationery 26 Wolbraeh &amp; Braeh, 1 dox. pillows eoven 27 A. M. Clark, iodoform, peneilsharpener ami guage 28 Rolit. Wright, 2:!'^ lbs. butter (a 22 eenta, "&gt;4 lhs. batter (a 27&gt; eents, .'54 doa (a 18 eenta 2!i .Mrs. Qrothen, 122Lj lhs. butter (§ 27 eei 2f» Expreaa charge*, for pAtienta 30 Win. Brothaus, 72'.. butter (a 2."&gt; cents. 67 30 Win. Brothaus. 721.. butter (a 2.~&gt; cents. (17 His .batter (a 22 cen 18 centi May 2 Deposited with State Treasurer Balance on hand Total May 2 Clem Oidley, 15 bu. applet ui $1.15 4 Eric Johnson. M 1 ■&gt; U»s. butter 6 G. A. Rose, services in orchestra 7 Fk. Quade. 44 lbs. butter tents, 86 doz. cess (a 18 cent&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p032">340 9 Ifi &lt;2 10 9 T. C. Johnson, 12 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 10 C. B. &amp; Q. R. K. freight bill : 14 Adams Express Co.. express charges 14 Geo. Aufdenkamp. 135% lbs. butter @ 85 cents, 27 1-3 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 38 40 38 40 fWm. Grothaus, 72 lbs. butter @ 25 cents. 161/4 doz. eggs (a 18 cents 20 93 20 93 14 Stein Bros., merchandise 5 80 5 BO 14 Rutherford Bros.. 2 flange unions 1 00 iS 14 Rutherford Bros.. 2 flange unions 14 C. W. Jacobs, sharpening mowers 14 C. H. Mansfield, picture molding 14 C. W. Jacobs, sharpening mowers 1 50 14 C. H. Mansfield, picture molding 3 60 3 60 16 International Stock Food Co.. 125 lbs. stock food, 3y 2 doz. poultry food 14 00 16 International Stock Food Co.. 125 lbs. stock food. 3V2 doz. poultry food 16 J. J. Holcombe Mfg. Co.. 1 doz parrafine holders 16 Schmitz &amp; Deines. stationery 16 Jones &amp; Brandies, one burr for buggy axle 16 Jones &amp; Brandies, one burr for buggy axle 17 T. W. Walters, entertainment 17 T. W. Walters, entertainment 10 00 10 00 22 95 17 Sanitary Bedding Co., 2 beds and springs 18 M. W. Baxter, cash adv. butter and egfi 18 B. &amp; M. Co., % on interstate mileage book 17 Sanitary Bedding Co.. 2 beds and springs 22 18 M. W. Baxter, cash adv. butter and eggs 22 M 122 *4 18 B. &amp; M. Co.. ' - on interstate mileage book . M. \Y. B. *J 00 2n no M. W. B {('. S. Palmer. 75% lbs. butter ui 25 cents. 11 lbs. butter (a 22 cents. 7 doz. eggs 18 cents 22 56 r(". S. Palmer. 75% lbs. butter (a 25 cents, 11 lbs. butter (a 22 cents, 7 doz. eggs Ut 18 cents 22 56 W. II. Palmer, 18 doz. egga Ui 18 cents 3 2i 3 24 K \V. II. Palmer. 18 doz. egga ui is rents 90 John Aufdenkamp. 22% &gt;!&gt;*• butter @ 25 20 John Aufdenkamp. 22% lbs. butter (S 25 cents, 65y 2 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 17 41 cents, 65y 2 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 20 H. Schriner, entertainment 20 Mrs. W. O. Clark. 20% lbs. butter @ 25 cents 21 T. A. Shattuck. 8 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 23 Eric Johnson. 138 lbs. butter (a 25 cents. H .S 2(1 II. Schriner, entertainment 6 00 20 Mrs. W. (). Clark. 20% lbs. butter (a 25 cents :: 21 T. A. Shattuck. 8 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 1 44 23 Eric Johnson. 138 lbs. butter fa 25 cents. 23 doz. eggs (a 18 cents 38 64 23 doz. eggs (a 18 cents 38 64 26 G. Hoeffer. 16ij lbs. butter (a 25 cents, it doz. eggs (a 18 cents 5 75 26 G. Hoeffer. 16io lbs. butter (a 25 cents, it doz. eggs (a 18 cents 27 Mrs. Grothen, 258 lbs. butter (a 27 cents. 4:i doz. eggs @ 18 cents 77 40 12 24 28 P. J. Robinson, cash advanced on eggs </seg>
            <seg id="p033">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. INGLJ 341 38 43 31 Stein Bros.. Co, hardware, et 31 Singer Sewing .Machine Co.. needles 31 Wolbaeh &amp; Brack, ti spools thread 31 Schmitz &amp; Deines, stationery 1 Deposited with State Treasurer Balance on hand Total doz. eggs (a 18 cents 4 J. Robinson, circus. 156 tickets (a 2."» cents 7 Adams Express Co.. charges 7 44 J B. &amp; M. R. R. Co., U on interstate mileage book (M. \V. H. ss 9 John Aufdenkamp. 61 doz. eggs (a 18 c..nts Id Mrs. W. A. Cole. 6 doz. e^trs ui 18 cents 11 \V. II. Palmer. 36 doz. efgfi (r/ 1 - 11 Mrs. T. A. Shattoek, ti &lt;loz. eggs (§ I' - ll C. S. Palmer. 38 lbs. butter (r; 25 cent! 11 P. C. Johnson, ti doz. eggs tn 18 cents 11 Wm. (Jrothaus. H2 lbs. butter u/ 25 eenti 11 (ieo. Aut'denkamp. 133 lbs. butter (it 2."&gt; cents. 37 doz. eggi 15 Fk. Quade. 4(1 lbs. batter senta, 75 doz. 1 08 6 4* 1 08 9 50 1 08 20 00 1") W. II. Crutcher, surgical supplies 16 Stein Bros., L r "ni|s as per receipt 16 Schmitz &amp; Deines as per receipt 28 C. s. Palmer. :i(l' . lit*, butter (&lt; 28 Robt. Wright. 117 lbs. butter (a 25 cents. .")1 doz. egtrs (a i&gt; eenta 28 Win. Gn.thaus, 79 lbs. butter (g :&gt;:&gt; eenta, 17 &lt;loz. em fia 18 cent* June 1 E. Einspahr. 50% lb«. butter (a 2.") rents, 105 dot eggs (a 18 mits $ 22 78 1 Fk. Quadt-. 51^ lhs. butter (a 2."&gt; cents. K&gt;4 31 60 IS 8 Mrs. W. (). Clark. 24 lbs. butter (a 25 ft 8 doz. eggs (a 18 cents 9 Eric Johnson. 127 lbs. tetter (a 25 eeata, "&gt;1 doz. egv egps - Hnts </seg>
            <seg id="p034">342 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT £ 18 Wm. Grothaus. 42 1 fc lbs. butter (a 25 cents, 5 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 11 53 18 Sharp &amp; Smith. 3 marshall masks 3 16 18 M. W. Baxter. 1 refrigerator, 30 00 22 Mrs. W. O. Clark. 6 lbs. butter (a 25 cen1 1 50 23 Robt. Wright. 22 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 41 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 12 ■*&gt; 23 Stein Bros., supplies as per receipt 7 11 24 J. B. Cornelius. 30 doz. eggs (a 18 cents 5 4i» 28 M. W. Baxter. 3 R. R. books (a 60 cents 1 B0 28 Stein Bros., shears, clippers, mattresses 14 75 28 Adams Express Co.. express charges 1 00 29 Stein Bros., 3 hog waterers $4.50. 2 mat - tresses $7.00 11 50 29 Stein Bros.. 1U yds. linen @ 98 cents 1 47 18 E. L. Simon, voucher No. 45, paid at Lincoln 26 75 21 M. W. Baxter, voucher No. 46, paid at Lincoln _ 208 90 1 Deposited with State Treasurer _ 948 86 1 Balance on hand _ 200 00 Total | 1.789 02 29 Mrs. W. A. Cole, 10 doz. eggs @ 18 cents $ 1 80 1 H. J. Hauck, board and car fare for patient 3 95 1 Geo. Aufdenkamp, 1021/. lbs. butter (a 25 cents, 2iy 2 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 2!» V&gt; 1 A. B. Cole, 11 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 1 98 1 G. H. Haney &amp; Co., harness repairs 5 15 1 Jesse Gidley. expense to Lincoln and return 3 70 2 C. S. Palmer, 22 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 5y 2 doz. eggs @ 18 cents ti 4!&gt; 6 W. H. Palmer, 21% doz. eggs (a- 18 cents 6 Eric Johnson, 138 lbs. butter (a 25 cents, 39 doz. eggs (w 18 cents 41 52 6 Fk. Quade, 55*4 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 97 doz. eggs (cL 18 cents 31 34 8 J. Aufdenkamp, 33 1 2 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 60 doz. (a) 18 cents 19 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. INGLESIDE 343 12 T. A. Shattuck. 7y 2 doz. e{ 1 35 12 A. H. Cole, 25 lbs. butter (a 25 cent* l»f doz. egga (a 18 cents 12 Mrs. \Y. &lt;). Clark, 11 doz. egi: - cents 1 98 Mrs. Grothen. 4441- lbs. butter (a 27 cents, 85 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 135 31 1") Adams Express Co., express charts 46 15 American Express Co.. express charges 46 Mrs. Wm. Grothaus, 107 lbs. butter (a 25 cents, 36 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 33 23 16 W. H. Palmer, 21 doz. ecgt &lt;fl 18 centa 3 78 20 Fk. Quade, 31 lbs. butter (§ 25 cents. 27 doz. eggs (u) 18 cents 17 47 21 New York Clipper, advertising 2 50 21 J. Cornelius, 7% doz. eggs (5 !*• eenta 1 33 22 J. Aufdenkarap, 29 lbs. butter (a 2~&gt; 49 doz. eggs @ 18 cents cents. 16 07 22 C. S. Palmer, 35y 2 lb. butter (n SS etmA doz. eggs @ 18 cents 10 49 C. S. Palmer, 35y 2 lb. butter Ui IS cent doz. eggs @ 18 cents 10 49 22 M. W. Baxter, cash adv. 12 lbs. butter @ 25 cents 3 00 M. W. Baxter, cash adv. 12 lbs. butter @ 25 cents 3 00 23 C. Pierson, 30 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 5 40 23 C. Pierson, 30 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 5 40 23 W. 0. Clark. 1") doz. eggs @ 18 cents 2 70 23 W. 0. Clark, 15 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 2 70 23 Geo. Aufdenkamp, 73 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 49 doz. eggs @ 18 cents J7 "7 23 Geo. Aufdenkamp, 73 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 49 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 27 "7 28 Eric Johnson. 12(1'^ lbs. butter (a 2."&gt; rents. 42 doz. eggs @ 18 cents, 4 bu. applet 28 Eric Johnson, 120V 2 lbs. butter (3 25 cents $1.00 41 K* 28 J. D. Cornelius, 65 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 11 70 29 F. C. Johnson, 19% doz. eggs (a 18 een1 29 Mrs. Grothem, 121 lbs. butter (a 27. S doz. eggs @ 18 cents 34 1 1 30 W. H. Palmer, 20V;, doz. eggs (&lt;i 18 cuts 3 69 30 Robt. Wright. 41^ doz. . 18 cents 7 47 30 Wm. Grothaus. 47 lbs. butter © 25 cents, lti doz. eggs @ 18 cents 14 64 30 C. Pierson, 16 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 27 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 8 86 30 J. D. Mfltthews, voucher 47 60 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">344 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT :50 Rex Craighead, voucher No. 48 F. J. Morgan, voucher No. 4!&gt; .50 Total + 736 31 1 Singer Sewing Machine Co., repairs 1 John E. Smith, labor 1 65 2 50 1 W. E. Harper, entertainment 20 00 4 J. Cornelius. 5% doz. eggs @ 18 cents 4 Mrs. W. A. Cole, 10V 2 doz. eggs @ 18 cents. W iy% lbs. chicks (a 14 cents 2 94 6 Wm. Grothen, 52% lbs. butter @ 27 cents, 10 doz. eggs @ 15 cents 15 97 6 C. Pearson, 19 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 21 doz eggs @ 18 cents 8 53 6 Geo. Aufdenkamp, 62 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 38 doz. eggs (a 18 cents. 1 ."&gt;!.. lbs. chicks (a) 15 cents 24 65 Freight charges. St. J. &amp; G. I i 10 Fk. Quade. 48 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 53 doz. eggs (5 18 cents. 40 doz. eggs (a 15 cents 12 Cecil F. Havcrly. entertainment 16 C. S. Palmer. 53 lbs. butter (§ 25 cents. 8 doz. eggs @ 15 cents. T'^doz eggs @ 18 eeati v: I 1 - R. W. Adams. 3 doz. Avatermelons 19 C. B. &amp; Q. R. R.. 3 freight bills 1 77 1!( Sehmiti «t Deines, stationery li 19 C. Pierson. 21 lbs. butter (a 25 cents 20 W'm. Grothaus. To lbs. butter (g 25 cents. 17 doz. 1") cents. 12 doz. eg| 18 cents, ss lb. chicks (a 13 cent! 2d Singer Sewing Machine Co., repairs 22 V. E. (jaugwisli. return of patient 5 imi 22 W. Kister. auto service •)•) 22 Henry Kister. blacksmith work Henry Kister. blacksmith work Schmitz &amp;. Deines. stationery 22 Schmitz &amp; Deines. stationery •)■&gt; 23 Lloyd Tracey 3% bu. apples (a $1.00. 24 Stein Bros.. 2 kettles, and 120 bolts 2:&lt; Lloyd Traeey 3% bu. apples 24 Stein Bros.. 2 kettles, and 120 bo 2o F. ( ). Phipns. entertainment </seg>
            <seg id="p037">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. INGLESIDE 345 ■&gt; i &gt; i ■&gt; i &gt; i ) ,() ,1) 5(1 K 111 17 in 2 50 J. B. Cornelius. 45 doz. eggs @ 15 cents Wm. Huston, detaining escaped patient Mrs. W. O. Clark, 11 doz. eggs @ 15 cents Geo. Aufdenkamp. 93 lbs. butter (a 25 cents. Express charges on moving picture ma - c'nine C. S. Palmer, 25 lbs. butter Ui 2.~&gt; eeni doz. eggs (a 15 cents. 62 lb. chicks @ 12V 2 cents M. W. Baxter. 4 electric fans Beatty Baum Chemical Co., Balance carried forward 281 10 A. L. Rickel. enterainment J. H. Hnagland. draracc 6 00 E. &lt;i. Shattuck. return of patient A. Cole, 18V-; dox. eggs 18 cents \V. F. Karney. entertaintmeni L Gidley, 15Va lb«. bees wax @ 30 cents Erie Johnson, lt&gt;:5 lbs. butter (a 25 eenti 18 &lt; 25 stein Bros.. 6 jardiners, $6."&gt;:}, 6 jardiners $4.69. 2 creamers |7.00 36 doz. eggs (a 15 cents Total 1 57 Fk. Qoade, 1"&gt;'- lbs. butter (a 25 rents, 83 doz. eggs (a 15 cents. ( !Mrs. &lt;i rot ha in. 2:58 lbs. butter (a 27 r.-nts, 8 doz. eggs (a 15 eenti \ r. T?ifkpl pntprainment .1. C. Swartz. »gt. 1,000 mile R. R. hook fM. W. B. \Vm. (irothaus. W - 2 l tls - butter (a 2.~&gt; eents, Id doz. eggi Ui IS cents doz. etrtrs (a 15 cents 12 Geo. Aufdenkamp, 48 lbs. butter Ui 2."&gt; eenta 2'&lt; doz. ftrtrs (n 1 - L.I. Gidley, 30 Lbs. honey (a 12% eeata Geo. Aufdenkamp, 21 u lbs. batter (» 28 cents, 6 dor. eees (3 20 cents Wolhaeh &amp; Hradi 2 doz silku </seg>
            <seg id="p038">346 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 17 Singer Sewing Machine Co.. repairs 1 80 17 J. W. Lehr, agent 1,000 mile R. R. book (J. Gidley 20 00 19 A. B. Dick Co., 2 1 - doz. mimeograph pads 1 4&lt;&gt; 19 Kansas City Paper house, 2 bolts manila paper 2 28 20 Mansfield Glass Co.. i •_, gal. paint and var- nish remover 1 25 21 Fk. Quadt\ 27% lbs. butter @ 25 cents. 16 lbs. butter (a 28 cents.. 39 doz. egi; 18 cents. 22 doz. eggs (5 22 cents 5 21 J. Cornelius. 18 doz. eggs (o 22 cents 3 96 21 Schmitz &amp; Deines, stationery _ 7 15 21 Stein Bros., axle grease, crockery, etc.. as per bill _ 22 W. H. Palmer, 19y 2 doz. eggs (a 15 cents, 18 doz. eggs (a 22 cents 6 89 22 Aug. Kern, traveling expenses. Omaha 5 00 22 Mrs. W. A. Cole. 34 doz. eggs (a 22 cents 7 4S 22 J. W. Cole, return of patient 22 C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. freight charges on 3 bills 24 Mrs. Grothen. 100 lbs. butter (5 27 cents. 42i ., ib s . butter @ 30 cents. 12 doz. eggs @ 22 cents, 11 doz. eggs @ 18 cents 44 A~ 24 Wm. Grothaus, 23y 2 lbs. butter @ 25 cents, 42 lbs. butter @ 28 cents. 12 doz. eggs (a 22 cents, 80 lbs. chicks (a 13 cent 30 67 24 W. Catron, 15 bu. apples (a 75 cents 11 25 27 W. H. Palmer, 11 doz. eggs @ 22 cents 2 42 29 Stein Bros., goods as per bill 25 68 29 Haynes Bros.. 5 paint brushes 2 70 29 C. B. &amp; Q. R. R.. charges on 2 freight bills 4 87 14 Thos. Shattuck. voucher No. 54 500 00 15 F. J. Morgan, voucher Xo. "&gt;.") 60 00 15 Rex Craighead, voucher Xo. 56 60 00 15 F. C. Baldwin, voucher Xo. ."&gt;7 60 00 15 J. D. Matthews, voucher Xo. 58 60 00 Balance carried forward 109 ~- * 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">HOSPITAL, FOR INSANE. INGLESIDE 347 Oct. 19 Truax Greene &amp; Co., for 1 truss ._$ l 98 • 1 Carl Fischer. 4 quint paper Ui 17 cents. 68 Carl Fischer. 4 quint paper (a 17 cents M.rs. O. Hotter, 24 lbs. butter (w 30 cents, 9 68 1 M.rs. G. Ilolfer. 24 lbs. butter @ 30 cents, 9 doz. eggs (a 22 cents 9 18 I Mrs. \Y. A. Coli". .V., doz. eggs in 22 cents, 52 lbs. chicks (a 12 cents 7 45 3 Mrs. W. A. Cole. .V., doz. eggs (a 22 cents, ■"•2 lhs. chicks (a 12 cent- 7 45 3 ti 3 M. O'.Meara. 5 kraut barrels 3 75 If. O'Meara. 5 kraut barrels 6 Stein Bros.. 132 yds curtains (a ."&gt;&lt;&gt; cents 66 00 Stein Bros.. 132 yds curtains (a .")() c. &gt; Mrs. Grothen. !&gt;&lt;&gt;i._&gt; lbs. butter (a 30 cents, 9 66 00 7 Mrs. firothen. 90% lbs. butter @ 30 cents, 9 t diiz. eggs (a 24 cents 29 31 doz. eggs (a 24 cents 29 31 v &lt;J. \Y. Lchr. agent. 1 expren package 30 s G. W. Lehr, agent. 1 express package G. W. Lehr, agent, freight charge- A. H. Brooks, exprm 30 8 G. W. Lehr, agent, freight charges 1 74 1 74 H 8 A. H. Brooks, exp 85 8 F. C. Johnson, 2&lt;) bu. apples @ 50 cents, 12 do/., eggl (a 18 eellts 12 16 8 II. 8. Brown &amp; Co., electrical supplies 8 85 8 L. W. Woohvorth &amp; Co., 1 doz. hammer&gt; 1 20 12 A. B. Cole. 15 lbs. butter (a 30 cents 4 50 12 12 N. C. Williams. 10 lbs. butter (a 30 rents 3 15 12 13 F. Quade. :i9U lbs. butter (a 30 cents, 12 n doz. eggs (a 24 cents, 81 doz. eggs @ 22 cents 21 99 21 99 13 G. W. Lepold. 25 His. but? ")i/ 2 doz. eggs (a 24 cents 8 82 13 Mrs. C. II ''j lbs. butter (a- 30 cents, 7% doz. eggs (a 24 cents 10 85 Mrs. C. Hoefer, 29% ll)s. butter (g 30 cents, 7 1 , doz. eggs (a 24 cent- 10 85 13 J. B. Cornelius, 15 doz. eggs (a 22 cents, 15 13 J. B. Cornelius. 1") doz. eggs @ 22 cents, 15 doz. eggs (a 24 cents doz. eggs (a 24 cents 6 90 6 90 14 F. V. Nash. 21."&gt; lbs. chicks (a 12 cents 25 80 F. V. Xash. 215 lbs. chicks (a 12 cents B«y, 22 lbs. chicks (a 11 cents H. I'techt. 24 lbs. butter Ui 30 &lt;-ents Mrs. Grothen, W y» lbs. butter (a 30 cents 25 80 14 14 L. S. Bay. 22 lbs. chicks (a 11 eestl 2 51 14 20 H. Dteeht, 24 lbs. butter (a 30 cents 7 20 2ii 21 Mrs. Grothen, !&gt;* '. lbs. butter (a 30 cents HH lbs. chicks Ui 12 cents &gt;i 20 Jesse (Jidley. expenses trip to Omaha and re - turn _ _ 6 80 6 -0 21 C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. for mileage book 20 00 20 00 22 A. B. Cole. 67% lbs. chicks (a 11 cents, 11 doz. eggl ('/ 24 cents 10 08 10 08 22 E. Wright, 15 do* egga w 25 12 doz. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 348 22 W. II. Palmer. 10 dox. eggs (a 2."&gt; cents 22 Mrs. G. Hoefer, 11 lbs. butter Ut 30 eenti doz. eggs ui 25 rents % 4 .I") 4 55 28 Win. Grathaus. 12:5 lbs. butter (a 30 cents. 4 Win. Grathaus. 12:5 lbs. butter Ui :!() cents. 4 doz. end (" 25 cents, in doz. ef cents. 7 1 -. doz. eggs (a 22 cents doz. e^tr* (" 25 cents, in doz. . 24 cents, 7 1 - doz. egg* (&lt;i 22 cents 44 65 44 65 29 M. I'teeht. 17 lbs. butter (a 30 cents. 2 doz. eggs U/ 2.") cents 5 73 29 If. I'techt. 17 ll)s. butter Ui 30 cents. 2 doz. eggs (&lt;/ 2.") cents 6 90 I] X. ('. Williams. 23 lbs. butter (a 30 cents 6 90 \. ('. Williams. 23 lbs. butter (a HO cents 31 :*1 31 Mrs. 0. Hoefer, 14 lbs. butter Ut 30 cents. 2 Mrs. G. Iloefer. 14 lbs. butter (a 30 cents. 2 doz. eggs (§ 25 rents doz. eggs (&lt;•/ 2.") cents 4 B5 4 85 11 T. A. Shiittuck. 13 gill. Moor's Stock Remedy (a $1.50 19 5C 19 50 31 Qeo. Aofdenksmp, s.ji., lhs. butter (S) 30 Aufdenkamp. S:ji 2 lbs. butter (§ :&lt;() cents. 5 dnz. eggl @ 22 cents. 5 doz. eggs _'•") cents. 10 doz. eggs @ 24 cent- 29 mi 30 W. H. Swanaon. voucher No. 60 200 0(1 30 G. P. O'Meara. voucher No. SI Adam Lichtenberp. voucher No. 62 4.". 00 30 61 50 30 Rex Craighead. voucher No. 63 60 00 30 J. D. Matthews, voucher No. 64 60 00 30 F. J. Morgan, voucher No. 65 Burroughs Adding Machine Co., voucher No 60 00 30 66 185 00 200 00 758 46 31 Balance carried forward :*i Deposited with State Treasurer Total $ 2,066 46 2 Jas. McCleery, return of patient $ :&gt; 00 2 Correct error of two credits of cash warrant No. 1.42.") credited April 8. 1910. in full. $49.35, and in part to bal. acct. of March 1!UO $45.39 45 :W 2 J Giiilpv 40 lhs hnnev Ui 121., r . Pn ts 5 00 J. Gidley, 40 lbs. honey (a 12y 2 centa 10 Mrs. J. Iloefer. 13 lbs. butter Ui 30 cents 3 90 10 H. If. Alexander, tuning piano, etc. 7 00 11 Mrs. Grothen. 177% lbs. butter (a 30 cents 53 25 12 Mrs. Grothaus. 85 lbs. butter {a 10 cents. 260 lbs. chicks (a 12 rents 56 70 \filfp O'MpnrH 4 lcraiit barrels 4 ''** </seg>
            <seg id="p041">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. INGLESIDE 349 De 13 A. B. Cole, 2?S ll)s. butter Ui 30 cents. !• doz. cents, 12 doz. eggs (a 24 cents, 191 lbs chicks (a 1 1 cents 12 90 18 M. Utecht, 3Hi lbs. butter (a 30 cents 21 ■]. AufdenJuunp, 4:5 lbs. butter (a 30 cents 22 ('. W. Leopold. 26% lbs. butter (a 30 eei 22 American Express Co., express on 4 crates 7 95 chick 22 Stein Bros., good as per receipt 22 C. D. Hoff, 2 gasoline tank.s 22 Singer Sewing Machine Co., repairs 29 55 JS 22 Mrs. E. A. St. John, 5,750 cabbage plants (a) 30 cents 22 C. F. Hogg. 58 lbs. butter (a 30 cents, 1 24 M 26 Carl Gidley, 486 lbs. chicks (a 10 cents.... 26 C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. 2.000 mileage book (M. W. B. 40 00 26 H. S. Brown &amp; Co.. electrical supplies 26 If. I'teeht. 19' ._. lbs. butter 30 cents 30 Stein Bros. ■ spuons. gravy beater, churn, etc 30 Schmitz &amp; Deines. drugs, stationery 30 C. B. &amp; Q. li. H.. 6 freight bills 30 .Mrs. &lt;i. Hoefer. 32 lbs. butter (n 30 cents 30 C. W. Leopold, 16% lbs. butter ui 30 cents 20 Rex. Craighead. voucher No. b'T 60 00 20 P. J. Morgan, voucher No. I 20 J. I). Matthews, voucher No. 69 60 00 I if) 00 1 Balance on hand 76 16 Total (a 28 cents, '20 doz. eggs 18 Robt. Wright. 29 lbs. butter (a 30 mb1 (1OZ. ffJiTS Ul 2."&gt; Ct'Ilt^ 22 J. J. Poore. 130 squash egga ui $7.50 22 Wm. (irothaus. ."&gt;4 lbs. butter (a 30 cents. 5 doz. eRffa (a 2.") rents 22 Schmitz &amp; Deines. stationery </seg>
            <seg id="p042">350 CASH RECAPITULATION By cash on hand Dec. 1. 1908. in State Tr asury Balance on hand. Warrants received from State Treasurer Cash from other sources Total Expended by voucher Expended in cash in State Treasury Cash on hand to carry to December account Total $22,414 59 JESSE GIDLEY $ 1U7 78 610 54 ,$ 5,636 74 16,059 53 $22,414 59 $ 5,636 74 13,540 69 3,161 00 76 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE 351 STEWARD'S CASH REPORT rpts and Disbursements for the Biennial Peroid Ending No - vember 30, 1910. Receipts. 1908 1 1 To balance cash on hand $ 107 78 Paul McDill. 4 old razors 2 00 12 E. Nathan. 2.890 lbs. old iron 7 22 Itf Kauf &amp; Rindesacher, 2,591 lbs. hides 259 10 17 M. Davenport, difference in pay roll 1 93 17 Alma Davenport, difference in pay roll 1 67 24 John Cornelius, slop from Dec. 20 to Jan. 20 10 00 Sub Total •&gt; Repayment warrant X Repayment warrants N 63 90 &gt;. S47 to 853 inclusive 319 08 9 Total 1909 1 Balancf on hand 18 Austin Ryan, old slatf 18 Henry Sehriner, difference in Henry Sehriner, difference in pay roll Emma Zander, difference in pay roll 18 Emma Zand&lt;&gt;r. difference in p; 18 28 Kauf &amp; Rinderspacher. 1,928 1 28 Kauf &amp; Rinderspacher. 1,923 lbs. hides Sub Total Sub Total 16 Repayment warrant No. 923 16 Repayment warrant No. 921 Repayment warrant No. 921 to 922 and !&gt;24 to 928 243 73 Total $ 61") 74 fash received from Geo. W. James retiring Steward $ 121 95 Geo. B. Cornelius, swill for February Rudge &amp; Guenzel, freight bill 4 4 6 Ijibbie Garrison, lard barrel E. Nathan, bones for 1 year 12 50 11 27 Arthur Blake. 1.99.") lbs. hides at $10.50 209 47 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">352 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 11 Repayment warrant No 11 Repayment warrant No 11 Repayment warrant No. 988 49 73 989 15 00 990 to 996 inclusive 373 41 Total .$ 793 20 1 Balance on hand .$ 84 79 i John B. Cornelius, swill for March 6 Twenty head cattle. South Omaha, (con - demned) U J. 1'. Rafter, check No. 977 surplus pay roll 13 J. P. Rafter, check No. 138 surplus pay roll 22 Twenty-three head cattle, south Omaha (con- ."&gt; no demned 25 J. R. Holmes, load kindling Suh Total 849 ti4 10 Repayment warrant N 1,007, 1,008, KM)9 995 51 Total Apr. 1 Blanee on hand. 1 Austin Hyan. 1 hog 1 John Cornelius, .swill for April 8 For 9,284 lbs. hogs a1 16.20, South 1") 11 1-3 bu. parsnips Ui ■"&gt;(• cents 2 1") 14 •&gt;;, lu 00 Omaha 57f 5 65 1 John Cornelius, swill for April 575 tin 1") 11 1-3 bu. parsnips (5 50 cents 2-i Austin Ryan, load kindling ;,n 23 E. Nathan, old iron 13 60 23 E. Nathan, old iron 13 tin 27* l&gt;;, 900 tin 21 2,650 lbs. hides (a #10.50 27s 25 Sub Total I 900 tin 26 Repayment warrant Nob. 1,032 to 1,036 in - clusive s ]:{ t ; is Total $ l f 036 7&gt; lt&gt; Repayment warrant Nob. 1,032 to 1,036 in - clusive 136 1&gt; Total May 1 Balance on hand | 200 00 1 John Cornelius, swill for -May 10 on 1 11 2-'l bu. parsnips !l 4.", - 1,458 lbs. hides at $11.50 HIT fiT Total &gt; 387 12 1 Balance on hand ■'on nil 1 John Cornelius, swill for 1 1 1 2-3 bu. parsnips 1,458 lbs. hides at .+ 11 . .M •iv 10 00 I 4.") ■)O Hm tii 387 12 June 1 Balance mi hand I 200 "7 :: </seg>
            <seg id="p045">11 South Omaha, 1 ear ho;.' 17 Seth Marsh, load kindling Total 1 Balance on hand 2 For hides 2 Fred Blake, error on hogs 3 John B. Cornelius, swill for July 15 R. C. Allen, for feit tragei 15 Lewis Cremeans, forfeit wages 15 R. L.. Hubbard. forfeit wage* 1") C. W. Fleming, forfeit wagea 17 1,230 lbs. hides, at $13.50 4 76 Ititi 0a rotal 1 I Maine on hand ■i John B. Cornelius, swill 17 E. Nathan, old rubber. 17 934 lbs. hides Ui 12 cent 17 E. Nathan, old copper 17 E. Nathan, old rubber for August 112 08 :• 2~&gt; E. Nathan, old bras 25 E. Nathan, old iron 21 Ke, 152 l 1^ John 1&gt;. Cornelius, swill for September 28 John B. Cornelius, kindling $1.50. old bbl $1 &gt;tal 16 Repayment warrant No. 1,153 Total ul&gt; Total •nifiit warrant No. 1 Sept. 20 -I. Helms, kindling 21 1,454 lbs. hides (t •_'4 Seth March, kindling </seg>
            <seg id="p046">354 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 30 1,604 lbs. hides (5 +12.7.") 2(i4 51 Sub Total 200 (mi Repayment warrant N&lt; 1 203 18 Total 1 Balance on hand $ 113 89 John B. Cornelius, for swill 1 1 E. Nathan, 7(K) lbs. rajrs at 25 c nts 1 75 12 .]. P. Rafter for forfeit of Ann on wa a Mitehean 4 26 Setli Marsh, kindlin 50 18 19 625 lbs. hid' 12.7.") 79 68 Sub Total 204 08 168 66 9 Repayment warrant No. 1 •&gt; 14 Total 1 Balance on hand John B. Cornelius, swill E. Nathan, old iron E. Xathan. old iron 1,711 lbs. hides (a 11 c€ for Dei ml 4 p i&lt; 10 28 7 25 31 188 21 287 77 168 03 nt Sub Total Repayment warrant No. •) 2.". 1 ')] Total 1910 Balance on hand E. Nathan, old ra^s E. Xathan. old iron Nebraska Mercantile C 1 1(1 21 22 bv be rror vouc r &gt; No. 7 Sul) Total 15 Repayment warrant No. 1 2 33 Total $ 473 84 1 Balance on hand $ 133 41 South Omaha. 22 head cows (condemned 1 4 Will F Shav 1 bull calf </seg>
            <seg id="p047">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE 355 E. Xathan. bonei Thrasher for coal J. D. Cornelius, load kindling 3 00 0 9 20 1 50 Hastings Foundry, old E. Xathan. old bra- - 1,589 lbs. hides (a $10.25 2.140 lbs. hides (a *10.2r&gt; 34 98 iron 79 as ) 2* Sub Total Part repayment warrant No. 1 ,425 to h il &gt;* lect Cash fund warrant 1.42.") t Car load bogs, South On i) bal *ha Mar ■ h a&lt; r 1,603 11 s 1,65&lt; Total $ 20o imi 1 1 Balance on hand 191 1 A. Spellman, bones to Jan. 1st 1.720 lbs. hides Ui 10% centi 42 head cattle. South Omaha 8 no &lt; — - — "^ 1 •'" 2*; Total Balance on hand ■&gt; South Omaha, 62 hc&gt;_ J. Helms, kindling EL L. Simon. tl:{ meals (ft 9 15 20 cents 18 Sub Total 18 Repayment warrant, paid at Lincoln v uch at Lincoln v uch 1,788 02 Total 1 \i I i t 1 .* 656 68 | 172 24 3 40 Total 1 Balance on hand 7 E. N'athan, old iron 12 Hastings Foundry, r Total . Cornelius, old bed er No. 45 21 Repayment warrant, paid er Xo. 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">356 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 1 1 1.690 lhs. hidi's (a &gt; l -j cents Peters &amp; Edholm. part on Austin Ryan. bbl. of oil Gallon gasoline Id boiler 11 11 Charge for telephone Julia Boyle, difference in Seth Marsh, old lumber 14 14 av roll 30 10 00 Sub Total 1 Repayment warrant No. Repayment warrant No, Repayment warrant No, Repayment warrant Xo. 1.625 1 1 1626 1627 till (Ml 9 1 03 to bal Total 1 16 meals, plumbers (5 20 :-ents 6 6 6 a John Cornelius. 1 bull calf J. McBride. 8 meals (n 2n eent John Cornelius, kindling L. W. Pomerene Co.. eheek for 68 m 20 ct-nts als (a 26 942 lbs. hides (a 9U eent Sub Total 240 47 40 00 U Repayment warrant. Xo. Repayment warrant Xo. 1 Repayment warrant. No. 1.634 635 9 9 281 10 200 00 1.702 Total 1 Balance on hand 3 Hastings Foundry, old iron Hasting! foundry, old rags o Oliver Lumber Co., eement sacks Peter Pekel, 17 meals (a 2'i c.-nts Austin Ryan. 1 bbl. oil nta Austin Ryan. 25 gal. turpentine (a 75 cent John Heiser, 1 cow o 10 40 14 14 14 21 15 Carpenters. 44 meals (a 20 cen 15 1.184 lbs. hides (a 8H cent^ </seg>
            <seg id="p049">0 Sub Total 14 Repayment warrant. No 25 Repayment warrant. X&lt; 744 1 1.781 1,778 t 1 mmi to r jimbur sit fund 1,331 10 in Nov. 1 Balance nn hand 1 bull .-alf rms. 1 cow 2:! Whitebreast &lt; 'ual &amp; Lumt it ( o.. 1 car p 20 Re To G 22 Old sacks. 27 John Heiaer, 1 eow elusive 25 Repayment warrant. N 1 Total Balance on hand 10 1,576 ll.s. hid- 15 &lt;)\t\ PiltTv 20 2 car« condemned cattle, Smith Omaha 14^ 1,138 15 Sob Total 1-S Repayment warrant. No*. 1814 to 1820 1 E. Fort, 1 Wm. II 1.749 lbs. hid sents Total 07 "&gt;4 nt warrant. No*. l.!»4!t to 1.951 in- ]&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p050">358 MONTHLY ADMISSION OF PATIENTS Male Female Total inber. January. February, March, ' 1!M)S 18 11 29 1 !»()!» 20 l'IMII 13 i 1909 17 i I l!t(»!t 4 11 i 190! I 19 I 1909 13 1909 i) 14 August. 1909 Id in 9 I ember &gt;ber. ember ?mber. lary. ruary. 1909 4 s lllll'l i 1909 !l •&gt; 11 1909 14 6 20 1910 17 10 27 liHn s \ I l!M(i 4 4 I 12 9 4 ■ &gt; 16 Auiriist. Hi 12 E ember ber. ti 4 11 raber I) 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">359 RESIDENCE OF PATIENTS, BY CO1 Male Adams 1 •"&gt; Female Total 23 Boone ... 5 2 7 Buffalo 1§ - 27 4 6 a,,,,- 2 3 Cheyenne 1 1 2 cu, a 10 Carter 11 8 19 Dawei 1 0 1 Dawson 12 7 19 Dun.lv 2 it 2 Fillmore •&gt; 2 7 Franklin + :i 7 Frontier 2 2 4 Furnas •' 4 9 Garden 2 Seld 2 0 2 per - 1 ley () 1 1 Hall. » 15 Hamilton 10 i) 10 Harbin 4 12 Hayea •* 1 ."&gt; Hitchcock 3 2 5 Honker 1 0 1 Howard ~ :i Hi Jefferson 14 14 28 Kearney 6 ■1 9 Kimball 4 1 .") Lancaster 1 ii 1 Lincoln 4 3 .7 Logan 1 1 ci — Merriek 4 ■_&gt; Merrill 1 i) 1 Nance « 10 Nuekolls </seg>
            <seg id="p052">360 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT Phelps 4 8 : 11 1 Red Willow Saline i .) 0 1 1 Scottebluff Seward 1 1 2 3 0 1 Sherman Thayer . Valley 3 !) 9 6 •1 4 2 1:5 4 W.bster Wheeler 4 11 i 0 1 1 10 11 21 261 153 414 AGE OF PATIENTS WHEN DECLARED INSANE Years Male Female Total Eeen 10-20 een 20-30 een 30-40 een 40-50 een 50-60 een 60-70 een 70-80 een 80-90 een 90-95 it 3 12 66 32 98 V2 97 .).) 37 20 :&gt;! :*1 99 53 :51 14 ■ 21 12 !) 0 i 1 i 1 1 (I I'nknown 0 Total .261 153 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE 361 NATIVITY OP PATIENTS Malt- Female American Alabama Colorado Illinois lit 1!» 1 1 0 o 3 3 2i) Id 24 1:5 Indiana Iowa 6 6 3 •&gt; Kansas 6 4 ; Kentucky If mine 0 9 Ksaehusetts higan 9 4 9 1 1 .Missouri Nebraska 6 ' 44 IK 9. •&gt; New Hampshire New Jersey (I 1 New York 11 s 3 Eth Carolina nsylvania 0 3 3 lti K 14 21 I Tennt'sse* Texai 1 1 1 1 (i 1 Vermont 1 West Virginia Virginia 9 o •&gt; 0 Wisconsin 6 13 i </seg>
            <seg id="p054">362 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT ale Total ; i ti 1 ti i 1 I ! &gt; &gt; 1!. ! .»:. NATIVITY OF PATIENTS (Foreignborn) Male Fern* tria Belgian Hohemia ada China .... 4 (I 1 1 i 0 :\ (» 4 3 1 Denmark England uany ■&gt; 1 6 30 Id 1 0 4 0 (I ;;;:r" .) i Mexico Norway i •) it 9 i i .) land Sw.-den Assyria 3 o 12 i 1 1 0 o Btzerland mown l:* 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">363 L W. Barber Male 4 Female 0 Total Blacksmith ■&gt; 0 Bookkeeper 1 0 Butcher 1 0 ( 'arpenter _ ti II Clerk 1 ( 'oal miner 2 CM 2 Domestic i) 17 Dressmaker {i 2 Kutrineer 1 o Farmer 142 ii &lt; iardener 1 Groeer 1 Harnessmaker •&gt; Housekeeper 11 :&lt; per 32 0 Landlord 1 I) Laundress i) 1 Liveryman 1 Mail carrier 1 Mechanic •&gt; Musician 1 n No occupation 27 14 Painter 2 it Pharmacist 1 Physician 1 ii Preacher 1 0 Printer ■&gt; Prostitute 1 Ranch hand 2 0 nek owner :* 0 Restaurant keei per 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">364 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT x\. x\. Is borer 1* 0 R. R. station agent 10 1 Saleslady _ 0 1 1 Salesman 2 0 I Saloonkeeper 10 1 '&lt;&gt;1 teacher 1 2 ■5 Stonemason 2 0 2 ographer 0 2 9 Student 2 0 2 Switchman _ 10 1 Til known :i 0 -i Welldigger 2 0 I Total 261 153 CIVIL CONDITION OF PATIENTS Male Female Total Divorced Married Sin^l, 1 i * 101 S 85 119 36 Bowed nown 27 28 6 ■i Total 261 153 RELIGION OF PATIENTS Male Female Total 25 17 41' Catholics testants religion 142 ins 74 25 Unknown 20 8 2:{ Total 261 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">365 EDUCATION OF PATIENTS Business Colic College Ili&lt;_'h schoi Illiterate Poor l"n know FORMS OF DISEASE OF PATIENTS Mai. rYw u &lt; lerebral Svphili •&gt; •» n 1 tfusional Insanity piwt-operativi icntia. Alcoholic ii Dementia, Epileptic Dementia, Paralytic Dementia, Partial Dementia, Precox Dementia, Primary Dementia Secondary Dementia, Senile ■&gt; 1 ii N » • &gt; • &gt; 12 2fl 1 13 :»4 25 tcntia. Senile with delirium epsy 0 It I I | I j 1 1 1 1 ■ \ n •i Imliecilitv s (I s tnity. Circular nity. Delusional nity. Epilepti*' nity, Hallucinatory •) I 0 * 4 12 8 1 1 o 1T( s "" Total T.»t .1 AliMilmli </seg>
            <seg id="p058">366 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT Insanity, maniac-depressive Insanity, Post-typhoidal Kleptomania, with dementia Mania, Acute • ) ! 25 Kia, Acute-furious ia. Chronic 3 27 Mania Hysterical Mania Recurrent Mania Religious Mania Simple Mania Suicidal Melancholia Acute Melancholia Aggitata Melancholia Attonita Melancholia Chronic Melancholia Delusional Melancholia Hallucinatory Melancholia Hypoehondriaeal Melancholia Suhacute 0 :! :-! s i:&lt; .» 1(1 .) ■&gt; (i 13 13 (i o 21 2(1 41 3 0 0 0 3 1 1 17 12 0 14 Id 9 9. 1 :{ it; (i 4 S Not insane Paranoia i Paresis ianoia Sexualis terior Sclerosis choses Alcoholic choses Epileptic choses Neurasthenic ! li 3 9 : Kchoses Presenile delusional choses Traumatic (I 3 1 4 Senility 1 () 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. INGLESIDK 367 HEREDITARY INFLUENCES Male Female S Aunt insane 3 li 0 6 ,) ] 1 1 Kts (2), Brother (1), insane t and eousin insane 1 - Brother insane •&gt; •&gt; ■&gt; Kher and sister insane her tubercular 0 I) 0 .5 ! Brother imbecile 1 Kher insane (1), brother imbecile (1 her and aunt insane 1 1 o 0 Kin epileptic, 2nd cousin insane in insane 0 1 1 •) i 1 Cousins (2) insane Father insane .5 1 3 1 1 Bher and grandfather insane her tubercular li :} .5 6 11 Father intemperate Father epileptic ,) 1 1 •&gt; 1 1 Father epileptic, sister insane 0 :{ Father paralytic it l I her chronic pluml&gt;ism her apoplectic her intemperate, brothers (2i in perate her intemperate, sister insane her intemperate, sister epilpetie 1 o ■2 II I Father apoplectic Father intemperate, brothers (S) intem- 0 1 1 perate 1 1 9, Father intemperate, sister insane li 1 1 0 1 1 Father intemperate, uncle insane 0 1 1 Father intemperate, mother insane Father and mother intemperate, mother Oil insane (I 1 1 Father intemperate, uncle epileptic Father intemperate, grandmother insane 0 1 1 2 0-' Father and aunt insane n 1 1 Father and brother insane Father, uncle and aunt insane </seg>
            <seg id="p060">368 IASD COMMISSIONERS REPORT Father and grandparents intemperate o 1 1 rer and mother blood relations, cousins (2) insane 1 o 1 Father Careinoma. mother tubercular 0 1 Father paralytic, brother insane 1 1 (I Father tubercular, son insane (I 1 1 1 1 Father and mother blood relations 1 :-; Father and mother tubercular 1 Father and mother diabetic 1 ! II 0 Father suicide, sisters (2) insane 1 ther. uncles (2 aunts 2 inaan&lt; grandfather, mother, sister* brothers (2) tubercular 1 0 1 Father's relatives intemperate, mother's relatives tubercular 1 0 0 0 (I ! Grandfather and uncle insane 1 Grandfather intemperate 3 ,1 Grandfather insane I I Father intemperate, mother tubercular. uncle insane and suicide 1 0 ; Grandmother tubercular 1 Grandmother tubercular, uncle scrofu- lous 1 0 0 ! Grandfather intemperate and paralytic 1 Grandparents blood relation. aunts scrofulous 1 0 o ! Grandfather intemperate mid paralytic 1 Grandparents blood relation. aunts scrofulous 1 o 0 0 i Grandparents intemperate 1 Greatgrandfather insane 1 .Mother insane H i i Mother tubercular 4 0 4 Mother suicide ] 0 i Mother insane and tubercular 1 0 Mother apoplectic 1 0 Mother insane, father tubercular cousins (2) insane, child epileptic 1 1 0 ther, sister (1) tubercular, sister (1) insane 1 (i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">369 Mother imbecile : 1 Mother, aunt and ancle insane (• ! Mother mentally deranged short tint* o Mother, sisters (3), brothers i2 . tuber- cular 1 1 (I Mother and sister insane ] 1 Mother, sister and brother insane 1 0 : Mother Carcinoma u 1 Mother paralytic 1 0 ! Mother asthmatic &lt;i 1 Mother and brother suicide, sister de- mented, father paralytic, brother nervous 1 ! II Mother and brother tubercular i» 1 Maternal relatives scrofulous 1 (I Mother epileptic 1 0 I) ! Mother and aunt hypochondriacs 1 &gt;s Paternal grandparents insane, brother Kyphosis 0 1 1 Sister insane 1 •) Sister tubercular .) ii Sister (1) tubercular, sister 1 Carei noma • &gt; 1 1 Sister scrofulous 0 o •&gt; Uncle intemperate 1 o 1 6 Uncle insane 3 it - ) Uncle suicide 1 1 Unknown v I 30 Si Negative, as far as known 62 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">ALLEGED CAUSE OF INSANITY Male Female Total Abuse arnl ridicule of neighbor* Alcoholism 1 o 1 4 0 1 1 .) Aiieinia ! E&gt;ndectomy -intoxication bra] Embolism Ibirth i l o !) 10 3 i) i ' Kfiiit'ineiit in penitentiary genital defects 1 (i ■&gt; 1 ■) 0 Evulsions in infancy uinal abortion ■&gt; ■) (I ii 1 1 ; Kth of husband lestic difficulties ii ■&gt; i; Domestic difficulties and religion Kndometritis l n l (i Epilepsy 11 1_&gt; Klepsy and intemperance insure and worry 1 ii ■&gt; 1 ■&gt; n it Financial difficulties rYight (I •&gt; teral debility editj 0 11 11 :{() 14 44 Heredity ami intemperance Heredity and ii :{ (I :; (I Heredity and masturbation Heredity and overwork II •&gt; (I •&gt; Heredity and religion Heredity and injury Heredity and finances Heredity and ill health Heredity and syphilis Heredity and dissipation 4 4 4 i •) t'dity, grief and intemperance ntile paralysis 1 ! 0 (i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. INGLESIDE 371 Injury to head Intemperance (I 1 1 I) {) II I) i 1 Intemperance and head injury Intemperance and worry Intemperance and sun stroke Jealousy 4 9 4 , 1 1 I) I) 0 I) it ion Ee affairs turbation lingitis « ; Meningitis and senility Menopause Nostalgia : Ktaljria and lov rstudy (I II o it Overstudy, worry and excessivt Overwork and eontinenient Overwork and worry smokin K 1 1 o •&gt; 1 s i 1 9 1 o i) it 2 3 Puerperal-Eclampsia Religion 1 £ Senility Senility and Trauma Senility and physical ailments i Senility and Seerosis Separation from child Suppression of -Menses Syphilis ;; Syphilis and intemperance Solitary life i 1 1 1 1 1 1 Trauma to head 12 it ii o 12 Trauma to head, and religion Trauma to head and epilpesy Tumor of cerebellum. 1 1 : 3 i i trwork, worry and injury 'si.s mancy Krvation and exposure ual exec—ci stroke </seg>
            <seg id="p064">l.u\M&gt; COMMISSIONERS REPORT 1 2 a Typhoid fever 1 nknown 4:. 25 70 6 0 0 0 Worry and ill health Worry and masturbation Work and environment 1 1 414 261 153 Total CAUSE OF DEATH Female Total Male o 1 1 1 o 1 1 1 Acute Nephritis (i 2 Acute pulmonary congestion Apoplexy it s E inoma of rectum inoma of stomach inoma of pancreas e not recorded 1 1 1 I) Cerebral tumor 1 l.ral hemorrhage hral syphilis Chronic Myocarditis Chronic Nephritis •&gt; •&gt; 4 4 0 Died while home on parole Dementia Preeox 4 4 Exhaustion from Chronic Melancholia &lt;• 12 Exhaustion from Acute .Mania i .) (i 11 Exhaustion from Epilepsy ■) 9. Exhaustion from Epileptic Dementia 2 o t) u Exhaustion from Epileptic Mania t; 6 l G 0 40 Exhaustion of Senile Dementia 8 Exhaustion from gtetus-Epilepticus 4 i ■i 10 6 4 Exhaustion of Chronic Mania riliroid .Myocardi' i- ' (I 1 Acute dilitatkon of h.-nrt Iliaustion from Paranoia 1 liaustion from Seconday Dementia kuxtinn nf Senile Dementia -^ </seg>
            <seg id="p065">373 fnnanition : InHucnz Killed at home I accidental ; .Mciiintritis Paresis 15 Paresis syphilitic 1 Peritonitis 2 Pneumonia. Lobar 9 .&gt; i Pressure from (Joitr 1 (i Pulmonary Eden 1 it Senile Dehilitv 1 1 it Senile Gangreni it Suicide, with &lt;^lass in heart Suicide by strangulation 1 I) Septicaemia 1 II therculosis. Pulmonary berculosis Intestinal 11 14 ii 1 1 Total Ho 65 DISCHARGED AS CURED Male Female Total Alcoholism Aeui .Mania Acute 3 •&gt; Mania Acute furious .Mania Religious 1 i ii Melancholia Acut 1- I Melancholia Hallucinatory Melancholia Simple 1 u ti •&gt; - » Psychoses, Traumatic u Total U </seg>
            <seg id="p066">374 DISCHARGED AS IMPROVED Male Female Total Cerebral syphilis Circular insanity Delation*! insanity Dementia Preeox 1 0 1 ■) 3 1(1 0 111 0 0 •) 1 1 : Kterical insanity ia Acute 0 13 X .Mania Recurrent .Mania Religious :{ 2 i (I •) Manic-depressive insanity .Melancholia AgitaU 1 1 II 9. (t •) ■ancholia Attonita ancholia Chronic II 1 1 12 (i 18 Kncholia Hypoehondri ncholia Subaeute .1 1 1 n (I 1 4 .; .Myxodoeina ! .Melancholia periodic Paresis 1 Partial Dementia i Ichoses. .Neurasthenic choses Traumatic iodic Insanity ■) 1 1 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p067">&gt; &lt; &gt; i &gt; &gt; ■&gt; 10 DISCHARGED UNIMPROVED Male I-Vinal Dementia Praecox Delusional Mania ii Epilepsy o it Imbecility 2 1 •&gt; Melancholia Acut* Melancholia Chronic "J 4 •&gt; Melancholia Attonita o 1 Posterior Sclerosis 1 Partial Dementia -&gt; Paranoia &lt;&gt; • ) Recurrent Mania o Senile Dementia &gt; Not insane / Total </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>