<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00024">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Lamb Feeding Experiments with Grains and Dried Beet Pulps</title>
               <date value="1932-03">1932-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 268 March, 1932 Lamb Feeding Experiments with Grains and Dried Beet Pulps JAMES A. HOLDEN, Superintendent SCOTTSBLUFF EXPERIMENT SUBSTATION I^r I I i ■*tH- i "-H : * "• I 1 fr»"i Pi THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY Cottonseed cake in a corn-alfalfa ration increased the gain per lamb, lowered the feed requirement per 100 pounds of gain and pro - duced lambs with a higher selling value. In these experiments corn produced faster gains, gains with less feed, and lambs with a higher selling value than barley, dried molasses pulp, or dried plain pulp. On the basis of returns per lamb, these feeds appear to have about 75 per cent of the value of corn. There seems to be little difference in the feeding value of barley, dried molasses pulp, and dried plain pulp. Dried molasses pulp is more palatable to lambs than dried plain pulp, but does not appear to have any higher feeding value. Beet tops increased the gains, reduced the requirement of concen - trates and alfalfa, hay for 100 pounds of gain, and increased the sell - ing price. i Corn silage showed no marked effect on gains or selling price of lambs but materially reduced the amount of alfalfa hay consumed. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Lamb Feeding Experiments with Grains and Dried Beet Pulps ••".••■ JAMES A. HOLDEN The tests herein reported were begun in the fall of 1925 and continued three consecutive winters. There were 13 lots with 25 lambs per lot each winter and each test lasted 120 days. In the tests there were four major comparisons: 1. A ration of corn and alfalfa hay was compared with a ration of corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. 2. Corn, barley, dried molasses pulp, and dried plain pulp were compared when fed (1) with cottonseed cake and alfalfa hay, (2) with cottonseed cake, beet tops, and alfalfa, and (3) with cottonseed cake, corn silage, and alfalfa hay. 3. Beet tops were compared with corn silage when fed in rations with corn, with barley, with dried molasses pulp, and with dried plain pulp. 4. There were comparisons with and without corn silage, and with and without beet tops in rations of corn, of barley, of dried molasses pulp, and of dried plain pulp. OUTLINE OF RATIONS Lot • 1, Corn and alfalfa hay Lot 2, Corn -* Lot 3, Barley With cottonseed cake and Lot A, Drjed molasses pulp f alfalfa hay. Lot 5, Dried plain pulp J Lot 6, Corn *j Lot 7, Barley I With cottonseed cake, beet Lot 8, Dried molasses pulp j tops, and alfalfa hay. Lot 9, Dried plain pulp J Lot 10, Corn "| Lot 11, Barley I with cottonseed cake, corn Lot 12, Dried molasses pulp f silage, and alfalfa hay. Lot 13, Dried plain pulp /■ FEEDING When the lambs had reached full feed, corn, barley, or dried pulp was fed at the rate of one pound, per lamb daily, cottonseed cake at the rate of one-third pound, and silage at the rate of 1.6 pounds daily during the winter of 1925-1926 and one pound daily during the next two winters. Where </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 268 uT tv£ S f?d&gt; the J an ? bs were given a11 the y would clean ?, P&gt; i J he . la ™bs in each lot were fed all the alfalfa hay they wou d eat without any waste. No uneaten food, such as stems ent lotJ S y '7 a f Wei + ? h6d back and credited t0 the ent lots. The daily ration was fed in two equal portions— morning and evening. In each case it required aboSt 45 days to get the lambs up to a full feed of grain? INITIAL COST AND WEIGHT PER LAMB The initial cost of the lambs weighed into the lots-, after allowing for the shrink to the feed lots, and with freight paid 3 "^ 8 ?14.50 for those bought in the fall of 1925 ?1&lt;3.25 for those bought in the fall of 1926, and $13 75 for £s sy&amp;s? 6 fa " ot 1927 - The averase *»• ** Ss The average weight per lamb was 59 pounds the first JSSw' f + if S + T° nd&gt; and 6 ° the third - The * average initiS ZHffiS Sr e iSSK 57 - 7 pounds and the avei " age APPRAISED VALUE AT END OF TEST Each spring at the close of the experiment the lambs in the different lots were appraised by expert commission men The market tops representing. the highest price paid at Omaha for Western fed Iambs on the clay the lambs were appraised were as follows, per hundredweight: . ppr " lsea ' Spring of 1926 §13.00 Spring of 1927. 1575 Spring of 1928 16.75 Three-year average $15.17 The appraised values here used for each lot are the aver - ages of three appraised values of each particular lot At the close of the feeding test in the spring of 1926 the market top at Omaha for fat lambs was ?1.50 less per hun! d Q97 P £ Unds than lambs cost as fee ders; in the spring of 1927, the top was $2.5.0 more and the next spring it was S3 higher than the cost. • ■ - • T it ave rage feed-lot gains per lamb- were 34.3 pounds dur- £ S Jt 6 2 • ™ inter » 39.2 Pounds the second, and 36.4 pounds the third winter, with a three-year average of 37 pounds of gain. Deducting a six-p&amp;und shrink from feed lot to market eaves an average feedlot-to-market gain or 31 pounds The lowest average feedlot-to-market gain for any one lot was 26.5 pounds and the highest average was 34 pounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Feeding Lambs Grains and Dried Pulps experimental results and discussions : CORN AND ALFALFA HAY VS. CORN, COTTONSEED CAKE, AND ALFALFA HAY The lambs in Lot 1 were fed corn and alfalfa hay and those in Lot 2 were fed the same ration with the addition of cotton - seed cake. The lambs fed cottonseed cake made 6.9 pounds •more gain and were appraised at a higher price (Table 1). Table 1. — Comparison of corn and alfalfa hay with com, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay for fattening lambs — average of three tests Lot 1 Lot 2 • •',' Corn • Corn Cottonseed cake Alfalfa hay Alfalfa hay Pounds Pounds Average initial weight per lamb 57.9 57.7 Average final weight per lamb •. . . 90.4 97.1 Average gain per lamb. 32.5 39.4 Average daily gain per lamb 0.27 0.33 Feed required per 100 pounds gain: Corn 337 278 Cottonseed cake ... 82 Alfalfa hay. 805 627 Appraised values per cwt $14.85 $15.05 The lambs in Lot 1 made an average gain of 32.5 pounds, while those in Lot 2, where cottonseed cake was fed, made 39.4 pounds gain. In Lot 1 the lambs were fed 337 pounds of corn and 805 pounds of alfalfa for each 100 pounds of gain; Lot 2 required 278 pounds of corn, 82 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 627 pounds of alfalfa hay. The 82 pounds of cotton - seed cake replaced 59 pounds of corn and 178 pounds of alfalfa hay. With the prices that prevailed during the experi - ment the cake cost about the same as the corn and alfalfa hay it replaced. The appraised value at the end of the feeding test was $14.85 per hundredweight for those in Lot 1 and $15.05 for those in Lot 2. This same comparison had been conducted during three sets of previous experiments or with nine lots having a total of 225 lambs for each ration. Where corn and alfalfa hay were fed the average amount of feed consumed per lamb was 101 pounds of corn and 215 pounds of alfalfa hay and the lambs made an average gain of 31 pounds. Where cottonseed cake was fed with corn and alfalfa hay, the feed consumed per lamb was 101 pounds of corn, 204 pounds of alfalfa hay, </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 268 and 32 pounds of cottonseed cake ; the average gain per lamb was 37.4 pounds. The lambs fed cottonseed cake consumed the same amount of corn and only slightly less alfalfa hay than those not fed cottonseed cake. The 32 pounds of cotton - seed cake, therefore, produced 6.4 pounds of gain, or one pound for each five pounds of cake fed. The cake-fed lambs sold for 25 cents more per hundredweight. In these tests if corn costs $1.40 per hundredweight, alfalfa hay $10 per ton, and fat lambs sell at $12 per hundred pounds, then cottonseed cake can profitably he fed until it gets as high as $55 per ton. But if corn costs 75 cents per hundredweight and alfalfa hay $6 per ton and fat lambs sell at $6 per hundred pounds, then cottonseed cake must sell below $30 per ton to be profitable. COMPARING CORN, BARLEY. DRIED MOLASSES PULP, AND DRIED PLAIN PULP WHEN FED WITH COTTONSEED CAKE AND ALFALFA HAY In addition to cottonseed cake and alfalfa hay, Lot 2 was fed corn, Lot 3 barley, Lot 4 dried molasses pulp, and Lot 5 dried plain pulp. The gains made per lamb in each of these lots, the feed requirement per 100 pounds of gain, and the appraised value of the fat. lambs at the close of the test are given in Table 2. Table 2. — Comparison of corn, barley, dried molasses pidp and dried plain pulp when fed with cottonseed cake and alfalfa hay — average of three tests Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 Lot 5 ■ Dried Dried Corn Barley molasses plain pulp pulp Number of lambs 75 75 75 75 ..,.,., Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Average initial weight per lamb... 57.7 58.1 57.8 58 0 Average final weight per lamb .... 97.1 93.1 94 0 92 3 Average gain per lamb 39.4 35.0 36.2 34*3 Average daily gain per lamb. 0.33 0.29 0.30 o!29 Feed per 100 pounds gain: Corn 278 Barley.. 315 .....'. '.'.',/... Dried molasses pulp 305 Dried plain pulp 322 ' ' Cottonseed cake 82 '92" '89 '" 94 '■■ •Alfalfa hay. 627 649 613 619 Appraised values per cwt $15.05 $14.80 $14.75 $14.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Feeding Lambs Grains and Dried Pulps As shown in the table, where corn was fed the lambs made larger gains, required less feed per 100 pounds of gain, and were appraised higher. There was little difference between the lots fed barley and the two fed dried pulps. The lambs in the corn lot made 4.2 pounds higher gain and sold at more than 25 cents per hundredweight above the averages of the barley - and pulp-fed lambs. In* feed requirements per 100 pounds of gain, 100 pounds of corn was equal to 113 pounds of barley and 3.6 pounds of cottonseed cake, or 110 pounds of dried molasses pulp and 2.5 pounds of cottonseed cake, or 115 pounds of dried plain pulp and 4.3 pounds of cottonseed cake. COMPARING CORN, BARLEY. DRIED MOLASSES PULP, AND DRIED PLAIN PULP WHEN FED WITH BEET TOPS, COTTONSEED CAKE, AND ALFALFA HAY The same rations used in Lots 2, 3, 4, and 5 respectively were also fed to Lots 6, 7, 8, and 9, with the addition of beet tops. The average gain per lamb, the feed requirements per 100 pounds of gam, and the appraised value per hundred - weight at the close of the tests are given in Table 3. Table 3. — A comparison showing the results from feeding corn, barley, dried molasses pulp or dried plain pulp with beet tops, cottonseed cake and alfalfa hay — average of three tests . . Lot 6 Lot 7 Lot 8 Lot 9 Dried Dried Corn Barley molasses plain pulp pulp Number of lambs per lot 75 75 75 75 . • -,.•,., , Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Average initial weight per lamb . . . 58.3 58.0 58.0 57 9 Average final weight per lamb .... 98.4 96.4 95 4 960 Average gain per lamb 40.1 38.4 374 38 1 Average daily gain per lamb. 0.33 0.32 0.31 o!32 Feed per 100 pounds gain: Corn 272 Barley.. 287 ' '.'.'.'.'.'. ]'."['. Dried molasses pulp 295 Dried plain pulp . . .' '... . . 289 Cottonseed cake 81 84 ' 86 " 85 Beet tops per ton beets 2.1 2.0 2 1 2.2 Alfalfa hay 369 380 387 379 Appraised values per cwt $15.05 $14.90 $14.95 $14.85 As was true in the other comparisons, although the differ - ences were not so great, the lambs fed corn made higher gains required less feed per 100 pounds of gain, and were appraised at a higher value than the lambs fed barley or either of the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 268 two dried pulps. There were not any marked differences in the lots fed barley and the two dried pulps. The average gain per lamb was 40.1 pounds in Lot 6, 38.4 in Lot 7, 37.4 in Lot 8, and 38.1 in Lot 9. The grains or dried pulp required per 100 pounds of gain in Lots 6, 7, 8, and 9 respectively were 272 pounds of corn, 287 pounds of barley, 295 pounds of dried molasses pulp, and 289 pounds of dried plain pulp, and the cottonseed cake was 81, 84, 86, and 85 pounds. The beet tops and alfalfa hay consumed were approximately the same in each lot, being an average of 380 pounds of alfalfa hay and the tops from 2.1 tons of beets. The lambs fed corn were appraised at $15.05, the barley lot at $14.90, the dried molasses pulp lot at $14.95, and the dried plain pulp lot at $14.85. In this comparison the lambs fed corn made 2.1 pounds higher gains than the average of the other three lots. In the other comparisons with the same rations, except beet tops, this difference was twice this amount or 4.2 pounds. Beet tops also narrowed the spread between the feeding value of corn and that of barley and the two dried pulps. One hun - dred pounds of corn made the following replacements: 105 pounds of barley, 1.1 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 4 pounds of alfalfa hay; or 109 pounds dried molasses pulp, 1.8 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 6 pounds of alfalfa hay ; or 106 pounds of dried plain pulp, 1.5 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 4 pounds of alfalfa hay. COMPARING CORN, BARLEY, DRIED MOLASSES PULP, AND DRIED PLAIN PULP WHEN FED WITH COTTONSEED CAKE, CORN SILAGE, AND ALFALFA HAY The four lots in this comparison were fed the same rations as the four lots in the first comparison, except that corn silage was added, and they differed from the four lots in the sec - ond comparison in that the corn silage replaced the beet tops. In addition to cottonseed cake, corn silage, and alfalfa hay, Lot 10 was fed corn; Lot 11, barley; Lot 12, dried molasses pulp ; and Lot 13, dried plain pulp. The gain per lamb, feed requirements per 100 pounds of gain, and appraised value ai-e given in Table 4. The lambs fed corn made 38.1 pounds of gain; those fed barley, 35.5 pounds ; those fed dried molasses pulp, 35.6 pounds; and those fed dried plain pulp, 35.8 pounds. The appraised value was $15.05 per hundredweight for lambs fed corn, $14.85 for those fed barley, $14.90 for those fed dried molasses pulp, and $14.80 for those fed the dried plain pulp. The lambs fed corn made 2.5 pounds higher gains than the average for those fed barley and the two dried pulps In </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Feeding Lambs Grains and Dried Pulps Table 4. — Comparing corn, barley, dried molasses pulp, and dried plain pulp when fed vnth cottonseed cake, corn silage, and alfalfa hay— average of three tests Lot 10 Lot 11 Lot 12 Lot 13 Dried Dried Corn Barley molasses plain pulp pulp Number of lambs per lot 75 75 75 75 Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Average initial weight per lamb . . . 57.9 58.0 58.0 57.8 Average final weight per lamb .... 96.0 93.5 93.6 93.6 Average gain per lamb 38.1 35.5 35.6 35.8 Average daily gain per lamb 0.32 0.30 0.30 0.30 Feed per 100 pounds gain: Corn 286 Barley: ...... 311 Dried molasses pulp 310 - Dried plain pulp 308 Cottonseed cake .;.... 85 91 91 90 Corn silage 323 354 346 344 Alfalfa hay 447 471 464 428 Appraised values per cwt.- $15.05 $14.85 $14.90 | $14.80 this comparison 100 pounds of corn replaced 2 pounds of cottonseed cake, 8 pounds of corn silage, 7 pounds of alfalfa hay, and 109 pounds of barley or dried molasses pulp, or 108 pounds of dried plain pulp.. As was true in the other two comparisons there were small differences between the lots fed barley and the two dried pulps. The corn silage slightly increased the gain in the barley and dried plain pulp lots but in the other two lots it was less. The average for the four lots was the same. An average for the four lots shows that a ton of corn silage replaced 7 pounds of grain, 1.5 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 1,022 pounds of alfalfa hay. Both beet tops and corn silage improved the barley and dried pulp rations more than they did the corn ration. While the beet tops improved the corn ration con - siderably, they improved the barley and dried pulp rations even more. COMPARING CORN, BARLEY, DRIED MOLASSES PULP, AND DRIED PLAIN PULP WHEN FED WITH DIFFERENT ROUGHAGES Corn, barley, dried molasses pulp, and dried plain pulp were compared under three different conditions, the roughage being the variable factor. In one comparison alfalfa hay was the only roughage fed, in. another alfalfa hay and beet tops were fed, and in still another alfalfa hay and corn silage were fed. In each of the three comparisons corn proved to </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 268 be superior to barley or either of the two dried pulps. The corn-fed lambs made faster gains, required less feed per 100 pounds of gain, and were appraised at a higher price. This higher feeding value of corn appears to vary somewhat with the roughage fed. Corn had its highest relative feeding value m the comparison where alfalfa hay was the only roughage Here the corn-fed lambs made 4.2 pounds higher gain than the average of the other three lots, as compared with 2 1 pounds more where beet tops were fed and 2.5 pounds more where corn silage was fed. It appears that barley has its highest relative value when fed with beet tops and alfalfa hay; dried molasses pulp has its highest when fed with alfalfa hay alone; and dried plain pulp is best when fed with corn silage and alfalfa hay. Even here are small and indicate that there is but little difference in the feeding value of barley, dried molasses pulp, and dried plain pulp. Averages of the three comparisons show that the lambs in the three lots fed corn made an average gain of 39.2 pounds - the three lots fed barley made 36.3 pounds; the three lots fed dried molasses pulp made 36.4 pounds ; and the three lots fed dried plain pulp made 36.1 pounds. The average appraised value for each of the three lots was $15.05 per hundredweight where corn was fed; $14.85 where barley was fed- $14 87 where dried molasses pulp was fed; and $14.80 where dried plain pulp was fed. In order to better compare the feeding value of barley and the two dried pulps with that of corn, the following values are assumed : One pound of corn is equal to — One-half pound of cottonseed cake, Three pounds of alfalfa hay, Seven and one-half pounds of corn silage. Using these values to adjust the differences in cottonseed - cake, alfalfa-hay, and corn-silage requirements per 100 pounds of gam, the results show that barley and the two dried pulps had an average feeding value of 82 per cent pf that of corn in the comparison where alfalfa hay was the only rough - ag^ ?* ; ,* 89 ,. per cent that of corn when fed with beet tops and alfalfa hay; and 86 per. cent that of corn when fed with corn silage and alfalfa hay. In the three comparisons barley and the two dried pulps had an average feeding value of 86 harw 1 ? 5 COrn - Likewise, in the three comparisons, barley had an average of 85 per cent; dried molasses pulp 86 per cent; and dried plain pulp 87 per cent of the feeding value </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Feeding Lambs Grains and Dried Pulps This is on the basis of feed replacement value only. The fact that corn produces faster gains and lambs of a higher selling value also has an intrinsic value which must be con - sidered. From the standpoint of profit or loss per lamb it is doubtful that barley or either of the two dried pulps has more than 75 per cent of the fattening value of corn. The feeding value of barley or of dried pulp is materially in - creased when fed in a mixture with corn. The addition of molasses to dried pulp appears to improve its feeding value but little, if any. The dried plain pulp seems to have about the same feeding value as the dried molasses pulp. Dried molasses pulp is more palatable and is preferred by livestock, but from the standpoint of feeding value there seems to be little difference. BEET TOPS Beet tops were fed in Lots 6, 7, 8, and 9 in comparison with Lots 2, 3, 4, and 5 fed the same respective rations with - out beet tops. The beet tops proved to be a good roughage feed for fattening lambs. The lambs made faster gains, required less concentrates and alfalfa hay per 100 pounds of gain, and sold at a higher price. They had their highest replacement value in the lots fed barley and dried plain pulp and their lowest value when fed with corn. The average for the four lots showed that the tops from one ton of beets re - placed 10 pounds of grain and dried pulp, 2.6 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 118 pounds of alfalfa hay. These re - placed feeds usually cost about twice as much as the beet tops. The lambs fed beet tops made 2.3 pounds more gain and were appraised at 10 cents more per hundredweight than those fed alfalfa hay as the only roughage. CORN SILAGE The lambs in the four lots where corn silage was fed made the same average gain as those fed the same rations without corn silage. Where it was fed with corn and dried molasses pulp, the gain per lamb was less, but where it was fed with barley and with dried plain pulp the gain was more. The appraised value, except where corn was fed, was increased by the addition of corn silage. Corn silage had its highest relative feeding value when fed with dried plain pulp, and second, with barley. Its highest value came in reducing the amount of alfalfa hay rather than the concentrates. In all four lots it materially reduced the alfalfa hay requirement. In the barley and in the dried plain pulp lots it also reduced somewhat the concentrates required per 100 pounds of gain, but in the other two lots, </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 268 where corn and dried molasses pulp were fed, more concen - trates were required with the corn silage. The average of the four lots shows that one ton of corn, silage has a replace - ment value of 7 pounds of grain and dried pulp, 1.5 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 1,022 pounds of alfalfa hay. AMOUNT OF FEED PER THOUSAND LAMBS To assist beginners in arriving at the approximate amount of feed that will be required to feed 1,000 lambs 120 days when fed these various rations, Table 5 has been prepared. The amount of feedlot-to-market gain per lamb is also given. This feedlot-to-market gain is based on the initial weight after at least a week's fill on alfalfa hay and water and the final weight at the feed lot with six pounds taken off to cover the shrink to market. The data recorded in Table 5 are based on the averages of the respective lots for the three winters. TABLE 5. — Amount of feed required per 1,000 lambs averag - ing 57 pounds token fed 120 days and the feedlot-to - market gains per lamb — average of three tests Lot 1. Corn and alfalfa hay: ' , Corn (tons) ; : 55.15 Alfalfa hay (tons) 130.G5 Average feedlot-to-market gain per lamb (pounds).'. 26.5 Lot 2. Corn, cottonseed cake, alfalfa hay: Corn (tons) 55.15 Cottonseed cake (tons) 1G.1P Alfalfa hay (tens) 123.35 Average feedlot-to-market gain per lamb (pounds): 33.4 Lot 3. Barley, cottonseed cake, alfalfa hay: : Barley (tons) 55,15 Cottonseed cake (tons) ;, 16. 1G Alfalfa hay (tons)..... 113.83 Average feedlot-to-market gain per lamb (pounds) 29.0 Lot 4. Dried molasses pulp, cottonseed cake, alfalfa hay: Dried molasses pulp (tons) 55.15 Cottonseed cake (tons) .-. 1G.16 Alfalfa hay (tons) 110.93 Average feedlot-to-market gain per lamb (pounds) 30.2 Lot 5. Dried plain pulp, cottonseed cake, alfalfa hay: Dried plain pulp (tons).... 55.15 Cottonseed cake (tons) 10.16 Alfalfa hay (tons) :..... 106.33 Average feedlot-to-market gain per lamb (pounds) 28.3 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>