<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00029">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00029</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Effect of Environment on Potato Degeneration Diseases</title>
               <date value="1924-03">1924-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 2S Effect of Environment on Potato Degeneration Diseases R. W. GOSS DEPARTMENT OF PLANT PATHOLOGY LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MARCH. 1924 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Introduction •» 5 Consideration of the Problem _ &amp; Experimental Data 10 Greenhouse Experiments 10 Field Experiments 15 Field Experiments with Miscellaneous Mosaic 27 Correlation of Experimental Results with Mosaic Incidence in Commercial Fields 31 Dmci ssion 37 Literature Cited 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY 1. The symptoms of potato mosaic in the Bliss Triumph variety are Influenced to a great degree by environmental conditions. 2. Temperatures above 70° F. tend to decrease the number and severity of the symptoms, while temperatures below that point increase their visi - bility. 3. Mottling was found to be the most constant symptom when tem - perature alone was varied. High temperature with intense sunlight caused the disappearance of this symptom. 4. Wrinkling, curling, and rugosity were eliminated at the higher temperatures on mild mosaic plants. 5. High temperature is a greater factor in masking mosaic symptoms than low moisture or increased sunlight, altho under field conditions all -i usually occur together. 6. The symptoms of mild mosaic reacted more quickly to environ - mental factors than the more severe types and the combination!! of mosaic and spindle-tuber used in these experiments. 7. The effect of the environment on the symptoms decreased with the increasing age of the plant. 8. Under field conditions mosaic was more severe with early planting while spindle-tuber was more severe in the late plantings. 9. Short periods of 4 to 8 days of high temperature and increased sunlight were found sufficient to eliminate the leaf symptoms of mild mosaic and to decrease those of the more severe types. 10. The symptoms of mild mosaic under certain conditions appeared more serious than the symptoms of the more severe types of mosaic ap - peared under other conditions that were less favorable for the manifesta - tions of the symptoms. 11. Climatic conditions as noted above can be correlated in commer - cial fields with: la) Changes in the appearance of the symptoms on the plants during the same season (b) Changes in the amount of visible mosaic in the same region for different seasons (c) Changes in the amount of mosaic found in northern grown seed from Nebraska when planted in the southern states 12. In view of the data presented in this paper, the author believes that the effect of high temperature, intense sunlight, and low moisture in masking the symptoms of mosaic in western Nebraska is of as great im - portance as aphid transmission of the disease. 13. In order to select healthy seed, to determine the percentage of mosaic, or to rogue properly, the conditions under which the plants are growing must be considered, and the work done at the most favorable time rather than at any fixed date. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Effect of Environment on Potato Degeneration Diseases R. W. GOSS DEPARTMENT OF PLANT PATHOLOGY INTRODUCTION During recent years much of the in vest i •rational work on the degeneration diseases of the potato has been directed toward the -eparation and identification of a number of diseases formerly grouped under the general names of mosaic, leaf roll, and "run - ning out". Extensive studies have also been made on methods of transmission, host range, overwintering and the identification of the evasive causal factor. ' Investigations of this type, however, have progressed slowly U'caus*- of the necessity of developing new methods of research, because of the complexity of the problem, and because of the lack of knowledge regarding the causal factors. Meanwhile then* is an immediate and pressing demand from the seed grow - er- and the inspectors of certified seed for advice and instruc - t ion regarding these diseases. Their chief interest is in the problems of (1) the recognition of these diseases in the field. (2) their effects upon yield rate, and (3) methods of control. It seems, therefore, desirable to present here the results of certain preliminary studies which contribute in some measure to a better understanding of these more practical problems and to point out some of the factors, and their effects, which must be considered in a study of these problems. CONSIDERATION OF THE PROBLEM In discussing the :i problems outlined above, emphasis will l&gt;e laid upon the first, i. &lt;•.. the recognition of these diseases in the field. This is prerequisite to a proper investigation of the other 2 problems. The symptoms of mosaic and related diseases have l&gt;een known in a general way for a number of years. The recent pub - lication:- on the subject, however, have caused a temporary con - fusion in the minds of workers not specializing on these diseases, but it is hoped they will eventually lead to a clearer understand - ing of the problem. The confusion, however, is nevertheless present. Quanjer (1921) (1923) describes from 6 to 8 different degeneration diseases occurring in Europe, Murphy (1921-B) li-t- &lt;; diseases of this type, and Schultz and Folsom (1023. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 l&gt;. &lt;&gt;1) distinguish 7 diseases occurring on the (riven Mountaiil variety. They al.-io note that combinations of these diseases inayj occur, thus increasing the complexity of the problem. When we! consider that tlieM' authors were working with different varieties.! under different conditions, hiuI often used different ternjs to describe similar symptoms, the reason for the resultant confusion i&gt; obvious. Schnltz and Folsom (1923) give a very clear defini - tion of the symptoms used in (heir descriptions. This should result in materially increased clarity of description in American |&gt;a|&gt;cr&gt;. Their terminology will l&gt;e used thruout this paper. Schultz and Folsom ( l'.'i'O) ( 1923) demonstrated the possi - bility both of intervarietal transmission of certain degeneration ses and of varietal modification of symptoms. However. the problem of varietal manifestations of the-e disea-e- i&gt; -till largely unsolved. The other factor to Ik* considered, that of the effect of en - vironment on the disease symptoms, has already received con - siderable attention. The masking of symptoms has l&gt;een observed by numerous workers. Most of the statements in the literature. however, regarding this phenomenon have Ihhmi based on general observations: and often where experimental evidence is pre - sented, detailed data regarding the environmental factor- are lacking. The only experimental evidence secured under controlled con - ditions with which the author is acquainted was presented by Johnson (INS). He found the optimum temperature for the IBMtrtnoe of the symptoms to lie between 14 and IS ('. "Above "JO" ('. symptoms disappear, the rate of recovery from the disease being increased in proportion to increase of tempera - iiv within the limits of host development. To completely in - bit the disease, however, within a |&gt;eriod of one to two week*, teni|&gt;erature of -J4 to \i-&gt; ('. is necessary: and this may !»■ garded ■* the maximum tem|&gt;crature for mosaic manifestation the jK&gt;tato. New leaves, free from symptoms, appear quickly this temperature, and older leaves gradually Iom' their symp - ins. the rate of 'recovery' being roughly proportional to tin - re of the leaf." He does not state the ty|&gt;e of mosaic or the severity of the symptoms on the plants with which he was work - ing, or the variety of potatoes used, nor does he mention soil moisture or sunlight, altho it is to l&gt;e assumed that they were kept similar in the parallel tests. Schultz, et al. (1919, p. 250) report that parallel plantings in Maine and Colorado showed an absence of mottling in Colo - rado and distinct mottling in Maine. Plantings in Maine and at </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 7 Washington, D. ('.. gave somewhat similar results. Plantings made for 3 successive seasons in northeastern and southwestern Maine showed mottling to !*■ inhibited in southwestern Maine, and the return of the progeny to northeastern Maine resulted in the reappearance of mottling. Xo data are given concerning the environmental factors of these different localities or the type of ntosaic being studied. Schultz and Folsom (1923, p. 99-102) iv|M&gt;rt a number of experiment* in which the symptoms of these diseases were affected by climatic conditions. They found that mottling was particularly masked on mild mosaic plants when grown in Virginia in comparison with Maine and Long Island plantings. In greenhouse ex|&gt;eriments they found wrinkling and mottling to be more marked at 16° than at 24° C. and that the transference of the plants from the high to the low tempera - ture increased the symptoms on the new foliage. They found mottling to be more; distinct on caged than on uncaged plants in the field. In other experiments with various types of mosaic, they report t hat a reduction in sunlight decreased the apparent dwarfing and increased mottling. In fertilizer experiments they found a decrease in the percentage of mosaic and in the distinct - ness of nvottling. during the first part of the season. by high nitrogen and potash fertilizers. In none of this work, except in the greenhouse experiments, do the authors present very detailed information regarding temperature, moisture, and sunlight (aside from shading in insect cages) occurring in their experiment &gt;. They do not report, with the exception of the one experiment in Colorado, a change from distinct mottling to an absence of mot - tling. They find that a difference in climatic conditions results chiefly in a difference in the distinctness of the mottling. l»nt that the stage or type of mosaic remains the same. Ducomet ( \'.&gt;2-\) in a recent paper discusses the influence of environment on the symptoms. He lays great stress upon mois - ture as well as temperature, and correlates the appearance of mosaic with wet seasons or with local wet regions in dry seasons. From his greenhouse experiments conducted at 12°-15° and IT - ±2 C, some of the plants being under cloth, he concludes that "basses temperatures et air sec favorisent les deformations: tem - (M'ratures elevees et air humide favorisent la maculature." It is to Ih' noted, however, that his high temperatures were not as high a&gt; the temperatures employed by Johnson (1922), nor as high as the temperatures often occurring in the field in Xe - ltr;i*ka. He found the disease to be more evident under cloth, lie does not give any detailed data on temperature or moisture in his field observations. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 Murphy ( l'.^Jl ) olwerves that, "a high temperature and favor - able conditions for quick growth early in the season reduce the symptoms of mosaic." lie notes that a mean temperature of 71.1 F. during June at Ottawa resulted in the suppression of the symptoms of mosaic while in the previous year, with a mean tenijx'rature of »'&gt;1.n F., the disease was severe. He shows that the symptoms of the disease were masked under certain condi - tions, but that the plants remained a source of infection for neighboring healthy plants. The symptoms reappeared when tubers from these plants were grown the following year under more favorable conditions for the appearance of the disease. He finds that early planting favors the appearance of mosaic. The -•me author ( 1!&gt;'23) considers that moisture as well as tempera - ture may influence the appearance of the disease. In considering the second question, i. e.. the effect of these dlMMM on yield, no attempt will be made to review all the literature. Numerous investigators have reported variable de - fWWr in yield m lxing due to the.se diseases. A few points in relation to this phase should be considered here, however. The effect of locality on yield rate in relation to these disease - \* of considerable importance. Schultz and Folsom (1923) re - port that an all-mosaic condition reduced the yield rate of (ireen Mountains more on Long Island than in northeastern Maine. Murphy (li»"21) reports that plants in which the symp - tons of mosaic wen' masked gave practically as good yields as MJghboring healthy plants. Data presented by Edgerton and Tieltout (19*21) and other unpublished data obtained on Xe - braaka grown seed in Louisiana, show a much greater decrease in yield, due apparently to mosaic, in the South than in Nebraska. It has been noticeable, however, in many of the yield tests that there is a considerable variation in the amount of mosaic present in different strains of jx&gt;tatoes giving about the same yields and «•£» vena. An example of this is shown by Edgerton and Tie - bout (1921, p. 11). Their data show that Lots Nos. 2 and 3 have practically the same yield, but differ in the amount of inoNaic by about 30 per cent. Again. Lot No. 10 outyields Lot \i&gt;. ."&gt; by about •"&gt;•"&gt; bushels, altho the amount of mosaic is the *am«« in both canes. This can be accounted for by the possibility that different types of mosaic were present, together with the fact that different types of mosaic affect the yield rate differ - ently. Very little evidence has been published on this point, and more information is needed to determine the tolerance of differ - ent types of these diseases to be allowed in our seed potatoe- for different localities. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Regarding the control of these diseases, a great number of factors nui&gt;t be taken into consideration, but do not properly Wong in this paper, except for certain phases of the problem in relation to environment. The general methods of control usually advised have comprised roguing, selection of healthy lulls, seed plats, and isolation. Schultz and Folsom (19*21, p. 7"&gt;) have noted a regional variation in the amount and spread of mosaic in experimental fields, apparently due to the effect of climate on the amount of aphid infestation. Quanjer (1921. p. !»:&gt;i found a difference in the spread of leaf roll and related ■ i :—.-:»-«-- iv lien part- of split tubers wen- planted in different localities. He found more green flias present in localities where the .Ii-.;i-i -pread the most, but apparently does not think this is the M)l«- explanation. Murphy (1921) has also noted regional differences in the spread of mosaic. Thus the effect of environment is of considerable importance in determining the degree of isolation necessary in seed plats. The amount of infestation is important as regards the time of roguing or of hill selection. The direct effect of masking on the ability to distinguish and remove diseased plants is obvious. Another factor in relation to control is the possible trans - mission of the disease from native plants, and this again will vary in different localities. This short review of the literature must lead one to the con - clusion that environment exerts a marked influence upon the symptoms, the spread, and the effect on yield of these diseases. The exact conditions causing the masking of symptoms and the degree of masking, still remain to be demonstrated for the vari - ous tyj)es of mosaic in different varieties, and practically no information is given regarding the effect of such factors on the spindle-tuber disease. Until the effect of these external factors on the apj&gt;earance. spread and yield is determined for the dif - ferent varieties and for the different diseases, it is manifestly impossible to come to a clear understanding of these diseases in the various potato growing sections and to combat them intel - ligently. The problem still remains in many ways purely a local one. Conditions in Nebraska and other dry land sections of the West are markedly different from those prevailing in the East, where most of the experimental work in the United States on these diseases has been performed. It has long been evident that experimental results from eastern states cannot be applied, in toto. to the potato sections of the West. Conditions of tempera - ture, moisture, sunlight, aphid infestations (usually very scarce). </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 un&lt;l paaiblf native hosts other than the potato are very different fruiu thoae occurring in the Kast. The varieties l&gt;eing grown ■re not those ii|m&gt;ii which most of the reported experiments have been conducted. The appearance of these diseases and even the -verity of the different ty|x-s in their effect on yield are very diver-*-. Increases in mosaic in the absence of great numbers of aphids are common. The necessity for further work on this pn&gt;l&gt; lein in various parts of the country, but particularly in the West. even at the risk of considerable duplication, cannot be too great I v emphasized. EXPERIMENTAL DATA GREENHOUSE EXPERIMENTS KrPCCT Or TEMPERATURE ON THE SYMPTOMS DECEMBER 22. 1922. TO APRIL 16. 1923 The following experiment was planned to determine the clfiil of temperature on the symptoms of certain degeneration duMNrs in the BliflH Triumph variety. Bl. The -.eed used in this and the following ex - t&gt;. i-xcept where otherwise noted. wsi&gt; obtained from Dr. Folsom. Maine Agricultural Experiment Station. August 'M. l!&gt;±i. and was designated by him as follows: mild in niediiim plus mosaic, spindle-tuber, spindle-tuber -j-niild mosaic, ami curly dwarf (spindle-tuber-t-leaf rolling mosaic). hi a ivcent publication. Schultz and Folsom &lt;l'&gt;2:i) state that their former designation of medium plus mosaic is in part a combination of rugose mosaic with spindle-tulier. The ma - terial sent to the author undoubtedly shows both mosaic and spindle-tuher characteristics on the vine and spindle-tul&gt;er symp - tom* on the tubers. l»ut has not appeared a- serious a- the spin - dle-tuber-)-mild mosaic. MtiktJi. — C &gt;ne tul&gt;er fn&gt;m each of these ."&gt; lot~ of seed was cut into 4 e&lt;|iial sized pieces and used for planting at 4 different temperature*. Thus all 4 plants listed in Table 1 under each disease were from the same mother tuber. The plants were grown in 10,000 gins, of soil in galvanized iron containers in which the soil moisture was kept approxi - mately constant by methods previously described by the author. (IShiS). The soil was held at ±i |&gt;er cent moisture (dry weight), this being e&lt;|ual to the soil moisture equivalent. 1 Im - mediately after planting, the containers were placed at the (!&gt;■- "Dm author ia indebted to Mr. J. C Ruwel of the Acronomy Department. Nebraska Calkat of Afrirultur*. for the detrrmination of soil moisture equivalents. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">*ired temperature. The temperatures used were 15 . 20 . 25°, mid 30 ('. These temperatures were held constant for both air and soil in teni|&gt;erature cases described by Peltier (15J-23). On February !». when the plants were half grown, they were trans - ferred to different temperatures, the plants at 15 and 20 l*&gt;ing removed to a greenhouse held at approximately 2."&gt; . The plants at S&gt; and 30 were transferred to temperature cases held at 18 . The light conditions were approximately the same in all cases. The sunlight during the experiment was very weak, and as a result the plant.-, were considerably etiolated. Observations were made every week during the experiment. and after the temperatures were changed, observations were made separately on the old and new foliage. Healthy tubers were grown in each set as controls, and in every instance re - mained healthy except for chlorosis and leaf dropping at the liigli temperatures, so that these symptoms were not recorded for the mosaic plants. The extent of dwarfing was determined by comparing the infected plants with the controls in the same litmiltx. — A summary of the symptoms appearing on the in - dividual plants is given in Table 1. The results show a rather uniform and marked gradation in the absence or in the severity of the symptoms of the various plants growing at dif - ferent temperatures. More symptoms were present and they were all more distinct at 15° than at 20 C. At "2.") the mild mosaic plant ap|&gt;eared healthy while at HO many of the symp - toms &lt;iii all plants were al&gt;sent. When plants growing at l.V were transferred to 25 C . the symptoms usually persisted in a milder form on the old leaves, while in most instances the new leave- appeared healthy. The symptoms )&gt;ersisted longer on these plants than on the plants transferred from 20' to ■!■&gt; . The reverse was true on plants grown at '2~i and 30° and trans - ferred to l."&gt; . Here the old leaves sometimes developed symp - toms under the more favorable tempera tun* conditions while in most instances the new leaves showed very distinct symptoms.' These were never as distinct on the plants previously grown at :&gt;&lt;&gt; as on those grown at 25°, and in most instances they were not as distinct even on the new leaves at IS as they were on plants started at 15°. Evidently the high temperatures not only masked the symptoms, but inhibited the development of the symptom^ when the plants were changed to a lower temperature. Contrary to expectations, under the conditions of this experi - ment, mottling of the leaf was the most persistent symptom pres - ent : this was possibly favored by the weak sunlight conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">degeneration diseases appearing on the foliage developed during the period of growth, (/) before and (II) after the rhatuje of temperature 1 war I ? S m E t I II Is a MILD MOSAIC 1 li Won 1 II M M«r. A ft»r t II IS Mer. Afl»r I M W« S II Ti M» Alu-r I :io Mo^ 4 II If hfar. Aft-r MEDIUM + MOSAIC I II ! Brfor. I 11 : tt M., Afur 1 H Mm S II U I BUM. AfU-r 1 U M« • II It | More A fU-r I '*•»*». 4 II U i Mm. Af,,, SPINDLE-TUBER 1 It Mot. 1 II W {Mm. I Attar • &lt; M IMm S II ti BWor, After I tt Brian a u it im» ! Altar I MM- 4 II It M^ After PteauJ D— h«c M— T—p«t»tm» dMfd F«bru»ry ». p&lt;Mtt due April 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 13 Table 1. — Conclided. — Effect of temperature upon the xi/mp - tonm of certain degeneration (lixeaxt « appearing on the foliage developed during the period of growth, (/) before and ( II ) after the change of temperature* Planted December 22 Temperature chanted February 9, plants dug April IS Symptoms Foliate IVn,i formed before I M I Miscellaneous Penod Infill before M Miscellani Plant ..1 Temp. or after * g i? * notes No. troth *C. temperature f a 3 1 = g I I I I ' I I I SPINDLE-TUBER + MILD MOSAIC ■The symbols deaifnate the severity of the symptoms, i. *., + = very distinct, * = moder - ately distinct, - = slifht, 0 = absent. The absence of any symbol indicates that the symptom did not appear at any time durinf the experiment. *The abbreviation S. T. under miscellaneous refers to the spindle-tuber symptoms on the new tubers. was probably the least permanent symptom. When plants were transferred to higher temperatures, one of the first changes was the decrease and usually the elimination of wrinkling. Curling and rugosity reacted similarly, both being less persistent than ruffling and more persistent than wrinkling. 1 2 i I I IS Before . + * + + + (Uprifhtnee. II SS ' Before * * — * * * Tuber. S. T. + i Altar * - 0 • - «l 1 20 ' Before - + + f Uprif htnee* II 25 Before » — — Btittlene*. i Altar * 0 • Tuber* S. T. - I 16 Before « • - 0 f Uprif htneei II 15 Before * - • - • Brittleneei After • + - + * I Tuber. S. T. + 1 SO Before 1 II 15 Before — — — j Tuber. S. T. + After - - 0 I Uprifhtnee. 1 Bilttlenes. Tuber. S. T. - {SKS2T ; Tuber. S. T. + Tuber. 8. T. + I | i I | | i i I l^ CURLY DWARF ■ i i i i i i i i i 1 2 4 I IS Before + + + + + +( Slight rolling II 26 Before . . . + + - + + + Uprif htnee* | Altar + *• + + + ( Britthnea* I SO Before + • * — - [ Uprightnee* i II «6 Before + *___* Tuber. S. T. + Altar + - 0 - - - 1 I 25 Before + -0*00 I Slight rolling ; II 16 Before .....+ + - * - + Uprifhtnee. Altar + + — + + + [ Tuber. S. T. « I M j Before + • 0 • 0 f Slif ht rollinf I II IS Before + * 0*0 Uprightnee. After + * * * * I Tuber* S. T. * I Slight rollinf Uprightnee. , Brittlenee. i Uprightnee. &lt; Tuber. S. T. + - - - Slight rolling Uprif hina ; Tuber* 3. T. - : Slight rolling 1 Uprifhtnee. Tuber. S. T. * </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 The symptoms of spindle-tuber were apparentiv les.- intiii - enced by temperature tlian those of mosaic. The ereetness. spin dleness. kikI slight dwarfing of tlie vine along with the ruffling &lt;&gt;f the leave- and the tuber symptoms, remained fairly constant The results presented here show that ;t temperature some - where between 2(1 and ■_'.*&gt; i&gt; the critical j&gt;oint in determining the presence or absence of mosaic symptoms. As the teni|&gt;era - lure is increased the symptoms tend to disappear, while the re - \ci-r i- true of lower temperatures. The data presented here agree in general with those of Johnson &lt;li&gt;2"2). One important fact that will 1*&gt; noted later in connection with field observations was the apparent greater severity of mild mosaic under certain conditions, for example at 1"&gt; . than a more severe type, such us medium plus mosaic or curly dwarf, growing under a different set of conditions, for example at 30 ( . tit must 1h- rememljered that in this experiment only one en inmental fact&lt;ir wa- varied and that variation in other factor - dd probably cause a change in the apparent temperature ct on symptoms. It i- true that the seed used in this experiment may have been infected with other diseases the previous year, as the\ had l&gt;eeii grown in the field -iibjert to infection. However, thi- H periniciit was not conducted in any attempt to prove or di-pro\&lt; - the previous diagnosis of the disease and the fact that the plant - of each disease type at each temj&gt;erature were grown from the same tnlter eliminated to a great extent all factors other than the one under consideration, i.e.. temj&gt;erature. It is evident from this one experiment, and from other tc«t - made showing the same results, that the symptoms of these di-eases may vary so greatly under different conditions that it would l»e an impossible task to attempt to classifv such disease* in commercial fields. While it may lie held that this experiment was conducted under different conditions from those occurring in the field, it will be shown later that such results can Im- ob - tained tinder field conditions. EFFECT OF SUNLICHT ON THE SYMPTOMS FEBR 19, 1923. TO MAY 25. 192S I*-ing mild mosaic, medium plus mosaic, and curly dwarf need tulnrs from the same source a- in the previous ex|&gt;eriment. a preliminary test was made of the effect of shading on mosaic symptoms. Tulter- from these :5 lot- were halved and one-half grown in direct sunlight while the other half was grown under </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 15 •J thicknesses of cheesecloth. Healthy tubers were planted and grown under the same conditions. The air teinj&gt;erature was kept at approximately 18° C. and the soil was kept at a rather high soil moisture content. The nwttling of the foliage was in every instance more dis - tinct under shade than in the sunlight altho it was present on nil plants. Rolling, streaking, and burning were present on the medium plus mosaic and curly dwarf plants in the sunlight and absent under shade. The streaking occurred only on the steins and petioles. Wrinkling, ruffling, rugosity, brittleness and curl - ing varied considerably during the experiment l&gt;oth in sunlight and shade and no clear cut difference was noted under the •! conditions. Rolling, uprightness, rigidity, streaking, and dwarf - ing were present in medium plus mosaic and curly dwarf plants and iib-cnt in mild mosaic plants. In all instances the symp - toms were more severe in curly dwarf plants. While the number of plants was small, a clear cut difference was present in regard to mottling and rolling. More extensive and carefully controlled experiments may show differences in the appearance of other symptoms not evi - dent in this preliminary test. There was a distinct difference in what might lie termed the severity of the disease, with the 3 types used under both con - ditions. FIELD EXPERIMENTS III 1!&gt;"2S experiments were conducted in an effort to determine the effect of environmental conditions on the symptoms of these diseases in the field. Method*. — Ex(&gt;eriniental plots were located in various sec - tions of western Nebraska. The potatoes were grown under different conditions and with different dates of planting as fol - low- : Plot A— Planted May 15 — Scotts Bluff Substation. Mitchell. Nebraska. Plot H— Planted May 15 — Scotts Bluff Substation. Mitchell. Nebraska, irrigated. Plot C— Planted June 1— Scotts Bluff Substation. Mitchell. Nebraska, irrigated. Plot D — Planted June 1 — August Gadeken's farm. Bushnell. Nebraska. Plot E — Planted May 10— Muldoon farm. Dawes table Chadron. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 F — Planted June 1 — Muldoon farm. Dawes table f. 1. — (iraph showing air temperatures for all 1923 Experimental Plots. Plots E, F, G, and D represented by mean weekly temperatures. Plots A. B. and C represented by the mean temperatures for the periods between the mosiac readings as listed in Tables 2-7 All mean temperatures obtained from 2-hour readings, i.e.. 12 readings every 24 hour* instead of usinK maximum and minimum temperatures. tubers from the same hill were used similarly. Air temperature records were kept at each plot (figure 1) and soil moistures were also determined weekly in the plots located at Mitchell. Rainfall and sunshine records were obtained from the IT. S. Weather Bureau records made at the Substation. In Plots A and B. notes were taken on the date of emergence, and the mosaic readings were made at least once a week until the middle of August, partly by the author and partly by Mr. William Morrow. Field Assistant. In the other plots, readings were Chadron, Nebraska. Plot G— Planted June 20— Muldoon farm, Dawes uble. C'hadron, Nebraska. In each of these plots potatoes were planted from the same source and with the same diseases as those listed on page 10. The seed used was cut into pieces averaging about -V) gins, in weight. When possible, the different pieces from the same tuber were planted in different plots in sequence. In other cases. 1 s /ttVdHC ■^/•E/G flr^Q I/O i I s -■■- v % W *-n I </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 17 made :\ times during the season by the author. At digging time, all hills were dug. weighed and graded separately. h'tMiiitx. — Xo attempt will be made here to take up the records of the symptoms occurring on the individual plants of each plot, but some specific examples of the effect of external conditions on the appearance of the symptoms will be shown. Fm general it can Ih&gt; said that the differences in symptoms be - tween the different plots were no greater than the differences observed during the season in any one plot. As an example. Tabij: 2. — Symptoms appearing on mild mosaic plants. Plot A &gt;Ths nabob and in Tables 2-6. 7 and 8 refer to tht decree of severity of each .ymptom as nprassntsa by Igwas 1 to 5, the extremes being: 1 — •• ver/ alight" and 6 — "vary aevera." These were the a Tray symptoms on all plants. Usually the symptoms were identical or nearly so in all plants of earn disease. The omission of any symbol indicates that the symptom did not appear. \nt» I I i i Date !j S &gt; « U I a 5 i I I I 1 June 15 I __I__L_^_ L_L_L 2 1 1 -- June 19 -....- I I - I .... .............. .......... June 23 rr--,.,.ll, tfc£ — k- — M— M— h- h-h-h-h-[ June 27 June 30 July 4 __Ld_ __ __1_ . ... i i i . . July 10 July 14 July 18 July 22 July 26 Aug. «... Aug. 8 Aug. 11 Auk. 16 ri : __ .... S 2 1 2 * 1 2 1 8 12 2 11 S 3 S S ! 1 2 .4 2 t t 1 | 2 4 2 ! 2 3 1 3 i 1 8 ! 2 3^2 2 ... ! __^ . ....... .. .__i — </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 the changes will l&gt;e shown in detail only for Plot A. In examin - ing the following table*, it is well to keep in mind the tempera - ture curves shown in figure 1. The most marked differences occurred, as in the greenhou!*&gt; experiment, with the mild mosaic plants. It will be. see.n from Table -1 that the symptoms during the early season were not very reliable, but as the seaxm progressed they became more fixed. Comparing Table _' with the temperature curve shown in figure 1 for Plot A. it will lie seen that from June SO to July 10 the temperature rose rapidly, and this corresponds with the dis - appearance of the few symptoms previously present. A sharp drop in teni|)eratiirt' after the 10th accompanied by O.H inch of rain and a decrease in sunshine resulted in the reappearance of the symptoms in a more serious form. This was followed by another sharp rise in teui|&gt;erature resulting in the disappearance of mottling and a smoothing out of the previously wrinkled leaves. It is evident that with the increased age of the plant the effect of teiuj&gt;ei-atiire on such symptoms as wrinkling and rugosity is not as marked as on the younger plant. Another drop in temperature accompanied by rainfall resulted in the second reappearance of mottling as well as other leaf symptoms. which continued to be very evident thruout the remainder of the season during which record* were obtainable. While the mottling .showed greater changes than apjx'ared in the green - house experiment, the author believes this to have l&gt;een due to the fact that the intense sunlight occurring during these periods of high temperature was great enough to cause these change-, while in the greenhouse, as already noted, the sunlight was weak. At the altitude of this experiment, about 4.000 ft. a- in many other regions of the West, the sunlight is intense enough •luring the middle of the day to caux- the leave- to droop and become flaccid. In Table 'A are shown the symptoms for the plants listed a&gt; "medium plus mosaic", also in Plot A. We find the same gen - eral changes as shown in Table •!. The mottling was not a - evident on these plants as on those listed as mild mosaic. How - ever, this mottling and also curling showed the greatest effects of teni|K»rature changes, altho the severity of all t&gt;ther leaf symptoms was also decreased during the same periods. The addition of uprightness and rigidity to the list of symptoms as well as the increase in ruffling was probably due to the spindle - tuber apparently present in this combination called medium plus mosaic. Other symptoms, as rugosity and curling, were greater than in mild mosaic. The same general relation to the effect of temperature is evident. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">ENVIRONMENT AND i OTATO DEGENERATION DISEASES 19 I' AHI.K :i. Symptom* tl /&gt;/m&lt;i ri n (/ on mrrfititn /&gt;/»* ntoxttii plant*. Pint A ft plant- p For txpluution of lymbob see Table 2 III Table 4 are listed the symptoms of plants atfecteil with spindle-tuber -(-mild mosaic. These plants appeared more seri - ously diseased than the medium plus mosaic plants. The up - rightness and rijfidity of the plants were more marked, and dwarfing occurred that was not evident in the other plant* listed in Table* •! and 3. A decrease in the {Terminating power of such s«&gt;ed was also evident. Here again the same genera 1 effect of temperature on the symptoms was noticeable. Mottling was the least permanent symptom. The other leaf characters showed very slight changes Date June 15 I I * i 1 1 I I 1 I I I * - g 1 Lilllllli l HA 1 1 1 •■•'••- June 19 112 1 l~- - I L 111 June 23 •N» •■■• - — !— — — I— i— — — — — — June 27 •■ ■ 1 I ill ■ ■■ ■■•■ -!— M— — — — — — June 30 . 1 1 1 I 1 ... 2 I 1 1 July 4 i 1 l l ~ 2 ~*\*\ " !•■■ — — — — — —;—!— — —I— July 10 ■ h ! 2 ' ' 1 ■■ ■■!■■■ M — July 14 I L' I A i 2 5 July 18 ... 1 2 2 ... 1 I 1 ■ — July 22 12 2 2 2 1 July 2% — — — ; 1 2 | 3 3 3 2 1 — ! 1— I !—!—!— I — Aug. 4 2 3 I 3 3 3 j 4 I 1 Aug. •.... 1 3 » j 4 2 3 — . 1.1 Aug. 11 1 3 8 4l2 3 Aug. 16 "l : 4 [71 4 2 ~3 " .: </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 4. — Symptom* appearing on npindle-tnber-\-mihl »/.&lt;*.//'. plant*. Plot A d plants) 1 - L'For i^llMrtn. of tymboh «m T.bie 1. TkfM md pians (ailed to terminate . Averse* f»nnin»tion 8 days later than mild Mimic that could be oorrelat«d with teni|)eratur«'. indicating that tl i« - more serious the manifestation of disease, the le^s will be the effect of external factors. Table 5 shows the symptoms of curly dwarf plants listwl in the same manner. The effects of changes in temperature as noted for the other disease types were here hardly discernible. The greatest change noticeable in the field was in regard to rigidity and brittleness which decreased during the hot, dry periods. It is true, however, that if the numerical symbols representing the severity of the symptoms be added for the Date Date I | I | |l I ill I Jlf I | I I ! I I I'! ! ill till I I i! _| i I I 1 , I ! I 1 I 1__ 1 1 June 15 . . . . . I .111)1 June 19 «-» ........... I ............... 1 ................ Iune23 i^— — — t— — 7-hHiz •• . : | | ...... . 1 1 1 ! r~ * tune 27 • ., .2 1 2 tune 30 fuly m 4 1 222 211 2 3 2 1 4 2 1 (uly 10. . 2 I I I 1 1 I ■ I I I I 1 I I I 1 'u'yi* *H . .1 ...Hi. 4 . . 2 2 ............... 1 fuly 18 .. i 2 r*~i 8 * • ' ill fu.y22. illy 22 .1 1 I... I I 2 j 3 - 2 i 3 8 1 .............. ■ 1 • S^^ 6 4 2 4 6 3 4 i -■I fuly26 ■■■•••■--"-"•■•■•■■■••• ,u«. 4... «• « ....... S3 2 3 3 3 51 ............ i . . lUf . 8 1 1 1 6 I 2 1 | 2 3 t 2 ,-,.11 ! | j 1 5 2|2 2 2 2|2 i « ■ t t t Tfi '~~T~ </seg>
            <seg id="p021">For explanation of symbols am Table 2. various dates it will be found that there was again a slight de - crease during the period from July 14 to 22, with the greatest number occurring on July 2fi, thus corresponding with the other types. Differences were also noted in the field that were impossible to tabulate. It was clearly evident again that the more severe disease types react only slightly to temperature. The outstanding plant symptom here was the severe dwarfing occurring thruout the season. The addition of streaking and leaf dropping to the symptoms was apparently the result of the addition of ''leafrolling mosaic" to spindle-tuber. These symp - toms were more marked in the latter part of the season. Environment and Potato 1 Degeneration Diseases 21 I'abi.k ."). — Symptoms appearing ok (k plant i curly dwarf plants. Plot A !*/ Date June 15 June 19 | ]f | f | I § I I I I 1 1 2 o 1 S s j ]! — ......... ... — M I— :- — - — l i ... June 23 June 27 - 2 1 2 1 2 3 1 1 1 1 i H - - — H - — 2 4 2 4 2 3 3 4 4 2 3 5 2 4 3 4 6 5 5 5 4 5 6 4 3 5 4 4 with early t 2 ... June 30 July 4 . July 10 July 14 July 18 July 22 '. 3 1 5 4 6 4 .... i 8 4 5 6 3 5 5 5 3 5 5 5 4 3 4 — 4 1 — H H H — - - — r— — - H — i - m i H m H - H - H H — —i - H July 26 Aug. 4 Aug. 8 Aug. 11 Aug. 16 5 5 4 5 5 5 3 5 6 1 ... 1 3 4 ...I t ... I 3 5 Practically defoliated » 2 - H 1 2 H i 2 2 H - i 5 Dligh .i ■ j .1 i .1 ! it </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 p i It i&gt; c\ ich'iit fnmi this experiment that tin- differences » served on these plants during the season were s&lt;&gt; jrivat that reading for mosaic |&gt;errenta&lt;res or for disease types iiim&lt;I&lt;- duri certain parts of the season would !&gt;&lt;• subject to great error. June 19 i June 23 1 1 June 28 July 4 July 10 July 14 1 1 July IX 1 July 22 Aug. 4 2 2 1 9 Aug. 8 4 2 1 L ! 3 1 Aug. 11 5 2 2 Aug. 15 5 3 2 1 'For riplmnmtion of aymbob ««• Tabl T.vklk (I. — Soil inoi*turi '■'•/" ■&gt; **&lt; •/ a* /» •/■ rent of moist u timU. /'/of* .1. Ii.,,,.,1 &lt; . W i June July Aft Sfpumt une u 10 19 26 3 10 18 M 2 9 18 25 S I l» Jf. HI Plot A 112 88 84 67 89 81 76 63 M 94 M U Plot B 96 71 IT 52 4X 52 65 66 66 XT 71 U I Plot C 105 77 84 M W 70 74 59 7M KM)' 7:i li. 1( l_ &gt;Irri(M«i. FaULK 7. ■■-&gt;///// I'tmiix •&gt;,&lt; mihl /,,,,*&lt;/;&lt; /.hint*. I'lot H (8 jthliit. • . " » I D - I] I I f I t l I l I I Hi June 15 2 June 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 23 i It 1^ alx) seen tliat readings on these diseases taken under liverse conditions and at different stages of growth would be -nhjt'ct t&lt;&gt; considerable error. For example, the medium plus noaair plants on July 18 and ±1 did not show as serious symp - obm a.-, tlif mild mosaic plants on July "2&lt;» and August 4. In comparing theae symptoms with those of the correspond - plants in Plot I&gt;. it was found that the symptoms thruout ilic waaaa were not as serious km in Plot A. The mild mosaic plants of Plot B arc described in Table 7 as an example of the htf'erences occurring. If this table Ik 1 compared with the. cor - esponding Table -J for Plot A, it will l&gt;e seen that the same itfcrcncc- in regard to temperature effects were, present, but tat all symptoms wen' less severe than in Plot A. One of the ffcivnces in the external factors l&gt;et\vet&gt;n these plots is shown Table &lt;',. representing the soil moisture as \wr cent of the soil noistuif equivalent. It is evident that the plants in Plot B wee grown under drier conditions, and this may have had some rti'ii on the symptoms. While this was an irrigated plot, no rrigation was made until after August 1"&gt;. i.e., after the last i-aii- readings, because of the abnormally wet weather. There ■re. however, other differences in the soil of these plots that may have contributed to the effect. Plot B was a medium silt loam, while Plot A was a light sandy loam. The temperatures were about the same, that is. the plots were Itx-ated on the same farm. Whether or not the soil moisture was chiefly responsible for the difference* in symptoms is not entirely clear. Soil moisture xperimentti an- l&gt;eing conducted in the greenhouse under control oiulitioiis to obtain more information on this point. Kffi rt of Date of I'luntiiKi mi f/n- Symptom*. — This test was ade to determine the influence of the age of the plants on their reaction to environment, as shown by changes in the symptoms. The :5 plots designated as E. K. and (i were planted at 20- dav intervals as follows: Plot K on May 10. F on Junefi. and (J on June 80. All plots were in the same field. A&gt; in previous experiments, the mild mosaic units were more influenced by environmental conditions than were the other unit&gt; and will be used for an example. Three readings were made, on July &lt;&gt;. July 18, and August 20. The temperature record of these plots is shown in figure 1. The mild mosaic readings are listed in Table 8. In this table the readings for the mild mosaic plants in Plot D are also listed. Inference to the temperature record for these plots in figure 1 will show a distinct correlation between the rise in tempera - ture and the disappearance of the symptoms. The mean weekly </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 Table 8. — Symptom* mi mild monair plant*, it* related t&lt;&gt; &lt;l&lt;it&gt; &lt;&gt;i pltiiitint/' 1 tei»i)X'rature&gt; had been low during the early jrrowtli of the plant - in Plot E and even tho the mean temperature rose to 7:5 F. during the week ending July 6. the symptoms were still plainly evident. On the younger plants in Plot F. the symptoms on this date were much slighter, the high temperatures of the pre - ceding week apparently having had a greater effect here than on the older plants in Plot E. The plants in Plot (1 were not up at this time. During the period between the first reading on July »i and the second reading on July 18, the temperature increased ami the result was evidenced by the disappearance of the symptoms d.u til 1 ili in liJ iili I 11 I ii i I is l I l i \ i I II PLOT E PLANTED MAY 10 I I I II III July 6 .... 67 2 1 2 2 | 3 2 **«•••■ « ...... ii i ...i : I 'II! :;•':;! PLOT P PLANTED JUNE 1 ' ' i I i I ! '&lt; I I I I i I i July « 36 1 ill 1 1 July 18 48 AU..20 ,1 1 3 8 5 5 i i i i ' ' i i PLOT G PLANTED JUNK I I I I I I I ! I July 18 28 Auf . 20 61 118 3 11 i i i ' i i i : ' PLOT D PLANTED JUNE 1 July ■.!..{» 1 1 2 2 1 July M IM ...... I 8 1 3 I . I Auf . 24 85 2 3 2 2 2 5 I I ■ , j ■ 'For explanation of •ymbok « Table 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 25 on the plants in Plot F. The older plants in Plot E showed symptoms that were slighter, but that still were as evident as those in Plot F at the previous reading. Xo symptoms were present on the young plants in Plot (i. The period from the second to the third readings, July 18 lo August 20. showed a marked decrease in temperature, and its effect wa&gt; made evident by the reappearance of the symptoms in Plot F in a severe form, and by the first appearance of symp - toms of the disease in Plot G. The plants in Plot E were ma - ture at this time. It is again evident that the older the plant is the slighter will be the effect of weather conditions that are unfavorable, for the appearance of disease symptoms, while in a young plant the symptoms either will fail to appear or may disappear during hot weather only to ap|iear later during a period of lower tem - perature. It may also l&gt;e noted that the late planting in Plot G &lt;lid not show symptoms until very late in the season, so that diseased hills in commercial fields planted late and growing under such weather conditions us were present here, might easily be missed if inspections were made early in the season. In the same way. if inspections were made during periods of hot weather, the diwMC in young plants such as those in Plot F would not be detected. The other mosaic units showed somewhat similar reactions. luit MM symptoms were present at all readings. Apparently the more severe diseases or combinations of diseases were less influenced bv the environment, as was found in Plot A. Considering all the units in general in Plots E, F. and G. it may l&gt;e said that the mosaic symptoms were more severe in the earlier plantings while the reverse was true of the spindle-tuber symptom* The plants listed in Plot I), grown from the same units as thaw in the other plots, showed more distinct symptoms on the mild mosaic units thruout the season. A glance at the tempera - ture record in figure 1 will show that the temperatures were ■hrmys lower than at the other plots listed. The seed was planted at al&gt;out the same time as in Plot F. and the readings were made at approximately the same dates. The absence of the symptoms on the mild mosaic plants at the second reading in Plot F and their distinctness in Plot D. are especially sig - nificant in regard to temperature. Effect on Yield. — While the previous experiment was not conducted in an effort to determine the effects of disease on yields, the difference in yield of the different disease types was </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 / I v Tablk !•. — Arena/? yield* in i/niinx /&gt;&lt; r /titwt from &lt;/&lt; - t&lt;l)n-x from all /tlotx. /!&gt;Ji , r /&gt;, riinriitx Number Total weight Marketable of plants so evident tliat tin- data were collected. In Table !• aiv sliowi the average yields per plant. This i- nude up from all of the ' plots previously listed. The niimlier of plant- was -&lt;&gt; small am the experimental error would 1*&gt; »» jjreat tliat no atteni|»t \va made to compare yields of the various plot&gt;. The averages hen presented are fairly representative. The mild imtsaii- units ii every case gave the greatest yield. The medium plus mosaic am the mild niosaic-rspindle-tiiher unit- varied in the different plot and gave about the same yield, being considerably less than tin mild mosaic. Spindle-tuber alone reduced the yields in even to a point approaching that of curly dwarf. Pr»ctioalh 100 per cent of the tubers produced by the mild mosaic - -pin dle-tul&gt;er plants and by spindle-tuber alone were of the ven severe elongated ty|&gt;e with numerous shallow eyes rharacteristii of tul&gt;ers affected with spindle-tuber, while curly dwarf plant: produced 40 per cent of this ty]*- of tul&gt;crs. indicating the ptm ence of spindle-tuU'r in this symptom complex. Medium plu mosaic evidently has its spindle-tulnr characteristics masked t. a great extent by the rugos*' mosaic present in its complex 1h - cause, of the tul&gt;ers produced, only J per cent showed chamc teristic spindle-tulier symptoms. No control plants are listed, as the rows grown for control showed enough serious mosaic to reduce tlie yields slightly be low those of the mild mosaic units. Grams Grams Mild mosaic . 47 435 336 Medium plus mosaic 24 264 197 Mild mosaic + spindle-tuber :J9 189 112 Spindle-tuber 25 173 6.S Curly dwarf 25 86 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases FIELD EXPERIMENTS WITH MISCELLANEOUS MOSAIC In l'.'i'l ii few preliminary experiments were started to study he effect &lt;&gt;f environment on the symptoms iind yields of mosaic !•' \l&lt; t/im/x. A number of tulnr units of Bliss Triumph ic -&lt;•&lt;■&lt; I ami also ■ number of units of rogued Bliss Triumph re obtained from Maine.' Another lot of seed containing a rh percentage of atomic was obtained from Minnesota. Con- \\ - were planted with certified Hlis- Triumphs from Ne- wa- divided by cutting the potatoes in :\ pieces and Temperature* for May 4 to July 13 inclusive. ind 3 Temperatures for June 10 to August 19 inrlusi Table Id rihows the mean weekly air temperature at the 3 l&gt;lot~ during the experiment. Further details regarding these |)lot~ have Im-cii previously dex-rihed. (loss (1928). No aphids were observed in any of these plot&gt; during the season. Re**lt*. Table 11 gives the data on the percentage of disease present and on the yields resulting from these tests. The mosaic reading- were baned chiefly on the leaf symptoms. The mosaic plants in all plots flhowed a -light dwarfing so that the rows were distinguishable. No attempt was made to examine each individual plant anv more rkwely than would be done, in certification work. In general, the Maine manic &gt;&lt;"ed showed the greatest amount of disease and produced the lowest yield in all plots. The Maine &gt;d obtained from Dr. E. S. Schultx. U. S. Dept. of Agriculture planting at 8 different locations, as follows: l'lot 1 Planted April 80 at Lincoln. Nebraska. Plot •_&gt; Planted May •_'&lt;) at the Substation at Mitchell. Ne- l&gt;raska. clry land culture. Plot :\ Planted May 20 at the Substation at Mitchell. Ne- braska, irrigated. T.\BUE 1&lt;&gt;. Mi mi irril.l 1/ ii'ir ti in j&gt;&lt; rtlfn n fur i &lt;wt /xirnti r&lt; iri'rkx f,,r ),i,its i. .'. iii,d •;. /«/ &lt; omparatire tteeka 1 12 3 456789! 10 Plot 1 57 57 81 76 69 79 79 78 80 79 Plots 2 and -i 1-\ 69 79 69 78 79 76 71 73 73 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 Table 11. — Di*enne perr-entiif/ex and yield* far 1921 experiment* Par eat of rli Total Total yield Number Percent — . . yield in per plant of term- gram* based on ■ad .nation Distinct j Mild \ No per check* as mosaic mosaic j symptom* plant 100 per cent rogiied seed ran al&gt;out the same as the Minnesota iuo&gt;aic -&lt;-ni. while the controls showed the lowest amount of disease ami the highest yields. AYhen comparing the different plots it is evident that the greatest amount of disease apj&gt;eared in Plot 1. with Plot- _' ami 3 following in the order of decreasing amounts. When it i&gt; con - sidered that all of these plots were planted with s«hm1 from the same mother tubers it can be seen that there was a very great difference in the appearance of the disease in the different plots, the masking being very great in Plot 3. and that these differ - ences can be explained by a comparison of the temperatures shown in Table 10. The mosaic readings in Plot 1 were made tMay 20, that is. at about the end of the second week shown Table 10. and it will be seen that the mean temperature aver - aged very low, below 60° F.. for this period. In Plots 2 and 3 the readings were made August 16, that is, during the tenth week as shown in Table 10. and it can be seen that the tempera- Per rrnt Per cent I Per cent I /'rr rent PLOT I i Gram* I Prr m,t Chaefca 217 tT.« 7.0 I M 81.4 187 100 Maine rofiMd 61 98.S ' J0.4 M.0 MM ,70 91) 46 95.S 4*4 48 A ll.« 77 41 Mi.n~tam.-ie M M.1 ! M.7 j S5.S | KJ 143 76 PLOT t — aaa US S74 100 Maine rocued HI 41.5 ti.0 17.* IT". :„« 89 Maine moeaic l» 50.0 tJl «.5 29.1 Mi 50 MinneaoU moaair ■I 73.1 lt.O M.O i -mi 247 66 PLOT 8 SI* «.7 .1 m 100 Maine roffued »« 78.4 5.7 5.7 Hy| ... 60 Maine moaaic 1^ 81 J 5.1 | 15 J T».4 Hi Minneaota moaair til i 8.1.8 4.5 ' 8.4 H I ■I 81 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 29 Ian averaged above 70° F. at this time and during the preced - ing weeks. The difference in the amount of disease between Plots 2 and :5 is not so easily explained because the tempera - lures were practically the same. Plot 3 was irrigated and the soil moisture during most of the experiment was higher than in Plot 2. but nevertheless the amount of mosaic symptoms appear - ing during the experiment was very small. The soil in Plot 3 wa&gt; more fertile and the plants made a much more rapid and vigorous growth. as evidenced bv the yields. It might be noted here that the conditions in Plot 1. where i lie greatest amount of disease was observable and where the lowest yields were obtained, were very similar to conditions pre - vailing in the southern potato states as will be pointed out later. A very low mean temperature and high soil moisture during the early growth of the plant favored the development of mosaic -yinptoms. and a very high temperature during the later part of the -eason was unfavorable for normal tuber development. It is clearly evident from these results that the time of mak - ing an examination in the field and the conditions under which the plants are growing must 1m&gt; considered if accurate percentage readings of mosaic are to be made. In 1922 a composite sample of the Maine mosaic seed from all three 1921 plots, comprising 330 plants, was planted at Lin - coln on May .V It might be expected that a considerable in- crease in the amount of mosaic would occur. Nevertheless sev - eral readings made during June and July showed only 5.6 j&gt;er cent of distinct mosaic. There was some dwarfing and curling &lt;&gt;f leaves of all plants, but this was also present on the plants in the control rows planted with certified seed. The healthy rows could not be distinguished from the mosaic. The abnormal a|)|&gt;earance of the leaves as well «s the low percentage of mosaic can probably l&gt;e explained by an examination of the temperature records for this year. The mean temperature during June and July when the mosaic readings were made was 75° F. for each month, and the soil moisture was considerably lower than in 1921. The germination and yield both total and marketable were as high for the mosaic rows as for the checks. In 1!&gt;:W. seed from the 1022 plot was divided by cutting tubers into a number of pieces and by dividing the tubers from the same hills so that corresponding seed pieces from the same hill were obtained. These were planted in the 7 different plots described on page 15. Mosaic readings were made at least 3 times during the season. The results tabulated in Table 12 are made up from the total symptoms, that is. if a plant showed distinct mosaic at any time during the season, it was listed </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 under that heading. The increase in the amount of distinct mosaic in Plot A over Plots H and (' was ii&lt;rain evident. Tin conditions influencing tlii&gt; have already lieen discussed mi pagi 23. Plot D as in the previous experiment showed a large amount of mosaic. The most noticeable difference, however. oc riirred in Plots K. F. and (i. These, as already noted, tw planted in the same Held at intervals of -Jit days. It was notice al)le that the first planting in Plot K showed bv far the greatest it. amount of mosaic, and that there was a considerable decrease n the next planting. Plot F. while in the last planting, in Plot (1 *&lt;l |&gt;er cent of the vine- appeared healthy. i — — ii — — . It must lie remembered that these different perwntagwti ol mosaic were found on plants obtained from the same seed am that this seed was from the l'.'2-J experiments grown in tun from the plants listed in Table !». originally obtained a&gt; ntoxaii units from Maine. It is ajrain clearly evident thai the diffid - ences obtained in the readings for mosaic were due to the con ditions under which the plants were growing rather than to ai increase in the actual amount of disease caused bv transmission. The yields of the various plots in Table 1"J are not listed, a - no clear-cut comparisons could l&gt;e made. The plants listed a - distinct mosaic did produce the lowest yield per hill, but th&lt; mild mosaic plants often outyielded the ones on which no mosaii symptoms ap(&gt;eared and sometimes yielded more than the con trol plants. Table 12. — l&gt;i*ea*e percentmje* from mix&lt;t Ihmeoux inimni, perinifiitx, MM N of mat &gt;er I Per cent germ- ination P« Distinct mosaic Vr rent of d i Mild mosaic 1 i — * a* No symptoms Per cent Per cent Pi r rent P'r ren 'lot A 112 9:1 26.6 49.5 17.1 'lot B M 96 8.6 41.7 49. R lot C m 99 6.9 MJ :!9.2 'lot D m 81 L'5.7 46.9 27.2 'lot E 52 100 17.2 53.S 'lot F 157 H2 ll.fi 46.5 39.7 'lot G 147 m 7.9 11.5 H0.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 31 CORRELATION OF EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS WITH THE MOSAIC INCIDENCE IN COMMERCIAL FIELDS Tin 1 results obtained under control conditions and in the previous field experiments justify the question as to the effect of environmental conditions on the selection of seed potatoes l»ein}r &gt;!iip|M'd to the South. While it has l&gt;een generally ob - served tliat these diseases are nmch more serious in the South. no published data are at hand comparing the growing condi - tions of the Smith with those of the northern seed producing state*. It lias alwav&gt; l&gt;een evident that seed sent South con- tained a higher percentage of degeneration diseases than was re - ported in the northern fields from which the seed was obtained. This was often attributed to aphid transmission late in the &gt;eason in the North resulting in a higher j)ercentage of disease in the progeny. The problem in Nebraska, that is. the increase of Mosaic both in our northern plantings as well as in the plants grown in the South, could not lie explained on this basis, inas- much ii&gt; aphid* are very rare in the dry hind sections of the West. In 1 !•:*&lt;•. l'.'-Jl. and l'.&gt;±i. the author in many observations could not find more than an occasional aphid present in a very small number of the fields inspected. In 1923, the high rainfall na- a-Miiiied t&lt;&gt; l«e more favorable for an infestation, and a close inspection &lt;&gt;f fields was made. • . . i The author peraonaJhr inspected a!&gt;out --'.(KM) acres of dry land potatoes and ih unable to find more than a trace of inhids. A survey 1 «as made of IS fields in Scotts Bluff County. ... * . 1 ««• ■ . ..I ■ .1 " • . If* II 1&lt;» of which were irrigated. Eight of the 10 irrigated fields con - tained aphid* on 18 per cent of the plants. Seven of the 8 dry land fields in the same locality contained aphids on 4 [km- cent f the plants. In all cmbh. only one or two aphids were present mi a plant. Ina*inuch a&gt; all *eed now certified in Nebraska and most of the general seed crop are grown under dry land conditions, the -mall number of aphids present in what can Ik- considered the most favorable year for an infestation, would hardly account for an\ considerable increase in the percentage of mosaic. The following record obtained from the certification records of the Horticultural Department. Nebraska Agricultural Col - lege i'nd from reports from Mr. &lt;1. L. Tiebout and Dr. ('. W. Edgerton of the Louisiana Agricultural Exjieriinent Station. given some idea of the amount of mosaic in northern grown seed potatoes when planted in the South. made by Mr. William Morrow. Field A«»i«tent. This sur </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 The average of mosaic in 4 strains grown in Nebraska in 1021 was 0.4 per cent. These 4 strains tested in I^oni-iaiiii in 1922 showed 10.0 per cent mosaic. The same seed grown by the same growers in commercial fields of Nebraska in li&gt;22 showed 1.0 per cent mosaic. In the 1!&gt;2:5 tests in Louisiana. 11.1 per cent mosaic was reported, while in 102:5 the records in Nebraska showed f&gt;.() per rent mosaic. These differences between Louisiana and Nebraska |&gt;ercentages in the same stock, can In- explained by tlie effect of different environmental conditions on the symp - toms of the disease. A certain number of strains of Bliss Triumphs grown in Ne - braska in 1022 were planted a.t Baton liouge. Louisiana, and mosaic readings were made by Mr. 11. &lt; ). Werner of the Horti - cultural Department of the Nebraska College of Agriculture, on April 23. 24. li&gt;i*:J. The following table show.- the average |&gt;er - centage. of mosaic }&gt;er field in the commercial fields in Nebraska in 1022. in the Louisiana tests in 102:5. and in the commercial fields grown from the same seed in Nebraska in 1923: Number of strains Nebraska 1922 Louisiana test 192:1 Nebraska 192 Per tent Per rent Percent 4" I ii » &amp;.S 16.9 !Some of the lots tested in Iymisiaim showed enough mo discourage their planting again in Nebraska and these field - •e listed separately. These tests show not only the effe&lt;-t of until- conditions on the visibility of mosaic symptoms, but ;dsn use to which such a test can l&gt;e put in eliminating undesirable -. It must also Im- noted that the Louisiana readings include plants grown in the test plot- while the readings in the coin - rcial fields of Nebra-ka would be influenced by roguing. In 12 most of the roguing was done after the mosaic reading - re" made so that the visible mosaic in the -train- planted in ,h Louisiana and Nebraska in l'.&gt;-_&gt;:5 had been removed. In !3 a considerable amount of mosaic had l»eeii removed from fields before the mosaic readings were made. These fact - would tend to increase the difference- shown in the shove table. Considering now the conditions under which these crop- were B»wn, we find a marked correlation between the weather con - ions and the amount of visible mosaic. In figure 2 the mean weekly temperatures for comparative weeks of different potato sections of the country are plotted. For this purpose a 2-month period was taken covering the time from the emergence of the plant to the time the foliage is fully developed. These periods may not be exactly comparable, but </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 33 Tut they are elose approximations made by a number of observers in the never*] localities. Mosaic readings are made in Nebraska chiefly in July, while in Louisiana the disease usually appears very marked in April. AVhile the -2-month period shown in figure - may extend over a greater length or time than that usuallv used for the detection of mosaic it is believed to cover the |ktum1 during which mosaic symptoms would be greatly in - tiueiu-ed by external conditions. Further monthly data are pre - sented in Table 13, covering a 3-month period and compar - ing the 1923 data for Brownsville and Louisiana, from which figure 2 is composed, with the normal monthly mean for those localities. It can be easily seen that Kimball. Nebraska, temperatures .ire consistently higher than the others and for (&gt; weeks are above 70 V. It is also true that these diseases are usually severe at the _' southern points and in Maine and this can be directly cor - related with the lower temperatures occurring in those localities. r i /70 ' , ,^^- &lt; — / ...I i y/ sr^ ' / / *-.. _I /r \ /i * . — -j / / / V MMB*u , Ntae — -- ! [ &amp;ATBN BOUS, U — — ■ — — PBtsaif isif.it. 5r. — 7~ BOOWKSWUi Ttr a aUhliiiiiinii ii|iii nil COMPaDATlvt-^ v/ECKS aph showing weekly mean temperatures for comparative weeks ito growing sections. . Nebraska. Tune 15 to August 15, six-year average. Me, Maine, June 15 to August 15, ten-year average, touge, Louisiana, March 15 to May 15, 1923. nllc, Texas, January 15 to March 15, 1923. -mal trmperatures !&gt;y months for Baton Rouge anil Brownsville a ■ I' Ma ks of &lt;iiffer« Feren e are shown </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 Tabu: 13. — X or null monthly menu trtupertitim . prfi'if/itatioit. a h&lt;I xmtx/i'iK fm com fHimtit'e month* in '/iff' nut poUitu xectionx .1 Com- June July Aufunt Kimb.ll. Nebr Jan. Feb. March Brownsville. Tex. June July August Prt*j*i|u»- Ule. Me. parative month. F Xvrwml Mi K.i.:i 64.2 71.1 72.6 69.7 67.6 1 48.4 56.4 59. K : tv l M i 4 65 M 4.7 M 2.4 1.7 3.5 &gt; : Ml :i KAYS LEAR ,AND PARTLY CLOUDY 1 l* i io&lt; 18 (it: IS 116) 10 (SO 15 (14) 1Z 116 4 I 'Normal temperature* and precipitation; Kimnall. Union Kouge. and Bn.« v the I). S Weather Bureau Month rumpiled from 6-year records. T urn o( the Maine Auric E»pt Si»t Eulated from the departure* from normal given b 1923. Normal and clear days for Kimball wen ine were obtained thru the courtesy of Dr. P&lt;&gt;lx l are from H to 11) year record* in every instan il Th. 'Flic usual assumption that southern p«&gt;tatoe&gt; ilo not make pood set'il Ih-i-hiisc of tin- liijfli temperature* at which they art- jfrown would apply, in the early crop at lea&gt;t. only to the |mti«mI ijurinfl which tuber formation takes place. At Utth Brownsville an&lt;l Uaton UniiiTi' tlif Icnipt'ial lire increases rapidly during the latei ■itap' of f! row th. while it decrease's in Maine and Nebraska : tin* would U' even more evident if the ln-t month of the potato «eas(»n wen 1 shown. If we compare the temperatures for the months in th* \;iriou - srotions during which mosaic determinations arc usually made. /. r.. from the third to the -ixth week inclusive ;i- shown in fijrure •2. it will U&gt; s«H'ii that there is considerable difference in the tem- Iterutures. It is also evident from Table 13 that no clear cut correlation can In- made between mosaic ami rainfall or even sunshine. Rainfall, however, is here considered only for the stated period of vrowth. and can often In&gt; correlated with lower teni|M'ratures and decreased sunlipht. If the precipitiition records of the mouths preceding; planting were considered, ii would influence the amount of moisture in the soil. Tlii&gt; would necessitate a comparison of the different soil I y pets ami &lt;-:iim&lt;&gt;t M«rch April May Ja Bmton Rouse, La. H TEMPERATUR \orwtal IW.I B ■ I \ «1 .0 58.6 Kh | «7.» 73.8 7S.S PRECIPITAT () 4. SI «.:) 4.7i 6.2 II. 8.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 35 undertaken here. It i&gt; clearly evident, however, that low nperatures ire oeeetmry for the appearance of mosaic symp- un- and iliat the mean temperatures in the southern states and i Maine art nmdi lower than for the corres|&gt;oiiding periods of .Towtli in Nebraska. The point used to represent temperature ■onditious in Nebraska. /'. &lt; .. Kimlmll. has even a lower mean temperature than other need potato producing sections of western Nebraska. V complete -ludv of the problem, however, must also take consideration the effect of these factors on plant growth. true that the number of clear days i- not greatly different •-c different HectKHis, as shown in Talile IS. If we would rutider the intensity of sunlight, however, it would be found ai the Nebraska fields are subjected at their high altitude to a ry interne sunlight which usually cause-, all the leaves to droop i midday and this factor in combination with high temperatures sually ill t pwmwi the risibility of mosaic symptoms. The record- here -hown explain very well the differences in c readings &lt;&gt;f mosaic in Nebraska and Louisiana as previously &gt;ted. The correlation shown for widely different locations can Iho he made for different seasons in the same region. The dif - ! erenoe in the amount of mosaic present in the commercial Held- Kimhall County. Nebraska, in L9S2 and 1!&gt;'_':5 was considerable i- shown by the following table: &gt;f fields Total acreage Average percentage of mosaic per field 44 607 i&gt;.«; 1333 3.0 \bmil Id |M*r cent of the lields in HfcM were planted with seed u th&lt; 1H-J-J crops. In lihi'2. no Held- were rejected in this unity on account of ino-aic: while in 1!&gt; - J:&gt;. It fields were re - •iteij. and arerajwd B.0 per cent mosaic h no aphids could be found and they were very scarce the inciva-c of disease could hardlv Ix- attributed to iphid tran-mission. If the weather conditions are considered, it is very plain that these re&gt;iilt- were not cau&gt;ed by aphid transmission, but that what probably occurred was a masking of the symptoms in l'.&gt;'2'2. tint- preventing successful rogning and seed selection. An ex - amination of figure '-\ will show that the mean weekly teiii|&gt;era - tiires for \'.)'J % 2 were abore 70 F. for the greater part of the -ea-on. The teni|M'iatures were highest during the period when inspections are usually made in the fields. In 10*23 the mean temperatures were consistently below 70° V. A comparison of </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 Flti. 3.- — Graph showing weekl K IM3 and 1923. Records taken at the \ hraska. Mi:m* obtained r"r rainfall ami sunshine shows an increase in the precipita 1023 over that of 1!&gt;'J"2. and a considerable decrease in the ! of clear days as tabulated In-low : June July August ■t.. 1923 1922 1923 1922 192.', 192 Clear days 13 22 10 15 12 1 Rainfall, inchr.i 4.70 2.08 2.48 1 .ok The saiiwe reaction evidently occurs in other mctioos a- shown by the data in Table 14, obtained from Dr. Folsom of the Maine Agricultural Experiment Station on the relation of weather conditions to the appearance of mosaic symptoms at Presque Isle, Maine, for the comparative years of 1921 and Folsoni notes that 1021. the poorest year for tin- appearance of mosaic symptoms and in which symptoms did not appear ii! some plots known to have the disease, had low precipitation for May. June, and July and a high mean temperature for July, compared with the normal, (see Table IS). In 19-23. the late-t year l&gt;otli for growth of the plants and the appearan&lt; f mosaic symptoms, late planting was correlated with low temperature in I oust/tea , mb 1922 1923 I L I A \A N s ~A 1111 1 *&gt;•! . ii -■f ■ ■c </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 37 Table 14. — Relation of weather to the appearance of mosaic symptoms at Presque Isle, Maine in 1921 and 1923 ' uJjTture P-iPiUtion Ctar £g Clear J£g 1*21— Poor kiomic nymptomn: l»2t — good mmtmic symptom*. May urn! low precipitation in May and June. This, how - ever, followed ti winter of heavy snowfall and the ground was very wet in May. Good mosaic symptoms appeared in 1923 and were correlated with low temperatures in July and August. DISCUSSION It has lieen shown that under control conditions high tetn- I M-ni tu res (above 70' F.) seriously decrease the visibility of mowic symptoms. The same effect hsis been observed in Held ••x|&gt;eriment&gt; ami in commercial fields. The mottling of mosaic leaves i&gt; decreased by high temperature and the addition of in - tense sunlight eliminates this symptom. High teni|&gt;eratiires tend ti) produce a smoother leaf, tints masking the symptoms of wrinkling, curling, rolling, and rugosity. High soil moistures apparently favor the appearance of such leaf symptoms. It must Ix' remembered, however, that under average field conditions in Nebraska, increased rainfall usually is accompanied by decreased temperatures and sunlight. When all 3 factors are controlled, temperature appears to have the greatest influence. Field experiments have shown that a short period (4 to 8 iliivs) &lt;»f high temperature with intense sunlight, eliminates the symptom* of mild mosaic. The symptoms are more affected by environmental conditions during the early growth of the plant and the effect decreases with age. The more severe types of 1921 rj: 121 123 19: "F. .,. in. In. .Vo. No. No. .Vo. May 53.4 46.5 1.63 u. » 10 14 10 June 58.8 59.2 1.58 0.82 13 7 21 6 July 71.8 62.4 2.49 4.32 19 5 16 6 August 60.8 58.8 5.43 2.32 15 8 15 11 Sept 56.3 54.1 3.15 2.98 16 6 20 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 mosaic do not react us rapidly or completely to external condi - tions as the milder t.\'|&gt;es. The date of plauling in the same locality resulted in a wide divergence in the amount of visible mosaic at any specified date. Taking all these factors into consideration, it must l»e ad - mitted that there will necessarily lie a large error in Held read ings made without regard to these factors. To make an accurate estimate of the amount of mosaic in a Held, it become- necessary to consider the date of planting and the environmental condi - tions under which the plant has lieen growing, particularly with reference to the |&gt;eriod immediately preceding the examination. Determination of mosaic 1 shoidd not Im- made on very voting plants unless under the most favorable conditions. a&gt; the symp - toms will lie masked more rapidly than on -lightly older plant-. Itoguing to Im- complete should he done only during periods when the appearance of the symptoms of the disease is favored by climatic conditions. It has !&gt;ecn shown that these results not only can explain to a large extent the variations in mosaic readings during any one year in a particular Held. l&gt;ut also the changes occurring during several seasons in the same locality or even the apparent increase in mosaic occurring when "northern grown" -eed from the west ern states is planted in the southern states. The examples shown in the southern states, i. ... liatou Kouge. Ijouisiana. and Brownsville. Texas, indicate that the tempera lures prevailing there, a- in Maine, are normsilly low enough during the early season to favor the appearance of mosaic symp toms. The reverse is true for Nebraska and probably a con-id erahle area in the West. The low temperature in the South din - ing the early period of growth is often followed by extremely high temperatures during the period of tuber formation, thus greatly decreasing their yields. In Nebraska, there nre indication- that mild mosaic does no) materially decrease the yield. However, accurate |&gt;ercentages of this type are difficult to obtain because of the rapid masking of symptoms. Combinations of this type of mosaic with -pindle - tulier would occur in the fields and would reduce the yields ma - terially. Therefore, there is no reason why this apparently le— injurious type of disease should be allowed any greater tolerance in seed potato*--. The reversing of certain tvpe- of the disease occurred when grown under different conditions. That is. under certain condi - tions, medium plus mosaic, or mild mosaic-|-spindle-tuher. ap - peared much less severe than mild mosaic grown under other con- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Environment and Potato Degeneration Diseases 39 ditioiis that were more favorable for the ap|&gt;eaiance of the symp - toms. 'Phis complicate:- the problem and makes it impossible to detect any particular disease t\|&gt;c with certainty, under field conditions, even when inx-ct transmission i:-. eliminated. Wliile mosaic symptoms are more evident with early planting and lower temperatures, t lit- reverse appears to l&gt;e true for spin - dle-tuber. Spindle-tuber and combinations of spindle-tuber with mosaic result in ;i greater decrease in vield than mosaic alone. — _ — p.- — - - - — - — . - — — In the opinion of the author, the effect of the hij;h teni|&gt;era - tin-*-, low rainfall, and intense sunlight in certain areas of the West i^ of n&gt; &lt;_n-eai iin port a nee as aphid transmission. They are often the chief factors responsible for the apparent increased amounts of mosaic in our seed stock, the masking of the symp - toms preventing jrood results from roguinj; and seed selection; Miid of these factors temperature is the most important. Further work is greatly needed in the West for the proper him tt-r-t a in 1 i n&lt;r of this pro)&gt;lem. which in most of its aspects is considerably different from those in the eastern states. This is trw regarding the environment, the varieties l&gt;eing grown, the niinilier of aphids present and the |H&gt;ssible presence of other in - -ect Mirriers of the dix-ax' a&gt; well as the native plants which mav !«■ pos&gt;il&gt;le over- wintering hosts. The work re|x&gt;rted in this publication is preliminary in nature and is liein^r followed by further studies on the effect of temperature, moisture, and sun- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">1 2 3 4 I. * I I 9 M 11 12 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 26 LITERATURE CITED Ducomet, V. 1923. Sub La Visibilite Des Symptomes De La Mosaique De La Pom me De Tkkkk Rpt. Int. Conf. of Phytopathology A Be. Bnt. Holland, p. 39-43. Gobs, R. W 1923. Relation ok En\iii«n \if\t and Otiikk Ka&lt; tors to Potato Wilt Cauhed by Fihakiiu Oxyspoki m. Neb. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 23, 84 p. Johnson, .lames 1922. The Relation or Ais Tempekatire to the Mokaii Diheam* of Potatoes and Other Plants, 'in Phytopathology v. 12. no. 9, p. 438-440. tig. I. Murphy, P. A 1921, (A). Investigation of Potato Diseases. Canada Expt Farms. Div. Bot. Bui. 44. ser. 2. 86 p. 35 flg: 1921, (B). Some Recent Work on Leaf Roll and Mosak . / Roy. Hort. Soc. Rpt. Internat. Potato Conf. p. 145-152. Peltier, (leorge I. 1923. A Stihy ok the Em ikon mentai Conditions Inhikmi- THE DlCYKMtPMK.NT of STEM Rl ST [\ THE AhhENI'E OK .' Al.TEII.NATK Ho.sl II INKEITION ST1IMKS WlTH F'l i I I \ Graminis Thitk i Kukm III imp Fokm IX. Nebr. Agr. Kx Sta. Re«. Bui. H, '&lt;1 l&gt; pis. 1 12. Quanjer. H. M 1921. New Wdhk on Leak-Ciki ami Ai i.ieii Diheahkh in Hoi In Roy. Hort Soo. Rpt Internat. Potato Conf. p. 127 14 1923. Uk.\»:k.m Kkmark- on Potato Disk.ask He ( Rpt. Internat. Conf. of Phytopathology and Kron. Kntomol ogy. Holland, p. 23 28. pig. 1-4. Schultx. E. S.. Kolsoni, Donald, et al 1919. lXVESTUiATIONH &lt;)\ THE MoSAII Dltil IS* Of rllE Illlsll l'c In Jour, of Agr. Res v. 17. no. fi. p. 247-27:?. col. pi. A-E 25-30. Schultz, E. S., k Kolsoni. Donald 1920. Transmission of the Mokaii Diska.sk of Ikisii Potatoes It; Jour. Agr. Res. v. 19, no. 7. B. :!!."&gt; :!:!7. pis. 49 .".«. 1921. Leafroll, Net-Necrosis and Spindling-Sprout of the AgT. Res. v. 21, no. 1, p. 47-80, Irish Potato. In Jour. pU. 1-12. 1923. Transmission. Variation and Control ok Certain Deokn kkation Diskamks ok Irish PoTAToes. In Jour. Agr. Res. v 25. no. 2, p. 43-117. pis 1-15. &lt;M. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>