<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00039">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00039</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>State of Nebraska Division of Fire Prevention Sixteenth Annual Report 1924</title>
               <date value="1924">1924</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION \ Sixteenth Annual Report 1924 CHARLES W. BRYAN GOVERNOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">• </seg>
            <seg id="p003">STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Office of State Fire Marshal Hon. Charles W. Bryan, Governor, State of Nebraska. Dear Sir: As required by law, I have the honor to transmit to you herewith the 18th Annual Report of the Division of Fire Prevention. It is gratifying to say that there is being manifested more interest in fire prevention. This has been accomplished by a more general co - operation by the public. Fire departments and companies have been active in the "prevention" of fires. Effective service has been rendered by the various chambers of commerce throughout the state. The pub - licity given by the press to this great cause has proved its effective - ness. Civic leagues and schools rendered valuable assistance. The fire loss for 1924 is less than any year since 1919. Fire de - partments and companies are being provided with more adequate fire - htfhting equipment, which has added materially in reducing the fire loss. The fire loss for 1924 amount to $2,698,486.46 less than in 1923. The fire losses exclusive of Lincoln and Omaha are over a million dollars less tKan last year. Our volunteer companies are to be commended in this connection. In the year 192S, 316 towns had fire chiefs. At the close of 1924 we have 397, or a gain of 81 towns. There are, however, about 200 towns that show a population of 100 or over without fire chiefs. There were 73 incendiary tires during the year, requiring special investigation. There were 159 fires of "unknown" origin. The cir - cumstances and facts disclosed by investigation were such that they could not be otherwise classified, not being able to ascertain the cause. In accordance with the provision of Section 8150, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1922, there has been collected from Fire Insurance Com - panies and transmitted to the State Treasurer during the year the sum of $21,746.40. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 The following gives our record of the activities of the department: INSPECTIONS DURING 1924 During: the year 1924 our inspectors inspected 309 towns and cities in Nebraska. During this time 8,765 inspections have been made arm 8,822 orders issued in the work of fire prevention. The inspection record shows the following; orders issued: Gasoline and kerosene 34Z Cleanup 3194 Chimney - 432 Electric Wiring- 2009 Metal or asbestos under stove 566 --3194 Metal or asbestos under stove Red ligfrt and Are escape 52 Repair building 182 Condemnations recommended 23 __ 182 Condemnations recommended Miscellaneous . 1842 Total orders issued . 8822 Total inspections made 8765 Number of towns inspected 9ti&amp; Number of fires investigated in 19B4 73 Number arrested for arson 20 Number convicted for arson. CAUSES OF FIRES REPORTED TO THIS OFFICE FROM DEC. 1, 1923 TO DEC. 1, 1924 Balance ot Omaha Lincoln State Total Spark* from chimney on roof 364 42 78" 474 Defective chimney and stove pipe 25 3 43 71 Children and matches 23 2 12 37 Oil stoves 19 4 41 64 Defective electric wiring 23 13 46 82 Cigarettes and cigars 36 1 14 51 Overheated stoves, furnaces and pipes 29 8 38 75 Oil burners * 7 1 7 15 Incendiary .. 19 6 48 73 TP Electric iron 17 1 6 24 Mice and matches 8 7 15 Communicated fires 16 -_ 18 34 Spontaneous combustion 25 3 14 42 Lamp explosion 4 2 6 Lightning 1 — 15 16 Soarks from locomotive 2 8 10 4—26 1 -- 15 16 Moving picture film S 3 6 Hot ashes 16 2 12 30 Bonfire and burning trash 42 4 12 58 Short circuit in automobile 5 5 7 17 Unknown 43 11 105 159 Carelessness with matches 18 1 1 20 Paper and rag3 pasted over flue hole 7 18 GtM Dlate 5 5 Gasoline lantern 4 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Starting fire with coaJ oil or gasoline 2 4 6 Candles and candles on Christinas trees 9 9 Candles and candles on Christmas trees 9 Thawing out water pipes , 5 1 6 Fire place 3 — 3 6 Gasoline explosion 11 1 8 20 Fireworks 5 13 9 Painter's and Plumber's Wow pots 2—13 Oil heate«l on stove 2 2 4 8 Wood and inflammables too near hot stove or pipes 9 — 12 21 Smoking in bed . 1 _. 2 I Oil overflowed into furnace pit 3 14 Chicken brooder and incubator 2 2 4 Steam pipe 1113 &lt;"-as Heater 111 Hot metal __ 1 1 Ammonia explosion 1 1 Short circuit on radio »et 1 — 1 From friction 5 &amp; Water back in stove exploded 1 1 Fumes from alcohol took fire 2 t ignition of kerosene from leak in pipe 1 1 Grease in conveyor took fire 1 1 Lighted gas jet against wall 1 — 1 Chemical explosion 1 1 Hot nvrteor , _. 1.1 Sun's rays on defective glass in window set fire to mattresses 1 1 Fumigating building 1 1 DEATHS AND INJURIES Deaths Injuries Men 10 41 Women 15 10 Children 9 8 Total 34 59 CAUSES Deaths Injuries Bonfires . 4 1 Gasoline, kerosene and oils 18 36 Hot ashes in wooden box 1 2 Smoking in bed 1 2 Children ami matches 2 Electric wires 1 2 Acetylene gas tanks ' 2 1 Alcohol igniting 2 Cias stove explosions — 3 Open flame and lights * 4 __ Unknown 1 1 3 Moving picture film flrea 8 Firemen fighting fires 6 Total 34 59 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS AND PROSECUTIONS This department made seventy-three investigations, and found that moat of them were set fires, but it was impossible to get sufficient evi - dence in most cases to convict. The cases were dropped until further evidence appears. The following arrests ami convictions were made: Abe Hamir-ett, Macy, Nebraska. Fire Aug. 21, 1923. Pool hall. Abe Hammett lost life. Feb. 1, 1924, Arthur Kyriss, proprietor rival pool hall, confessed hiring Lon Watson and Clarence Stewart, of Walt Hill, to burn building. Also confessed hiring Ed Garner several months previous to burn building but failed. Garner pled guilty and was bound over to district court. Kyriss, Watson and Stewart released on $10,000 bonds. Kyriss later kille&lt;! in Iowa. Case against others still pending, but both are serving time on grand larceny. Prank I. Olson, Grand Island. Fire at Ord, Feb. 9, 1924. Con - victed May 9 of having hired Edward M. Anderson to burn his barn at Ord. Anderson confessed and convicted. Olson convicted and ap - l&gt;emled to supreme court. Cast- pending. David, John and Alico (sister) Gard, Omaha. Fire Feb. 15, 1924. Incendiary. Over-insurance. Dismised before coming to trial. Alex. Swanstoski, Ogalalla. Fire Mar. 13, 1924. Bound over to district court for murder of John Jefferies and setting fire to house to hide crime. Case pending. Mrs. Grace Mattison, Central City. Fire April 20, 1924. Trial May 22. Acquitted of arson charge. Ross Wainwright, Grand Island. Fire Mar. 25, 1924. Rival dance pavillion. Incendiary. Convicted together with accomplice, George Durbin. Ira Mann, farmer, near Fairbury. Fire Aug. 7, 1924. Incendiary Over-insurance. Confessed and convicted. James N. Pappas, Deweese . Fire Oct. 1. Owner General Store. Incendiary. Pappas and Robert Roth, accomplice, convicted. William Fiedler, near Surprise. Fire Oct. 14, 1924. Charged with arson. Threshing machine. Tried and case dismissed. Insufficient pviavnoBL F. Mauro, Joe Benak, and Paul Genco, Omaha. Fire Nov. 11, 1924. Italian grocery store and sausage factory. Stock and fixtures $8,000. Stock insured for $21,200. Arson charge. Case dismissed Nov. 18. Insufficient evidence. DEATHS CAUSED BY FIRE Arlington Nina Schlapper, a fourteen year old girl succumbed to burns caused by coal oil lamp exploding which she was lighting. Ainaworth Virginia Guy, four years old. Clothes caught fire from cook stove. Died from burns. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Albion Frank Flakus died of bums received while starting fire in kitchen range with gasoline — a daily practice of his. » Beatrice Frank Carter (colored) died from burns received when he overturned an oil lamp. Chester Miss Leota Brunbaugh, nineteen, a school teacher, died from burns received when she threw kerosene on a Cozad Mrs. J. W. Neslund died from burns received when her clothing caught fire from an explosion caused by kerosene-soaked rag with which she was wiping off a stove. Cairo Mrs. Otto Da hike and three year old son dead from burns caused by fire in a straw shed. Mrs. Dahlke met her death in trying to rescue the child. Fremont Kmil Larson, fifty-six, burned to death in his bed. Cause of fire, kerosene light exploded. Grand Isfctnd Arlene, three year old daughter of James Rigsly, died from burns received when her clothes caught fire while playing around a bonfire. Hubbell Daughter, five, and son, four, children of Ed Browe. died from bums received because father started fire with kerosene. Humboldt The four year old son of Mr. and Mrs. Emil Stalder was fatally burned while playing around a bonfire. Henderson Isaac -V. Peters died from burns received at the National Refining Oil Station. Homer Mrs. Sam Garner and her three year old child died from bums received when oil took fire that she wan heating on top of stove. Kearney Mrs. Harold Kerwood died from burns received when her house took fire. Saved her baby by throwing it out of an upstairs window. Lincoln Holland McDougal, age twenty-one, died from burns received when a gasoline blow torch which he was us - ing exploded. Naponee Mrs. Harvey Stover burned to death. Clothing caught fire from bonfire. Norfolk Miss Christinp Lundquist, forty-four years old, died from burns received from heating linseed oil on stove. Oil took fire and in trying to get it out of house, caught her clothes on fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 &gt; Omaha Leo Jankowski, seventy-six years old, burned to death in rooming house fire, which was caused by janitor putting hot ashes in wooden box. Omaha Marie Mano, three years old, died of burns when het clothes caught fire from bonfire. Omaha Axel Swanson Med of bums received in the explosion and fire at the United States Oil Works. Omaha Mrs. Lillian Erickson and her baby boy ten months old died of burns caused by explosion of kerosene use&lt;l to light kitchen stove. Omaha August Halagordo, seventeen years old, burned and mangled. Died from explosion of acetylene tank. Omaha Mrs. Mabel Voy, age thirty-five, died from burns caus - ed by her dress catching fire from cigarette. Omaha Hans Johnson, sixty years old, died of burns received when electric light wires shorted and exploded fume - in the interior of a gasoline tank car which he was cleaning. • Omaha Mrs. Martin Dunham, eighty, burned to death while looking for some clothes in a closet with a lighten candle. Mrs. Eugenia M. Earl, ninety-two year old recluse, burned to death when she attempted to put out a fire started by an over-heated kitchen range in her home. Pawnee City- Mrs. George Burg died from burns received in a fire that destroyed her home, cause, defective electric wir - ing. Mrs. Joseph Payton, aged seventy-six, burned to death while trying to start tire in kitchen stove with kero - sene. University Place Mrs. Myrtle Clifton died from burns received while fill - ing and lighting an oil stove. BURNS AND INJURIES CAUSED BY FIRES Arlington Mr. and Mrs. Chas. Schlapper and two children, bo&gt; and girl, painfully burned from explosion of coal oil lamp which caused the death of another girl. MM Spring,. Mrs. J. W. Marples burned about face and hands when fat meat she was rendering caught fire. Perry Witchman, age fifteen, received severe burns on face and hands when he put lighted match in an empty gasoline tank. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">'^A^H^^^^^^^^^^a^r- 9 Bramani Louis Merph, a blacksmith, had a hand and arm severe - ly burned when the hose burst on the oxygen tank. Burwell Mrs. Julius Phillips was badly burned when gasoline took fire from friction while cleaning clothes. Chadron Mrs. Welling severely burned by alcohol which she was disposing of as state officers raided her husband's shoe shop. Dorchester Firemen slightly burned fighting a bam fire. Cause unknown. Doniphan Mr. Graf, owner of garage, badly burned when shut - ting off faucet on gasoline tank wagon which had tak - en fire from static electricity while delivering oil. Kremont Harry Hauser, fireman, slightly hurt in fall from lad - der while fighting fire at a residence. Gretna Mrs. Wm. Hemphill and baby slightly burned about face and hands. Mrs. Hemphill was heating gasoline in pan of water on cook stove. Guide Rock I.. C. Farquhar, movie operator, slightly burned about face and hands when fumes of film in booth exploded. Hershev Sixteen year old son of Wm. Cross burned on hands and fare, caused by starting fire with gasoline, think - ing it was kerosene. Havelock J. W. Hoffman, movie operator, severely burned from reel of film. Kearney Iva Messner, sixteen year old girl, badly burned in us - ing kerosene to start fire. Knnball Miss Frances Grubb severely burned by explosion of kerosene with which she was starting fire. Kearm v J. McNulty slightly burned on face and hands from the gasoline tank on his auto, which took fire while filling. Kearney Truck driver of A. B. A. Oil Company slightly burned about face and hands when explosion occurred at the storage station. Cause probably static electricity. Kearney C. R. Barlow fell from roof and fractured hip while fighting a fire which destroyed his home. Cause, de - fective chimney. Kearney A. M. Wescott burned on hands and face from a fire caused by oil burner in cook stove. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 R. W. Campbell severely burned when car he was work - ing on burst into flame, catching his oily clothes on fire, also his hands, which were wet with gasoline. L. O. Deardorf burned on foot and leg when trying to remove an oil stove that had exploded. Captain A. A. Barney, a fireman, received a face burn while fighting a fire caused by a furnace oil burner. H. C. Lewis badly burned from starting fire with gas oline. W. Kulla burned about head and face trying to put out a chimney fire. J. P. Frazier burned on hands and face while cleaning itilk dress with gasoline. Walter Lake, fireman, hurt when truck crashed into a filling station on way to a fire. R. R. Young, barber, slightly burned on neck and head when gas water heater set fire to shop. Millerton Fred Brammeier badly burned about face anil hands when lubricating oil from his car which he was warm - ing up on the stove exploded. City Mr*. S. T. Williamson badly burned from waist to feet Dre** caught on fire from heating stove. City Alex. Walker badly burned from explosion of alcohol in auto radiator. Had cap off and struck a match. Newman Grove Frank Rose's little child badly burned by gasoline light while parents were absent. A. E. Champlin, an oil truck driver, badly burned about face and hands when static electricity set the gasoline on fire. Silas Wheeler, Wheeler Cash Register Company, ser - iously burned when he threw coal oil on furnace fire. Dr. C. E. Clark and Charles Wilson injured because of Are in rooming house set by hot ashes in wooden box. Albert Ericlcson slightly burned when trying to save wife and child. Cause, lighting fire with kerosene. Mrs. Frank Lester severely burned and little daughter slightly burned when Mrs. Lester looked for escaping </seg>
            <seg id="p011">• DIVISION OF FIRK PREVENTION 11 Omaha W. C. Stroop was severely injured ami two other men slightly injured when a large underground gasoline tank which they were cleaning with steam exploded. Omaha James Clark, forty years old, a cripple, badly burned when he fell asleep while smoking. Night clerk, William Sherlock, was burned about hands and arms when he carried Clark from room. Rock vi lie Joseph Heil badly burned from starting a fire with kerosene. Shelton Ira Vorhees, state law enforcement offieer, severely burned about face, head and arms when he poured gas - oline over barrels of mash and other material in a hootch cave he had captured and set it on fire, which caused an explosion. Sidney Douglas, the small son of Paul Martin, badly burned from falling into pile of hot ashes in yard. Amputa - tion of legR may be necessary. Schuyler Sanford Van Housen, movie operator, severely burned about face and hands when film caught fire. Syracuse Mm. Charles I Ionian badly burned in fire which de - stroyed the home. Cause, defective electric wires. Wvmore Dave Rhoades badly burned on both hands when an oil stove exploded in his shop. He attempted to carry it out. Wvmore Jas. Johnson anil Bert Moroney were seriously burned when filling a lighted lamp with gasoline which they thought was kerosene. Wakefield Mrs. Nels Youngquist probably fatally burned start - ing fire with kerosene. Wvmore Guy F. Marquardt, fire chief, hurt in fall from a lad der at a fire. Wahoo Fireman hurt by falling glass at a fire in battery sta - tion. Cause, overheated electric motor. Wymore Robt. Mundell, owner dry cleaning plant, badly burned from tank of naptha in which he was cleaning silk. Exploded from static sparks. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">iL&amp; 12 M.\ I r.K.N I II Aft.M AL Kfc* r\J K «. KIKK LOSSES DURING 1»24 The '.otal lire Ion* reported to this Department from IMS, to Dee»mlK-i 1, IVH, is m» follows: No. of l/uss on Lohh on Kin accordance witli Section 8151 Compileil Statutes of Nebraaka, IMS, the sum of $619.50 wa&gt; paid in the month of January, 1924, to fire chiefs and other authorized officers, for reporting to this Depart I flren of preceiintr yeur in localities where no paid fliemen art- Renpectfully submitted, L. U. KIJYK, State Fire Marshal Th« '.otul lire loaa reported to this Department from December 1. IMS. to DeeemlK-i 1, IVH, i« a* follows: if Lokh on Ixms on Total Firex HUlgh. Contents LlM ■kp ... W9 $6O2,5S3.7J $474,r&gt;0:i.6»i *1, 077,067 .3* — 1« «a^J76.70 41,587.20 106,263.!Hl met- of State 884 SC8.435.2-2 335,1 14.2 i 6»8,549.4fi TuUI 1«€6 Sl,02»,665.64 (861,205.10 $1,880,870.74 lluililiii|{&gt; reported repuiretl in 1924 19 Ol&lt;l liuililintr&gt; reported torn ilown in I'.t24 13 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>