<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00038">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00038</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>State of Nebraska Department of Trade and Commerce Division of Fire Prevention Fifteenth Annual Report 1923</title>
               <date value="1923">1923</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">State of Nebraska Department of Trade and Commerce Division of Fire Prevention Fifteenth Annual Report 1923 CHARLES W. BRYAN Governor </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">3 STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Office of State Fire Marshal. lion. Charles W. Bryan, Governor, State of Nebraska. Dear Sir: In compliance with the state law, I respectfully submit to ou the 15th Annual Report of the Division of Fire Pre- vention. The necessity of the work being done by the Fire Pre - vention Department has not as yet been impressed upon the people of our great state. The department seeks and caters to co-operation of the general public in this great life and property saving cause. Many times we are subject to criti - cism for requesting the removal of fire hazards, which, if permitted to remain, would surely lead to the unexpected fire. The service rendered to the public in "Fire Prevention" can well be measured by what has been accomplished in Accident Prevention." To know that in the year 1922 our country's loss of life was about 15,000 and approximately 18,000 painfully burned and injured — many of them being scarred or crippled for life, the major percentage being women and children, to say nothing of the one-half million or more in property destroyed, and Nebraska paying its part in the toll — we must conclude that this is a matter that may not be passed idly by. The only corrective remedy is by the prevention of same. To first accomplish results we must depend upon the co - operation of our citizens in exercising care to prevent fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 It is easy to say that the fire could have been prevented, but it is enough that the country and state have suffered the loss of life and property in the past, of which over eighty per cent was caused by the lack of care, and from this history we may prepare for the future. Very effective and efficient work is being accomplished in this connection by our chambers of commerce, insurance companies, civic leagues and schools, our department co-op - erating as far as possible. We also commend the press for the publicity given to the cause. Too much may not be said in praise of the fire de - partments for the effective and efficient service rendered not only in extinguishing fires but also in the inspection and prevention of fires. Permit me to submit that from 19,157 inspections made during the year, 4,887 disclosed the necessity of a general clean-up of the premises, and 3,837 cases disclosed defective wiring. A thorough investigation has beer, made by an investi - gator in all fires which were presumed to be of "incendiary origin." S. M. Souder, former County Treasurer Lincoln County, North Platte, convicted Dec. 22, 1923, for arson. Sentenced fifteen to twenty years in the state penitentiary . Frank Ambrose, Crete, Saline County, Nebraska. Con - victed of arson Mar. 19, 1923. Sentenced to state peniten - tiary. Appealed to Supreme Court. Frank Crist, Anselmo, Custer County, Nebraska. Pleaded guilty to arson. Sentenced Oct. 19, 1923, to one year in state prison. The department has record of four deaths and eleven in - jured, caused by fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">A number of fire escapes have been placed during the year at the suggestion of this department. The following compilation will best demonstrate the ac - tivities of the Fire Prevention Department for the year 1923: INSPECTIONS Dl RING 1923 .7 Presumably Incendiary Kirp Investigated. JNJURKD: E. K. William.-, Columbus, xlightly burned. John Morrison, Randolph, severely burned on arms ami legs. Ray Heishey, Randolph, severely burned on arms and legs. .» (jasoline and Kerosene 823 Cleanup 4387 I himney 760 Klectric wiring * 3,837 Metal or asbestos under stoves 744 Red lijcht and fire escape 216 Repair building 327 Condem nations 88 Miscellaneous 2.529 Total order- '. : 14,201 Total Inspection 19,157 No. of Fires Loss on Bldffx. I .&lt;&gt;.«- on Contents Omaha , 632 $897,719.31 $1,513,4X6.26 Lincoln 230 166,121.00 109,667.00 Balance of State 614 918,326.85 964,936.78 1,475 $1.982,167.1fi $2,587,190.04 lOtal loss $4,569,857.20 1 .(&gt;.-- on BMtf-. and Contentx. Omaha $2,411^05.67 Lincoln — 276,788.00 Balance of State 1,882,368.63 Total - $4,569,357.20 .*4.."&gt;«a,3.-)7.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 on fitcc Mm. Ryba, Columbux, xliichtly burned on hand* Mrs. Weatherby ami mother, Norfolk, Hlightly burned from ■MM Mr. Eden and three women, Beatrice, slightly burned. DEATHS: Thou. Cappock, Rulo, died from shock on learning of fire. Boy in Eden fire at Beatrice burned to death. Dr. Nelwm, Omaha, burned to death trying to put out fire Mrs. Jennie Smith, Omaha, died from burnt* in lamp explosion. ( ALSF.S OK KIRKS lU.I'nKI Kl) TO THIS OFKH'K FROM DKC 1. 1922. TO DEC. 1, 192.1 Omaha Number Lincoln Balance of Number State Total Incendiary 3 12 ■ ■ 28 !•;:, !■ Unknown S9 Sparks from chimneys on roof 210 ■I 124 M 2 10 26 Children and matches IS Oil stoves 1« ■»:, Spontaneous combustion 10 It 11 Hot ashes 28 4^ Fire place ■1 ■i I Gasoline explosion H Defective stove and furnace pipe ■i Defective chimney 19 42 M Defective electric wires 13 ■&gt; &gt;i 41 II Sparks from trains 1 11 Overheated stoves and furnaces .__ 1!» ■' 30 51 Blow torch ■&gt; 2 4 Coffee urn Connecting wires 14 17 :&gt; Careless use of matches 36 x 44 Ifl Candles on Christmas trees 11 1 Hot coals on floor 1 1 Cigarettes 38 • 13 .,7 Clothes cleaning compound 1 1 Oil burners in stoves 1 1 4 Clothes cleaning compound 1 1 Oil lamp 1 I o Gas heaters 12 13 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">. Cob*, rubbinh and kindling clone to furnace 4 4 - Bonfire* it " 8, Great* on utove 8 &gt; • Klectric iron IX :t 4 m Movie film fire i 1 &lt; nicicen Droooer ■■ .. &gt;■■■■■-■_——■■■■■ __ 1 1 Ua» engine « 1 Lightning H 11 1* 26 Belt friction \ .. 1 1 Fire work.* «n&lt;l fire crackers 4 * 6 Klectric light bulbs 1 1 Paper on stove 1 1 Auto l&gt;ack fire I t Thawing frozen pipe* •J 2 Smoking in be&lt;l 8 1 4 Inflammable material too close to fire 4 4 Burning out tar in a down pipe 2 2 Water coil burst in furnace 1 1 Sparks from welding machine __ 2 2 Overheated motor 1 Grease in ventilator pipe 1 1 i Sparks on carpet from open flue hole 1 1 Short circuit of battery on gas engine 1 1 Burning papers 2 Explosion of annealing oven 1 -_ 2 i Ignition of battery l' 1 Burning weeds 1 1 Sparks in papers 1 Sparks in sacking 1 Gas left turned on in mangle 1 1 1 1 Ignition of gasoline from match 1 Boys made fire in cellar 1 Oil in furnace overflowed 1 1 1 1 Awning on fire from electric sign _. l 1 Overheated stovepipe 2 2 Lantern in basement 1 1 Short in battery Key left turned on and overheated l 1 1 wiring 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">FIRE LOSSES DURING 1923. The total fire loss from December 1, 1922, to December 1, 1923 is as follows: No. of Fires Loss Lincoln 230 $ 275,788.00 Omaha 632 2,411,205.57 Balance of State 615 1,882,363.63 Total 1476 $4,569,357.20 Respectfully submitted, L. B. FRYE, State Fire Marshal. -s </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>