<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves</title>
               <date value="1933-10">1933-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 68 A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves A. E. BARAGAR AND EDNA B. SNYDER Department of Home Economics LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OCTOBER, 1933 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">FOREWORD By its very nature this report will appeal only to technical people. To fill the needs of those who are not interested in experimental procedure and tech - nical results but wish only to know how to choose wisely and operate economically an electric stove, a non-technical bulletin is being prepared. ■ ' ' ■-.'■'".:' ' ' ' '.''■' ■■':■'■■ ':■ CONTENTS Summary .". 3 Introduction 5 Purpose of investigation 5 Description of stoves and utensils 6 Apparatus and general test methods 11 Part I — Surface Units 16 Experimental procedure 16 Results 20 Conclusions 43 Part II— Ovens 44 Theory. 44 Experimental procedure 47 Results 50 Conclusions 61 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY Five commercial electric stoves having major variations in types of surface units, in the construction, lining, and insulation of the oven, and in the retail price were studied to determine (1) the efficiency and tame of heating of the various surface units, and (2) the merits of differently constructed ovens. SURFACE UNITS The efficiency and time of heating for both cold and hot starts for short-time tests of three types of surface units, namely open type, solid cast type, and tubular or ring type solid, were found by heating successively 4, 3, 2, and 1 pounds of distilled water from 72° to 206° F. in various sizes and types of covered and uncovered aluminum and enameled pans. For long-time tests for both cold and hot starts the efficiency was found by heating 4 pounds of distilled water in covered aluminum and enameled pans from 72° F. to the boiling point, after which the water was kept boiling for the remainder of the one-hour test period. Energy was measured with a Sangamo-type H-C watt - hour meter and checked by a potential-current-time product. For all surface-unit tests the potential was kept constant at 220 and 110 volts. The temperature of the water was measured with copper-constantan thermocouples connected to a Leeds &amp; Northrup portable potentiometer. Ihe radiation and convection loss of the various utensils at the boiling point of water was found by using an immersion heater. Comparative time-of-heating results have been presented in tables, rwo efficiencies have been considered, minimum and actual. The minimum efficiency includes as the output only the amount of energy necessary to heat the water through the 134 degrees of temperature change, while the actual efficiency includes as the output the amount of energy necessary to heat the water and pan and also the energy lost by evaporation. For the long-time tests the radiation and con - vection loss of the utensils at the boiling point of water was also in - cluded in the output. The results of the surface-unit tests indicate the following: 1. Unite having a small watt rating are more efficient than units having a large watt rating. 2. The tubular and the ring-type unite are the most efficient for general use. 3. The open units of stove E were more efficient than the open unite of the other stoves studied. 4. The cone and reflector unite are efficient for short-time processes when started cold, but for all other processes they are inefficient when compared with the other open-type unite studied. 5. The solid cast unite are inefficient for cold starts but for long-time processes they are very efficient. 6. The utensils should have straight side walls, should not be too high, and should be of a size to fit the unit exactly. The cover should make perfect contact with the side walls. 7. For short-time processes either enameled pans or black-bottomed aluminum pans should be used on open and tubular or ring-type unite. * or all solid cast unite, aluminum pans with bottoms making perfect contact with the unit should be used. 8. For all long-time processes aluminum pans should be used on all unite. OVENS The ovens were rated by determining and comparing, for empty ovens, (1) the time and energy required to preheat, (2) the total heat </seg>
            <seg id="p004">loss, (3) the heat loss per square foot, (4) the heat loss when the oven door was opened, (5) the time rate of cooling, (6) the calibra - tion of the thermostat, and (7) the temperature distribution in the oven for various average temperatures. All average temperatures were measured by five copper-constantan thermocouples connected in parallel in the mid-plane of the oven. Shields were used to protect one set of couples from radiant energy. The temperature distribution in the oven was measured with fifteen copper-constantan couples arranged in three planes with five couples in each plane. For steady-state teste three exterior oven temperatures were also recorded. Energy was measured with the watt-hour meter and checked by a potential-current-time product. The results for the preheating teste, the heat losses, and the time rate of cooling are shown graphically. Thermostat and heat distribution results are shown in tables. Where a ranking involves time or energy the ovens are ranked in ascending order of the time and energy required. The results of the oven tests indicate the following: 1. In the order of the time and energy necessary to preheat with all units on high, the ovena ranked in the order D, C, E, A, and B. 2. For totai heat loss the ovens ranked B, A, C, E, and D. 3. For the heat loss per square foot the ranking was B, A, E, C, and D. 4. The heat lost when the oven door was opened, was almost the same for ovens B, C, and D for oven air temperatures up to 400° F., with oven A next in order and oven E losing the most heat. For oven air temperatures above 400° F., the ovens ranked C, D, B, A, and E. 5. Oven B cooled most slowly and oven D most rapidly, the order of ranking for all being B, E, A, C, and D. 6. In energy required to preheat and to maintain at a desired tem - perature for one hour of thermostat operation, oven D was the most economical. For periods of thermostat operation greater than one hour, oven B was the most economical. The remaining ovens ranked C, A, and E for all periods of thermostat operation; oven E used the most energy. 7. Because of the principle of operation, the thermostat on oven B should not be compared with the other thermostats. The calibration of the thermostat of oven E was the most accurate, with that of oven A next. The calibration of the thermostat of oven C was too high at 450° and 500° F. and much too low at 300° and 250° F. The calibration of the thermostat of oven D was fairly accurate at 450°, 500°, 550°, and 600° F., but the average temperatures were much too high at 400°, 350°, 300°, and 250° F. Oven D had the most sensitive thermostat. 8. The temperatures of the oven air at various locations in the oven was found to be sufficiently uniform for practical purposes in all stoves. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves A. E. BARAGAR' AND EDNA B. SNYDER » Department of Home Economics During the last few years, the use of electrical energy for cookery has been increasing m popularity wherever it can be obtained at a favorable price when compared with the cost of other forms of energy. In the past, cost of operation and a popular belief that electric cookery was slow have tended to prevent the general acceptance of electric stoves m spite of the efficiency and convenience they offer. 8 PURPOSE OF INVESTIGATION Most of the recent research on electric stoves has been done by manufacturers, and the results are not available to the public. As early as 1915, disinterested institutions began to publish bulletins on electric cooking appliances, 4 but since no complete study comparing various types of electric stoves is ' Table 1. — Dimensions Over nil Cooking top Stove . Height from ~~ Maximum Maximum -Might from floor to tou width Depth length width floor to top ofcoo king Width of oven top I lixchcit Inches Inches Inches Inches Inches A 44% 23% 40% 82% 24% | 22% B 42 ,4 24% 4B',i 33% 22% 24% C 38% 20% 44% 33% 20% 20% D 40 22 42 32 22 22 E 47 25% 40% 82% 25% 25 Ovens Interior Exterior Stovo Height of Height Width Depth Volume "Width Depth ov | ||jJ,* p cooking top Inches Inches Inches Cu. ft. Inches Inches Inches Inches A 14 16 18% 2.40 19 20% 23% I 7% B 14 16 17 2.20 17% 19% 19%' 13 '" 14 14 18% 2.10 18 18 21 » 10% D 16 14 19 2.46 &lt;BY. 16% 21 11 E IS 16 18 2.50 20% | 21% 24 8% 1 Portion of sides below Lottom of oven not included. 'Thickness of oven door.i not included. 1 Formerly instructor m the Department of Physics, University of Nebraska. ' Research specialist m Home Economics. * For comparison of efficiency of electric stoves with other types of stoves, see Bulletin No. 3, American Gas Association Inc. Testing Laboratory, Cleveland, Ohio, 1928; Bulletin No. 830, Agr. Exp. Sta., Purdue University, 1930; and "Kitchen Tests of Relative Cost of Natural Gas, Soft Coal, Coal Oil, Gasoline, and Electricity for Cooking", Ohio State University, 1917. ♦"The Economics of Electric Cookine". P. W. Gumaer, University of Missouri Bul - letin, VoL 16, No. 27. 1916: "Electric Cookine Appliances". R. G. Kloeffler. Kansas State Agricultural College Bulletin, Vol. 1, No. 20. 1917; "Electric Ranges", C. W. Piper, Bulletin No. 2. Engineering Experiment Station, Purdue University. 1910; "Electric Range for the Home", Harriet C. Brigham, Bulletin 102, Engineering Ex - tension Service, lowa Stat* College, 1929; "Baking Vegetables Electrically", V. W. Swartz, Scientific Paper No. 167, College of Agriculture and Exp. Sta.. State College of Washington; Report No. 86956 for Electromaster Inc.. The Electrical Testing Lab - oratories, New York, 1030; Private communication from the Bureau of Standards, 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 available to the public, this investigation was undertaken for the purpose of determining, first, the efficiency and time of heating of the various surface units and, second, the merits of different types of ovens on representative ranges now on the market DESCRIPTION OF STOVES AND UTENSILS General features. — The ranges used in the study have been designated as A, B, C, D, and E. The important dimen - sions of each stove are listed in Table 1. In Table 2 are listed the general features. All of the stoves were equipped with convenience outlets and reciprocating and load-balancing switches. On stove E all of the units were individually fused and a master switch controlled the entire stove circuit. Table 2. — General features Stove grta. Exterior Platln(t wlrin8 *£■£*£? A $175 White Chromium on rim of oven door Simple Easy enamel B $176 Gray None Simple Easy enamel C $125 White None . Too many Hard to get enamel wires at lead wires D $126 White Small chromium band on rim enamel of oven door Simple Awkward E $200 White Chromium on rim of oven door enamel and around bottom of stove Simple Easy Surface units. — The important features of the various types of surface units are given in Table 3 and in Figures 1 to 10. On all of the stoves, the surface units had three heat positions, high, medium, and low. High used the full Table 3. — Surface units No. of Type Watt Diam. Diam. Insulator Location Stove units rating of rim of unit block on stove Inches Inches A 3 Open 2000 1034 8H Pressed asbestos Right front Tubular 1200 10% 5% None Left front Open 1000 10% 6% Pressed asbestos Rear center Solid 1 2000 10% 8% Pressed asbestos Left front Solid » 1000 10% 6% Pressed asbestos Rear center Tubular ■ 2100 10% 8 None Right front B 8 Solid I 2260 9% 8%" Asbestos Right front Solid 16C0 9 k- 8',i Asbestos Left front '"•■ : - Open 1200 I 9% 6 % None Rear center C 8 Open 2000 9% 8 Vone Front center Opan 1260 8 7 None Rear left Solid 1100 8 6%_ Nope Rear right D 4 Cone ft reflector 1300 8 6% None Right front Cone ft reflector 1890 8 6% None Left front Cone ft reflector 1300 8 6% None Right rear ; Cone ft reflector 1800 J) 6'/s None Left rear E _ Open 1600 9 j 8 Composition block Right rear Solid 1500 9 T_ None Right front Open 1000 9 5% Composition block Left rear ' Solid 1000 9 -V, Mon* Left front 1 Additional equipment. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Fig. 1. — Open unit, stove A. Fig. 2. — Solid cast unit, stove A. •—""' Fig. 4. — Solid unit, stove B. Fig. 3. — Tubular unit, stove A. Fig. 5. — Open unit, stove B. Fig. 6. — Open unit, stove C. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Fig. 7. — Solid unit, stove C. "' lljU IbLHa Fig. 8. — Cone and reflector unit, stove D. Fig. 9. — Open unit, stove E. Fig. 10. — Solid unit, stove E. power rating of the unit, medium used half the power rating of HIGH, and LOW used one-fourth of the power rating of high. Hence, for equal time periods, high used the full energy of the unit, medium used one-half as much energy as high, and LOW one-fourth as much energy as high. On stoves A and E, the two heating elements were connected in series for high, with a potential of 220 volts across the combination. The two heating elements on stoves B and C were also connected in series for high, but the application of voltage was different. Because of the construction of the switch, a potential of 110 volts was applied across each heating element, the total poten - tial being 220 volts. With the application of voltage in this manner, different current readings were obtained in the outer wires of the three-wire circuit, if the resistances of the two heating elements were not equal. Thus on stoves B and C </seg>
            <seg id="p009">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves it was necessary to take current readings in both lines !•_, and L, when the unit was on high (see Fig. 28). The two heat - ing elements on stove D were connected in parallel with an applied voltage of 110 volts across the combination for high. On all of the stoves a single heating element with a. potential of 110 volts was used for medium, while both heating elements connected in series with a potential of 110 volts were used for Low. The units on stoves B and E were rated at 110-220 volts, while those for stoves A, C, and D were rated at 115 - 230 volts. Figure 8 shows the unit of stove D equipped with an open grid. Two of the grids, however, have at the center a thin metal baffle, 3 inches in diameter. Since the only variable feature of the units is the grid, a complete description would require the terms "cone and reflector baffle" and "cone and reflector open", but in order to abbreviate the terminology, the words "baffle" and "open" will be used in future designa - tions. The surface characteristics of the solid-type units are shown in Figures 11 to 16 inclusive. The figures portray only enough of the unit and utensil to show the faulty contact between unit and pan. For best results the surface of the unit should make complete contact with a flat-bottomed pan. j***"^ | "p fist* B*rrp-*s &gt;|i«^ J / / \ \ Fig. 13. — Cross-section of 1200 - / / /^HHHl^ \ \ watt tubular unit, stove A. l\:\ &lt;§11&gt;' : /'■/'' *" IG " -** — Cross - section of ; \ \^ j y y ! solid-unit heating element; ! IN. V^! '\^r /\ j stove B.^ r "^^^^^S^^^^^^^^r i Fig. 15. — Cross - section of Fig. 11. -Surface condition of rf™f t^ d p ,nit h&lt;?ating 2,000-watt solid unit, stove A. element, stove E. ln.rB~r.~r St*. ~. 1* I ' -' I g^T"^"' ft jji!iBl' I !l*sad \ ~__mm r =s^ ' IW5 "^i—fl—^-^ ' Fig. 12. — Cross-section of 1,000- Fig. 16. — Cross - section of watt solid-unit heating element, 1.000-watt solid-unit heating stove A. element, stove E. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Ovens. — Table 4 is a tabulation of the important features of the ovens studied. The oven-heating units are shown in Figures 17 to 21. Only one unit, rated at 2,000 watts, 230 volts, Was used on stove D. It was placed about 4 inches from the bottom of the oven. The remaining stoves had a unit at both top and bottom of the oven, each rated at 1500 watts. A baffle was used over the lower unit of ovens A, B, C, and E to prevent baking by direct radiant heat. ' Table 4. — Ovens I Baffle Stove Lining Insulation Ventilation Type Location A Blue enamel Removable Ih." above Miperal wool Fixed unit B Black enamel Removable 1%" above Mineral wool Adjustable unit C Blue enamel Integral Immediately Mineral wool Adjustable with unit above unit D Chromium plate None Air None ■ E Aluminum Integral 1\_" above Asbestos cell Adjustable with unit unit __, tmm " Thermostat 0ven rfreqJt ' TiBhtneM S Type Location indicator jofdoorflt A Spiral bimetallic strip. Right side, upper None Fair 110 v. magnetic relay back corner B ■"1st bimetallic strip. In the door Push button Fair 110 v. magnetic relay C Spiral bimetallic strip. Left side, upper front Red light Poor mercoid switch corner D Nitrogen pressure thermom- Middle of heating Red light Poor eter, mercoid switch clement E Flat bimetallic strip. Upper center, right Red light Good 220 v. magnetic relay aide The effectiveness of "the mineral- wool insulation used in ovens A, B, and C depends upon the uniformity of packing. Upon removal of the exterior walls it was found that the packing was quite uniform except for the doors. The door of stove A was poorly packed ; in fact at two large spots the insulation was not more than y_ inch thick. The doors of stoves B and C were better packed than the door of stove A, but the packing was not entirely uniform. The oven of stove D depended upon dead-air space for insulation. The oven of stove E combined dead-air space and asbestos-cell for insula - ting material. The asbestos was in the form of a cellular block 2 inches thick, cut to fit exactly. This type of insula - tion assures a uniform packing. Utensils. — -The utensils were purchased from open stock at the local department stores; they were all nationally adver - tised. Table 5 gives the data for these pans. The diameters listed do not include the roll at the outside of the pan ; hence </seg>
            <seg id="p011">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Table 5. — Utensils Utensil No. Type Material Jf'bStom Height Capacity Inches Inches Quarts 1 Sauce pan Rolled aluminum 7.000 4.260 3 2 Sauce pan Cast aluminum 7.875 4.750 4 8 Sauce pan Green enamel 7.250 4.250 3 4 Sauce pan White enamel 8.250 5.000 5 6 Stock kettle Rolled aluminum 7.875 6.876 6 6 Stock kettle Rolled aluminum 9.000 6.876 8 7 Skillet Cast aluminum 9.260 2.000 8 Skillet Cast iron, black 0.500 1.870 .. Weight Utensil No. without With Condition of bottom Lid fits pan cover cover Pott-tula Pounds 1 0.930 1.117 Recessed Tight 2 1.672 2.273 Concave upward, slight Tight, vapor seal 3 1.608 2.007 Concave upward, great Poor 4 1.922 2.685 Concave upward, great Fair 5 0.821 1.101 Concave upward, great Tight, clamped 6 1.578 1.937 Recessed Tight 7 2.023 Concave downward, great ................................ 8 4.769 Concave downward, great „ _ they denote only the surface which makes contact with the unit. Cross-section views of the utensils are shown in Figures 22 to 27. , , APPARATUS AND GENERAL TEST Jf ~V METHODS * ,jA .*!7 .jAJjl Measurement of energy. — JJ A* // Jr—j\ JJ %. The stoves were operated on a JJ ((// If // (( y, — 110-220 volt, three-wire alter - // UA. Uj) J** t''ZZ^A nating-current circuit. A Gen - // (Tfl^T/jf /TsAs I ' '"""' eral E l ec t r ic Type mbjs induc - « // /&gt;/ jAZZs j on voltage regulator was / J/C "'Z"?™* used to regulate voltages of f -Jf ,&gt;*~~~ 100 to 120 volts and 200 to 240 volts. For tests requiring Fig. 17.-Oven unit, stove A. regulation of potentials J&gt;e - yond the range of the in- ,/^^&amp;^ duction regulator, j suit- //^y^^^ " able resistance was in- ///»&gt;y^s§^^^^ troduced into the line in /j//^/^^ i t^^^ i . front of the regulator. W^//M/0m^^&gt;JZ^ "*" Both current and poten- ffl&amp;#/0fffl^/&amp;M^^ tial were measured with Weston Model 155 in- struments. Currjents |3\&amp;L greater than 10 amperes 1 r- / "l^^^^ were measured by! using /^^fc/T 'Ssfrsa^^ a Weston Model 461 cur- W^. rent transformer ih con- Fig. 18. — Oven unit, stove B. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 /^5x. junction with the 5-am - //\ E*Si^^ pere ran 2 e ammeter. //JS^Wa^^^s^ Energy was measured /A^^Brm^^s. by a type H "^ Sanga - //&lt;^^-_^a^^^^^^^^s^ mo wa tt-hour meter. 5 A (/M+ffi $NS£^&lt;ft J**ZZf&amp;§iu!^^*_ potential - current - time '^C^^J^^vSTfe^^^r !$£2»^7 product was used to C^^v^^^^^^Se^jPj^^^C// check this watt - hour ji meter energy. 0 For tests '"/S/.^^V^o^^^fj^I^^ °^ * ong duration, that /b « r^U^ ra / y\7 ;^J®T^^2ffix 2^&gt;v * s &gt; any time over one " / *"~ ur ~" half hour ' the time was 4 " measured by an Elgin watch, which had an Fig. 19.— Oven unit, stove C. error of about one min- Fig. 20. — Oven unit, stove D. ute per week. A stop watch calibrated lf_\^___WuT =:^r^__* "7-1 Jl against the Elgin watch //WW 111 !! /?/ "w _t was used for short-time l[£ y -.Mfr m /fL r .. (mMlL tests. The potential- /jMjLfJT Jj MffTOHr!^ ifcKi— current product was // / / /^ *^"^jffi ty fl y fcj checked against a Wes- A|&gt; f&gt; » fy foaJk a/Jr~ ton Model 310 single- llf f f xl m_ r__W_j^CyPr~ J phase wattmeter and fp pm_ nHul " Ijfw^l. (nr found to differ by about aT/ iirijf IJi___i___wLa!ZZ'~'ZZ 0.9 per cent, which is ll^J^jW^jv ' / W within the limits of as- WHgHgMJ^»^r signed error for the * y Watt-hour meter. Fig. 21. — Oven unit, stove E. i Originally^ readings on this instrument were accurate to 10 watt-hours, but by increasing the length of each mark, the length of the pointer, and the number of marks on the 10 watt-hour dial, readings of 2.5 watt-hours could be made with greater accuracy and readings to 1 watt-hour closely estimated. • Because of the absence of inductance and capacitance in the test circuit, no power factor had to be considered in tbe potential-current-time product. For all tests the load waa a straight resistance. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves c -cs N c ,sir~ /^^^ AS*-^ ~^^H^ -y — \ ' "^^^f^-^ ' f • ; ' ' — t* — i M JJ — T T J I Fig. 25. — Cross-section of utensil 4. -Hbsr i - Fig. 22. — Cross-section of utensil 1, . . including thermocouple. rft^ __ . J^ , _JS- J * — 6V i-l f t_ ~* *~ Fig. 26. — Cross-section of \ J I utensil 5. Fig. 23. — Cross-section of utensil 2. r i j — * — - vl ■*] ' S Fig. 27. — Cross-section of utensil Fig. 24. — Cross-section of utensil 3. 6. In order to determine how closely the energy as measured by the watt-hour meter should agree with the energy cal - culated from the 1 potential-current-time product, errors were arbitrarily assigned to the watt-hour meter, voltmeter, am - meter, and time readings. Maximum errors allowed were: 0.5 volt for the potential, 0.01 ampere for the 5-10 ampere range, and 0.02 ampere for the 20-ampere range for the cur- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 rent and 0.5 second for the time. The allowable error on the watt-hour meter was assigned as 1 watt-hour on the initial reading and 1 watt-hour on the final reading. To this should be added an error of 2 watt-hours due to slippage in the gears on the 10 watt-hour dial, so that the maximum error would be 4 watt-hours. »«.'i» 1mm. r_\__?\ n : MgrrSTAT Vc.rAsr 1,7*** I ——————————————————— JtftVlA. Ks—.jnwt _*"_[ I H 1 ,__ I ♦ P*-"^! Zsatfir iSeOtmrr /o_*sm-r \\r\ I- 1 jtiwUiw TTTn Otm*r /owt-mt *"" TAr [~^Cfrs , --[ l^Sftl 1 t /&amp;__r—. ~ [ — ' re-5] (c3| I ZJy^BH — -,-\ r OTw,a l r^ ,, * f ] 4 I fegj 0»r«r I CW««r 7i4-i«.~„ IvVVVvJ /&lt; ""&lt; , . Immsjism //satis Fig. 28. — Wiring diagram of power table. S'nSftiri' .?" ¥' Circuit 2=L » ••"&gt; N- S, and S,=heavy knife switches. D.P.D.T.S.=doubIe-pole double-throw switch. D.P.S.T.S.=double-poIe single-throw switch. For convenience, the various instruments used for meas - uring and checking energy and voltage were mounted on a "power table", so wired that the instruments could be con - nected to any desired range and circuit by closing the proper switches. Figure 28 shows the wiring diagram of this table. Measurement of temperature. — Temperatures from 32° to 700° F. were measured by copper-constantan thermocouples connected either to a Leeds &amp; Northrup portable potentio - meter or a Weston Model 322 pyromillivoltmeter. 7 These couples were calibrated at the boiling point of water, at the boiling point of naphthalene, and at the melting point of lead, and were found to agree exactly with the e.m.f .'s published by the Leeds &amp; Northrup Co. For temperatures too far be - yond the calibrated range of the copper-constantan couples, that is from 700° to 1800° F., iron-constantan thermocouples of No. 22 wire connected either to a high-range portable of melSng'iJe?*" U *' nB therraocoa P Ie "' * be eoi * junction was kept at the temperature </seg>
            <seg id="p015">A Study of I Five Commercial Electric Stoves I potentiometer or a pyromillivoltmeter equipped with a suit - able multiplier were used. The temperature of the hot element wires was measured by a Leeds &amp; Northrup Morse - type optical pyrometer. Since all of the literature published by the stove manufacturers for the consumers' benefit and the thermostat markings are in Fahrenheit, that scale of temperatures is used throughout this bulletin. By using a system of threads for parallax readings, the potentiometer could be read to 0.02 millivolt with an allow - able error of 0.01 millivolt. The pyromillivoltmeter could be read to 0.05 millivolt with an error of 0.02 millivolt and when a magnifying lens was used this instrument could be read to 0.02 millivolt with an error of 0.01 millivolt. Trans - lated into temperature for a copper-constantan couple, it is possible to measure to about 0.07° F. with the portable poten - tiometer and the magnified readings of the pyromillivoltmeter as ordinarily used. This temperature can be given only Table 6. — Resistance of units Resistance in ohms Stove Unit Before use j After use IR' I R" | R ""RM-R" R' I R" I R R'+R" 1000 open 24.84 25.04 49.80 49.84 2000 open 11.16 12.35 23.49 23.51 11.29 12.66 23.88 23.94 1000 solid 24.68 24.26 48.94 48.94 24.46 24.72 49.13 49.18 2000 solid' 11.54 11.86 23.38 23.40 11.54 11.88 23.36 I 23.42 A 2100 tubular | 12.04 I 12.51 24.60 24.66 1200 tubular 21.90 21.07 42.94 42.07 21.09 1200 tubular „ ™ 21.46 20.04 41.43 41.49 (new unit) Lower oven' 16.03 16.77 31.75 81.80 16.28 16.97 32.15 32.20 Upper oven 15.81 16.47 32.24 32.28 15.83 16.57 32.35 32.40 '.200 open 24.16 24.83 48.51 48.54 24.14 24.38 48.45 48.62 2250 solid 9.70 9.70 19.36 19.40 9.73 9.90 19.67 19.63 B 1600 solid 14.30 14.21 28.47 28.61 14.21 14.09 28.22 28.30 Lower oven 18.71 13.28 26.94 26.99 13.80 13.72 27.43 27.52 Upper oven 13.71 18.81 27.47 I 27.62 13.67 13.78 27.38 27.45 1100 solid 25.21 21.89 46.67 46.60 24.94 20.90 45.77 46.84 1250 open 17.89 19.80 87.67 87.69 18.37 20.61 38.93 88.98 C 2000 open 12.66 12.21 24.76 24.77 12.98 12.94 25.82 26.S7 Lower oven 16.18 16.39 Upper oven 16.16 16.39 Cone 1 16.86 I 16.78 33.61 33.63 17.51 17.50 34.96 35.01 Cone 2 16.92 17.15 34.06 84.07 17.75 17.62 85.20 35.27 D Cone 3 16.80 16.71 33.53 86.64 ...... — -•• Cone 4 16.96 16.75 83.68 £3.71 17.70 17.63 35.13 35.23 Oven I 26.88 26.60 1600 solid 14.68 17.88 32.63 32.56 14.62 17.65 32.22 32.27 1000 BOlld 21-88 25.35 46.67 46.68 20.93 25.04 45.91 45.97 V 1500 ODCn 15.30 16.30 30.60 30.60 15.56 16.65 31.06 81.11 E loOOopIS 24:66 24.86 49.00 49.02 24.90 26.22 50.05 60.12 Lower oven 16.01 16.02 30.00 30.03 15.43 15.31 30.68 80.74 Upper over. 15.13 15.05 | 30.15 30.18 15.06 15.06 30.04 80.11 R' is the resistance of one heating element, R" is the resistance, of the other hasting element, amd R is the combined resistance of R' and R in series. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 approximately, for the temperature-e.m.f. curve is not a straight line. Its slope decreases for higher temperature. Weighing. — All weighing was done on a Fairbanks beam-balance with standardized weights ranging from 5 pounds to 1/16 of an ounce. 4.u ** e8^ tance measurements. — Before the stoves were used the resistance of the cold heating elements was measured with a Wheatstone bridge box, equipped with a sensitive galvano - meter. When the experimental work was completed, the resistance was again measured on the same Wheatstone bridge box in order to determine any change in the resistance of the units. Table 6 shows the comparison of resistances. These measurements indicate a slight degree of deterioration for open units. However, the units were not used long enough to permit any definite conclusions about serious deterioration. PART I— -SURFACE UNITS A few of the reports available to the public have listed the efficiency of certain types of units, but none of the recent re - ports have compared the efficiency and time rate of heating of units used on modern electric stoves. A glance at the drawings of different types of units reveals a decided differ - ence in construction of units of similar type. Besides this dissimilarity there are the different types to consider. EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE The various factors determining efficiency are: (1) the initial condition of the units, whether hot or cold, (2) the utensils, (3) the amount of water, (4) the temperature change of the water, (5) the evaporation loss, and (6) the duration of the test. Hence it was necessary to divide the experimental tests into three groups : I- — The input .tests for the determination of efficiency for short-time periods, !!• — The input tests for the determination of efficiency for long-time periods, HI.— The output tests for all efficiency calculation. SCHEDULE OF TESTS Gjoup I. — The tests in this group were divided into three sections: (1) cold starts with the cover on the utensil, (2) hot starts with the cover on the utensil, and (3) hot starts with the cover off the utensil. Hereafter the tests in this group will be referred to as cold start, cover on ; hot start, cover on; and hot start, cover off. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves 7 I Group II. — The type of tests considered in this group has been designated as prolonged boiling. The tests were oper - ated with both cold and hot starts with the cover on the utensil. Group III. — This group consists of all the tests devised to determine the output by the use of an immersion heater. METHOD OF TESTS Group I. — For all tests in Group I, the unit was operated on high. The effect of the amount of water was determined TABLE 7 -i£l e S w "* iK^pSSfffA&amp;a eacn unit water fa utensiL In stove I Unlt utensils order to decrease the number 9m n ♦ ., i , * . s . _ °t tests and to avoid duplica - 2100 tubular 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 6 .. . . _ . ., 2000 open i, 2. s. 4. 6 tion between pans of similar fooSsoi'id i: 1: 1: 1; I material, not all the utensils 1200 tubular ;.;.*. 4, g were used on each unit. After 1000 open 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 . . , . , - . , reducing the number of tests b fioS Solid i,V*.b.l to a minimum, a total of 1,432 1200 open i, 2. .', * tests were made in this group, 2000 open 1,2.8.4,6 27 per cent being repeat tests. noSsond i \; l\i:\ Table 7 shows the pan num- D 1800 baffle 1, 2, 8, 4. 6 Jf" **** the On W l" Ch isoo open i, s. 4, 6, e they were used and Table 8 1000 solid i, 2, s. 4, 6 shows the relation between E isooSud I'J'J'o'i the size of the pan bottom and , isoo open 1 1. 2', s. .' the size of the unit. Follow- Table 8. — Size of utensil vs. size of surface unit q,_. tt_i. Pans which Pans larger Pans smaller Stove Unit fit nnit than unit than unit 2100 tubular 4 6 1. 2, 8, 5 2000 solid 4 6 1, 2, 8, 6 2000 open 4 6 1, 2, 8, 5 A 1000 solid 1 2. 8, 4, 5, 6 1200 tubular 1 2, 8, 4, 5, 6 1000 open 1 2,3,4,6,6 2250 solid 4 6 1, 2, 3, 6 B 1600 solid 4 6 1, 2, 8, 6 ' 1200 open _.. 1, 2, 8, 4, 6, 6 2000 open 2, 4, 5 6 1, 8 C 1250 open 1, 3 2, 4. 6, 6 1100 solid .... 1. 2, 8. 4, 6, 6 D 1800 2, 6 4, 6 1.8 1500 solid .... 2. 4. 5. 6 1, 8 1600 open 2, 6 4, 6 1. 8 E 1000 solid 1 2, 3, 4, 5. 6 1000 open —. 1, 2. 8. 4, 6. 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 /^^^ J9\ perature was measured by AyS^/^ three couples in parallel. The r^j JS T :^J&lt;&amp; i same amount of water and the I I w. fo\/ J / same pans were used as for §_*£s!Za *^^&gt;^C \. e * n P u * tests. The pan was fl/""" iT^S^j^S^^ placed on a base made of in - ll r_m ■Ls^^ ia su^ a ti n K board. For all the ~\\ _^_^jr^^ P ~As&amp;jT\ ou tP u t tests, the energy-time V*^^!^^^^. psffl. 1 curves of the input tests were /^7^1I?!^jK^V P 1 duplicated as nearly as pos - ' W7f/if^\l RVvvV b* sible ; thus the radiation and (ill luV | kill || M convection loss of the utensil WAvoX^^IJUy J 11 1 j should approximate that of I \^s^^w^»^&gt;y^ was regulated so that the in - f\a^^««» A^^__r put was kept constant. The |." - "^^ It) desired potential was found by a trial-and-error method. Fio. 81. — Immersion heater coil Energy readings were record - with terminal assembly. eyery two mhmtes and ammeter readings every minute. At the end of the test the water was weighed to determine the evaporation loss. In order to compute one of the outputs for the prolonged boiling tests the radiation and convection loss at the boiling point of water was found. The apparatus was set up as in the preceding closed-cover immersion-heater tests. Four pounds of distilled water were used in each test. The poten - tial was adjusted until an input was found which would keep the water gently boiling; then this input was held constant for one hour. The same procedure was followed for violent boiling. This constant input would just compensate for the radiation and convection loss of the pan. Evaporation loss was recorded. RESULTS Temperature as a function of time of heating. — Repre - sentative curves (Fig. 32) have been chosen to compare the temperature of the water with the time of heating for the various types of surface units. For utensils other than No. 1, these curves would be slightly shifted either to the right or the left, the shift depending upon the relation of the utensil to the unit. All of the curves except 3 and 4 show regularity in change of temperature with time. Probably the decrease in slope after the first six minutes for No. 3 is due to the change in the rate of absorption of heat by the reflector. At the beginning of the test some time was necessary for the cold surface of the reflector to become sufficiently hot for heat </seg>
            <seg id="p021">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves I I I I I I 1,1,1 U N JJ I □ I J I I II to be rapidly trans - ~"ZZIZ^i_2 E ?il-7'.^zzzz_z ferred b y conduction | Z/Lj-ZZZ-2Z^---*t-- to the under surface I ZZZZti-$2jZ$Z'iiiz- ?*--— and lost. As the tem - t,ZZ~~t i "jt tc-^ iim 1' t ~ perature of the reflec - | XZ-ZZAtt -^Z-^-AtzZZZZZZZ tor increased more | ZZ%ii j_\ Zt_~ g^-f--- --r--- heat was lost by radia - |--^2^^i^ tion and convection, * leaving less available "j^^ J ' ' ' I J I I I I J I I | | j | | j | to be transferred to i?to qo a- • , . "Vr "*"" „ . the utensil and water. Fig. 1^^ 1^^ 68 for vanous The same explanation probably holds for Solid line=cold start: broken line-hot start. Data „„■_,„. VT/% A *«.» +V,„ taken from utensil 1 tests with four ponnds of CUrVe JNO. 4 IOr the wnter: (1) large tubular, (2) large open, (3) small "conp and rpflpptor" tubular, (4) cone and reflector, (5) large silld, (6) *-«"** ««U reiiecior rmall flat ring, solid. (7) small open, (8) small solid. Units Of StOVe D. If (9) large tubular. (10) Urge solid, (11) large open, "/ " Z Is (12) cone and reflector, (18) small solid, (14) the temperature - time rmMl open. __ . .. curves for both open units of stove E were plotted they would exhibit the same change in slope when aluminum pans were used. Probably the change in the rate of absorption of heat by the unit, coupled with the more rapid loss of heat at higher tem - perature by the aluminum vessels when compared to enameled vessels, accounts for this change in slope. 18 (See Table 9.) For all the hot-start curves a change in slope was due to a change in the rate of transfer of heat as the time increased. Usually the transfer of heat to the utensil was more rapid at the beginning of the test because of the amount of heat stored in the unit. Since the same conditions of stored heat could not be obtained exactly for each hot start, considerable variation in the time necessary to heat the same quantity of water for different tests would be expected. The personal estimation of the proper condition of the unit for a hot test is a deciding factor in this type of test. Probably a linear variation in the times required to heat various quantities of water in the same pan from 72" to 206° F. was the best as - surance that the hot conditions of the unit were all similar at the beginning of a test. "Supplementary tests showed that thc exterior temperature of the aluminum pans followed very closely the temperature of the water, while the exterior temperature of the enameled pans lagged several degrees behind the temperature of the water. This difference in exterior pan temperatures is probably due to the more rapid conduction of - heat by the aluminum pan. The great difference in conductivity is evident when the conductivities of aluminum, steel, and porcelain are compared. At 212° F. the con - ductivities are: aluminum 0.40, steel 0.107, and porcelain 0.0026. Since enamel-ware utensils are porcelain-covered steel, the conductivity of the pan will be between 0.107 and 0.0026. The aluminum pan Is at least five times more conductive than the enameled pans. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Time of heating and efficiency. — Two efficiencies have been calculated, a minimum efficiency and an actual effi - ciency. 14 When determining the efficiency for any unit and pan the same input was used for both minimum and actual efficiency. The input was the total energy used to obtain the desired temperature change of the water. Since for each specific test the input is the same for both minimum and actual efficiencies, these efficiencies will depend upon how much of the input is considered as doing useful work and how much of it. is lost. The output for the minimum efficiency is the same for all short-time tests hav - ing equal quantities of water. It is the amount of heat, ex - pressed in watt-hours, necessary to heat 4, 3, 2, or 1 pounds of water from 72° to 206° F. For the long-time tests, it is the amount of heat necessary to heat 4 pounds of water from 72° to 212° F. In the actual efficiency all heat that is not delivered to the utensil and the water is considered as loss. This efficiency represents the maximum amount of heat that the unit is able to deliver to do useful work. The factors considered in calculating the output for actual efficiency are the mass of the water, the water equivalent of the utensil, the evaporation loss, and the radiation and convection loss of the pan at 212° F. The radiation and convection loss of the utensil from 72° to 212° F. was omitted from the calculation, since it could not be calculated nor found by experimentation. Because of the low temperatures involved, however, this fac - tor would be small. To compute the energy lost by radiation and convection at 212° F. it was necessary to know the time during which the water was gently and violently boiling. These times were determined by the input tests. . The radia - tion and convection loss expressed in watts is given in Table 9. Table 9. — Maximum radiation and convection loss of utensils for boiling water Utensil Gentle boiling Violent boning No. Watts Watts 2 zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz mio mio 3 18S.6 1M.6 4 193.6 216.0 5 104.0 119.0 6 183.5 16S.S " About fifty immersion-heater tests were made to find experimentally the output for short-time tests. These experimental outputs are important, for they include the energy necessary to heat the waiter and the utensil and to supply the radiation and convection loss. However, for two reasons the tests were abandoned: first, the energy necessary to heat the immersion heater was also included, and second, the time necessary to perform the required number of tests Was prohibitive. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves To compute the water equivalent of the enameled pans it was necessary to determine the specific heat of enamel ware. The specific heat was determined by a method of mixtures. A portion of an enameled pan which had been previously damaged was used as the test material. The average of four trials was used as the specific heat. The result obtained was 0.124." For the aluminum vessels the specific heat used was 0.217. When computing the water equivalent of the utensils, the temperature change of the pans was considered to be the same as that of the water. For the short-time tests with covered pans no evaporation loss was considered in the output. Upon condensation of the water vapor the heat which was used to vaporize the water was considered as given up to the cover and the walls of the pan. It is by this method that the cover must receive most of its heat, because the imperfect contact between the cover and the side walls will not allow sufficient transfer of heat by conduction to account for the temperature of the cover. For the cover off tests, whatever vapor was lost was added to the output. 16 For short-time tests the formula for computing the actual efficiency for covered utensils was: *——-«, . &lt;*~_?i2*zFo x io. % «., For the uncovered utensils the formula was: Percentage of efficiency = [0.2928 (m+w) (Ti— T 0 )] + 17.8c Input in watt-hours x 100% &lt; 2 &gt; where m is the mass of water in pounds w is the water equivalent of the pan in pounds Ti is the final temperature in degrees Fahrenheit Tn is the initial temperature in degrees Fahrenheit c is the amount of water vaporized expressed in ounces 0.2928 is the conversion factor to change B.T.U.'s to watt-hours 17.8 the heat in watt-hours necessary to change 1 oz. of water at 206° F. to vapor at 212° F. The formula for computing actual efficiency for long-time tests was : Percentage of efficiency = [0.2928 (m+w) (T t — T 0 )] + (af -f bt") + 17.7c Input in watt-hours x 100 % &lt; 3 &gt; where m is the mass of water in pounds w is the water equivalent "of the utensil in pounds ■ \\ 2? 1 " reBUlf ia not to J» considered aa a precision measurement. "Since most of the vaporization takes place near or at the boiling point, the evap&gt; ration loss for all tests has been computed on the basis of all tho vaporisation occurring at the boiling point. Tbe error introduced by this assumption is small. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Ti is the boiling point of water in degrees Fahrenheit To is the initial temperature of the water in degrees Fahrenheit a is the radiation and convection loss in watts for gentle boiling b is the radiation and convection loss in watts for violent boiling f is the time in hours for gentle boiling t" is the time in hours for violent boiling c is the evaporation loss expressed in ounces 0.2928 is the conversion factor to change B.T.U.'s to watt-hours 17.7 is the heat in watt-hours necessary to change 1 ounce of water at 212" F. to vapor at 212° F. The efficiencies for all units and utensils for both hot and cold start short-time tests are given in Tables 10 to 14. The efficiencies for the long-time tests are given in Tables 15 and 16. The efficiencies are not the only important features of surface units, for a complete analysis requires a comparison of the time rate of heating and the distribution of time when the switch is on high, low, or off. Comparisons of the tune and energy necessary to heat four pounds of water from 72° to 206° F. in each utensil on each unit for cold start, cover on ; hot start, cover on ; and hot start, cover off are shown in Tables 17, 18, and 19. In these tables the units are arranged so that the time and energy are listed in ascending order. Supplementing the energies are the minimum efficiencies given in Tables 10 to 14. Pans 1, 3, and 4 have been grouped together since they were used on all units. However, these tables show that the units can - not be considered alone, for there is a definite relation be - tween the utensil and the time of heating and energy consump - tion for each unit. For short-time heating on the large open units the greatest efficiency was obtained with the enameled pans, while on the small open units it was obtained with the small aluminum pan No. 1. Both the large and small open units were least efficient when used with pans 2, 5, and 6. The reasons for these re - sults can be easily explained. First, the transfer of heat from the unit to the utensil was almost entirely by radiation ; therefore the contact between the bottom of the utensil and the unit was not an important factor. It is, however, essential that the bottom of the utensil be a good absorber of radiant energy. This requirement was met by the enameled pans and the black-bottomed aluminum pan. The second factor to con - sider is the relation of the diameter of the pan to the diameter of the unit. Utensil 4 exactly fits and utensil 3 almost fits the large units, while utensil 1 exactly fits the small units. In other words, utensils 3 and 4 are too large for the small units and utensil 1 is too small for the large units. Pans 1 and 3 are the same height, but owing to its larger diameter pan 3 has a larger surface for radiation and convection loss. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Thus, on the small units, utensil 1 may be used to better advantage than 3. Four factors made utensils 2, 5, and 6 undesirable to use on the open units: (1) the polished bottoms of the aluminum pans reflect a part of the radiant energy back upon the unit and less is absorbed than for the enameled pans; (2) the diameters of pans 5 and 6 are too large for either the large or small units; (3) the walls of pan 2 are too thick; and (4) the pans are too high. On all the solid cast units greatest efficiency was obtained with the cast aluminum pan 2, while least efficiency was obtained with the enameled pans 3 and 4. The 1200-watt tubular unit was most efficient when used with utensils 1 and 3 and least efficient with utensil 2. The method of transfer of energy from the tubular unit to the utensil changed when the unit was started cold. At the beginning, the transfer was almost entirely by conduction, but as the unit continued heating the coils grew red in color so that the transfer was almost entirely by radiation. Hence for the cold start the maximum efficiency from this unit at the beginning of the heating period was obtained when the heating element made good contact with the bottom of the utensil. As is shown by Figure 13, such contact was not possible with utensil 2 but was possible with the recessed bottoms of utensils 1 and 3. Obviously, pans 1 and 3 were better adapted tojthe 1200-watt tubular unit than pan 2. The 2100-watt tubular unit was most efficient when used with pan 4 and least efficient with pan 6. Pan 6 was much too large for the unit. Greatest efficiency was obtained on the ring-type units when used with pans 1 and 5, but this type was least efficient with pans 4 and 6. The transfer of heat was almost wholly by conduction, but because of the small thermal mass and the thinness of the metal casing, the unit proved to be very efficient. Since the inner ring was usually elevated somewhat above the outer ring, a utensil with a re - cessed bottom was better adapted to the unit than a pan with a perfectly flat bottom. Utensils 4 and 6 were much too large for the ring units. Tables 15 arid 16 show that for long-time heating, great - est efficiency was obtained on all of the units when used with pans 1 and 2 and least with pans 3 and 4. The reason for this is the difference in the radiation and convection loss for aluminum and enameled pans. Since enameled pans are good absorbers of radiant energy they are also good radiators. During a sustained cooking process the radiation and convec - tion loss of the enameled pans was far greater than that of the aluminum pans of similar size. This is shown in Table 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Table 10. — Percentage of efficiency of surface units, stove A | Pounds. | Utensil 1 | Utensil 2 I Utensil 8 Utensil 4 [ , Utensil 8 | Utensil 6 Unit | of water I Minimum | Actual || Minimum [Actusl j Minimum lActual | Minimum jActnal | Minimum |Actua} | Minimum [Actual COLD START. COVER ON 3 2,000 open 4 37.6 89.0 37.8 40.8 89.6 41.5 40.6 48.0 — 34.2 86.8 E 8 84.6 86.2 82.7 36.8 86.6 88.8 36.5 89.4 — 80.4 88.5 gj 2 29.8 31.7 27.4 81.9 80.3 83.0 32.1 85.9 — 24.7 28.6 £. 1 22.4 25.6 20.0 26.6 23.4 27.6 j 28.8 29.4 — 1 — 17.8 23.4 CO 2,000 solid 4 29.4 80.4 84.8 87.6 26.7 27.9 25.4 26.8 27.9 80.0 W 8 26.8 28.2 29.9 88.2 24.8 26.8 22.9 24.7 22.2 24.6 &gt; 2 21.1 22.6 24.4 28.4 21.4 28.8 18.5 20.6 — — 18.4 21.2 1 12.0 18.7 16.6 20.8 13.7 16.2 12.0 14.8 12.6 16.5 H 1,000 solid 4 48.5 45.0 45.0 48.5 88.0 89.7 84.6 86.6 36.6 88.2 1 M 8 87.8 89.7 88.8 48.1 36.0 88.1 80.7 83.2 81.0 82.8 I ...... I" 2 83.0 35.2 30.4 85.8 29.6 82.2 25.6 28.5 26.0 28.3 1 21.7 24.7 28.2 80.8 19.8 23.6 16.5 20.8 17.6 20.6 CO 1200 tubular 4 60.6 62.6 47.5 61.8 60.0 62.6 57.5 61.0 56.0 68.6 Ef 8 56.0 58.6 44.4 49.2 56.6 60.1 54.0 58.1 51.5 « 54.5 T 2 48.8 62.1 38.8 45.0 48.0 62.6 46.8 62.2 44.4 48.1 -_ 1 88.2 43.6 I 28.2 87.6 87.3 44.0 85.0 48.1 82.4 88.0 £J 1,000 open 4 64.8 66.2 48.5 52.4 49.0 51.4 47.9 50.8 45.8 47.2 gj 8 47.0 49.8 48.7 48.5 47.5 60.3 48.6 46.9 89.5 41.9 2 2 40.7 43.6 36.0 41.9 88.9 42.5 87.6 42.0 83.5 36.8 g 1 80.6 34.8 26.1 84.8 29.7 85.1 27.4 88.8 24.4 28.6 Eg 2100 tubular 4 47.7 49.5 46.9 50.6 47.0 49.2 40.6 52.4 40.2 42.0 41.5 44.8 Q . 8 43.6 45.6 41.9 46.5 42.8 46.4 46.1 49.8 87.6 89.8 88.2 42.1 \X\ 2 87.8 40.5 85.1 40.8 86.4 89.7 38.2 42.6 82.0 34.7 82.0 86.8 1 27.0 30.9 26.0 I 83.8 26.8 31.1 ( 26.9 88.2 23.2 27.2 21.9 28.7 \jj HOT START, COVER ON C 2.000 open 4 46.7 48.4 56.5 60.0 52.4 64.7 71.0 75.3 I 49.7 68.6 £ 8 64.4 57.0 57.8 635 60.1 68.7 72.7 78.6 50.6 65.8 L, 2 40.5 43.5 50.0 58.1 58.6 63.9 €3.7 71.2 I 42.9 49.6 H 1 84.4 39.2 84.1 45.8 46.2 54.6 63.4 66.0 ...... 1 I 28.0 36.6 m 2,000 solid 4 54.6 66.4 87.8 95.0 57.5 60.0 68.2 67.0 55.0 59.3 2 8 61.6 64.8 71.0 78.7 64.0 57.1 59.9 66.9 68.6 64.6 _ 2 68.2 67.6 79.0 91.9 65.8 71.9 46.6 67.4 59.8 69.0 2* 1 68.7 72.8 71.9 95.5 65.9 77.9 68.2 67.0 68.1 82.6 * 1,000 solid 4 70.0 72.4 I 87.8 94.7 55.3 58.0 49.7 62.6 76.0 79.2 8 66.8 70.0 78.9 82.0 72.7 77.0 60.6 54.5 65.1 69.0 2 78.2 88.8 68.1 79.1 65.5 71J&gt; 69.8 77.4 70.0 76.0 1 76.0 86.8 I 63.8 84.6 47.9 I 56.6 60.0 74.0 68.7 74.6 ,.....* </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Table 10. — Percentage of efficiency of surface units, stove A — Continued | Founds Utensil 1 Uiersil 2 ' Utensil 8 ' ' Utensil 4 j Utensil 6 Utensil 6 Unit | of water | Minimum |Actual | Minimum | Actual | Minimum |Actual j Minimum [Actual',1 (Minimum |Actual | Mlnimunl lActual |^. HOT START. COVER ON— (Continued) „ 1200 tubular 4 78.6 76.0 67.6 62.1 71.8 76.1 64.2 68.0 59.7 62.2 j 8 71.0 74.6 65.6 61.7 64.8 68.6 69.4 74.7 58.2 56.4 _\ 2 65.9 70.5 62.7 61.2 68.6 76.0 68.7 71.1 61.0 66.6 — m 1 64.3 73.4 40.3 58.5 65.9 77.9 67.3 70.8 47.0 65.1 «; 1.000 open 4 61.8 68.5 60.8 65.7 59.6 62.4 70.9 75.0 59.1 61.7 __ ' y 8 67.0 70.8 65.6 72.6 66.8 70.8 70.1 75.6 61.6 65.0 g 2 66.4 71.1 69.4 69.0 64.6 70.4 65.2 78.0 59.0 64.0 3 1 67.0 76.6 49.5 66.6 60.4 71.4 56.5 69.7 48.8 57.1 — u 2100 tubular 4 64.5 66.8 59.6 64.6 59.6 62.4 67.2 71.2 54.8 56.6 85.5 59.7 m 2 61.6 66.1 47.9 55.6 54.9 59.8 62.2 69.5 47.1 51.2 51.0 I 58.8 H 1 66.0 62.6 44.9 59.7 50.6 60.0 58.5 72.4 42.5 49.7 42.6 | 55.9 HOT START, COVER OFF g 1 2 000 open 4 56.9 64.1 66.4 69.0 50.5 57.9 54.0 68.5 45.0 57.9 g ' open Bgo B4(( g9B 49 j. B? 2 Bg j. 71 g 48 9 fi24 f» 2 62.0 69.6 87.2 52.1 62.6 65.1 69.0 77.8 86.9 57.5 g 1 60.6 71.0 39.5 66.7 48.9 64.7 54.9 89.9 26.9 54.7 M 2 000 solid 4 69.5 77.5 . 80.1 91.6 47.6 65.7 47.6 60.6 54.5 69.3 g ' 3 60.2 69.3 78.0 92.9 88.6 47.7 58.7 71.6 52.0 70.2 r&lt; 2 47.9 58.9 73.8 98.0 54.5 70.6 48.4 57.0 61.0 71.6 g 1 43.9 66.6 69.8 109.0 66.5 76.8 40.7 62.0 ...... — 88.7 63.5 r 1000 solid 4 79.6 96.5 66.6 86.2 52.4 67.3 49.6 70.5 68.2 66.1 hH i,uuu bohu s flB2 g00 gi7 489 640 B46 774 4i6 B4B LJ 2 71.8 92.8 C2.6 91.6 58.5 79.0 40.1 69.6 42.6 67.0 M X 66.0 92.3 53.4 98.0 38.4 65.1 42.0 75.9 88.0 64.1 o 1200 tubulsr 4 66.0 78.9 45.8 61.4 60.4 80.2 56.5 76.8 49.4 64 7 [J 1200 tubular 4 oo.u «j q |(j 7g9 &amp;fj _. 4g&lt; g 2 57.2 71.9 42.5 62.0 58.0 85.0 58.4 76.0 40.8 61.0 O 1 j 48.9 C6.5 30.4 61.5 43.9 74.5 | 43.0 77.6 27.6 74.7 1000 cnen 4 55.0 78.6 61.3 74.6 61.6 77.6 I 56.9 83.3 46.0 68.1 W 1,000 open J o 74() 4gg 747 B7 j 74 9 . 47R 7B0 480 fi82 g 0 66.8 78.1 89.5 62.0 54.5 78.5 I 42.8 72.0 44.9 68.0 2 1 64.1 78.9 84.6 66.8 61.0 80.9 | 89.6 69.1 84.0 67.1 g 2100 tubular 4 59.1 66.9 63.2 68.8 64.5 62.5 I 63.2 74.8 I 47.7 56.0 47.9 61.6 W 2100 tubular « g« g4 . 4fl 4 |M B8&gt;g g22 | 6((2 ?2 g 4 „ B B2 g „ _. M  - 2 64.9 64.4 I 46.5 I 62.5 I 61.0 I 63.0 I 68.5 73.5 I 43.4 66.0 48.4 61.0 | I j B2.6 | 71.0 | 37.6 | 59.2 I 44.9 | 61.1 I 52.6 74.5 I 87.6 65.1 88.4 | 65.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">■ Table 11. — Percentage of efficiency of surface units, stove B I Pounds Utensil 1 1 Utensil 2. / I Utensil 8 UtensU4 Utensil B Utensil 6 Unit | of water '{"Minimum |Actusl |Actnal | Minimum |Actual j Minimum lActuall Minimum |Actaal | Minimum lActual C0L1&gt; START, COVER ON &lt;Z| 2,250 solid 4 82.8 84.0 41.9 45.2 81.8 88.2 27.4 29.0 ™ : 82.2 84.8 S ' 8 27.9 29.2 86.0 40.0 27.2 28.8 28.6 25.5 27.4 80.2 2 2 24.4 26.1 28.8 88.6 20.0 21.9 22.6 25.2 „ 21.4 24.7 £ 1 16.8 J8.6 18.8 25.0 14.7 17.4 12.4 16.4 1 — 18.2 17.8 jjg 1600 solid 4 42 6 44.1 I 86.2 87.8 82.8 84.7 86.2 87.6 89.4 42.4 W 1500 solid 4 42.8 44 1 ..... g() ? g 8g g £ 2 80.2 82.8 ~ 20.8 28.7 22.7 26.4 28.4 80.8 29.0 88.4 1 18/T 2M ! 17.2 20.8 14.2 17.6 18.6 21.6 15.8 20.6 __ 1200 open 4 67.5 59.6 42.1 45.6 52.8 64.7 49.6 62.7 ,. M P 8 49.2 51.5 88.8 48.1 46.8 49.1 47.0 60.6 * 2 44.0 47.0 84.6 40.0 42.2 46.0 89.9 44.5 1 82.9 87.6 24.1 T 82.0 81.1 86.8 81.6 89.0 — I CO HOT START. COVER ON Sj 2,260 solid 4 112.0 I 116.0 141.0 162.6 65.8 68.9 67.9 61.4 69.0 74.8 ' 8 106.8 112.0 208.0 280.6 66.8 70.8 76.6 82.5 77.2 85.0 2 84U0 90.0 197.5 229.5 65.8 71.8 74.5 88.2 „ 118.0. 180.0 ft) 1 99.0 112.8 188.0 250.0 ( 70.5 88.5 58.1 71.8 — I — 110.0 148.4 M 1600 solid 4 64.6 66.8 ...... 62.4 64.8 68.6 72.8 106.8 111.0 79.0 85.0 2 1600 SOlld 4 64 0 0£0 - 6g7 ?i9 BgB 6gl Mi0 j g„ ggj « S 88.8 951 70.3 76.5 65.8 73.6 116.0 126.0 98.7 114.0 \\_ 1 94i0 Vfth ZZ. AA- 74.5 88.0 54.9 67.8 86.8 101.8 84.0 110.0 g 1200 open 4 62.7 65.0 66.0 60.6 70.2 78.6 I 67.9 71.9 - W open t4 b Bg 7 62 9 g7 6 ... | 68 7 6g g __ _ 2 68.0 78.0 55.2 64.2 68.7 69.5 69.4 66.5 CO 1 62,7 71.6 89.9 68.0 68.5 69.2 | 52.7 65.0 — 1 G HOT START, COVER OFF C 2 260 solid 4 104.0 114.2 129.0 1161.0 66.0 64.1 65.1 77.2 — — «.0 99.7 w 2.250 folia J iu».u ji g7 4 gg g „ g JJ9 , • I 119.5 187.1 118.0 151.8 68.6 75.1 67.0 87.7 98.8 127.9 3 1 116.0 148.0 155.0 244.0 61.8 69.9 66.6 86.0 80.7 127.8 Z iiuin «au 1 B2.8 98 0 65.0 76.4 61.6 74.5 99.4 118.6 70.9 87.2 -. 1500 solid 4 82.8 98.0 „ oo u to . MJ mJ) g&gt; 2 840 986 Z 60 8 78.0 57.2 75.1 85.9 105.8 100.0 182.0 °° 1 BU 110.9 Z Z 64.5 80.3 58.1 88.6 83.2 117.8 94.0 148.8 1200 onen 4 62.5 76.6 46.9 64.2 55.8 71.0 50.6 70.0 1200 open j »« jo » 47 0 gB 0 M B 7J B B7 B 78 j 2 66.4 72.6 89.6 69.7 64.6 73.6 62.8 77.5 1 52.0 76.9 82.4 54.6 54.5 80.8 52.6 79.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Table 12. — Percentage of efficiency of surface units, stove C I Pounds 1 Utensil 1 Utensil 2 '. Utensil 8 I Utensil 4 Utensfl6 Utensil 6 Unit j of water | Minimum |Actuall 'Minimum |Actual | Minimum |Actual I Minimum lActualll'Minimnm lActnal | Minimum lActual COLD START, COVER ON M 2.000 open 4 45.1 46.7 80.2 42.8 44.1 46.1 42.9 45.8 84.8 87.0 £ 8 87.8 89.6 84.8 88.6 89.6 42.0 40.0 48.0 80.4 38.5 — 2 88.0 35.2 29.8 84.6 84.0 87.2 88.2 87.1 _- 24.6 28.8 Q 1 24.0 27.4 20.6 27.5 25.8 29.9 22.9 28.8 16.5 21.6 1260 open 4 49.0 50.6 50.1 I 62.6 46.9 49.7 89.6 U.8 " 8 46.6 48.7 44.6 47.8 48.0 46.8 86.4 88.6 O 2 40.8 48.1 89.5 48.0 87.2 41.6 80.6 88.2 "3 1 80.8 86.2 _. 27.4 82.4 26.4 82.6 22.2 26.1 .. 1100 solid 4 68.0 60.0 60.0 64.6 61.8 64.0 52.1 65.1 — ..... - m 3 68.9 66.5 67.8 64.1 53.6 56.9 48.0 51.8 — &lt; 2 47.4 50.6 45.0 62.6 47.6 62* 41.4 46.2 H 1 84.6 89.6 82.1 42.6 88.5 89.6 81.1 88.4 - HOT START. COVER ON X 2.000 open 4 60.4 62.0 66.5 60.0 69.1 61.9 I 58.6 62.0 48.6 47.0 g ' 3 55.0 67.6 68.7 59.0 58.6 66.9 61.1 65.9 46.5 51.2 g 2 58.7 67.6 52.0 60.5 63.0 67.9 54.6 61.0 40.6 46.7 K 1 88.7 44.2 44.9 59.6 47.9 66.6 | 47.0 68.1 — I 82.1 42.0 M 1250 onen ' 4 66.5 68.7 .. 60.1 68.0 62.6 66.1 52.6 65.0 _ g 1250 open 4 «».» •«.&lt; .... gB g g9 9 BW g4 0 44 4g g « 2 60.8 65.2 55.6 60.6 60.8 67.9 48.1 62.8 _ g 1 Wio 69.4 64.0 64.9 62.0 64.8 40.7 47.7 .... i ...... f 1100 solid 4 I 72.6 75.0 70.0 76.5 64.6 67.7 67.2 71.2 gtj 7))g 74)) 7()0 77g gg0 gg9 g4g jjg LJ 2 71.8 77.0 67.6 78.6 68.7 69.6 65.6 62.0 . — . — — \___t 1 | 69.8 79.1 59.0 78.4 49.5 68.4 60.6 62.6 — ft HOT START, COVER OFF tj 2,000 open 4 45.7 52.8 I 68.1 68.8 68.8 68.6 56.5 68.5 48.5 68.0 g z.uuu open 4g go B g2 jg, 5j.j „ 2 49.4 60.0 44.6 61.8 47.1 61.1 58.0 69.6 — — 88.2 57.9 1 87!2 50.1 88.8 60.6 46.0 67.6 45.4 74.4 ~~ 26.7 65.9 CO 12K0 onen 4 63.7 76.5 60.1 72.5 62.0 66.0 42.6 58.0 ...... g 1250 open 4 M7 (•» ?2 g Bg . 7g g gg g 4g 0 o 2 61.8 68.0 - 57.5 74.4 60.0 71.1 41.6 58.8 „ fi 1 Jgil 64.9 60.5 70.4 46.0 76.8 82.1 64.8 W 1100 solid 4 61.0 74.9 68.8 78.1 65.5 69.9 49.2 66.6 ..... I — • nuu soiio BgB ggB BB9 71(; B40 70B 4g0 gg8 2 62.6 77.0 68.6 82.0 62.3 78.6 50.8 71.6 I 69.9 88.9 89.9 67.4 47.0 74.6 48.0 70.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Table 13. — Percentage of efficiency of surface units, stove D I I I I i i i g f Pounds Utensil 1 Utensil 2 Utensil 8 . Utensil 4 . Utensil 6 I Utensil 6 M Unit | of water | Minimum |Actuall||Minlmum |Actual | Minimum lActuall Minimum lActnall Minimum lActual | Minimum |Actual g COLD START. COVER ON CO 1800 baffle 4 46.9 48.5 86.4 39.4 46.0 48.2 I 50.1 68.1 82.1 84.6 W 3 44.5 46.5 82.9 86.5 44.2 47.0 48.0 46.5 ... —. 80.2 88.3 &amp;► 2 87.8 40.6 29.6 84.4 87.6 41.0 88.6 48.0 26.4 80.5 1 80.4 84.7 21.1 28.0 28.4 83.6 | 29.4 36.4 ™. 21.2 27.8 __ 1800 open 4 50.0 51.7 60.1 52.5 50.5 68.6 81.4 82.7 38.8 86.4 fg " . 48.0 50.8 46.0 47.6 45.8 49.4 82.0 88.9 30.0 83.0 F 2 41.8 44.7 40.8 44.5 40.7 45.6 28.8 81.8 24.4 28.2 1 ttJ J?!! 81.8 87.6 30.0 87.0 24.0 28.0 19.9 \ 26.1 CO HOT START. COVER ON &gt; 1800 baffle 4 60.1 62.0 I 41.6 45.0 I 61.1 68.6 I. 67.6 61.0 86.4 89.8 . 8 52.7 55.8 41.1 45.6 62.0 56.0 67.8 61.7 ...... .... 86.2 39.9 hrj 2 49.4 63.0 | 88.9 45.2 48.6 68.0 52.6 68.8 88.8 38.4 m 1 44.0 60.1 | 24.7 82.8 85.8 41.7 | 39.9 49.8 — 80.0 89.1 fig 1800 open I 4 66.5 58.5 I ' ..... I .... I 66.0 68.5 59.5 68.0 88.8 40.6 89.2 42.8 5 open KJ g0 B Bg B 6L0 g7 2 J9 , 899 44 „ £ 2 62.6 56.5 ...... ...... 52.6 57.6 62.1 58.2 84.2 87.2 36.4 42.0 o f 1 48.0 54.6 I ..... f .... I 87.6 44.5 48.1 58.4 27.8 $2.6 SS.6 44.0 f__\ HOT START. COVER OFF M 1800 baffle 4 47.1 57.9 I 28.8 42.4 46.8 56.4 51.0 67.6 w.n.b. w.n.b. £ 8 46.5 48.1 80.2 44.5 46.0 58.8 47.8 68.1 w.n.b. w.n.b. S 2 40.5 54.4 25.8 88.2 48.9 59.2 47.9 67.5 w.n.b. w.n.b. L, 1 82.9 40.6 w.n.b. w.n.b. 40.6 69.7 84.6 68.4 w.n.b. w.n.b. a 1800 cnen 4 51.8 62.9 ...... 49.4 I 60.8 60.4 I 65.8 81.5 48.1 w.n.b. I w.n.b. \\_\ 1800 open 4 51 » e^» . | gg ffc(| Jg&gt;g 4J g 2 48 5 80.9 48.4 61.0 46.5 I 68.6 26.1 89.5 W.n.b. w.n.b. 1 48.Q 57.8 85.1 1 57.7 89.6 | 69.1 22.8 42.8 w.n.b. | w.n.b. m Notb: w.n.b. = Would not boll. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Table 14. — Percentage of efficiency of surface units, stove E f Pounds Utensil 1 Utensil 2 Utensil 8 I Utensil 4 1 UtersUS Utensil 6 Unit | of water | Minimum |ActuaU IMInimum |Actual | Minimum JActual I Minimum |Actuall| .Minimum lActual | Minimum lActual CO COLD START, COVER ON 3 1500 solid 4 47.5 49.1 47.6 51.4 45.0 47.1 42.8 46.4 — 42.1 45.8 g 8 48.8 46.0 45.8 60.1 89.8 42.1 88.0 41.0 87.4 41.1 K 2 87.6 40.8 86.9 48.0 86.8 40.0 82.6 86.3 81.0 85.7 - 1 27.4 81.4 1 28.9 81.8 1B___ 81.8 22.4 27.6 .... 28.2 80.4 §g 1600 open 4 45.1 46.7 44.8 47.9 45.7 47.3 43.3 45.9 ™ \~ 86.8 89.6 3 40.9 42.9 85.7 39.6 41.8 48.7 89.5 42.7 34.2 87.6 KtJ 2 83.8 35.7 28.7 38.4 83.4 86.5 88.4 87.8 27.5 81.7 g 1 25.0 28.6 20.6 28.7 26.6 80.2 24.2 29.9 19.6 26.0 g 1,000 solid 4 64.0 66.0 48.3 60.6 49.1 52.0 60.1 62.3 45.4 48.9 ' 8 46.9 49.1 45.2 48.0 48.0 46.4 44.4 47.0 40.5 44.5 Q 0 49.7 43.6 86.4 89.8 85.4 89.6 88.5 41.8 33.2 89.2 £$" 1 80.7 86.0 28.2 88.4 25.6 81.6 26.8 81.4 28.6 30.9 g 1.000 open 4 55.0 67.0 60.2 54.1 51.0 63.4 51.0 54.0 - g ' 8 60.0 62.5 44.2 49.0 47.5 10.3 45.0 48.7 ~ - S 2 43.0 46.0 86.2 42.1 41.0 44.8 89.0 43.5 W 1 83.8 38.6 26.0 34.5 82.2 88.2 28.8 1 85.6 — g HOT START, COVER ON C 1600 solid 4 71.8 74.4 78.6 86.0 74.4 77.7 69.6 78.8 ,70.8 76.4 fl s.v. «»u 722 g02 719 7gl 7gg gQ0 ggn „g 2 68.7 78.6 68.6 79.8 64 6 70.4 68.4 76.4 67.0 72.2 brj ■ 1 45.2 51.6 60.0 79.8 52.6 62.8 62.7 77.5 . — . — 46.6 60.7 _-* 1500 open 4 68.5 66.9 61.0 66.0 69.1 62.0 68.7 67.6 55.7 60.0 W open g() B M1 6g0 gg9 gB0 gg7 g 2.6 O 2 60.6 64.9 46.7 54.4 57.6 62.6 60.8 67.9 49.7 57.3 « 1 60.4 69.0 46.6 60.3 60.8 71.0 58.6 72.8 49.4 64.6 g 1 nno rnliri 4 68 1 70.5 70.0 78.0 76.0 79.4 76.4 79.6 70.2 76.6 « 1.000 solid 4 681 WA ?g 4 7B B g0 fl gg j 7g „ 2 752 806 70.3 76.5 72.6 81.0 61.7 67.0 65.8 76.0 «" 1 .1.1 66.4 62.2 73.5 68.0 71.7 62.6 78.6 52.6 69.0 g 1.000 open 4 68.0 70.4 62.6 67.6 73.0 76.4 62.0 65.8 — — &lt; l ' P • 8 70.0 78.4 69.5 66.1 74.0 78.5 65.0 70.0 W 2 68.6 78.2 66.8 66.0 66.6 72.7 57.6 64.1 w 1 . 65.4 74.5 43.1 57.4 65.9 77.9 64.5 67.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 77... g Table 14.— Percentage of efficiency of surface units, stove E— (Continued) 3 _ / Pounds' I Utensil 1 / Utensn2 i UtenslU UtensiU 1 UtensUS , Uteml "V , __ Unit I of water I Minimum lActuallj IMInimum lActual ) Minimum [Actual | Minimum | Actual,! IMInimum lActual | Minimum lActnai jg HOT START, COVER OFF 3 S3 Hi SS Si » 85 SS 3g z z |I g g 5 55 SS 8 B ?:S SS ii:S » SS SS z z S§ SS &gt; 1500 open 4 68.0 67.2 68.7 64.6 60.1 69.6 67.2 79.7 48.4 62.1 open gfl2 g|)0 71 a ggB ,j_j 50.2 68.6 *W I K SS SS SS SS SS SS 7S.I z z fti S5 | i*» — 8 4 m ss ss ss ss ss ss ss sts ss E I 660 720 "'■' Z 615 811 57.2 78.4 59.9 79.0 47.4 78.8 5 1 50.7 78.9 Z.' ...... 53.4 78.6 40.7 71.2 48.5 71.0 w.n.b. w.n.b. » 1000 onen 4 I 69.6 71.6 42.5 64.9 60.1 74.0 47.1 67.8 M 1,000 open J gg() Mg „ B &lt;&lt; j 66.4 -•• g&gt; 2 59.0 76.6 84.0 49.7 55.6 76.0 49.4 76.0 ..... ~~ S 1 57.0 80.2 w.n.b. |w.n.b. 46.5 68.6 85.3 81.7 -;-; ■____ ___. L, Note : w.n.b. = would not boil. H OO </seg>
            <seg id="p033">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves In all of the tests the efficiency was greater when a cover was used on the utensil. In several cases when no cover was used the water could not be raised to the boiling point. This is shown in Table 13 for pans 2 and 6 on stove D, and also in Table 14 for pan 6 on stove E. Supplementary tests showed that owing to the oversized bottom of the pan when compared to the unit, there were not sufficient convection cur - rents established to distribute the heat throughout the entire mass of water. The water boiled at the center of the pan but at the outer portions the temperature was never higher than 194° F. This was also true for pan 6 when 3, 2, and 1 pounds of water were used. All of the units except those of stove D were more efficient for hot starts than for cold starts. The exceptions were with utensils 2 and 6 for hot STARTS, COVER OFF On Stove D. Table 15. — Efficiencies for long-time tests— cold start Unit, stove.. Evaporation etoUo violin" Eneryy Minimum Actual and utensil ■ jog, j^jj j^U used efficiency efficiency Ounces Attn. Min. Watt-hrs. Per cent Per cent 1200-T-A-l 1.600 16 29 327.0 50.3 80.8 1000-O-E-l 2.760 16 24 847.5 47.4 80.8 1100-S-C-l 1.750 18 24 857.5 46.0 73.9 1200-O-B-3 1.626 14 24 362.0 45.6 81.0 1000-O-K-3 1.250 22 18 367.0 44.9 81.0 1000-O-A-l 2.000 13 24 373.0 44.0 70.0 1200-T-A-8 1.600 22 22 376.0 48.7 80.8 1100-S-C-2 2.876 20 23 377.0 48.6 84.6 1000-S-E-l 8.000 13 27 881.0 43.1 74.2 1200-O-B-l 3.000 8 80 805.0 41.6 71.0 1000-S-E-3 1.876 22 17 402.6 40.8 71.8 1600-S-E-2 4.376 20 25 410.0 40.0 85.6 1000-O-A-2 3.000 7 27 412.0 39.9 74.0 1000-S-A-2 8.250 15 23 412.0 89.9 76.9 1500-O-E-3 1.600 11 83 415.0 39.6 74.0 1250-O-C-l 8.750 8 89 415.6 39.6 72.0 1000-O-A-8 ' 1.125 17 20 422.6 88.9 66.6 I260-O-C-3 2.000 15 27 425.0 38.7 72.8 1BO0-S-E-1 2.760 7 38 427.0 38.5 67.0 1000-O-A-4 1.750 20 16 440.0 87.4 74.8 1B00-O-E-1 3.000 8 37 442.0 87.2 65.7 1300-O-D-l .600 17 26 444.6 37.0 54.8 1800Ba-D-l 1.760 18 26 447.6 86.7 69.8 2100-T-A-l 1.760 11 88 448.0 36.7 61.8 2100-T-A-2 2.250 22 26 456.0 86.2 70.2 1100-S-C-3 2.750 20 20 466.0 85.8 67.7 1500-S-E-3 6.000 23 21 472.5 84.8 81.0 1B00-S-B-1 5.000 10 84 480.0 84.2 67.6 2250-S-B-2 6.000 20 28 484.6 84.0 79.8 2100-T-A-4 8.000 28 19 489.0 88.6 78.9 1300Ba-D-4 1.250 26 19 491.0 88.6 70.2 2000-O-C-4 2.000 8 88 491.0 88.4 76.6 1000-S-A-3 8.260 12 20 497.0 88.1 61.7 1800-O-D-4 1.600 81 13 605.0 82.6 68.7 2000-O-A-4 8.260 19 28 605.0 82.6 77.8 2000-S-A-2 7.260 8 - 38 624.6 81.4 77.6 2000-O-C-l 8.876 4 41 629.5 31.0 67.8 2000-O-A-2 6.000 8 38 646.5 - 30.1 67.2 1600-S-B-6 6.00C 6 86 669.0 29.4 63.9 1500-S-B-S 6.876 15 26 686.0 28.1 66.6 2000-I-A-3 3.876 6 84 661.0 24.8 61.6 2250-3-B-9 BM0 7 SB MSJ) 24J! 64.0 •Explanation of' designation: 1st column, watt ratine of unit: 2nd column, type of unit -where T is tubular, O is open, S is solid, and Ba is baffle ; 3rd column, stove letter : and 4th column, -pan number. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Table 16. — Efficiencies for long-time tests — hot start n_» f ..„„„ Time of Time of _ „. . " mnSut7_7n't Evaporation gentle violent Enerp Minimum Actual and utensil* lom j^j boa used efficiency efficiency .,___■-. Ounces Mm. Min. Watt-hrs. Percent Percent }f00-S-B-l 8.750 10 48 181.0 90.6 223.4 JfOO-S-B-e 8.760 12 42 218.0 75.5 197.0 22B0-S-B-2 14.500 18 42 260.0 63.4 212.5 ISSS"?^ 1 8 - 500 " » 8 286.6 67.6 106.0 1000-O-A-l 2.250 10 S3 290.0 66.6 94.8 1200-O-B-l 2.500 7 . 38 290.0 56.6 97.1 1000-O-E-l 1.760 15 80 801.0 64.6 89.8 1100-S-C-2 8.000 12 S3 308.0 63.4 106.8 1200-O-B-3 2.000 6 S9 808.0 53.4 104.0 I000-O-E-3 1.000 18 24 310.0 68.0 98.7 2000-O-A-2 4.760 6 46 812.5 62.6 120.0 1B00-S-E-1 2.600 29 22 824.0 50.8 89.8 1600-S-E-2 6.500 6 48 825.0 50.6 118.0 1500-S-E-3 4.000 6 43 825.0 60.6 112.8 1200-T-A-l 2.500 24 21 326.0 60.6 86.6 1B00-O-E-1 3.876 4 42 880.0 49.8 93.1 1100-S-C-3 1.600 22 23 386.0 46.2 91.8 1000-O-A-2 2.876 10 28 387.0 48.8 ; 92.3 1000-O-A-3 1.000 19 20 344.0 47.8 82.2 1000-S-E-3 2.260 17 28 347.0 47.4 92.6 2100-T-A-l 2.750 23 28 S50.0 47.0 84.4 1250-O-C-l 4.000 6 39 851.0 46.8 60.8 1200-T-A-3 2.250 20 24 852.0 46.6 90.0 1100-S-C-l 10.260 16 30 855.0 46.4 118.0 2000-O-A-4 3.500 19 82 366.0 46.3 116.0 1000-O-A-4 1.S76 22 19 363.0 45.4 93.0 1000-S-A-3 3.600 13 27 866.0 46.0 90.8 2100-T-A-2 3.250 21 80 B66.0 45.0 94.0 2000-S-A-3 8.760 0 48 872.0 44.2 120.8 1000-S-A-2 6.600 0 42 874.0 44.0 103.4 1300-O-D-l .876 15 30 876.0 48.8 67.8 1500-O-E-3 8.000 17 80 880.0 43.4 89.8 1B00-S-B-3 9.260 29 20 389.0 42.4 115.9 2000-S-A-2 6.000 5 45 390.0 42.1 101.2 12B0-O-C-3 2.000 22 23 896.0 41.6 79.5 2260-S-B-3 2.000 11 40 896.0 41.5 84.2 2100-T-A-4 3.600 33 18 407.5 40.4 99.8 2000-O-C-l 4.250 14 85 419.0 89.2 76.2 1800Ba-D-l 1.125 17 27 422.0 39.0 60.6 2C00-O-C-4 4.S75 25 23 464.0 85.4 80.3 ]S00Ba-D-4 3.000 25 18 492.0 33.4 75.7 1300-O-D-4 3.125 6 40 492.0 SSA 79.6 'Explanation of desisnation: 1st column, watt ratine of unit; 2nd column, type of unit where T is tubular, O is open, S is solid, and Ba is baffle ; 3rd column, stove letter ; and 4th column, pan number. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves TABLE 17. — Comparative time of heating, energy consump - tion, and minimum efficiency for U pounds of water, cold START, COVER ON Pan 1 Pan S Pan 4 Unit t Unit w eft Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff f-10.48 e-261 60.6 f-10.68 1-258 61.3 f-10.05 e-276 67.5 E-11.90 1-272 68.0 a-11.95 e-264 60.0 a-11.90 1-803 62.1 j-11.90 1-276 67.6 i-12.17 i-802 62.8 j-12.64 r-310 61.0 a-12-87 r-28S 65.0 g-12.37 r-310 61.0 g-14.26 n-813 50.6 h-18.67 c-291 54.8 p-18.92 n-815 50.1 n-14.44 m-815 60.1 0-18.87 q-292 64.0 n-14.67 k-315 60.1 e-14.67 i-318 49.6 e-18.95 n-316 60.0 e-14.70 c-322 49.0 m-14.70 f-320 49.5 p-14.08 k-323 49.0 0-14.74 q-327 48.S p-14.72 q-822 49.1 n-14.82 f-331 47.7 1-15.38 f-836 47.0 o-16.55 c-330 47.9 m-15.75 o-332 47.5 k-16.92 m-342 46.0 k-16.58 k-837 46.9 1-16.00 m-337 46.9 m-15.97 p-346 45.7 h-17.62 p-365 4S.3 k-16.17 j-350 45.1 h-16.13 o-351 46.0 1-17.96 j-369 42.9 b-16.53 P-3B0 45.1 b-17.40 j-358 44.1 b-19.47 O-370 42.8 i-17.48 d-364 48.5 i-18.98 a-399 S9.6 q-19.53 a-390 40.5 q-17.90 b-371 42.6 q-19.70 d-416 S8.0 1-20.00 d-458 34.5 r-18.B2 a-420 87.6 r-20.00 h-137 36.2 r-20.13 h-482 32.8 c-19.58 B-481 82.8 c-21.20 k-498 81.8 c-22.00 s-676 27.4 d-28.03 b-686 29.4 d-26.20 b-580 26.7 d-29.22 b-624 25.4 Pan 2 Pan 6 Pan 5 Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff' C- 9.42 1-264 60.0 f-12.00 q-348 45.4 f-12.60 e-282 56.0 f-10.65 r-315 50.2 ff-12.20 o-375 42.1 e-16.00 q-816 50.1 a-18.00 c-826 48.5 a-14.13 f-380 41.5 h-16.00 c-849 45.3 b-13.6C o-332 47.6 h-14.78 h-401 39.1 q-18.88 f-893 40.2 j-13.85 c-333 47.5 j-16.60 p-430 86.8 k-20.16 k-899 89.6 O-IS.92 f-337 46.9 O-15.70 j-460 84.3 n-23.08 d-482 36.6 p-14.48 d-352 46.0 p-17.87 n-463 34.2 c-23.52 h-437 86.2 1-16.67 P-3B7 44.8 b-17.44 n-467 38.8 d-27.00 n-603 31.4 e-19.00 i-375 42.1 q-20.82 B-490 82.2 m-20.10 b-378 41.9 n-21.18 m-492 32.1 r-20.47 j-404 39.2 m-23.07 b-666 27.9 c-21.68 a-424 37.3 d-22.45 m-4S4 S6.4 j.23.63 b-455 84.8 Legend : a=2000 open, stove A ; b=2000 solid, stove A : e=1000 open, stove A ; d=100O Solid, stove A; e=1200 tubular, stove A; f=2100 tubular, stove A; B=2250 solid, stove B: h=1600 solid, stove B: 1=1200 open, stove B; J=2000 open, stove C: k=12B0 open, stove C; 1=1100 solid, stove C: m=1300 baffle, stove D ; n=1300 open, stove D ; . o=1600 solid, stove E ; p=1600 open, stove E; q=1000 solid, stove E; r=1000 open, stove E. t=time in minutes ; w=energy in watt-hours ; eff=minimum efficiency. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Table 18. — Comparative time of heating, energy consump - tion and minimum efficiency for U pounds of water, hot start, cover on Pan 1 Pan 8 Pan 4 Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff E- 3.53 b-141 112.0 k- 6.08 o-212 74.4 a- 6.80 q-211 74.5 f- 7.82 e-215 78.5 b- 8.35 r-216 78.0 gr- 6.88 a-222 71.0 b- 8.77 1-218 72.5 f- 8.42 e-220 71.8 f- 7.40 c-223 70.9 h- 8.97 O-220 71.8 o- 8.82 i-225 70.2 b- 7.68 o-227 69.6 p- 9.98 d-226 70.0 j- 9.05 q-226 70.0 h- 8.45 h-280 68.6 a-10.55 q-282 68.1 a- 9.25 c-243 65.8 j- 9.22 i-233 67.9 i-10.72 r-288 68.0 p-10.66 1-244 64.8 o- 9.68 f-285 67.2 k-11.90 k-238 66.5 h-10.98 k-262 60.1 p-10.08 1-285 67.2 e-12.20 h-245 64.5 n-12.93 f-265 69.6 n-12.12 e-246 64.2 n-12.77 f-245 64.6 k-18.20 c-265 69.6 k-12.62 p-248 63.7 1-18.08 p-248 68.4 q-18.42 , J-267 69.1 m-12.67 b-250 63.2 O-IS.63 i-252 62.7 r-14.00 p-268 59.1 q-12.78 k-253 62.6 m-14.60 c-268 61.8 i-14.03 b-275 57.6 1-18.70 r-254 62.0 d-14.72 n-280 66.5 1-14.23 n-282 66.0 e-14.12 n-266 59.5 r-15.09 b-290 64.6 m-14.33 d-282 55.8 i-14.75 j-270 58.6 i-15.73 i-314 50.4 c-17.67 a-302 62.4 c-14.95 e-273 67.9 c-17.82 m-815 50.1 d-18.11 h-302 52.4 f-16.42 m-275 57.6 Q-19.27 a-338 46.7 e-21.16 m-809 51.1 d-20.60 d-818 49.7 Pan 2 Pan 6 Pan 5 Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff Unit t | Unit w eff B- 2.75 B-112 141.0 e- 5.75 h-200 79.0 h- 5.45 h-148 106.8 b- 6.52 d-179 87.8 h- 7.82 o-22» 70.8 f- 9.22 q-207 76.4 0- 8.40 b-180 87.8 b- 8.80 q-225 70.2 q-12.85 d-208 76.0 f- 8.42 O-201 78.6 f- 9.07 B-229 69.0 d-18.68 e-264 59.7 ' a- 8.73 1-226 70.0 o- 9.87 p-288 59.7 e-14.68 c-267 59.1 1- 9.75 r-252 62.5 a- 9.86 f-285 55.5 k-15.05 f-291 54.8 p-10.66 p-269 61.0 p-11.69 b-287 66.0 c-17.97 k-800 62.6 d-12.18 c-260 60.8 j-12.30 a-S18 49.7 h-18.88 n-407 88.8 1-13.32 f-265 69.6 q-13.37 j-362 48.6 e-14.67 e-276 67.6 n-18.63 n-402 89.2 r-16.68 i-282 56.0 m-20.15 m-484 86.4 m-17.62 a-284 65.5 i-17.55 j-285 65.5 c-17.55 m-880 41.6 . Legend same as for Table 17. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Table 19. — Comparative time of heating, energy consump - tion and minimum efficiency for 4 pounds of water, hot START, COVER OFF Pan 1 Pan 8 Pan 4 Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff E- 8.78 R-152 104.0 E- 7.02 h-243 65.0 _- 6.10 p-235 67.2 b- 6.93 h-192 82.3 h- 8.87 q.247 63.9 f- 8.00 k-242 66.1 h- 7.08 d-198 79.5 j- 9.15 O-250 68.0 a- 9.05 q-243 66.0 f- 8.52 b-227 69.6 f- 9.23 c-267 61.5 h- 9.43 f-250 63.2 a- 8.67 c-228 69.4 a- 9.63 e-261 60.4 p- 9.52 o-255 62.0 o- 9.53 q-234 67.6 b-10.28 p-262 60.1 j- 9.67 h-267 61.6 p-10.96 e-239 66.0 O-10.43 k-262 60.1 b-10.17 c-278 66.9 j-11.80 k-248 63.7 p-10.53 r-263 60.0 c-10.61 j-280 56.5 d-12.62 i-253 62.5 k-18.07 j-271 58.8 n-14.S8 e-280 66.6 k-12.70 ' 1-269 61.0 a-14.62 e-282 66.0 q-14.68 a-293 64.0 e-18.89 r-263 69.6 e-14.70 1-285 56.6 m-14.67 k-304 52.0 m-13.80 f-267 69.1 q-14.82 i-286 66.8 k-15.50 m-810 61.0 n-14.00 p-272 58.0 m-16.03 f-290 64.6 c-15.73 i-312 60.6 q-14.08 a-278 66.9 1-16.76 d-302 62.4 c-18.42 n-314 60.4 1-16.62 c-287 65.0 r-16.93 a-313 50.5 1-19.12 d-319 49.6 i-16.72 n-805 51.8 c-17.00 n-820 49.4 i-19.60 1-321 49.2 r-17.27 m-335 47.1 i-17.95 b-332 47.5 d-20.31 b-332 47.6 c-19.18 J-846 45.7 d-19.87 I m-345 45.8 r-21.75 r-335 47.1 Pan 2 Pan 6 Pan 5 Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff Unit t Unit w eff 8- 8.05 s-122 129.0 E- 4.65 g-186 86.0 h- 6.75 h-169 99.4 b- 6.02 b-197 I 81.1 h- 8.22 h-228 70.9 f-10.45 q-236 67.2 a- 8.72 o-229 69.0 b- 8.85 O-270 68.5 q-14.05 d-297 53.2 f- 9.47 d-237 66.6 f-10.47 b-290 54.5 e-17.17 e-320 49.4 a- 9.67 1-271 68.8 a-11.02 q-309 51.0 k-19.04 1-331 47.7 j-10.07 a-280; 66.4 o-ll.SS p-826 48.4 d-19.30 c-343 46.0 p-11.87 p-294 68.7 j-12.44 f-330 .47.9 c-28.12 k-371 42.6 d-16.18 f-297 63.2 p-13.33 a-861 45.0 n-23.42 n-502 31.6 1-16.23 j-298 68.1 q-18.60 j-363 43.6 e-19.40 c-308 61.8 m-w.n.b. c-20.68 i-337 46.9 n-w.n.b. i-21.32 e-S45 45.8 r-24.15 r-371 42.5 m-26.10 m-559 28.8 I I Legend same as for Table 17. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Table 20. — Grouping of units relative to utensils for com - parative time of heating and energy consumption COLO START, COVES ON HOT START, COVER ON HOT START. COVER OFF Time ' Time Time Utensils Utensils Utensils 184266 184265 13426 6 f f f g f f g g a g g h ffggggh gaafge fbgbhf bhfbhf jjjaah bffobq hjaabq aggbhq hobffd ffhffe hpnjjk pjhaoe aapoak oneoon a a j j a k objjod oomppe Jpoppc pobpjc poplbd khpdjn jpodpn nloeq ennlq dknlq mkkmn nkken knqem lmhrm lqmrm eemen k h 1 ■ c qrqm mqki bbbd mill nmer !&lt;qi dlec qlem qqi r m i lrl r r r ice i c i eee cdr rid il d d oed cdr COLO START, COVER ON HOT START, COVES ON HOT START, COVES OFF Energy Energy Energy Utensils Utensils Utensils 184265 184266 184266 e 1 e I q o goqghh ghpggh lenrgq eradoq hqgbhq iilefe leebqd doqood rrrohf oiooge befdbe enmepk dqhlpc oeolqf qkifid qgirff qphapc nefdah rlfpbk ekepfk kqqpnn kklcan krjfan ffeig ffefj ijcJi omkgm hepen lgacm mppjb pjblm rlkln i o j a ipka rime p j o ir. cbri pfir daab nnnm adnm hdd bdj cad a h h jag nnl ggg mhm mbb b b b a m d J m r Legend same as for Table 17. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves In order to compare more easily the different units with respect to time of heating and energy consumption, relative to the utensils used, the grouping of units as given in Tables 17, 18, and 19 is given in Table 20. This table shows, first, that for both cold and hot starts for all the utensils studied, the units having a high watt rating heated the same quantity of water through the same temperature change in much less time than the units having a small watt rating, and second, that in most cases the units having a small watt rating used the least energy while the units having a large watt rating used the most. An exception to the latter appeared for the hot starts on units that were able to store a large amount of heat. The desirable units to use may be easily selected from this table. The desirable units are those which heated the water rapidly with a small consumption of energy. Units which fulfill these requirements are found in the middle sec - tion of the groups. In general, they are the tubular and ring - type units. •AXi "g 0 " S2T |j~; ""J" SSL Fig. 33. — Percentage distribution Fig. 34. — Percentage distribution of time for prolonged boiling, of time for prolonged boiling, hot cold start. start. Last number on notation denotes pan Last nurr.ber on notation denotes pan number. number. Time distribution for long-time heating is shown in Figures 33 and 34. Triangular co-ordinates were chosen, for only one point was necessary to designate the time distribution for each test." For long-time cooking the unit should be oper - ated on low and off as much as possible, for the purpose of "The vertices of the triangle denote the maximum conditions of 100% HIOH, 100% LOW, and 100% OFF while the bases opposite the vertices denote the conditions of O/o hue 0% LOW. and 0% off respectively. A particular time distribution is given by^tne intersection of three co-ordinates. Point 12 on Fig. 84 may serve as an illustration. This point is at the intersection of 85% hiqh, 20% u&gt;w. and 45% oft. This point de - notes the time distribution for the 1000 open unit of stove A used with pan 4 Hence for utensil 4 on the 1000 open unit of stove A the unit was on HIUH 35% of the time, en LOW 20% of thc time, and on off 45% of the time. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Table 21.— Grouping of units for various classes of time distribution for long-time processes — cold start Group I Group II Group III Group IV Group V Group VI Group VII ' " i 2250-S-B-2 2100-T-A-4 1500-S-E-2 1500-S-B-5 1200-O-B-l I000-O-E-3 1300-O-D-4 2000-S-A-2 ... 2000-O-C-4 1250-O-C-l 1300Ba-D-4 1000-S-A-2 1000-S-E-l 2100-T-A-l 1500-S-B-l 1250-O-C-3 1600-S-E-8 1000-S-A-8 2000-O-A-4 1500-O-E-l 1500-S-B-3 1000-O-A-3 2000-O-A-2 „, . 1200-T-A-l 1200-O-B-3 „.. 1100-S-C-3 2100-T-A-2 ..i 2000-O-C-l 1000-O-E-l 1000-O-A-4 2250-S-B-3 J. 1600-S-E-l 1000-O-A-2 2000-S-A-S J 1100-S-C-2 1000-O-A-l ...... 1300Ba-D-l 1000-S-E-8 ~ 1100-S-C-l j iBoo-o-E-3 ; „;._. 1300-O-D-l . „ -i 1200-T-A-8 See Table 21A for explanation of designations. Table 21A. — Grouping of units for various classes of time distribution for long-time processes — hot start Group I Group II Group III Group IV Group V Group VI Group VII 1500-S-B-l 2000-O-C-l 1000-S-E-l 1000-O-A-4 12B0-O-C-3 1000-S-A-2 1300-O-D-4 2000-O-A-2 1600-S-E-l 1000-O-A-l 1000-S-A-8 1100-S-C-l „.„ 2000-S-A-S 1500-S-E-S 1300-O-D-l 1000-O-A-8 1000-O-A-2 2250-S-B-2 2100-T-A-4 1200-T-A-l 1100-S-C-3 1600-S-B-5 1500-O-E-3 1200-O-B-l lSOOBa-D-4 2250-S-B-3 2000-O-C-4 1100-S-C-2 _. _. _, 2100-T-A-2 ;.. 1250-O-C-l ™ „.. 2100-T-A-l - : 1000-O-E-8 „„ 2000-S-A-2 1200-O-B-3 2000-O-A-4 „_. . 1000-O-E-l „ 1500-O-E-l ISOOBa-O-l „ 1600-S-E-2 1200-T-A-S ~. 1500-S-B-3 lOQO-S-E-3 ,.:. Explanation of designation: 1st column, watt rating of unit; 2nd column, type of unit where T is tubular, O is open, S is solid, and Ba is baffle ; 3rd column, stove letter ; and 4th column, pan number. Group 1 — OFT 60% or greater; Group II — OFF from 40% to 60%, nion less than 20%. Group III— off from 40% to 60%, HIOH from 20% to 80%. Group IV — off from 40% to 60%, HIOH greater than 80%. Group V— oft from 20% to 40%, high less than 80%. Group VI— OFT from 20% to 40%, high greater than 30%. Group VII — off less than 20%. utilizing stored heat. When the time distributions are grouped in different classes as shown in Tables 21 and 21A the units are again found to fall in a descending order of watt rating. The units of high watt rating were operated on LOW and off the greater percentage of the. time, while the units of low watt rating were operated on HIGH and LOW the great - er percentage of the time. However, the data in Tables 15 and 16 show that the energy consumption was greatest for units of high watt rating and smallest for units of low watt rating. From the point of view of economical operation, units of low watt rating should be used whenever possible. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Table 22. — Temperature of the open unit heating wires measured with the optical pyrometer „. Tr „ If Bright- Black-bottomed Uncovered stove Unit bottomed pan teakettle unit Degrees F. Degrees F. \ Degrees F. A 1000 open 1647 1620 1506 2000 open 1801 1685 1607 B 1200 open 1604 1488 1488 C 2000 open 1686 1584 1660 1250 open 1677 1644 1503 D "SkSSSr removed 1561 1678 1660 Deteriorated reflector 1828 1688 1688 Polished reflector 1821 1670 1605 Blackened reflector 1602 1692 1542 1000 open 1810 1640 16 40 The efficiency data show that there was a great difference in the efficiencies for units of the same type. A considera - tion of the temperature of the various heating elements does not account for the difference in efficiencies. The tempera - tures of the open-unit heating wires as measured with the optical pyrometer and the temperatures of the solid heating units as measured by the iron-constantan thermocouple are given in Tables 22 and 23. The results show that the tempera - tures of the open heating wires were nearly the same for each unit studied. The temperatures of the solid-unit elements having a high watt rating would lead one to predict for them a higher efficiency than for those of low watt rating. How - ever, the results of the efficiency tests show that such was not the case. Aside from showing the maximum tempera - tures obtained for each element these data proved to be of little importance. To determine what becomes of the heat . which is lost, temperatures Table 23. — Temperatures of were measured at various surface units measured p i ac es in the wiring compart - with an iron-constantan ment an( j a t several locations thermocouple on the cooking top. The re - &lt;»„™ unit Tempajture su it s obtained are presented — = — S^nrr in Tables 24, 25 and 25A a 2000 solid 1572 These tables indicate that 1200 tSmUr 1093 much heat was dissipated into b isoo solid 1448 the wiring compartment and 2260 solid 1708 the cooking top. Tempera - c noo solid 1493 tures in the wiring compart- E isoo .oiid 1476 ment show that more heat looo solid 1193 was lost from the units on </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Table 24. — Average temperatures in wiring compartment Stove Unit combination Maximum temperature at steady state ! 2" from bottom 4." from bottom A 1,000 open. 2.000 open, 2,000 solid. Degrea F. Degrees F. 1,000 open, 1200 tubular, 2100 tubular. 117 184 B» 1500 solid, 2250 solid. 1200 open 104 1?B C 1100 solid. 2,000 open, 1260 open. 249 264 E 1500 solid, 1500 open, 1,000 BOlid, 1.000 open 118 148 1 Maximum temperature of tray 282° F. Table 25. — Maximum surface temperatures on cooking top average room temperature 75' F. Stove A Stove B Stove C Stove E Location of with 100 ° With 1000 couples ope ?'„J^ 0 and 2000 With all With all With aU and 2100 open and units on unite on units on tubular units 2000 solid hioh hioh higS ; on high on hioh Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Center . 279 819 896 811 272 Right front corner „ 249 187 179 Left front corner....... . ...... log 1R7 ,ii Right back corner 174 173 241 Left back corner 165 164 234 Center of front edge.... 184 196 278 283 167 Center of side edge 177 170 222 162 86 TABLE 25A. — Maximum temperatures on cooking top of stove D when only one unit is on high — woerage room temvera - ture 75° F. r __ , Left front Right front - Location of couple unit on unit on ; hioh hioh Directly in front of unit on cooking top .._„ " ''se?* " Left front corner of wiring compartment top„„.„......... „ 258 168 Switch knob. _ m 150 Center of cooking top..... ....... .....„„.. __......„...„...„... ......... 198 Left back corner 'of cooking top...., ,- "95 Midway between left front and back units on wiring compartment top................ ....................«.««™..„....„.....„ m .„. 126 stove C than from any of the other units, and also that the "1,000 watt open — 1,200 watt tubular — 2,100 watt tubular" is a better combination of units for stove A than the "1,000 watt open — 2,000 watt open — 2,000 watt solid" combination. A temperature of 725° F. was found for the reflector of the unit on stove D, showing that a great amount of heat was lost from this unit by radiation and convection. This temperature indi - cates why the cone and reflector unit was so inefficient for hot starts. Because of the position of the tray underneath the heating units of stove B, much of the heat lost from these units was dissipated from the cooking top. These results are a rough check of the efficiency results, because temperatures in </seg>
            <seg id="p043">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves the wiring compartment and on the cooking top were least for combinations of the most efficient units. CONCLUSIONS From the results of the efficiency and comparative time of heating data and the heat-loss temperature data the following conclusions may be drawn : 1. The efficiency of surface units depends upon: (a) the power rating of the unit, (b) the type of unit, (c) the initial condition of the unit, (d) the quantity of water used, (e) the kind of utensil, (f) the size of the utensil bottom with relation to the size of the unit, (g) the exterior surface area of the utensil exposed to the air, and (h) the use of a cover on the utensil. 2. Units having small watt ratings were more efficient than units having large watt ratings. 3. If the time of heating is the important factor to con - sider, units of high watt ratings should be used. 4. When a compromise between time of heating and efficiency must be made, the tubular and ring units are the most desirable for both cold and hot starts. 5. The open units of stove E were more efficient than the open units of the other stoves studied. 6. The units of stove D were efficient for short-time pro - cesses when started cold, but for all other processes they were inefficient when compared with the other types of units. 7. The solid cast units were inefficient for cold starts but for long-time processes these units were very efficient. 8. The utensils should have straight side walls, should not be too high, and should be of a size to fit the unit exactly. The cover should make good contact with the side walls. 9. For short-time processes either enameled pans or black - bottomed aluminum pans should be used on open and tubular or ring-type solid units. For all solid cast units, aluminum pans with bottoms making good contact with the unit should be used. 10. For all long-time processes aluminum pans should be used regardless of the type of unit. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 PART II— OVENS Of the available reports, that from the Bureau of Stand - ards (see page 5, footnote 4) is the only one recording at - tempts to determine the actual efficiency of ovens. These in - vestigators tried two methods of determining the efficiency, but both methods are open to criticism. Using the same meth - ods, the authors obtained results similar to those of the Bureau of Standards. 18 Another method tried by the authors proved a failure. Briefly, the test was as follows. It is obvious that if a mass of water, the water equivalent of a container, and the desired temperature change of the water were known, the output could be computed. If the time re - quired to produce the desired temperature change could be found, the maintenance rate for the empty oven could be in - creased to compensate for the energy required to heat the water. By this method it should be possible to keep the oven at a constant temperature. The great difficulty, however, is to determine the required time. Since the actual efficiency seemed impossible to obtain by this method, a different theory was developed and tests performed to determine the inef - ficiency of the ovens. The results are explained in the follow - ing pages. theory The assumption may be made that the same test body can be raised from the same initial temperature to the same final temperature in each oven. Hence the output would be the same for each oven. On this assumption the input could be calculated from the simple formula : Input = output + heat loss, where heat loss is composed of, (1) the energy necessary to preheat the oven, (2) the energy lost by radiation and con - vection from the exterior surface of the oven, and (3) the energy lost when the oven door is opened. Since the output is assumed constant, the heat loss should be an indication of the relative merits of each oven. The factors which determine "The success of the first method depended upon the measurement of oven temper - atures when a cold body was placed in a hot oven. Obviously a temperature gradient is established between the oven walla -and the test body; so more than the required energy to heat the body is necessary to keep the oven at the desired temperature. Hence the oven-air temperatures as measured for this method are too high. In the second method a maintenance rate waa determined that would just keep the empty oven at the desired temperature. Using this maintenance rate, the cold test body was intircUuccd into the oven and left there until it had been heated through a deflnite temperature change. Knowing the maintenance rate for the empty oven and the loss from opening the door, it was possible to compute the efficiency. However, this method is open to the criticism that as soon as the cold test body is introduced, the oven air temperature drops. Hence the computed efficiency is not the efficiency of the oven at the temperature at which the maintenance rates were determined. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves the amount of energy necessary to preheat an oven to a de - sired temperature are: dimensions, insulation, size of the heating coils, and thermal capacity of the inside. As soon as the temperature of the air within the oven be - comes greater than that of the air outside the oven, heat be - gins to flow from the inside to the outside of the oven. Hence for both the preheating and the maintenance of an oven at a constant or average oven air temperature there is involved a transmission of heat from the inside to the outside of the oven for both steady and unsteady conditions. 10 "The fundamental laws of heat transmission were developed by the French physicist Peclet and published in his TraiBt da la ehaleur in 1853. The type of transmission that must be considered here is one where heat must pass through materials and also be dissipated from a number of surfaces by radiation and convection with only the temperatures at the extreme transfers being known. A complete development of the formula used will be found in Kent's "Mechanical Engineers' Handbook" in the section on Heat Insulation. A brief summary of the laws and mathematics involved is as foUows: Assuming that the state of steady heat flow has been obtained, the calculation of the heat transmitted depends upon the fact that the total flow of heat computed at any section perpendicular to the direction of flow must be equal to the total flow" at any other section. For combined conduction and surface effects, the equations involved are /T, f(t) dt T, where H ls the heat transmitted per unit of time, S is a shape factor involving area and thickness. Ti and T- are the temperatures of the two surfaces, and f(t) is the coefficient of heat conduction if it varies with temperature. H=E(T»— T 0 ) where H is the heat transmitted per unit of surface area, Ti is the surface tem - perature. To is the air temperature and E is a factor expressing the total transfer of heat per unit area, per degree difference in temperature, per unit of time. rfc=S(T— TO where H is the heat flowing per unit area, T is the temperature of the. hot surface and T' is the temperature ot the cold surface confining the air, and S is the air space coefficient expressing the flow of heat per unit area per unit time per degree difference in temperature. For flat parallel plates the shape factor S is — where A is the area and B the B thickness ; hence the flow of heat per unit area through the wall in Figure 85 may be written as: H=E,(T— T 1 ) l =£-(T 1 — T,)=^(Tr-T,)=S(T r -T4)=-i(T^-T,)=E,(T B — T.) B, B, B» If U=the over-all transmission coefficient in heat transmitted per unit of area per unit of time per degree of difference in temperature between hot and cold air, then the equations are: Tj = ■ 1 B, B, 1 B, 1 _-j — + — + — H — H — Ei Ci d S C E, or in general H = U(T— T c ) 1 where U = — — - • 2a)+2(i)+2(£) Values of the various surface temperatures may be found from the equations: Tl = T --;T, = T,-i^;T. = T s -^;T 1 = T.-^:T. = T &lt; -^;r. = T 5 -5 E x Ct Cs S C, a. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 nt_tt_ Figure 35 represents the a. *££££,. r ra* A_-»f2:.fZ..r_ oven wall of stove E. Thia *tZ .. H? wa^ was chosen as an ex - &lt;s—«&amp;■&lt;! ~ ample because all of the co- W&amp;*- efficients that must be con - 5 : ?-i» sidered as the heat passes q ~ ' a - |i "~* from the hot interior to the A.—*, tlC« .«««-« outside air are involved. As - tsesm ~~ "fe^ p2ST suming that the steady state _ „_ • has been reached, if H is the Fig. 35.— Oven wall of stove E. heat transmitted at right te&amp;T^cW^MeV W__% -_t%_£% ****** to the wall per unit of i&amp;^^^ tt^5S^l3 Sue *f e * P^ ""J ° f tlme ' T J he of outside waii. Ti=temp. of coid side of air temperature on the hot outjide wan. B,=thickness of Uning. „jj„ j m il. • s. B&gt;=tbickncss of insulation. B 3 =thick n ess side, and T 0 the air tempera - of outside wall. Ci=coefficient of conduc- frnrp nn tllP ori\A biHp Trio -ro tion of Uning. Cs=coefflcient of conduction ™ r . e "J 1 } ae COI( J S1Qe » lne re_ of insulation. Ctf=coefficient of conduction lation between the heat trans - of outside wall. Ei=transmission coef- ■•i j , _ _ . ficient of hot side. E^transmission coef- mitted ana temperature IS fleient of cold side. S=air space coefficient. given by the equation : H = U (T— To) (4) where U is the over-all transmission coefficient. The value U is composed of the conduction coefficients, C; the surface transmission coefficients, E; the air space co - efficients, S ; and the thickness values, B. The relation of the coefficients to U for any combination of parallel materials is given by the equation : U = (5) =(a +=(«+= (3) Tire actual value of U is not easily found, for the three coefficients E, S, and C are functions of temperature. Since the coefficient 1 of surface transmission, E, is the sum of radia - tion and convection it varies with the kind of material, with the temperature, with the difference in temperature, and with the freedom of air circulation. The air space coefficient, S, is even more complicated, for it is the sum of the conduc - tion, convection, and radiation. B is the only value which may be easily determined. If all the coefficients involved in equation 5 could be determined for each part of the oven the preheating energy and the radiation and convection loss energy could be computed. The exterior surface temperatures listed in Tables 26 and 26A indicate why the determination of these coefficients would be difficult. These tables show that the heat is not transmitted equally through each wall and since the coefficients are functions of temperature they would </seg>
            <seg id="p047">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves vary for different sections of the oven. However, despite the fact that these coefficients were not determined, equation 5 may be successfully used to explain some of the results obtained. Table 26. — Maximum, exterior oven temperatures for the steady state. Average room temperature 77° F. of oven Location of couple Stove A Stove B Stove C I Stove E Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Front corners, 2 in. from edge 124 120 114 115 Back corners, 2 in. from edge.. 107 116 112 114 Mid-point, 2 in. from front edge .._ 185 126 126 126 Oven top Mid-point, 2 in. from back edge 124 121 128 Mid-point, 2 in. from right edge 180 121 121 Center of top 117 108 106 118 Mid-point of right edge. 110 114 106 126 Mid-point of left edge 112 118 108 121 - Mid-point of front edge 147 169 .-;„ 190 . Center of outside..- 112 115 121 112 Center of side facing cooking top _ 117 112 118 188 Sides Mid-point of outside, 3 in. from vertical edge 129 127 126 ISO Right vertical edge * 169 171 176 Left vertical edge 149 142 175 Center 188 182 129 133 Mid-point of the rim at top.... 222 188 179 173 Oven door Mid-point of the rim at bottom 176 178 126 166 Handle I 163' 1S8J 121 1 Metal trim of handle. Table 26A. — Maximum exterior oven temperatures on stove D for the steady state — average room temperature 77° F. Location of couples Temperature Degrees F. Center of outside................... - — . — ............ .'....■■ 178 Mid-point of lower outside edge..., ™~~ 121 Mid-point of upper outside edge ........... .. ....... 170 Hack vertical edge, level with cooking top .-. 138 Center of top - 181 Center of door, ,i , mu ■'. ■■■■■■■ 168 Plating on door - — ................... ... — ............ , 188 Junction between door and oven 281) experimental procedure The preheating energy, the radiation and convection loss energy, and the energy lost due to opening the door are easily found by experiment. The specific problem is to compare five ovens which differ in size, type of lining, type of heating element, thickness of walls, kind of insulation, exterior finish, and type of thermostat. With these differences in mind the following set of tests were developed. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Schedule of tests. — 1. Determine the energy and time necessary to preheat the empty oven to 250°, 300°, 350", 400°, 450°, 500°, and 550° F. for both closed and open vent. 2. Determine the time rate of cooling of the empty oven from 500° F. for both closed and open vent. 3. Determine the empty oven heat loss for steady conditions for both closed and open vent. 4. Determine the heat loss of the empty oven for closed vent when the door is opened. 5. Calibrate the thermostat and determine its sensitivity with the oven empty at 250°, 300°, 350°, 400% 450°, 500°, and 550° F. 6. Determine the uniformity of temperature of the oven air. Method of tests. — Copper-constantan couples were used to measure all oven temperatures. During the test three ex - terior temperatures were recorded: (1) on the rim of the oven door, except for stove D where the couple was secured to the rolled edge, (2) at the center of the outside wall, and (3) at the center of the top. The couples were fastened with a strip of adhesive tape about 6 inches long. About five inches of the couple was kept in contact with the hot body so that conduction of heat from the couple tip would be reduced to a minimum. For tests 1 to 5, five couples in parallel were used to measure the oven air temperature. A couple was placed at each corner of the oven about two inches from each wall and one couple was placed at the center. The couples were arranged so that each tip was in the mid-plane of the oven. For all stoves except D, unshielded couples were used when the ovens were heated only by the lower unit. In order to measure the air temperature of stove D the couples were shielded as a protection from the absorption of radiant energy from the unit. They were likewise shielded when the upper units of the other ovens were used. Several methods of shielding were tried but the best results were obtained with the shield shown in Figure 36. Unless the couples were care - fully insulated from the rack from which they were suspend - ed, it was found that the rack sometimes became part of the couple circuit. Glass tubing was used to prevent this. The temperature distribution of test 6 was measured by fifteen couples arranged in three planes with five couples in each plane. A couple was placed at each corner about two inches from each wall with the remaining couple placed at the center. The lower plane was from one to 1^ inches above the baffle, </seg>
            <seg id="p049">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves f ::: "7'--"-.: ;^^~"~ l ~~~ "^ the center plane was yjTfi the mid-pJane of the T"~~7 r "~ • ' ■ ~~~ ~ " "'""". J^ oven, and the upper w™, oe en. • 1 a a st u . til tbe maximum ther- FiG. 36. — Shielded couple for oven test. s. * _• mostat reading was obtained. The maximum for stoves A, B, and E was 550° F. ; for stove C, 500° F.; and for stove D, 600° F. As the tem - perature passed through 250°, 300,° 350°, 400°, 450°, and 500° F., energy and time were recorded. Thus with a single heat - ing the energy and time necessary to preheat an oven were found. This was the only test that required shielded couples for all ovens. From six to eight tests were made for each oven and the average used for plotting curves. 2. Rate of cooling. — The time rate of cooling was deter - mined by heating the oven to 550° F., using only the lower unit. With the unit off the temperature was recorded as the oven cooled. During the first period of coohng, temperatures were recorded every two minutes, but as the temperature difference between readings became less the time was extended successively to 5, 10, and finally to 15-minute intervals. For stoves having adjustable vents, cooling data were obtained for both closed and open vent. 3. Oven heat loss. — By adjusting the voltage, an input was found which would keep the oven air temperature constant to within 1 degree from one to two hours after the oven had reached the steady state. Usually two hours were required to obtain equilibrium conditions. The heat loss was deter - mined at 300°, 400°, and 500° F. for both closed and open vents. From the consumption of energy and the time of the test, the heat loss in watts was computed. During this test and the test following, the three exterior oven temperatures previously mentioned were recorded. To obtain comparable results the room temperature was kept constant to within one degree. The room temperature chosen was 77° F. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 4. Open-door loss. — This test was more difficult than the heat-loss tests, for equilibrium conditions could not be main - tained. The open-door test was made immediately following the heat-loss test. To compensate for the heat loss due to opening the door it was necessary to increase the input slightly. The oven door was opened for 20 seconds at five - minute intervals. The voltage was adjusted until an input was found that would keep the average temperature constant for at least one hour. From the known energy consumption and the time of the test, the open-door loss was computed. 5. Calibration of the thermostat. — A calibration was begun after the oven was heated to the highest thermostat setting. The thermostat was allowed to operate through four cycles before resetting and cooling to the next thermostat tempera - ture. Energy and temperature were recorded at two-minute intervals and at each off and ON of the unit. For all calibra - tion tests the potential was held constant at 220 volts. Time for the short ON and off periods was recorded with a stop watch, while the Elgin watch was used to record the total time. The thermostats were calibrated at 250°, 300°, 350°, 400°, 450°, 500°, and at 550° and 600°F. where possible. 6. Temperature distribution. — The temperature distribution within the oven was measured after equilibrium conditions were established. The inputs determined in the oven-heat - loss tests were used to keep the ovens at 300°, 400° and 500* F. The five couples in the mid-plane were used to measure the average oven temperature. Temperatures for each thermocouple were read at five-minute intervals until the average temperature had remained constant to within 1 degree for at least one hour. The temperature at a particular location was determined by taking the average 'of the readings recorded while the average temperature remained constant. results The energy and time necessary to preheat the various ovens are shown in Figures 37 and 38. The small energy consump - tion and the short time required to preheat stove D are the result of two factors, (1) the power input was less than two-thirds the input of the other stoves, and (2) the thermal capacity of the insulation and the inside was small. Stove B required the most energy because of the large porcelain heating blocks which greatly added to its thermal capacity. It will be noted that at first the energy required for stove E was greater than the requirement of stoves A and C, but at about 225° F. the/ curve drops in between the curves of </seg>
            <seg id="p051">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves am — [ — i — i — . — i — i . __p_____^ T[ P j *•• . J- *• — »fl» i. i» ' J. ' J_ ' ZL 1 O^.AUlSr^_~_ _ *«,, r «1 '/i ' J. I 1 I 1 I J, I J, I Fig. 37. — Preheat energy »- *.»—«-,«.«—. k^-_t for ovens. FlG - 38.— Preheating time as a func - tion of oven air temperature. stoves A and C. The large amount of metal surrounding the lower unit probably accounts for this increase in energy at low oven-air temperature. Also, since for preheating part of the heat transmitted is in the form of radiant energy of short infra-red and long visible wave lengths, the surface transmission coefficients E played a prominent part in the absorption of energy by the lining. Assuming that the con - vection part of the coefficient is about the same for each oven, it would follow that the coefficient E would be less for stoves D and E because of the bright surface of their linings. The total heat loss for the steady state for the various ovens plotted against oven-air temperature is shown in Figure 39. However, because of the oven differences previously listed the total-heat-loss curves do not serve as a comparison of the five ovens. In order to reduce the ovens to a common basis the total heat loss was divided by the inside oven area in square feet. This calculation assumes that the flow of heat is the same through each wall, and although this is not true, the results obtained can be explained approximately by using equation 5 (page 46) if all comparisons are made at the same oven air temperature. The heat loss per unit of area is shown in Figure 40. Ovens A, B, and C, which were similar in construction, will be considered first. They had the same </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 II | I I I I I | u || | | | | | | | m ill :i:::: p r rX I . , I _, ' jjt Jtl — ' a* O*. Aa tt—rrmrr m _~n. ftawf *i^* ' _, ' 1 Jg 1 __ 1 Fig. 39. — Oven heat loss for fig. 40.— Oven" heat loss per empty oven for steady state. square foot of inside surface. kind of oven lining, the same kind of insulation, and the same kind of exterior surface. Oven A had a chromium-plated rim around the door, while ovens B and C had porcelain enamel doors. At the back of ovens A and B there was an air space between the insulation and the outside wall. The side wall thicknesses were 2%, 1%, and 2 inches respectively for ovens A, B, and C. Although the coefficient of conductiv - ity of mineral wool varies with the density of packing, namely from 0.26 (density 6 lb. per cu. ft.) to 0.29 (density 18 lb. per cu. ft) the packing for each stove may be considered as constant without introducing much error. For ovens A, B, and C, l U (6) 1 1 B, B, B» Ei E« Ci Os C3 for all walls except the back of ovens A and B. For the backs of ovens A and B, U= (7) 1 11 Bi B, Bi — + — + — + — + — + — _,, __ S Ci C2 Ca where Ei= surface transmission coefficient of lining E2=surface transmission coefficient pf outside wall Bi= thickness of lining B2=thickness of insulation B 3 = thickness of outside casing </seg>
            <seg id="p053">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Ci= coefficient of conduction of lining C2= coefficient of conduction of insulation C 3 = coefficient of conduction of outside casing S =air space coefficient. Of these factors B„ B 3 , C„ and C 3 may be considered as constant, leaving E„ E 2 , B 2 , C 2 , and S to explain the differ - ences between the ovens. It is obvious that any increase in E, C, or S will increase U, and any increase in B will de - crease U. Since the same insulation is used in each stove, C 2 may be disregarded. The exterior oven temperatures given in Table 27 are about the same for each stove, so E 2 may be Table 27. — External surface temperatures of ovens for heat-loss tests Temperature setting Stove Position of couple 300 400 BOO 600 Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Rim of door 146.4 176.2 207.0 ...„ A Center of side 92.4 102.2 114.0 Center of top 95.5 104.1 116.2 Rim of door 126.2 149.2 172.4 B Center of side 94.6 103.4 113.3 Center of top 94.9 99.0 107.6 ........ Rim of door 180.6 153.4 179.0 C Center of side 96.9 105.2 114.1 Center of top _... 91.9 98.3 105.2 Rolled edge of door.. 116.8 141.0 166.9 184.9 D Center of side 109.1 132.5 155.1 172.6 Center of top 114.9 189.9 163.5 181.6 Rim of door. 122.0 143.9 170.8 E Center of side 91.5 101.7 111.1 Center of top 94.6 103.5 112.5 Average room temperature 77.5° F. omitted. This leaves only E_, B 2 , and S. Again the curves show that stove B, which had the smallest value of B 2 , had the smallest heat loss per unit of area, and also the smallest total heat loss. It is doubtful that the coefficient S had much to do with this small heat loss, for the air space was so wide that heat could easily have been transferred to the outer surface by convection. For stove C the explanation is un- Table 28. — Vent loss in watts for empty oven for equilibrium conditions Oven air Stove B Stove C Stove E . Roon } temperature temperature Degrees F. Watts Watts Watts Degrees F. 800 9 83.0 9 77.5 400 6 49.5 14 77.5 500 3 78J) If) 77.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 doubtedly tied to the coefficient E. Investigation disclosed a large crack between the door and the oven face. This allowed air from the outside to circulate through the oven, thus increasing the convection currents, which increased E and also allowed heat to escape through the same crack. It will also be noted in Table 28 that when the vent was open, the vent loss was large for this oven. The vent loss was the difference between the total heat losses for open and closed vent tests. Here is an example of an oven that had excellent insulation, well packed and thick, and the desired result was lost because of poor door construction. Probably the greater heat loss of stove A may also be attributed to faulty door construction. In this case it was due to careless packing of the insulation. Under the inner casing two large pockets were found where the insulation was not greater than %-inch thick. As shown in equation 6, a decrease in the value of B increases U, which in turn increases H. The oven of stove E was well constructed. The door was tight-fitting with a broad chromium-plated rim which helped to decrease the heat loss. The oven lining was bright alumin - um, so the coefficient E t should have been less than the corres - ***■*-. A,, a.. cost-ms ponding coefficient of stoves hi. »/WiMn«r.r * * Amrb-siunm.T. A and B. Its wall thickness *- - * -* was 2% inches with a half- ~* inch air space between the in - » *" sulation and the outer shell ; a, hence this larger value of B 2 e _ should decrease U as com - pared to stove B. The great SS?iT—— —TZSSr difference in the ovens was /*„««„„« A the insulation. The asbestos - cell used in oven E has a con- Fio. 41.— Oven wall of stove D. ductivity coefficient .which is Ei=transmission coefficient of lining, alrnnqt twiro aa lartri* aa trio E^tranrmiseion coefficient of outer wall. *"««»» twice as large as ine &amp;S? lc, S.^!i.. of i, Unlv *; Bj=thickness of coefficient of mineral wool baffle. B3=thieknras of outer wall. Ci= . .. ., . , , conductivity coefficient of uning. c=con- and it was this larger value ductivity coefficient of baffle. C==conduc- _* _n _„v,;_v, „a&gt;„*..„4-„J *,&gt;_ 4.1 tivity coefficient of outer wall. S, and __ OI Ls WmCtt accounted IOr the =** * p * ce "^"t- higher heat loss. The oven wall of stove D is shown in Figure 41. The value of U for this oven is: ' U= (8) 1 B, 1 B, 1 B, 1 — + — + 1 h— + — H Ej Ci Si Ca S- Cn Es where the important coefficients are Ei, E2, Si, and S2. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Since the values for B lF B 2 , B g , Ci, C 2 , and C s are practically the same as for stoves A, B, C, and E, these coefficients may be neglected. Ei will have a value near that of E t for stove E but E 2 will be higher than the corresponding* coefficients for the other stoves because of the higher external wall tem - peratures shown in Table 27. However, the loss must have been due to the coefficients S, and S 2 . Of the three modes of transfer involved in these coefficients, radiation, conduction, a-a-. — , — , — , — . — . — . — . — . and convection, convection Bf55jSs= probably played the prom - *l "*i f"~ M inent role. Each air space "Jj was about Vk inch wide and .' j . since the space was not *" "tiff broken there was an excel - /J '/ lent opportunity for circula - ss- t' , ~r — ** on °^ a * r currents. It is \ ■'/ / probably by this method that *„. J-'-fr- most of the heat was trans - • " • /// / f erred from the interior to /// the outside. .' 7/f- The heat loss in watts \ // J when the oven door was — v"y opened is shown in Figure £ / 42. The accuracy of the data „ 7 fZy_ for these curves depends up - &amp; on the accuracy of the total , _ I I ] I _ 1 heat-loss data. Knowing the lte 4.&gt;^ n ..ta...r-« n " energy consumed when the Fro. 42. — Heat loss when oven door door was opened for 20 sec - was opened. on( j g a +. g ve m j nu te intervals and the total heat loss at the same oven air temperature, one can compute the loss due to opening the oven door from the formula : 900A Heat loss in watts = 15 B (9) t where A is the watt-hours recorded for the open-door test, t is the time of A in minutes, and B is the total heat loss in watts at the same oven - air temperature as for A. Although the ovens were in the unbalanced state for this sort of test, it is the opinion of the authors that the results obtained are of the right magnitude and occur in the proper order. Because of its larger opening it would be expected that oven E would have the greatest loss. Probably the large mass of porcelain block helped to keep the loss of oven B low at the low temperatures, even though its opening was the same as </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 AAAAAAAA.AAAAAA AAAAA -1 -I tlle °P en i n e? °t oven A. iff rrrrrrr rrr rrr rr to show how the average J. temperature was deter - | I | | | | mined, the variation of j" ■ oven air temperature ;„ I with time for oven E at 400° F. is shown in Fig - |« ure 43. The cooling . _L I I I J Ll I I I I 1 1 1 1 curves for the five ovens iL-i/w,, are shown tn. Figure 44. Fro. 48.— Variation" of oven temperature Except for stove E the at 400° F. with time when door was results fall in the same opened for 20 seconds at 5-minute inter- order as the curves of vals for stove E.' heat loss per unit of arefl j I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I | 'I I in Figure 40.*° I"^ - ------------------ From the point of «_C^ view of the operation of | A-^%;^^ an electric stove and the «.f T^-^^ig;;::- calculation of heat loss * ~~^~n^^^5^-5~^i; _ mz f° r the unsteady state. I I^^sSliS-: probably the most im - i"- ~l:=:=rf« Ii- portant test is the cali - i -■ bration of the thermo - 1. eslJ" ~^~^ stat. Owing to the ex- Fro. 44.— CoolinVcurves, closed vent. * re ™. e len « th &lt;&gt; f . • &lt;«H - bration curve, it is divid - "i — » i -,1*1 nz — "fl — z^rr ed into portions for illus - . Ml\mr. JJ\IKA_ _ NjLlA- tration. Figure 45 shows ~T^ ¥ W{ UWT9X &lt;JY\I\J\ the calibration curve of -JJ 1 Ju^ P \ -If J —^ stove E. The calibration j-r-T r -[[""""i^.- — I "n curves for the other i a/A \ t\ (\lf\ A l\ l\ stoves are similar to this POTW^jAT^^Tt curve - K each portion is ' U V 1 VlN V f i \sXH-y joined to the preceding j-fi 1 — -i r—n 1 1 r portion, the complete i\fl\ l\ \ r~ picture of the total curve * ! TF\F "^—Efertej^T - " is shown. The line indi- Jj v J — .Uv N — y M &gt; J eating average tempera - s'.,, ak &lt;-k. „rr"~w 4.- * . ture for each thermostat Fro. 45.-Thermostat calibration for stove getthy? wag drflwn gQ that the area of the curve above the line was as nearly equal as possible to the area below the line. The average temperature for each ther - mostat setting is compiled in Table 29. To show the variation • However, the cooling curves represent the transmission of heat for the unbalanced state so that the curves of heat loss per unit of area might not be expected to have the same order as the cooling curves because of the different qualities of the ovens. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Table 29. — Calibration temperature vs. thermostat settings Average calibration temperatures Thermostat stove A. Stove B. Stove C Stove D Stove E. setting original original original — -._, — ; _ _ original test test test Original Bailie test test over unit Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. 600 . . 607 478 660 662 619 646 482 568 625 589 600 516 690 626 503 405 502 450 458 651 468 455 S6S 460 400 406 602 408 416 382 395 350 360 457 330 378 307 347 300 293 . 398 * 275 883 290 290 250 243 887 183 298 270 228 200 178 „;;;. .-_■ •;-;. between calibrated temperature and thermostat setting, the differences between the two are listed in Table 30. The thermostat circuit of stove B operates on a different prin - ciple from that of the thermostats of the other ovens. When once the thermostat disconnects the units from the circuit, the units remain off. The only way that the units may be turned on again is by hand. For this reason it is hard to compare this oven with the others. This method is called Table 30. — Difference between calibration temperature and thermostat setting Temperature difference in degrees Fahrenheit Thermostat stove A. Stove B. Stove C. Stove D Stove E setting „!£„., orijrfn.1 orl^-l original , B . me original test test tegt test over unit ______ 600 .. . + 7 -122 660 +2 +69 — 5 —118 + 8 625 +14 500 +15 + 90 +26 +8 — 96 +2 450 + 8 +101 +18 +6 - 87 0 400 + 6 +102 + 8 +16 — 68 — 6 360 0 +107 —14 +23 — 43 — 3 800 — 7 + 93 -26 +33 — 10 —10 250 — 7 + 87 —67 +48 + 20 —22 200 I —22 ;______-. ~~___. the "Dutch Oven Method." In order to obtain sufficient energy for cooking it is necessary to preheat to higher tem - peratures than indicated on the thermostat. This accounts for the great difference between calibration temperatures and thermostat settings. The best calibrations were obtained for stoves A and E. The temperatures of oven C are much too high at high temperatures and much too low at low tem - peratures. If the operator relies upon the thermostat settings as an indication of proper oven temperatures, oven D cali - brates much too high at low temperatures. The effect of </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 as." placing a baffle over the unit in oven D was observed and the results are shown in the column headed "baffle over unit." Temperatures at 250" and 300° F. were brought closer to the temperatures indicated by the thermostat, but above 300° F. the oven-air temperatures were much too low. The sensitivities of the thermostats that is, the maximum temperature differences through which the thermostat oper - ated, are listed in Table 31. At 350°, 300°, and 250° F., the oven temperature remained almost constant at times for stove D. Occasionally humps were produced and these have been indicated by listing the sensitivities as varying between cer - tain values. Table 31. — Sensitivity of thermostat Thermostat Temperature range through which thermostat operates setting s *? Te A Stove C, j Stove D. j Stove E, : original test original test j original test I original test Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. Degrees F. 600 „.. __ 22 650 66 .... 22 46 525 56 600 69 62 26 62.5 460 59 66 28 68 400 61 67 22 61 J60 61 62 16-0-26 66 800 62 56 15-6 64 260 68 68 2-? 64 200 60 .... „„ An important table is No. 32, which shows the average time per cycle and the time and percentage of time that the lower unit was on per cycle. An exception should be made in the 400°, 350° and 300° F. columns for stove D. The values given here are not per cycle, but on an hourly basis. This was necessary, for cycles were not always produced at these thermostat settings and those that were produced were very irregular. It is interesting to note the effect that a cold body in the oven had upon the data in Table 32. Two fruit cakes having a combined weight of about 5 pounds were baked in the oven of stove E with the thermostat set at 275° F. The total baking period was 4 hours and 15 minutes, including the heating of the oven. The cakes were placed in the cold oven. The oven was heated to 330° F. before going off and the thermostat operated through 5 complete cycles and one partial cycle. The time per cycle increased from 32 minutes at the beginning to 41 minutes at the end. The average per - centage of time ON was 18.67. The average oven tempera - ture increased from 245° to 255* F. It will be observed that these temperatures agree well with the calibration data in Table 29, where it is shown that an oven temperature of 250° F. required that the thermostat be set at 275° F. The </seg>
            <seg id="p059">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Table 32. — Total time per cycle and time unit was on per cycle q,„„. Time per cycle in minutes for thermostat settings Stove Distribution of time - 600° F. 650° F. 600° F. 460° F. 400° F. 350° F. 300° F. 250° F. A Total (miss.) 22.91 22.22 24.25 25.00 27.60 33.22 41.75 On (min.) 10.33 9.16 8.06 6.94 6.08 5.44 4.84 On (p. ct.) „ 45.0 43.0 33.2 27.8 22.0 16.4 11.6 C Total (min.) 16.00 15.00 17.00 21.00 25.00 62.60 On (min.) 6.45 6.41 6.07 4.60 4.45 4.14 On (p. eU) 43.0 36.0 29.8 21.9 17.8 7.9 D Total (min.) 3.73 4.22 5.15 4.78 60.00 60.00 60.00 On (min.) _ 2.11 1.86 1.86 1.69 16.00 10.00 9.19 On (p. ct.).- 56.5 44.0 36.2 33.2 25.0 16.7 15.3 E Total (min.) 18.87 20.33 23.67 27.00 31.00 38.25 46.76 On (min.) 8.88 8.28 7.85 7.26 7.18 6.20 6.13 IQn (p. et.) 47.0 40.7 33.1 26.9 23.2 16.2 11.0 time per cycle falls approximately between the columns 350° and 300° F. in Table 32, as likewise does the percentage of time the unit was on. Such a result would be expected when an actual baking is performed. The temperature distribution of the oven air at 300°, 400°, and 500° F. is given in Table 33. From the practical point of view the oven temperature may be considered as uniform. From the data in Table 32 and the preheating data in Table 34 obtained from the calibration curves, it is possible to calcu - late the energy required by each oven during a certain period of time. The power inputs in watts for both upper and lower units and for the lower unit only are given in Table 35. For Table 33. — Temperature distribution in ovens Stove B _. _ Location Stove C of coupler Stove A Closed vent Open vent Closed vent 500 400 300 500 400 300 500 400 800 600 400 800 • p » j? « p. ° F. ° F. " F. ° F. ° F. * F. • F. ' F. ' F. 1 . 499* 398* 298 480 891 299 483 404 298 485 391 800 2 494 400 300 505 402 291 502 387 290 482 389 299 8 497 400 302 507 401 800 506 400 801 498 400 805 4 473 383 296 496 400 306 600 416 806 491 896 802 5 511 407 811 635 412 296 610 395 296 467 378 288 B 482 387 291 490 394 296 491 404 294 493 394 300 7 489 393 298 602 401 297 497 396 293 489 892 299 8 507 405 303 602 404 299 602 402 298 508 404 308 9 496 399 (02 493 897 803 497 408 802 617 410 809 10 512 422 816 516 407 294 510 895 294 488 894 300 11 486 388 289 4R6 393 306 488 410 801 490 892 298 12 479 387 298 514 408 288 494 890 286' 489 391 298 IS 515 410 803 610 409 804 607 408 800 509 404 805 14 485 889 301 490 396 805 498 412 806 617 413 310 15 523 418 807 528 412 297 517 896 294 493 894 800 Average 498 898 802 499 401 299 600 400 298 499 899 302 Upper plane: 1, right front; 2, left front: 3, center; 4. right back: 5. left back. Mid-plane: 6, right front; 7. left front; 8, center; 9, right back; 10. left back. Lower plane: 11. right front; 12, left front; 18. center; 14, right back; 15, left back. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 Table JXL— Temperature distribution in ovens — (Continued) Location ofrenvelit StoTe D Stove E of couples Closed vent Open vent 500 400 800 600 500 400 800 500 400 800 500 400 800 °F. °F. "F. °F. °F. °F. °F. ' F. • F. ' F. °F °F °F 1 ..I 22i 292 B94 494 396 S05 403 °8* 291 498 399* 294* 2 i22 222 222 B06 * U s92 298 «1 M« 292 484 888 289 5 500 400 299 616 610 407 806 602 399 304 499 400 298 4 1ST 222 294 601 600 40 ° 47 » °° 4 294 479 890 294 6 494 898 292 600 500 398 303 614 406 S10 608 404 307 2 122 222 22 B 598 496 896 ° 02 «» 892 296 493 396 296 . 4 22 222 222 B9B 49S 89S 298 «6 896 297 497 398 295 5 525 4 22 52 6 01 ° B1S 410 8U 607 402 303 sos 404 300 ,S 522 4 2« 221 605 501 401 304 401 898 299 488 895 295 10 608 405 808 600 499 398 803 519 412 821 610 411 817 •2 4 S2 122 22 4 B99 49B 89B 297 487 888 294 488 sss 289 12 490 898 294 602 495 394 298 492 888 294 492 891 293 I? 221 4 2J 2 01 625 512 406 805 616 406 804 609 410 801 H 222 4 2S 80 ° 60 ° 497 896 297 482 886 205 476 887 289 s " 5io i_l 222 601 498 89B 297 B17 41B 8 " 607 420 818 Average 409 899 800 500 809 803 499 898 302 496 399 301 example, the total energy required to preheat and maintain oven temperatures for thermostat settings 300°, 400°, and 500° F. when the thermostat operated for one-hour and two - hour periods, exclusive of the preheat time, is listed in Table Table 34. — Time required to preheat ovens using both units data taken from calibration tests Thermostat settings Stoves ■ . 650° F. . 500° F. 450° F. 400° F. 350° F. 800° F. 260° F. Min. Min. Min. Min. Min. Min. Min. A 20.0 17.0 14.6 12.0 10.0 8.3 7 0 B 28.8 21.4 19.5 17.8 16.5 18.2 1L2 C „... 17.6 12.6 10.7 8.8 6.6 4.8 D 13.6 10.5 8.3 7.6 6.0 5.1 45 E 17.5 14.3 12.2 10.8 9.1 8.0 6.0 36. The results were calculated in the following manner. The number of times that the unit was on during the one - hour and two-hour periods was determined from Table 32. By multiplying the number of times on by the average time per cycle and the watts input for the lower unit, and adding to this the energy required to _ „_ preheat, which is the product Table 35.— Power input in of the time listed in Table 34 watt8 J 01 " wew units and the watts input for both . input of oven units Units, the total energy Was stove Both units Lower unit obtained. The results in on H10H on H » 0H Table 36 show that for a one- watts watu hour period of thermostat £ 2-212 \_\ operation oven D was the c 2.883 1,494 most economical to operate. 1 s',063 1,%.% </seg>
            <seg id="p061">A Study of Five Commercial Electric Stoves Table 36. — Total energy required to preheat and maintain oven temperatures for thermostat settings of 800°, 400°, and 500° F. Operation of thermostat Operation of thermostat for one hour for two hours Stove . . — 300° F. 400° F. 500° F. 300° F. 400° F. 500° F. Watt-hrs. Watt-hm. Watt-hrs. Watt-hrs. Waiters. Watt-hrs. A 680 1.114 1,627 958 1,468 2,227 B 789 969 1,168 739 969 1,198 C 649 1.019 1,483 871 1.422 2,126 D 421 667 968 692 1,109 1,617 E 688 1.117 1.392 994 1.505 2.055 For the two-hour period oven B was the most economical. For all periods greater than two hours oven B definitely used the least energy, provided the oven did not have to be turned on again during the baking period. However, since most baking operations are completed in less than 2&gt;/% hours it is impractical to compare the ovens for long periods. conclusions The conclusions to be drawn from the results of the oven tests are as follows : 1. In preheating to the same oven-air temperature, oven D required less than half as much energy as ovens A, C, and E, and less than one-third as much as oven B. Rated accord - ing to the least time and energy necessary to preheat to the same oven-air temperature, the ranking was D, C, E, A, and B. 2. Oven B had the least total heat loss and oven D the greatest. According to ascending heat loss, the ovens ranked B, A, C, E, and D. 3. If the total heat loss is divided by the inside area of the oven, ovens C and E change places in ranking. Rated accord - ing to the heat loss per square foot, the ranking is oven B, A, E, C, and D. 4. The heat loss when the oven door was opened was almost the same for ovens B, C, and D for temperatures up to 400° F., with oven A next in order and oven E losing the most heat. For oven air temperatures above 400° F. the ovens should be ranked C, D, B, A, and E. 5. The cooling curves indicate that the heat loss was much greater at high temperatures than at low temperatures. Be - cause of its small thermal mass, oven D cooled rapidly. In the order of slowest cooling, the ranking was B, E, A, C, and p. 6. In energy required to preheat and to maintain at a de - sired temperature for one hour of thermostat operation, oven </seg>
            <seg id="p062">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 68 D was the most economical despite its high heat loss. For periods of thermostat operation greater than one hour, oven a TOB j ™ most economical - The remaining ovens ranked C, A, and E for all periods of thermostat operation oven E requiring the most energy. ' 7. Because of the principle of operation, the thermostat on oven B should not be compared with the other thermostats. The calibration of the thermostat of oven E was the most accurate, with that of oven A next in order. The calibration of the thermostat of oven C was too high at 450° and 500° F and much too low at 300° and 250° F. The calibration of the thermostat of oven D was fairly accurate at 450°, 500°, 550°, "J^/S?. 0 V.S:' The avera « e temperatures were much too high at 400°, 350°, 300°, and 250° F. Oven D had the most sensi - tive thermostat. 8. The temperature of the oven air at various locations was sufficiently uniform for practical purposes. [2ViM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>