<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Vegetable Variety Tests at the Scottsbluff Substation</title>
               <date value="1936-06">1936-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 300 June, 1936 Vegetable Variety Tests at the Scottsbluff Substation Lionel Harris 19 wKKBKuSB^S-^^S^^^^^^Sx^^^S^Sl^^i Variety tests of cabbage and cauliflower. Scottsbluff Substation, Mitchell, Nebraska Cooperative between Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station and Division of Western Irrigation Agriculture, U. S. Department of Agriculture The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction 3 Climatic Conditions 3 Soils and Location 4 Irrigation and Cultivation 4 Results with Vegetables Trit d 5 Asparagus 5 Bush Beans 5 Table Beets 6 Cabbage 6 Carrots 8 Cauliflower 8 Celery 9 Chard 10 Sweet Corn 10 Cucumbers 10 Eggplant and Peppers 11 Endive &#132; 13 Kohlrabi 13 Lettuce 13 Muskmclons and Waternelons. . : 14 Okra \ 14 Onions 14 Parsnips 16 Peas 17 Radishes 18 Salsify ! 18 Spinach 19 Squash and Pumpkins 19 Sweet Potatoes 20 Tomatoes 20 Turnips 22 Crop Rotation m the Garden 23 Additional Publications 25 Planting Table \, 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Vegetable Variety Tests at the Scottsbluff Substation Lionel Harris Acting Superintendent, Scottsbluff Substation This bulletin reports results of vegetable variety tests at the Scotts - bluff Field Station for the five years 1931 to 1935. Extensive yield tests have been made with varieties of the most important crops for the North Platte valley. Varieties of the minor crops have been tested for quality, time of maturity, and general adaptability. The work has been chiefly concerned with varieties and other problems from the standpoint of the home garden. Climatic and disease conditions have caused considerable variation m the yields of some crops from year to year. These conditions, together with marketing problems, are factors that limit the expansion of vegetable production m this area. The problems of production, from the standpoint of climate and disease, are described. They are apparent also m the data presented. A larger market for commercial production is con - stantly becoming available through truck transportation. The results in - dicate that cabbage and onions have commercial possibilities, and that cer - tain varieties of tomatoes, peas, beans, sweet corn, and red beets have can - ning possibilities. Vegetables constitute one of the most important foods eaten by man. They are rich m substantial food elements, and are valuable m supplying certain minerals and vitamins which have been found to be essential to the normal growth and health of the body. As a source of bulk foods, which are essential to a healthful satisfaction of the appetite, they are un - excelled. From the home garden vegetables may be obtained m the best quality because they are fresh. A good home garden increases a farm family's standard of living at a small cost. CLIMATIC CONDITIONS The main factors responsible for the low yields m some years were lack of irrigation water and rainfall, hailstorms, and a short growing season. During the past 26 years the average yearly precipitation at the Scottsbluff Field Station has been approximately 14 inches. Over 11 inches of this amount fell during the growing season. During the five years these tests were performed the rainfall averaged 3.4 inches below normal. During two years (1934 and 1935) irrigation water was inadequate for the pro - duction of high yields of vegetable crops, particularly onions, celery, and cauliflower. The lack of abundant irrigation water affected the yields more than the low rainfall; however, insufficient rainfall, particularly spring rainfall, which was the only moisture available for germinating and estab - lishing the plants, also affected the yields unfavorably. Hailstorms on two occasions caused serious damage to the onion and transplanted crops like The work at the Scomblurf Substation ll carried on m cooperation with the Diviiion of Western Irrigation Agriculture. The author is detailed from that diviiion. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 tomatoes, cabbage, etc. This appears to be one of the major risks in vege - table production here. The average length of the growing season has been 133 days. On an average the last frost in the spring occurred on May 16 and the first in the fall on Sept. 26. These dates varied considerably and when the varia - tion was toward a short season, certain vegetable crops were seriously menaced. For example, the frost oi Sept. 15, 1934, destroyed the tomato crop and other transplanted crops at the height of production. Despite these conditions it has been found that most of the vegetable crops grown in the temperate zone may be produced here successfully, but with crops adapted to long, warm seasons, s ich as melons, peppers, tomatoes, and eggplant, only the early varieties can be depended upon for satisfactory results. It was only during the langest and warmest seasons that mid - season and late varieties of these crops gave good results. In a few cases disease was the chief cause of low yields. The severe winds occurring during the early spring sometimes caused damage to the plants that were above ground very early. SOILS AND LOCATION Good drainage and high fertili ;y are important in soils growing vege - table crops. The soil at the ScottsDiuff Field Station, a friable sandy loam, is typical of soils on the bench lands bordering the North Platte river and is well suited to growing vegetables. The surface soil, which varies from one to four feet in depth, is under ain by an irregular layer of clay, locally called Brule clay, and beneath this is sand of a varied texture. The drain - age of both the surface and subsoil is very good. Good drainage and high fertility are important in soils growing vege - table crops. Large quantities of veil rotted barnyard manure have been used, to maintain the soil in a high state of productivity. The loose nature of the soils in this area is paiti rularly favorable for the production of clean, normal-shaped root and bu b crops. IRRIGATION AND CULTIVATION When available, irrigation water was applied often enough and in sufficient quantities to keep the slants growing steadily. Irregular irri - gation resulted in poor-quality vegetables: onions produced double bulbs; turnips and radishes became bitter and of coarse texture; tomatoes and cabbage cracked; many other vegetables became rough; the growth of celery was stunted; and table beet; did not acquire the desired succulence. It was found necessary to give n ost crops a light irrigation about once every week. Other crops such as tomatoes, eggplant, cabbage, cauliflower, carrots, parsnips, corn, beans, peas, etc., were irrigated with good results every 10 days to two weeks, depending upon the soil moisture and cli - matic conditions. Generally if the soil sticks together when crumpled in the hand, moisture is considered adequate for plant growth. When tomatoes began to ripen, particularly in a cool fall, thev were irrigated sparingly, as too much water at this time tended to produce unnecessary </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Vegetable Variety Tests vegetative growth and delayed ripening. The vegetables were cultivated otten enough through the summer to control weeds. The shallow culti - vation practiced brought about good control of weeds if performed when the weeds were small. Deep cultivation was avoided, as it destroys many of the plant roots. RESULTS WITH VEGETABLES TRIED Asparagus.— Asparagus has been found to be well adapted to western Nebraska. It is a perennial and should be planted in the home garden in a relatively permanent location. Good results have been obtained by planting crowns five inches deep in lister rows spaced five feet apart and the plants two feet apart in the row. The crowns were planted the first of April. They were covered with two or three inches of soil when first placed in the trench, which was filled in later by cultivation as the small shoots emerged. A bed of the Mary Washington variety of asparagus was set out in 1931. The first cutting was made in 1933. The yields per acre respectively for the seasons of 1933, '34, and '35 were 1.507, 2,086, and 2,106 pounds. During the last two years, yields would have been higher it more irrigation water had been available. This crop is well adapted to the conditions in this valley and might well be grown for canning pur - poses. 6 r Bush Beans.— Because of the variability of the weather from year to year and during any one year it has been found desirable to make several plant - ings of beans throughout the season. The first of these made the 10th of May was sometimes killed by a late frost or was seriously retarded by cold weather, but if it escaped, fresh beans were produced early in July. The results indicate that it is worth while to risk one very early planting of beans. However, it has been found desirable to delay the main plant - ing until May 25th or June 1st. Plantings of most varieties made at this date began bearing about nine weeks later. When properly irrigated and picked regularly— that is, a thorough picking at least once a week - beans remained green and productive for a period of seven to nine weeks after the first edible beans were produced. When beans were thus properly picked the need for successive plantings was not so great. Several varieties were planted each year for five years. Refugee Wax and Kidney Wax have been found to be good wax varieties and Stringless Greenpod and Stringless Refugee, good green-pod varieties. During the years 1931 and 1933, when the plants were not severely affected by bac - terial blight, these varieties yielded from 80 to 110 pounds per 100 feet of row (Table 1). Bacterial blight reduced the yield fifty per cent in 1935, and destroyed the crops entirely in two other years (1932 and 1934). During these years none of the varieties showed great resistance. However, the disease was slightly less severe in Stringless Greenpod and Refugee Wax than in the other varieties. Mosaic affected beans to some extent every year. Damage from these diseases can be avoided to some extent by planting seed harvested from healthy plants of the least susceptible varieties. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 Table 1. — Results of variety tests with bush beans at the Scottsbluff Field ' Station, 1931 to 1935. Yield {pounds) Variety Year Da y» to j firit harvest p a acre | Pcr 10o .f t . row Refugee Wax 1931 61 15,786 861 1933 58 20.411 111.3 1935 72 » 4,820 25.8 Av. 64 13,672 74.4 Stringiest Greenpod 1931 61 11,001 60.0 1933 58 19,847 108.2 1935 79 8,320 44.6 Av. 66 13,056 70.9 Bountiful 1931 65 10,533 57.4 1933 58 22,242 121.3 Kidney Wan 1933 58 20,293 110.6 1935 72 5,220 27.9 Giant Stringlcss Greenpod . 1933 58 17,899 97.6 1935 79 5,520 29.5 Rustproof Golden Wax 1931 67 • 9,433 51.4 Pencil Pod Wax 1935 . 72 6,100 32.7 Tender Green 1935 72 4,520 24.3 Webber Wax 1935 72 5,900 31.6 Brittle Wax 1935 72 7,300 39.1 1 Because of unusually low temperature during May and June of 1935 beans came into bearing later than in most years. Table Beets. — Table beets are rel ited to sugar beets, and like sugar beets were found to be well adapted to this area. Table beets have produced exceptionally well here and with frequent irrigation were of the best qual - ity. The cultural methods used for sugar beets were found to be very satisfactory; however, table beets w« re thinned to stand only 3 or 4 inches apart. A satisfactory practice in the home garden has been to avoid thinning until late June and early J lly when the roots are 1 to 1 Y 2 inches in diameter and can be used on the table as thinned. When thinned early the young, tender tops may be us:d for greens. Relatively small beets were more desirable for table use or canning. The crop gave the best results when planted early in April. Later plantings were made success - fully if rainfall was plentiful or irritation water was available to get them started. Detroit Dark Red was thef best variety tried here. It proved to be of very good quality for canning or immediate table use. Cabbage. — When early cabbage » :ed was sown in the hotbed during the early part of March and good plants were transplanted to the field the early part of May, cabbage heads of edible size were produced by ten or eleven weeks after transplanting. Copenhagen Market and Golden Acre were the most satisfactory varieties tested, the three-year average yield of both having been 9.1 tons an acre ( 933-35). Heads averaged 3.1 and 2.8 pounds respectively (Table 2). The heads of the Early Jersey Wakefield variety split more readily and were )f poorer quality, being less firm than the two other early varieties named </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Vegetable Variety Tests The midsummer variety, Enkhuizen Glory, was transplanted the last week in May, and began producing heads of edible size in 94 days. The heads averaged 3.8 pounds each and the three-year average yield was 11.1 tons (Table 2). This variety has produced the finest cabbage grown at the station. The heads of Enkhuizen Glory split less readily than those Table 2. — Results of variety tests with cabbage at the Scottsbluff Field Station, 1931 to 1935. nSSnhS*,, Weight of cabbage produced Variety Year to firit Pounds I Tom I Pounds per harvcit per head I per acre I 100-ft. row EARLY VARIETIES Golden Acre 1933 69 3.8 13.3 183.2 1934 86 2.1 4.2 57.9 1935 72 3.4 9.8 135.0 Av. 76 3.1 9.1 1253 Copenhagen Market 1931 88 43 13.5 186.0 1932 85 3.8 11.6 159.8 1933 69 3.3 11.6 159.8 1934 70 2.3 7.1 97.8 1935 72 2.9 8.7 119.8 Av. (1933-35) 70 2.8 9.1 125.8 Early Jeney Wakefield... 1932 76 23 8.0 110.2 ]933 84 3.4 12.1 166.7 MIDSUMMER VARIETIES Enkhuizen Glory 1931 106 5.8 11.7 161.2 1933 84 4J 14.7 202.5 •934 93 3.5 10.7 147.4 •935 93 3.6 8.1 111.6 Av. (1933-35) 90 3.8 11.1 153 8 LATE VARIETIES Penn State Billhead 1931 113 4.9 12.5 172.2 1932 125 4.0 13.1 1KM 1933 132 5.5 19.0 261.7 1934 124 3.3 7.0 96.4 1935 129 4.7 12.3 169.4 Av. (1932,'34-35) 126 4.0 10.8 148.7 Flat Dutch 1931 129 5.6 14.0 192 8 1932 120 3.6 83 114.3 1934 124 ■ 35 5.7 78.5 1935 129 6.6 15.1 208.0 Av. (1932.-34-35) 124 4.5 9.7 133.6 Danish Ballhead 1932 125 3.0 10.7 147.4 1934 124 2.8 6.9 95^0 1935 129 4.7 11,1 152.9 Av. 126 3.5 9.5 130.9 of the early varieties, but slightly worse than the later varieties. They did not keep quite as well in storage as the late varieties. Late cabbage has been seeded directly in the field about the tenth of May with good results, but the best results have been obtained by seeding in the hotbed early in April and transplanting strong, stocky plants to the field the last of May. The late varieties were harvested and stored the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 last of September. Penn State Bal head gave a three-year average yield of 10.8 tons per acre, Danish Ballhead a three-year average of 9.5, and Flat Dutch a three-year average of 9.7 Table 2). The two Ballhead varieties kept better in storage than Flat Ditch and they also split less rapidly. Cabbage worms, which have been numerous, have been controlled effectively by dusting the heads f-equently with lime and lead arsenate in the proportion of one pound o: arsenate to eight pounds of hydrated lime. In rainy weather it was necessary to dust the heads after each rain. Aphids on cabbage have been tioublesome at various times. Control measures used were pulling and burning the first few plants affected, and if attack was more general, spraying, with the nicotine spray used for pea aphids. Cabbage has been stored successfully on shelves in the potato cellar and also in an outdoor pit, w lere the heads were covered with straw and soil. For pit storage the roots were left attached to the heads. Carrots.— Carrots germinated and grew very slowly for the first thirty days after seeding. A long perioc of favorable soil moisture was neces - sary in order for the plants to es ablish themselves firmly. Early April plantings placed the seed under the favorable influence of all the spring rains. Later plantings were often a failure because of inadequate moisture in the first inch of soil. The seed could not be planted deeper than one inch. spring rainfall was deficient as in 1934, the crop was started with irrigation water. Light irrigations every five or six days for three weeks were necessary to get a good stand. Carrots planted early in April were ready for use the middle of uly. A desirable practice in the home garden has been to delay thinning until the roots become Y 2 to 1 inch in diameter, when they can be used as early carrots. The main crop should be thinned to two inches apart in the rows. All the varieties tested were well adapted to this area, but there was some variation as to quality. From this standpoint, Nantes, Amsterdam Forcing, and Chantenay were found most preferable. They had comparatively small cores, which also most nearly approached the desired red color. Danvers Half Long was a very good type, but with less desi able interior color. Carrots have kept very well buried in moist sand in the potato cellar. Cauliflower. — Cauliflower planted in the hotbed early in March and transplanted to the field the middle of May began producing edible heads the latter part of August. Only fai • results were obtained with cauliflower in two (1931 and 1933) of the fi:e years that it was grown here. One other year (1935) the results were very poor because of heat and lack of irrigation water and during two years (1932 and 1934) the plants grew well but produced no marketable h :ads. In these years the supply of irri - gation water was irregular and inadequate, owing to a general shortage in 1934 and a canal break in 19S2. Fair results were obtained when a regular and adequate supply of irrigation water was available. These facts indicate that a regular supply of irrigation water is necessary in order to obtain even fair results with cauliflower. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Vegetable Variety Tests Being a cool-season crop cauliflower was doubtless influenced unfavor - ably by the period of drouth and extreme hot weather which prevailed during most of the years tests were performed. Cabbage (also a cool-seas - on crop) was unfavorably influenced but to a lesser degree by these con - ditions. Burpee's Best Early, Dry Weather, Snowball, and Dwarf Erfurt were the best varieties tried. They yielded from 51.6 to 59.2 pounds per 100 feet of row as averages for the three years in which edible heads were produced (Table 3). Approximately half of the plants produced market- Table 3. — Results of variety tests with cauliflower at the Scottsblufi Field Station, 1931 to 1935. Days from Plants Weight of cauliflower produced Variety Year transplanting producing _ v "* to first edible Pounds I Pounds I Pounds per harvest heads per head I per acre I 100-ft. row Per cent Burpee's Best Early 1931 98 87 3.3 15,380 105.9 1933 113 59 ' 2.2 9,000 62.0 1935 118 16 1.2 1,407 9.7 Av. 110 54 2.2 8,596 59.2 Dry Weather 1931 98 78 2.2 10,360 70.9 1933 113 74 2.6 13.520 93.1 1935 118 10 0.9 635 4.4 Av. 110 54 1.9 8,172 56.1 Snowball 1931 98 63 3.2 12,940 89.1 1933 113 61 2.0 8,820 60.7 1935 118 11 0.9 726 5.0 Av. 110 45 2.1 7,495 51.6 Dwarf Erfurt 1931 98 66 2.9 9,900 68.2 1933 110 73 2.3 11,660 80.3 1935 118 16 0.8 998 6.9 Av. 110 55 2.0 7,519 51.8 Danish Perfection 1933 113 53 2.1 7,680 52.9 1935 118 10 2.6 1,951 13.4 Vietch's Autumn Giant. . (Failed to mature) able heads. Vietch's Autumn Giant and Danish Perfection were too late in maturing to be of value in this area. The same insect pests attacked cauliflower as cabbage and were controlled by the same methods. Celery. — The production of celery required very careful attention to growing conditions, particularly soil moisture. When irrigation water was available every five to seven days, fair results were obtained with the Giant Pascal and Golden Self-Blanching varieties. Celery planted in the hotbed the last week in March and transplanted to the field the last of May was ready for use early in September. Plants with crowns at least '/4 of an inch in diameter were used for transplanting at a distance of 6 to 8 inches apart in rows that were 20 inches apart. When irrigation water was not available every five to seven days the crop was a failure. An unusually fertile soil was also found to be necessary. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 Chard. — The culture used for r;d beets proved satisfactory for chard. The crops are related botanically. Chard, a leafy vegetable, when planted early in April provided the best su timer greens obtainable in the garden. Lucullus and Fordhook Giant prov :d to be desirable varieties. Sweet Corn.— By planting early 1 midseason, and late varieties of corn the 10th to 15th of May, corn for lable use or canning has been available from the latter part of July to the middle of September. The results of. successive plantings of an early variety have been less satisfactory. It has been found advisable, however, to riake a late planting of Golden Bantam about the middle of June. The be: t early varieties tried were Gill's Early Market and Sunshine. Golden Bantam was the choice midseason variety and Stowell's Evergreen and Country Gentleman were good late varieties. Gill's Early Market began producing edible ears in 80 days, Sunshine in 86, Golden Bantam in 90, and th( late varieties in 103 days (Table 4). The average yield of these varieties las been from 4.2 to 7.6 dozen ears per 100 feet of row, and the average veight per car ranged from 6.7 to 11 ounces (Table 4). Golden Gem was the earliest variety tested but was considered of poor quality. Corn ear worm has been troublesome and was difficult to control. The recommended control measure is dusting the silks with equal parts of powkred lead arsenate and finely ground sulphur or flowers of sulphur wheA a fifth of the ears show silks. It has been found elsewhere that temperature has great influence on the quality of corn. 1 In hot weath :r the best edible quality is maintained for a shorter period than in cool w&lt;ather. The late varieties or late plant - ings ripening in cool weather in the fall maintain good quality two and one-half times as long as early varieties ripening in hot weather. Conse - quently the best chance for getting good-quality corn for home canning is in the fall when the weather is cool. In hot weather sugars are changed to starch more rapidly than in cool weather. It has also been found 2 that for the best quality, corn should te eaten or canned as soon as possible after picking, and that if corn is ke pt at all after picking it should be kept in cool temperatures. Otherwise quality diminishes. Cucumbers. — Cucumbers planteil the 20th of May were ready for table use the middle of July. When a jfew plants were started in pots in the hotbed and transplanted to the field the last of May, cucumbers were avail - able the first of July. Keeping cucumber vines thoroughly and regularly picked either at the slicing or pickling stage prolonged fruiting and in - creased the yield. When this practice was followed only a few vines were required to supply sufficient for aj family. The Arlington White Spine was the best variety for slicing. Green Prolific, Boston Pickling, and Chicago Pickling were the best bidding varieties, and they were also good for slicing. Little trouble las been experienced with the striped cucumber beetle. The control measure recommended for this pest is dust - *C. O. Appleman and S. V. Eaton, Journ. , Igr. Research 20:795-805, 1921 •CO. Appleman and J. M. Arthur. Journ. Agr. Research 19:137-52, 1919. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Vegetable Variety Tests ing the plants with a mixture of one ounce of calcium arsenate and one pound of powdered gypsum. Hydrated lime may be substituted for the gypsum but is not so effective. Table 4.— Results of variety tests with sweet corn at the Scottsbluff Field Station, 1931 to 1935. Vrictv 1 Year | fir^ f '° al | *%** | ioQ E»r. w J Av^ w^ EARLY VARIETIES Day&gt; Dozens Dozens Ounces Golden Gem 1931 69 850 65 4n 1935 78 385 2.9 \o Gill's Early Market 1932 73 982 ., 1933 « 476 3.6 97 1934 « 352 2 7 88 Av - «0 554 4.2 93 Sunshinc &gt;»&gt; 76 1.016 7.8 60 "32 87 1&gt;240 „ ■ 1933 « 732 5.6 9 2 J9« 100 34J 2 . 6 , 0 ; 2 1935 83 116 3.2 8 8 Av. (1932-35) 88 683 5.2 9 1 SpanUhGold 1931 72 M 99 ,1.5 / 7 The Bur P« "933 80 604 4.6 8 2 MIDSUMMER VARIETIES Golden Bantam 1931 81 1.328 10 2 6 1 HI] » &gt;.«»3 12.9 6.8 1933 88 1.086 8 3 7 1 1934 100 419 32 gJ 1935 87 467 3.6 56 Av. (1932-35) 92 913 7 0 6 9 Black Mexican 1931 93 1,345 103 6 7 VanBU " d 1932 91 1,209 9J 116 ■ LATE VARIETIES Stowcll's Evergreen 1931 94 954 , 73 106 1932 104 1.089 8 3 97 1933 102 869 6.6 132 1934 108 454 3.5 10.6 Country Gentleman 1932 103 953 73 gg ■933 102 1,121 8 6 95 I93 1 108 431 33 99 1935 99 679 5.2 8*5 ' Av - 103 79£ 6A 9.5 Eggplant and Peppers.— Eggplant and peppers planted in the hotbed the last week in March and transplanted to the field the first of June be - gan producing edible fruit about August 20th. For satisfactory growth of eggplant and peppers in the hotbed it was found necessary to maintain a higher temperature than was required for either cabbage or tomatoes. Damping off was not as destructive of pepper and eggplant as it was of tomato, cabbage, and cauliflower plants under the same conditions. In </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 transplanting eggplant and pepper plants to the field, great care was exercised to preserve as many roots as possible, and the results were profitable. Setting these plants one to two inches apart in shallow boxes or flats a month before they were tn nsplanted to the field was found to be definitely worth while. From the standpoint of yield and quality Black Beauty and New York Improved, which produced large, dprk, glossy fruits that averaged about 14 ounces each, have proved to be the most promising varieties of egg - plant. Both varieties were ready f c r use in an average of 84 days from the date of transplanting. Black Jeauty returned a three-year average yield of 14.55 tons an acre, and N^w York Improved 12.59 tons (Table 5 )- Eggplant was attacked by the s ime insects as the potato. Flea beetles Table 5.— Results of variety tests with eggplant at the Scottsbluff Field Station, 1?32 to 1934. Varictin I v B , Dayi *4 Av - w dght , . Yield per Varieue. | Year aawie per fruit Acre yield 100.ft.row Ouncet Tons Pounds Black Beauty 1932 81 12.5 19.93 274.5 1933 78 11.5 15.75 216.9 1934 93 19.2 7.98 109.9 Av. 84 14.4 14.55 200.4 N. Y. Improved 1932 81 13.5 16.82 231.7 1933 78 U.5 15.85 218.3 1934 93 15.8 5.10 70.2 Av. 84 13.6 12.59 173.4 -ohe Purple 1932 81 3.7 10.00 137.7 1933 78 8.0 9.25 127.4 1934 93 10.7 2.53 34.8 Av. B4 7.5 7.26 100.0 Extra Early Dwarf 1933 71 6.0 14.46 199.2 and the Colorado potato beetle have done some damage to eggplant. Both insects were satisfactorily controlled by dusting the plants with arsen-' ate of lead and hydrated lime mixed in the proportion of one pound of lead to ten pounds of lime. Calcium arsenate gave equally as good results as did lead arsenate. Harris Earliest and Ruby King were the best varieties of peppers tested at this station. The fruit of Ruby King averaged 2.1 ounces while that of the Harris Earliest averaged 1.6 ounces. Ruby King gave a three-year average yield of 593 bushels an acr , and Harris Earliest gave 455 bushels (Table 6). Both varieties began to mature in 82 days from the date trans - planted. A large, blocky-fruited variety called the Chinese Giant, with fruit averaging 3.1 ounces each, retimed a three-year average yield of 317 bushels per acre. This variety produced some exceptionally fine peppers, but was later in maturing (95 days) than Harris Earliest or Ruby King. Sunnybrook, a round tomato-like |&gt;epper, began to mature in an average of 91 days, and gave a two-year average yield of 445 bushels an acre, with the individual fruits averaging 1.6 cunces. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Vegetable Variety Tests Table 6.— Results of variety tests with peppers at the Scottsbluff Fteld Station, 1932 to 1934. Varieties Year Dav&gt; to Av. weight Acre yield Yield per mature per fruit ACre yicla iOQ. ft . , ow „ . _. Ounces Bushels Bushels Ruby King 1932 79 2.3 714 49 1933 74 1.9 . , gss 5 ; 9 i9 » 93 2.1 209 14 Av. 82 2.1 593 4.1 Harris Earliest 1932 79 1.3 443 31 1933 ™ IS 672 46 M* 93 1.5 250 17 Av. 82 1.6 455 3a Chinae Giant 1932 95 3.1 430 3 0 1933 88 2.7 504 35 ' 93 &lt; 102 3.5 18 O 'l Av - 95 3.1 317 2.2 Sunnybrook 1933 88 1.6 603 4 2 _| 93 &lt; 93 Ui 287 2 !o Endive. — Endive sown the middle of June produced good greens for fall or winter use. To avoid bitterness it was necessary to irrigate the crop frequently, particularly a month previous to harvest. Bitterness was also avoided to some extent by blanching the center leaves, which was accomplished by tying the outside leaves above them. For winter use the plants were dug, with a ball of earth attached to the roots, and stored in the potato cellar. The Large Green Curled variety has given satisfactory results. Kohlrabi. — For early kohlrabi good results have been obtained by seed - ing in the hotbed late in March and transplanting the plants to the field about the middle of May. For a late crop the seed has been sown direcdy in the field the middle of May, and the results were satisfactory. The plants were spaced 8 to 10 inches apart, and each plant produced an edible fleshy stem which if harvested at 2'/ 2 to 3 inches in diameter was firm and of high quality. When the stems were allowed to grow to 6 to 8 inches in diameter they frequently were woody and coarse in texture, and consequently uninviting at the table. The Early White Vienna variety has been found to be satisfactory in this area. Kohlrabi was found to be a thrifty, vigorous-growing crop and did exceptionally well here with plenty of irrigation water. Lettuce. — The results with head lettuce have been very unsatisfactory. When planted early in April, lettuce began to head the middle of June. At this time the hot summer weather was generally just beginning, and under this influence seed stalks were sent up rapidly through the partially formed heads. During one year when cool weather extended late into June, 23 per cent of the Hanson variety, 17 per cent of Stonehead Riviera, </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 26 per cent of New York Wonderful, and 9 per cent of Salamander pro - duced fair heads. During the othei four years no satisfactory heads were produced in any of the varieties, although the plants grew very well up to the time of heading. The heads produced during the one year remained edible for a short period of time an 1 were not of the desired compactness. The leaf lettuce produced was of excellent quality. Successive plantings were made every two weeks beginning early in April, and in this way lettuce was available through most of the summer. Black Seeded Simp - son and Early Curled Simpson were found to be very good varieties. Muskmelons and Watermelons, — In the average season it has been found inadvisable to plant muskme ons and watermelons earlier than May 20th. Previous to this time the so 1 was frequently too cold for the best results. When planted May 20thJ ripe fruits from the earliest varieties were generally available the middle of August. The late varieties were a week to two weeks later. When melons were plantd on a south slope in preference to a north slope or level land, the fruits began ripening earlier and a higher percentage of the fruit set on the vines ripened before the first fall frost. Irrigation was necessary every ten days to two weeks. How - ever, it was found that frequent rrigation retarded the ripening process somewhat, although larger fruits were produced. The earliest varieties of muskmelons tested were Extra Early Osage, Perfecto, Emerald Gem, Hale's Best, and Hearts of Gold. They were all of good quality, although Emerald Gem, Hale's Best, and Hearts of Gold were considered the best. Later varieties were Rocky Ford and Early Hackensack. The late varieties ripened 40 to 60 per cent of their crop before the first fall frost, while the early varieties ripened 70 to 90 per cent. The earliest varieties of water - melons were Will's Sugar, Klecklcy Sweet, Cole's Early, Irish Gray, and Winter Queen. Tom Watson was about a week later. From the stand - point of size and quality, Kleckley Sweet, Irish Gray, and Winter Queen were the best of the early varieties. The melon aphid has been troublesome in certain years. The control measure recommended is dusting with a nicotine-lime dust containing 3 per cent nicotine. Okra. — Okra planted the 20tt of May began producing tender pods which were ready for use in soups and stews the 10th of August. Tender pods were available from this time to the first fall frost. The Early Perk - ins Mammoth variety has produced well here. Onions. — Onions planted the first of April and under the influence of abundant spring rainfall and plenty of irrigation water through the sum - mer have produced good yields by the first of September. This was par - ticularly true of certain varieties, namely Sweet Spanish and Yellow Val - encia. In order to produce smoot'i, high-quality bulbs it was found neces - sary tp maintain a uniform growi h in the onion plant. Irregular growth owing to injury, careless cultivation, and irregular irrigation resulted in de- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Vegetable Variety Tests formed and unmarketable bulbs. The onions had to be cultivated very carefully and irrigated at least once a week in order to maintain the de - sired growth. On two occasions a light hailstorm checked the growth by mildly injuring the tops and the result was many deformed bulbs. Irrigation water was withheld from the crop a week or two before harvest to give the bulbs a chance to ripen. -In harvesting, the bulbs were pulled by hand and allowed to cure for four or five days on top of the ground. Then the tops were cut off and the bulbs placed in sacks and allowed to cure in the field for a week or more, after which they were placed in storage. Proper storage conditions for onions are a dry air and a temperature just above freezing. The humidity of a properly operated potato cellar was found to be too high for satisfactory onion storage. The fruit cellar in the basement of the house, if it is partitioned off from the furnace and can be kept cool, is a good place for a few onions. On a large scale a bin in the potato cellar may be partitioned off and kept dry and cool. On a highly fertile, loose, sandy soil and with plenty of irriga - tion, as many as six to eight good onions per foot have been grown with - out serious crowding. On heavier soils the plants should be spaced about three inches apart. In 1934 irrigation water was available only three times during the summer and the crop turned out a complete failure. During 1932 and 1935 onions were damaged somewhat by light hailstorms and the yields were consequently low for these years (Table 7). Sweet Spanish and Yellow Valencia were the best varieties tried. Sweet Spanish gave a three-year average yield of 415 bushels an acre or 15.9 pounds per 100 feet of row, and Yellow Valencia gave a three-year aver - age yield of 400 bushels an acre or 15.3 pounds per 100 feet of row (Table 7). The bulbs averaged 4.0 ounces each in size. These varieties kept as well in storage as the best of the other varieties, namely Australian Brown, Mountain Danvers, and Yellow Globe Danvers. On a commercial scale it has been found that onions can be planted with a beet planter by mixing one pound of onion seed to two pounds of bran and setting the planter to plant beet seed at the rate of fifteen pounds an acre. This distributes the onion seed at the rate of 3 to 314 pounds an acre, which under favorable conditions should give the desired stand of six to eight onions per foot. However, onions planted in this manner can be team-cultivated only once or twice without serious injury to the young plants, for onion rows spaced the same distance apart as beet rows are too close for much team-cultivation. For such cultivation, rows should be spaced 24 to 30 inches. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 Table 7.— Results of variety tes.'s with onions at the Scottsbluff Field Station. 1931 to 1935. ™» 1 *- | sb 1 gai \"%£F\ ffijJT Sweet Spanish 1931 ,50 OU " C " *"£" T? |" ;» 3.6 « 9 . S; }*» 5&lt; 4.4 389 14.9 1935 5 ° 3.9 378 14 5 Av. (1932.-33.-35) 51 4.0 4I5 , 5 9 Yellow Globe Danvcri... 1931 44 ,„ „. 1932 37 i; 6 ?35 52 1933 « 3.7 381 ," 1935 50 2.7 158 60 Av. (1932.-33.-35) 144 2.7 224 8 6 Yellow Valencia 1932 50 43 526 20 1 J»33 ,54 4.7 432 ,6.5 1935 150 3.0 241 9 2 Av ' t.O 400 J 15J &gt;932 139 2.7 287 110 W33 ,51 4.3 448 17 .1 19 35 150 2.9 228 8 7 Av - l« 33 321 12.3 Pri « uker '932 138 2.6 268 10 3 193 3 153 4.4 365 140 1935 bo 3.0 223 8 5 Av - "7 3.3 285 10.9 White Valencia 1932 38 2.0 239 9 1 1933 ,46 3.6 221 85 1935 150 2.9 218 83 Av - 1« 2.8 226 8.6 Southport Yellow Globe. 1931 153 30 , n 5 FUt Yellow Danver. 1931 ,44 .. 23 8 91 Australian Brown 1931 j 50 lgfi Mounuin Danveri 1931 139 .. 177 6g Parsnips.— Parsnip seed, like carrot seed, germinated and grew very slowly for the first month. When rainfall was abundant after planting good results were obtained, but he crop was a failure when rainfall was deficient. Planting early in April assured the crop of the most favorable moisture conditions the season could offer. In dry seasons frequent irri - gations were necessary to start th: crop. Frequently after heavy rains and ua u 1? , Were Up&gt; the scil crusted ove r the seed, and these crusts had to be broken to permit the t:nder seedlings to emerge. Parsnip roots nave been left in the ground through the winter and they have been dug and stored in moist sand in thJ potato cellar with equally good results. Ine disadvantages of leaving the roots in the ground were that the roots were difficult to dig for use whin the ground was frozen and that they began to grow as soon as the weither warmed up in the spring. As soon as the roots began to grow they became woody and of poor quality. Pars- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Vegetable Variety Tests nip roots have been kept in very good condition up to the middle of June by placing them on ice used to keep the potato cellar cool in the spring. Ice has been obtained very cheaply by storing it when the lakes were frozen solid during the winter or early spring months. Long Smooth Hollow Crown and Improved Guernsey have been found to be good varieties. Table 8. — Results of variety tests with peas at the Scottsbluff Field Station, 1931 to 1935. ~- i Z D V" '° Acre yield, pounds Pcr c , n . Lbs. shelled Variety Year first *^ r " ""' peaj pcr I harvest Shelled | Unshelled shelled lQQ-ft. row EARLY VARIETIES Alaska 1931 72 2,250 5,000 45.0 8.6 1932 70 3,114 6,146 50.7 11.9 1933 59 3.588 6,407 56.0 13.7 1934 70 677 1,766 38.3 1.7 1935 67 1,784 3.567 50.0 6.8 Av. (1932-35) 67 2,290 4.471 48.7 8.5 Radio 1933 64 3,021 5.808 52.0 11.6 MIDSUMMER VARIETIES Laxtonian 1932 78 3,777 8.584 44.0 14.5 1933 65 3,420 7,199 47.5 16.7 1934 76 1.423 3,309 43.0 5.4 1935 78 1.374 3.435 40.0 5.3 Av. 74 2,499 5,632 43.6 10.5 Hundredfold 1932 76 3,854 8,760 44.0 14.7 1933 66 3,430 7,036 48.7 13.1 1934 76 753 1,930 39.0 2.9 1935 77 1,652 3,303 50.0 6.3 Av. 74 2.422 5.257 45.4 9.3 Thomas Laxton 1931 76 2,067 4,594 45.0 7.9 1932 72 3,895 8.421 46.3 14.9 1933 65 3,201 6,739 47.5 12.2 Laxton's Progress 1931 81 1,932 4,293 45.0 7.4 Gardus 1931 76 1,562 3,675 42.5 6.0 Little Marvel 1934 71 919 2,250 40.8 3.5 1935 73 2,219 3,699 60.0 8.5 LATE VARIETIES Strategem 1932 87 3.195 7,374 43.3 12.2 1933 80 3.435 7.308 47.0 13.1 1934 92 1,603 3,563 45.0 6.1 1935 84 2,675 5,350 50.0 10.2 Av. 86 2,727 5.899 46.3 10.4 Dwarf Telephone 1931 "88 2,290 5,389 42.5 8.8 1932 86 3.893 8,651 45.0 14.9 1934 91 1,844 4,041 45.6 7.1 1935 83 1,751 3,501 50.0 6.7 Peas. — Good results with peas have been obtained from early April plantings. The late spring frosts of the last five years in this area have never seriously affected peas planted at this time. In one instance peas four inches high survived a temperature of 12° below freezing without </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 serious damage. By planting carlkr, midseason, and late varieties about the 10th of April, peas have been available from about the 20th of June to the 20th of July. Alaska has proved to be the most satisfactory early variety, Laxtonian and Hundredfo d the most satisfactory midseason vari - eties, and Strategem and Dwarf Telephone the most satisfactory late varieties. The average yield of theke varieties has been 8.5 to 10.5 pounds of shelled peas per 100 feet of row (Table 8). They are all goodSuality peas From the standpoint of quality in the home garden the midseason and late varieties proved to be betder than the early Alaska variety Because of the serious damage brnsed by the powdery mildew disease, late plantings of midseason or I e varieties have not been satisfactory at all. Fair results have been obtained from late plantings of an early variety like Alaska, although the yield was rather low. However the advantages of having fresh peas throughout the summer months may be considered sufficiently desirable to iccept the lower yields of the late plant - ings. The pea aphid, a green plant louse, has damaged peas here to some extent. For control of this insect, which sucks the juice from the plant, dusting with nicotine-lime dust containing 4 per cent nicotine is recommended. Natural enemies, particularly ladybird beetles, have how - ever, been very effective in the control of this pest. To enjoy the best flavor of peas, cook and use them immediately after picking Peppers^-See under Eggplant. Pumpkins. — See under Squash. Radish.— Early varieties of radifhes planted the first week in April were ready for the table five to six weeks later, provided rainfall was abundant. Successive plantings of early varieties were made every ten days during April in order to have a fresh supply of radishes for the table through most ot May and June. Beginning the :enth of May, successive plantings of the summer varieties were made and these supplied radishes through July and August. The early varieties, plaked late, soon became pithy. Late in July the winter varieties were planted and were ready for immediate use or storage the last of September. Desirable varieties for early spring planting were Scarlet Button, Sparkler, French Breakfast, Rapid Red, and Crimson triant. 1 he best summer varied s were White Icicle and White Strass - burg. Round Black Spanish and White Chinese were found to be good winter varieties. Winter radishes^ were stored successfully in moist sand in the potato cellar. As soon as the first radishes planted in the spring emerged they were attacked by numerous black flea beetles, which ate holes in the leaves and, when rot controlled, completely destroyed the crop. These flea beetles were very effectively controlled by dusting the plants with lime and lead arsenJte (one pound of the arsenate to eight P ° U c i -I *" mi «ure Was applied with a burlap sack. 7 Salsify.— Salsify, one of the W s common vegetables, was found to be a valuable crop for home garderJ in western Nebraska. When planted in April it produced very well for fall or winter use. As with parsnips, the roots have been left in the ground over winter, and they have also been dug </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Vegetable Variety Tests and stored in moist sand in the potato cellar with good results. The crop has not been affected by insect pests or diseases. The Mammoth Sandwich Island variety produced satisfactorily. Spinach.— The most satisfactory growth of spinach has occurred dur - ing the cool spring months. Spinach planted April 15th was ready for use about the 10th of June. As hot weather set in during the latter pL o June, all vanet.es tested went to seed rapidly. King of Denmark; Long Season, Bloomsda le, and Giant Fill Basket proved to be good-yielding h.gh-quahty varieties. They have yielded about 35 to 40 pounds per 100 feet of row (Table 9) King of Denmark and Long Season grew^bout a week longer than the other varieties without forming seed stalks. Bc- Table 9.— Results of variety tests with spinach at the Scottsbluff Field Station, 1931 to 1935. Variety Year to fint Poundi produced harvest 7T~ t-z — .-- King of Denmark i^ ~^ ""* 1932 59 14.709 56J 1933 54 13,559 519 1935 « 8.010 30 6 L ° n * Sea '° n 1 93 « 62 7.702 295 1932 59 9.412 36 0 1933 « 11,199 n 8 B1OOImdaIe » 32 52 ,2.560 4BI 1933 50 12,525 47 9 193 5 55 4,581 17 5 Giant FM-BaAet 1932 „ „ m 1933 50 9.867 378 Thick Leaved Round 1 931 50 2 2gg g? Prince.. Ju.iana 1935 „ Gi * ntNoble 1935 « 7^644 292 cause of the short harvest season, which was generally not more than two weeks, a very small planting in the garden was found to be sufficient for tamily needs For spinach during the summer months the New Zealand yanety was planted the middle of April. This is botanically quite different rT rw u Varie S eS ,' P™ ducin S a busl &gt;y P^nt with small leaves on ™ A fi^f "^ tH r 1C L aVCS ° f tCnder g r ° win S ti P s arc used fo ' greens A. hfty foot row of this supplied an abundance of greens all through the summer. Squash and Pumpkins.— The 20th of May has been found to be a satisfactory date for planting squash and pumpkins. Summer squash was ready for use during the latter part of July. The winter varieties of squash and pumpkins in a normal season were mostly well matured by the first fill x°f St ' T mm . er varieties which have done well here were Vege - table Marrow and Early White Bush. A few vines have been found suffi - cient for family requirements. The most satisfactory winter varieties were </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 Table Queen, Banana, Buttercup, and Improved Hubbard. As to vari - eties of pumpkins, Small Sugar, Sweet Sugar, and King of the Mammoths proved to be good ones. Usually winter squash and pi mpkins were not harvested until the first frost had killed the vines. Dur ng 1932, however, the first frost, which was 20° F., or 12 degrees below f eezing, was severe enough to injure some of the fruit. For winter storage , squash was handled carefully in order to avoid bruising, and in picking for storage it was found profitable to leave the peduncle or stem attacned to the fruit. Squash and pumpkins have kept well when stored on : helves in a dry, warm room. Some dis - tance from the furnace in the t asement of the house was a satisfactory place. The squash bug, a large, dark insect with an offensive odor, that sucks the sap from the vines, proved to be a limiting factor in the production of squash here. The pest completely killed many of the vines. It is difficult to control. Strong nicotine sprays and dusts will kill only the young nymphs. On a few vines fair control may be had by hand picking the adults and the eggs and destroying them. At night adults gather under boards and shingles placed abou the plant and in this position are easily destroyed. Cleaning up and destroying weeds and crop remnants in the fall, which serve as shelters for overwintering, should prove helpful. Pumpkins were damaged less by the pest than squash. Sweet Potatoes. — Few sweet potatoes have been grown in this region. In favorable seasons, however, fairly good results may be obtained, as was the case at this station during the unusually hot summer of 1931, when the Red Bermuda variety gave a yield of three pounds of sweet potatoes per vine, and the Nancy Hall gave two pounds. In 1932 the Porto Rico, Nancy Hall, and Yellow Jersey variet es averaged only one pound per vine. The season of 1932 was cooler and not so favorable for the growth of sweet-potato plants. Of the varie ties under trial, Red Bermuda and Yellow Jersey were the best. An objection to Porto Rico and Nancy Hall was that they frequently matured tuliers rather deep and a long distance from the center of the vine. It has bxen found advisable to obtain sweet-potato plants from a commercial grower, as their production in the hotbed re - quired rather special conditions. The plants were set out in the field after danger of frost injury and spaced two feet in the rows, which were three feet apart. Tomatoes. — There has been considerable variation in the yield of tomatoes during the five years these tests were performed, due in large measure to the variability of the weather and to disease conditions. Bac - terial canker damaged the crop mildly in 1932 and seriously in 1933. In 1934 and 1935 the crop had to be replanted because of hailstorms which occurred shortly after the first plants had been set in the field. In 1934 the growing season was cut short by a severe frost the middle of September. This, together with the late stait, resulted in a short harvest period, Sep - tember 1 to 15 (Table 10). </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Vegetable Variety Tests Table 10. — Results of variety tests with tomatoes at the Scottsbluff Field Station, 1931 to 1935. Days to Percentage of yield ripened Tomatoes produced Variety Year e rI . harvest To I Sept - ' ! Sc P l - 16 Per I Per I Per . mtvch Aug 31 | , Q 15 | |o , fn|it | acrg 1 1()(Mt row Early Varieties P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. Ounces Tons Lbs. Penn Bute Earliana. 1931 67 -9 59 32 .. 34.4 526 1932 67 11 -19 40 3.8 24.1 369 1933 67 47 47 6 5.2 18.1 277 1934 81 .. 100 .. 5.4 5.6 86 1935 63 13 54 33 4.6 10.0 184 Av.('33-35) 70 20 67 13 5.0 11.2 182 Sunnybrook Earliana 1932 67 12 46 42 3.8 24.9 381 1933 68 44 51 5 5.3 18.4 282 1935 61 10 44 46 3.8 8.1 148 Red River 1933 67 65 34 1 5.0 17.4 266 1934 81 .. 100 .. 5.2 5.3 81 1935 60 16 47 37 3.8 9.5 175 Av. 69 27 60 13 4.7 10.7 174 "«1 Head 1933 67 65 34 1 5.4 17.5 268 1934 81 ..100 .. 5.0 3.1 47 1935 60 13 48 39 3.9 7.9 146 Av. 69 26 60 14 4.8 9.5 154 Second Early Varieties Chalk-i Early Jewel. 1932 67 12 44 44 4.1 18.6 285 1933 78 17 62 21 5.1 18.1 277 1934 85 .. 100 .. 5.2 2.3 33 1935 74 9 31 60 3.8 7.1 131 Av.C33-35) 79 9 64 27 4.7 9.2 147 Johri Baer 1931 69 4 50 46 .. 24.7 378 1934 81 .. 100 .. 5.8 2.8 43 1935 74 7 17 76 5.0 5.6 102 Bonny Bc5t 1933 74 19 54 27 5.7 17.1 262 1934 81 .. 100 .. 5.8 3.8 58 1935 60 5 22 73 4.3 4.6 84 Av. 72 8 59 33 5.3 (s 5 1.15 Self Pruning 1933 74 9 45 46 4.8 18.7 285.4 Midseason Varieties Break o 1 Day 1932 84 7 37 56 4.9 13.6 208 1934 85 .. 100 .. 7.2 2.4 37 1935 84 9 29 62 4.7 5.3 98 Pritchard 1932 84 6 45 49 3.9 11.7 179.4 Fordhook First 1932 84 7 46 47 3.9 12.1 184.7 Early Santa Clara... 1931 89 5 64 31 .. 29.4 45C 1932 84 4 30 66 9.3 10.2 156 Late Varieties Stone 1931 89 2 58 40 .". 17.7 271 1932 84 7 36 57 4.3 12.1 1S5 1933 84 3 37 60 6.5 13.9 2i_ - 1934 88 .. 100 .. 7.9 0.2 1935 84 4 23 73 4.5 3.4 63 Av. (-33-35) 85 2 53 44 6.3 5.8 55 Greater Baltimore... 1935 84 5 18 77 4.7 5.8 1U Ponderosa 1931 89 4 59 37 .. 20.9 319 Marglobe 1931 89 5 58 37 .. 14.1 216 1934 88 .. 100 .. 8.5 0.8 i2 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 The most satisfactory, varieties in good years also proved to be the most satisfactory in poor years. Because of obvious unsuitability, certain varieties were discarded from the test after the first or second year's trial and others were added as the work progressed. In view of this and of the large seasonal and disease influenc: in different years the varieties shown in Table 10 are comparable only by years grown, and the averages are comparable only where varieties we re grown the same years, as in the case of Red River, Red Head, and Bonr y Best, and also of Penn State Earliana and Stone. When tomatoes were planted in the hotbed the first week in April and strong plants transplanted to the field the first of June, early varieties be - gan ripening fruit about August 10th. Second-earliest varieties began ripening about a week later, midseason two weeks later, and late varieties about three weeks later (Table 10). In favorable years the early varieties ripened most of the fruit set on the vines, whereas about 40 per cent of the fruit of the late varieties was still green at the time of the first fall frost. The rate of ripening was faster for the early varieties. Most of the tomatoes of early varieties harvestejd were picked by September 15, where - as a high percentage of the late varieties was picked during the last half of September, when the crop was in danger of frost injury. Although yields varied considerably from year to year the results with early varieties were considerably better than with late varieties. The yields of early varieties varied from 3 to 34 tons per acre, while the yields of late varieties varied from 0.2 to 21 tons (Table 10). As to quality, the fruits of Red Head and Red River were better formed than the Earliana. John Baer, Chalk's Early Jewel, and Bonny Best were smooth, good-quality tomatoes, better than Self Pruning Bonny Best produced larger and just as smooth tomatoes as Chalk's Early Jewel. The midseason and late varieties produced high-quality tonatoes but were too late to be of general value in this area. In long, favorkble seasons some of them, particularly Break O'Day, Pritchard, and For.lhook First have produced fairly well. Tomatoes, particularly the late varieties, ripened a medium red here. For home canning only the reddest ton atoes were used. The best-quality fruits were obtained early in the season shortly after they had begun to ripen. Flea beetles were troublesome early in the season but were satisfactorily controlled by dusting the plants With arsenate of lead and lime. For con - trolling bacterial canker, disease-free seed and crop rotation are recom - mended. Turnips. — Turnips are a cool-season crop and only spring or fall plantings have given satisfactory results here. The spring crop should be planted April 1st and for fall use July 1st. The crop was ready for use eight to ten weeks after planting. When irrigated regularly— once every week or 10 days — the turnips produced were of good quality, but when not they became bitter. Purple Top and White Egg have been found to be good varieties. Turnips were itored satisfactorily in moist sand in the potato cellar. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Vegetable Variety Tests CROP ROTATION IN THE GARDEN The systematic rotation of crops should be practiced in the garden to help maintain the soil fertility and to aid in the control of certain plant diseases. Because some diseases affect only one crop or confine their at - tack to related crops, this should be effectively accomplished by planting the vegetable crops according to natural relationships. Plants are related and grouped into families on the basis of similarities in general structure and mode of reproduction. Every gardener in a general way knows the relationship of his vegetable crops. Some relationships such as that be - tween cabbage and cauliflower, or between peas and beans, are obvious to anyone. The most important vegetable crops for western Nebraska be - long to nine families as follows: Related Crops Scientific Name of Family 1. Peas and beans Leguminosae (Pea family) 2. Carrots, parsnips, celery, parsley Umbellifcrae (Parsnip family) 5. Potatoes, eggplant, peppers, twnatoes Solanaccae (Potato family) 4. Cucumbers, melons, squash, pumpkins Cucurbitaceae (Gourd family) 5. Cabbage, cauliflower, turnip, radish, Cruciferae (Mustard family) kolrabi, rutabaga, Chinese cabbage 7 S Z' et , , Gramineae (Grass family) « £T£ *" °? k? u Liliaceac (Lily family) 8. R=d beets, spinach, chard Chenopodiaccae (Goosefoot family) 9. Lettuce, sals.fy, endive Compositae (Composite family) A plan ■ for systematically rotating these nine groups follows: 1st— Determine how wide a strip of ground will be necessary to grow the de - sired amount of crops in each group. 2nd-The widest strip, whatever its width, is the key strip, and the crops grown in it are moved across the garden the full width each year. 3rd-The crops in the smaller strips of ground should follow the widest strip in the order as first planned 4th- Ihe length i of the rotation system depends upon the fraction of the total width of the garden plot that the widest strip takes up. If it takes up a third for instance, it would be a 3-year rotation; a fourth, a 4-year rota - tion, etc. The widest strip need not be a simple fraction of the width of the garden ,n which case the rotation may be 3% or 4'/, years, etc., in length. 5th— An accurate plan of the garden should be kept each year and at least one side should be permanently marked with iron stakes in order to start from the same point each year. 6th-Onions planted from seed adjacent to onions started from sets frequently suffer considerable damage by thnps (a small insect pest) which spread in great numbers from the earlier onions. To escape this, plant onion sets in the perennial border. 7th— The plan is flexible and may be made to suit conditions in any garden. It should be as useful in the market garden as in the home garden. 8th— Figure 1 shows a plan of a four-year rotation system for a family garden. The detail planting for each crop is shown the first year in \&amp; £:jt^ l °»\ h rs£$$&amp;i tjr uscd with sood ™*« &lt;°&lt; ** - — &gt;— </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 and the place of the "key" group or gourds, in the other three years, is shown. The fifth year the cycle sta ts over again and the crops are arranged the same as the first year. In order to preserve the benefit of rotating vegetable crops according to their family relationships, it is necessary where two or more plantings of the same crop are made in one season to confine these plantings to the family to which that particular crop belongs. For example, late plantings of radishes may follow early cabbage or early radishes; late lettuce or endive may follow early plantings of lettuce, and late peas may follow an early variety of early-planted peas. To change crops from one family to another through the summer destroys the rotation. ADDITIONAL PUBLICATIONS Since the purpose of this bulleiin is mainly to discuss varieties of vege - tables and to report the results of tests, the reader may wish further material on vegetable gardening. By calli g at the office of a county agricultural agent or by writing to the College of Agriculture, Lincoln, one may obtain Nebraska Agricultural Extension Circular 1211, "The Farm Vegetable Garden", and Circular 1208, "The Home Garden Hotbed". Others also are available, some of which have been published by the U. S. Department of Agriculture, and a list of both Nebraska and U. S. bulletins may be obtained from the College of Agriculture or the county agent. The circulars mentioned above contain additional information about management practices, including the use of sprays to control insects and other pests and diseases. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Vegetable Variety Tests ROTATION PLAN FOR A HOME GARDEN IRON STAKE— sj- FIRST YEAR „ =jWpN STAKE CRASS • CORN- LATE VARIETY \ nuiv » 1 CORN- MID-SEASON VARIETY I H : CO"N- EARLY VARIETY .1 BEANS-WAX l FAMIUf i «-..«. «T BEANS- GREEN ) 4TH UKUMES M PEAS -LATE VARIETY I YEAR J PEAS — MIDSEASON VARIETY PEAS EARL* FOLLOWED BY LATE PLANTING Hf OF EARUT VARIETY 7 CARROTS \ COMPOSITE 2L SALSIFY ENDIVE FAMILY 5_ LETTUCE— 1ST— 3RD PLANTING LETTUCE— 2ND PLANTING GOOSEFOOT T~ " SPINACH NEW ZEALAND SPINACH FAMILY *• TABLE BEETS CHARD GOURD ' ,,,„ i TABLE BEETS V FAM1Lr FAMILT '" ONIONS GROWN FROM SEEDS / 3RD : -t YEAR EARLY RADISHES FOLLOWED BY SUMMER RADISHES .1 EARtr TURNIPS FOLLOWED BY SUMMER RADISHES MUSTARD 1? CAULIFLOWER KALE / FAMILY LATE CA»»ACE KOHLRABI \ LATE CABBAGE \ EARLY CABBAGE FOLLOWED BY WINTER RADISHES AND TURNIPS ft TOMATOES OKRA GOURD I • FAMILY FAMILY " E0C PLANT PEPPERS 2ND YEAR ! EARLY POTATOES : / MUSKMELONS CUCUMBERS GOURD •_ FAMILY cvi SQUASH PUMPKINS WATERMELONS JRON. 3TAKE . WON STAKE^^ PERENNIAL RHUBARB ASPARAGUS ■ HORSERADISH BORDER «, onk)n xjs PARSLEY Fie. 1. — This plan provides for grouping of vegetables by families and movement each year a distance equal to the size of the largest family group, which is the : gourds or cucurbits in the plan above. The distance may be varied as preferred. ! Okra and New Zealand spinach do not belong to the families with which they '■ arc placed but arc so placed for convenience. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 300 -5 '■ o ■■ .1 o c St&gt; • 3 t&gt; o t »,c * —.sac : &amp; 111. I If! f &amp;i a .i :-i i t I ;!| i ||l a ilJifi I tin il i ■:'■■ _l I g I ;! s llp irl § £l IjtiI 3 ! ! ■ • i ° * 5"- ' " " "*«* ■ * *°» -U-OOI 2 2 : &amp; a : 2 : : • : J : Ml! • ''■ i *s \i\ :4 si i [ ! : g «x»i i;| _i« _l ; ji ill i «i l| - !&gt; i flfiliili] ilijlllllifiiliiil g : .- .. \ RR '. •* JS3. % * • o 2 **^ It t III -i It l| •4* ___^^^^^^^_ . *** **" °° °° -*• -* «^&gt; iA n &lt;n r* «(N W"W - "J '^SSS i s * -3 s = = S * * sag i sS S^ L i _ I si « S § e (fjtpoi) noqd j; ■ • » S « 22 I« J |_ a»iiA nantia " « S SS SSS g S • SSS S SS »«, "* («aq3Ul) 8ut 2 fj W -xngdjogxtoa *" S _ g. „ - _, _r - » - v, _, - vr $ m&lt;^d &gt;J pSS| i £ s 8 s : s s g 5 g g g g g g g si : » s: _■ ST4S - vr v. SSi r -t xx a - = -s- • "". ... . . ... ,55SS!l M Ss &amp;s ■ I j '.! 2 U "a j j il —V\ \ Is II I j;T IN I ][ ji 5 : j ;2^ ;ss I j la-is i! is I J_! ! ! 11 Jll M ! IN 1 M li 3 :S&lt; =2f ::&lt;&lt;i s : a » : &lt;&lt; s •* :3a :s.S::&lt;a5 5;l3 L . 5 I; \ II m " " I • ■ Tl a I f 8 II lit 1 fi 1 ll-a III 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Vegetable Variety Tests ■ _■ • • • ° §' u • . k :I 5 : i il _ * 1 I II j , I s ■•:■{ |;i il ! -I i : .ii i; i.,j g. : "7 : : : § "S - _ J • 5 £ ° * s: : J : I I ;'■ ! !. . ! I S I ; | : ■•! j \ I I :j I j ; moj -jj-ooi s '■ s ■'■'■'■ : i i i : a £ : • «"Pl»!Ar; ; - J ; : : : - : : : £ R ; : o : ° t : : : ■§ : ■ ■ b2 : : lilllillllJiili SiUiili ill I ,w»«,S| SSg§gSSRsSSgg3 * H. ; — "" ;•'•■•■"■'•■.■" " 1 I § i i I I * («=q3ui) nurid g 5 2 = g " -1 u »«»q =3un« !a „ vo •= d 1 • . » • I s • « ■ « s? e i a a " m -° 52°i * 3 5 * ** S? d tt | 2 3 (isq^ui) 3ui : - -]Ut|d }O ipd 3c j r^,,» _____ -,^_ Jj — - • «n ■* . s moj -ij-oor g H .^ »i « ; i : ; h N - : N - 4 £ I J3d p33 S Z.-1 £. X Z -° - - - - ° ° • ° ' ° S B "i 1 : : III'. '■■ '■ ' * " : 1 uspjrs oi 6 : |2 : ' : : '• : : -co ' : — jortdsurjx &gt;.: o:::: ::: \ *J ™ : : jf — • 5 : : i i i '■■ \ i ; : i •: j s i 1 S! ! Hi! ; M i ! i| ! ! K I : ' • a : : : • ■ • • : : :&lt; : i| s - 'E'E 'E : | .,V'l.'." : : ? -" !5 &lt;&lt;&lt; :e&gt;&lt;&lt;&lt;-- 0 :: &lt; o s 1 . III : 1 1 1- '■ 3 /I ,1 ■ .| 1 ! i I I M 1 il 5 ilf 1 1 1 tifJtlfi f 1 - 1 ' OS _ CCCK -2 in ia j. .^ Si f. r- i - l-J'/iM) </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>