<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00024.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00024.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE STATE VETERINARIAN OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE STATE VETERINARIAN OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA By DR. PAUL JUCKNIESS, State Veterinarian 1910 Til* CUflin PrmtioJ Co. Unmraily PUcc. Ntfaruk. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">• </seg>
            <seg id="p003">To His Excellency, Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: I have the honor to submit herewith the Fifth Biennial Report of the Office of State Veterinarian, for the years of 1909 and 1910. Respectfully, P. JUCKINESS, Deputy State Veterinarian. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">' Upon assuming the duties of this office, the 10th day of January. 1909, the expense fund for the office was found to be entirely exhausted and a good many cases left over for investigation. A great many calls were sent in and urgent requests made to investigate where animals were dying in large numbers from contagious and infectious diseases. I was obliged to advance the money out of my own pocket to make some of the investigations, which was afterwards returned to me through a deficiency bill. A good many cases were never investigated and some were left over until the first of April when our new appro - priation was available. The funds for this Department have been entirely inadequate to carry on the work of investigating contagious and infectious diseases among animals in this state. The work in the office has increased so rapidly that it became necessary to have an additional clerk employed during the spring months, when the inspection and dipping commenced in the quarantined area of the State. After making numerous investigations of pure bred animals which were imported from other states into Nebraska, and finding great num - bers of them affected with tuberculosis, I came to the conclusion that Nebraska was being made the dumping ground for diseased animals from various states, as we had no provisions made to protect the stock raisers of Nebraska. I found it absolutely necessary to draw up such regulations as would protect the live stock raisers of our State. Rules and regulations were promulgated which provide that all cattle to be used for dairy and breeding purposes must pass a negative tuberculin test before being permitted to enter the State, and that all horses, mules and asses must pass a satisfactory clinical inspection and be found to be free from glanders or any other contagious or infectious disease. These regulations have proven to be of great benefit to the stock raisers of Nebraska, as all cattle entering the State must now either be accompanied by proper certificates of health and test charts or be inspected and tested at destination in this State. In several instances cattle which were not accompanied by the proper certificate of health, were shipped into this State and offered for public sale. These animals were either tested by myself or my assis - tant and a number of same were found to be affected with tuberculo - sis; later slaughtered at South Omaha, where Federal inspection is maintained, and lesions of tuberculosis were demonstrated in all such cases. Had we not had these regulations such diseased animals would </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 BIENNIAL REPORT have been sold as healthy and . would have probably infected a good many health animals. This shows the value of our present quarantine regulations and the protection they afford stock raisers against the in - troduction of diseased animals into their herds. We have similar regulations in South Omaha which provide that all dairy or breeding cattle sold at the stock yards must be tuberculin tested or accompanied by tuberculin test chart before being permitted to be removed. Dr. A. D. Melvin, chief of the Bureau of Animal In - dustry, at Washington, D. C, consented to detail a veterinarian inspec - tor to make all such tests free of charge, providing the State employ an assistant to the federal veterinarian. I have therefore kept a man regularly employed to assist in making these tuberculin tests at the South Omaha stock yards, which has been of great value to the dairy - men and stock raisers who wish to buy at South Omaha. TUBERCULOSIS. Tuberculosis is a contagious disease caused by specific organism, mycroscopical in size, which enters the animal body either by the ali - mentary canal or the respiratory tract, or may be introduced into the system by inoculation. The tubercle bacilli does not grow or multiply in nature excepting in the animal body or blood drawn from an animal. The tubercule bacili when expelled from the body may live for months and when taken into the body again through the respiratory tract or the alimentary canal has the power of penetrating through the mucous membranes or may be taken up through the lymphatics or enter the bloom stream and be distributed to any part of the body. Lesions of tuberculosis may be found in any organ or glands of the body. When the lesions are extensive, the muscular structures and also the bones are involved. Tuberculosis affects human beings, cattle, swine, chickens, and other animals which are of minor importance. Experiments have been carried on by the United States Depart - ment of Agriculture as well as other investigators, showing that the bovine type of the tubercle bacilli taken from a cow affected with generalized tuberculosis, has been changed to the human type by growing it on solidified human bloom serum. The tubercle bacilli of human type originally obtained from human sputum, after passing them through cattle were changed to the bovine type. The tubercle bacilli originaly obtained from a man after being passed through a sheep was also changed to the bovine type of__tubercle bacilli, which indicates that the human being can become affected from the bovine type of tu - berculosis. Experiments have also been carried on showing that the tubercle bacilli will live in butter for eight months or longer without losing its vitality, which clearly demonstrates the possibility of trans - mitting the disease from all dairy products obtained from cattle af - fected with tuberculosis, and also from the cattle which are exposed to the affected cattle, as animals are very likely to carry some of the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATE VETERINARIAN 7 infection upon the surface of their skin, and when being milked small particles of the infection may be dropped off into the milk pail and in this manner the germ be introduced into the milk from animals which are perfectly free from tuberculosis. Regardless of the question of the communicability of tuberculosis from animal to man and the bearing of animal tuberculosis on public health, it is a well known fact that this disease causes heavy finan - cial loses to the live stock industry of this State; and while the saving of human life affords the highest motive for combating tubercu - losis, the prevention of financial loss is alone a sufficient re«eon for undertaking the eradication of the disease from our farm animals The loss per annum through tuberculosis, from farm animals and their pro - ducts, in the United States, is estimated at twenty-three million dollars. Tuberculosis has progressed to an alarming extent in our State and is undoubtedly on an increase, as no measures^had been taken against it in Nebraska until a short time ago, and then the measures were entirely inadequate to cope with the conditions. The animals principally affected are cattle and hogs. The disease spreads very rapidly among cattle that come in close contact with each other, as in dairy cattle and pure bred herds. Experiments made by the Bureau of Animal Industry, as well as other experiment stations, have proven that one cow affected with tuberculosis will infect a number of healthy animals when exposed tc the diseased one, in a, wery short time. It has also been proven that the disease is easily communicated from cattle to hogs by the common practice of giving hogs skimmed milk and allowing them to feed on their excrements. The usual dissemina - tion of tubercle bacilli in cattle is through the feces. Tuberculosis of cattle may be acute and run a rapid course from time of infection to death. As a rule it is insidious, chronic and slowly progressive, and the bodies of its victims are able to adapt or adjust themselves to the gradually increasing destructive changes that it causes, until quite extensive harm has been done or vitally impor - tant organs have become seriously involved. The result is that the disease may be present in the body a long time without external mani - festations of its existence. It may attack any part of the body singly, or several organs at the same time. The economic advantages of eradicating tuberculosis from farm animals are too apparent to require extended discussion. They will come to the individual stock raiser and dairyman as well as to the public and the nation. Breeders are beginning to understand that it is unprofitable to go on raising cattle while tuberculosis exists in their herds. The practice is becoming more general for buyers of breeding and dairy cattle to have such animals tested before placing them in their herds, and the breeder who can give assurance that his herd is free from tuberculosis has a decided advantage in making sales. With the agitation in favor of a more wholesome milk supply there is a </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 BIENNIAL REPORT growing demand for milk frcm healthy herds at higher prices, and as this demand increases the dairyman who cannot show a clean bill cf health for his cows will find it more difficult to market his products. To overcome the great losses before mentioned is worth consider - able effort and expense. The benefit to follow from the eradication of tuberculosis from farm animals are so great and so obvious that the necessary expenditures, even though they must be heavy, may be re - garded as a highly profitable investment. All cattle in the State which are to be used for dairy or breeding purposes should be tested with tuberculin and tagged or branded, so they may be identified for future reference. All animals reacting to the tuberculin test, indicating that they are affected with tuberculosis, should be tagged or branded as reactors and those passing a satisfac - tory negative tuberculin test should also be branded or tagged as tuberculin tested and passed. The reacting animals should be immedi - ately segregated from the healthy or passed animals and either sold for slaughter, subject to inspection, onlv at such establishments where federal inspection is maintained in the State, or placed in quarantine and used for breeding purposes only, according to the Bang method. The premises should be thoroughly disinfected, and in herds where the disease is found, the tuberculin test should be repeated at intervals of six months, and after the disease has apparently been wiped out, the test should still be applied once a year, until it is known beyond doubt that infection does not remain and has not been re-introduced. Investigations of tuberculosis in this State for the past two years has demonstrated that the disease is quite prevalent in cattle and hogs. In dairy- districts about 28% of the cattle tested were found to be affected ; among the pure bred herds, from 10%. to 50% ; in some herds as high as 90%. Dr. A. D. Melvin, chief of the Bureau of Animal Industry, of Wash - ington, D. C, consented to assist us in testing cattle for tuberculosis and furnished three veterinarians from June, 1909, to June, 1910, to test cattle in co-operation with the State; and has also furnished tuberculin, which is dispensed through my office to the veterinarians of this State. During the past two years, approximately sixteen thousand cattle were tested free of charge to the owners. Applications were made and several thousand more cattle would have been tested, had not the Gov - ernment withdrawn their men and our funds become exhausted. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE VETERINARIAN 9 M MHKK OF CATTLE TUBERCULIN TESTED 1&gt; THE STATE FROM JVIB, 1909 TILL NOVEMBER, 1910. ■/. *1 - u O ■f. In Union Stock Yards, Government and State IT.". 4,l&gt;7'J 148 148 Co-operative, by Government ♦These cattle include the dairy herds of Douglas county About 3% of all hogs slaughtered under federal inspection, at South Omaha, are found to be affected with tuberculosis. This per cent could be greatly reduced, and in time the disease could be entirely eradi - cated, if all the hogs which were sent to market for slaughter were tagged under a system so that when any were found tuberculous on post mortem examination, they might be traced back to the place ot origin, thus locating the centers of infection. Steps could then be taken to test all dairy or breeding cattle upon such premises and those found affected, disposed of as previously suggested. It is a well established fact that the source of infection in hogs is through feeding products of tuberculous cattle and their excrements, and also animals which have died from tubercuiosi?. The source of infection should be removed, the premises thoroughly disinfected and such other measures taken as would be applicable in such cases. NUMBER OF CATTLE AND HOGS SLAUGHTERED UNDER FEDERAL INSPECTION AT SOUTH OMAHA, AND NUMBER FOOD TO BE AFFECTED WITH TUBERCULOSIS. •We are only able to secure the approximate figures for these dates Veterinarians By State Officials... . *SM 4..V21 800 14 8 1&gt;! 38 Total . 1,3-10 ISMS i,:;t'j L3»l M CATTLE HOGS DATE . Total Dis- i Killed eased Total Dis- Killed eased October 1906 to June 1907 595,355 1.47H July 1907 to June 1908... 6O7,O6."&gt; July 1908 to June 1909 651,313 &gt; July 1909 to June 1910 »690,000 '•,:&gt;&lt;)() 1,670,817 34,576 Ml 48,494 i,!i!ii),;uii :&gt;i.4S'.t 1,500,000 48,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 BIENNIAL REPORT HOG CHOLERA. Hog Cholera and Swine Plague are now considered to be one and the same disease, of which the specific organism has not been identi - fied; however, it has been proven that this disease is caused by a filterable organism. It is a well known fact that it is one of the most highly contagious and malignant diseases found among hogs. The losses in this State from cholera alone are estimated from one to three million dollars a year. There has been no known treatment or preventive until recently, when the Government, through their experiments, found a method by which hogs may be immunized or protected against hog cholera. This new treatment is not recommended as being a curative agent, never - theless it has some curative effects. During the last two years thir - teen thousand hogs were immunized in this State by the Government method and excellent results were obtained. We have taken the serum and applied it to hogs in herds where cholera existed and have saved from 80% to 90% , when we were called to make investigations before many of the hogs were diseased. In some instances, in large herds, where we were called as soon as there was any evidence of disease, we have saved as high as 98%. The United States Department of Agriculture has recommended that the various States where hog cholera is prevalent erect labora - tories to manufacture their own hog cholera serum and that same be dispensed through the State. The method of manufacturing this anti - hog-cholera serum is as follows: A hog may be taken which has never been exposed or affected with hog cholera, take for instance a hog weighing a hundred pounds, and injected with 2 c. c. of virulent blood, or in other words, with the blood of a hog which is affected with an acute virulent form of hog cholera; at the same time this hog is also injected with 20 c. c. of potent anti - hog-cholera serum; this gives the hog a mild form of the disease and protects him at the same time, and after about three weeks this hog is known as an immune hog. A hog which has recovered from an attack of cholera is also an immune hog and may be used in the same way. The next step to be taken is to make the immune hog what is known as hyperimmune. Large quantities of virulent blood are in - jected Into the immune hog, either intravenously or subcutaneously, at one time, and is known as the quick method. When small quantities of virulent blood are injected into an immune hog at various intervals, it is known as the slow method, of which the final results are the same, as an immune hog which passes through either of the above methods and recovers is known as hyperimmune, or more than immune. A hyperimmune hog has more than ordinary resisting power against hog cholera, and is now ready to furnish protective serum for other hogs which are to be immunized against the disease. The serum is now </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE VETERINARIAN 11 secured by placing the hyperimmunized bog firmly in a crate, or on a table, and cutting off the tip of its tail — which has been thoroughly sterilized — and drawing the blood into a sterilized receptacle. After a large quantity of the blood is drawn, a ligature is placed around the tail to prevent the hog from bleeding to death, and the animal is put back into the pen. After about a week, the hog is again placed upon the table and the blood drawn in the same manner and the hog again returned to the pen. The hog may be thus bled four times and then, after seven to ten days, be placed upon the table, killed and all the blood now taken. After each bleeding the blood is immediately defib - rinated, a small quantity of carbolic acid or other preservative being added, and is then ready to be tested for potency as anti-cholera serum. The method of testing the potency of the serum is as follows: Three hogs are inoculated, each weighing from 50 to 100 pounds, with 2 c. c. of virulent blood; two of these hogs are injected at the same time with 15 c. c. each of the serum 10 be tested. The other hog is left without any protective serum. If this hog which has not been pro - tected becomes sick with hog cholera within eight days, and is ready to die within fifteen days, while the two receiving the immunizing serum continue in good health, then the serum may be considered potent and suitable for field work, in doses of 20 c. c. for hogs weigh - ing from 50 to 100 pounds. , TWO METHODS OF IMMUNIZING HOGS AGAINST CHOLERA. The Serum-Simultaneous Method has been limited in field work and is only used at the present time in this State during the process of manufacturing the serum. Dr. Niles of the United States Bureau of Animal Industry, through Dr. A. D. Melvin, the chief of the bureau, has done some excellent field work in this Slate by means of this method. The Serum-Simultaneous Method consists of the hog being injected with the hog cholera diseased blood and also a Quantity ot the anti - hog-cholera serum at the same time. In this way the hog is given a mild form of the disease and protected at the same time, which renders life-long immunity to the animal so treated. The Serum-Alone Method has been generally employed throughout the United States and consists of using the anti-hog-cholera serum in herds where some hogs are found to be diseased with cholera. Only the hogs which are apparently well are injected and permitted to re - main in the same pens with the diseased hogs and in this manner ac - quire sufficient exposure to contract the disease and are at the same time protected with the serum. Hogs passing through this process also acquire life-long immunity. When the anti-hog-cholera serum is injected into hogs which have not been exposed to hog cholera or treated with the diseased blood, i\ only renders immunity for a short time. If adequate appropriations are made, large quantities of serum </seg>
            <seg id="p012">BIENNIAL REPORT 12 may be stored up for emergencies, as the serum will remain potent with ordinary care for several years. Then should cholera break out in any locality in the State, the diseased herd could be immediately inoculated, as well as all hogs in the immediate vicinity. In this man - ner the disease could be entirely controlled. The last Legislature made an appropriation of $5,000 for the bien - nium for the purpose of manufacturing hog cholera serum at the State Farm, which was to be dispensed free of charge for the control of out - breaks of cholera. This work was in charge of Dr. J. H. Gain, and when the fact became known that such serum was available, hundreds of requests for the same were made at my office and also of Dr. Gain. The appropriation was entirely inadequate to cope with the conditions as they existed in our State, and therefore Dr. Gain was unable to sup - ply the demand. Dr. A. T. Peters, who was connected with the State Farm, made preparations for carrying out the process of manufacturing anti-hog - cholera serum. All veterinarians of the State were invited to the Ex - periment Station and a two days' conference was held. Most all the veterinarians took advantage of this opportunity to become thoroughly familiar with the methods of manufacturing and modes of injecting the serum. We then arranged to have the veterinarians make hog cholera in - vestigations and treat hogs at the State's expense. We were obliged, however, after a short time to discontinue the free services of veteri - narians for hog cholera, as our appropriatfon was entirely too small to /make such extensive investigations along this line. Eight thousand hogs, averaging 175 i&gt;ound&amp; apiece, have been im - munized by serum furnished free by the State, with a loss of less than 10%. About five thousand hogs were immunized with serum sent in from other states with equally as good results. We have over three million hogs in this State, which are valued at over thirty-five million dollars. In the year ending March 31, 1910, 150,447 hogs died, the estimated loss in hogs from disease alone being over one and a half million dollars. Statistics of the year 1909 show a loss of 290,000 hogs from disease which, valued at $7.25 apiece, amounts to over two million dollars. SCABIES. There is no disease that is of such importance to the stock men of -^_^.he western part of the State as mange in cattle, on account of the thousands of head which are affected over so large a territory. Few realize the great task for State and Federal officials to cope with this disease, on account of the many perplexing difficulties in trying to eradicate the same. Cattle mange or itch is a specific disease of the skin, and is caused by the mange parasite Psoroptes Communis Varietas Bovis. This small </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATE VETERINARIAN 13 mite multiplies very rapidly, causing irritation and inflammation of the epidermis and dermis. Cattle mange is spread by contact with diseased animals and through the medium of infected quarters, cars, etc. It may also be spread by any means by which, the parasites or their eggs may be transmitted frcm one place or one animal to another. The mites attack the skin and cause it to become thickened and covered with crusts and scabs, with a consequent loss of hair. Intense itching accompanies the disease, and affected cattle are more or less constantly rubbing and licking themselves. Psoroptic mange com - mences at the root of the tail, or on the neck, or withers, and gradually extends over the back and sides and may finally affect nearly the en - tire body. In serious cases the skin may become ulcerated; the ani - mals become greatly weakened and emaciated and finally die. On May 1st, 1908, the Honorable Secretary of Agriculture and the Chief of the Bureau of Animal Industry decided to remove the federal quarantine from about one-half of our State and consented to co-operate with the officials of this State in the control and eradication of scabies. Since compulsory laws have been enacted and the stockmen have be - come familiar with the methods of dipping and the Government has recommended a uniform dip, good results are being obtained. The most satisfactory method of treating cattle for mange and eradicating the disease has been found to be by means of dipping the animals in a vat filled with a liquid of such a nature that it will kill the parasites without injuring the cattle. The only dips recognized for dipping cattle for mange are Lime-and-Sulphur dip, Tobacco-and- Sulphur dip, and Beaumont oil emulsion. In order to make dipping a success, it must be repeated within ten days. . The greatest trouble that has been experienced in eradicating mange has been due first, to the lack of efficient laws regulating the disease; second, to the lack of sufficient appropriation for securing competent men to supervise dip - pings. During the dipping seasons of the past two years I employed four competent assistant state stock inspectors, at a salary of $75 a month and expenses, to supervise the dipping of infected cattle in the quarantined area under the directions of the Government veterinarians. Owing to the activity of the Federal and State inspectors, we have en - tirely eradicated the disease from Dawson, Custer, Boyd, Hayes, Hitch - cock, Chase and Dundy counties, and therefore they have been released from Federal quarantine. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 BIENNIAL REPORT INSPECTIONS AND DIPPINGS OF CATTLE FOB SCABIES IN THE QUARANTINE AREA OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR OF 1909, AND THE FIRST NINE MONTHS OF 1910. INSPECTIONS YEAR Inf. Exp. Free Total 1909 304,920 380,271 469,477 1,154,668 1910 _ 239,548 270,089 371,153 880,790 Total 544,468 650,360 840,630 2,035,458 DIPPINGS Infected Exposed Free Total 1st 2nd 1st 2nd 1st 2nd Total 1909 .... 128,497 95,035 298,625 3,160 12,262 102 537,681 1910 .... 93,222 72,249 ! 202,921 26 12,703 381,121 Total 221,719 167,284 | 501,546 3,186 i 24,965 102 918,802 COMPARATIVE RECEIPTS OF EXPOSED AND DISEASED CATTLE AT SOUTH OMAHA YARDS DURING THE YEARS OF 1908, 1909 AND 1910. EXPOSED DISEASED 1908 1909 1910 1908 1909 1910 Jan. Feb. March _ April _ _____ May June ... _ July „ August Sept. Oct. Nov..._ Dec Total •Estimate. 14,718 2,393 987 11,995 1,722 799 10,076 1,709 1,751 7,969 858 1,120 1,911 937 625 1,688 1,092 2,747 5,412 3,362 2,811 9,260 \ 9,918 5,064 12,791 11,497 1,078 9,977 11,056 4,328 6,496 5,914 2,086 3,954 1,946 »l,000 96,347 52,422 24,396 2,732 640 527 71 94 547 548 2,324 3,480 5,977 3,572 1,279 21,791 495 607 116 J 330 253 1,055 I 1,426 4,314 i 3,638 5,454 ; 6,751 1,133 25,572 662 454 855 422 653 573 403 3,213 1,571 5,272 1,100 •500 15,678 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE VETERINARIAN 15 GLANDERS AND FARCY. Glanders and Farcy are one and the same disease, differing only in that the term glanders is applied to the disease when the local lesions predominate in the internal organs, especially in the nostrils, lungs and air tubes, and that the term farcy is applied when the principal mani - festation is an outbreak of the lesions on the exterior or skin of the animal. The term glanders applies to the disease in both forms, while the term farcy is limited to the visible appearance of external lesions only, however, internal lesions always exist, although they may not be evident. Glanders is a contagious constitutional disease of the horse, ass and mule, and is readily communicable to man, dog, cat, rabbit and the guinea pig. It runs a variable course and usually produces the death of animals affected with it. It is characterized by the formation of nodules, of connective tissue, which degenerate into ulcers, from which exude a peculiar discharge. It is accompanied by a variable amount of fever, according to the rapidity of its course. It is subject to vari - ous complications of the lymphatic glands, of the lungs, the testicles, of the internal organs, and of the subcutaneous connective tissue. Glanders is found frequently in the most insidious forms, and we recognize that it can exist without being apparent; that is, it may affect a horse for a long period without showing any symptoms that will allow even the most experienced veterinarian to make a diagnosis. Public watering troughs and the feed boxes of boarding stables are among the most common recipients for the virus of glanders, which is most dangerous in its fresh state, but cases have been known to be caused by feeding animals in the box stall in which glandered animals had stood several months before. While the discharge from a case of chronic glanders is much less apt- to contain many active bacilli than that from a case of acute glanders, the former, if it infects an animai, will produce the same disease as the latter. It may assume from the outset an acute or chronic form, according to the susceptibility of the animal infected, and this does not depend upon the character of the disease from which the virus was derived. Glanders is one of the most dangerous diseases with which we have to contend in this State, and from which a great many contro- * versies arise, as the State does not pay any indemnity for animals which are destroyed for being affected with contagious or infectious diseases of malignant character. There being no known treatment for glanders at the present time, all horses being affected with this disease are immediately destroyed. In the past two years, over three hundred requests were made to investigate suspected cases of glanders located in various parts of the State. Investigations of these cases were made as early as possible, the majority of them receiving my personal attention, the others being investigated by assistant state veterinarians. Approximately a thou - sand head of horses have been examined under the supervision of -this </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 BIENNIAL REPORT department, of which 153 were found to be affected with glanders and were ordered destroyed and burjed or burned, and the premises thor - oughly disinfected under the supervision of competent veterinarians. We have at the present time forty-four horses which have been ex - posed directly to other horses affected with glanders and which are now in quarantine for further investigation. Glanders is not confined to any locality, but seems to be prevalent over the entire State, and to give it the proper attention, it would re - quire the entire time of at least one veterinarian to make complete investigations and tests. INFLUENZA. In the Spring of 1910 numerous requests were made to this office to investigate a disease among horses. Animals were reported to be dying in various parts of the State. In several instances I was called in consultation with veterinarians where their clients were losing horses from a disease that did not seem to yield to any treatment. The disease was diagnosed as Influenza. This disease seems to be prevalent, more or less, in this State at all seasons of the year, especially at sale stables, where it is commonly known as shipping fever. It usually runs a simple course, with a loss of about 3% of animals affected. Climatic conditions seem to have a great influence in connection with this disease, as many complications were met with in most cases dealt with last Spring. On some larms as many as nine animals died out of ten, in spite of all modern methods employed to check the disease. Besides the usual medications, such agents as bacterins, influenza antitoxin, anti-strepto cocci serum, and nucelin solution were adminis - tered. In certain localities when the disease first made its appearance, the best results seemed to have been obtained from the influenr.a anti - toxin. Influenza is a contagious disease of the horse, mule and ass. Young horses, from three to six years old, seem to be most susceptible. After one attack an animal is usually immune, but may become affected again. Symptoms of the disease appear about the seventh day after the exposure, when the animal seems depressed; there is inflammation of the conjunctiva, discharge from the nose, elevation of temperature ranging from 104 to 107 degrees, rapid pulse and accelerated respira - tion. The animal becomes dejected, stands with his head down and seems to pay but little attention to surrounding objects. When the disease is not complicated, the animal usually makes a recovery in three weeks. In complicated cases the animal may appear to have made a complete recovery and then die in a short time without any apparent cause. Autopsies were held on a number of cases in which some of the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE VETERINARIAN- 17 following lesions were present: Multiple abscesses of the peritoneum, lungs, spleen, kidneys and liver; inflammation of lungs and intestinal tract. FORAGE POISONING. Several investigations were made and autopsies held on horses that had died in Nuckolls, Clay and Fillmore counties. These animals seemed to have died from drinking stagnant water or well water which had been contaminated with surface drainage or forage which had fer - mented and become moldy. There are certain molds and bacteria -which under these conditions generate a toxine which is deadly poUon to animals. In most cases the disease was very rapid and fatal. In some instances the owners would hitch the horses in the morning ready for a day's work, the animals being apparently healthy, and within an hour one of the horses would stagger, fall down and never be able to rise again, and probably die within twelve hours;, other horses in pas - tures would be apparently well in the morning and be found later in the day to be down and unable to rise, and die within twelve to forty - eight hours. In most cases the animals showed a staggering gait for a very short time, or were found down and unable to rise. The tempera - ture normal, involuntary twitching of the muscles, paralysis of the whole body, delirium, in which the animal sometimes goes through a series of automatic movements as if trotting or running. No abnormal conditions were found of the internal organs of most cases posted. Three cases showed small areas of inflammation along the intestinal tract. VESICULAR EXANTHEMA Dourine was reported to exist in Boyd county, and upon investiga - tion one stallion and twelve mares were found to be affected with Vesicular Exanthema. The animals were placed in quarantine and left for treatment under the supervision of a local veterinarian. It was later reported that all animals affected made a complete recovery. SWAMP FEVER Swamp Fever, Malarial Fever or Pernicious Anaemia has been quite prevalent in this State for the past two years. The disease starts with a remittent fever, followed by weakness and emaciation, in spite of a fairly good appetite during the entire course of the disease. The visible mucous membranes become pale and the animals become very weak. Some animals seem to yield to. treatment for a short time, later become weaker and usually die. The specific organism causing this disease has never been isolated and identified. There is no specific treatment known, and about 80% of all horses affected die. This disease is mostly found on the ranges of this State. Experiments have been carried on by various stations without obtaining satisfactory results. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 BIENNIAL REPORT DECOMPOSED POTATOES. Several requests were made to investigate a disease which existed among horses in Scotts Bluff county. Upon my arrival I found, owing to the fact of potatoes being so plentiful in that county during the Spring of 1910, that the farmers were feeding large quantities of them, some of which were in a state of decomposition. Before my arrival, upon one farm five head of horses had died and several others in the immediate vicinity. 1 ordered the potatoes withheld from the animals, and no further deaths were reported. L_ ERGOTISM. Ergot is a parasitic fungus which develops among grasses grown on rich soil in hot, damp seasons. Rye seems more favorable to ergot than other grains, and blue grass ihan oilier grasses. Many different grains and grasses may also become affected. The fungus manisfests itself on the seed, and is easily recognized. The ergot when taken into the body with food stuff is absorbed and sent out through the blood, producing a degeneration and obstruction of the small arterial branches which supply blood to the distal extremities of the body where the cir - culation is weakest, thus producing dry gangrene of the feet, ears and tail. Cattle seem to be more susceptible than other animals to the in - fluence of ergot. Ergotism manifests itself by lameness in one or more limbs, swelling around the ankles or legs below the knees and hocks, which may result in only a small slough of tissue or the loss of a toe, but may slough off the entire foot. Ergot also causes serious digestive disorders. It also contracts the uterus and causes abortion. Considerable ergotism has existed in the State during the past iwo years. In a number of cases the animals were so seriously affected that they were ordered destroyed. A change of food, local antiseptic, and internal treatment were given animals which were only slightly affected and good results obtained. MALIGNANT CATARRH During the winter of 1909-10, I was called in consultation to ascer - tain if possible the cause of a disease which existed in Dodge county. I was informed that a farmer purchased at South Omaha about a hun - dred feeders under a year old.. After having them home for a short time some of them became sick and were dying. At the time of my arrival fifteen head had died and six or seven more were sick. An autopsy was held and from lesions and symptoms present, a diagnosis of malignant catarrh was made. Recommendations were made to re - move the healthy animals from the infected quarters, and medicate the diseased ones. A week later I made another visit to the premises, ac - companied by Dr. Wm. Thompson of the Bureau of Animal Industry, who confirmed the diagnosis. In the meantime seven or eight more </seg>
            <seg id="p019">STATE VETERINARIAN 19 animals had died, and as many more were sick. The owner had made no effort, however, to remove the healthy animals from the small shed, which was overcrowded, nor had he made any attempt to treat them. These animals were kept under supervision for some time; the last report received indicated that fifty had died. This is the first time that malignant catarrh has made its appearance in our State. Malignant catarrh is an acute infectious disease of cattle, affecting principally the eyes, respiratory and digestive tracts. The sinuses of :he head, the urinary and sexual organs are also frequently affected. The organism which causes this disease has never been isolated or identified. Artificial inoculation experiments have failed to transmit this disease. The disease is usually ushered in with a chill, followed by a fever, profuse secretion of tears, inflamed conjunctiva, ulceration of cornea, followed by perforation and subsequent escape of the aqueous humor. There is a dribbling of saliva from the mouth and a discharge from the nose. Upon post mortem examination in the cases above described, small ulcers were found in the stomach and intestines, besides inflammation of the respiratory tract. MYCOTIC STOMATITIS. During the latter part of July and the months of August and Sep - tember, letters and telegrams were sent in from all parts of the State, asking that I investigate a disease among cattle which was thought by the stock raisers to be foot and mouth disease. Upon investigation the disease was found to be Mycotic Stomatitis, which is not contagious, but is caused by a mold or fungi which grows upon the forage, especi - ally on clover. The mold or fungi is very irritating to the mucous Membrane of the mouth and causes inflammation which developes into ulcers, which are found over large areas on the mucous membrane of the mouth and tongue. This condition produces salivation and inap - petence, and secondarily, affects the feet, which become painful and swollen. Superficial erosions of the skin, particularly of the muzzle and teats and udders of cows, may also be present, with some eleva - tion of temperature and emaciation. A very small per cent of the ani - mals affected die if properly treated under the directions of competent veterinarians. We have had excellent results in using dilute hydro - chloric acid, boracic acid and potassium permanganate as a wash twice a day. COTTON SEED MEAL POISONING I was called to investigate a disease in cattle in Thayer county in the early part of February, 1910. Upon my arrival the owner informed me that he had bought 150 head of yearlings at the Kansas City mar - ket, and after having them on heavy feed of corn, alfalfa and cotton </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 BIENNIAL REPORT seed meal for about four weeks, several became sick and died. At the time of my visit twenty-five had died and eleven were sick. The ani - mals exhibited the following symptoms: Profuse lachratnation, diar - rhea, drooping head and a staggering gait. One animal that was down and unable to rise was destroyed and an autopsy held, which revealed an acute form of heamorrhagic gastro ententes, indicating cotton seed meal poisoning. I advised the discontinuance of feeding cotton seed meal and most of the sick animals recovered and no further losses were reported. SEPTICAEMIA H AEMORRH AGICA. Two cases of Septicaemia Haemorrhagica in cattle were reported during tl^e past two years, in Boyd county. They were immediately in - vestigated; several animals died and were cremated. The remainder of the herd were removed from the infected premises. ANTHRAX. Two cases of Anthrax in cattle were reported from Cedar and one from Stanton county. The herds were immediately vaccinated by assist - ant state veterinarians, and the disease checked. Anthrax is one of the most rapid and fatal diseases known to man or beast. The car - casses of all animals which die from Anthrax are cremated. The re - mainder of the herd are removed from the infected premises or vac - cinated. The vaccination should be done by competent veterinarians, as the vaccine used is the attenuated anthrax baccilli. Vaccine should only be used in herds where the disease is present. BLACK-LEG. Several investigations were made where young cattle were dying in great numbers. They were found to be affected with black-leg. Most persons handling cattle recognize this disease whenever present and vaccinate at once. Many ranchmen vaccinate all of their calves before the disease has manifested itself and have no losses from this source. Government vaccine is furnished free of charge to owners of cattle and is obtained through either this office or Dr. Gain at the State Farm. LIP AND LEG ULCERATION Lip and Leg Ulceration is a disease which has affected sheep in a mild form in most of the Western States for a number of years. For the past two years, in certain localities in Wyoming and Montana, the disease has become very virulent and thousands of sheep died. The Government veterinarians were called upon to assist in controlling the disease; several counties were placed in quarantine and inspections were made of sheep which were in transit and in feed lota and which had originated from the infected quarters. AH animals found to be in- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">STATE VETERINARIAN 21 fected at feed yards in this State were cut out and placed in quarantine and treated. In several instances the treatment proved unsuccessful and the sheep were later shipped, on permits, to South Omaha for slaughter. Some bands yielded readily to treatment and were later re - leased frcm quarantine. This disease is caused by the necrosis bacillus. This same germ also affects other animals as well as sheep, and is termed necrobacil - losis. The germ enters the body through ebrasions of the skin, usually affecting the mouth, lips and legs, also affecting the genital organs of both sexes. This State has experienced but few losses from this disease. Under the present regulations, sheep are only admitted into this State from the infected territories upon permits from Government veteri - narians. We found a number of calves to be affected with this same infec - tion in Colfax county. Eight calves died before the case was reported. Upon the arrival of my assistant several more were found diseased and were treated. No further losses were reported. The disease mani - fests itself in calves by necrotic ulcers in the mouth r.nd intestinal canal. Animals become weak, intoxicated and die when not taken care of. A few cases in hogs have been reported by the Government in - spectors at South Omaha. INTERNAL PARASITES. Several investigations were made where hogs were reported to be dying of hog cholera and upon examination were found to be affected with internal parasites, such as Ascaris Suilla, which is a worm rang - ing from seven to twelve inches long and usually inhabits the small intestines; the Echinorhychus gigas, a parasite three to twelve inches long which inhabits the small intestines of the ho?, and Sterongylus Paradixus, which is a thread like para3ite one to two inches long and infests the bronchi and lungs of hogs. When large numbers of the Ascaris Suilla or Echinorhychus gigas parasites infest the animals, they produce a derangement of the diges - tion. The animals infested become unthrifty, later emaciated and the disease proves fatal in small pigs In a number of instances these conditions were treated successfully. Several investigations were made where farmers were losing small pigs which seemed to cough, stand around with arched back, have con - vulsions, be unthrifty and later die. Autopsies were held and the Strongylus Parodixus parasite demonstrated. Treatment for this dis - ease in hogs is impractical. Investigations were made in several Counties where calves were dying without any apparent cause. On one farm twelve head had lingered along for several weeks and finally died. Upon my arrival several more were found to be sick and the owner informed me that </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 BIENNIAL. REPORT they were affected with diarrhea which he was unable to check. The animals which had died were similarly affected, having become gradu- ally weaker and died. One of the sick calves was destroyed and the Strongylus Contortus parasites found in great numbers. This is a parasite, from one to two inches long which is found in the small in- testines and stomach of cattle. LIVE STOCK 1&gt; NEBRASKA c o °i*2 . 2 Live \ar*i 2 S 55"2 2 s-oS £ z « Stock « « 8 o 2 - - BBh' «" • « c £ 6e i- wed*; -t-C +» « •-* s «■ 3 v &lt;/- ra z; Horses _... 1,045,000 $112,860,000 00| 19,855 $108 00 $2,144,340 00 Mules _.._ 72,000 8,568,000 00 119 00 Cattle _... 3,919,000 97,314,000 00) 156,760 28 45 4,4M#B 00 Swine :3,201,OO0 35,211,000 00 150,447 11 00 1,654,917 00 Sheep 393,000 1,729,000 00 18,078 4 40 79,543 20 Total _..|8,630,000 $255,682,000 OOl 345,140 $8,338,622 20 STATE California $ 106,351,000 $ 27,500 Idaho - ; 48,697,000 16,687 Kansas , 270,057,000 17,700 Maine _ ' 24,652,000 ' 65,000 Massachusetts 21,261,000 107,000 Minnesota 154,310,000 54,000 Missouri 251,222,000 14,600 Montana i 77,716,000 24,500 Nebraska 255,682,000 10,140 New Hampshire _ _ : 13,417,000 15,000 New Jersey 27,410,000 37,000 North Dakota 107,959,000 10,000 North Carolina 71,537,000 20,000 Ohio 230,162,000 50,000 Pennsylvania 164,191,000 180,500 South Carolina _ ' 45,738,000 14,000 South Dakota : * 128,202,000 10,000 -* Wisconsin 178,507,000 83,831 Wyoming 71,362,000 13,250 The above figures give the live stock valuation and the appropria </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE VETERINARIAN 23 tion made by various states for the investigation and control of con - tagious and infectious diseases. It will be noted that Nebraska with its live stock valuation of over two hundred and fifty-five million dol - lars has comparatively the smallest appropriation of any state in the Union. I hereby recommend that a Live Stock Sanitary Board be created with the following provisions: (1) Legal provisions should be so made that the executive officer must be a veterinarian. (2) The executive officer should be appointed by a small non-par - tisan board. (3) Said board should consist of stockmen and veterinarians. (4) Final authority for general policies and general methods should rest with the board. (5) Election, term of service, and pay of executive officer and other appointees engaged in state live stock sanitary control work should be in the hands of the board. (6) Board members should do no field work in person and should receive no pay other than actual expense incurred in attending neces - sary board meetings. (7) The Board should be invested with authority to suitably dis - pose of animals affected or exposed to communicable disease. (8) The board should be authorized to issue necessary operative quarantine regulations. (9 The executive officer and deputies should be invested with the necessary power so that they may enter premises; inspect; quarantine; and enforce disinfection. (10) The law should prescribe penalties for violation of law or regulation. (11) The law should provide that anybody who knows of or sus - pects the existence of any communicable disease must report to the state under penalty. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">NOTICE TO CATTLE OWNERS AND TRANSPORTATION COMPANIES. Regulations Providing for the Extermination of Itch, Mange, Scab and Lice in Cattle. Cancels All Previous Resolutions — Effective On and After August 16,1909. Lincoln, Nebr., July 7, 1909. Whereas, the State of Nebraska has been under quarantine for Cattle Scabies by the Federal Government, and wheroas, upon request of the Governor and the Deputy State Veterinarian of the State of Ne - braska, the Honorable Secretary of Agriculture and the Chief of the Bureau of Animal Husbandry have decided to remove on May 1, 1908, said Federal Quarantine from the counties of Red Willow, Frontier, Ciosper, Phelps, Buffalo, Sherman, Valley, Greeley, Boone, Antelope, Knox, and all counties lying east and south of these, and have con - sented to co-operate with the officials of the State of Nebraska in the control and eradication of scabies within the State. Now, therefore, pursuant to authority granted by Chapter 4, Article 2, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, it is hereby ordered: First — That all of the area of the State lying west and north of the above named counties shall be under quarantine for scabies in cat - tle and that the regulations of the Honorable Secretary of Agriculture, known as B. A. I. Order No. 143, now effective in the interstate move - ment of cattle are hereby adopted to control the inspection and the movement of cattle from and within the quarantine area of the State of Nebraska. And, provided, that no cattle shall be permitted to be removed from markets or feeding-in-transit yards within the State of Nebraska to points in the State for feeding or stocking purposes, except on cer - tificate issued by the employees of the Bureau of Animal Industry or by the Deputy State Veterinarian or those duly authorized by him. And, provided further, that no cattle which are affected with scabies will be permitted to be moved except on special permission, to the most available dipping vat for the purpose of dipping, and in no instance shall they be permitted to move from the quarantine to the non-quarantine area of the state. It having been brought to my attention that some portions of the State of Nebraska now under quarantine for scabies or mange in cat - tle, are free from said disease, or nearly so, I hereby order that cattle shall not be shipped, trailed, or otherwise moved or allowed to drift </seg>
            <seg id="p025">STATE VETERINARIAN 25 from one county of the quarantine area of the state to another county in the quarantine area of the state; except after such cattle shall have first been inspected by the Deputy State Veterinarian, or his assistant, or by an inspector of the U. S. Bureau of Animal Industry and found to be free from scabies or mange. Cattle which are a part of a diseased herd, but which show no vis - ible signs of infection, may be shipped or trailed from- one county of the quarantine area to another county of the quarantine area ONLY AFTER one dipping under the supervision of a state inspector or an inspector of the U. S. Bureau of Animal Industry and the dipping is done in a dip approved by the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Cattle which are infected with scabies may be shipped from one county in the quarantine area to another county in the quarantine area ONLY AFTER such cattle have been dipped twice under the super - vision of a state inspector or an inspector of the Bureau of Animal In - dustry and the dipping must be done in a dip approved by the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Second — When information is received that scabies exist at any point in the non-quarantine section of the state as above named, such herds of infected or exposed cattle and premises will be at once quar - antined until they have been properly disinfected under the supervision of the Deputy State Veterinarian, or an assistant state veterinarian, or an inspector of the Bureau of Animal Industry. Section 5, Chapter 4, Article 2, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1907, provides: "The Deputy State Veterinarian shall also from time to time give and enforce such directions and prescribe such rules and regulations as to separating, modes of handling, treating, feeding and care for such diseased and exposed animals from coming in contact with each other and perfectly isolate from other domestic animals which have not been exposed thereto, and which are suspectible of becoming infected with the disease, and the said Veterinarian or his agents, are hereby au - thorized and empowered to enter upon any grounds or premises to carry out the provisions of this act." Third — All railroads, live stock transportation and stock yards com - panies and their employees, and all other persons are hereby forbidden to transport, drive, or in any way handle cattle in the State of Ne - braska except in compliance with the foregoing rules. Fourth— All inspectors of the Bureau of Animal Industry located in the State of Nebraska are hereby designated as assistant state veter - inarians, to serve without compensation from the state, and are author - ized to inspect cattle and to control the movement thereof in accord - ance with the above regulations. Fifth — All previous regulations issued by this department provid - ing for the extermination of itch, mange, scabies and lice in cattle are hereby revoked. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 BIENNIAL REPORT REGULATIONS REGARDING THE IMPORTATION OF LIVE STOCK INTO THE STATE OF NEBRASKA. To Managers and Agents of Railroads, Stockmen and Others: First — All persons desirous of shipping or driving live stock of any class, into the State of Nebraska, should secure at the point of origin a certificate of health for the same from the Government, State or Deputy State Veterinarian or his assistant, declaring the said animals to be free from all contagious diseases. A copy of said health certifi - cate should be sent to the State Veterinarian at Lincoln, Nebraska, as .early as possible, and a copy must be attached to the way bill accom - panying the shipment. Second — Horses will be admitted into Nebraska only when accom - panied by a health certificate signed by a Government or State Veter - inarian, or endorsed by a Government or State Veterinarian, who is familiar with the conditions at the' point of origin of same, certifying that they are free from all contagious diseases, including horse mange or itch, and glanders farcy. Third — A like certificate of health for shipment of dairy and breed - ing cattle, together with a certificate stating that they have passed the tuberculin test, and are found to be free from tuberculosis, is necessary with all shipments of said animals. When shipments are not accompanied by the tuberculin test cer - tificate, such tuberculin test should be made in acordance with regula - tions of the U. S. Department of Agriculture, the animals will be quar - antined upon arrival at destination or suitable points enroute, until tested and released by the State Veterinarian or his duty authorized assistant. Tests must be made by a veterinarian who is a graduate of a veterinary college such as is recognized by the American Veterinary Medical Association, and must be registered in the State of Nebraska, and authorized to make such tests by the Deputy State Veterinarian. Charges and expenses for making said tests to be paid by the owners of said stock, and charges shall be lien upon cattle until paid. Fourth — Hogs imported into Nebraska for breeding purposes, or for exhibition at the State Fair, not intended for immediate slaughter, must be crated and accompanied by a certificate stating that they were free from disease w"hen they were shipped. Such animals must not be permitted in, nor loaded from stock yards. Fifth — Transportation companies should see that healtn certificates, according to the rules above, are attached to way bills of shipments of live stock destined to points in Nebraska. Sixth — When live stock enters into the State of Nebraska not ac - companied by the proper health certificate, the State Veterinarian or his assistant may inspect such stock at the point of entry into the state before issuing such permit, and the owner of said stock shall pay the expenses thereby Incurred. When not inspected at point of entry, </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE VETERINARIAN 27 said stock must be held at unloading point in the state until inspected and released. Seventh — All cattle bought at public market or stock yards in the State of Nebraska to be used for dairy purposes, or breeding cattle eligible to registry in the State of Nebraska must be held in quaran - tine and tested with tuberculin and found to be free from tuberculosis before being permitted to be removed from such public yards. All cattle to be used for dairy and breeding purposes in the State of Nebraska which are accompanied by a tuberculin chart showing that they have been tested within six months prior to date of arrival and found to be free from tuberculosis shall be permitted to be removed without further test. Under no circumstances shall animals covered by this clause be permitted to be moved from public stock yards for breeding or dairy purposes until they have been, tested and found to be free from tuber - culosis. All animals found to be affected with tuberculosis within the State of Nebraska shall be sold subject to inspection only to such es - tablishments where federal inspection is maintained within the State of Nebraska. GENERAL RULES. To Shippers of Live Stock, Managers and Superintendents of Transpor- tation Companies. In accordance with the laws of the State of Nebraska regulating the importation of live stock: You are hereby advised that the following charges for said inspec - tions are considered legitimate, but do not include other expenses which may be incurred in making such inspections, such as livery, etc.: For a clinical inspection of cattle, horses, mules, or asses, a charge of $2.00 for one animal and 50 cents for each additional animal until charge amounts to $5.00. The latter fee includes carload lots. The fee for applying the tuberculin test to cattle over six months of age to be used for breeding or dairy purposes, shall be $5.00 for one animal, $1.00 additional for each animal up to ten head, and 50 cents for each additional animal over ten head. In case it is necessary to test horses with mallein, the charges will be the same as for the tuber - culin test. No test will be accepted as being official unless made by a registered veterinarian who is authorized by the Deputy State Veterin - arian or an employee of the Bureau of Animal Industry who is a vet - erinarian, and the temperature is taken three times for a perior of eight hours prior to injection and four times starting at the period of eleven hours after injection up to the twentieth hour after injection. Charts of tests must accompany duplicate certificates of health and be forwarded to Dr. Paul Juckiness, Deputy State Veterinarian, Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 BIENNIAL REPORT Eighth — Except &amp;s otherwise provided in this net, any person who shall violate, disregard or evade, or attempt to violate, disregard or evade any of the rules, regulations, orders or directions of the Deputy State Veterinarian, establishing and governing quarantine, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof, shall be fined to any sum not less than ($50.00) fifty dollars nor more than ($200.00) two hundred dollars. PAUL JUCKINESS, Deputy State Veterinarian. Governor and State Veterinarian In testimony of my approval, I have hereunto subscribed my name and caused to be affixed the Great Seal of the State and do hereby pro - claim that the above order of the Deputy State Veterinarian shall be in force and effect from and after August 16, A. D. 1909. ASHTON C. SHALLENBERGER, GEO. C. JUNKIN, Governor. Secretary of State. * </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>