<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>CANE VERSUS SPUR PRUNING FOR GRAPES</title>
               <date value="1929-11">1929-11</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 237 November, 1929 CANE VERSUS SPUR PRUNING FOR GRAPES C. C. WIGGANS Department of Horticulture - ■ ■ THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION ■ LINCOLN ■• • •• ':[■■: ' W. W. BURR, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY The grape is an important small fruit in Nebraska, being rather generally grown in the home orchard, and becoming of increasing commercial importance in restricted areas in the southeastern portion of the state. This fruit responds markedly to good care and annual pruning. Con - siderable difference in opinion as to the most desirable method of pruning has existed, many growers favoring "spur pruning" and others using "cane pruning." Concord and Moore Early varieties planted in 1918 were used in a comparison of the merits of these two types of pruning. Records cover the years 1922 to 1928 inclusive and were taken from 1078 plants, involving 61,096 buds which produced 68,277 clusters. Cane - pruned plants consisted ordinarily of 6 canes, 8 to 10 buds in length and a few 2-bud renewal spurs, while spur-pruned plants carried 15 to 20 3-bud spurs. The data collected included (1) percentage of fruiting buds, (2) number of clusters, (3) weight of clusters, (4) relative amounts of old and new wood both on the plant and in the prunings, (5) leaf areas adjacent to certain buds, (6) some chemical analyses of dormant Con - cord canes and (7) limited information concerning the speed and ease with which these two types of pruning can be done. Records were such that the performances of individual buds in certain positions could be summarized for the entire period. Cane and spur pruning gave an average percentage of fruitful buds of 56.1 and 58.3 respectively for the Concord and 55.9 and 55.2 for Moore Early. With young plants or with plants recovering from the effects of a freeze, spur buds were generally more fruitful, but in normal years the cane buds had the advantage. In only 4 of the 11 comparisons did the spur buds fruit in the larger proportion. The most fruitful portion of the Concord cane, as measured by per - centage of fruitful buds, was from Bud Number 3 to Number 7 with Bud 4 at the top. On Moore Early canes, fruitfulness increased rather consistently from base to tip. On spurs the middle bud was the most fruitful. The bud at the extreme end of the Concord cane or/spur was below the average in fruitfulness. The average number of clusters per bud with Concord were 1.20 and 1.17 for cane and spur pruning respectively and 1.06 and 1.00 for Moore Early. The number of clusters approximates very closely the curve for the percentage of fruitfulness. Cluster weights. averaged 65.7 and 62.9 grams respectively for cane - and spur-pruned Concord and 53.2 and 51.5 for Moore Early. On the basis of production per bud, however, cane pruning was 7 per cent more advantageous on Concord and 15 per cent on Moore Early than spur pruning. The most productive bud on the Concord cane was No. 7 with an average total yield of 86.2 grams (product of average cluster number and average cluster weight) while on Moore Early it was No. 10 with SO.O grams. The middle bud on the spurs was most productive with a total weight of 79.2 and 62.7 for Concord and Moore Early respec- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION, BULLETIN 237 ,l»,ly Tot.1 production. » 1—t .« tie We ..I hi S h,« .t «,. Bud 3, decreasing more or Analyses of various parts of Moisture, sugar, starch, f^J™**^""^ No des 1, 5, and 9. the Concord cane gave results very snnUar * ° r ' d increaS e Spur-pruned Concord plants in a 6 year pe cane-pruned of 357.5 per cent in the length *£^? &amp;* average percentage of ff^r^ A^ssjjs- S 3 si.5 a tto."^^ »-"&gt;"' - ttae lh " cane pruning. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CANE VERSUS SPUR PRUNING FOR GRAPES C. C. WIGGANS The grape is one of the more widely grown fruits in Ne - braska. A small vineyard is found on nearly every farm, especially in the eastern end of the state, and at a few points commercial plantings have been made. The commercial acre - age is located under rather favorable conditions so far as soil, climate, and disease and insect prevalence are concerned, and the crop can usually be placed upon a fairly satisfactory market. These commercial plantings have been enlarged somewhat in recent years, especially in the vicinity of Brown - ville, Omaha, and Nebraska City. Thriving and producing fruit under a great variety of con - ditions, the grape is not so particular in its environmental requirements as some of our other fruits. Again, it differs from other species in that the most profitable crops are secured from plants which have been subjected to severe annual pruning. A reasonable amount of new growth must be produced each year if satisfactory fruiting is to be secured. Such development is encouraged both by good cultural meth - ods and fertile soil and by pruning. Of these means, pruning is. perhaps, the most influential. An unpruned plant, regard - less of other environmental conditions, soon becomes an un - profitable one, but a pruned plant will often survive other - wise unfavorable surroundings. Grapes are pruned for two primary purposes: (1) to pro - duce a framework to conform to a given desired pattern and (2) to regulate the production by removing surplus fruit buds, thus causing the plant to produce its maximum crop annually. Endless variation is found in carrying out the first purpose. The number and length of the fruiting canes, the direction of their growth, and the disposition of the hew snoots depend upon the wishes of the individual grower. In carrying out the second purpose, however, not so much difference is to be noted. To be sure, one grower prunes severely and another less so, but an analysis of recommendations and practices on this point shows that these fall naturally into two rather distinct groups, namely, cane, or long, pruning and spur, or short, pruning. No matter what type of training is followed, the fruiting canes are left of reasonable length, 6 to 10 buds, or are shortened to 2- or 3-bud spurs. A grape-growing dis - trict develops its peculiar type of pruning which may vary little or much from that used in another. Each method has its vigorous defenders and the surprising thing is that a fair </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 237 crop of fruit is usually secured, regardless of the type of pruning employed. Much has been written about the proper way to prune a grape plant but, in the main, these writings apply to the European or Old World species. Literature with respect to the American types has not been so plentiful and only within the past ten or fifteen years has anything really authentic been available. Nearly all of the writers during this period Fig. 1, — Concord cane-pruned, single-trunk plant before pruning. have been concerned primarily with a comparison of the various training systems, the size and length of the most pro - ductive canes, and other, similar problems. Apparently, little attention has been paid to a direct comparison of cane and spur pruning, for only one writer, Maney, 1 has made any extensive report of such work. Maney reported a single year's results, secured in a com - parison of cane and spur pruning. Old plants previously pruned to spurs in a vineyard near Council Bluffs were pruned 1 Maney, T. J. Iowa Agri. Exp. SU. Bulletin 160, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 237 report covering the work for the first ten years of the life of the vineyard. EXPERIMENTAL MATERIAL AND METHODS The plants used in this experiment were set in the spring of 1918, the spacing being 8 by 9 feet. The rows run east and west. Two varieties, Concord and Moore Early, were used, there being six rows of 21 plants, or 126 plants, of each variety. Almost a perfect stand was secured and no replants were set later than 1919. Fig. 3. — Concord spur-pruned, single-stem plant before pruning. The soil of the Experiment Station vineyard is a mediumly heavy loam. The ground slopes to the east. There is good windbreak protection on all sides except the north. Altho the site is somewhat low, no frost damage or drainage troubles can be traced to this source. Shallow, clean cultivation has been practiced each year until about July 15, but no cover crop, aside from the usual growth of weeds and grass, has ever been used. One mediumly heavy application of barnyard manure was made </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">Cane Versus Spur Pruning for Grapes been selected and, as nearly as possible, the same number of buds left on each plant. It was planned to allow approxi - mately 60 buds to remain on each plant except in 1922 when the number was slightly smaller on account of the vines being younger. These buds were distributed in the one case on six canes 8 to 10 buds long, and in the other on 15 to 20 spurs 3 buds long. . Naturally, situations have developed which have inter - fered somewhat with the comparisons- — a fruiting branch « ' Fig. 6. — Concord cane-pruned, double-stem plant after pruning. was broken off by the wind, sufficient satisfactory fruiting wood was not produced, or for some reason or other, the upper part of the plant failed to make its usual growth. As a conse - quence, the number of buds varied slightly from year to year, and likewise the number of plants considered. Under certain circumstances it was rather difficult to be sure whether a given bud was an auxiliary bud or the first bud on the cane or spur growth. Hence, in a few instances the cane or spur was cut either too short or too long. Production from all buds beyond the third bud in the case of the spur and the tenth on </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 237 the cane has been eliminated from all calculations. It is felt, however, that a fair comparison of the two pruning types has been made and that the data and conclusions presented here - with are representative of what may be expected from a young vineyard under eastern Nebraska conditions. EXPERIMENTAL DATA NUMBER OF BUDS Data relative to the average number of buds per plant and the total number of plants considered during the various years Fig. 7. — Concord spur-pruned, double-stem plant before pruning. : are given in Table 1. The numbers in 1922 are somewhat below the average because fewer rows were under considera - tion and, also, the young plants were not capable of carrying as many buds as later. The average number of buds on all plants was slightly be - low 60, the spur-pruned having slightly fewer than the cane - pruned ones. This difference is due, mainly, to the fact that the cane-pruned plants each carried several 2-bud renewal </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Cane Versus Spur Pruning for Grapes spurs. Such spur buds were always considered in the same way as cane buds on the same plant. The counts were always made" at harvest time and, hence, vary somewhat from the actual number left at pruning time because of accidental breakage occurring during the summer, especially on the cane-pruned plants. During the first two years the canes were seldom over 8 or 9 buds in length, altho later this length was increased to 10. PERCENTAGE OF FRUITFUL BUDS The percentage of buds that actually produce fruit is of more importance, of course, than the number left on the plant Pig. 8. — Concord spur-pruned, double-stem plant after pruning. at pruning time. Table 2 presents such information for each type of pruning with each variety. Apparently the type of pruning used made little difference over a period of years upon the percentage of buds producing fruit. The table does show, however, that with young plants there was a decided advantage in spur pruning. In 1922, for instance, spur buds were productive in 73.8 and 55.9 per cent of the cases for Concord and Moore Early, respectively, in comparison with 58.4 and 46.4 per cent for the cane buds. Also in 1926 the Concord spur buds apparently survived </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021">Cane Versus Spur Pruning for Grapes This work was continued for four years with the Concord and five with Moore Early. Loss of the crop in 1925 inter - fered somewhat, making crop data available, in only three and four years, respectively. A survey of these data reveals no significant differences which can be traced to the yearly shifts in the pruning system. Seasonal differences are those which stand out most plainly. The same tendency is exhib - ited which was mentioned earlier, namely, that cane-pruned plants have some tendency to produce more and larger clus - ters per bud, with a larger total production per bud than do spur-pruned plants. Plants pruned as just described did not accumulate any large amount or great length of old wood but they responded in no way differently from plants which received repeated prunings of the same type. About the only point of signif - icance which can be mentioned is that in cases where old wood has accumulated Unduly on spur-pruned plants, no hesitancy need be felt m changing the system to cane-pruning and then back to spurs again. LEAF AREA MEASUREMENTS . In ? n . effort to fi nd an explanation for the varying produc - ing ability of the different buds on the spur or cane, leaf area measurements were made in two different years, 1924 and 1927. It was thought that possibly the amount of leaf surface subtending a given bud was correlated with its pro - ducing power. All measurements taken were made on canes produced on vines that were cane-pruned the previous spring Measurements were made both of the primary leaf and of any leaves on the axillary shoot, in case such had developed. In 1927 leaves were collected from representative shoots and measured in the laboratory, while the 1924 measurements were made in the field. The leaf blade was spread out on a flat surface, covered with a pane of glass, and its area deter - mined by the use of a planimeter. All data were taken about September 25th, so that very nearly the maximum leaf growth is represented by these measurements. Table 9 gives the averages for 50 measurements of leaves subtending Buds 1 to 10 inclusive for Concord and Moore Early. Only the 1927 data are included, but very similar results were secured with 1924 measurements on Concord alone. These data show a decidedly larger leaf area subtending Nodes 2 to 7 than elsewhere on the cane, with the greatest amount at Node 3. It decreases rather uniformly toward the outer end of the cane — this holding true for both primary and secondary leaves. Possible explanations for this state </seg>
            <seg id="p022"/>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 237 is naturally a matter of only a few seconds. When calculated on an acre basis (600 plants), however, the difference might be worth consideration. It should be borne in mind that the plants under consideration here were all pruned carefully so as to leave a given number of buds on each plant. Under field conditions such care would not be necessary. Also, these were relatively young plants and did not present the com - plicated problem of older ones. ; Another phase of the field problem which was not con - sidered in these investigations has to do with the speed and ease of harvesting. Since all of these clusters had to be weighed individually no attempt was made to calculate the relative rate at which harvesting could be done. However, casual observation would lead to the conclusion that the fruit from the cane-pruned plants could be harvested more quickly and also with less damage to the clusters than would be the case with spur-pruned ones. The fruiting parts where spurs alone are used are crowded somewhat closely together and it is difficult to reach the clusters. Also, many clusters are held by tendrils which have to be loosened before the cluster is free. With the fruiting canes extended along the wires a large number of these difficulties are eliminated and harvest - ing thereby made easier and faster. GENERAL CONCLUSIONS AND RECOMMENDATIONS In the light of the experiments herein reported the con - tentions of many growers that spur pruning is just as satis - factory as cane pruning seems justified. They do not support to any great degree the conclusion of Maney that cane prun - ing is markedly superior to spur pruning so far as productive - ness is concerned. As a result of the work from 1922 to 1928 inclusive, with a young developing vineyard, it may be definitely stated that the two types of pruning as here practiced did not materially affect the percentage of fruitful buds. Buds on very young plants or on young vigorous tops developing after winter or frost injury did give some response to the type of pruning. There seemed to be a slight tendency for cane buds to pro - duce somewhat larger clusters and also more clusters per bud than did the spur buds. The result of these differences was approximately 5 grams per bud when total production was being considered. On the basis of 60 buds per plant and 600 plants per acre, the increased production of cane over spur pruning would be in the neighborhood of 400 pounds per acre. The most clusters, and likewise the biggest clusters are pro - duced from buds at some distance from the base of the cane. With spur pruning such advantage is, of course, sacrificed </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Cane Versus Spur Pruning for Grapes but is partially compensated for by the heavier production of spur buds over the first three buds on the cane. Unquestionably spur pruning does permit or require the accumulation of old wood faster than cane pruning During the first ten years of the life of a vineyard, however, this seemed to be an inconsequential factor so far as production was concerned. There is a question as to whether such con - ditions might not be of importance as the vineyard increases in age. Under such circumstances, however, after a single year of cane pruning, spur pruning could be again estab - lished if that type of pruning is desired. Spur pruning, particularly with young, well-pruned plants can be done probably somewhat more rapidly than cane prun - ing. With older vines or with less vigorous ones, however, more difficulty would be encountered in finding a sufficient number of satisfactory fruiting branches because of the much greater number needed in spur pruning. Also, with increas - ing age trunks become longer unless proper renewal methods are used, thus still further increasing the difficulty in locating good fruiting parts. When spraying time and harvesting time come, spur-pruned plants are also at a disadvantage Quality will be lowered because disease is likely to be more prevalent under the crowded condition existing with spur - pruned plants. Likewise, harvesting will be slowed down because of the twisted, tangled condition of many of the clus - ters and many clusters will be broken during the harvesting process. All things considered, it is doubtful that spurred plants can be handled any more economically than cane - pruned ones. Since there is so little difference between the two pruning systems when only productivity and pruning convenience are considered, the deciding factor in choosing the pruning type must be sought in another direction. Thus, the probability of the work being satisfactorily done enters into considera - tion. Spur pruning too often and too easily develops into simply a shearing process. It is so easy to leave the basal parts of all canes regardless of their number and fruiting possibilities instead of limiting the fruiting spurs to the proper number and selecting these from suitable parts as near the root system as possible. Such haphazard pruning entirely too common — results in overproduction one year and underproduction the next. On the other hand the average workman will soon master the cane pruning method and then be able to follow it satisfactorily with much less supervision. It is much simpler to select 6 good canes 10 buds long than 20 spurs 3 buds long. Growers who have changed from spur </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 237 to cane pruning have seldom if ever gone back. Consequently when the problem is viewed from the various angles it seems only sound judgment to recommend cane pruning for the use of the Nebraska grape grower. [4M] j </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>