<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Bindweeds and Their Control</title>
               <date value="1934-05">1934-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 287 May, 1934 1 Bindweeds and Their Control T. A. KIESSELBACH, N. F. PETERSEN, AND W. W. BURR Department of Agronomy \ ££P , * !^ __r_^_B__L_J_Hl*A_l S_K_R i^L4H I (_____ ' JB _H __^V_i _aBT_i _» _W% i__U^__^__l [ A Field Overrun with Bindweeds .. , ':.' ' ■ '■■'..••■.■■ ■ ■ . t ,' : '■ •■ .'■ THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Conclusions and General Recommendations 3 Introduction "" 7 Origin and Prevalence of Bindweeds -ZI"ZZ'Z""*IZ."I 7 How Bindweeds Affect Cultivated Crops ."""!!.".".""""" 8 Bindweeds and Related Plants Found m Nebraska """ 8 Bindweeds and Other Weeds 10 How the Two Common Species Differ 10 Detailed Description of the Field Bindweed *™.. .12 The seedling j2 The mature plant 13 Propagation and Spread of Bindweeds 16 By means of seeds lg By vegetative parts _ * 17 Experiments m Eradication 21 Eradication by Clean Tillage '".'.'.'l'"."""": 22 Implements _ 22 Rate of plant starvation through clean tillage 1... 23 Renewed growth from roots cut at various depths 25 Effect of frequency of tillage 26 Effect of depth of tillage upon frequency of cultivation 28 Follow-up treatment 28 Chemical Treatments 28 Sulphuric acid 29 Arsenic compounds 29 K.M.G. — "Kill morning glory" 11-1Z..T...11..1".." 29 Carbon bisulphide 29 , Common salt , 30 Sodium chlorate 32 Nature of sodium chlorate. 33 Time of application _ 34 Rate and manner of application 37 Relation of chlorate requirements to soil fertility. 41 Treatments of lawns for bindweeds 42 Effect on various plants and succeeding crops 43 Other chemicals ; 46 Eradication of the Hedge Bindweed 46 Literature Cited 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">CONCLUSIONS AND GENERAL RECOMMENDATIONS This bulletin reports observations and experiments during a 15-year period at Lincoln, Nebraska, concerning: the identification, growth habits, means of dissemination, and eradication of the small, white-flowered bindweed, Convolvulus arvenais. Bindweeds not only reduce yields very materially but greatly increase the labor and cost of growing crops. This weed has come to be a very serious menace m Nebraska and other states during the last 25 years, and immediate steps should be taken to curb its further spread and wherever practical to begin an eradication program. Bindweeds are spread by means of (1) seeds, (2) root fragments carried by farm and road implements, (3) transfer of infested soil ad - hering to the roots of plants as nursery stock, and (4) by natural spread from root extensions at the margins of infested areas. On land that is free of bindweeds, care should be taken to avoid their introduction. Infested grain or forage seeds should not be sown. Feed - ing infested grain or forage to livestock may be a means of spread since bindweed seeds may pass through livestock and still grow. The fertiliza - tion of lawns and farm lands with manure produced from such feeding ghould be avoided, as bindweeds become established thereby. Threshing machines are a frequent cause of introduction from other farms, and the locality of straw stacks should be examined as possible new bind - weed centers. Where bindweeds are still confined to small patches on a farm, their immediate eradication is advisable. Cases are known m which entire farms have become overrun m twenty years from a very small neglected patch of a few hundred square feet at the beginning. ..If it is impossible to begin immediate eradication m a severely infested area which has become difficult to farm, the bindweeds may often be held somewhat m check by planting to alfalfa or some kind of smother crop. Seed production by the bindweeds growing m the alfalfa is prevented by the frequent mowing. While the so-called smother crops, such as broad - cast or closely drilled cane or sudan grass, do not kill the bindweeds, they weaken them, retard their marginal spread, and prevent seed pro - duction if the stand of forage is heavy and the growth rank. No crop has been found which 'will destroy the bindweeds in* infested fields. Usually when such land is being cropped to small grain, it is advisable to practice clean fallow during the entire interval between crops. If corn is grown, thorough tillage methods designed to hold down weed growth should be practiced. Sheep turned into the corn during late summer and fall will reduce the rank weed development after cultiva - tion ceases. If it is decided to eradicate the bindweeds, there are just two practical methods now available for extensive use, namely, clean fallow and chem - ical treatment. Either method involves the loss of the land for at least a year or two. The additional cost of fallow is chiefly labor, whereas the chief expense of chemical treatment is the cost of the material. Clean fallow. — Fields may be rid of bindweeds by one or two years of fallow during which the weeds are not permitted to make more than a week's growth above ground. This practice is based on the principle of root starvation. The work must be very thoroughly done with an implement designed to cut off all vines approximately four or more inches below the soil surface. With more shallow cultivation less sur - face growth would be permissible. Occasional weeds that are skipped should be hoed off by hand. If such fallow commences m the spring, about 15 cultivations will be required the first year and six or more during the second year. This virtually means the loss of the land for a two-year period. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">If the fallow is started m midsummer immediately after harvesting a small grain crop, the eradication might be completed by fallowing throughout the following year. This method, if successful, would in - volve the loss of but a single crop. Cropping practices for several years thereafter should be of such a nature as to prevent seedlings which may arise from seed carried over m the soil from becoming established. Where the infested acreage is rather large, eradication by the fallow method is least expensive. The ordinary farm disk and corn cultivator are unsuitable for clean fallow because they permit too many weeds to slip by without being cut off. Cultivators which are equipped with overlapping duck-foot snovels are very well adapted for this work. Such cultivators operate best m trash-free soil. Standard implements especially designed for summer fallowing are available. Eradication with sodium chlorate. — Sodium chlorate is the! most effective and cheapest chemical known for destroying bindweeds! The pure chemical is recommended rather than any mixture with other salts such as calcium chloride. It is cheaper and less is required per acre. One of the disadvantages of sodium chlorate is the fire hazard. With proper preventive measures there is but little risk to the person applying the chlorate. These consist of such care by the operator as wearing rubber boots while spraying, and rinsing these and other clothing! which have become wet with the solution before it dries. Fires can be largely avoided by dry application. The calcium chloride included m commercial mixtures is very hygroscopic and tends to reduce fire hazard. Such a mixture should for this reason be preferred around buildings and! along railroads, where there is more danger of fire than m ordinary I fields. Removing trash and then applying pure sodium chlorate on the bare ground would be safe almost anywhere. Drills and sprayers used for applying chlorates should be thoroughly cleaned after use. Wooden implements which come m contact with chlorate should be kept well painted. Spraying near frame buildings or hay and straw stapks is hazardous and dry treatment is safer. Present prices make chlorate very expensive for application on large fields, especially where land is cheap and the cost of the treatment would be more than the value of the land after the weeds were de - stroyed. On small patches the cost need not be charged up against the land treated but against the whole field or farm which would otherwise become infested m time. In recent years the wholesale price has ranged from 7 to 10 cents per pound. Though much has been said as to the proper time to apply sodium chlorate, there is but little evidence that any one time of the year is much better than another, provided soil moisture conditions are jfavor - able for keeping the chlorate m solution. When applied to very dry soil it tends to remain inactive as long as the dry condition continues, which may lead to some loss by decomposition. The best periods to treat under our climatic conditions would seem to be May and \ June, before the hot, dry weather sets m; and September or October after the hot, dry period is past. Though the results appear to indicate that sprays are somewhat more effective than dry applications, the advantage is slight and will hardly pay for the extra trouble of making up solutions and spraying. I Most farmers do not ha^e a sprayer and would be obligeofto procure one for the purpose. If chlorate is purchased m the form of coarse crystals ranging from the size of a kernel of wheat to that of a pea, it may be drilled into the soil with a grain drill. Used m a water solution, the fine crystal and powder forms are suitable. If used as a spray, a solution of from one to three pounds of sodium chlorate to one gallon of I water is desirable. In the case of extensive operations, this may be applied by </seg>
            <seg id="p006">means of a power sprayer. Hand sprayers are convenient for small areas and for follow-up treatments. The stronger solution saves work and time, but may result in a less uniform distribution of the chlorate. Perhaps the most discouraging feature of chlorate treatments is that it is impossible to determine in advance just how much chlorate will be required. The amount needed varies with soil fertility, more being re - quired on fertile soil. Large, vigorous roots with a large food reserve are much harder to kill than small ones with a scanty supply of stored food. Soil texture also has an effect; chlorates act more promptly in loose, sandy soil than in heavy soils. This may be due to more rapid penetration of the chlorate but may also be due in part to a difference in root development in such soil. For average conditions, 2% to 3 pounds per square rod, or 400 to 480 pounds per acre would be suitable as a first application. For con - ditions where soil or climate is quite different from that at the Experi - ment Station, local experience would be a better guide as to amount. Care should be taken to provide for uniform and complete coverage of the infested land. Follow-up treatments should be given as the results of the first ap - plication indicate they are necessary. Time should be allowed for the first treatment to act before applying more. Some weeds often persist with a sickly appearance for several weeks or even months after effective treatments. If the plants show signs of recovery as a result of insufficient application, a second treatment should be given within perhaps a month or two after the first. In case of late summer or fall application, the follow-up treatment may be given the following spring. Delay in follow-up treatments should not be too long, as the weeds may recover after the chlorate has decomposed or has been so dispersed by leaching as to reduce the concentration in the soil. The amount of chlorate required in the follow-up treatment may vary from 5 to 200 pounds per acre, depending upon the number and vigor of the surviving weeds. If only scattered plants or patches remain these may be treated individually. After chlorate applications, a cropping system should be followed which permits destruction of any seedlings which may develop from viable seeds carried over in the soil. Other chemicals. — Ordinary salt applied at about 1 pound per square foot is a very effective treatment. This amounts to approximately 20 tons per acre and is therefore very expensive. Salt damages the soil far more than do the chlorates. Carbon bisulphide is expensive and does not work in all' kinds of soil. The labor of applying is also ex - cessive. Arsenical compounds are expensive and uncertain in their action, and a menace to livestock. A proprietary mixture by the name of Chloron was highly advertised for bindweed extermination in this state by its manufacturer in 1932. In Experiment Station tests the tops were killed but there was no per - manent injury of the roots, and the plants quickly recovered. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Bindweeds and Their Control T.A. KIESSELBACH, N. F. PBTBRSEN. AND W. W. BURR Owing to their rapid spread, perennial character! ex - treme persistence, and successful competition with culti - vated crops, the small, white-flowered bindweed (Convolvulus arvensts) has become the worst weed menace m Nebraska In case of heavy infestation, grain, yields are greatly re - duced, the cost of crop production is increased, and conse - quently land values depreciate. Its spread has been very rapid during the last 25 years and it has now become so firmly established m many localities that serious attention should be given to its control and eradication. That bind - weeds may be eradicated and the land restored to normal productivity has been fully demonstrated by tests ai the Nebraska Experiment Station extending over a period of 15 years. To plan an effective eradication program it is essential to recognize the plant, and to know how it grows and spreads and the relative merits of various cultural and chemical treatments. The purpose of this bulletin is to supply this information. ORIGIN AND PREVALENCE OF BINDWEEDS Field bindweeds are native of Europe and adjacent Asia. Through a study of the literature l it is found that they were first introduced into this country along the Atlantic seaboard, and were limited for a long time to the states on or near the coast. Their presence was first reported from Virginia m 1739. Other early reports indicate that jthey were found m Pennsylvania m 1812, Massachusetts m 1814, and Maine before 1824. The spread westward seems to have been quite rapid after the building of railroads. They were reported from Topeka, Kansas, m 1877. During the eighties they wer^ re - ported from Wisconsin m 1882, Ohio m 1885, Missouri m 1886, Nebraska m 1888, lowa m 1889. By 1900 they had been introduced m most if not all of the western states and they are now well established as weeds m all but the south - eastern states, where the climate does not seem favorable. Introduction m the western states may have been from the eastern states, or directly as an impurity m imported seeds. They are said to have been planted as ornamentals and it may be possible that their seeds have been mixed With those of related cultivated plants and their spread hastened thereby. 1 ConsiHtinsr chiefly of floras and weed bullctirs from various states. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 8 HOW BINDWEEDS AFFECT CULTIVATED CROPS Bindweeds, like other weeds, compete with crop plants for water and soil nutrients and thereby reduce yields. They also tend to smother cultivated crops by climbing upon them. In small-grain fields the matted vines interfere with the opera - tion of binders and with the drying of bundles in the shock. In corn they interfere with cultivation and after the corn is laid by they grow vigorously the rest of the season. Because of frequent cutting they do not smother alfalfa, but they compete with it for moisture to great depths. At depths of 5 to 20 feet the subsoil averaged 18.2 per cent moisture con - tent in an infested area in 1930, compared with 25.9 per cent in an adjacent similarly cropped weed-free portion of the same field. BINDWEEDS AND RELATED PLANTS FOUND IN NEBRASKA Bindweeds are part of a large group of plants called the morning-glory family, scientifically known as Convolvulaceae. Like nearly all members of this family found in temper- tgj ate climates they are herba- V ceous vines. If a support is m Jk *^ . available, they climb by twin- _^^k / ; ;\ ing around it ; if none is pres- VZA j_M-.- : - Z\__ __\\ ___ ent they spread over the i£v^_«_k _i "I ___ ground, forming a mat of '&lt;^ ■■ _-"- 7 __ tangled vines. v'&amp;g&amp;lZ^™~\w 1 N N! ' m .Kinds of bindweeds. — v^PfB - j \ m Three kinds of bindweeds I ~^ H^BH \ occur as weeds in Nebraska. \ A X i\ "^ All are perennials and belong * . \\ J \ to the genus Convolvulus. ife'(©) \ / * Of these. (1) the field bind- !f^!\. x Ti X weed, C. arvensis, is by far • - _______ the most difficult to control. . \ Tt i&lt;i thi* kind with which FlG - 1.— Leaf of the field bindweed It is this kind wren wmen (rf ht) and of the climbing the major part of the experi- buckwheat (left). The latter is ments reported in this bul- broader, more pointed at the tip, letin are concerned. (2) The and has a deeper sinus at the Vmrlo-o WtiHtopoH C &lt;tpr.ii/m. base. These two weeds may be hedge bindweed, c. sepiwm, distinguia hed -from each is the only other sort that other by the young leaves at the occurs in cultivated fields of growing point of the vines; those the state, and it is far easier of wild buckwheat are rolled tr* o-s+ArmiTiRTP Means for downwards while those 01 the to exterminate. Means lor bindweed „__, folded upwards as distinguishing these two Will s hown in the cross sections be - be discussed later. (3) C. low. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Bindweeds and Their Control 9 repens, sometimes considered a variety of No. 2, under the name of C. sepium repens, occurs along railroads near Lincoln and m prairies near Bennet, but has not been noted as a" weed m fields here. It is said to be a serious weed m western Kansas and may be found m western Nebraska. It differs irainly from the hedge bindweed m having very short internodes, short stems, and more hairy foliage. It appears better suited for dry climates. A fourth kind, which was introduced as an ornamental from Japan, and known as C. Japonicum, sometimes escapes. If it is planted care should be taken not to let it get into fields or gardens where it might be difficult to control. This species closely resembles the hedge bindweed except for the flowers, which look somewhat like a small, double rose. This double - flowered variety does not produce seeds and spreads only by means of rhizomes. Fig. 2.— Comparison of the leaves and seed bolls of the field bindweed (left) and the hedge bindweed (right). Other related plants. — Four species of the morning- glory family not listed as bindweeds occur as weeds m Nebraska. These are.(l) Evolvvlus pilosus, a small herb of little im - portance which occurs m the western part of the state but is more common m the Great Basin region ; (2) Ipomoea \epto - phyUa, the bush morning glory, which grows m dry sjoil m the western part of the state, has stiff branches, which do not twine, and is not known to occur as a weed m cultivated ields; (3) the common ornamental morning glory, /. purpurec ; and (4) the ivy-leafed morning glory, /. hederacea. Both \t the latter two are annual vines which frequently occur as weeds on cultivated land. Because of their "hard seeds", which may </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 10 remain viable in the soil for several years, patches of these last two species may persist 'for rather long periods after seed production has stopped. BINDWEEDS AND OTHER WEEDS Since bindweed seedlings can be exterminated easily, it is important to recognize them as soon as they appear. After they become well established they are less likely to be mis - taken for other weeds, but then eradication is a slow and difficult process. Generally speaking, bindweeds and other common morning glories climb by twisting or twining around their supports rather than by means of tendrils as do wild cucumbers and grapevines. Aside from the various kinds of morning glory the only other common twining weed in Nebraska is the climb - ing wild buckwheat. Because of resemblance in foliage and general appearance, wild buckwheat is easily confused with field bindweed. When in bloom the bindweed is readily dis - tinguished by the flowers, which are like those of the culti - vated morning glory but much smaller and white, or light pink in color. The wild buckwheat does not have showy flowers, and above each leaf the stem is surrounded by a tubular sheath as is usual in the buckwheat family, but want - ing in the bindweeds. The leaves at the growing point of the stem of the bindweed are simply folded upwards along the midrib, while in the very young leaves of the buck - wheat each half is rolled up from the edge, unrolling as the leaf expands. Bindweeds differ from wild buck - wheat in having a milky juice like the milkweeds but much less abundant. When a fresh stem is broken and squeezed the milk can readily be detected. Figure 1 shows the difference between both young and mature leaves of these plants. ! The cultivated morning glory and the ivy-leafed morning glory are annuals and may easily be distinguished from the bindweeds by the form of the leaves and size and color of the flowers. HOW THE TWO COMMON SPECIES DIFFER The hedge bindweed is a much larger plant than the field bindweed, having larger flowers and leaves. The form of the leaves is also quite different, as may be seen from Figure 2. In the hedge bindweed there are two broad bracts at the base </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Bindweeds and Their Control 11 of each flower covering the base of the flower, while m the field bindweed the bracts are very small, narrow, and placed some distance below the flowers. The hedge bindweed spreads by means of rhizomes or underground horizontal stems Iwhich form m summer or fall and are the only parts to survive the winter. On the other hand the roots of the field bindweed survive and spreading results, m the absence of rhizomes, by stems which grow from the lateral roots. In the jhedge bindweed the food reserve, mainly starch, is m the rhizome, while m the field bindweed the food accumulates m the cortex of the enlarged upper part of the roots. Views of the cross section of the root of the field bindweed and of the rhizome of the hedge bindweed are shown m Figure 3. Field observations indicate that the hedge bindweed is more subject to spreading through fragments scattered by farm FIG. 3. — Cross section of the root of the field bindweed (left) andlof the rhizome of the hedge bindweed (right). Note the abundant con - ducting tissue m the center of the former with food stored only m the cortex, while there is relatively little conducting tissue m the latter with food stored m both pith and cortex. implements than is the field bindweed. This may doubtless be accounted for mainly by the fact that pieces of the rhizome of the former were found to develop new roots far more quickly than did root pieces of the latter, as illustrated m Figure 4. Such pieces of field-bindweed root will bjecome established only if covered rather deeply or under extended favorable weather conditions. The rhizomes of the hedge bindweed are also favored by slower drying and higher food reserves per unit of length. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 12 Tabulated Comparison of rr-— r — -t---^3_&amp;— — -— ■ -&gt;. Field Bindweed (Convolvulus crvensis) xf fcv Introduced from Europe. ■ _Z__ *««**»**'( V\ .;". Stems 1 to 8 feet or more. / _WBL \ \\ V'' ft Width of flowers. 1 inch. j KmS l f Flowers 1 to 3 at each node. J _H P V / Two small narrow bracts on flower stalk ' jfiffiL / - at some distance below flower. »__■__ f ■•^!i Leaves small, auricles at base pointed. I^«_l_fl» *"*~^ Vegetative propagation by buds on roots. I ■■■ J Boot system with deep taproots which 1 A ) persist for many years. \ _t_ 1 Seed capsule not dehiscent, seeds often '____" — _________ " - N retained a lone time. • Style shed entirely or its base retained as f^\~~__\ "!-■ j a single point on the capsule for some / \ time. \ _; \ : — ~ ™^ «.; Hedge Bindweed (Convolvulus septum) ' YTfcHr 7 1 Stems 8 to 10 feet. V • 1^ — """A^-.Jfck. .it/ J Width of flowers, 1% to 2 inches. y I .. _ YJs. J ■ Only a single flower at each node. / . lfi&gt; f r ' Bracts broad cordate, covering base of j vi ISW I \ the flower. &gt; I •" G J I ' t Leaves larger, auricles lobed. L \}/ ; "a'- Vegetative propagation by rhizomes. ' I !■ \ V Boots formed on rhizomes anew each year. \/ _^_-Jsss' ' _ Seed capsule dehiscent, seeds generally ""&amp; .—. ' t I shed soon after ripe. I \ Base of style retained, generally splitting t V into two points on the capsule. * I DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF ___ * . . - ■ THE FIELD BINDWEED The field bindweed, being Fig. 4. — Comparative growth from by far the most important as cuttings of the hedge bindweed n. wpprt in Nphraska is the &lt; left &gt; and field bindweed (right) a ween m JNeorasKa, is to three weeks after planting- Tbe one considered in the rest of small p i ant is from a cutt ing this paper except in the last that had been merely dropped on paragraph on page 46 where the soil surface without cover - the eradication of the hedge in &amp; The more rapid rooting of bindweed is discussed. the hed^ e bindweed is apparent. THE SEEDLING The first two leaves, or cotyledons, of seedlings of the morn - ing glory family are so distinctive in form (Fig. 5) that they serve to distinguish them from other seedlings likely to occur in fields. The cotyledons of the field bindweed are smaller than those of other common morning glories, being about 5/16 in. long and 3/16 in. wide, a little wider at the tip than at the base. Shortly after the seed leaves are fully formed, short stems and branches begin to form with leaves like those of mature plants but smaller. When about six weeks old the plants have several vines 4 to 6 inches long and present a bushy appearance, as shown in Figure 5. Root growth is relatively more rapid than stem development and a seedling of this age may have roots reaching a depth of 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Bindweeds and Their Control 13 to 25 inches. The main root has three to six comparatively large lateral branches and numerous hairlike branches. At this stage the main root and larger branches begin to enlarge and starch accumulates m the cortex. Towards fall a num- v¥3R9 ber of buds form on the upper f f^* r «iP'i A part of the main root from V i^-^ which growth starts the fol- £ : ;• -f5:" W^ lowing year. The seedlings "\ I do not ordinarily bloom the \ \ first season. . \ THE MATURE PLANT 1 The appearance of the mature plant varies greatly with the conditions under which it grows, such as fertil - ity, soil moisture, and soil treatment. Furthermore m some patches because of hereditary differences, the -V/* 1 plants are vigorous, with l^tf i broad large leaves, while m I nearby patches under similar T conditions the vines may be """" ' ""k^"*- 3 - t -■' - - small with small, narrow Fig. s.— Seedlings of field bird - lea yes. weeds. The younger T plants Roof *v*f»m TVio -r.-^; (right) still have the seed rr,o^l^f *£' ?,■ V P' leaves or cotyledons, with char - mary root Of the seedling de- acteristic notched tips] The Velops into a long taproot. seedlings at left show the de- After a lateral growth Of 20 velopment at age of six weeks, to 40 inches the main branches turn downward. Food storage is maximum m the upper few feet, resulting m root enlarge - ment m that region. An excavation was made m a patch of bindweeds and the roots exposed to a depth of 20 feet A photograph of these is shown to a depth of 8 feet m Figure 6 Some of the roots were taken out and weighed m foot sec - tions. From these weights it was estimated that m a 20-foot root one-half the total weight is m the upper five fe£t, and one-fourth of it is m the upper two feet. The weights of successive foot sections m the upper 11 feet of soil ark illus - trated by two representative plants reported m Table 1 Severed roots left uncovered resumed growth and produced plants at a depth of nine feet, which is evidence of food stor - age beyond that depth. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 14 Steins. — The vines vary from lVfc to 6 feet or more m length, and from 1/16 to y$ inch m diameter, depending on growing conditions. Twisting of the stem during growth ! is evident from the jMßßnß^ffimgSKgi^ijfi£i| spiral form of the {^^^^■•■"■■■'^^^^^^^^^■ ?^^r"V.i ? J longitudinal ridges on 'j^^MJ^^M^^^^^^^^'i^^^i i* s sur f ace - When a r^MJiß^^^l^^tli^p^^^^^p^S fresh stem is broken, '■'^Kg^SKF^t^^^SS^^^^ : ¥^^^i * l * s f° u . n d to contain "^^i^^S&amp;^k^'^l^fcrtASll^i'-P^^ milky juice or latex as "CT^^^lJ^^Mm'i^^Pi^^^wfW^m * s common m the -9Hlm9Hrara^^rara|K morning-glory family. l-^gaßßKi^fiaillglgHlfiialJß^ Leaves. — The leaves -4^Bfi^^Bßßßßßa«ll^HmlS^fiEßj are alternate and '■M shaped like an arrow - !■ head. A few at the -] base of young stems :J^^H|^^HflHß§f^H3i«BffiPl are sometimes oval, "■^^^B^^BB»ffl^BpliWHj||ifl lacking the basal .m lobes. Though vari - tM able, the leaf form, ™ as illustrated m Fig- P^^^HH^D^H|HH&amp;n^HHE9^£ ures 1 and 2, is rather characteristic, so that IjiH^Jlis^^^^- -'f'^^ .^£S;?^»j the plant may be re- cognized by the leaves. Fig. 6.— Roots of well-established field . Flowers. __ Where bindweeds exposed to a depth of eight the plants have not feet. Further excavation showed that been disturbed, flow - some had penetrated 20 feet desp. ering usua i ly begins m early June, reaches a maximum m late June or July, and declines again m August. During the flowering period a stalk bearing one to three and rarely four flowers appears m the axil of each new leaf, two being the most common number. Table 1. — Weight of foot sections of bindweed roots to a depth of 11 feet Root Ist 2nd 3rd 4th 6th 6th 7th Bth 9th 10th 11th Total No. foot foot foot foot foot foot foot foot foot foot foot ACTUAL WEIGHT (prams) 1 I 1.5 I 0.9 I 0.7 I 0.8 I 0.8 I 0.7 I 0.6 I 0.4 I 0.4 I 0.4 I 0.3 I 7.4 2 I 2.4 I U| 0.8 | 1.1 I 1.1 | 1.1 | 1.1 | 1.1 | 0.6 | 0.5 | 0.4 I 11.6 RELATIVE WEIGHT, COMPARED TO FIRST FOOT (.per cent) 1 1100 I 60 I 47 I 63 I 63 I 47 I 33 I 27 I 27 I 27 I 20 I 2 1 100 | 64 183 I 46 I 46 I 46 I 46 | 46 I 25 1 21 I 19 | </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Bindweeds and Their Control 15 Usually but one, rarely two, of these develops a seed boll. Cultivation, especially plowing, tends to delay flowering and may prevent blooming altogether. The flowers as shown in Figure 7 are shaped like those of the cultivated morning glory but are much smaller. They are white or pinkish in color, the pink becoming more pronounced as the flowers fade. The corolla is from 2/3 to one inch long compared with about two inches in the common cultivated morning glories. Four seeds start in each flower but fre - quently these do not all reach maturity. A yellow honey 1 gland is found within the flower surrounding the base of the pistil. The flowers open early in the morning, at six to seven o'clock in midsummer, and close shortly after noon. In cool or cloudy weather both opening and closing may be delayed. Flowers once closed never open again, and if not fertilized while open they fail to set seed. At the time of blooming the flowers are held erect or horizontal but after fertilization the flower stalk (Fig. 7) bends downwards while the seejds de- Fig. 7. — Vines of the field bindweed bearing flowers and seed bolls. Seeds magnified two diameters are shown at upper right. | </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 16 velop. Seed production is favored by dry, sunny weather, and may fail altogether in a rainy period. There is consequently a great difference in the amount of seed produced in different seasons as well as at different times in the same season. In a very favorable place 1,419 seeds were found on a square yard, while in a square yard under less favorable conditions but 36 seeds were produced. Figure 8 shows abundant seed production of vines in a fence row. Of 477 flowers which were studied in detail in 1923, 74.6 per cent failed to set seed ; 5.2 per .cent failed to mature the seed set; and only 20.2 per cent matured seed averaging two seeds per boll. Seed. — The seed boll is nearly spherical and when all four seeds develop each seed is nearly the shape of a quar - tered sphere. If, as often happens, some of the seeds fail to develop the rest occupy the space and are thus modified in shape. Where but a single seed develops it may be nearly spherical. The mature seed is nearly black and is about one-third the size of a wheat grain. The surface is slightly roughened (Fig. 7), giving a pebbled appearance. The seed coat is very impervious to water so that germination is often delayed as in the case of the "hard seed" of sweet clover. The germ - ination may be hastened artificially by scarification or treat - ment with sulphuric acid. In the soil the seed coat gradually loses its impermeability to water and seedlings may continue to come up for years after seed production has been stopped. This has been found to occur for at least six years. Viable seeds were found in grain that had been stored for ten years. PROPAGATION AND SPREAD OF BINDWEEDS BY MEANS OF SEEDS Seeds of bindweed were found to be mature in from 24 to 28 days after blooming, corresponding very closely with the time required from heading till ripening in oats. Under con - ditions when blooming begins early in June the seed will ripen by the time that small grains are harvested. This is most likely to happen when the seed bed is prepared by disk - ing, since deep plowing delays development of the weeds. In germination tests with immature seeds it was found that 10 per cent were able to grow when harvested 17 days after blooming, or about 10 days before ripe. A large percentage germinated when harvested 21 days after blooming. The seeds tend to remain in the seed bolls a long time after they are ripe without shattering, and will thus become mixed with </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Bindweeds and Their Control 17 the grain or straw when the grain is threshed. SomJ of the seed bolls may become broken and the seeds scattered by handling and hauling the bundles at the time of threshing, bpecial precautions should therefore be taken to avoid intro - duction of bindweeds through threshing equipment. weeds may be intro - duced by the use of m- /\ jf; \ 'iV&amp;yM /' •' '. " fested grain for seed. \ / tW '.- '«\ / -'v^-Vi /» I #\d spreading viable seed 7U "J&amp;» •■■«/! I "*i # /iT" ,sft by feeding infested /nf if\ -^ra '/H-L/ V ' \-&amp;£j grain to livestock is M 7 U, / A -A / 1 / $uf/ not generally realized. I'^V %i. (\',^l/V\ V ljSk* Since the seeds have a "! .- /a™ "Z / -r33&amp;7. through the digestive Jtt/JYU * &gt;&lt; &gt;f- t^*3cl!tP~ afl which this may occur, STa I^WfcF' V-f V l^^T^^ a horse was fed 200 W/fltW ' V 4T &gt;^1 «t)i Qw--%l^^C &lt; ■bceab mixea witn oats "^—^^m^^^^l f^*- — ■' 'TiryHrHIIITrWMBnS*^ during each of 5 con - secutive days. Of the FIG - 8 - — Abundant seed production 6f field 1,000 seeds fed, 127 bindweeds growing on a fenctj. were recovered intact. They were then scarified and planted Twenty-four of them, or 19 per cent, germinated and produced seedlings within two months. Similarly treated seed which had not been fed to livestock germinated 73 per cent. Thus it is apparent that bindweed seeds m common with those of I many other species (24) * may be carried and scattered by livestock and through the use of infested barnyard manure. BY VEGETATIVE PARTS Growth from underground stems.— ln the fall before the old vines die down, buds form a short distance below the sur - face of the soil from which the new growth starts m the spring. If the field is plowed new buds form at the bottom of the furrow. In either case when growth starts m the spring from these buds the basal part of the new stem re - mains underground and may be considered as a rhizome. •Numbers In parentheses refer to literature cited on paces 46 and 47. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 18 Such rhizomes are shown m Figure 9. The leaves remain as scales and neither stem nor leaves develop any green color underground. The same thing happens when a bud on a lateral root grows to the surface. This underground part of the stem may form roots and finally assumes the appearance of being part of the root system. Some pieces of the _„ mmm iw _jwiij iiii nually, the under- ■"■ J ground portions of FIG 9 ._ Formation o f new ste ms from the plants Subject to Scat- cu t ends of bindweed roots at bottom of tering by farm imple- furrow after plowing. The part cut off mentS are more likely * nd turned over m the furrow seldom be - *■« h« nTirloi-n-rniiTir) comes established as a new plant m culti - to be underground vated soil Sprouts which have not yet Stems than true roots. reached the surface are shown at left. New plants thereby The formation of leaves at the stem tips m , v V&gt;pr&gt;nmf» pqlnhlißh- above ground is shown at center, the re - may become estabnsn- sumpti * n o£ the fo ii O wing season ed under favorable before plowing is shown at right. conditions. Growth from lateral roots. — Second only to seed produc - tion as a means for spread is the growing of plants from buds on lateral roots by means of which patches enlarge. As soon as young plants become well established they begin to send out lateral roots. Seedlings six to eight weeks old, if grown under favorable conditions, will have several such roots. They occur mainly m the upper foot of soil. Lateral roots com - monly turn abruptly downwards at a distance of 20 to 40 inches and develop into the tap roots of new plants which arise at the turn. Buds may also form along the horizontal part, giving rise to stems. These new plants soon form laterals and the process is repeated. The upper part of the </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Bindweeds and Their Control 19 tap root enlarges to a depth of several feet and actL as a storage organ, while the rest remains relatively slender. Fig- Ur S, show s buds and shoots growing from a root. The lateral root connections may persist for a long ;ime if not destroyed by cultivation. In experimental studies of the eradication of bindweeds by till - age or covering, such connections f Mk make it necesary to work with -^Db a large plats, since a plant cannot be ME&amp; ■fc'T^ starved out if connected with emUf^ UMJ^** others growing outside of the plat. \/M From observations along borders Nrf M** of clean-fallowed fields it appears - ' that such connections may extend I jf I nearly a rod. Some were actually traced for over 14 feet. Ufi f The rate of spread by these ' lateral roots will vary according jiff to soil and climatic conditions. :Jr"^V Competition with other vegetation jl. . iLI is also an important factor. A ' young, isolated, seedling bindweed — *-, I * which started growth m the fall of — 1922 had attained a height of four m ' inches by May 27, 1923. By Aug- IG ; i°-— Horizontal root n«t it VinH oonf an fnn. nAAU-;** i °^ ncld bindweed turn - wJ • 5 additional ing down and ivin shoots varying from 19 to 25 rise to a cluster of inches distant from the parent sprouts at the turn, plant. Such a colony Of ten small Shoots may also form on plants observed May 27, 1923, m- &amp; JSTSL « creased to 25 plants the following end of the main literal August through formation of ro °t forms the tap root shoots from lateral roots. ? £ the n f w plants] aris- In-the spring of 1924 a border J!£"Sh&amp; b Sir£ of bindweeds 70 feet long was horizontal part of the allowed to spread into a bindweed- ma i n root will develop free field. By fall they had ad- their own ta P roo fs - vanced on the average 13 feet. This patch is shown m Figure 11. A small patch of bindweeds was started from cuttings July 30, 1923, and permitted to spread into the surrounding weed-free area. A few dozen additional plants came up from lateral roots before fall and during the following summer the patch enlarged 12 to 13 feet m all directions. This plot is also shown m Figure 11. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 20 Fio. 11. — Field bindweeds spreading vegetatively. Upper view shows the spread from an infested border into a bindweed-free field. Below is shown a patch of bindweeds which has spread from three rows of root cuttings planted the preceding summer. The location of these three rows is indicated by the stakes at center. In both cases the bindweeds spread about 13 feet m each direction m a season. Growth from root fragments. — The root system consists of relatively large roots with a thick cortex m which starch is stored, and of small hairlike roots. These smaller roots may be ignored m propagation except insofar as their presence aids m the establishment of pieces of the larger roots and underground stems. In various tests, pieces of the larger roots which were an inch or more m length formed buds readily and developed into new plants under favorable cir - cumstances. Bindweed plants starting from root cuttings are shown m Figure 12. Such root fragments must contain enough food to support the plant until it reaches the surface. The new root system develops rather slowly and the piece dies if the soil dries up before its formation. Exposure of the root piece for a considerable length of time to dry air and sun prevents growth even if it be later covered with moist soil. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Bindweeds and Thedj Control 21 root fragments were — r \l* X *■ pared with 50 per cent &#132;_ -^T^l. &gt; w\! posure to the sun. |^9n^s®Hf &gt; Bindweed roots were | .M ' "?yy '-'ifeimltajjC/ * ment room, or when I^^HHHiBsBSSBB .&gt;^ ~~ left m a shady place out doors on moist Pig. 12.— New plants from field bindweed SOll. From these tests ro °t cuttings varying m length from one it is apparent that to six mcn es. Any portion of the larger spread by these means * oots y giv « rise to a new P la 4 under is likely to occur rmiv favorable conditions. The slow ievelop- U^der favoraWp nwf ?""? ° £ new roots com P a «d "with stems unaer iavorable mois- i s characteristic. ture conditions. EXPERIMENTS IN ERADICATION Two general practices have been found to result m com - plete eradication of well-established stands of bindweed, The methods involve either clean tillage or treatment with her - bicidal chemicals. Both employ the principle of starving out the plant by preventing vine growth above the ground, Ihere - by depleting the reserve food supply of the roots. It is well known that any ordinary green plant will die from lack of food if top growth is prevented. The choice of method becomes a serious problem, since clean summer tillage involves much labor and the loss of at least one and often two seasons of crop, and treatment with the most practical chemical, sodium chlorate, entails 1 con - siderable expenditure for material m addition to the labor of application and material losses to the succeeding crops. Both methods have been successful m experimental studies and m extensive eradication projects. Other proposed methods that were tried m these investiga - tions have either proved limited m their application 01 have completely failed. The former class includes smothering with a cover of impervious material for a period of one or two years. This would be practical only m case of very [small </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 22 patches. Treatment with ordinary salt is very effective but expensive and destructive of soil productivity. The second class of treatments which resulted m complete failure includes certain other chemicals, pasturing, and the planting of cane, sudan grass, and sweet clover as smother crops. Many papers bearing on these problems of eradication have been published by other workers, some of which are listed m the bibliography. The tests which are reported m the fol - lowing pages were made on heavily infested land m Lancaster county. 8 ERADICATION BY CLEAN TILLAGE IMPLEMENTS The prime requisite of any implement used to eradicate bindweeds by clean tillage is that it shall cut off all the plants underground. An ordinary disk pulverizer is not satisfactory because many plants are skipped. The plow does good work but is relatively slow and more than one or two plowings m one year would seldom seem advisable. Standard equipment designed especially for summer fallowing, such as "duck-foot cultivators and rod weeders, is available. An ordinary corn cultivator with wide "duck-foot" or "sweep" shovels has been used successfully on plowed ground. A one-row machine of this type is convenient for small patches. Wider machines are efficient for larger fields. For use m connection with the clean-tillage experiments at this station a six-foot alfalfa cultivator was adapted by attaching wide overlapping duck - foot shovels to the cultivator shanks. The shovels could be raised and lowered by means of levers. In reporting these tests, this machine, illustrated m Figure 13, will be known as a duck-foot cultivator. At the California and Washington experiment stations an implement with a long, horizontal blade instead of a series of smaller shovels has been used successfully. A large V - shaped blade has also been used. Such implements have a possible advantage of fewer places for trash to collect. Sugar companies m California have operated heavy cutting imple - ments as subsoilers at depths of 12 to 18 inches, thereby checking the bindweeds so that sugar beets could be grown on infested soil. Although implements operated at such depths require considerable power, they should, m connection with ordinary clean fallow, make eradication possible with relatively few treatments. t?™£ In certain special technical studies Involving extensive use of hand labor. JnSta .««^pletdTsurrounded by dean tiW '»« d WCTe «»P lo »ed. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Bindweeds and Their Control 23 Fig. 13. — Cultivator equipped with overlapping duck-foot shovel 3 for exterminating bindweeds by the clean-fallow method. This ma :hine was used m the tests reported m this bulletin. A view jof the shovels is seen below. Where a bindweed patch is very small, a garden hoe or spade may also be used effectively for providing clean summer fallow. References to the question of eradication by tillage are listed m the "Literature Cited" under the numbers 3, 6, and 29. RATE OF PLANT STARVATION THROUGH CLEAN TILLAGE Land fallowed 4 inches deep. — Because of the import - ance of root starvation m connection with bindweed control through clean tillage, a test was made during 1922 and 1 1923 to determine the rate of depletion of root reserves. A rather uniformly and heavily infested area of land was selected. Beginning with April 29, 1922, clean tillage to a depth of 4 inches with the duck-foot cultivator was continued until July 28, 1923, when extermination of the old plants was complete, as evidenced by failure of any plants to come up thereafter. While the field was being fallowed, the roots were collected at monthly intervals from representative areas 3x4 feet to a depth of 4 feet for the purpose of determining their pro - gressive changes m weight and composition. The moisture - free weight of the excavated live roots was determined a chemical "fodder" analysis made at each interval. These </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 24 analyses served as a record of the gradual exhaustion of living roots. The results are recorded m Table 2. While there were slight inconsistencies m the trend from month to month, Table 2. — Effect of continuous clean tillage upon the mois - ture-free weight and composition of &gt; live bindweed roots per acre 1 of infested land ==_— -^— = - =^=== Moisture-free weight of roots Fodder analysis of live roots to a per acre • depth of 4 feet DatS lit" 2nd 3rd 4th ~ Pro- iNitrogen - foot foot foot foot Total tein Fat Ash Fiber free extract ' Xo»! 107 U&gt;: Lbs. lit. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. eU 19 A^&gt;rn!!9 165 177 74 IB 431 16.5 8.1 11.7 19.0 60.7 £g?~f 117 88 61 21 277 16.7 8.6 11.1 24.0 45.6 J^H 82 61 22 8 173 17.7 3.6 12.4 27.4 88.9 ££?f| U3 82 45 10 250 13.5 4.5 14.4 26.5 42.1 Aug.!!:::::::: "1 21 1? 5 67 13.5 4.2 v* 27.2 89* 19 5,.. 17 28 13 2 60 16.4 3.5 14.9 28.9 363 SJSS? 47 si 9 6 94 14.0 8.7 18.2 28.0 41.1 s,™?io 5 8 6 6 24 16.5 4.0 13.0 28^ 88.2 jub '&amp; &gt;:.:::::: 0.2 I I I 19 ie.6 2.9 13.0 35.2 ss-s •Results based on Bz4-foot excavations to a depth of 4 feet. due doubtless to initial stand irregularities m the different areas, the principle of depletion of root reserves is clearly in - dicated. While the moisture-free weight of the live roots m the upper four feet of soil was 431 pounds per acre on April 29, the corresponding weight on July 29 of the follow - ing year had been reduced to 19 pounds. Furthermore, the roots which remained alive on this last date were unable thereafter to produce new growth which reached the surface. This gradual root exhaustion is accompanied by death of increasing portions of the root-system. The portions which remain alive have a composition rather similar to the normal roots, although materially higher m percentage of crude fibre and lower m digestible carbohydrates or nitrogen-free extract. Results of similar work m California were reported by Bioletti (4). He estimated total roots per acre at from 2i/ 2 to 5 tons m the upper 7 feet of soil, and showed that a single season of fallow reduced the root weight to approxi - mately one-third that on land receiving either ordinary or no cultivation. Land fallowed 10 inches deep. — Beginning with April 29, 1922, and extending to June 30, 1923, an infested area of land 10 x 10 feet comparable with that described m the preceding section was spaded to a depth of 10 inches when - ever the first bindweed shoots appeared above ground. All portions of the plant found within the upper 10 inches of soil were carefully removed and weighed at each interval. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Bindweeds and Their Control 25 The lengths of interval between spadings and the weights of plant material removed are shown m Table 3. Sinc^ this plant material represents substance drawn from the root re - serves at lower depths, a good idea is afforded as to the rate of root depletion. This is expressed m terms of amount of Table 3. — Effect of clean cultivation to a depth of 10 inches repeated whenever new growth reaches the surface, upon the weight of new plant material formed m the upper 10 inches of soil during the interval Weight of growth removed No of Interval (moisture-free) spading Date a ™£ Pounds per acre +«■»«-•«*«« + Grams per plat ' treatment (lOxio ft. area) For k.,, interval P" Uy Days 1 4/29/22 .... 263.9 258.4 2 S/IS/22 16 11.4 11.0 0.69 3 6/2/22 IS 37.8 86.3 2.02 4 6/16/22 13 19.5 18.8 1.45 6 6/27/22 12 19.2 18.4 1.53 6 7/12/22 15 16.1 15.4 1.03 7 7/26/22 14 6.5 6.2 0.44 8 8/11/22 16 6.2 6.0 0.88 9 9/5/22 25 8.1 8.0 - 0.12 10 10/2/22 27 0.8 0.8 ' 0.03 11 6/6/23 215 0.1 1 0.1 12 6/80/23 6(5 &lt;M&gt;B &lt;M&gt;B 0.01 1 Mostly from a single plant. No other plants showed up m 1923 except seedlings. growth per day per acre within the soil to a depth of 10 inches. Aside from the first interval, the reduction m weight of plant material recovered was fairly gradual until finally growth was discontinued after June 30 of the following year. The total growth produced entirely from root reserves weighed at the rate of 369 pounds per acre at the end of 14 months, when further growth ceased. This represents) about 80 per cent of the weight of roots m the upper 4 feep of a corresponding infested plat at the beginning of the test. RENEWED GROWTH FROM ROOTS CUT AT VARIOUS DEPTHS A study of the potential growth possibilities of severed roots was made by observing the time required fo: - new growth to reach the surface from different depths. Su ch in - formation is important as an indication of the necessary frequency of tillage m relation to depth of operation. A trench with a sloping bottom which reached a maximum! depth of 28 inches was dug m an infested area and refilled with root - free soil for the purpose of noting the time required for the shoots to reach the surface from various depths. The results from these trenches were supplemented by observations from </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 26 refilled excavations four feet deep. New growth started at a depth of four feet but never reached the surface when covered to this depth. Whereas new plants emerged from a depth of three inches (Table 4) m five days, it required 68 days from a depth of 28 inches. The roots cut at the greater depths were relatively handicapped because the reserve food is more plentiful m the upper portions. TABLE 4. — Days required for plants to reach the surface from bindweed roots cut and covered at various depths — 1923 D«Pth of cutting and covering tTrT.Vh'Tface Inches Days * „ „ n b Z!!.™™™!™ZZZZ!™Z™Z"!Z."!™ o 8 „«........„ . 10 10..........._. _„■„.. _ 13 12. _ &#132;■..■.■■■■■.■■■.■■■■■■...■■■■■■■.■■.■■.■.■■■.. ll« 28ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ.ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ 32 26_.™___...._..__...._..._._ ..„ . 43 28 . „ . . 63 48 * 1 Plants never reached the surface from a depth of 48 inche*. EFFECT OF FREQUENCY OF TILLAGE In the spring of 1924 an experiment was begun to deter - mine the effect of permitting the weeds to make some growth between clean cultivations. The cultivation was done uni - formly to a depth of four inches by means of the duck-foot cultivator. The treatments differed only with respect to the amount of top growth permitted between cultivations. One plat was regularly cultivated as soon as the weeds made their first appearance, or m case of rain as soon thereafter as soil conditions permitted. A second and third plat were scheduled for cultivation approximately three and six days later, respec - tively. The frequencies of cultivation for the various treatments and the effects on weed numbers are shown m Table 5. At the end of the first season, September 19, the three plats had received respectively 16, 13, and 10 cultivations. On October 16, 27 days later, 50, 17, and 9 plants per square rod were found growing on these respective plats. On June 20 of the following year the corresponding number of plants had been reduced to 4, 2, and 1 per square rod. Each of the plats was then given additional cultivation on June 23, July 3, and July 18. Cultivation was then discontinued and no additional plants appeared on any of the plats. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Bindweeds and Their Control 27 Table 5. — Comparative effectiveness of immediate and slightly delayed tillage after emergence of bindweeds m a system of eradicaton by tillage — 1924-1925 1 | Time of cultivation with respect Month t0 me °' bindweed emergence Immediate I 8 days after I 6 days after NUMBER OF CULTIVATIONS TO COMPLETE ERADICATION May, 1924 11l June, 1924 „ 6 4 » July, 1924 8 8 £ August, 1924 6 8 ' § September, 1924 2 2 'J June, 1926.................... 11l July, 1U25. ....... „ 2 2 2 TotaL...««««.«. M 19 16 1 13 NUMBER BINDWEEDS PER ACRE PERSISTING AT SPECIFIED DATES' October 16, 1924 I 6,025 1,676 826 June 20, 1925.................... J 400 200 125 September 1, 1926............ I 0 0 10 1 Data secured from 1/25-acre plats, 22x80 feet. * Original number of plants estimated as approximately 20,000 per acre. Since the longer intervals with some weed growth proved even slightly more effective than the more frequent clean till - age, it appears that a week of vine growth following tillage may draw more upon the root reserves than it replenishes through photosynthesis during such a brief initial period. With a shallower cultivation replenishment of food reserves m the roots would doubtless start more promptly. It i^ con - cluded from this and other demonstrational tests of similar nature that a brief delay m cultivation following emergence is permissible, but care must be taken to avoid long delays. Morgan (22) has found that cultivation every two weeks was as effective m the extermination of perennial pepper - grass, Lepidium draba, as weekly cultivation, though the weeds began to appear on about the tenth day. In some attempts to eradicate bindweeds from infested fields by means of tillage, extermination was incomplete be - cause of lack of thoroughness. In general practice, soil con - ditions permitting, it is considered desirable to cultivate whenever top growth is resumed m order to insure against unduly prolonged delays which may be enforced by Irainy weather. Furthermore, any weeds skipped during cultiva - tion should be hoed off m order to add to the thoroughness. In some extensive field operations it has been necessary to continue the clean cultivation throughout the second season before eradication was complete but m no case has a longer period been required when the tillage was thoroughly exe - cuted. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 28 A variation from the procedure above outlined which is suggested as having practical possibilities is to begin the clean tillage immediately after small grain harvest early in July. If this is continued the rest of that year and throughout the following season, the root reserves are likely to become so depleted that growth will not be resumed the following spring. In such event only one season's crop would be lost. EFFECT OF DEPTH OF TILLAGE UPON FREQUENCY OF CULTIVATION A study was made in 1923 of the relative effectiveness of medium and deep tillage in the eradication of bindweeds by clean cultivation. In the absence of suitable power equipment for the deep tilling, the work in this experiment was done with a spade. The cultivation was given the first year when - ever the bindweeds appeared above the ground, beginning with June 16 and continuing until growth ceased. Whereas 18 cultivations at an average depth of 5 inches were re - quired this first year, only 9 were needed at a depth of 10 inches. On May 2 of the following year it was estimated that half of the original number of bindweeds survived after the more shallow tillage, compared with 10 per cent for the deep cultivation. All of the plats were then plowed and uni - formly cultivated thereafter when needed with the duck-foot cultivator until July 28, when growth ceased. It is apparent that fewer cultivations are needed with deep tillage. More power and different machinery would be need - ed, however, and it seems probable that a depth of 4 to 5 inches following an initial deep plowing is most practical under ordinary farm conditions. FOLLOW-UP TREATMENT After an established stand of bindweeds has been extermin - ated by tillage, the problem of its possible reestablishment through seedlings still remains. If the infested field has been so handled in the past that bindweed seed matured and re - mained on the land, then the soil is likely to contain seed which may germinate at any time during the next few years. It therefore becomes necessary to be on the lookout for seed - lings and provide for their early destruction. This may be best achieved through the use of intertilled crops during this period. CHEMICAL TREATMENTS A number of chemicals have been recommended by manu - facturers or investigators for the extermination of bindweeds. Most of these and some other herbicides have been tested in connection with these investigations at the Nebraska Experi- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Bindweeds and Their Control 29 ment Station. Results are reported for tests with common salt, sulphuric acid, carbon bisulphide, sodium arsenite, K. M. G. (a proprietary compound of arsenic) , sodium chlorate J and Atlacide (a mixture of sodium chlorate and calcium chloride) . Of these only salt and the chlorates gave such satisfactory results that they may be recommended. References concern - ing these chemicals may be found in the "Literature Cited" on page 46. Other chemicals tried in preliminary tests were sodium perchlorate, ammonium thiocyanate, bleaching powder, Chloron, sodium sulphite, and sodium fluosilicate. SULPHURIC ACID Four plats, each 10 x 10 feet, were located in an alfalfa field which was heavily infested with bindweeds. These were treated respectively with sulphuric acid at the rates of 1,000, 1,500, 2,000, and 4,000 pounds per acre. The acid was diluted with 30 parts of water before appli - cation. The alfalfa was killed by all of the treatments, while the bindweeds were killed to the ground and quickly re - covered. Though a good herbicide for some annual weeds, sulphuric acid is not effective for bindweeds. ARSENIC COMPOUNDS A series of plats were sprayed with sodium arsenite in 1923. The rate of arsenic per acre varied from 11 to 217 pounds. The stronger applications killed the foliage but none did appreciable permanent damage to the bindweeds. K. M. G. — "KILL MORNING GLORY" K. M. G. is an acid solution of arsenic and has been reported to kill bindweed roots to a depth of several feet under cer - tain conditions in California. Eight plats were treated with this herbicide in 1926. Eight different rates of application were tested, ranging from 2V6 to 10 gallons per acre.j All rates except the weakest completely killed the foliage of the bindweeds. The weeds completely recovered within three weeks after all of the treatments. K. M. G. was not con - sidered as of value for killing bindweeds under our conditions and was discontinued. Crafts (7) describes methods for making acid arsenical herbicides. CARBON BISULPHIDE Carbon bisulphide applied to the soil in holes has been re - ported as an effective eradicator of bindweeds by several ex - periment stations and was therefore included in these tests. Five plats were laid out in 1923. Plats 1, 2, 3, and 4 were 20 x 30 feet and had a well-established growth of bindweeds. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 30 Plat 5 was an isolated patch of bindweeds about 40 x 50 feet in area. The respective treatments applied to these five plats may be described as follows : Plat 1.— -Holes were 20 inches deep and 3 feet apart each way. Four ounces of carbon bisulphide were used per hole. (All holes were one ____[ m diameter and were made with a soil auger. They were filled with soil after insertion of the chemical.) Plat 2.— Holes were 20 inches deep and 3 feet apart each way. Two ounces of carbon bisulphide were used per hole. Plat 3. — Holes were 20 inches deep and 2% feet apart each way. Four ounces of carbon bisulphide were used per hole. Plat 4.— Holes were 12 inches deep and 3 feet apart each way. Four ounces of carbon bisulphide were used per hole. Plat 5.— -The soil was treated by applying carbon bisulphide in the furrow while plowing. This was plowed about 10 inches deep June 6, 1924, and the carbon bisulphide applied at the rate of 4% ounces per square yard. A border about 10 feet wide was also treated all around the patch. The entire field, including these five plats, was planted to corn on June 17, 1924. Neither the corn nor the bindweeds were noticeably injured by the treatments. Even if it were effective, the cost would be prohibitive ex - cept for small patches. An application of four ounces per square yard would cost $85.00 per acre for chemical alone at 7 cents per pound. Rogers and Hatfield (26) of the Colo - rado Experiment Station estimated $400 as an approximate cost per acre for carbon bisulphide and labor. COMMON SALT Salt application has long been recognized as a means of pre - venting the growth of weeds, and has been recommended (6) for bindweeds. If used in sufficient amounts, it prevents the growth of bindweeds but also prevents the growth of most other plants. In a firm soil it is leached out very slowly and treated plats may remain barren for many years. Annual rate-of-application tests were made with dry salt during the years 1919-24. The rates have varied from 14 pound to lt/ 2 pounds per square foot. The rate of 1 pound per foot is equivalent to approximately 20 tons per acre. One pound of salt per square foot proved ample in all tests. Three-fourths pound per square foot proved nearly as effec - tive, while smaller applications were only partially effective For example, in 1922 it was estimated that one-fourth of the weeds persisted where i/ 2 pound was applied, and five-sixths of the weeds survived following an application of _ pound per square foot. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Bindweeds and Their Control 31 Examination of the root systems m salted areas has dis - closed that the salt does not kill beyond the depth of concen - tration sufficient to kill directly. When the shoots fail to get through this layer, the root is starved and finally dies. In the summer of 1930, the plats receiving one pound or more of salt per square foot six to ten years previously Were still bare of vegetation. A photograph of part of this area is shown m Figure 14. Plats with the weaker doses had some grass but still had bare spots. In 1931 Kochia, a plant which mS^'^^^S^^"' ■■"■'■ ' - ' ■"-■■ "-■•'■ Fig. 14. — Effect of 1% pounds of salt per square foot six years after application on a small patch of field bindweeds. can endure a high salt content m the soil, covered most of these areas. Most of the soil receiving a pound of salt per square foot would still be unfit for growing ordinary [field crops 10 years after treatment. It seems likely that salt at one pound per foot would render a heavy loam soil unfit for use for at least ten years under our climatic conditions. Sandy soil might recover sooner. When salt is applied to a very dry soil, the plants may remain alive temporarily until there is sufficient moisture to dissolve the salt. Plowing under the salt would tend to avoid such delay and would also prevent loss by washing m case of heavy rain. Since chlorates are more effective and the acre cost is less, there seems but little excuse for the use of salt except that it may be on hand while the chlorates will have to be procured </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 32 for the purpose. It might therefore be convenient for small patches which might otherwise be neglected. An application of 20 tons of salt per acre, at $8.00 per ton, would cost $160.00 per acre, while a normal application of 500 pounds of chlorate per acre at eight cents per pound would cost $40.00 per acre. SODIUM CHLORATE Sodium chlorate has been found very effective m the eradi - cation of bindweeds, and superior to all other chemicals tested. Thorough applications of relatively small quantities, accom - panied by simple follow-up treatment, may normally be ex - pected to exterminate even the most persistent stands (Fig. 15). It has been found that considerable leeway is permis - sible m the time and manner of application, but that uniform distribution of a sufficient amount is essential. The quantity of sodium chlorate required may vary m different fields and parts of the same field, for reasons that are not yet fully understood. Fortunately no material loss results if the or- Fig. 16. — Views of adjacent fields which had been cropped similarly to temporary pastures daring 15 years. Both fields were equally in - fested with field bindweed m the summer of 1932. The field shown at right was treated with 480 pounds of dry sodium chlorate crystals per acre applied m the fall with a grain drill, while that shown at left was left untreated. Both were plowed and sown to sweet clover m the spring of 1933. In the treated field the sweet clover seedlings had mostly died when photographed late m May, where - as a good stand was secured m the untreated field. With some supplementary chlorate application m spots m 1933, the treated field has been essentially rid of bindweeds. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Bindweeds and Their Control 33 iginal dosage is found to be insufficient and additional chlorate is added within a reasonable time. Apparently the dosage required increases with the organic matter content and fertility of the soil and with the size and vigor of root development. In order that application may! be fully effective, it is essential to have sufficient soil moisture to maintain the chlorates m solution. This chemical has been used for many years m Europe as a weed exterminator. In the United States, Latshaw and Zahnley (17, 18), at the Kansas Agricultural Experiment Sta - tion, were the first to report results and recommendations concerning its use for bindweeds. Since then a numberj of other experiment stations have reported favorable results, and chlorates have come to be used to a considerable extent on farms. Numerous reports of the use of chlorates are cited m the bibliography. The purpose of these tests, which have continued at the Nebraska Experiment Station during the last eight years, has been to study the effects of time, manner, and amount of sodium chlorate application, and to observe the after-effects upon succeeding crops. Nature of sodium chlorate. — Sodium chlorate is a salt which can be secured commercially as powder or as fine or coarse crystals. All are equally effective for weed treatment. The powder is more easily dissolved m water, and is there - fore more convenient for spraying, but costs slightly more to produce. The crystals are better suited for dry applica - tion, either by hand or with a grain drill. The powder is niore likely to become lumpy m the container than the crysals. I When kept pure, sodium chlorate is neither inflammable nor explosive. If properly packed it can be handled and trans - ported with little danger. On the other hand, owing to! its strong oxidizing properties, a mixture of chlorate with any inflammable substance, such as sugar or sawdust, becomes highly inflammable or even explosive. The inflammability of any organic substance is greatly increased if soaked with a chlorate solution and dried. Materials which burn readily may take fire spontaneously when mixed with chlorates. Several dozen spontaneous fires have started m lawns and pastures at Lincoln m connection with weed eradication | ex - periments. Most of these fires originated along cindered driveways, which had recently been sprayed with sodium chlorate. These fires have proved difficult to extinguish and spread rapidly even where the grass was very short. A lawn fire was once started by sparks when a shod horse crossed a </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 34 cement walk where the adjacent grass had been sprayed. On two occasions shoes which had become wet with chlorate spray and dried, later took fire spontaneously while being worn. Similar instances have been reported elsewhere. All spontaneous fires here have occurred on hot, clear days when the temperature was near the maximum. With proper preventive measures, there is but little fire risk. These consist of such care as (1) wearing rubber boots while spraying, and rinsing these and other clothing which has become wet with the solution before it dries; and (2) keeping wooden implements which come in contact with chlor - ate solution well painted. Spraying should never be done near frame buildings or straw stacks. There is practically no danger to the operator or likelihood of starting fires when sodium chlorate is applied directly to the soil in infested fields. When inflammable materials are sprayed with chlorate solutions there is no danger of fire so long as they remain moist. Solutions of sodium chlorate evaporate readily and the sprayed objects soon dry. An admixture of calcium chlor - ide to the chlorate reduces the inflammability because of its affinity for moisture. A commercial herbicide of this sort by the name of Atlacide, which has been tried in these experi - ments, contains approximately 40 per cent calcium chloride and 60 per cent of sodium chlorate. The calcium chloride in itself has little effect on weeds and therefore serves as an adulterant of the chlorate. This is offset to some extent by the reduced fire hazard. Because of its affinity for moisture, Atlacide quickly becomes moist and sticky when exposed to the air, and therefore is less easily applied in the dry form than is the pure sodium chlorate. However, cases of spon - taneous combustion following the use of Atlacide have re - cently been reported by Tingey (30). Other commercial mix - tures of chlorates with substances designed to reduce the fire hazard are "Vegecide" and "Occysol." Time of application. — At the time these tests were begun in 1926, it had been concluded by some investigators that the sodium chlorate must be absorbed by the foliage in order to be effective. If this belief were well founded, it would seem better to apply the chlorate in the evening when it would remain in solution longer and permit greater absorption by the leaves than if applied during the hotter and drier part of the day when drying takes place quickly. Early attempts by some workers to explain the intense killing action of this </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Bindweeds and Their Control 35 chemical attributed it to some injurious effect upon the leaves which prevents normal carbohydrate elaboration with conse - quent starvation. Based on such a principle, it seemed (ad - vantageous to apply the treatment to the vines, after they had made considerable growth, in the form of a fine spray. Accordingly, a local experiment was planned in 1926 to deter - mine whether the effectiveness of spray treatments is I in - fluenced by the time of day that applications are made. Three uniformly infested 1/40-acre plats were sprayed on June 5 at the rate of 160 pounds of sodium chlorate per acre. Tliese were given a second spray treatment of 120 pounds 3V 2 months later. A duplicate test was started August 28, \fith its second treatment given approximately seven weeks later. In each test one plat was treated in the morning while the air was still humid, another at about noon when the air was dry, and the third was treated in the evening when the I air would soon become humid. The results are given in Table 6. A few plants survived the following year in all plats, knd Table 6. — Comparative effectiveness of chlorate sprays applied at different times of the day on heavily infested lands— 1926 j Chlorate per acre Planbi Time of day — — . alive per . irst Second _ . . square rod spray spray I iotal on g/gg g7 SPRAYS APPLIED JUNE 5 AND SEPTEMBER 18 ,? : ?!! A - M I 160 I t20 I 2E0 | 2 ««iJ A. M 160 120 280 5 5:80 P. M. I 160 I 120 I 280 I 9 SPRAYS APPLIED AUGUST 28 AND OCTOBER 4 7=80 A. M I 160 I 120 1 2B0 I 6 1:00 P. M 160 120 280 6 6:30 P. M 1 160 I 120 I 280 I 5 it was concluded that the time of day had no significant effect. In connection with these experiments and field observations, bindweeds have been treated with sodium chlorate during - several years at various times between April 1 and October 26. The time of year has not proved to be an important factor in these tests, provided there was sufficient soil mbis - ture to dissolve the chlorate and thereby cause it to act upon the root system. Those applications giving the poorest 'im - mediate results were made during hot, dry periods when |the surface soil was extremely dry. Even here the disadvantage was more apparent than real, since the dormant chlorates [be - came active and the weeds were destroyed when rain fell. Such delayed chlorate action is more conspicuous with dry treat- </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 36 ment during a very dry period, as the weeds may continue to grow for several weeks without apparent injury, while a wet spray kills the surface foliage rather promptly regardless of soil conditions. Plowing under commonly results m prompt solution and action of the chlorate. Fig. 16. — An extreme case of the effect of fall application of sodium chlorate on the corn crop planted the following spring. The corn has failed completely on the area treated, while a rather heavy sup - plementary chlorate treatment was still necessary to fully destroy the bindweeds. A normal crop can seldom be grown the year following treatment. The results from two specific tests may be cited as follows : As previously shown m Table 6, applications were equally effective m 1926 whether applied m June or August. In 1929, single dry treatments of sodium chlorate were applied on a series of bindweed plats at semi-monthly intervals be - tween July Ist and September 15th at the rate of 400 pounds per acre. All these treatments were quite effective, though a few plants survived m all the plats. The uniformity of results reported m Table 7 indicate that the time of application with - in this ten-week period had little influence on the effectiveness Table 7. — Effect of single application of sodium chlorate applied at different times between July 1 and September 15 on well-established bindweeds — 1929 D«to of application grate ' ' Pounds Number ' July 1 1929 * 00 Few jSfr 18. 1929 \ «0 Few Aucuat 1 1929 * 00 Few Anfust IB 10291." *00 None sStanbe;- iVI «0 Very few September 18. 1929 — - -.- - «"&gt; F«w </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Bindweeds and Their Control 37 of the treatments. In seasons of severe midsummer drouth it was found advantageous to delay treatment until late sum - mer or fall when moisture conditions were more favorable. Rate and manner of application. — The amount of sodium chlorate required per acre to fully exterminate bindweeds is an important factor in determining whether its use is prac - tical. In recent years the price of this chemical has ranged between seven and ten cents per pound. At an average price of eight cents per pound, an application of 500 pounds I per acre would cost $40.00 for the material alone. An unneces - sarily heavy application would be unwarranted in view of | this cost. In addition to unnecessary expenditure, such heavy applications may seriously reduce the yields of succeeding crops as shown in Figure 16. For these reasons, numerous tests have been made, comparing various rates of application. In August, 1926, eight different rates were tested as single spray applications. The amounts ranged between 40 I and 400 pounds per acre. The heaviest dosage of 400 pounds gave best results but was not quite enough, as the number of plants surviving the following year was five plants per square rod. In conjunction with this test, rates of 320, 480, land 640 pounds per acre were applied in 2, 3, and 4 equal applica - tions at 20-day intervals, respectively. The numbers of weeds surviving were 26, 5, and 2 per square rod for the different treatments. In 1927, six 1/40-acre plats were laid out in an infested corn field. On September 25, after the corn had matured, these were sprayed respectively with sodium chlorate solution at the rates of 60, 120, 160, 200, 240, and 320 pounds per acre. In response to the heaviest application, 90 per cent of the plants were, killed by the following season. The other rates were too weak to be effective. Extensive spray applications may be made with power equipment, while small .areas may be treated with an air - pressure hand sprayer. Dry and spray applications. — In September, 1928, sodium chlorate was applied both dry and as a spray at rates of 160, 240, 320, 400, and 480 pounds per acre. All applications of 320 pounds or more were completely effective. Some weeds persisted where 240 pounds or less were applied. No marked differences were noted between results of dry and spray treatments. Numerous seedlings appeared on all of these plats in the spring of 1930. While these were first notejl on April 9, they continued to come up till fall, some surviving the following winter. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 38 In another field sodium chlorate was applied at the rate of 320 pounds per acre to three plats. In one the chlorate was sprayed on the vegetation, in another the vegetation was hoed and raked off and the chlorate sprayed on the bare ground, and in the third the chlorate was applied dry. No great difference was noted in the relative effectiveness of the differ - ent methods of application. Applying dry sodium chlorate with a grain drill. — In October, 1928, sodium chlorate was applied dry to duplicate plats at the four rates of 160, 240, 320, and 400 pounds per acre. The dry crystals were drilled with an ordinary farm grain drill with rows spaced seven inches apart. The field was then plowed to a depth of five inches. The heaviest application destroyed most of the weeds, only a few coming up the next year. These were entirely eliminated with a few additional pounds per acre applied directly to the surviving weeds. The lighter-treated plats had to be retreated until finally all were rendered free of bindweeds by additions which, with the original treatment, totaled 400 pounds per acre. Sodium chlorate and Atlacide applied both wet and dry at various rates per acre. — A rather inclusive test was laid out in 1929 in 1/40-acre plats in a heavily infested apple or - chard. Dry and wet treatments of both sodium chlorate and Atlacide were applied at seven different rates, ranging be - tween 160 and 400 pounds of chlorate, or its equivalent of Atlacide, per acre. Each rate was applied in 1, 2, and 3 treatments, respectively. In case of the single treatments, the entire amount was applied on July 15, at which time the weeds had made a rank, heavy growth. In the case of two treatments, these were applied on July 15 and September 3, respectively, in the proportions of 65 and 35 per cent of the whole. Those plats receiving three applications were treated on July 15, September 3, and October 16 in the proportions of 60, 20, and 20 per cent for the successive treatments. Owing to systematic differences in spil type which par - alleled the frequency-of -application test, this phase of the experiment did not materialize in a comparable manner. The data may be summarized, however, with respect to the other differences in treatment, as reported in Tables 8 and 9. Table 8 records the amount of chemical applied in the in - itial treatments, as specified in the original plan, and also the amount applied in the follow-up treatments which were designed to complete the eradication. The effectiveness of the various treatments is shown by the number of surviving </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Bindweeds and Their Control 39 TABLE B.— Comparative effectiveness of sodium chlorate 1 , and Atlacide when applied at various rates m both the dry\ and spray form on land heavily infested. Original applications made m 1929, follow-up treatments as needed m 1930 and 1931 Weeds alive per square Rate per acre rod following f Manner Original Follow-up Original Follow-up „. . , ' treatment* treatment 3 treatment » treatment lotal 8/25/30 6/16/31 Pound* Pounds Pounds Number Number SODIUM CHLORATE Dry 160 287 447 78 4 200 347 647 147 8 240 207 447 68 1 280 183 463 47 8 820 127 447 31 8 860 170 630 17 1 400 87 487 9 0 Average 280 194 474 65 4* Spray 160 242 402 146 11 200 263 463 69 13 240 128 368 29 3 280 95 376 80 4 820 70 390 11 2 860 48 408 B 0 400 33 433 a 0 Average 280 124 404 '. 42 5 ATLACIDE (approximately 60% sodium chlorate and 40% calcium chloride] Dry I 280 398 678 88 0 860 403 753 96 6 420 260 670 42 8 490 48 638 21 0 660 188 748 24 8 630 98 728 18 8 700 148 843 18 8 Average i 490 218 ~| 708 43 8 Spray 280 | 357 637 05 0 BSO 298 648 86 8 420 188 608 62 a 490 170 660 26 4 660 163 713 37 a 680 160 780 11 0 700 138 833 15 2 Average 490 207 697 46 4! . n^lfl^ h i tr , e *^ nent J l | the ,«"' e jage for 3 plats receiving, respectively, the amounts specified m 1, 2, and 8 applications. ' The original treatments were applied m the summer and fall of 1929. Their effectiveness is measured by weed counts on August 26, 1930. • The follow-up treatments were applied September 4. 1930, and June 30 1931 m amounts estimated sufficient to complete eradication. It was found a year later that some bindweeds persisted on all of the plats and it is estimated that an additional 26 pounds per acre would have been required m the fall of 1981 to complete the extermination. weeds determined after both the original and the follow-up treatments. With an average of only about four plants' re - maining per square rod, it appears probable that the remain - ing number could be effectively eliminated by light applica - itons to the individual plants. Although there are some incon - sistencies, the general indications are that (1) the effective- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 40 Table 9. — Summary of resvlts from applying sodium chlorate and Atlacide m both the dry and spray form on land heavily infested with bindweeds. Original treatment applied m 1929 and a follow-up treatment m 1930 and m 1931 * Weeds surviving per p]ats Hate per acre— l 929 square rod after Manner overawed Orisinal Follow-up „ , Original Follow-up treatment treatment Total treatment treatment ' Number Pounds Pound* Pounds Number Number SODIUM CHLORATE TREATMENT Dry I 21 I 280 I 194 I 47* I 65 I 4 Spray | 21 I 280 | 124 1 404 I 42 | S Average | 42 j 280 | 169 | 439 | 49 | 6 ATLACIDE (approximately 60% sodium chlorate and 40% calcium chloride) Dry I 21 I 490 I 218 I 708 I 48 8 Spray | 21 I 49') I 207 I 697 I 46 1 4 Average | 42 | 490 | 218 | 708 | 46 4 RATIO OF AMOUNT OF SODIUM CHLORATE TO ATLACIDE USED PER PLAT Dry .57 I .90 I .67 .... 1 &lt;£ray ■■■■ .57 I .60 I .58 -. ™ Average ~ -. .67 I .75 I .62 I ™ 1 ~ •S^o C binSw^ds r0 persilSd 'on all plats In 1982 and required a small additional chlorate treatment for complete extermination. ness increases with the amount of chlorate; (2) insufficient initial treatments may be effectively supplemented by later additions but may lose m efficiency if the time is unduly pro - longed; (3) it makes but little difference whether the initial treatment is relatively large or small, since rather similar total amounts will be used to effect eradication; (4) the re - sults indicate that the spray was 15 per cent more effective Table 10. — Effect of extra heavy dry applications of sodium chlorate and Atlacide on land m apple orchard heavily in - fested with bindweeds. Original application made m 1929. FoUow-up treatment m 1930 l ' Weeds alive per square Rate per acre rod followinir Original Follow-up Oritrinal Follow-up life? "gsr Total - t^w- t flsff t " Pounds Pounds Pounds Number Number SODIUM CHLORATE 480 I 160 I 640 I 13 I 0 600 80 680 9 0 720 I 40 I 760 I 5 I 0 ATLACIDE 800 I 40 I 840 I 12 I 0 1.050 40 1.090 « o l|2oo I 85 I 1.285 I 20 I 0 » These treatments and results are comparable with those reported m Table 8. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Bindweeds and Their Control 41 than dry treatments with sodium chlorate, while both methods appear equally effective in case of the Atlacide; (5) plound for pound Atlacide proved 62 per cent as effective as sodium chlorate. Heavy applications. — In 1929 a series of plats were given treatment at higher rates than in the main orchard series' just described. The details of the initial and follow-up treatments and results are given in Table 10. Such heavy initial rates are not ordinarily advisable. A few weeds survive at almost any rate, though there are fewer with the heavy applications. More chlorate per acre was used than required with lighter initial applications followed by supplementary treatments. There is greater loss in case of heavy treatments due to injury to succeeding crops. A moderate initial amount followed by retreatment of mots where weeds continue to come seems a more desirable pro - cedure. Relation of chlorate requirements to soil fertility — In connection with a number of experiments, as well as in the general work of eradicating bindweeds on the Station farm, it has been found that different fields as well as parts off the same field have differed greatly in the amount of chlorate re - quired per acre. Frequently these differences have been [asso - ciated with soil fertility, the more fertile soil requiring the more chlorate. This was illustrated by a series of 20 1/10-acre plats scattered over an infested field. Of these 20 plats the five showing the highest organic matter content, as calculated from their total soil nitrogen content, required an average rate of 539 pounds of sodium chlorate per acre for complete eradication, while the five which were lowest in organic matter required an average application of only 374 pounds per acre. The 10 plats having intermediate amounts qf or - ganic matter required an average of 432 pounds of chlorate per acre. Based on these 20 treated plats, a correlation co - efficient of 0.53 was found between the amount of chlorate applied per plat and the percentage of organic matter ia the soil. A somewhat more detailed study was made of two regions in this field which differed decidedly with respect to the lux - uriance of bindweed growth. Within each area, an untreated ' 1/40-acre plat was surrounded by four similar plats receiv - ing chlorate treatment. In both areas the bindweeds had, been established for many years and the difference in growth is regarded as evidence of difference in soil fertility. Based on 1 x 4-foot quadrats excavated to a depth of 5 feet (Table 11) , </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 42 the untreated areas contained at the rate of 1,237 and 257 pounds of roots per acre (moisture-free basis) respectively. The corresponding total organic matter contents of these two plats to a depth of 2 feet, as calculated from the soil nitrogen, were 3.38 and 2.28 per cent, respectively, which suggests a marked difference in soil fertility. The surrounding plats required corresponding amounts of 603 and 340 pounds of chlorate per acre, respectively, to bring about complete eradi - cation. Table 11. — Amounts of sodium chlorate required per acre to eradicate bindweeds on heavily infested areas differing in soU fertility and vigor of bindweed growth — 1980-1981 Moisture-free weight of bind- Degree Organic matter' weed roots per acre 1 Roots Sodium of ■ III 1 per acre, chlorate aoil Upper 2nd 2nd Surface 2nd 3rd 4th 5th upper required fertility 6 m. 6 in. foot foot foot foot foot foot 5 tt. per acre p. a. p. a. p. a. lu. lu. lu. lu. Lb: iu. Ju. Very fertile 4.77 3.97 2.40 503 402 237 71 24 1,237 603 Relatively infertile 8.80 2jj4 1.50 92 56 49 40 20 257 840 ■Analytical determinations were made by M. D. Weldon of the Agronomy Department. The organic matter was calculated by multiplying the total soil nitrogen by 21. The weights of roots per acre were calculated from lx4-f oot quadrats. Just how the fertility produces this difference in results of chlorate treatment has not been determined. It may be that the organic matter tends (1) to hasten the decomposition of the chlorates either chemically or biologically, (2) to absorb ■ the chlorate, thus rendering it less effective, or (3) the fer - tility may have caused a more vigorous development of the bindweeds, and the larger, more vigorous roots are harder to kill. Other observations indicate that soil texture may also be a factor influencing the effectiveness of chlorate treatments. Chlorates applied to a loose, sandy soil killed the bindweeds quickly, and the harmful soil effects rapidly disappeared so that other plants were soon able to grow in the soil. It is also possible that differences in soil acidity may affect the action of chlorates on plants (35) . Treatments of lawns for bindweeds. — Various tests have been made to determine whether sodium chlorate may be applied to infested bluegrass lawns in such a way that the bluegrass will survive and the bindweeds succumb. The treatments have varied from frequent light applications to single heavy applications. The outcome has been so variable and uncertain that little assurance may be offered of a satis - factory result, although it may sometimes be achieved. No </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Bindweeds and Their Control 43 one manner of application has been outstanding m its supe - riority, or can be depended upon always to secure the desired result. Since heavy applications designed to kill the bind - weeds rapidly have m general done no more permanent in - jury to the grass than have slow-acting, frequent, light treat - ments, they may be regarded as most desirable. They re - quire no more total material and greatly reduce the labor and duration of the eradication program. Forty acres of bluegrass on the Agricultural College cam - pus and pastures were treated with sodium chlorate during the summer of 1932. The procedure was based upon the plan of a heavy spray followed by one or two supplementary spray treatments whenever necessary. Accordingly the first spray was varied from 300 to 480 pounds of sodium chlorate per jacre applied m solutions of 1, 2, or 3 pounds per gallon of waiter. Ten acres of this land seemed m need of respraying m the fall because of prompt recovery of the weeds and were given an additional spray of 100 pounds per acre. In many places the grass which was just recovering from the first spray was killed by the respray. Several acres which had been left unmowed all season withstood the chlorate treat - ment with less injury to the grass than adjacent mowel or grazed land where killing of the grass was sometimes very severe. In one area which had been used as a heavily manured vegetable garden for many years previous to seeding with bluegrass, retreatment was needed throughout, as compared with only scattered retreatment on adjacent land. Lowland areas all needed retreatment, while the single treatment on the less fertile slopes was more effective, needing retreat - ment only m spots. Ordinarily where the grass as well as the bindweeds have been destroyed, the grass can best be re - established by preparing a thorough seed bed and reseeding as soon as the soil has recovered from the action of the chlor - ate. Scattered bindweeds may be removed from lawns [with a minimum of grass injury by spudding and inserting a small quantity (a half teaspoonful) of dry sodium chlorate into the hole. Effect on various plants and succeeding crops.— ln con - nection with some of the preceding tests, it was found that there was a marked difference m the way .chlorates affect different plants. Chlorates may be absorbed by the leaves when these are sprayed, or the roots may absorb chlorates applied to the soil. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 44 ' Some leaves have a sleek, smooth surface which is not easily wetted, so that practically all the spray runs off, while the leaves of other species are easily wetted and quickly absorb the chlorates and die. Lamb's quarters or cabbage may be sprayed without apparent injury to the leaves, while pig weeds have shown injury from the light mist blown on them when adjacent plats were sprayed. Some plants are able to grow in soil containing consider - able amounts of chlorate without apparent injury, while others are very sensitive to chlorates in the soil. Probably all absorb chlorates, but some are less injured than others. It has been said that different varieties of the same crop may show a difference in resistance to chlorates (35). A differ - ence in the action on the leaves due to difference in the amount absorbed is common to all herbicide sprays but a difference in action on different plants after absorption is rather a unique character of the chlorates. The question of the relative tolerance of different kinds of plants for chlorates should be studied more than it has been. Losses might be reduced by growing the most resistant crops after chlorate treatments. In spraying around trees, shrubs, and other perennials it would be desirable to know which are resistant enough so that it is safe to spray around them and which are not. The common grain crops such as wheat, barley, oats, corn, and cane are quite susceptible to chlorates when planted in treated soils. The duration of such harm - ful effects varies with the amount of application and soil tex - ture. The injury from a large application on a heavy soil may last for a year or more. Some of the legumes appear to be more resistant, both when sprayed and when planted in treated soil, than the grain crops. The following have been found somewhat resistant here or reported elsewhere as resistant: red clover, white clover, sweet clover, peas, soy beans, and vetches. Aside from these legumes beets, mangles, and cabbage appear fairly re - sistant. Among trees and shrubs, pines, red cedars, and Douglas spruce are relatively resistant, while arbor vitae has been damaged by spraying. Elms and lilacs were not seriously injured by applications sufficient to destroy bindweeds arOund them. Several kinds of spirea and ninebark were found sensitive to chlorate sprays. Cottonwood seedlings were able to grow in soil which had a very heavy application of chlor - ate. In spraying around pines in the orchard it was noted that the old pines showed no injury, and that seedling pines came up where the soil had received a heavy application of </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Bindweeds and Their Control 45 chlorates. Delevoy (10, 11) reports that beds of some ever - greens such as pines and Douglas spruce may be sprayed after the seeds have been planted with enough chloratejs to keep out most weeds without injuring the tree seedlings.) Old apple trees have generally shown no injury from chlor - ate application to the soil up to 800 pounds per acre. A much heavier rate killed some young trees. Cherry trees have usually shown resistance but have sometimes been killed. In spraying around apple trees care should be taken to avoid getting the spray on the leaves, as they are easily killed. The effect on corn yields may be illustrated by the follow - ing tests: On October 1, 1928, about two acres of a par - tially infested cultivated field were treated at the rate of 400 pounds of chlorate per acre. One portion of the infested area was treated dry and the other with spray. The treatment was followed by a period of rainy weather. An additional application of 50 pounds was made in June, 1929, to the re - gions which appeared to need it. The field was planted to corn in 1929. About 8 per (cent of the hills in the treated area showed evident chlorate in - jury in June ; some were killed, while most seemed to recover. However, when dry weather came about tasseling time the treated area dried up badly and many stalks were barren. A number of 20-hill sections were harvested ; those in the treated area averaged 10y_ bushels per acre, while those in the rest of the field averaged 28 bushels per acre. In 1930 this field was again planted to corn and abcut 2 per cent of the hills showed seedling injury, these most y in retreated areas. . Otherwise there was no apparent effect and normal crops have been grown since. The few bindweeds that have appeared each season have been treated individually and the field may now be considered free from bindweeds and the soil practically recovered. This field has a fertile soil and required heavy applications and perhaps therefore showed more persistent soil injury than would be expected in less fertile soil requiring less chlorate per acre. In another field treated in the fall and planted to corn in the spring, there was extensive injury and killing (Figj 16) in the seedling stage. The following year the corn crop started out apparently normal but when dry weather jame at about tasseling time the treated areas wilted badly[and most of the stalks were barren, while untreated parts of the field remained normal. This wilting was probably due to root injury which did not become evident till water loss became too great for the impaired root system. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 287 46 OTHER CHEMICALS Sodium perchlorate was tried because it had been reported injurious to crop plants when occurring as an impurity m Chile saltpeter used for fertilizer (25) . This chemical seems less effective on bindweeds than do chlorates and costs more per pound. Ammonium thiocyanate proved effective m limited field tests and appears to merit further trial. Bleach - ing powder was tried on a small scale, and Chloron, which appears to be largely chlorinated lime, was tried more exten - sively. Bindweeds were killed to the ground but they re - covered fully within two weeks. The active ingredient m these is probably calcium hypochlorite. Sodium sulphite, which seems effective on some weeds, such as sheep sorrel (Rumex acetosella) and perennial smartweed, was tried but has proved ineffective for bindweeds. Deem (9) and Delevoy (11) reported using another proprietary compound, Occysol, consisting of sodium chlorate, sodium fluosilicate, and sodium chloride. This is claimed by the manufacturers to have largely replaced the pure chlorates as an herbicide m France because of freedom from fire hazard. This compound has not been tried here but one of its ingredients, sodium fluosilicate, has been tried on a small scale. It kills bindweeds when used m very dilute solutions m water cultures but is much less effective when applied to the soil. ERADICATION OF THE HEDGE BINDWEED Although hedge bindweed is a serious pest m this state its eradication is rather easily effected because its rhizomes, from which all growth begins annually, are short and contain rela - tively little food reserve compared with field bindweed. A single season of clean fallow is known to have killed out well - established stands. Deep plowing followed by a prolonged dry period m mid-summer should aid materially m a fallow program. A small patch was sprayed three times with sodium chlorate applied at the rate of a total of 250 pounds per acre during late summer and fall. Very few plants appeared the next year. This would be a desirable method of exterminat - ing along fence rows or other places where cultivation would not be feasible. LITERATURE CITED (1) Aslandcr, Alfred. (S) liarnum, Clyde C. Chlorates as plant poisons. The control of wild morning-glory. Jour. Amer. Soe. Agron. 18:1101-02. Calif. Exp. Sta. Circ 256, p. 22, fiz - -1926. 18. 1928. (2) . (4) Bioletti, Frederic T. Experiments on the eradication of The extermination of morning-glory. Canada thistle with chlorates and Calif. Exp. Sta. Circ. 69, p. 12, fig. other herbicides. 6. 1911. Jour. Aer. Res. 36:916-34. 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Bindweeds and Their Control 47 (6) Bowser, W. E., and Newton, J. D. (21) Loyer. Decomposition and movement of Emploi des chlorates pour la de - herbicldcs in soils, and effects on struction des herbes dans les cereales soil microbiological activity and sub- dc printemps. sequent crop growth. Compt. Rend. Acad. Aer. France Canad. Jour. Res. 8:78-100. fig. 9. 9:957-60. 1923 ranee (6) Call, L. E.. and Getty, R. E. (22) Morgan, A. The eradication of bindweeds. Experiments in hoary cress control Kans. Agr. Exp. Sta. Cire. 101. 1923. Lepidium draba. coniroi. (7) Sl"** 8 " A ' ?' , , . , ,„„. i°V. r - Art. Victoria 29:406-9. 1931. The use of arsenical compounds in (23) Neller, J. R. the control of deep-rooted perennial Effects of chlorates upon thd cata- SCrdia 7:361-72. 1983. St,"™* ° f *' r00ta °&lt; bi^ (8) and Kennedy, P. B. Jour. Agr. Res. 43:183-89 1(31 The physiology of Ctmvoivulun arven- (24) Oswald. E. 1. sis in relation to its control by The effect of animal dices tion and chemical sprays. fermentation of manure oi, the Plant Physiology 5:329-44, fig. 6. vitality of seeds. raBnure on ,ne ,o» JS? 0- t «r ,„.» M f Exp - sta - BA 128. 1908. (9) Deem, J. W. (25) Pellet. H., and Fribourg. G. Control of weeds with chlorates. Le nitrate de soude perchlorate. Ses New Zealand Jour. Agr. 48:105-10. effets sur la vegetation (10) Dclevoy. G. Annales de la Science Agron nn La destruction des mauvaises herbes 199-225. 1903. ' par le chlorate de sonde. (26) Rogers, Charles F., and Hatfield Ira Bui. Soc. Cent. Forest. Belg. 82:476- Carbon disulfide for the eradication 89, fig. 2. 1929. of perennial weeds. CU) . Colo. Exp. Sta. Bui. 847 fie 12 L emploi du chlorate et de l'occysol 1929. ' comme herbicides. Bui. Soc. Cent. (27) Schefer, E. G. Forest. Belg. 40:273-89 and 889-58. The bindweed. /,»» i 988- . . Wash .- A*r- Exp. Sta. Pop. Bui. 187, (12) Hansen, A. A. fig. 6. 1927. Sodium chlorate as an herbicide. (28) , Lee, o. C and Nelle- J R. Proc. Ind. Acad. Sci. 38:139-42. 1929. Eradicating the bindweed with s'odl (18) Hulbert, H. W.. Bristol. R. S., and ium chlorate. Dmaweea wltn «»- Benjamin, L. V. Wash. Exp. Sta. Bui. 236 fie 4 Methods affecting the efficiency of 1929. ' B " chlorate weed killers. (29) Stewart, George, and Pitman. D W Idaho Exp. Sta. Bui. 189. 1981. Ridding the land of wild morning - (14) , Rcmsberg, J. D., clory. and Spence, H. L. Utah Exp. Sta. Bui. 189. 1024 Controlling perennial weeds with (80) Tingey, D. C. chlorates. Spontaneous combustion on weed Jour. Amer. Sec. Agron. 22:423-83. plate sprayed with a solution of 1930. Atlacide. (16) Kennedy, P. B.. and Crafts, A. S. Am. Jour. Agron. 25:297-98. 1938 The anatomy of Convolvulus asrvmsis, (81) Vigor, S. H. wild morning-glory or field bind- Chemical weed killers, weed. Scientific Agr. 9:687-93. 1929 Hilgardia 5:591-622, fig. 27. 1981. (32) Walker, Ernest. (16) Korsmo, E. -__'.' — '. Suggestions upon the care of apple Ugress i nuti dens Jordbruk (Weeds orchards. in modern agriculture). (Pp. 193-94, Carbon disulphide for Oslo, 694 pp., illus. 1925. killing sassafras sprouts.) (17) Latehaw, W. L., and Zahnley, J. W. Ark. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 91. 1906 Experiments with sodium chlorate (38) Wilcox, E. V. and other chemicals as herbicides for Carbon bisulphide for killing weeds field bindweed. Hawaii Agr. Exp. Sta. Press Bui. Jour. Agr. Res. 85:757-67, fig. 2. 26. 1910. 1927. (84) Willard. C J. (18) and . Killing field weeds with chlorates. Killing field bindweed with sodium Ohio Exp. Sta. Bimonthly Bui 146 chlorate. pp. 158-68. Sept.-Oct., 1980. Kans. Exp. Sta. Circ. 136, fig. 10. (35) Yamasaki, M. 1928. On the cause of varietal distinctions (19) — nnd . in certain crop plants in" regard to Magnesium and calcium chlorate as the resistance to the toxic action of substitutes for sodium chlorate for potassium chlorate. killing field bindweed. Jour. Imp. Agr. Exp. Sta. (Tokyo) Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. 20:1329. 1:805-26, pi. 4. 1981. 1928 (20) Loomis, W. E., Bissey, Russell, and ' Smith. E. V. Chlorates as herbicides. Science 74:485. t5M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>