<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Insect Pests of Stored Grains and Their Control</title>
               <date value="1922-12">1922-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">&lt; A.G •)0 December. 19: iv\ Insect Pests of Stored Grains and Their Control \I fl. SWKN'K adult beetle, enlarged 5x Ricrr/n kal experiment station THE L'XIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN' ■U. (From (hitu-nden, 18! </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS rtrue grain w;&gt;evils eadelle E grain beetles flour haatlM mealworms The Angoumois grain ■ The Indian-meal moth The Mediterranean floui The meal snout-moth Other caterpillars occasi Preventive measures rroying stored grain pests by lution Destroying stored grain pests by </seg>
            <seg id="p003">INSECT PESTS OF STORED GRAINS AND THEIR CONTROL H. SWKNK. STATK 1 SWKNK. STATION KNTOMllI.OCIST aware that their warfare against destn warfare against destructive in- ar not ended when their wheat is in the bin and their corn is in the i their wheat is in the bin and their corn lered crops become immediately subject of stored grain, commonly called "weevi ipred crops become immediately subject to attack of stored grain, commonly called "weevils." The 5 never small, but it becomes of especial serious - prpvailing low prieos for grain, unusually large n the farm granaries and cribs, awaiting an im - et. When once started in the grain, these pests ally that the farmer finds he must either destroy once, or allow the pests to seriously damage it. ;&gt;etent authorities that -in the United States stored ■ of over $100,000,000 worth of grain and grain s never small, but it becomes of especis prevailing low prices for grain, unusu: in the farm granaries and cribs, awaitin ;et. When once started in the grain, tl •ally that the farmer finds he must eith« once, or allow the pests to seriously d petent authorities that -in the United Sta ss uf over $100,000,000 worth of grain a loss being proportionately much heavier in are about -0 species of insects that inji ng proportionately much heavier in the South N n Nebraska there are about -0 species of insects that injure stored \ irrain more or less. Some are beetles and their larvae, others are the iome are beetles and their larvae, other ill moths. To the oths. To the farmer all are "weevil," farmer all are "weevil," tho that .' applied only to two beetle species -th applied only to two beetle species -the granary vil. The following paragraphs and illustrations eevil. The following paragraphs and ill *1 more important stored grain pests to mportant stored grain pests to be found at the farmer maj ie farmer may recognize the particular pes particular pest or pests ury to his grain, and may then apply t his grain and may then apply the proper UK KM r ( RAIN WEEVILS S WEEVILS , » -A weevil Calm .' \_j, _^H^i~ is common in 7/ _^3^ * raska, is a mm- » . ' f^Hw^i* \ &gt;wn to blackish, x --iA '''^^P't beetle, a little \ inch long, with . ,_ a a stout snout i_a££F^^H^^^^ i with elongate ■^T'^^^B x iltjt it it* Umjth- It infests not „ also stored oats, \ kafip. The fe- Ft*;. I. — The prain we&lt; ♦ * i ,_„ '/'*-.' ■ : ■ . the trut* granary :i and katir. The ft Fl&lt;:. 1. — The grain the true granary mout to bore a „„,„„,,„, e nl»ntwi about 6x, enlarged about 6x. natural %itt 1 of grain, after »' » ide : , r - the , rire wwvil same: a. larva, enlarged about tiny hole into a kernel of grain, after enlarged about -Ix: '.pupa. linute white egg same From Packard, 1869 white egg 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 XkBKASKA Kxi'Klil MINT STATION. ClRCll. AH 1 I in the hole. This process she repeats many times in different kernel during her period of life, which extends over several weeks. In a few days the egg hatches into a short, fat, footless, white, grub-like larva that at once begins to eat out the inside of the kernel. By the time th larva is matured fig. 1, o) and a little less than one-eighth of an long, it changes to a white pupa ifig. 1, 61 inside the kernel, which ha; been hollowed out to a mere shell, and a few days later the new 1 tl» comes forth. All the time that the beetles arc laying eggs in some they are gnawing nto and eating out others, so that the beetles an The whole life cycle is only larvae are about equally destructivt weeks during the warmer months, so that the insect undergoes 4 generj i tions in a year, and can increase enormously in a granary, once it becom infested. It has been estimated tha an. in the r, produce 6.000 desieml; The rice weevil Calm s;i appearance as the true granary w color, usually relieved by iV the base and two near th dense, and not arrunqi-d hi infested by the true granary v.i and meal, and even cereal p s it is not found doing serious ini true granary weevil, being mo: history is essentially like th I'iil it possesses wings, it sometimes inf* THE ( ADEM.K Next to the true grain weev ie ca has in recent years proved to 1 bom imi in southeastern Nebraska, and it is also at times a seriou pest. In the fall and early winter of 1921 a ber to middle December, it was unusually injurious t both in the farm granaries and in the eoun a southeastern Nebraska west to Dundy, eastern Frontier, western Da and southeastern Custer counties, and north to Douglas, Colfax Nance counties. In northeastern Nebraska it did consider stored oats at the same time in 1921. The adult is an oblong, flattened, blackish beetle aboi an inch long, distinctly constricted at the joining of the thorax and abdomen The larva is a broad, tiattish worm about three-fourths of an inch long, whitish in general color, with the head, some marks on the thorax, and the tail dark brown, the last ending in two sharp point* see cover illustra- tion). Both the beetles and their larvae feed on the stored grain, going from kernel to kernel, and eating out the embryo and causing much </seg>
            <seg id="p005">K i I'k.si of Stobeo (Iruns 5 ant, especially to grain intended for planting w purposes. Th?y also feed on oth?r stored grain pests to some extent. The fe-historv is much like that of the mealworms, which are discussed i &gt;eyond. The eggs are laid in the spring and summer, and the resulting arvae, when fully grown, live over as such until the following spring. There is thus but the one generation in a year. THE GRAIN BEETLES There are several kinds of related ifamily Ciieujidae), small, reddish- iout one-tenth of an inch long, to be found commonly *n beetles, a elevators, infesting all kinds of grains, as well as in anaries ar warehouses, and the household, infesting flour, meal, and other real products. The commonest one of these in Nebraska is the saw- toothed grain beetle iOryzaephilu.-- surinamensixi, shown in S* the accompanying illustration, which differs from the other species in having 6 saw-like teeth on each side of the thorax. This species is sometimes found in dried fruits and meats, sugar, salt, and nuts as well as in cereals and cereal products. Another very common /I S species in Nebraska is the foreign grain beetle iCathar- Mf y tus adeenai, which is of broader form than the preced - jj? A inr -jn/1 Vi-.i^ tViu tlii*(v-»v ifiiicr ilmn Jntm ti'ith f/mwi&gt; •drena&gt;, which is of broader form than the preced- and has the throax wider than long, with convtx and prominent front angles. A less common ■ ; siaes ana prominent iront angles. a less common species is the square-necked grain beetle Silcanu* mellatus), which has the thorax about square and rnIM ni'ifnf. as indicated by the name. The flat grain beetle ■ l.uemophlotu* putiUus) is another less common distinguished by the ntirrou-, slightly concave- onger and more slender antennae than in the three i? &gt;eetles lay their small, elongated eggs on the grains slender, whitish, active larvae, which feed on food, nibbling here and there, until full grown. They made by sticking together pieces of the infested i laterial. and in a week or two have changed into beetles. In warm ration requires only about 3 or 4 weeks, but in cooler A A-eeks are required. There are thus 4 to 6 generations ■a THE FLOl'R BEETLES There are several kinds of related ifamily Tenebrionidur , small, eddish brown beetles, commonly known as flour beetles or "flour weevils," which chiefly infest flour, but also corn meal or other grain products. and occasionally are found in stored grain in granaries and elevators. In mills and feed stores they often abound in flour. The commonest of </seg>
            <seg id="p006">»■&gt; NkIIKA-KA Kxl'KlilUKNT STATION. ( ' 1 lit I I . \ I: these flour beetles in Nebraska is a aperies known as the conf ■P beetle- Triholium ttmfwmm . which is of a rust red color and ab sixth of an inch lone, its larval sta white w a quarter of an inch long with tha tip of th- tail en lint? ir point* rig. t, c . Another common spseiM in N T !-!&gt;.-:i-ika is the tiny, sma flour beetle Piiloru* nit:tbtinji . which is h h of an inch Ion;;. Th^ b?etle ■Tr^' '" '- —■ only one-twelfth of an inch Ion;;. Th.^ b?etle only one-twelfth of an in tifiixria'ux is also frequently found V ,- Alpkitaph'.igtt* UfaaeUtmt fi ul«i frequently foun 1 Alphilophngiis hifiixriaiux is also f 1 in grain dust in Nebraska granaries, but i* un- y in Nebraska granaries, hut is un- ,/T" j^ j'Z^ pest. h ' | 'XT^ beetles lay their tiny unite eggs in f V- A. important as a pest. These flour beetles lay thrir tiny white tfjaji ia These flour beetles lay th the flour, in cracks and corners of flour bins or racks and corners of flour bins or - the Hour, in cracks ai barrels, on the seams of flour sacks, etc. T l barrels, on the seams of Hour sac seams of Hour sacks, etc Th"&lt; ■ \V J £~ lays, and during the sumnvr m mtha c \ , ■G^ hatch in a few days, and during the MMMf m mtha hatch in a few days, and dur the resulting larvae become fully grown in :i or the resulting larvae becom irvue become fully grown in :i or a 4 weeks. During the spring Bad (all, • !• v lop- 4 weeks. During tht •ing the spring Ukd fall. &lt; I. v-loi.- H' 1 ■■ :: T: i j ?■ , - ''" ur '"' slower, and 14 or 15 »."k- are i,,,ti.- ment is much slower, and 14 or 15 wet&amp;n ar ■ required for a generation instead of about 5 J" i (teneration instead of about 5 weeks. Nevertheless, there are 4 rmtiom A weeks. Nevertheless, there are 4 or 5 Ktterat heless, there are 4 or 5 mentions ofaM.. m -ni.f i«rv» mi THK UALWOUI in a year. " in a year. THK UALWOUlt IHK ME AM WORMS The mealworms to be found in Nebraska are t i(irm&lt; to be found in Nebraska are two species of lor \ slender, cylindrical worms, about an inch long whet rical worms, about an inch long when fully grown, tr occur frequently in stored grain but more especially occur frequently in stored grail y in stored grain but more especially in meal. bran, a o'her grain products. They arc the larva&gt; o'her grain pnxlucts. They ar o'her grair - •! i ! '. t-i4Ci« blackish iHftles. about Iive-eigr i££t blackish beetles, about five-eight lis of an inch loi '■ 1-ilsCi* blackish beetles, about flrr rigl * i ' , „ that have the thorax hromiUi ' • . - &lt; \ domen. In one si»i /r&amp;\" Tcrtrbrio ittoli'ttr-. the worm \JtiW /i Sjf.r .'/'"""' color with darker joint: J^L L^ a nhii'inf) blackish; while in tl /jr\/' trS dark mealworm Ttnebrm &lt;&gt;l&gt;*&lt; V^^Fv ~tj brownish with dusky joints i f^ that have the thorax hmadhj joined to the i that have th H- ft, , -. \ domen. In one specif , ,. \ domen. In one species, the yellow meal wo Ttmhrin itmli'ttr-. the worm is of a shiny wcj 'i. J%y I/'""" ( olor with darker joints, and the beetle %fe, r a .ihirtiny blackish; while in the other speci.s. : Z J dark mealworm Fi y -i dark mealworm TiP'hriu oh*i urn* . the worm TTy brownish with dusky joints and the bt-i-tk ll* ih,ll black (to 1 . TTy brownish with dusky joints and the beetle is 'Br* dull black rig. 1 . SgSw K Y' i &lt;l»ll black tig. 1 . IK- 1 Fig. 4. The dmrk meal- The l&gt;eetles begin to appear in the spring and •ar in the spring ar worm ' T&gt; ii. d/i.i "*" r " r ''- " continue to put in an appearance in diminishing S mealworm, and .-. adult turti niie; )&gt;, pup». en- numbers all thru the summer. They are art llmT^ou'th' P»rts 'and at night, hiding in the daytime. The femak ol abdomen of mealworm. deposit their white eggs singly in clusters in the grain or meal. These eggs hatch n 2 or 3 weeks, Le Baron. 1874. and the resulting small whitish worms become fully grown and colored within the next 3 or 4 months. After becoming fully grown the mealworms remain unchanged until the following spring, when they begin to pupate. The pupal stage lasts 2 or 3 weeks. There is thus but a single generation of mealworms in a year </seg>
            <seg id="p007">[nsect I'k.sts of ; SrnitKi) (ii:\iN I THE ANGOUMOIS (iKAIN MOTH r corn in the crib, are frequently y Nebraska by small whitish caterpillars, about hen fully grown, with a yellowish head (fig. three of these caterpillars may com- of wheat, rye. or barley usually there is but aterpillar to the grain. These caterpillars burrow into the kernels 24 per cent in corn and of over 50 )m l:! tc &gt;er cent in wheat when so infested. In the adult stage this pest is a small, r huffy moth slightly lined and spotted with black. 1 narrow, pointed wings, bordered with a long delicate fringe, and ■t half inch in expanse of wings fig. 5, c\. It is urged about 1 '-.x; &gt;, t'KK. fa labial palpus of male moth ast intuit of'nupa much enlarged: .'", grain of mrr ■nlarged: .*", grain of mrr natural *iw. Frorr mbers in the grain fields and granaries of the province 1 736. As early as 172N, however, it had estab- \ outh Atlantic coast of the United States, and is now eater part of this country. ile Angoumois grain moths, emerging from the stored grain bins, and cribs in late May and June, not only lay their inute, ova!, white to reddish eggs singly or in clusters of 20 to 30 itored grain in the bin or crib, but, flying outside to the fields, ly eggs under the chaff of the kernels in the young green heads h&lt; )f standing small grains. Each female moth lays about 100 eggs. The eggs hatch in 4 to 10 days and the tiny caterpillars burrow into the grains thru almost invisible openings and feed on the starchy material within, hollowing out the soft interior of the grains (fig. 5, /). The caterpillars reach maturity in 20 to 24 days, pupate within the hollowed kernel, and in a few days produce the adult moths of the new generation thru a hole in the kernel. This second brood of moths occurs a little Angoumois grain moth iSUotroga cereale la) because it wu </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 XkBKVSKA Kxi'KRIMKXT STATION. ( 'l Itl I I.Alt 15 after harvest, and lays its eggs between the tof kernels of immature corn in the field « the small grains in the shock or stack, generations follow every 5 or 6 weeks on rain in the crib or bin until cold weather s, making in all about 4 generations in a A badly infested ear of corn is covered the small round exit holes of the moths 6). During the winter the caterpillars n inactive within the grain kernels, t when the grain is stored in warm ngs, when there are 5 or 6 generations in r. THE INDIAN-MEAL MOTH Cereals and cereal products of all kinds n Nebraska are at times injured by small caterpillars, about a half inch long when full rown, of a whitish color tinged with pinkish, rellowish, or greenish fig. 7, o , that spin silken tubes thru the food material and profusely web together the grains or food par- ir ticles with threads of silk. This pest is known aa the Indian-meal moth &gt;Plodia interpunc - tella), its adult stage being a moth with a wing expanse of nearly three-fourths of an inch, with the basal third of the front wings and all of the hind wings soiled light gray and the outer two-thirds of the front wings coppery brown fig. 7, e). When attacking grain the caterpillars show a special fondness for the germ. Not only cereals and cereal products are attacked, but seeds, dried roots and bark, dried fruits, nuts, etc. In 1918 at Lincoln it was even found 4 a- ruining a large Pig. 7. The Indian-meal moth supply of nut {Plodxa inttrpuncttlla): a, cater- - or .j,, u«U :«. pillar; b. pupa; c. adult n&gt;oth-*n- Cand y he ld "&gt; One Urged about 2' 2 x: d. head and of the chain tborax of caterpillar —much enlarged Fn;. 6. — Ear of pop con showing work of Angoumoi grain moth. (From Riley (From Ril*y and Howard, 1889.) Stores. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Iwit Pests ok Storkd (Jraixs 9 The Indian-meal moth lives entirely within doors, and the number annual generations varies from 4 to 6, according to the temperature of the building. The female moths lay their minute white eggs singly or in groups of 3 to 12 directly upon the food substance, until a total of about :)50 eggs have been laid. The eggs pillars become fully grown, pupate moths in about a month. hatch in about 4 days and the cater - and produce the next generation* of THE MEDITERRANEAN FLOl'R MOTH Rather closely related to the Indian-meal moth is the^Mediterranean our moth Epheslia kuehniella), which, while it will on occasion attack grain, bran, meal, and cereals after the manner of that species, is pre- and mostly found in Nebraska in the flour|mills eminently a flour pest It does much injury iy spinning thru the lour, causing it to bc- m py and matted, and by clog ging the milling ma - chinery. The cater - pillars of the Mediter - ranean flour moth greatly resemble those of the Indian - meal moth, but are a little longer and mon slender, of more uni form diameter, with F|( . 8 _ Thp Medit( , rran(&gt;an flour motn ,,;„,,,,„„ tll ,,_ longer and more cylin- ■.■•«■! .: &lt;i, raterpillar: ''.pupa: .and/, adult moth — enlarged 'vlin- '.•//»&gt;: n, raterpillar: ''.pupa; -. and /. adult moth *-nlanced 'x; '/, head and thorax of raterpillar: •■. abdominal joints of al less conical imme much enlarged. (From Riley and Howard, 1889.) abdominal legs, minute but distir ;ui aokish warty spots bearing short hairs on the body which warty spots in the Indian-meal worm are colored like the rest of the body and therefore hardly distinguishable fig. 8, a). The moth has a wing expanse of somewhat less than an inch and its front wings are pale leaden gray with more or less distinct cross-markings of blackish, while the hind wings are soiled whitish thus being larger and very differently colored from the preceding species (fig. 8, c and /&gt;. The eggs of this moth are laid in the flour or on the milling machinery in mills, or on the grains in granaries. They are tiny and white, hatch in about 3 davs, producing caterpillars that mature in about 6 weeks, mean - while spinning an immense amount of webbing. The moths of the next generation appear 8 to 12 days after the maturity of the caterpillars. The life cycle thus consumes about 9 weeks, and in well-heated mills there may be G or more generations in a year. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nkbraska Kxi'KiiniKNi Statiox, Cii!&lt; i i.\n IS THE MEAL SNOIT-MOTH The meal snout-moth {Pyralis farinoMa) is of about the same size as &gt;e Mediterranean flour moth, having a wing expanse of about an inch, &gt;ut is very differently colored from any other of the grain moths, its ront wings being centrally light reddish brown, bounded by two wavy curved white lines, at the base before and at the apex beyond which the color deepens to a chocolate hrown. The caterpillars are about an inch ong, whitish shading to orange yellow toward each end, with the head liny brownish red. They attack all kinds of grains and grain products. especially meal and bran, wherever places. Each caterpillar .constructs with particles of the food material. causing the infested meal or brar kernels of grain to adhere in ropy 8 weeks, and there are :{ or 4 gener these are in warm and slightly damp for itself a long tube of silk mixed which it develops to maturity, thus to become stringy or the infested nasses. The life cycle rt ations in a yew OTHER CATERPILLARS OCCASIONALLY INFESTING GRAIN In March, 1920. the Nebraska State E ■ceiv County some ears of red flint corn grown in 1919 that wert with small caterpillars which had holl sun- at the germ end, especially those kernels tnuan to injure corn only occasionally. Ii in Nebraska. The common webbing clothes moth 7 been suspected of possibly occasionally breed Indian-meal worm, and a number of the moth ■un injury to stored wheat at Seward was reported at about the sarr It is not, however, to be as yet regarded as a serious pest in Nebra: PREVENTIVE MEASURES Small grain left in the field in the stack until early fall, as is some - imes done, may become seriously infested with the Angoumois grain moth or the rice weevil. In order to avoid such field infestation, if there is great probability of injury, the grain should be thrashed from the hock, or, if stacked, then as soon after harvest as circumstances will permit. Granaries should be so constructed as to be as cool and dry as possible The caterpillars were identified as the larvae of a tineoid scientifically as CMmM xorghirllu, a southern insect pest me ol seed that had not before been found as far north a.-- Kfbfiilri a. i V a reared from stored corn and wheat. In latter September &lt; pillars were found heavily infesting stored dried «wi copiously webbing the dried grains together after the of 19-J1 its cater corn at Omaha ■ manner of th </seg>
            <seg id="p011">.1 )KST i x&gt; l'l STS "I Iw St&lt;&gt;RKI1 (illAlN- 11 y not become so damp as to induce heating, since use of "weevil" of all kinds. Frequent agitation grain will destroy many of the caterpillars of the nd other grain-infesting larvae. Granaries should be easily kept clean, without cracks in which accumulate and the pests breed continuously even when rently empty, and with tight-fitting doors and windows fumigation. grain left in bins or granaries will serve to quickly grain put in with it. Therefore, before new grain is iin should be thoroly fumigated with carbon bisulphide; old grain should be removed, the floors, walls, and ceil- thoroly cleaned, and the floors sprinkled with air-slacked )uld b? again removed before the grain is stored) or r gasoline (care being taken to keep away all fire iquid has evaporated and the vapors have dis- 'cessary, the whole granary fumigated with carbon dioxide fumes. Especially should all accumulations ind refuse grain or meal be removed and all corners lime, as th;»se serve as breeding places for stored grain pen crib shows serious infestation it cannot be suc - hat condition, but should promptly be shelled, stored granary, and there fumigated ROYING STORED GRAIN PESTS BY FUMIGATION satisfactory method of destroying stored grain pests or kinds is by careful fumigation. Various vapors have been arbon bisulphide, carbon tetrachloride, chlor - acid gas. sulphur dioxide, and others of less im- vapors, the most practical from the combined safety to the operator, efficiency, availability, and harm - germination and flour-making qualities of the grain, is ide bisulphide iCS ) is a heavy liquid, with a very disagreeable •aporates wry rapidly upon exposure to air, forming a vapor air that tends to p?n?trate downward in the grain, and kills suffocating them. To a great degree the successful destruc - i grain p.&gt;sts by a fumigation with this vapor depends upon ■ss of the preparation for the fumigation. It must be re - har the vapor of this chemical is very penetrative, and unless quite tight it will seep out and the effect of the fumigation be lost. It is necessary for the vapor to remain in the bin ngth for the proper length of time so that it may penetrate </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Exruxbxt Station. ('ircti.ar 15 ) K ii h to all parts of the interior of the bin without escaping from the bin. Al large holes and cracks should be pasted over with paper or pluggw tight with cotton batting or rags. Doors and windows should be mad tight by the same methods, but some arrangement should be made for th opening of a window or door from the outside when the fumigation completed. The top of open bins can be made sufficiently tight with canvas or blankets, since the vapor works downward. Everything shoul be made ready before the fumigation is begun, and after it is begun should be carried thru as rapidly as possible. The liquid carbon bisulphide should be evaporated from shallow pan at the top of the bin, or sprinkled over the grain, or both. It is desirabl to have the liquid evaporate as rapidly as possible, and over al! part of the infested grain, hence only shallow pans, with a large evaporatir surface, placed here and there over the grain and containing a or less of the liquid, should be used. In large bins, especia grain is not to be used for seed, it is also a good plan to lo&lt; the end of a gas pipe, thrust the pipe into the grain. 1 with a rod, pour a quantity of the chemical down int • rpipe, and then withdraw it and use at another spot. The amount of liquid carbon bisulphide to use deper amount of grain to be fumigated, on the tightness of thf temperature at the time of the fumigation. The warmer li rapidly the carbon bisulphide will evaporate, and the mo t»ke up before becoming saturated with it. Also the higr perature the more active are the insects, and becaus rapid breathing when active they succumb ■a&lt;l of the vapor. It is useless to attempt fumigation witr at a temperature under 60 F. At a temperature of 7(1 r tion is satisfactory. In empty or nearly empt\ only scattering pests, at 70 F. one pound of carbor gate 300 cubic feet of air space; at «0 F. it will fumigate 40' Pat 90°F. it will fumigate 500 cubic feet. At a *s, in filled tight bins, one pound should be use&lt;i grain. If the bins cannot be made thoroly tigh rl need to be doubled. Since it requires a certain amour kill any insects at all, the degree of the infestation is in determining the amount to use. but it is well to use ratr amounts when the pests are very abundant. In case the grain is not to be used for seed, the vapo kept confined in the grain for 48 hours. A good plan is to app liquid at midday on a Saturday and open up the bin the followin Monday noon. Grain intended for seed purposes should be fumigate^ for 36 hours. At the close of the proper period the bin should be opened and aired thoroly for several hours before being entered for any lengt of time. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">In I Aithou ■i ■ i I t hea H .1 f it it 1 xp I ii'i v a KIT PksTS u F St&lt;&gt;KKI&gt; (iliAIN PRECAUTION e the liquid carbon bisulphide is not explosive, and mmy be lar caution when in tightly sealed cans or drums. tired with air, highly inflammable and explosiee. The any form of fire, even the slightest spark, and at a any flame of above 297 °F., which is a lower ignition of gasoline vapor. It is therefore, absolutely necessary any kind be brought near to a bin in process of fumigation. where the odor of the vapor is noticeable. Smoking •qually dangerous, and there is a real risk in the buttons, driving of nails, or hot steam pipes. All thing that might ignite the vapor, should be tion that is necessary in connection with fumigation ide is to avoid inhaling the vapor in any considerable nged period, without breathing some fresh air. If, his chemical, there is felt any dizziness or nausea, the sought at once, when the ill effects will usually pass minutes. Also, since the vapor has an accelerating •t action, persons having any heart trouble or weakness ny extended part in fumigating operations with carbon ide may be purchased in exactly the desired amount, tound cans to 50-pound, 100-pound or 500-pound drums, d will vary according to the amount purchased. If a ■quired, the carbon bisulphide can be obtained most am jobbing firms handling it in drums. The drums ble at the price charged, if in good condition, and the iited with the return freight. The cost of enough completely destroy the pests in 1,000 bushels of grain than $10, or at the rate of a cent a bushel, and erably less. bisulphide, carbon telrachlorid is not inflammable :le in the presence of fire, hence it can be used under lere carbon bisulphide could not be used. It is, nsive than carbon bisulphide and is not so efficient ■quire twice the amount of carbon tetrachlorid to . as compared with carbon bisulphide. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nkbkaska K.M'kiiimkm Station, Cikiii.ak lii DESTROYING STORED GRAIN I'ESTS BY HEAT t Before the use of carbon bisulphide as a fumigant to destroy n pests became general, the subjecting of these pests to gre; the principal method of destroying them. The adult moths h. kly die at a temperature of 116 C F grain-infesting caterpillars will qui while their caterpillars and pupae beetles and flour beetles perish at cadelle, one of the most resistive 11 die at about 118 F. T will die at about 118 t. 1 he gra mperatures of llf* or I'H) r T t. dies at a temperature of 122.5 F A temperature of 120 F. continued f 3 minutes, or even 115 K. continu ?d for 12 hours, is fatal to a grain pests. Inasmuch as wheat »n be subjected to a temperat high as 150 F., for a short tim without destroying its germinat power, the practicabil where faciliti ■at ing the proper amount of hea u i a at hand in the farm grana above described must be n the farm. h( at of all the stored gra However, in only occasional instan </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>