<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  DOES IT PAY TO SPRAY NEBRASKA APPLE ORCHARDS?</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLET I N AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION NEBRASKA. n XX, Article VII. DOES IT PAY TO SPRAY NEBRASKA APPLE ORCHARDS? A. EMERSON" and F. E. DENNY. DiSTRiBiTEn May 2, 1!hi-&lt; I'm Uiuvebsity &lt;&gt;k Nebraska. &lt;&gt;K THE &lt;&gt;K </seg>
            <seg id="p002">\»rth Plat A U Hakckek. B.S&lt; A. / Lawrence Bruxek. BJc., KnUi E. G. MoNTXiOMKKV. 1 ( Frank J. Phiimi's. M.F . Pi Erwin H. Bakihu'k. Ph.D., ( G. R. Chatbikn. A.M.. Hitihitaii h R. A. Emebson. B.Si .. BortU ultur O. V. P. Stoit. C.E.. Irrigat G. A. Lovelanh. B.S( . I'- Almn Kkyskk. A.M.. HoiU PSnyukk. M.S., SuiH'ntiteiitli-nt i tal 8ttfttta 3ai.n, M.D.C.. Ass'k iatf in Animal Pathology Maodanz. Jr., A.B., Asuistatit in Animal Husban Sturoeyant, A.M.. Assistant in Annual Pathnlmjy Stella A. Habtzeu., A.M.. Assistant in Chemistry E. M. Little. B.Sc, Assistant in Hairy Husbandry Martin Nelson. M.S.. Assistant ta fieM Cl F E Denny, A.B., Assistant ii 'lure S W. Pebix. Farm Superintr NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THI RCGIHTI O' TMr UNIWCflSITV (HAS S ALI.KN. / Lincoln \VM O. WHITMORE, Valley FREDERICK H. ABBOTT. Aurora VICTOR G. LYFORI), Falls C ('HAS. B. ANDERSON I HE COIPLAND. B«ia THE STATION OFFICERS IUKNETT. B DALES. M I'll . F \VM W. MARSHAL! THE WORKING STAFF H. R. Smith. 1; B A. T. Petebs. D.V..M Fhmouck D. Hui.ii. l'n.1). /:■ F J Alway. Ph.D., Ch&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p003">DOES IT PAY TO SPRAY NEBRASKA APPLE ORCHARDS? BY R. A. EMEBSON AND F. B. DENNY. the Spraying Demonstrations. — It has been for some time that thoro spraying will prevent or at least lessen injury from apple scab and codling-moth. It is nerally conceded by all who have tried it that by the appli - tion of proper spray materials we can secure a crop of apples rger in size and better in quality. But the question which the uit grower would like to have answered is, Does it pay to do l&gt;o the increase in yield and the improvement in quality of pay for the trouble and expense of spraying? for the purpose of answering this question, as well as give practical demonstrations of the efficiency of spraying in ltrolling apple pests, that the spraying work was begun in ind continued in 1907. It was felt that the proper way to It r.Tinine the question was to spray in various orchards in many tof the state during a series of years; that is, to spray in r when the crop was large and in one when it was small, in i year when the price of apples was high and in one when the arice was low, in orchards well equipped for spraying and in &gt;rchards with poor facilities for spraying. Thus at the end &gt;f a series of years it would be possible to say definitely whether, under the existing conditions, it pays to spray. The results of the work in the year 1906 were reported in Bulletin 98 of this Experiment Station. The present bulletin gives the results in the year 19(17. The conditions in 1906 were far different from those existing in 1907. In the former year apples were plentiful and low in price, while in the past year they were scarce and high priced. In both cases, however, spray - ing gave profitable results in every orchard where it was tried. IT 1 I If t vt'R pvp QT ATT O\ OK PRR VOL XX ART VII </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Duvn It Pay to Spray Nebraska I/'/'' &lt;»&lt;hu Thk Pashm to tbi OoorcaATioa in 1907. — Tin- ipm carried on the past year in two orchards, both in ton county. One of the orchards was located at Blaii w demonstration work, and of these nine. - three were not sprayed. The varii i SI trees i and Kails Genet i l'i orchard seven rows we ii ;i block of twentv trees wa with the si&gt;r;iyed trees. The var •As originally planned, the wor cooperation with the Bureau of Plant Ii ment of Agriculture, and under this plar ■a seven orchards, including the two in Washington eountv. mentior above, and one each in Richardson. Pawnee. Nemaha. Johnson, a counties. Owing to the almost complete destruction of the a the five orchards last named, the Departmont of Agriculture withdre from the work, and the ExperiniPi alone, in the Washington county nnhar.N owned 1&gt;.\ .Messrs. McConnick and Koopman; tl til. h. m Ideated at Arlington, and was owned by M The ownen of the orchards, besides furnishing deionatratk&gt;B and the appliances for spraying, • f the materials for spraying and the t&lt;&gt; apply ilie material to the trees. The Depai culture itf tlie Experiment furnished a li spraying to direci the mixi - and the application o( the sprai -in-li in '\riiei s the arork for the - and wpr V. Weatgate and J. L. stahl.* - of spraying. I'd.- The amount and n spraying. 3d. — The time and and applying the spray, tth. The vield and \ from the sprayed and anapra; The Plats of Btcaybs and (TNSPKi orchard nine rov - the orchard w. &lt; w </seg>
            <seg id="p005">V In each v 1 double \ t'd trees were similar in size, fruit fulness. that a perfectly fair comparison could The dates of spraying th- May lM to Ttli Mav :27th to With June Wh ..Inly Mth :in.l 27tk \mnwt Ltdl and 20th :&lt;•. that these are the &lt; i nd. of cour i actually app red that These ied in the work t would lw the proper d Exact dates on which to ■pray that year can not be given. For ■ ivinir, the reader is referred to the recommen- . ■ U.S DO Al'l'I.IANcKS I"sKI&gt;. Til' • spraying work the |iast year were: U Rordeanx mixture and 1'aris green: 4th and iisenate of lead. The Bordeaux mixture 30 formula; that is. three pounds of iimls of lime, and fifty gallons of water, l'aris to the P.ordeaux at the rate of one-third of a for the tirst two sprayings, and at the rite of and per barrel for the third spraying. Arsenate at the rate of two pounds per barrel of water, was used in the last two sprayings because it foliage and fruit better than Paris green and is injure the foliage. hard ■ barrel sprayer was used to apply the spray, unqis were provided with long how. extension rods, ermorel no/./ </seg>
            <seg id="p006">t 0 Uoet It Pay to Xpruy Xtbraaka Apple Orchards* THE COST OP SPRAYING. Ee figures given below show the cost of spraying in each or 1. The prices of materials quoted are those actually paic le ownere of the orchards, and the price for labor is figure the prevailing price of farm labor in that locality. Blair Orchard.- — Mount Hope Fruit Farm, owned by Messrs M« Corinick and Koopman. Trees twenty-seven years old. Aver - age number trees sprayed, 78. Sprayed five times, using L,72C gallons of spray mixture. Used horse and wagon, two to thret men. Oeming barrel pump, one to two leads of hose, exteusioi rod, and double Verniorel nosi Bluestone. 71^ lbs. at ll&lt; Lime, 114^ lbs. at i. 17.fi Paris green. 6$ ll&gt; nate of lead, -•'• lbs. at r_' Cost of material E;n, 14£ hours at 15c ?n. 26 hours at 15c ree. 4&lt;H hours at ~U Cost of applying Total cost Total quantity of spray per tree. 22.4 gallons Cost of material per gallon o.s, Cost of applying per gallon 1.0c; per 4 Total cost per gallon . . per tr&lt;H\ U i Arlington Orchard. — Owned by Marshall Bros. Trees fifteei rs old. Average number Rprayed. 88. Sprayed four times ng 1,450 gallons of spray mixture. Used team and three men tflt consisted of a Morrill &amp; Morlev barrel pump, two leadi hose, extension rods, and double Vermorel noz/ </seg>
            <seg id="p007">i PI Tot nr nd sr i rher ■light r sp iuced 1 r raved ai he fruit so Blair Of raded int Spray Xebraska Apple Orchards t T lie 18.42 .80 at 35c 2.97 it 121c 88 ♦13.07 itenal it 15 $io.4&lt;; us at 15c 75 l"&gt;c applying 15.67 |28 1 t t ty of spray per tree. 15 gallons rial f&gt;er gallon, ying per gallon 0.7c; per tree, l L5e 1.2c; per tree, 17Jc wt per gallon 1.9c; per tree, 28.8c lying five times cost in one orchard 40.3 cents per craving four times in the other orchard cost if. The cost of spraying as here shown is somewhat are two reasons for this. First, all the materials it retail prices, and second, in one orchard the facili- aying were not the best. The cost of spraying may by buying the materials in large lots at wholesale by providing better facilities for spraying, such as itfornis. more convenient water supply, and power iVith trees 15 to 20 years old it is possible to reilim - spraying to twenty or twenty-five cents per tree for THE RKRl"LT OF SPRAYING. wing statements show the yields obtained from the 1 from the unsju-ayed trees, and the amount of money Id for in each case: hard. — All fruit that was picked from the trees was ••first:" and "seconds." The first grade was made </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Does It Pay to Sprcy Nebruika Apple Onltu 8 ippearance, includi t resulted in deca\ \\&lt;i&lt;- wormy where this had n grade included all picked fruit not classed as firs 1 the seconds grading, hauling to town, load nto cars at teu cents per bushel. T per bushel foi 1 The windfalls wen culls. The actua termined HI |mi- cent ■ lit I'll ushel w windfalls w •rayed fru - Windfall Total 21 —prayed trees 8.5 lm. *'.i 0.4 *' Seconds ti.."i III! Windfalls 18.0 ba. 2.88 0.8 bu Total "|&gt; Hi fruiis of fair size ami ■old few $1.25 per bxmhel, an i I, not including comt &lt;&gt;( pai the trees) was, thereto M s|il-;|\i,i ti Firsts 171.5 bo. I] 33.(1 hu. |14. Hi I.r, bo. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">\ Han packing- a barrel. T estimated i •J h'aUn Genet ral Total Yield Val value. per tree, per tree. 79.7 bu. bu. $5.31 bu. bu. hll bu. 20.5 bu. tinman/ s 101 .6fi bu. •J-J.tC) I.S bu. 71 1.7 spraying $l.~n So. 1 grade included only fruit tliat was of •ance and free from blemish of any kind. The included undersized and underrolored fruit that d some larger Of more highly colored fruit thai was ■ee from codling-moth or other injury. The mils fruit that was decaying or from other causes tin uit was sold for f4.50 per barrel, and No. 2 fruit for barrel, f. o. b. Arlington. The culls were not sold. st 50 ceota eaeh at the orchard. Picking, grading, md hauling to town was estimated at 3D cents per he net value of the fruit lvalue on the trees I was therefore at $:?.70 per barrel, or BUI per bushel, for 13.5 bu. &lt;•:: t.&lt;&gt; l&gt;u. $4.55 :',o.7 bu. ::.2 bu. 0.75 hn. .13 0.1 hii. 0.1)1 *4.n:; 0.4 bo. 90.46 :;.74 1&gt; bu. .42 A-J ii.I !&gt;u. .01 All fruit wns ended into No. 1. N </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Ill r No. 1 fruit, and |2.7(i per barrel, or l JU cents 2 fruit. us h lhn ha Total Total V i 20 sprayed tree alue. per r* No. 1 fruit :&gt;,:&gt; tm. $43.05 1.75 bi s No. 2 fruit :i.v2." bu. 34.43 1.9 bi Culls 7.11 tm. 0.3 bi Total 80.25 bu. f 77.48 4.0 In 10 uusprayed trees No. 1 fruit. .. 0.75 bu. 93 0.1 No. 2 fruit . .10.25 bu. :t.i"&gt; i Galll - bu. Cull sun bu. h Total Lt.66 I. u. $ld.l6 Total .19.00 bu. 110.10 1.8 ■tmary. .'it sprayed trees iivt'd \\- - m. )v in UMprayed tr» n L9.0Q unaprayed trei n L9.00 bu 10.16 Diferai Differ.n, of spraying per i iv»- si iif ipraying per t rt-»- &lt;!aiu per tree due to spray in lin per tree due to spmyiii- Errmct or Si&gt;kayi\&lt;; seen from the above itatementa 1 1 • creased the yield of fruit upon the tm yield per tree was •'!.." bushels upon tht bushels upon the unspraved trei the former ,18 upon the latter. In the otl yield of 4 bushels per tree upon tt bushels upon the unsprayed trees. Thus had not given a belter quality of fruit, tht alone would have been more than enough t&lt;&gt; -rive a profit fi ■praying. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 IV 1 I va v kuit.— But spray the yield of fruit, it produced fruit of i in one orchard the No. 1 fruit constituted entire crop on the sprayed trees, and only entire crop on the unsprayed trees. In the tereeatage of first grade fruit was 61.8 on the 22.4 on the unsprayed trees. The culls from nted only 8.7 per cent of the entire crop unsprayed trees 42 per cent of the crop was un Pay to Si-kay? — Knowing as we do the cost of spraying, unount of money that was obtained from the sprayed ayed trees, we can determine definitely whether or not spray. In one orchard spraying gave a net gain per the cost of spraying of fl.70. That is, spraying not for itself, but yielded an extra profit of more than $♦&gt;"&gt; besides. In the other orchard the gain per tree due to was *_'..".•;. Stated in another way, this means that the produced on the average over $100 per acre more by yi-il than if it had not been sprayed, and this, too, ivo deducted the cost of spraying. be observed that only two varieties of apple, Ben Davis i Genet, were included in the records given above. With he results might have been somewhat less favor iet. owing to its habit of late blossoming, usually ion like that of 19(17 than many other va \s a matter of fact this variety constituted a small per - if the trees from which the records were made, there ■en only 20 Rails Genet out of a total of 131 trees. All ivere Hen Davis, the most commonly jirown commercial winter apple in Nebraska. F.ven with such desirable s these the fruit of the unsprayed trees was of eom- y little value. Furthermore it was very unsatisfactory handle. In this connection it is worth while to note the </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 It I'nii to 8p &gt;raska \ 1,1,1. siMtcin.iii ol Mr. &lt;;. A. Marshall of Marshal of the orchard! where the spraying work was done. In d the results of the Experiment Station's L90 1 ! sp fore the recent meeting of the Nebi . Mr. Marshall %s "We learned boh i tiling along tli not been told you i apples. Von ran sort three Im trees to one bushel from the others &gt;f three &lt;&gt;v fruit. When th n w irairini .1, 4th. — Ten weeks after the Jill v I 5th.— Three weeks later nun gust). Brom manuscript of the Annual Report of the Mai tural Society for 1908. sprayed Bpravi Ke growii Kid be uivtn about ;is follow .u» i- the cluster buds :.l. hist after the peti id. — Three weeks In the lii'si three ■prayings, Bordeaux inixtur on, preferably araenate of lead, should be used. Ai </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 the rate of from 14 pounds to '2 pounds &gt;f spray. If Paris green is to be used. irrel is recommended. The advantage* -l r Paris green arc that it adheres to tlit tlci-. th; t it will not injure tin f.. nd that t i ins in suspension in ■!ms making possible a re even di- slid above, it ve, it ,s naive tliau I'aris grecm. Paris reen I formula (3 pound formula (3 pooadi i Dd "II gallons of wafer i is bett ■omewhai stronger mixtnr water i is l&gt;elii me what - mixture his fore. Tlie weaker mil ive. i&gt; re. The weaker mil ive. is 'ly to injure the fruit or folia-. kfl.v to injure the fruit or foliage. At ren weaker arixtare may sometii l&lt; anx. slark th. iker mixture may sometimes n we dilute each with half the required water, h with half the required water &gt;!kt thoroly. 'inly to prevent apple seal,. The horo iil.v to prevent apple seal,. The - therefore the most important part &lt;■ i therefore the most important part of the ied in a liue misi. i. ,&gt;.. pumped at H should be applied in a line misi. i. e.. ponped &gt;1 ru a tine nozzle, and should be used in sin thoroly the hrifB, ezpaading leaves, ami yoaag well to lake advaniaire of the . } rer the trunk and - with spray. The poison is added to the Bordeaux nozzle, and should be used in suln the twipi. expanding leaves, anil voting ike advantage of the almost well to i the trunk and . The poison is added to the Bot other insect! that may aj ily in curculio and any other insects that nay appear early in inf. In caw no tach insects are troublesome the ; left out at this lirsr sprayin&lt;r. but since the exti rery sim:iII it is usually advisable to apply poison Bordeaux olid application is of the utmost importance. It is usu considered the most important spraying for the codling i&lt;&gt; sueh insects are troublesome the : lis tirst spniyin&lt;r. »&gt;ut since the extra n is ■anally adriaaMe to apply jujison with l'.ordeaux tioa is of the utmost importance. It is usu most important spraying; for the codlini; h. and in this reirion is nrobahlv as innmrt-int ..° .,„,- »., region is probably as important as any spr;iv </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 O i and various leaf dkMMH. The spraying mixture must contain arsenate of lead, or kmm other insect icide. and mixture. The aim of this spraying, as far as th&gt; is concerned, is to fill the open calyx c-njis of the sm with the poison spray, there ti IoIk'8 so that the larva of th custom of catering tlie liitle and be killed before doing a] calyx cups of most rar» than a week after the petals held l.v th • codling-moth, following Apple at the calyx end. m preciable injury to the fi apple remain open fall. If this spraying th upward and outward. To Ik ■ure of srettinc calyx cups it is therefore best to dir downward in so far as is practicable. Wh drip from the tree, it is practically ini ••ups of the little apples with the poison spra l&gt;er tree at this application than at any oth In using Bordeaux mixture for apple i spraying, it is important to remember th V apples are susceptible to injury from the Bordeaux The injury usually takes the form of a russet appears] is much less noticeable at maturity, in all but yellow apples, than at any time before. It sometimes cans pies to become out of shape and even in severe cast opea. In no case with which the writers are fainili lM'st to Rtop spraying before or ;is snon as the drenching the tree. It is therefore nec&lt; in accomplish what ii is intended to. ii must !*• given after the flowers fall, [adeed since the first Hm and therefore the first t&lt;&gt; fall and the first to clow tli lulus, are, barring accident, the onea thai produce the &lt; often imperative, particularly in the case of larjre ore l&gt;efrin this second sprayinp before the petal* from all opening tluwers have fallen. At the time of this applic little a]»j»les are tisuallv erect in position with Tl, </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Spray Xehraxka Apple Orchards? 15 f ts from the Bordeaux by any means equalled scab and codling-moth commonly do to un- No one should hesitate therefore to spray from fruit. But since strong Bordeaux is probably n weaker Bordeaux and since the hea\ at this time for the control of the codling - &gt;e more injurious than a lighter one, it is best rpiililc varieties, as weak a Itonleaux as ontrol scab. Just how weak a mixture will IIll &gt; in check cannot be said, but some tests made by the ndicate that two pounds of blnestone to the barrel of ivill hold scab in check fairly well. In case of such va is Ben I&gt;avis. Jonathan. Roman Stem, and Grinn - lerefore probably best to use only two pounds of Ma irrel at this second spraying. liird spraying is given about the time the eggs of dn tli are beginning to hatch, usually about three weeks ic towers fall. By coating the foliage and fruits with it this time, the worms can be killed even tho they do &gt;i pt to enter the apples at the calyx end where poison iid spraying is awaiting them. Indeed many of vae. it is thought, will be killed on the leaves without ting to enter the fruits. Owing to its adhesive qualities te of lead is best used at this time. This spraying comes e as a rule to have any appreciable effect on scab on the i tins region, but Bordeaux should be included in the spray precaution against injury from various leaf diseases M.I otherwise practically defoliate the trees early in fall and the fruit to ripen and fall prematurely. Spraying for the second brood of the codling-moth is not very :. iKially practiced in this state, but at least one late spraying is nal in case of winter apples if sound fruit is to be pro - iuced. In about 50 days after the eggs of the first brood begin i&gt; hatch, the larvae of the second brood are coming on. The ourth spraying should therefore be given about seven weeks </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Ippli Ore) tli &gt;er w A mply n H-k lii )f the stock si tubs with w Does It Pay to f&lt;pray Xebraska after the third or about ten weeks after is generally late in July. The spray mate ib geueranv larc in -luiy. rue spray niateria always be arsenate of lead. 1'aris green i foliage at this season and does not adl effective against larvae, which ; i weeks. There is little lined at this time and it may therefor Ewepaie a barrel of Bordeaux, then, the stock solutions, pat five gallons ne tub. or barrel, and Three gallons stone in another Tub. till up the tw&lt; of spraying. A tifih spraying is noi always i I, and fourth ■praying! have been orchard baa been gpi ud where codling i " '" ' ' " &gt; ""i mi: i often lie omitted without njurv codling-moth larvae are coming on in nl - tilth spraying about thi where near the mi spraying, like the fonrth. slum),] i&gt; alone. In making Bordeau: one prepared beforehand barrel of line (200 pounds) can !&gt;• box. It will keep indefinitely if L The Milestone can also In- kept in ttocl the bottom of a ban-el of water to diss • l « i • i • * stirring and even then will dissol in a coarse sack (burlap is good) and i surface of the water, it will dissolve in inon to make op the stock solution of 1 the rate of one pound of lime or blaeston </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 i 1 With tl lie fl \ most pai it form. Th iously made, and finally pour the two dilute thru a strainer into the spray barrel. rchards it will pay to have an elevated plat pply tank for water, and a second platform wer to hold two small tanks for the stock n tanks, each with a capacity (if at lilute the line and hluestone stock shut-off valves should lead from thi ■pray tank. tent the P.ordeaux can be made and the few minutes, whereas, with the ineon rrnneeinent, found in main required for mixing the spray pump is used, and :\ : nic work in a large orchard, I have a "helper wagon" to haul the will transfer the spray mix r r" to the spray tank in a few minutes, tlm prayer and the crew of three or four men ijrth of time. Such an arrangement is of e where the orchard is at a considerable dis water supply platform above the spray tank from which x' directed. Where two leads of hose are work on the ground and the other on the plat ee leads, two men usually spray from the ground, lie platform. In the second spraying, how •rtant that the spray be directed downward for t is well to station two of the three men on the men on the ground should have lout; ho* itfonn 1&lt;&gt; the spray jminp in xtcnsion rods eight or ten fret lon&lt;: work is to !*■ done. It will be nm- lcr to reach the tops of tali tra </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Does It Pay to Spray Nebraska Apple Orchards f t h it r •i r 5 feet is none too long. This insures a freedom of nmvei in directing the spray not attainable with short hose. Att ing the nozzle to the extension rod at an angle is al help in properly directing the spray. The spray should be discharged from the nozzles under pressure to insure a miit-like spray, for with such a spray easier to cover all parts of the tree thoroly without over-sj inv r an\ part than is the case with a coarse spray. The pr should also be as nearly constant as possible to insure an distribution of the spray. A pressure of 100 to 150 pour the square inch is desirable, and can be maintained wit! rtion with a gasoline power spray pump. With hand is not possible, bat care should be exercised to kt pressure as high and as constant as possible at all tin with the best hand pomps can sufficient pressure be it by one man to run two leads of hose, and even thf should change frequently. With three men in tfr with two leads of hose, each man should pui spray material and then hold a nozzle wh barrels are being pumped. With a gasoline p crew of three men, with a &lt;|uiet team, can run th hose and spray almost twice as fast as the san hand pump and two leads of hose and can do the w Where, as is sometimes the ease, one man drive other pumps, and a third holds one nozzle, the work little more than a quarter as fast as it would w number of men with a power sprayer, and the cost is correspondingly greater. But of course gasoline pow sprayers, on account of their cost, are out (if the qu&lt; small orchards except where several farmers will band to; to get the sprayer, or where one man will make a businee spraying orchards just as is done in case of threshing gra shelling corn. In an orchard of twenty acres containing proxiniately 1,000 apple trees, a power sprayer should pay itself in two or three seasons by reducing the expense for labor </seg>
            <seg id="p019">■ i i i i y 4 per i oi me Kin mw jr«&gt;o«l gasoline power sprayer will ta nided for preparing the spray mixture and f&lt; orchard. I MM AH rations were conducted in two orchards fa Nebraska, in 1!&gt;H7. The win of thi ii demonstrate the props' methods of spraying a|i determine whether, under the conditions existing ii sprav. i I'agt &gt;rchanl two plats of trees were set aside for tht plat was sprayed and the other was left unsprax.d &gt;n. Care was taken to have these plats as nearh that a fair comparison could be made rage l of the orchard furnished the trees for the demon aid the entire expense of spraying. The Bxperi furnished a representative to t&gt;e present at each 1 direct the mixing and application of the sprav and rds on the work as it progressed, i l'age l.&lt; ■ used were Hordeaux mixture and Paris green ■it sprayings, and arsenate of lead alone in the 'age •st of spraying and of the he sprayed and anspr ;ept of the entin ie of the fruit from i in. i induced a net gain per in the other orchard. It increased the yield of rchard and liv ■' 1 Imsliels ushels per tree in one ie other orchard. The improvement in the SJOalitT of o very noticealile. In one orchard the sprayed trees • cent of No. I fruit while the unsprayed trees gave ent of No. 1 fruit. In the other orchard 01. S per rop on the sprayed trees was first grade fruit while of apple orchard if the proper c«i l-i'c of * l.Tll in one oivh.-ml </seg>
            <seg id="p020">w Ehe cost of aprajiag araa tree for foar aprayiaga, iar&lt;l for five •praying* fouud in &lt;m.' orchard to I and 40.:: centa per tree • Pages ii 7. i BoggeatkHM are gives in applyiag apra; auxtorea, vcniciicc in this work are [ Poor or Ive ifvayiaga are recon n,l,,l. [ n the ii mil nti-ol apple scab, the tii II w «uh -4 per «e»t of the crap «. the wmpnjed m grade. (Pages 10-11.) regard to methods oi pn iimI Viii-ious :iii-aiiji,Mii&lt;-ii &gt;iiitt'«l out. i I'aavm u; is of these Bordeaux mixtni l&lt;ad are recommended to &lt; tdling-umtli, ii nd \;n &lt; &gt;! Bpraviaga with araenate &lt;&gt;f l*ad aloi </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>