<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00062.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00062.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Better Sires, Better Stock Build Better Breeding</title>
               <date value="1924-10">1924-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Better Sires — Better Stock Build Better by Breeding BY H. P. DAVIS DEPARTMENT OF DAIRY HUSBANDRY Improvement in livestock depends upon three principles: breeding, selection, and proper feeding and care. Each is important, but breeding is essential to any permanent im - provement. Constructive betterment thru breeding is ob - tained primarily because of the operation of the laws of hered - ity, which, simply stated, are that — "Like tends to produce like." Applied to milk production it means that the high-pro - ducing dairy cow tends to produce a daughter who is a large milk producer, and that the bull whose sire's daughters were heavy milkers and whose dam gave a large flow, will likely transmit this quality to his own daughters. The further back the ancestors have been heavy producers, the more likely will the animal possess that quality. Consequently, the pedi - gree of a dairy cow or dairy bull that for 3 or 4 generations shows every ancestor to have been a proved large producer, gives good evidence that such an animal possesses the inherit - ance for large milk and butterfat production. It is manifestly impossible and impracticable to increase the milk and butterfat production of a large area, such as the state of Nebraska, by disposing of all the low-producing dairy cows and by replacing them with higher producing ones pur - chased either within or without the state. Some good dairy cows can be added by purchase but their number as compared with the total will be small. In purchasing cows on any large scale there is also some danger of buying diseased animals, even tho the buyer and the state veterinary officials exercise the greatest care. Economy and logic indicate that the most satisfactory method of obtaining higher-yielding dairy cattle is to breed them. Nebraska raises the feeds — corn, oats and alfalfa — that will grow dairy cattle and can raise them as cheaply as any region. The method is simple. Use purebred dairy sires on the present cows. By the use of good purebred dairy sires great improvement can be obtained in a single generation. The heifers sired by a purebred dairy bull out of scrub or common cows will possess 50 per cent or one half of the char- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 24 4 acteristics of the sire. Such females are almost certain to be better than their dams. If these "half bloods" are bred to a purebred bull of the same breed, their heifers will be "three - quarter bloods" or will possess 75 per cent or three-fourths of the blood of a dairy breed. "Three-quarter blood" cows bred to a purebred sire of the same breed produce "seven - eighth bloods" or in other words they possess 87 1/2 per cent or seven-eighths of the inheritance of the dairy breed to which the sire belongs. This plan can be continued, the next gener - ation being 15 16, the following one 31, 32, the next one 63 64. Following such a plan it is feasible to increase rapidly the pro - duction of the herd by grading up thru the use of good bulls. Many have followed this plan successfully. Why should good purebred sires of a dairy breed be used for herd improvement instead of a "grade" bull out of one of the "best cows" in the herd? Too frequently the latter kind of sire is used, and at the end of a decade almost certainly the offspring produce less than their mothers and grandmothers. This is because the ancestors of the bull have not been selected for their milk qualities for any considerable period. They are mixed and carry all sorts of characteristics many of which are undesirable. The ancestors of a good purebred dairy sire, on the other hand, have been selected for hundreds of years for one quality — milk and butterfat production — and con - sequently those characteristics have become intensified or well-fixed and following the laws of heredity will tend to be transmitted to his offspring. No one can tell with certainty just what the daughters of a particular sire will produce until after they have been milked. But it can be stated with certainty that the daughters of com - mon or scrub cows sired by a good purebred dairy bull will be better producers than their dams. As nearly as can be esti - mated, the average production of the Nebraska dairy cow is under 2600 lbs. of milk per year. Assuming that to be the figure, if the milk tested 4 per cent butterfat, the average butterfat yield per year would be 104 lbs. Even at low feed prices such cows at best yield only a small return each year. If the average cow's yield is 104 lbs. of butterfat, approxi - mately one-half of the dairy cows in the state are well below the production that will yield a profit. A good example of improvement obtained thru the use of good purebred dairy sires is seen in the Holstein-Friesian herds of the University of Nebraska at the North Platte Sub - station, North Platte, and in the herd of the Dairy Husbandry </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Better Sires — Better Stock 5 Department at Lincoln. The latter is the older and was es - tablished more than two decades ago. In 1923 the average of all the Holsteins in the latter herd for that calendar year was 15,626 lbs. of milk containing 565 lbs. of butterfat. The improvement in that herd has been brought about almost en - tirely thru breeding to good sires and the selection of the good animals. These herds are rather notable in that during the entire period of their development the sires used have repre - sented a consistent effort to follow the principles of line breed - ing. PRINCE ORMSBY MERCEDES DEKOL Prince Ormsby Mercedes DeKol 47003 was the first sire used at Lincoln. He was the son of Sir Ormsby Hengerveld DeKol 31212 out of Daisy Mercedes Pietertje 2d 53643 a daughter of DeKol 2d's Paul DeKol No. 2 23366. He left only Fig. 1.— Prince Ormsby Mercedes DeKol 3 daughters in the herd that completed official yearly records but these daughters should be enough to establish the fame of any sire. See Table 1 A. Of course the largest producer was La Verna Lincoln 227365 whose yearly production of 29,555.5 lbs. of milk containing 1048.46 lbs. of butterfat or 1310.60 lbs. of </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 24 80 per cent butter still stands as the highest butterfat record of the state. She was out of the best cow in the herd at that time but despite the high production of LaMay 122176, 26.660 lbs. of milk, 773 lbs. of butterfat, Prince Ormsby Mer - cedes DeKol was able to increase the production of his daugh - ter LaVerna Lincoln 2895.2 lbs. of milk containing 274.97 lbs. of butterfat. The other daughters, Allie Lincoln and Kittie Gerben Lincoln, produced respectively 336.25 lbs. and 67.94 lbs. more butterfat than their dams. The average of the 3 daughters was 3114.4 lbs. of milk, 226.39 lbs. of butterfat, more than their dams. This is an increase of nearly 16 per cent in milk and approximately 35 per cent in butterfat over exceptionally good cows. A bull that could bring about such an increase if used on Nebraska cows would produce daugh - ters that would increase the annual receipts from dairy pro - ducts by 30 million dollars. What is a bull worth? It de - pends on his daughters. The pity is that Prince Ormsby Mercedes DeKol did not leave 200 instead of 3 daughters. •m.m mm m" « KING SEGIS HENGERVELD VALE King Segis Hengerveld Vale 60344 was the next bull used on the dairy herd at Lincoln. He represented the combination Fio. 2. — Kinlt Segis HenKerveld Vale </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Better Sires — Better Stock 7 of the King Segis and Hengerveld DeKol breeding, being a son of the former out of a daughter of the latter. Altogether he left 10 yearly record daughters of which 7 were in the Uni - versity of Nebraska herd and consequently had dams with records. See Table 2 A. The average production of these daughters was 17,734 lbs. of milk containing 605 lbs. of butter - fat or 756 lbs. of butter. Of these, 3 made their records at 2 or 3 years and might have been expected to increase materially their production. The dams produced an average of 15.482 lbs. of milk containing 533 lbs. of butterfat or 666 lbs. of 80 per cent butter. These dams wera very good cows as is evidenced by their records, yet King Segis Hengerveld Vale increased the production of his daughters over their dams 2252 lbs. of milk containing 72 lbs. of fat, or 90 lbs. of butter. This increase for a single year on 7 daughters amounts to 15,764 lbs. of milk, or more than 6 times the aver - age yearly production of the Nebraska dairy cow. For 5 milk - ing periods from 7 cows the increased milk production of the daughters over and above the production of their dams would amount to 78,820 lbs. or over 39 tons. This quantity is equal to the production of 31 Nebraska cows for one year. If butter - fat were to be considered, the yearly surplus of King Segis Hengerveld Vale's 7 daughters over their dams would amount to 504 lbs. of butterfat worth, at 35 cents per pound, $176.40. By the use of this bull there actually was created $25.20 more wealth each year from each of his daughters as compared with their dams. If each of the 500,000 dairy cows in Nebraska were daughters of King Segis Hengerveld Vale the yearly in - crease in wealth over their ordinary yield would amount to $12,600,000. A good dairy sire creates wealth. Why not more money for the man who milks? More milk means more money. KING GERBEN LINCOLN King Segis Hengerveld Vale was the sire of several good sons, 2 of which were used in the herds of the University of Nebraska. When he was bred to Katy Gerben, that grand old foundation cow who died with a nail in her heart at 20 years of age, the resulting bull was King Gerben Lincoln 124930. This bull was used for a time at the North Platte Substation and later was sold. King Gerben Lincoln left 8 daughters at the North Platte Substation that made yearly records. These daughters averaged 17,662 lbs. of milk containing 605 lbs. of fat or 757 lbs. of butter. See Table 3 A. In milk produc- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 24 tion each daughter of King Gerben Lincoln was equal to 7 ordinary Nebraska cows and in butterfat production 6 com - mon cows. At 35 cents a pound for butterfat such a cow would bring in $211.75 in a year. Three or 4 cows of that kind would pay the grocery bill for the average family. The great difference between a cow of good production and one of poor production is in the inherited qualities for milk and butterfat production, provided both are properly fed. Few can afford to purchase on the market cows that will produce 600 lbs. of butterfat. No one that is milking cows can afford to be without a sire whose ancestors or whose offspring in - dicate that he will raise the production of his daughters com - pared with the dams. In most herds the only hope of improve - ment comes from the sire, yet scrub or grade is used merely because he is cheap. In fact, he is expensive but the cost in small production does not come for several years and so is not noticed. The farmer who uses a scrub bull pays for a good purebred sire but never uses him. Why not get what you pay for? King Gerben Lincoln was bred to high-producing cows yet the 3 daughters of the high-producing cows with records averaged 52 lbs. of butterfat higher than their dams. The Fio. 3— King Gerben Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Better Sires — Better Stock 9 difference in favor of the daughters was one-half the produc - tion of Nebraska's average dairy cow. Great transmitting sires wisely used would insure larger and more economical production. KING DERBY LINCOLN King Segis Hengerveld Vale was bred to Kittie Gerben Lin - coln, a daughter of Katy Gerben and of Prince Ormsby Mer - cedes DeKol. The resulting male was called King Derby Lin - coln. He was used for a time in the herd at Lincoln and left 9 remarkable daughters. The mothers of these cows were an exceptional group, averaging 613 lbs. of butterfat and includ - ing that famous cow LaVerna Lincoln who for years held the state record with a production of 29,555 lbs. of milk contain - ing 1048 lbs. of butterfat or 1310 lbs. of butter. Despite this, King Derby Lincoln was able to raise the production of his daughters to an average of 20,244 lbs. of milk containing 719 Fig. 4. — Katy Gerben lbs. of butterfat or 899 lbs. of butter. Their story is not finished and it is certain that the younger cows will improve their records still more and raise the average production. In fact, every one will have a record above 600 lbs. of butterfat shortly. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 24 King Derby Lincoln created wealth. Because he could and did transmit high butterfat production, his 9 daughters pro - duced $332.15 more worth of butterfat than their dams in a single year. For such a short lifetime as 5 milking periods, this bull with only 9 daughters added $1660.75 to the wealth of Nebraska over and above what the original cows produced. Consider that if sires like King Derby Lincoln had been used on the dairy cows of the state when the daughters came into milk, six-sevenths of all the cows could be discarded and the remaining one-seventh would still produce the same quantity of butterfat. In other words, 63,500 cows would produce as much as 445,000. The economic waste of feeding the large number of low-yielding cows is enough to bankrupt the state. When one cow will do the work of 7, why keep the other 6? It is hard to estimate the worth of such a sire as King Derby Lincoln, yet bulls of such breeding can often be purchased for as low as $150. When buying a young sire, it is particularly important that in addition to his individuality his pedigree indicate that his ancestors have been good producers. Par - ticularly his dam and his sire's dam should have good records. For many herds, almost any purebred dairy bull would sire Fie. 5. — Kittie Gerben Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Better Sires — Better Stock 11 daughters better than their dams, but males are cheap enough so that a selected one can be used in practically every herd. That the "sire is half the herd" is a common saying. The truth is that in most cases he is the sole source of improvement. Too frequently, however, the investment in the sire is less Fig. 6. — King Derby Lincoln than in one cow and seldom is the expenditure for the head of the herd equal to one-fourth the value of the herd. Put the price of 2 or 3 good cows into the right kind of a bull and he will bring you large returns on the investment. VARSITY DERBY MATADOR King Derby Lincoln bids fair to be a good sire of sons. One son, Varsity Derby Matador, has 4 daughters which average 15,804 lbs. of milk containing 588 lbs. of butterfat or 735 lbs. of butter as 2-year-olds. This remarkable average will be maintained by later daughters coming into milk at the North Platte Substation where he was used. See Table 5 A. At first it may be thought that his daughters are poorer than their dams, but when the difference in age is considered they are well above their dams. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 24 RELATION OF AGE TO PRODUCTION For easy figuring, the production of younger animals may be compared with older ones on the following basis In comparing a record, divide the pounds of butterfat by the per cent for the age. For example, N. P. Hengerveld Segis Rose, a daughter of Varsity Derby Matador, produced 474.67 lbs. of butterfat at 2 years, 1 month. By referring to the chart it is evident that at 2 years and 1 month the pro - duction is 70 per cent of that expected at maturity. 488.67-4 - .70=698.1 lbs., or the quantity that might be expected from her at maturity. It is evident therefore that this cow could be considered to have produced more than her dam. Gerben Segis Pledge Rose, whose butterfat production was 631.88 lbs. Seven-day records of production are made by Holstein cows, and in order that the bulls mentioned may be studied on that basis, these are given just after the yearly records in the tables. Yearly records are the most accurate measure of a cow's ability to produce, but when these are not available, 7 day records furnish a measure of her production. Sires will tell the story of the success or failure of a dairy herd. Better sires, better stock; larger production, larger profits. Good purebred dairy bulls will mean more money for the man who milks. [20M1 yrs. — 2 yrs. 2 mos 70 per cen yrs. 3 mos. — 2 yrs. 5 mos 72 % per cen yrs. 6 it&gt;os. — 2 yrs. 8 mos 75 per cen yrs. 9 mos. — 2 yrs. 11 mos 77% per cen yrs. — 3 yrs. 2 mos 80 per cen yrs. 3 mos. — 3 yrs. 5 mos 82% per cen yrs. 6 mos. — 3 yrs. 8 mos 85 per cen yrs. 9 mos. — 3 yrs. 11 mos 87% per cen yrs. — 4 yrs. 2 mos 90 per cen yrs. 3 mos. — 4 yrs. 5 mos 92% per cen yrs. 6 mos. — 4 yrs. 8 mos 95 per cen yrs. 9 mos. — 4 yrs. 11 mos 97% per cen yrs. or over ...100 per cen </seg>
            <seg id="p013">I « I ?. s = a »s a 9 ■ : m oo tf o n ■ • : | Ul! -asll | s i £ 2-i3l i i Jlai Mf- i|Jlil i=f-sS ilii- IS sssssas i a^ndaiii: siiil=M j?3^2; *«2Sg|SS- 3^-r~ old's!?—^!1^?S ;!iCi^ a. n a. j 5 5 5 ►.•5 ■« "4- ?.5.£ ".5 Rifi sif"! I MO r jSSaS • s — C &gt; BE S 3 n = S 5 5 2.1 3 3 S i || fail i 13 « !•: ■si 5 * si S-a©fe «ss|=^ii -s j2i= ss 4 o 2 fc a q ? s^ K Q W Q O C &lt; £ !£,, "~£££ ji3-££X~££££ji " £££.0.0.0 &gt;. £.o£ SS«o 2wt-« "° «&lt;oa&gt; «at- ONa "* T 01 o « *" N °° Jnoo ■5 Ss^ *w w » — , — 1 — "^ — ' &gt;&gt;. 1 &gt;• — , &gt; — » — ■ J, n •*^ ' — • — "5 .-«»rt a.? . m &gt;• ?TZ . m s . • &gt;&gt; ! E &gt;« _^ s r. — n- -&gt; —^^&gt;-.^Mt- n -, t- 3 ~ 2 J IS g ESS" ™ m r~. _j ri </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 24 JC </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Better Sires — Better Stock 15 ■/. -- •i| 1 m i il i a*° jj 1 *. ©&gt; — — « u^ - !Ji §ss ~s~ " !] 1 £ i 252 « « 3 Jl.l !i |u 5 5 £_* s x s ■!! sss ii ii § ffli S ||| 355 8 *|£S S sist c a) a ■ ||| ** «- bfl a, L S |g -Si Sg : 85£ I* ail *o 15 | Iff B | ■its «5 Jl &gt; «■« s« fc3!i= -^0000 «D O3K t- VOS .£.0 fej- il , Z : i e -z "H ». j&lt; ri =.-».» ". ~.°. "=. -»•:•: a : "S"! E 1? S: r w x — o teai a wn m - - s; *j £ I I ill i iz i u : ; *MV " :44 ■■■ 1 8-8 *"g ;i 3:1:13; 11 M II 1 »8 a I i ; i| :i ;i| : ill is Up; I ! lisls ttj en 3 ! M « !! ( ¥l &gt;l||||lj|| IIS || «| | </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Experiment Station, Circular 24 SO S3 I i «t^Qe5««t&gt;Q i ■■£■ © eo « « ea « w N ■5 ©wco«;oa5oejcj *- *- e °. * E ' "- °°. *1 N . ". r^ 3 I-' ft CO — * c; i* CO X _. „ — 00 Si *&gt; « £ g £ s2S-"2S2 ■ o oo ."1 rH ooie" *- ass 5 -S 3«S ■■e S 5 OS 112111 i|9 I s 1^ I zppi tin z •s «: •2 go -- * P S •* i S Ii2lla III- &gt; o ■i Si S fe -^ C »" = — — ac-t-© P * * to x-«ic &amp;5 S? g co 3 s sl I sgisgs sss§s ess* CC o •* &amp; - °C r- A E^ m 21 til -i t* -2 iCiONiexc «i«- «— 3 = - 2 5 ii SS ►J o £ IS ' 5 ei ** ' se r" ai ~i in^fioci © &lt;c o « iftiOCJWXtt x-roi— ac •i * 5 * 35 w^ 2 * It^i x^-«t-N» -rc-itiO r-NOi 2 J J a 1 858159 ?222 2SS M I w r MM - !l_ — XCJlCi^N -XCN COt-OJ 2 „- N — 0C3-.C* Wt-«ift t-t-N NN — &lt; .. 49 I ~ fi K * ts^n^^oo 9tc- ; ■ S rr " II III Ill-O |" S Q « '« •4 S ,r " 2IjJ.il J.J.' 10 :g r. B 3 fc 2 Q -S a aoeCN X H i- (I c c I! 1 I ili itM is? in 1 — P aso'0'fi&gt;B&lt; SoSzc &lt;&lt;&lt;: a. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Better Sires — Better Stock 17 fc» 3 OO0&gt;CO-*iO KCQANN^n »■«■•-. -^ if. *r t w ■M 3. TJT^^ VTTT 6 ??? t77 : i« &lt; koo« -v *c ro "«f co oo « ?a c- io «— ;gg '5 • -If. -S ■ :SS s;a §:£:»: ; |5 : : J ;(5 :::::£- :g g ;i | ■ OS ,oS :m&lt;2&gt; :S • : o»O :^g ee™ = = 1 iSgEff !iiii! s :i* its II = li^lifililf |«ili ~| if j li^iiiiiiiljiiis in § i -— s L ". *. *. ~ **" P x . *. t- -1 -1 -S ?J CT) --^- D) N MT N — OJ — 00 - c- — m t- — os t-wa o — c: x § -"lassfieooNWiCNNNo 00* oi t- qo id » t^ e-^ ca so W =0 oi *H"S*H S ■^■odadejo^-odeJoO'v^owN ft, « ■* e* Tf^r ■* 4O 09 -v eo II 5 &lt; II 15 00 a '! 1&gt; : : : : : : : : SS 5 . . ■ lull Biiifi j| S ign iislifliifl ■ 41 50 »s aj S i to-ioaon oo ■* w us m to to us»eo -«Am 3 w i- 3 to ■* cr « »o BW»N«qq « *&amp; w «= « » s - tdcotdusia -r r* — — ig w o ot-n o — rt g»5 £ — m — cm — — t&gt;K««xao — m &gt;-™ t&lt;ico ~ ,- 2 ibnoiootf) o»o»c»o-«-ua oowo uat--^ g -S 3 "I * "^t *^^ *i ® 0 ! ! ii. C4NNNN ««^-^« 5m — « £ . W </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 24 lfeB-3 £ 25 £ S 5n 8 1 J i M 1 t- »t- s 3 1 S s - * y i is ss in i .= 52 'S'S'2 £ '" - CCO O £ "-C 1 «, a; a « e -*^» ' -£ « «« *" •" to — £ j j c ct-" *:^: o o c o 2 s 5 Z Z- x, zzz | C 5t- t-t. OOC o ' » !O3t X — i2 22 x l (i _-t— — L ~ £. £, £ •M JJ 8 r r i © x " •- s~s — ■ « "5 • 1^ -2 j -5 S3 —\ I— &gt;C B S| 2 J «S s = s i.i H % to III I /. •5 3 « »sg £ dSS &amp; V &amp; f|5 .r^: ?: *• • TS « a It 7 « ■: jjss I &gt; ,= S - ji °.joJ *|| " ■a r •* 'fl- X . »a t« &gt; 1 n £ B K Cw C3 w w C^CCZ •^ ~ I = a: -; ■' " J ~ J c = z * "^ ™ X i cfc!"^ aOift o cc ic ot*«c icac™ QffiZ ■v air*;— a» .&gt; =o " ■s t r ; x a ». r-«'» r-:-;^ I g T * •; I J |4 «!*' SS3 Si- "*- e ■=' P n; S s-^;— xxxt-; — oi«— c c J Kl r- . m s 2E 2 £ xxic ttcii XXX od «.:« J; x. !r"i j* H •• J; ,i 1 6. «« • o « -S«5 §S 2 %■ "7x5 I i « z |i Of^ « x x —at: »»k 7*1 85 «. N"f « 1 t -M&gt;C TO! ■4 tL~ g i ■= S?2 g S S S3S ggg J£ » J g * U S3 | 1 | SP3 ||" » .3 S s £ 88 I 1 I SS3 gg- a W , a a tt X " I' - .4 Vf •? V t xt r' N . , &lt; 5 V? T V T xt-w i. i. ~ &lt; osw ■» 4 it. Eg 3d 5- : fl-8 X «r. t - -c ■- 1, oo ■ is Co tj s p s i j &lt;li 11 X X f-i 1 | i| i 1 1 Hi Esi 51 II I H Hi K I I 5 3 I I »^ US a II m f iff SI Z$ % t $ III £!£ — H ! i ! ffl is ft in fir ii </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Better Sires — Better Stock 19 *- f- — •-. .- -~-x--r x- Oi -r. — — l- r*. t- te t-t-^te cd n — sjoj — nn n — M n t-te t- l- 5 ti X X X SC ta ~: X NO N OltCiO •J«OS ■ ■ 0 XxXiC ■ &gt;» CO •j. O CQCCO2HO OC CfiCQ &lt; XM-&lt; X i! -5 SO tC — «S e-(D © OS »O A — Z x x tt o&gt; oi t&gt; --f i - •m" -i &lt;b ua — — — XX — — — i - jc : - 1 5??fsfi ft ill 4 5*31 s »©iieost-ea© t-oo as o — *■ 1 1 1 r. t . l- — i « . - OC — — — cj — c* oe to tc »? w oot-^ to'ia 93 rCNNeiNCJN — — — — 53 3 r. m fa i Tf n-mnk^o ostf cv — terns w -*2 a ic ic ~j ©i — o cd x »O95 «ci enocci b — i . r — Ci3sxiex»o»o — « t-x xt-os t-o . &lt; I IT IT I 1 !l II 'E' "^ — ■ *•■"" _r :' : ce s | ipi II J |j !! I iii If U iil I] t lip n n 51 it I liiiiil il fi ill If </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 24 a t i_ - : — OIXSD — — SO eC«O * " - jo -." w wt^t-cccc^riO^ 1 w t- t- f NOOONKM Q x — i.- i - l - . - x n x — x a 5 os -tfos-^xxasaos x * as a os fXUJOO^W^ g r;ONCift*-U5M C5 N «D tS O tt CJ t0 SC iS ic x t-as os — cm us t- ri ?i — ■t :: — —* — &gt; M M X ci i ~*t" pJSs B9 r-i &gt;. ■I — X I" ?] b3c 55 Si s; "u « °- — — x — e ■HE X — XX 'ii r. xc* x Sa IK dtx xx «&lt; ™ M 5 ■* XM ■*?] C 1 ! C: CM ~. W« NN MN— M -- DC B x SS :H5 !5 ad.9s x9_"a « — if.: 11 ?3 3II2J «j 5, S 8 ? «5 . HP iW 3 M sr M — s IE =51 Illll SS cscs res - 7i - - &gt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Better Sires — Better Stock 21 ? o ;c 91 -? — — B0«-4 I-Xr— :- A -~ 00 -q kiown « ia »o t-N X — NN~ — « — C- &lt;O 3 W C- ■- — — fix — — ci6 x asao t- — — oo t---.— a £ : : : :« 1 1 l! iilJ 1 1 ■J. ■ r. .- — — .--- -1 Tl * ?! ill ;111| il! : iiiilsPi2i&gt; i CJ X aoxoi-i — 00 t- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 24 z z zz </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Better Sires — Better Stock 23 5 .- X C- X X X 8 BE O ; - i- xm-i ?] Z^j * a ri x £ -.' -&lt; i-e ass s S 1&amp; 3-3 2 ao SZ age o !i t ik ; ceo &lt; £ .1 i£ w 2 s? : ' :it i ; -i 21 1 -I y h g II : III !! (■ ps,, : t :g s !i tfiiHil NOD »fi^ — — O&gt; — /:'?]!-:=-:.-• t- t- C^_ CM — — — — — * i i sis -I -=S I iH ti 111 ! 1! * CO C0C&lt;O « ISO N ©~«D iff O 3 «-; 3 00 SC O, ** °° °°. -r — • — — ' o* aoco t- oooi C-J N C-l M « »- — — N N __ i X x — t- r: — -h ci -ci~- S — t* © Oi O « O» r-; — "* SO « J m —ox t- c-oj t- — — n t-io ir; t "&lt;r re ?: sc sc m &gt; II I S UK it i Q ill it s If ill i *i ni u z Ik %&amp;. : ? : -£l : -«-l &amp;&amp; zz zzz z zz &lt;:&lt;&lt; a.0. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">PUREBRED SIRES AND HERD IMPROVEMENT Sec Ucw7?aj&gt;/ffiythe Proportion of Native 3lood/j5fcot/iw7«r Dimi/iisAes when a PUREBRED Sire is Used. (\1 ft C^AtcUC Coct/S / Us%o Purebred Ai*t AiUsaA/mdtr oldua/ifaufe in7ux&gt; Gener - ations tka*. ia^fiutuiitk cAeGrade - fa Gum*) Replace SCRUB ©GRADE Sires With GOOD PUREBREOS. Courtesy U. S. Department of AKricultur </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>