<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Summer Hog Feeding</title>
               <date value="1920-12">1920-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 176 December, 1920 Summer Hog Feeding H. J. GRAMLICH AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">INTBODUCTION Pastures are used extensively for the production of porlc during summer months. The belief always has been that green forage greatly cheapens the cost of production. In this state, generally speaking, spring shotes are allowed to graze on pasture thru the summer and are fattened for market during the fall and early winter months. The hogs that are actually fattened and marketed off of grass are in the main fall pigs. The permanent hog pastures which are utilized most in Nebraska are first, alfalfa, and second, blue grass. In some sections we find con - siderable red clover; however, not in the quantity that we have the other two grasses. Hog men who do not have permanent pastures such as thase usually depend on some annual crop. Foremost among these annuals is rape. This is sown early in the spring and is ready for pasture very shortly thereafter. Several experiments have been conducted recently at this Station to ascertain the relative efficiency of rape and alfalfa for summer pasture and to determine the comparative valuu of rape pasture in contrast to the dry lot. This bulletin set' forth the details and results of these tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMER HOG FEEDING EXPERIMENT No. 1 OBJECTS The objects of the experiment were first, to ascertain the value of rape pasture. A second object was to ascertain the practicability of feeding semi-solid buttermilk and ground corn to fattening hogs, in comparison with a shelled corn and tankage ration, both on rape pasture and in dry lot. DESCRIPTION OF PIGS The hogs used in the experiment were fall pigs bred at the University Farm and allowed to follow experimental steers thruout the winter. They carried a predominance of lard-type breeding, and were not fleshy at the opening of the trial, altho weighing in the proximity of 140 pounds. DURATION OF EXPERIMENT The pigs were on test during a 45-day period from May 2*5 to Julv 10. 1917. PRICES OF FEEDS As this experiment was conducted during the early summer of 11&gt;17, when corn prices were the highest that they had been known to be, the cost of grain shows relatively high. A charge of $l.(&gt;0 per bushel is made for corn, $75 per ton for tankage and '&amp;y 2 cents per pound for semi-solid buttermilk. Added to this is a charge of y» cent per head daily for the rape pasture. This would provide an acre rental of $14 per season for land used in this manner. THE VALUE OF RAPE PASTURE WHERE HOGS ARE FATTENED ON A SELF-FEEDER WITH CORN AND TANKAGE. Lot 1 was fed in a dry lot with ample sunshade but no green feed of any kind, whereas lot 2 had access to a fourth of an acre patch of rape pasture. The initial weight of the hogs in these lots was practically 143 pounds. They were on feed 45 days and at the close lot 1 weighed 222.43 pounds and lot 2. 235 pounds, showing a materially larger gain in lot 2 than in lot 1. The average daily gain was 1.76 pounds in lot 1 and 2.06 pounds in lot 2, an increase of .3 pound in the rape lot. Under daily $ 1.60 per bushel Pankage 75.00 per ton Buttermilk 3^c per pound Sape Pasture *£c per day </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 176 ration in the table, the pigs in lot 1 consumed less feed than did those in lot 2, the amount being 6.4 pounds of corn in lot 1 in comparison to 7.53 pounds in lot 2, and .36 pound of tankage in lot 1 and .25 pound in lot 2. Considering that both lots of pigs were on self-feeders and had access to what feed they wished at all times it is safe to draw the conclusion that having access to the pasture undoubtedly increased the appetites of the pigs in lot 2 and caused them to consume more feed. Average gain 79.13 92.73 Average daily gain 1.761 2.061 ♦Figured on a basis of $15 for both cost and selling price, with interest at 7%. As to the feed required per pound gain, lot 1 required 3.63 pounds of corn and .2 pound of tankage, whereas lot 2 required 3.65 pounds of corn and .12 pound of tankage; there - fore it took .02 pound more corn and .08 pound less tankage where the pigs had access to rape pasture. The cost of 100 pounds of gain in lot 1 amounted to $11.14 and in lot 2 to $11.13, giving therefore virtually no difference, altho consider - ing that there was a greater gain in lot 2 the pasture would prove of advantage in that it would get the pigs ready for market quicker than the dry lot. 1 a Lot 1 Lot 2 umber in lot . 10 10 RATION Corn Tankage Corn Tankage ■ Rape pasture verage initial weight . . .verage final weight . . . 143.3 222.43 142.3 235.03 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Summer Hog Feeding 5 Upon figuring the profit, there is quite a margin in favor of lot 2 on rape pasture, the net profit in this group being $3.39, whereas it is but $2.85 in lot 1, a difference of 54 cents per head. This profit is based on an original and final price of 15 cents per ponnd. Considering that there were ten hogs on this pasture during the 45-day period and that the hogs in the pasture yielded 54 cents per head more profit, the fourth of an acre of pasture during the 45-day test netted $5.40, besides the $2,25 rental charged. On a basis of an entire season's pasturing, this would be returning a very satisfactory and profitable rental from the land. The hogs which had rape pasture, in addition to corn and tankage, ate more, gained more, and returned a larger profit than those fed corn and tankage In a dry lot. It will be noted that the nutritive ratio of the ration con - sumed by lot 1 was 1 :7.3. This would be classed as a medium wide ratio. In lot 2 the ratio is wider, being 1 :8.1. This is based entirely on the grain and tankage consumed in this lot. Could the rape consumed be ascertained accurately, the ratio would be narrower, as rape contains a rather high protein content. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bixletix 170 6 THE USE OF RAPE PASTURE IN CONJUNCTION WITH A FULL FEED OF GROUND CORN AND SEMI-SOLID BUTTERMILK. Lot 3 Lot 4 Number in lot 10 10 Corn Corn Semi-solid Semi-solid buttermilk buttermilk Rape pasture Average initial weight Average final weight . Average gain 144.3 144 231.27 86.97 245.7 101.7 Average daily gain 1.933 2.26 'Based on a cost and selling price of $15, with interest at 7%. During recent years creameries have been disposing of their surplus buttermilk in various forms. Eventually most of it has reached the feed lot, altho it is not long since when most cf it went into the gutters. Owing to the fact that buttermilk con - tains so much water it is a very bulky feed to handle, and conse - quently creameries have sought to develop some method of concentrating it. One method found quite practical has been to reduce the buttermilk to a semi-solid state. To do this 700 pounds of buttermilk is evaporated to 100 pounds of the semi-solid product. This commodity is sold extensively to hog men to be fed as a substitute for fresh dairy products. The companies manufacturing it recommend that it be diluted suffi - ciently to mix well and then worked in thoroly with a ground corn ration in the proportion of approximately two parts of buttermilk to five parts of corn. .verage daily ration (pounds) Corn Semi-solid buttermilk X.524 1.235 8.711 1.236 'ounds feed per pound gain Corn Buttermilk 4.41 .64 3.85 .55 lost of 100 pounds gain $14.84 $13.05 "rofit or loss* $0.06 $1.78 utritive ratio of ration . . 1:8.02 1:8.05 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Simmer Hoc, Feeding 7 In order to ascertain the effect of rape pasture where the. above ration is fed. lots 3 and 4 were compared. The pigs in lot 3 pained 1.93 pounds per day in contrast to 2.2(5 pounds gained by lot 4, the pasture group, a difference of .33 pound per day. The daily ration does not differ as much as between lots 1 and 2, the two lots receiving corn and tankage. The pigs in the dry lot consumed K.~r2 pounds of corn daily, whereas those on the ra]&gt;e consumed S.71 pounds. The buttermilk con - sumption was identical, namely. 1.23 pounds. mi-solid buttermilk, when fed as a substitute for tankage. conjunction with corn, failed to show any economical advantage. This applied both in the dry lot and on rape pasture. rape pastur Owing to the fact that the pigs running on the rape pasture made so much greater daily gain on practically an identical ration of grain and buttermilk, a great deal less feed was required to produce one pound of gain in lot 4 than in lot 3, the actual figures being 3.85 pounds of corn, in contrast to 4.45 pounds of corn in lot 3, and .55 pound of buttermilk in lot 4 in contrast to .64 pound in lot 3, a total in lot 4 of 4.4 pounds in contrast to 5.05 pounds total feed required in lot 3. Due to the fact that the pigs in lot 4, which had access to the rape pasture, made so highly satisfactory a gain, their cost of gain was naturally reduced. It amounted, including pasture, to $13.05 per hundred, whereas lot 3 in the dry lot cost $14.84 to put on 100 pounds of gain. Figuring the purchase </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Ui'iaetix 17(5 and selling prices of these hogs at $15 per 100 pounds, lot 4 made a profit of $1,78 whereas lot 3 actually returned a loss of 6 cents per head. This trial would indicate that the use of rape pasture was well justified, as it increased the rate of daily gain by .3 pound, increased the profit per pig by $1.84, and materially reduced the feed per 100 pounds gain. ECONOMY OF SEMI-SOLID BUTTERMILK VERSUS TANKAGE, BOTH IN A DRY LOT AND WHEN PIGS ARE RUNNING ON RAPE PASTURE. Nutritive ratio of ration* 1:7.3 1:8.02 1:8.1 1:8.05 'Based on cost and selling price of $15, with interest at 7%. For several years corn and tankage has been the standard ration used in fattening hogs, especially where running on rape pasture. The table above gives two opportunities to compare a ration of semi-solid buttermilk and corn with tankage and corn. By referring first to lots 1 and 3, we have two lots fed &gt;t8 1 am am Lot 1 Lot 3 Lot 2 Lot 4 umber in lot . . 10 10 10 10 RATION Ta C nkLe Se " d ™£. KS Tankage buttermilk Rape B but j£™ lk Average initial weight Average final weight Average gain 143.3 222.43 79.13 144.3 231.27 86.97 142.3 235.03 92.73 144.0 245.7 101.7 Average daily gain 1.761 1.933 2.061 2.26 .verage daily ration (pounds) I Corn Tankage Buttermilk 6.397 .357 8.524 1.235 7.531 .246 8.711 1.236 'ounds feed per pound gain Corn Tankage Buttermilk 3.633 .202 4.409 .639 3.654 .119 3.85 ' .547' ' Cost of 100 pounds gain . . . $11.14 $14.84 $11.13 $13.05 Profit or loss $2.85 —$0.06 $3.39 $1.78 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Summer Hog Feeding 9 in the dry lot, lot 1 having access to corn and tankage and lot 3 to corn and semi-solid buttermilk. In lot 1 there is a daily gain of 1.76 pounds, whereas in lot 3 there is a gain of 1.93 pounds. This gives a materially larger gain where butter - milk was fed. The daily ration is likewise much greater in lot 3, being 8.52 pounds of corn and 1.24 pounds of buttermilk, in contrast to 0.4 pounds of corn and .36 pound of tankage. Under the feed required to produce one pound of gain, the corn and tankage ration is shown to be the more economical, requiring almost one pound less of corn and requiring but .2 pound of tankage, whereas lot 3 required .6 pound of butter - milk. The difference in cost of 100 pounds gain between these two lots is likewise found to be very marked. In lot 1 it amounts to $11.14 and in lot 3 to $14.84. Due to this disparity in cost of gains, lot 1 showed a profit of $2.85, whereas the buttermilk lot showed a loss of 6 cents. From this test it would seem that the corn and tankage ration has quite a margin over the corn and buttermilk ration, with feeds charged at the prices used in this trial, in spite of the fact that the buttermilk lot made a materially larger daily gain. The buttermilk in this trial was charged at 3*4 cents per pound. Turning for a moment to the other lots, which had access to rape pasture, lot 2, which had corn and tankage in the self - feeder, gained 2.06 pounds, jn contrast to a gain of 2.26 in lot 4, which had the corn and buttermilk. The daily ration is again materially larger in the buttermilk lot, being 8.71 pounds of corn and .25 pound of tankage. However, as the buttermilk pigs gained somewhat more rapidly the difference in the feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain is slightly in favor of lot 2, fed corn and tankage. The cost of 100 pounds of gain shows quite a margin in favor of lot 2, it being the cheapest gaining lot of the experiment, costing $11.13 in con - trast to $13.05 in lot 4. The profit is the largest in lot 2 of any lot in the experiment, being $3.39, in comparison to a profit of $1.78 in lot 4, fed on corn and buttermilk. From this test it would seem that the use of buttermilk for fattening market hogs was not justified at the price charged in this trial. From the two comparisons cited above it will be seen that the semi-solid buttermilk in both instances produced a materi - ally larger gain, and it should be given credit for this. How - ever, the gam was produced at a higher cost and as a result the margin of profit greatly reduced. This leads to the conclusion that one might be justified in feeding semi-solid buttermilk at the prices used here under certain conditions: For instance, the producer of pure-bred hogs who desires rapid growth; or the man who desires to fit show barrows, or crowd hogs for sale </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 17(5 10 purposes. In such cases one might overlook a minor difference in the cost of producing for the greater gain secured. EXPERIMENT No. 2 INTRODUCTION In recent years there has developed a practice of shipping thin shotes from irrigated districts where an abundance of alfalfa is produced into the Corn Belt and fattening them for the market. This practice has developed to such an extent that there is now scarcely a community that does not have a number of feeders who depend almost entirely on western and southern shotes for their supply. OBJECTS This experiment was planned with a view of using southern hogs to ascertain their gaining propensities on heavy grain rations where free access to pasture was allowed. A second object was to ascertain the advisability of substituting hominy meal for corn when fed in conjunction with tankage to pigs on alfalfa pasture; and likewise, the advisability of allowing pigs access to both corn and hominy in conjunction with tankage when on alfalfa. A third object was to ascertain the advisa - bility of feeding a corn and semi-solid buttermilk ration to pigs on alfalfa pasture in contrast to the corn and tankage ration. The last object was to ascertain the relative efficiency of alfalfa and rape pasture where hogs running thereon have access to a full feed of ground corn and semi-solid buttermilk. PLAN OF THE EXPERIMENT The experiment was planned so that each lot had access to pasture, lots 1 to 4 inclusive having alfalfa and lot 5 having rape. In addition to the pasture each lot was allowed a full feed of the particular ration allotted to it. With the exception of lots 4 and 5 self-feeders were used. Hence the pigs decided for themselves the amount of feed they would consume. In lots 4 and 5 feeding was done twice daily and the pigs were allowed all of the mixture of corn and buttermilk they would consume at each feed. Weights were taken three consecutive days at both the start and close of the experiment and at 10-day inter - vals during the trial. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Summer Hog Feeding 11 DESCRIPTION OF THE PIGS USED The hogs used were Texas pigs weighing at the time the experiment started an average of 106 pounds. They had been immunized against cholera with the double treatment several months prior to the time the experiment started and conse - quently were in good shape to gain satisfactorily. They repre - sented a mixture of breeding and many of them appeared to carry considerably more age than the average pip weighing 100 pounds. They cost at the opening of the experiment 10 cents per pound, net. The pigs were divided into five, groups of 1l' each. RATIONS FED Lot I : Corn, tankage, alfalfa. Lot II : Hominy, tankage, alfalfa. I^ot III : Corn, hominy, tankage, alfalfa. j j , o 7 Lot IV: Corn, semi-solid buttermilk, alfalfa. Lot V: Corn, semi-solid buttermilk, rape. PRICES OF FEEDS The price of $2.00 per bushel charged for the corn repre- sented the prevailing price during the summer of 1917. altho it is a price far above the average for a series of years. At the time this experiment opened corn could not be bought for less than $2.25 per bushel. However, before the close of the trial, it was down to a price slightly below $2.00. Hence, the latter figure was used. This makes the corn actually cost a trifle over 3!/2 cents per pound. The hominy feed, it will be noted, was charged at $70 per ton, which is 3Vfc cents per pound. This was the prevailing price at the time the trial was in progress. Normally, hominy feed and corn sell at almost the same price, at times there being a shade difference in favor of the hominy feed. The semi-solid buttermilk is sold in barrels containing approximately 500 pounds net. The 3^ cent per pound price was the charge where sold in barrel lots, altho in carload lots a quotation of 3 cents prevailed. Hence, corn, hominy and buttermilk are charged in this trial at practically the same price. The tankage is charged in this test at $80 per ton, or 4 cents per pound, and the pasture is charged at the rate of V£ cent per day per hog. Considering that these hogs were fattening on a full grain ration % cent per head daily should prove a very liberal allowance for the grass consumed. Corn $ 2.00 per bushel Semi-solid Buttermilk 3%c per pound Hominy Feed 70.00 per ton Tankage 80.00 per ton Pasture y&amp; per head daily </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 176 12 CAN HOMINY FEED BE SUBSTITUTED IN WHOLE OR IN PART FOR CORN WHEN FED WITH TANKAGE TO PIGS ON ALFALFA PASTURE? Owing to the unprecedented demand for com for milling purposes it had risen in price to such a figure that the feeding of it in quantities seemed prohibitive. With so high a price for a feed stuff it is natural to seek a substitute. Considering that such tremendous quantities of corn were being milled it was but natural to look to the by-products of corn after the various parts which are used for human consumption have been extracted. The problem arises as to whether these by-products •ots 1, 2 a Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 umber in lot 12 12 12 RATION Corn Tankage Alfalfa Hominy Corn Tankage Hominy Alfalfa I Tankage Alfalfa Lverage initial weight .verage final weight .verage gain 105.41 221.63 116.22 104.41 200.41 96.00 105.66 213.00 107.34 iverage daily gain 1.937 1.6 1.789 Average daily ration (pounds) Corn Hominy Tankage 6.681 5.462 .356 3.983 2.127 .341 .355 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Hominy Tankage 3.444 3.415 .222 2.226 1.189 .191 .183 Cost of 100 pounds gain $13.29 $13.15 $13.16 Average initial cost @ $16 Interest, 60 days @ 7% Cost of feed $16.87 .20 15.46 $16.70 .20 12.62 $16.91 .20 14.12 _ . . 29.53 31.22 Total cost 32.53 Selling price per 100 pounds 17.75 17.60 17.80 Gross receipts per hog 39.34 35.27 37.91 Profit per hog . . 6.81 5.74 6.69 Nutritive ratio of ration 1:7.4 1:8 1:7.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Summer Hog Feeding 13 are of value in pork production and whether they can be substi - tuted for corn in the pork ration. Of these various corn products hominy feed is the most common one sold in this terri - tory. This is the resultant part after the corn has been put thru a dry grinding process to remove the corn meal and corn flour. This substance contains approximately the same per - centage of moisture as does corn and at the same time contains 10 per cent of protein, 65 per cent of carbohydrates and 8 per cent of fat. It, therefore, is almost identical in composition to corn. The crude fibre runs slightly higher. However, based on the chemical composition of hominy feed it should, theoreti - cally, at least, substitute for corn in the animal's ration. Hominy feed, tankage and alfalfa failed to give as good results aa either a straight corn, tankage and alfalfa ration, or one in which hominy replaced but a portion of the corn. Lot 1 in this trial received corn and tankage in separate compartments of the self-feeder. Lot 2 received hominy in place of corn, while lot 3 received both corn and hominy, as well as the tankage, each being in a separate compartment. All three lots had access to alfalfa pasture. Regarding first the rate of gain in these three lots, there is quite a material difference, especially between lots 1 and 2. Lot 1 gained 1.94 pounds per day, whereas lot 2 gained but 1.6 pounds. Lot 3 is approximately half way between 1 and 2 in rate of daily gain, or 1.79 pounds. While the gain would be classed as good in all three of these lots, still there is quite a margin in favor of the straight corn and tankage lot. In order to ascertain the relative economy of these three rations, </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Iii lketix 170 14 it is necessary to know the amount consumed per day. The pig^ in lot 1 consumed 6.(58 pounds of corn and .30 pound of tankage, whereas the pigs in lot 2 consumed but 5.46 pounds of hominy and .36 pound of tankage. In other words, the tankage con - sumed in the two cases was identical but the hominy pigs had consumed less feed by 1.22 pounds per day, signifying that the hominy probably was not as appetizing as the corn, or that it was so bulky that they could not handle as much of it as they could of the corn. Lot 3, which had access to both the hominy and corn, consumed daily 3.98 pounds of corn, 2.13 pounds of hominy and .34 pound of tankage. Again the tankage con - sumption is practically the same as in lots 1 and 2. The corn consumed amounted to almost double the hominy consumption, indicating that the pigs apparently relished the corn more than they did the hominy, altno they doubtless found something satisfying about the hominy or they would not have consumed that much. The total hominy and corn combined amounts to 6.11 pounds, which is an amount midway between the corn consumed in lot 1 and the hominy consumed in lot 2. Under feed required to produce one pound of gain, in lot 1, 3.44 pounds of corn and .18 pound of tankage were required. In lot 2. 3.42 pounds of hominy and .22 pound of tankage, or slightly less hominy and somewhat more tankage than in lot 1, were required. On a basis of the amount of feed required in these two lots to produce one pound of gain, the hominv returned a value of $3.55 per 100 pounds, in comparison with the corn at $3.57. In other words, in producing the gain in lot 2, the hominy proved to be worth practically as much pound for pound as the corn. In lot 3 it required 2.23 pounds of corn and 1.19 pounds of hominy together with .19 pound of tankage to produce one pound of gain, a total which is approxi - mately the same as that in lots 1 and 2. In this lot the hominy, when compared with lot 1, returned a value of $3.63 per 100 pounds, or a slightly greater value per pound than the corn. As the hominy is charged in this test at $3.50 per hundred, it returned slightly more than its cost price in both lots 2 and 3. The cost of 100 pounds of gain with feeds at the extremelv high prices quoted is $13.29 in lot 1, $13.15 in lot 2 and $13.16 in lot 3. This shows a comparative closeness in each instance, altho both lots 2 and 3 are slightly lower than lot 1. The hogs were appraised in their lots before selling and the amount of finish which each ration had produced is quite well indicated by the prices. It will be noted that lot 1 was valued at $17.7o| lot 2 at $17.60 and lot 3 at $17.80. The pigs in lot 2 were the poorest finished lot in the experiment. Their hair was dull, they lacked the flesh and they were not what </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Simmer H&lt;kj Feeding 15 would be called a finished group of hogs, whereas lots 1 and 3 would rank as comparatively good for hogs of their class. It will be noted that the final weight varied from 221 pounds in lot 1 to 200 pounds in lot 2. These hogs were, therefore, what might be classed as a medium to light class of butcher hogs. Figuring the net profit per hog. lot 1 has the advantage, the actual profit being $6.81. As the hogs in this lot sold for $1.7.") per hundred more than their initial price, there is quite a wide margin of profit. This is made doubly wide by the fact that the hogs gained well. Due to the relatively low gain in lot '1 and the fact that this lot was discriminated against in A partial substitution of corn for hominy, when fed with tankage to pigs on alfalfa pasture, resulted in a slightly lower gain and a some - what reduced profit, altho more satisfactory results were secured than where corn was entirely replaced by hominy. selling price, their profit was $5.75, or $1.06 per head less than lot 1. In lot 3, which had access to corn, hominy and tankage, the profit amounts to $6.71, which is almost identical to that in lot 2. The interesting fact as brought out by the figures above is that while the pigs in lot 2 were the lowest gainers, they were relatively economical gainers in that they were not heavy eaters and required, if anything, slightly less feed to produce one pound of gain than did the pigs in either lots 1 or 3. This bears out the thought that it is not always the heaviest eating animal that is the most efficient gainer. Had lot 2 succeeded in attain - ing a high degree of finish and sold with the other two lots, the profit would be materially greater. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 176 16 From the above it would seem proper to draw this conclu - sion : That hominy feed cannot be profitably substituted entirely for corn when fed with tankage, but that it can be used as a partial substitute for corn to very good advantage. The above statement might have to be modified in case the hominy feed was relatively cheaper. For instance, if hominy feed were $10 per ton less in price than corn, lot 2 would show a larger profit than lot 1. As a rule no such margin exists, however. CAN SEMI-SOLID BUTTERMILK BE UTILIZED IN CONJUNCTION WITH CORN ON ALFALFA PASTURE AS A SUBSTITUTE FOR TANKAGE? ant Lot 1 Lot 4 umber in lot 12 12 RATION Corn Tankage Alfalfa Corn Buttermilk Alfalfa .verage initial weight .verage final weight .verage gain i verage daily gain 105.41 221.63 116.22 1.937 108.91 237.37 128.46 2.141 .verage daily ration (pounds) Corn 6.681 7.039 Buttermilk 1.418 Tankage .355 Pounds feed per pound gain Corn Buttermilk Tankage 3.444 ' .183 3.288 .662 Cost of 100 pounds gain . . $13.29 $14.29 Average initial cost @ $16 Interest 60 days @ 7% Cost of feed Total cost per pig $16.87 .20 15.46 32.53 $17.43 .20 18.36 35.99 Selling price per 100 pounds 17.75 17.90 Gross receipts per pig . 39.34 42.49 Profit per pig. 6.81 6.50 Nutritive ratio of ration 1:7.4 1:7.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Summer Hog Feeding 17 Creameries have been manufacturing the product termed semi-solid buttermilk and disposing of the same to hog pro - ducers. This is merely buttermilk evaporated to a material extent. It is sold in barrel lots in a semi-solid state, as the name implies, and fed to hogs diluted with water and mixed with ground corn. In order to give this product a trial and to ascertain its comparative value with tankage, lots 1 and 4 were fed, lot 1 having access to corn and tankage in self-feeders, and lot 4 fed twice daily, the corn and buttermilk being mixed in the proportion of five parts of corn to two of buttermilk. As regard the daily gain, while lot 1 gained 1.94 pounds, lot 2 gained 2.14 pounds, an increase of .2 pound, which is quite a marked increase, especially considering that lot 1 made a very satisfactory gain. Under daily feed consumed, lot 4 took con - siderably more feed than lot 1, the exact amount of corn con - sumed in lot 1 being 6.68 pounds, in contrast to 7.04 pounds in lot 4. While lot 1 took .36 pound daily of tankage, lot 4 con - sumed 1.41 pounds of buttermilk, a total therefore in lot 4 of 8.46 pounds of feed daily in contrast to 7.4 pounds in lot 1. As regard the feed required to produce one pound of gain, in lot 1 it required 3.44 pounds of corn and .18 pound of tankage. In lot 4 slightly less corn was required, but 3.29 pounds, in conjunction with .66 pound of buttermilk. Therefore, the total feed required runs somewhat higher in lot 4 than in lot 1, which exemplifies the fact that often the heaviest eaters are not the most economical gainers. Based on the feed required to produce one pound of gain, the buttermilk in lot 4, when compared with the feed required in lot 1, only returned a value of $1.74 per hundred. Too much emphasis should not be placed upon this comparative value of the buttermilk, however, for two reasons. In the first place, it will be noted that it caused the pigs to gain much more rapidly than those fed tankage. Considering that there was a $2.00 margin between cost and selling prices, and that the pigs in both lots put their gains on at considerably below selling price, the profit would naturally be proportionately closer to the profit of the tankage lot due to the added gain secured. Another reason the buttermilk should not be criticised too severely is that the pigs receiving it carried considerably more finish than those receiving the tankage. This is indicated by the fact that the selling price of $17.90 was placed upon the buttermilk pigs in contrast to $17.75 the price on the tankage lot. The cost of producing 100 pounds of gain is $13.29 in lot 1 and $14.29 on the butermilk pigs, a difference of $1.00 per hundred against the buttermilk. This cost of gain is the highest of any lot in the test. As a result of the higher selling price and the </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station IUixetin 170 exceedingly heavy gain produced by the pigs in lot 4, their net profit is almost as great as that in lot 1, the figure being $6.50 for the buttermilk lot and $6.81 for the others, a difference of but 31 cents. From these figures the inference can readily be drawn that should one desire a very rapid gain on hogs he might be justified in feeding the buttermilk, even tho it would make the gains cost more. It is probable that the chief value of the semi-solid buttermilk will be in developing and crowding pure-bred stock for sale purposes, and as a substitute for sow's milk at weaning time for both pure-bred and grade pigs. A COMPARISON OF RAPE AND ALFALFA PASTURE FOR HOGS FATTENED ON A CORN AND SEMI-SOLID BUTTERMILK RATION. Lots an a 5 Lot 4 Lot 5 umber in lot . . 12 12 RATION Corn Buttermilk Alfalfa Corn Buttermilk Rape .verage initial weight . .verage final weight . . . verage gain 108.91 237.37 128.46 105.75 224.25 118.5 .verage daily gain. . . . 2.141 1.975 .verage daily ration (pounds) Corn Buttermilk 7.039 1.418 6.963 1.404 'ounds feed per 100 pounds gain Corn Buttermilk 328.8 66.2 353.2 71.3 ... ost of 100 pounds gain. $14.29 $15.33 Average initial cost @ $16 Interest, 60 days @7% Cost of feed $17.43 .20 18.36 $16.92 .20 18.17 Total cost per pig 35.99 35.29 illing price per 100 pounds $17.90 $17.75 rross receipts per pig . . . 42.49 39.80 ofit per pig 6.50 4.51 utritive ratio of ration 1:7.5 1:7.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Summer H&lt;m; Feediku 19 Two of the chief pasture crops depended upon for pork production in most parts of Nebraska are alfalfa and rape, the former a perennial, the latter an annual. When alfalfa hay is selling at a high figure there are times when an acreage seeded to rape for hog pasture is considered very advisable in order that the alfalfa may be used largely for hay. There are times, likewise, when following a severe winter killing, or moving to a new farm, one must resort to some annual crop for immediate pasture. Under such conditions, rape is \ised almost entirely. The feeding of lots 4 and 5 was planned to ascertain the rela - tive efficiency of these two pasture crops when used by hogs fed a full feed of corn and semi-solid buttermilk. The plan was to allow the pigs in each lot practically all of the feed which they would consume twice per day. The&gt; were handled similarly in both instances and the difference in results is due as nearly as can be ascertained to the forage provided. It will be noted that where the pigs had access to alfalf;t in lot 4 the daily gain was 2.14 pounds, in contrast to 1.07 pounds in lot 5 on rape pasture. The daily feed consumed was almost identical, being 7.04 pounds of corn and 1.42 pounds of buttermilk in lot 4, in comparison to 6.96 pounds of corn an&lt;l 1.4 pounds of buttermilk in lot 5, a slightly greater consumption in the case of lot 4. However, when it is considered that the pigs in lot 4 made a considerably larger gain than those in lot 5 it is found that they actually made their gain on les - grain than those in lot 5. Checking the figures shows that while it took only 3.29 pounds of corn to produce one pound of gain in lot 4. it took 3.53 pounds in lot 5, and while it took .66 pound of buttermilk in lot 4 it took .71 pound in lot 5. or a total of .20 pound more in lot 5 than in lot 4. Due to the additional amount of feed required to make the gain, the cosf of gain is higher in the case of the pigs running on rape pasture. The alfalfa lot made its gains for $14.29 whereas the pigs on rape made theirs for $15.33. Lot 5 did not show the finish which lot 4 showed and was valued at 15 cents per hundred less than lot 4. As a result of the difference in valua - tion and the more expensive gain by the pigs in lot 5, their net profit per head is much less than those in lot 4, the difference Iwing $1.99. the profit in lot 4 being $6.50 in contrast to $4.51 in lot "). This makes lot 5 the lowest profit lot of the entire </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 176 20 test and likewise the most expensive gainer of the test by $1.00 per 100 pounds. From this trial it would seem that rape is not as valuable as alfalfa for hogs that are on a full feed of corn and butter - milk and that the margin between the gains and the profits is very decisively in favor of the alfalfa. C5M) </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>