<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00041.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00041.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Third Annual Report of the Nebraska Dairyman's Association</title>
               <date value="1915-02-01">1915-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Nebraska Dairymena Association Secretary* Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, Feb. 1, 1915 His Excellency, John H. Morehead, Governor of Nebraska: SIR: In compliance with the law in this case made and provided, I hereby transmit the Annual Report of the Nebraska Dairymens Asso- ciation for the year 1914. Yours respectfully, R. W. McGINXIS, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">OFFICERS OK THt ASSOCIATION 191J. I.ARK, President Ravenna PEARSON Vice-PreslJent Moorefield R. W. MeGIXXIS, Secretary-Treasurer Lincoln KOAKD OF DIRECTORS E. M LITTL£ Clark* H. FRAXDSEX Lincoln HENRY FISHBACK Beatrice DAVI D COLE Omaha A. S. XELSON Stromsburg </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">TABLE OF CONTENTS Officers of the Association. 1915 i List of Members • Programme Annual Meeting _ - 1* Address of Welcome — Chancellor Avery _ 14 President's Annual Address— E. M. Little 10 Report of Treasurer _ It List of Committees _ — 10 Address of C. A. Nelson _ M Advantages of Dairying in Western Nebraska Ueut. Gov. Jas. R. Pearson _ 98 Danry Farm and Herd Management — Prof. J. H. Frandsen SS Remarks of Regent Whltmore - 4S Remarks by Regent Brown 44 Feeding the Dairy Cow — C. L. Burlingham 4* Dairying Conditions in Wisconsin — S. C. Bassett. ... SO Remarks by Dr. Warren, Cornell University 54 Labor Saving Devices on the Dairy Farm — Thos. E. Culp M Rei&gt;ort of Auditing Committee _ W Nominating Committee Report •• 59 Election of Officers _ M Resolutions by Prof. Haecker 60 Care of Cream on the Farm — Prof. R. C. Jensen 62 Planning Dairy Buildings — E. G. Woodward „ 71 Constructing Dairy Buildings — Prof. U W. Chase 78 Dairying with General Farming — Prof. A. L. Haecker 81 Cream Grading — Prof. E. L. Redfern 87 LMsoussion — Prof. J. D. Jarvis 88 Butter Quotations •• , tO Rules for Grading Cream 91 Report of Resolutions Committee 91 Cow Judging Contest H Nebraska Ice Cream Manufacturers Association 97 List Creameries— Milk Dealers— Nebraska 40J </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 9 LIST OF XEXBERS Honorary Life Mentors. Hon. \V. D. Hoard Ft. Atkinson, Wit Hon. C. L. Gabrilson New Hampton, low* Prof. W. A. Henry Madison, Wl». Hon. A. C. Tupper Osage, Iowa 1. H. Monrad Naerum, Denmark I. G. Lombard Omaha, Nebr. Life Members. P Ashburn Gibbon, Nebr. J. Dixon Avery T Pittsburgh, Pa. Elijah Allen Omaha, Nebr. Mrs. D. P. Ashburn Gibbon, Nebr. W. C. Andreas Beatrice, Nebr. C Bassett Gibbon, Nebr. I M. Bayley Gibbon, Nebr. G. \V. Bemis Sutton, Nebr. Bates, Wilcox and Streeter Omaha, Nebr. John Baumer Omaha, Nebr. C. W. Beals &amp; Co Omaha, Nebr. R Bingham &amp; Son Omaha, Nebr. Henry Bolln Omaha, Nebr. W. H. Buck Gibbon. Nebr. L. J. Babcock Gibbon. Nebr. J. M Bennett Hebron, Nebr. W. L. Dovee Gibbon, Nebr. L. S. Coffin Ft Dodge, low* \V A. Carpenter Sutton, Nebr. H. G. Clark Omaha, Nebr. Hon. J. B. Dinsmore Sutton, Nebr Hon. Jas. H. Davis Gibbon, Nebr. \V. C. Drury Gibbon, Nebr I. N. Davis MUford, Nebr. M Dabelstein Waterloo, Nebr. Charles Dabelstein Waterloo, Nebr. Dr B. B. Davis, Bee Building Omaha, Nebr. •Deceased </seg>
            <seg id="p008">10 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION •Henry Etc he Omaha, Nebr. T. If. Eb«y Omaha, Nebr. Prank T. Emerson Omaha, Nebr. Wm. Eiche, SUtlon B Omaha, Nebr •G«o. E. Evans GIbbson, Nebr. Englewood Dairy Co 37th and X Sts., Lincoln, Nebr. •Hon. R. W. Furnas Brownville, Nebr. P. 8. Fulmer Gibbon, Nebr Charles Finch Omaha, Nebr. H. F. Flint Gibbon, Nebr. •T. J. Fisher Gibbon, Nebr •Hon. H. Fieldgrove Shelton, Nebr •T. G. Fureguson Stella, Nebr. H. C. Gliasman Station B, Omaha, Nebr. E. W. Gunther Albion, Nebr Germantown Cry Co Germantown, Nebr. Chr. Hansen Chicago, 111 E. F. Howe Omaha, Nebr • Louis Helm rod Omaha, Nebr D. H. Hurley Omaha, Nebr •I. \V. Harrel Gibbon, Net Prof. A. L Haecker Lincoln, \"€ J. K. Honeywell Lincoln, Net Hon. E. J. Hainer Lincoln, Nebr W. H. IJams Omaha, M P. E. Her Omaha, Nebr A. Jonas Madison, Nebr •J. J. King West Point. Net 8. H. Knight Chicago, 111 Kirachbraun ft Sons Omaha, Nebr. •Thomas Kirk Gibbon, Ne Morelle B. King York, Nebr Henry Krumhauer Lincoln, Nebr Wm. Lewon Omaha, Nebr P. W. Lessentln Omaha, Nebr E. M. Uttle Clarks, Nebr Otto Magenau Fremont, Nebr J. C. Merrill Sutton, .Net •Murnen ft Noble Gibbon, Nebr •Markle ft Swobe Omaha, Nebr Martyn Bros Omaha, Nebr •Max Meyer Omaha, Nebr Dr. G«o. L. Miller Omaha, Nebr •Prank E. Moores Omaha, Nebr W. T. Mount Omaha, Nebr •Deceased </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THIRTIETH AXXl'AL CONVENTION' 11 R. W. McGinnis Lincoln, Nebr. R. OKeefe Omaha, Xebr. A. A. Olson Stromsburg, Nebr. John T. Paulson Omaha, Nebr. Peycke Bros Omaha, Nebr. Chas. Pinch Omaha, Nebr. Henry Pundt Omaha, Nebr. I. W. Pierce Gibbon, Nebr. Allen Root Omaha, Nebr. Riddle ft Riddle Omaha, Nebr. J. H. Rushton Fairmont Cry, Omaha, Nebr. E. T. Rector Fairmont Cry, Omaha Nebr J. A. Reedy Lincoln, Nebr. I. R. Roberts Lincoln, Nebr. I. G. Southwick Bennett, Nebr. Wm. Seivers Omaha, Nebr. )tto Stuben Omaha, Nebr. H. Silvernail Gibbon, Nebr. Schroeder &amp; Co Omaha, Nebr. Hon. W. M. Sutton Table Rock, Nebr. Hon. B. R. Stouffer Bellevue. Nebr. has. W. Stevenson Soo City John Snedden Eagle, Nebr. has. F. Swager Omaha, Nebr. us Treitschke Omaha, Nebr. F. H. Vaughn Cheyenne, Wyo. Prof. H. H. Wing Ithaca, N. Y. Hon. \V. G. Whitmore Valley, Nebr. D. H. Wheeler Omaha. Nebr. Wideman &amp; Co Omaha, Nebr Ed Wittig Omaha, Nebr. C. S. Woodruff Gibbon, Nebr. W. Rlghter Woods Station B, Omaha, Nebr •Deceased </seg>
            <seg id="p010">12 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION List of Annual Members. V. W. Bouska Lincoln, Xebr H. V. Bricker Greenwood, Nebr. Z. H. Cbittenden Uncoln, Nebr O«O. Burke Stromsburg, Nebr. Dtrid Cole Omaha, Nebr Unirltbi ChrUtengen Minden. Nebr E. D. Comstock Jr Benson, Nebr. A. D. Fitch Scotts Bluff, Nebr. E. W. Froat Central City, Nebr J. H. Frandaen Uncoln. Nebr T. A. Qlereng Lincoln, Xebr Baratrd Grady Raymond, Nebr, J. C. Grtffln Uncoln, Nebr. X. W. Hennlngsen Superior, Nebr D. U. Hildebrand Seward, Nebr W. K. Hewitt David City, Nebr. E. M. Ho»r Walthill, Nebr. B. Svaii King Valley, Nebr. E. W. Kubn Lincoln, Nebr C. A. Kramer Lincoln, Nebr., R L, F. Mndcren State Farm, Lincoln, Nebr R. W. McGinnis Uncoln, Nebraska U C. McCartney Lincoln, Nebr., R. H. Meulenberg Geneva, Nebr J. P. Nestlebuah 2104 Maple St., Omaha, Nebr R. J. Pouon 307 X. 24th St., Lincoln, Nebr. W. E. Rundtll Lincoln, Nebraska C. M. Rydberg State Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. C. B. Swan Omaha, Nebraska H. U. Serere Palmyra, Nebraska O. A. Severe Palmyra, Nebraska J. a Shepherd 529 N. 16th St., Lincoln, Nebr P. F. Trowbridge Decatur, Nebraska Paul Thursen 1550 N. 32nd St., Lincoln, Nebr. J. W. Vedlock 745 J St., Uncoln, Nebr. A. E. Wllkenaon cj Beatrice Creamery Co., (hicaga, 111. D. 8. Wiley Benson, Nebraska Frank Wright Beatrice, Nebraska H. O. Weller Raymond, Nebr. Htnry Wilkinson cj t Beatrice Creamery Co., Chicago, Nebr. H. C. Young Lincoln. Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Uair&gt; Crowd to National l&gt;; ir\ Show. I'hiiaKo. 111., r.il I </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 13 THIRTIETH ANMAL MEETING OF THE &gt;KBKASkA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Wednesday and Thursday January 20 and M, 191a. Sessions to Be Held in Assembly Room, 110 Plant Industry Building, University Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska. PROGRAM WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 20 1«:M o'clock A. M. Address of Welcome Chancellor Arery Address of President E. M. Little Report of Secretary and Treasurer R. W. McGinnis What Dairying Means to Your State C. A. Nelson, Waverly, Iowa (One of Iowa's most successful dairymen) Advantages of Dairying in Western Nebraska Lt. Got. J. R. Pearson Dairy Farm and Herd Management Prof. J. H. Frandsen WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 10 1:00 ©Tl©fk P. TL Feeding the Dairy Cow C. L. Burlingham, V. S. Dairy Division Labor Saving Devices on the Dairy Farm Thos. E. Culp THURSDAY, JANUARY 21 »:00 o'Clock A. «. (Business Session) Care of Cream on the Farm Prof. R. C. Jensen Cream Grading E. L. Redfern Planning Dairy Buildings Prof. E. G. Woodward Constructing Dairy Buildings Prof. L. W. Chase </seg>
            <seg id="p013">14 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION THURSDAY, JANUARY 21 1 KM) ..'( I.K-k P. JL Dairying with General Farming Prof. A. L. Haecker Cow Judging 4:00 P. M. COW Jl MUM. CONTEST The Cow Judging Contest is open to members of the Association only Anyone may become a member of the Association on payment of $1 Gold, Silver and Bronze medals will be awarded to the contestants winning first, second and up to eighth places. Everyone is Invited to become a member of the Association and tak part in this contact E. W. FROST. E. G. WOODWARD, Superintendents Doat fail to see the educational exhibits prepared by Prof Fraadsen and his assistants in the old dairy pavilllon. Instead of an exclusive Dairymen's Banquet this year we will join with all the other organized agricultural associations, etc., to be given Wednesday evening. January 20, at the Lindell Hotel, $1 per plate. REMARKS The Lindell Hotel will be headquarters for the Dairy Association For programs or other useful information in regard to the annual ■anting call on or address, MR. E M LITTLE, President, Clarks, Nebraska MR. J. H. FRANDSEX, Dairy Husbandry Department, University Mat* Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska. MR. R. W. McGIXNIS. Secretary Treasurer, 1024 0 Street, Lincoln Nafcnaka. State Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska, January 21st, 1915. The President, in calling the Thirtieth Annual Meeting of the Ne - braska Dairymen's Association to order, said that the first number on Um» program was an Address of Welcome by Chancellor Avery, and it gave him pleasure to introduce him. ADDREtW OF WELCOME BY CHANCELLOR AVEBY From the Interest that is taken by almost everyone in the dairy •redact* it ought to be possible for almost all persons to say something a* that ubiquitous subject. I think, however, it would be hard for me (a speak strictly as a representative dairyman. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">15 I shall speak to you from the ethical, aesthetical and the material - stic standpoints. On the ethical side, I claim that the dairyman stands for truthful - for representing things as they are. Right here I want to speak I my own record on the score of veracity. At one time I was talking o the editor of the Farmer. He was accusing the University of not keeping faith. I told him that on one occasion President Butler met President Eliot and said: "Eliot, it is fearful; they have accused me of lieing." President Eliot replied., "That is nothing. They have proved it on me." So, as 1 was explaining that the President of Harvard had not escape the imputation of bad faith, the editor said, "We want men who have hearts and lives that we can rely on." So I have cut out joking to editors. Speaking of veracity, I want to recall to your minds that one year ago 1 promised, in the name of the Regents, — and I didn't know at that time that our distinguished friend of the cow, Brother Brown, would be on the Board, — that the first building to be provided for by the Uni - versity would be the dairy building. Now the first plans for it are and you have the privilege of seeing them today. Now I want to turn from the ethical side of the subject to the esthetieal that the dairymen represent. They did not always have this virtue. I can remember when butter was obtained at the country stores in close proximity to onions and would not represent the aesthetic at all. Things have now changed. The dairymen now stand for cleanli- Butter is now produced under clean, hygenic conditions and it done up in handsome rolls, with fine aroma, and of the best dairy product that can be found. We have gotten into the artistic side of life. The dairymen are advancing along lines of practical art Of course, we cannot escape the materialistic side, so I would also touch that phase of dairy instruction. I remarked to my friend Frand - s- n last summer that we might hitch up our auto and run a few thou - sand miles through dairy states. The suggestion came that we take along our wives as cooks. Because we lived on the butter and cheese and all those things that we picked up from dairymen along the line, this precaution was scarcely necessary for our welfare. We first went to Ames. The thought that entered my mind first was, "Why doesn't Nebraska train all her dairymen instead of sending them to Ames?" We have been behind Iowa. But, in a little while, as soon as we get our new dairy building erected, we will be ahead and fann - ers' sons and others will come to Nebraska for training in dairying in - stead of going to Iowa. Then we went across to Waterloo and saw some famous herds. According to my wife, I there made the mistake of my life, because as I was looking at a $26,000 bull, instead of keeping my eye on him I turned around and looked at an automobile. Then we went across the corner of the state to Wisconsin. One of the things that pleased me was the prosperity of the people in that sec- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">16 lion of the country. I thought that if they could do all theae things an J have such prosperity on that soil, how much more could be done in Nebraska with our splendid soil. Prom there we went to Madison, a dairy section in Illinois, going through Elgin in the night time. I wanted to pass that place in the day time and »ee how they fixed the prices on butter. Mr. Frandsen •aid that was immaterial; so from there we went on to Lansing and saw the best laboratory anywhere in the west. Then we went across to Missouri and Kansas and return, making a trip of some 2,300 miles la nineteen days, and visiting the principal dairies, both public and private. In the west We saw people having all the comforts of life, and even those outside of the dairy belt. We saw painted and untainted h«»Mi. kept and unkept buildings, and observed a general condition of wealth and prosperity. 80 it was to me a most instructive trip, which emphasized the value of dalryiag to any state that will pursue it intelligently and scientifically. Gentlemen of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association, I welcome you here today. I started out rather facetiously in describing to you how dairymen have all the virtues of the ideal, moral, ethical and material - istic side of life. I now want to say in all seriousness that I welcome yw here today. I am glad you are here I hope that this t'niveristy and the dairymen of this state will always continue their present of vary close sympathy and co-operation I thank you Ta» President: We all appreciate this very warm welcome given by the Chancellor The next in or-«r on our program is an address by the Pr aad 1 will now ask the Vice President to take the chair. The Vice President: The next number on our program this m !■( Is an address of our President and we will now have t of listening to him This Is the thirtieth annual convention of the Nebraska Dairy - ■•li Association. During the last fifteen years we have met regularly M the State I'niverslty campus and each year the attendance has b*ea large, the Interest in the discussions good, and I am sure every - one has derived more or less of benefit in being present. This year your board of directors have prepare! a program relating especially 10 dairy farming, giving only those subjects which bear directly on ■silk production a place on the list This, together with the selection of speakers well qualified to handle their special assignments should nuke the pr— ent meeting the most Interesting and instructive in our No a»an Is entirely original in his work. The foundation for all PBK»IDE&gt;rs A&gt;MVL ADDKESS </seg>
            <seg id="p016">THIRTIETH A.NXt AL CONVENTION 17 his thoughts are obtained from others and by arranging what he MM and hears in a way to meet his own particular needs he is almost certain to increase his ability and develop his efforts to a more per- t enu Our meeting here is particularly for this purpose. We are litre afforded the opportunity to meet others who are following the same line of work and to get their views on matters pertaining to the dairy industry. After each address time will be given for thorough dis - cussion and if you want further information or wish to learn how any certain point particularly affects your business do not neglect to ask a question, for in this way and only in this way, do we remember. During the past year dairying has made good progress within our state. Dairy manufactures hare continue- to develop along lines best adapted to our particular needs, the numbers of strictly dairy cattle have materially increased and our market conditions have shown a healthy expansion. In a general way we have been affected by a nation-wide malady. The foot and mouth disease, which played such havoc in the eastern states has in a way constricted checked our growth for the present as it has cause! the destruction of many valuable cattle and has caused a quarantine to be placed on shipments of cattle into the state. We need more dairy cows and as we cannot draw them from the outside we take immediate measures to carefully husband our herds and make every effort to develop our own dairy stock and increase their numbers as rapidly as possible. The Federal Government is to be commended upon the prompt manner in which they are controlling this malady. It was only through extremely rigid quarantine regulations that the disease has been thus far kept under control. The dairy cattle exhibited at the National Dairy Show were all exposed to the disease and have for the most part recovered. Through the efforts of the owners these cattle have been isolated a short distance from Chicago and an effort will be made to study the disease and its after effects on these animals. The result of this project will add greatly to our present knowledge and will teach us how to combat similar contagious diseases in the future. The present world war has caused us to think more seriously of our immediate affairs for when it came upon us we were not entirely sure of the stability of our national business. As the war has continued, now - ever, we have gradually become accustomed to its influence so that, at the beginning of this new year we can realize that it will in no way decrease our promise of prosperity. This extreme calamity also teaches us the importance of the agricultural industries in maintaining a nation's welfare against the influence of outside disasters. Surely we should have faith in our industry and strive to maintain it as it is at present the greatest agricultural industry in the state. It was our ambition at the beginning of the present year to run a dairy train through a part of Nebraska as we did in the year pre- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">18 ceding. Thl» U such a bis undertaking, however, and the funds of the aaaaclatlon tre to meager that it became impossible. Primarily the Nebraska Dairymen's Association is an educational institution, and our earnest purpose should be to always keep the people of the state in losich with the progress and possibilities of dairying. It is inevitable, therefore, that aside from meeting here each year in anual session, we ahaaM do some work out in the field. To consummate this purpose fu4a mutt be made available and our only recourse is a larger ap - propriation from the state. It seems pertinent that we appoint a legis - lative committee to look after this matter and such other business as may affect dairying, before the legislature now in session. Wbea agricultural subjects were first introduced into the curriculum of our I'nlverslty dairying as at the present time, was one of the prin - riple cowraes of study and one of the first buildings to be erected on thU rampu* was the Dairy Building. At that early date it wag suf - fldul for the purpose but we all realize that on account of the present large enrollment of students in dairy subjects and on account of the ever Increasing number of problems calling for experimental investiga - tion ll U sow entirely Inadequate. I understand that the first building to be roastruoted In the agricultural group under the now available levy will be a dairy building. As this association dedicated the old bHlMlac years ago, I sincerely hope that we may in like manner dedi - cate the new building and in another year that we may meet in this n a* boate appropriately surrounded by the tools and emblems of our During the last few years of development in the dairy field the qwstloa of quality In dairy products has been a very important prob - lem. ThU qaeeUon has become especially important since the reduction la tae tariff permitting imported butter to compete with our butter on a saore eqaal footing. After a careful survey of the field and on account of our method of marketing it is very difficult to control the condition of tbe raw product. Education will aid in solving the problem, but H la ever so slow. The grading of cream with a consequent premium for a good article would aid us and should all other means fail I be - lieve It necessary for the good of the industry to frame laws regulating this point. It can be easily realized that sometime in the near future we saast have quality and the sooner we can improve our products so that they will meet the products of the entire world and stand the acM teat the better. If I were permitted to formulate a motto for this ts—rlitlon for the coming year and for all future time the thought • ould be simply this: "NOT MORE COWS, BUT BETTER COWS; XOT MORE BITTER. BUT BETTER BUTTER ' fae President: At this time it is a pleasure to me to call your - atteatloa to the fact that Mr. Hodgeson, the architect, having in charge tae plans for the new dairy building, is present in the room with those </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THIRTIETH AXM'AL CONVENTION 19 lans. I trust you will all avail yourselves of the opportunity of ex- amining them either at this time or at the noon hour. The next number on our program is the report of the secretary- treasurer, who will now give his annual report. Khl'OKT OK TKEASl KEK To the officers and members of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association: Herewith is presented, In a summary form, the transactions of the association for the year 1914. Respectfully submitted R. W. McGINMS, Treasurer, December 31, 1914. KcrripN Cash on han u January 1, 1914 $ 2.73 Received membership fees 215.00 Received state appropriation 1,462.06 Total $1,679.79 Expenditure* Paid— Badges S 55.43 Paid — Cow Judging premiums 158.70 Paid — State Treasurer membership fees 215.00 Paid — 'Expenses speaker to deliver address 34.79 Paid — J. W. Brewster, reporting proceedings 50.00 Paid — V. S. Culver, taking dairy census 11.00 Pai^ — Printing Annual Reports 375.00 Paid — Postage 44.94 Paid — Traveling expenses, officers 40.80 Paid— Office supplies 34.63 Paid — Balance expenses milk cow train 66.00 Paid — Stationery and printing 37.J0 Paid — Expenses annual meeting 97.80 Paid — Salary, Secretary, including November and December, 1913 350.00 Paid — Freight, telephone, express and Incidentals 11.53 Cash on hand 88.98 Total $1,679.79 The report of the Treasurer was referred to an auditing committee consisting of H. C. Young, T. A. Geirens, E. C. Woodward, Auditing Committee. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION 20 I will bow make my appointments of committees as follows The President: 1 am pleased to announce that Mr. ('. A. Nelson •f Waverley. Iowa, ha* arrived and he will now address us on the subject of "What Dairying Means to Your State." LMr C. A. NVImiii : Mr. President and Gentlemen of this Conven - , Farmer*, Legislators, Doctors, and every big man, and butter maker* of Nebranka: I am glad to be with you today. How many txiftrr-niakmt are there here today? You are pretty well represented. T«w arc not all farmers. I am proud of Nebraska. Iowa comes this morning to extend congratulations to her sister state on the west. I fo*l that It 1* a treat privilege and influence to live next to Nebraska, aM you people can congratulate yourselves that you live next to Iowa. The ftr»i time I ever heard 01 Nebraska it was not very favorable. A mi had rosae over here and had gone back to Iowa, and the report a« made was not good. You have a grand state here. You have sim - ilar condition* to those in Iowa. You have a splendid society and I am proud of Nebraska and to know that she is doing so well. We are ■at anxious to have our citizens come over here and buy your land. They ran bur their homes here perhaps a trifle cheaper than they can la low*. You are fooU enough to sell your alfalfa hay to feed to our cows. I coajsted alfalfa stacks on my way over here until I was satisfied you had a grot abundance of it. 1 also noticed some herds. I did not notice L&lt;l«al parpoae cow. The thoroughbred cows were under shelter. Your Iry cow must be very good as they have made something like ninety million dollars for your state. Alfalfa hay alone has not done that, •till I am glad to know that you have alfalfa hay. It is the thorough - bred dairy cow that counts. I also noticed silos. I am in favor of BM. I am sure It would not hurt you if you had a few hundred more re*r slate. The thoroughbred cow has made good in every respect. »jf are Increasing the Jairy output in every way. Just before I left M MM of them gave me twin calves. Xaw what has the dairy business done for your state? Iowa Is RE8ObL'TlOX8 COMMITTEE E T KBCTOK J. H. FRAXDSEX W. C. ANDREAS AUDITING COMMITTEE H 8 HM T. A GIEREXS E. C. WOODWARI .NOMINATIONS COMMITTEE C r UCIBBR8 A. L HAECKER A. E. WILKINSON 1.KGIS1.ATIVK COMMITTEE J H PKAIUON A. L. HAECKKR R. W. McGINXIS J S </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 21 a wonderful state. It is the biggest of the little states. She has thirty - five million acres of land and thirty million of them are under culti - vation. Our cattle are worth a million dollars. Our farm land is jump- wonderfully in price. What has caused this? Something has made it. One writer has said it is the o»ly state in the Union that is American. Our people are not all American but still more American than other - wise. Iowa is the most American state of any state in the Union be - cause her people are loyal to the government, loyal to everything that tends to build up a state. I do not say that that there are not foreigners within her borders but they are almost patriotic. We have no people wondering how Germany is going to come out; wondering how Iowa is going to come out or Wisconsin. We are not trying to beat Wiscon - sin, Illinois or Nebraska — we are simply trying to beat Iowa, make her record better, and if we do it will be because of the thoroughbred dairy cow. She has done more for the people than any other one ani - mal on the farm. One of the grandest things that God ever did was when he create-! the dairy cow. It took Him several thousand years to do it, but it has been done. He placed her on a business basis. Where- ?r we go and find the dairy cow, there we find prosperity. Why is that the dairy cow is a thing that brings prosperity? It is because -he is the gentle, good-natured animal that does things when she has a chance. When God brought a Savior to the world, where was He born? He was born in the cow stable. He wanted to place Him in an mosphere where there was gentleness surrounded by such a spirit that should have, and that the greatest personage in the world should have. I say to you, if you don't love the Savior of mankind you are not fit to have a dairy cow around you, because she is sweet, gentle and pure, and God loves her because she brings peace, prosperity, gentleness and joy to the world. When you buy a dairy cow you get eace an- prosperity. She buys the automobile, she buys the piano or the bouse, she buys horses and wagons. She creates an atmosphere f society, peace and joy, and brings everything to the home that makes society worth living. If you look at her record what has the dairy cow done? She is the only animal that goes out in the field, alfalfa field, corn field, and meadow and eats everything. What does she do? At night she brings in her reward to her owner that is to go out for the benefit of the human race. She enables you in every way to be a great man. At night she pays you for everything you have expended on her during the day and gives you a big profit. Did you ever hear anything like it? Of a cow paying for your time, paying you cash on the spot? She does not ask for a year's credit There is not another animal on the farm that gives cash for what they do. The dual purpose cow never pay her bills. You farmers are making a mistake in keeping the dual purpose cow, and especially in letting her go to the field for pasture at this time of the year. You are robbing yourselves and your family of the proper profits that you shouU be making. No man has a right to do anything that robs his family, his home, or his country or to do </seg>
            <seg id="p021">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION •B&gt;ifeing that In any way will lessen the greatness of man. If any of yoti fellows are working on that plan you are a disgrace to Nebraska. If you don't know where you are today by figures and by your cream ■alaawe aaefts, then you had better get wise and find out where you ar». kMttw you are losing money every day. What has the dual ywyOM cow done for Iowa* Answer: Iowa, in her early history, bad what might be called a dairy cow, a dual purpose cow. She helped %» brtofee over those early times when we raised corn and wheat and grain to ship to Chicago. Now it is different. Our farmers have the real dairy cow, thoroughbred cows. The cow of those early days helped I* lead the family while we were struggling to get a foot-hold, but now we have gotten our foot-hold and our thoroughbred cows and creamery •utloM have Increased our capacity for creating wealth. Iowa is as wealthy u any state In the Union. There are a few counties and in tbe MMttorn part of the county I live in that are not paying as strict attt-nilon to the thoroughbred cow as we are; but the; are fast cutting out the dual purpose cow. The dual purpose cow is an outlaw! tMilk ought to be sold for 50 cents a quart. If the people had to 40 cents a quart for milk, they might not pay for it long at that i. Look at pork, look at beef, look at everything that we buy. If liut milk where it belongs, pure, sweet and healthful and nice. 50 «MU w— Id not be too much, then where would the dual purpose cow go* Ik* would be ulicarded and everybody would buy a thoroughbred dairy cow. Blllle Bryan would have one — when they sent him back bore from Washington — everybody would buy a ftolstein thoroughbred dairy cow. Your country would increase millions upon millions in wealth, and no Iowa farmer, then, would be able to come over here and bay Nebraska land because you would forge to the front when prices earn* up to where they ought. Our ttatr it trying to pass a law now where milk shall be milk. It is the greatest thing we ever attempted. It will be the best thing erer aoae If It becomes a law — when the dirty farmers will be put out aa« when they will have to furnish and sell first-class clean milk 1 If plint I A dirty man cannot sell milk to white men. Such a law a* that will put our state way ahead of everything, so far, in this ••■■try. I hate to ship my milk to a factory where it is considered no totter than the milk of a very dirty farmer who allows bis hogs to wallow through it. so to speak; where all the fertility of the soil that tko eow happens to take on is not cleaned off by the farmer before bo milks, but Is shipped away in the milk. Look at the different dairy •Matrtea of the world. Are they fighting* No. Denmark is at peace with the world, and so is Holland. They are at peace milking the Holitrta eow. Look at 8wiuerland. look at the United States, look at all the dairy countries, they are at peace with God, man and the dairy eow. Look at Germany, it is a hog -eating country. Look at England. H la a beef eating nation. They and all other animal-eating countries are always fighting. You never find a dairyman fighting or quarreling. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THIRTIETH AXNl'AL CONVENTION 23 They are at peace with their families and the dairy cow. I tell you it is true that wherever the cow is shown and used as a part of the business and of the borne, there you find the highest state of civiliza - tion. There the children are going to school to be educated in dairying and then come back to the farm to make it proiuce more than the father ever did. It is a great subject for consideration. If every farmer in Iowa was a dairyman you could not buy land there for $1,000 an acre. If you have never been in the dairy business you can little realize how much a man can pay for land or what interest he can pay. There is no animal that keeps the farm in such a splendid condition of fertility as the dairy cow. In Iowa and in Nebraska too much of the virgin soil has been shipped away in the sale of wheat and corn; the farmers have not thought or cared much about what becomes of the farm in the future or the future generation. But you will see that that time is coming when the fertility of the soil will be gone where nothing but grain, corn and wheat is raised and shipped away from the farm. By the use of dairy cows the fertility of the soil is maintained. In that way the fertility of the soil and the prosperity of the farm has been maintained and millions of young men have been kept at home instead of looking for more lucrative business in the cities and towns. Where dairying has been followed you cannot buy the land for $1,000 an acre. Where they have not kept a dairy they have robbei the soil and many of them are now coming back to the dairy cow. We sent out a dairy train through the state of Iowa and held institutes and farmers' con - ventions and the result has been wonderful. It was visited by hundreds farmers all along the line. Our next step will be the organization of each county and put a man in there who will go from house to house and compel farmers to see that which is best for them and their farms. If we cannot get the best thing at all times we must go after it. I tell you what Iowa has done and if it will not convince any common-sense farmer he ought to be sent to the state penitentiary. A man, who will sit around and do nothing, never try to build up his boys and girls who will never try to build them up into stately manhood and womanhood on his farm. — he is the man that we have to fear. He is an anarchist, and a man who is not trying to do everything he can to help his family and the state, who does not care whether he goes to an election or not, who does not care whether you dairy or not, or whether he does or not, and who does not care whether he properly feeds his horse3 and cows, — he is an anarchist. He is not doing anything at all towards building up the statt. 1 might say we have a lot of them in Iowa the same as any other state. They are back numbers. We have to send a special m»n to them in order to convince them, or to get their boys to attend a dairy school and get a dairy education. We have some wealthy farm - ers in Iowa. Many art' run down at the heel, however, and not fit to be called farmers. They make their money not only by the sweat of their brow, but by working every member of their family in the field and working themselves like dogs. The value of their farms has in- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">24 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION creased by the crops they have by good luck and by good years, and by CvlB* their own way in everything, by saving and skimping and starv- I their families. I can point out their children when I see them. TtMJT always run their tongues out when they see anybody. They are so bashful, and they have to cross their toes before they go to sleep. TWy are- the fellow* who are keeping down the enterprising farmers of Iowa They don't buy any newspapers and if you ever ask them if they waat to subscribe, they get very wise, look you in the face as tfc— 1» they would give you to understand that they were no fools and as much as to say, "I know as much as them college professors. They go around the country preaching while we are at home doing real work." That is the conation of things with some of the farmers. If you get all the enterprising, honest farmers of the middle west you will find that they are the fellows who are feeding the world. They are the fellows who do things. I tell you the time Is coming when land will •» ml up into smaller farms with more intensified farming and with more beautiful, lovely homes. I don't believe you will find a climate anywhere belter than in Iowa and Nebraska. When Ood made man he did not send him down here as a joke If He had left him in the Adam and Ere state, it might have been a Jok*. If Adam and Eve had had some good dairy cows they never wow Id have fallen into sin. but with nothing to do they committed the sia an: then the trouble began. I believe God wanted man to have trouble because that is what makes men and women, and what makes as better through the experience we get. If this experience and trouble that man Is having doesn't make the man better, I do not know what will ■make us better. The easiest way and the safest way to do it — I say it It the Sate way — If exactly by the route of the thoroughbred Holstein cow. That will save everybody and make our homes everywhere better Mi beautiful and put everybody on a social footing. I noticed la a recent Issue of a Chicago paper an account of 200 men being offered Jobs m Michigan. They were in charity hospitals or ■ onm and they refused the offer of $25 a month to go up into Michigan aad work. They said they did not want to work in Michigan, but wanted to work 1b Chicago. If I had been president of that charity organiza - tion those men would have had to shuffle out into the snow or else MMpt the offer of $15 in Michigan. The idea of feeding a lot of peo - ple and then when work comes to them they will not accept! Such charity la all wrong. I would not have had them one minute. If they aid not work they would have to get out and rustle. That is what makes us a better nation, by getting out and working and doing things. Ton can neither beat nor cheat all of the American people at the same time. The day Is coming when we will all see things running right. Perhaps It may not be Just exactly as we would state it now but it will b# right. 1 hare thought about this dairy cow business until I believe It is the only business for the farmer. We all want minds of our own, e*ws of our own and property of our own. Someone has said that if </seg>
            <seg id="p024">25 THIRTIETH ANNIAL CONVENTION all people thought the same way they would all be alike and there would be no difference. We all want characters of our own, both in private and in public life. I have a neighbor who has a son who is learning to be a dairy farmer. That father is under my instruction. He is now in favor of the Holstein cow. Dairy education is becoming very general in our state, and especially in our county. We are now making over 8,000 pounds of butter to the square mile. We now have creameries and cheese factories. If you are looking for land you cannot find a finer piecf of land in Iowa. Twenty years of my life has been spent there and I know. I have seen it change from a beef cattle country to a dairy country. When I became interested in Holstein cattle and bought that breed of cattle they called me a blamed old fool. They said they always knew that I was a fool but when I bought the black and white cow and brought her into that county there was nothing there but the dual pur - pose cow. When I put that Holstein herd in, there was not a thorough - bred cow in that county. Now there are thirty-five herds. At that time there was not a silo in the county. Now there are four or five hundred silos. Riding along the other day in the car I counted twenty - six silos within a short distance. I will say that there are many farm- rs who put in two silos. There is also a better method of feeding, specially for the dairy cow. Farmers find so much difference in the amount of work and the amount of milk production in having silos over the ol- way of letting the cow forage in the field. There are more boys going to dairy schools from that county than ever before; and we have a splendid system of schools in Beemer county. The only thing that can be said against that county is that she has licensed the sale of malt and spirituous liquors, she is a saloon county. But our legislature is going to repeal that law and no one will be able to buy liquor in that county after that. I am not a booze-fighter as some are in Nebraska. If you come over there after we have changed our law you will have to drink Holstein milk and that might make some people sick. The saloon takes off the men, the saloon fills the jails with men, the saloon keeps the penitentiary full of men, and our reform schools busy in taking care of the children of the disobedient. The minute the saloon closes in Iowa, or any other place for that matter, anil the dairy cow gets its work in, it will change the order of civilization. That is encouraging. I like to look upon the bright side of life. I could tell you many things about the bitter disappointments I have had in getting my dairy herd. Your heart would be full of disappointments should I tell you of the trials and patience I have had to exercise — patience in regari to th« building up of the herd, patience in regard to the foot and mouth dis - ease and weeding out the scrubs. All of this has cost me thousands of dollars. All this experience will make men worth more to themselves, to the church, to the school and the country as well as your sons and daughters. What are we living for if not to make ourselves, our chil - dren and the country better? I have had a hard and checkered expei- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">26 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION •me* in forging ahead to my present condition. People would say to M*eaa«n, "Have you heard of Nelson?" "No, Who is Nelson?" Do you, ferMn, know yourselves? Have you yet had an introduction to your - selves? Do you know your capabilities and whether you could select and brawl up a food dairy cow? Do you know whether that cow could lire without you? Can your wife live without you? If she can then the thoroMChbred HoUteln ilalry cow can. I don't want you to have her if IN cta'l lire with her. because owning the dairy cow means to have a •w**t tamper and the doing of things about her that are seasoned with tfptr The dairy cow is bettering the conditions of mankind. I be - eam« acquainted with myself one morning when I awoke to the fact that 1 was living far behind and beneath the ordinary citizen. My father wu a soldier. He gave me an education that he thought perhaps WSS sufficient for me as a farmer in those days. He never gave me an edu - cation that I sbouii have had because an education a few years ago for tka farmer wu not counted for much. He thought if I could ad, subtract. multiply in figure and read a little that that was enough, that the farmer did not need anything more, and that it was not necessary for me !• know anything because he was not educated. Learning was cheap. and the life of the farmer was cheap, everything was cheap and that is Ik* reason that my father did not educate me. I woke to the fact that I ueiicvf that I deserved an (duration and 1 said to myself. I will rise, thing* that I believed would be for my betterment. aid front that time 1 began to study and investigate and put in practi Bo you see. fellow farmers, the value that I put on a university education. By It you become better enabled to fulfill the duties and re- MWMlbiUUea of life no matter whether on the farm, in the church or la the legislature. That Is the value I put upon school education. I iBllk we have one of the greatest institutions over at Ames that there is: perhaps no better than you have here, but, undoubtedly, a little more advanced. But It is one of the finest institutions that can be placed within the borders of any state. It is one of the institutions of learning that la doing more good to build up the young men of our nation tfcu anything else except, perhaps, the church. Of course, the church goal hand in hand with everything along the line of civilization. I am MM &gt; Stickler for any particular creed of the Christian religion, but I am • Mathodlat myself. I know I am better for having been regenerated. W« must all come up through trouble and trials to the proper sense of what life is, to know what you are and where you are going. You Ky worship wherever you may, but you must worship at the shrine of in* truth I am no smarter than you are; you no smarter than I. Perhaps I should not say that these college professors do not know any more than i, but they do not in all tbings. We are on very much of an equal - ity Ik many things. By the use of what we have we apply our knowledge 10 fealM up our characters. How is it that it makes one man smart and aaother man a fool; makes one man broad in his views and another man </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 27 narrow? He is not always just as big as he thinks he is, and no older. it is the development of the brain that makes this difference. The con - sideration of these things brought me more than money. I am not Hy - ing now for money. If I weTe, I would be a failure. Perhaps I waa hasty in accepting your invitation to come to Nebraska at this time, but I love to make friends. I wanted to see you and to snake your hands, for if we ever get to heaven there will be no Iowa, Nebraska or any other state over there but the sweet and pure life of communion. All these thoughts add to my comfort and blessing. That is the reason I came over to see you. I can say I am glad I am among the living. I am glad that you extended the invitation to me. When I was on the farm and before coming to a propor realization of what I was or might be, $4 a day behind a team I thought was enough. I was a good hand in the field, but I soon found I could find men cheaper and that I was worth more than they; that I could hire a man for |2o&gt; a month, but I believed I was worth $200 a month behind a cow. Farmers, don't you think yon are worth more at the barn, more around the house, more superintend - ing the affairs of your business than you are in the field with a team? You may be poor, you may have to work hard, but I tell you that just as quick as I could I dropped much of that field work and gave my services, my knowledge and experience to taking care of the dairy cow. I weighed the milk, I 'ested the milk. I knew erery day where I stood. Somebody asks you what have you made this year, and if you have it in dttail on the balance sheet you can read it off like a book from the first day of January to the last day of the year. There Is no consola - tion to the enterprising and ambitious farmer so great as to know e tunds in Us business. The farmer has heretofore not been looked upon as favorable for positions of trust in the state. He has been called a hay-seed, or even "any old thing," because of his position. That is the reason he has never been in the legislature and never been elected as governor or president, but the farmer is beginning to be looked upon with more re - spect. Today he is enjoying more than ever before the position that tie should as a farmer. He Is filling the banks with money and making the people of the state stand up and take notice. Twenty years from cow you will find his sons filling the chair of governor and occupying positions of trust in the legislature, in the halls of congress and in both public and private life. He will make laws that will be more suitable for the agriculturalist and the farmer — not that I would have him discriminate against other citizens of the state. I believe every man should have justice. Nine - tenths of the farmers are better equipped to make laws than the law - yers. Lawyers make laws for the lawyers. So often we hear of such and such a law being "unconstitutional," and that in such and such a case an injunction is served, or some writ of habeas corpus, and mat - ters become conglomerated and mixed. I want the farmer to take his place in the business world and in society. I would not want him to </seg>
            <seg id="p027">28 tan anarchUt or a socialist, but I want him to be an honest man and believe that every other man should have his just dues. The dairy - a should be honest as well as the merchant. LI sold my whole herd of cattle, of dual purpose cows, for $1,200. I »e sold thorough-bred dairy cows, one of which would bring as much aa $M« or MOO or |1,000. That price is nothing for a good thorough - bred dtirjr COW. Just think of what you are losing by not having the »r«pw kind of cows to make the proper kind of profit for you. By that kind of a dairy heri your profits would be from $2,000 to $14,000 a year. At that price your land could not be bought and the banks would be fall of your money. These are conditions and prospects that you need and should have in Nebraska. They belong to you. Gentlemen, I have not tried to flaunt myself or my abilities in any way before you today, but I have just tried to show you the better aid the most profitable way of farming, a way of looking upon the bright aid* of everything and trying to make the world better and evtrythlng around you better. The farmer has a right to claim these ihlngi. 1 have seen Beemer county change from a beef feeding county to a dairy country. I-and is higher in Beemer county than in any other Cinty except it might be Black Hawk county. I told the farmers m they came to meet the dairy train throughout the state that their land was worth $500 an acre and they again called me a fool. You can get Into a quarrel quicker by telling them that than anything else. They doat like the idea of land being worth $500 an acre, because that value weald require them to have brains to run It and make it pay. I have ■om land in Black Hawk county sell for $505 an acre, and land in ■mbmt county sell from $200 to $300 an acre. That requires better buildings and better conditions. It ought to be sufficient inducement for the boys and girls to quit thinking of going to the towns and cities, but learn to work the farm and work it better than their fathers did. Wkat has this condition of things done for Iowa? It has put Iowa on the Bap all over the world. And it is the dairy cow that has done it aad built up the soil. We are also growing better corn, better hogs, kMaar b*af cattle and everything better. It is the dairy cow's business to increase and make more valuable everything about the farm. Iowa soli Is good, and I want to congratulate you upon your soil, which win soon improve if you follow the dairy business. I am not looking for cheap land. When I went into the dairy business I imme - diately determined to improve the soil of my farm, which has been done 1 am one of those who believe that the farmer should have as good at anyone else. My dairy herd is the best I have been able to make It, and the great trouble that is now on my mind is to know what to do with it when I am gone. Some day I expect to pass away. and then what will become of my herd? I have no boy that I can giTt It to that will take hold and carry on and still continue to build up one of the best herds In the- land. I woul- like to call your attention, gentlemen, before I close, to </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 29 the value of a testing association which shall test roar milk. I tell you it will enable you to build up your herd. It will tell you where each individual cow stands. Whether she Is making you a protlt or not, and If a profit, how much, and whether it Is the profit you should bare. I am glad, gentlemen, to be with you today. I want you now to go out and, in the strength of your manhood, to build up your dairy, your family, the community where you live and the church you attend!. Hare a purpose and an aim to live for all the good that you can do. If yon don't there is a responsibility resting upon your shoulders. I hare shown you enough, if you never hear anything more, to enable yon to become a great man in your business and in your life, and to fill the Important places in both public and private life. I thank yon. (Ap- The President: We are all glad to receive the message that Mr. Nelson has brought us from Iowa. Personally, I am glad that he could be with us this year. We have heard about dairying in Iowa. I want Mr. Nelson and you to know also that we have dairying west of here, and the next number on our program this morning Is on the subject of "Advantages of Dairying in Western Nebraska," by Lieut - enant Governor J. R. Pearson. ADVANTAGES OF DAIRYING I&gt; WESTERN NKBK1SK \. Address of James Pearson, Lieutenant Governor, before the Nebraska State Dairy Association, January 20, 1915. Mr. President and Gentlemen :- I realize that it is nearly noon and therefore I will be quite brief. I have not prepared as completely as I should, but shall confine my re - marks to a few items I have jotted down. There are natural conditions in the west just as there are in all parts of the state — certain conditions that have to be met Too often people try to make conditions come their way instead of the people meeting the conditions. Many people go west and the very first thing they think of is farm - ing those broad fields that are spread out before them. Forthwith they go to work breaking out the ground, and thus thousands of acres have been broke that should not have been. Some years great crops arc produced and some years the crops are light or a failure. After a few light crops the farmer finds himself discouraged, and the first chance he gets he sells, and the new man breaks out a little more. When we do have a crop in the west it is a bumper, but the uncer - tainty of crop years puts up a condition that must be met. In early days the west was considered a range country and, of course, was sparsely settled. Great herds of beef cattle grated over the plains formerly trod by the buffalo. No thought of dairying was even considered then, because butter was not worth hardly anything. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">30 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION As years passed and land values in eastern Nebraska and across the Mlaaouri River became very high, the tide of homeseekers drifted west. The ranches were divided up Into homesteads. The lack of rain and the hot winds (from Kansas) soon demonstrated the uncertainty of real farming. A new method must be inaugurated or the west must be abandoned. In some places it seemed at one time that abandon - ment would have to be. A little later the cream markets came for - ward until now the cash is ready for the cream every day. Passenger trains carry splendid cream cars all over this state. Market advantages are most excellent. Thousands upon thousands of acres of grass (not as high as timothy or alfalfa, but rich natural grass) goes to waste every year. At the same time thousands of people in these large cities are living in a mere existing state of being; dependent for work, and when unable to procure work, dependent upon charity. Would it not be very profitable to encourage these two conditions to meet, the unem - ployed to go upon those lands, even as renters, with only a very few rows, and grow up with the country, have pure air to breathe, pure, fresh water and milk to drink; the children to go to a rural school, even though a sod structure (better for them than growing up as waifs of the city streets and educated, half-hearted, in crowded ward schools. I wish I had an audience of those people. 1 feel for them and I know a chance is before many of them in western dairy conditions. It is not absolutely necessary that a beginner should buy expensive cows like those Brother Nelson has, but get such cows as your finances will stand, and then take good care of them. Build up a herd in time. Western Nebraska always has grass and a crop of forage. By using the silo, as is being done more and more each year, the feed question is pretty well solved. In many cases silos can be simply dug, Just a big hole in the ground, which is very cheap an I effective. We have a very healthy climate. High, dry altitude, plenty of pure water. Some places the wells are deep, but an endless amount of water, and by putting up windmills and tanks (we have plenty of wind to run the mills) the water question is solved. LMany men have financial failures in the west because they tried farm field crops only. They would put in a couple hundred acres of corn, go over it a couple of times with a two-row machine, and if the crop was poor call it bad luck and try again, etc. Others have went right on through the light crops that have visited certain parts of the west in good shape by milking a bunch of cows. Cream checks, calves and a few pigs raised on the skim milk have kept up all the expenses of the home and farm. At the same time those men go ahead with field crops, and whatever they raise in the way of crops to sell is Just that much clear profit, while the fellow who will not milk cows gets in debt so bad through light crop yean that it will take a couple bumper crops o ever square him up; without getting ahead. Now land in Eastern Nebraska and Iowa is high, very high, conse - quently we have lots of Iowa people who come to Western Nebraska to </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THIRTIETH AXNTAL CO.VVEXTIOX 31 mike a living. We have an area of almost 78,000 square miles and a population of nearly 1.200,000 people. Draw a line across the state from north to south so that you have one-half of the land on either side and you will have about one-seventh of the people on the west side of the line, six-sevenths of them, on the east side. That means that 39,000 western sections hare about 171,000 people and that 30,000 eastern sections have about 1,028,000 people. These figures will just give yon some idea of the wonderful acreage advantage the western man hat over the eastern man. It must be remembered that dairying in the west requires atten - tion just as in every other part of the state. Automobiles have been known to be detrimental in many cases; that simply by going off to town (or some other seaport) and staying until late at night, leaving the milking until nearly midnight or possibly until morning. Dairying sometimes is a failure, but always for a cause, vii. : in - ferior animals, inferior feeding or inferior care. Many western fel - lows run short of feed because of not having siloed a plenty In proper time. That is their fault, not the fault of the country. Sometimes you will see printed matter, issued by land agents, Mt - tinp forth the big crops raised, etc., all of which may be true; but re - member those crops do not appear every year. You must not figure on a wheat and corn check every year, but with a herd of good dairycows you can figure on a cream check every month. Western Nebraska raises choice corn and Email grain, and some years produces in great abundance, but not every year. I do not mean to say we should quit farming out west, but I do say dairy and farm both, as the cream is sure and the field crop possible. Mr. President, I want to add that the old hen is also a great bene - factor to the western people. Poultry and eggs are good prices and cash markets await every egg or chicken. I can remember years ago when eggs were five and eight cents per dozen and chickens twenty to twenty-five cents apiece. How different the conditions now. Western Xebraska has a rich soli, great broad acres of grass and fields. Opportunity awaits the man who will go into the west and look well after his cow and hens, as well as his fields. Farm less acres and milk more cows, that is the idea. If you won't milk or care for poul - try, don't come west; but if you are willing to meet those conditions just as they are, come west, you, and all your wife's relations. The west is not a fruit growing country, generally speaking, and if people want to engage in such other industries not In line with nautral conditions, they should seek those parts naturally adapted to such conditions. The fundamental principles, "Mr. President," is to meet the conditions of nature, that is what I mean. The west has ideal dairy conditions, most emphatically so, and as fast as the people are educated to those facts, just that fast will the west come into its own as a new empire. It is necessary in every avenue of life, in ordter to gain success, </seg>
            <seg id="p031">32 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION that you put forth every effort within your power. If you come west to build a home, remember that the laws of natural conditions are ever present and you must abide by them, with a whole-souled energy. The dairy cow, properly handled, is the keynote to the successful western home builder. (Generally speaking). tCome ye that are heavily ladened, from the cities and carve for urself a life of more independence; out on the plains with the cow the dependable source of Income. Thank you. Whereupon this meeting took a recess until 1 o'clock p. m. STATE FARM, WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 20, 1915 Afternoon Hvswion The President called the association to order and announced that the first number on the program would be a paper by Prof Frandsen on the subject of "Dairy Farm and Herd Management." DAIRY KARJI A&gt;D HEHI» tfAMGEMM By J. H. FRANDSEN, Professor of Dairy Husbandry University of Nebraska. Mr. President and Gentlemen: As the title indicates, I will endeavor to deal only with the busi - ness side of dairying in this paper. Dean E. H. Bailey says: "The requirements of a good farmer are at least four: The ability to make a full and comfortable living from the land; To rear a family carefully and well; To be of good service to the community; To leave the farm more productive than it was when he took it. In my estimation these requirements can most easily be met by the good dairy farmer. It is my earnest desire that this thought may re - ceive the most careful consideration of an ever-increasing number of Nebraska farmers. It is encouraging to know that here in Nebraska the growth of dairying has been on the increase with the necessity for more intensive methods of farming as the cost of land has ad - vanced. The farmers of Nebraska are at present milking about 700,000 dairy cows whose product for 1614 was about $21,000,000. STOCK FARMING AS COMPARED WITH GRAIN FARMING The following statistics show the average income per acre from grain farms and stock farms in several middle western states and also the average for the United States. Although no statistics are available regarding the Income from grain and stock farms In this state, Ne - braska conditions will be found very similar to those of Illinois and </seg>
            <seg id="p032">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 33 Grain Stock 110.60 $12.54 inc Missour 7.69 9.55 «a 8.8« 13.17 &lt;n 7.72 11.99 ncreased income from stock farming over grain farming mounted to 18 per cent in Illinois, 24 per cent in Missouri and 48 p«r :n low UGGESTIOXS FOR DAIRY FARMERS r and better developed states are still far in advance of Ne- braska in the number of dairy cows, as shown by the following statistics: The state of New York has 30.4 cows per square mile; Wisconsin, 26.83 cows per square mile; Iowa, 24.84 cows per square mile; Kansas, 8.5 cows, and Nebraska 7.9 cows per square mile. This shows that dairying has been developed as a leading industry in states where land is high priced and intensive methods of farming are followed. Our cheaper ands give Nebraska a special advantage in marketing high priced pro - ducts, since the freight on butter and other dairy products to large -ntral markets is very much less than the freight upon wheat, corn ay and other coarse products. DAIRYING CONSERVES FERTILITY By marketing the products of the farm in the form of butter or ream, only 5 per cent of the fertility contained in farm crops is sold n the product. When marketing corn, wheat, hay, etc., practically all ertility required to grow the crop is sold from the farm. Thus, by ng raw materials of the farm to dairy cows, we are not only manu- facturing high price: products, but retaining upon the farm almost all tilizing material taken from the soil by the growing crop. THE PERSONAL EQUATION It is certainly true in dairying, as in any other business, that one's success in a large measure is gauged by his love and interest in the business. The personal equation is an important factor here as else - where. Success or failure to a large extent depends on the kind of a man in charge of the business. If a man has no natural inclination towards the cows, if he is unwilling, so to speak, to form a partnership with her, his chances for profit from her products are quite remote. The successful dairyman is not only a good farmer, but he must be a good business man from a producer's and manufacturer's stand - point. It is his particular business to select such a dairy machine as will most efficiently manufacture the rough, coarse products of the farm, such as alfalfa, silage and the grains, into a high priced, con - centrated article like milk and butter fat, and to so manage this bust- </seg>
            <seg id="p033">34 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION ness as to get maximum results from his dairy machine. He will find that there are many advantages in having cows freshen In the fall or early winter because in Nebraska butter is generally fully one-third higher In winter than in summer. Cows which freshen in the early winter time and are well cared for go on pasture at the time when they would naturally be drying up, and this lengthens the milking period an. increases the annual yield fully twenty-five per cent; besides, the farmer hag more time to milk cows in winter than at any other season. LOCATION OF DAIRY FARM The location of the dairy farm is a question that must be decided largely by the individual farmer. However, it depends; 1st. On the amount of capital to be invested; 2nd. On whether a highly specialized form of dairying, such as re - tailing, is to be carried on, or whether dairy products are to be sold in the form of cream or butter; whether one desires to develop the pure brei cattle business or do the work to a large extent with grade cattle; 3rd. There must be adequate market facilities. If one is engaged in the production of cream, perhaps it is not difficult to secure sufficiently good market or railroad facilities, but if a market for milk or sweet cream, of pure bred stock is desired, It is absolutely essential that at - tention be paid to the question of location in relation to markets; 4th. It is generally desirable that consideration be given to the matter of selecting the dairy farm community, for in this way one can take advantage of the benefits that come from being engaged in a busi - ness for which the community has already established a reputation. It also makes it possible to secure co-operation in the matter of building up the best herds and in developing the best market where products can be sold to the best advantage. SIZE OF DAIRY FARM No definite suggestion can be given regarding the sire of the farm as that depends on very many factors, such as fertility of the soil, the rainfall, and other climatic conditions, and on the general management of the farm— whether there are to be side lines such as hogs, poultry, cash crops, etc. The farm should be of such a sUe as to proiuce all the dairy feeds that can be grown economically in the particular sec - tion in which it is located. From a farm management standpoint it should be of such size as to make most efficient use of labor, horse power and machinery. For example, if a farm of 160 acres can be worked efficiently with about the same man and horse power and machinery as 120 acres, the farm would with good management yield a greater in - come even though part of the crops could not be utilized by the dairy </seg>
            <seg id="p034">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 35 AMOUNT OF FEED NEEDED PER COW The amount of feed needed for each cow depends upon whether the cows are to be allowed the usual amount of pasture or whether they are to be kept up. It should, however, be generally understood that while some pasture is desirable, the teed secured in this way the most expensive feed the cow gets. The cow in pasture will need for the year from one and one-half to two tons of alfalfa and from fire to six tons of corn silage. If kept entirely off pasture she will need from two and one-half to three tona alfalfa with six to seven tons of corn silage. THE LABOR PROBLEM ON THE DAIRY FARM Without doubt the question of securing competent labor on the airy farm as well as for general farm work is one of the real prob- lems confronting the farmer. The scarcity of labor on the farm is due mainly to the following factors: 1. The failure of the farmer to so diversify or intensify his fanning perations as to make it posible for him to furnish steady employment the year around. 2. Failure of young men to really appreciate rural conditions ompared to work in other lines, wages, privileges, etc. 3. Unwarranted dislike of the work and life under farm condi - tions — in rural districts. Perhaps the principal cause of this dislike is the apparent lack of amusements, lack of something new, long hours of work and poor board. 4. Uncomfortable surroundings between working hours. 5. Employees' inability to intelligently direct or explain the under - lying principles of the work involved, so as to make it of interest to the man doing the work. That these factors, real or imaginary, exist in the minds of the hired men may as well be conceded at the outset These objections or prejudices, as the case may be, must be over - come by the dairyman before he can secure and keep the most desirable and efficient kind of help so necessary in the operation of a dairy farm. In regard to the first factor, it might be stated that the success - ful dairyman has his work sufficiently diversified and uniform through - out the year so that he can offer steady employment throughout the year. This should appeal to the ambitious, intelligent laborer, as it does not necessitate his seeking employment in the city for several months each year. No laborer can satisfactorily train himself for both rural and city work, consequently, he follows the lines of least resistance and secures the more steady work in the city, though naturally his training and taste would be in favor of country life. Many young men are entirely misled by the apparent attractive sal - aries offered in cities which likely would cease to have its attraction If they realized the heavy expenses involved by life in the city — that </seg>
            <seg id="p035">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION 36 board and room under city conditions becomes a very serious factor in reducing the glimmering salary used as a bait in calling them to the They often fail also to give consideration to the monotony of fac - tory life, the insanitary surroundings, bai air and lack of healthful ex - ercise without which the health is frequently undermined in a few short years. The charge that there is on the farm in many cases no effort made to provide amusement or to reduce long hours of toil is not without foundation. While it is undoubtedly true that emergencies arise that call for hard work and long hours, nevertheless a sincere effort should be made to so systematize the work as to accomplish maximum results n definite regular hours. Frequently, by carefuT and judicious planning, more work can be accomplished in this way than by haphazard routine covering a longer time. As a matter of fact, much of the hired man's prejudice against dairying arises from the fact that on some dairy arms it is customary to annex dairy work to an otherwise full day's work. In the strong dairy sections of the eastern states the owner tells us that the time spent with the dairy cows is the most profitabk of the day's routine. He is. therefore, perfectly willing to plan the work bo that the milking becomes a regular part of the day's work instea of being considered something in addition to a day's work. Lack of amusement mentioned by some as an objection to farm life can be solved to a certain extent by the thoughtful manager by catering to a small extent the desires and wishes of the young man in his employ. First, by keeping his mind busy while at work and off work; by entrusting him with limited responsibilities, such as fe&lt; valuable calves, care of the cows on test, keeping of cow records couraging him in asking questions concerning the underlying pri practices and progress of the work in hand. The normal healthy boy craving for diversion or amusement should at U-ast to a certain extent be recognized. It can be done even under farm conditions. Perhaps boxing gloves, a punching bag, a few maga - zines and farm papers will do the trick. In some cases, neighborhood baseball clubs will satisfy their every want along this line, or a trip to town on certain half holidays or evenings — as seems best under existing circumstances. The kind of help most desired for farm work is, of course, an in - telligent human being and will not be satisfied by having assigned to him a cold, dingy, insanitary room. It will generally be found a good investment to provide cheerful, comfortable quarters for the help. This may be done by assigning a room in the house for the hired man's use or where there are a number of men, a comfortable bunk house may be built for their use at moderate cost. In many dairy sections the labor question has been solved by the erection of small cottages so that accommodations may be provided for married men. In many ways, this simplifies the situation, as under </seg>
            <seg id="p036">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 37 this condition the farmer does not have to provide board and would be relieved of many of his social obligations. However, one of the strongest arguments in favor of turning more to the married men for the hired man is the fact that a man married and settled down In a comfortable location is more satisfactory and will be more reliable, steady and dependable for the work so necessary on the dairy farm. THE DAIRY HERD Show colored slides of dairy breeds) In selecting a breed for the dairy farm it Is well to consider the purpose for which the product is to be used. That is, If rlchnesa i* not demanded, it obviously would be to the breeder's Interest to select a breed giving large quantities. If rich or highly colored milk la de - sired, other factors should govern. However, if cream is sold no par - ticular consideration on this point is necessary, except as to whether a large or small amount of skim milk is desirable along with the butter fat. Some attention should, however, properly be given to the character and quantity of feeds available. If a small quantity of concentrated feeds is most available, such breeds as by size and environment have adapted themselves to these conditions are most desirable, such as the Jerseys and Guernseys. On the other hand, if the locality produces )arse. rough feeds more abundantly and economically, a large, rugged breed, such as the Holstein, Ayrshire or Brown Swiss should be given consideration. Where experience and capital will permit, it is desirable to go in for ure bred stock. This is particularly true in this state as long as we can enjoy the present phenomenal demand for better dairy stock. In this connection it may be of interest to know that thousands of inferior dairy cows are annually shipped into Nebraska from the eastern state*. The only excuse for this has been the absolute impossibility of secur- dairy stock from reputable home breeders. In a general way it is best to combine the production of dairy products and the production of dairy stock. If the herd is started by purchase, great care should be exercised as most of the animals found for sale are the lowest producing ones, or yet worse, those suffering from diseases so objectionable from the dairyman's point of view; for example, tuberculosis and contagious abortion. Perhaps for the man with small capital and only ordinary experience, no better ad - vice can be given than to select the best possible grade cows of the breed desired, and then select with the greatest care a pure bred sire. By this plan the poorer cows can soon at small expense be placed by the heifers from the best producing cows. In this way a high pro - ducing herd will have been secured in a few years and at a relatively small outlay. In the meantime the farmer has gained valuable experi - ence which will make it possible and profitable for him later to engage in the pure bred stock business, should he so desire. To quote from Ex- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">38 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION Governor Hoard: "It is better to grow into dairy farming than to go into it." Although starting in with grade cows, the dairyman should certainly bear in mind that he cannot afforj to head his herd with anything less than a good pure bred sire. In selecting such a sire, the most important bing to consider is the performance of his ancestors, and especially lis dam, for it is a recognized fact that high producing cows reproduce heir characteristics through their sons much more readily than through their daughters. Therefore, it is highly important that the dam's form, milk producing machinery and her milk record: be given careful scrut - ny. Of course, the bull himself should show good dairy type, but this should not be the leading guide in his selection, for outward appearances do not always corerspond to his ability to beget high producing daugh - ters. Although a bull of such type will cost what may seem a very high price, if we remember that "The bull is half the herd," we will soon realize that he is a bargain at any price — while a bull that lowers the average production of the herd instead of raising it from fifty to one hundred pounds is a luxury which no dairyman can afford to meddle with, even though a scrub may be had at a small cost. By the use- of a good dairy sire and the best grade cows which the capital invested will permit, by the judicious use of herd records, scales and the Babcock test for weeding out the lowest producing cows, and by gradually replacing these with the heifers from the best cows, it require* only a period of three or four or five years to build up a herd which will put the dairy farmer on the high road to success. In the matter of care and feed for the dairy bull the same careful methods bold as in the care of cows. The old practice of allowing him to run with the cows should never be permitted. Moreover, he is naturally of a nervous disposition and therefore should not be excited or teased in any way. He should be provided with comfortable quarters, sanitary and well ventilated, and given the run of a small lot or pasture wbere he may get the exercise so important to his welfare, or he may the same as for a cow in milk. He should have less roughage, a mod - erate amount of silage and the same grains as are used for milk production. AGE OF BULL FOR SERVICE While there is a slight difference in age of maturity of bulls from different breeds it is generally estimated that light service can be secured from a bull eleven months of age. However, it is not advise - able to breed more than two cows per week up to the time he is fifteen months old. As he matures the amount of service may be increased gradually. As the average herd is managed no one bull should be ex - pected to breed more than forty or fifty cows. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 39 SELECTING THE DAIRY COW The essential points of a good dairy cow are indications of con - stitutional vigor, good capacity, development of the nervous system, good blood circulation, and the ability to produce milk abundantly. 1. Constitution.. .Well-distended nostrils and good heart girth, due to breadth and depth of chest, are the best indications of that quality health and vigor commonly referred to as constitution. 2. rood Capacity. Great length from shoulder to hip bones, together with great width and depth of barrel, indicates well-developed digestive organs, which enable the cow to consume and digest large quantities af food. •"t. »rvous System, or Nervous Temperament. A good dairy cow is active and intelligent. Large, bright eyes, set rather far apart, a broad, well-dished face, and a spare and angular form are good indications nervous temperament. 4. Blood Circulation. A good circulatory system is necessary to carry the digested food from the abdominal region to the udder. The milk veins should be large, tortuous and branching, entering a num- er of large wells. 5. Producing Ability. The digested food is converted into milk only after reaching the udder. A large udder that is soft and pliable but not abby when empty, well developed forward and attached rather high nd, and teats of medium size and squarely placed are the best indi- ations of the cow's producing ability. CARE AND MANAGEMENT OF THE COW If one wishes to make an engine do maximum work, it is always started at full speed before power is thrown on. In the same way if a cow is expected to do maximum work, special attention should be paid to her care and feeding some two months before freshening. It is well to follow a plan of having her dry about this length of time so as to give her an opportunity for rest and to prepare for the next lactation period. Just previously to freshening, grain ration, light, laxative and cooling, should be fed. Such grains as bran, oats and linseed meal are very satisfactory. For roughage, alfalfa and corn silage are preferable and may be fed in the usual amounts. CARE OF COW AT CALVING TIME It is desirable to place the cow in a box stall a few days before freshening. The stall should be clean and thoroughly disinfected. This will do much to prevent complications later on, both as regards the cow and the calf. Avoid worrying the cow — simply see that everything is normal and give her plenty of time. For nourishment, feed grain sparingly and give only lukewarm water. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">40 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION UDo not milk the cow clean for the first few days to guard against k fever. CARE OF COW FOLLOWING FRESHENING For the first few days following freshening the digestive system s still weak and there is a tendency toward indigestion, bloat or im - laction. For this reason greatest care should be exercised in bringing he cow on full feed. In a general way it can be said that the grain ation may be increased about one-fourth pound per day. Continue o increase as long as the cow responds by giving additional milk. \fter she reaches her normal condition the following brief and simple ules will aid in determining the amount of feed required by the cow: 1. Feed all the roughage, such as alfalfa, corn silage, etc., the cow will eat up clean. 2. Feed approximately one pound of grain for every three pounds of milk produced per day. 3. Give the cow as much feed as she will consume without gaining in weight. 4. Feed some succulent feed, such as corn silage or roots, to make the ration more palatable. 5.Be prepared to supplement the pastures by feeding silage when the dry season sets in. THE CALF AND HEIFER Inasmuch as the department has a bulletin on calf raising in press which any one interested can secure, this question will not be discussed in detail in this paper. It may be well, however, here to emphasize the fact that it is only in raising the calves from the best cows that the herd can be materially improved. The principal object to keep in mind in the feed and care of the growing heifer should be to keep her in a thrifty, growing condition without her becoming unnecessarily fat. It is held by many breeders that a large amount of roughage will cause her to develop her digestive organs to the maximum which is desired for milk production. Corn silage and alfalfa are most desirable feeds for this purpose. Heifers of the larger breeds should be bred so as to freshen at about two and one-half years of age. The smaller breeds may freshen at about two years of age. FIVE ESSENTIALS IN DAIRY HERD MANAGEMENT 1. The sire is more than half the herd. Be sure that the sire heading your dairy herd will transmit dairy characteristics. 2. Weed out the unprofitable cows by use of the Babcock test and the scales. 3. Raise and keep all heifer calves from the best cows. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">THIRTIETH ANNCAL CONVENTION 41 4. Winter dairy as much as possible under your conditions. It ves you more milk, better prices, and less cost. Provide comfortable quarters for milch cows. MARKETS AND ADVERTISING Generally it is easy enough to secure some kind of a market, but to secure the best kind of a market frequently requires persistent ef- fort. To get the best of prices requires the production of finest quality. This is nowhere so true as with dairy products. The merits of the goods must be systematically called to the attention of consumers. In other words, it is legitimate and even desirable that a certain amount of advertising should be done. Dairy products, especially pure bred live stock, rely on regular and persistent advertising, though advertising like reputation requires the expenditure of both time and money be - fore results are apparent. Regarding pure bred live stock it is well to remember that the amount of advertising he can secure through breed association and official testing is the cheapest and most effective at his disposal. It has always appeared to the writer that many farm - ers utterly fail to realize the necessity for pushing and advertising their goods and to realize some of the possibilities for advertising at their disposal. From my point of view it is bad taste, as well as bad judgment, for a farmer to permit the use of his barn roof or fence for the advertising of Bull Durham tobacco. Spearmint gum, or Peruna ,and the many other things one sees on a journey through the country. We judge a paper by the advertising it carries, a man by the company he keeps, and per - ethical, practical and profitable would be a neat, attractive sign and bulletin board calling attention to the products for sale on the farm. One farmer recently told me that one sign near the railroad track had een responsible for the sale of three high priced, pure bred animals. Question: Will you please explain what is meant by the mammary s&gt;stem? Prof. Frandsen: I am not sure that we have much time to take this matter up just now. However, perhaps I can explain very briefly the principal essentials. We desire the good dairy cow to have large, prominent milk veins. While these veins carry impure blood from the udder back to the heart and lungs, they are still important because their size is generally in direct relation to the size of the arteries carry - ing a large amount of food material to the udder from which the milk constituents are made. As part of this system we want large milk wells, and by milk wells we mean the openings in the abdominal wall ■ ermitting the milk veins to get back to the heart and lungs. We like to have a large, well-rounded udder giving ample room for the manu- </seg>
            <seg id="p041">42 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION tture of these products into milk and carrying away some waste teric). A Member: I have traveled in Wisconsin. I think that Wisconsin University offers a good proposition in the line of extending credit to students more than our western schools do. Prof. Frandsen: Yee, I think this is true. The well organized dairy farms of the eastern states offer splendid opportunity for students specializing in dairy work. Many of the managers of these large farms ell me that they in turn welcome the coming of these bright young col - ege students on account of the new ideas and the best of scientific training of which they are so willing to give. Many of these farm man - agers tell me that their dairy work has been so re-arranged or improved aa to considerably increase the dairy income. We encourage all of our students to spend two summers in practical dairy work on some dairy farm whose owner has made a striking success of the particular kind of dairying in which he is engaged. Prof. Haecker: I was in Minnesota this year and they told me they were introducing the same method there and it seems to me a very good one because it enables the farmer or dairyman, as the case may e. to get the work of some splendid young man during the summer months. At the same time it gives the young man a university credit t the agricultural college when he gets back. I have always claimed hat the fundamental or foundation training for a young man who wishes to get all the knowledge concerning dairying is work on the farm n taking care of the cattle. These farms are doing the work well nough to give good instruction to young men or students in agriculture. t is a compliment to the farm and the farm gets the services of good oung men and the students get the benefit of the credit after they go back to the college. I think the credit farm idea is the one that we need to start in this state. We have a splendid agriculture college here nd we have lots of good farmers throughout the state and right around lere — whether it is a stock, poultry, hog or dairy farm. It is of great benefit to the young man where he can put in his vacation for profit to himself and the farm where he works. I know of a young man, a student whose home is in the western part of the state where they have not had diversified farming. He came down here and is taking the college course. He came from a little town and is anxious to learn agriculture. He is ambitious to go where they have cattle or do dairying and also to learn how to care for the farm and cattle. He spends the summer to great profit in this way and he gets credit when he comes back. In other words, it gives this young man an opportunity to work and at the same time he gets credit. It tends to give the man employing him much interest in this institution and at the same time an interest in the young man. Prof. Frandsen: I think this proposition offers splendid possibil - ities, and I cannot resist the temptation in this connectoin to say that </seg>
            <seg id="p042">THIRTIETH AXXTAL &lt; OXVEXT1OX 43 the dairy and extension departments realize the necessity of this kind of help. Last fall we were successful in getting appropriation to put on two men for work of this kind with the farmers. It Is the duty of these men to go among the farmers and assist them in improving the dairy farm or selecting better stock. I would like at this time to ask Mr. Burlingham and Mr. Andreas to stand up so that the audience may make their acquaintance and 1 wish to say that the dairymen of the state can get the services of these men whenever they are wanted for work in the field. The President: While the room was darkened for the slides for Prof. Frandsen, a couple of gentlemen slipped in here very quietly whom you all know and I believe would be pleased to hear a few words from them — Regents Whitmore and "Ned" Brown. I think Mr. Whitmore was one of the original members of this association and has been in constant attendance at every meeting for thirty years. 1 now have the pleasure, not of introducing him to you, but, on your part of asking him to speak to us along such lines as he might feel disposed to speak. Regent Whitmore: Mr. President and Gentlemen: In view of the very interesting program which I see you have here this afternoon I could not think of taking more than a few minutes of your time to respond to the President's very cordial introduction. It is true, as the President has said, that I was in the organization of this dairy association thirty years ago. It makes me feel like I was a trifle old. It does not seem possible, but it is a consolation to re - member, as Dr. Holmes has said: "A man is only as old as he feels," and I feel just as good as I did thirty years ago, and I think, sometimes better. I do not have to work now as hard possibly as I did at that time. But it is almost incredible to see the progress that this indus - try has made in this state during that time. I am surprised that I have gone into other business than dairying, but it seems as I said almost incredible that in that time Nebraska has come to an annual production of 930.000,000 a year, as I understand it. I remember about the dedication of that little old dairy building over there. It was our first dairy building erected here on the campus. It was a frame building and then without any veneering. I remember that I then had the honor of assisting in the dedication of the building. It was very properly the beginning of things on this campus. Now notice what we have here today. It is interesting to me to compare the conventions of that time with the conventions that are held here this year. At that time about a half-dozen constituted the convention in any one of them. Today they are holding their meetings separately and in - dependently of every other with an attendance of many times greater than then. It is a great source of consolation and satisfaction to me to note </seg>
            <seg id="p043">44 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION that in all these years I have had my little part in the up-building of these numerous industries that have sprung up in our splendid state. I remember though that all these things that we have here today are the result of hard and continuous work. But 1 am pleased to state that we are facing better things and hoping to build up this campus faster than we have in the past. It is a pleasure to note that we are getting the re - sources to do It with and pleased to state that the building for this as - sociation is soon to commence and we will soon have a building here as good as any in the United States. Regent Brown and myself have just come from a meeting of the industrial committee of the Board of Regents with the architect and in discovering how much money we can possibly spend out of the appropriation we shall have to put in this building, we have decided that it is possible to go $25,000 more than the Board of Regents at first expected to expend on the building. That ought not only to make it an ideal building for the present but will meet all the requirements and needs of the dairy industry in this state for many years and possibly 200 years as far as durability is concerned; and the equipment is to be up-to-date so that neither Iowa, Wisconsin or any other state can come over here and show us where it is in - ferior in any respect. While I am on my feet I want to take a minute to say that it was very refreshing to me to sit here this morning and listen to the cyclone, Nelson, from Iowa. I have had the pleasure in many places of listening to another distinguished citizen of Iowa for several years, Uncle Henry Wallace. I am surprisei to see what a pessimist he has become and in the matter of placing value upon farm lands, so I was very glad, indeed, to note the value that Mr. Nelson places upon the value of Iowa land. He told us that be told the farmers of that state that their land was worth $1,000 an acre, and that milk ought to be worth 50 cents a quart. I say it is worth while to hear a man like that. Honestly, I believe this man comes mighty nearer telling the truth than old Uncle Henry Wal - lace. Right here in this city last week an association calling themselves the Farmers' Union put up a set of resolutions that I was ashamed of. It doesn't look to me like the farmers of Nebraska were going to the dogs. You don't look to me like you were going bankrupt. You don't look to me like you were skimping along on $200 a year! But 1 am talking too long. The President: I am sure the words of Regent Whitmore are an inspiration to us and we are glai to know that he is really a farmer and dairyman. A younger man and a man who has not spent the number of years as Regent Whitmore, but, nevertheless, who is a true dairyman and farmer, I am now pleased to call upon to speak a few words to you. There is no use introducing him to you because you all know him — the Honorable Ned Brown. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 45 Mr. President, Ladies and Gentlemen: This morning at another meeting we took seats in the rear of the room and were called upon, is afternoon we walked up to the mourners' bench and we are ailed upon to speak. No matter where we seat ourselves, we are neraily called upon to make ourselves known and the cause that we present. F ong time before my personal memory makes any record of, a told that I had a great interest in milk production . The first dol- I ever made as a Nebraska farmer I made by selling butter on the Lincoln that I churned from the milk myself. I have not en - en out of touch with dairying in Nebraska. I will say in ly support of that that there came to my place night before last a brand new calf and 1 was fully in touch with the principles of dairying at 1m It is a pleasure to be introduced to you as one of the members of the Board of Regents of our State University. Especially is that true when such a one will be identified officially and participate in maturing ans for the erection of the new dairy building that we are to have on this campus. I trust you have seen the plans. If not, you should try and do so. As Regent Whitmore said, when that building is erected it will be the best dairy building in the United States, not because this Board of Regents has so much wisdom, but because a man who is on the Job in the dairy department has the wisdom and experience that enables is to get a building that will be as near perfect in every respect as lossible — I refer to Prof. Frandsen. (Applause). We have had his xperience and counsel in the matter of arranging details for the building. He certainly is a conservative and economical business man and when we get that building we will have the best dairy building in the United States for all dairy purposes. It is going to place a great obligation upon the Dairymen's Association to live up to the new order if things which I trust the association will surely do. And if you re - lect the present secretary, we will then have the best looking secre- tary of a dairymen's association there is between Lincoln and Uni - versity Place! The President: We appreciate the remarks on the part of Regent Whitmore and Brown. By reference to the program you will see that the next number la a paper by Mr. C. L. Burlingham. He will take as his subject, "Feed - ing the Dairy Cow." </seg>
            <seg id="p045">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION 46 FEEDING THE DAIRY COW By C. L. BITRLINGHAM Mr. President .and Gentlemen: I am glad to have an opportunity to speak to you on any subj»vt affecting dairy cows. After listening to the good talks we have heard today, we are in much the same condition as a fellow dairyman of ours who recently took his girl into a restaurant and treated her to ice cream. Being greatly embarrassed, he could think of nothing to say. Finally, as they sat there looking at each other, be blurted out, "Su=ie. ain't you glad this is us?" I believe that is just the way this associa - tion feels today, we are "glad this is us." The subject you have as - signed me is "Feeding the Dairy Cow." This topic is an important one and well deserves our atention. I am glad to discuss it with you, but am a bit embarrassed because the few things of which I wish to speak are those which you Nebraska farmers have told me on the farms of Nebraska. Riding through southern Wisconsin recently, I tried to discover, if I could, Just what it is to make Wisconsin a great dairy state. 1 re - membered distinctly the farms of Nebraska and compared them with those we were passing — trying to find one factor which accounts for Wisconsin's dairy success, which I might bring back to Nebraska an. ask you to consider. The farms we saw were fertile. They produced good crops, but I could not forget thousands of acres of grains and tsses we have here. I decided Wisconsin's dairy greatness has not le because of greater soil fertility. Many Nebraska farmers have suggested that we do not have suita - ble feeds for dairy cows. I turned my attention, therefore, to studying the kinds of crops we could see. I notices fields where heavy corn had grown and large meadows where alfalfa had been harvested. Other field crops were In evidence, but as I recalled Nebraska's long rows of C)rn and her millions of tons of alfalfa, I decided that Nebraska's rela - vely low returns per cow cannot be blamed to lack of feeds. Then I began to see a real difference between the two states. There were no haystacks in the fields. Large barns house the hay as well as the grains. Very few cattle could be seen in the stalk fields. There were no stalk fields. Wisconsin farmers do not send their milk cows out to try to regain part of the forty per cent of the corn crop con - tained in the stalks, husks and leaves. They cut their corn and store it at the barn as fodder, or in the silo as silage. Here, I decided, is the one thing which indirectly has more to do with making Wisconsin a great dairy state. Her crops are stored in the barn in a comfortable place for feeding — the hired man does not cut a cow's rations short be - cause he hates to go out into the snow for feed. No storm is severe enough to prevent the milk cows being fed. With mows full of hay and a silo filled with succulent, palatable feed. Wisconsin milk cows are </seg>
            <seg id="p046">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 47 heavily fed throughout the winter. Too often, winter finds Nebraska cows poorly nourished, frequently because their feed has been left in the fieli where they have to go after it in the cold or trusted to the tender mercies of a hired man who cuts their ration short rather than haul in feed throughout a Nebraska winter. Here is the secret: Wis - consin takes better care of her feeds; her cows are better fed. So the message I want to bring in talking of "Feeding the Dairy Cow" will be to store feeds where they can be conveniently carried to the cow in winter and then to feed more liberally. Lately I heard an old lady give a young woman some advice which I think we can very well use in the ow business. The young woman had recently been married and had ad trouble with her husband. She asked, "What in the world shall f o so I can get along with him better?" The older lady replied, "Feed brute." If we apply this same ruling in caring for cows ,we will along with them better." Some of you have said to me, "What about feeding the 'boarder cow?" How about the scrub cow?"' I say to you honestly, I think there is more scrub feeding to good cows in our state than good feeding to scrub cows. AnJ yet there are cows which, even under excellent feed - ing will not be profitable. It is not difficult, however, to detect these ws and sell them out of the herd, so that the cows left will not have support the so-called 'star boarders,' but will have a chance to return us profits. The Babcock system of testing cows leaves us very little *x&lt;-use for not knowing which cows are paying for their feed. Often - times we can cull out our poor cows simply by looking them over care - fully — studying them to determine whether they have qualities indicat - ing milk production. We need to think more about our cows. I met a man not long ago who wanted me to ocme to his farm and tell him what to do with his cow. We went out to see her and out in the field we found the worst looking cow I think I have ever seen, and I knew at once what to do with her, but I hated to tell him. I asked. "Now, you want me to tell you what I'd do with that cow?" He replied, "Yes, I do." I said, "I'd knock her in the head." He looked her over for a moment, began to smile, and said, "By George, I believe I will knock her in the head." He knew as well as I that the ow was not worth feeding, but he had never stopped to think. A number of Nebraska farmers have said to me: "We haven't the necessary feeds for milk cows." I want to say to you that we have — that the fields of Nebraska alfalfa and corn, if fed in the best form, furnish all the feeds our milk cows need. Occasionally a cow will pay a large profit on feed we find necessary to buy, but for the large ma - jority a combination of alfalfa hay and corn silage, with perhaps a little corn and cob meal fed with the silage, makes an excellent milk ra - tion. We do not fully appreciate the feeds we already have. Do you know that if one of the fields of alfalfa which we see every day were set down 'in our friend, Mr. Nelson's, part of Iowa, they would have to </seg>
            <seg id="p047">48 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION build a fence around it to keep curious neighbors from coming in and trampling It down. We are fortunate to be able to grow this wonder - ful feed for milk cows. I talked with a man from Massachusetts the other day who is shipping Nebraska alfalfa back to his cows, feeding it at a cost of $28 a ton, and making money on it. Yet we hesitate to buy it at $7to $8 a ton and sometimes skimp our cows when we own it. If we cannot raise alfalfa we can buy it; if we haven't the money we can afford to trade for it. I visited a man's farm lately who feeds twice per day a gallon of shelled corn and a gallon of oats each to his cows. Heavy grain feeding, you will say, and costly with corn at seventy cents and oats at forty to fifty cents. This man did not feed alfalfa because be would have to buy it. He fed high priced grain because he had it on the farm. Alfalfa hay was selling at $4.50 in the stack a short distance away. He could have made the best day's wages of his whole winter by trading a load of corn and oats for alfalfa. Many farmers buy concentrate? when we can more profitably feed more of our farm-grown feeds. I believe that before we feed costly eeds, which we have to buy, to our cows, we should fill them up with 'arm roughages. A great deal of wheat bran is being fed in the state where it can profitably be replaced by alfalfa, which those men who study feed analysis tell us is fully as valuable, pound for pound, as a eed for milk cows as wheat bran; i. e, if we had a ton of wheat bran setting on one side of the room here and a ton of Nebraska alfalfa on the other we would have as much value in the alfalfa as in the bran if we are to use it with milk cows. Alfalfa furnishes large amounts of protein, which goes to rebuild the tissues of the body and furnish a necessary part of the constituents of milk. The cow needs something else — something to furnish energy and heat. We have it on our farms. Our corn crop furnishes all of this part of the cow's ration that she needs. Before the dairy cow can return the most for this feed, however, we must put it in its best form — it should be fed as silage. We need more silos. When we have them and fill hem with good silage, we have an ideal combination when we feed it with alfalfa. Several of the most profitable herds of the state are being fed nothing besides these two feeds. We need more silos. Here is the best recommendation for the silo that I know. I have never met a silo owner who, if you offer to pay him for the silo's cost, will let you take it off the farm. Each man who has stored his corn crop as silage, saving a large part of the thirty-five to forty per cent of the value of the crop commonly left in the field in the husks, leaves and stalks, realizes the silo's economy. Every feeder who has watched his herd produce uniformly high throughout the winter when fed on silage and alfalfa and then has cut the silage out of the ration and seen good pasture grass fail to keep up the milk flow, when substi - tuted for silage, realizes l:s value as a feed for cows. More silos should be In use in the state. We need a stimulus — something to make us dig </seg>
            <seg id="p048">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 49 or build them. In Kansas one county received such a stimulus as Ne - braska seems to need. A farmer who was digging a silo there was ad - vised not to put a cement bottom in it so that in case he happened to get too much water in at Filling time the extra liquid would drain off and leave the silage firm. He failed to follow the advice, with the re - sult that as he fed too near the bottom of the silo be found wet, sloppy milage with pools of liquid standing around on it. You know that silage is nothing more nor less than canned sauerkraut — a kind of fermenta - tion. Well, the old farmer tasted the liquid and liked it so well that he drank enough to become — shall we say intoxicated — anyway he was drunk there in the silo, and his neighbors all came and found him in that condition. There was a good thing which came from this, however, in that in one Kansas county the next year there were ninety silos built and every one had a cement bottom. When we have built the silo, let us make that our first rule of feeJing — to feed all the silage and alfalfa that the cow will eat up clean. For variety's sake, it pay3 o add other hays, corn stover, Kafir corn, etc., to the list of roughages. If we have cows which produce — well, let us make our second rule of feeding as follows: Feed one pound of grain to each three or tour pounds of milk produced per day. * If the grain ration is below six or seven pounds per day corn and cob meal has been the most economical grain feed. Where cows produce heavily additional feeds may be used. Cottonseed meal has proved the cheapest concentrate source of protein the state this winter A third rule of feeding which we may find valuable as a guide is to keep the milk cow in a uniform condition of fleshing from the time she has reached her full flow of milk :o near the end of the milking period. If milk cows begin laying on flesh and gaining in weight dur- ing lactation, their feed should be lessened; if cows begin to get thin when giving milk, they will pay for more feed ani the dally ration ould be increased. I want to give you some results obtained by Professor Eckles which show us the difference in feed requirements of different cows. He has pointed out that one type of cow uses a great deal of her feed for main - taining her body, while another type uses a larger proportionate part of her feed in the manufacture of milk and less in maintaining her body. (Here the speaker referred to charts.) The President: We have had the pleasure this afternoon of listen - ing to Regent Whitmore, one of the charter members of this associa - tion. It is very fortunate that we can listen to another charter member and one of the organizers of the association, and not only that, but one who has been the secretary of this association for the last 85 years, with </seg>
            <seg id="p049">50 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION the exception of one year, when he was president. I refer to Mr. Sam - uel C. Bassett. I have the great pleasure of asking him to say a few words to you. Mr. Bassett: Mr. President, and Gentlemen of the Association: n the month of Augus , 1914, in order to study and better under - tand dairy conditions in the state of Wisconsin the writer made a ourney of 389 miles in the state. Starting from the shore of Lake Michi - gan, the first day's journey, to the west, was 50 miles; the next, to the west, 9€ miles; the next, to the east, 96 miles, and thus back and forth n a zigzag manner, working towards the southern part of the state, he Journey was made. The trip was on a local train, making stops at every station, thus giving opportunity to note dairy and agricultural conditions and to make some inquiries of local travelers on the train. Where stops over night were made a day or sometimes more was taken and drives made out into the surrounding country in order to visit local co-operative creameries ami thus get slightly in touch with creamery conditions. In the 1912 annual report of the Nebraska dairymen's as - sociation, on pages 136-142, are given tables showing number of milk cows to the square mile in each county of both Nebraska and Wiscon - sin, these tables based on 1910 United States census returns. These tables disclose that Nebraska had an average of eight milch cows to the square mile and Wisconsin 26. In Nebraska three per cent of our counties had 20 or more milch cows per square mile; in Wiscon - sin seventy per cent of the counties had 20 or more milch cows per square mile. On this Journey two features, relating to the dairy industry, were given especial attention: First, the breeding of the milch cows as seen from the car window; no possible opportunity was overlooked to learn in regard to this matter, and it can be said, from first to last on the trip, every milch cow seen, showed the dairy type; not tha; all were registered dairy animals, or high grades, but cows of the dairy type, cows showing dairy breeding, were everywhere seen, and not one in which beef breed was most prominent. How is it with regard to the breeding of milch cows in Nebraska? On page 3(2 of the 1913 annual report of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association will be found the returns of a dairy census, taken by the association; the area taken was a township, six miles square. This township is located in a county having an average of 19 milch cows to the square mile; also in the township is a creamery, which has been continuously in operation since the year 1884. The statistics of this dairy census discloses that there were 90 farms, with an average of five milch cows per farm; that on these farms were 45 registered Here - ford and Shorthorn bulls, 42 grade beef bred bulls and three dairy bred bulls. The breeding of the bulls used on these farms also tells the breeding of the milch cows. In this township 97 per cent of the milch cowg were beef bred — 3 per cent dairy bred, and what is disclosed in </seg>
            <seg id="p050">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 51 this township dairy census as to the breeding of milch cows is doubtless true as to the state at large, and that is, that not to exceed 3 per cent of the milch cows on our farms are, as registered or grades, dairy bred. Second, the second feature kept constantly in mind was the use made of the silo in Wisconsin. It will be recalled that in the years gone by many prominent dairymen from Wisconsin, such as Hoard, Henry. Glover and others have attended our annual meetings and advocated the use of the silo on dairy farms. Also we have in the state such silo enthusiasts as Haecker, Frandsen, Schwager, Little. Frost and others too numerous to mention. I had fully expected to find a silo on practi- cally every dairy farm in Wisconsin. I had prepared a blank on which to ally every silo seen from the car window, whether it be near or far, just that it was seen from the car window at which I sat. The first day I journeyed 50 miles, passing through three counties, having an average of 43 milch cows to the square mile as reported in the 1910 L*. S. census. On the trip I counted nine silos, and was quite concerned at the few noted, thinking I must have been careless, for I expectei to note many times that number; hence I determined to be more careful in the future. The second day I journeyed 96 miles, passing through five counties, reported as having an average of 36 milch cows per -■quare mile. On this trip of 9« miles I noted 21 silos. The third day's journey was 96 miles, through five counties, reported as having an average of 40 milch cows per square mile and the number of silos noted was 118. To keep count of the number of silos took so much time that the attempt was abandoned. As disclosed from the car window, the use of the silo on Wisconsin Jairy farms is by no means universal. Also it appeared that on many dairy farms, which, from the car window, gave evidence of being well managed and of the owner being prosperous and progressive, there was no silo in sight. A day was spent at Ft Atkinson, the home of W. D. Hoard and of Hoard's Dairymen. The Hoard's Dairymen plant is doubtless the best equipped dairy publication plant in the world. A large force is em - ployed, an : all the latest and up-to-date machinery, there are large, well furnished offices, and no time or expense is considered too great to furnish to the world at large the latest and most authentic informa - tion relating to the dairy industry. A visit was had and greatly enjoyed with Ed Webster, well known to Nebraska dairymen. Mr. Webster is one of the editors of the Dairymen. It was a source of much regret that Prof. Glover, one of the editors, was not at home. The writer met one of Gov. Hoard's sons, a member of the firm, W. D. Hoard &amp; Sons. The son is one of those genial, lovable kind of people it is a real pleasure to meet and know. Gov. Hoard was so kind as to drive me out to the Hoard's Dairymen farm, of which Mr. Hoard has immediate charge, r Is a model dairy farm, located about a mile or so outside of the town of Ft. Atkinson. The cow barn was the cleanest, sweetest smelling, best arranged dairy barn the writer ever visited. Mr. Hoard was so kind as to drive me out to see his herd of Guernsey cows — 40 head </seg>
            <seg id="p051">52 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION — all as near alike as a pod full of peas. He remarked that they represented his life's work in breeding a herd of registered dairy cattle. As recalled, all but one of the number was of Mr. Hoard's own breed - ing, a beautiful sight to a dairyman. We drove through a pasture field, the finest ever seen with but one exception, that in Yates county. New York; both were natural pastures — had nevtT been plowed. Mr. Hoard stated (I quote from memory) that on one fieli, on his farm, of some 25 acres, he paid $600 to have the surface boulders and rocks removed (the rock being crushed for road making purposes), such rock on the surface are by no means uncommon in Wisconsin. On some such fields after the surface rock has been removed, the field cannot be plowed or tilled on account of rock formation beneath the surface; still many such fields furnish good pasture. As we passed a field of check-row corn, a small variety about six feet in height and which the writer estimated wouli yield from 30 to JO bushels per acre, Mr. Hoard was asked if this corn would be put in the silo? Quick came the reply, "By no means, this corn will be cribbed; t is worth more to feed handled in that manner than in any other." Continuing, he said, "I'll show you our silage corn;" so we drove to another field. The corn was of the Ried's Yellow Dent variety. It was some eight feet in height and planted so thickly in rows that no trs had formed. It had been so dry that there was little foliage ex - ;it at the top of the stalks. The writers ventures to drop this suggestion, or query: If in Wis - consin, on a model dairy farm, it is most profitable to crib and thus feed a field of corn yielding 30 or more bushels per acre, rather than to silo same, will not the same hold true in Nebraska? The conclusions reached in this mater, as to a comparison of dairy conditions in Nebraska and Wisconsin are summed about as follows: As a pasture state Wisconsin is much superior to Nebraska, and a very considerable per cent of the farm lands in the state can only be used for pasture purposes, not being tillable for the raising of crops; and yet, forage crops for dairy cows can be as cheaply and as certainly pro - duced in Nebraska as in Wisconsin. Farming is better done in Wisconsin than in Nebraska, much les waste on the farms. Farm operations in Wisconsin require much more manual labor than in Nebraska. Having this manual labor on Wisconsin farms it is utilized in the keeping of dairies. In Nebraska we make a large use of machinery in our farm operations and as a result use a minimum of manual labor and hence have not the manual labor on the farm to make use of in dairying. In Wisconsin the average farm has 119 acres; In Nebraska, 297 acres. Wisconsin today excels as a dairy state because the cows kept on her farms are, in whole or large part, dairy bred. The one thing most needed in the development of the dairy in - dustry in Nebraska, is not the building of silos of the establishment of </seg>
            <seg id="p052">THIRTIETH AXXCAL CONVENTION 53 ocal and co-operative creameries, it is the use of dairy bred cows &gt;n our farms for dairy purposes. When we have on our Nebraska farms dairy bred cows, as is the case in Wisconsin, the silo and the local and co-operative creamery will come and be made use of as a matter of course. 8. C. BASSETT. Since returning to Nebraska I have received a letter from Wiscon - sin in regard to a campaign that is now being waged for the erection an appropriate memorial to "The Father of Modern Dairying" upon the agricultural campus of the University of Wisconsin, in which every - body is invited to contribute who has been benefitteJ by Mr. Hoard's efforts in the development of the dairy industry. I take the broad ground, you know, that in all these matters when we helped agriculture we help all the people, because all of the people are interested in agri - culture. So I say, let everybody contribute who would in either a small large way I would like that we, as an association, endorse this matter, because Wisconsin has been truly helpful to .Nebraska in many ways. For the last 2.'i or 30 years I don't think we have held an annual meeting along agricultural lines but what Wisconsin has sent a man down here to help us out. Wisconsin is the originator of ideas along agricultural lines, and they have always been helpful. So I would like, if agreeable to the association, for us to endorse this matter as an association, as it would in turn be endorsing Governor Hoard. I am delighted to be here today. It gives me pleasure to meet yon once more. I have missed but one meeting of the association since it was organized. I cannot expect to take a very active part in the work f the association hereafter. You know, there comes a time when we ave to turn our work over to others. And it is the same thing in re- gard to the work on my farm. When my boys get of a certain age I turn the work over to them. I can remember in the early days of this association when a few of us met and organized and when we would adjourn and help the others organize. My time for organizing has gone by. (Applause). The President: We are pleased to have Mr. Bassett with us today and to listen to the work he has done and the trip he made to Wiscon - sin. It is interesting and instructive. As I understand it, this letter states that there is a movement on foot -here in Wisconsin to erect a bronze statute to the "Father of Modern Dairying," to be erected on the campus of that university at Madison. As Mr. Bassett suggests, the best way to handle it would be for our association to endorse it in its entirety. On motion, duly seconded and carried, the matter was referred to the Resolutions committee. I notice we have with us today a former Nebraska man and a man who has as his special line of work the teaching of subjects similar to the class on ;he program this afternoon — I refer to farm management — </seg>
            <seg id="p053">54 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION a man not afraid to tell you what kind of a cow to buy for a certain business or a certain location. I believe it will be worth your while to listen attentively to what he has to say — Doctor Warren, of Cornell University. Doctor Warren: Mr. President and Gentlemen: UI will try and carry out the suggestions that your president has e in saying what I think, whether in the line of a cow or any - thing else. My experience leads me to say that the best place to raise bogs is the place where feed is cheap because hogs are easily shipped and corn is not. The best place to raise hogs is where you have a rea - sonably supply of cheap corn. So, if 1 wanted to raise hogs, I would pick out a spot where corn is cheap and the supply was reasonably steady. The best place in the world to produce butter and cheese is at the place where the feed for the dairy cow is the cheapest. You can produce butter anywhere and ship it around the world. It costs more to ship alfalfa hay. The best place to raise pork and to make butter would be in Nebraska, Kansas and Iowa, where feed is the cheapest. A perfectly simple proposition. Corn in New York state costs T5 cents, and here in Nebraska, 50 cents, and the difference in the price of butter is practically nothing. Hay costs twice as much there as it does here. How much difference in the price of butter? How much difference in the price of hogs? Nothing. I can check up in a week's time what they pay for hogs after they get there. It seems to me, then, that pre-eminently this section of the country s adapted to the production of hogs and butter. What is the best hing to do with skim milk? Pre-eminently, to feed it to the brooding sow, to pigs an 1 chickens. So, the logical thing to go with the dairy business is hogs. But if you raise hogs you need corn, if you raise corn you need hogs. There you have a combination that I do not see how you can beat. If you can sell hogs and winter wheat off the same farm, and raise alfalfa and corn to feed to your hogs, you ought to get through the winter without any county help. I think you should keep n mind that sort of combination which provides you a full year's work. I have made investigations as to what kind of farming is best adapted to each state. The best dairy state in the Union is Wisconsin. Butter is best made where feed is the cheapest. What class of farming pays the best right along, without any exception? It is strikingly shown that diversified farming does. By this practice you can employ help the year round. He milks cows twice a day — he does not milk cows all day. Some men can milk 25 cows a day, and do a good day's work at other things besides. With regular help you can, on rainy days, instead of permitting him to go to town and getting drunk, fix up the barn; give the cows an extra currying, and do other little things, though very important Jobs. We find, as a matter of fact, from results obtainei from three thousand farms — dairy farms — that good •tied farms and diversified farming do the best. They have the use </seg>
            <seg id="p054">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 55 of their horses and regular labor throughout the whole year. In this way they sell enough other things off the farm to pay the expense*. In other words, a good sized diversified business — something more than just milking, is the best. Milk is a part of farm business, a good sixed business, diversified business, along with good crops and good cow*. In this we have the mos: profitable sort of combination we can get. I believe it is universal the world over. Here and there we have a farmer who goes off iuto the pure bred usiness. He is an exception, the farmer who gets to developing his ows to such a point that a single animal becomes worth from two to ive hundred dollars, goes to the extreme in the matter of pure bred attle. But, by way of diversity, he has better cattle and sells some a year. From the sale he realizes cash profit. He devotes all ime to dairying but not all his time to milk production. He is specializing to a high degree. As this country develops it is Inevitable that we shall do more dairying. We keep in 'the United States about one dairy cow to each family. That proportion will continue. When » population doubles the number of dairy cows must double because takes about one dairy cow to supply a family. If you have more families you must have more dairy cows. Beef is the most expensive food we can buy, and is becoming less and less used. I am not saying anything to stop eating beef, but you see that more and more persons must go into dairying. There will be more in ten years then there are now because the population will increase. So it is going to increase no matter what you or I may think about it. We have in Nebraska a large amount of stalks standing out In the field. The single purpose cow (not the dairy or dual purpose cow) — i you have lots of them whose primary function is to eat a lot of •T, worthless stuff — gives something in return for it. She is a single purpose cow, and you say you will keep her because you have her. Here and there some one will step into dairying, and it almost always happens that the people who start Into dairying know but very little about dairying out here because they have been used to that way — the single purpose way of taking care of their cows. A man who knows something about raising beef cattle knows very little indeed about taking care of a pure bred dairy cow. Those farmers ought to take to that kind of work. He gets out of them what he puts into them. So when you find a farmer like that, no matter what you or I may think about it. he hates to go to work taking care of his dairy cow on any other or different line. He cannot turn that pure brei dairy cow out into the corn field to browse; he cannot put anything like that old dried-up corn into a dairy cow. He might just as well try to put it into an automobile and try to run it. It will not work in the automobile, neither will it in the dairy cow. Now, when you come across a farmer who is used to taking care of his cows in that manner, he needs a little help and in - struction and advice. It is a different proposition, he will have to find out. He does not want to put anything into a cow that is not fit for the </seg>
            <seg id="p055">56 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION use for which It was intended, because that cow machine wants to be crowded to its capacity, or else it will use up the stuff just to lire on without giving any milk product. So I believe it is exceedingly im - portant, when you change to dairying, that you should put it down that you do not know anything about it at first. The fact that you don't know how to take care of the ordinary cow is evidence enough that you do not know how to take care of the dairy cow. I suppose the most highly developed center of Holstein pure bred attle is around Syracuse, N. Y., where they have raised them and al - alfa for one hundred years. The land there grows alfalfa without any ffort. Why is it a Holstein center? Because it is an alfalfa and corn enter. Nature knew what she was about when she made that land. She made the hills and she made the stones which have no fertility. There was no fertility in them for ages. But alfalfa has come to stay. There is now the great center for the Holstein cattle. There is also a great center for alfalfa and corn. It has developed into a great Uve - tock center where they can sell an animal any dn&gt;. if you want to &gt;uy you can buy a car load of them. Why should not any other section which grows alfalfa just as easily be such? It grows easier here, be - ause, when you come to rain and sunshine, you can't beat Nebraska why should not Nebraska, in time, be the center of a great dairy in - ustry, since it is so well adapted for corn, and so far for milk and butter. Why should it not be a great center of datry products and hogs? t seems to me that this is inevitable. There are a few states where the and is somewhat cheaper, but there is no large area that will grow corn nd alfalfa any better. Iowa will beat you on corn but not on alfalfa. Vhere you gain in one you will lose in the other over there. It seems o me you have great opportunity here in Nebraska for wonderful de - velopment (Applause). LThe President: The next number on our program this afternoon is paper entitled, "Labor Saving Devices on the Dairy Farm," by Mr. os. E. Culp. Mr. Culp: Mr. President and Gentlemen: A modern dairy is the greatest asset of the American farmer. The dairy can not be com - pletely modern until it has been equipped with the devices that tend to modernize the old labor proposition. The history and use of these devices began back through a number of years and extended down to the present day. I might enumerate a number of these that have been relegated to the heap of ancient customs, and been replaced by the more modern devices, but we will pass over a long list of these and omit a discussion that belongs to the more ancient history of dairying, for it would be an imposition upon your time to more than make now and then a passing reference to this part of dairy history to this gathering, whose knowledge is so far superior in the subject under consideration. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 57 After passing over a long period we discover the hand separator taking the place of the old method of skimming with the old skimming ladie in the open air where the dust, foul odors and many other sources if filth were overcome as well as lessening the time required to get the ream from the milk, even though we did not consider the difference in the loss of butter fat in the skim milk the advent of the separator was a great money saver to the dairy industry. The new stanchion, in - stalled in the dairy barn increase.; the output of the dairy herd by ad - ding to the cows comfort. We cannot place too much stress upon these conveniences that tend to pacify the old "lady" of the dairy, provided, we desire to attain the best results. The litter carrier, compared with the old fork method, or even the wheelbarrow, in removing the refuse from the barn seemed to be the crowning convenience. The fresh water "lines" that have been installed in the barn with the drinking cup attached that old "bossy" is privileged to remain in - side on those stormy days and sup of the sparkling water tempered at the supply tank, these conveniences cost but little and add much to the "queen's" comfort and more to the income and production end. The Silo: One of the greatest additions to the dairy, furnishing a succulent food, even when oli mother earth is covered with a blanket of the coldest snow, and old Kink Winter has sapped the juices -from every particle of food stuffs, the herdsman proceeds to the silo and brings forth a morsel of food that would tempt a king. After a hard day's work you "come up" to the house, groom your hands and face, partake of a hearty meal carefully prepared by the gooi Housewife, and after you have had your fill, you push yourself back from the table and eave a sigh of satisfaction and are ready to take up another day's This, gentlemen, is but satisfying the animal nature in the man, jnsidering our superior wisdom over that of the lower type of ani- ais, if you please, we readily comprehend the necessity of catering comforts of the "creature" that we may attain to the best results. The agricultural wealth of a community the world over is meas - ured by the number of profitable dairy cows it contains. Thirty-five years ago, and even a much later date in some sections of the country, the cow produces milk that the farmer might have a full pitcher upon the table, ani butter with which to make his bread the more palatable, today the annual sale of butter alone is a half billion dollars, and we are as far from the zenith as we were then. The cow does not give milk but it is necessary to take the white fluid from her, and the process now generally in use, viz., hand milking, is the indigestion of the dairy industry. No phase of the dairy business is so troublesome — so hard to manage— so liable to make you "throw up" the game. Solve that problem and dairying would not only be the most profitable, but the most pleasant of business enterprises. CITY GIRL The milking taken care of, and you could double your herd. The </seg>
            <seg id="p057">58 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION mechanical milker, commonly called the milking machine, fills every requirement and fills it well; better than the best hand milker. \v:ti it one man can do the work of four men, and do it much better in ever? respect. The milking machine may now be said to have gained its second wind and from -this time on it will be one of the most important factors in the development of dairy farming. Lit is a fine piece of machinery, not intricate, and requires the same re and attention that should be given other machinery on the farm. The advantages in the use of the milking machine on the dairy herd are numerous. The saving in labor, and the labor problem is truly one of great importance to dairymen of large or small caliber. The use of the milker insures the cow against abuse or rough treatment, for the machine has not been invented that will rise up and take the milking stool to persuade the cow that she should not switch her tail or rais&gt; - her foot in remonstrance to some imaginary infringement upon her rights. After a very few milkings the cow seems to enjoy being milked by a machine, and it is indeed very seldom that she appears nervous during the process. Cows do not fall off in milk flow so early when the machine l8 used, owing to its uniformity in work, leaving the udder and teats in a more healthy condition. The milk taken by the machine if a more sanitary product, lower bacterial cornit and more valuable milk is assured owing to the fact that all stable air, dust and dirt are ex - cluded from the milking parts. In a health report from Binghampton. N. Y., we note: "Out of 33 dairymen delivering milk, the government test Shows that the milk from the dairy using the machine contained one-twentieth as many bacteria as the next best dairy in competition." This is only one of many tests we coulJ call to your attention There are a number of other points we should be pleased t cuss, but time and space does not permit. Gentlemen of the association, it is now up to the farme great dairy stale, as well as to the dairy farmers of all state DU to the full realiza.ion of the value of the milking machine in their barns We predict that in five years we have accepted the silo, modern &gt;arn equipment and other inventions for the benefit of the man who milks the cow and there is no reason why we should not now commence a thorough investigation into the merits of the mechanical milker. It is the real solution of many perplexing problems of the dairy Industry and t IB certainly to our advantage to acquaint ourselves with such a boon. There are a number of these machines of different makes and types manufactured, each of which claims certain advantages, and each special make Will have its supporters and users, but each manufacturer is aim - ing to accomplish the same work, viz.: The solution of he milking problem. y Shall we Join hands with him in the solution of this great problem ranting the dairy industry of today? </seg>
            <seg id="p058">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 59 Whereupon, this convention took an adjournment until Thursday, January 21. 1913. at 9 o'clock a. m. SECOND DAY'S &amp;ES.SION STATE FARM, THl'BSDAY, JASIARY 21, 1»U 9 ..'(look A. X. Meeting called to order by President, who said : Secretary FranJsen is getting out a list of dairy cattle breeden In the state of Nebraska. He wishes me to announce that he regrets It la not ready for distribution at this time, but any one who will sign and either hand to him or send to him the registration card giving name and address, will receive a copy sent him by mail. I wish at this time to call attention to the Cow Judging con - test this afternoon. We have some very fine medals this year for the successful ones, as you will see here upon the secretary's desk. We will now listen to the report of some committees. REPORT OF AUDITING COMMITTEE Mr. Young: Mr. President .the auditing committee beg leave to make the following report: That we have carefully examined the accounts of the Secretary- Treasurer for the past year and find said accounts all correct. H. C. YOUNG. T. A. GIBRENS, E. C. WOODWARD. Committee. On motion the report was adopted. While I have the floor, Mr. President, your committee desire to present a resolution, at least would recommend, if possible, that the fiscal year of this association be changed from April 1 to January 1 each year. On motion the resolution to adopt January 1st as the beginning of the fiscal year was carried. REPORT OF NOMINATING COMMITTEE Mr. Haecker: Mr. President, the Nominating Committee beg leave to submit the following report as the officers for the ensuing year: </seg>
            <seg id="p059">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION 60 For President. J. S. CLARK, Revenna. For Vice President, J. R. PEARSON', Morefleld. For Sec'y and Treas.. R. W. McGlNNIS, IJncolr Board of Directors: J. H. FRANDSEX, HENRY FISHBACK, E. M. LITTLE. ARTHUR S. NELSON". DAVID COLE. Signed: A. L. HAECKER, A. E. WILKINSON. C. F. LJEBERS. EMr. President, I move you that the secretary be authorized to ca ballot of the association for the election of the proposed officer nded. Carried. The Secretary: 1 now cast the ballot of the association for t tion of the above named officers for the ensuing year. Professor Haecker: I would like to offer two resolutions to com before the association at this time separate from the Resolutions Com mittet 1 : U First: That the members of this association and the assoc on record as commending Prof. Franisen, the head of the ai Epartment of this institution, for his work in originating new work in »am grading and offering instructions to the men in the field along z line of grading cream. Second: That this association endorse the cream grading mov ment even to the extent of backing it up by legislation if necessary. It is absolutely hopeless to improve the quality of Nebraska butter and to improve the price until we have a better cream grading system t is of as much importance as the grading of wheat and corn. I have been in the state many years and have seen many efforts that have been made from time- to time to get a system of cream grading in this state and this first resolution is offered as commending Prof. Frandsen in his work. Prof. J. D. Jarvis: What is good for the producer generally is good for the manufacturer. An association like yours which repre - sents all branches of the dairy Industry, farmers, dairymen, creamery - men, manufacturers of dairy products and the consuming public cer - tainly ought to go on record as trying to help build up the dairy industry. I believe the two resolutions which have been offered ought to h* adop'ed by this association, because your dairy school is the first school in the world to give a special course in cream grading. Prof. Frandsen has the unique distinction of being the first Pro - fessor in Dairying to give a special course in cream grading, and the </seg>
            <seg id="p060">61 THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 1 iples upon which Nebraska cream can be grade! is certiinly fair and equitable and the farmer and creamery man will profit by it. By this grading of cream farmers will receive better prices for their tter fat. They will become interested in the production of better ream to make into butttT and thereby make a better quality of butter ndustry instead of letting it decline. To the creamery man. it means he will receive a better quality of earn, interested In better cattle and interested in developing the dairy H&gt;- will be able to reduce the cost of manufacturing butter by receiving a better quality of cream and thus obtain better prices for his more uniform quality butter. Poor, sour, dirty cream is uneconomical to the manufacturer of butter because it causes abnormal losses in manu- ter. Due to the tariff, the foreign importation of butter, ir and the butter manufactured by the large condensed milk factories, there is an increase in the amount of extra butter on the market and this increase has caused a greater range in prices between extra, firsts and seconds. Creameries that make only firsts and seconds are in direct competition with oleomargarine and process butter, and if they do not grade their cream and pay according to grade they will have a more time in making a success. This association certainly ought to go on record as favoring the grading of cream. We, as Americans, believe In progress, believe in iliiine up and not tearing down, believe in education, believe in dis - &gt;atin^ prejudice, believe in encouraging the spirit or providence and ereby rendering a happier, better and more prosperous people. You ould put these resolutions before the people of Nebraska so they may see how important it is to grade cream properly and demand a differen - tial in price between first and second grades of cream. If the state sanitary laws were enforced with the farmers, they would provide them - selves with receptacals, or coolers, which will control the temperature of the cream on the farm and also prevent a large amount of unneces - sary dirt and bad flavors from getting into the cream. The acidity of cream generally shows cleanliness in production and handling; it Is con - trolled by temperature on the farm and in transportation to markets; it is controlled by frequent delivery to the creamery, and also by the richness of cream. All these factors are important to the dairy in - dustry, and I believe this association will not make a mistake by adopt - ing the resolutions. The President: You have heard the motion, gentlemen. All those in favor of the resolution will please signify it. Contrary, otherwise. The resolutions were adopted. Professor Frandsen: If not out of place at this time, I desire to express my appreciation of your kindness in passing this first resolu - tion as affecting my work. While I appreciate the compliment that has been paid to me, the biggest value, it seems to me, will be the moral support it will give us in our further work. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">62 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION I would also be glad to speak to you at this time about this model of a cow that you see here on the speaker's desk. The idea was con - eived, or originated, with the Nebraska Cream and Improvement As - ociatlon as a fitting way of advertising the dairy Industry of Nebraska. n the Nebraska Dairy Show it caused more comment than any one single hing. I heard many favorable comments on it. and since returning home have received very many letters asking if it would be possible to get miniature paper weights of it. The credit of making it, as far as I know, is due Mr. A. E. Wilkinson. He did it in a few days. I do not know what he might do if he had time. Another thing in which you are particularly interested in dairying is the fact that this morning at 5 o'clock Katie Gerben was given a new grand daughter, weigh" 118 pounds. I Applause). bThe President: It Is suggested by our secretary that Professor ndsen name this grand daughter, and I offer the suggestion as a Is for a resolution to that effect. The President: Now, if there is no further business we will pass on to the morning's program and the first we have is a paper entitled, "Care of Cream on the Farm," and it gives me pleasure to call on Mr. R. E. Jensen at this time to give this talk. (ARE OF ( KK \M O&gt; INK KARX By PROF R. C. JENSEN IMPORTANCE OF GOOD CREAM Butter has been from prehistoric times one of the most highly prized of all human foods, not primarily on account of its high food value, but on account of the fine flavor which it imparts to other foods when cooked with or spread upon them. The flavor of butter, there - for, measures its commercial value when placed upon the market. In our moiern creameries most butter is made perfectly as to workman - ship, the chief defect being the flavor. It Is true that the butter maker with his up-to-date methods can greatly improve the quality of butter made from pure cream, but with all the modern methods no butter maker is able to turn out as good a product from poor cream as he could with good cream. It is safe to say that the cause of most of out poor cream - ery butter lies with the producer of the cream and the station operator rather than with the butter maker. The fact that the butter is made at the creamery and not at the home does not release the farmer from re - sponsibility regarding its quality. Not only is the farmer responsible (or the butter made from his own cream, he is in a large measure re- </seg>
            <seg id="p062">THIRTIETH AXNIAI. CONVENTION 63 5pon=ible for the quality of the entire churning, as his cream may in:ro - luce enough ba : flavor to affect an entire churning. Good butter can always be sold at a high price, in fact, the public is clamoring for higher quality in this commodity. There always has been and always will be a great demand for good butter and the con - suming public will pay a high price for the quality of butter which it desires. Those who are more familiar with the conditions assert that probably only half of the butter offered for sale on the markets can be rated as good table butter. A large part of the butter is bought at a low price and ultimately finds its way to the renovating factory. When good butter is scarce, a large part of this poor butter is thrust upon the consumer at a price equivalent to that paid for better grades. This is surely a deplorable condition for our butter industry to be in. It seems to me that the best way to compete with the oleo industry is to produce a butter so good that no one would care to use a butter substi - tute. The only way that better butter can be produced is to better the quality of the cream produced on the farm. It will T&gt;e a big job and the only solution of the situation is to educate the farmer so that he will see the importance of good cream and realize bis responsibility in the production of good butter, anl then it is up to the creamery to pay for this according to its value which can only be measured by quality. ButUT made from good cream will have better keeping qualities than butter made from poor cream, because many of the undesirable fermenta - tions which are present in poor cream will be carried on into the fin - ished product. CAUSES FOR DETERIORATION OF CREAM Bacteria are microscopic one-celled plants or organized ferments which multiply by cell division and are the lowest order of plants. We will find bacteria very widely distributed in nature, In fact, wherever life is possible, there we will find bacteria. They are found in water, in the soil, in the air, in dead animals and plant tissues, on the skin, on the hair, in the upper air passages and in the intestinal tract of man and beast, in dust, dirt, etc. It is these organisms or fermentations which cause milk and cream to undergo changes, thereby causing them to sour and spoil. It is true that there are unorganized ferments or enzymes inherent in milk which may bring about certain change's, but these changes are Insignificant compared to those brought about by bacteria. Time will not permit a detailed discussion of bacteria, but without some knowledge of their action we cannot fully understand the prin - ciples involved in the production and handling of good cream. It will, therefore, be necessary to mention a few of the different types of bac - teria commonly found in milk and cream and briefly explain their action. The most common type of bacteria is the type which produces acid </seg>
            <seg id="p063">64 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION commonly known as the lactic acid bacteria. These organisms are the friends of the butter maker. They cause milk to sour an '. are probably directly responsible for the desirable flavor which is found in butter made from well ripened cream. This tyi&gt;e is also indispensable in the production of good cheese. Cream that has been properly handled and cared for will always contain a preponderance of these desirable germs and even though they do cause the cream to sour, they will produce a clean acii flavor which is very agreeable. When cream contains a pre - ponderance of these germs, the undesirable germs can not grow to any advantage; therefore, the lactic acid bacteria hold in check putrefactive fermentations which produce bad flavors. Besides the lactic acid bacteria there are several other types which cause a decomposition once they gain access to the cream. These types cause a decomposition of the protein of the milk, causing disagreeable flavors and odors. These organisms are usually associated with filth; therefore, cream that has been produced under insanitary conditions is sure to contain great numbers of these germs which cause poor cream. Butter fat has great absorbing properties. It will absorb most any odor or flavor with which it may come in contact. It is this great ab - sorbing property of butter fat that makes it so important for us to control the named fermentations. Due to the wide distribution of bacteria in nature, it is absolutely impossible to produce milk whirh does not contain a great variety ol them, and it is not at all difficult to see how they can gain entrance tc the milk. Milk is contaminated to some extent in the udder, but with healthy animals the only possible channels for bacterial infection of th« udder is through the teat. All other contamination tak some outside source. Even though we can not produce milk free from bacteria, scienc has taught us how we may control those that uo gain access. Tw things are essential in controlling bacterial growth; namely, cleanl ness and temperature. Freshly drawn milk forms a suitable media for the growth of most bacteria. They will grow at lower temperatures, but not so well. At 70 degrees P. growth is still quite vigorous, but when the temperature drops below 50 degrees F. growth is very meager. We should, therefore, practice cleanliness as much as possible in order to prevent large num - bers of bac eria from getting into the milk and cream, and we should keep these products at a low temperature in order to inhibit the growth of those which have gained entrance. WHY DO WE HAVE POOR CREAM? There are many people who blame the hand separator for the poor quality of cream which is delivered to the creameries. It is not the use of the separator, but the abuse of the separator which is responsible </seg>
            <seg id="p064">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 65 or a large share of the poor cream. We should be surprised to know iow many farmers wash their separators not more than two or thre« times a week and there is a vast number who only wash their separ - ators once a day, and many use dirty water in washing utensils and flushing the bowl. The warm milk left in the bowl is a very favorable media for the development of millions of bacteria which contaminate ;he next milk that is run through. And still the farmer is not wholl&gt; to blame for such existing conditions. Many farmers know that such ractices are not proper and there are others who sincerely believe lat there is no use in washing a separator oftener than once a day. &gt;arator agents have been in a large measure responsible such conditions. There have been thousands of separators agen: told the farmers that his separator because nly needed washing once a day and now we, who are working for a etter quality of cream, must correct these erroneous ideas which are firmly fixed in the minds of so many farmeTS. Do not blame the separator for poor cream, but use it as it should lsed. and we will fill a big gap in the production of good cream. would hardly be proper to say that competition was a cause for ream, but the keen competition as it exists at present is certainly no incentive for the production of better cream. The average farmer will not be as painstaking in producing good cream when he knows at he will not get any more for it than his neighbor who produces very poor grade. DAIRY METHODS WHICH WOULD IMPROVE THE QUALITY OP CREAM ows are essential in the production of clean milk. Cows ring with some udder disease are sure to produce milk which is an is often dangerous. Tuberculosis is probably the worst and most dangerous disease from the standpoint of sanitary milk pro - duction and can not be guarded against too carefully. Guarding against tuberculosis is fully as valuable to the producer as it is to the consumer. The construction and location of the barn are important factors n the production of good cream. The barn should be so constructed that an be easily cleaned and the stalls made in such a way that the 1 may be kept as clean as possible. The walls and ceilings should be tight so as to exclude as much dirt as possible. There should be enough windows to supply lots of light, as direct sunlight is one of the beat germicides known. The barn, if possible, should be located on a high place where the yard can have good, natural drainage. This is important so the cows may get into the stable without wading knee-deep in mud. The yard should be clean and not filled with large piles of manure. Feeding has its influence upon the quality of cream. Such feeds as garlic, turnips and ragweed impart undesirable flavors to the milk </seg>
            <seg id="p065">66 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION and cream. Sudden changes from dry feeds to green feeds also have a bad effect upon the flavor. Fee-Ing and bedding should not be done just before or during milking, as the shaking of feeds and bedding create a lot of dust, a certain amount of which is bound to get into the milk during milking. This dust carries with it great numbers of bacteria which may cause undesirable changes or flavors. If the cows are to be brushed and cleaned, this should be done 20 or 30 minutes before milking so as to give the dust a chance to settle. If a little care is exercised, it will not be difficult to arrange the work so that the barn air will be as free from dust as possible. If off flavors appear in the milk as soon as it is drawn it is quite reasonable to assume that the trouble is with the feed, but if the off flavors do not develop for some time after milking, then the chances are that the trouble is |M to bacterial action. Probably more filth and dirt get into the milk during milking time than at any other time. There is always sure to be some dirt adhering to the udder of the cow and if the udder is not properly cleaned there will be a great deal of dirt falling into the pail during me milking pro - cess. Much of this filth is manure, much of which goes into solution and c»n not be strained out. You have all seen some people milking the dirtiest cows in the dirtiest places imaginable, an '. the milkers no cleaner than the cows they were milking, and still offer their milk for sale to be used as human food. It is impossible to produce clean, pure milk under such conditions, and still such conditions really do exist. When one is milking he should remember that he is producing a food for human consumption and should exercise as great care as he would in producing any other food proiuct. This udder of the cow should be washed be- fore milking and the personnel of the milker should likewise be clean Milking with wet hands is a dirty practice and should not be done. As soon as the milk has been drawn from the cow it should be re - moved from the barn to a separate milk room or milk house and strained through a suitable strainer. The best type of strainer is one in which the milk must run through a layer of absorbent cotton placed between wo layers of cheese cloth. The cheese cloth and cotton should be burned after each milking and never tried to be cleaned. Even at the best, straining only removes the visible dirt and not the dirt that has gone into solution. Do not think that because you are going to strain your milk that you do not need to be careful about getting dirt into the pail. The milk room or milk house should be separate from the barn be - cause if the milk is left in the barn it absorbs odors which give milk an objectionable flavor. If you can not afford a milk house you should at least try to provide a separate room where the milk may be handled. The milk house or milk room need not be expensive but should be pro - vided with plenty of light and an abundance of cold water for cooling and some means of supplying hot water for washing should also be pro - vided. In the summer time it should be screened to exclude flies. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 67 Separating should be done as soon after milking as possible and the cream cooled immediately. The cream should be cooled as soon a- possible in order that the growth of the germs will be checked and us decrease the chances which otherwise might take place. If the cream is allowed to stand for a number of hours at a warm temperature, there are sure to be changes occuring which are very apt to produce un - desirable changes. Inasmuch as we can not always tell what kind of fermentation is going on, we had better try and stop it as much as pos - sible, and the best way to do this is to keep everything as clean aa pos- sible, and cool the cream quickly and hold at a low temperature. Adding warm cream to cold cream largely destroys the benefit derived) from cooling, as the warm cream raises the temperature so that bacteria will grow more luxuriantly. The degree of coldness depends largely upon cooling facilities, but at any rate should be cooled to 50 degrees if possible. There are three methods of cooling; viz., water, ice, pit. Of course, ice is the best means of cooling, but not all farmers are supplied with it and must, therefore, resort to some other method. A very efficient and satisfactory way of cooling is to have a special tank between the well and the stock tank so that all water which goes to the stock tank must pass through the cream tank. This tank should be constructed so that when the cans are placei in the tank, water can circulate about them freely. The water should enter the tank at one end and be forced to the bottom of the tank and the overflow located at the other end and at the same height as the ran. If this tank is well insulated, fresh water in the tank once a day will maintain quite a low temperature; while if the tank Is not Insulated, it should be filled oftener. When fresh cream is put into water it should be stirred a few times as this will hasten cooling. It is cooling the cream and not the mere fact of getting it into the water that is im - portant. Some special coolers are used which have a small can for fresh cream so cream can be cooled before mixing with cream of older separation and not involve extra labor. Where ice is not available and there is not an abundance of cold wa er. a deep pit or well can be made quite suitable for cooling. Such a pit should be 15 or 20 feet deep, and can be cemented, bricked or boarded up according to other conditions. This is a very inexpensive way of cooling. There should, in a case of this kind, be some mechanical de - vice for lowering and raising the cream from the pit. A simple hoisting apparatus as used in open wells serves the purpose nicely. Keep the cans in the cooling tank until time for delivery and deliver not less than three times a week in the summer time and twice a week in the winter time. Cans should be wrapped with a blanket In the summer to protect the cream from the hot sun and wrapped in the winter time to protect against freezing. There has been a great deal of doubt in the minds of many farmers as to the richness of cream to skim. A rich cream has better keeping qualities than thin cream; there- </seg>
            <seg id="p067">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION 68 te, cream should be skimmed so as to contain 35-4.'. per cent fat. A ber cream may entail a Io3s of butter fat. SUMMARY In summing up the subject I might say that cleanliness is the great - st factor in the production of gooi cream. If cream is not produced lean, all other precautions will not rectify the fault. It is also neces - sary to keep the cream cool in order to hold in check fermentations which might produce undesirable flavors. Other factors such as fre - uent delivery, rich cream, healthy cows, etc., are also important. Spe - ial emphasis should be laid on all factors which enter into the pro - uction of good cream. If carelessness is allowed to rule at any step, t is apt to undo all the good done at other times. DISCUSSION Being asked in regard to the Sturgis can, Professor Jensen said: I think the Sturgis can will maintain a low temperature for a long time I believe it would be all right if properly handled. If the cream properly cooled before being shipped it will reach the creamery in good condition, but if the cream is not, I have my doubts about the u ness of the can. I believe the Sturgis can will be of the more ber in shipping milk than in shipping cream Q. How many hours do you mean when you say, "a long tin A. From 12 to 18 hours. Cream ought not to be in tra than that. Q. Have you experimented so as to know that the ten would not rise in that length of time? A. We took one of these cans, filled it with water at 48 degre Fahrenheit and set it out in the sun with a temperature of 106. The next iay at noon the temperature, if I remember correctly, wa below 60 degrees Mr. Chase: Cream that is shipped 300 miles is sometimes chang from one car to another, and from one platform to another. When those cans get to the creamery I have seen many of them in which the cream was simply rotten and often they would explode and the cap blown off. Another thing, often in the western part of the state the creamery stations pay from one to two and three cents more than wf can get for but er fat. Often that cream is gathered and cream of dif - ferent grades are put together which would certainly put it in bad con - dition, and then we have to stand the chance of the cream getting to the creamery, or destination, in good condition, fresh and pure when all these conditions would tend to put it on the bum. Mr. Jensen: There is no question but what most of the cream arrives at most creameries in poorer condition than when it leaves the farmer. The proper way for that creamery to do, as are now running would be for that creamery to grade that cream as you delivere ' it at the station. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 69 If the cream was all right, fresh and pure when it left the farmer, I don't believe it would be his fault if it met with all these conditions that hare been mentioned here and it did not arrive at the creamery in good con - dition. There is no doubt but what the cream should be graded as it is delivered by the farmer at the station and paid for according to its qula - ity as determined there and then and not as it might be when it arrives at the centralized creamery. But if the farmer shipped his cream direct to the creamery then he would probably be held responsible for that cream. The President: That is the idea. In other words, cream grading pri - marily helps to better conditions and to get better prices. A Member: I am wondering if something could not be done to in - duce our legislature to have sheds for these cans and cream at depots erected by the railroad companies. I have seen cans of cream explode at the railroad station. A man undertook to pull the cream can lid off; he took a hammer and knocked it off. When he hit the can with the hammer the can exploded and the cream all went up in the air, and he kicked :he can off the platform and said it was no good. Mr. Severe: Mr. President, there is one other thing or point I would ke to bring up at this time, and that is that the creameries dry the can* before they ship them back. My experience is that the can should be scalded out and thoroughly dried out before being reshipped. In hot weather there is an odor about it, if it is not thoroughly scalded and dried out, that would knock a man down. While fanners are responsible for bad cream, I believe the creamers are, to a certain extent, responsible too, for the bad condition In which the cans are returned to the far - mer. On the return of the can to the farmer with say a pint, or a half a pint of water in it, and sitting out on the platform in the hot sun it will be in very bad condition by the time it reaches its destination. I care not how hard you try to wash it after its return in such condition, if it has a sediment in it of this description it takes a large amount of washing to get it clean and in proper shape for the cream to be again shipped to the creamery. The quarrel I have with the station men Is that they simply empty the can and leave some of the watw in it and then put the can down where it stands until the next day. The consequence is that you have a bad can. If the creameries in washing their can* would thoroughly dry them before they put the lids on to be re-shipped the can would go to the station in a whole lot better condition and we would all get better results. A Member: There is much importance to be attached to that state - ment. There is more truth than poetry in what the last gentleman said. I have been shipping cream for ten or twelve years, and I have had more trouble along that line than any other. I scald my cans, and after I »cald them I turn or lean them up to dry out. If I had a rack I would leave them there until ready to use again. In that way the condensed steam runs out and your cans are sweet and clean. If I threw the can down without drying it out, I would have a sediment in the bottom, and if 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">70 I in that condition I would have a very poor grade of cream or milk. Ik would be condemned right away. I do not care how careful you i in washing the can and steaming it, if there is anything left in torn of the can that causes a sediment if you leave it there ten or hours the can is in very bad condition, and properly, it should ded again. Mr. Hamilton: I live in the western part of the state. I am not a member of this association, but interested in the subject and in what the gentleman has Just said. When I first went out in the western part f the state I took cream twenty-five miles to station. I had no real ood method of keeping it. I had three 100-lb. cans. I was in my cave ne day and, digging down in the sand, I found it cold. That gave me n idea and, taking my spade, I dug down and put my 100-lb. can in the sand and put some water around it. I took that cream to the station nd Professor Kincade said, "You are bringing some fine cream," and hen I told him how I kept it, as I have Just stated. We do not have the conveniences that you have in some other places. We do not have the tarns that some have which sometimes carry contamination. We have the open air. We milk our cows in the open air, and try to put it through the separator as soon as drawn. We never mix different grades f cream until thoroughly cooled. In this way we are able to send a bet - ter grade of cream to the station than some other people who have better privileges than we. I have a home in Syracuse as well as in the west. A woman brought a little can of cream in, I should think about two quarts. That cream was kept where it gets an odor. It is skimmed and the cream is set away in the kitchen, and the odor from the kitchen contami - nates the cream. This is a great question, a question that you people have got to consider carefully, because the centralized creameries are opposed to cream stations. At Alliance we have a cream station. When it started up, at first they had to go according to the centralized cream - eries. They are now paying, and all summer long, less. At Syrcause they are paying from one to two cents better than at Alliance. They have found a good market for the cream. At first every morning I would receive a line saying "Send us your cream. We will give you a better price than those other fellows will give you." Then when you send the first can or two there is no doubt about it, but very shortly afterward your test will go down to normal and even below. Those fellows are in the business to make money. They make more money than you do who keep and milk the cows. If you are out through the country you know how ordinary country batter is made. The average farmer does not take care of the milk or cream, and likely does not know how. We are going to instruct the farmer how to take- care of his cream, how to raise good cows and how to take care of them afterwards. I raise turnips, and I can feed my cows turnips in the morning right after milking and there 1b no odor to the milk or cream. Prof. Jensen: I think this gentleman over here brought up a very important point regarding transportation of cream wnen he mentions </seg>
            <seg id="p070">71 the fact that the railroads don't take care of the cream properly In trans - sit I used to be connected with the dairy commission in Dakota. I call to mind one instance of a farmer selling cream less than 100 miles from market It took about 18 hours for the cream to go that 100 miles. The cream came down from a little town, transferred at a little town nwt Scotland, and that cream sat out there on the west side of the railroad station from 12 o'clock noon to 12 o'clock at night We found that we uld not persuade or compel that depot agent to even run, or roll, that cream around to the shady side of the depot I think there ought to b« some way to induce or compel the station agent, or men at the railroad station, to take better care of cream that is transferred from one point to another. By so doing the cream would reach the creamery in much better condition. I know of another place where the cream sat out under the direct rays until the temperature of the cream was up to 100 de - grees. Still we could not persuade the depot agent to even roll those ans of cream around in the shade. I think there should be some way of compelling better service in the matter of taking care of the cream at railroad stations. Mr. Trowbridge: In regard to this matter of taking care of the cream, you may talk to the farmer about clean cream as much aa you please, but as long as those conditions exist there is not much encourage - ment or inducement for the farmers to take very much care of his cream. You will find those same conditions at every railroad point that receives or transfers cream. At almost every hour of the day you will find cream -ruing out in the sun. As long as we have those conditions to con - tend with there is not much use of talking to the farmer about clean ream Prof. Jensen: The proper handling of cream under the circumstance* List mentioned here is a very important matter. There are many factors at enter into it. Some day it is going to be better. If we hare no trouble in one way we will have it in another. I believe if we all work hard for it and long enough, it will come. One thing is sure, if we sit down and wait for the better conditions they will never come; but if we work for them we will get them. (Applause.) The President: The next item or paper on our program today la ne by Prof. E. G. Woodward. His subject is "Planning Dairy Build- Ingi PLANNING DAIRY BUILDINGS By E. G. WOODWARD, Assistant Professor of Dairy Husbandry, University of Nebraska. During the discussion I want you all to understand that I am not an architect and will not attempt to give detailed specifications for the con - struction of any of the dairy buildings. I do not claim that all my views are correct, but will attempt to present my ideas with reasons for them, and each one of you may take your choice. It is Impossible to prepare </seg>
            <seg id="p071">72 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION El-ch will meet the requirements of all dairy farms. Each farm has dual problems. Ideal plans for one will not be satisfactory for The kind of buildings will necessarily depend somewhat upon of dairying followed. Buildings suitable for the raising of pure ■k and for producing cream will, as a rule, differ from those for the production of certified milk. However, there are certain fundamental principles applicable to the planning of dairy buildings for any farm. I consider the following points to be essential ones in a modern dairy barn: 1. Cleanliness. 2. Comfort. 3. Convenience. 4. Good ventilation. 5. Good light. 6. Moderate cost. 7. Permanency Cleanliness. Cleanliness should be the first consideration in the dairy barn because nothing can be too clean for the produciton of food for human use. Further, the price of milk is coming to be determined by its cleanliness. The cleanest milk demands a premium on the market. At the present time there is a widespread agitation throughout the coun - try to provide for similar distinction between the price of clean and dirty cream. So long as the consumer demands and is willing to pay for the increased cost of clean milk, the producer should meet his de - mands. Hence, any plan which does not provide for a high degree of cleanliness in the barn where this milk is produced is at fault. Comfort. Every dairyman knows that to Induce his cows to the high - est production comfort is essential. We cannot expect a cow kept in uncomfortable quarters to do her best work any more than we, our - selves, can expect to do our best work when worried or dissatisfied. It is not always possible to provide features in the dairy barn which make for the greatest comfort and at the same time conform to the rules of greatest possible cleanliness. The cleanliness of the barn, how - ever, should be placed first, and we should choose a plan which pro - vides the greatest cleanliness along reasonable comfort. Convenience. Next in importance to the physical comfort of the ani - mals which must stay in the barn must come convenience for the man who does the dairy barn work. In many dairy barns in use now much ime is wasted because of improper arrangement. An hour spent in onsideration of this point when the barn was planned would have saved many hours thereafter. Good Ventilation. Ventilation has been quite generally neglected in the planning of dairy barns until the last few years. Pure air is essen - tial to health and to the efficiency of the cow. The oxygen of the air la of just as much importance as the feed which the cow eats because the feed which she eats is of value to her only in so far as it can be oxidized by the air taken into the lungs. The results of expeiments at </seg>
            <seg id="p072">THIRTIETH ANNL AL ( ON\ ENTION 73 *//W X I I a "3 M • — o 1 I !. u 1 1 — 3 r T I ■ 3 S g |! 3? -a a i| » a H si is 3 a d 1 » 6.1 I &lt; n 5 1 is _ a- Si I! I = t v\ J «7/^ VJ •*//V P*Zt vk </seg>
            <seg id="p073">74 .NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION Ee Wisconsin station point out the fact that cows stabled in poorly ventl ted quarters use feed less economically and produce less milk than e same cows housed in quarters with good ventilation. tiood Light Good light in the dairy barn is necessary in order to keep the barn clean; also for the comfort of the cows and convenience of the dairymen. It is extremely difficult to keep a dark dairy barn clean. We mus: have light to see dirt. Moderate Cost and Penaaneaty. It is needless to say that, with a few exceptions, we desire dairy buildings to be moderate in cost and durable in construction. However, these points will undoubtedly be dis - cussed by Professor Chase. Location. It is necessary that the location of the dairy barn meet the require - ments of cleanliness, comfort, convenience and good light. The site chosen should be well-drained in order to maintain a clean barnyard, for without a clean barnyard we cannot hope to keep the barn as clean as it should be kept If we are unable to choose such a location it will be necessary to provide paving of some sort in the cow yard. Such a location is also essential to the comfort of the cow. No cow can be comfortable when she must stand for hours in mud and wade through filth to the barn. The barn must be so located that it will be con - venient to the pastures and the calf pens, as well as to the other farm buildings and to the house. To get the greatest amount of light into the dairy barn it must be built the long way north and south. This insures the entrance of sunlight during some time of the day along the whole of both broadsides. The sun is really in the south only a short time in the middle of the day. ARRANGEMENT There are many points regarding the interior arrangement which shouli be carefully studied that they may conform to the essentials first mentioned. Modern dairy barns are, as a rule, built for two rows of cows. Very seldom are more than two rows provided for because the middle row will be shut off from the light and also on account of factors in construction which will no doubt be mentioned by Professor Chase. Whether these two rows of cows face toward the center or the outside of the barn is largely a matter of personal favor. Those who favor facing the cows toward the center will argue that the sunlight falls on the gutter where it is most needed. It is also stated by some that the feeding of the cows is more convenient when facing in. Those who favor facing the cows towards the outside argue that this arrangement facilitates cleaning of the stable and that better ventilation can be obtained. Some also say that the herd is handled more easily because the cattle come into the barn through one door. This manner of arrangement is not of vital importance and one can take his choice and still have a system that can be made to meet </seg>
            <seg id="p074">THIRTIETH AXXl'AL CONVENTION 75 gi 3 u 'I — c !l — ii ■^ 5 I,' I ° - J \f ■-M a ■ ■ i p: § ■ x k B M s ■ | / •4 1 5- I H 5 S mo ° U i s§ I a s I- : *Z 1 — 5 — :- = « il I s° § II! "o 2 •9fc 3 9 o a.- -g x * m l 8 il M - » C x Z a — — £ -^ ••- H Sa fj Ik * 1 K* - 4 v ■■ .- H T— 2T </seg>
            <seg id="p075">76 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION </seg>
            <seg id="p076">n f o -^ CE ! — - ii _2 — 1 \-\ — - - - - H H H H - / ■ m « ■ ■' PI! I Is - 2 35 | S H ! "i fe " H g ■ .111 2-: § § § s§s ! i t *" * . * $ ** ss ■I 3 =* S ° w ° a ■§ &gt;; 2 O *J *-i i ~™ § •H.lf-I a / ) / / M V -i. •- J 2 m _j -i * | I x o P? J i I </seg>
            <seg id="p077">78 b essentials previously mentioned. Personally, I favor facing t towards the outside because I believe the daily cleaning of t , which Is the hardest chore, is simplified. GUTTERS Possibly no other one feature of the dairy barn is so essential to thorough cleanliness as a properly constructed gutter behind the cows. The accompanying illustration shows cross section of desirable and undesirable gutters. MANGERS There are many types of mangers and several of these give ex - cellent satisfaction. It is essential that the manger be such that the cows will not throw too much hay out and also of a nature that can be easily cleaned. Whether partitions should.be put into the manger it is a matter which each individual can decide. It is true that when partitions are placed in the manger each cow gets the feed allotted to her and no more. It is also true that a manger with partitions is a preventative against the spread of disease from one cow to another. TYPES OF STALLS The material of which the stall is built should be of a nature which will not become slippery when wet and will be impervious to moisture Along with this, it should be comfortable for the cow. Cement is the fiversal material for the construction of dairy barn floors. The finish &gt;uld be floated, or roughened with a steel broom on all stall floors alley ways where the cow must walk. The President COXSTBtTTIXG DUET BIILDI&gt;«S By PROF. L. W. CHASE tthe subject of a very important branch of the dairy business, and I speak for his paper a warm welcome. The President: "Constructing Dairy Buildings" is the subject of a paper, or talk, by Prof. L. W. Chase. We will now listen to what he has to tell us, which I know will be of great interest to us all. Professor Chase: Mr. President and Gentlemen: The construction dairy buildings is entirely too lengthy a subject to be considered in the few remaining minutes this morning hence, I shall confine my remarks to a brief discussion of materials for dairy barns. PERMANENT OR SEMI-PERMANEXT CONSTRUCTION Buildings constructed of wood are now generally considered of a semi-permanent type, while those which are constructed of stone, brick, clay blocks, concrete or concrete blocks are considered as per- </seg>
            <seg id="p078">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 79 Local conditions will nt-arly always be the determining factor relative to the material to be used. Permanent construction is always to be desired where the methods arming are permanent. This condition very seldom exists where the :i is rented or where the farmer is getting well along in years. It does more often obtain where a young man takes hold of a farm and ► •xpects to make it his home and his source of income. When the metho- of farming is not permanently settled upon It often well to build permanent buildings as this will in part assist in aking the method of farming more permanent, and the sooner the rn farmers quit changing from one system of handling their farms !o another the sooner the farms will become a steady paying proposition. On dairy farms the buildings should be of either good, permanent •onstruction, or of rather cheap, temporary construction. When frame mildings are made as sanitary as masonry buildings they cost approxi- mately as much and sometimes more. Hence, unless it is expected that they will be remodeled or removed they should be of permanent material to avoid the cost of upkeep. SEMI-PERMANENT CONSTRUCTION Probably, in order to produce a maximum amount of the cleanest milk a frame barn should be built as follows: The outside board* to of drop siding well painted and kept perfectly tight, while the inside the walls should be smoothly plastered and free from all cr«»ao— 1 corners. No .oubt such a type of construction would be more expensive than many beginners in the dairy business would care to use. This, then, brings up the point of how to make cheaper types of construction sanitary and keep the interior of the barn warm and well ventilated. Barns which are built of one inch drop siding or one inch vertical siding are very seldom sufficiently tight to need other kinds of ventila - tion except what fresh air will leak through the boards and cracks. The ventilation in such barns is generally very good, but it is often im - possible to keep the temperature as high as is deemed best by good Barns of this type can never be as sanitary as barns with tight walls, but by whitewashing the walls, ceilings and stalls about once r twice a year, they can be made very light, clean and healthful. This rocedure is recommended in all old or dingy barns. Siding: Two general kinds of siding are now in use, drop and vertical, with top siding being occasionally used. The latter is so easily split that it is not a very serviceable material for barn walls. Vertical siding bends itself very easily to the framed type of con - struction, but the drop siding is better adapted to the balloon type of construction which is being very extensively used in the central west When using drop siding care must be exercised in having it dry. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">80 reping it dry and painting it after it is placed on the building before gets wet All Joints should be made very tight, but in nailing the boards care must be used to avoid splits and avoid having the nails pointed tFir, cypress an; white pine are the best kinds of wood for siding. ellow pine, however, will be much cheaper and is quite durable if ell laid, well painted and kept painted. Roofing: Three general types of roofing are now in general use. Galvanized iron, some form of the so-called rubberoids and shingles When good grades of rubberoids are used, we are not in a position to say which material is the best for the roofs. Shingles are the standard, while galvanized iron or steel is becoming very popular in some sections and goo' grades of the patent roofings have proven satisfactory in many instances. Generally speaking, such roofings are not adapted to roofs which are very steep. PERMANENT CONSTRUCTION Brick, clay blocks, solid concrete and concrete block buildings can be classed as those of permanent construction and which of these is the best will depend uj&gt;on the taste of the builder, the distance from tht material, and the local cost. Brick buildings are no doubt as durable as any and probably mor durable than the other types, but because of the cost of material an the labor required to lay them, they are the most expensive. Clay blocks, commonly known as hollow tile, when hard burned. make very cheap, permanent buildings. If such blocks are used for exterior work they should be hard burned and uniform in color . By using pilasters and reinforcing the walls one and a half stories high can be built of five inch blocks. With a properly colored mortar joint such a well would have a very pleasing appearance. Concrete blocks make a very stable wall and one which car constructed by men who have had a limited amount of experienc - masonry. Pourei concrete also makes a very serviceable wall and one which Is absolutely sanitary and durable. In handling such material t'r.e labor item is quite large and considerable ingenuity should be used in handling the concrete in the raw state and in the wet state. In general, masonry buildings are warmer than single wall frame buildings, but it is highly important that they be well ventilated with ventilating flues or shafts. With proper ventilation the inside of the buildings can be kept warm and dry. Floors: The floor for the dairy barn has always been a problem. Earth is Insanitary; plank floors are expensive to keep up and are col i and unsanitary, while concrete Is very hard and rigid. Attempts are continually being made to produce a floor which is sanitary, warm. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 81 Flexible and durable. So far, experiments along this line have met with only a slight degree of success. Some users say concrete floors are cold, but they can not be colder than the earth beneath unless the air above is colder than the earth. When the stable is kept warm, that is, not colder than 40 degrees, the earth beneath the cows will not get colder than from 40 degrees to 50 degrees, an, the floor will be about 45 degrees. Although concrete is not claimed to make an ideal cow barn floor it is probably nearer to it than any other material we now have, and no doubt is cheaper than anything but earth. In placing the concrete leave the surface where the cows walk rough and other places smooth. Have plenty of slope, not less than one inch in ten feet for drainage. Have the floors where the cows stand and walk five inches thick. Use a mixture of about one part cement and four and a half to five parts of sand. To make the rough surface use a wooden trowel (home made) covered with burlap or an old carpet. AFTERNOON SESSION The President: Our first paper this afternoon is entitled "Dairying With General Farming," by Prof. A. L. Haecker. This subject is of vital importance, an- I hope we shall have a general discussion. DUKYIM. WITH GENERAL KVKMIM. By A. L. HAECKER Professor Haecker: Mr. President and Gentlemen: The general farmer if this country Is really the producer of the principal amount of dairy products. It Is not the so-called dairyman, though we would like to have it so, but the man on the farm who is carrying on general farming and milking a few cows. This is the source of our butter and cheese; therefore, to build up the dairy industry from a national stand - point and make it more profitable, we must turn our attention to the man who keeps a few cows and calls it a side line In his business. Conditions which confront this general farmer, lowering his profit in the business or increasing it, influences the national dairy business. Hard winters, dry summers, short grass, flies, poor feeding and poor cows, all have their influence. Fortunately, a cow's life is more than one or two years, otherwise we might be shut off entirely from oar butter supply or be flooded so the price would drop far below a profit. Dairying is different than growing wheat, corn and cotton. In one year we can increase our acreage, but it takes several years to increase our cows. Now, let us face this issue as we find it and the question is, what ■•an be done to improve the dairy business of the general farmer? In the first place, it is necessary to get a good profit from the cowi. This </seg>
            <seg id="p081">82 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION !t be the base. Without profit he will neiiher feed his cows nor milk n, and w« cannot blame him. So long as we have dollar wheat and corn, we cannot expect farmers to quit growing these two crops a large scale. We must encourage the grain farmer and corn rer to keep a few dairy cows and give them proper care, and I think have much encouragement to hold out as an inducement. This whole country is short of cattle and yet it is a natural cattle country. It is proper, sensible and wise that we keep live stock on our farms in the middle west. No better way can the cheap roughage be marketed in distant lands than through live stock. It is a means of condensing our over supply of raw material into a commodity which can be transported' around the world. Butter, beef, pork, mutton and eggs should be the finished products as well as grains. The dairy business gives a stability to a country by bringing in cash throughout the year. It fits in with the swine growing and will work in harmony with general farming. WINTER WHEAT LAND The general farmer has been taught by our schools and Agricultural Press to plant alfalfa and rotate his crops in order to retain the fertility of his soil. "Plant alfalfa," has been the cry for 20 years, urged on every hand by every speaker and all the farm papers, but now that he has planted alfalfa and harvested thousands of tons of hay, what is he going to do with the hay? There will be thousands of tons of alfalfa hay that will not be fei. but will lay in the stack all summer to spoil. We must use a balance in this method of farming. The great study K management has taught us the economic principles of making n departments balance. Every year there is a large waste of I on any farm where grain is grown awl no live stock kept. Live stock in this way may be considered consumers of by-products of the general farm, but it must be kept in mind that good feeding is the only kind which is profitable. It is all right to feed the by-products of the farm to the live stock, but do not fool yourself by poor feeding and under nourishment It is almost impossible to conduct a general farm without having failures of various crops which will change the rotation and make it necessary to produce forage rather than grain. To cite examples of these: Drouth conditions which destroy the corn, but which do not de - stroy the fodder. By putting the corn crop in a silo, it can be turned to as great a profit as though it produced a normal grain crop. This silage can be held over for one season or two or three years if need be. A vigorous growth of fall wheat or winter rye will often furnish an abundance of splendid pasture. Catch crops are often necessary to plant and these can be turnei to good profit by feeding them to live stock. Cane, cow peas, Soy beans, millet or oats can be grown often where other crops fail. All this forage makes excellent hay or silage, and often can be used as pasture. Then we have the alfalfa hay crop </seg>
            <seg id="p082">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 83 which is our cheapest source of protein, and which every Nebraska tamer should grow. To best use this hay you must have live stock. Of course, some of it can be sold, but to use it on the farm means to in- rrea.-e the fertility of our soil and obtain its greatest worth. We must awake to our responsibility. Not only as a nation, but as farmers here middle west When peace comes, and peace will come sometime, we will no doubt receive many people from the Old World. This immigration with our na ural increase in population, will divide up our farms, de - manding more intensified and economic farming. We must pre- serve the fertility of our soil, we must study the subjects of Eco - nomic Crop and Stock production, and when we do this, we will dis - cover that the dairy cow is one of the most valuable animals on the farm to utilize our waste forage and surplus grain. It is this cow that can produce the best of human food out of what is now largely wasted. Because we live in a land of plenty does not excuse us for wasting. To do the best we should be equipped. We should have enough cows to use up these products. We should have silos, for with the silo we can pre - serve what we grow. We can defy the drouth. We can supply good pasture winter and summer at little cost. Alfalfa to furnish the pro - tein, corn silage to furnish ihe carbon-hydrates and good live stock to consume these products will be making the most of our farm op - portunities. The general farmer shoulJ. hold two things in mind in planning for the future First, more live stock on the farm and, second, less waste of forage. The first is necessary in order to correct the second. We are told to stop burning straw, but this will not be stopped until we have stock to consume the straw. Dairying with general farming should be practised in this country and will be, for it is fitting and wise. We would scarcely feel the need of extra feed if we should have a half million more dairy cows. In fact, I believe we have grown a surplus of stock food in this state to feed a half million cows, and this half million cows would produce millions and millions of dollars; would enrich our soil, and would give us a solid, substantial condition of farming. It would enable us to sup- y that great live stock demand which is coming from the western states, from the irrigated sections and the great valleys which are being reclaimed by the government. When Mexico gets through fighting she will want live stock and stock products; and, as for Europe, well, it is not a question of iemand or market or price, but it Is a question of'how much we can produce. Here is such an opportunity. The harvest is great. Let us turn in and reap it, but keep in mind, we must use the best instruments. Mr. Jarvis: The points brought out by Professor Haecker's paper and remarks, if followed in the management of the farm, will hare a tendency to keep people on the farm instead of going to towns and elsewhere. Increased population means intensified farming. By dairy- </seg>
            <seg id="p083">84 .NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION ing, his farm becomes more fertile and productive. Besides making him a living, those who come after him will make more profit than If he speculates in grain farming depending upon the weather and the pres - ence of the grass hoppers or the Hessian fly not coming. The farmer should tie to something that will make him a living proposition. Professor Haecker: I have noticed in the last few years encour - aging signs looking oward the betterment of general farming. The first is the encouraging signs of better and higher prices for our stock. Only a few years ago a grade cow could be bought for $40.00. I have bought and put in the yard here grade cows giving as high as 400 pounds of butter a year for $45.00. These cows actually made from $150 to $200. Xow we are having much better prices for our dairy products, and they are in keeping with the prices paid for stock. The next encouraging sign is the better feeding methods. I mean the recognition of the silo as a means of making a ration to balance alfalfa. We should clearly understand the balanced ration — that one element of it is a cheap sort of protein, and the other a cheap sort of carbon-hydrates. It Is a matter of conservation and people are now recognizing those things. About 18 years ago I spoke much concerning the silo. I hardly can say I wasted my breath in that matter, but now the general public, the farmer, if you please, is finding out these things. In fact, he knows considerable about good feeding. He knows a good deal about the balanced ration; the economical production of rations. He is finding that in Nebraska we can produce cheap rations. There is another good sign, an : that is the increase in the price of land. As land goes up we find dairying becomes more popular. With the higher prices of land we are inclined to work better and use better methods. We have not enough feeding cattle in this country. If there is any country or state that can afford to raise beef, it is Nebraska — here where we have the cheapest corn and cheapest hay. With more cattle, no matter what kind, we will have much better conditions. Our business, I mean this Dairymen's Association, is not only a place to get together and exchange ideas, but also to get the man here who is not a dairyman, but who wants to know about these matters. We must not only show him that there is a profit in the business, but also that by entering the business he will better his condition and ncrease the value of his land. This is a subject upon which I would ike to hear from others. U Question: Suppose we put in 100,000 cattle in Nebraska, what effect uld it have upon the sale of butter in this country? Answer: You cannot consider those things. I do not think it would influence it one iota. bit we had in Nebraska today 200,000 more dairy cows than we have we would have a better market for dairy cows; better price for" r products than we have now, because we would make it a buying </seg>
            <seg id="p084">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 85 center for dairy cattle. We would hare people coming In here from all parts of the country to buy. There are hundreds and hundreds of cars of cattle going through Nebraska every year to the great western country. We might just as well grow this stock here that is in demand, and will be in demand for a long time — as long as people live in this untry Question: Is butter fat higher in Nebraska than in Iowa? Answer I do not think it is. There is not so much difference in e of butter fat in the different states. t I found that in New York state hay was $26.00 a ton, and $9.00 here. This must be taken into consideration when we compare values. The east cannot compete with Nebraska in either stock or stock products. Mr. Jarvis: I was up in Minnesota in 1905 where wheat was selling around 33 cents a bushel, and the price of land was in the same ratio; ery low prices there for two or three years. I went up there with two r three other men. We would meet around in school houses and hurches and we urged diversified farming, especially in dairy counties. That country is now covered with cheese factories where once they raised nothing but wheat. Wi.h dairy farming we always have more or less diversity. The point I wish to make is that we should not be switched aside because we are now getting $1.45 for wheat and $1.25 for corn. We must raise some grain, but we may Just as well have some cows that will consume it and make our farming more diversified that when the change comes it will be all the better. Mr. Carlisle: I am a farm demonstrator. I would like to have the views of you gentlemen in regard to something better, perhaps, than timothy and alfalfa for pasture. Our demonstrator last year or - ganized a sweet clover campaign. He was the man to bring sweet lover before the majority of the farmers. He says he would like to ave you visit a man in Battle Creek who has nine years' experience. Together with others who ha I sown sweet clover we went. He w*a very enthusiastic in regard to the benefits to be derived from sweat clover as pasture. He never had but one or two cases of bloat Said he could guarantee at least two bead more on sweet clover than on other pasture; and we can cut more hay. If we can secure this clover to pasture one head more to the acre and have no trouble with bloat. We had a sweet clover discussion in these meetings last year and. If I remember correctly, the experience showed in faror of sweet clorer. Mr. Harrison: In regard to sweet clover, I live in the western part of the state and we have to be careful what we raise. I met a farmer the other day who said he put in 80 acres of alfalfa and did n&lt;* get anything of a stand. I put out 10 acres and got a good stand about in the same locality. I have raised sweet clover. I drove the cows over there one day. They ate it. The next day they broke in and went right down after that sweet clover. As to whether the cows will eat It or not, I think that is proof pretty conclusive. I Inoculated by taking soil from alfalfa land. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">86 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION The President: We know now that there must be bacteria in tbe soil for the successful growth of some plants, and there is always more certainty of growth if there is inoculation, but you will get a start without the inoculation if the bacteria is in the soil. They have to be there, but if not, you will not get a stand without the inoculation. L Question: Does not he soil have to be seeded one year after other? The President: Every other year, and then it will seed itself Question: How is the ground prepared? UAnswer: It must be inoculated. You don't need to do it the nd year. Cattle feeding on it will do that. Question: What is the best variety, yellow or white? Mr. Carlisle: From my experience I have learned that yellow is the most suitable for grazing purposes. Yellow is the better for pasture. Be sure and do not set the annual yellow or annual white. By that you would have to sow it all over again the next year. L Question: Is there any way of telling whether the land nee culation or not? Answer: Write to the University and they will tell you A Voice: There is very little land in Nebraska that needs clover Inoculation. It will grow less humus than alfalfa. Wherever you find sweet clover growing on the road side in your locality, you need not bother about inoculating the soil. The sweet white biennial is the most generally recommended. It grows a little taller and coarser than the yellow but so far has been the most popular. Question: How do you prepare the ground for sweet clover? Answer: Get the Nebraska Bulletin of Agricultural Department In regard to the preparation of the soil, I think, if the soil is not in bad condition, if there are no bad, noxious weeds In your pasture, Is to sow It on the snow at any time up to the first of April. In that manner the seel will sink down into the soil by thawing and freezing and the animals tramping over it. Sweet clover needs a firm seed bed, and will grow best where it does have it, and where there is some tramping on the soil. It should be sown on top of the ground with your grass seeder. If your pasture is in bad shape it is best to plow it up. Cattle should not then be turned in upon it until it gets several inches high. Better give it that much of a start. And it could be pastured too heavily at the start. Mr. Carlisle: Do not make the mistake and buy Annual clover seed. I think sweet clover hay is better than alfalfa hay as a feed. There is more stem to the alfalfa, I am told, than there is to sweet clover. The President: Mr. Wilson, of the Shorthorn Breeders' Associa - tion is here and wishes to make an announcement. UMr. Wilson: Gentlemen: I only wish to extend an invitation to to attend the Shorthorn Breeders' Association meeting. On motion, the invitation was accepted. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">THIRTIETH ANMAL CONVENTION 87 The President: The next paper on the program is by Protestor Redfern, on the subject of "Cream Grading." Mr. Redfern has left the state of Nebraska and gone to Iowa, and I will, therefore, ask our secretary to read the paper that Professor Redfern has so kindly pre - pare' for us. (The paper is read by Secretary McGinnis as follows). (REAM (iKUHVt. The quality of cream sold in Nebraska for the purpose of butter making is not good and that there has long been a desire to improve this quality, are admitted facts by all familiar with condiions. The problem which has confronted those interested, has been how to raise this quality under the conditions of buying which obtain in this state as well as several other states in the Great Middle West. Grading cream offered for sale and paying according to quality is generally admitted as the only solution of this problem, for so long as there is only one price for good and bad cream, the producer has no incentive to use more care in producing and handling his product and a large percent of bad cream wil continue to be delivered to the stations. The station system of buying cream apparently is with us to stay, and" though it presents many difficulties in the way of regulation and con - trol, it seems to be the best method under our conditions where so many farmers do not milk cows in earnest, but merely as a means of obtain - ing a little "ready cash" to meet the family demands between crops. The result is that he will not give his few cows and their product the nec - wmttf care, as his best efforts are directed toward producing good grain crops, and fattening hogs and cattle for market. When we begin to pay the producer for taking better care of his cream, then will the quality improve, and Nebraska butter will begin to score higher in the markets. The man who makes dairying a business will take better care of hii ws ani produce a better product. Too few men in Nebraska are really dairymen but are content with a few cows to furnish milk and butter for the family use. The surplus, after being held several days under unfavorable conditions, is sold to the factory agent to be made into butter. Under these conditions, it I* next to impossible to get quality. Strong competition In the cream business has prevented the creameries from adopting a system of grading at the stations and paying on quality. The desire to get busi - ness and hold it causes the operator to grade dishonestly with the result that nothing is gained. It has remained for the Food and Dairy Commissions in the various states to take the matter in hand and issue rules for buying cream on a quality basis. Our neighboring state, Kansas, has probably done more along the quality development than any other state and has met with some success. A few years ago the authorities there tried out the plan of grading cream by the acid test and were partly successful, being able in their experiment to improve the quality of the cream from the stations using the test. It is recognized, however, that high </seg>
            <seg id="p087">88 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION acidity is only in part indicative of quality, so there may be present putrefacative bacteria and mouldy flavors which can not be detected by -he acid test. Factories grade entirely by taste and smell, and it is obvious that the only successful method to use at the station in grading the patrons* cream, is the same method as is used in the factory. Kansas is now rying this method of grading at their stations, and paying for it ac - cording to grade. So far, they have discovered that the station op - erator is able to grade closely by tasting and smelling the cream, that No. 2 cream is decreasing and No. 1 increasing, also that with a few ex - ceptions the patron is in favor of the plan. The Nebraska Commlsison adopted a plan similar to that of Kansas, as an experiment with a trial period in which no difference in price would be made. We have noted some Improvement, and when the price is made* to vary with the quality, there will be greater improve - ment. It may be necessary to eliminate the operator who will grade dishonestly in order to get new business from his competitor, but the sooner this class of men are eliminated from our great cream buying system, the better it will be for the dairy industry. The time has come for the valuation of cream on a quality basis, which is admitted to be the only rational method of buying and selling any commodity To make it successful, however, the creameries must work in absolute harmony with the State Department, for without this co-operation the system must fail. It is hoped that at this critical time that those in - terested will use every Iionest effort to establish for all future time, a rational system in Nebraska, of buying cream. The President: Is there any discussion on this paper? I think it wouK be proper to call on someone familiar with cream quality and cream grading. I see in the audience Prof. J. D. Jarvis. and I will ask him to take the lead in the discussion of this paper. Mr. Jarvis: Mr. President and Gentlemen: It certainly gives me great pleasure to be with you today. Last week I was with the Dairymen of Missouri and Oklahoma. Those associations went on record recom - mending the grading of cream, and this morning your association went on record for the same thing The grading of cream is very important, and it reminds me of the story of the Irishman who just came over to this country to visit his brother. The brother said to him, "Mike, did you ever see a circus?" Mike says, "No, I never did." "Well, they have an animal in the circus called the giraffe, a very peculiar looking creature with a long neck and small head, and say, it is remarkable." Mike said, "I would like to see that giraffe." In the afternoon they went to the circus and saw the animal, and after Mike carefully viewed it from every angle he finally said to his brother, "Pat, there is no such animal as a giraffe." But the animal was there just the same, and the dairymen often say there la no such thing as the grading of cream. Gentlemen, the time is here when we MUST grade cream and pay for it according to grade, because </seg>
            <seg id="p088">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 89 t is an economical problem. It means economy to the farmer, to the reamery man and to the consumer of dairy products. n a dairy association we should have farmers, dairymen, creamery and all parties interested in the dairy industry. This association he medium of uniting the producer, manufacturer and con- dairy products. The farmer who is interested in caring for few cows an- who may not be classed as a dairyman should belong is association because it is the instrument for his protection. The who breeds Jersey or Holstein cattle, should belong to this imi iation because it will protect his interests. The same is true of the manufacturer and consumer of dairy products. Your dairy association today means the entire dairy industry of Nebraska. It should be true iu all the states. Some of the states have amended their constitution and by-laws so as to make their dairy association an organization for protection against the evils in the dairy Industry, unfair laws, unjust discrimination, etc. You must remember that dairying in the pact SO years has grown rapi-ly from a very disorganized branch of agriculture to a well organized branch of agriculture. Dairy products are second to the corn crop in value to our nation. We see in the northern states like Minnesota, Wisconsin, Michigan and New York, more of the dairy type of cows which have made dairying successful In those states. We these states becoming very prosperous. In fact, Wisconsin claims o be the most progressive state in the Union. Dairying gives more abor to the farmers. It causes them to employ help throughout the e year. Dairying is a cash business and has a tendency to cause farmers to become thrifty and pay cash instead of asking credit. I enables him to make a living first, or, in other words, it enables im to make the pennies before he makes the dollars, and, if the farmers if Nebraska will use the dairy cow as a nucleus of their farm business and build all o her branches of farming, like poultry, hog raising, fat cattle feeding and small grain farming, around it, they will have a daily cash income and will do less speculating in the business of farming. According to the Dairy Commissioner of Wisconsin, their dairy iroducts amounted to $100,000,000 last year, about one-fourth of the ost of the Panama Canal. This large amount of money came to the farmers in that state, not in any lump sum, but in small sums throughout the entire year. Yon did not see in the daily papers or agricultural papers any notice where Wisconsin farmers wanted from 15,000 to 20,000 men to help harvest their milk or butter fat crop. No, because the men were on the farm through - out the year. Dairying is often called, "THE HARVEST THAT NEVER STOPS." The grading of cream is very important to the dairy industry be - cause it is an economical factor to the farmer, creamery man and the consumer. On Monday, Professor Bouska had the New York butter quotations for January 9th on the board to explain the relation between </seg>
            <seg id="p089">90 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION the quality of butter, score of butter, quality of cream, price per pound of butter, and I am using this table to show this same relation. Difference in price between Extra Butter and Packing Butter is 14 cents. Difference in price between Extras and Firsts is 4 cents, and difference in price between Extras and Seconds is 12 cents. Who lost this money? Did the manufacturer lose it? Yes, they may have lost a little, but the greater part is lost by the farmer who produces the butter fat. Why did not the farmers receive it? Because their product was not worth it; they allowed the cream to deteriorate on the farm or in transit to the market. The milk from which ladles or packing stock" was made was just as good as the milk from which the extra butter was made when it came from the cow. If the milk or cream which made the packing stock had received the proper care on the farm in regard to cleanliness, control of temperature, and frequent delivery to the market, there would not be this wide difference between Extras and Packing Stock and the farmers would have received more money for their butter fat. By studying the above table you will see that poor quality cream is uneconomical to the farmer and the creamery. To the farmer it means a lower price for his butter fat; unprofitable dairy. It causes him to continue "soil mining," by selling his soil's fertility through grain farming and speculation instead of building up the soil by keep - ing better and a greater number of dairy live stock. To the creamery industry, it means a lower quality of butter, a greater manufacturing cost, due to abnormal losses of butter fat. because of inferior quality of cream; greater marketing cost, because the market is flooded with poor quality of butter and the severe com - petition that creamery received from the manufacturers of oleomargar - ine. These facts show "why" Nebraska cream should be sold by grade, and the following rules adopted by the Northwest Dairy Officials of Des Moines, Iowa, December 11, 1914, show "how" Nebraska cream should be sold by grade: We, your Committee on Resolutions, do hereby recommend the following resolutions: First: That three grades of cream be established, and known and described as follows: EXTRA Extra grade cream is sweet cream suitable for table use and such as will not curdle in hot water, tea or coffee. luality of Butter. Score of Butter. Quality of Cream. F rice of Butter '.xt ras 92 and up Extra . . . .34 to .35 "irsts 88 to 91 leconds 83 to 87 jadles and Packing Firsts Seconds . . . .31 to 33 . . . .23 to .30 Stock Below 83 Illegal Cream . . . . . . .21 to .22 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 91 FIRST GRADE First grade cream shall consist of cream that is clean to the taste and smell, slightly sour, containing not to exceed four-tenths of 1 per cent acid, and to contain not less than 25 per cent butter fat, and free from lumps, curd, dirt and all other foreign matter. SECOND GRADE Second grade cream is cream that is too sour to grade as first grade, weedy, or having other undesirable flavors or odors. ILLEGAL CREAM Illegal cream is cream that is very old, rancid, mouldy, dirty, or urdy, or that which is produced from an unclean separator, or that is stored, handled or transported in unclean cans, or that has been pro - duced, handled, separated, stored or transported in violation of the State Dairy Pure Food or Sanitary Law, and the sale, purchase or manufacture of such cream for any food purpose, should be prohibited by statutes. J. H. FRANDSEN Professor of Dairy Husbandry, University of Ne- braska, Chairman of Committee. J. B. NEWMAN, Deputy Food Commisisoner, Illinois. A. P. RYGER, Dairy Commissioner, South Dakota. Member: Do we have to trust to the honesty of the creamery man ve us that 14 cents in grading cream? Mr. Jarvis: Yes, you have to trust the creamery operator, and I believe the farmers and creamery operators can come to an under - standing, which will be beneficial to both parties. If you demand the grading of cream — the creamery operators will grade and pay you what the product is worth. I am gratified to know that this associa - tion went on record this morning asking for the grading of cream, and will be willing to co-operate with the creameries to produce a better quality of cream and creamery butter. Your Dairy Commissioner said yesterday, that large numbers of farmers in this state do not take good care of their cream on the farm, or in shipping to the market It is the care the milk and cream receives from the time it is produced to the time it is shipped to the cream station that determines whether it will be poor or good quality. When you mix a poor quality of cream with good cream, the poor quality is a bad starter and starts the good quality cream on the down grade. It is like keeping one rotten apple with three good apples for a period of time. The rotten apple does not improve the good apples. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">92 There are three methods of determining the quality of cream: the enses, taste and smell. — the acidity content and the butter fat content. You may say that these tests are impractical, but I say to you that they are practical and are reduced to a practical working basis. I: is up o the cream station to use the method of testing cream for acidity and to find out whether it comes in as Extra, First, or Second grade. That s one of the reasons why Wisconsin has made such rapid progress in he past 25 years. It is due to the fact that their farmers realize that airying i8 an important branch of agriculture and that they must pro - duce a better quality of cream. The State University, Farmers' Insti- Utes and Agricultural Workers in that state have been teaching farmers and creamery men these facts for the pa8t number of years. Their armers are now delivering fine quality of cream and are receiving he highest market price. The game thing can be true in Nebraska. If you deliver your cream sweet to the creamery, the creamery man will be able to make the aighest quality of butter that will bring the highest market price. I believe that if you wouli do this, it will build up the dairy industry It will be an incentive for you to milk better cows and for other farmers who are not milking cows to go into the dairy business. Professor Haecker said that dairying is an economical factor to the farmer, be - cause it enables him to keep better live stock, to get better prices for his grains and hays, by feeding them to the dairy live Stock and enables him to go more into diversified farming. Better dairying is good for the creamery man because it gives him a better Class of cream to manu - facture in;o butter. Better quality butter enables the creamery to ob - tain better prices; enables the creamery to make a better quality of butter, which will not have to compete with firsts, seconds, or oleo - margarine, if the farmers and creamery men would get together on the grading of cream and assist the Dairy &lt; ommisisoner in enforcing the laws upon the statute book there will be an increase of dairying in Nebraska that will make her one of the greatest dairy states In the Union. (Applause). Member: I was in Professor Haecker's office at University Farm, Minnesota, and he told me that the farmers of that state were receiving 8 cents a pound more for butter fat there than they were in Nebraska. WhyT Mr. Jarvis: Because Minnesota farmers produce a better quality Of cream. Minnesota farmers realize that dairying is an important branch of agriculture and they realize that they must produce a good, Clean cream. They are following the instructions of Professor Haecker to produce a good, clean product, to have the temperature of cream under control on the farm, in transportation to the market and to deliver their cream sweet, or of a clean acid flavor to the creamery. They receive more than they do here in Nebraska or in the south - western states, because the farmers of Kansas, Nebraska and Oklahoma. a class, do not appreciate cleanliness. They do not appreciate </seg>
            <seg id="p092">THIRTIETH AXNTAL COXVEXTTOX 93 nperature of cream on the farm, and the frequent delivery of cream the creameries. Of the 1,000 creameries in Wisconsin, about 85 er cent receive nearly all hand separated cream, and the cream is n-eet or of a clean acid flavor. The farmers realize the importance f better quality cream, and are willing to follow the suggestions of leir cream market. That is one of the reasons why Wisconsin Is FIRST in Butter, FIRST in Cheese, and FIRST in the number of dairy cows. niscrssiox Professor Bouska: I wish to add something more to this question of prices. These prices are made up by selecting the highest price to represent one en- and the lowest price to represent the other end with - out full regard for the conditions that produce those prices. It is nearly 2fl years ago since I made my first creamery butter. I worked in the Iowa dairying school and then worked as a cream inspector in Iowa for a year and a half. At that time we had In our section of the country a number of co-operative creameries, and I became acquainted with many interesting conditions. I found that among co-operative cream- eries themselves the same condition existed that Mr. Hamilton spoke of this morning. You will remember how he said that at the start in trying to get business they would give a higher price at the start and w they would cut it down. There are some creameries who do that in order to gain in the business and in order to gaid new busi - ness. By confessing that I need not create the impression that people in the creamtTy business are not as honest as people in other business. creamery business you will find some people who will do things lould not do One winter in Ames we did not have enough material, so one of my brother instructors went to a town not far away where a co-operative creamery was run just the way it ought to be. we thought. We made an agreement with them to ship us all their cream. We were to pay them for butter fat on the basis of what the butter sold for, but give them the benefit of the overrun. You understand that. In making butter. 100 pounds of butter fat yields from 115 to 120 pounds of butter — so they were to get the benefit of that. At the end we made settlement with them, but they were dissatisfied. We gave them about 80 per cent overrun, but they claimed a bigger overrun. This same instructor who made the agreement went out there to see the directors. He told them It was impossible to get as much over - run as they claimed; that the only way to get at it would be by cutting the test. They called on the butter maker and he said he had been cutting the test down in order to make less butter fat and a bigger rice. Here and there you will be able to pick out a case of that kind. Go into the state of Minnesota, or any state, and you will find that all the prices are not alike. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">94 UQues ion: Why don't the creameries in Minnesota' all pay the e price if they have the ideal conditions? Answer: You must make an exception there. You must take all these extreme cases of very high and very low prices into consideration. The conditions should be looked into in each individual case in order to come to a reasonable conclusion. There is another thing in which Minnesota and Wisconsin farmers get a price that does not obtain or exist here which they might count of value and they might not. They deliver cream right at the creamery. There is no expense attached to the delivery. The expense of the trans - portation of the cream to the factory comes out of the price. In the sending out of quotation prices and checks, one or two cents in postage for every one of those transactions has to come out. In Minnesota this extra expense is not deducted from the price. This extra expense in Nebraska is about 4 cents a pound for butter fat When you study the thing closely you will find prices harmonize better than if you compare only these extreme prices. You can create an exaggerated impression that is not representative and which is not fair. Question: I like dairying and I would like to have some one tell me why, in Nebraska, where you have Farmers' Co-Operative Creameries centralized with three, four or five agents in the same town, some of the farmers will take their cream to those agents instead of patronizing their own institutions? Professor Bouska: I can give, perhaps, some specific case. My father has been president of a co-operative creamery in Northern Iowa 21 years. My father's brother-in-law shipped his cream out of town and did not take it to the co-operative creamery because he was sus - picious. He said that certain ones always held the same office all the time, and he believed there was something crooked; that someone must be getting a rake-off because they were in the office all the time. You will fin i a great many of them all over the country who, for some reason or other, will not patronize that kind of a creamery. There was a gentleman here this morning who owns a creamery in Nebraska. A: one time his creamery was situated on the outskirts of the town, while a competitor of his had a cream station right in town. The local creamery paid 2 cents more for butter than the cream station. The cream station in town is convenient for the farmer and it gets just as much cream as the creamery gets for 2 cents more. You would naturally think that all of them would take their cream to the local creamery and get the 2 cents a pound more, but they would rather take 2 rents less in town and save the drive to the creamery. I know of another creamery in Iowa in which a friend of mine is interested. The butter maker looks after the business. Some of his friends, people who pretend to be loyal, left their cream at the com - petitor's cream station down town and did not take it to the creamery, some two or three blocks out of the way. When they brought cream to the creamery again, he butter maker asked, "Where have you been?" </seg>
            <seg id="p094">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 95 They replied. "We have been busy harvesting and we left our cream with the man in town because it was handier." The President: The Resolutions Committee is now ready to report »nd we will listen to their report. HE PORT OF RESOLUTIONS COMMITTEE WHEREAS, We have felt the need of a new Dairy Building on the rniversity Campus as an aid to better dairying in this state; WHEREAS, Plans are completed for a thoroughly modern and well equipped Dairy Building, be it RESOLVED, That we express our sincere appreciation to the Hon - orable Board of Regents, to the Chancellor, and to all others whose ef - forts have brought about this great stimulus to better dairying in Nebraska. WHEREAS, We believe one of the best means of bettering dairying Nebraska is by advertising the progress already made; WHEREAS, The exhibit placed at the 1914 Nebraska State Fair by the Nebraska Dairy and Creamery Improvement Association has been widely commended, be it RESOLVED, That we express our thanks to this association for the splendid work it has done. RESOLVED, That this association hereby expresses its appreciation of the valuable service to dairying to Nebraska which Mr. E. L. Redfern has rendered during his years of service, and further, that we express our regret that he is leaving the work at this time. RESOLVED, That we, as an association, recognizing the great work which Governor W. D. Hoard has done for dairying, wish to endorse the movement now under way to erect an appropriate memorial to "The Father of Modern Dairying," upon the Agricultural Campus of the Uni - versity of Wisconsin. RESOLVED, That, recognizing the value of putting dairying on a business basis and the benefits to be had by testing cows, we endorse the pow testing association and will use our best efforts in promoting this work. WHEREAS, We believe one of the befit means of advertising and promoting the industry of dairying is by exhibiting the best types among the several dairy breeds; WHEREAS, The dairy cattle exhibits at the Nebraska State Fair have been small in number and many of the pure bred herds of the state are not represented at this Fair, be it RESOLVED, That we recommend to the State Fair Association, as a means of bettering this line of work, the appointment of a Dairy Cattle Superintendent, whose duties it shall be to promote dairying by encouraging a larger exhibit of dairy animals and to superintend this department during the State Fair. WHEREAS, Additional dairy work along lines educational and experimental is greatly needed in Nebraska; </seg>
            <seg id="p095">96 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION WHEREAS, The available funds are insufficient to carry on this work efficiently, be It RESOLVED, That this association respectfully petition the State Legislature for substantial appropriations for dairy work. RESOLVED, That we tender our appreciation to the officers of this association for the efforts they have put forth during the past year in carrying on the work, and for the arrangement and careful direction of the program of this convention; And be it further Resolved, That we pledge our best support to the newly elected officers, to the Dairy Department of the University of Nebraska, and to all other forces working toward the common end of making dairying greater in Nebraska. Committee: PROF. J. H. FRANDSEN, Chairman. W. C. ANDREAS. Motion carried that the report be accepted and committee discharged The Prestd«nt: We will now adjourn to the Dairy Cow Barn, Judging Pavilion, where the cow judging contest will be held, and this meeting will stand adjourned. THE COW JUDGING CONTEST This event as usual was interesting but the number of contestants was nat as large as usual on account of two other judging contests being in progress at the same time. kThe same rules and regulations were in effect as former years only e President decided to give gold, silver, and bronze medals to the win - rs instead of cash prizes as in former years. The following is a list of those winning medals and score each on€ Score Henry O. Weller Raymond, Nebraska gn W. E. Rundall 1341 D St., Lincoln Z. H. Chittenden 2734 Everett St., Lincoln 80 J. W. Vedlock 745 J St.. Lincoln 80 C. A. Kramer R. F. D., Lincoln .x. E. Swan King Valley, Nebraska R0 L. C. McCartney R. No. 7, Box 309, Lincoln 76 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">THIRTIETH AXMAI. CONVENTION 97 Xlnatex of the Fifth Annual Meeting of the NEBRASKA \SS4MIATIU&gt; OF ICE IKKVM MASCFACTCBERS January t8 and i», Itl5 Omaha, Nebraska. The Fifth Annual Meeting of the Nebraska Association nf Ice Cream Manufacturers was called to order by the President, R. W. McGinnis, t 2:30 p. m., in the Rome Hotel. Roll call of members present as follows ACTIVE Beatrice Creamery Co Beatrice, Nebraska Dickey, Robert North Platte, Nebraska Fairmont Creamery Co Omaha, Nebraska Franklin Creamery Co Lincoln, Nebraska Fremont Ice Cream Co Fremont, Nebraska Hathaway, H. C Lincoln, Nebraska Harding Ice Cream Co Omaha, Nebraska Holdrege Ice Cream Co Holdrege, Nebraska McGinnis Creamery Co O'Neill, Nebraska Peterson, H. O Genoa, Nebraska Steifer, P. J Geneva, Nebraska Verdigre Creamery Co Verdigre, Nebraska Waterloo Creamery Co Omaha, Nebraska Wolz Baking Company Fremont, Nebraska Freitag &amp; Co Norfolk, Nebraska ASSOCIATE Allen Candy Co Pontiac, Illinois Baker Ice Machine Co Omaha, Nebraska Confectioners' and Bakers' Supply Chicago, Illinois Creamery Package Mfg. Co Omaha, Nebraska Davis Cooperage Co Martinsville, Indiana Downey-Turnquist Co Chicago, Illinois Kt-nnedy &amp; Parsons Co Omaha, Nebraska Nelson, C, Mfg. Co St. Louis, Missouri Sethness Co Chicago, Illinois Wes ern Rock Salt Co Kansas City, Missouri Crown Cordial Extract Co New York City Consumers' Glue Co - St. Louis, Missouri Twin City Separator Co Minneapolis, Minnesota Riirhter Mfg. Co New York, N. T. </seg>
            <seg id="p097">98 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION HONORARY Frandsen, J. H Lincoln, Nebraska Ringer. F. J Lincoln, Nebraska Upon motion duly seconded and carried the minutes of the last meeting were not read The report of the treasurer for the past year was then read, show ing as follows: January 1st, cash on hand $146.96 February 5th, received from secretary 182.00 February 19th, received from secretary 10.00 May 14th, received from Beatrice Creamery Co. May 14th, received from Nebraska Cream Co. September 22nd, received from John Petrow 2.C Total »350.9« EXPENDITURES February 9th, Fairmont Creamery Co t 16 64 February 9th, Rees Printing Co 29 February- »th. Myrtle A. Kelley 48 May 14th, Rees Printing Co. July 7th, M. S. Hartman 1915, R. W. McGinnis January 12th. F. G. Caldwell January 13th, Stanley Green Total * Cash on hand Total »3-"&gt;( There being no objection, on motion duly seconded the treasurer was ordered received, approved and placed on file. Next the report of the secretary for the past year was read. "I believe that the Ice Cream Manufacturers of Nebraska have had a most satisfactory year, and the prospects are fair for an increa volume of business during 1915. This association gained seven active members in 1914. making 2 The associate membership gained the same number. At that rate th association is not growing as rapidly as it should, although previous meetings have been very successful and full of interest. The Program Committee nas arranged for some fine numbers on the program, which is to follow, and the entertainment feature has not been overlooked. If this meeting pleases you, tell your neighbor manufacturer about it, and get them to come next time; for no one ever regrets the time and </seg>
            <seg id="p098">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 99 money it takes to attend these meetings when he measures up the bene - fits derived. I sincerely hope that each one of you will feel that it has been good For you to meet with us at this time, and that we may have you all back with us another year. There being no objection, on motion duly seconded and carried, the report of the secretary was ordered received, approved and placed on file. Report of Standing Committees was next on the program, but Mr. Clark, of the committee, being absent, the report was not read. The next scheduled event was an Address of Welcome by Mayor Dahlman. The mayor having not yet arrived, President McGinnis asked Mr. Brewer to tell about the Iowa Association. Mr. Brewer stated that the Iowa Association has the same trouble as the Nebraska Association in interesting the smaller dealer in the association. The smaller dealer thinks of his own business and doesn't give any at - tention to his competitor, said Mr. Brewer. Mr. Brewer said that they intended to interest the smaller dealer by group meetings as done Illinois L'i&gt;on motion, duly seconded and carried, Mr. McGinnis appointed Mr. Harding as Vice President, as Mr. Dodds was absent from the con - vention. The meeting was again called to order after a recess, and an Ad- Welcome was delivered by Mayor Dahlman. Mayor Dahlman stated in his address that he was glad to have such a convention held in this city. The mayor thought the Ice Cream Manufacturers had picked out a splendid day to hold their meeting, the thermometer registered zero weather. Dahlman also called at - tention to the growth of Omaha, and the size of the buildings being erected at the present time. He stated that he had come to the meeting to extend a welcome and to present the key to do as you please while staying in the city. The mayor hoped that the next meeting was a success and that the association would hold their next meeting in the ty of Omaha. Ex-Mayor Wolz of Fremont next made a speech in response to Mayor Dahlman's address. An address (Travelogue) by J. H. Rushton was next on the program. Mr. Rushton described his trip abroad last summer, telling some of his experiences and observations. He told many interesting things about cities in England, France, Germany and Switzerland. Mr. Rushton declared he doesn't admire the business activity of either London or Paris, and said, aside from the Bank of England, he saw nothing that impressed him with very much favor. Mr. Rushton told of the pleasant peasant life in France, and also* described the wine industry in that country. Mr. Rushton described so vividly the scenery of these countries </seg>
            <seg id="p099">100 the members present enjoyed the talk and agreed that it was the t best thing to seeing these countries personally. UMr. J. M. Harding was the last speaker of the afternoon. Mr. rding's subject was "The Shipper — The Shipped — The Shippee." Mr. Harding gave many good pointers in this talk. Mr. Harding gave the following "Don'ts": U Don't start a man wrong by praying for bis business. Make a want your goods. Don't curse him with unlimited credit. Don't always accept to let that nickel off that the other fellow is going to give him. Don't let the dealer manage the business for you. Mr. F. G. Caldwell announced that there was to be a theater party and that all those expecting to go should meet at the Rome Hotel promptly at 7:45. The President announced that the meeting would adjourn until 10 a. m. the following day. Vice President Dodds was unable to be present on account of sickness. At the meeting the following day, Prof. J. H. Prandsen of the Dairy DiYision of the Nebraska State University, delivered an address on "Stabilizers"; Mr. Hunt of Holdrege, Nebraska, delivered a very inter - esting talk on "Return of Empties." In the afternoon Prof. R. A. ?uever, Assistant Professor of Pharmacy of the Iowa University, de - ivered a very good talk on "Vanilla." An address was also made by Mr. F. I. Ringer, Commissioner of the Nebraska Manufacturers Associa - tion. Mr. Ringer described the new workmen's compensation and em - ployers' liability law. Then, under the head of unfinished business, the President an - tunced that the next order of business was the election of officers for i ensuing year, which resulted as follows: President, J. M. HARDING, Omaha, Nebraska, Vice President, W. C. HUNT, Holdrege, Nebraska. Treasurer, F. G. CALDWELL, Lincoln, Nebraska, Secretary, STANLEY GREEN, Omaha, Nebraska Upon motion, duly seconded and carried unanimously, the following gentlemen were elected members of the Executive Committee for the ensuing year: LEROY CORLISS, Omaha, Nebraska. ROBERT DICKEY, North Platte, Nebraska, GEORGE WOLZ, Fremont, Nebraska The President then gave the association members a chance to pre - sent their Tiews. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">101 Mr. Anderson of the Western Rock Salt Co., Kansas City, was the to speak, then Mr. Baker and Mr. Allen of tbe Baker Ice Machine Co. Mr. Righter of the Righter Mfg. Co. of New York, talked on the growth of the ice cream industry. Mr. Allen of the Allen Candy Co.. Pontiac. Illinois, also made short talks, after which Mr. Brewer of the Iowa Association invited all members of the Nebraska Association to attend their convention next year at Des Moines. Upon motion, duly seconded and carried, a vote of thanks was extended to Mr. McGinnis, retiring president for five years of faithful ervice in the association. It was announced that all members were invited to attend an enter- tainment by Knights of the Full Moon of Council Bluffs, and that all tending to go should meet at the Rome Hotel at 7:30. It was voted by ballot that the next meeting of the association ould be held at Lincoln, Nebraska. Upon motion, duly seconded and carried, the meeting then adjourned. WHOLESALE MAM I U TTRERS OF K'E CREAM IN NEBRASKA, 1*14 Beatrice (old Storage Co Beatrice, Nebr. Rucklos Bros Deshler, Nebr. Geo. F. Wolz Fremont, Nebr. Van Horn &amp; .Meyers Lexington, Nebr. West Point Ice Cream Co West Point, Nebr. Frietag Ice Cream Co Norfolk, Nebr. Hartington Creamery Hartington, Nebr. Buffalo Creamery Co Kearney, Nebr. Broken Bow Co-op. Creamery Co Broken Bow, Nebr. John Petrow Fremont, Nebr. Keystone Creamery Co York, Nebr. Franklin Creamery Co Franklin, Nebr. Frankline Ice Cream Co Lincoln, Nebr I^ouis K. Burkhalter Wymore, Nebr. H. O. Borham Gering. Nebr. Hastings Ice Cream Co Hastings, Nebr A. H. Keeppel Nebraska City, Nebr. Mendenhall &amp; Carey Hebron, Nebr J. F. Russell Ansley, Nebr. F. L. Regan Grand Island, Nebr. Swanborn &amp; Hult Wahoo, Nebr Geneva Mfg. &amp; Supply Co Geneva, Nebr Robinson Ice Cream Co Central City, Nebr P. J. Steifer Geneva, Nebr. David City Ice Cream Factory David City, Nebr, The Folsom Bakery Lincoln, Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p101">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION 102 Crawford Cream Co Crawford, Nebr. J. J. Chalupuik Verdigree, Nebr. F. E. HoUtein Alliance, Nebr Ravenna Creamery Co Ord. Nebr Higley Bros Blair, Nebr Holdrege Ice Cream Co Holdrege, Nebr. Fremont Pure Butter Co Fremont, Nebr Peter G. Bacakos Falls City, Nebr Orleans Creamery Co Orleans, Nebr McGinnis Creamery Co O'Neill, Nebr A. N. Richards Tecumseh, Nebr Roher &amp; Berger South Omaha, Nebr John Gilkerson Gordon, Nebr Davis Ice Cream Co Tecumseh, Nebr P. H. Hermes Falls City. Nebr Nebraska Cream Co Central City, Nebr F. E. Clark, Albion. Nebr Stuckey Ice Cream Co Lincoln, Nebr Alliance Creamery &amp; Produce Co Alliance, Nebr John Schiappacasse Plattsmouth, Nebr E. C. Byerly Chadron, Nebr W. A. Barnard Stromsburg, Nebr G. R. Dodds Superior. Nebr Collins Bros. Ice Cream Co Lincoln. Nebr Seward Creamery Co Seward, Nebr Leibold &amp; Jensen Nebraska city, Nebr Oakland Bottling Works Oakland, Nebr Plainview Bottling Works Plainview. Nebr Atteberry Bros Mitchell, Nebr Greens Ice Cream Co Nebraska City. Nebr Farmers Co-op. Cry. Co Fullerton, Nebr Reeds Ice Cream Co Randolph Nebr J. H. McCltntock Cedar Rapids. Nebr R. R. Dickey North Platte, Nebr Gothenburg Candy Kitchen Gothenburg, Nebr F. J. Johan sen Ains worth , Nebr Columbus Candy Kitchen Columbus, Nebr Webb &amp; Co Valentine, Nebr Wm. Poesch Columbus, Nebr Theo. Harrsch Niobrara, Nebr, H. O. Peterson Genoa, Nebr Fairmont Creamery Co Omaha. Nebr Fairmont Creamery Co Grand Island, Nebr. E. B. Kauff man Norfolk, Nebr Rieder &amp; Rollins McCook, Nebr Young tt Laird Superior, Nebr North Platte Candy Kitchen North Platte, Nebr C. C. Jones Columbus, Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p102">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 103 A. W. Dorland Bennet, Nebr. Farmers Co-op. Creamery Co Omaha, Nebr. rown Arapahoe, Nebr. me Dairy Fairbury, Nebr. at Omaha, Nebr. lllel Bak Fremont, Nebr. B. Fraser &amp; Son zy Cafe Auburn, Nebr Deshler. Nebr. A Plainview, Nebr. th A. Beenpy Minden. Nebr. RETAll I* K ki: \M MAX K UTl RKKS. 1914 ( asady &amp; Kriet Palisade, Nebr ;eronek Bros Ord, Nebr. *w 1. Young Newman Grove, Nebr. leo. D. Bervey Bassett, Nebr. T. A. Xeill Trenton, Nebr. W. L. Schultz Atkinson, Xebr. Frank L. Mettlen Winside, Nebr. Frank L. Mettlen Winside, Nebr. Sidney Drug Co Sidney, Xebr. Sidney Drug Co Sidney, Nebr. Frank Johnson Louisville, Xebr. Frank Johnson Louisville, Nebr. Geo. F. Woltz Fremont, Nebr. Woltz Fremont, Nebr. ( '. F. Zimmerman Naper, Nebr. F. Zimmerman Naper, Nebr. A. E. .Mayers Superior, Nebr. A. E. Mayers Superior, Nebr. Mrs. Nelson Rantz Red Cloud, Nebr. rs. Nelson Rant z Red Cloud, Nebr. las. P. Cooper : Arcadia, Nebr. as. P. Cooper ; Arcadia, Nebr. A. O. Gordon Merna. Nebr. A. O. Gordon Merna, Nebr. S. H. Showers &lt; Lin wood, Xebr. H. Showers ' Lin wood, Nebr. Moore &amp; Copeland Arcadia, Nebr. loore &amp; Copeland Arcadia, Nebr. .1. R. Smith Alliance, Nebr. I. R. Smith Alliance, Nebr. W. Wallace Burwell, Nebr. W. Wallace Burwell, Nebr. Nemetz &amp; Co Plattsmouth, Nebr. Nemetz &amp; Co Plattsmouth, Nebr. P. F. Peterson Bloom ington. Nebr. P. F. Peterson Bloomington, Nebr. G. H. Dubois Colon, Nebr. G. H. Dubois Colon, Nebr. New York Bakery Fremont, Nebr. New York Bakery Fremont, Nebr. Smith &amp; Shafer Sargent, Nebr. Smith &amp; Shafer Sargent, Nebr. Hugo Soil Humphrey, Nebr. G. L. Brown Arapahoe, Nebr. Arthur Metzner Holbrook, Nebr« J. W. Harman Orchard, Nebr. Dambach Pharmacy Hayes Center, Nebr. \V. F. Solt Lyon«, Nebr. A. E. Culson Dannebrog, Nebr. Saratoga Drug Co. ■ Omaha, Nebr. 3. R. Htll Culbertson, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION 104 Grand Island Candy Kitchen Grand Island, Nebr Stone Drug Co North Platte, Net&gt;r. J. H. Ewing Bassett, Nebr. Robinson &amp; Robinson Danbury, Nebr. A. D. Townsend W. Landkamer M. Magner Cook Bros. C. A. Buckmaster Royal R. Marshall Hooper, Nebr. M. W. Wheeland tc Co. H. H. Cone L. H. Waldter John J. Ackerman S. S. Stinneth P. Peterson P. 8. Holtzinger Royal Chocolate Shop Logerwell Drug Co Naper, Nebr Peter G. Bacakos Falls City, Nebr U M. Clark Scotia. Nebr R. F. Cihacek Howells, Nebr Johnson Drug Co Ord. Nebr Palisade Pharmacy Palisade. Net S. S. Weatherby Staplehurst. Nel The Tanner Pharmacy Lynch, Nebr Davis Ice Cream Co Tecumseh. Nebr A. W. Messersmith Taylor, Nebr H. J. Felber Wayne, Nebr Guy Meyers 2921 Leavenworth St., Omaha. N&lt; P. H. Hermes Falls City, N&gt;l, A. E. Neir Aurora. Nebr Arcade Rest Grant, Nebr Opera House Pharmacy Plainview, Nebr Farrens &amp; Neimeyer Hastings, Nebr Crystal Candy Co Omaha. Nebr Arthur A. Schuster Grand Island. Nebr Theo. Larsen Wilsonville, Neb H. C. Hansen Verdel. Nebr Herrington Drug Co Newman Grove, Nebr Royal Chocolate Shop Grand Island, Nebr p. R. McCleery Alma. Nebr Lexington Candy Kitchen Lexington, Nebr A. W. Dorland C. L. McLoud R. C. Hoffman H. C. Bullis Lomax Ice Cream Co. send Ponca, Nebr. ler Alexandria. Nebr Pierce. Xebr M » r N »' r laster Ashland. Nebr k Co Campbell. Nebr Ashland. Xebr. 2218 No. 24th St., Omaha. Nebr. Hendley. Xebr. Wauneta. Xebr. 534 Xo. 24th St.. South Omaha. Xebr. Pleasanton, Xebr. Ihop Grand Island. Xebr. nd Bennett, Nebi 1 Hay Springs, Nebi in Me I jean. Neb Humboldt. Xeb ream Co Hastings, Neb </seg>
            <seg id="p104">THIRTIKTH AXXVAI. CONVENTION 105 Homer Grimm W. T. Mincer M. E. Mickelson J. H. Hebner W. \V. Mahannah J. P. Kirwin I. H. McClintock Curtis Home Bakery- Sam Hoffer &lt; olumbug Candy Kitchen G. C. Glover Madison, Nebr. North Platte Candy Kitchen North Platte, Nebr Peter Zirbilis Omaha, Nebr. Mrs. M. A. Clopton Burton, Nebr. Young &amp; Laird Superior, Nebr. A. B. Yoder Talmage, Nebr A. M. Wuetsbaugh Neligh, Nebr Doolittle Produce Co North Platte, Nebr. Hastings Candy Kitchen Queen City Confectionery F. R. Happock R. O. Phelps G. H. Koeppel James Miller M. Roberts Abariotes Bros. Huff &amp; Dailey The Folsom Bakery T. B. Dawson Gates ft Son I. W. Lewis Geo. A. Beeney Geo. E. Cline J. E. Brown Cedar Valley Cry Monowi, Nebr Cozad, Nebr Bartlett, Nebr Bristow, Nebr. Butte, Nebr Butte, Nebr Cedar Rapids. Nebr Alliance, Nebr Haigler, Nebr hen Columbus. Nebr Am. Poesch Columbus, Nebr £. ('. Jones Columbus, Nebr rt. O. Peterson Genoa, Nebr t. S. Chipperfleld Virginia, Nebr IValter Planek Madison. Nebr Hastings, Nebr Hastings, Nebr Fullerton, Nebr Omaha, Nebr Nebraska City, Nebr Madison. Nebr Beaver City, Nebr Omaha, Nebr. Wisner, Nebr Lincoln, Nebr. Sidney, Nebr David City, Nebr Taylor, Nebr Minden, Nebr Wauneta, Nebr Springview, Nebr Greeley. Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p105">106 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASSOCIATION- LIST OF LICENSED (KEAMEBIES IS NKIUMSK \ FOR THE YEAR 1914 Creamery. Town. County Beatrice Creamery Co. . Lincoln Pure Butter Co. Golden Creamery Co. . . Omaha Cold Storage Co. Fairmont Creamery Co. Fairmont Creamery Co. Fairmont Creamery Co. Lincoln Lancast Lincoln Lancasu Fremont Dodge Omaha Douglas Omaha Douglas Crete Salint Grand Island Hall Farmers Co-Op. Creamery Co. David Cole Creamery Co Omaha Douglas Omaha Douglas Waterloo Creamery Co. McGinnis Creamery Co. Nebraska Cream Co. Omaha Douglas O'Neill Holt Central City .Merri F. E. Clark . P. H. Hermes Wm. Betcher Albion Boone Pierce Fieri Hygenic Dairy £ Creamery Fontanelle Separator Cry. Co. ... Germantown Co-Op. Creamery Co Ravenna Creamery Co Fairbury leffersi Fontanelle Washingt Cermantown Sevvard Loup City Shermar olumbus Cream Co. . . Fremont Pure Butter Co. Riverton Co-Op. Cry. Co. Orleans Creamery Co. . 'ortland Creamery Co. "ranklin Creamery Co. Humbolt Creamery Co. Holdredge Creamery Co. Ravenna Creamery Co. J. J. Chalupuik Columbus Platt Fremont Dodge Riverton Frankli Orleans Harla ( 'ortland Gage Franklin Franklin Humboldt Richardsc Holdredge I helps Kavenna Buffal Verdigre Knox Keystone Creamery Co. York York Ijtncaster Milk Producers Assn. N'eligh Creamery Co Lincoln I Lancaster Neligh Antelope Fred Scneider Wes- Point Cumming Alliance Cry. &amp; Producers Co. Kirschbraun &amp; Sons Alliance Box Butte Omaha Dougla Beatrice Gage Beatrice Cold Storage Co. . . Alamito Sanitary Dairy Co. lenningsen Produce Co. . . . Valley Co-op. Cry. Co. Farmers Co-op. Cry. Co. rounce Cry Co., R. P. D. . . Adams Center Cry. Co Broken Bow Co-op. Cry. Co. Martin Nelson Omaha Douglas Superior Nuckolls Pannebrog Howard Wolbach Greeley Raymond Lancast Archer Merrick Broken Bow Custer Fremont Dodge St. LJbory Cry. Assn. St. Libory Howard Falls i ity Richardson </seg>
            <seg id="p106">THIRTIETH ANNUAL CONVENTION 107 Frank Johnson I^uisville CmM Martinirton Creamery Co Hartington Cedar iffalo Creamery Co Kearney Buffalo Van Horn &amp; Meye North Platte Lincoln A. \V. Dorland Bennett Lancaster \rr. ilia l"o-op. Cry Arcadia Valley (1 ( 'reamery Co Seward Se ward Blue Valley Cry. Co Hastings Adams Swift &amp; Co Lincoln Lancaster (iretns ice Cream Co Nebraska City Oto Farmers Co-op. Cry. Co Fullerton Nance Farmers Creamery Co Hemmingford Box Butte Webb ft Co Valentine Cherry a E. (ladd Or«J Valley Switzer Creamery Co Norfolk Madison Home Dairy (Earl Tuttle) Grand Island Hall A. Bisel Albion Boone Erickson Butter ft Egg Co Newman Grove Madison arl Rosche Leigh Colfax Sorens Sorensen Kimball Kimball Fairbury Cry. Co Fairbury Jefferson edar Valley Creamery Co Spaulding Greeley arpenter Deshler Thayer </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>