<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00074.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty Third Biennial Report Labor and Compensation December 1, 1930 to December 1, 1932</title>
               <date value="1932-12-01">1932-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Twenty Third Biennial Report Labor and Compensation December 1, 1930 to December 1, 1932 IS CHARLES W. BRYAN, Governor and Labor Commissioner i CECIL E. MATTHEWS, Chief Deputy Labor and i Compensation Commissioner | LEWIS-HOCK rRIMTINS CO.. LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STAFF Charles W. Bryan, , Governor and Commissioner Cecil E. Matthews,.. Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner Stephen Vai1,.... Chief Investigator Frank A. Dutton, , .Assistant Investigator P. j. Barrett, ; . .Factory Inspector Anna Rotruck, ; . File Clerk Dorothy Miller, _ Stenographer </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL December 1, 1932. To His Excellency, CHARLES W. BRYAN, Governor of Ne - braska: In compliance with the laws of the state of Nebraska, I have the honor to submit herewith the official report of the Department of Labor for the years 1931 and 1932. Respectfully yours Cecil E. Matthews, Chief Deputy Labor and Compensation </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Lincoln, Nebraska, December 1, 1932. To His Exellency Governor Charles W. Bryan, Capitol Building, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Governor Bryan: I have the honor of reporting to you herewith, the records of the De - partment of Labor and Compensation as provided by law, for the bi - ennium of 1931-32. Insomuch as the compensation records are compiled as of July Ist of each year, it is impossible for me to report for the year 1932 m com - pensation matters at this early date, however, all other data covers the records of the Department up to the present time. Two years ago the Labor Commission requested a biennial appropriation of $46,000. However, m your wisdom you declined to ask a legislative appropriation for that amount, but instead requested an appropriation of $36,000, which was given this Department. I am happy to report to you that the cost of conducting this Depart - ment and administrating its affairs m a careful and prudent manner for the past 17 months, justifies me m informing you that the total appropriation needs of this Department for the biennium of 1933-34 calls for the sum of $30,500, or a reduction of 15 per cent under the legislative appropriation for 1931-32 and 35% per cent under the request - ed appropriation of the previous head of this Department as shown m his annual report. I am sure you will be gratified with this report and that it fully vindi - cates your attitude m your fight m 1931, when you made a rugged stand against the increased demands Upon the tax dollar of the Ne - braska taxpayer, as made by the interests then found opposing re - trenchment m appropriation matters. This Department has operated the past 17 months with two less em - ployes than formerly - - one of those employes being a Code secretary. In spite of the decreased number of employes to handle the work of this Department, the fact remains that the year 1931 witnessed 10 per cent more compensation cases filed and heard than any previous year. Salary reductions made m this office saved the taxpayers of Nebraska for the year 1931, the sum of $2,568.09. Other savings m the matter of maintenance and supplies have exceeded $2,000.00, which of course, means double that sum saved for the . biennium. The labor situation, because of unemployment, has been full of human tragedies and heartaches. Not m the history of the laboring man of this state, has he been confronted with such hardships and disappoint - ments and his family so meagerly provided for at his hands. In spite of it all, he has proved his quality of citizenship and his moral worth to society, m the loyalty he has. shown to his government m spite of the disheartning and humiliating condition under which he has lived. Em - ployers m every nook and corner of this state have sought heroically to do their part to alleviate the unemployment situation. Only m oc - cassional instances have employers dealt unfairly with distressed labor - ing men. While Nebraska has a female labor law regulating the hours of female employment m certain lines of labor, there are no regulatory hours as relates to male employment and m certain quarters the hours of such employment have been unfair to labor. I therefore suggest that a fair and just limit of continuous labor In one day, be placed upon all in - dustries aside from agricultural, m the employment of male labor. I respectfully call your attention to another abuse that has arisen, that has to do with labor employed m the beet fields of this state. Under the </seg>
            <seg id="p005">contract system m vogue, the employee must await as late as December 15th to collect his full wage m the beet fields. Too often he finds that his employer has issued orders to the sugar beet companies to pay other obligations he has created and the laborer finds nothing left to pay him and his family for his summer's work. The employer many times Is insolvent. It appears to me that a just solution of this state of affairs is to make the sugar beet company which contracted the beets, recognize the labor claim of the employee as a first lien upon the beets he has helped to grow and harvest. The following compilations from the card record system of this De - partment shows the following compensation records as relates to in - jured men for the years 1930-31: Medical Compensation 1930 " Cards - $332,382.35 $407,555.16 Lump Sum and other Settlements 100,133.77 Total $332,382.35 $507,688.93 1931 " Cards - $305,881.42 $307,413.38 Lump Sum and other Settlements 129,273.40 Total $305,881.42 $436,686.78 1930 - Total Medical $332,382.35 1931 - Total Medical $305,881.42 Difference $ 26,500.93 1930 - Total Compensation $507,688.93 1931 - Total Compensation 436,686.78 Difference $ 71,002.15 1930 - Total number of accidents - 21,902 1931 - Total number of accidents - 18,498 Difference 3,404 1930 - Total number of deaths 76 1931 . - Total number of deaths 39 1932 - Total number of deaths 40 You will note m the foregoing that the amount of compensation paid m 1931 is $71,002.15 less than m 1930. This will be accounted for when it is noticed that there were 3,404 less injured employes m 1931 than m " Prom the above figures we also arrive at the following comparative facts as relates to where the policy holder's premium payments went on the average, to all the injured employes for the year 1931 : To the injured employe, as compensation $23.60 To the hospitals and doctors as per medical 16.53 At a glance ie will be noted that hospitals, surgeons and medical prac - titioners received an average of $15.17 m 1930, which was increased to $16.53 m 1931, per injured man. The compensation rates to the injured man were lowered because of a decreased wage scale, but the costs of medical and hospital did not follow the economic trend, but m fact were increased $1.36 per Injured man. This is not a creditable showing m be- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">half of the medical profession of this state and apparently, will not be corrected until the aid of a new Medical Fee Schedule is invoked. The medical and hospital costs for the injured employes for the year 1931, lacked only $30,804 of equaling all the compensation payments made to 18,498 injured men. I mention &gt;w« fact so that employers of labor throughout the state may know where a large portion of their compensation liability insurance payments go. The economic situation demands and this commissioner hopes to so adjust this excessive cost upon the backs of the employers of labor, that there will be no such picture of excessive medical costs m compensation matters revealed m future reports of this Department. For your further information and as an interesting comparison, be ad - vised that the administrative costs of the Labor and Compensation De - partment per injured man m 1931, was 81 cents per each injured em - ploye reported. The legal end of the compensation division finds the following interest - ing comparisons; which have to do with the cases heard and passed upon by the commissioner or his assistants, where the employer and employee could not agree, but submitted the matter for ascertainment to the Compensation Commissioner: Petitions filed December 1, 1930 to December 1, 1931 .....520 Petitions filed December 1, 1931 to December 1, 1932 479 Decrease 41 Awards entered December 1, 1930 to December 1, 1931 282 Awards entered December 1, 1931 to December 1, 1932 242 Decrease 40 Dismissals entered December 1, 1930 to December 1, 1931....171 Dismissals entered December 1, 1931 to December 1, 1932....237 ' Increase 66 Appeals from awards Dec. 1, 1930 to Dec. 1, 1931.... .". 115 Appeals from awards Dec. 1, 1931 to Dec. 1, 1932 117 Increase 2 Appeals from Dismissals Dec. 1, 1930 to Dec. 1, 1931 45 Appeals from Dismissals Dec. 1, 1931 to Dec. 1, 1932.. 66 Increase 21 In the above picture will be noticed a decrease m claims made for compensation of nearly 10 per cent as compared with 1931, the high year. Also there were correspondingly less awards made, There was, however, owing to the stress of the times, a greater effort made to settle claims after appeals were taken and as a result more settlements and lump sums were made m 1932 than m 1931. Approximately 85 per cent of all appeals taken were settled or lump summed before reaching a higher court for decision. This is one of the abuses m compensation matters that should be elimin - ated. Employers and their insurance carriers m a majority of cases, appeal solely to the end of securing a settlement on a more favorable basis than the award granted, with no intention of having a higher court decide the matter. The Compensation Act of this state should abate such practice m the interest of the injured employee or his de - pendents. One other matter of grave import as relates to the Compensation Act of this state. It has to do with the excessive costs on appeal from the District Court to the Supreme Court. In compensation matters fees for </seg>
            <seg id="p007">transcripts should be reduced to the actual cost involved m transcribing and not upon the statutory rate now prevailing, which is unreasonable and unfair to the laboring man found appealing. The Supreme Court should be available to him at the least possible cost. The Compensation Law should carry an amendment m another par - ticular and that has to do with the supreme court's interpretation of Section 48-115. This section provides that "every person m the service of the state or of any governmental agency created by it, under any appointment or contract of hire, express or Implied, oral or written, but shall not include any official of the state, or of any governmental agency created by it, who shall have been elected or appointed for regular term of office, or to complete the unexpired portion of any regular term." The supreme court holds that the above provision prevents a street commissioner who has charge of the light and water system of a city, from coming within the provisions of the compensation act, despite the fact that many cities have carried compensation insurance covering their employes, only to find that when a water and light commissioner met with accident, the insurance company denied liability and hid behind the court's interpretation of said provision. This section should be amended go that Injustice to the injured city employe will no longer be possible. CECIL E. MATTHEWS, Chief Deputy Compensation Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Public Library Commission Bulletin Vol- 2 Lincoln, Nebraska, January, 1933 No. 1 Published quarterly for free distribution Entered as second-class matter January 10, 1931, at the post office at Lincoln Nebraska, under act of August 24, 1912. NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION ANNIE C. KRAMPH, Chairman North Platte, Nebraska E. A. BURNETT Chancellor of the University of Nebraska ( . GILBERT H. DOANE Librarian of the University of Nebraska GEORGE H. TURNER State Librarian CHARLES W. TAYLOR State Superintendent of Public Instruction NELLIE M. CAREY, Secretary j TABLE OF CONTENTS The Sixteenth Biennial Report of the Commission </seg>
            <seg id="p010">■ ■ - LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Honorable Charles W. Bryan, Gov - ernor of Nebraska: Dear Sir : Complying with the re - quirements of the law, I herewith present the secretary's repoi't of the Nebraska Public Library Commis - sion for the biennium ending Novem - ber 30, 1932. Respectfully yours, Annie C. Kramph, Chairman -4 1 I </seg>
            <seg id="p011">NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION Secretary's Report December 1, 1930 to November 30, 1932 i Two changes m the membership of the Commission occurred during the biennium. The five year term of Miss Edith Tobitt of Omaha ex - pired m December, 1930, and Miss Annie C. Kramph of North Platte was appointed by Governor Weaver to fill the vacancy. Miss Tobitt served as president of the Commission throughout her term of mem - bership. Judge Charles B. Letton, state librarian, died May 1, 1932. Mr. Letton became a member of the Commission m 1927. Mr. George H. Turner, who succeeded Judge Letton as state librarian, therefore be - came a member of the Nebraska Public Library Commission. Miss Nellie Williams, a member of the staff of the Commission since 1915 and secretary since 1921 resigned m September, 1931, and was later married to Dr. William C. Beaven of Hannibal, Mo. Miss Nellie M. Carey of Hastings came to the Commission as secretary October 1, 1931. ■ The resignation of Mrs. Edna Booth Pagel, m charge of the travel - ing libraries since 1925, was accepted to take effect August 1, 1932, and Mrs. Harriet Hotze Hawn was appointed to take her place. In addition to the secretary the staff consists of Miss Dorothy Wood - row, reference librarian; Mrs. Hawn, assistant m charge of the travel - ing libraries, and some part-time help from students. ACTIVITIES The work of the Commission is divided into three main activities: promoting the establishment, growth, and improvement of public libra - ries m the state, loaning books, and the supervision of libraries m the state institutions under the Board of Control. PUBLIC LIBRARIES Assistance to libraries can be given most successfully through visits and the secretary or some other member of the staff does as much field work as funds and time permit. During this biennium 88 visits were made to public, school and institutional libraries. In many of the visits the secretary met with one or more members of the library board to discuss local library problems. As part of the field work, the secretary attended each of the five district library meetings held m May, 1932, at Fairbury, Wahoo, Nor - folk, Kearney and Scottsbluff, and had charge of the round table discussion of various library problems at the morning sessions. Through these meetings she came m contact with 157 librarians and trustees, and- also visited a number of libraries. In spite of the economic situation m this biennium several new libraries have been started, and others have written for information and help. Many questions m regard to library laws, methods, and other problems are answered by correspondence. 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">The number of tax-supported libraries listed this year is 161 an increase of 21 for the biennium. While many of these report only a small income, the amount listed does not indicate all of the help re - ceived, since rooms, heat, light or janitor service are often furnished A number of other libraries listed this year under Association Libra - ries are on the border-line, and no doubt will soon be on the list of tax-supported libraries. BOOK LOANS Each year brings many new patrons to the Library Commission. In this biennium there has been a marked increase m the number of re - quests from schools, particularly rural schools. It is impossible to *v £ equests with the Present book collection, and the reduction of the book fund for the biennium July 1, 1931 to June 30 1933 from $6,000 to $2,500 has been a serious handicap. Most of the re - quests come from small schools which are unable to furnish sufficient books for the children to have the necessary supplementary reading. The reference work continues to occupy an important place m the days work. Books, magazines, pamphlets and clippings are sent out m answer to inquiries on a wide variety of subjects; The Library Commission is the only place to which many people m Nebraska can turn for this information, and numerous letters of thanks show appre - ciation for this service. Searching for the right material, addressing, wrapping, weighing and stamping the packages of necessity takes a good deal of time Practically all of the books loaned by the Commission have to be packed or wrapped, since the majority of the patrons live at a distance The books go to even the most remote parts of the state. During the biennium books have been sent into each of the 93 counties m Ne - braska and to 599 communities. Since the traveling libraries are checked for three months, this means that many people have an oppor - tunity to read the books before they are returned to the Commission and the number of volumes checked from the Commission gives little idea of the total number of times the volumes circulate. INSTITUTIONAL LIBRARIES Since 1911, the Commission has had an appropriation for providing books for those confined m the Institutions m Nebraska under the Board of Control. The Commission buys, catalogues, and rebinds the books, but someone connected with each institution has charge of loaning the books. The circulation reported for this biennium was 97,263 volumes. PUBLICITY Beginning January 1, 1931 the Commission has published a quarterly bulletin, the biennial report being published as one issue of the bulletin. The bulletin aims to provide m each issue articles which will be of practical application to libraries m Nebraska and to eive news of the various libraries. ™£ n » September, 1932 &gt; the secretary gave five radio talks over Station WCAJ, m which she told about the work of the Commission library conditions, and offered suggestions for reading. In November 1932 she gave one talk over Station KFAB m the interest of Book Week. ' 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">From time to time articles have appeared m various newspapers m Nebraska telling of the [work of the Commission or of the help the local library has .received through visits, loans, or m other ways. Exhibits were furnished for the annual meeting of the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs m Chadron, Oct. 11-13, 1932, and for the state meeting of the county superintendents of Nebraska m Lin - coln, Feb. 16-18, 1932. BUDGET The budget for the expenses of the Library Commission for the biennium from July 1, 1931 to June 30, 1933 is $19,200. A reduction was made m the following items: Book fund, $3,500; Institutional libraries, $2,500; Salary fund, $4,800. This reduction has materially handicapped the functioning of the Commission, but by careful at - tention to every detail of the administration of the funds and the most rigid economy, the Commission has continued to serve its three-fold purpose, although it ha^ not been able to give the service it could have given with an adequate fund. Many requests could not be filled be - cause the books were not available. SPECIAL NEED FOR BOOKS "The message of books was never more needed, not only for en - lightenment and strenghtening the mind, but for spiritual sustenance and inspiration, to awaken faith and courage, the will to live and achieve," says Mr. M. F. Gallagher, chairman of the trustees section of the American Library Association. Recognizing the special need for books during a period of depression, the Library Commission has made every effort to supply them, particularly to communities which were without library service, but where there was a great hunger for books, and to supplement the service given m other places. That the public libraries are doing their part m supplying people with reading material is shown by their annual reports which are given elsewhere m this bulletin, and which show mounting circulation records. Nebraska, however, still has a number of counties without public • libraries and many other places not within reach of a library, for Nebraska is a 'state of wide, open spaces and scattered population. The Nebraska Public Library Commission, now thirty-one years old, is filling a place not filled by any other organization m Nebraska. 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">SUMMARY OF STATISTICS Volumes m Library Volumes m library Nov. 30, 1932 38,585 Volumes added from Dec. 1, 1930 to Nov. 30, 1932 3,410 Volumes withdrawn from Dec. 1, 1930 to Nov. 30, 1932 1,343 Volumes m library Nov. 30, 1932 , 40,652 Record of Loans The following is a classified arrangement of the requests filled and the loans made from Dec. 1, 1930 to Nov. 30, 1932. Borrowers Requests filled Volumes Groups of residents ■. 321 19,501 Public libraries 753 16,063 School and college libraries 1,303 59,416 Study clubs 654 2,121 Other organizations . 22 1,380 Individuals 6,871 17,042 Total '. 9,924 115,523 Expenditures Dec. 1, 1930 to Nov. 30, 1932 From From Appropriation Appropriation . 1929-1931 1931-1933 Binding $ 417.86 $ 509.83 Books 2,273.97 1,589.23 Institutional libraries 2,332.72 1,037.05 Maintenance '. 1,160.47 1,784.85 Miscellaneous cash 133.01 Salaries and wages 4,555.50 6,926.44 $10,740.52 $11,980.41 $10,740.52 Total. $22,720.93 Appropriation July 1, 1931 to June 30, 1933 $19,000.00 Miscellaneous cash (Estimated receipts) 200.00 Expended July 1, 1931 to November 30, 1932 ll,98o!41 Balance 7,219.59 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE LIBRARIES Department . . Location Vols. Director Legislative Reference Bureau Lincoln '. 50,000* Edna D. Bullock Public Library Commission Lincoln 40,652 Nellie M. Carey State Historical Society Lincoln 60,000 Mrs. C. S. Paine State Library Lincoln 96,791 George H. Turner • Chiefly pamphlets and clipping. U. S. GOVERNMENT HOSPITAL LIBRARY Vejerans' Administration Hospital Lincoln 1,400 Florence Markus SCHOOL AND COLLEGE LIBRARIES School. ■ Location Vols. Librarian Beatrice Junior High School Beatrice 1,600 Valeda Wood Concordia Teachers College..: Seward.. 5,400 H. O. A. Keinath Cotner College Lincoln 11,500 Earnest W. Lundeen Creighton University Omaha... 43,982 Mrs. L. M. Reynolds Dana College Blair 4,959 Dorthea Jensen Doane College Crete : 25,111 William B. Hunt Fairbury High School Fairbury ; 3,000 Beatrice Hullett Fremont Senior High School Fremont r 1,410 Wilma Sargent' Grand Island Schools R. J. Barr Junior High School. Grand Island 2,264 Catherine Glade Senior High School : Grand Island 3,650 Alice E. Paine Walnut Junior High School Grand Island 3,400 Anna M. Dormer Hastings College Hastings 17,191 Marguerite Nesbit Hastings High Schools Hastings 4,800 Glen H. James Kearney Schools Junior High School Kearney 1,471 Katharine Major Senior High School Kearney 2,425 Lucile Hrubesky 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">SCHOOL AND COLLEGE LIBRARIES— (Continued) School Location Vols. Librarian Lincoln schools Bethany High School .....Lincoln 1,200 Tillie Larsen College View High School Lincoln ; 1,000 Elma Buchanan Everett Junior High School Lincoln 1,150 F. Schmeling Havelock HiglrSchool....; Lincoln 300 Lillian Griffiths Lincoln High School Lincoln 6,130 Emma E. Snyder Irving Junior High School Lincoln.. 1,630 Aimee Johnston ™ s ™ H 'S h . S^ool- ••••--• --- Lincoln 950 Anne R. Munson Whittier Junior High School Lincoln : 2,750 Anna H. Bethune Mvu cr j 2 i e i ge Waho ° 5 ' 000 A - T - Seashore Midland College Fremont 18,000 Georgia. Fuhrmeister Nebraska Central College Central City 2,700 Milo H. Crosbie Nebraska Wesleyan University Lincoln :....: 24,196 Mrs. W. G. Bishop v 01 "^ di f/"°«. H u Ig S Seh ° o1 Norfolk 2,400 Laura Kidder North Platte High School North Platte , 2,355 Margaret Watson Omaha schools • . ■ Benson High School ..Omaha : Emily S. Thomsen Central High School Omaha 22,250 Zora Shields £ or , th 'High Schoo Omaha 5,000 Catherine Nichol South High School Omaha 11,073 Ivae Walker Technical High School :....omaha 14,833 . . May Ingles Omaha Municipal University Omaha 10,460 Inez L. Chestnut Scottsbluff High School and Ol Juni ° r College Scottsbluff '. 2,000 Mrs. Jay E. Hall State Teachers College Chadron 18,137 Mrs. Anna B. Bright State Teachers Co ege Kearney 20,062 Anna V. Jennings State Teachers Co lege Peru 40,628 Grace M. Petersen State Teachers College Wayne 17,000 Josephine Silvers Union College : Lincoln 13,500 D. Glenn Hilts University of Nebraska Lincoln 264,755 Gilbert H Doane York College York 11,760 Edith M. Cone 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE INSTITUTION LIBRARIES Population . Circulation Institution ' Place (Exclusive of Volumes ■ for Superintendent Employees) Biennium Boys' Industrial School, Kearney 189 1,506 4,959 R. V. Clark Girls' Training School, Geneva 190 1,016 5,469 I Lena E. Ward Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln* 115 I Mrs. E. J. Mouden Home for Feeble-minded, Beatrice § 1,014 1,015 3,832 I Dr. J. A. Burford Hospital for Tuberculosis, Kearney 154 1,687 4,515 Dr. L. T. Sidwell Industrial Home for Women, Milford 85 700 4,003 M. Evelyn Meyer Orthopedic Hospital, . Lincoln f 90 1,678 296 | Dr. F. A. Alcorn Penitentiary, Lincoln 844 4,000 26,456 | W. T. Fenton Reformatory for Men, Lincoln 402 1,519 11,495 I A. W. Miller Reformatory for Women, York ♦ % 42 I Dr. Alma Chapman School for the Deaf, Omaha § 204 1,530 3,535 I F. W. Booth Soldiers' Home, Burkett * 280 I Ivan S. Gallant Soldiers' Home, Milford * 143 I Charles F. Jackson State Hospital for Insane, Ingleside 1,547 1,880 16,098 I Dr. G. E. Charlton State Hospital for Insane, Lincoln 1,205 1,238 6,402 I Dr. D. C- Griffiths State Hospital for Insane, Norfolk 954 761 10,203 I Dr. J. C. Nielsen • No report. t Books loaned from Library Commission. t Incomplete. § No books circulated during summer. 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">ASSOCIATION LIBRARIES There are m Nebraska a large number of libraries financed other than by taxation. Usually they are organized and maintained by some club or organization. Information has been received during the biennium of the following, some of which report receiving a small appropriation. In some cases room, heat and light are furnished. If other towns should be included m this list such information would be appreciated by the secretary of the Library Commission. Anselmo Hyannis Bancroft Keystone Bassett Leigh Battle Creek Lodgepole Beaver City Lushton Belvidere Mason City Benkelman Melbeta Bertrand Minatare Berwyn Mullen Big Springs Murray Blue Hill Nehawka Bruning Nemaha Brunswick North Loup. Callaway Orchard Carleton ■ Palmer Chester Palmyra Clarkson Papillion Crab Orchard Paxton Crookston Platte Center Dannebrog Potter Davenport Ralston Daykin Republican City Deshler • Roseland Diller Ruskin Dorchester Salem Douglas . ' ' Shelby Dunbar ' Shickley Eagle Stapleton Edgar Stuart Elgin Tobias Elkhorn . Union Elm Creek Valentine Elmwood Verdon Emerson Waco Fairmont Waterloo Grant Western Gretna . Wilber Haigler Wilcox Hardy Wilsonville Howells Wolbach Hubbell 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">TAX-SUPPORTKD LIBRARIES ' Expenditures &lt;&amp; ' Place § % 'c i 3 fc ° Librnrian 1 Adams 535 1922 $ 250 $ 180 % 36 $ 15 11 1,750 2.90" Mrs. Florence Disher 2 Ainsworth 1,378 1912 900 500 207 199 25 4.622 16,114 Mrs. F. R. Galbraith 3 Albion 2,172 1900 1,500 640 305 637 16 6.000 22,008 Mrs. Jennie Graden 4 Alexandria 421 1921 140 60 28 56 4 1.100 Mrs. Alma Beer 6 Alliance 6,669 1909 3,454 1,208 680 1.5J6 30 .11,010 55,217 Mrs. Blanche E. Prettyman 6 Alma* 1,236t 1910 1.213 GOO 227 415 21 4,342 11.027 Jennie E. Egelston 7 Ansley • 1,323t 1916 650 180 262 140 12 3.993 11.918 Mrs. F. L. Dewey 8 Arapahoe 1,017 1920 620 319 218 103 8 3,406 11,200 Mrs. L. Stevens 9 Arcadia* 1,137t 1917 1.450 467 262 476 33 5.463 14.646 Grace Hagood 10 Arlington 622 1918 350 107 127 31 6 2,247 5,025 Mrs. M. E. Winset . 11 Arnold • 1,676t 1920 1,593 600 407 586 20 3,504 9,072 Lara C. Peterson 12 Ashland 1,786 1902 1,100 300 326 465 15 4,636 16,000 Mrs. Margaret Parrinh 13 Atkinson • 1.761T 1922 800 300 12 36 3,500 20.450 Mrs. Sylvia Richards 14 Auburn 3,068 1914 2,475 934 569 946 7 7,655 27.695 Mrs. Lillian Mastin 16 Aurora _ 2.715 1908 2,600 816 326 748 30 5,956 21,597 Lillian Moore 16Axtell* 891t 1926 400 180 76 16 10 1,025 4,779 Mrs. C. I!. Dossett 17 Bayard 1,659 1919 1.266 420 182 307 13 2.051 19,466 Mrs. A. H. Butler 18 Beatrice 10,297 1893 9,000 3.292 2.121 2,112 66 20,779 109.327 Madge Evans 19 Beemer • 1,103t 1924 140 52 63 20 2 730 2.500 Ethel Martin 20 Bellevue 1,017 1920 120 120 20 f&gt; 1,200 3,900 Julia A. Schultz 21 Blair 2,791 1917 2,175 720 456 886 30 6,832 24,826 May McQuarrie 22 Bloomfield 1,435 1908 1,100 600 204 320 30 2.937 14.060 Mrs. E. L. Durbin 23 Bridgeport ;.. 1,421 1922 1,100 445 300 399 12 3,700 13.407 Louise Estill 24 Broken Bow 2.715 1910 2,335 1,020 412 996 33 6,477 24.325 Clara B. Johnson 25 Burwell • 1,166 1912 029 420 216 442 22 3,898 12,909 Mrs. Maude Fuller 26 Carroll 401 1904 300 75 90 135 6 1.800 4.629 Mrs. C. E. Jones 27 Cedar Rapids 743 1914 400 208 118 22 8 3.600 17.358 Mrs. E. L. Melvin 28 Central City 2,474 1889 1,700. 900 456 296 30 8,759 28.340 Mrs. Eva Hord 29 Chadron 4,606 1908 3,624 1,200 1.491 838 27 9,814 45,951 Mrs. Loie Skiles 30 Chappell 1,061 1920 1,200 480 576 58 15 3.205 14.881 Mrs. D. E. O'Connor 31 Clarks • 1.484t 1919 480 36 146 20 3,782 5,716 Cleo Schnnk 32 Clay Center !133 1910 788 480 131 224 30 3,227 6,954 Bertha F. Jessup • Township library. t Including township population. 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES— (Continued) Expenditure! X ' Pla« I - 1-3 ■ S § Librarian n a™ 2 JS or S 3 5 c v .13 Columbus 0,898 1901 $ 4.500 S 1.587 $ 1,099 $ 876 42 12.114 57,41*5 Rose Riddell 34Com«tock« 730t 1925 714 220 103 79 7 1.734 5,312 Mrs. Enola Strunk 36 Corad 1.813 1917 I.SOO 480 103 650 24 3.744 12.500 Edith Allen 36 Crawford 1.703 1912 608 2f&gt;4 271 38 9 3.858 17,134 Mrs. Maude Smeak 37 Creiuhton • 2.014t 1913 400 240 110 50 10 2.652 10.1GG Mrs Adela Horn 38 Crete :. 2,865 1878 2,600 720 384 668 30 9 617 18 682 Mr. CF Baker ?9 Crofton • , 1330t 192 C 500 150 100 9 i, 2 G5 6,022 Mrs. Emir Eliasson 4 ? R U L be . r '"?.". Mil 5^2 115 12G 16H » s 2.560 8,305 Aliene Mcllee 41 Dakota City 417 1922 205 49 119 4 1704 4 612 42 David City 2.333 1891 2,600 840 503 1,236 33 u',lol 2g',334 'Mrs^'Laura V ' Paui 4» DeWitt 534 1902 300 104 87 158 5 2,804 5 707 Ruth Warns "Elwood 509 1918 . 260 .... 150 50 7 1.850 5 291 Mr.7 Luella R.Dow « gwinir 588 1928 250 180 5 12 500 900 Althea Posson 4 £ a . ir £ U , r . y 6&gt;192 19 ?° Clo0 ° 2 ' 100 *** h2M 51 12 ' 2|(5 67 - 331 M «- N a&lt;"n' Ellsworth 47 |57 1913 .... . .. Mrs Alma F Fwinir 49 Franklin 1,103 1915 679 240 247 239 12 8.246 12.196 Delia M Carter BO Fremont 11.407 1901. .7.982 2.181 1.908 3.316 54 16.141 94 664 Mildred J Palmer II FrUnd .2H 909 1.020 312 170 520 30 2.651 8.!)74 Rotha Doner 52 Fullerton 1.680 1914 495 403 275 14 5,394 24.671 Mrs. P. M. Joritenscn «J geneva .662 1906 1.786 900 242 550 38 6.450 20 841 Mrs! Isabel B?xby 54 Genoa 1,089 1902 489 156 278 . 38 10 2,147 8,635 Ella Munson K»r^ nK . Hlli J.n'n 'n- f?S Ml 295 21 5&gt;007 39,340 . Mrs. Nellie M. Perrlne 56 Gibbon* 1.363t 1910 9i, 440 236 368 15 3.778 8.293 Mrs. Lou H. McLaren 57 Gordon 1,958 1922 1.200 285 228 100 25 3.494 9 766 Mrs Grace Hummel 58 Gothenburit 2.322 1915 2,000 960 375 615 32 3 961 13 511 S Frances Botldn 59 Grand Island .: 18.041 1884 10,000 3.405 2.389 .-|.834 57 16,863 71991 Daisy Houck 60 Guide Rock 690 1918 687 300 87 209 15 2.863 7 166 Kathl-rine Guy • 61 Hartin K ton 1.568 1914 • iI.KOO 370 370 !)00 15 ' Mrs Kate S Bryant 62 Harvard - 865 1916 1.300 375 118 351 31 2,897 1..710 M C F KM I 1, 63 Hasting. 15.490 1904 7,500 3,985 2.222 1.561 72 16/T47 140 476 Hazel Merry 64 Hay Spring 853 1922 400 180 CO 82 8 4,000 6.000 Mrs. Mary O. GoIT • Township library. t Including township population. ' 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES— (Continued) Expenditure* &gt;• Pi n -« b "2 -oj" v o Librarian 65 Hebron , 1,804 1919 $ 1,320 t 438 $ 325 t G95 ' 30 6,019 12,238 Mrs. May Mclieth 66 HemitiKford 1,026 1923 250 73 202 5 1,768 3.300 lllenna RohrbauKh 67 HoldreKe 3,263 1895 2.701 900 734 1,175 35 8,138 41,221 Mra. Eva L. Stanley 68 Hooper 985 1913 318 180 83 55 9 2,900 6,360 Mrs. H. F. Waterman 69 Humboldt -.— : — 17435 189TJ 1,200 480 274 146. 32 4,000 10.561 Mrs. J. K. LiftKett 70 Imperial " 946 1927 585 265 194 239 7 2,401 8,743 Mrs. Norma Heebner 71 Kearney 8,575 1890 4,500 2.280 976 1,382 48 13.410 44,245 Mrs. Mary Early O'Brian 72 Kimball 1,711 1919 1,350 600 480 293 30 4,459 15,448 Mrs. Alice G. Irvin 73 Laurel 864 1909 . .... :.. ••■•■- Roy L. Lathrop 74 Lexington 2,962 1919 2.600 855 648 1,361 48 6,453 21,753 Mary Cooper 75 Lincoln 75,933 1875 53,799 .25,825 15,344 12,082 86 99.000 659,525 Lulu Home "6 LonK Pine 937 1921 201 125 48 8 9 915 6,000 Mrs. M. J. Potter 77 Louisville 969 190f 325 120 60 "0 9 3,022 6,406 Edith F. Shryoek 78 Loup City • 2,054t 1917 2,269 763 198 62K 36 5,082 26,438 Harriet Gallaway 79 Lyons 985 1921 422 240 187 245 9 3,260 7.338 Frankie L. Smith 80 McCook 6,688 1902 4,000 1.476 940 1,073 50 6,000 .50.840 Millicent Slaby 81 Madison 1,842 1907 2,262 1.156 420 640 36 6,833 36,136 Mrs. Anna D. Johnson 82 Merna • 1,322t 1916 1,800 480 215 969 19 9,500 11,952 Mrs. James L. Ridenour 83 Me.-riman 362 1927 181 104 34 7 6 597 953 Mrs. G. E. Mattißon 84 Milford 832 1929 325 204 112 66 10 1,345 9.578 Mrs. B. Hillier 86 Minden 1.716 1907 1.000 480 314 44 24 5,525 14.761 Mrs. Helen Slusser 86 Mitchell 2,053 1915 1,067 480 328 175 23 4.814 20,966 Mrs. Fern SlemmonH 87 Monroe* 57Gt 1920 175 120 48 1.200 1,300 Mrs. C. I. Wood 88 Merrill 756 1917 516 180 78 28 8 3,087 4,175 Mrs. Ethel Wilson 89 Nebraska City 7,230 1896 2,900 1 680 498 951 33 12.600 39,087 Anne Stevenson 90 Nelifth : 1.649 1904 1,800 494 406 628 15 5,500 32,745 Mrs. Carrie M. Jones 01 Nelson 903 1908 400 219 104 68 17 2,600 8,012' Alice E. Ruddell 92 Newman Grove 1,146 1923 1,300 475 571 196 16 3,038 25.121 Mrs. Margaret Dillman 93 Norfolk 10.711 1908 5,703 2,663 933 1.226 45 11,928 67,534 Laura Durland 94 North liend 1,108 1908 1,000 660 277 257 30 3,153 12,143 Laura Roump 96 North Loup' 1,143t 1928 160 110 63 8 2.000 8,100 96 North Platte 12,061 1911 4,760 2,667 1,885 1,422 60 15,386 91,84!) Eleanor M. Wheeler 97 Oakdnle 663 1925 240 105 36 87 10 3,065 9,000 Gertrude 11. Gove • Township library. t Including township population. 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">TAX-SUPPORTED MHKAItIKS— (Continued) Expenditure)* •*• Place .ox "b-J o „ J Librarian !&gt;8 Oakland 1,438 1920 t 1.834 $ 377 $ 732 S 142 14 r.,127 21,070 I.ydia Hill 99 Oitallalii 1,631 1928 .100 161 74 72 0 1.950 4.672 Mrs. O. Parker 100 Omaha ''U.OOO 1877 114.364 80.072 10,937 87.36G 70 1D3.351 805.426 Edith Tobitt 101 O'Neill 2.019 1012 1.500 715 420 40(1 24 4,21)2 12,120 MaryMcLaiiKhlin 102 Or J* 2.004t l'J22 724 300 388 37 IK 3,300, 10.340 Grayce E. I'ullcn 10.1 Orleans' 1.43»t 1017 1,000 OS7 20.1 0.13 34 5,738 13.108 Dorothy M. Mahn 104 Osccola 1,054 1901 400 128 220 51 12 2.512 0,888 Mrs. Jessie C. Marquis 105 Oshkosh 843 1921 2SO f.O 71 5 ' 2.077 7,000 Mm. L. H. Stroud KMi Pawnee City 1.573 11100 1.200 780 314 2311 35 2,500 13,008 Mrs. Flora M. Fullerton 107 I'ender 1,000 1904 100 44 75 40 4 5,750 8.725 Aleta Ilentz 108 Pierce 1.200 1907 500 300 88 252 il 4,107 0.154 Mrs. J. A. Andrews 109 I'lainview 1.216 1908 1,600 504 348 824 24 3.337 14.404 Mrs. GeorKe Kirk 110 Plattsmouth 3,791 1893 3,073 2.030 486 1,053 33 18,730 43,287 C. Olive Jones 111 l'olk 532 1912 300 5 500 Mrs. Mary McDaniel 112 Poncn 1)20 190!) 450 120 215 21)1 8 6,890 7.425 Mrs. M. Line 113 Randolph 1,145 1918 8!)2 225 193 187 8 4.000 13.743 Mrs. C. A Kerr 114 Ravenna 1,559 1918 1.103 000 15!) 323 24 .5,720 20,440 Nellie V Clark 115 Red Cloud 1,519 1918 1,500 720 150 550 30 6.905 19,996 Yola Swartz 110 Rushville 1.006 1922 450 135 60 179 8 7,973 Mrs. A. L. Hollstien 117 St. Edward 1.030 1925 500 300 205 8 8 2,649 10,047 Gertie A Anderson 118 St. Paul 1,621 1915 300 72 4 2,200 3.468 Mrs. Ina M. Luick 110 Sarßcnt * 1,644t 1928 360 150 21 5,005 14.017 Mrs. Flora A. Cropper 120 Schuyler 2.588 1911 1,800 600 292 060 24 7,000 15,679 Mrs Alice Carl 121 Scotin 474 1927 340 0 216 235 4 1.384 5,940 122 ScottsblufT 8,465 lUI6 5.323 ■ 1,953 1,897 1.116 30 14,863 68,215 Mrs. Nellie Wilson" 123 Scribncr 1,000 1900 658 300 79 98 22 3,021 4,021 Lucille Wapelhorst 124 Seward 2.737 1890 2.200 600 553 482 24 6.460 25.547 Mrs. Emma llredi-kamii 12I&gt; Shelton • 1.434t 1912 1.250 600 130 202 20 6.456 10,070 Mrs C S Ilurkerd 126 Shickley 389 1923 205 75 100 30 8 2.100 5,000 Mathilda Lichti 127 Sidney 3,306 1917 2.000 720 064 712 27 7.080 17,537 Mrs. Constance Corbctt 128 Silver Creek • BOSt 1918 1,021) 540 342 1)0 30 ' 2.880 7.750 Mrs Mary Cobel 129 South Sioux City.... 927 1920 300 120 l!i0 49 7 3,950 10.400 Mrs. A. L. Mathwiit • Township library. * " \ t Including township population. 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">TAX-SUPPORTED UHRARIES— (Continued) Expenditures * "o Place § 1 1-5 S.I Librarian 1 sl S I 1! I III! 130 Spaldinir X3:&gt; 1 11 1 1 $ 710 t 185 $ 14S $ 146 7 2,177 0.473 Mrs. Frank Dunning . HI Soenccr* 1,254t 191J 400 324 45 314 _JJ 3,060 U,74« Gladys L. Kirk 182 Springfield "'.'. 419 1026 250 144 59 17 G 939 4.36G Mrs. Rose M. Davis 133 Stanton 1.479 11)15 1.300 GOO 156 453 30 . 4,549 8,391 Mrs. J.. D. Elm°re 114 Sterling 702 1904 400 300 113 74 14 2.725 G. 540 Mrs. M. E. Hollenback 135 Stratton GG3 1928 300 IGS 200 5 1.500 G.OOO Mrs. E. H. Bailey 1.16 Stromxbun! :. 1.320 ' 1917 750- 540 161 24 3.H28 9,291 PeKKie Halden 1)7 Superior 3.044 1884 1,712 1,080 609 551 36 11.600 47,700 Mrs. Lucy Conn 138 Sutherland 753 1920 359 16.1 50 88 10 1,500. 10.694 Mrs. D. C. Wilson 110 Sutton 1.540 1910 950 480 100 245 33 1.540 4.500 Sibyl H. Jarrett 140 Syracuse" .... 947 1901 500 • 120 119 121 10 .3,465 3,866 Mrs. Laura Mason 141 Table Rock 673 1917 210 144 57 49 14 1.176 5.269 Mrs. Allie Wood 142 Talmagc 474 1904 414 180 97 f»6 12 1.543 5.G7.1 Sophia Moller 143 Tecumsch 1,829 18»2 1,000 520 275 163 .10 10,000 15.6 M Mrs. R. W. Campbell 144 Tckamah 1.804 191G 1,276 GOO 167 638 .10 6.000 14.400 MY«. J. A. Clark 146 Tilden 1.106 1922 1,500 440 116 145 29 2,036 17.360 Mrs. Mattie Cunningham 146 Trenton' .... 865 1924 221 200 21 6 2.000 .1,800 Mrs. A. T. McCoy 147 Ulysses' I.OOSt 191G 600 192 2HG 56 7 3.300 7.092 Mrs. M. F. Withers 148 Valley .... 1.039 1902 456 300 250 40 2,000 G.OOO Mrs. Anna Howard 149 Valparaiso 523 1916 200 115 50 20 3 1.000 2.500 Mrs. Lena A. Ettleman 150 Wahoo 2,689 1924 1,800 720 672 45 22 2.689 20,000 Mrs. Grace E. Oldham' 161 Wausa • 1.209f 1920 1.500 360 267 393 10 3.375 10,323 Roue Hanks 152 Wakefield 1,112 1920 912 300 337 253 12 5.782 12,386 E. Ruth Collins 163 Walthill 1.162 1921 220 4 1,509 Mrs. Harry L. Kcete 154 Wayne 2.381 1909 2.700 1,380 634 618 27 6,335 28,831 Mrs. E. S. Hlair 155 WccpinK Wattr 1.029 1017 1,103 300 154 286 12 6.362 14,416 Mildred Hart 156 West Point 2,225 191G 949 480 299 131 19 4,500 14.400 Minnie L. Frahm 167 Wiiiside 483 1911 30.1 188 58 103 10 2.250 5,678 Mra. Etta I'errin 168 Wisncr 1.327 100.1 325 180 39 7 2.260 Jessie 11. Kay 169 Wood River . ... 751 1906 500 180 7.1 103 12 4.508 9.408 6ahra J. Abbott IGO Wymore 2.680 1917 2.G00 1.197 594 707 30 6.966 4.1.257 Gladys Pirie IGI York 5,712 1894 4.840 1.834 000 D.SI 3 12 1 1.650 .11.060 Ada Hansard • Township library. t Including township population. 15 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>