<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-First Biennial Report of the Commisioner of Public Lands and Buildings and of the Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds to the Governor of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1918-12-01">1918-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TWENTY-FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT 1 of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings and of the Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds to the GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA DECEMBER 1, 1918 By G. L. SHUMWAY Commistioner of Public Land* and Building* and Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Fund* </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">STATE OFFICERS 1917-18 Keith Neville Governor Edgar How aid Lieutenant Governor Charles W. Pool Secretary of State George E. Hall Treasurer Wm. H. Smith Auditor Willis E. Reed Attorney General G. L. Sbdmway Land Commissioner W. H. Clemmons State Superintendent Victor E. Wilson Railway Commissioner H. G. Taylor Railway Commissioner Thos. L. Hall Railway Commissioner STATE OFFICERS 1919-20 Samuel R. McKelvie Governor P. A. Barrows Lieutenant Governor D. M. Amsbeuy Secretary of State D. B. Cropsey „. .Treasurer George W. Marsh Auditor Clarence A. Davis Attorney General Dan Swanson Land Commissioner W. H. Clemmons .State Superintendent Victor E. Wilson Railway Commissioner H. G. Taylor Railway Commissioner Thos. L. Haix Railway Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">COMMISSIONERS OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS OF NEBRASKA F. M. Davis 1877-1880 A. G. KENDALL 1881-1884 Joseph Scott 1885-1888 John Steen ,. . . 1889-1890 A. R. HUMPHRIY ., 1891-1894 H. C. Russell 1895-1898 J. V. Wolfe 1897-1900 George D. Follm* 1901-1904 H. M. Eaton 1905-1908 E. B. Cowles 1909-19 IS Feed Beckman 1913-191* G. L. Shum way 1917-1918 Dan Swanson 1919- P </seg>
            <seg id="p006">COMMISSIONER'S OFFICE 1917-18 G. L. Shumway Commissioner 1917 L Deputy Commissioner G. E. Emery, January, 1917 •Geo. E. Copper. February and March, John W. Thomas, April, 1917, to date Miss June H. Lundmakk. Chief Clerk E. B. Zimmerman. Bookkeeper Job Pinker, January to October, 1917, incl Mrs. Metta I. Loeber. November, 1917, tolRecorder and Delinquent Clerk date Miss Genevieve Chbistensen, Jan,. 1917, to Nov., 19171 Mrs. Olive Groff, December, 1917, to September, 19181 Stenographer Miss Nellie A. Dolan, October 1918, to date •Deceased. DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING Robert Harvey, St. Paul State Surveyor Philip L. Rouse, Peru Deputy E. C. Simmons, Pender Deputy B. W. Benson, Central City Deputy R. C. Beatty. Lexington Deputy Dan Nippell, Antioch Special Deputy </seg>
            <seg id="p007">"HONOR BOLL" Philip L. Rouse, Graduate Nebraska University, February 1916 Volunteer 5th Nebraska (on border) 1916 Volunteer 5th Nebraska June 11 1917 In training at Camp Cody, September 14 1917 Arrived in France, September 29 1918 Rank— 1st Lieut. Headquarter' s Co., 134th U. S. Infantry, in charge of one-pound cannon platoon 34th Division. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">IN MEMORIAM GEORGE FRANKLIN COPPER Born at Peru, Indiana, April 17, 1863 Died at Omaha, Nebraska, March 29, 1917, after a brief illness of pneumonia The Seventh son and Thirteenth child of Mr. and Mrs. N. P. Copper Education: Public Schools; University of Lincoln, Illinois; Life - long self-application Newspaper Work : Publisher Keith County News 6 years, Ogalalla ; Publisher Independent Era 6 years, North Platte ; Corre - spondent World-Herald, 12 years, Omaha; The Stockman's Brand, South Omaha Married to Hester Frances Bronson, Hiawatha, Kansas, November 12, 1901. No children. Mrs. Copper is in Red Cross Official: County Superintendent, Keith County; Civil Engineering Department, Union Pacific; Deputy State Land Commissioner, February and March, 1917 Was a communicant of the Presbyterian church, and a member of the Masonic and Woodman fraternities Homesteaded near Lexington, Nebraska, 1885 Department, Omaha World-Herald </seg>
            <seg id="p009">COMMISSIONER OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS Lincoln, Nebraska, December 1, 1918. To His Excellency, Keith Neville, Governor : Sir : In compliance with the constitutional requirement, I have the honor to submit the following report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, who is also the Secretary of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds, for the biennium beginning December 1, 1916, and ending Novem - ber 30, 1918. Under the present law, the Board of Educational Lands and Funds is the custodian of the Capitol building, Governor's mansion and State Fair grounds. During the past two years, under the direction of the Board, the follow - ing improvements were made : A building at the State Fair grounds for the exposition of swine, for which the legislature appropriated $80,000. The cost of the building was in excess of the appropriation in the amount of $22,899.54. This has been paid by the State Fair Board, and we would recommend it be refunded by appropriation. Nineteen thousand, seven hundred and ninety-eight dol - lars and forty-eight cents was also paid by the State Fair Board for installing new car tracks and building a new entrance. Arrangements are made for reimbursing the Fair Board by an extra charge of live cents street car fare. In our opinion, the legislature had better appropriate this and eliminate the extra charge of fare. The legislature of 1917 appropriated $2,000 for the installation of a new boiler in the engine house on the Capitol grounds. Owing to the sudden demands for all material used in the construction of boilers, it was found that the boiler would cost instead $5,445.00. The dangerous condition of the old boiler made it imperative that the new boiler be in - stalled, and a deficiency has been recommended by the Board for $3,445.00 less $39.95, (an expense incurred by the State for covering the boiler), or $3,405.05, net. The dirt and smoke inconvenience from the State boiler house has been apparent to the people residing in the vicinity of the Capitol. An opportunity was offered for the installation of a fuel-saving device, com - monly known as a smoke consumer, by the Nebraska Fuel Saving Company, with the understanding that the Board would approve the payment thereof and recommend it to the legislature, and the device was installed upon thirty days' trial. The cost of installation was $1,950.00 Twenty-four hours continuous running without the device, and twenty-four hours con - tinuous running with it, resulted in a saving of nearly $1.00 per hour, in winter weather. The legislature appropriated $50,000.00 for the rebuilding of the south wall of the east wing of the Capitol building. Upon investigation, it was found </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT that this construction would cost considerably in excess of that amount, owing to war conditions and prices. It was, therefore, deemed advisable by the Board to not enter into the construction thereof and the appropriation is conse - quently unused. ESCHEAT LAND During the present administration the State became the owner of the following escheat lands : Northwest quarter of Section 28, Township 15, North, Range 45, West of the 6th P. M., Garden county. North 62 feet of Lot 5, Block 35. Original town of Sidney, Cheyenne county, Nebraska. North half of Section 2, Township 12. North, Range 52, West of the 6th P. M., Cheyenne county. LOST LAND RECOVERED In the report of December, 1916, I tind 1,400.69 acres of "unclassified" lands. Some of these lands formerly bordered on the Missouri river, but had been washed away by floods and the changing of the channel. I made an investigation and found that the river had returned to the State lands, in Dakota county, 286.83 acres ; Douglas county, 160 acres ; Nemaha county. 85.80 acres. The land in Nemaha county has been placed under lease. That in Douglas county is appraised at $100 an acre and has been advertised for leasing. That in Dakota county is yet to be re-valued, and an order has been issued for that purpose. SELL CITY LOTS I recommend that city lots and buildings be appraised and sold to the highest bidder. We have a number of such lots in Lincoln, two lots in Calvert's Addition to Auburn, a fractional lot in Sidney, and a number of lots in Kearnev. STATE PARKS My attention was called to the fact that among the unclassified lands were tracts of five, ten and twenty acres in several counties over the State. These were originally subdivisions under the law which provided timber for the use of the people. The attention of the Lincoln Automobile Club was called to twenty acres lying eight miles south of this city. After an examination, the association leased the twenty acres and have converted it into a park. There are some grand old trees, — a number of elms, hack - berry, and scattering walnuts — over this tract. The shade is so dense that grass does not properly develop under the trees, and I would suggest an amendment to the law, permitting the removal of a portion of the timber from school lands, under the direction of the Land Commissioner, where it may be found that the proper conservation and profit of the tract be better observed by the sale and removal of such timber. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE PARKS 11 I would recommend also the creation of a State Park Commission, of which the Land Commissioner should be made chairman, and an examina - tion of other tracts of State land of less than forty acres; also private lands which might be acquired ; to determine their availability for park purposes. All such tracts found to be suitable, if belonging to the educa - tional lands, should be leased under conditions that will permit automobile associations, or others, to make them desirable camping places, and steps should be taken to acquire other sites. One of the essentials for this is the stabilization of the rental to be paid, and another that the Park Commission be permitted to trim up live trees and remove some of them where the shade is found to be too dense for good camping purposes. REAPPRAISEMENTS During the 1917 session of the legislature, I proposed a bill for taking an inventory of the educational lands in conjunction with the Conservation and Soil Survey. The estimated expense was about $20,000.00 The legis - lature, however, appropriated to this department for reappraisements and re-checking the sum of $10,000.00. Seven thousand, nine hundred and twenty-two dollars and six cents has been expended. Thirty-six and one-half counties, embracing 750,453.89 acres, have been reappraised, with the net result that the yearly income was increased $110, - 745.75. This increase is for the benefit of educational funds, and helps every school in the State. By January 1, 1919, two other county re-appraisements will be complete, increasing the income approximately $6,000 over above amount. NEW AUTHORITY FOR STATE BOARD In October, 1915, the school lands of the south half of Cherry county, containing 125,000 acres, were ordered reappraised for leasing purposes, and in January, 1917, no action had yet been taken by the county board. I have constantly urged and requested the county commissioners of Cherry county to take up and finish this work, but I have been unable to get them to do so. An appraisement of a strip of townships through the middle of the land ordered re-valued, has been received. Because no further action has been taken by the county board, the Commissioner has prepared an appraisement list, on the same percentage of increase over old appraisement as that shown by the portion of the land reappraised, and this was adopted by the State Board as the true value. I would recommend that the law authorize the State Board to pro - ceed with an arbitrary increase of valuation in counties where the county commissioners decline to do their duty, and in counties where the county commissioners have made reappraisements and have, in the opinion of the State Board, valued the lands out of proportion to their true value, the same power should be extended to the State Board to change such valuations. Appraisements for school lands should be subject to equalization by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. The courts have already decreed this power inherent in the State Board, but the process is indefinite. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 12 INVENTORY OF SCHOOL PROPERTY An inventory of the State school lands should be taken. Each tract should be mapped, showing the character of the soil, water-ways or lakes, hills, valleys, table lands, timber, native hay, cultivated areas, roads and improvements, and a statement prepared showing what the land M best suited for and any other information that any owner would reasonably want to know about a farm. These maps should be prepared in conjunction with the Conservation and Soil Survey, and filed in the office of the Com - missioner of Public Lands and Buildings. Reduction for Improvements and Residence Residents upon school lands who have substantial improvements thereon and who make such showing, should be entitled to a reduction of 1 per cent from the regular interest rate, under regulations winch will protect the actual settlers. Minimum Value for Leasing The constitution provides a minimum price of $7.00 per acre where lands are sold. There should also be a minimum price for leasing purposes of, I should say, $2,00 per acre or more. I have no exact idea fixed of this valuation, except that it is not necessary to lease a single section of the poorest quality of Nebraska school land for less than about $100 per year. Hundreds of sections appraised during Commissioner Beckman's incumbency of this office, were valued so low that they bring from $15.00 to $40.00 per section. Some of these can be reappraised during the next two years, and a number of them are worth ten times the present valuation. Anyone refusing to lease at the fixed minimum price, who shall con - tinue to use the land by letting stock run over it and pasture it, or who cuts hay from it, or otherwise appropriates it for his own use, should be held for the rental, and it should be made collectible by law. Lands Should Be for Homefolks The use of state lands should be confined to actual citizens of the state, as far as possible, and any owner of a lease who shall live in another state or shall remove to the jurisdiction of another common - wealth, should be made subject to the state courts and the jurisdiction thereof in any and all questions relating to state lands. Some of the lease - holders in the potash section threaten the federal court as a final resort to plunder the state of this valuable product. Opposed to Sale I would urge that the state retain its title to school lands and not sell any more than it is absolutely compelled to sell under the present law, except as indicated above. If lands are to be sold, or any parcel thereof, free and </seg>
            <seg id="p013">INVENTORY OF SCHOOL PROPERTY 13 open bidding should be the rule. It is the only way to get the true value thereof. Recently land sold for $60.00 per acre in Wyoming, under open bidding, and the same quality of land in the same neighborhood across the state line in Nebraska, where the law does not permit competition, sold for $20.00 per acre. Leases issued prior to July 9, 1897, permit the owners to apply to purchase or re-lease, but the statute could be improved. When such applications are made, the exclusive right to purchase could be obliterated. Income Returned to the Counties One of the arguments for selling school lands is that part of the counties have sold their quota, while in other counties the state retains their acres and as a result there are losses to local taxation. The lands are not deeded and are not taxable. I recommend that 20 per cent of all rentals received from school lands be set aside and returned to the several counties in pro - portion to the school land acreage therein and the rentals derived therefrom, and that it be divided to the several school districts of each county in pro - portion to the acres of school land in such districts. The Legislative Refer - ence Bureau, and several others, have found this percentage and the process of distribution to a be a just and proper return to the counties and districts from which it is received, in order to balance the losses in local taxation. Leasing for Minerals At the regular session of the legislature of 1917, Representative Stearns introduced a mineral leasing bill, prepared by me, but in the crowding of bills upon the committee and the lack of knowledge relative to possible mineral resources in the state, the bitl never left the committee. On May 2, 1917, a number of citizens, viz., W. S. Ridgell, F. M. Broome, K. A. McRae, Clyde A. Rossiter, and James C. Quigley, made a request for leasing for the development of potash and minerals a number of sections in Sheridan and Cherry counties. The condition was that they should have one year to examine thirty-nine sections named, after which they should select five, one for each member of the company. The lease was approved by the Board, and it was apparent to the Commissioner that many similar applica - tions were likely to be made, so many that an individual action and contract in each case would be impracticable. I, therefore, requested the adoption of rules governing the issuance of mineral-oil leases in Nebraska. The fol - lowing rules were adopted, and blanks in accordance therewith prepared by the Commissioner and approved by the Board. RULES GOVERNING THE ISSUANCE J3F MINERAL-OIL LEASES ON STATE LANDS IN NEBRASKA Adopted by the State Board of Educational Lands and Funds In the absence of any statutes governing the productions of minerals, gas, oil, potash, or other valuable substances from school and other public lands of the State, the Board of Educational Lands and Funds has adopted the following rules : </seg>
            <seg id="p014">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 14 Any lands desired to be prospected shall be applied for in writing. If the land is covered by agricultural lease, the said agricultural lessee shall be notified by the Commissioner, and he may also apply for the prospecting privileges, if he so desires. In such case, or in other cases where there are two or more applicants for a mineral prospector's lease upon the same tract, the Commissioner shall cause the same to be advertised for a period of not less than twenty days in some newspaper in the county in which the land is situated, and all who desire may bid a bonus for the privilege of acquiring the mineral prospector's lease. Such privilege shall consist of the right to enter upon said land to pros - pect for minerals, gas, oil, potash, or other valuable substances by borings, excavations, or otherwise, and should such right be acquired by other than the agricultural lessee, the mineral prospector lessee shall pay all damages done to growing crops and for the use of the lands actually occupied by structures and for excavations, borings, or buildings that may be necessary for the successful prosecution of the work, and no such structures, excava - tions, borings, or buildings shall be within ten rods of the dwellings or barns of the agricultural lessee. Prospectors must begin examination of the chemical or geological possi - bilities within six months and must begin actual borings or excavations or buildings upon said tract within one year and must have a productive well, mine, or plant in operation within three years. A showing satisfactory to the State Board must be made on or before December 1st of each year. If at the end of a three-year period an unpro - ductive well has been bored to the depth of 3,000 feet, and prospector desires a continuance of the lease for further prospecting, the lease shall be renewed upon application, and an additional three years granted, subject to the prose - cution of the work with due diligence. The terms of such prospector's lease shall not be less than $1.00 for each lease annually and one-eighth royalty of all minerals, gas, oil, potash, or other valuable substances, requiring the same to be delivered in pipe-lines, tanks, or proper receptacles suitable for receiving the same, or cash market value thereof, at the option of the State Board. Mineral prospector lessee shall have the right to a renewal of the lease upon the same terms, so long as such mineral, gas, oil, potash, or other valuable substance is being produced in paying quantities. The Board shall reserve the right to the State of revoking and cancelling any lease at any time it is convinced that the mineral lessee is not operating in good faith, and is dilatory and negligent in the work, or in the reports required by the State, by giving said mineral lessee thirty days' notice. Each person shall be entitled to a lease upon one section only upon these terms. A prospecting privilege extending over more than one section may be obtained for a reasonable length of time until the lessee has deter - mined, by examination, which of said sections he prefers for continuing his work. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">RULES TO GOVERN POTASH LEASES 15 Supplemental Rules to Govern Potash Leases from the State of Nebraska Applications will not be accepted from one person for more than five sections, from which a selection of one section must be made and the others canceled within thirty days. Failure of applicant to make such selection within the thirty days will forfeit all rights under such application. Within ninety days after the selection, as aforesaid, applicant shall com- mence a construction of his production plant. Present applicants for more than one section for prospecting and develop- ment of potash resources shall be governed by the foregoing rules, and the Land Commissioner is directed to forthwith send notices to all such appli- cants that said selections shall be made within the said thirty days. The following leases, under these rules, were issued : County Description Name Banner All 16—19—57 M. E. Shafto Banner All 36—19—55 Geo. A. Jones Banner W &lt;/ 2 &amp; SE % 36—19—57 Wm. T. Young Banner All 36—19—56 Prairie Oil &amp; Gas Co. Sioux All 16— 2ft— 55 John M. Alexander Sioux All 36—31—56 A. E. Alexander Garden All 16— 23— #6 J. E. O'Brien Garden All 16—23—45., G. T. Haines Sheridan All 36—25—46 S. I. Dankers Sheridan All 16—25—44 F. J. Birss Cherry W V 2 NW, SE NW, S V, of 16—29—39 F. A. Cumbow Frontier NW NW, E y 2 NW, NE SW, E Y 2 of 36— «— 28 Roswell H. Johnson Frontier W V 2 &amp; W V 2 E ]/ 2 36—7—27 J. C. Scott Frontier All 36— 6—27 Irving T. Honnold Frontier All 36 — 7—28 Florence Honnold Frontier All 16— 6—27 Edna Ford Scotts Bluff Frac. All 16—21—58 Kathryn Van Horn Scotts Bluff All 36—23—58 A. R. Honnold Scotts Bluff All 36—23—57 F. J. McCaffree Scotts Bluff All 16—20—53 Harry McCaffree Scotts Bluff All 16—20—54 Conrad B. Snyder Scotts Bluff All 36—21—56 Alice McCaffree Scotts Bluff All 36—22—56 Gertrude D. McCaffree Scotts Bluff All 16—21—56 Louie D. Snyder Scotts Bluff All 16—22—56 Harry A. Beale Sheridan All 35—26—45 Will S. Jay Sheridan All 36—24—44 J. P. Dailey Box Butte All 36—24—51 C. N. Crandall Garden All 16—20 — 44 H. B. Johnson Garden All 36—23 — 45 H. T. Johnson </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT County Description Name Garden All 36—23 — 44 O. R. Lamb Sheridan All 36—26 — 15 J. J. Harrington Cherry S'/i 16—31—28 C. H. Cornell Sheridan S Y* Sec. 9 &amp; N Y, 17—26—43 C. F. Brinkman Sheridan All 16—34 — 46 Charles Naylor Morrill All 16—18—50 Al G. Snedeker Morrill All 16—18—52 John K. Adams Banner All 16—19—54 Ward Hildreth Banner All 36—19—54 Leta Curtis Sheridan All 26 — 26 — (5 Frank Reida Garden All 16—21—46 Mae Weilage Sheridan All 36—24 — 13 Edw. E. Howell Sheridan All 16—26 — 13 E. G. Barnhart Sheridan All 28—27—44 Clifford N. VanLone Sheridan All 16 — 28 — 14 Charles B. Barnhart Garden All 36—23—46 John E. Farmer Sheridan All 36—25—15 Herman K. Mansfield Banner All 36—20—58 Owen A. Frank Sheridan All 36—34 — 16 F. M. Bell, Trustee Banner All 36—19—58 W. E. Frank Scotts Bluff All 16—20—57 Eceneith Honnold Banner All 16—19—58 E. D. McCall Scotts Bluff All 16 — 20—58 Lucy Dolphin Sheridan All 16—24—12 A. G. Emerson Sheridan All 16—25 — 13 J. C. Quigley Sheridan All 36—25—44 K. A. McRae Sheridan All 16—27 — 14 F. M. Broome Sheridan All 36—24 — 45 C. Rossiter Sheridan All 16—25 — 15 W. S. Ridgell Banner Eyi &amp; Eyi Vf l /i 16— 18— 54 C. S. Page Sheridan All 36—35 — 16 H. D. Lingle Morrill All 36—19—52 J. W. Rider Morrill All 36—19—51 Frank B. Johnson Garden All 16—22—14 N. R. Ackerman Sheridan All 36—33—45 Josephine G. Faes Sheridan All 16—24 — 44 Laura A. Beale Banner All 16—19—56 Wm. Frank Banner All 36—20—57 A. H. Langman Cherry All 36—27—10 Jarvis Richards Cherry All 18—27—40 Ethel Mae Nolds Cherry All 16—26 — 10 Richards &amp; Comstock Cherry All 16— 27— 10 Noe Cattle Co. Sheridan All 36—28 — 11 Walter Wightman Sheridan All 21—25 — 12 Jean Steuffer Sheridan All 20—25 — 12 '. .Chas. J. Jameson </seg>
            <seg id="p017">RULES TO GOVERN POTASH LEASES 17 County Description Name Sheridan X'A 17—25—43 Al Stanley Sheridan W'A 21—26—43 Al Stanley Sioux All 16—33—54 J. W. VanHorn Sioux All 16—34—54 •. Frank VanHorn Sioux All 36—34—54 Fannie VanHorn Sioux All 36—33—55 G. D. Taylor Banner All 16—19—53 W. F. Ellsworth Banner All 36—19—53 S. R. Wisner Dawes AH 16—34—48 Mrs. Mary P. Jay Dawes N 'A, N 'A SW, N 'A SE, S'A S'A SW of 16—33—48 S'A S'A SW of 16— 33— 48 W. W. Naylor Morrill All 36—19—50 Morrill All 36—19—50 Harry L. Ellsworth Garden All Garden All 16—22 — 45 16—22 — (5 Howard Beck Dawes All 36—35—50 Dawes All 36—35—50 Nelson H. Bedell Morrill All 27—19—50 Morrill All 27—19—50 Grace D. Bedell Dawes NE %, NE NW 36—34—49. Dawes NE % NE NW 36—34—49 August Schwabe Dawes N)4 36—34—48 Dawes K'A 36—34—48 E. F. Carpenter Dawes S'A 36—34—48 Dawes S' y 36—34—48 R. A. Maika Garden All 36—22 — 45 Garden All 36—22—45 W. W. Beck Sheridan All 36—34—45 36—34 — 45 Watson L. Purdy Sheridan All Sheridan S^ NE, S'A NW, S'A Sheridan S'A 36—33—46 F. A. Peterson Morrill All 36— 18~50 A. B. Winegar Garden ..All 36—21 — 46 Guy W. Myers Garden All 36—22 — 44 John W. Haines Sheridan All 36—27 — 45 Grace Haines Morrill All 16—22 — 47 Flossie Haines Garden All 16—22—46 Elsie M. Haines Garden All 36—21—45 Margaret E. Butcher Sioux All 16—34—55 Dan Jordan Sioux All 36—35—54 May Taylor Dawes All 36 — 35 — 49 Frank J. Flanigan Sheridan All 36—26—45 Carrie A. Birss Sheridan All 16—33 — 45 Mrs. C. W. Hammack Scotts Bluff All 16—22—53 R. E. McCaffree Morrill All 16—23 — 47 Mrs. John E. O'Brien Morrill E'A SW, SE NW 36—23—47 E. H. Beinert Morrill All 15—19—50 Dollie Kinnan Morrill All 16—19—50 V. P. Wittenmeyer ..All 22 — 19 — 50 Jessie A. Kinnan Sioux All 36—24—55 Wenzel Hiersche Scotts Bluff All 16 — 23 — 54 Anton Hiersche 36—25—54 1. L. Harper Sioux N'A 36 — 24 — 53 Mrs. Flossie Stanton Sioux All 16—24—53 M. O. Tallon Sioux All </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT County Description Name Sioux SYi 36—25—54 L. P. Smith Scottsbluff All 16 — 23 — 53 F. D. Tallon Banner All 16—18—53 C. C. Farlow Banner AH 36-^18—56 M. H. Tilton Banner All 36—18—53 Frank N. Dudley Box Butte All 16—24—47 M. E. Young Box Butte All 16—84—49 C. F. Smith Box Butte All 16—24 — 48 J. R. Farris McPherson N y 2 NW, SW NW, NW SW 16—18—35 J. Faes Dawes All 16—34—50 Frank M. Mayhew Frol «'er All 16—6—26 Alice »2!lsworth Franklin W ]/ 2 NW 36—4—13 Catherine Fitzgerald Garden All 16—23—44 Cordia J. Adams Garden All 16—23—43 John S. Adams Lancaster SE 16—10— 7 Roy M. Harrop Lancaster E l A NW 32—11—7 Roy M. Harrop Morrill All 16—19—51 Martha J. Kinnan Morrill All 36—22—47 C. W. Shipler Morrill All 36—21—19 Wm. Maunier Morrill All 16—23—50 Robt. O. Reddish Morrill All 16—22 — 49 C. M. Looney Morrill All 36—22 — 49. J. K. Snow Morrill All 36—23—48 Arvilla M. Snow Morrill All 16—22—50 Anna G. Jeffrey Morrill All 16—22—48 C. A. Snow Morrill All 36—22—48 R. H. Garrett Morrill All 36—21—50 Eugene Burton Morrill All 16—21—50 J. C. McCorkle Morrill All 36—22—50 Joseph Jeffrey Morrill All 16—22—51 Geo. G. Beams Morrill All 16—21—48 Geo. G. Waite Morrill All 36—21—48 Linford R. Fitch Morrill All 16—21—47 H. M. George Morrill All 36—23—49 Chas. A. Simmons Morrill All 16—23 — 49 Ora L. Ogg Sheridan E J4 9—27—46 L. E. Pilkington Sheridan E!4 21—27—46 L. E. Pilkington Box Butte All 36—24—47 A. S. Sandlovich Sheridan All 36—35 — 44 Eunice K. Barton Garden All 36—22—46 Florence Haines Sheridan All 36—24—46 John O'Keefe Sheridan All 36—34—44 James P. Connolly Sheridan All 36—35 — 43 Arthur N. Gross Sheridan All 16—26 — (2 J. P. Barrett Sheridan All 16—27 — 43 Fred R. Cox </seg>
            <seg id="p019">RULES TO GOVERN POTASH LEASES 19 County Description Name Sheridan All 36 — 27 — (2 Meyer Langerak Sheridan All 16—25 — tl C. A. Welsh Sheridan All 36—26—41 M. M. Johnston Sioux All 36—30—54 Geo. A. Hills Sioux All 36—29—54 Raymond Lewis Trabert Sioux All 16—31—56 Ralph M. Baker Sioux All 36—28—57 Roy C. Strong Sioux All 16—28—54 Herman A. Trabert Sioux All 36—30—53 Geo. J. Hand Sioux All 16—30—53 Glen Miller Sioux All 16 — 29 — 53 Mrs. C. L. Hill Sioux All 16—28—53 Daniel R. Conway Sioux All 36—28—55 Geo. A. Heilman Sioux All 36—29—55 D. W. Kenner Sioux All 16—30—55 Fred J. Peterson Sioux All 36 — 30 — 55 Laveta Darling Sioux All 36—28—56 J. H. Hawes Sioux All 16 — 28 — 56 L.C. Hartman Sioux All 36—29—56 F. A. King Sioux All 16—29—56 Frederick A. Bald Sioux All 36—30—56 F. B. Hartman Sioux All 16 — 30—56 George D. Darling Sioux All 16—29—55 Annabel B. Kenner Sioux All 16—30—54 L. H. Highland Sioux All 36—28—54 Mrs. Martha I. Trabert Sioux All 36—29—53 C. L. Hill Sioux AH 16—24—54 Paul E. Stanton Sioux All 36—24—54 Harry E. Gueck Webster ti ]/ 2 NW 29—2—10 Mrs. Elizabeth A. Beale Webster W Vz SE, SW NE, NW NW, S V 2 NW, SW 21— 2—10 Mrs. Elizabeth A. Beale Sioux All 36—35—55 M. Weidenfeld Dawes All 36—34—50 Samuel J. Palmer Lancaster Part NW NW 23—10—6 Roy M. Harrop Furnas W Y, SE 36 — 4—25 and NE, S'A 16—1—23 N. A. Huse Furnas All 16— 1—24 J. E. Rasmussen Furnas All 16—3—25 M. Edna Rasmussen McPherson ..All 16—19—34 Clyde L. Triplett McPherson All 36—19—35 W. J. Root McPherson K 'A NE, NW, NW SW S'A SW of 16—19—35 Austin J. O'Malley McPherson NE, SE NW, NE SW, S'A SW, SE 16—18—35 T. E. Heskett Furnas All 36—3—24 Mary B. Mickel </seg>
            <seg id="p020">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 20 County Description Name Furnas AH 36—3—25 Chas. McCaffree Red Willow All 36—1—30 E. G. Penney Red Willow W y 2 NE, Vfy 2 SE 16— 4— 27 &amp; W/2 &amp; SE 36— 4— 27 Eva L. Gray Red Willow All 36— 1—26 Robt. R. Gray Red Willow All 16—2—28 Albert Bunting Frontier N/i &amp; SW 16—5—26 G. H. Watkins Sioux All 36—31—55 W. B. Wolfe Red Willow SW % 36—2—27 and N and SW 36—2—26 Rhoda Robins Red Willow All 16—2—26 Geo. R. Chatburn Red Willow NW 36—2—27 and NH and SW 16—1—28 Daisy Johnson Red Willow All 16—1—30 Harry E. Maybee Red Willow All 16— 2—29 Lee H. Maybee Red Willow All 36—3—26 Harry Porter Red Willow All 36— 1—28 Harry Harpster Red Willow SE NW 36—4—28 and SE NE 16—3—27 and all of 36—3—27 except W Vi SW Philip J. Harrison Cherry ti'A 27—35—39.. J. C. Carson Mineral leases approved but not issued : County Description Name Banner All 16—18—56 Patrick O'Grady Sheridan All 16—26 — 41 J. L. King Sheridan All 36—26—42 Hallie Stanley Sheridan All 36—25 — 42 F. M. Stanley Sheridan All 36—26—44 Mrs. Myrtle Stanley Sheridan All 36—26—43 Geo. W. Stanley Garden All 16—22 — 43 William T. Pace Sioux All 16—33—55 Charles T. Coffee Frontier All 16—5—25 Geo. Steele Box Butte All 36—24 — 47 Fred O. Haines Cherry All 36—30—29 F. W. Anderson Box Butte SW NE, SE NW Furnas 36—26 — 47 Charles E. Heath . . All 36 — 1—22 Harry Anderson The Fawn Lake Ranch Case Acting on the theory that it interfered with agricultural leases already in existence, a case was instituted in the district court of Cherry county by the Fawn Lake Ranch Co. against F. A. Cumbow. The district court was convinced that there was no material measure of damage to the ordinary leaseholder, an award of one cent being made. The lowering of water </seg>
            <seg id="p021">FAWN LAKE RANCH CASE 21 levels in the sand hill lakes is generally considered beneficial to agriculture, as it makes more hay in the valleys. The case was appealed to the supreme court, which, while practically affirming that there were no material dam - ages, declared the leases issued by authority of rules adopted by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds were invalid. It closed its decree with the following statement: "The plaintiff is entitled to the use and occupation of the lands until the legislature sees fit to confer upon the Board power to vest others with the right to enter upon the lands and remove minerals therefrom." Mineral Leasing Law A special session of the legislature was called, to meet March 26, 1918. In the call, the Governor included the proposal of enacting a statute for the leasing of State lands for mineral purposes, and for the validation of leases heretofore existing by authority of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. Representatives Thomas, Beal, Stearns, Lampert, Naylor, Norton. Tracewell, Fultz, Craddock and White introduced the bill, which, with the several amendments, became Chapter 7 of the Extraordinary Session of the legislature. This legislative act was drawn with the view of meeting every emergency indicated by the supreme court, and the legislature conferred therein powers upon the State Board and outlined methods of procedure. Under this act, the Board proceeded with the issuance of mineral permits and leases. The following mineral permits and leases were issued thereunder County Deschiption Name Rock All 36—31—20 C. E. Woodbury Banner EJ4 16 — 19 — 55 Fred Anderson Banner All 16 — 18 — 55 Harry Anderson Cheyenne All 16—13—51 Carl M. Hardman Cheyenne All 16—13—52 Mark W. Woods Cheyenne All 16—12—51 F. H. Woods Cheyenne N}4 14—12—51 and N^ 14—13—52 : F. E. Stewart Cheyenne All 16—12—52 Charles P. Ross Cheyenne All 36 — 13 — 51 Geo. J. Woods Cheyenne All 36—14—51 Harry A. Nugent Cheyenne All 36—13—52 D. R.Jones Cheyenne All 36—14—53 Thomas H. Smith Cheyenne All 16—14—51 Robert A. Smith Furnas WJ4 16 &amp; N 54 36—1—25 Henry H. Wilson Furnas All 36 — 1 — 22 Florence A. Ryman Rock All 36—31—19 A. D. Scott Rock AH 36—30—19 J. E. Palm Rock All 36—29—19 Will Brookley Sioux All 36—31—57 Mrs. Wilfred Clare </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT County Description Name Sioux All 35—29—54 Emmet E. Bogan Red Willow All 16— 1—29 C. W. Ryman Cheyenne All 36—14—52 H. M. Stearns Red Willow All 36— 1—28 Harry Harpster Red Willow SE NE 16 &amp; all except WJ4 SW 36—3—27 and Philip J. Harrison SE SW 36—4—27 Sioux All 16—32—55 Chas. H. Essex Sioux All 16 — 31 — 54 Herbert C. Jennings Sioux All 36 — 31 — 54 Geo. E. Thompson Sioux All 16—31—55 W. H. Essex Sioux All 16—32—56 W. B. Shurtleff Mineral permit approved but not issued County Description Name Morrill All 16—22—58 F. E. Stearns I hesitate to elaborate upon this question, for it seems that the ground has been well covered several times, and I wonder if people care to read more about it. But the request has come from such sources that I will prepare it for permanent record. Also the continued reiteration of potash speculators that the State Board is holding up production of potash, calls for a response. Section 16 of the mineral law says if holders of original invalid leases have made extensive or expensive preparations and are ready to proceed with development, they have certain vested rights. If, "at the discretion of the State Board," they have no such rights. then Section 9 controls, "Where there are two or more applications" they must be advertised and go to the highest bidder. The district court says neither of these methods can be followed, but suggests a method previously rejected by the supreme court, and previously denied by the legislature. The mandate of the supreme court separated the agricultural lessee from any claim to minerals and put such resources in the "permanent" school fund instead of the "temporary" school fund, where lease money is directed. The State Board desires to follow the law, to obey the mandate of the supreme court, and also that of the district court, and could do so if there were no contradictions. There being a conflict of opinion, we have asked a final analysis by the supreme court. The consequences of the delay are clear, and we wish the counsel of all the litigants could have joined in our request for an immediate hearing of the case. Their having failed to do so renders the State Board blameless for the delay. Perhaps a record of this case in court should be made here. Mr. T. L. Briggs and Mrs. A. R. Honnold were applicants for the min- eral rights on the section. When the lease was offered at auction, Mr. Briggs </seg>
            <seg id="p023">MINERAL LEASING LAW 23 refused to bid, and Mrs. Honnold was a lower bidder, which left them both out of it. So any alleged irregularities in which it is attempted to show that I displayed favoritism, did not result favorably to my alleged favorites, and my motion and vote helped the work of eliminating them. If, how - ever, all of these irregularities were true, it would be a gain for the State. Brigg's attorney, Mr. Dilworth, started negotiations at "seven or eight per cent," and now, from no less authority than Mr. Briggs himself, the bid is raised $10,000.00 and several per cent royalty. According to his own figures, this would make $50,000.00 increase over his first con - templated figure. Taken at its face value, and the supplied figures, the approximate value of the lakes is $1,000,000.00. Briggs' first offer of "seven or eight per cent" would make $70,000.00 or $80,000.00. Now his offer would make $135,000.00 to the State, or an advance of $55,000.00, and he intimates that it might be more. Therefore, our refusal to give him the lease on first appeal, regard - less of laws, rules and other people's rights, has served well for the inter - ests of the State. And if you will look up the reason for most of the criticism of this department concerning potash policies, you will find behind it the fact that we have blocked someone who expected to get the State's potash for nothing, or for inadequate compensation. If all "mistakes," "juggling of applications," "irregularities" and other "mismanagement" should turn out so well, the State will be better paid. I confess having been active in working for the enactment of a mineral law, but the validation section was of minor importance. The main thing was to get a workable statute in harmony with the already expressed opinion of the supreme court. And that law was enacted. Section 16, the validation section, could have been omitted and suited me just as well, but as it is there, we tried to do what it says: If the holders of invalid leases make applications, we should issue new leases, or not, as each case merits. Wilkinson Lake In the case of Wilkinson lake, partly upon State lands in Section 16-26-45, and partly on private lands. W. E. Sharp, John Krause and H. L. Sams agreed upon a division of the handling of the potash waters thereof, and I asked that it be put in written form for our files before I took it before the Board. I was later informed by Mr. Krause's lawyer that his client repudiated the agreement, which made that effort without return. I was always willing to use my good offices in other cases to get all the claimants together for the production of potash or oil, where an agreement could be made that would give the State an undiminished royalty. If the holder of an invalid lease, who has made application for a new lease under Section 16, and the agricultural lessee, and all applicants for the mineral rights on a given tract will get together on any written agreement of division so the State will not lose thereby, and if the Board determines "at its discretion" that the best interests of the State and the public will be served, and will so direct, a mineral lease should be issued. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Thomas L. Briggs, by his attorneys, challenged the law and the opera - tion thereof in the district court of Lancaster county, and an injunction was granted restraining the State Board from proceeding further under the operation of this act. An appeal was taken to the supreme court and the case was argued on November 6th. Another suit should be brought to separate Mr. Briggs from his agricul - tural lease, he having proven an undesirable tenant, by his litigatious, con - tentious and obstructive conduct. STATE INDUSTRIAL DISTRICTS The Extraordinary Session, by the following resolution, directed the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings to secure data relative to the cost of building a state-owned sugar factory, the cost of producing beets and the cost of reduction to sugar : RESOLUTION Whereas, reports are that sugar factories have made enormous profits the past year, and failed to follow the usual custom of profit - sharing with beet growers, and Whereas, because of losses in some cases and small profits to farmers, where the refineries made large profits in others, a num - ber of growers have quit sugar beet production at a time when the country needs sugar, and Whereas, the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings is from that part of the state where sugar beet production is a standard part of agriculture : Be it Resolved : That the Land Commissioner be, and is hereby, required to prepare a statement of cost of production of beets, and facts concerning the cost of factories, and operation thereof, that the next legislature may consider the feasibility of erecting a state-owned refinery." The first difficulty that suggested itself was the constitutional right of the State to enter into such undertakings. The following plan has been evolved by which the State might indirectly assist in the construction of industrial plants : The present statute provides for co-operative effort in the building of irrigation and drainage canals. The irrigation district law was prepared in its initial form in 1893, by R. B. Howell, J. H. Darner, and the present Land Commissioner. In 1895, it became a law by the valuable assistance of the late Capt. W. R. Akers. By the same process, industrial districts may be formed, embracing territory or property which is desired for building sugar factories or other industrial plants. By hypothecating the credit of a community a first-class basis for bonds will be made available, and the legislature has power to authorize the invest- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">STATE INDUSTRIAL DISTRICTS 25 ment of State funds in such bonds. This is a sensible thing to do. Nebraska money would thereby back up Nebraska enterprise and add to the material improvement of the commonwealth. If the State will purchase fifty or one hundred thousand dollars of a million dollar bond issue, it will establish and stabilize a market for the balance, as it has done for irrigation bonds. Industrial districts can be formed, covering any internal and co-operative improvement ; a sugar factory, or any other factory, a packing house, or terminal yards for marketing stock, a water-power plant, or for road building or transportation systems. Co-operative districts need not be alone for the producer. Labor, clerical and manual, can unite for co-operative buying and distribution, or for the manufacture and sale of any product. The federal reserve system became stronger than a hundred Morgans, because it combined all the created assets of the nation. Industry is an asset ; it is the one great basic asset of all material wealth. United labor — municipal corporations composed of intelligent laboring men — assures a tangible result, and is the best foundation for credit. The federal government has already arranged credit for the hypothe - cated labor of farms, thru the federal reserve ; and by co-operation thru the federal farm loan banks. A new step should be for federal banks of industry. But until that is done, states with proper conservative judgment can invest public money in the bonds of well organized plans which pledges the toil and integrity of few or many men. The duty of the state or federal government is to its people, to adopt those policies which develop the physical, moral and intellectual resources of its people. Opportunity, genius and potential greatness will follow, if industrial municipal community energy receives the backing of the state's financial power. • It would be impossible to make an approximate estimate of the cost of raising beets or of producing augar at the present time or for the future. There are available figures of the time before the war, but beets now cost $10 per ton, while then they were $5 to $6. Labor and all materials used are very high. Fifty to one hundred per cent increase in all depart - ments is probably true. Farm help has also cost so much more that the increase of beet prices is not velvet, by any means. Just what is to happen in the next year or two is problematical. The standard of all prices may be kept up or there may be material reductions. As between the cost of producing sugar — and the cost of beets — there is a paper pjofit of nearly one hundred per cent. But there is to be taken from that, interest on the investment, cost of new experiments, many of which are completely lost, cost of maintenance, obsoletion and substitution of new for discarded old machinery and equipment. I have found it difficult to find what per cent these several items represent. The original cost of the factory at Scottsbluff was reported to be one and one-quarter million dollars. The old Ames factory was offered at $400,000. For what it was purchased, I do not know, but I do know that car-loads of the material shipped therefrom to Scottsbluff were out of date and never used. Also </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT train-loads of other new machinery and construction supplies were shipped in and used. Hundreds of men were employed for over a year in the construction. Every year new machinery takes the place of old. I am of the opinion that the reported cost of the plant was not greatly exaggerated. The new, modern factory built at Gering also cost over a million dollars before war prices. The factory just completed at Bayard, in the midst of the war, represents an outlay of a million, eight hundred and fifty thousand dollars. At present it would be impossible to obtain material or labor to build a factory, but this condition, we anticipate, will not long obtain. It is safe to say that a 500-ton plant will cost at least $1,000,000.00 if built within the next two years. A larger plant would be preferable and more economically operated, and a smaller plant than 500 tons of beets daily capacity would be impractical. A ton of beets this year costs the factories $10, plus freight and re - handling at stations. It would yield nearly 300 pounds of sugar. Old, standard figures are 281 pounds, but the sugar content is greater than ordinary this year. There was a time when sugar in the sack in storage at the Scottsbluff mill represented a total cost of $3.85 per hundred pounds. Mr. Havemeyer once made the average cost as low as $3.21 for all western plants. Careless estimates would put it at $7.50 per hundred this year, without taking into account any obsoletion and deterioration of the plant. Beet raisers generally make low estimates on the cost of raising beets. They fail to make any computation of much of their own labor, or interest on the cost of the land, or taxes — including irrigation costs, or deterioration of machinery, or the depreciation of horses. Including all these, the cost of producing a ton of beets will exceed $8.00 average. The Special Committee of the United States Food Administration says $7.92 in 1917. The costs in 1918 were higher. Alfalfa land — after three or four years of beets — should be put back to alfalfa at an expense of about $10 per acre. This does not give the farmer a big profit, but it furnishes him employment at good wages, in addition to whatever profit there may be. The factory fixed expenses include interest on the enlarged bond issue usually present in the case of consolidations, reorganizations and the like, where water percolates into the capitalization. The complaints against privately owned factories are: They do not share with the producer in years of abnormal profit. Profit sharing was the policy prior to 1917. They are careless of the interest of free-holders whose acres are de - voted to growing beets. They are alleged to have favorites — giving preferred banks and stock - feeders advance information of value. This may be an unjust suspicion only. The Commissioner regrets that there is some basis for these complaints. The principal criticism is because they abandoned profit-sharing, at a time when they could well afford to keep it up, and being at a time when the </seg>
            <seg id="p027">SALINE LANDS 27 country needed the sugar, their action had the effect of reducing acreage of beets. SALINE LANDS Shortly after taking charge of this office, I found irregularities existing concerning the sale of several thousand acres of saline land. I sent the following message to both the House and the Senate : "As Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, I deem it proper to lay before you an unfortunate condition with relation to saline lands ceded by the United States to the State of Nebraska, and to suggest the restoration of many thousands of acres which rightfully belong to the com - monwealth, and which should yield annually large sums of money needed in the building up of Nebraska's public schools. "After examining the records I am convinced that the larger portion of saline lands has been illegally taken from the State. "None of these lands are worth less than $100 per acre, and their average value per acre is probably $200 or more. The original grants were for 45,594.24 acres. Of this, about 7,200 acres were legally sold. Over 38,000 acres are involved in the illegal procedure. This acreage is largely in Lancaster county. "The value of the lands, exclusive of improvements, is many millions of dollars, perhaps nearly or quite as much as the total present permanent school fund of the State. "Being directly in charge of public lands that contribute to the support of the schools, I deem it my imperative duty to call your attention to this valuable estate, now temporarily removed from the custody and management of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. "In view of the fact that you are now here assembled as the direct representatives of the people, it would seem best that I lay the matter before you, and ask your counsel, guidance and co-operation. "I would be glad to go more into detail, but think it inadvisable until a regularly authorized committee shall ascertain if its judgment confirms mine, and determines what, if any, official process or procedure may restore this valuable property to the use and benefit of the people of the State." The Senate immediately directed a committee, composed of Hon. John A. Robertson, chairman, Hon. William Soost, Hon. Willis Wilson, and Hon. C. W. Beat, to investigate. They made the following report : </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT REPORT OF THE COMMITTEE ON SCHOOL LANDS AND FUNDS RELATING TO SALINE LANDS IN NEBRASKA Legislature of Nebraska Thirty-Fifth Session 1917 Report of Committee on School Lands and Funds Mr. President: We, your Committee on School Lands and Funds, to whom was re - ferred the communication of G. L. Shumway, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, relating to the saline lands of Nebraska, have made an investigation and beg to report as follows : We find Section 11 of the Enabling Act shows the following: "That all salt springs within said state, not exceeding twelve in num - ber, with six sections of land adjoining, or as contiguous as may be to each, shall be granted to said state for its use, the said land to be selected by the governor thereof, within one year after the admission of the state, and when so selected to be used or disposed of on such terms, conditions and regulations as the legislature shall direct." The numbers of the lands selected and confirmed comprise 45,594.24 acres, and a complete list is attached and marked "Exhibit A." Location of the salt springs attached and marked "Exhibit B. About 17,500 acres of saline lands were sold by Governor Butler without legislative action. These are indicated by "Exhibit C." In 1887, "An act to relieve parties holding contracts for the purchase and lease of lands from the state," etc., may have had in view the confirming of the titles to these lands, but it is not clear or specific. Article III. Section 17, of the Constitution of Nebraska of 1875, provides as follows : "The legislature shall never alienate the salt springs belonging to the state." Section 18 says : "Lands under control of the state shall never be donated to railroad companies, private corporations or individuals." The railroads have 183.12 acres of saline lands for terminals and right-of-way, for which deeds were issued from 1887 to 1893, and some acreage is occu - pied by railroads for which there has been no compensation and no record in the Land Commissioner's office. Chapter 91, Session Laws of 1885 "An Act to provide for the sale and leasing of the saline lands and the development of the salt interests of the State of Nebraska." This Act provided for the appraisement of all the saline lands owned by the State on the 1st day of March, 1885; (the Land Commissioner's report of 1885 shows 12,092.25 acres) and the sale of so much thereof as would be necessary to put down a salt well on the salt flats in Section 21, Town - ship 10, Range 6, the manner in which such well should be put down and </seg>
            <seg id="p029">SALINE LANDS IN NEBRASKA 29 appropriating $50,000.00, or so much thereof as was necessary, out of the saline fund to carry into effect the provisions of the Act. Section 1 of said Act excepts "that portion of section twenty-one now owned by the state and all of section twenty-two and the south half of section fifteen, all in township number ten, north of range six, east of the sixth principal meridian, and also except each and all of the salt springs owned by the state, and forty acres of land with each spring upon which the same is situated" from the list to be appraised subject to sale. The portion of Section 21 then owned by the State was all thereof ex - cept 160 acres along the south side, which had been set aside as a Model Farm by the legislature, and later sold by authority of the legislature and by the Regents of the State University. Section 1 of this Act of 1885 has not, so far as we find, ever been repealed. There was sold under this Act, 1,584 acres. (Attached and marked "Exhibit D") for which was received $20,027.50, and this was used in the putting down of the well as aforesaid. The saline lands set aside for Normal, Model Farm, Penitentiary and Asylum take up the balance of the original grant. Chapter 94, Session Laws of 1889, is : "An Act to provide for the leasing of the saline lands belonging to the State of Nebraska." This chapter provides only for the leasing of the saline lands, Chapter 22, Session Laws of 1893, is: "An Act to amend Chapters Five (5) and Six (6) of an Act entitled "An Act to provide for the leasing of the saline lands belonging to the State of Nebraska, approved April 5, 1889, being Sections 3808 and 3810 of the Consolidated Statutes of the State of Nebraska of 1891." This chapter contains an added proviso that a lessee of said saline lands may apply in writing to the chairman of the Board of County Commissioners or Supervisors, as the case may be, to have the lands embraced in said lease, or any part thereof, appraised for the purpose of sale and when so appraised said saline lands embraced in such application shall become subject to all the provisions governing the sale of educational lands belonging to the State, etc. The act contains no repealing clause. Your attention is especially called to the fact that this Act, as expressed in the title, can only cover leasing of these lands and cannot authorize the sale and does not repeal the law especially reserving the land in Sections 21, 22 and 15. Township 10, Range 6, East. Your attention is called to the further fact that this Act amends an Act relating only to the leasing of the saline lands, and does not repeal the act it amends. The Constitution of the State of Nebraska, Article III, Section 11. contains the following : "No bill shall contain more than one subject and the same shall be clearly expressed in its title." Under the provisions of the Act mentioned above, it appears to this Committee clearly without legal authority, that saline lands have been sold, described in "Exhibit E," to the amount of about 10,000 acres. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 30 In July, 1913, Mr. J. S. Dickman, owner of a lease on a tract of saline land, said lease dated September 19, 1908, made application to purchase same. Hon. Fred Beckman, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings at that time, doubting the authority of the Commissioner to sell such land, asked the Attorney General for his opinion on same, and received the following reply : Hon. Fred Beckman, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Sir: In your letter of the 19th instant, you state that J. S. Dickman, owner of a lease of saline land, bearing date September 19, 1908, has made an appli - cation to you for the purchase of said land. You inquire whether or not the Board of Educational Lands and Funds should grant a sale. In answer to your question, I will say that, in my opinion, the Board has no legal right or authority to sell said land. The proviso contained in Article II, Section 16, Chapter 69, Compiled Statutes of 1911, would seem, from its reading, to give the lessee the right to purchase such land, but, as I view the law, said proviso is inoperative and void. The original act, of which same forms a part, was passed in 1889, under the title "An Act to provide for the leasing of the saline lands belonging to the State of Nebraska." Nothing is said, either in the title or the body of the original act, of any right to purchase saline lands. In 1893, said original act was amended by an act entitled "An Act to amend Sections rive and six of an act entitled "An Act to provide for the leasing of the saline lands belonging to the State of Nebraska, approved April 5, 1889, being Sections 3808 and 3810 of the Consolidated Statutes of Nebraska of 1891." I am of the opinion that the title to the amendatory act is insufficient to sustain a provision grafting on to an act for the leasing of school lands provisions for selling same. Very respectfully, Attorney General. By GEORGE W. AYRES, July 29, 1913. Deputy Attorney General. These, Mr. President, are the facts as we find them, taking the same from the Enabling Act, the Constitution of Nebraska, Session Laws, Statutes and in the records of the office of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, and it is our conviction that these lands are the property of the State of Nebraska, and that immediate action should be taken to regain and retain possession of the same. Respectfully submitted, JOHN A. ROBERTSON, Chairman, WILLIAM SOOST, WILLIS WILSON, C. W. BEAL. February 19, 1917. GRANT G. MARTIN, </seg>
            <seg id="p031">SALINE LANDS IN NEBRASKA 31 Abstract of Salt Springs Selections, Granted to the State of Nebraska Under Act of Congress approved April 19th, 1864, and confirmed by the Secretary of the Interior in Clear List No. lA, December 23, 1872 Clear List No. IB, June 21, 1873 Clear List No. 2, April 12, 1878 Clear List No. 3, February 1, 1886 Clear List No. 4, January 18, 1881 Compiled by Robert Harvey, State Surveyor By Authority of G. L. Shumway, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings January, 1917. ABSTRACTS OF SALT SPRINGS SELECTIONS Granted to the State of Nebraska Under Act of Congress Approved April 19th, 1864 and Confirmed by the Secretary of the Interior December 83, 1872. Date of State Selection June 15, 1867. Government Clear List No. 1A NW 'A Section 3, Town 9 N, Range 6 E 154.51 acres N Vi Section 7, Town 9 N, Range 6 E 314.83 acres NE 54 Section 8, Town 9 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres SW % Section 5, Town 10 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres N 'A Section 2, Town 11 N, Range 6 E 311.80 acres S Y, Section 29, Town 10 N. Range 6 E 320.00 acres SE % Section 6, Town 10 N. Range 7 E 160.00 acres SW Va, Section 24, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 160.00 acres N Vi SE Vi, &amp; SE Va, SE 54 Section 30, Town 11 N, Range 7 E. . 120.00 acres N l A Section 32, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 320.00 acres NW 54 Section 4, Town 8 N, Range 5 E 169.40 acres N Vi &amp; SE 54 Section 2, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 480.00 acres All Section 4, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 639.88 acres SW 54 Section 10, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres N 54 Section 14, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres All Section 18, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 633.60 acres NE % Section 20, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres All Section 24, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres SW Ya Section 28, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres E Vi Section 32, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT All Section 4, Town 10 N, Range 5 All Section 4, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 635.12 acres E 635.12 acres All Section 14, Town 10 N, Range 5 All Section 14, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres E 640.00 acres All Section 2, Town 11 N, Range 5 All Section 2, Town 11 N, Range 5 E 624.16 acres E 624.16 acres All Section 22, Town 11 N, Range 5 All Section 22, Town 11 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres E 640.00 acres All Section 24, Town 11 N, Range 5 All Section 24, Town 11 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres E 640.00 acres Date of State Selection Date of State Selection June 15, 1867. June 15, 1867. Government Clear List No. lA (Saline) NE % Section 28, Town 11 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres NE % Section 34, Town 11 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres N y 2 Section 4, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 318.07 acres All Section 10, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres All Section 14, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres NE Ya, Section 18, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres All Section 20, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres AH Section 22, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres W Vt Section 24, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres W/ 3 NEJ4&amp; WJ4 SE !4 Section 24, Town 12 N, Range 5 E. 160.00 acres W Yi Section 8, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres W Yi NW Yt, &amp;. W X SE % Section 8, Town 12 N, Range 5 E. . 160.00 acres N Yi and SW Yt, Section 18, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 491.32 acres S Yi Section 2, Town 8 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres S Yi NE Y* &amp; SYi NW 54 Section 2, Town 8 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres E Yi Section 10, Town 8 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres W Yi Section 12, Town 8 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres All Section 20, Town 8 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres S Yi Section 5, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres W Yi Section 18, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 311.40 acres SW Yt, Section 28, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres W Yt Section 34, Town 9 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres E Yi Section 6, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 315.35 acres NE Y* &amp; SYi Section 7, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 467.82 acres W Yi Section 8, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres SE Y* Section 12, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres N Y 2 &amp; SW Yt Section 12, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 480.00 acres N Yi Section 17. Town 10 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres W Yi Section 23, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres NW Yt, Section 26, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres NE l A Section 27, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres N Yi &amp; SE Ya, Section 30, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 468.23 acres NE Yt &amp; S Yi Section 34, Town 10 N, Range 5 E 480.00 acres SE % Section 2, Town 11 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres NE Ya Section 11, Town 11 N, Range 5 E 160.00 acres Date of State Selection June 15, 1867. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">SALINE LANDS IN NEBRASKA 33 Government Clear List No. 1A (Saline) SW !4 Section 12, Town 11 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres N l A &amp; SE !4 Section 13, Town 11 N, Range 6 E 480.00 acres NW % Section 18, Town 11 N, Range 6 E 149.40 acres NE % &amp; S Vz Section 24, Town 11 N, Range 6 E 480.00 acres N y 2 &amp; SE !4 Section 25. Town 11 N, Range 6 E 480.00 acres E Vi Section 28, Town 11 N. Range 6 E 320.00 acres E Yi NW l A &amp; S 'A SW 54 Section 28, Town 11 N, Range 6 E. . 160.00 acres N y 2 and SW % Section 30, Town 11 N. Range 6 E 455.20 acres All Section 34. Town 11 N, Range 6 E 640.00 acres S Vi Section 2, Town 7 N, Range 7 E 320.00 acres SE 54 Section 4, Town 7 N, Range 7 E 160.00 acres E Y 2 Section 4, Town 8 N, Range 7 E 314.94 acres E y 2 &amp; SE l A Section 28. Town 8 N, Range 7 E 480.00 acres All Section 32, Town 8 N, Range 7 E 640.00 acres NE % Section 34, Town 8 N. Range 7 E 160.00 acres All Section 2, Town 9 N. Range 7 E 639.44 acres W y 2 &amp; SE !4 Section 10. Town 9 N, Range 7 E 480.00 acres SW '4 Section 5, Town 10 N. Range 7 E 160.00 acres N Y 2 &amp; SW % Section 7. Town 10 N, Range 7 E 476.04 acres N y 2 Section 12, Town 10 N, Range 7 E 320.00 acres N % SE &gt;4. SE % SE % &amp; NE '4 SW !4 Section 12, Town 10 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres NW U &amp; S 'A Section 24. Town 10 N, Range 7 E 480.00 acres All Section 26, Town 10 N, Range 7 E 640.00 acres All Section 34, Town 10 N, Range 7 E 640.00 acres All Section 14, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 640.00 acres NW % Section 26, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 160.00 acres NE % Section 28, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 160.00 acres All Section 8, Town 10 N. Range 8 E 640.00 acres NW K Section 20, Town 10 N, Range 8 E 160.00 acres All Section 28, Town 10 N, Range 8 E 640.00 acres All Section 34, Town 10 N, Range 8 E 640.00 acres NE % Section 20, Town 11 N, Range 8 E 160.00 acres All Section 26, Town 11 N, Range 8 E 640.00 acres All Section 28, Town 11 N, Range 8 E 640.00 acres All Section 32, Town 11 N, Range 8 E 640.00 acres 35,849.91 acres </seg>
            <seg id="p034">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 34 ABSTRACTS OF SALT SPRINGS SELECTIONS Granted to the State of Nebraska Under Act of Congress Approved April 19th, 1864 and Confirmed by the Secretary of the Interior June 21, 1873. Date of State Selection June 20. 1867. Government Clear List No. IB N Yi Section 21, Town 10 N, Range 6 E 380.00 acres S K Section 21, Town 10 N. Range 6 E..- 320.00 acres All Section 22, Town 10 N. Range 6 E 640.00 acres S y, Section 15, Town 10 N, Range 6 E 320.00 acres NE 54 Section 4, Town 9 N. Range 6 E 154.07 acres SW V A Section 4, Town 9 N. Range 6 E 160.00 acres NE Va, Section 26, Town 11 N. Range 6 E 160.00 acres W l A Section 10. Town 8 N. Range 6 E 320.00 acres NE % Section 30. Town 8 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres All Section 26, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 640.00 acres All Section 8. Town 9 N. Range 5 E 640.00 acres SW 'A Section 6, Town 9 N, Range 6 E 153.53 acres NE % Section 24, Town 9 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres S y 2 Section 26, Town 11 N. Range 6 E 320.00 acres NE H Section 28, Town 11 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres SE % Section 18, Town 9 N. Range 7 E 160.00 acres SE % Section 31, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 160.00 acres All Section 34, Town 11 N, Range 8 E 640.00 acres W Vi Section 2, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 317.42 acres All Section 20. Town 11 N, Range 7 E 640.00 acres S Vi Section 23. Town 11 N, Range 7 E 320.00 acres S Vi Section 19, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 318.32 acres SW % Section 14. Town 10 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres S Vi Section 4, Town 12 N, Range 5 E 320.00 acres 7,663.34 acres </seg>
            <seg id="p035">SALINE LANDS IN NEBRASKA 35 ABSTRACTS OF SALT SPRINGS SELECTIONS Granted to the State of Nebraska Under Act of Congress Approved April 19th, 1864 and Confirmed by the Secretary of the Interior April 12th, 1878. Date of State Selection June 20, 1867. Government Clear List No. 2 NW 54 Section 8, Town 9 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres N Vi SE 54, SW 54 SE 54 &amp; SW % Section 28, Town 10 N, Range 6 E 280.00 acres SW 54 Section 18, Town 9 N, Range 7 E 160.13 acres N J4 SE 54, SE 54 SE 54 &amp; SW % Section 13, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 280.00 acres n y 2 se y 4 , sw y 4 se 54 &amp; SW 54, Section 22, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 280.00 acres W 54 NE 54 &amp; S y* Section 27, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 400.00 acres e y 2 ne y 4 , n y 2 nw y A n y 2 se %, se y 4 se y 4 &amp; SW H SW 54 Section 30, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 320.00 acres 1,880.13 acres ABSTRACTS OF SALT SPRINGS SELECTIONS Granted to the State of Nebraska Under Act of Congress Approved April 19th, 1864 and Confirmed by the Secretary of the Interior February 1st, 1886. Date of State Selection June 20, 1867. Government Clear List No. 3 SE 54 Section 14, Town 10 N, Range 6 E 160.00 acres E y, NE % Section 27, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 80.00 acres w h ne y 4 , sy&gt; nw 54 &amp; n y* SW 54 Section 30, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 159.55 acres 480.38 acres </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT ABSTRACTS OF SALT SPRINGS SELECTIONS Granted to the State of Nebraska Under Act of Congress Approved April 19th, 1864 and Confirmed by the Secretary of the Interior January 19th, 1891 Date of State Selection Nov. 13, 1890 Government Clear List No. 4 NW % Section 33, Town 11 N, Range 7 E 160.00 acres Note: The original list of selections was filed June 80, 1867, and with the time limit stated in grant (one year from admission of the State in the Union) but the filing of a corresponding list omitting the above tract. Selections completed by filing List 4 November 13, 1890. See case of State of Colorado 10 L. D. 222. For full explanation see Clear List No. 4 of Saline Lands. VoL page LIST OF CORRECTIONS Errors to be added to total Clear List lA— NE % &amp; SE J4 Section 7, Town 10 N, Range 6 E (See plat for area) 0.10 acres Clear List 2— N ]/ 2 NW % &amp; SW % SW V 4 Section 10, Town 11 N, Range 7 E (See plat for area) 0.38 acres Total to be added 0.48 acres Areas to be deducted Clear List IA— N 'A SE *A, Section 4. Town 7 N, Range 7 E (Relinquished to U. S. by Act of L 89, Feb. 86, 1881) 80.00 acres Clear List IB— NE l A Section 28, Town 11 N, Range 7 E (Confirmed in List lA) 160.00 acres Clear List No. 2— N y 2 SE % 4 SE % SE ft Section 30, Town 11 N, Range 7 E (Confirmed in List 1 A) 120.00 acres Clear List 3— E ]/ 2 NE % Section 87, Town 11 N, Range 7 E (Preempted 1860, Nebraska City Office) 80.00 acre* Clear List 3— Error, Section 30, Town 11 N, Range 7 E. (See plat) 159.55 acres Total to be deducted 599.55 acre* </seg>
            <seg id="p037">SALINE LANDS IN NEBRASKA 37 RECAPITULATION Clear List lA 35,849.91 acres Clear List IB 7,663.34 acres Clear List 2 1,880.13 acres Clear List 3 639.93 acres Clear List 4 160.00 acres Total 46,193.31 acres Add .48 acres 46,193.79 acres Subtract 599.55 acres Total area of grant 45,594.24 acres EXHIBIT B. Location of Salt Springs No. 1— NW '4 Section 3, Town 9, Range 6 No. 2— N 'A Section 21, Town 10, Range 6 No. 3— NE % Section 8, Town 9, Range 6. No. 4— N Vi Section 6, Town 9, Range 6. No. 5 — N Vi Section 2, Town 11, Range 6. No. 6— SW Vt, Section 5, Town 10, Range 6. No. 7— SW % Section 14, Town 10, Range 6. No. 8— N Vt SE 54 and SE !4 SE»4 Section 30, Town 11, Range 7. No. 9— SW % Section 24, Town 11, Range 7. No. 10— N y 2 Section 32, Town 11, Range No. 11 — SE 54 Section 29, Town 10, Range 6. No. 12— SE J 4 Section 6, Town 10, Range 7. EXHIBIT C. In In 9 — 5 S Vi—Z All 2 (except SW %) SW S 'A SE 54— » In 8—5 NE 54—20 In 10—6 NW %—i In 8—6 ne y 4 — 6 S 'A NE 54—2 S y 2 &amp; NE %— 7 SW 54-« S Vi N WJ4— 2 SE 54-2 SE '4—12 w y 2 — 13 N yi—n SW Va—2 W 'A— 12 In 8—7 e y 2 — 4 E *A SE % NE '4—27 e y 2 &amp; nw y 4 — 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 54—34 54—24 NE %— 34 In 10—7 NW 54—18 s 54— 24 N 54 &amp; SE J4-7 SW 54— 15 E 54 W 54—28 N 54— 25 NW 54 &amp; SE 54—24 N J4 &amp; SW 54— 30 SE 54-34 S 54 &amp; NE 54—26 N J4 &amp; SW 54 &amp; NW 54—18 In 11—7 SW 54—13 All 14 NW 54—24 SW 54-28 E 54—32 w y, sw 54—24 W 54 NW 54—26 S 54—27 In 9—6 SW 54—5 SW 54—18 NE 54—26 SW 54-28 NW 54-34 NE 54—33 In 11—8 NE 54 SE 54 &amp; W 54 SE 54 SE In 10—8 In 9—7 All 2 All 2 All 24 SW 54—10 SW 54—18 W 54—26 All 26 In 10—5 W 54-14 SE 54-14 NE 54—28 All 28 N 54—32 In 12—5 W 54 &amp; W 54 E In 11—6 LAND SOLD UNDER ACT OF 1885 All of Section 8, Town 9, Range 5. S 54 NW 54 Section 24, Town 9, Range 5. N 54 Section 4, Town 10, Range 5. NE 54 Section 14, Town 10, Range 5. EXHIBIT D EXHIBIT E In 10—6 S 54—15 In 9—7 SE 54—18 In 8—6 N 54 - N 54 S 54—21 All 22 W 54—10 W 54—23 NW 54—26 NE 54—30 In 12—5 W 54—2 All 4 N 54 NE 54—27 SW 54, W J4 SE 54 &amp; • NE 54 SE 54—28 In 10—7 SE 54—26 NW 54—26 SE y 4 — 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">SALINE LANDS IN NEBRASKA 39 As shown by the records, the above is the list of saline lands owned by the State subsequent to the sale of the 1,595 s acres under Act of 1885. Governor Neville sent the following message to the legislature : "From the report of the Legislative Committee on School Lands and Funds, relating to saline lands of Nebraska, it appears that an act was passed in 1889 under the title 'An Act to provide for the leasing of Saline lands belonging to the State of Nebraska.' It further appears that in 1893 said original act was amended by an act entitled 'An Act to amend sections 5 and 6 of an act entitled, 'An Act to provide for the leasing of the Saline lands belonging to the State of Nebraska, being Sections 3808 and 3810 of the Consolidated Statutes of Nebraska of 1891.' " The amendment to the act passed in 1893 provided for the sale of the saline lands of the State and under the authority of the act the State sold several thousand acres of such lands. On June 29, 1913, the Hon. Grant G. Martin, Attorney General, by the Deputy Attorney General, rendered an opinion to the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings to the effect that the Board of Educational Lands and Funds had no legal right or authority to sell the saline lands of the State, for the reason that "the title to the amendatory act is insufficient to sustain a provision grafting on to an act for the leasing of saline lands provisions for selling same." It follows that a cloud rests upon the title of all saline lands sold by the State under the act of 1893. These lands were purchased in good faith. The State received what the land was reasonably worth at that time and has had the use and benefit of the purchase money for many years. The 'The inclusion of the SE % Section 23 was an error. 2 The inclusion of the NE % Section 26 was an error. •''The total acreage here named should be 1,584 instead of 1,595. In 9—6 SW tf— * SE J4-5 SW 54—6 N 'A—I N y 2 -6 NE J4— 24 N J4 &amp; SW J4— 34 In 11—7 E J4 &amp; NW 13 S 54—19 All 20 SW &gt;$, N }4 SE J4 &amp; SW S4 SE y 4 — 82 S #— 23 1 All 26 NE J4—34 In 11 — 6 W *A &amp;■ SE }4— 2 NE 54—24 SE K-25 S H— 26 E H— 28 S y 2 SW 54—24 NE 54 &amp; E 54 NW 54—262 E 'A NE y 4 , N 'A NW 54 SW 54 SW 54, N H SE 54 &amp; SE &amp; SE 54—30 SE 54—31 N In 11—8 In 11—5 All 34 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 40 purchasers have developed the land, placed improvements and established homes thereon. I am convinced that while the State may not be legally bound, it is certainly morally bound to perfect the title to all the saline lands purchased in good faith, and I submit herewith a bill for that purpose. The following bill was introduced and became, in due time, a law : House Roll No. 799 Introduced by the Governor A Bill for an Act to legalize, validate and confirm all conveyances and agreements heretofore made by the State of Nebraska concerning saline lands and to empower and direct the officers of the State to perform all contracts involving said lands, heretofore executed, when complied with by the original purchasers, their heirs or assigns, and to declare an emergency. I cannot agree that the Act was curative. Saline lands, sold under the defective law, still belong to the educational lands of the State, and that all salt springs and lands originally selected as salt springs, still belong to the educational lands of the State. SLACKER LANDS In several counties the school lands are slackers. They are not being put to the best uses for producing food or revenue. These lands should be classified and their uses regulated. In a number of counties, a conspiracy is evidenced involving county offi - cials, lease holders and some of the other financial elements, in keeping down the school land values, and holding them back from development. Misrepre - sentation is often indulged in ; lands that better be devoted to raising grain and potatoes are kept in pasturage. Efforts are made to further depress values by stories of the ravages of loco weed and sage. A number of affidavits are on file, in addition to the solemnly attested statements of the county commissioners, and among them we find the name of the president of a bank. This affidavit declares that the true value of the lands on the high tables around Alliance is from one dollar to two dollars per acre. One particular section of this land was before this office with a bid of a valuation of twenty-five dollars per acre, and several others were in a similar situation. Land adjoining this particular section has since sold as high as forty dollars per acre. Further evidence of the conspiracy came from letters from the county assessor, and other reputable men who were familiar with land values, protesting against the low values placed on school lands. The perjured statements of the conspirators are available and if. in the opinion of the governor, or the legislature, it is the proper thing to do, they can be turned over to the grand jury. Conspiring against the property of the state schools, and sworn statements intended to deceive and defraud the State, needs the robust attention of head officials in charge. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">SLACKER LANDS 41 Leases that can be reached by legislative enactment, or pried loose from speculative and non-productive holders, can better be devoted to a new plan of actual settlement and scientific cultivation, with preference given to returning soldiers. The secretary of the interior is promulgating plans for the reclamation of lands to furnish homes for the returning soldiers. This department has suggested the selection of slacker acres that are already in the farming belt, and that do not need reclamation. These acres could be appropriated, appraised, purchased at true value, and turned over to the soldiers at actual cost and upon easy instalments extending over a period of twenty or thirty years. Secretary Lane's constructive work should meet with hearty approval by all, because it is right for the public and right for the boys from "over there." And the proposed additional plan appeals to us as right. During my recent trip over the State, I observed many thousands of acres of wheat lands in practically an unproductive state. In one instance, the owner of a seven-thousand-acre tract had been offered twenty dollars per acre for his land. He declined the offer, declined to put a price upon his land, and declined to put it into wheat or to rent it for that purpose. We have been dividing wheat with the soldiers, and proud to do our bit, and we have also been dividing our wheat with the owner of these slacker acres. Many school land lessees are pursuing the same unpatriotic course, and, as Secretary Lane has so tersely put it, this condition obtains in nearly every state of the union, and is a matter "that should be dealt with in a very robust fashion." State Owns the State Resources Executives and courts are beginning to recognize that the power of officers temporarily in authority, is limited. They cannot, while holding a commission from the people for a short time, separate from the people something that belongs to all the people for all time. They cannot convey to one of the units of our government, any public necessity, even if they are temporarily vested with a commission to look after it. Therefore, I, for the State and in behalf of the children, the legitimate heirs of the great estate called the school fund, assert for them the title to all the coal, oil, gas, potash, commercial clay and gravel, and other valuable substances needed for public or general use, that are to be found on land of the State or on land that once belonged to the State. As Commissioner of Public Lands, I make forthwith the demand that each and every person who has taken from any such lands any such products of value, shall render an immediate statement and accounting. Any who wish to continue or to engage in the removal of any valuable substance from any lands belonging to the State, or which has heretofore belonged to the State, are hereby given notice to observe the proper procedure necessary : namely, the terms of Chapter 7 of the Extraordinary Assembly of the Thirty-Sixth Session of the Legislature of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT The Sheep Yards Case Of the 1,400 acres of unclassified land shown in the last biennium, 329 acres were in Lancaster county. Naturally, an investigation would follow where 329 acres of land disappear so near to the State Capitol. It was found that 320 acres had been set aside by a legislative act in 1879 for the use and benefit of the hospital for the insanse. About seventy acres of this is not being used for the original purpose, but is occupied by sheep yards, incident to the Burlington railroad. The Commissioner is required by law to keep a record of all public lands, yet the record of what became of this land consisted of a lead pencil notation that it was leased to C. E. Perkins. There was no record of how it came into the possession of the Burlington. A blind research extracted from the files of an old document, that it had been leased by the Board of Public Lands to said Perkins, and afterwards to the Burlington. That for a few years the rental was paid into the school fund, and then and there - after to the hospital for the insane. The Commissioner made the demand that it be paid into the school fund, and the Burlington agreed to pay it into court, that the title thereto might be litigated. This agreement was violated and in accordance with the statute a delinquent notice was sent. Proceedings for an injunctive order were instituted, and the railroad's contention was sustained by the district court. An appeal was taken to the supreme court and an argument had. The case is important, in that it is an effort to depart from the free and easy days and customs of frittering away school property. The Com - missioner was unable to secure from the legal department of the State a view of the facts and the law that coincided with his own, or to obtain any expression of realization of importance in the issues. The services of Dexter T. ■ Barrett were secured, after consultation with other members of the board, and the powers granted by the constitution and the law to the Commissioner had been considered. In the light of the facts and the law, we arrived at incontrovertible conclusions as follows : That the decision of the trial court was contrary to the evidence and the law, and the plaintiff did not establish that it would be irreparably injured or that it had no adequate remedy at law. The claim for injunctive relief was purely doubtful, contingent and speculative. The Act of the Fifteenth Legislative Assembly of Nebraska, found at page 150 Session Laws of 1879, is unconstitutional and void for the reason that the land here in controversy is saline land, granted to the State of Nebraska under and by provisions of Section 11 of the Enabling Act of Congress relative to Nebraska, and coming directly within the purview and provisions of Section 3, Article 8. Constitution of Nebraska, making said land a part of the perpetual school fund of the state, thus rearing a con - stitutional barrier against setting over said land to any other use and purpose than the benefit of the common schools of the State. That the land in controversy is not an endowment of the Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p043">THE SHEEP YARDS CASE 43 Hospital for the Insane but belongs to the common school fund of the State and is subject to the exclusive jurisidiction of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds for the uses, purposes, and requirements therefor, pre - scribed by law, and, in the same category as all other leased educational lands in this State relative to appraisement, re-appraisement, leasing and rental payments thereon. A disturbing thought invades the mind of the Commissioner. The de - cisions in the courts of Lancaster county are so frequently at variance with the opinions held by me, and earlier decisions being also fundamentally different from my conceptions, one is almost led to the conclusion that the counsel for railroads are almost invariably right, and my judgment is very frequently in error. Of this the future shall be the judge. Railroads on State Land Commissioners Eaton and Follmer, during their administrations, found that under an obsolete statute, large areas of land were occupied by railroads for rights-of-way, and terminals, and that there had been no compenstion to the State. This was clearly an infringement upon the constitution, which denies donations of public lands to railroads. This agitation resulted in the payment to the State for all the lands so occupied, except the Union Pacific and Burlington. The Union Pacific, having received its charter from the United States prior to the Enabling Act, creating the State of Nebraska, did not come under the constitutional inhibition. The Burlington held out against the contentions of Commissioners Follmer and Eaton, just as it has held out against the present Commissioner, maintaining that the old statute is operative against the constitution and the subsequent State laws. Delays and elections are depended upon to prevent the Burlington from doing that which all the other railroads have done; namely, pay for the land they occupy and use. Section 5956 Revised Statutes 1913, reiterates the old law in question, and should be repealed, and the maps filed with the Secretary of State should be directed by statute to the office of the Land Commissioner, where, under the constitution, they belong. The indictment against the Burlington still stands. Hang-over laws of the old regime, and shrewd counsel, have thus far resisted progressive measures, and annulled the plain provisions of the constitution, and defeated that which every other railroad has con - ceded as a fair settlement. Evidently the conception of moral obligations and legal responsibilities differs with different people, and the slacker in civil life does not differ materially from evasion of military dujy. The Bartley Defalcation For a generation the legislature has neglected the duty imposed by the constitution, providing that the school funds of the State shall never be depleted. The failure of the Capitol National Bank, and the defalcation of Treasurer Bartley took from the educational funds of the state $293,680.03. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT This, with interest for all the years, belongs in the school fund, and the legislature should make suitable provision by a levy to replenish the treasury for the amount due. A levy of one-fourth of a mill will pay it out in two or three years, and the oath of office to "obey the constitution" should inspire every mem- ber of the legislature to see that this is done. At the close of the last session, a number of members informed me that they had no idea that it had not been repaid, until the question of endeavoring to collect it from the directors of the defunct bank was up for discussion, and then it was too late to introduce a proper measure. This is carried as a suspended account in the State Treasurer's office. The amounts of the defalcation are as follows : General Fund $114,997.69 Sinking Fund 180,101.75 Temporary School Fund 38,820.44 Live Stock Indemnity Fund 3,843.39 Permanent School Fund 270,133.45 Permanent University Fund 9,775.93 Of this, there has been paid back to the general fund, $85,058.19. None of the sinking fund has been paid back. Of the temporary school fund, $5,115.10 was paid back. This was paid by the receiver of the Buffalo County National Bank, $501.00; F. M. Prout, of the Bank of Wymore, $894.94; Norris Brown, of the Bank of Orleans. $1,200.00; First National Bank of Orleans, two payments of $1,259.58 each. To the live stock indem- nity fund, nothing was paid back. To the permanent school fund, the attor- ney general, for J. S. Bartley, paid back $1,442.81; Central National Bank, of Grand Island. $447.16; Central National Bank, of Grand Island, $44.72. Total paid back to the permanent school fund. $1,934.69. Nothing has been paid back into the permanent university fund. The legislature of 1895 appropriated from the general fund for the purpose of repaying to the school funds the amount then supposed to be due for the shortage caused by the failure of the Capitol National Bank of Lincoln. This amounted to about $181,000.00. This appropriation never reached its destination. Mr. Bartley disposed of it for personal uses and for that he was sent to the penitentiary. Subsequent efforts in 1897 to again appropriate $181,000 apparently failed of passage. The amounts remaining due the school fund are as follows : Temporary School Fund $ 33,705.34 Permanent School Fund 250,198.76 Permanent University Fund 9,975.93 The constitutional requirement is that the permanent school fund shall never be depleted. Interest at five per cent should be added to the amount given from 1893 until date to make the fund intact. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">DEED REQUESTED FOR CAPITAL BEACH 45 Deed Requested for Capital Beach Among the many outstanding sale contracts, with relation to saline lands, are those covering 400 acres, known as Capital Beach. Two hundred and forty acres of the land embraced in these contracts were originally the most distinguished of the salt springs, which the constitution says shall never be alienated from the people. By reference to the special report on saline lands herein, it will be found that the Enabling Act, the constitution, and the statute of 1885, relating to saline lands, specifically forbade the sale of the lands in question, namely the Northeast quarter and the East half of the Northwest quarter of Section twenty-two, township nine, North, range six. East, in Lancaster county, together with other lands. Geologist Hahn, who made the first examination for the government, declared this salt spring to be in an impassible morass, and Geologist Russell, who superin - tended the putting down of the salt well, elaborates upon the salt springs found on this land. The present holders of the sale contracts maintain there are no salt springs. Officially there are, or there would have been no saline lands. Underlying this tract, hundreds of feet deep, is excellent gravel and sand of almost unlimited quantity and value, needed for public enter - prise and improvement of the roads. A mixture of this gravel and sand with the clays of Lancaster county, will make highways of quality second only to pavement, and the State should retain and use it in connection with federal road work. Thousands of tons of gravel and sand will be needed for the new Capitol building and other public structures. The owners of the sale contracts, issued under the faulty law, by care - less officials, and contrary to every public safeguard, have made a demand for a deed. The present Commissioner will not participate in a transaction so palpably at variance with constitution, law and duty. We have notified the holders that the removal of the deposits of gravel and sand constitutes spoil and waste, which under the law is sufficient reason for cancellation of their contracts. To hope to avoid this they have paid the face value of the contracts to the county treasurer. A few days after the passage of the mineral statute of 1918, this depart - ment received a receipt from the county treasurer of Lancaster county, show - ing the final payments made. This receipt bore a date two or three days before the new law became operative. The sinister significance of the date is emphasized by the fact that the new law imposes a more drastic and man - datory duty upon the commissioner. When it shall be brought to his atten - tion that spoil and waste are being committed on land under contract, the Land Commissioner is required forthwith to cancel such contracts upon his records. FOREST RESERVES In the State of Nebraska there are situated two forest reserves. The Niobrara Reserve is in Cherry county and contains 115,963 acres. The Bessey Reserve is situated in Blaine and Thomas counties in the following </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT proportions : Blaine, 10,546 acres ; Thomas, 79,565 acres. A total of 206,074 acres is the net forestry area in forest reserves. Twenty-five per cent of the receipts from the leasing and uses of the land are paid to the State. This amounts to about $2,000 per annum, viz: $2,019.07, the latest report. The legislature, by Chapter 212 of the Session Laws of 1917, authorized an exchange of the isolated school sections within the national forests, for other sections in a compact body or elsewhere. The Commissioner made an examination of the school lands of these two reserves. There are none in Blaine county. He also made an examina - tion of lands which it was proposed to exchange for the isolated sections in Thomas and Cherry counties, and after the approval of the county officials in the counties in which they are situated, he made his recommendation to the State Board of Educational Lands and Funds. On the 10th day of Septem - ber, 1918, the following resolution was passed unanimously by the State Board : RESOLUTION Whereas, the legislature by Chapter 212 of the Sessions Laws of 1917. authorized the exchange of school lands isolated within the National Forest Reserves in the State of Nebraska for other lands, and Whereas, the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings has examined the lands and conferred with the County Officials in coun - ties in which such lands are situated, and has made selections in approval of the judgment of such officials, which selections are agreed to by the local forester : Therefore, Be it Resolved, that the State Board of Educa - tional Lands and Funds will approve of such exchanges, and will issue quit claim deeds to the United States for the described lands upon the approval of the Department of the Interior, and such other action as may be required of the United States Government for transferring to the State of Nebraska other described lands in lieu thereof. Lands to be transferred to the United States are : Section 16, Township 21, Range 26. Sections 16 and 36, Township 22, Range 26. Section 16, Township 21, Range 27. Sections 16 and 36, Township 22, Range 27, all in Thomas county. Lands to be transferred to the State of Nebraska are : All of Section 1. All of Section 2, in Township 22, Range 28. All of Section 23. All of Section 26. All of Section 35. N / 2 of NW %, and SW % of NW 'A, and W X of SW % of Section 13. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">FOREST RESERVES 47 And E 'A and SE % of NW % and E V 2 of SW % of Section 14, in Township 23, Range 28, all in Thomas county. Other lands to be transferred to the United States are : • Lots 4 and 5, of Section 6, Township 30, Range 31. All of Section 16, and Lots 5 and 6 of Section 6, Township 31, Range 31. All of Sections 16 and 36, Township 32, Range 31. All of Section 36, Township 31, Range 32. All of Sections 16 and 36, Township 32, Range 32. All of Sections 16 and 36, Township 32, Range 33. Lands exchanged therefor to be ceded to the State of Nebraska by the United States are : The SE Vt, of Section 6. The N y 2 of NE 54 and SW of NE, and SE 54 of Section 7. The N y 2 of N 54 of NW, and N / 2 of NW of NE, and NE of NE, and S 54 of Section 8. All of Section 9. All of Section 10. The W yi and the W 'A of the E ]/ 2 , and NE 54 of NE 54 of Section IS. All of Section 17. The NE 54, and NE 54 of SE 54 of Section 18. All of Section 20. All of Section 21. The N 54 of Section 28. The N Vi of Section 29. All in Township 32, North, Range 30, West, in Cherry countv. Existing leases upon lands to be deeded to the United States are to be cared for by the United States upon the terms of said lease until the date of expiration thereof, or such other arrange - ments entered into between said lessees and the Unitd States, agreeable to both, whereby existing leases may be surrendered to the State for cancellation. These selections are in harmony with the wishes of the forestry officials as well as the people in the vicinity of the lands, and. in our opinion, are as good or better than the lands which the State proposes to relinquish. They are better situated and will bring more revenue to the State under lease. In looking over the thousands of acres of land already in forests and increasing the value of the lands on which such forests are situated, and also increasing the values of the land in the vicinity; also noticing the thrifty growth of certain classes of trees, I am led to believe that it would be a wise policy for the State to enter into forestation of different sections that might be selected by a forestry commission created for that purpose. As a name for the highway connecting the Niobrara Reserve and Valentine with the Bessey Reserve at Halsey, I have suggested the "Pine Tree Trail," and urge that the road be marked with the planting of jackpines </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT through the hill portion thereof, and cottonwood or poplars marking the road through the valleys. THE HAYWOOD CASE Some time after being inducted into this department, my attention was called to the condition of the leases issued June 12, 1897, to G. A. Hay - wood, now deceased. D. C. Eldrege and Charles Harding appeared at the office with the original leases and what they purported to be the assignments of the original leases conveying the leases to Richards and Cairnes Com - pany, and from said Company to them. It appeared in the meantime that G. A. Haywood died and that Fay M. Haywood furnished the office with proof of this death, together with proof of the heirs, and assignments from the heirs to said Fay M. Haywood. An affidavit had also been tiled stating that the original lease was lost and asking for a certified copy thereof, which had been issued by Commissioner Beckman. The record was com - plete, according to law and rules of the office, placing the title in Fay M. Haywood. The assignees of the original leases, even if their assignments had been in proper shape and legal form, had neglected to have such assign - ments placed of .record as required by law. The record of the account was very much mixed. At least ten differ - ent parties had paid the rental upon this land during the period of years. The Commissioner ruled that the assignments of Harding and Eldrege were not admissable of record, being confusing to the record and making two titles in one tract of land. The matter was taken by Attorney Stout, of Omaha, before the State Board. Three members of the State Board, viz.. Governor Neville. Attorney General Reed and Treasurer Hall voted for a resolution that it was the sense of the Board that these assignments should be placed of record. For reasons above stated, the Commissioner declined to do so. He is directed by the constitution and the statutes with individ - ual authority for keeping the records of all the lands belonging to the State, and it is his duty to keep them in good form. An original action for a mandamus was instituted in the supreme court by Harding and Eldrege. There being a number of important legal questions involved and the Attorney General, being by his voice and vote, disqualified for acting as attorney for the Commissioner, I employed W. T. Thompson and Dexter T. Barrett to represent this department of the State. A deficiency claim has been tiled with the legislature and has my approval, as the service ren - dered is worth many times the amount to the State. As a result of this case, new values will be established and the tem - porary school fund be materially increased. The legislature should make it clear that it is impossible to do by indirect action that which to do directly is expressly forbidden by the statute. Applicants for leases of educational lands must make an affidavit that they are not the owner of leases of more than 640 acres, including that for which they apply. It has been the custom of the office to record assignments conveying to one person more than 640 acre*. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">IMPROVEMENT OF RECORDS 49 IMPROVEMENT OF RECORDS Owing to the condition of the records — there being no alphabetical index of lease-holders in the office — it was next to impossible to prevent such abuses. We, however, prepared and opened up such an index, which now makes it possible for the Commissioner to keep a check upon the number of leases and acres in one's possession. The Attorney General, by a written opinion, informed this office that the rule of one section to one lease - holder only, which obtains at the time of leasing, does not necessarily follow the assignment of leases to another lease-holder. This appears to me as clearly an evasion of the statute and it is important that the court deter - mine the issue or the legislature amend the law. BOOKKEEPING AND FEES Predecessors have frequently overlooked the law which requires a penalty for each delinquent contract. I have adopted the policy of following the statute in this particular, which has increased the fees of the office many hundreds of dollars, as may be seen by the report of fees collected. Our bookkeeping department reports having also collected penalty interest on rentals, which was overlooked and neglected by predecessors, running back as far as 1911. The amount thus delinquent and collected was due from about twenty different counties and in the aggregate amount of more than $2,000. The primary cause of the delinquency was the fault of the county treasurers and carelessness of former bookkeepers in checking up the amount of penalty interest thus due and delinquent, and demanding it at the time receipts were received. IMPROVEMENT OF CAPITOL GROUNDS Each year of the past biennium, the city water supply has proven inade - quate for the demands. The State uses, upon the Capitol grounds and in the building, cost more than $3,000 annually, and still the lawn and trees suffer for the need of moisture. There is a well, situated near the engine house, that yields water of excellent quality. This should be connected up with the engine house motor and a suitable tank provided, for furnishing the state house and grounds with the supply to properly care for their needs; also a few hundred extra dollars should be expended each year in seeing that the trees, lawns and flowers have considerate attention. The saving of water charges will ade - quately compensate the State for the investment. HISTORICAL SOCIETY BUILDING Facing the Capitol grounds are some lots and the foundation for a building, intended for the some-day-historical-society-home. The State will some time in the near future have a new Capitol building. I would suggest that the first step be taken by biulding a substantial structure on the foundation referred to, which can be used for the temporary housing of </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT some of the departments of the State while the Capitol structure is under way, and after that be devoted to the uses of the display and conservation of the most valuable historical records, and museum, which are now in quarters notoriously inadequate and menaced by possible irreparable loss by fire. This would be an economical program for the State. SURVEYING The work in the department of surveying has been strenuous. The State Surveyor needs an assistant and clerk at a salary of not less than $1,000 per annum. The compensation of $5 per day fixed by the statute for deputy state surveyors is insumcien. Demands for competent men at $8 and $10 per day have made it difficult for the department to retain the present efficient force. I would recommend a maximum of $10 per day for the next biennium. as there is much work ahead and little probability of imme - diate wage reduction. THE KRAUSE DEED AND LEASE On February 17, 1817, a deed was issued to John H. Krause covering the S Vi SE !4 16-26-45. Sheridan county. This land was reviewed by Com - missioner Beckman and the authorization of its sale was made on January 4, 1917. Apparently the Commissioner and the County Commissioners failed to take into consideration the location of a lake containing potash brine, which is largely on this particular tract. This fact was known to Mr. Krause, who had had the analysis made, and he kept the information from the appraisers. An established principle of law is that purchasers must play fair. I would recommend that a suit be brought against Mr. Krause to return to the State the title to the land so surreptitiously obtained, and for damages or an accounting for the amount of potash taken from this particular tract, unless he turns over to the State the royalty of 20 per cent paid, or to be paid, by the American Potash Company. The lake in question extends into a tract leased by John H. Krause, viz., the north half of the southwest quarter of said section. He has committed spoil and waste and this lease should be cancelled. A portion of the lake extends into othei sections in which the State has no interest. The surveying department has established the corners and has supplied maps covering the area and giving the meander lines of the lake, so that it will not be difficult to deter - mine what portion belongs to the state and the part that belongs to private parties. REPORT OF AMERICAN POTASH COMPANY The pipe line to this lake was put in by the American Potash Com - pany, the pumping plant being situated on the S Vi SE % of said section. Appended herewith is a complete statement of the amount of potash waters removed from this lake by the American Potash Company, which state - ment was furnished me by W. E. Sharp, the president of said Company. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">HOU :S PU PED FROM SC OOL SEC ION Date Hours Gallons Beaume Sp. Gravity LbR. Dry Solids Dec. 2, 1917.. 3, 4. 5, 6, Jan. 2, 1918 3, 4, 5, 6, Feb. 11, 14, 15. 17, 18, 20, 23, 24, 26, 27. 28, Mar. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8. 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 6 4 12 10 9 24 20 24 21 11 H 6 36,000 24,000 72,000 60,000 54,000 144,000 120,000 144,000 126,000 66,000 51,000 36,000 48,000 60,000 12,000 6,000 78,000 108,000 132.000 132,000 135,000 135,000 120,000 144,000 48,000 144,000 117,000 144,000 144,000 144,000 144,000 144,000 144,000 54,000 108,000 144,000 138,000 129,000 57,000 69,000 72,000 14 14 14 14 14 12 12 12 12 12 11 10 12 9 8 10 9 1.1069 1.1069 1.1069 1.1069 1.1069 1.0902 1.0902 1.0902 1.0902 1.0902 1.0821 1.0741 1.0902 1.0662 32,070 21,380 64,140 53,450 48,106 108,240 90,200 108,240 94,710 49,610 34,892 22,230 36,080 33,100 5,840 3,705 43,030 59,580 64,240 55,770 65,^00 83,362 66,200 70,080 23,360 70,080 49,432 70,080 70,080 70,080 60,840 70,080 60,840 22,815 52,660 70,080 58,306 62,780 27,740 33,580 35,040 x 10 2 1 u is 22 22 22* 22! 20 24 I 9 8 7 1.0584 1.0741 1.0662 1.0662 1^584 1.0507 1.0584 1.0741 1.0662 1.0584 1.0584 1.0584 1.0507 1.0584 1.0584 1.0584 1.0507 8 10 9 8 8 24 191 21 8 7 8 8 8 7 8 7 7 8 8 24 24 24 24 24 9 18 24 23 1.0584 1.0507 1.0507 1.0584 1.0584 1.0607 1.0584 1.0584 1.0584 1.0584 7 21} N 12 8 8 8 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT HOURS PUMPED FROM SCHOOL SECTION— Continued Date Hours Gallons Beaume Sp. Gravity Lbs. Dry Solids Mar. 22, 1918 23, 9 2 54,000 12,000 8 8 1.0584 1.0584 26,280 5,840 2,253,846 or 1,126,923 tons .verage Date Hours Beaume Lbs. Dry Solids July 13, 1918... 14, 15. 16, 17, 18, 19, 14.25 3.5 20.5 23.25 9.75 15.5 23.5 23.5 23-5/12 12 and 13 3 7-6-10 10 10 7 7-8 9 81,334 4,615 64,968 107,676 45,153 49,115 81,713 97,221 111,353 20. 2&gt; 23, 24, 25, 26. 27, 28, 29, 30, Aug. 3, 1918 6, T. 23-5/12 23-5/12 23-1/12 21-6/6 22-2/3 20-2/3 23-1/2 9-1/4 2-1/6 2-5/6 13-7/12 3-11/12 9-10 10 11-12 12 8-B 10-B 10.5 11.5 13 14 21 10.5 Beaume 9-8-7-6 each 45 min. 111,150 123,768 130,113 79,677 104,944 97,625 126,459 57,973 1,312 29,997 66,280 10,140 Rained Av. Beaume 7 9, 10, 22, 23, 6-1/4 4-7/12 8 12.5 14.5 10 11 36,735 31,815 37,050 75,625 14-3/4 1,763,811 or 881.1905 tons Average K'O 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">LIEU LANDS 53 LIEU LANDS The United States government is still indebted to the State of Nebraska 1,280.54 acres, lieu lands to fill the quota of educational lands due the State. During the biennium, I have made the following selections in Grant county to cover a deficiency of other lands heretofore selected but not approved. The department has not formally clear-listed this to the State, but it will come in due time: SW SW 20-23-36; SE SE 21-23-36; SW SW 22-23-36; SW SE 23-23-36. Oil and Gas During the summer of 1916, I occupied much of the time in geological examination of western Nebraska and eastern Wyoming. I became con - vinced that proper conditions obtained there for the accumulating of gas and petroleum. Dr. G. E. Condra, of the Conservation and Soil Survey; Prof. Schram. State Geologist, and other geologists of note, agree that the territory is worthy of the interest of investigators. Three operators are now in the field. Moderate quantities of gas have been tapped in Banner county, near Harrisburg, at a depth of about 5,000 feet. The Prairie Oil &amp; Gas Co. has 7,200 feet of casing and are driving the drill into the deeper rocks. In a number of other places. Stockville, Red Cloud, Wilcox, Humboldt, Bassett and Chadron, operators have drilled and are drilling ; some of them at a depth of 3,000 feet or more. Still others contemplate early action in Furnas, Red Willow, Franklin, Sheridan, Scotts Bluff and Sioux Counties. Gas twenty miles south of Scotts Bluff and Gering, and oil seepage at Riverton and Inavale. and the "coming in" of a well yielding 1,500 barrels daily at a point about thirty miles from the northwestern corner of Nebraska, make it reasonably certain that oil and gas sands underlie a considerable area of the State. The Commissioner has encouraged such investigators. Oil and gas prospectors hold some of the leases that have been declared invalid. They have asked for new leases under the new law, but action thereon is post - poned awaiting the determination of the supreme court. In our opinion, the proper conservation and encouragement of this industry will result in a large income to the school funds of the State as the industry develops. INCREASED SCHOOL FUNDS The state schools of Nebraska will receive $120,000 additional money next year and each following year, forever, because of the activities of this department during this biennium. By following the policies evolved, the income may be greatly increased. Two million dollars of tangible assets have taken the place of neglected, unused and forgotten school property, and it is rented at six per cent. There is more property that needs revaluation, for the good work is not completed. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT RULES AND REGULATIONS PERTAINING TO THE LEASING AND SALE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS The following paragraphs are intended to answer a majority of the inquiries made by prospective lessees and purchasers of educational lands, as well as many questions asked by county treasurers. The State seldom has any unleased lands, and then only at about the time auctions are held as described hereafter. These auctions occur generally but once each year at the offices of the various county treasurers. Lease Contracts The Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings may at least once in each year designate a day and hour for offering in a public manner, at the office of the county treasurer in the respective counties, lease contracts on all of the educational lands, which may be subject to lease in that county at the time of such offer. The same shall be subject to lease at an annual rental of six (6) per cent on the appraised value. Provided, that if two or more parties desire to lease the same land, the officer having control of the auction shall lease to the person who will pay the greatest amount of cash bonus in addition to six (6) per cent on the appraised value as annual rental. Lease rentals are due in two installments. January 1 and July 1 of each year. If not paid within six months after due. the lease holders are de - clared delinquent and notice is sent them, if their postoffice addresses are known; if unknown, advertisement is made in a newspaper. Ninety days after date of such notice lease contracts are declared forfeited and are sub - ject to auction thereafter. (See Fees.) Delinquent lease holders are not permitted to bid at the sale of the lands they have forfeited, but at any time before the land is offered at public auction, they may reinstate their leases by paying all back rents and penalty fees. (See Fees.) All school lands under lease are subject to appraisement every five (5) years, if the Board of Educational Lands and Funds so elects. Any lessee of land situated within the area irrigated or to be irrigated from irrigation works constructed or controlled (or to be constructed or controlled by the United States or its duly authorized agencies) or any lessee of any 40-acre tract or government subdivision, any part of which is under irrigation, may purchase the same. (See Sales.) The holders of lease contracts executed prior to July 9, 1897, are given the right, at the expiration of said contracts, to make application for and receive new lease contracts upon said lands, and they will not be required to compete for the contracts, and the rate of rental will be the same as stipu - lated in the old contract; Provided. That all of the rental due on the old contracts has been paid. Leases dated prior to July 9. 1897, may also be converted into sale con - tracts, the lessee making application to the county clerk, before the expiration </seg>
            <seg id="p055">LEASING AND SALE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS 55 of his lease, the county commissioners appraising the land for sale purposes, and the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings reviewing such appraise - ment. The lessee thereupon pays one-tenth of the principal, and interest at five (5) per cent from date to the first of the following year. If lessee has already paid his rental for the same period, he is refunded this amount. He surrenders his lease contract and receives a sale contract running twenty years. (See Sales.) Leases dated on July 9, 1897, and after (at the expiration of twenty - five years from the first of January next following the date of lease) are not subject to renewal excepting upon the terms and conditions per - taining to new leases. Lessee may surrender the premises or re-lease them under ordinary competitive conditions, he being entitled only to the movable improvements on the land. The amount of school land authorized to be leased, direct or by renewal, to one person is limited to 640 acres. Sale Contracts A lease holder whose lease may be converted to a sale, desiring to pur - chase the lands described in his lease, should apply to the county clerk in which the land is located, to have same appraised by the county board for the purpose of sale. Such appraisement shall be subject to review and approval by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds, before the same shall become effective. Upon the sale of any lands on which full payment is not made, the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings will issue a sale contract run - ning for a term of twenty (20) years, showing the land purchased, the amount paid, the amount due, and the time when the interest and principal are due, and on the payment of such amount, according to law, the pur - chaser or his assignee shall be entitled to a deed to such land. The con - tract holder has the privilege of making payments on the principal at any time and in any amounts, which should be done just on or before January 1, thus reducing the interest of the ensuing year. The owner of a sale contract may, at any time, pay any portion of the purchase price thereof to the treasurer of the county in which the land is situated : Provided, all interest at that time earned and due, has first been paid ; and when the principal is paid in full, other than at the first of the year, interest upon the obligation having been paid for the entire year, the county treasurer receiving such principal payments may refund to the payor, out of any interest money then in his hands, the interest so paid in advance in excess of the amount earned and due at the time said final pay - ment is made. Refund receipts are furnished by the Land Commissioner for this purpose. All unpaid principal on sale contracts draws interest at five (5) per cent per annum, payable annually on January first of each year, in advance. Sale contract holders making final payment to county treasurer should also surrender their contracts, that same may be forwarded to Land Com - missioner with receipt showing fhe full payment. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Deeds are ordinarily issued once each month immediately following the meeting of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds, which authorizes such issuance. No educational lands shall be sold for less than seven dollars per acre, nor for less than the appraised value as approved by the Board of Educa - tional Lands and Funds. Notes The Board of Educational Lands and Funds meets on the second Tues - day of each month. No assignment of a school land lease or sale contract is valid until re - corded in the office of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, and will not be recorded if any interest or rental is due at the time said assign - ment is offered for record. The original sale or lease contract must be sent in with the assignments or the latter cannot be recorded. The contract will be returned with the recorded assignments. When a subdivision of not less than forty acres in any contract is assigned, a new number is given the assigned portion on the ledger ac - count, and a certified copy of the original should be given to the assignee. When assignments are made as above, the original contract must be re - duced and the interest or rentals, as the case may be, is adjusted to the new conditions. Whenever a lease or sale contract becomes lost or destroyed, a certified copy of the same may be procured by filing an affidavit of lost copy. Fee for recording affidavit, fifty cents, and for each certified copy of contract, seventy-five cents. Such copies may be used in lieu of the original for the purpose of passing title. When interest on a sale contract or rental on a lease contract is not paid when due, county treasurers will collect "penalty" interest at seven per cent for the time purchaser or lessee has been tardy in making such payments. Improvements on leased land, and the owner's equity in land under sale contract, are subject to taxation. County treasurers are requested to send in school land receipts at least once each week. Sometimes tardiness in this particular leads to consider - able unnecessary correspondence and occasionally to delinquencies being charged against contract holders who are not in arrears but whose receipts have not been sent in to the Land Commissioner's office. Lands escheating to the State under the alien act are appraised and leased in the same manner as educational lands. If lessee shall be in default of rentals for six months, or if purchaser shall be in default of interest for one year, county treasurers shall collect delinquent notice fee of fifty cents, as set forth in table of fees under head - ing of "For Notice of Forfeiture." </seg>
            <seg id="p057">LEASING AND SALE OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS 57 Fees For the issuance of a lease or sale contract, each 40 acres J0.50 For recording assignments, for each contract assigned .50 For recording affidavit of lost contract 80 For certified copy of a contract .75 For recording any instrument, each 100 words .10 For copies of maps or plats, each hour's work .40 For delinquent notice for each contract JO For notice of forfeiture of lease or sale contract Publisher's Fee For reinstatement '. 50 For recording order of forfeiture, where redemption is made before auction, for each tract of 40 acres or less 50 Where publication in newspaper is required in lieu of ordinary delinquent notice, the actual cost of such publication is charged where redemption is made. NOTE — Fees payable to the State should be remitted by draft or money order, payable to State Treasurer. Personal checks and stamps are not acceptable. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">IAPPRAISEM INT OF LEASED LANDS County Old Value New Value Increase Annual Inc. Antelope Adams Banner Butler Blaine Box Butte Brown •. Colfax Clay Cm S. 1-/2 Cherry Custer Douglas Dakota Dawes Dixon Frontier Furnas Gage Garfield Garden ........ $86,580.00 12,620.00 26,898.00 11,062.00 23,746.82 68,444.60 51,578.63 970.01 5,468.00 3,260.00 99,621.87 123,192.11 6,717.00 7,707.27 73,328.00 9,226.00 58,430.00 41,871.75 5,673.00 33,662.87 45,820.25 20,888.80 19,640.95 64,256.60 76,494.40 151,109.23 10,293.20 63,652.15 28,955.64 19,238.75 5,082.86 15,490.00 9,220.00 53,080.40 51,215.25 6,444.00 14,033.80 $217,460.00 42,280.00 43,760.00 24,338.00 62,332.80 75,696.00 89,645.83 4,297.50 10,900.00 10,983.30 238,392.46 315,965.64 17,354.00 14,952.12 107,275.81 40,302.00 261,736.00 204,246.60 9,087.00 82,732.10 200,930.50 58,980.00 61,622.25 102,208.50 123,035.48 264,300.68 23,621.75 92,360.27 84,665.98 59,352.00 28,067.93 34,780.00 16,680.00 78,395.80 73,301.00 13,645.00 51,142.55 $130,880.00 29,660.00 16,862.00 13,286.00 38,585.98 17,251.50 37,967.20 3,327.49 5,432.00 7,723.30 138,770.68 192,773.63 10,637.00 7,244.85 33,947.81 31,076.00 203,306.00 162,374.75 3,414.00 49,069.23 155,110.25 38,091.20 41,981.30 37,951.90 46,541.08 113,191.35 13,328.55 28,708.12 55,710.34 40,113.25 22,985.07 19,290.00 7,460.00 25,315.40 22,085.75 7,201.00 37,108.75 $7,852.80 1,779.60 1,011.72 797.16 2,315.16 1,035.09 2,278.03 199.65 325.92 463.40 8,326.23 11,666.41 638.22 484.89 2,036.87 1,864.66 12,198.36 9,742.49 204.84 2,944.15 9,306.62 2,285.47 2,518.88 2,277.11 2,792.46 6,791.48 799.71 1,722.49 3,342.62 2,406.80 1,379.10 1,157.40 447.60 1,618.92 1,325.15 432.06 2,226.53 Gosper Hall Hayes Hitchcock Holt Jefferson Keith Lou p Merrick NuckoUs Phelps Polk Red Willow Rock Thayer York Totals. $1,394,964.11 $3,240,726.64 $1,845,762.53 $110,745.75 iheridan and S&lt; otts Bluff count: ies are to be re- alued before iuai 1, 1919. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">IU &lt; J ;§i i ■ ■ - ; . . .OS 2 . i» © © . &gt;o © © .HN0O g • •&lt; - ao . © .5 . &gt;o n to So o CO ao . CO .-&lt; 00 © ■ ' © © © OS SN 00 OS . ■ f-4 I «!9O«on^vnw«He«MnxHNas9 NNOft^d'-«cJ'-c-'fF-fidteNai«x3it-'« NOxnuSNt-voxt-ooiNaoNnioHnx^a t-^as^^H co^oo^^o^aq^t-^ost-^^o^os ■^■^oo^e^co^t- co t- »o t-u^ co"^*o'©"'t-^'tcrce't*'&lt;e'o6" oo'»-^t-'t-'c&lt;ror^c&gt;J •»« coco-h nco I 0 CO «O : § 8 § S S ■» ■» d d &lt;f . © ■* U5 Tf . FH IO N P5 « ■ P4 V" t~ o o ■ -H © 00 ■ t^ © ©' . t- «o t- -^ in © ■* &lt;» :8 §§§§§§ : oo : ad M « x « n ' . © . t- OS © OS IO t- .00 « U3 O_ T t- ;K . ■«"•«■ os e&gt;f -J • O V 00 CO II- N cm -h n -h eo o a&gt; - - ~ ■«00-»1&lt;t»kOCM'-'000-^'OOOU5 O00O . «3 N O ifl N O » « « W oo_ — ' w &gt;HtO 5 I oooocoiooot-t-ooooo: ©t-ot-oxse© I O : : : :::::::::::: :? :::::: : :-g :::::::::::: :o ::;::: : Jj : j : I : : ; : : : igb : : g : : : ill|lli^lltl2|||lEl &amp; l! •OCCl-«.2oOOi-333SS$4&gt;.CJ=.C.2o:3 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT II ■* . m ■ c ! o o t- :SSS - o o . o . io . © O .00 OS . 00 00 .04 . t- 8 2 : : :§j : : 0 ' : o ' &gt;* o ■ ■ 1 : :• ii 1 • : : : o © o :3 S : in o — o ' .NMIO « . . 00_ •-•_ O&gt;_ . I ff)- i 3 to in o o t- f; « O&gt; ot-^~ooooo . « » &lt;■ co N ■-&lt; ec o e o o o o » O &lt; N — . to ; rt eJ I i eiio»H&gt;.«i&lt;q»ON»GCt;Hiesiio^(.»ie n^tOHwtp^^iHMiocDXtDnH^idAdxn'V N»9i0t-Ot-«NHi0il&gt;O«&gt;-«N9&gt;1icefu)H M X -H » M II » fl » IO » X - t-_ « « M IO « - Tf M X -J' m to t~ o &gt;o eJ e$ m &lt;o t-" « »h so &lt;e o" oo t-" V n" M«« Nhmnh §£= :gg?2§gg§2 :g§g§i :g?g^§g oi cq ioooi-i'vteoou: 6 i' o w id vudvoo SU3 xnxot-^nt- . ie a is . onxism -h_ eo_ «o_ n «_ eo_ &gt;o oj_ . io * o » » a » t-_ &lt;oe*f ■»t-^«oeJeJ nm" ao m ei ** ■ o" -&lt;" » o t." l § "3 w g S 5" oo w © oo &lt;©■»■** ■ o»ertt-ni-ia«-&lt;t-«noi tD IO 5 CO Htt CO • -OXt^MKC|IOeQSOMVOt-OS ■» — ~ oi ■»&lt;• o to ; 't-'«H«nx'«&gt;d&gt;cnNd&gt;a eoco no^d . . «o&gt; o^ao &lt;h»boooi 00 i-^CC CQ ION M H m &lt;; «S O O b; W Ol Ol »O t^ W3 X tJ" t- oo o co t&gt; ia ce ' g «— : - -e9Ooec&gt;oteoo&gt;oa09&gt;mn ■ - N « t- « o n ao o 4 a n n « 'aHN^co^ndiddnQH ! iMtO N_ ©_ SO t-_ O»_ N O^ 00 t-^ ob" t-^ «T eJ V c U3 TC &lt;&lt;-l«&lt;-l«iOOOQ** o» oo -^i «e « o ■* o oo m to n«Nn«ie»w J • oToTeo i-T &lt;o 8 : ■O^t-t-t-NXNOX ■i-Tt-'ci 1 » h « » V V • *H *^ 5 t 55 O 0 [ 1* |_| 1 1 J4 ] 1 1 1 1 } j j 1 1 1 j | J ijjiiiijjfjijljijljijji </seg>
            <seg id="p061">r and ; ■&lt; J 8 ; ! o «o : : . o « . . . OO ■* . . . . . t- ! is w4 Is Is &lt; M 8 : :8 I 1 ■ a&gt; - . t- . o X ■ o ■ ■ • 'eo ! © :S :°° if §2§ S — « N • O «P O 00 Cl ■ f^ t- IO i-« oq ~ -r ;aiooiot-'c&gt;t-'ooo»ot-' .HMSH»NtBN»«««l ifl M N !D O h A C4 M 93 ■ O • . tc . '. m '. © • i^ O^NOITMOOIOIIlON-lOBN^l-OIOnt 1 »t-t-&lt;|Ol&lt;qt;&lt;|N»»»*t- # eHG0»NXt(i» _ KNo'a'cixVeddH^en'onidx'xt-'tD'xV eg ««-.H«o»«[-^»^«t-o«nt-Hoooir't- •m aoxc)OCQiopiten^ | eoN^ | uxoxtfi04 l xioa P. ri us « eJ oo" «o od «o m m -* oo" co" r-* V t-* as" V «" as" «c C- 1 „ „ „ j; N -HN ■• N i-l * - | I 8SSSSSS :&amp;!SSSSS SSSSS d ho o6 6 to : a io to m m d I o x o cj — ■ t-_ N 1O « « X ■■*."?. ■* * *&gt;. °. ■* * °°. **. *i t-ToO* ■ tO rt N t»" t-" ■^'^H'QO^^t-^ ■ o&gt; e- o • t- p : oo «e o ; t-_ «c *\ oc" ■* t-T c .2 £ S c 1 &lt;c to x t^ io oi 3! uise4&gt;O(dt-^a6d aocoeococoooaocQ x&lt;0NAt*^xoM f-lf-H . C0*-&lt; 00 «-» ■ Ol US 00 ■ CC i— ' © ' b-' tJ 44 ; m t- n : co w •» — &lt; St- e^MO .-Hoousioooojoooot-oeo^-iw t-; CO i-&lt; «0 ■*• 'XAOO^OOa^lOq^VIQM^X^ X OO t- 94 CO CC AAOHNOCQAXtOCOAHCQOOSQ A tO R CO O H OkOOO-^C&amp;lQOOAejIOIOOt-lO t-_ O «5 ■* . N Ol rt « O 00 hSh*BH^«)« n »-? r-^ .-J of of «s" no t-" i-T eJ of •» I «94»M00»n00OlO0DMONOlOXI«O&lt;COO ~-ii3^-&lt;£iCox — -*r x t- x ~- csi^". icouso'. r?©t~os ySIO^t^OO^C^C^OO^OO^OO OO^t-^-^t^OO^i-^^-^C^W C^ i-^ b" « ih" m" n » t-" h » t-^ to «" t-" cm" ~ a&gt; of of ej &lt;o •» &gt;- : : : : 1 J8 | M U i M ! i M jj i i;L!i : ° !llif^il||Iiiiin I lit </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT ■&lt;^ ;gg : : a ; ■ • o :| : S "3 : • • • 10 • ■ ■ • e» ■ : : : :S : § : . . : : «• : 3 : ; ; ; • frf • :8 i 1 — ■ ] ■ o» ■ CO : od o o o . t- O 00 00 : :» ■ © O A O O O O O o o O .i-cN . w IO eCCCNOOMN . eo i 03 i I ■a So 1 II X -^ eJ : 3 S 8 8 2 8 8 8 g § § § 8 § § :|||S "SSSSSSSSSg . W l* t CO M O9»nttXU}H(]XN ; £2 w co" -h" r-i oo fc V eo w 3 2 s If "ssgssss^^s^eSsJaSeS^^ 1- - ? m — m52S ( " NOO( "' : 00 &lt;O «&gt; .-! «' ■« -I eo «&gt; OS t-'o £ " " 2 ""* we* to *+ m S2S"* eg5DOOi:&gt; 50&gt;0'WO ©C-OOO-HNON© «" «j io" 8 ||ilii||jll|888^SLs^| </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 BASING A.» ND SA k.LE OP r ed )UC CATIONAL LANDS ■ ■ © »-* ! © © . © N :::::: g M M M ! s £2 i Is n CO o o :s ; ■ t-H ■ I t- is 1 p « evi to us £ T5 tO CO © US M U H IO 00 (« « f-l © © Q eJ rt — CO © . to w . ■»(■ ■* . © o . to 1* 10 t- © © © © 06 00 to © to N -^« OJ N I I 5;a&gt;so-H-&lt;ao«&gt;©coN©cOT|i©t- loo , MHMM^^OciuSt^lfldlOtOQO CO 01 t0tD4U3X4O)t-«3HiOnijir&lt;(C U3 £ ©" io* «"•-&lt;■» o ©* i-T oo" eo" V t-* © a&gt; oo" r^ eo n « h h h h «h cc • 2 © © © © ■3 © C4 © © Q. "fl« OS -^ -^ 1 s g s s •g to ■«* aT t-* a, £ coo ■ © © eooo In -co© -©© ■©©©© 31 ' ! fc © © to :odc4too*cd .U3CO .Ud© OC4r^9)^f •t 1^!. .c&gt;m . * » *. H . o : : 1 £ "3 CQC0ttC09)NW&gt;Oi-i -CCCD^OO I 1 C'm N»»u5w-;Q0^iO00 ■ 00 ft O CO N ol) co 'dio^«Jt»'N'Hrt " h x f' w ad '•M S °* O3N»N»««Tf ; A tO « CO IO «J I 5 • is StcOTfOTyootoioteeotooo — m o^io^oo^-^c^a^ oo^ © oi oo^ © © t- •g eJ "" le w" « co" co* -&gt;" co* cm" co" to - S £ 5u3NcoosNodowweo •► N " OMIT. O 00 C4 &lt;C oe d id . N 00 M U5 . 4 n e v —•" ■* «" £ ::::::::::: :J :: g I : i ; : : i : :f : :g : : lilllslilllllll H </seg>
            <seg id="p064">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 64 LANDS, NOVEMBER 30, 1918 County Total Acres Acquired Total Acres Deeded Total Acres Under Sale Total Acres Under Lease Un- Contract classified Contract Adams Antelope (Univ.) Arthur 20,480 31,400 1,600 25,600 26,880 25,530.45 23,675.28 40,960 22,652.72 40,998.90 30,813.29 17,487.88 640 18,360 16,720 1,360 1,160 4,120 40 960 10,560 200 25,600 25,920 24,810.45 2,714.53 16.01 40,038 11,930.87 40,285.50 7,235.05 12.27 200 180 Banner Blaine Boone Box Butte 160 18,347.21 722 3,430.78 556.40 21,685.97 16,467.8? 640 960 560 2,597.53 200 7,291.07 157 1,880 640 Boyd Brown Buffalo Burt (Agr. CoU.)... Butler Cans Cedar (Univ.) (Agr. Col!.)... Chase Cherry Cheyenne Clay Coif ax Cuming (Agr. CoU.)... Custer Dakota (Univ.) (Agr. CoU.)... Da wes Dawson Deuel '.. D ixon (Univ.) (Agr. Coll.)... Dodge Douglas Dundy 21,687.10 19,733.98 26,964.36 1,920 25,405.47 33,280 245,169.21 43,840 21,240 14,459.69 19,044.70 960 21,081.90 19,473.98 25,395.36 1,520 23,597.26 1,585.48 2,301.23 853 20,460 14,028.59 18,164.70 960 80 160 890 80 1,000.30 280 6,952.98 360 316.67 840 20,354 291.54 525.20 100 679 320 807.91 31,414.52 235,915 42,667 320 420 114.43 40 92,017.98 7,163.19 320 640 49,280 36,105.15 16,800.70 15,931.20 640 16,378 5,542.77 320 603.92 812.43 36.08 1,440 7,771.60 1,275.94 626.95 55,285.98 818.05 510.83 47,027.57 7,683.55 25 14,692.50 43.12 744.40 66.31 12.23 20,625 789.14 14,493.54 640 2,240 18,481.88 9,160.23 33,257.01 2,187.77 18,391.02 8,898.62 762.50 40 90.86 75.07 240 62 124.54 32,254.51 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">.n\j a.\u i RELATIV FACT; TO STA E LANDS— Continued County Total Acres Acquired Total Acres Deeded Total Acres Under Sale Contract Total Acres Under Lease Contract Un- '■lassified Fillmore Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage Garfield Garden Gosper Grant Greeley Hall Hamilton Harlan Hayes Hitchcock ... Holt (Univ.) .... Hooker Howard Johnson Jefferson Kearney Keith Keya Paha Kimball Knox (Univ.) (Agr. Coll.) . Lancaster (Saline) . . . (Normal) . . Lincoln Logan Loup Madison 20,648.51 20,471.85 34,560 25,602.80 24,637.31 20,480 66,006.61 16,640 29,000 20,475.30 19,507.71 20,487.56 20,400.69 25,920 25,494.87 87,536.60 8,322.10 26,158.59 23,041.44 13,440 20,484.08 18,581.40 45,662.90 26,382.46 36,618.88 42.893.81 4,480 33,491.20 31,236.84 32,789.44 12,804.80 97,892.89 20,480 20,393.28 24,639.43 2,240 30,720 14,976.21 20,448.51 9,088.39 6,002 9,371.20 24,302.81 1,281.58 1,283.97 11,522 2,920 10,835.30 16,292.45 20,480 12,219.86 673.31 1,729.22 7,012.02 3,120 14,573 12,916.67 17,887.93 13,880 2,357.10 790.85 699.22 24,670.62 3,120 28,001.47 29,750.37 30,321.50 12,484.80 12,609.56 252.41 930.65 22,039.43 1,480 200 4,737.10 6,116.50 5,392 120 80 4,023.25 2,278 671.46 3,160 729.05 3,486.91 1,184.59 51 7,160 1,282.10 120 3,201.89 160 1,667 1,360 4,913.86 1,160 6,646.36 22,438 10,839.60 214.50 19,118.42 60,699.39 2,840 25,408.54 6,480 2,486.21 7.56 4,665.42 24,062.10 23,714.65 73,364.58 3,920 26,038.59 5,261.52 363.33 929.15 3,341.40 38,269.42 24,431.61 35,895.54 13,155.53 840 399 764.45 673.64 80 72,410.20 17,520 18,644.33 2,280 160 30,120 2,609.59 3.50 28.60 5.03 122.52 24.12 5,067.66 520 5,090.73 720 1,464.88 240 12,772.93 2,707.59 818.30 320 600 600 1,040 2.02 329.42 100.20 (Univ.) MePherson . Merrick 11,326.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT DS — Continued County Total Acres Acquired Total Acres Deeded Total Acres Under Sale Contract Total Acres Under Lease Contract Un- classified Morrill Nemaha Nuckolls (Univ.) Otoe Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce (Univ.) . . . . (Agr. Coll.) Platte Polk Red Willow Richardson Rock Saline Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff Seward Sheridan Sherman Sioux Stan ton Thayer Thomas Valley Washington . . Wayne (Agr. Coll.) Webster (Univ.) Wheeler York 62,677.58 11,942.34 21,049.10 4,916.68 21,992.44 20,034.85 31,523.75 20,228.60 20,480 3,197.67 10,114.56 23,655.48 16,787.68 25,485.30 10,400 40,232.40 20,480 8,988.27 26,390.99 25,467.65 20,560 94,472.07 20,477.20 80,972.22 15,360 20,472.35 25,600.00 20,453.62 13,849.86 15,360 15,648.98 20,480 3,330.21 11,493.49 19,929.10 3,741.16 21,242.44 19,674.85 65.13 16,028.60 13,320 2,798.31 9,274.56 22,206.38 15,585.68 7,409.50 9,470 800 20,360 8,584.39 25,910.99 4,460.22 20,280 1,772.87 9,651.93 160 13,360 18,356.35 10,960.11 40 760 1,023.42 490 280 160 2,560 1,680 399.36 320 360 280 5,469 360 4,600 48,344.20 381.25 360 152.10 260 80 31,298.62 1,640 5,480 520 1,089.10 922 12,600 570 34,832.40 120 6.80 43.06 27.60 119 440 9,466.87 200 845 4,474.75 1,280 1,640 1,698 284.88 40 11,534.56 80 91,854.20 6,350.52 79,532.22 360 418 25,590.70 2,930.88 1,260.30 6 9.30 13,592.09 12,090.26 15,000 15,638.64 16,953.87 14,769.29 523 19,166.61 3,930.65 402.40 360 3,080 1,713.38 2,160 440 96.90 10.34 6.13 17,803.48 20,480 20,480 440 1,320.81 17,797 873.39 Totals. . . 2,978,575.05 1,144,000.49 210,016.83 1,622,435.28 2,122.45 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">EDUCATIONAL LANDS SUMMARY 67 ! IB •ft «ft^ -r M X [ £ 5 ■j ■ a - i-i so OJ O © 00 t- CD *O X -- cc co V N C C N B "* X 31 CO "* t-""©*© ©"«* tON © O 00 H « 9 © 00* »" t- O o o w ■*_ ?: ©*" of ao" w~ 30_ » t- n w o ; «s ci « ■* oc g' C&gt; 6 oi * M ■* X © : t-H_ t-_ 00^ oo* tfi" os" w" «" ~ *r x r: — f- — — -t o » OS « OC g' ci © oi •+ M ■* X © *« x* o oT w" oa" r. * x r; - i ©^ &gt; •c r : I 3 M j IJIjI UD&lt;«Z ■ — - 2 i i 2 3 IS 3 S to *e&gt; o» © — ,- »-H 1-1 X V h X O OJ Z? — O CO N N oNHa © oq » » « © '* 4« -* «d co* t-* * ©* « to n o* o« ci « » &lt;• * w o °\t» e »- « » ifl* (O rH -; r ® ~ to_ Mi M Nil! iil Nil! li3NJi3:jj3j 1:3;: ', 1/3 •« : : •■« : : : * ""S : : ( c .r = ■ b .« 2 ■ c £ ■ c - s • IJ-Sjl Illi I ill IIijI o c bars o o c txs o o tcs o c m^; o UD&lt;i«ZJ3&lt;»ZU&lt;M U3&lt;wZ • S : 1 I ; ; V 1J • • ** S S : « - ; &amp; 1 -S 2 3 C ■ V i I i i £ 8 J £ S u S u &lt; &lt; D &lt; I jjiN 1:3:: fflil ■J3&lt;wZ •o 8 1 n fa rt o b u 3 C 5 I c 1 u ■— C &gt;. 1 1 C •o 6 (A I ■ ■ i 1 &gt;. ■o 1 I C VI </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT RECEIPTS OF THE DEPARTMENT FOR THE BIENNIUM Rentals on lease contracts $ 500,139.75 Interest on sale contracts 273,112.01 Bonus and added interest 13,558.24 Principal on sale contracts 602,048.98 Fees, December 1, 1916, to November 30, 1918 6,000.23 Total receipts for the biennium SI ,394,857.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">APPROPRIATIONS 69 i^oc OS t-' »1 ao v&gt; v&gt; ■&lt;* o ec to oo a&gt; i 3 : S .' ao to 1 I H 5§ 8SSSSi|S888 S 00 O^ 00 t*" »-^ Oi T] 00 1 S t^ « Ifi Aw O H • ■ ■ CO H«nd«Ki« : : : w w» t^ hoi io ac ih O M M « . . . W - : : : ft § h a o o o o § § § § § aT *a oS cS oS ;§§§§ ■ «" N O O 00 s s u iJl s « g 00 ' SJ : O &gt;O O «O — O 00 • t- GO 90 V A O « -!«»&lt; v ™ eoi » rt o t- ■* » ; -h" US' M ' O re o" ] 11 ih 5 « a 3 C « l M M ; sgj |J g : : : : : = |j 1 ill ; ■.tn5** hi ill! S"Bj9-b«8 &lt; 8 &lt; 8«e BfillliSSiA •8-B 8 1 1 I If 1I| i l </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING Robert Harvey, State Surveyor and Draughtsman Department Duties The Statutes of 1903 defined the duties of the State Surveyor and Draughtsman, to be, to take charge of, under the supervision of the Com - missioner of Public Lands and Buildings, the field notes, maps, charts, and records of the United States Surveys, conduct the correspondence relating to surveys, grievances or disputes growing out of conflicting surveys of lands or lots, and to prepare the advice, instructions and opinions, and issue same under the approval of the Commissioner. And to issue a circular of instructions to the County Surveyors of the State for their direction and guidance, in the restoration and establishment of lines and preservation of corners in conformity with the laws, rules and regulations governing the surveys of the United States and established rules of surveying, and perform such other duties as the Commissioner may require : And in case of any disputes among owners of land arising or by reason of any survey of boundaries of lands within this State, or, in case of dispute or dis - agreement between surveyors as to the survey of boundaries, when petitioned for, shall be referred to the State Surveyor, who is made the arbitrator to determine and settle such disputes by making the necessary examinations and surveys to settle said disputes, and whose decision shall be prima facie evidence of the correctness thereof. The law provides for an appeal to the courts from the decisions of the State Surveyor in making such surveys, by any person having an interest in the lands affected by the survey. The law provides for the appointment of competent and experienced deputies to make surveys assigned to them. Field notes and maps of surveys made by the State Surveyor or depu - ties are to be reported and, if approved by the Commissioner, they become a part of the records of surveys of his office and a certified copy sent to the County Surveyor of the county where the survey was had, for record in his office. The per diem and expenses of the survey is to be paid by the parties directly interested in the survey, and when made by the State Surveyot there shall be paid to the State Treasurer the sum of $6.00 for each day of actual service performed; but when made by a deputy he is entitled to $5.00 per day and necessary expenses to be paid by the parties interested in the dispute. Correspondence relating to surveys is constantly growing and during the biennium 1.015 letters have been written and information given in a large number of telegraph messages and telephone and personal calls from county and private surveyors and land owners. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 71 Permanent Records Complying with the law requiring the issuance of a circular of Instructions to County Surveyors, the first circular was issued in pamphlet form, November 21, 1903, and consisted of 50 pages, and was, with the excep - tion of a short table on the hourly change of the magnetic needle, borrowed from the Coast survey, wholly from my own experience of thirty-five years in active field practice in government surveys, county surveys, and expert work in retracements, searching for corners and a study of their character - istics, to thoroughly understand their many different conditions, so as to be able to intelligently pass on their identity. In 1914, a second edition of 68 pages was printed. The subject matter of these editions is not to be found in any text - books and is principally discussed under the subjects of designation of cor - ners, memorials placed in corners, methods practiced in establishing govern - ment corners, gradual obliteration of corners, value of government field notes in the retracement of original surveys, remarks on searching for govern - ment corners, retracement of lines, evidence of witness trees, trench and pits, fractional sections of the township, closing corners in parallels or boundary lines, subdivision of sections, subdivision of quarter sections, sub - division of section 6 and perpetuation of corners. The latter showing actual conditions of witness pits when uncovered, and has tables of Latitude of each of the Standard parallels, lengths of a degree of Longitude on each parallel and of each mile of Latitude from the Base line to the North boundary. These are distributed to the County Surveyors of the State, law - yers, judges, and land owners who may call for them. There have been calls from eight states for copies so that the supply is being rapidly depleted. The entire treatise was devoted to land surveying, but there are fre - quent inquiries for a circular on town-site surveying and retracements, which was not included for the lack of appropriations. Sand Hill Surveys In the sand hill region of the northwest part of the State which is being rapidly recognized as a valuable grazing region, settlers and land seekers have had great difficulty in finding the original land lines on account of the gradual obliteration of the surface indications of the corners. Many surveyors and "locaters" who usually were not surveyors, made extended surveys without finding corners and made new corners in imi - tation of the government corners, differing widely from the original lines, and in course of time became recognized by many as the original corners. These surveys were generally extended by the first settlers into the valleys to cut out the valuable hay flats, which caused so much dissatisfaction and suspicion among the later settlers, especially "Kinkaiders," that the govern - ment was induced to begin the system of resurveys. The first was made twenty-four years ago by a system of independent surveys, cutting out the claims of the actual settlers wherever they were claimed regardless of their </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT position which was a violation of the law governing the survey of the Pub - lic Lands, causing so much confusion and dissatisfaction that the govern - ment abandoned the method and had recourse to the law of proportional measurement, which has been the law for a hundred years. Under the law of proportional measurement all distances between known (government) corners are pro-rated according to the lengths stated in the government notes, so that there can be no favoritism or "cutting and trying," but is purely a question of measurement and calculation as to where the restored corners are to be established. The law presumes that the new corners occupy the identical place of the original corners, which presumption may of course be overcome by proof that it existed elsewhere. Since 1907 the government has operated, in Nebraska, several surveying parties each year and during 1917 and 1918, thirty-five townships have been re-surveyed, making a total of 218J4 townships resurveyed since 1907 under the law of proportional measurement. So far as this office is informed, these resurveys have given general satis - faction, although there are cases where the lines are at a considerable dis - tance from where the original lines were supposed to have been, as to cause some to feel that they have a just cause for complaint, but in general the benefits arising from having permanent lines established offset any loss sustained. The title to nearly all the land in Nebraska has passed into private hands, so it will not be long before these parties will be withdrawn and settlers' recourse will be to private surveys or applications to this department. During the biennum, there have been received from the General Land Office at Washington, D. C, the following records of resurveys, to-wit : Field Notes Resurveys — Exterior Township lines of Township 25 N., Range 39 W. Township 26 N., Range 39 W. Township 25 N., Range 40 W. Township 26 N., Range 40 W. Township 21 N., Range 41 W. Township 23 N.. Range 41 W. Township 24 N., Range 41 W. Township 21 N., Range 42 W. Township 22 N., Range 42 W. Township 23 N., Range 42 W. Township 24 N., Range 42 W. Township 21 N., Range 43 W. Township 22 N., Range 43 W. Township 23 N., Range 43 W. Township 24 N., Range 43 W. Township 21 N., Range 44 W. Township 22 N.. Range 44 W. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 73 Township 23 N., Range 44 W. Township 24 N., Range 44 W. Township 21 N., Range 45 W. Township 22 N., Range 45 W. Township 23 N., Range 45 W. Township 24 N., Range 45 W. Township 27 N., Range 45 W. Township 22 N., Range 46 W. Township 23 N., Range 46 W. Township 24 N., Range 46 W. 5th Guide Meridian through Township 24 N. 6th Standard Parallel through Ranges -36-37-38-39 W. 6th Standard Parallel through Ranges 40, 41, 42, 43, 44, 45 and 46 W. Resurvey — Subdivisions. Township 22 N., Range 46 W. Township 23 N., Range 46 W. Township 24^ N., Range 46 W. Tract 64, Section 1, Township 22 N., Range 47 W. Section 20 and Lots in NE '4, Township 22 N., Range 53 W. Surveyed by the Reclamation Service, accepted by the Gen- eral Land Office. MAPS Resurveys. Township 26 N., Range 39 W. Township 25 N., Range 40 W. Township 22 N, Range 46 W. Township 23 N., Range 46 W. Township 24 N., Range 46 W. Tract 64, Section 1, Township, 22 N., Range 47 W. Lot 4, Section 31, Township 23 N., Range 32 W. Section 20 and Lots in NE l 4. Township 22 N., Range 53 W., surveyed by the Reclamation service and accepted by the General Land Office. Lots in Township 22 N., Range 53 W. Indexing Government Surveys Supplemental Map of Section 30, Township 23 N., Range 54 W. It was expected that considerable progress would be made during the biennium in the continuation of the matter of arranging, abstracting and indexing the records of the Government surveys, but it has been prevented by the lack of sufficient clerical help and calls for information induced by the war activities. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT Internal Improvement Lands Soon after the declaration of war. April 6, 1917, a request was received from the railroad companies and the government for a statement of the num - ber of acres of land the state had donated to railroad companies to aid in the construction of railroads in Nebraska. The Enabling Act of Congress, 1804, authorized the citizens of the Territory to form a constitution and provided, among other donations to place it on equal footing with other states, a grant of 500,000 acres of land to aid in the works of Internal Improvement, to be selected by the governor from unoccupied government lands. The second session of the legislature passed an act. February 15, 1869, providing for the conveyance of 20,000 acres of these Internal Improvement lands for each ten miles of railroad constructed after that date. Lands were selected by the governor, or his agent, at various times, all being east of Range 25 West, and the lists certified by the officers of the respective United States Land Offices and sent to Washington for approval. Six lists of land were approved, to-wit : The procedure by the railroad companies to obtain title to these Improve - ment Lands, under the act of February 15, 1869, was to notify the governor of the completion of ten miles of road, who would then appoint a commis - sion to examine the same and upon favorable report, a deed would be issued, signed by the governor and secretary of state. It appears from the records of conveyances that great care was not exercised in making up the deeds, for some of them state that a specified number of acres are conveyed, but when the tracts are added up they do not agree. Again there are a number of deeds that appear to describe tracts compiled from the selected lists and executed before they were approved by the Secretary of the Interior, and it was no uncommon thing for the deeds to describe tracts that never were confirmed by the Secretary; there - fore, the State never owned the lands and could not pass title. The government conveys its lands according to the official plats of survey. Now it frequently happened that the deeds described certain tracts as containing a certain number of acres while the same tracts appear as containing a different number in the approved Clear Lists by the Secretary, and when compared with the official plat of survey it may be found that a different number of acres is stated from either, for instance, — Clear List No. 1, March 29, 1870 359,708.06 acre: Clear List No. 2, October 13, 1871 94,232.96 acre: Clear List No. 3, June 1, 1872 18,441.22 acre; Clear List No. 4, May 27, 1873 22,173.94 acre: Clear List No. 5, January 7, 1874 880.00 acre: Clear List No. 6, February 24, 1874 8,656.61 acre Total 504,092.79 acre: </seg>
            <seg id="p075">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 75 Section 12, Township 1 North, Range 15 West, is described in the State's deed as containing 583.90 acres; the same tract is described in the govern - ment's approved Clear List as containing 597.20 acres, while the official plat of survey gives the area as 597.40 acres. Section 18, Township 20 North, Range 2 West, is described as containing 640 acres; the same tract is described in the government's approved Clear List as containing 640 acres, while the official plat of survey gives the area as 632.20 acres. The amount actually conveyed is what is stated in the official plat. To arrive at a correct summary as to the total number of acres conveyed by the State, each description with its specified number of acres was copied from the State's deeds, twenty-four in number; in parallel columns were copied the specified number of acres in the government Clear Lists, and compared with the official plats of survey, and the necessary additions or subtractions made to show the exact number of acres conveyed. Typewritten copies were made in duplicate, and a certified copy furnished the C. B. &amp; Q. Ry. Co. of the lands acquired by it, and a tabulated statement of the total amount of Internal Improvement Lands certified by the approved Clear Lists to the State, the amount specified in the State's deeds, and the amount conveyed, according to the official plats of survey sent to the government. The office copy will be bound with suitable indexes for ready reference in the future when looking up the title of these lands, which the office is very often called upon to do. On account of the lack of clerical office force this department has had no assistance whatever in this work excepting the typewriting and proof reading. Colored Plats Prepared This department during the biennium and mostly during 1918, has, on eight-inch plats, colored each tract granted by the government to the State under each and every kind of grant, excepting common school, in the order in which they are specified in the approved Clear Lists. Each kind of grant has a suitably arranged index. In the plats of the Internal Improvement Lands, are recorded in different colored inks, the acreage specified in the State's deeds and in the government Clear Lists; this part of the work has not yet been quite completed. When the whole is finished and bound with proper indices, it will be a ready and convenient reference and a colored picture of every tract of special grant of lands to the State. This has been a laborious piece of work, but when completed will justify the labor as a means of saving time in poring over lists whenever a call is made for an examination of the records. Land and Water Areas by Counties In June, 1918, an agent of the Department of Agriculture, Washington, D. C, made a personal call to secure a statement of the number of acres of land in Nebraska, which has never been compiled, although some authorities quote and publish the area of counties and of the state in square miles. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT This department, recognizing the need of a more accurate statement or compilation, had, several months previous, begun compiling the number of acres of the land and water area of each township by counties from the records of the government surveys. The land areas are taken from the statement of acres as recorded in each plat of survey, and in many cases the water areas have also been recorded, otherwise they have to be calculated. The water areas are only those of the meandered lakes and streams. Streams less than twelve rods right angled width, and ponds and lakes which were not meandered, are not considered in the calculations. This work has required the handling of over 2,000 maps of survey two or three times, and the work of compiling the data has not been quite com - pleted in time for inclusion in this report. Rebinding Field Notes and Reports The constant deterioration of the leather bindings of the old volumes of field notes requires that they be replaced with new bindings, which so far have been of uniformly colored khaki or binder's cloth, and during the coming biennium a large number should be bound. The large amount of field notes of resurveys on hand in manuscript and the large amount which no doubt will be received from the General Land Office in 1919, should be bound so as to make them more accessible for reference. Field Work Applications for examinations and surveys to settle disputes are by law made to the Commissioner and referred to this department. On account of the increasing demands on the time of the State Surveyor, very much of the field work must be executed by the regularly appointed deputies, under direct instructions and official supervision of the State Surveyor. It has thus far been the policy of the several commissioners to have a few deputies who could devote all, or nearly all, of their time to the field work and be in closer touch with the methods and requirements of the office, than with many who could only give a small portion of their time and then only at long intervals and could not, therefore, harmonize their working methods and of compiling their notes and maps with the office require - ments. It has been the aim of this department to engage deputies of expe - rience in land surveying, who are capable of handling the complicated cases that are usually appealed to this office for solution. The demand is for surveyors who also are expert in the retracement of lines and searching for lost or obliterated corners. During the last two years the "Good Roads Commissions" and war activities have called to their service many of the surveyors and engineers, so that we have been unable to secure sufficient force to do much more than dispose of 1917 applications. We have endeavored to take up each applica - tion in the order of filing, but at times have had to break the rule, especially </seg>
            <seg id="p077">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 77 in cases of litigation when it would be a hardship to have the cases continued. We have been confronted with another serious difficulty, and that is the wages allowed a deputy, which is $5.00 per day, according to the state- ment. Our deputies are mostly County Surveyors who can, under the law, command from $6.00 to $8.00 per day in their own counties, and when en- gaged on private work outside of their counties can command $10.00 per day. Under present conditions of high prices of living and of labor when day laborers receive $4.00 and $4.50 per day (as we have been advised) it is humiliating to the deputy to put his expert knowledge, gained by hard study in the field of experience, and use of valuable instruments with attendant risks, on the same level of the wages of the day laborer, and in contrast with the greater fees reaped by the professional man who depends on his knowledge and the evidence he gathers to win his case in court. There have been filed during the biennium, twenty-one applications for surveys. Twenty surveys have been executed and one continued. Tabulation of Surveys Below are tabulated the number of the surveys, name of applicants and location of surveys made during the biennium : No. of Location Survey Name of Applicant of Survey 200 Keith County, by county clerk Keith County 201 Walter A. Muhr Morrill County 202 Fritz Hockmeier Stanton County 203 L. R. Nelson Deuel County 204 Vine F. Palacz and Fred Lehn, not completed Howard County 80S C. J. Oldaker Kimball County 206 Fred Albers and Eleven Others Valley County 207 E. F. Halloway Greeley County 208 Eric Bunteen and Eleven Others Cherry County 209 Perkins County, county commissioners Perkins County 210 W. O. Dungan Kearney County 211 Mrs. Mary Sullivan 4 Franklin County 212 John F. Piefer Scotts Bluff County 213 Herman Luedke, et al Stanton County 214 W. T. Draper and E. C. Kilpatrick Sherman County 215 State of Nebraska, by Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings Box Butte County 216 Charles Murphy and Thomas Akeson Cass County 217 Lakeside Ranch Company Sheridan County 218 Geist &amp; Son Buffalo County 219 Marcus Sievers and Others Keith County 280 T. C. Halley Scotts Bluff County </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT SOME SURVEYS No. 200 was a resurvey of Township 14 V, Range 40 W., applied for by the commissioners of Keith county. The original survey of the Town - ship lines was established by W. J. Allason and Nicholas J. Paul in 1869, and were found intact, but no corners whatever of Charles Winpf's survey of the section lines in 1872 were found. Deputy B. W. Benson made the resurvey in 1917. The survey of the section lines of Township 14 N., Range 38 W., by Charles Winpf in 1872 had long been a subject of dispute and litigation, therefore, in 1917 an application signed by the land owners in the south half of the township was filed, praying for an investigation of the identity of a number of alleged original corners, and if found to be spurious, then to make a resurvey. Upon examination, it was found that the sides of the witness pits of the alleged corners were practically seven inches, instead of about twenty, a condition almost identical with that which I found in Town - ship 14 V. Range 35 W., in 1906, suggesting that both were the work of the same locator. A resurvey of a part of the township was made by Deputy Benson, as applied for. No. 208 was the retracement of the north boundary and resurvey of the south and east boundaries, and subdivisional lines of Township 28 N., Range 38 W. This township has been the subject of dissension for many years and of correspondence with this department for more than ten years. The application for a resurvey had been denied by the government, therefore, the appeal to this office. A number of original corners were claimed to be known which, upon examination, proved to be true, but their position in the township was such as to cause complicated conditions, entailing a great amount of investigation and search for original corners. The resurvey was executed by Deputy E. C. Simmons, and was completed in the spring of 1918. The original survey was made by G. E. Kentner in 1882. No. 219 was for retracement and resurvey of a number of school sections in Townships 25 and 26, N., Ranges 44 and 45 W., to determine the proportion of the potash lakes on State lands. There are twenty-three applications for surveys to be carried over to the next surveying season. Fee* The only income of the department is derived from fees for filing of applications for surveys, examination of the field notes and plats of surveys made by the deputies, per diem of the State Surveyor for field work, and copying of field notes and plats of surveys. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">DEPARTMENT OF SURVEYING 79 There have been received the following fees, which have been paid into the State Treasury, to-wit: Oregon Trail By legislative enactment, the State Surveyor, Secretary of the State His - torical Society and State Regent of the Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution were appointed a commission to mark the Oregon Trail through the State of Nebraska. The death of the Secretary of the Historical Society and war activities have delayed the completion of the setting of the monuments under the appropriation of $3,000. There are five more to be set up. When this is done, drafts of the locations will be prepared for the report of the work. iling applications for surveys I 41.01 Examination of the notes and plats of surveys 58.01 'er diem of State Surveyor for field work 114.0) opying field notes and plats 349.2: </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>