<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Co-Operative Law A Law Providing for the Organization and Incorportation of Co-Operative Companies and Associations</title>
               <date value="1921">1921</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE BUREAU OF MARKETS AND MARKETING LINCOLN BULLETIN NO. 112 CO-OPERATIVE LAW A LAW PROVIDING FOR THE ORGANIZA TION AND INCORPORATION OF CO-OPERATIVE COMPANIES AND ASSOCIATIONS Secretary of Agriculture EFFECTIVE APRIL 23, 1921 LEO STUHR WC ANDREAS. Chief of Bureau </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Anv iiinnl i I i 2 Section 1. Co-operative companies or anv panics, liol lew than live, may torn tra Mee. X. Articles of incorporation company shall provide in it* articles o\ First, that tin corporate name, live corporation Second, till directly, more I company : Provi in anot her such than twenty pel Fourth, that Ike net profits of I expenses, and iapiial stoek dividend part tltfc*. shall b« distriliutftl as a |&gt;; patrons or i-ustoiners, or employees i both or all, wliti may be either st.»i or both as shall be speeitied ill the proportion to the value or volume u service rendered 1o the company &lt;l such appoitioiiiiient is made: I'rov id&lt; be fonstrue&lt;l to prevent the setting as a surplus fuiul for the benefit of the &lt; Sec. :!. Powers. — Every ornnfae under this a&lt;t shall sons, not less 1 lian foil loiporatiim for 1 1 1 « adoption of arti&lt; with like power* and tint -\i-c|)t as herein provided Third, thai &gt;liviil&lt; shall mil e\rectl ten l" [&gt;aid t Ihicoii. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">1 corporate name; plain iiml defend in courts ml alter 1 lie same ml all siicli real estate as e business of 1 lie iMimj)any; tin 1 right of stockholders to ritilit of stockholders to nt tilt H&gt;rdinate officers and agenta as the naif officers and agents as the require, Mid t&lt;» allow the* I lie MMMflCMmi and re^ula- Khali require, and to allow then ipai d, sell, assign or transfer the shares , nssitcn mt transfer the shares operative companies which it operative companies which it f such stock, to exercise all the ich stock, to exercise all the ownership, including the right \\ uei-ship, ilteladiliK the right h iiidi\ id ndividiuU stockholder may he al stockholder may he irdless of the number of shares •cjiardless of the number of shares y stockholders meeting. holders meeting aiiv stoc Fees. — I he fees for t lit- incorporation of co-operative e incorporation of co-operative bum required by law of other hpsc required l&gt;y law of other pcrativc corporations shall he re tive corporations shall he re - and tilings as is ic(|iiircd of ml tilings as is re&lt;|iiired of Corporation. — No corporal ion, company, linn or as- poralion, company, linn or ns- poiated as ■ co-o|)ei-;itivp cor- c the ward* '"co-operative" or any a par! of ils name. Any person or MM- e provisions of tliis section shall be deemed ■nor and for each day's continuance of the 1 one hundred dollars </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Sec. li. Number of members.— When-vei 4 members of a co-operative company composed stockholders shall he less than 1 went y-li\ e, said terminate and tlie same shall be dissolved without the part of the state Sec i. Repeal.— Thai Article XV, t vised Statutes of Nebraska for 1913 as ai II ded 1)\ t !•!!• and also Chap See. H. Emergency. — \Y shall he in full approval. Session Laws of Win sion Laws of Nebruki pealed. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>