<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Sales Value and Assessed Value of Nebraska Farm Land:  1921-1934</title>
               <date value="1935-07">1935-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 77 Sales Value and Assessed Value of Nebraska Farm Land: 1921-1934 ELEANOR H. I UNMAN Department of Rur.il Economici *"°r- — i 1 — — i — i — i — — — i — p . ' ■ : SAL£S PRKC 5 ""^ J "~~-^^^^ ASSESSED VALUE *'°° CROUP B COUNTIES^ $»o- ■*" ♦«•' ~ VS:-«i. $4 o — j _ : . ; $40 ♦** ' " ' ■ 3 -^ - $20 CROUP A COUNTIES ■*£ '':I.■ ! I I ' I '»» &gt;«&gt; ■»• iis^ issi imt l»a rSS» i»3o 53 ivi — 333 — aU Sales price and assessed value per acre of Nebraska farm land sold during thirteen years,. Each division line represents twelve months ending March 31 of the year specified. Group A counties constitute roughly thc northwestern half and Group B thc southeastern half of thc state (sec page 5). LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JULY, 1935 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Introduction 3 Sources of the data 3 Limitations of the data -1 Counties omitted 5 Survey by Districts ' 5 Geographic districts 5 Sales reported 6 Size of tracts sold 7 Acres reported as sold 8 Distribution of acreage sold 8 Reported turnover rate 9 Sales price per acre 10 Percentage decrease m land price, by counties 12 Assessed value per acre 12 Ratio of assessed value to sales value of farm land l.i Assessment ratios, by counties I.j Land Sales, Classified According to the Rain of the Assessed Value to the Sales Price H Distribution of sales, by ratio groups j.j District variations m distribution of sales. . \y Sales price per acre, by ratio groups 18 District variations m price per acre, t y ratio groups &#132; . . . 19 Land Sales and Assessment Ratios, by Salts Value of Tracts 19 Distribution of sales, by value of trac 5 19 District variations m distribution of silcs by value. . . 20 Assessment ratios m various salcs-val ie groups 20 ; District variations m assessment ratios m the respective sales-value classes 22 Conclusions 22 Suggested Remedies 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Sales Value and Assessed Value of Nebraska Farm Land: 1921-1934 1 ELEANOR II. HINMAN How to secure just and equitable estimates of the value of farm land as a basis for taxation has always been a vexatious problem. Since general property taxes are based on assessed valuations, considerable variations in such valuations have the same effect on the individual taxpayer as raising or lowering the rate of taxation. By such variations, an assessor may m effect arbitrarily raise or lower the rate of taxation in a precinct. What is even worse, he may and frequently does, quite unintentionally, in effect lower the rate of taxation for one farmer and raise it for his neighbor. State tax commissions and state and county boards of equalization have not been entirely successful in their attempts to overcome this evil. The existing assessment law in Nebraska went into effect April 1, 1921. The present study attempts to show how the assessed valuation? of farm real estate made under that law compare with the actual sales value of the farms sold during the 13 years ending March 31, 1934. Comparable data preceding April 1, 1921, were not obtained. The administration of the law under the former state constitution was sufficiently different so that it was not thought advisable in this study to compare data obtained under it with data obtained under the present constitution, which- went into effect on the day mentioned. For a discussion of the general property tax and its present administration in Nebraska the reader is referred to Chapters V, XT, and XII of the University of Nebraska Tax Primer. 2 Sources of the data. — The data used in this study include records of 35,753 tracts of farm land in 93 Nebraska counties sold during the 13 years ending March 31, 1934. The sales data were compiled from the county deed records. The assessed valuation of each tract reported as sold, at the assessment period preceding its sale, was obtained from the records of the county treasurer. This compilation was made in different years by two agencies having slightly different objectives and methods. Data for the eight years ending March 31, 1929, were obtained by the railroads of Ne - braska, and were placed on file with the state tax commissioner and the state secretary of agriculture to support the contention that railroad prop - erty was assessed at a higher rate than farm property. The compilation was made by employees of the railroads, who traveled from one county seat to another. During the depression the railroads ceased to keep such complete records of farm-land sales and ceased to place such records on file at the state capitol. However, beginning with April 1, 1929, the state 1 This study was product:' under ;t cooperative agreement with the Division of Land Fconcmic. of the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Acknowledgments arc due to the slate tax commissioner, the state secretary of agriculture, and the railroads of Nebraska for the loan of the records user); and to I. O. Rankin for initiating the study and supervising the tabulation of parr of the data. 3 The University of Nebraska Tax Primer (G. O. Virtue. Gen. Ed.), published by the Nehr. Agr. l'.xp. Sta., 1933: Chap. V (Tax Circular 5) by Ralph II. Cole. The General Property Tax; Chap. X! (Tax Circular II) by R. J. W. Ely, The Relative Tax Burden; Chap. XII (Tax Circular 12) hv F-. Glenn Callcn, Tax Administration in Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Nebraska Acr. Exp. S"a. Research Bulletin 77 tax commissioner required all coun:y assessors to send him records of all "bona fide sales" of farm land occ jrring during the preceding year, and of the assessed valuation of such ltind. The data presented here for the five years ending March 31, 1934, were obtained from these compilations. Limitations of the data. — Since all data presented in this study were gathered annually and represent transactions which were on file on April 1 and occurred during the 12 monhs preceding that date, it follows that the compilation omits altogether sales occurring previous to April 1 of any given year but not placed on file until after that date. As February and March are normally the months when Nebraska farm land changes hands most rapidly, such omissions sometimes include a considerable pro - portion of the sales during any gi /en year. The omitted deeds perhaps include a larger proportion of sales to non-resident purchasers and to purchasers residing at the edge of the county than the deeds filed more promptly, but there is no reason to lielieve that this distinction significantly affects the value of the data for thb purpose of this study. Data for the eight years ending March 31, 1929, are further limited to sales of tracts of 50 acres or more in size; and data far the five years ending March 31, 1934, are limited to sales of tracts of 40 acres or more. Since a record of all land transfers in 11 Nebraska counties had been assembled by the Rural Economics Department in connection with an - other study,' 1 the figures gathered by the railroads in the same counties were checked against this other compilation. Aside from the omission of late filings noted above, the principal difference between the two com - pilations resulted from a lack of clarity in some of the deeds themselves, for sometimes it was impossible to determine whether the value of the mortgages resting on the property was included in the consideration named, or whether it was in addition thereto. The clerks employed by the rail - roads were instructed to omit such doubtful cases. In obeying these in - structions they omitted most sales at prices far below the average land price in a given county. By locating; such tracts on a soil map it was found that many of them were inferior! land and in such cases the omitted transactions were probably true sales. In dealing with these doubtful cases the state tax commissioner relied upon the special knowledge of the county clerks and county recorders. Since the degree of such special knowledge unquestionably varied from county to county, the dependability of the data probably varies somewhat also. Another possible source of discrepancies is the circumstance that each county clerk or county recorder was allowed to form his own defini - tion of a "bona fide sale". In tabu ating the data from the state tax com - missioner's office only sales by war anty deed of tracts of 40 acres or more were tabulated, nnd the obviously doubtful cases were omitted. Sales to banks, life insurance companies, a id other credit corporations were uni - formly omitted as being certainly forced sales. * E. Hi Hinrnan, Hiitory of Farm Laml I rkc» in Eleven Nebraska Cuunlin, 1873-1933, Ncbr. Agr. Exp. Sla. Ro. Bui. 72, 1934. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Sales and Assessed Value of Farm Land Briefly; the data used in the present study cannot be any more adequate than the county record? from which they were obtained. These records admittedly have defects. They are, however, the only body of data readily available during intercensal years for an extensive study of land values and assessed valuations and have been widely used for this purpose It is believed that the data presented are sufficiently reliable to delineate correctly the important tendencies of the period studied. Counties omitted.— Data were obtained from all Nebraska counties for the twelvemonth ending March 31 of 1922, 1925, and 1927 In other years there were from one to 20 omissions. In 1931-34 there doubtless were some counties having no land transfers which the county clerk or recorder could classify as "bona fide sales". In earlier years the omis - sions represent merely a failure to cover that county. 4 NORTHWEST \ I i i ~^^~- \ I I'^-i—lXK SOUThWEST^X i Z^\ 1' (trK Fig. 1. — Location of the eight districts included in this study. SURVEY BY DISTRICTS Geographic districts.— For convenience in presenting data, the 93 Ne - braska counties have been combined into eight geographic districts as shown in Figure 1. Three of these districts— the Northwest, Southwest, and North— together compose the Group A counties, which include mainly the western grazing and dry-farming areas. The five remaining districts comprise the Group B counties. According to the 1930 census, farm land ™f , per acre were Iower in each of th e Group A counties except Scotts Bluft than in any of the Group B counties except Custer/' Extensive irri- g atlon ln Scotts B1 "ff accounts for the fact that the land values in that J Fificcnth Census of th: U. S., 1930, Vol. II, Pt. 1, pp. 1218-22. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 77 county were conspicuously higher than in other Group A counties. The three eastern districts — Northeast, East, and Southeast — together include all the counties having the highe it land values and some counties of mod - erate values. The Central and South districts were intermediate hetween the three eastern districts and th&lt; Group A counties in respect to average land values per acre. Table I.— Percentage distribution of Nebraska farms, land in farms, and land area according to the regional groupings used in this study} Counties Farms Land in Land in 1930 farms area P- ct. P. ct. P. cf. AH 100.0 100.0 100.0 Group A 22A 52.9 55.1 Northwest 7.7 17.6 18.4 Southwest 7.4 12.3 12 3 North -.3 23.0 24.4 Group B ; , 77.6 47.1 44.9 Central 1 1 .9 9.9 95 South 8.3 6.2 5^9 Northeast 17.3 10.-J 9.9 East ' 23.0 1 1.4 10.8 Southeast 17.1 9.2 8.7 1 Fifteenth Census of the U. S., 1930, Vt 1. II, Pt. 1, pp. 1204-17. The Group A counties together comprise 55 per cent of the land area of the state and 53 per cent of the land in farms, but contained only 22 per cent of the farms in 1930, as ndicated in Table 1. The most extensive farms were in the North or sand-hill district, which includes 24 per cent of the land area and 25 per cenfJ of the land in farms, but included only 7 per cent of the farms. The feel that the three Group A districts con - tained more acres but fewer farrns than the' five Group B districts should be remembered in interpreting tic sales data. Sales reported. — Table 2 shows the distribution by districts and years of the farm tracts for which salts data and assessed valuations were ob - tained. This table does not include all salesl occurring in the state for the reasons stated in the introduction. However, the trend of the sales re - ported probably reflects with tolerable accuracy the trend of all sales oc - curring in the state. The number of sales reported increased from 2,573 during the year ending March 31, 1922, to 3,725 during that ending March 31, 1927, and decreased to 1,358 during that ending March 31, 1934. The decrease in the numbbr of sales was much more severe in the Group A (mainly dry-land) cour ties than in the Group B (mainly corn - belt) counties. The Group A counties, with only 22 per cent of the farms of the state in 1930, had 36 per cent of the 1 sales reported during the 13 years ending March 31, 1934. This indicates a considerably more rapid rate of turnover than in the Group B counties. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Sales and Assessed Value of Farm Land Table 2.— Number of sales of farm land reported during the specified periods — Nebraska counties, by groups and districts. 1 .§ G T Group A districts Group B districts §J is is S = §• = g =3 N.W. | S.W. N. C. S. I N.E. [ E. S.E. - &lt; '' "*= " &lt; " I I | j | THIRTEEN YEARS ENDING MARCH 31, 1934 1921-34 35,753 12,959 22,794 4,543 4,154 4.262 4.053 2,890 4,195 6,660 4,996 BV YEARS ENDING MARCH 31 1922 2,573 1.040 1,533 354 284 402 215 205 369 394 349 1923 3,125 1.031 2,094 304 349 378 419 265 409 600 401 1924 2,950 980 1,970 311 324 345 382 196 419 587 386 1925 2,763 788 1,975 242 326 220 347 256 304 556 512 1926 3.530 1,119 2.411 245 544 330 420 402 378 689 522 1927 3,725 1,413 2,312 607 401 405 359 246 499 694 514 1928 3,576 1.443 2.133 600 369 474 436 220 362 714 401 1929 3,510 1,429 2,081 617 466 346 389 231 376 685 400 1930 3,019 1.110 1.909 480 221 409 381 270 259 588 411 1931 2.530 1,096 1,434 285 393 418 254 121 321 368 370 1932 1,864 635 1,229 236 191 208 197 161 214 370 287 1933 1,230 454 776 136 142 176 116 170 118 169 203 1934 1,358 421 937 126 144 151 138 146 167 246 240 1 Includes all sales of farm land which were regarded by county records as "bona fide" sales, and which were filed prior to March 31 of the specified years. Sales occurring prior to March 31, but not filed until after that date, were not reported. Size of tracts sold. — The average size of the tracts reported as sold during the 13 years ending March 31, 1934, varied from 512 acres in the North (sand-hill) district to 116 acres in the East district. The average for the Group A counties was 371 acres per tract and for the Group B counties 139 acres. The size of the tract sold is not stressed in this study because unpublished tabulations indicate that within the same district there is very little relation between the size of the tracts sold and the ratio of assessed value to sales value. s2Sd"| '■ I l i I I i I i 1 &gt; |s*no ACRES «OCJ »00- CROUP A COUNTICSE?-.^ / ~ -"-x — v~r — v 300-^ .^^ \ ,00 f t CROUP B COUNTICS — \ 200 -^.^ -\ 200 TOO - &gt;-* - 00 &lt; ; i i I i | ■ IM2 Si3 i»2« i»» SSI S2T IMS it2* IU0 M3I «32 ItU «34 Fic. 2. — Number of acres sold during thirteen years in two groups of Nebraska counties. Years are from April 1 of the previous calendar year to March 31 of the specified year. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Agr. Exp. !&gt;ta. Research Bulletin 77 Acres reported as sold. — Althoi gh they include only slightly more than half of the land in farms, the Grc up A counties reported a conspicuously larger number of acres of farm land sold than the Group B counties in every year except those ending March 31, 1925, and 1934, as shown in Figure 2. The decrease in the prire of farm products commencing in the summer of 1920 produced a situation which by 1924-25 impelled many mortgage-holders to refuse to renew mortgages on western-Nebraska farms. This credit deflation produced ma w foreclosures there in 1924-25 and also reduced the number of voluntary land purchases. Credit in the eastern «*\ i | | : -, p froo - DISTRICTS feV^-wv.:-.*:'.*..':.':"::.:.:.:.-.-.-.-.-..-.-: 1922 1924 1920 1928 1930 1432 iq"3/i Fic. 3. — Percentage distribution, by districts, of the acreage of farm land reported as sold during thirteen years. Years ; re from April 1 of the previous calendar year to March 31 of the specified year part of the state was less contracted during those years, and land sales less affected than in the western part. Fifty-three per cent of the bank failures in Nebraska in 1923-25 occurred in the Group A counties as compared with 37 per cent in 1920-22 and 12 per cent in 1926-27.° From 1926 to 1931, the acreage sold was large, especially in the Northwest (panhandle) and North (sand-hill) districts. The price of feeder steers was high and there was a demand for grazinj; land. The extension of the cultivated acreage in the panhandle counties was another important factor. Distribution of acreage sold.- -Figure 3 shows the percentage distri - bution, by geographic districts, &gt;f the acreage reported as sold during each of the 13 years studied. Sine: land prices and ratios of assessed valua - tion to sales value differ considerably from one district to another, the varying proportions of land sold in the respective districts affect the aver - age figures for the state and sometimes render them a poor indication of the changes occurring in the res] active districts. "Report of the Nebraska State Banking C immission. 1927. (Computed.) </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Sales and Assessed Valce of Farm Land Table 3. — Number of acres sold during the specified periods for every 1,000 acres extant in farms. 1 ■= a g. o. Group A districts Group B dittricti _ §.5 = S cS ; .5 8 = os 5s I I i j i j £ &lt; I 5 s 5 s NWi ) s - w - I N&lt; c - ! s - ' N - E - ■ F - : s-e- THIRTEEN YEARS ENDING MARCH 31, 193-1 192134 176 203 147 190 221 212 163 162 123 148 146 BY YEARS ENDING MARCH 31 J922 14 17 11 16 15 20 10 13 13 10 11 1923 17 19 15 15 25 20 20 16 12 15 12 I«4 15 16 14 13 17 19 18 1 4 4 2 «5 13 12 13 13 16 11 )5 15 0 3 16 926 8 21 17 15 24 21 If, 24 14 16 5 92' 18 21 15 27 22 17 14 14 15 15 5 1928 19 23 15 26 22 21 17 14 14 l" p J9M 19 22 15 24 21 21 16 „ J r „ «° 20 25 15 24 22 27 14 16 14 5 5 931 16 22 11 17 19 25 12 11 10 9 2 ?•« 12 15 9 14 II 17 9 11 6 11 8 W3 7 9 5 10 .8 8 5 9 3 6 0 19j -t / 7 7 5 7 9 6 9 4 7 9 ' U. S. census figures for the number of acres in farms were u f cd for 1925 and 1930; interpolations ,n', C n "J 1 C , C^ S Rgur " for l 9 22-24 and 1926-29. In the absence of figures in&lt;licntin B trend since 1930, the 1930 number of acres in farms was used for 1931-34. Reported turnover rate. — In the Group A counties during the 13 years ending March 31, 1934, 203 acres of farm land were reported as sold for every 1,000 acres of land in farms in 1930. In the Group B counties dur - ing the same period 147 acres were reported as sold for every 1,000 acres in farms. The reported turnover rate by individual years ranged from 7 to 25 acres in the Group A counties and from 7 to 17 acres in the Group B counties. The actual turnover was undoubtedly somewhat higher than the reported turnover shown in Table 3, but the table indicates exactly the proportion of all farm land in the respecti%e districts which is in - cluded in the sample studied. Fig. -1. — Number of acres sold during thirteen years endin K March 31, 193-1 for every 1,000 acres in farms, by counties. Sales were unrcportcd in three or more years from the counties that are left blank. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 77 Figure 4 indicates the reported turnover for all counties reporting in 11 or more years out of the 13. The counties with the highest reported turnover rates were all in Group A. They were, in order of precedence, Kimball, Thomas, Scotts Bluff, Cherry, Red Willow, Loup, Morrill, and Deuel. The counties with the lowest reported turnover rate were Boone, Dawes, Douglas, and Burt — all but one of them Class B counties. Table 4. — Price per acre of farm land sold during the specified periods, and percentage decrease between 1921-22 and 1933-34. M ■ '- e c Grouj -V districts Group B districts II £.3 |.5 , 1-6*-OSOb l| j | I %E %l %\ N.W. j S .W. j N. C. I S. j N.E. j E. jS.K. BY YEARS ENDING MARCH 31 1922 S61 S27 SI 16 332 S34 S22 S62 S77 $128 SI59 S134 1923 56 20 105 25 • 23 lfi 58 71 128 144 129 1924 58 21 104 29 26 14 56 67 123 149 116 1925 61 20 102 20 30 14 58 66 123 144 113 1926 56 20 100 24 33 10 61 67 106 141 119 1927 55 21 108 23 28 13 61 68 119 146 US 1928 50 20 102 22 33 II 60 61 113 142 117 1929 50 20 100 24 32 10 56 61 113 143 111) 1930 44 15 95 21 27 8 54 62 107 131 117 1931 38 15 86 22 28 7 49 64 89 121 99 1932 36 12 79 14 21 8 43 54 89 107 93 1933 29 10 62 11 17 7 38 40 72 91 74 1934 31 10 53 12 19 5 27 38 69 73 58 PERCENTAGES OF IIECREASE DURING 13 YEARS 1921-34 49 63 54 63 44 77 56 51 46 54 57 Sales price per acre. — The ave age sales price per acre of the farm land sold in the Group A (mainly cry-land) counties declined from $27 in the year ending March 31, 1922, to $10 in that ending March 31, 1934, or a decrease of 63 per cent, as ihown in Table 4. Meanwhile the price per acre in the Group B (mainl' corn-belt) counties declined from $116 to $53, or a decrease of 54 per cent. However, because of the smaller proportion of cheap western lane sold during the year ending March 31, 1934, the average sales price for the state as a whole fell only from $61 to $31, a decrease of 49 per cent, or less than the decrease in either of its two component parts. This exariple illustrates the unsatisfactory nature of all-state averages in a state having as wide a range of land values as Nebraska, and explains why sucr averages are not stressed in this study." The North district, where land prices fell from $22 at the commence - ment of the period studied to $5 ;it its close, had at once the cheapest land of the eight districts and the greatest price decrease as measured in per - centages. The East district, with prices falling from $159 to $73 during the period studied, had the highe.t land prices in each of the 13 years. Figure 5 illustrates the changts in the average sales price of farm land per acre between the year ending March 31, 1922, and that ending March 31, 1934, in each of the Nebraski counties reporting. In the former year there were only two counties (Blaine and Hooker) with a land price lower </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Sales and Assessed Value of Farm Land MARCH3..,9 22 E£ jS^^^p^fe YEAR ENDING 3^~- . OjJ ° c— ~- ° |V «.w» . I *■»"■« ff*fK T"?'/*' ""I •!*&gt;■— «K* &gt; V C Ji i"\ ' J MARCH31 * 1934 SpUS^^^^^^PIl E3$1-S9 g|42O-$3» [3JoO-*79 Q$I8O-$I»» (g]$rO-$IS Q$4O-$SS [T!]$80-$99 g$200lMORE O$l00-$I19 @$I«O-$I7» DnO REPT. Fig. 5. — Avcracc sales price per acre of the farm land sold in Nebraska counties during the twelve months ending March 31, 1922, and during the twelve months ending March 31, 193-4. than $10, while there were three counties (Dodge, Cuming, and Wayne) with a land price higher than $200. In the latter year 15 counties, all in Group A, had a land price of less than $10, while the highest prices re - ported were in Cuming county, where sales averaged $121 per acre. It should be noted, however, that many Nebraska counties reported very few "bona fide sales" during the year ending March 31, 1934. Of the 81 counties reporting in this year, 23 indicated less than 10 such sales. The statistical basis of the land prices for this year is accordingly rather slight in these counties." 1 The counties reporting Icm than 10 sales during this year: Arthur, Banner. Maine. Bonne. Box Butte, loyd, Cedar, Cheyenne. Dakota. Danes, Dcuel, Gospcr, Greeley, Hooker, Keja Paha, Knox. McPhcrson, Otic, Pierce, Thuriton. Washington, Webster, and Valley. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Fig. 6. — Percentage decrease in farm ] ind price per acre between the twelve months ending March 31, 1922, : nd those ending March 31, 193-4. Percentage decrease in land pi ice, by counties. — Ten counties, as shown in Figure 6, had a price decrease of 70 per cent or more between the year ending March 31, 1922, and thai ending March 31, 1934. Nine of these ten were included in Group A and seven of them in the North district. Three counties (Greeley, Hall, a id Harlan) reported less than a 40 per cent price decrease. Assessed value per acre.— The average assessed value per acre of the land sold in the Group A counti :s remained fairly constant at $10 or $11 from the commencement of the period studied through the year ending March 31, 1929, and then decreased gradually to $7 in the last two vears studied. The assessed value per icre in the Group B counties rose from Table 5. — Average assessed valu * per acre of jarm land sold during the specified periods and percentage decrease between 1921-22 and 1931-34. S u z. 5- Gro " ' -\ uutricts • Crimp IS districts | .5 | .£ £ .5 | =| = I = I N.W. ! i.W. | N. C. | s. N.F.. E. | S.E. BV VEARS ENDING MARCH 31 1922 S30 Sll £61 S13 S13 510 S29 S38 S67 S86 S75 1923 32 10 63 13 10 8 30 -40 7X 92 78 1924 34 11 65 15 13 7 31 40 76 93 78 1925 38 11 66 11 14 8 32 41 SO 95 78 1926 35 10 64 14 If. 6 35 38 72 92 79 1927 34 11 69 13 13 (1 34 42 7h 97 79 1928 31 11 66 12 15 6 34 34 ' 76 95 79 1929 31 10 65 12 14 6 33 35 76' 94 74 3930 30 9 67 12 15 5 33 40 8&lt;t 95 84 1931 27 9 64 15 15 5 32 47 67 90 75 1932 29 8 66 10 13 5 30 42 79 92 81 1933 ?4 7 54 7 10 5 29 34 65 77 68 1934 24 7 42 8 10 4 20 26 56 58 49 PERCENT \GES OF DECREASE DURING 13 YF.ARS 1921-34 20 30 31 3 : J 23 60 31 32 K. H 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Sales and Assessed Value of Farm Land $61 in the first year studied to $69 in the year ending March 31, 1927, remained at about the same value until the year ending March 31, 1932, and then declined abruptly to $42 in the last year studied. The percentage decline in the assessed value, as shown in Table 5, was less in every dis - trict than the decline in sales price shown in Table 4. In the three easternmost districts, the decline in assessed value did not commence until the year ending March 31, 1933. In the two remaining Group B districts (Central and South) it began a year earlier. rcx ™rr. •°i : ■ i ; ! ' ' 1 i 1 90 »o - / N so CROUP B COUNTIES -, «o - / T I - eo s^ /CROUP A COUNTIES-' 40 - 40 ! ■ ' 30 ] ; : : i : : i L 1922 1923 1924 1925 1926 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 1934 Fig. 7. — Percentage ratio of the assessed value to the sales value of Nebraska farm land sold during thirteen years. Years arc from April 1 of the preceding calendar year to March 31 of the specified year. Ratio of assessed value to sales value of farm land. — -Since the sales value of farm land dropped so much earlier and so much more than the assessed value, it follows that the ratio of assessed value to sales value increased during the period studied. Specifically, it rose from the year ending March 31, 1922, to that ending March 31, 1933, and declined somewhat in the ensuing year. Throughout the period studied this ratio was considerably lower in the Group A counties as a class than in the Group B counties (Fig. 7). In the former it rose from 42 per cent in the first year studied to 67 per cent in the peak year, and declined only to 65 per cent. In the latter it rose from 53 to 87 per cent, and declined to 79 per cent. The rise was most rapid in 1922-24 and 1930-33. In three districts — the Northwest, Southwest, and East — the peak year for the ratio of the assessed value to the sales value of farm land came during the 12 months ending March, 1932, or a year earlier than in the remaining five districts. All districts except the North cut assessed valua- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Nebraska Agr. Exp. J TA. Research Bulletin 77 tions between 1932 and 1933, but only in the three mentioned did these reductions exceed proportionately the drop in land prices. The decline in the ratio of assessed to sales valu: shown by the Class A counties during the two years ending March 31, 1929, was due to two diverse causes. In the Northwest and Southwest districts land prices increased during these two years — a condition not found in other districts. In the North district reductions in assessed values were slightly more than proportionate to land-price reductions. Assessment ratios, by counties.- -Figure 8 shows that there was a great difference between counties in the ratio of the assessed value to the sales price of farm land, even in the s: me district and during the same year. For brevity such ratios will be referred to as "assessment ratios". Although most of the Group A counties hid lower assessment ratios both at the beginning and at the end of the period studied than most of the Group B counties, there were counties w th high assessment ratios in Group A and with low assessment ratios i l Group B. Also, individual counties passed rather easily from an assessment ratio which was low relative to that for the group in one year to an assessment ratio which was high relative to that for the group in aiother year, and vice versa. The small numerical basis, in certain of the counties, especially in the year ending March 31, 1934, probably emphasizes these divergences. LAND SALES, CLASSIFIED ACCORDING TO THE RATIO OF THE ASSESSED VALUE TO "HE SALES PRICE Distribution of sales, by ratio groups. — If all tracts were assessed at about the same proportion of th&lt; ir actual sales value, the tendency in- Table 6. — Percentage ratio of assessed value to sales value of -farm land sold during tl e specified periods. ■it &lt; S •- - d Crimp A districts Group B districts II fa !| : I S | =| = o N.W. I S.W. | N. C. S. I N.E. | E. j S.E. I'.ct. i'.ci. I'.ci. I'.cr. /'.&lt;■/. I'.ct. t'xt. P;ct THIRTEEN YEARS ENDING MARCH 31, 1934 1921-34 63 53 65 51 48 57 58 61 66 67 69 BY YEARS ENDING MARCH 31 1922 50 42 53 39 39 45 47 49 53 54 56 1923 56 48 58 52 45 48 52 56 60 59 61 1924 60 52 62 54 48 52 56 61 62 64 67 1925 63 53 65 56 48 57 55 59 65 66 69 1926 62 53 64 59 47 60 58 57 68 65 66 1927 f.2 55 64 58 48 57 j 56 61 66 66 66 1928 62 53 65 56 45 58 : 57 56 67 67 68 1929 61 50 65 53 45 55 59 58 67 66 67 1930 68 61 70 58 55 70 61 64 75 73 72 1931 71 61 74 65 52 72 66 74 76 75 76 1932 80 66 84 73 61 65 71 77 88 86 86 1933 82 67 87 61 60 73 76 85 90 84 92 1934 77 65 79 65 56 80 73 70 81 81 84 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Sales and Assessed Value of Farm Land ■MPHMI YEAR ENDING »~-~ fl"-"-*- °° 'j^'^-fiff RATIO GROUPS m UJJDER pn40-44 rq55-59 rrn 70-74 fra 85-09 W 30P.CT. LiJp.CT. tJP.CT. V&amp;P.CT. UJRCT. gS]?J&gt;Z54 f^345-49 (TTTI60-84 17^75-78 M9O P.CT. Eap.CT. UJp.ct. LUIp.ct. Np.ct. BrMORE: [^ 35-39 fT7]50-S4 (=365-69 ittj 80-84 I— I NO Kilp.cT. l23p t CT. Bp.ct. HpTct. Urept. Fig. 8. — Ratio of xht assessed value to the sales value of the farm land sold during the twelve months ending March 31, 1922, and March 31, 1934. dicated in the foregoing tables for the average assessed value and the average sales value to approach each other might under normal circum - stances result from an improvement in the administration of the law. It might indicate that assessors were making more accurate appraisals. Un - fortunately very little improvement in accuracy of appraisal is demonstrable. A very wide range between the ratios of the assessed value to the sales value of the individual tracts sold was characteristic of all counties and years. The rise in the assessment ratio indicated in Table 6 and in Figures 7 and 8 resulted almost exclusively from the decline in the sales price of rarm land. It means that an increasing number and proportion of the tracts were assessed for considerably more than they would bring at a sale. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 77 This condition is clearly shown in Figure 9, representing the percentage distribution of the farm land sales in Group A and Group R counties re - spectively which fell into the specified "ratio groups". The "ratio groups" are established according to the ]&gt;ercentage ratio of the assessed value to the sales value of the individual tracts sold. Although it is the intention of the law that the assessed valuation should approximate the actual sales value of the property, this was the case in only a small fraction of the sales. From 4 to 15 per cent of the tracts sold in the Group A counties curing the respective years studied, and 1922 I92S 1920 1931 193* I &gt;2^^I92SI92«I|S3I1932 CROUP A COUNTItS CROUP 8 COUNTIES Hiio'rcT. Fic. 9. — Percentage distribution of the sales of farm land in groups classified accord - ing to the ratio of the assessed v luc to the sales value of the tracts sold. Years are from April 1 of the previous ralendar year to March 31 of the specified year. from 4 to 24 per cent of those ii the Group B counties were assessed at about the same amount as that :or which they sold (90-109 per cent of the sales value). In the Group A counties the modal group — that con - taining more of the sales than any other — was the 30-to-49-per-cent ratio group during the first four yeais studied and the 50-to-69-per-cent ratio group during the remaining nine years. From one-fifth to three-eighths' of the sales in this block of couities were included in the modal group in different years. In the Gro ap B counties the 50-to-69-per-cent ratio group was the modal group during the first ten years studied and con - tained from one-third to one-ha f of the sales, but the 70-to-89-per-cent ratio group was the modal grou j during the remaining three years and contained about three-tenths of t ie sales. A wide range between the ados of the assessed value to the sales value of the individual tracts was especially characteristic of the Group A (mainly dry-land) counties, in this group of counties ' from 21 to 3 per cent of the tracts sold in the respective years studied had an assessed value less than 30 per cent of the r sales value, while from 1 to 1 7 per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Sales and Assessed Value of Farm Land had an assessed value of 150 per cent or more of their sales value. For the Group B (mainly corn-belt) counties the corresponding percentages were from 4 to 1 per cent in the under-30-per-cent ratio group and from 1 to 7 per cent in the 150-per-cent-and-more ratio group. This widespread inequality in assessment ratios must have borne heavily on the owners of over-assessed property, especially during the depression years when the taxation of farm land has constituted a burden unprecedented in the history of this country. DOCS. DCCS. l4O rn r~i r~i ttttt~i r~r~i i \ r~i r~r^ ttt* 0 \ I grcxp b |rat«o groups f V COW1ES 120 UNDER 50 P.CT. -V t -p/^-i 1 120 50-69 P.CT. \V^~S S-— \ 70-89 ptCT. \A \ — «-90-IO».f»CT. — --&gt;- \l 100 1 H0PXT.1M0RE i- % / N** 1 °° :ii --" r pry CROJPA ""Ss / \ f 60 {J™$^ \f K/ V^i i o ii ii i i 'T i~* II i I I I i I | I L 1922 925 (928 1931 1934 I 22 1929 1926 ' 1931 1934 Fio. 10. — Price per acre of the farm land sold during thirteen years, grouped according to the ratio of the assessed value to the sales value. Years arc - from April 1 of the previous calendar year to March 31 of the specified year. Of course, a wide range between the assessed and the sales value was not always the fault of the assessor. Especially during the great depres - sion, farm land was frequently sold at sacrifice prices by landlords needing money for some other business, or by owner-operators who found them - selves unable to keep the farm going. Also, the actual consideration paid on a transaction often differed very considerably from that recorded in the deed. Such cases, however, are believed not to have been numerous enough to account for the extremely scattered distribution shown in Figure 9. District variations in distribution of sales. — The three geographic dis - tricts included in Group A did not vary significantly from the group as a whole in respect to the percentage distribution of the farm land sales among the various ratio groups described above. Of the five districts in - cluded in Group B, the East and Southeast were conspicuous for the </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Nebraska Agr. Exp Sta. Research Bulletin 77 relatively high degree of concentration in the 50-to-69-per-cent and 70-to - 89-per-cent ratio groups, especial y during the middle years of the period studied. In every year between \pril 1, 1923, and March 31, 1930, from 74 to 83 per cent of the sales ii each of these districts fell in the com - bined groups just mentioned. Assessment ratios were less uniform during the first two years studied, periaps because of the difficulty of adjust - ment to a new law, and also during the last four years because the great depression had thrown land pri :es into confusion. Table 7.— Price per acre of Nelras\a farm land sold, grouped according to the ratio of the assessea vhlue to the sales value of the tracts sold. Year per Price per acr : at various ratios of assessed to sales value Ma d rc"h g 31 oY'aU Under 30-19 7^ J^ i 30 . H9 150 land 30 p.ct. sold P"- P«- ?.a. p.ct. p.ct. p.ct. p.ct. ™,"J GROLP A COUNTIES 1923 S 2o S « S l\ 5 ?i S15 sn S18 S9 S5 Ivlt 20 34 25 17 14 in 7 7 c 1924 21 29 25 23 15 4 7 10 f 1925 20 28 29 20 5 9 g 4 - 1926 20 43 33 19 II 8 5 5 4 1927 21 33 27 23 14 9 I f 1 1928 20 34 28 19 14 9 7 7 5 1929 20 36 26 21 14 8 6 7 4 1930 15 32 28 19 11 . g % S A 1931 15 30 26 19 13 9 5 1 t !?32 12 21 15 18 \i 10 o \ \ 1933 10 24 23 11 8 7 k , '934 10 24 17 M 6 8 5 5 \ GROL P B COUNTIES ™1 S !&gt;« S' 2 ' S131 $20 S85 S75 S62 $49 S38 ■923 105 118 119 108 93 75 64 34 4? !924 104 131 105 17 93 72 54 45 28 1925 102 90 105 13 10D 69 52 60 53 926 100 104 104 112 95 59 43 45 33 927 108 162 103 120 104 78 56 34 37 928 102 110 95 112 102 70 39 47 25 »» 10 9 'I? 97 114 95 60 37 28 20 930 95 37 98 114 96 74 57 27 22 '31 86 99 90 97 90 76 64 30 15 \*% " »» 89 94 92 73 50 46 43 '33 62 17 82 82 68 58 47 43 33 193 -» 53 43 63 67 59 47 35 32 22 Sales price per acre, by ratio groups. — As shown in Figure 10 the average price per acre sold in tie ratio groups just discussed tended to vary inversely to the assessment ritio. The land assessed at much less than its sales value was the high-pric:d land, except for the under-50-per-cent ratio group in the Group B coun ies, where the price was somewhat lower in most years than that in the 5C -to-69-per-cent group and about the same as that in the 70-to-89-per-cent group. This exception was only apparent and resulted from the fact that iracts assessed at less than 50 per cent of their sales value were much mor: common in the medium-priced Central and South districts than in the relatively high-priced Northeast, East, and Southeast districts. Tracts assessed for considerably more than their sales value (110 per cent and more) were the lowest-priced of all ratio groups in both Group A and Group B counties in all years. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Sales and Assessed Value of Farm Land Table 7 shows that the relations above hold true in the main, even when the ratio groups are studied in more detail than in Figure 10. The irregularities in the extreme ratio groups in the Group B counties are due mainly to the small number of instances in these groups. District variations in price per acre, by ratio groups.— In general, in every district, the price in each successive ratio group from the second lowest to the highest was lower than in the ratio group immediately pre - ceding it. There were a few exceptions in individual districts and years, especially in the Central, Northeast, and East districts. In other words, in every geographic district the cheap land was seriously overvalued by the assessors and the good land undervalued in relation to the average assess - ment ratio for that district. This resulted mainly from the circumstance SSL. , , . . j , -==™5SS $ISyOOO M4D OVER 1 I 93CtOOO OVEf V. 1 : \ i-jlrti 'I flPv 1922 1925 1926 1931 1934 1922 1925 1920 (931 1934 CROUP A COUNTIES CROUP B COUNTIES Fig. 11. — Distribution of the sales value of farm land during thirteen years, according to the sales value of the tracts sold. Years are from April 1 of the previous cal - endar year to March 31 of the specified year. that assessors tend to center their estimates too closely around the average assessed value of land per acre for the county or precinct where they of - ficiate, and do not make sufficient allowance for differences between the good and poor land. LAND SALES AND ASSESSMENT RATIOS, BY SALES VALUE OF TRACTS Distribution of sales, by value of tracts.— The inverse relation between the assessment ratio and the total amount paid for the tracts sold appears to have been even closer than that between the assessment ratio and the price per acre. Figure 11 show's the percentage distribution of the sales of farm land by sales-value groups. In the Group A counties the per - centage of sales for amounts less than 55,000 increased from 34 in the first year studied to 77 during the last year, while in the Group B counties the corresponding percentages were 8 and 32, respectively. In the Group A counties 20 per cent of the yales between April 1, 1932, and March 31, </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Nebraska Acr. Exp. !»ta. Research Bulletin 77 1934, were for sums of less than $1,000, but there were relatively few sales for such a small amount in he Class B counties. At the other end of the scale, sales for $15,000 and) more accounted for 20 per cent of all Group A sales during the first yeir studied, and decreased to only 2 per cent of all sales during the last y ar. In the Group B counties the cor - responding percentages were 48 a id 9, respectively. District variations in distribution of sales by value. — The North (sand - hill) district had a larger proportion of sales under $5,000 in value than the Group A counties as a whole, especially from the year ending March i i i i it i I I i i I i r~i i v™ GROUP A GRCJPB . . cou* ties cou «nes / \ ioo : . J. A, no «o -£— ■/**&gt; '^S*** =3 TTZP s \ *° :__■- i»-L ..■. ' \ VALUE GROUPS I UNDER S5.000 $5*&gt;00-S»,999 20 1 $0,000-$ 14,000 20 — S.^OOAND | J 1 I I I | I I I I I | I I II || I | | 1922 1925 1928 1931 B 4 1922 1925 1928 1931 1934 Fic. 12. — Percentage ratio of the a sesscd value to the sales value of farm land sold during thirteen years classified according to the value of the tracts sold. Years are from Apri 1 of the previous calendar year to March 31 of the specified year. 31, 1926, to the close of the pcrioc studied. More than four -fifths of the sales in this district were for less tl an $5,000 during the two years ending March 31, 1934. More than half were for less than $2,000. While three - fourths of all sales in the Northv est district and more than three-fifths of those in the Southwest district during the same two years were for less than $5,000, most of such lo -priced sales in these two districts fell between $2,000 and $4,999. In Group B the Central and South districts of course had a larger proportion oi sales for less than $5,000 and a smaller proportion for $15,000 or more tha i the three districts further east. Assessment ratios in various sales-value groups. — As shown in Figure 12, the ratio of the assessed value to the sales value of the tracts of farm land sold commonly varied inversely to the sales value of such tracts. The most valuable tracts were assessed it a much lower rate than the general rate for the count)' or group of :ounties under consideration, and the </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Sales and Assessed Value of Farm Land least valuable tracts were assessed at a much higher rate. In their es - timates, the assessors evidently made much less allowance than did purchasers for the low earning power of the poorer farms or the pro - ductivity of the better farms. Of course the result of this defect is to make the burden of taxation bear most heavily on the poorer farms which are least able to carry it. Table 8. — Percentage ratio of the assessed value to the sales value of the Nebraska farm land sold annually by warranty deed, classified accord - ing to the value of the tracts sold, for the 13 years ending March 31, 1914. ' ALL CROUP A COUNTIES Vear ~~ Under | SI. (Kill S2.000 53,(100 S4.00I) S5.000 S7.5OO 510.000 515,000 ending ."" to to ti&gt; to to lo to anil March.il da»cs si .000 I 1,999 2.999 3,999 4,999 7 ,499 9.999 14.999 over I'.cl P.ct. I'd. l'.cl. P.ct. P.ct. P.cl. P.cl. I'.cl. I'.cl. 1922 42 92 69 61 60 54 51 46 -42 35 192? 48 100 72 f&gt;7 59 56 53 49 44 44 1924 52 121 79 69 62 58 55 51 49 4'. 1925 53 92 HI 73 71 65 57 53 47 45 1926 53 101 85 73 67 6&lt; 52 52 47 49 1927 55 86 81 75 70 62 58 52 51 49 1928 53 92 78 70 67 59 54 51 53 46 1929 50 101 90 68 62 52 52 49 49 42 1930 61 102 110 92 79 70 58 55 56 49 1931 61 126 107 91 77 68 59 54 54 53 1932 66 138 Mi 83 89 66 69 64 59 53 1933 67 165 105 97 81 74 55 56 53 51 1934 65 184 102 81 74 60 59 48 45 34 ALL GROUP II COUNTIES Year All I Under S2.50O S5.000 S7.5OO 510.000 515.000 520,000 525.000 530.000 ending to to to to to to to and March 31 clasps ' S2.5OO 4.999 7.499 9.999 14.999 19.999 24.999 29,999 over P.cl P.cl. I'.cl Pel. P.cl. P.cl. P.cl. P.ct. P.ct. P.cl. 1922 53 91 73 &lt;A 61 56 55 53 51 48 1923 58 124 77 67 64 61 60 57 56 52 1924 62 132 SO 70 68 65 62 61 59 55 1925 65 90 78 71 69 66 64 63 61 61 1926 64 94 75 71 66 65 63 63 63 60 1927 64 103 78 72 68 66 65 65 62 5" 1928 65 99 76 69 68 65 65 64 62 61 1929 65 99 76 71 69 66 65 62 63 60 1-/10 70 122 83 78 74 72 71 70 64 60 I9?l 74 117 K8 R2 78 74 73 70 72 66 1912 84 122 110 94 93 84 80 77 68 71 19!? 87 137 105 9? 92 84 78 69 62 76 1934 79 135 93 87 80 75 69 56 66 62 In the Group A counties farm tracts selling for less than $5,000 were assessed at from 59 per cent of their sales value during the year ending March 31, 1922, to 92 per cent during that ending March 31, 1933. The corresponding percentages for tracts valued at $15,000 or more were 35 and 51 per cent. In the Group B counties each sales value group had a higher assessment ratio than in the Group A counties in every year studied. But the tendency for the assessment ratio to be lower on the higher-priced land was quite as clear-cut in the eastern as in the western counties. The assessment ratio of the under-$5,000 sales in Group B stood at 110 per cent in the two years ending March 31, 1933. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 77 The extent and degree of the inequality is indicated even more clearly in Table 8, which shows assessment ratios in more narrowly graded sales - value classes than could be shown in the graph. Assessment ratios in the lowest sales-value class (under : 51,000 for Group A counties and under $2,500 for Group B counties) were more than 100 per cent during nine years out of thirteen in the Group A counties and during eight years out of thirteen in the Group B coum ies. Each successive sales value class was assessed at a lower ratio. The highest-value class shown ($15,000 and over in Group A and $30,000 and o\er in Group B) was assessed at from 34 to 51 per cent of its value in different years in Group A, and from 48 to 76 per cent in' Group B. District variations in assessment ratios in the respective sales-value! classes. — The Northwest ( panha ndle) district exceeded all the others in the range between the assessmen : ratios in the different sales-value classes. During the year ending March 31, 1934, farm tracts in this district selling for less than $1,000 were assessed at 211 per cent of their sales value, while tracts selling for $15,000 cr more were assessed at only 29 per cent of their sales value. The range in other years was also relatively great, but somewhat less extreme thar, the example given. The South district showed slightly less variation be ween the assessment ratios in the various sales value classes than any othc ■ district. CONCLUSIONS As a result of the foregoing study certain conclusions may be formu - lated as follows: (1) Nebraska farm land prces fell much more rapidly than assessed valuations during the 12 years ending March 31, 1933. Land values, in genera!, declined throughout this period. The assessed valuation of farm land remained approximately constant from April, 1921, up to and in - cluding the year ending March 1, 1929, in the western part of the state (Group A counties), and up to and including the year ending March 31, 1932, in the eastern part of the state (Group B counties). (2) In consequence, the ratio of assessed value to sales value rose during this period, and remained high even after valuations had been cut. Since taxes are based on the ass:ssed value, a rise in the ratio of assessed value to sales value has the saif e effect as an increase in the rate of tax - ation. (3) The assessed valuations of individual Nebraska farms commonly vary widely from their potential sales value in such a way that a dispro - portionate amount of the tax b lrden is placed on the poorer farms. In every geographic district, as shswn in this study, the cheap land was seriously overvalued by the assessors and the good land undervalued in relation to the average assessment ratio for that district. (4) While the western and northern (Group A) counties had, in gen - eral, a lower ratio of assessed vulue to sales value than the remainder of the state, the variation between individual tracts in respect to such ratios was particularly wide in those counties. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Sales and Assessed Value of Farm Land (5) It seems reasonable to conclude that the over-assessment and consequent over-taxation of the inferior farms was probably a contributory cause to the large amount of tax delinquency occurring on such farms during the trough of the depression (1931-33). During the period of the depression the tax burden on some of these seriously overvalued farms must have been nothing less than confiscatory in nature. A more equitable - assessment of farm land would, in consequence, be of great assistance not only to the unfortunate owners of these overburdened properties, but also to the administration of county finances. (6) The rather serious assessment situation revealed in this study indicates the need of a much more careful consideration of assessment problems than has yet been made in Nebraska if our tax laws are to be administered with equity. Some of the remedies which have been advised by economists are briefly indicated herewith. These remedies are not mutually exclusive, but would complement each other. SUGGESTED REMEDIES (1) "The office of the local assessor should be made appointive in - stead of elective. The local assessor should be made directly responsible to the county assessor, and he, in turn, to a state official such as the state tax commissioner or to a body such as the state tax commission. The entire personnel of tax administration should be taken out of politics. Each man's appointment should be based upon ability and training, and his tenure of office should depend upon the type of service he renders while filling the office. The compensation he receives should be sufficient to attract capable men and to induce them to inform and improve them - ielves while holding office." 8 (2) "The office of state tax commissioner can be rendered effective by legislative enactment. Instead of dividing the work (as at present) between the tax commissioner and the state board, with emphasis on the position of the state board, the legislature could vest the commissioner with all the powers exercised by the two agencies at the present time, except that equalization would have to be approved finally by the state board. In addition he could be given the power to make rules and regu - lations for the guidance of local taxing officials and to suspend county and precinct assessors for inefficiency or misconduct in office. With thq addition of these powers sufficient state supervision could be established in Nebraska to improve the efficiency of local tax administration and to insure uniformity in assessment." !l (3) "Grading or appraising a tract of farm land is a technical job. If it is to be properly done, men trained in technical fields will have to be called on for at least some assistance. Soil surveys have been completed for many couniies, but these do not consider the individual farms as units. In some of the irrigation districts the land on individual farms has been "Ralph II. Cole. The General Properly Tax, cited on pat;c 3. * I:. Glenn Callcn. Tjx Administration in Nebraska, cited mi page '. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Nebraska Agr. Exp. 5ta. Research Bulletin 77 graded from one to five according to its productivity. This is a develop - ment in the right direction because it focuses attention upon the important objective, that of evaluating the potential long-run production of a farm . . . Some of the factors affectirg productivity, of course, change with , time, such as the operator, demanc for certain farm products, organic mat - ter content of the soil, and the lik&lt; . However, the more permanent factors such as the depth and character of the surface soil and subsoil, natural drainage, topography, climate, and possible losses from erosion are so im - portant that a scientific classification of land on the basis of these factors j would be highly useful . . . tc tax authorities in assessing land for taxes, and to government agencie: in evolving a land use policy."" • W. G. Murray. I he I.aml Appraisal I'mlilcm, Journal of Farm Economics 16 (No. 4): 611-12, (umber, 1934. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>