<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00031.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00031.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE STATE INSURANCE BOARD DECEMBER 24, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">FIRST RIENNIAL RKPORT OK THE State Insurance Board </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">rT BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE STATE INSURANCE BOARD. ■ Lit l ii II. Mor 1 ture. u r-.-port ol its of? '.oard ny au'horized to do bu »d in this state for tlir loimr of capital, anil the kinds rds ot t rt cont ;i:imf rs and employe* ■ sine nisatton o &lt;■ Insurance Board tnd the whole amount itemized, ami the I of the department dur - &lt;ih peril ii. This report contains recommendations which, in the itemized, ami the • of the department dur d the a n ain- recommendations which, in th judgment of the Board will strengthen the act and aid the Board :;• judgment of the Board will strengthen the act u:&gt;d aid the Board ;n prt ituting violations :aud. dishonesty, and will raise tntinu violatioi !he standard of insurimce in this slate, which Ls desired by every insur - ompany authorized in this state that e\: business standard of insurance in tl desi mpany authorized in th that expects to secure its imsinea through honest methods; it is desired by the insuring public as it is being ted to realize that tQe insurance department will willingly use its • fforts and exert its authority when necessary to ■■ and rough honest methods; it is desired by the insuring public as it is being icated to realize that the insurer department will willingly use its [forts and exert its authority when necessary to &lt;ecure justice and fair dealing. Among the recommendations in this report is one made with the hope ' uring legislation to prevent a dishonest Hie insurance agent from air dealing Among the recommendations ii this report is one made with the hop* a dishonest lile insurance agent froir making, with or without the connivance of his company, estimates or Eises impoysible of fulfillment in order to secure an application, report will include a few comments upon the subjec's of insurance are of particular interest to the public at this time, such as rate ig. discrimination in fire rates, state insurance. Workmen's Com ition Law, policy provisions, the views of the actuary of this depart- nent, together with the report of the examiner ABUSES OBSERVED IN THE CONDUCT OF THE INSURANCE BUSI - NESS AND HINTS TO THE MANAGERS AND AGENTS - It must not be inferred from what may be said under this heading that the insurance business as it is transacted in this star. -:ener- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 T HtKXXlAL KKI'ORT OK uli&gt; s|)&lt;-iiking. conducted upcn a high plane of br.sint--.- ethics, or that it is not worthy of the confidence of the insuring public. That there are a few exceptions, none will deny, but we can truthfully say that the excep - tional cases which furnish the basis of our criticism are becoming fewer year by year, and will, we trust, in a little while altogether cease to exist IVe realize, also, that those charged with the supervision of this •tment. or, for that matter, any supervisory official, is impelled to undue prominence to things that cause him almost daily annoyance rritation. and to overlook, in some degree, the enormous daily trans is which are entirely satisfactory to the public, and which are never :ht to his attention at all until he comes to make up his totals at the of the year, and is startled by the enormous volume of business done. it is up to the various insurance companies authorized in this state to give to the public the best possible service, such as fair treatment in adjusting losses, liberal terms in policy provisions and the elimination of clauses that are inserted for the purpose of deception or advantage They should eliminate the unscrupulous adjuster who is working upon the theory that the lowest settlement is the best settlement. They should eliminate the &lt; gent or officer who !s trying to build up his business by advertising some small or imaginary disadvantage on the part of the com - peting company, as such agent cr officer is only sowing distrust and creating suspicion when he attempts to increase his business by maligning his opponent. Let us all work for higher ideals, better confidence in the business we represent and enthuse the public with our sincerity. They should eliminate exhorbitant salaries and padded expense ac - counts of the officers; eliminate the idea that the money paid to the company belongs to the officers and that they can squander and expend it to suit their pleasure; eliminate the thought that because they did not get the same salary when the company was young they are justified in attempting to make up this imaginary deficiency by voting money to themselves; eliminate any subterfuge to draw money from the company in addition to the salary the public record discloses, and when all this is done we will have no fear of any agitation made towards State Insurance reaching beyond the agitator. The solution rests with the companies and State Insurance will be a factor in the near future if the companies insist upon fighting each others interest. Let them work together in giving confidence to the insured and they will find an unlimited and prosperous field for all kinds and classes of companies in this state. MISREPRESENTATION OF LIFE INSURANCE AGENTS I This subject is one of the most vexatious the department has to con - with and some law should be enacted providing against this malicious tice. We have many complaints, even affidavits, from the victims, also from other disinterested parties, but when the agent's attention illed to his false statements he usually has seme driver who is being a commission if he lands his application, make a counter affidavit, after due consideration and overwhelming evidence, the department ses the company that a hearing will be held to show cause why their </seg>
            <seg id="p005">TIIK STATK IX8URANCK HOAKH agent V license should not be cancelled, and usually before tli - hearing they will forward to the department a request for the cancel! of the agent's license. But this act does not require the company to return to the applicant the money or note given in payment of such mis:' sentation of poiicy. The policies issued are probably worth the money paid, but many men could not be induced to nrike an application for a policy if tht agent would state the truth to him. Not until the poh delivered does the applicant discover that he has been deceived an peals to the department for the return of his monoy. but the Board has no direct authority in such cases. This method applies to only a small per - centage of the life companies doing business in Nebraska, but this small percentage is retarding the other companies from establishing confidence with the insured, and that he can rely upon the statement of the when application is made. Companies should be held responsible to the insured tor any promise made by their agent in soliciting an applii and each agent should furnish to the applicant a complete statement devoid ot any technical terms, so tl.at the insured can compare his pcl'cv when received nnd immediately notify the company of any discrepancies and upon the refusal of the company to incorporate into the policy premises made in the statement of benefits, they should be compelled tn .mmediately return all the money paid by the insured and reimburse him for all expenses connected therewith. DISCRIMINATION IN FIRE INSURANCE, AND RATE MAKING I Within the past three or four years there has arisen a strong public iment in favor of the state assuming the function of making the rates ire insurance. In several states laws have been enacted establishing i rate bureaus, under the charge of the Insurance Commissioner, and her states such bureaus, established by the companies, have been put. certain degree, under state supervision. In some sections where there exists a strong sentiment in favor of tht state assuming the function of prescribing the rates for fire insurance or where such sentiment has crystallized into law. the attitude of the public is undoubtedly due to b feeling that the companies have combined to fix extortionate rates and that the power of the state should be exerted to prevent extortion. I This condition cannot be said to prevail in Nebraska, and wha itisfaction exists is due to gross discrimination in rates on risks of il hazard. In many cases the discrimination exists between cotnmuni similar in size, in class of buildings and in f're protection. In other tnces the discrimination is made between insurers in the same com - ity, due. no doubt, often to property influence and often to the simple ety of the agent to secure the business, and the culpability of the pany in giving countenance to the demoralizing practice of rate cutting KFire insurance is a necessity; its importance to the community can - be overlooked; but unless it shall be conducted by the companies g safe and conservative lines, government must and will be called i to assume this service to society. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">ie the solvency of the companies as mar thev shall not be extor What is needed is stability The older companies bare accumulated a vast amount of data bas upon their experience covering a period of many years which should be ; importance to the public and to themselves as furnishing basis upon which to predicate adequate yet equitable rates upon all kind Bi s of risks, so far as the physical hazar.l is concerned. t is true that rates cannot be made upon statistical experier but it is equally true that equitable rates could not be made witliou ical experience In 1913 th^ Convention of Insurance Commissioners, reeognizi Eance of the rating problem, ami that it is the particular field nee in which the public is, at this time, th._- most deeply in!' ted a committee u&gt; investigate and report upon fire insuram committee held several hearings in Chicago and New York, in * k and mutual companies took part, and whi;. ..us were reported to have been 'spirited and illumina -ire no' yet advised as to the final recommendations by th. ept that it has drawn up certain tentative bills, some of wni I are along the jine herein The question is one that cannot be long ignored and if the state is • r!y to discharge its obligations to the public it must take hold of the - r in such a way that it may be in a position to say what rates are i and equitable, and this it cannot do unless, tangible evidence milted in substantiation. It ;s said that the fact that the insurance companies have not jt combined their experience and \ised the results as a basis for rate making is due partly to mutual jealousies and partly to the fear that the informa - tion, should it become available to the public, would be used as an abso- lute measure of rates unqualified by judgment. We certainly do not favor the making of h'r» insurance rates by thf Kit is our belief that state-made rates ha\e usually proved to be ary and unse'entific. and have been found to require constant es. thus aggravating the very condition th' j y were called into exist- 10 cure, unstability. We recommend thai the activity of the state in this matter be con for the present, at least, to the acquisition of data upon which to base a classification of risks. This can be done partly by following the Kads which have been used for many years by the rating bureaus lished by the companies; surveys, maps, etc., and partly by taking itaee of such statistical data in relation to the loss experience of the might be available, and which, so far as their experien ■state is concerned, they should be required to contribute. Prom the information thus obtained a classification of risks could be made and established, giving, of course, the public and the companies opportunity to be heard as to any inequality which might be thought to . blit- thai enough t </seg>
            <seg id="p007">UK STATE INSURANCE IKiAlil It ).\l t On account of the taxation committee appointed by yourself, it necessary to make any extended recommendations on this subj. to advise that some legislation should be enacted requiring that all paid by insurance companies in this state be paid direct to ihe Treasurer through the Insurance Board, in orde- that a just and • payment be made by all companies, which is not done under the pi - local taxation method. As nearly all the sta'es have laws taxing foreign companies' premium receipts, this state under the reciprocal law would receiTe a large income even if no law existed taxing premiums, or le other fees ot charges. This can be verified by noting that of the fees and taxes collected by this department. $1!*. 458.24 was paid to the State Treasurer where no law of this state would have lequired such colle, These charges are simply made to retaliate agairst the other states be - cause of charges levied on our companies, if they desire to do business in such other itate. Kven though the reciprocal !aw. in a measure, takes care of our leniency upon the question, the incoming legislature should make provision for uniform taxation and fees to be charged regardless of the kind or class of company. If any exceptions exist they should be effective upon all companies, as none of the companies or their officers doing business under the provision of the law are doing so from a benevolent motive, but with the thought of gain in some form, and the companies paying the least taxes and fees are usually the ones receiving the greatest benefits in the state. Equal taxation should be the legisla - tor's motive in arriving at the proper method of taxation. regardl« the object of such tax or th&gt; We have many young and When iiich classificatioa ■ panies doing business in the &gt;tate would be required to til- rates for each of the varic i| hazards, which could !!■ tpd from except by the public filing of a supplen: become effective only at the » -xpiration of a cert.iin number We believe that if Um 'ablish a m department nil*'- iitrol of I Insurance would be found to enforce siability of fire insurant i ■mpetition or interfering with tiie constitutional rights of tht Wt believe it to be equally the duty of the state to guard th- panies against unreasoning and unrt-asonuhle conpetitkMI, which imperil their solvency, as well M to jjnard tile publi extortion should the companies "set together' and Beck to exploit the people instead of cutting one anothers throats. Should the department we recommend be Board would soon b&lt;? in position to pass upon the adequacy of th-- schedules filed, and. if it should later become necessary tor the st.i make the rates, the preliminary work would have been accomplished and a basis at hand. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 FIRST BIKNNIAL REPORT OF the laws of this state and consideration should be shown them in taxation in order that they may receive the same benefits in their home state that foreign companies receive in their home states, and every honest induce - ment should be extended to encourage and foster the advancement of companies organized under the laws of Nebraska that will aid in promot ueir interest and prosperity to the end that they may extend to the policy holders liberal settlements and economical management. WORKMEN'S COMPENSATION LAW The Workmen's Compensation Law of 1913 was suspended by refer - endum petition and was votr-d upon at the November. 1914. election and ratified by the people. This law therefore became effective December 1, 1914. The duly of administering this law is placed upon the Insurance Department. By its terms this law provides that employers who shall employ five or more employes shall be required to pay compensation In case an employe shall receive accidental injuries causing either the dis - ablement or death of such employe arising out of or in the course of his employment, without regard to the negligence of the employer. The em - ployer shall also provide medical and hospital treatment, and a funeral benefit in case of death due to accident. While the law does not make it compulsory either that the employer shall come under the compensation provisions of this law. or. if he elects to do so. that he shall insure his liability, the fact is practically established that employers generally will elect to be governed by this law as to compensation of injured employes, and that they will insure their risk, either in the stock companies qualified to write this kind of insurance, or in mutual companies, organized under the law of Nebraska, comprised of a number of employers organized into a mutual association. Nearly all of the miscellaneous companies transacting liability busi ness in this state have signified their intention of writing this class of insurance and have submitted policy forms for approval. We believe that none of the forms submitted have been found to be entirely in harmony with the provision of our law and all have had to be modified in many respects, involving a great amount of additional work in the Department Two mutual companies are being organized by the employers and a great deal of the rime of the department has been occupied in connection there- As Workmen's Compensation Laws are of very rcent origin in this country, there is very little data available upon which to base either the rates or reserves of the insurance companies underwriting this hazard. The companies have adopted manuals of premium rates which are ad - mittedly tentative and subject to revision whenever experience shall be available sufficient to base more equitable rates. In regard to reserves, this department has formulated a basis for the guidance of Nebraska companies, subject to revision which experience may show to be neeeMiary. ■In this connection it seems to this department rather unfortunate the reports may by employers, of accidents received by employes and </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THK 8TATE INSURANCE HOAKI) of the &lt; ( inpensation paid thereunder, should have h&lt; made to a State Department other than the Insurance Department Necessarily these reports must be the basis upon which premium and insurance reserves shall be calculated. In connection with this class of insurance, we th! nk is proper to call attention to the long period of time during which compensation is required to be paid in entail contingencies and the obvious necessity that ■ ance of tiiis class should be written in the strongest kind of companies xample. the compensation for the loss of ■ limb or an eye extends during a period of from 125 week.- to 215 weeks; the compensation in case of dtath extends for a period of 350 weeks; wh'le the compensation for total disability extends during the remainder of the life-time of the employe. While the liability of the employet is not released by insuring there is no surety that he will remain solvent. At any rate, the in undertakes the entire responsibility and. in case of the insolvency of the employer, becomes directly liable to the employe or the dependents of a deceased employe. Because, therefore, of the long and uncertain period of time during which an insurance company will be called upon to pay these benefits, it becomes a matter of the utmost importance that the insurance companies transacting this kind of business shall not only be solvent beyond any reasonable doubt a.t the present time, but that its solvency, or at least its ability to meet these compensation claims I hence, shall be as nearly as possible made certain. Irhe thought has occurred to us that this can be assured only by a sit made with the State, proportionate to the volume of insurance of nature transacted by each company, with a certain minimum of. say, 00. This deposit to be for the protection of the policy holders and oyes in this state. It is believed that a law of this nature would not il any ureat hardship upon the companies and would in a great sure guarantee the fulfillment of the n&gt;&lt;|uir- inents of this law INVESTMENT OF RESERVES There has been considerable agitation tor several years j n favor of legislation which would compel life insurance &gt;-ompanies of other states to invest in the securities of a state, an amount which should at least be equal to the reserve accumulations on the policies held by citizens of the In at least one state a law of this kind w*i enacted. A law of this kind might perhaps be of benefit in some states in the way of forcing more active competition in the investment market and lower interest rates, and tne slogan, "keep your money at home," strikes a popular chord, especially when backed by a fo:midable array of figures showing the large amount of premiums collected from the people of the state and the comparatively small amount returned in the way of death EPhere seems to be little occasion for legislation of this nature in state for the simp 1 . that Nebraska investments, panic ■ ] sk:i farm niortjitpes. a""- very attractive to many of the foreign life </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 tl i : it will be touMd that ihe investments made by sui n tx - will i;rtatly ramed tl M held to protect the polici. of this state. K Exhibit.- will l;e iittaciic! to ihis report showing the compani.-&gt; iiipaiiies withdrawn; companies organized. aU.; also exhit ■ I IUM collects, and the amounts , xpended for salar ■xpen- illy submitted L (J. BKIA.N </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE IXSURAXCK B 11 i f 1 t UK REPORT OF THE ACTUARY DUTIES OF ACTUARY It is difficult to define the duties of the Actuary of the Insuran jartment. The word actuary means one skilled in insurance. The d ailing to the lot of the Actuary of an Insurance Department da not differ ntterially from the duties falling to the lot of the Actuary of an iroblems ance company, except that the company actuary has to me jresented in his own company only, while the Department Actuary xpected to have knowledge, particularly technical know !&lt; &lt;1 o all kinds and classes of insurance One of the ch:ef duties of the actuary is to audit the am nents and to pass upon the financial responsibility of all com par mitted to transact business in ti Tne 1913 nnnir ompanies transacting business in Nebraska, as follows Regular Life Conpaah i vary large proportion of th- tion with this w ither corrections, or more explicit information, or both Another duty of the actuary is to pass upon the applicat business in the state The duty imposed upon the actuary in relation to the poli( ■; and other forms used in connection with these con) the one r&gt; ing the greatest proportion of his time and attention. Section 139 of the Insurance Code provides. "No insurance policy or certificate of any kind (I be issued or delivered in this state unless and until of the thereof has been filed with the Insurance Board and approved b - law prescribes certain provisions which must be incorporated in every :y of insurance. It also prescribes other conditions which are not permissible. It therefore follows that every form of policy issued by tand every company must be carefully read and examined, not only respect to the statutory provisions and statutory prohibitions, but respect to its general fairness and its freedom from ambiguous or itive conditions. The life and accident co uments submitted by foreign companies desiriim admissi ■ssment Life Companies Stock Fire Companit ■- I"-* Mutual Fire ami M sec kim-on* 14 Farm Mutual* Fraternal* AeeMmt, Casualty and Miscei; The statements rendered by these companies are in book fan ug in size from 17 fipes. for tho fraternal '«e». fc he life companies, and each | ■ compilation of figures whic ■nust be verified. There is a great amount of correspondence In </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 ■anC iiumuer of polities. Some companies have presented lor approval over one hundred different forms, which nearly all have a large number and are continually changing. One of the most important duties of the actuary is 10 test the suf - ficiency cf the reserves carried by the Nebraska life and accident com - panies and the equitable distribution of the surplus of the companies whoso policy holders are promised participation in the profits of the com pany. This requires technical knowledge of the construction of Insurance premium rates and tables of reserves as well as a knowledge of the meth - ods employed to properly apportion and distribute the profits accruing to the various classes of policy holders. DISTRIBUTION OF DIVIDENDS In die examination of life insurance companies it has come to our knowledge, in more than one instance, that dividends to policy holders art not always made in accordance with the earnings properly belonging to that certain class of policy holders according to the terms of the policy That is, the company may consider it advantageous, for advertising pur - poses, to pay, during the earlier years, dividends greater than may have been earned, which practice is just as culpable as to withhold from the policy holder dividends to which he is justly entitled. In other cases the company may have used extravagant estimates in writing the business and have paid dividends for the first few years according to such esti - mates, although not earned. The result of paying fictitious dividends in the earlier years of a policy is disappointment in later years when the company is obliged to reduce the dividends to the actual earnings. In such cases we have found that the management, when called upon by the policy holders to account for the reduction in dividends, is inclined to blame seme other agency rather than to admit that it is due either to fictitious dividends in the earlier years or to the use of deceptive mates by the agent when taking the application. USE OF ESTIMATES The most flagrant abuse in connection with life insurance is the use of estimates by agents in soliciting. While this abuse is not as general as it formerly was, the few companies that still resort to the practice are using this device in an even more flagrant manner than was the case when it was more generally practiced by the life companies. In our opinion the need cf a law which shall effectively prohibit the use of esti - mates is a more urgent need than any other remedial measure in connec - tion with the insurance business. LIMITED ACCIDENT AND SICKNESS POLICIES I Accident and sickness insurance is not yet standardized in anything the same degree as life or fire insurance, and a surprising variety of :y contracts are presented for approval. We regret to say that many lese forms offered by a few foreign companies are deceptive and are </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THK STATE INSURANCE MOAKD 13 I f c A I culated to deceive the public. The policies rtferred to are sold at * w price and to a casual reader the contract affords a surprising nui : benefits for the small premium charged. It is only when the p ler meets with misfortuno and presents ■ el lira to the compai: arns that his policy does not cover the accident in questior re;&gt;son that the company pays the benefit only in case the ac 1 while riding, as a passenger, in the enclosed part of a railwa yance or steamboat, or by being crushed by the walls of a falling r or the burning of a hotel or theater. The insurance companit kind of contracts call them •Limited Policies," but the nai they are known in the Insurance Department is "Fak.- Pc ml it hiis been the strenuous endeavor of the Department, du list cne and one-half years, to stamp out and prohibit the isstiai. *ss of insurance contracts, which our experience indicates are not Id for what they really are. and as sold in this state are lit 1 1 - ml It has also been the practice of icies covering sickness in which the sickness benefits are restri. ew named dieases. a large proportion of which would never happen to i. rson in this climate. Our opinion of this &lt;lass of insura: etter than that expressed in regard to the limited accident insu erred to, and our treatment of such policies is along the same .i It is difficult to write regarding this phase of the insurant vithout a feeling of indignation, and in stamping out such practices we eel that the Insurance Department has done a work of benefit to eople and of still greater benefit to the companies desiring to tra: traightforward business, that are injured because of the disi &gt;r;ictices on the part of a few of their competitors. ASSESSMENT COMPANIES The people of this state are to be congratulated upon the rep. the. old insurance laws, which permitted the organization of life I ance companies upon the assessment plan without requiring either quate rates or the providing of any fund for the payment of either I or expenses in the years immediately following organization. Under the Insurance Code companies of this class cannot be orsaniz-d und.&lt; ircumstances Of the old state companies organized on this plan, one has oea exist during the current year, while another may be said to be heading toward certain dissolution. Another company of this class, recenti ganized, had been found to have resorted to very questionable in order to obtain business and it is doubtful if it will be able to qu for the continuance of its UcaaM at the end of the present lit •■ RATES OF FRATERNAL AND ASSESSMENT COMPANIES There has been during the past few years a marked incre. knowledge en the part cf t: &gt;. on the subject of li; iome companies of this &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK »urance. It is now realized, as never before, that a contract promising to pay to the dependents of a living person a fixed sum at his death, re - quires that there shall be accumulated a fund for the payment of such sum. While it is not known when any individual will die, of a large num - ber of persons of a certain age, now living, it is reasonably certain how many will die during the first year and how many will die in each year thereafter until the last person of the group shall have passed away Prom tables worked out with the utmost pains by actuaries it is not a difficult task for one skilled in life insurance to calculate, with a rea - sonable degree of certainty, how much should be paid each year by a person of any cetrain age to provide an adequate rate of premium. The sum of the contributions of a large number of persons, each paying a fixed and adequate premium according to his age at time of entry into the organization, will provide a fund which, improved at interest, will fur - the means to pay each and every policy at death. As stated in the beginning of this paragraph, the public, generally, now realize that in order for a company or association to maintain its solvency the premi - ums paid by the individual members of such association and from which all death claims must be met shall be sufficient. In many of the states laws have been passed providing that no corn - shall be organized or admitted to transact business in such state m its rates shall be such as to provide an adequate reserve according to a fixed and recognized standard. These laws also provide that fra - ternal organizations already organized in such states or admitted to transact business therein must have their policies valued in order to tain their ability to meet their policy obligations as they shall mature. ling to the present rates of contribution. Similar valuations must be at intervals of three years, and if the company, at the first valua - tion, does not show a condition of solvency it must at each three year interval threafter, show a certain percentage of gain, or, we might say, a decrease in its condition of insolvency, otherwise it shall not b&gt; mined to continue business in such state. I'nfortunately no such law has yet been formulated by means of nent life associations shall be measured. The law referred to is what is commonly known as the Mobile bill, and is the result of a compromise agreement between the convention of State Insurance Com - missioners and the leading fraternal associations forming the National Fraternal Congress, and is thought to be a most excellent law and one which will eventually place the fraternal associations upon a safe and Bound basis or compel their retirement from business. No law of this kind has as yet been passed in this state, but it is hoped that the fraternal associations will themselves cause such a bill to be introduced in the near Comparison of the rates charged for identical benefits, by the various fraternals and assessment associations transacting business in this state, show the haphazard and altogether unscientific basis of the rates charged. This can be illustrated by showing the monthly rates charged by a few organization? doing business in Nebraska. The net monthly rates per </seg>
            <seg id="p015">revision for the protection of the members SETTLEMENT OF LIFE POLICIES UPON LAPSE In the Insurance Code, which became effective, as regard the approval of policies or contracts of insurance. July 1, 1914, as to foreign com]. . domestic companies were given until July 1. 1915, in which to meet the Mine requirement. This was unfortunate, and it has been found, in the course of Kninations, that some of the domestic life companies are making settle ts with policy holders, who terminate their insurance by lapse, which d not be permitted if the provisions of the law governing such mentB were in force. It is only just to say. however, that several of the Nebraska life companies have voluntarily submitted their policies : proval and have placed themselves fully under the provisions and r - tions of the act before they were compelled to do so by law. Respectfully submitted. H. S. WIGGINS 11,000 of insurance of five different &lt;"oni|&gt;&lt;ui member at age 40 are respectively: No. 1 No. 2 '■*&gt; No. 3 M No. 4 ■«- No. 5 The net monthly rate for $!.■&gt;»'■ oi insurance ;it this age by the I recognized table of mortality is $1.79. showinK the absolute m </seg>
            <seg id="p016">KIKST BIKNMAL KKIOKT OK 16 REPORT OF EXAMINERS We herewith submit a resume of th«&gt; work of examination of insiir companies performed by u since the date of our appointment, viz August 18, 1913. During this period we have examined seventy-two insurance con |p;mies incorporated in Nebraska, as follows: Kiirm Mutual Fire. Lightning. Tornado and Hail Com pan:? Life Companies 9 Fraternal Companies 4 Ki, Accident, Casualty. Surety and other Miscellaneous Companii hese examinations have shown that, with very few exceptions braska companies are conservatively and safely managed and are worthy of the confidence of the public; that their methods of accounting are well planned and accurate; that in most companies the expenses have been kept within a reasonable limit. The Farm Mutual companies should be particularly commended upon their economical management. In a number of these latter companies, however, the assessments made are too low and prove insufficient to take care of the losses incurred, leaving a deficiency or we might say an apparent insolvency at the close of the year. Thw matter that can be easily remedied by making the assessments high enough to take care of all probable claims and leave some balance to be carried over to the following year. ABUSES K&lt;ouom\. however, does not prevail in all companies. Our exam - inations disclose the fact ihat in some of our Fraternals the expenses of the supreme lodge conventions are excessive and extravagant to a marked degree. Some of our Life companies were found to have ex - pended considerably more than the entire first year premium income for expenses directly chargeable to the acquisition of new business. CLAIMS Klii our earlier examinations, we found a few cases where claims were settled equitably, but technicalities were relied upon for defenses. At present time we are glad to report that every Nebraska company ex led is settling its claims upon the broad basis of equity. I In every examination that we have made, we have received courte - treatment and the records and books of the companies examined have i freely offered for our inspection and all papers called for produced. Respectfully submitted. Examiner. Examiner JOHN W. JONES, Jr., C. S. CLAYTON. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">COMPANIES ADMITTED DURING THE YEAR 1913 FIRE COMPANIES Alliance Assurance Fire Ins. To Ltd Admitted Sept. IS. |fl| London. Kngland Hague. Holland irk Pin Ins. Co. of Newark. New Admitted April 21. 1913. LIFE COMPANIES ■Farmers Lite Inf. Co. of Kenver. ( \dmitted July 11. It Northwestern National Life Ins. C pany. Admitted Sept. 19. l!»i: Minm Minn. Mil MISCELLANEOUS COMPANIES ■ago Bonding &amp; Surety Company ot Chicago. Ill Admitted April 3 1913. ■&gt;n Casualty Company, Philadelphia. F'h Admitted April 7. 1913. ASSESSMENT COMPANIES ■ &gt;Ien's Protective Association, Dm Moines. Iowa Admitted July 22, 1913. ■ herhood of all Railway Employees Chicago 1)1 Admitted July 11, 1913. FRATERNAL COMPANIES COMPANIES WITHDRAWN DURING THE YEAR 1913 FIRE COMPANIES ■xiean Union Fire Ins. Co. of Philadelphia. Pa . in hands of March 27, 1913 ■alo Commercial Ins. Co.. Buffalo. N. Y. withdraws fron January 31, II Ci'Iumet Ins. Co. of Chicago. 111., reinsured in National Union Fire Ins Co.. Philadelphia Hawkeve * \h s Moines Fire l «d in Iierlands Fire &amp; Life Ir.s. Co.. The Hagu&lt; Admitted April 7. 1913. ark Fire Ins. Co. of Newark. NVw -lock ('i)mpany Railway Mail Association. Portsmouth. X. H Admitted Xnvembcr 14. ItiS. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 FIRST BIKXMAI. REPORT OF Fir. und Ins. Co., of San Francisco, Cal., January 1. 1h Imperial Fire Ins. Co. of Denver, Colo., reinsured in German American Ksurance Company of New York, N. V., May 1, 1913. ntile Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co.. Boston. Mass.. withdrawn January 31, 1913. LIFE COMPANIES Hartford Life Ins. Co.. of Hartfcrd. Conn., reinsured in the M'ssourl State Life Fire Ins. Co. of St. Louis. Mo., February 17, 1913 MISCELLANEOUS COMPANIES American Automobile Ins. Co.. St. Louis. Mo., withdrawn January 31, 1913. American Bonding Co. of Baltimore, Md.. merged with Fidelity &amp; Da Company of Baltimore, Md. January 2, 1913. •Frontier Accident Ins. Co. of Lincoln, Nebr., reinsured in the Lincoln A&lt;* cident Ins. Co. of Lincoln, Nebr. February 17. 1913. National Business Men's Accident Association. Omaha. Nebr. rr&lt; appointed June 17. 1913 •Re»umeii business in 1914 rANIES ORGANIZED IN THE STATE DURING THE YEAR 1913 MUTUAL COMPANIES Automobile Mutual Insurance Company of Omaha, Nebraska Licensed June 30, 1913. ■Chester Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company, of Dorchester. Nebr Licensed June 6, 1913. ■ners' Mutual Ins. Co. of Scotts Bluff County. Scotts Bluff. Nebr Licensed May 21. 1913. ■lge Mutual Insurance Company of Custer County, Broken Bow. Wbr Licensed January 2, 1913. LIFE COMPANIES Prairie Life Insurance Company of Omaha, Nebraska. Stock Company Licensed June 4, 1913. Prime of Life Ins. Co. of Omaha. Nebraska. Stipulated Premiums Licensed June 11. 1913. Fidedity Life Association of Nebraska, Lexington, Nebraska. AmmmI Company. Licensed March 4, 1913. MISCELLANEOUS COMPANIES Frontier Accident Insurance Company. Lincoln, Nebr. Stuck Company Licensed February 17, 1913. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Tbe Old Line Accident Ins. Company. Lit: Licensed June 28, 1913. :i Accident Insurance Company. Lincoln. NeSjr Licensed June 28. 1913 rMPANIES WITHDRAWN, LICENSE REFUSED AND REINSURED IN 1914 Ehe Royal Union Mutual Life Insurance Company oi rew from tbe state at the expiration of their lie ■&gt; because of the practical prohibition by the toMmaea Code of r semi-tontine dividend policies. ■fhe Western Life Indemnity Company of Chicago, an association, was refused a NMVtl of M cial condition. The Pacific ( i.tlty Cmtpai I Francisco was r&lt; i-f license because of its financial condition and the extreme limitations of its accident and sickness policies used in tiki* his bein only kind of business transacted by this company in Nebraska K'he Farmers Life Insurance Company of Denver wa ie for the reason that it seemed to the department that the con ; operating principally for the purpose of selling its capital ■ r than for the legitimate transaction of the life insurance business. I This company is incorporated with an authorized capital of $1,000,006. led into 333,335 shares at $3. On par. The selling price &gt;■ llt.M per e, $3.00 of which is credited to capital stock &lt;&lt;nd $ nses, to premium on capital stock. Tbe surplus paid in by - erg was, as it appeared to us. being used in an extravagant way. not for the purpose of transacting life insurance by conservath ■ imate methods. \ Ehe company succeeded in obtaining a restraining order from i States court preventing the Insurance Board from interfering with siness in this state, and has. we are informed, continued its trans - s in this state without a license from the Insurance Board. Ehe Western Life &amp; Accident Company of Denver was refused a al of its license because it refused to report a reserve liability on me basis that is required of Nebraska companies transacting a r business. The State Insurance Company of Nebraska, of Omaha, reinsured its business in the National Fire Insurance Company of Hartford ■The Title Guaranty and Surety Company of Sorauion. Penn.. r red its business in the American Surety Company erf N&gt;« York. K'he Nebraska Mutual Life Insurance Company of Hastings NVbr jred its risks in the Mutual Protective League a ■I 1. 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 K1RST BIKNNIAL RKI'ORT OK The Central National Life Insurance Company, of Lincoln, Nebraska, a mutual legal www life company, has been capitalized. Capital stock COMPANIES ADMITTED DURING THE YEAR 1914 FIRE COMPANIES drain Dealers Mutual tire Ins. Co.. Indianapolis. Ind March 21, 1914. ■Brunswick Fire Ins. Co.. New Brunswick. N. J. Captial stock $ larch 21, 1914. Globe ft Rutgers Pin Ins. Co.. New York, N. Y. Capital stock $4 July 9, 1914. County Fire Ins. Co.. Philadelphia. Pa. Capital stock. $4im.nm November 14. 1914. LIFE COMPANIES Old Colony Ufe Ins. Co.. Chicago. 111. Capital stock. I11C.301.87 May 26. 1914 MISCELLANEOUS COMPANIES Georgia Casualty Co.. Macon. Ca. Captal stock 13 October 16, 1914. Biic Protective Assn.. VVoreesUr. Mass. Capital stock. $100.0' ovember 21. 1914. COMPANIES ORGANIZED Farmers Assessment Tornado Ins. Assn.. Wahoo. Nebr May 2, 1914. ■raska Hail Insurance Company. Lincoln. Net May 7, 1914. ■ners' Co-operative Hail Ins. Co.. Grand Island. Nel March 20. 1914 r)UNT OF MONEY RECEIVED FOR FEES AND TAXES. AND PAH) TO STATE TREASURER FOR THE GENERAL FUND JANUARY 1, 1913, TO DECEMBER 1, 1914 Kint previously reported to Deo. 1. 1913.. ived from Dec. 1. 1913, to Dec. 1. 1914 — ...$145.589 67 1 17 Filing Annual Statements Agents' Licenses Taxes 92.296 60 Admission of Companies 3300* Other Fees . . 196.43 Annual Statements— Reciprocal Agents' Lionises — Hf </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THK 8TATE IN8VRANI E HdAUli 21 Other Ft lpr Taxes — Recii&gt;] Sheriffs' Fees Miscellaneous T surer FINANCIAL STATEMENT ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914 SALARY OF INSURANCE COMMISSIONER 125. 1914 L. Q. Bian II, 1!U4 L. O. Bian 28, 1914 L. Q. Brian 25, 1914 L. Q. Hrian 26, 1914 L. G. Brian 30. 1914 L. G. Brian 29, 1914 L. G. Brian 29, 1914 L. G. Brian 28, 1914 I* G. Brian 28, 1914 L. G. Brian To balance Dec. I, 1914 SALARY OF BOOKKEEPER II, 1914 Balance of appropr 31, 1914 Lillian E. Pet. 25, 1914 Lillian E. Pet. 31, 1914 Lillian E. Peters 28, 1914 Lillian E. Pet 25, 1914 Liilian E. Peters 26, 1914 Lillian E. Pet 31. 1!U4 Lillian E. Peters 29, 1914 Lilian E. Peters 29, 1914 Lillian E. Pet 28, 1914 Lillian E. Peter - 2X. 1914 Lillian E. Peters . . ioi ■ To balance Dec. 1. 1 HI 4 SALARY OF STENOGRAPHER Feb. 25, 1914 Maynetta Marks Mar. 31. 1914 Maynetta Marks Apr. 28, 1914 Maynetta M;irks May 25, 1914 Maynetta Marks June 26. 1914 Maynetta Marks July 30, 1914 Maynetta Marks Aug. 29, 1914 Maynetta Marks Sept. 29, 1914 Maynetta Marks Oct. 28. 1914 Maynetta Marks Nov 28 1914 Manett Total (!*•[&gt;( ' ■ 1, 1914 Balance of appropriation 31, 1914 L. G. Bri. ■ 1, 1914 Balance of appropriation 31, 1914 Maynetta Marks </seg>
            <seg id="p022">ill 058.71 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT () OFFICE EXPENSE! Jan. 1, 1914 Balance of appropriation Jan. 2. 1914 Lincoln City Directory * ti.Oi Jan. 7, 1914 American Express Co 57.4i 57.41 2 7! Jan. 7, 1914 State Journal, supplies . . . 2.81 Jan. 7, 1914 Harry Porter, supplies 7.3i Jan. 7. 1914 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. C&lt; Jan. 9. 1914 Jan. 12, 1914 Jan. 13. 1914 Jan. 14, 1914 Jan. 14. 1914 Jan. 15, 1914 Jan. 21. 1914 Jan. 22. 1914 Jan. 31, 1914 Feb. 3, 1914 Feb. 3. 1914 Feb. 4. 1914 Feb. 4. 1914 Feb. 24. 1914 Feb. 25. 1914 Mar. 2, 1914 Mar. 2. 1914 Mar. 2. 1914 Mar. 4. 1914 Mar. 4. 1914 Mar. 6. 1914 Mar. 11. 1914 Mar. 13, 1914 Mar. 23. 1914 Mar. 24, 1914 Mar. 25. 1914 Mar. 26. 1914 Mar. 26, 1914 Mar. 31. 1914 Mar. 31. 1914 Mar. 31, 1914 Mar. 31. 1914 Mar. 31, 1914 Apr. 1, 1914 Apr. 2. 1914 Apr. 3. 1914 Apr. 8. 1914 Apr. U. 1914 Apr. 14. 1914 Apr. 13, 1914 Apr. 27. 1914 Apr. 27. 1914 Apr. 28. 1914 Apr. 2K. 1914 Apr. 28. 1914 May 1. 1914 May 2. 1914 May 4. 1914 May 5. 1914 May 5. 1914 May 7. 1914 May 7 1*14 H. S. Wiggins, actuary State Ptg. Co. (An. St. Blanks) State Journal, supplies Enterprise Planing Mill, repairs Star Van &amp; Stor Western Union Tel. Co State Journal Co.. ptg Underwood Type. Co.. repairs May E. Sharpe, extra help American Express Harry Porter, supplies Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. Co Postal Tel. &amp; Cable Co H. S. Wiggins, actuary May E. Sharp, extra help American Express Co Office Equipment &amp; Supply, supplies. Brandton Ptg. Co.. An. Stat. Blanks. . Bessie E. Kaup. extra help Kudge &amp;Guenzel Postal Tel. &amp; Cable Co Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. Co Burroughs Add. Machine Lincoln Ptg. Co.. mailing env L. G. Brian, expenses Kearney Illinois Ptg. Co.. abstracts Maud Grossenbach. extra help Claflin Ptg. Co.. ptg. laws May Sharpe, extra help Mrs. M. Fairchild. extra help B. B. Mann, extra help State Journal Co.. letter heads Sanitary Towel Co Harry Porter, supplies H. S. Wiggins, actuary. Feb Jacob North &amp; Co.. ptg. rept. . Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. Co H. S. Wiggins, actuary. Mar Folsom Bros.. Wiggins bond . . Office Equip. &amp; Supply Emily L. Brian, extra help Elenor M. Draper, extra help B. B. Mann, extra help * . . . . M. Fairchild. extra help May Sharpe. extra help Brandton Ptg. Co Harry Porter, supplies American Express Postal Tel. &amp; Cable Co Jacob North &amp; Co., ptg G. O. Hearn, postage Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. Co 337.50 18.00 3.35 4.75 . 7.67 .68 74.84 2.00 67.50 .83 6.35 I.M 348.75 57.50 .83 6.60 ::26.98 2.5H 3.00 1.48 8.15 .".en. 5i) 43.00 5.75 5.80 20.00 416.16 36.00 35.00 I'll. (Ml 35.88 3.75 9.6:. 182.50 85.65 7.50 :!45.0i&gt; 25.00 6.50 1 li.OO 16.25 K.oe 65.00 H.M I.M 3.10 -in 1.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">- . 1 .\ 1 r* 1 .N . i K.\.M r- nUAnl' 1914 State Ptg. Co., ptg. po. Hay 1914 Eaton Fry Co.. ribbon. . . . :i 1914 Eaton Fry Co.. ribbon State Journal, license blank May 11 1914 State Journal, license blank 44,21 1914 44.:'i! May 25, 1914 M. Sharpe, extra help 1914 M. Sharpe, extra help ... «5 0( May 25, 1914 M. Fairehild, extra helj 1914 M. Fairehild, extra help. May 1914 B. B. Mann, extra help 1914 B. B. Mann, extra help June l 1914 Abb landis. book ... in. oi June 1 1914 Harry Porter, supplu •jr, June 6 1914 Jacob North &amp; Co., pts. June 1914 Postal Teleg. Co 8J N xr. June s 1914 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. Co. 1914 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. Co. Western Union Tel. Co. . . Eaton Fry Co., typewriter ribbon State Journal Co., envelop* - June 13 1914 Western Union Tel. ( 1 LH 1H 14 1.14 June it; 1914 Eaton Fry Co., typewriter ribbons. . . 24. 0&lt; 1914 24.0&lt;l June 26 1914 State Journal Co., envelopes. 1914 June 26 1914 M. Fairehild 50 June 29 1914 H. S. Wiggins, actuary, Ma&gt; . June 29, 1914 Lillian E. Peters, exp. Fremonr 1914 Lillian E. Peters, exp. Fremonr June 29 1914 Minnie Seyhoid, extra help 1501 15.00 July 1914 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. Co. s July 17 1914 H. S. Wiggins, actuary. .Jin; . 1914 H. S. Wiggins, actuary. .Jim luly 1914 Western Union Tel 1914 Western Union Tel July 30, 1914 L. G. Biian, exp. Omaha and K- 1914 L. G. Biian, exp. Omaha and F- Jul.v 30. 1914 If. Fairchild, extra hel 1914 M. Fairehild. exna help July 1914 G. O. Hearn, post ,1. lon.ui 10 Allg 1914 Harry Porter, su; 9.1(1 1914 V. P. R. R.. mil. ; - Aug Aug. 5. 1914 Office Eqpip. At Supply, Buppl'ei 1914 Office Eqpip. &amp; Supply, Buppl'ei Aug. t, 1914 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. C 1914 Lincoln Tel. &amp;■ Telt m Aug 1914 Rudge &amp; Guenzel. suppliei 1914 Rudge &amp; ( ■t &gt;plic Aug 1914 M. FairchlW, supplies 1914 M Fairchild I 1914 Gee Durbin, postage 1914 1914 H. S. Wiggins. kCtomr] .luh 1. 1914 H. S. Wiggins, actuary. Juh gi7i .'1 1. 1914 L. 0. Brian, exp. Ansley and Fn 1914 L. G. Brian, exp. Ansley and Fremont 1914 H. S. Wiggins, actuary. Aug 1914 H. S. Wi niaiy. Aug 1914 Adams Kxpr 1914 Adams l^xjiress 11H4 Minnie E. Bey bold, extra help '14 1« t 1914 Harry Porter, sup] ■ 1914 Harry 1 .ippiie Sept 1914 Lincoln Tel. *.- Telei; 1914 Li Tel. Tel 10. 1914 Office Equip. &lt;fc Supply, guppll 1914 Office Equip. &amp; Supply, lappltei t Sept. 12, 1914 G. W. Bonnell. H. R. fare. L O. Brian. 44 60 l 1914 G. W. Bonnell. R. R. fare. L. O. Brian. 44 61 88, 1914 Western Union Tel. C 1914 Western Union Tel. Co. . 8 1914 L. O. Brian, exp. Ashvillt Columbus, Ohio Sept. 29. 1914 L. O. Brian, exp. Ashville. N I umbu Ohi 29, 1914 Sanitary Towel Co 1914 Sanitary Towel Co 4.51 1914 Spectator Co., books Iii.imi 1914 P Si C&lt; books 10.00 Sept. 30, 1914 H. 8. Wiggins, actuarv 1914 H. S. Wiggins, actuary Sept. 30, 1914 M. Fairchild, extra he 1914 M. Fairchild, extra help . Sept Oct 1914 Adams Express Co 1914 Adams Express Co [i Oct. 12, 1914 M. McUerraott. extra heli 1914 M. McDerraott. extra help 11.25 Oct 1 1914 Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teleg. Co. 730 1914 15 1914 Western Union Tel. Co Oct. 20. 1914 Folsom Bros.. Wiggins bond Oct 1914 Spectator Co., fees and tax book Oct. 27, 1914 H. E. Trelevan. roll for machine Oct :u 1914 Hammond Ptg. Co., ptg. summari M. Faircliild, extra help Underwood Typewriter I Harry Porter, supplies Lincoln Tel. &amp; Teli - 716.10 Oct ;i 1914 17.50 Nov 1914 1.00 Nov fi. 1914 1914 ()&lt;t </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nov. 9, 1914 Alfred M. Best, life report book Nov. 12, 1914 H. S. Wiggins,, actuary, Oct. 202.50 18. 1914 Office Equip. &amp; Supply, supplies 4.00 Nov. 25, 1914 State Journal Co., ledger 28.25 -v 1914 M. Fairchild, extra help 2H.7", To balance :J, 734.64 $1 1 CASH FUND Balance January 1,1914 * 134.95 Balance carried forward from 1912 193.4m Per diem and expenses examining insurance compa panles. etc Mli.74 $ 8 ■ DISBURSEMENTS C. 1914 C. S. Clayton, expenses. I 44.30 12, 1914 J. W. Jones, Jr., salary 166.66 15, 1914 G. W. Bonnell, mileage 40.00 19, 1914 C. S. Clayton, salary 166.68 Feb. 2. 1914 C. S. Clayton, expense 77.70 2. 1914 J. W. Jones, Jr., expense. 71.15 Feb. 24. 1914 J. W. Jones, salary 166.68 Feb. 24, 1914 C. S. Clayton, salary 16C.66 2. 1914 B. H. Wiggins, extra help. . B. H. Wiggins, extra help. . B. H. Wiggins, extra help. . B. H. Wiggins, extra help. . B. H. Wiggins, extra help.. B. H. Wiggins, extra help. . B. H. Wiggins, extra help. 2. 1914 24.65 2. 1914 39.25 2, 1914 90.20 2. 1914 15.00 2, 1914 25.00 2. 1914 Mar. 2. 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help 30.00 2, 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help. . ::s.4:, 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help.. 25.45 2, 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help. . 15.00 2. 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help. . 30.00 2, 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help. . 89.75 2, 1914 C. K. Pierce, extra help. . 1 15.00 Mar. 3,1914 C. S. Clayton, salary 1M.M 3. 1914 C. S. Clayton, expenses. . 52.10 3. 1914 J. W. Jones. Jr.. salary 166.66 Mar. 3.1914 J. W. Jones, Jr., salary 166.66 1914 J. W. Jones, Jr., expenses 51.50 4. 1914 &lt;;. W. Bonnell. mileage 40.00 Mar. 9, 1914 H. S. Wiggins, actuary.... 81.50 7. 1914 B. H. Wigg'ns, extra help 20.00 7. 1914 B. H. Wiggins, extra help. B. H. Wiggins, extra help. B. H. Wiggins, extra help. B. H. Wiggins, extra help. 2H. mi 7. 1914 35.00 7, 1914 45.00 10, 1914 52.14 10, 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help. . 10. 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help. . 45.00 Mar. 10, 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help Mar. 10, 1914 C. E. Pierce, extra help 35.00 Mar. 31, 1914 J. W. Jones, Jr., salary 166.68 J. W. Jones. Jr., expenses 41.85 31. 1!»14 Apr. 1, 1914 H. S. Wiggins, actuary 42.60 Apr. 1. 1914 C. S. Clayton, expenses 42.80 Apr. 1.1914 C. S. Clayton, salary 166.68 4. 1914 Cm R I &amp; P R R- mileage. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">■ Apr. 4. 1914 H. 8. Wiggins, actuary . Apr. IS, 1914 Minnie Seybold, extra he\\&gt; Apr U, 1914 Jl. S. Wiggins, actuarj ".. 1914 C. 8. Clayton, expenses Apr. 25. 1914 C. S. Clayton, expenses Apr. 29, 1914 .1. \V. Jones. Jr.. expert tlil May 2, 1914 .1. W. Jones. Jr.. salar\ J. 1914 ('. S Clayton, salary. .... 1914 C. 8. Clayton, expenses _.'&gt;, 1914 J. W. Jcnes, Jr.. expen&gt; ft, 1914 C. S Clayton, salary IT. 1914 .1 W. Jones. Jr.. salary... 17, 1914 H. S. Wiggins*, actuary.. J5. 1914 J. \V. Jones. Jr.. expens ft, 1914 C. S Clayton, salary 17. 1914 J. W. Jones. Jr.. salary 1914 il Wiggins, actuary June 22, 1914 C. S. Clayton, exi • June 22, 1914 C. S. Clayton, exi June 29. 1914 .1. \V. Jones. Jr.. nptmmm June 29. 1914 .1. W. Jones. Jr.. exp. June 29, 1914 J. W. Jones, Jr., salary.. June 29, 1914 J. W Jones, Jr.. salary June 29, 1914 C. 8. Clayton, expense^ JH 1914 June 29, 1914 C. S. Clayton, salary. J9. 1914 J. W. Jones. Jr., mileage Inly 14. 1914 yton. mileage 29 1914 M, 1914 J. \V. Jones. Jr., mileage 14 1914 .luly 16, 1914 C. S. Clayton, el] 1«, 1914 July 16, 1914 J. \V. Jones. Jr.. expen^. &gt; Hi. 1914 July 17, 1914 H. B. Wiggins. actuar&gt; 17 1914 July 30. 1914 J. W. Jones, Jr.. salary. 1914 July II, 1914 C. S. Clayton, salary 31 1914 Aug 11. 1914 .1. \V. Jones. Jr., expen- B, 1914 C. S. Clayton, expenses. . . . ;l. li»14 J. W. Jones. Jr.. salary.. 11 1914 Aug. 22. 1914 C. S. C ■ i 'i i ;;i 1914 Aug. 31, 1914 J. \V. Jones. Jr.. expen- Aug. 31. 1914 J. \V. Jones. Jr.. expt- 1 Aug. 31, 1914 C. S Clayton, salary u Aug. 31, 1914 H 8. Wiggins, actuary . 8. 1914 C. S. Clayton, expense 33.25 s J8, 1914 Q. W. Bcnnell. mileage. Clayton.. 28 Sept. 28, 1914 C. S. Clayton, expense... U9, 1914 H. S. Wiggins, actuary.. 2S 9 Sept. 30, 1914 C. S. Clayton, salary :!0, 1914 C. S. Clayton, sal Clayton, salary Oct. 2, 1914 J. W. Jones. Jr.. e ]&gt;• 2. 1914 J. W. Jones. Jr., salary. . 1914 1914 Oct 28, 1914 J. W. Jones, Jr.. salary 28 1914 Oct. 29. 1914 C. 8. Clayton, salary 1914 .1 \V. Jones, Jr., mileage 1914 ( Clayton, salary. Nov. -11. 1914 J. W. Jones, Jr., expt Nov. 27. 1914 J. W. Jones, Jr.. salary Tota </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 FIRST BIKNXIAL REPORT OK LEGAL SECURITIES DEPOSITED WITH STATE INSURANCE BOARD BY THE DOMESTIC INSURANCE COMPANIES IftES AND ADDRESS OF ALL INSURANCE COMPANIES AUTHORIZED TO TRANSACT BUSINESS IN NEBRASKA, JANUARY 1, 1915 STOCK FIRE INSURANCE COMPANIES Aachen k Munich Fire. New York, N. Y Hartford, Conn. Agricultural Watertown, N. Y Alliance Assurance . . New York, N. Y Bankers Life Ins. Co., Lincoln $108- Bankers Reserve Life Co., Omaha 104,200.00 Central National Life Ins. Co., Lincoln . Columbia Life Ins. Co.. Fremont 106.010.00 39,800.00 Commonwealth Life Ins. Co., Omaha ... 106' Klkhorn Lifp t? Accident Co., Norfolk 101.100.00 German American Life Ins. Co.. Omaha 100 . Guarantee Fund Life Assn.. Omaha. . . BM Midwest Life Ins. Co., Lincoln IM Prairie Life Ins. Co.. Omaha 111 600.00 Security .Mutual Life Ins. Co.. Lincoln 100.700.00 Scandinavian Mutual Life Assn.. Minden " MISCELLANEOUS COMPANIES Automobile Muiiial Ins. Co.. Omaha * I American Accident Ins. Co.. Lincoln. 1 00,095.00 Home Casualty Ins. Co.. Omaha. . . Lincoln Accident Ins. Co., Lincoln. . . 4 Lion Bonding &amp; Surety Co., Omaha . . I I National Accident Ins. Co., Lincoln. 11 t\ Fidelity &amp; Casualty Co.. Omaha H ■ Old Line Accident Ins. Co.. Lincoln. . . Union Accident Ins. Co.. Lincoln. . 10,002.85 Western Indemnity Co., Omaha. . . 5.000.00 Woodmen Accident Assn.. Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Imericaa Druggists Kirt Cincinnati Ckktn, ill Anglo-American Reinsurain Assurance . . New York, N Y Hoston. Mm* Toronto. Can Bih American Assuran lo German Buffalo. N V Ionian \V\v York. X Voik N V ( amden Fire Ins. Association., i aimifii. N I Citizens St. Louis. Ma of New York New Yak. M Louis. Md New York N Y Columbia I. rm ) &lt; ity. &gt; lonimercial Union Assurance. . New York. N Vork. N Y Commercial Union Fire New York. N New York N I New York N Y Commonwealth NVw York. N ( ( ncordia Fire Mil'.vauk Milwaukee. Wih ( ontinental . New York. N New York. N. Y Connecticut Fire ford. Conn Kty Fire Ins. Co que Fire. &amp; Marine. . . . able Fire and Marine Philadelph a. Penn Dubuque. la 1'rovidence. K. I Farmers I todar Kapids. la Federal Jersey City. N. .1 Fidelity-Phemx Fire New York X. V Fire Association of Philadelphia. Firemens Philadelphia. Penn Newark. N. J Kiremen's Fund San Francisco, Cal Franklin Fire Philadelphia. Penn General Fire Assurance New York. N. Y German Alliance New York. N Y &lt; ierman-American New Ycrk. N. Y Germania Fire New Ycrk. N Y Girard Fire and Marine Philadelphia. Penn Glens Falls Glens Falls. N. Y Globe &amp; Rutgers Fire Ins. Co New York N. Y Hamburg-Bremen Fire New York. N. Y Hanover Fire New York Hartford Fire Hartford. Conn Home New York N. Y Imperial Assurance Co New York. N Y Indemnity Mutual Marine New York. N Y Insurance Co. of North America Philadelphia Penn Insurance Co. of State of Pennsylvania Philadelphia Penn Law, Union &amp; Rock New York N Y Liverpool &amp; London &amp; Globe. England Chicago. Ill Liverpoor &amp;. London &amp; Globe, New York New Ycrk. N Y London Assurance Corporation New York. N Y London Sc Lancashire Fire New Ycrk. N Y Mannbeim New Ycrk. N V </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK unics Philadelphia. IVnn Mechanics and Traders New Orleans. La Michigan Commercial Lansing, Mich Milwaukee Mechanics Milwaukee. Wis Minneapolis Fire nad Marine Minneapol s. Minn National Fire Hartford, Conn. National-Ben Franklin Pittsburg. Penn Nationale Fire Providence. R. National Union Fire Pittsburg, Penn Netherlands Fire and Life Chicago, 111. New Brunswick Fire New Brunswick, N J New Hampshire Fire Manchester. N. H Newark Fire Newark, S. .1 Niagara Fire New York. N. Y Nord-Dutche Fire New York. N. Y North British &amp; Mercantile New York. N. Y North British and Mercantile Ins. Co New York. N. Y North River New York. N. Y Northern Assurance New York,. N. Y. Northwestern Fire and Marine Minneapdis. Minn Northwestern National Milwaukee. Wis Norwich Union Fire New York N. Y Old Colony Boston. Mass Orient Hartford. Conn Palatine New York. N. Y IVnnsylvania Fire Philadelphia. Penn Peoples National Philadelphia. Penn Phenix Fire Providence. R. I Phoenix Hanford, Conn Phoenix Assurance Co New York, N. Y Providence Washington Providence R. I Prussian National Chicago, 111 Queen Ins. Co. of America New York. N. Y Reliance Philadelphia Penn Rhode Island Providence. R. I Royal Chicago. Ill Royal Exchange Assurance New York. N. Y Scottish Union &amp; National Hartford, Coun. Security New Haven, Conn Springfield Fire and Marine Springfield. Maw. Standard Fire Hartford Conn. St. Paul Fire and Marine St. Paul, Minn. Sun Insurance Office New York. N. T Svea Fire and Life New York N. Y Union Fire Providence. R. I Union Marine New York. N. Y. i'nited States Fire New York N. Y ' ern Assurance Company Toronto. Can. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">THK STATE INSURANCE HOARD 29 New York Williamsburg City Fire . Brooklyn. N V MUTUAL FIRE. TORNADO AND HAIL INSURANCE COMPANIES Automobile Mutual Omaha. Neb Capital Fire Mutual Lincoln. Neb Federated Merchants Mutual Omaha Neb. (irain Dealers National Mutual Fire . Philadelphia IVnn Miller* Mutual Fire . Alton. 111. .fillers National Fire . Chicago. Ill National Hail Mutual . Lincoln, Neb Nebraska Hardware Mutual... .Lincoln, Neb Ketail Merchants Mutual Fire . Omaha, Neb Union Fire Mutual Lincoln Neb ASSESSMENT HAIL AND PLATE GLASS INSURANCE COMPANIES Farn.ers Co-operative Hail National Plate Glass Grand Island. Falls City, Neb Nebraska Hail Lincoln. Neb ASSESSMENT FIRE AND TORNADO INSURANCE COMPANIES Antelope Co. Farmers Mutual. ... Neligh, Neb Battle Creek Mutual Battle Creek. Neb Boone Co. Farmers Mutual Albion. Neb. Boyd Co. Farmers Mutual . Naper. Neb Cedar Co. German Farmers Mut. Fire Clay Co. Mutual . Hartington, Neb. Clay Center, Neb E&gt;n Co. Farmers Mutual ester Farmers Mutual ing House Mutual Central Mutual Fire.. . Lexington. Neb. . Dorchester, Neb. . Lincoln. Neb. Hastings. Neb Farmers Alliance F. &amp; L. Mutual Aurora. Neb Farmers Assessment Tornado . . Wahoo. Neb Farmers Mutual F. &amp; L. of Burt Co Craig. Neb. Farmers Mutual of Thayer Co . Carleton, Neb Farmers Mutual of Geneva . Fairmont. Neb Farmers Mutual Ins. Assn. of Dodge Co Ames, Neb. Farmers Mutual Home Hooper, Neb Farmers Mutual Home Tornado Hooper. Neb Farmers Mutual of Buffalo Co Kearney, Neb Farmers Mutual of Nebraska Lincoln. Neb. Farmers Mut. of Burt, ('timing and Dodge Cos Oakland. Neb Farmers Mut. of Madison, Pierce. Wayne ami Stanton Norfolk Neb. r armers Mut. Fire of Madison. Platte and Stanton Madison. Neb Farmers Mutual of Plymouth . Plymouth. Neb Farmers Mutual Fire and Live Stock . Plattsmcuth, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">I BIENNIAL REPORT OF 30 Farmers Mutual of Saunders County hmm Mutual of Scotts Bluff Co.. . Farmers Mutual of Wausa S-'eottsbluff. Neb Wausa. Neb Farmers Mutual of York County Farmers Union Mutual York. Neb Fremont Neb KYanklin. Neb Kklin County Farmers Mutual as Co. Farmers Mutual Co. F. &amp; L., T. &amp; C. Mutual lan Fanners Mutual Beaver City. Neb Blue Springs. Neb Colon. Neb. Klkhorn. Neb German Farmers Mutual Fire. German Farmers Mutual of Sarpy Co.. German Farmers Mat. Ins. Association German Farmers Mut. Fire of York Co. German Mutual of Dodge Co Seward. Neb York, Neb. Scribner. Neb German Mutual Fire of Nemaha Co. and Vicinity. German Mutual of Saline and Seward Counties. . Grunge and Farmers Mutual Johnson. Neb. Milford. Neb. Blaii. Neb. Grange Mutual of Custer County Hammond Precinct Mutual Broken Bow, Neb Haven pot. Neb Jefferson County Mutual Diller, Neb. Minden, Neb Bennett. Neb Kirth, Neb. Kearney County Farmers Mutual.. Lancaster County Farmers Mutual. Lancaster &amp; Gage Farmer., Mutual . Leigh German Farmers Mutual Madison Co. Farmers Mutual Mutual Proiective Fire Aasn Leigh, Neb. Battle Creek, Neb Seward, Neb. Nebraska Lumbermen's Mutual Ins. Assn.. Nebraska Mutual Lincoln. Neb Lincoln. Neb Nemaha Co. Farmers Mut. F. &amp; L. North Nebraska Mutual Tornado. . Nuckclls Co. Farmers Mutual . Auburn. Neb . Norfolk, Neb . Nelson, Neb. Nysted Farmers Mutual Pawnee County Mutual Dannebrog, Neb. Pawnee City, Neb Holdrege, Neb. Phelps Co. Farmers Mut. F. tt L. Pierce Co. Farmers Mutual Pierce, Neb. Platte Mutual Plattsmouth. Neb Osceola, Neb. Polk &amp; Butler Co. Farmers Mutual Richardson Co. Farmers Mutual. . ■ Roman Catholic Farmers Mutual. . Scandinavian Mut. F.. L. &amp; T Scandinavian Mut. Live Stock. . . . State Farmers Mutual Falls City, Neb Petersburg. Neb Axtell, Neb. South Omaha, Neb Adams. Neb. Sterling Farm Mutual Svea Mut. Ins. Assn.. . Malmo, Neb. Kennard. Neb Wilber. Neb. Kgton Co. Scandinavian Mut. 1 Union Mut. Ins. Assn.... (Jretna, Neb Axtell, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">STOCK LEGAL RESERVE LIFE INSURANCE COMPANIES MUTUAL LEGAL RESERVE LIFE INSURANCE COMPANIES Lincoln. Xeb Fremont. Nc h Columbia Life Eiecticut Mutual Lif€ orn Life &amp; Accidei lity Mutual Life. . . lan American Life Hartford Con Norfolk, Neb. . Philadelphia. 1'* . Omaha. Xeb. LaFayette Life Kachusetts Mutual Life esota Mutual Life .... . . St. Paul. Minn. . . Newark. N. J. . . New York, N V . . Montpelver. Vt . . Boston. Mass. Kal Benefit Life al Life Xational Life New England Mutual Life 1'nion Central I Hankers Life of Ues M (Vntral National Life . . LaFayette. Ind . Springfield. Ml </seg>
            <seg id="p032">KIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK 32 New York Life. New York. N. Y Northwestern Mutual Life Milwaukee, Wis. Northwestern National Li!e Penn Mutual Life Minneapolis. Minn Philadelphia. Penn Pbcenix Mutual Life . Scandia Life Hartford. Conn Chicago. Ill Security Mutual Life Lincoln. Neb Security Mutual Life Binghamton. N. Y State Life Indianapolis, lnd State Mutual Life Assurance Worcester. Mass Union Mutual Life Portland, Me ASSESSMENT LIFE ASSOCIATIONS Fidelity Life Association of Nebra ka Lexington. Neb Guarantee Fund Life Association Omaha. Neb Illinois Bankers Life Assr. . . Monmouth. Ill . . Burlington. It. Merchants Life Assn. National Life Association Des Moinea, la Prime of Life Ins. Association Omaha, Neb. Minden. Neb Omaha. Neb. Scandinavian Mutual Aid Assn. Western Life Indemnity CASUALTY, SURETY AND MISCELLANEOUS COMPANIES Aetna Accident and Liability Hartford. Conn Aetna Life Hartford. Conn. American Bonding Baltimore Md American Casualty Reading. Penn American Credit Indemnity New York, N. Y American Fidelity Montpelier, Vt American Mutual Surety Lincoln, Neb. American Surety New York, N. Y Casualty Co. of America New York. N. Y Chicago Bonding Chicago, 111 Continental Casualty Chicago, 111 Employers' Mutual Liability Ins. Co. of Neb Omaha, Neb. Employers Liability Assurance Corporation, Ltd... Boston, Mass Equitable Surety St. Louis, Mo Fidelity £ Casualty New York, N. Y Fidelity &amp; Deposit Baltimore. Md. Frankfort General New York, N. Y Frontier Accident Lincoln. Neb. General Accident, Fire &amp; Life Corp Philadelphia, Penn Georgia Casualty Co Macon. Ga Globe Indemnity New York. N. Y Great Eastern Casualty New York. N. Y Great Western Accident Des Moines. la </seg>
            <seg id="p033">TMK STATK INSURANCE HCAKh Hartford Steam Boiler Inspection Home Casualty ... Omaha. Neb. Illinois Surety . Chicago. Ill Indiana &amp; Ohio Live Stock Inter-Ocean Casualty . Crawfordsville. Imi . Lincoln. Neb Kansas City Casualty Lincoln Accident . . . Omaha. Neu Lion Bonding &amp; Surety Lloyds Plate Glass . . . . New York. N. Y Chicago. 111. London Guarantee *&gt;• AccHent Co Loadon &amp; Lancashire Guarantee &amp; Accident Maryland Casualty New York. N. Y Baltimore. Md Wcrce.-ter Muss Boston. M, Masonic Protective 4M Massachusetts Bonding . Klronolitan Casualty . . lional Accident New York. N Y Lincoln. Neb National Fidelity &amp; C'asu illy National Life U. S. A National Surety New York N Y Boston. Mass. Newark. N. I. New York N Y Chicago. 111. New England Casualty New Jersey Fidelity &amp; Plate Glass New York Plate Glass North American Accident Northwestern Live Stock. r,n Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp Line Accident Pacific Mutual Life Pioneer Preterred Accident Reliance Life Pittsburg. Penn Muskogee Ok la Denison. Tex. Detroit, Mich. Indianapolis. I nil Hartford. Conn Hartford. Conn Lincoln. Neb. Southern Surety Southwestern Surety Standard Accident .. Standard Live Stock Travelers Travelers Indemnity L'nion Accident . . . Union Casualty Casualty . Philadelphia. Penn . New York. N I ■ delity &amp; Guaranty ealth &amp; Accident . a Indemnity Baltimore. Mr Saginaw. Mich Omaha Neb. ASSESSMENT HEALTH AND ACCIDENT ASSOCIATIONS American Accident Lincoln. Neb. Bankers Accident Des Moines. la Brotherhood of All Railway Employees Chicago. Ill Omaha. Neb Chicago. III. Moines, la. New Ycrk. N Y Lincoln. Neb. Lcs Ans*tes, i Lincoln. Neb. New York X. Y </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 . •• As Fraternal Protective Assn. . . . Boston. Mass. Moines, la Omaha, Neb. Eideiu Bnefit Health &amp; Accident As ka Workmen Accident I 'asualry Assn :i ia Aurora. Neb. Omaha. Xeb. Omaha, Xeb. Wailali. Maa Omaha. Neb. I i;in* Health Assn. of Amerii Fra'ernai Accident. . . Krs Health Association . . i Travelers Accident Ass en Accident Assn nuil n. Neb ■ FRATERNAL BENEFICIARY ASS CIATICNS tor Lutherans- A o U. W Etherhood of American Yeomen . of Locomotive Firemen &amp; Engineniei . of Railroad Trainmen Cleveland. O. St. Lea Chicago, 111. K Knights of America Order of Fore I Workmen New Prague atin Springfield, ill. Court of Honor Banish Bro. in America Omaha, Neb. Lincoln, Neb. Lawrence, Kat Toronto. Can Chicago, 111. I&gt;egree of Honor. A. O. C W Fraternal Aid Union Independent Order of Fore&gt; Indepentent Order of Vikings. Knights of Columbus New Haven. Conn Topeka. Kan. Knights &amp; Ladies of Security Knights of the Maccabees cf the World Knights of Pythias Detroit. Mich Indianapolis. Ind. Port Huron. Mich Port Huron, Mich Columbus, O. Eof the Maccabees cf the World of the Modern Maccabees. . . . Auxiliary to Bro. of Railroad T Loyal Mystic Legion Trainmen Hastings, Neb. Mason City, Ia Reck Island, II Des Moines, Ia Fulton, 111. Modern Bro. of America Modern Wocdmen of America Mystic Toilers Mystic Workers of the World National Fraterial Society of the Deaf National Union Chicago, 111 Toledo, O. Chicago, 111 Polish National Alliance Railway Mail Assn . Portsmouth, N. H . Ft. Madison. Ia. . Boston, Mass. Roman Catholic Mut. Protective Society Royal Arcanum Appleton, Wis. fiawfordsvllli .Grand Island, Neb lines. la. Peoria. III. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">b Aurora. Neb Royal Highlanders Royal League Chicago, 111 Royal Neighbors of America Rock Island. N Sons of Herman Columbus. Neb United Commercial Travelers of America Colum rn Bohemian Catholic Union. ... Spillville. la rn Bohemian Fraternal Assn Cedar Kas Woodmen Circle • • Omah Woodmen of the World </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>