<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>UNIT ELECTRIC PLANTS FOR NEBRASKA FARMS:  A SURVEY OF PRESENT CONDITIONS AND A STUDY OF TYPES OF PLANTS</title>
               <date value="1929-05">1929-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 235 May7 1929 UNIT ELECTRIC PLANTS FOR NEBRASKA FARMS A SURVEY OF PRESENT CONDITIONS AND A STUDY OF TYPES OF PLANTS E. E. Hii.vckktt and E. B. Lewis Agricultural Emrinccrinir Department * THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS ■ Summary '. 4 Introductory , c Distribution of plants 5 Sources of material..: G Battery-type plants „ 7 Summary of questionnaire reports on plants 7 Sizes of plants 7 Cost of plants ■_ 7 Age of plants, fuel, fuel-consumption, and uses of electricity 8 Makes of plants. ; _; g Cost of repairs g The storage battery 9 Length of life and uses of storage batteries 10 Two sizes of batteries compared 12 Analysis of data from a battery-type plant 13 Uses of electricity 13 . Fuel cost per kilowatt-hour.: 15 The automatic-type plant 15 Questionnaire reports 16 Sizes 16 Cost of plants ; 16 Uses of electricity. 16 Age, fuel consumption, and repair bills 17 The life of the starting battery ;. jg Analysis of data from two automatic plants 18 Operation of an 800-watt automatic plant throueh two periods __ !g Operation of a 1,500-watt automatic plant during one year.... 20 The semi-automatic type plant 22 Some hints for prospective buyers '. 23 Size .~1.™Z~1.:"™ 23 Type of plant " 24 A word about choosing make of plant 25 Care and operation 1 '25 Expenses ' " 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY Data were secured from 30 different makes of battery-type plants, 2 makes of automatic type, and one semi-automatic type in use for ordinary purposes on Nebraska farms. These plants range in size from 600 to 3,000 watts. The 850-watt size was the most common battery-type plant and the 1,500-watt size the most common automatic type found in use. The average cost of the battery-type plants was $500.00 and of the automatic type, $585.00. Those farmers having battery-type plants reported a total of 29 different uses for electricity, with an average of 4.6 uses per plant. Those having the automatic type reported a total of 36 different uses with an average of 6 uses of electricity per plant. (The extent of these uses has not been determined nor have the various uses been compared.); The highest number of different uses for electricity for any one plant was 11 for the battery-type plant and 13 for the auto - matic. The owner of the one semi-automatic has 9 uses for his plant. Increasing the number of uses of electricity from a plant apparently does not shorten its life.- The oldest battery-type plant from which data were secured was 20 years old and the average age of all battery plants reported on was 6.16 years. The oldest automatic plant studied was 7 years old and the average age of all the automatics was 2.4 years. The range in the age of battery-type plants reported worn out or discarded because badly worn, was from. 7 to 11 years, with 9.9 years the average life. The reports from the owners of automatic plants do not indicate length of life. The 3-year-old battery-type plants required an average annual re - pair bill of $1.40, as against a bill of $4.85 as an average for 9-year - old plants of the same type. The average annual repair bill for the 2.6-year-old automatic-type plant was $3.02. Plants on which careful measurements of fuel and oil were made showed costs of from 11.7 to 15.25 cents per kilowatt hour for fuel and oil when averaged over a period of 1 year under ordinary service to the owner. The oldest battery reported still in use was a 20-year-old Edison and the oldest lead-plate battery was 12 years old. The average life of batteries reported worn out in service was 6.03 years. The 80-ampere-hour battery had shorter life than the 160 - ampere-hour battery when discharging for the same number of uses of electricity, but the estimated cost of charging was very much the same and the initial cost of the 80-ampere-hour battery much less. Batteries worn out in service as starting batteries on automatic plants had an average life of 2.4 years. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">UNIT ELECTRIC PLANTS FOR NEBRASKA FARMS E. E. Brackbtt and E. B. Lewis This study and survey of types of plants, the uses of cur - rent, cost of operation, life of plants and batteries, and the tactors influencing these items was made in an attempt to give practical answers to many inquiries from owners or prospective owners of light plants. The increasing use of electricity as a chore boy and labor saver on the farm and the isolation of a large percentage of Nebraska farms as far as power lines are concerned, make the study of unit farm electric plants of importance. Until recently, lights and one or two appliances were the only ways in which electricity was used. Not longer ago than 10 or 12 •years very few farmers had or cared to have the use of electricity, but such is not the case now. Plant owners verify this statement in their comments. One owner says "We feel electric lights are not a luxury but a real necessity and more than pay for themselves in the way you can care for your young stock and chickens." Another says, "It is worth $100 00 a year for washing alone, to say nothing of the other things that electricity may be used for." Another, "I think the plant the best improvement on the farm." Another says he (&lt; would rather be without a car than electricity." Another, I think electricity the best labor saver on the farm " One owner suggests the scope of usefulness when he says "The thing to do is to get a plant large enough for the average small tools and the household appliances that are operated bv electricity. ■ T " ' . DISTRIBUTION OF PLANTS The 1928 assessors' reports show that over 13,000 Nebraska farm homes use electricity. Of this number, 10,229 are re - ported as using unit farm electric plants. The remainder buy electricity from private companies or municipalities. The. distribution of these plants over the state is shown in Figure 1. The largest portion of these plants are the so-called battery-type, which store electricity in a storage battery The automatic plants, which use only a starting battery and must operate whenever electricity is wanted, are second in number, and the newer semi-automatic, which use the battery for small loads and starting, and automatically start running for heavy loads, are third in number. </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">Unit Electric Plants for Nebraska Farms on farms dose to Lincoln. These plants were run by the larmers themselves. Normal farm conditions were obtained Accurate- accounts of supplies and repairs were kept and I'lt-Lt^iS AVG1TG US 60- Each type of plant was studied separately and the factors affecting the performance, the cost of operation, and the life this buSet?n iPa PartS ° f thG PlSnt are given P rominence in BATTERY-TYPE PLANTS Some plant owners in answering the questionnaires gave some very general and very good information. One owner 5£f m * w P01 . nt 7 h^ n he says « " In buyin &amp; a Plant, one should select a^standard make that is sold by a reliable man " Ihis position is well taken and applies to almost any good piece of equipment. A possible reason for the advice given above comes from an owner who says, "Our chief difficulty at present is no service from company or agents." Others volunteer such valuable and definite information as "Our electric service has cost us about $9.50 per month for 10 years. This covers full life of plant and battery." Another, Our refrigerator costs about 10 cents per day to operate " SSr^w 1 * t0 «w d ?^ U r, h0W they may eet more use out of their plants as "Would like some way of cutting down charg - ing rate towards finish of charge." Also, "I want to connect a radio directly to plant without using A and B batteries » bTsatisfactor " F&gt; Sm wonderinfir if the electric would SUMMARY OF QUESTIONNAIRE REPORTS ON THE PLANTS Sizes of Plants.— Of the reports from farmers, 455 were considered complete, enough to be of value. In these returns n i. Sl e were answered by all those making re - »°h i Jn 6 S^-watt^size in the smaller plants and the l?250 - and 1,500-watt sizes in the larger sized plants were the greater number. The number of each of the various sizes reported was as Number of Plants Size Number of Plants Size 24 600 watts 12 1,250 watts il ZfS^S 8 12 1,500 watts ? 2 • „ 850 watts 1 1,750 watts ? • J'SSS Wa H S 1 2 ' 000 wat *s 1 ....1,200 watts 2 3,000 watts * Co8 *&lt;f/ t P x Ian iST" These b attery-type plants varied in cost from $265 to $800 with average cost $500. The first cost depended not only on the size of the generator but also on the size of the original battery. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 235 Age of Plants, Fuel, Fuel-consumption, and Uses of Electricity. — The average age of the plants reported on by owners of 442 plants was 6.16 years. The oldest reported on was 20 years old. The questionnaires showed also the following : 153 plant owners used kerosene as fuel. 181 plant owners used gasoline as fuel. 121 plant owners did not report fuel used. 304 plant owners estimated an average consumption of 120.1 gallons of fuel per year. 255 plant owners estimated an average of $29.52 as the cost of fuel and oil per year. 222 plant owners had records of repair costs averaging $2.82 per year per plant with average age of 5 2 years. 449 plant owners made an average of 4.6 different uses of electricity. 19 plant owners reported using Edison batteries; 436 or the remainder, reported using lead plate. Makes of Plants. — Thirty different makes of plants were reported as follows : 1. Alamo . 2. Ashbrook 3. Assembled — Cushman-Lauson 4. Assembled — Fairbanks-Morse and Western Electric 5. Assembled — Fairbanks-Morse and General Electric 6. Assembled — Ford and Fairbanks-Morse 7. Barber Dwinell 8. Black Swan 9. Cushman 10. Delco . 11. Diamond 12. Edison 13. Fairbanks-Morse 14. Fritchle Wind Electric 15. Fuller-Johnson 16. Homelite 17. Jupiter 18. Lalley ' 19. Matthews 20. Montgomery Ward &amp; Company 21. Phelps 22. Sears, Roebuck &amp; Company 23. Sheldon Sales Company 24. Stearns 25. Swanlite 26. Swartz 27. Universal </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 235 may also be the most mystifying and expensive part of the plant. Manufacturers try to give definite instructions on battery care and operation and try to build the battery itself to meet requirements. Even with these precautions, the reaction to battery operation by plant owners is extremely varied. One plant owner says, "Pulling a refrigerator directly from bat - teries is too hard on them." Another says, "My original battery was short lived because the refrigerator was too heavy a load." Another says, "I attribute the Jong life of our batr tery to following the directions that came with the plant." Another says, "My battery depreciation is about $40.00 per year." Another suggests possibilities when he says, "I use two sets of batteries." Another perhaps starts an argument when he states, "I would not advise anybody to attach radio to light plant batteries." There must be a large number of plant owners who do not agree with this last statement be - cause many do have their radios using light plant batteries. Length of Life and Uses of Storage Batteries.- — A sum - mary of the questionnaire material on the age and the uses of storage batteries follows: 228 users discarded 252 batteries at an average age of 6.03 years each. 187 users still have the original battery at an average age of 4.22 years each. 37 users had not replaced batteries reported worn out. 415 users report age of present battery 2.85 years each. 455 users have lights (all that answered the question on battery plants — 100 per cent). 147 users pump water — 32.52 per cent. 346 users wash clothes — 76.55 per cent. 330 users iron clothes — 73.00 per cent. 222 users have radio hook-up — 49.11 per cent. 132 users charge batteries — 29.20 per cent. 84 users separate — 18.58 per cent. 57 users have electric power in shop — 12.61 per cent. 39 users have vacuum cleaner. 4 users have milking machines. 21 users use light to increase winter egg production. 30 users use toaster or grill. 11 users grind feed. 2 users pop corn. 3 users shear livestock. 2 users dry clothes. 4 users use curling iron. 13 users have electric fans. 23 users have electric refrigerators. 24 users have grindstone motor. </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 235 of the battery? This question can be answered in part by noting some of the items reported by farmer owners. The 12-year-old batteries had been used for supplying lights, pumping, washing, ironing, and radio hookups. Some of the 11-year-old batteries increased the number just given by adding cream separating. Some of the 9- and 10-year-old batteries were still adding lights to increase winter egg pro - duction. On the other hand, some of the batteries were worn out after only one year of service for lights only, some after one year for lights and iron, and some after one year of use for lights, pump, washing machine, iron, radio, battery charger, milker, and increase in production of winter eggs. Some of the batteries worn out in 2 years were used for lights and iron only. The graph in Figure 4 compares the average number of uses of electricity reported by farmers with the age of the battery. It is shown here that the owners of the older bat - teries are enjoying about the same number of uses for their electricity as the owners of the newer batteries. In other words, increasing the number of uses does not necessarily shorten the life of the battery. The reports of owners of the 1- and 2-year-old batteries were not considered in the data for this graph because in these 2 years the uses for electricity were being gradually discovered and their effect on the bat - tery was too indefinite because of the short time of ownership. Two Sizes of Batteries Compared. — Another question often asked by the farmer about to buy a plant for the first time or by a plant owner who finds it necessary to replace his battery is, "What size of battery shall I buy?" The two most common sizes used were the 80-ampere-hour and the 160-ampere-hour batteries. By choosing only those reports in which the farmer had worn out or replaced his battery, the items in the following table are available: Size of Battery x 80 ampere 160 ampere . hour hour. Average life (years) 5.06 6.57 Average number of uses 5.28 5.10 Days between charges Summer 6 8 Winter 4 4.3 Estimated cost per year of fuel and oil (dollars) .-. 30.31 . 30.40 Estimated amount of fuel per year (gallons) 115.4 125.3 1 The above are averages from 49 batteries of 80-ampere-hour size and 35 batteries 3f IGO-nmpere-hour size. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Unit Electric Plants for Nebraska Farms The items as listed above were selected from only those reports indicating something definite. In most instances the fuel cost and fuel used per year were estimates. A few, how - ever, had records. The average life of a battery was found by comparing the date of purchase and the date of replace - ment. The remaining items were given as the usual practice of the plant owners. In a good many instances, the reason for buying a larger battery was the expectation of longer life for it. From the table we find the 160-ampere-hour battery lasted 1.5 years longer than the 80-ampere-hour battery under about the same number of uses of electricity. The cost of the fuel and oil for the plant to keep the battery charged is a small amount more for the 160-ampere-hour size. Since the 160-ampere-hour battery costs much more than the 80-ampere-hour, a study of the above-mentioned table might easily decide the buyer in favor of the smaller battery. As shown in the table, the 80-ampere-hour size needs charg - ing more often than the 160-ampere-hour battery for the same type of load. For this reason, the type of load the plant is expected to carry must often decide the size of bat - tery. For example, the owner may have an automatic load, like the mechanical refrigerator, that will come on and dis - charge the small battery too low before he can find it con - venient to start the plant. The extra storage would mean in this case extra convenience. In a good many cases where it is convenient to operate the plant when any load draws heavily on the battery, the 80-ampere-hour battery will give as good service as the larger sizes and the total battery expense will be cut accordingly. One plant owner reported having an 80 - ampere-hour battery 5 years old and not worn out, from which he drew electricity for 10 different uses. ANALYSIS OF DATA FROM A BATTERY-TYPE PLANT The graphs in Figure 5 are made from data secured by accurate measurements of fuel consumption and accurate metering of current used from an 850-watt plant observed on a farm near Lincoln. These readings were made the first of each month by some member of the Agricultural Engineering Department. This plant was 4 years old when the data were taken. Uses of Electricity. — A family used the plant in much the same way as many other farm families do, or will use a farm electric plant. A deep-well pump, a cistern pump, a refrigerator, a washing machine, a radio, an iron, and one or two small household appliances were used besides the lights for the house, barn, and garage. Over 600 gallons of kerosene were used by this plant during the year's time recorded for the figures from which the graph </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 235 farm use." "We consider our plant our best investment.' "Satisfied 100 per cent." "We like the plant but the cost of operation on a small load should be lower." "Makes excellent light and the power we use is very satisfactory. The most undesirable feature is the inability to have any light unless the motor runs. In case of sickness or with small children, this is very objectionable." QUESTIONNAIRE REPORTS The reports from users and the data from these reports were separated from the data on the battery-type plants for several reasons. The automatic type has been in the field less time. The most common size is 1,500 watts as compared to 850 watts for the battery-type plant. The automatic plants are in a field where apparently the owners demand more capacity and wish to get away from heavy battery replace - ment expense. Because this type of plant has been in the field but a short time, it is impossible to have data showing probable length of life of the plant or parts, as with the older battery-type plant. Fifty-seven good questionnaire reports were received on 2 different makes of this type of plant, the Kohler 110-volt and the Delco 32-volt. Sizes. — The sizes of the plants reported on were as follows : 2 were 2,000-watt plants. 40 were 1,500-watt plants. 2 were 850-watt plants. 10 were 800-watt plants. 1 was a 750-watt plant. 2 owners did not indicate sizes. Cost of Plants.— The automatic plants cost originally from $465 to $835 with the average cost $585. These plants have entered a field slightly different from that of the battery - type plants. This partly accounts for the extra capacity found in the average generator, and as a consequence partly accounts for the greater average price of the automatic over the battery-type plants. Uses of Electricity. — It is also interesting to note the uses for electricity from this type of plant. 57 owners or 100 per cent have lights. 47 owners or 82.45 per cent have motor on washing machine. 25 owners or 43.9 per cent have motor on pump. 44 owners or 77.2 per cent have electric iron. 27 owners or 47.4 per cent charge car batteries. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Unit Electric Plants for Nebraska Farms 20 owners use toasters. 17 owners have electric motor on separator 4 owners grind feed. 3 owners run hair-clippers. 11 owners have radio hook-ups. 1 owner slices ear corn. 1 owner has corn popper. 9 owners use lights to increase winter egg production. 3 owners use electric sheep shears. 16 owners have electrically equipped shop tools. 1 owner dries clothes. 7 owners have electric refrigerators. 1 owner has air compressor. 7 owners use grills. 3 owners have motors on milking machines. 2 owners have electric drills. 1 owner has posting machine. 1 owner elevates grain. 1 owner has electric soldering iron. 2 owners have cream testers. 1 owner operates fanning mill. ; 1 owner cuts green feed for poultry. 1 owner thaws out frozen pipes. 1 owner has room heater. 2 owners have electric fans. 2 owners have waffle irons. 1 owner has electric curling iron. 57 owners report an average of 6 different uses of electricity per plant. It might be well to note many of the 36 different uses of electricity as reported. About 50 per cent were for house - hold and 50 per cent for outdoor purposes. Usually this ar - rangement gives better satisfaction and more returns in real service and net profits to the user. Too often the main uses for electricity are only in the household, or are for con - veniences. But net savings of time and labor from these uses do not show the possibilities of adding to the farm in - come and cutting down the farm expenses that the use of «lectric energy for outdoor chores shows. Age, Fuel Consumption, and Repair Bills. — The range •J. e^ ages of the automatic plants was from y 2 to 7 years, with the average age 2.4 years. This was an average on 54 plants. Forty-three plant owners reported an estimate of gasoline used per year. This average was 408.6 gallons. The average estimated cost of fuel and oil per year was $94 08 This was taken from 41 reports. The average annual repair </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 235 In 1927 fuel was cheaper. This same plant owner used 428 kilowatt-hours at an average cost of 11.8 cents per kilo - watt-hour for fuel and oil and his fuel consumption averaged .63 gallon per kilowatt-hour. It is impossible to tell why these curves take the relative positions they do without knowing just what use was being made of electricity in this farm home. The iron was the heaviest load this plant had to carry. Five other uses were reported for the plant. During only a very little time did this plant run under a load heavy enough to bring about good fuel economy. Operation of a 1,500-watt Automatic Plant During One Year. — In Figure 8 the graphs were drawn from data on the 1,500-watt automatic-type plant. These data were re - corded the first of each month by members of the Agricultural Engineering Department. An analysis of the curves shown clearly brings out some definite points for and against the automatic plant. The owner of this 1,500-watt plant has a good-sized poultry farm. " In the winter when he used lights to increase pro - duction when eggs were high, he had a full load for his plant most of its operating time. During this time his fuel con - sumption was as low as .44 gallon per kilowatt-hour. The cost per kilowatt hour was 6.55 cents when his gasoline cost him an average of 14:89 cents per gallon. During the summer months when the plant of 1,500 watts capacity had to operate to supply lamps of from 25 to 60 watts for egg-candling, the fuel consumption ran high for the number of kilowatt-hours used. At the highest point in the cost curve the fuel consumption reached 2 gallons and the fuel cost reached 29.78 cents per kilowatt-hour. For the year, this plant had an average consumption of .73 gallon or a cost of 10.87 cents per kilowatt-hour for the gasoline alone. When the oil cost was added to the above, the average cost for fuel and oil over the period of one year was 11.72 cents per kilowatt-hour. The owner of this 1,500-watt plant used 684 kilowatt-hours during the year the data for the graphs in Figure 8 were recorded. His total bill for fuel and oil was $80.16 for the year, or $6.68 per month. These carefully observed plants were not picked for any special reason but because the owners were ready to co - operate with the University in securing first-hand information on plants in operation on farms. However, the facts in the graphs from data on these plants show what might easily happen in the operation of a plant of this type on any farm </seg>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022"/>
            <seg id="p023">Unit Electric Plants for Nebraska Farms Figure 9^ shows the fuel" costs and monthly current con - sumption of and from the semi-automatic plant now being used on the same farm and by the same people as the battery - type plant represented by the graphs in Figure 5. The farmer exchanged his battery-type plant for the new plant, retaining his almost-new 160-ampere-hour battery For the summer months shown, this man with his new plant is obtaining an average fuel consumption of .56 gallon of gasoline per kilowatt-hour and an average cost of 9 2 cents per kilowatt-hour with gasoline at 16.5 cents per gallon The average for all the months shown in the graph is .60 gallon ot gasoline per kilowatt-hour. The cost figures do not include oil, labor, repairs, interest, or depreciation These costs seem higher than they should. However this man is conscientiously trying to follow the manufacturer's instructions A smaller battery, which is usually recom - mended for this plant, would change, these costs to some ex - tent, depending on the needs of the owner of the plant in his use of electricity. The values and meaning of the graph -Sra'SiSU^fp^?." 16 " ° Perat ° r beCOmeS SOME HINTS FOR PROSPECTIVE BUYERS SIZE To determine the size of plant best suited, it is first neces- - sary to determine the load you expect to use within the next few years. Figure out the equipment that you probably will own at a given time. See if by planning the different uses ot equipment you can conveniently operate the plant without too great a load. For example, if your largest load apparently necessary at one time is for six 50-watt lights, or 300 watts, plus the iron at 500 watts, your total necessary load would be 800 watts. The plant assuring you the 800-watt output could carry the refrigerator at 300 watts, the water pump at 300 watts and some other small appliances like a vacuum cleaner, all at the same time. (The nearer a full load operation when S wtl ?' 1S run " in f' the bett er the fuel economy.) If »£j £ e t l me il ou nnd , xt necess ary to have 1,000 watts as a load, the plant to meet requirements must be larger at all times than the largest necessary load. As mentioned before by doing some planning, the largest loads may be lessened. ' To aid in the planning of the expected load for your light plant, a partial list with the power required is given: </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 235 50-watt lamp 50 watts Sewing machine 50 watts 16-inch fan 90 watts Battery charger 150 watts Milker (portable) 150 to 250 watts Cream separator 150 to 300 watts Vacuum cleaner 100 to 200 watts Water pump 250 to 350 watts Washing machine 150 to 350 watts Refrigerator 200 to 250 watts Flat iron 600 watts Heater (headlight type)....... 600 watts Waffle iron 600 watts Motors require about 1,000 watts per horse-power — *4 horse-power taking about 250 watts, Vs8 horse-power taking 500 watts, etc. TYPE OF PLANT Usually the battery-type plant is the 32-volt plant. When the higher voltages are obtained the size of the storage bat - tery and its cost make this plant out of the question for most farmers. Where the battery-type plant is mentioned in this bulletin, the 32-volt plant is meant. The advantages of a 32-volt plant may be said to be, first, its simplicity ; second, the lessened danger from shocks in the low voltage; third, the storage battery insures light instantly and usually keeps a reserve to draw on in case of plant trouble; and fourth, the first cost is low. The disadvantages of the battery plant are, first, getting 32-volt equipment;- second, the high cost and relatively short life of the storage battery ; third, the cost of wiring is more for the low voltage; fourth, the poor economy in trying to carry the low voltage any distance; and fifth, the extra care of battery. In the automatic-type plant we have, first, the higher voltage which is standard for most lamps and heating equipment ; second, the higher voltage makes it economical to carry greater distances than the 32-volt system ; third, wire is smaller for 110 than for 32 volts and thus is less expensive; and fourth, the starting battery is small and costs much less than the storage battery. But on the other hand, the automatic plant is more complicated, there is no reserve stored up if plant fails to operate, and the cost of fuel is high per kilowatt-hour if the amount of current being consumed is small. Recently there has come on the market the semi-automatic plant. This plant has a small battery used both for starting and storage and for small amounts of current. When the </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Unit Electric Plants for Nebraska Farms to the automatic, P Wv er in^hatit "f^ 8 ° ne objection light or small load without starHnt lh SuppIles the emergency but because of its Iw voltegeYt aXa^StWE " ld We ' of the farmer if he must car™ n l ?u- the requirements able distance. ry part of hls current a consider- A WORD ABOUT CHOOSING MAKE OF PLANT you spend your money Sum un tEi UdlC + ed people before vantages shown and Jse yoTr Z^S^&amp;Sa^ CARE AND OPERATION the plant in I c1ean?warm tut well^ntiiatld""^ ° iL 3*? some one person resDonsihlp f™ +v. ventllate .a place. Make current yoS are abfeTo produce do vou^r^/ 011 - - M^ e the saving of time and labor. Remember that^f S6 T Ce in the Pla y nt P S Sn!fro C n h o?m^ give your plant an % you when it operates. rather than a small one EXPENSES . tions brought about if they hook un tn SSf« e °l the condi " company line to get electricity from Lv Clty or power costs or expense! may be' *£££{% °£ s S Tdi£? </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 235 units, that is, cost per year, cost per month, or cost per kilo - watt-hour. If we assume some such average conditions as were brought out in our reports from farmer users of plants, coupled with other definite data we have secured, and assume the request comes from an average farmer, we can answer the request with a fair degree of accuracy. The following examples are offered for that purpose. For the first example, assume a battery-type plant costing originally $500.00. The battery at $200.00 will make the cost of the engine and generator equipment $300.00. To have all figures consistent assume a 3-year-old plant and turn to averages from the data secured. The average life of plant is found as 9.9 (10) years, life of battery 6.03 years, the aver - age fuel consumption 120.1 gallons per year, average cost of fuel and oil $29.52 per year, the average repair bill for a 3 - year-old plant $1.40 per year. Avoiding the small fractions for easier calculations, costs will be about as follows : OVERHEAD EXPENSES Interest on investment 6 per cent on value of 3-year-old plant ($310.00) 3 $ 18.50 Depreciation Battery — $200.00 at 16% per cent (6 years life) 33.34 Engine and generator — $300.00 at 10 per cent (10 years life) : 30.00 Tax :.;.. 2.50, Insurance .*..'. .90 OPERATING EXPENSE Fuel and oil 29.50 MAINTENANCE Repairs and service 1.40 TOTAL FOR YEAR '. .' .$116.14 AVERAGE MONTHLY EXPENSE , 9.68 AVERAGE COST PER KW. HR. (allowing 240 Kw. Hrs. for annual consumption of current) .484 This estimate of current used per year may be too high for the amount of gasoline or kerosene used (120 gallons) per year. This is based on an operation of .5 gallon fuel per kilowatt-hour (Kw.Hr.). That amount is considerably lower than that secured by the plant owners from whose plants data were carefully secured by measuring the fuel and metering the current. For further examples of costs we will take the records of two 5-year-old plants, one battery type, one automatic. On these plants most of the costs shown are costs as taken from the farmers' book accounts and data secured by the Agricul - tural Engineering Department. 1 Three-year-old plant value $500.00 minus 16 2/3 per cent depreciation on buttery and minus 10 per cent depreciation of engine and generator for each of the 3 years. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Unit Electric Plants for Nebraska Farms t^jS^^^^ 0 * a 5 - year - old battery - OVERHEAD EXPENSE Interest on investment 6 per cent on value of 5-year-old plant ($183.30)......$ 11.00 ucprcc in. Lion Battery— $200.00 at 16% per cent (6 years life)... 33 34 Taxes'" 6 generator— $300.00 at 10 per cent 30.00 .insurance".'.'"."';.;.;;.;;;."; i 2 -j;° OPERATING EXPENSE " 90 Fuel and oil QO O1 MAINTENANCE " 89 - 21 Repairs and service ; 28 50 TOTAL FOR YEAR *iqk ak AVERAGE EXPENSE FOR ONE'moNTH " ik9q AVERAGE COST PER 269 The current was metered from this plant. Total current used m the above year was 726.7 kilowatt-hours. The two items — fuel and oil and repairs and service — required an exact cash outlay for this farmer and these two items alone made his costs 16 cents per kilowatt-hour when his fixed over - head is not taken m account. pla^'fflSS $585. 00 h )T figUreS ° n " 5 " year -° ld aUt ° matic OVERHEAD EXPENSE Interest on investment 6 per cent on value of 5-year-old plant ($243.40) $ 14.61 Battery— $42.00 at 33% per cent (3 years life) 14 00 Engine and generator— $543.00 at 10 per cent Taxei 10 .^^. 1 "!^;;;;;;:;;;;;;;;;;;; 5^° Insurance f'52 OPERATING EXPENSE , ° Fuel and oil a , oo MAINTENANCE B1^ 8 Repairs and service.... , 66 33 TOTAL FOR YEAR , 2 q 4 17 AVERAGE PER MONTH it'll AVERAGE COST PER KW. HBZZZZ^ZIZZZZZZZZZ 342 This farmer used 684 kilowatt-hours during this year's operation. Operation and maintenance alone cost 21 6 cents per kilowatt-hour. Both owners of the plants in the last two examples had some overhauling done, making their maintenance high These two examples showing costs as really found in the operation. of these 5-year-old plants are not placed here to </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 235 frighten any prospective purchaser — both owners feel they could not get along now without electricity — nor is it the aim to laud one plant over the other but to show costs that really do have to be met when anyone receives good benefits from a farm electric plant. Farmers who use the electricity from their plants for several beneficial tasks around the farmstead feel that their plants are very efficient and inexpensive hired men or chore boys. [10M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>