<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00025">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00025</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  SPRAYING APPLE TREES</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Experiment Station Agricultural LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. I". S. A. PRESS BULLETIN NO. 37 (EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. 6) </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SPRAYING APPLE TREES Department of Horticulture when to makt- tht- first - second spraying that in figure 5 somew ) B&gt; R F H </seg>
            <seg id="p003">MIXING THE SPRAY. spraying depends almost wholly upon when ut on and how they are applied. The two principal ihe apple scab and the arm. Tin ither injurious insects and fungous dis - lianl, but if the orchard is properly treated for II in a large measure be controlled the apple scab and codling moth are bo well ■ • ..us can be given for fighting them. The ii develops upon the flowers, leaves, and able weather conditions. i y ;i few .: 'Ucly. damp weather. .1 dropping of the young fruits later due to this orkinf upon the young I us. In addition to this loss. .1 pt in he rendered unlit for the market by the miisualh Nebraska . r being unfavorable for haxe be. &gt;ns rather than the should inn .ili. union their fungicide sprays, thinking t»&lt;&gt; materials thai may lie used to control apple » ■ 'inmercial Ihae-iulfur solution. One is equally ntrolling this . .ime-sulfur is some - in that no wUlm devices are required for ■ ■ •• - :i;u&lt;h &lt;1;iiil;« r in russeting certain varie - : Jonathan. Most commercial brands of lime- Haumi- Win n they are put up in this ■ i lie diluted about imes with water before i hen the on. Bordeaux mix- Mtag fn sli stone lime, copper sulfate ( Milestone I. H mnla used in making Bordeaux mixture is — t pouixls copper sulfate; I pounds stone lime; ions water. nk the lime in a little water and dissolve the copper n warm water Dilute each of these to 25 gallons and -trainer should be used to keep the coarse of lime out of the sprayer. Ed at the rate of 2 pounds to 50 gallons of material, is recommended for controlling the codling moth worm. ■ &lt;1 with tl ix mixture or ir, in the second .^plications </seg>
            <seg id="p004">First Spraying — After the cluster buds of the apple* open but before the individual flowers expand use lime-sulfur or Bordeaux mi v figure 1.1 Second Spraying — Kor cfteetiTC work this application inust !&gt;• between the time the nV a to drop and the time the cal&gt;\ close (See figures 3 and 4 ) I'se th. ,1 that wa - the first application pl&lt; for ear I gallon! I Third Spraying Tl second, using the M Fourth Spraying of worms, and to fifty gallons. It shou of .Inly METHOD OF APPLICATION The firs-i mist spray ami to getting the ' much folia. large branches M&gt; the mist float thru &gt;»!■[ careful not to com The second epra&gt; ii principal obje&lt; I cups before th' with the fungicide In spray downward a&gt;- mm a coarse spray for I ent sized hoi' increase* with the size of the The third and four A well-pruned tn and actual amount of material needed An average sized app gallons of spray material for the four ings, three contain the fui trees 18 or 20 year*; old will require ab. 35 gallons of concentrated liuie »ulfur M pounds of lime and :• 1 be nee.i </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>