<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00035">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00035</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  SIMPLE WATER SUPPLES FOR THE FARM</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, Nebraska, U. S. A. SIMPLE WATER SUPPLIES FOR THE FARM By L. W. Chase Department of Agricultural Engineering. A system of obtaining water for house use which should be abandoned DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION* C. W. Pugsley, Superintendent. Distributed September 22, 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Alfalfa Management. I Cost of Growing Crops in Nebraska. Testing Seed Corn. &gt; .V 4 Cooking and Sewing. Part I. — Judging Horses and Cattle Part II. — Corn. 5 Part III. — The Home Garden. Spraying Apple Trees. 6 Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. / S Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm. The Selection and Care of Seed Corn. &gt;) Organization of Nebraska Boys' and Girls' Clubs. Co-operative County Farm Demonstrators. Nebraska Boys' Potato Clubs. (Growing Potatoes.) Agricultural Extension Short Courses. io. i i l_&gt; 14 The Climate of Nebraska. A Course of Study for Home Economics Clubs Twelve Lessons in Sewing. IS Twelve Lessons on Foods and Their Preparation. Simple Water Systems for the Farm. 17 - l&amp; Inexpensive Silos and Silage Machinery Saving the Corn Crop. 19 2O. Filling the Silo. 21 The above bulletins will l&gt;e sent free to residents of Nebraska uix&gt;n request to DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION University Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Needs of Supplies. Convenient water supplies are commonly looked upon as luxuries which only the well-to-do may enjoy, but a little investigation will show that there is no adequate reason why some sort of a system of piping water into the house should not be found on every farm. Where water must be carried in pails four or five rods it is evident Fig. 2. Carrying water is work for a man and should not be done by a woman. Carrying water up hill is tiresome, hard labor and dangerous work 3, in winter. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 that the smallest possible amount of water will be used in the house and this lack of water must require the expenditure by the housewife of more time and labor in doing such work as scrubbing, cleaning vegetables, dish washing, and laundry work, besides the difficulty in producing as satisfactory results as when plenty of water is available. The time saved in the one operation of dish washing when plenty of water is used will forcibly demonstrate the actual economy of a water system, — for if ten cooking utensils are used in a day the Fig. 4. Illustrating the fact that when one goes down hill for a pad ot water anil returns he lowers and raises the body 12' or more when be should only raise the pail of water that distance. difference in the value of time required to wash them when they are at once filled with cold water and when they are allowed to dry before being washed will in a year amount to $20.00. This amount of money will suffice to install a simple water system or would pay the interest upon one which should be complete in every detail. By watching the water meters in a number of Lincoln houses it has been found that the average per capita consumption of water is 15 gallons a day, even where water is not used for flushing a closet. If only one-third this amount were considered an average for those </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 who have no water supply system, it can readily be seen how much time is required to carry water from the well to the house. On one farm the work of carrying the water from the well to the house was sufficient each year to have dug a well twenty-four feet deep and four feet in diameter and walled it. This work was largely done by the woman of the house, whose strength was al - readv taxed to the limit with other necessary work. tnother example might be cited here of wasted energy which irs on a farm where the well is down in a draw below the barn, water is pumped through a pipe from the windmill just over well up to a water tank on the side of the hill beside the barn, [l sufficient water to soak two barrels of corn is carried back way down to this well every day of the year. The distance i&gt; cient to take about fifteen minutes for a good stout man to »Fig. 5. An inefficient method of handling water. The simple hydrant ild have been connected in the pipe at the water barrel and thus saved labor of carrying water from tank to barrel. Ef the water from the tank to the barrel. At 20 cents an hour quires $18.20 worth of time in one year. If this farmer had stopped to think about it, he could with $3.00 worth of time $5.00 worth of material, a total of $8.00, have put in a hydrant over this pipe and let the water run into the barrel and thus saved a great deal of hard labor. Type of Water System. If one desires varieties in water systems he can have them. There are springs, cisterns, rain water barrels, open wells, bored wells, dug wells, driven wells, windmill driven pumps, hand pumps, gasoline engine pumps, water tanks on towers, and pneumatic pres - sure tanks in the basement. There is not space here to consider all of these, so only a few of the simplest and cheapest water systems A *K A m </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Frank Brown's Water System. The following is a description of one of the simplest water sys - tems and one very easy to operate. The well was of necessity in a low place out in the pasture. The barn was just at the top of a hill, and slightly down the slope beyond was the house. The water was originally pumped from the well into the horse trough beside the barn. When the owner of this farm decided to have a water system in the house, he simply ran a pipe up through the horse tank two or three feet higher than the tank; then, down at the lower end of this pipe, he connected a pipe running on down to his house. There, by means of an open tank and a common sink faucet which was I"ig. 6. Frank Brown's water system, illustrating a cheap but efficient method. teed on the end of the pipe, he has it now arranged so that when wants water in his tank at the house, he simply opens the faucet and the windmill pumps the water past the horse tank to the house tank. When the house tank is full, the faucet is closed and the water is forced up through the standpipe in the horse tank until it overflows into the tank beneath. The cost of this system, which furnishes an abundant supply of water right in the house, was pos - sibly $17.25, including all labor. Cistern with Tank Pump and Elevated Barrel. K)f course, every farmer is not so situated that he can put in as venient a water supply as that just described at so small an ex - pense. However, every farm is so situated that where there is any </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Simple Water Supplies for the Farm 7 rain whatever during the year a water supply can be had from a cistern which will furnish water for everything about the house ex - cept drinking purposes, and by use of filters it is very satisfactory water for drinking. To make a water supply of this nature, one must have a cistern just outside the house. Then a cistern pump on the sink board in the kitchen will answer for pumping water from the cistern to a common bar - rel, or preferably to a galvanized iron or cop - per tank located in some of the rooms on the sec - ond floor, or in the attic if the house is a one - story house. On top of the water in the barrel should be a float con - nected by means of a pulley to a guide or in - dicator down in the kitchen to tell how much water there is in the bar - rel. The common tank pump such as is used by threshers is much more satisfactory for pumping water into a barrel this way than the cistern pump, since it pumps so much faster and the labor of pump - ing is not very heavy. Of course, where a bar - rel of only about 50 gal - lon capacity is used in A simple and cheap yet efficient water FiR. 7. system. the attic, it is essential that the water be pumped morning, noon, and night. This causes very little trouble, however, when one stops to think that it takes only two or three minutes per day to do all </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Cost of Cheap Cistern Outfit. Where the soil is such that cisterns can be made by simply plastering with cement plaster on the earth, a cistern can be made - very cheaply. Such a cistern with a one-inch wall should cost about $18.25, including all labor, or, making the estimate safely, say $20.00. If one can do the work himself, you see that a cistern can be built very cheaply. If the walls have to be three inches thick l&gt;ecause of loose soil, the cistern would then ]x&gt;ssibly cost at* nit l?42.&lt;So, including everything. The cost (if a one-inch wall cistern without labor, but including the pump, barrel, and all pipe fittings. should not be over $18.00. The two water systems previously described can lie built at an outlay considerably less than the cost of the time required in carrying water from the well to the home each year. The one which follows costs a little more. ].-j 8. The principle of the water system on the Chase farm, illustrated The System on the Chase Farm. On the Chase farm there is an open well just adjoining the back porch. This furnishes sufficient water for drinking pur - poses. Just beside this well is a cistern. For a number of years </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 the water was brought in pails from the well and from the cistern into the kitchen for use. This method, however, was unsatisfac - tory, so a galvanized iron tank holding about 120 gallons was placed in the attic. This tank in the attic was then connected to the cis - tern through a common cistern pressure pump which was set on a board adjoining the sink. The water is now pumped by hand to the tank, but the pump has such small capacity that it should be re - placed by a tank pump as illustrated. In the same pipe which runs fruin the pump in the kitchen to the tank, there is connected the cold water faucet for the kitchen sink, the cold water faucet for the bathroom, and the cold water faucet for the lavatory on the second floor. Fortunately, on this farm the kitchen and the bathroom are adjoining, so that the kitchen sink is on one side of the partition and the bathroom sink is on the other. Hence, there is very little pipe fitting to be done to connect the hot and cold water to the sink. Since there was not sufficient room in the kitchen for the hot water boiler, it was suspended from the ceiling in the bathroom and the pipe was run from the range up across the top of the kitchen to the tank. The convenience of the system is a feature worthy of comment. When one walks through the kitchen, a glance at the indicator on the kitchen wall tells how much water there is in the tank in the attic. There is always hot water in both bathroom and kitchen. This being soft water aids materially in all washing purposes. By having soft water in the water system, hard water can easily be kept in the range reservoir or in the teakettle, so that there is al - ways warm water for cooking purposes. Freezing. Having the tank in the attic brings up the question of water freezing in this tank. This system has been used for four or five years and the only time that the water has frozen anywhere was when a thin scum appeared on the tank during the long-continued cold spell in the winter of 1912-13, and this no doubt was because of the fact that the owner neglected to pump some of the warm water from the cistern into the tank at night. Pumping warm water through the kitchen into the tank every day keeps the water so warm that it takes considerable cold weather to freeze it during the night. The Amount of Water Used on the Farm. Before considering the outside storage tank system, or the pneu - matic tank system, the amount of water which should be used on the farm must first be considered. The windmill has been blamed </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 a great deal because of its inability to furnish water during a calm. Investigation has shown that the trouble is frequently because the farmer has not built a tank large enough to carry his family and stock through the quiet season of the year, or he has failed to purchase a wind wheel of sufficient diameter to run in light winds. By keeping track of two families who were using water from a pump, it was found that they averaged 5.8 gallons per day per person. In contrast to this, it was discovered that in eight families using water from city supplies 20.18 gallons of water were used per person per day. Three of these families were using, in addition to this, water from cisterns. Taking the families who were not using the water from a cistern, and who also had completely modern houses, it was found that there was an average of 22.2 gallons per person per day. The range is from a minimum of 14.7 gallons per person per day to a maximum of 34.5 gallons per person per day. It might seem from this that a water supply tank should be de - signed for the average, which is 22.2 gallons per person per day. This, however, would not do because some families use more water than others. Then, too, in the country there are the milk pails and separator, the churn, and other milk utensils to be washed which require large quantities of water and are not considered in estimating water for the use of city families. Furthermore, the work of the men in the country is such as should necessitate more frequent baths than is required of the professional man in the city. Hence, in planning a water system an allowance of at least 30 gal - lons per person per day should be made. Upon checking one family for four or five days it appeared that there were 10.4 gallons of water used per person per day in flush - ing the toilet in the bathroom. If a home is not to have this fix - ture, then the amount of water used per person per day could be reduced to about 20 gallons. The Animal Husbandry Department has figures showing that cattle and horses average about eight gallons of water per head per day, and hogs about two gallons. Iomputing then from these figures, it is evident that on a farm re there are five persons in the family, 30 head of cattle, 10 »es, and 30 hogs, about 530 gallons of water per day will be led. A tank should be sufficiently large to carry a supply for a k. This would require a tank which would hold 3,710 gallons, ch is a tank having a cubical content of 495.3 cubic feet. A angular tank 7 feet wide, 7 feet deep, and 10 feet long will 1 this amount of water, or a round tank 15 feet deep and 6.6 across will hold it, or a round tank 10 feet across and 6.3 feet p will nolu it. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Tank in the Ground on a Hill The fanner whose buildings are so situated that he can place a concrete tank in the ground on a hill which is in close proximity to his buildings and let the water run down into his residence and out </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 into the yards has an ideal situation for a water system. If the hill is sufficiently high so that he can obtain fire pressure, so much the better. the cost of such a c as this should be at $35.00, including ■ything but the cover. • material required lid cost about $18.00 $19.00 and the rest ild 1)C labor. K eight of Such a ;k Above Outlet, Many people have the idea that a water tank must be well up in the air in order to obtain a KThis is necessary Fig- 10- Rectangular concrete reservoir on the when it is desirable hi " at the North Platte Substation. that there be fire protec- Ifrom the water system, but one should never delay putting in ater system because he cannot have fire pressure — the other ; of a system are more important. When the tank is twelve above the top of the faucet of the kitchen sink and where the ! leading from the tank to the kitchen is one inch in diameter the tank is not over 100 feet from the kitchen, there will be a very of water at the kitchen faucet of about 9 gallons per ute. This is nearly 30 per cent more water than is delivered 1 kitchen faucet from the city pressure of Lincoln where the er is carried through a one-inch pipe a distance of 600 or 700 :. The cost of three-quarter inch pipe including laying should be over $2.60 per rod and of one-inch pipe not over $2.95 per . Inasmuch as there is only about 35 cents difference per rod, 1 generally advisable to use the one-inch pipe on low pressure. Constructing a Tank in the Ground. f'robably the cheapest and most convenient method of construct - a tank in the ground is first to excavate the hole, being careful ceep the sides straight and smooth ; then plaster a 1 to 2 mixture sand and cement to the walls; on this nail metal lath with long pies which will hold to the walls temporarily. Then plaster ee, four, and possibly five, or even six coats of cement plaster </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Ethis metal lath, making the wall about four inches thick. This be sufficient if the tank is not over seven feet deep and is in solid ground and the lath is well covered and well embedded e cement. Concrete Tank on Top of the Ground. When it is not possible to get sufficient fall to place the concrete tank in the ground, then it can very easily be placed on top of the ground and sufficient fall obtained. When a tank of this nature is built it is generally better to make it round, as the reinforcing holds much better. There are two methods of making such tanks. One is to build a form and pour in the concrete. The other is to buy a metal lath, known as Hy-Rib, which comes bent to the proper form. Set this lath up on the ground and plaster over it until the walls Fig. 11. Illustrating how t!ic pressure can similar to that shown by Fig. fl. be increased in a s\&gt;um I three or four or five inches thick. The material for a tank It in this way and having dimensions of 8 feet in diameter and feet deep should not cost over $8o. A graduate of the Nebraska iooI of Agriculture built a poured concrete tank 8 feet in diam - r and 15 feet deep with a 6-inch wall which cost only $125. : sand for this tank had to be shipped alxmt 35 miles and hauled ut four miles. The above price covers the cost of hauling, xd, and all labor as well as all material. Concrete Tank on Level Ground. When it is not possible to build a concrete tank on a hill, as pre - viously mentioned, it is often advisable to build one on the ground </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 t:r by grading up around the tank to give it elevation, or by ling the tank in the form of a standpipe, filling the interior of tank up part way with well tamped earth and on this earth ling a concrete floor and the remaining part of the tank. A built in this manner is very cheap, gives no trouble, and can ad by anybody, even if the house is on the highest part of the Bin elevated tank or any water tank in the yard is very unsightly. ;y should be placed in a grove or at least have trees and vines out around them to hide their lack of beauty. IFig. 12. Showing how the system in Fig. 9 can be modified to suit a piece of ground. Tanks in Tops of Silos. I 'hose who have cement silos or clay block silos can very con - iently erect concrete tanks on their tops. By this means a great I of pressure can be had, and the cost of the tower is nothing. : criticism of these tanks is made that the pipes are apt to freeze. s, however, should not be a serious criticism for the pipes can run through the chute and housed in the same manner as the :s to any of the steel tanks which are now being built on tops of ers for the small towns. Pneumatic Pressure Tanks. For years past there have been on the market pneumatic pres - sure tank systems, which consist of a pump in the well which will </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 pump both water and air to a tank in the basement. This tank in the basement is a steel tank which is perfectly air tight. The prin - ciple of such an equipment is to take the tank when it is empty and pump it as full of water as the air will permit. As the water starts Fig. 13. Illustrating a water tank on top of a masonry silo, into the tank, it starts compressing the air. When the tank is about two-thirds full of water the air is compressed into a small space, thus furnishing so much pressure that the pump will no longer pump and the windmill is shut off. Such a system permits of very high pressure, and conseqeuently acts as a fire protection </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 I case of snuii! fires. Not only that, but the tank is in the cellar ere there is no danger of freezing, and it is also out of sight. ice does not mar the appearance of the farmstead. Because of : cost of these tanks when they are bought in large enough es to furnish water for the stock as well as the house, they are ter adapted to use with gasoline engines, so that some water can pumped into them every day. A tank large enough to supply a m with water pumped by wind power would cost about $1,000. IA'here people have a convenient water supply for the stock it is en advisable that they use the pneumatic pressure tank system • the residence. But even when it is used for the residence only, windmill should be larger than for ordinary pumping purposes, that it will pump when the velocity of the wind is low. Compressed Air System. E hiring the past two or three years a system wherein air is com - ised into a tank by means of a pump has come into use. This then pumps the water from the well. It works so that when er is wanted one has simply to turn the faucet and the air starts •ing the water out. The writer has not yet had an opportunity nvestigate the system very carefully, but some favorable reports t have been heard. Power for Pimping Purposes. The water powers which are being used in Nebraska for furnish - ing water are the hand pump, the hydraulic ram in one or two in - stances, the gasoline engine, the windmill, the electric motor, and water power. Of these the hand power is being used the most, the windmill is next, and then the gasoline engine. During the past four or five years, the gasoline engine has been gaining in popu - larity very rapidly. This is probably because the ordinary supply tank is not sufficient to tide one over during a calm and the tras. &gt;- line engine can run other machines in addition to the pump. It is, however, a mistake to abandon the windmill on the farms of Ne - braska as long as wind is as free and easy to obtain as at present. The cost of the windmill and large supply tank is about the same as the cost of a good gasoline engine and a small tank. The cost of gasoline to pump the amount of water previously mentioned is about $10 per year. The cost of lubricating oil on a gasoline engine would be greater and also the cost of repairs, than on a windmill. The person who wishes to consider a water system with a gaso - line engine would do well to use the windmill for pumping the water when possible, but use the engine in times of calm. In such cases a s or 6 H.P. engine is to be recommended, as it can be used for a great many larger purposes than the small pumping engine. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>