<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00007">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00007</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>REPORT ATTORNEY GENERAL FOR BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1900, C.J. SMYTH, ATTORNEY GENERAL</title>
			            <date value="1900">1900</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-29</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Laura Weakly</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Validation</item>
				     </change>			
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-18</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
				     </change>
				     <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">REPORT 

Attorney General 

FOR BIENNIUM 

ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1900 

C. J. SMYTH, 

ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

JACOB NORTH * CO., PK INTERS 

LINCOLN, NEB. </seg>



            <seg id="p003">REPORT OP THE ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

State op Nebraska, Legal Department. 

Lincoln, Neb., November 30, 1900. 

To His Excellency, William A. Poynter, Governor: 

Sik — I have the honor to submit to you, in compliance 
with the law, thig, my second, biennial report covering the 
two years ending November 30, 1900. 

Schedule A contains copies of the opinions rendered. 

Schedule B sets forth the civil cases which have been disposed 
of, together with those that are now pending. 

Schedule C shows the criminal cases which have been 
finally adjudicated. 

Schedule D contains a list of the criminal cases pending. 

Schedule E discloses the condition of the appropriations 
made for the use of this office. 

Schedule F is a statement of the moneys collected through 
this office for the use of the state and accounted for to the 
state treasurer. 

I do not think that any useful purpose would be served 
by referring at length to all the civil cases which have been 
dealt with by this office during the last biennium, but most, 
if not all, deserve some notice. 

In the case of the State vs. The First National Bank of 
Alma the state sued on a depository bond, the bank which 
gave it having failed with $40,612.90 of the state's money on 
deposit. Special findings have been returned by the jury, 
and the case is now pending on a motion to enter judgment 
in favor of the state. This motion will be argued after 
Christmas. 

Nebraska Telephone Company vs. Cornell and Pacific Express 
Company vs. Cornell were cases in which the plaintiff </seg>


            <seg id="p004">4 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

sought to enjoin the State Board of Transportation from 
reducing the rates of telephone and express companies doing 
business in the state, on the ground that the law creating 
the Board and defining its duties was unconstitutional. A 
vigorous fight was made before the Board itself, then in the 
district court of Lancaster county, and finally in the Supreme 
Court. The state was successful in each contest. 

State ts. Ebright. This case arose out of the default of 
Ebright while Superintendent of the Institution for the 
Blind at Nebraska City. 

Blaco vs. State was an action on the Bond of ex-Oil Inspector 
Hilton. The state recovered judgment for the entire 
amount sued for, $6,759.33, and the judgment has been paid. 

State vs. Omaha National Bank is a case remarkable in 
more senses than one. It is remarkable for the facts on. 
which it rests, and also because of the conduct of the trial 
judge. It arises out of the transaction by which ex-Treasurer 
Bartley embezzled $201,884.05, of the state's money in 
the Omaha National Bank on January 2, 1897, five days before 
he went out of office. The bank was a state depository, 
and as such had on deposit $201,884.05 of state money. 
Bartley drew this sum on the morning of the 2d of January 
and delivered it to the Omaha National Bank in payment 
of a warrant which the bank had no title to. The act by 
which he transferred the money to the bank was the act 
which constituted the crime for which he suffers in the penitentiary. 
The bank's title to the money, therefore, rests on 
this criminal act and is of no validity in law, and hence the 
bank must account for the money. Such is the law as it has 
often been adjudged by the Supreme Court. 

In the first trial in the district court of Douglas county, 
Judge Baker expressly refused to follow the Supreme Court, 
and, consequently, instructed the jury to return a verdict 
for the bank. I brought the case to the Supreme Court, 
where it was reversed and sent back for a new trial. Under 
the rules of the district court, the clerk placed it on the </seg>


            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

5 

docket from which it went to the Supreme Court. Judge 
Baker did not hold that docket when the case was returned 
to it, but at his request the case was transferred to his docket. 
I thought this showed an unusual desire on the part of a 
judge to try a case, and' consequently objected to his hearing 
the case, but the bank wanted him to try it, and it said so, 
and he overruled my objections and proceeded to try the 
case. Ingenious counsel suggested to him that he did not 
have to try the case; that it was his duty to enter judgment 
on the old verdict, and this he promptly did. I filed a motion 
for a new trial, but he refused to consider it, or say when 
he would do so. Believing he had disobeyed the mandate of 
the Supreme Court in not granting me a new trial, I applied 
to that court for a mandamus to compel him to set aside 
his judgment and grant me a new trial. After a protracted 
fight, the mandamus was issued. Although, as the record 
shows, he had repeatedly declared that there was nothing 
in the case for a jury to pass on, he submitted the case to a 
jury with instructions which left no way by which the jury 
could find for the state. After being out about twenty-four 
hours, during which time they stood six to six, the jury returned 
into court and asked for an explanation of two instructions, 
but instead of explaining them, the court gave 
a peremptory command to obey the instruction already given. 
The result was a verdict for the bank. No other kind of a 
verdict could have been returned under the instructions. 

A motion for a new trial was promptly filed and submitted 
to the court. Under the mandamus it was Judge Baker's 
duty to take up the motion at once and pass on it without allowing 
other business to intervene, but he did not do so; 
instead he held it for more than two weeks and then showed 
no signs of disposing of it. Consequently I applied again for 
an order to compel him to pass on the motion. This order 
was promptly granted by the Supreme Court, and the motion 
for a new trial was overruled and judgment for the defendants 
was entered. I at once took steps to take the case to </seg>


            <seg id="p006">6 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

the Supreme Court. I had but a few days in which to prepare 
the record. When the clerk came to make the transcript 
he could not find the motion for a new trial. The last seen 
of the motion was when it was submitted to Judge Baker. 
When asked about it, the judge said he did not know where 
it was. The transcript of the record was completed, however, 
and the case was lodged in the Supreme Court in time 
to have it tried at the January term. 

There is no doubt in my mind but that, under the decisions 
of this state, as well as under those of nearly every other 
jurisdiction both English and American, the bank is liable 
to the state for the amount claimed, and I feel quite certain 
that that amount will eventually be recovered from it. 

The case of Mary Fitzgerald et al. against Poynter et al. 
was an action in equity wherein the sureties on ex-Treasurer 
Bartley's bond sought to enjoin the Governor and myself 
from further prosecuting the suit against them for upwards 
of $500,000. The bond case had been reversed by the Supreme 
Court at the instance of the state and was on the 
docket of the district court of Douglas county awaiting a 
new trial. A motion had been made by me to advance it 
and set it down for an early hearing. Pending action on the 
motion the sureties appeared in the Lancaster county district 
court and procured from one of the judges an order restraining 
the Governor and Attorney General from prosecuting 
the case in Douglas county. In the argument I denied the 
power of the court to restrain an executive state officer from 
performing a duty imposed on him by statute ; that to so restrain 
him would be to restrain the state itself whose agent 
he was ; that the restraining order was absolutely void and of 
no binding force on either the Governor or myself, and that it 
was only through respect for the court that I appeared at 
all. The judge before whom the matter was pending seemed 
to take that view of it and dissolved the order, but, for some 
unexplained reason, almost immediately reinstated it, and 
set the case down for argument before the full bench of three 

a </seg>


            <seg id="p007">EEPOET OF ATTORNEY GENffltAL. 

7 

judges. I presented the same argument to them that I had 
presented to th« one judge, and the matter was submitted 
with the request that an early decision be delivered. Pending 
the decision, the Governor and Attorney General were 
restrained from proceeding with the trial in Douglas county. 
A month elapsed, and no decision was given, no? was there 
any intimation as to when one would be given. Believing 
that the order was void, and that my duty to the state required 
me to disobey it, I did so, and entered on the trial in 
Douglas county notwithstanding the restraining order. I 
tried the case and secured a verdict for the state in the sum 
of |646,318.45. The morning after the verdict had been returned 
the Lancaster county judges handed down their decision, 
dissolving the restraining order and holding in effect, 
that the order was void. It was an unwarranted proceeding 
— a court restraining executive state officers from performing 
their duty under the law. 

Simpson vs. Union Stock Yards is an action pending in the 
U. S. circuit court for this district, and was brought by a 
stockholder of the Yards to restrain the Yards, the Attorney 
General, and the county attorney from enforcing the law 
regulating the charges of stock yards. The plaintiff has 
taken testimony at Kansas City, Chicago, Denver, and 
Omaha. To meet this testimony I employed Mr. Andrew 
Rose water, a very competent and experienced engineer, to 
prepare and submit a scheme for duplicating the yards, together 
with a statement showing the cost of the duplication. 
His testimony is in the record and shows for itself how very 
valuable it is. I approved vouchers for Mr. Rosewater in the 
sum of f 200, and he has been paid that amount by the state. In 
addition he has rendered a bill for $ 1,000. I do not know 
whether or not this bill is reasonable, but I believe it is, 
and that the legislature should allow it. Besides the testimony 
of Mr. Rosewater, other testimony was offered by the 
state, and still other collected by me through a careful examination 
of the Yard's books. This testimony, which has not </seg>


            <seg id="p008">8 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

yet been offered, can be presented in a short time and thus 
complete the taking of the testimony, for I understand the 
plaintiff does not desire to offer any in rebuttal. All the testimony 
would have been taken and the case submitted many 
months ago, but for the fact that the court thought it best 
not to take up the case until the Kansas Stock Yards case, 
now in the Supreme Court of the United States, and involving 
the same questions, substantially, as this case, has been 
passed on by that tribunal. 

Niagara Fire Ins. Co. vs. Cornell et al. is an action in the 
U. S. Circuit Court whereby the auditor and the attorney 
general have been enjoined from enforcing or attempting 
to enforce the insurance anti-trust law. It is based on the 
theory that the anti-trust law is unconstitutional. The constitutionality 
of that law has been settled by the supreme 
court of Nebraska in the standard oil case, and consequently 
there is little left to be tried in this case. 

In the case of Henry Bolln vs. The State, Bolln attempted 
to escape his sentenece of nineteen years in the penitentiary 
for embezzling about $100,000 of the public money of the city 
of Omaha by appealing to the supreme court to declare our 
statute authorizing county attorneys to prosecute by information, 
instead of by indictment of a grand jury, void as violative 
of the Federal constitution. The contention of Bolln 
was ingeniously pressed. I presented the case for the state. 
The law was declared to be valid, and the case was affirmed. 
This was a very important case. If Bolln's argument 
had prevailed, not only would it have entailed a great expense 
upon the counties in the future by requiring them to call a 
grand jury before a person could be tried for a crime, but it 
would have released more than two-thirds of those now in the 
penitentiary. 

McDonald vs. The State was a case inherited from my predecessor 
under the name of Bartley vs. Hayden, and grew out 
of the failure of the Capital National Bank, with $236,000 
belonging to the state. A most determined fight was made </seg>


            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

9 

to defeat the state's claim, but we finally won in the U. S. 
Circuit Court of Appeals, and the judgment of the lower 
court in favor of the state for $236,000 was affirmed; 
$35,454.27 have been collected by me on the judgment and 
paid into the treasury. 

State vs. First National Bank of Orleans was a case on a 
depository bond. Judgment in the sum of $ 15,825 was recovered 
against all the sureties served, but nothing has been 
collected yet. One of the sureties not served is solvent. His 
name is John W. Burton, and I have brought suit against him 
in Kansas. He has removed the case to the U. S. Circuit 
Court where it is now. 

The cases of Higginson vs. C, B. &amp; Q. Ry., C. &amp; N. W. vs. 
Smyth, C, B. &amp; Q. vs. Smyth, State vs. B. &amp;. M. R. R., State 
vs. F., E. &amp; M. V. Ry., State vs. C, St. P., M. &amp; O. Ry. all 
depend upon the validity of the law creating the board of 
transportation. If the supreme court adheres to its decision 
declaring that law void, these cases must go against the state. 
I have filed a motion for rehearing and hope it will be sustained. 


In the case of State vs. Kennard, the latter sued the 
state for about $20,000. The district court gave him judgment, 
but the supreme court reversed it, and on principles 
Avhich practically determined the case. Thus was the state 
saved upwards of $20,000. 

The State vs. The Home Ins. Co. was an action brought to 
recover from the insurance companies the amount of the 
Eugene Moore defalcation. The district court beat us, but 
th*e supreme court reversed it, and the result was that the 
state secured judgment. Some sixty companies agreed orallv 
to abide by the result of the decision. Some have done so, 
but how many I do not know. That matter is within the 
knowledge of the auditor and the treasurer. If all paid, 
as they should, the Moore shortage would be wiped out. 

Paxton vs. The State is the action brought to recover from 
his sureties the amount of Bartley's defalcation, amounting </seg>


            <seg id="p010">10 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

to |555,000, which, with interest, now amounts to about 
f 700,000. At the time of my last biennial report a judgment 
in this case against the state had just been reversed and the 
case remanded for a new trial. It was afterward tried, and 
a verdict directed for the state in the sum of $642,000. This 
judgment has been reversed upon one point only, and that 
point affects but $335,000. Every question in the case has 
been eliminated except the one, viz., Is the admission made 
by the state, when it declared by bringing its suit in Lancaster 
county against the first term bondsmen that Hartley 
had embezzled $335,000 in his first term, proof that Hartley 
did not have at the opening of his second term $958,000, in 
round numbers? The sureties themselves proved that he had 
a certain sum in cash and a certain sum in state depositories, 
and Governor Holcomb said he had the balance in bankable 
paper. No one contradicted any of this testimony. And 
even if Hartley was short $335,000 in his first term it would 
not even tend to prove that the above testimony was not true. 
He was short in his second term over $555,000, and yet he had 
over a million on hand. This shows how very little there is 
left in the case, and that the state must necessarily win. 

But whatever the outcome may be about the $335,000, the 
state is now entitled to a judgment for $220,000 which with 
interest from the 7th day of January, 1897, would amount to 
$281,600. About this there can be no sort of question. 

The judgment of reversal did not come until the 21st of 
November. This I deeply regret. Had the decision been 
earlier I would have tried the case before my term of office 
had expired, and thus relieve my successor of the great burden 
of familiarizing himself with the case. When the reversal 
did come the leading counsel for the sureties was very 
ill, and has not even yet recovered, and hence the case must go 
to my successor. 

The State vs. U. P. R. R. Co. is an action for penalties in 
the sum of over $600,000, on the ground that the company 
has violated the maximum freight rate law. This case pre- </seg>


            <seg id="p011">11 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

sents many interesting and important questions. The defendant 
company has expended about $20,000, it says, in 
preparing for the trial. By agreement, the case was referred 
to Hon. Ed. P. Smith and Judge E. It. Duffle to report the 
facts and the law. The state's testimony in chief and all 
the company's testimony is in, but much work yet remains 
for the state in the way of rebuttal testimony. 

No matter what the judgment may be in this case, the 
information elicited will be of incalculable value to the state. 

The standard oil case, as it is popularly called, is one 
brought under the anti-trurt law of the state. It took nearly 
a year of fight to establish in this case the validity of the antitrust 
statute, but success was finally attained. The parties 
are now awaiting the decision of the supreme court as to 
whether or not the defendant company must permit an inspection 
of certain of its books. If the order be in favor of 
the state, it will enable the latter to complete its case very 
soon. 

DEFECTS IN THE LAWS. 

It is conceded on all hands that the condition of the 
supreme court docket is deplorable. A case filed in the court 
to-day can not be reached for decision, unless specially 
advanced, inside of five years. • 

A litigant who has a just claim should not be required to 
wait that long before he receives a final adjudication in his 
favor. To make any litigant wait so long amounts to a 
denial of justice, but especially is this so where he is. poor. 
In fact, a poor man who has a claim against a wealthy one in 
this state had better take five cents on the dollar than go to 
law. He may recover in the district court, but his opponent 
can give a bond and take the case to the supreme court, 
and there it will remain for years. In the meantime the 
plaintiff is without his money, which, perhaps, he badly 
needs. Before two years are gone by, he will be willing to 
accept twenty-five cents on the dollar of hia righteous claim, </seg>


            <seg id="p012">12 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

and when he has paid his lawyer's fees and other necessary 
expenses, he has little if any, left. 

That the docket is so far behind is not the fault of the 
judges; this goes without saying amongst those familiar with 
the work of the court. Perhaps there are nowhere three men 
who labor harder mentally than the three judges of the 
Epreme court. Their hours are long and their work exact-5. 
The number of cases that may go to the supreme court 
n not be limited under our present constitution. How, 
then, is the court to be relieved? Permanently, by changing 
the constitution and increasing the number of judges. But 
that can not be done for many years. Temporary relief must 
be provided. There is only one way this can legally be done, 
and that is by authorizing the judges to call in assistance. 
Whether this assistance is to come from the district judges or 
commissioners is a mooted question in some quarters. I 
doubt that the legislature has the constitutional power to 
require district judges to perform any of the work of the 
supreme court, or, for that matter, to perform any work except 
that appertaining to the office of a district judge. True, 
they have been authorized to appoint park commissioners, 
etc., but I doubt the constitutionality of such laws. I think 
the most practical way of granting relief is through a commission. 
There should be enough commissioners to bring the 
work up to date as quickly as possible. Why should there 
not be? Why should not the court be given all the help 
needed to keep abreast of its work? If the treasurer, or 
auditor, or any other executive officer, or the superintendent 
of any state institution says he wants an additional clerk, 
or additional clerks, that the work of his office may be performed 
promptly, his request is granted without delay, and 
the question of expense is not raised, but when the court 
needs help men are found to urge economy, and, indirectly 
at least, to oppose the granting of the necessary assistance. 
This should not be. The court should have all the assistance 
it needs, and have it promptly. To have justice delayed, if </seg>


            <seg id="p013">REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

13 

not almost defeated, in our highest court, by reason of our 
unwillingness to grant the necessary relief, is a reflection 
on our state which should be removed, and at oncel In the 
foregoing connection there is another consideration which 
I would urge. The salaries of the judges of the supreme 
court are miserably low. Out of them they must pay the expenses 
of two trips a month from their homes to the capitol, 
each trip lasting about three or four days. Besides, each 
must pay the expense of an office and library at his home 
town. When all have been deducted, their salaries will not 
amount to much over |2,000. The truth is that more than 
half of the superintendents of the state institutions receive 
each anywhere from f 1,000 to $1,500 more than the chief justice 
of the state. In addition to their salaries, the superintendents 
are furnished quarters, fuel, lights, and board for 
themselves and families. The constitution prohibits the raising 
of the judge's salaries. Why not pass a law providing 
house rent for the judges at Lincoln? It is doubtful if the 
legislature could compel them to reside at Lincoln, but it 
might induce them to do so. If it succeeded, offices should 
be provided for them at the capitol, accessible to the state 
library. The judges then could consult together more frequently, 
and this I am sure would be very much more satisfactory 
to the court, the bar, and litigants. The additional 
expense would not exceed $2,500 a year, and the benefit 
derived would more than justify it. 

LEGISLATIVE JOURNALS. 

It is a fixed rule of decision of the supreme court that if 
the journals of the legislature show affirmatively that an act 
was not passed in a constitutional manner, the act is void. 
This emphasizes the supreme importance of keeping the 
journals correctly. As the journals have been kept in the 
past they are a disgrace to the capacity and intelligence of the 
body that kept them. The supreme court, speaking of them 
in a recent case, said : 

"In this case we have made a very careful examination of </seg>


            <seg id="p014">14 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

the journal of the house. For so important a record, it is, 
we must say, strangely fashioned, wonderfully made. It 
consists of loose sheets of paper bound together with a frayed 
and fragile twine." 

To keep them correctly would be an easy task if the legislature 
would make it a point to do so. The journal should be 
either printed or typewritten every night after the close of 
the day's session. Making it up out of scraps of paper and 
other make-shifts the most miserable should be discontinued. 
A committee of competent men should be created whose sole 
duty would be to see that the journals are kept correctly. 
No expense necessary to accomplish that end should be 
spared. Of what use is it to pay out a hundred thousand dollars 
for a legislature if its most important work is to be set 
aside because of the carelessness of a clerk or secretary in 
keeping the journals. 

CONCLUSION. 

Besides trying all the criminal cases brought to the supreme 
court from the lower courts ; advising county attorneys 
and state officers; performing the duties of a member of 
fourteen state boards, varying from the board of educational 
lands and funds to the embalmers' board; and trying the 
criminal cases against Bartley and Moore, this office has 
tried, during the four years which I have occupied it, civil 
cases involving in the aggregate nearly two millions of dollars. 
Final judgments have been recovered in the sum of 
$318,120.33, on which has been paid into the treasury about 
$50,000. 

All the serious questions in the Bartley bond case have 
been settled by the supreme court. The validity of the bond 
has been determined, although it was once adjudged by the 
district court to be invalid. Every dispute about $281,000 
of the shortage has been eliminated, and the state will be 
entitled to judgment for that amount whenever the case is 
called for trial. </seg>


            <seg id="p015">15 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Had the Omaha National Bank case been accorded a fair 
trial when it first came before the district court, or when it 
came the second or third time before that tribunal, the state 
would have judgment now for upwards of $253,000. The 
law of the case, however, is now so well settled by the supreme 
court that the next time the case comes before that court I 
think it will give such a direction to the lower court that even 
Judge Baker will enter judgment against the bank. 

But the cases brought to recover money and punish embezzelers 
do not represent, by any means, all the cases of importance 
tried during the last four years. There are many 
others i ivolving principles of great importance to the people 
of the state, and of much difficulty ; such for instance as the 
board of transportation cases, the Bolln case in the Supreme 
Court of the United States, the maximum freight rate cases, 
and the standard oil case. We successfully defended the 
power of the state to regulate railroads, telephone, telegraph, 
and express companies through a board of transportation 
against four separate attacks, three in the supreme court 
and one in the Federal courts. Then, as a last resort, the 
railroads attacked the manner of the passage by the legislature 
of the bill conferring the power, and they succeeded. 

My judgment is, after a careful study of nearly all the cases 
on the subject, that the only effective way to regulate railroads 
is through a competent commission with ample powers. 
Still a bill might be enacted reducing the rates on cattle, 
grain, etc., which would grant a great deal of just relief. 
Discrimination, perhaps, is one of the greatest evils. This 
the commission with the proper powers and means of executing 
them could eradicate. The state must provide for some 
sort of control, or else leave to railroad freight traffic managers 
the unrestricted power to fix such rates as they please. 
That they should not have that power must be conceded, especially 
when we reflect that the cost of transportation rarely, 
if ever, is taken into consideration in fixing a rate. A distinguished 
freight traffic manager recently testified, in effect, </seg>


            <seg id="p016">16 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

that the rate was governed entirely by the amount which the 
traffic Avould bear. 

The Standard Oil Company, through its counsel, made several 
vigorous assults on the validity of the anti-trust law; 
they urged that it violated the constitution of the state and 
the constitution of the nation. So determined and manyformed 
were the assaults that it took a full court year to meet 
them all and have it finally determined that the law was valid. 
In the work of enforcing the law against trusts my greatest 
difficulty has been in procuring evidence, but if the decision 
on the motion to inspect the Standard Oil Company's books 
be in favor of the state, not only the power of the state to 
control trusts, but also its power to compel them, whether 
foreign or domestic, to furnish evidence against themselves 
will be settled. This will be a long step forward, and will 
reduce very materially the difficulties in the way of the state 
in fighting the trust evil. 

In each of the foregoing suits my office was opposed by 
never less than two, oftener three, and sometimes eight of the 
leading lawyers of the state. This, of course, added greatly 
to the responsibility and difficulty of the work. 

My duties have brought me before the courts of every grade 
from the supreme court of the nation to the police court of 
our cities. I have found most courts fair and fearless. 
Some lacked the courage necessary to the proper discharge 
of their duties, but only one was in my opinion such as to 
make it improper to classify it here. We have a statute prohibiting 
judges from practicing law ; we should have one prohibiting 
them from practicing politics. But if such a statute 
would not be valid, we should have a public sentiment against 
it so energetic and powerful that the judge who considered 
the political effect rather than the justice of his decisions, 
or who became even an advocate on the political stump, would 
be made to feel that sentiment in the look and voice and 
words of every reputable citizen. Political parties could well 
afford to dispense with the services of judges as political man- </seg>


• 

<seg id="p017">HEPOBT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

17 

ipulaters. Fortunately there are but few to whom these remarks 
apply. Most of our judges have a correct conception 
of the sacredness and dignity of their positions. The sentiment 
I speak of should exist for the benefit of the judge who 
has not that conception. 

The period of my service as an attorney general will soon 
terminate. It has been a stormy one. Great have been the 
interests which I have had to combat. My only purpose 
throughout was to perform my duty and thereby prove loyal 
to my client — the State of Nebraska. In the performance 
of those duties I have no doubt aroused antagonism which 
will follow me out of office. Perhaps I am mistaken ; I hope 
so ; but I can not forget what was once said to me by a just 
«nd fearless judge : "The great combinations are awake while 
the people sleep." Never were truer words spoken. Whether 
their truth shall be made manifest in my case I, of course, 
do not know, but whether they be or not I shall always carry 
with me the consciousness that I at least attempted to perform 
my whole duty without fear or favor. He is a coward 
who shrinks from the performance of his duty before adverse 
power, however great. 

With pleasure I acknowledge the ever cheerful and efficient 
assistance given nte by Hon. W. D. Oldham, deputy 
attorney general, Paul Pizey, Esq., my assistant, and Miss 
Catherine A. Odell, stenographer. They are each and all 
entitled to share in any credit due to this office for the work 
it has done during the last two years. 

For the courtesies with which your Excellency has treated 
me in the performance of those duties which brought us together 
officially I am grateful, and cordially wish you success 
and happiness in your future undertakings. 

Respectfully submitted, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

2 </seg>



            <seg id="p019">OPINIONS. 

Lincoln, Neb., December 8, 1898. 

Col. TF. L. Henderson, County Attorney, Knox County, 

Creighton, Neb.: 

My Dear Sik — From your letter of recent date it appears 
that at the last general election there was submitted in due 
form to the people of Knox county the question whether or 
not a new county should be formed out of the territory now 
comprising that county; that there were cast 1,427 votes in 
the affirmative and 1,380 votes in the negative; that 2,993 
people voted at the election ; that the combined vote for the 
candidates for governor numbered 2,839, and that the candidates 
for governor received a greater number of votes than 
the candidates for any other office, and you ask my opinion 
as to whether or not, on this state of facts, the people of Knox 
county decided in favor of the erection of a new county. 

The question was submitted to the people under the provisions 
of sections 10 and 11, article 1, chapter 18, of the 
Compiled Statutes of 1897. Section 10 provides that the 
votes cast on the question shall be canvassed and the returns 
made as in case of election of county officers. Section 11 
provides that, "If it shall appear that a majority of all the 
votes cast at any such election in the county interested is in 
favor of the erection of such new county or counties, the 
county clerk of said county shall certify the same to the 
secretary of state," etc. To determine whether or not the 
question submitted has been decided in the affirmative, the 
county clerk must first ascertain the number of votes cast 
at the election, then the number of votes cast in favor-of the 
question, and, if the latter number is a majority of the first 

SCHEDULE "A." </seg>


            <seg id="p020">20 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

number, then the question has been decided in the affirmative. 
But how is the clerk to determine the number of votes cast 
at the election? No way seems to be provided in express 
terms. The number of votes cast may be ascertained by determining 
the number of persons who cast legal votes at the 
election, for, as we shall see later on, an illegal vote is not 
to be considered for 1 any purpose. The entire number of 
persons who voted at the election is disclosed by the poll 
books. From this number should be deducted the number 
of illegal votes, if any, returned by the judges and clerks of 
election. If there be none returned, then the presumption 
ia that all persons whose names appear upon the poll books 
cast legal votes and that each one cast one vote and no more. 
In the case under consideration you state that the poll book* 
show that 2,993 persons voted at the election and that there 
were no illegal votes cast. That being so, in my judgment, 
the people of Knox county have not decided in favor of the 
erection of a new county, for the reason that they cast only 
1,427 votes in the affirmative, or 69 votes less than a majority 
of the entire number of votes cast at the election. Those 
who contend that the question was decided in the affirmative 
insist that the number of votes cast at the election is determined 
by ascertaining the number of votes cast for the 
highest candidates, and if that be so that the greatest number 
of votes cast for any of said candidates was cast for the 
candidates for governor, being 2,839; that 1,427 is a majority 
of that number, and, hence, that the question has been 
decided in the affirmative. In support of this contention 
they urge the decision of the supreme court in the case of 
State ex rel. Hocknell vs. Roper et al., 47 Neb., 417. I do 
not think the case sustains their position. In that case the 
question presented to the court was whether or not ballots 
not accounted for, ballots rejected, and blank ballots should 
be considered as votes, and the court held that they should 
not. " In other words, the court held that void ballots — for 
the presumption is that the judges and clerks of election* </seg>


            <seg id="p021">21 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

did their duty, and that ballots rejected by them, or not 
counted or accounted for, were rejected or not counted, or 
accounted for, because of good reasons — were not to be considered 
for any purpose whatever; but that question is not 
in this ease. Every ballot cast in this case is, so far as the 
record shows, a legal ballot and hence entitled to be counted. 
It is further urged on the authority of the case of the State 
vs. Koper, supra, that the highest number of votes cast on 
any proposition or for any candidate is presumed to be the 
total number for which the requisite majority must be obtained. 
While this expression appears in the opinion, I think 
it must be construed with reference to the case then 
before the court, for it can not be that the court would 
assume that the highest number of votes cast for any candidate 
was the total number of votes cast, in the face of 
conclusive evidence that such was not the fact. In the absence 
of any evidence, I grant that the rule which I have 
just quoted would be the correct one. But it can not be so 
where the evidence shows that the highest number of votes 
cast on any candidate is not equal to the total number of 
votes cast. We know from the returns by the judges and 
clerks of election that the total number of votes cast in Knox 
county, that is, the total number of people voting at the election, 
is greater than the total number of votes cast for the 
candidates for any one office at that election. This we ascertain 
from the poll books, but it is urged that the county 
clerk has no right to consider the number of persons who 
voted at the election. He is limited in the evidence upon 
which he may base his- decision, say they, to the number of 
votes cast for candidates, as that number is ascertained by 
the canvassing board, and, since the canvassing board is not 
authorized to ascertain the number of persons voting at the 
polls, the clerk can not know legally anything about that 
"number. To this my answer is that under section 11, article. 
1, chapter 18, the clerk is not limited to anything in determining 
the number of votes cast at the election. So far </seg>


            <seg id="p022">22 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

as that section is concerned, he is left to determine in his 
own way the number of votes cast. The poll books present 
the best evidence of the number of votes cast, and therefore, 
if he is permitted to consult them, it would be his duty to 
be governed by what they show. May he consult them? In 
the case of the State ex rel. Welty vs. McFadden, 46 Neb., 
668, the supreme court, speaking through Judge Norval, says 
in the third paragraph of the syllabus: "The returns of an 
election consist of the whole election proceedings which the 
statute requires to be entered upon the poll books and tally 
list, viz., the certificates of the election officers, the list of 
those voting, and the tally list of the number of votes cast 
for the different persons, and from these the abstract of the 
vote is to be made." It appears, then, that the list of those 
voting is legally a part of the returns made to the county 
clerk by the judges and clerks of election. In the next paragraph 
of the syllabus, in the same case, the supreme court 
says : "In case of a discrepancy between the certificate and 
the tally list as regards the number of votes cast for a particular 
person, the canvassers must determine which is correct, 
after comparing them with the list of voters returned, 
and declare the result accordingly." In the case the court 
had then under consideration, the canvassers were called 
upon to decide a question. They found a discrepancy between 
the certificate and the tally list as regards the number 
of votes cast for a particular person, and they were authorized, 
says the court, in that event to compare the list of 
voters returned with the certificate and the tally list and 
determine therefrom which one was correct. Now, in the case 
which we are considering, the clerk, not the canvassing 
board, was called upon to decide a question, to-wit, the number 
of votes cast at the election. It was his duty to determine 
that fact from an examination of the returns made to him 
by the judges and clerks of election. In these returns, as we 
have seen, was a list of the voters. That list showed the </seg>


            <seg id="p023">23 

KEPOBT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

number of persons casting ballots, and, there being no illegal 
ballots cast, that list showed the number of votes cast. 

No one claims, as I understand it, that any person voting 
at the election cast an illegal vote. All admit that the total 
number of votes cast at that election is 2,993. The clerk is 
authorized to declare the question submitted carried if he 
finds that it has received a majority of all the votes cast at 
the election. It appears in this case that it has not received 
a majority M all the votes cast. From these considerations 
I am led to conclude that the people of Knox county have 
not declared in favor of (he erection of a new county out of 
the territory now comprising that county. 

Very respectfully, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., December 8, 1898. 

Letcis E. Walker, Esq., Bcnldeman, Neb. : 

My Dear Sir — In reply to your last letter I would say that, 
to our minds, the act of the party in taking a homestead in 
another state is clearly inconsistent with the idea that he 
intends to retain his residence in Nebraska, even though his 
family continues to reside here; but in a proceeding against 
the party for illegal voting, the question of his ib.dttt, being 
a question of fact, would have to be submitted to a jury, and 
what their verdict would be we could not anticipate. Likewise, 
what the holding of the land office would be on the 
question as to whether his voting in another state while he 
was claiming to have a homestead was such a violation of 
section 2297 of the United States Statutes at Large as to 
subject his claim to a successful contest, we are also unable 
to forecast. The rule is that the question of a man's residence 
i» governed by his intention. That he resides where 
he lias once chosen a residence until he leaves it without an 
intention of returning to it as a resident, but any act he </seg>


            <seg id="p024">24 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

may commit during his absence from a residence once fixed 
by him, which is inconsistent with the idea of his not having 
changed his residence, can be shown for the purpose of proving 
that he has actually changed his residence. 

In this particular case it is probably true that the election 
judges should not have allowed this man to vote, if the facts 
as stated by you were made known at the time. It is also 
probably true that in a civil contest his vote might not be 
counted. The whole matter is one so. largely agauestion of 
fact that it is impossible to state an inflexible rule that must 

govern- 

Very truly yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb., January 5, 1899. 
Hon. F. J. Birss, Hebron, Neb. : 

My Deab Sir — Your letter of the 3d, making inquiry as to 
wether or not the county.clerk who is "ex-officio" register of 
deeds is compelled to put his salary as clerk of the board 
on the fee book, has been duly received. 

You are advised that under the law of this state as construed 
by our supreme court such salary must be accounted 
for as part of the fees and must be placed upon the fee book. 
In other words, you are entitled to $1,500 per annum as you 

salary, and no more. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., January 5, 1899. 

J. Hammerly, Esq., Crcighton, Neb.: 

My Dear Sir — Your letter of the 24th ult., making inquiry 
with respect to the number of justices of the peace </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

25 

allowed in counties under township organization, and also 
other matters connected with the action of the town board, 
has been duly received. You are advised that townships in 
counties under township organization, except cities or 
villages of a certain class, are entitled to but one justice of 
the peace. 

The other matters in your letter should be referred to the 
county attorney of your county. He is made by law legal 
adviser, not only of the county but of the township officers. 
Consult him, and he will undoubtedly give you all the information 
desired. 

Very truly yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., January 10, 1899. 
A. E. Garten, Albion, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — In reply to your favor of January 7th would 
say that we are of the opinion that no person can legally 
hoJd the office of justice of the peace and assessor of the 
precinct at the same time. 

Very respectfully, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb., January 23, 1899. 

Hon. John B. Meserve, State Treasurer: 

Deau Sir — In answer to your question whether or not, in 
the opinion of this office, the county board in counties governed 
under the commissioner system may, for the purpose 
of discharging the indebtedness of a road district, levy upon 
the property of such district a tax which for county purposes </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
26 

REPOET OF ATTORNEY GENEKAL. 

would exceed 15 mills on the dollar valuation, permit me to 
say that it can not do so. 

My opinion is based on the reasoning of the case of 

C., B. &amp; Q. R. R. vs. Klein, 52 Neb., 259. 

I quote from pages 262 and 263: "Looking to all these 
provisions we think the framers of that instrument committed 
to the legislature the power to adopt one of two 
systems of county government : either to commit the management 
of the fiscal and other affairs of a county to some 
board, person, or tribunal, which should determine and assess 
the taxes necessary for the carrying on of the county government, 
in which event the taxes so assessed should not 
exceed 15 mills upon the dollar; or that the legislature 
should by law prescribe a system of township organization 
by which the affairs of the various townships of a county 
should be managed by the electors thereof, or some board or 
tribunal prescribed by law, and that these townships so 
constituted should assess such taxes upon the property 
therein for township purposes as they might see fit." 

Following this reasoning it is manifest that in a county 
nnder the commissioner system the board can not levy a tax 
to exceed 15 mills upon the dollar valuation. 

Yours truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., March 7, 1899. 

Hon. Hugh O'Neill, State Senator, Senate Chamber, Lincoln: 

Dear Sir — In response to your inquiry whether the legislature 
may, under our constitution, appropriate money for 
the construction of a bridge over the Niobrara river between 
Boyd and Holt counties, permit me to say that in my judgment 
the legislature may do so. This conclusion I base on 
the decision of our supreme court in the case of State vs. 
Moore, 40 Neb., 854, as well as upon general principles of </seg>


            <seg id="p027">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENEKAL. 

27 

constitutional construction. In the case just referred to, the 
legislature had made an appropriation of $7,495.73 to reimburse 
Seotts Bluff county for expenditures made in the trial 
of one Arnold, charged with murder. The auditor refused 
to allow the claim as presented and insisted upon his right 
to pass upon the correctness thereof. This right was denied 
by the county, and application was made by it to the supreme 
court for a writ of mandamus to compel the auditor to issue 
his warrant for the amount of the appropriation. In passing 
on the question thus presented, the court, on pages 858 and 
859 of the opinion, quotes extensively from Cooley on Constitutional 
Limitation, and concludes thus: "This appropriation 
may be unjust. In making it the legislature may have 
acted unwisely, but of these things the legislature itself is 
the sole judge. The courts can not inquire into the motive 
or justness of the law. Their only concern is with its 
legality." The conclusion of the second paragraph of the 
syllabus of the opinion is as follows : 

"Held, 

"(1) That the act was not in conflict with either the 
letter or spirit of the constitution. 

"(2) That the appropriation of this money was in the 
nature of a donation, and that no inquiry or objection is 
admissible on the part of the auditor as to whether the appropriation 
was just, whether it was bestowed upon an undeserving 
recipient, or what motives influenced the legislature 
to make it. 

"(3) That the only duty left for the auditor in the premises 
is a merely ministerial one. And that he has no authority 
to supervise the action of the legislature by an inquiry 
into the actual expenditures of Scotts Bluff county in the 
prosecution of Arnold." 

On page 858 in the opinion the court points out that there 
was no "legal obligation resting on the state to pay the 
expenses of the county, but the pow&lt;er of the legislature to </seg>


            <seg id="p028">28 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

appropriate money is not limited by the legal obligations of 
the state." 

From these quotations it clearly appears that there is 
nothing in the constitution which prohibits the legislature 
from making a donation, or which prohibits it from making 
an appropriation where there is no legal obligation to do so. 
There is no legal obligation on the state to build a bridge 
over the Niobrara river, but if the legislature should determine 
to build a bridge and appropriate money therefor 
its act would be, in my opinion, entirely constitutional. 

Very respectfully yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., March 23, 1899. 

Hon. J. V. Wolfe, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings, 

Lincoln, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — You have submitted to me the following question: 
The state by contract agreed to sell certain land to A; 
A rented the land to a tenant; A is delinquent in his payments 
; and the Board of Educational Lands and Funds may 
declare his right under the contract forfeited. What would 
be the right of the tenant to the crop sown ? 

In reply thereto, permit me to say that the tenant would 
be entitled to the crops. The title of A continues until the 
forfeiture is declared by the Board. The tenant of A had 
no way of knowing when he sowed his crops that the state 
would declare a forfeiture, but, if he did know that the state 
would do so, he had no way of knowing when it would do so. 

The tenant is, under the common law as well as under 
repeated decisions of the supreme court of this state, entitled 
to the crops sown. 

See: 

Sornberger vs. Vergren, 28 Neb., 299. 
Farley vs. McKeegan, 48 Neb., 239. </seg>


            <seg id="p029">REPOBT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

29 

McKean vs. Smoyer, 37 Neb., 694. 
Mundy vs. O'Neill, 44 Neb., 724. 

Very respectfnlly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., April 8, 1899. 

Mr. Frank McCartney, NebrasJca City, Neb.: 

Dear Slu — Your favor of the 7th was duly received. 
Therein you inquire whether the city council can, under the 
law, accept from saloon keepers a surety bond and thus comply 
with the requirements of section 6, chapter 50 of the 
Compiled Statutes of 1897. In answer thereto permit me 
to say that section 188a of chapter 16 of the Compiled Statutes 
of 1897, which appears to authorize the taking of a 
surety bond in all cases where bonds with two or more 
sureties are required, is in my judgment, void. This being 
so, section 6, supra, must govern, and that requires the bond 
to be signed by at least two good and sufficient sureties, free 
holders in the county in which the license is granted. 

If the council should accept a surety bond, such bond 
would be holden in case of the violation of its provisions by 
the saloon keepers, but the bond would pot be sufficient to 
justify the issuance of a license. 

Very truly yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., April 13, 1899. 

W. Z. Taylor, County Attorney, Culbertson, Neb.: 

Deae Sir — In reply to your favor of recent date, would 
say that we presume from the statement in your letter that 
the elevator on the B. &amp; M. right of way was assessed against 
George W. Wirt, as personal property for the years 1893, 
1894, 1895, and 1896. We presume this, although yoa do not </seg>


            <seg id="p030">30 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

state it in your letter, but from the location of the elevator 
being on the B. &amp; M. right of way, we presume it must have 
been assessed as a trade fixture or personal asset, and in 
answer to your first interrogatory would say that the taxes 
are a preferred claim on personal property to the claim of a 
mortgagee of said property. 

This question was settled by our supreme court in the 
case of Keynolds vs. Fisher, 43 Neb., 172, in which the following 
doctrine was laid down : "The lien of the taxes held 
superior in this case to the liens created upon the property 
by chattel mortgages executed subsequent to the delivery 
of the tax list to the county treasurer." 

Your letter does not state when the mortgage was executed 
on the property, but if it was executed subsequent to the 
delivery of the tax list to the county treasurer, then the lien 
was inferior to the tax lien. And unless the property was 
sold after the delivery of the tax books to the purchaser, it 
would be a superior lien for that year at least and attach to 
the property after sale. 

I However, our court held in the case of Hill vs. Palmer, 
2 Neb., C32, that "personal property sold and transferred 
ithout notice of taxes due, prior to warrant and levy, and 
ithout evidences of the statutory requirements creating 
en, held not subject to sale for prior taxes against vendor." 

Under this decision the question as to the tax lien attaching 
to the property after sale would turn, as you can see, on the 
question of notice, and would leave it a doubtful question, 
determined by the peculiar facts surrounding the case, of 
which we have not sufficient data from the statement in your 
letter to answer satisfactorily. 

You will notice, if you examine the decisions carefully 
just referred to, tliat the doctrine in this state is that the 
lien for personal taxes. is not a specific lien on each particular 
item of personal assets for which the taxes are levied, 
but that it is a general lien on all the personal property 
owned by the tax payer, whether it was assessed or not. </seg>


            <seg id="p031">31 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

My impression is that your safest plan in the matter which 
you refer to would be to answer in the bankruptcy proceedings 
and claim a general lien on all personal property, 
whether exempt or not, of the petitioner in bankruptcy for 
taxes, and to ask to have your lien made a preferred claim. 

This, I think, would be a safer plan than to attempt to 
levy the execution or take possession of the warehouse by 
other proceedings. 

Very respectfully yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General.* 

W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb., April 26, 1899. 

Hon. B. 0. Hostetter, Kearney, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — In reply to your favor of the 25th inst. would 
say that section 71, chapter 14, article 2, of the Compiled 
Statutes of Nebraska, was enacted as section 71, chapter 16, 
of the Laws of Nebraska, of 1883, and was then made applicable 
to cities of the second class having over 10,000 population. 
In 1885 this act was amended by chapter 14 of 
the Laws of 1885, and made to apply to cities of the second 
class having over 5,000 population. Since that enactment 
it is the opinion of this office that it is a legal and binding 
declaration on the rights of the city, and that all bonds issued 
by the mayor and council of a city of the second class 
having over 5,000 population, sinc% the enactment of the 
law, are issued subject to its provision. The rule is that 
purchasers of municipal bonds are charged with knowledge 
of the law under which the bonds are issued, and^if yonr 
bonds were issued since 1885, and since the organization of 
your city as a city of the second class having over 5,000 </seg>


            <seg id="p032">32 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

population, they are subject to redemption at the option of 
the city at any time after five years from their date. 

Yours respectfully, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb., April 26, 1899. 

Hon. John B. Meserve, State Treasurer: 

Dear Sir — House Roll, No. 431, which was approved April 
4 with the emergency clause, provides that "the officers of 
the bank seeking to qualify as a depository shall be ineligible 
to sign the bond provided for under this section." This 
provision presents two questions: first, whether or not directors 
are officers within the meaning of the law; and. 
second, whether, if they signed a bond as sureties, they could 
be held as such in the event that it is determined that they 
are officers. 

I will consider the first question. In our act on banks, 
wherever any reference is made to the subject, it appears 
that an officer and a director are considered as two different 
persons. Section 26, says "and no officer, director, or employee," 
etc. ; and section 28 says that "any officer, director, 
or employee" etc., thus indicating, so far as the laws of this 
state existing at the time House Roll No. 431 was passed 
are concerned, that directors were not regarded as officers. 
That the legislature in passing the House Roll just referred 
to used the word "officer" in the same sense in which it was 
used in the banking act is a very reasonable conclusion. 

Again, Bolles in his work on Bank Officers and Morse in 
hie work on Banks and Banking treat officers as a class 
distinct from directors. In the case of Vi£ Louisana State 
Bank vs. Senecal, 13 La., 525, the court declared that directors 
are not officers of the bank in the proper sense of </seg>


            <seg id="p033">33 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

the word. This opinion is approved by Bolles. From the 
foregoing it would appear that the conclusion should be 
that the legislature used the word "officers" in House Itoll 
No. 431 according to the meaning in which that word is employed 
in the standard works on banking, and hence that 
by "officer" is meant, not a director, but a person employed 
by the directory to manage the affairs of the bank. It must 
be conceded, however, that a director is in one sense an 
officer. And that possibly, when we consider the purpose 
which the legislature must have had in view when it passed 
House Koll No. 431, that it intended to include directors 
within the meaning of the word "officers." But I think the 
better opinion is that it did not so intend. 

This brings me to the second question, which is, whether, 
if the directors signed a bond as sureties, they could be held, if 
it should be determined that they were officers, within the 
meaning of House Roll No. 431. I have examined this question 
carefully. We have a statute which forbids attorneys 
to be taken on official bonds. There are many instances in 
which they were taken, and then a default occurred, and they 
sought to obtain their release, but the court in each case 
held them liable, and held the bond good. This is true, not 
only in our own supreme court, but in the supreme court of 
many other states, as shown by the memoranda attached 
hereto. It is also the rule laid down by Brandt on Sureties. 
Wherever a court is found which dissents from this rule, 
it will be found that it is in direct conflict with the decisions 
of our own supreme court, and therefore not authority in 
this state. 

In conclusion, therefore, I may say that it is my opinion 
that directors are not officers within the meaning of House 
Roll No. 431, and that if they are, and should sign a bond 
as surety, the bond would be valid and they could be held. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

3 </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
34 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Lincoln, Neb., May 19, 1899. 

Hon. J. F. Clegg, Mayor, Falls City, Neb.: 

My Dear Sir — Your letter of May 6th, signed by yourself 
as mayor and Messrs. Holland and Neitzel, eouneilinen, as 
committee of your city, making inquiry with respect to certain 
water bonds voted by your city in the year 1887 and 
1888, has been duly received at this office. These bonds contained 
a clause as follows: "Redeemable at any time after 
July 1, 1892, at the pleasure of said city, by giving six 
months' notice at the state fiscal agency in the city of New 
York at the time of payment of any coupon." The question 
propounded by you is, whether or not the city is compelled to 
give the six months' notice provided in the bonds in order to 
pay off the outstanding bond? 

We have given this matter a careful examination and have 
arrived at the conclusion that the city is not compelled to 
give such notice. These bonds were issued under the authority 
conferred by subdivision 15, section 69, article 1, 
chapter 14, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska. This statute 
provides that such bonds "shall become due in twenty years 
from the date of issue, but payable any time after five years," 
etc. This statute confers no authority upon the city officers 
to attach this further condition that six months' notice shall 
be given. The powers of city officers are expressly limited by 
the statute. If it might be said that they had authority to 
make a condition that six months' notice should be given, 
by the same course of reasoning it might be contended that 
they could attach a condition by which six years' notice 
should be given. That they have no such authority must be 
admitted. "As the bonds were issued under statutory power, 
the statute is the measure of the authority of the city council 
in the premises." 

State vs. Babcock, 24 Neb., 642. 

"All contracts made by municipal officers in excess of their 
powers are void." Omaha Natl. Bank vs. Omaha, 15 Neb., 
333. </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
35 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

In the matter of calling the elections at which each of 
these sets of bonds were voted, your city officers clearly 
attempted to act within the statutory provision above referred 
to. This is shown by the copies of the record and 
the copies of the notice enclosed in your letter. In neither 
of these appears anything with reference to this clause which 
now appears in the bonds requiring six months' notice to be 
given. The bonds in question were issued by the officers of 
the city acting under and by virtue of the statute and under 
and by virtue of the authority conferred upon them by the 
vote of the electors of the city. What authority was delegated 
to the officers by the voters is evidenced by the records 
of the city. 

"The records of a city are notice to all persons of the 
authority of its officers, and when they transcend the limit 
of the power granted, their acts are void." Wheeler vs. 
Plattsraouth, 7 Neb., 270. In this case the officers of the 
city, by inserting this clause in the bonds providing for six 
months' notice, clearly transcended the limit of the power 
granted, and their act in that respect is void. 

The authorities all agree that all persons dealing with 
municipal corporations must take notice of the laws under 
which they act, and any action by municipal officers in excess 
of the authority conferred by law is absolutely void. 

We return you herewith the copies of the bonds and other 
papers sent us. 

Very truly yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By Geo. F. Corcoran, 

Assistant. 

Lincoln, Neb., June 5, 1899. 
Hon. W. A. Poyntcr, Governor: 

Sir — At the request of your Excellency, I have inquired 
into the cause of the indictment and arrest of sheriff Dorgan,</seg> 


            <seg id="p036">36 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

of Dawes county, by the Federal authorities, for the purpose 
of determining whether or not, in my opinion, there was anything 
connected therewith by which it was sought to subordinate 
the civil authority of this state to the military authority 
of the United States, and, if so, whether the state 
should be represented by the attorney general in the defence 
of Mr. Dorgan. 

Briefly stated, the result of my inquiry is as follows : The 
house of a farmer living some distance from Chadron in 
Dawes county was broken into, and certain property stolen. 
The farmer, after some investigation, discovered the culprits 
and caused a warrant for their arrest to be duly issued and 
placed in the hands of sheriff Dorgan. The two persons 
charged with the crime, and whom the sheriff was authorized 
to arrest, were two soldiers belonging to that part of 
the army of the United States stationed at Fort Robinson. 
The sheriff, acting under his warrant, arrested the two just 
as they were about to step upon the train at the Chadron 
station to go to Fort Robinson. . With the soldiers arrested 
was a quartermaster's sergeant who, in very coarse language, 
forbade the sheriff to make the arrest and made some effort 
to prevent him from doing so. The sheriff, however, retained 
his prisoners; they were afterwards tried on the charge on 
which he had arrested them, were convicted, and are now 
in the state penitentiary. This is the sheriff's story to me. 
From the United States authorities I have learned that they 
claim that the two soldiers arrested by Mr. Dorgan had been 
arrested by a quartermaster's sergeant on the charge of desertion 
some time before the sheriff arrested them; that they 
were under arrest at the time that the sheriff took them into 
his custody ; that he knew they were under arrest ; and that 
in taking them away from the quartermaster's sergeant he 
was guilty of a violation of the Federal statutes, which provides 
for the punishment of any person who assaults an 
officer of the United States, or rescues a prisoner of the</seg> 


            <seg id="p037">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

37 

United States from such an officer, or aids or entices desertion 
from the United States military service. 

The Fifty-ninth Article of War provides in substance that 
when an officer or soldier is accused of any offence against 
the person or property of a citizen of the United States that 
the commanding officer, etc., of the regiment, etc., to which 
the person so accused belongs is required, except in time of 
war, upon application duly made in behalf of the party injured, 
to use his utmost endeavors to deliver the accused 
person over to the civil magistrate, and to aid officers of 
justice in apprehending and securing him. And it is further 
provided therein that, if such commanding officer refuses 
or wilfully neglects to do what is required of him by the provisions 
just referred to, he shall, upon conviction, be dismissed 
from the service. Whether under that article the 
commanding officer would be required to grant the application 
where the person charged with crime by the civil 
authorities was under arrest by the military authorities for 
an infraction of military law is a question upon which all 
the authorities are not united. 

The Judge Advocate General, in a note found on page 721 
of the Military Laws of the United States for 1889, states 
that, upon the arrest by the military authorities, the military 
jurisdiction attaches, and the civil authorities are not, as a 
matter of right, entitled to the accused until the military 
authorities have disposed of him. This opinion is not, however, 
as I view it, in accordance with the opinion of Attorney 
General Cushing, rendered many years ago and which is referred 
to by nearly all the authorities on military law as 
setting forth correct principles with regard to the interpretation 
of the Fifty-ninth Article of War. The opinion is 
exhaustive and displays much learning and great ability. It 
is certainly the result of that opinion that it is the duty of 
the military authorities to surrender to the civil authorities 
a person charged with crime at any time before the court 
martial has arraigned him and he has pleaded to the merits. </seg>


            <seg id="p038">38 

R f*jf^^if\ |^ CJI? ** F f^it*.^T\^^ KY It Pj Hi 1*^1^. A I i T 

I quote from page 423 of the opinion, "Nay, if the coart 
martial has gone only so far as to have arraigned the party, 
and he has pleaded to the merits, accepting the jurisdiction, 
it seems to me that the civil magistrate can not, then, interpose 
to try the act." (Op. Atty, Gen., vol. 6, p. 413.) 

In this view, Winthrop,. in his work on Military Law, concurs. 
(2d Ed., p. 125.) Lieutenant Ives, for many years 
assistant professor of law in the Military Academy, in his 
treatise on Military Law, sets forth similar views to those 
expressed by Attorney General Cushing and Mr. Winthrop. 
(p. 40.) In this connection he calls attention to the case of 
Captain Howe, tried in 1839, in which the commanding 
officer surrendered the captain to the civil authorities after 
the court martial proceedings had commenced, but he does 
not say this was required by a correct interpretation of the 
Fifty-ninth Article. 

In view of the foregoing, I am of the opinion that if sheriff 
Dorgan knew, prior to making the arrest, that the two soldiers 
had been arrested by the military authorities and were 
then in the custody of those authorities, it would have been 
his duty to have proceeded in the manner pointed out by the 
Fifty-ninth Article of War. And if he had done so, it would 
have been, in my judgment, the duty of the commanding 
officer of the detachment to which the two soldiers belonged 
to surrender them to him. In doing this, the civil authorities 
would not be conceding the superiority of the military, nor 
would they be, in the least, waiving the principle that the 
military is ever subordinate to the civil. That question 
would not be involved at all. The Fifty-ninth Article simply 
provides a mode of procedure for the assertion by the civil 
authority of its superiority to the military, and this mode, 
it must be conceded, is necessary to the proper discipline of 
the army. 

If, on the other hand, sheriff Dorgan did not know at 
the time he made the arrest that the two soldiers were under 
arrest by the military authorities, he is not guilty of having </seg>


            <seg id="p039">39 


violated tbe Federal statutes referred to. But that is a 
question of fact, and, of course, in no way involves the dignity 
of the state or its authority. For the reason stated, I am 
of the opinion that the state has no such interest in the indictment 
and arrest of sheriff Dorgan as would require the 
interposition of the executive. 

Very respectfully, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., June 7, 1899. 

Hon. Jan E. Lcyda, County Attorney, Falls City, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — In reply to your favor of recent date would say 
that in our judgment the work of making a new set of numerical 
indices could only be done under the supervision of 
the county clerk of your county. This record must be an 
official record, and no one is authorized to make it, by law, 
except the county clerk or a deputy under his charge. It 
seems to us that the proper method would be for the board 
to authorize the county clerk to employ additional help for 
the preparation of the new set of indices, and to allow the 
compensation fixed as additional help authorized by the 
board to the county clerk for such additional services. We 
do not think the county clerk himself would be entitled to 
receive any compensation in excess of that allowed by law, 
but, as this work is authorized by statute, we think your 
board would have the authority to direct the clerk to employ 
such additional help as would be necessary to prepare the 
numerical indices and compensate them for it. 

Very truly yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorncu General. 

By W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. </seg>


            <seg id="p040">40 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Lincoln, Neb.. June 8, 1899. 

Hon. R. P. Anderson, County Attorney, He ward, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — Your favor of the 5th inst. has been duly received. 
In reply would say that section 12 of article 2, Compiled 
Statutes for 1897, seems to make it mandatory on your 
board to make the levy therein, provided for in favor of the 
agricultural society organized under the provisions of that 
section, unless the existing county agriculture society fails, 
or has failed for two years or more, to hold an annual fair 
of at least three days. Now it seems to me that the question 
of the liability of your county for the levy this year turns 
on the question as to whether the society had neglected for 
two years to hold its fair, and that the passage of the act of 
1899 would not release you from the liabilities which occurred 
under the act of 1897, but would only make it optional 
for you for liabilities occurring under that act after its 
passage. It is true that section 13 of chapter 9 does provide 
that it shall be the duty of the agriculture society to annually 
offer an award premium. But section 12 above referred to, 
and also section 17 of chapter 2, refer to a neglect for the 
space of two years as being the cause of a forefeiture of the 
rights of such society to the provisions of the act under 
which they are organized. It therefore follows that, in my 
judgment, unless the society has neglected for two years to 
hold its fair, your county is liable for the levy provided for 
in section 12, of chapter 2, but will not hereafter be liable, 
and the board may hereafter use its discretion about making 
the levy. 

Very truly yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By W. D. Oldiiam, 

Deputy. </seg>


            <seg id="p041">41 

EEPOET OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Lincoln, Neb., June 16, 1899. 

J. T. Parker, County Attorney, St. Paul, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — In reply to your favor of the 15th inst. would 
say that, after a careful examination of the question propounded 
by you and a careful consideration of the decision 
of our supreme court in the case of John T. Bressler vs. The 
County of Wayne, 32 Neb., 834, I am of the opinion that 
section 32 of chapter 77, article 1, of the Compiled Statutes, 
does not apply to state or national banks; that section 33 
of said chapter was intended to provide a method of assessing 
the stocks of incorporated banks in this state, whether they 
be state or national ; that this section as construed and sustained 
by our court in the decision above referred to provides 
for the assessment of the shares of the stock of banking corporations 
at their cash value on the 1st of April. But there 
is no provision for deducting indebtedness from this valuation; 
nor would there be any warrant for deducting personalty 
or realty of the bank from their valuation; that that 
method of assessment only applies to other corporations than 
banking corporations; that section 33 applies to banking 
corporations alone and prescribes a particular method by 
which the shares of stock of such corporations shall be assessed; 
and that section and the provisions thereof are entirely 
independent and apply to a different class of corporations 
from those governed by section 30 and section 32 of this 
chapter. 

Very respectfully, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb., June 28, 1899. 
Hon. John F. Cornell, Auditor: 

Dear Sir — In reply to your favor of the 23d inst. would 
say that section 69a, chapter 43, of the Compiled Statutes </seg>


            <seg id="p042">42 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

of 1897 requires that "city and village insurance companies 
must set apart as a reserve fund not less than 10 per cent of 
the amount collected in cash at the time of issuing their 
policy." Under this requirement the 10 per cent must be 
calculated on the total amount of cash paid by the policy 
holder at the time of the issuance of the policy. The agent 
who solicits the policy is the employee of the company and 
not of the policy holder, and the 10 per cent reserve fund 
is for the benefit of the policy holder. Consequently, the 
amount which the company pays the agent should not be 
deducted from the amount actually paid in cash by the policy 
holder before the 10 per cent is reserved. 

2. If, at the time of the issuance of a policy, the policy 
holder pays 50 per cent of the old line rate, and this 50 per 
cent is called the cash percentage, and he also pays the 
registration fee, then the 10 per cent should be calculated 
on both the cash percentage and the registration fee. 

3. The statute is mandatory and positively directs that 
such part of the reserve fund as may not be needed for 
immediate use must be invested in Nebraska state, school, 
or connty bonds or state warrants, and under the statute no 
other kind of an investment is permitted. 

Very truly yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb., August 11, 1899. 

Mr. Jesse L. Root, County Attorney, Plattsmonth, Neb.: 
Dear Sir — In reply to your favor of recent date would 

say that I have examined the provisions of section 147, 
article 1, chapter 77, of the Revenue Law, and am of the </seg>


            <seg id="p043">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

43 

opinion that the intention of the legislature in passing that 
section was to prevent the necessity of carrying on the books 
of the county treasurer delinquent taxes which, after due 
diligence, he had determined to be uncollectible on account 
of the non-residence or death of the parties owing the tax; 
but there is nothing in that section which makes the striking 
of this delinquent tax from the list a payment of the tax. 
If any such construction bad been attempted to be authorized 
by the legislature, this act would clearly have been in conflict 
with section 4 of article 9 of the constitution, and I am 
of the opinion that, although the tax had been canceled in 
the manner prescribed in the section above referred to, yet 
if the parties against whom it was cancelled have returned 
to and now reside in Cass county, the tax can be collected 
from them, and I trust that you will contest this right in 
the courts of your district, and if judgment is given against 
the county that you will appeal it to the supreme court, where 
we shall be pleased to assist you in having this matter finally 
determined, as I deem it of great importance to the taxpayers 
of the state. 

Yours respectfully, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb., November 29, 1899. 

Hon. W. W. Wilson, County Attorney, Nebraska City, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — Your favor of the 29th, with respect to the 
amount of the bond to be given by the deputy county treasurer 
of your county, was duly received. It is my opinion 
that section 20 of chapter 10 is decisive of the question propounded. 
The Dond must be given in the same manner and 
for the same sum as the bond of the principal. This is in </seg>


            <seg id="p044">44 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

effect the language of the statute just referred to, and since 
there is no other statute upon the subject it must control it. 

Very truly yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., November 29, 1899. 

His Excellency IF. .4. Poynter, Governor of the State of 

Nebraska : 

Sir — Permit me to say that I have your letter of recent 
•date, in which you state that it has come to your attention 
that a man was shot in the village of LaPlatte, Sarpy county, 
this state, by two United States soldiers; that the civil authorities 
of that county have declined to take official notice 
of the affiair on the ground that the man who was killed and 
the men responsible for the killing were both at the time 
of the killing serving in the army of the United States, and 
amenable to the military authorities; that the tragedy 
seems to you a fit subject for civil inquiry, and you request 
that this office investigate the matter and report to you. By 
this I understand that you desire to know whether those 
guilty of the homicide are in law answerable to the courts 
of this state, and, if so, what steps are necessary to bring 
them before those courts. 

In reply thereto, I have the honor to say that the courts of 
Nebraska are the only tribunals competent to try those 
charged with violating the laws of Nebraska in times of peace, 
whether they be citizens or soldiers. The military offence, 
if any, committed by the soldiers in shooting down the fleeing 
soldier-prisoner may be tried and punished by military court, 
but the offence, if any, committed against the peace and 
dignity of this state can not be punished except by the civil 
courts of Nebraska. This rule is recognized by the army 
itself, by military writers, and by the supreme court of the 
United States, as well as by other authorities. </seg>


            <seg id="p045">45 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

The Fifty-ninth Article of War reads thus : 

"When an officer or soldier is accused of a capital crime 
or of any offence against the person or property of any citizen 
of any of the United States, which is punishable by the 
laws of the land, the commanding officer and the officers of 
the regiment, troop, battery, company, or detachment to 
which the person so accused belongs, are required, except 
in time of war, upon applications duly made by or in behalf 
of the party injured, to use their utmost endeavor to deliver 
him over to the civil magistrates, and to aid the officer 
of justice in apprehending and securing him, in order to 
bring him to trial. If, upon such application, any officer 
refuses or wilfully neglects, except in time of war, to deliver 
over such accused person to the civil magistrates, or to aid 
the officers of justice in apprehending him, he shall be dismissed 
from the service." 

"The martial or military law," says Tytler, page 81, "does 
in no respect either supersede or interfere with the civil and 
municipal laws of the realm; hence it appears that soldiers 
are equally, with all other classes of citizens, bound to the 
same strict observance of the laws of the country and are 
alike amendable to the ordinary civil and criminal courts 
of the country for all offences against those laws and breach 
of those duties." 

"Assault and battery and homicide" says Attorney General 
Cushing, "are violations of the municipal laws of the place 
where committed, to be tried and punished by the proper 
tribunal of the state or territory whose peace and laws are 
broken or offended." (Howe's Case, 6 Op. Atty. Gen., 511.) 

Mr. Justice Field, in the case of Coleman vs. Tennessee, 7 
Otto, 509, after stating that the Articles of War do not take 
from the civil tribunals the power to punish members of the 
army for offences committed against the laws of the state, 
says, "With the known hostility of the American people to 
any interference by the military with the regular administration 
of justice in the civil courts, no such intention should </seg>


            <seg id="p046">46 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

be ascribed to Congress in the absence of clear and direct language 
to that effect." 

Nor does the fact, if fact it be, that a court martial has 
tried and acquitted the man charged with the killing, affect 
in any way the power of the civil courts to investigate the 
affair according to their usual processes, and, if it be found 
that he is guilty, to punish him according to law. 

"A former acquittal or conviction of an act by a civil 
court," says Benet, "is not a good plea in bar before a court 
martial on charges and specifications charging the same." 
(Page 115.) 

"A conviction and sentence of such an offender by the 
proper judicial tribunal of the state is no bar to the subsequent 
proceedings of a court martial in a case where the 
criminal act for which the accused was indicted is also a 
breach of the Rules and Articles of War." (3 Op. Atty. 
Gen., 749.) 

Those are the views of the military authorities with respect 
to the effect of a conviction or acquittal by a civil 
court, and are based on the idea, as I have before suggested, 
that there are two distinct offences, one against the civil law 
and one against the military law. 

"An offence," says Mr. Justice Greer, speaking for the Supreme 
Court of the United States, "means, in its legal significance, 
the transgression of a, law." Therefore the transgression 
of the military law is one offence and the transgression 
of the state law another offence. 

"That either or both governments may punish such offender 
can not be doubted; yet it can not be truly averred that the 
offender has been twice punished for the same offence." 
(Moore vs. People, 14 How., 19.) 

Chief Justice Taney said of one charged with an offence 
against the law of the United States, and also against the 
laws of a state, that, "His punishment in one sovereignty is 
not a bar to his punishment in the other." </seg>


            <seg id="p047">EEPOHT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

47 

To the same effect are Wharton Cr. Law, 7 Ed., 435 ; Whit- 
Ing War Powers, 43 Ed., 188. 

It can not be gainsaid that the men guilty of the killing 
referred to in the letter of your Excellency are subject to 
the jurisdiction of the courts of Sarpy county, whether they 
have been tried and acquitted or not by a court martial. 

The county attorney of that county is the officer charged 
by law with the duty of investigating the offence, and if, after 
such investigation, he has reasonable cause for believing that 
a crime has been committed — the mere fact of the killing of 
one man by another not being enough to show that the law 
has been violated — it would then be his duty to file a complaint 
before a proper magistrate and have the supposed 
criminal brought before him for examination. 

Your Excellency, to whom the Constitution has entrusted 
the duty of seeing that the laws are executed, may address 
the county attorney a note requesting him to investigate the 
case and report to you his findings of fact. If he should 
report that in his opinion no crime has been committed, and 
that he will not therefore file a complaint, and you should 
still desire to have the affair subjected to a judicial investigation, 
my office will, upon your request, cause a complaint to 
be filed against the alleged offenders, and will have them 
brought before a magistrate for examination, where the act 
complained of may be judicially scrutinized and its probable 
legal effect determined. 

Respectfully, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., December 18, 1899. 

Jesse Tj. Root, Esq., County Attorney, Plattsmouth, Neb.: 
Dear Sir — Your letter of some days ago was duly received. 

In it you state that the county board is about to proceed to 
refund $80,000, court house bonds and also $ 10,000, railroad </seg>


            <seg id="p048">48 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

bonds of Plattsmouth precinct in Cass county, and that they 
inform you that they intend to refund both issues of bonds 
after applying avails of sinking fund to the redemption of 
bonds, under the provisions of sections 38 to 41 of chapter 9, 
Compiled Statutes of 1899, and asking an opinion of this 
office as to the legality of the sections under which the county 
commissioners are about to proceed, and whether such' act 
would be legal without first submitting the proposition to 
a vote of the tax payers. 

In reply thereto I would say that sections 3S to 41 of 
chapter 9 of Compiled Statutes of 1899 constitute chapter 8 
of the Laws of Nebraska of 1899. An examination of that 
act reveals that it is a complete and perfect act within itself ; 
that its title is as follows: "An act empowering corporate 
authorities of cities of the second class, villages, and counties 
to take up and pay off valid outstanding bonds of 
the issue and sale, or by the issue and exchange therefor, of 
bonds bearing an equal or a lower rate of interest, and prescribing 
a procedure in that behalf, and repealing sections 
141a to 1416, both inclusive, of article 1, chapter 18, of Compiled 
Statutes of Nebraska of 1897, and sections 11, 12, and 
13 of chapter 45 of said statute, and all acts and parts of 
acts in conflict with this act." 

You will see from an examination of this title that it is 
expressive of everything contained within the act; that it 
deals with the whole subject of refunding and discharging 
bonded indebtedness of counties, cities of the second class, 
and villages ; and that nothing in the act attempts to confer 
any authority to create a new indebtedness for any additional 
liability not already existing by the authorities enumerated 
in the act;. It only confers power on the board to refund 
and settle a matured indebtedness of the various municipalities. 
And I do not think the act is obnoxious to any doctrine 
laid down by the court in the case of The State vs. Babcock, 
21 Neb., 194, in which the court says, "A county or any 
of its subdivisions has no inherent right to vote bonds. The </seg>


            <seg id="p049">UKPOBT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

49 

right therefore is derived entirely from the statutes, the terms 
of which must be substantially complied with." 

This decision clearly limited the right of creating an indebtedness 
against a municipality to the statute requiring 
a legal petition in the first instance and a vote of the tax 
payers in the second, before any indebtedness could be entailed 
on the tax payers. But the provisions of chapter 8 of 
the Laws of 1899 deal with the right of the commissioners 
to provide for the payment and adjustments of bonded indebtedness 
already incurred by the tax payers, and not with 
the rights of the boards to either increase or add to an indebtedness 
already existing. I am therefore of the opinion 
that chapter 8 of the Laws of 1899 is a complete, perfect; 
and valid act, and repeals either directly in its title and 
subject matter all sections of the statute in conflict with it, 
or, by being a complete act by implication, would repeal any 
sections not enumerated therein as being specifically repealed. 
And from this conclusion it follows that, in our 
opinion, the action of the board would be legal in the matter 
stated in your communication. » 

Very truly yours, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb v December 19, 1899. 

To the Board of Secretaries, State Board of Transportation: 

GENTLEMEN — You, through your chairman, Hon. J. E. 
Edgerton, have stated to me that the railroad companies 
doing business in this state abandoned, on December 1, car 
load rates, and on that date substituted for them rates per 
hundred pounds, and thereby very considerably increased 
rates in that respect; that during the summer of 1897 the 
same companies made an attempt to make the same change; 

4 

By W. D. Oldham, </seg>


            <seg id="p050">50 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

that complaint was made to you by the shippers of the state ; 
Eou investigated the matter, all the companies being 
t and participating in the investigation, and that, as 
It of that investigation, you made an order directing 
the maintaining of the car load rates and forbidding the 
companies to substitute for them rates per hundred pounds; 
that by the action of the companies on December 1, referred 
to above, that order has been violated and is now being violated, 
and you ask me what remedy, if any, the state has in 
the premises. 

The statute seems to provide but one remedy in this case. 
Section 9 of article 8 of chapter 72 declares, in effect, that 
if any railroad company shall refuse to obey an order of the 
board, it shall be subject to a fine of not less than $500 or 
more than f 5,000 for each violation of the order. 

Section 16 provides that where the company refuses, after 
having received notice, to answer, and an order of the board 
is made, that an injunction may be obtained to prevent the 
disobedience of the order. 

Section 17 provides that where an order is made by the 
board adverse to the railroad company and an appeal is 
taken by the company to the district court, such order may be 
made by the court as the law shall warrant. 

In the case now under consideration I think that the only 
remedy which can be availed of by the board is that provided 
by section 9, to-wit, an action to recover in the name of the 
state the fine imposed by that section. 

Therefore, procure, if you have not "already done so, the 
evidence showing a violation of the board's order, lay that 
evidence before me, and this office will take action promptly 
to recover the penalties imposed by the statute. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. </seg>


            <seg id="p051">REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

51 

Lincoln, Neb.&gt; December 20, 1899. 

Hon. John F. Cornell, Auditor of Public Accounts: 

Dear Sir — There is now pending in the circuit court of 
the United States for the district of Nebraska a case wherein 
the following named insurance companies, that is to say : 

The Niagara Fire Insurance Company, of New York, 

The German American Fire Insurance- Company, 

The Traders' Fire Insurance Company, of Chicago, 
The National Fire Insurance Company, of Hartford, 

The Fire Association of Philadelphia, and the 

Springfield Fire and Marine Insurance Company, 
seek a permanent injunction restraining the State of Nebraska, 
through certain of its executive officers, from enforcing 
against them what is known as the anti-insurance 
compact or trust law. 

They, at the commencement of the case, secured a temporary 
restraining order, which is now and ever since has 
been in force. The ground of their contention is that the law 
is unconstitutional. 

These insurance companies, all foreign companies, do business 
in this state, not as a matter of right but through 
comity. If the state sees fit to exclude them, it may do so, 
or it can prescribe the conditions upon which they may do 
business. In view of this, their attitude in refusing to obey a 
just law passed by the legislature and signed by the Governor 
fully warrants you in refusing to them permission to do business 
in this state. If they are not willing to accept our laws, 
and especially a law which forbids trusts and unlawful combinations, 
they should not be permitted to avail themselves, 
through the law of courtesy, of the great benefits which accrue 
to them by reason of being permitted to carry on their 
business in the state. For these reasons I would suggest to 
you that you withhold from them permission to do business 
during the next year, or until they declare a willingness to 
comply with all the laws affecting them on the statute book. </seg>


            <seg id="p052">52 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

It is your right, in my judgment, to do this, and I am sure 
that it will be your pleasure. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., January 5, 1900. 

W, R. Butler, Esq., County Attorney, O'Neill, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — Your communication with reference to House 
Roll No. 251, entitled, "An act to amend section 3 of chapter 
28, entitled Fees, of the Compiled Statutes of the State of 
Nebraska, for the year 1897, and to repeal said original section," 
is received. 

In reply thereto I would say that I have some very serious 
doubts as to whether the act as compiled in the Session Laws 
of 1899 has ever passed either house of the legislature, and 
as to whether it can be upheld at all. 

The history of the law is briefly this : The bill, just as it 
is compiled in the Laws of '99, was introduced in the house 
as House Roll No. 251. It was amended by Representative 
Clark with a provision that it should not go into effect until 
January, 1900. This amendment was agreed to in the house, 
and the bill as amended passed the house with little or no 
opposition. It then went to the senate and was amended 
again there by Senator Prout, and passed the senate with 
bpth the Clark and Prout amendments to the bill. It then 
came back to the house and passed the house, the roll call 
showing that every member present voted for it, and also 
showing that every member present voted against it. The 
enrolling clerk then enrolled the bill as originally introduced 
into the house, but a bill that in fact never passed either 
house of the legislature. 

Our supreme court has held in the Dr. Abbott case that 
the enrolled bill governs when the journals of the house and 
senate show that it has passed those bodies. The language </seg>


            <seg id="p053">53 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

i 

of the syllabus of the case being, "The enrolled bill, authenticated 
by the proper officers of the house, approved by the 
Governor and filed with the Secretary of State, and the 
journals of the house are the official records of the proceedings 
of the legislature relative to the enactment of the 
law, and are the only competent evidence in the controversy 
in regard to the due passage of the bill, or in respect to alleged 
material errors in its substance." 

See State vs. Abbott, vol. 80, No. 6, p. 500, N. W. Reporter. 

Of course it is not the policy of this office to go in advance 
of the courts in declaring a law unconstitutional or in questioning 
the legality of the proceedings of the legislature, but 
this is a matter that has been agitated a great deal, and we 
had thought it well to inform ourselves, as well as the different 
county attorneys of the state, as to the exact status of 
the bill and the probable outcome of a contest as to its 
validity. Of course if the clerks desire to follow the law 
as it is printed in the Session Laws, we encourage and have 
encouraged them in doing so, but if they refuse, and you are 
compelled to litigate the case, the chances are, if the clerk 
has counsel to look the matter up carefully, that there will 
be serious doubt connected with the result. 

Very respectfully, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By W. D, Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb., January 19, 1900. 

Eon. John F. Cornell, Auditor of Public Accounts: 

Dear Sir — Permit me to notify you, officially, of what you 
already know through the newspapers and otherwise, that 
the supreme court of the state in the case of The State of 
Nebraska vs. The Home Insurance Company, to recover the 
amount of fees due from that company to the state, but which </seg>


            <seg id="p054">54 


were paid by the company to Eugene Moore, but not turned 
over to the state by him, has been decided in favor of the 
tftate, which means that the insurance companies must pay 
to the state the fees entrusted by them to Eugene Moore to 
be delivered to the state treasurer, but by him embezzled in 
the amount of about $33,000. 

It was understood between counsel for the insurance company 
and myself that some eighty other companies represented 
by them would abide the decision of the court in that 
r, and promptly pay to the treasurer the fees which, under 
judgment in that case, they would in principle be liable 
for, without further litigation. 

I have no doubt at this time that these companies will conform 
to that understanding, yet business principles would 
suggest that they be asked by you to do so, before you issue 
to them or their agents permission to do business during 
the ensuing year. And I respectfully suggest that you take 
that course. 

It has been suggested in some quarters that the payment 
of some $5,000 by Moore, after he went out of office, would 
make it difficult to determine which company owed the state, 
and how much was owed by each, but this is a mistake. The 
payment made by Moore will, under the law, since he gave no 
direction, be applied to the older accounts. The companies 
responsible for the amounts left after this application must 
pay. This may work a hardship in some instances, but it 
can not be avoided. 

I have suggested the above course of procedure, to collect 
the amount due from the insurance companies, because I 
think it is effective and will prevent a possibility of many 
lawsuits and consequently great additional expense to the 
state and the insurance companies. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General.</seg> 


            <seg id="p055">55 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Lincoln, Neb., January 12, 1900. 

Hon. P. L. Hall, Secretary State Banking Board: 

Dear Sir — Your favor of recent date, asking for an opinion 
from this office on the question of "what constitutes a banking 
business as contemplated by the statutes of the State of 
Nebraska, and especially whether or not in our opinion the 
buying and selling of exchange is exclusively the privilege 
of a bank," has been duly received. 

In reply thereto would say that section 2 of chapter 8 of 
the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, which provides that 
"Every corporation, partnership, firm, or individual, transacting 
a banking business under the laws and within the 
state, shall be subject to the provisions of this act and regulated 
by the State Banking Board" does not pretend todefine 
what the banking business is, within the meaning of 
this chapter, but leaves that question to be determined by 
the general application of the term "banking business," as 
denned by the courts and law writers of the country. 

Nor does section 182-35, of article 1, chapter 77, of the 
Statutes, give a definition of "banking" which is intended to 
define the business for the purpose of determining the control 
of your board over the banking business. This section, 
if you will notice, is for the purpose of directing the method 
of assessing certain classes of property for taxation. Its 
subhead includes, "bank," "banking," "broker," and "stock 
jobber," and does not pretend to divide the lines of duties of 
each of those branches of business, and separate the functions 
of one from the functions of another. Consequently, we are 
left without the aid of a legislative definition of "banking," 
and are compelled to look to the text writers, commentaries, 
and courts for a definition applicable to the question which 
you have propounded to us. 

Looking first to our standard lexicographer, Webster, for 
a definition, we find the following, "Bank. — A collection or 
stock of money deposited. by a number of persons for a particular 
use, that is, an aggregate of particulars, or a fund as. </seg>


            <seg id="p056">56 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

to establish a bank that is a joint fund." "Banker. — One who 
keeps a bank; one who traffics in money, receives and remits 
money; negotiates bills of exchange, etc." "Banking. — The 
business or employment of a banker; the business of establishing 
a common fund for lending money, discounting notes, 
issuing bills, receiving deposits, collecting money on notes 
deposited, negotiating bills of exchange, etc." 

Turning from AVebster's dictionary to Bouvier's Law Dictionary, 
we find the following definition of a bank, "An 
institution authorized to receive deposits of money, to lend 
money, and to issue promissory notes." This is a definition 
which has been commented on favorably in the case of the 
First Natl. Bank vs. Ocean Natl. Bank, GO N. Y., 278, and 
has also been commented on with approval in a leading case 
by the supreme court of Minnesota— the case of Farmers &amp; 
Merchants Bank vs. Baldwin, 23 Minn., 198. 

In the case of Oulton vs. Savings Institution, 17 Wallace, 
109, Judge Clifford of the United States supreme court says, 
"Banks in the commercial sense are of three kinds — of deposit, 
of discount, and of circulation. Originally the banking 
business consisted in receiving deposits, .such as bullion, 
plate, and the like, for safe-keeping until the depositor should 
see fit to withdraw. Later, banks began to loan by discounting 
bills and notes, or on mortgage, bond, or other security; 
and, at a still later period, to issue notes of their own, intended 
to circulate as money instead of gold and silver." 
"Modern banks frequently exercise any two or even three of 
those functions, but it is still true that an institution prohibited 
from exercising any more than one of them is a 
bank in the strictest sense." 

This decision has been criticised by some of the law writers 
as too broad, and as giving the term, "banking" a too 
wide significance, as the only question before the court determined 
by this decision was as to whether an institution 
engaged in the business of receiving deposits from the public 
in general was a bank, and his holding was in the affirm- </seg>


            <seg id="p057">57 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

ative. There are numerous other cases which have been 
determined by the various courts, in which the question was 
involved for the purpose of the construction of a revenue 
statute, but these would be of little assistance to us in the 
solution of the question that you have propounded. Guided 
by the light of the authorities above commented on, I am 
of the opinion that a banking business is one which is primarily 
kept at a place where deposits are received; and 
where the money of various depositors is commingled in a 
common fund for the purpose of loans or discounts or the 
purchase of negotiable instruments, and that simply the buying 
and selling of exchange, unless it was conducted at a 
place kept for the deposit of money, would not alone constitute 
the banking business; but if deposits were received, 
and drafts or checks issued against the deposits so received, 
then, in my opinion, such a business would be a banking 
business, as contemplated by chapter 8 of the statutes of the 
State of Nebraska, and would be subject to the control of 
your board. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Neb., February 19, 1900. 

Hon. John F. Cornell, Auditor of Hublic Accounts: 

Dear Sir — Your favor is at hand, desiring an opinion 
from this office on a construction of section 33 of chapter 
43 of the Compiled Statutes of 1897, commonly known as 
the Reciprocal Tax. The question on which you desire information 
is as to whether we have the right, under that 
section, to impose a reciprocal tax on companies from states 
where Nebraska companies have no established agencies or 
agents doing business. This question is one, in the proper </seg>


            <seg id="p058">58 


solution of which, much depends for an increase or decrease 
of the revenues of this state from foreign insurance companies. 


So much of section 33 as is necessary for construction is 
as follows : 

"Whenever the existing or future laws of any other state 
of the United States shall require of insurance companies incorporated 
by or organized under the laws of this state, having 
agencies in such other state, or of the agents thereof, 
any deposit, etc., greater than the amount required for such 
purposes from similar companies of other states by the then 
existing laws of this state, then, and in every such cage, all 
companies of such states establishing, or having theretofore 
established an agency or agencies in this state, shall" etc. 

Now for a proper construction of this statute we ha«e 
turned to the judicial construction on similar statutes by 
courts of our neighboring states, "our own supreme court 
never having been called on to construe the statute." 

One of the most ably written and 'best considered opinions 
on this question was delivered by Judge Brewer, now of the 
United States supreme court, while one of the supreme court 
judges of the State of Kansas, in the case of the Phoenix Ins. 
Co. of N. Y. vs. Welch, Supt, etc. The statute of Kansas 
reads as follows : 

"Whenever the existing or future laws of any other state 
or government shall require insurance companies organized 
under the laws of this state, applying to dp business by 
agencies in such other state or government or of the agents 
thereof," etc. 

Under this statute Judge Brewer held in the case cited 
that: 

"The contingency named in such sectirn arises when the 
laws of another state impose the conditional burdens and 
conditions, and is not delayed until some corporation of 
this state is actually subjected to such burdens and conditions." 
</seg>


            <seg id="p059">59 

EEPOET OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

This same doctrine was applied by the supreme court of 
Iowa, under a very similar statute to ours, in the case of 
State ex rel. Phillips vs. Fidelity and Casualty Co., 77 la., 
649. 

And the supreme court of Maryland, in the case of Talbott 
vs. Fidelity and Casualty Co., 74 Md., 538, lays down the 
following rules of construction of a statute of another state 
exactly similar to ours. They say: 

"The object of our statute is palpable. The design was 
to put insurance companies coming from other states into 
the same position as ours would be in the state whence they 
came. They were to be admitted on the same terms, and none 
other, than ours would be there. Companies coming from 
other states were intended to fare no better than ours would 
on going to their state." 

Nor is the case of State ex rel. vs. Insurance Co., 49 Ohio 
St., 444, in conflict with the determination of these cases. 
All that is held in that case is that companies must be formed 
in the state of Ohio for the purpose of doing business, which 
the company from the foreign state is engaged in, as a condition 
precedent to the right of the state to subject the foreign 
company to the provisions of the reciprocal or retaliatory tax. 
They say that, 

"To bring a case within the statute there must at least be 
an Ohio company formed to which the prohibitions of the 
New York statute would apply, should it attempt to enter 
and do business in that state." 

The doctrine of this case has been followed in Illinois, 
Indiana, Minnesota, and Wisconsin. In the latter state it 
was held, in the case of the Travellers Ins. Co. of Hartford, 
Conn., vs. Frick Ins. Comm., 99 Wis., 367, that, 

"The state is not estopped, by the failure of its officers to 
require compliance with the law at the proper time, from 
afterward insisting upon it; nor, the law being plain, can 
the doctrine of practical construction be applied to such 
action." </seg>


            <seg id="p060">60 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

and that, 

"The plaintiff being a foreign corporation all of the time 
and having its residence in another state, the statute of limitations 
does not apply in its favor." 

It is therefore the conclusion that the only condition 
precedent that is required of this state in order to make the 
provisions of the reciprocal tax act effective is that companies 
were organized under the laws of this state which would 
have been subject to the provisions of the statute of the foreign 
state, and that it is not necessary that we should have 
companies actually engaged in business in the foreign state 
and actually paying fees in cases' of those charged by the 
statute of our state to make this act effective. 

Yours very truly, 

Attorney (icncral. 

By W. D. Oldham, 

Deputy. 

Lincoln, Nkr., April 7, 1900. 

Hon. J. V. Wolfe, Chairman Board of Public Lands and 

Building*: 

Dear Sir— In compliance with your oral request to furnish 
you an opinion as to who has the power to relinquish children 
taken from the Nebraska Industrial Home, for adoption, you 
are advised as follows : 

The general provision for the relinquishment of children 
for adoption is section 797 of the Code of Civil Procedure. 
The fifth subdivision of that section provides that, "any 
person, corporation, or association to whom the custody 
or control of any minor child shall have been given by a 
written instrument signed and executed in the presence of 
at least one witness by," etc., "may consent to its adoption, 
provided said written instrument shall authorize said person, 
corporation, or association to piocure the adoption of 
said minor child by some suitable person." 

C. J. Smyth, </seg>


            <seg id="p061">61 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

This section is an amendment of section 797 of the Civil 
Code of the Statutes of 1895, which provided that the president 
of the board of directors or trustees of such association 
might consent to the adoption. So the provision as it now 
stands does not designate the officer who should consent to 
such adoption. 

Section 3, chapter 39a, provides for the appointment of an 
advisory board for the industrial Home, which board shall 
formulate, recommend, and submit to the board of public 
lands and buildings, rules for admission to said home, and 
by-laws and regulations for its government.' These rules are 
subject to change, amendment, or abrogation by the board 
of public lands and buildings at any time. Section 9 of 
said chapter provides that all applications for admission to 
said home shall be made to the board of public lands and 
buildings. There is, however, no provision designating what 
officer shall consent to the adoptions. We therefore, conconclude, 
fL-st, if the home has a rule by which a certain 
officer shall consent to adoptions, that that rule may be followed 
unless changed by the board of public lands and buildings. 
If no such rule has been adopted, the officer who would 
ordinarily give such consent to the adoption of children might 
give such consent, and it would be valid and binding unless 
the board of public lands and buildings have a different rule. 
What the facts are, as to whether there are any written rules 
in existence or not, I do not know. At any rate, the board 
of public lands an&lt; buildings has power at any time to change 
existing rules or formulate new ones. 

Hoping I have made myself clear, I remain, 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By Paul Pizey, 

Assistant. </seg>


            <seg id="p062">62 

H f *r*i *" ' Ur Al i L*li •&gt; £. x ul-^ t*K.\ 1 *• 

Lincoln, Neb v April 27, 1900. 

Hon. John F. Cornell, Auditor of Public Accounts: 

Dear Sie — I have your favor of the 25th inst. in which you 
state in substance that the Union Life Insurance Company 
of Omaha, Neb., organized under the provisions of sections 
70 to 90, both inclusive, of chapter 43, Compiled Statutes 
of 1897, has ceased to write insurance and is engaged now 
only in the work of winding up its affairs; that sometime 
ago it made arrangements with the Royal Union Mutual Insurance 
Company, of Des Moines, Iowa, whereby the latter 
company was to assume its outstanding policies whenever 
the insured consented to the change; that said Royal Union 
Company is required by the laws of Iowa to have on deposit 
in the hands of the auditor of the state of Iowa securities 
in a certain amount for all business written by it ; that the 
assumption of the policies of the Union Company requires 
it to increase its securities on deposit in proportion to the 
amount assumed ; that the Union Life has on deposit in your 
hands securities in the amount of f 100,000 for the purpose 
of securing the discharge of all liabilities of the company 
to its policy holders, and that, since the Royal Union has 
assumed some of these liabilities and intends to assume all, 
it desires to transfer a percentage of the securities now in 
your hands, equal to the percentage of the liabilities assumed 
by it, to the hands of the Iowa auditor of state, to be held 
by him for the same purpose for which it is held by you, and 
the question which you propound upon this state of facts is 
whether or not you have the power under the law to permit 
the withdrawal of the securities for the purposes stated. 

Section 90 of the law under which the Nebraska company 
was organized declares that no company organized under the 
laws of the state, etc., "shall continue or commence business 
until such company has transferred to and deposited with the 
auditor of public accounts for the security of its policy 
holders the sum of $100,000," 

Section 80 of the same law provides that "the auditor </seg>


            <seg id="p063">63 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

shall permit corporations or associations having a deposit 
with him of such securities to withdraw the same upon the 
filing with him by the president and secretary of such corporations 
and associations satisfactory proof that they are 
to be used for the purpose for which they are originally deposited 
in his office." 

These two sections must be construed together. What is 
the meaning of the first section — section 90? Does it mean 
that no company shall do any business, even that of winding 
up its affairs, unless it has on deposit, $ 100,000? We do 
not think so. The business referred to therein is, in my opinion, 
that of writing insurance. No company, under the provisions 
of section 90, may commence to write or to continue 
to write insurance until it has made the deposit provided for. 
If this be its meaning, then we can harmonize it with section 
80, which provides for the withdrawal of the securities whenever 
you are satisfied that they are to be used for the purposes 
for which they were deposited with you. This last section 
contemplates that there would be some time when a given 
company might have less than $100,000 of securities in your 
hands. Since the legislature intended that there might be 
a time when some of these securities might be withdrawn, 
it must have contemplated that there would be a time when 
less than $100,000 would be on deposit. Now it is my opinion 
that that time has arrived in the history of the Union Insurance 
Company. The purpose of the company in asking 
to withdraw its securities is to use them for precisely the same 
purposes for which you hold them, by depositing them in the 
hands of the auditor of the state of Iowa. And, this being 
true, I think it is competent for you to permit it to be done, 
being satisfied^ of course, from the evidence laid before you, 
that the securities will be put to the purpose just mentioned. 

I think, too, that under the circumstances which surround 
this Nebraska company and its policy holders, the safety of 
the rights of those holders will be served by this construction 
of the law. </seg>


            <seg id="p064">64 

REPORT OF ATTOKXEY GENERAL. 

Some of these circumstances are that, if the transfer is 
not permitted, many, if not all, the insured in the Nebraska 
company would be left without insurance payable at death 
unless they insure in a new company, and in that event they 
would have to pay a much larger premium on account of 
their advanced age, which would of course be much to their 
detriment. By permitting the securities to be withdrawn 
and deposited with the auditor of Iowa, those who desire 
may continue the policies which they hold in the Nebraska 
company at the same rate, nor is anyone required to enter 
into this arrangement unless he desires to do so. Therefore 
the transfer of the securities is done in effect at thy 
request of the insured for whose protection the securities 
were deposited. In the event that an insured does not desfre 
to accept a policy in the Iowa company for his policy of the 
Nebraska company, a sufficient amount would remain in 
your hands to secure the payment to him of all liability ol ! 
the Nebraska company to him. 

I am informed, too, that the present total value of all the 
policies of the Nebraska company now in existence does not 
exceed $ 50,000, or about one-half the amount on deposit, and 
that the Nebraska company does not propose to withdraw, 
or request leave to do so, more than $50,000, until you are 
satisified that every obligation of the Nebraska company has 
been satisfied. 

I return you herewith the papers handed me. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., May 28, 1900. 

Samuel Rinaker, Esq., County Attorney, Beatrice, Neb.: 
Dear Sir — You are doubtless aware from the press of the 

state that this office has been very busy lately in preparing 
and commencing and trying important cases, and for this </seg>


            <seg id="p065">REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

65 

reason we have been forced to lay aside our correspondence 
for the time being. We are very sorry that we have had to 
delay the answer of your letter relative to the taxation of 
telephones, but owing to the other matters we have been compelled 
to neglect your letter. Relative to the taxation of telephones, 
it is my opinion that, since our statute does not make 
definite provision for taxing this sort of property, it should be 
taxed in the same manner that telegraph property is taxed, 
and under the present telegraph law. 

Section 8 of the Revenue Act, if applicable at all to this 
sort of property, I think, withdraws the taxation of telephones 
from the assessors of the counties. 

In Iowa, before a special law was passed taxing telephones, 
the Iowa supreme court held ia the case of Iowa 
Union Telegraph Company vs. The Board of Equalization 
of the City of Oskaloosa, in the 67th Iowa, 250, that, owing 
to the similarity of the telephone system to the telegraph system, 
the method of taxation should be the same. Later, the 
Iowa legislature passed an act specially regulating the taxation 
of telephones, making them taxable by the state. The 
text-book writers show that the methods of taxing telephones 
and telegraph companies should be the same on account of 
the similarity of the two, unless the states have passed definite 
laws relative especially to the telephone companies. 

In the case of Wisconsin Telephone Co. vs. City of Oshkosh,. 
62 Wis., 32, the supreme court of Wisconsin held that, under 
a law for organizing and conducting telegraph companies^ 
regulating their charges, etc., telephone companies might 
be organized, and this on account of the similarity of the two. 
Later, the Wisconsin legislature passed a law taxing the 
telephone companies by.means of a stute license tax of 2J per 
cent of the gross receipts of such company. 

Croswell on The Law Relating to Electricity, sections 13-20, 
discusses this subject, and this work is perhaps as good 
as any we have. This question is being discussed considerably 
now in this state, and probably the matter will be 

r» </seg>


            <seg id="p066">66 

EEPOKT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

called to the attention of the next legislature, so that something 
definite may be done in regard to taxing these companies, 
but under the present condition of the law it is the 
opinion of this office that the laws for taxing telegraph 
companies apply to the taxing of telephone companies. Hoping 
we have satisfactorily answered your letter, we remain, 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By Paul Pizey, 

Assistant. 

Lincoln, Neb., June 22, 1900. 

Hon. J. V. Wolfe, Commissioner of Public Lands and Build- 

ings, Lincoln, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — Replying to your request of the 18th inst. No. 
25136, to answer a letter received by you from A. C Post, 
county treasurer of Thayer county, relative to the conveyance 
of school lands held under contract as a homestead, you are 
advised as follows : 

In the case of Crawl vs. Harrington, 33 Neb., 107, the 
court holds that school lands held under contract of sale are 
not an estate of inheritance such as is necessary to constitute 
dower in the wife of the purchaser. The facts in that 
case were as follows : Certain school lands were sold by the 
state in 1875, and one-tenth of the purchase price paid, the 
purchaser receiving a contract of sale. In 1879, an assignee 
of the purchaser conveyed said land to one K. by quit-claim 
deed. In the same year K. conveyed the land by quit-claim 
deed to one H. Under this state of facts the court say's at 
page 113 : 

"An estate less than a freehold is not an estate of inheritance 
at common law, and that law prevails on this point 
in this state. The Kearney Building and Loan Association 
had purchased the land in question and paid one-tenth of 
the purchase price thereon when Keenes purchased the same, </seg>


            <seg id="p067">67 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

The company could only convey an equitable title to the 
property, and the fact that a deed was made by one who 
possessed only an equitable title would carry no greater interest 
than he possessed. It was not, therefore, an estate of 
inheritance, and the wife took no dower therein." 

In that case, however, the question of a homestead right 
was not involved, and that case would settle this case conclusively 
if it were not for the fact that this property is 
being held as a homestead. 

Section 4, chapter 36, of the '99 Statutes, reads that, "The 
homestead of a married person can not be conveyed or incumbered 
unless the instrument by which it is conveyed or 
incumbered is executed and acknowledged by both husband 
and wife." 

While the court has held that this would not be an estate 
of inheritance, yet the fact that it is a homestead and occupied 
as such would bring into action another rule — the rule 
set forth in the statute just quoted. 

Our supreme court in the case of Giles vs. Miller, 36 Neb., 
346, lays down this rule in the second syllabus : 

"An undivided interest in real estate, accompanied by the 
exclusive occupancy of the premises by the owner of such 
interest and his family as a home, is sufficient to support 
a homestead exemption." 

In the opinion the court goes still further, and on page 349 
lays down the following rule : 

"We know that the purpose of the legislature in enacting 
the statute under consideration was to protect the debtor 
and his family in a home from a forced sale on execution or 
attachment. Keeping this object in view, and applying the 
liberal rule of construction which always obtains in the interpretation 
of exemption laws, we are constrained to hold that 
any estate or interest in lands which gives the right of occupancy 
or possession is sufficient, if coupled with requisite 
occupancy, to entitle the person to the benefits of the provisions 
of the section above quoted. The ownership need not 

• </seg>


            <seg id="p068">68 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

be of an estate in fee simple, but the owner of the equitable 
title occupying under the contract of purchase may claim 
the exemption of the statute." 

From these rules above set forth it is undoubtedly the law 
in this state, that where school lands are held under contract 
of purchase by husband and wife as a homestead, that fin 
assignment of such a contract by the husband must be sigm •¦! 
and acknowledged by the wife also in order to convey ih&lt;: 
homestead rights. But the rule we have shown above i» 
different where no homestead rights are claimed. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By Paul Pizey, 

Assistants 

Lincoln, Neb., June 29, 1900. 

Hon. John F. Cornell, Auditor of Public Accounts, Lincoln r 

Neb.: 

Dear Sir — I have your favor of recent date asking for my 
opinion with respect to the following matter, that is to say : 
The legislature of 1897 made certain appropriations for the 
Home for the Friendless. At some time prior to the 31st 
day of August of last year, vouchers in due form were presented 
to you for expenditure made as stated, for the use and 
benefit of the Home. These vouchers were approved by you, 
but the Secretary of State refused to approve them, and litigation 
followed. The consequence was that the vouchers were 
not approved by him until about a month ago. And the 
question now presented to me is whether or not you have any 
authority in law to draw a warrant at this time against the 
appropriation of 1897. 

The constitution in section 22 of article 3 provides that. 
"No money shall be drawn from the treasury except in 

? </seg>


            <seg id="p069">69 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

pursuance of a specific appropriation made by law, and on 
the presentation of a warrant issued by the auditor thereon." 

Section 9 of article 3 of the same instrument directs that, 
"Each legislature shall make appropriations for the expenses 
of the government until the expiration of the first fiscal 
quarter after the adjournment of the next regular session, 
and all appropriations shall end with such fiscal quarter." 

"The next regular session" of the legislature, after the 
appropriation of 1897 was made, adjourned on the 31st day 
of March, 1899. The first fiscal quarter after that adjournment 
expired on the 31st day of August, 1899, and with 
it, under the mandatory provision of the constitution, expired 
the appropriation made for the use and benefit of the 
Home for the Friendless. There is, therefore, at this time, 
no appropriation, specific or otherwise, on which you could 
draw a warrant for the above mentioned claims. 

This is so obvious from a mere reading of the constitution 
that it seems unnecessary to cite authorities. Yet I may be 
pardoned for presenting one or two. 

In the case of State vs. Babcock, 22 Neb., 33, it was held 
that, where the legislature adjourned on the 31st day of 
March, the appropriation made by the previous legislature 
continues "to be available for the purposes for which it was 
made until the end of the first fiscal quarter after the adjournment 
of the legislature." 

In this opinion, the decision of the supreme court of Illinois, 
in the case of the People vs. Needles, 96 111., 575, is cited 
with approval. In that case the auditor refused to draw his 
warrant in payment of a concededly just claim after the day 
fixed by the constitution of Illinois for the expiration of the 
appropriation. With respect to his refusal, the supreme 
court said on page 579, "We think the position taken by the 
auditor is correct by the express language of the constitution, 
'all appropriations, general, or special, requiring money to 
be paid out of the state treasury from funds belonging to the </seg>


            <seg id="p070">70 

EEPOET OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

state' shall end with the fiscal quarter after the adjournment 
of the next regular session of the general assemblage." . 

Again, a little farther down the page, referring to the same 
constitutional provision, we find the following paragraph : 
"This is a wholesome provision of the constitution, and it 
ought not to be frittered away by construction. It is better 
to submit to some inconveniences than that a safeguard so 

f valuable should be impaired in the least." 

But it may be urged that, since you allowed the claim 
before the expiration of the appropriation, the appropriation 
did not lapse, but, by reason of your allowance of the claim, 
was kept alive. The answer to this is that the constitution 
makes no exceptions. It is emphatic that appropriations 
shall lapse — die with the end of the first fiscal quarter after 
the adjournment of the session of the legislature. No act of 
yours, or the claimants, or of the courts, or of the legislature 
itself can prevent the happening of that which the constitution 
says shall happen. It is therefore my opinion, and you 
are advised, that you have no authority at this time in law to 
draw a warrant on the appropriation of 1897, and that a 
warrant drawn by you now would be absolutely void, and 
would furnish no authority to the treasurer to pay one cent 
thereon. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., June 30, 1900. 

Col. John C. Hartigan, Judge Advocate General N. N. G., 
Lincoln, Neb. : 

Dear Sir — In response to your favor of recent date propounding 
certain questions to me with respect to the construction 
of the military code of the state, I have the honor to 
submit the following reply : I do not deem it necessary to </seg>


            <seg id="p071">71 

KEl'ORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

repeat your questions. My answers will be, I think, sufficiently 
intelligible without doing so. 

Section 2 of the military code reads as follows : "The organized 
militia shall be designated as the Nebraska National 
Guard, to be recruited by volunteer enlistment, and to consist 
of not more than 2,000 enlisted men and the necessary 
commissioned officers to perfect the organization hereinafter 
stated ; to be organized into not more than twenty-eight companies 
of infantry, one troop of cavalry, and one battalion 
of artillery, which may be assigned to battalions and regiments 
by the commander in chief." 

From this it is clear that the national guard shall consist 
of three branches or classes, viz. : infantry, cavalry, and artillery. 
No deviation from these classes can be permitted. 
Therefore, I am of the opinion that a signal corps can not 
be organized unless it can be said to be a part of the infantry, 
or of a troop of cavalry, or of a battery of artillery. And, as I 
understand it, it can not be said to belong to any of them. 
It is, in itself, a distinct branch of the service. 

But what force or effect, if any, has section 14 in the construction 
of section 2? None, in my opinion. 

Section 14 is, in substance, section 4 of the Act of 1887. 
A comparison of section 4 of the law of 1887 with section 14 
of the present law will show the relation of the latter to section 
2. In the law of 1887, section 4 provided that, "The 
organization of the Nebraska National Guard shall conform 
to the provisions of the laws of the United States, and the system 
of discipline and exercise shall conform as nearly as 
may be to those of the army of the United States." 

It will be noticed that the organization of the guard according 
to the laws of the United States, was made obligatory 
by section 4 of the law of 1887. But that law did 
not have section 2 or any provision equivalent to it. Now 
turn to section 14 and see how it reads : "The organization, 
equipment, and system of discipline of the militia and na- </seg>


            <seg id="p072">72 

REPOET OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

tional guard shall conform as near as practicable to that of 
the army of the United States." In this last section the organization 
is to conform only "as near as practicable" to 
that of the army of the United States, while in the former 
section it was said that it shall conform, but the present law 
kas section 2, which the law of 1887 did not have, in which 
the organization of the guard is specifically provided for. 
Now there was a reason for making the change effected by 
section 14, and that reason was to make it harmonize with 
section 2. Section 2 is a specific provision dealing with a 
specific subject. Section 14 is a general provision dealing 
generally with the organization, discipline, and equipment 
of the guard. It is a familiar rule of construction, one that 
will occur to you at once, that a specific statute on a given 
subject is to be followed rather than a general statute on the 
same subject, and creates an exception to the general provision. 
The phrase "as nearly as practicable" found in section 
14 means, whenever not otherwise provided in the 
statute. 

What I have said above applies with equal force to the 
adding of a third major and two battalion adjutants, as well 
as to the formation of a hospital corps. You can not add a 
third major or battalion adjutants, for the reason that the 
statute provides specifically what officers a regiment shall 
have, and also provides for tke company officers, and these 
provisions must be observed. The hospital corps can not be 
formed without contravening the provisions of section 2, 
unless you can make an infantry company, or a detachment 
from an infantry company, serve the purpose of a hospital 
corps. 

I know that this opinion is not what you would like it 
to be, and therefore I regret very much that I have been 
compelled to adopt it, but I see no escape from it. The next 
legislature will be in session in a few months, and I am sure </seg>


            <seg id="p073">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

73 

what you desire may readily be secured through amendments 
to the present law. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., August 18, 1900. 

Di:au Sin — Please pardon our delay in answering your 
favor of the 7th inst. relative to the ballots to be used in an 
election for the relocation of county seat. We have had so 
much work in the office that it has been impossible to attend 
to our correspondence properly. It may be that this answer 
will be too late to be of advantage to you in the election, but 
I find in looking up the statute and the Nebraska reports that 
we have no law fixing the form of the ballot in a case of this 
kind. The same question came up before the county attorney 
and clerk of Knox county, and the county attorney advised 
the clerk there to place upon the ballot something like this : 

"What city, town, or place do you desire the county seat 
of Knox couutv, Nebraska, located at or in?" 

Designate here 

The clerk and county attorney each asked the opinion of 
this office, but we did not care to interfere with the county 
attorney's position in his statement. Any ballot which will 
apprise the voter of what he is expected to vote for is, in my 
opinion, sufficient since we have no specific law regarding 
it. If there are any petitions in your county asking that 
names of certain towns be placed upon the ballots I think 
those towns should be placed there and squares placed opposite 
them, in one of which the voter should put his cross, 
and u blank line should also be left for the voter to designate 
any (own not named on the ballot, if he saw fit. A square 
should be placed opposite this line also. If there are no 
such petitions I think it would be perfectly proper to place 

W. A. Heserve, Esq., Creighton, Neb.: </seg>


            <seg id="p074">74 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

the names of the prominent towns that would doubtless enter 
into the competition upon the ballot, leaving also a blank line 
as above mentioned. If you place on the ballot something 
like that advised by the county attorney of Knox county, I 
presume no square for a cross would be necessary. 

You ask if it is necessary to submit the question of relocation 
specifically. I understand under section 1 of article 3 
of chapter 17 that the request for the relocation has to be 
made by petition signed by three-fifths of the votes cast in 
the county at the last general election. When this is done 
the commissioners then call a special election at which the 
voters vote for the town which they would prefer to select 
as the county seat. 

Hoping these suggestions will be satisfactory, I remain, 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By Paul Pizey, 

Assistant. 

Lincoln, Neb., September 4, 1900. 

lion. J. A. Lcyda, County Attorney, Falls City, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — Yours of the 25th ult. was duly received. In 
it you state that the county clerk requested you to write to 
me and "ask as to the order in which the names of candidates 
should be put on the ticket at the coming election, that is, 
whether the fusion ticket at the last election shall be considered 
as one party and be entitled to first place for its 
candidate at this election, or whether the republicans shall 
be entitled to first place, they having doubtless cast the 
largest vote of any distinct party in this county." 

In reply thereto, permit me to say that in my judgment 
you must consider the three political divisions constituting 
the fusion party as separate and distinct parties. 

Section 140 of chapter 26 declares that "Any candidate </seg>


            <seg id="p075">75 

KEPOUT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

who shall be the regular nominee of one or more party conventions 
shall have the party title of each party so nominating 
him printed after his name." 

The fusionists claim the right, and justly so, I think, to 
have printed after the name of each of their candidates, the 
name of each party nominating them. This claim can be 
based only on the theory that the democratic, the populist, 
and the free-silver Republican parties are separate and distinct, 
and, hence, that the name of each should appear upon 
the ballot after the name of the candidate nominated by 
each. If the fusion party is to be treated as one party, by 
what legal name would it be designated upon the ballot? 
It could not be called the fusion party because the fusion 
party did not hold a convention within the meaning of the 
statute. It could not be called a democratic, populist, and 
free silver republican party, because no party by that name 
held a convention. But each of the last named parties held 
a convention, and each convention filed a certificate of its 
nominations, and by virtue of those steps, together with 
others, secured the right to have its name appear upon the 
ballot as a distinct party. Without further discussion, it 
must be clear that the fusionists can not be treated as one 
party for one purpose and as three parties for another purpose. 
My judgment is that they must be treated as three 
distinct parties. 

This, however, does not determine which party is entitled 
to have the names of its candidates placed at the head of 
the list. How is that to be determined? No fixed rule can 
be laid down. It is possible that the populist party polled 
more votes than the republican party, but it is impossible 
to determine that question to a certainty. It must, therefore, 
be determined according to the most reasonable method 
that can be adopted. The county clerk is the one to determine 
it, at least in the first instance, and he should examine 
the matter carefully and, from all the evidence which may </seg>


            <seg id="p076">76 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

be accessible to him, determine which party is entitled to 
the head of the ticket. 

In the case of Higgins vs. Berge, 74 Minn., a question 
similar to the one now under consideration was decided. 
The court says on page 15, "But there being no prescribed 
rule in such a case, the officers charged with the duty of arranging 
and printing the official ballot may resort to any 
rule or means to ascertain approximately the vote balloted 
by each party which he deems to be fair and practicable; 
and, unless he acts in the premises fraudulently and unfairly 
or clearly on an improper and prejudicial basis, his decision 
will not be disturbed by the courts." 

That rule is, I think, the correct one and should be followed 
by the county clerk of your county. 

Yours very truly, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., September 7, 1900. 

Hon. G. A. McCutchan, County Attorney, O'Neill, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — Yours of August 25 was duly received at this 
office, but owing to my absence not answered before. You 
enclose a clipping from a newspaper and say that the enclosed 
clipping was handed to you with the request that you 
submit the matter to me for an answer. The clipping reads, 
"Will the ballot have to be printed as the law reads, or can 
it be printed in two columns? By the latter form the ballot 
will be only one half as long." 

In reply thereto permit me to say that I can find nothing 
in the law which prohibits the printing of the ballot in two 
or more columns if necessary. This is the result of a careful 
examination, although not an exhaustive one. It is barely 
possible that something may be found in the statute which 
supports the idea which seems to have been in your mind 
when you dictated the letter. If so, I wish you would point 

C. J. Smyth, </seg>


            <seg id="p077">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

77 

I 

it out, or at least that which you believe to warrant the idea. 
It is true the law requires the names of the candidates for 
each office to be printed in this order, that is to say, the 
candidate of the party which cast the highest number of votes 
at the last election to be printed immediately beneath the 
designation of the office for which he is a candidate, and beneath 
his name the names of the other candidates, but 
whether this applies to each office or not, it does not require 
that the candidates for all the offices shall be printed in a 
perpendicular column, and I feel certain that if, in the judgment 
of the county clerk, the ballot should be orinted in two 
columns or in three, it may be so printed. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., September 28, 1900. 
Hon. J. G. Dort, Pawnee City, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — I have just received a letter from your county 
treasurer asking for my opinion with respect to the meaning 
of section 100, article 1, chapter 77, of the Compiled Statutes, 
in so far as it bears upon the charge to be made for advertiseing 
land on which there are delinquent taxes, and have replied 
to him to the effect that his question should have gone 
to you; that while it is my duty to advise you upon your 
application, that it would be discourteous to your office to 
interfere in the matter, except upon your request. But, owing 
to the fact that there is little time remaining between 
now and the day on which he must commence publication, I 
said I would forward my opinion to you to be disposed of 
by you as you might see fit. 

In the first place, he assumes that the description of the 
lot must be repeated for each year the taxes are delinquent, 
and then he asks whether or not he is permitted to charge 
ten cents for each description. </seg>


            <seg id="p078">78 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

It is my opinion that he is not required to publish the 
description of the lot more than once, and hence not permitted 
to charge the land for more than one publication. The statute 
says that, "For each town lot the sum of ten cents to 
defray the expenses of advertising, which shall be added to 
the amount due on said land or town lot, for taxes, and collected 
in the same manner as the taxes" shall be charged. 

To me it is clear that the entire expenses of advertising 
should be charged to the land. The statute just quoted says 
that ten cents shall be charged for each lot. The legislature 
could not have intended that ten cents would be sufficient 
to pay for the description of one lot repeated ten times, and 
there might be instances in which the taxes would be due 
for ten years, and, in that event, according to the treasurer's 
notice, the description would have to be repeated ten times. 
If the legislature did not mean this, and yet intended that the 
entire expenses of the publication should be charged to the 
land, it must have meant that only one publication of the 
description was necessary, and this, I think, is what it did 
mean. 

The treasurer can state in the opening of the advertisement 
that the lands described below will be sold for all taxes due, 
giving the years for which they are due, and then proceed 
and give the description of the lot and the total amount of 
the taxes due thereon, whether for one year, three, or ten, 
and this is what I conceive to be the requirements of the 
statute. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., October 8, 1900. 

W. R. Felton, Esq., Mt. Vernon, Iowa: 

Dear Sir — I have your favor of October 6 in which you 
say you would like to have a copy of the Nebraska Anti-trust </seg>


            <seg id="p079">79 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Law and then propound the following questions with respect 
to that law : 

"Was it the intent of the law to regulate or destroy trusts, 
and what effect has it had? Do you think there is such a 
thing as successful regulation?" 

In reply permit me to say, first, that the Anti-trust Law 
is not published separate from the rest of the statutory 
laws, and therefore it is not practical for me to send it 
to you. The intent of our law is to destroy trusts. A 
trust, within the meaning of that law, is a combination of 
capital, skill, or acts by any person or persons to fix the 
price of any article of trade, with the intent to prevent 
others from conducting the same trade, or for the purpose 
of creating restrictions in trade, limiting production, or preventing 
competition. 

Some one of these purposes must be present in each combination, 
and as the purpose is in its nature illegal and 
hurtful to the community, it would be entirely improper to 
attempt to regulate it. There is but one sufficient remedy, 
and that is one which will stamp it out of existence. 

As yet I have not been able to reach a final decision in 
any of the anti-trust suits which I have commenced. But it 
is my firm opinion, from a careful study of the question, that 
there is but one power capable of dealing effectively with the 
great trusts of the country, and that is the Federal government. 
The states may deal with local trusts, that is, 
trusts that confine their business to one particular state, but 
they, as a rule, are not very injurious, and the abolishment 
of them all would leave the great trust evil almost 
untouched. The great trusts of the country, those that 
affect the life of the nation, are the ones which are engaged 
in interstate commerce, and the states can not touch that 
commerce. It can be reached only by the Federal government. 
It is my judgment that if the present federal law, 
known as the Sherman Law, passed in 1890, was honestly 
and vigorously enforced by the present administration, that </seg>


            <seg id="p080">80 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

every trust engaged in interstate business could be abolished, 
but that law has not been enforced. Although more than 
406 illegal combinations have been formed since the incoming 
of the present administration, the Attorney General 
of the United States has commenced but three anti-trust 
suits. This Attorney General Griggs has admitted in a letter 
to Congress in response to an inquiry made by Congressman 
Gaines of Tennessee. 

I am as much opposed to the regulation of trusts as I 
am to the regulation of any other evil. As no regulation 
of trusts has yet been attempted, it is impossible to say 
whether or not there is such a thing as a successful regulation. 
The very purpose of a trust is to raise prices, or else to 
maintain unreasonably high prices. Either purpose when 
put into execution is bad for the community, and hence the 
community should not permit it. 

Glad to serve you at any time. 

Yours very truly, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., October 12, 1900. 

Victor 0. Johnson, Esq., County Attorney, Ord, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — Your letter of recent date propounding to me 
certain questions with respect to the construction of certain 
provisions of the Australian ballot law was duly received. 

You ask me whether or not a certificate of nomination 
presented to the county clerk less than twenty days before 
the day of election would be presented in time, and, if not 
presented in time, whether it would be his duty to receive 
it and file it. The parts of the statute bearing on these 
questions are as follows: 

"When nominations are made by a convention," etc., "as 
provided for in section 4 of this act, the certificates of nomination 
to be filed with the secretary of state shall be filed 

C. J. Smytii, </seg>


            <seg id="p081">81 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

not less than twenty-five days before the day fixed by law 
for the election of the persons in nomination, and the certificates 
of nomination herein directed to be filed with a county 
clerk shall be filed not less than twenty days before election" 
(section 134, chapter 26). 

"All certificates of nomination which are in apparent conformity 
with the provisions of this act shall be deemed to 
be valid, unless objection thereto shall be duly made in writing 
within three days after the filing of the same (section 
27). 

"Exceptions in this act otherwise provided, it shall be the 
duty of the county clerk of each county to provide printed 
ballots for every election of public officers in which electors, 
or any of the electors within the county, participate, and 
to cause to be printed in the ballot the name of every candidate 
whose name has been certified to or filed with the 
county clerk in the manner provided for in this act" (section 
139). 

What is the rule to be followed in determining the meaning 
of those sections? 

In Becke vs. Smith, 2 M. &amp; W., 195, Parke B. says, "It 
is a very useful rule in the construction of a statute to 
adhere to the ordinary meaning of the words used, and to 
the grammatical construction unless that is at variance with 
the intention of the legislature, to be collected from the 
statute itself, or leads to any manifest absurdity or repugnanc 
— in which case the language may be varied or modified 
so as to avoid such inconveniences, but no further." 

The rule there announced is the general rule. Apply it 
to the statute before us. What is the result? Section 134 
says that the certificate shall be filed not less than twenty 
days; section 137 declares that the certificate shall be taken 
as valid where it is in apparent conformity with the law, and 
section 139 declares that the clerk shall print on the official 
ballot only the names of candidates filed with him in the manner 
provided for in this act. </seg>


            <seg id="p082">82 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

These three sections clearly indicate the intention of the 
legislature. First, that the certificate shall be filed no, less 
than twenty days; second, that the certificate shall not be 
filed by the clerk unless where it is in apparent conformity 
with the law, and, third, that where it is filed in time, and 
not otherwise, the names which it contains shall be printed on 
the ballot. 

There is nothing in the act, so far as I can discover, 
which would warrant me in saying that to follow the ordinary 
meaning of the words used, and the grammatical construction 
employed, would lead to manifest absurdity or repugnance. 


Hence we should follow the plain meaning of the words. 
Whether this be true or not of section 134 and section 137, 
I am quite sure it is true of section 139. That section authorizes 
the clerk to print on the official ballot only the names 
of those candidates whose names have been certified to or 
filed with him in the manner provided for in this act. Now 
if the certificate was filed less than twenty days before the 
election, then it was not filed as provided in the act, and hencp 
the clerk would have no authority to print on the official 
ballot the names contained in the certificate. 

In determining whether or not a provision of the statute 
is mandatory or directory only, our supreme court has said 
in Hereford vs. City of Omaha, 4 Neb., 336-351 : 

"When some antecedent and prerequisite conditions must 
exist prior to the exercise of power, or must be performed 
before certain other powers can be exercised, then the statute 
must be regarded as mandatory." 

A prerequisite condition to the exercise of the power of 
a clerk to print the names of candidates on the official ballot 
is that they be certified to or filed with him as provided 
in the act. Hence the statute with respect to printing the 
names of the candidates on the ballot is mandatory. And 
since a failure to comply strictly with sections 134 and 137 
would render the act of no value, because the purpose of the </seg>


            <seg id="p083">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

83 

act is to have the names appear on the official ballot, I am of 
the opinion that it was the intention of the legislature that 
the provisions of sections 134 and 137, as well as 139, should 
be treated as mandatory. 

In the case of Howes vs. Turner, 1 C. P. D., 670, an 
English case, it was held that an election statute, providing 
that nine days at least before any election the town 
clerk shall publish a notice intimating the last day on which 
the nomination papers were to be delivered to him, and the 
day and hour at which the mayor would attend to hear 
and determine objections thereto was mandatory, and that 
the delivery of nomination papers to the clerk which left only 
seven clear days between the day of delivery and the day of 
election was delivered too late. 

To the same effect are cases of : 

Gothard vs. Clark, 42 L. T. R., 778 

Ex parte Drew, 9 S. C. Rep., 169-171 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., October 22, 1900. 
Joe Hand, Esq., Crawford, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — Yours of the 5th inst. was duly received. In 
reply thereto permit me to say that I am of the opinion that 
a retired soldier is entitled to the franchise. Section 2, chapter 
26, '99 Statutes, declares that all male persons of the 
age of twenty-one years or upwards, belonging either to the 
class known as citizens of the United States or the class 
know as persons of foreign birth who shall have declared 
their intention to become citizens, shall be entitled to vote. 

Section 5 says that no soldier, seaman, or marine in the 
army or navy of the United States shall be deemed a resident 
of the state in consequence of being stationed therein. This 
is the only exception. A retired soldier in my judgment can </seg>


            <seg id="p084">84 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

not be said to be stationed in any part of the United States 
within the meaning of the section just quoted, and if he be 
a resident of any given place for the time fixed by law he is r 
in my judgment, entitled to vote. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb., October 30, 1900. 

Hon. John F. Cornell, Auditor of Public Accounts: 

Dear Sir — Your letter of the 29th asking for my opinion 
with respect to the following question was duly received. 
You ask, where one specific appropriation has been made for 
fuel and lights and another for maintenance of a certain 
institution, and the appropriation for fuel and lights is exhausted, 
can a warrant be legally drawn for fuel on the appropriation 
for maintenance? 

In reply, permit me to say that I do not think it can, 
for the following reasons : The test by which any law is 
to be interpreted is the intention of the legislature, and 
whenever we can discover that we can discover the meaning 
of the law. When the legislature provided by appropriation 
a certain sum for a certain purpose, it must be clear that 
that is all which the legislature intended should be used for 
that purpose. Hence, when the legislature appropriated 
a certain sum for fuel and lights it meant that that sum and 
no more should be used for that purpose. The fund provided 
for maintenance was, in my judgment, intended to cover all 
those things for which specific appropriations had not been 
made, and that it can not be used for any of the things for 
which a specific appropriation was made. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. </seg>


            <seg id="p085">85 

REPORT OF ATTOttNEY GENERAL. 

Lincoln, Neb., November 2, 1900. 
P. E. McKMip, Esq., Humphrey, Neb.: 

Dear Sir — Mr. Smyth has been very busy in the campaign 
since your letter to him was received, and he has 
asked me to look up the matters you write about and answer 
the letter for him. 

Relative to your first question, as to whether your school 
district can recover moneys from the treasurer of the village 
of Humphrey, collected from fines levied by a justice of the 
peace (an ex-omeio police judge) for violations of village 
ordinances, you are advised as follows : 

In the first place, look at section 5, article 8, of the Constitution 
of this state. I will not quote the citations I make 
in this letter, but will simply refer you to them, and you will 
be able to look up their effect. There seems to be no question 
when it is easy to determine what money belongs to the 
school district, or is to be used for the benefit of the schools. 
The Constitution provides that in such cases the money is to 
be used for the benefit of the school within the village where it 
is collected. In the following cases the court granted writs 
of mandamus to compel the treasurer of the village to turn 
over the amounts of school money he had on hand to the 
school district. 

State vs. Wilcox, 17 Neb., 49. 

Primer vs. Brodbell, 28 Neb., 254. 
Guthrie vs. The State, 47 Neb., 819. 

Now in the case you mention, where fines are collected, 
there is no question, I think, that this money belongs to 
the school district, and the school district could compel the 
village treasurer to turn over such money to be used in the 
manner provided by law. 

Relative to the collection of money paid by peddlers, hawkers, 
fakirs, etc., it is more difficult to determine whether that 
money belongs to the school district or is collected simply 
for revenue for running the village government. Our court 
has discussed the difference between a license and an occupa- </seg>


            <seg id="p086">86 

EEPOET OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

tion tax, and in general the distinction made seems to be 
that a tax must be imposed solely for revenue. A license is 
imposed by the police power and is levied for the sake of 
restricting or regulating certain occupations. You will find 
discussions of this question in Pleuler vs. The State, 11 Neb., 
547, commencing on page 557. 

Another good discussion of the question, and wherein an 
occupation tax is sustained, is the case of The State ex rel. 
Sage vs. Bennett, 19 Neb., 191. 

I think that the Constitution and the cases cited above 
will enable you to decide whether or not the money collected 
by you from licensing occupations belongs to the village 
or the school district, and if it belongs to the school 
district, your right, I think, is unquestioned for the school 
district to collect said amount from the village. I also think 
from the adjudicated cases that the entire amounts that are 
due the school districts should be paid to the school districts, 
and all costs or expenses incurred in the collection of said 
amounts should be paid from any other proper source. 

This office is in receipt of a letter making the same inquiries 
that you make from Chas. Schmith, justice of the 
peace. If you will be kind enough to show this letter to the 
justice of the peace, it will save us the trouble of writing the 
letter over again! I will write him that we have given you 
an opinion in the matter and ask him to show our letter to 
you. 

Yours very truly, 

Paul Pizey, 

Assistant Attorney General. 

Lincoln, Neb v November 3, 1900. 
R. W. Boyd, Marquette, Xeb.: 

Dear Sir — Replying to your favor of the 15th ult. in which 
you ask whether any man is entitled to vote who came into 
your county on September 28 where you have to count the 
</seg>

            <seg id="p087">87 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

day iii which he entered the county and also election day to 
make the forty days required by the statute for his residence 
in the county before he Is entitled to vote, you are advised 
as follows : 

The statute reads : "Who shall have resided in the county 40 
days," etc., is entitled to vote, etc. The law knows no fractions 
of a day, and it is the opinion of this office that the 
statute means that a person must have resided in the county 
forty days before he is entitled to vote. This being the law, 
the fortj* full days in the case you mention would not expire 
until the end of the 6th day of November, which is 
election day, and your man would not be entitled to vote on 
the fortieth day. 

Yours very truly, 

Attorney General. 

By Paul Pizey, 

Assistant. 

Lincoln, Neb., November 3, 1900. 

Deab Sir — Replying to your oral request for an opinion 
from this office as to whether or not a person who attains 
his majority on the 7th day of November, 1900, will be entitled 
to vote at the election to be held on the 6th day of 
November, 1900, you are advised as follows : 

Section 3, chapter 36, '99 Statutes, provides, "Every male 
person of the age of twenty-one years or upwards," etc., ia 
entitled to vote. I interpret this statute to mean that a 
person must have lived twenty-one full years before he is entitled 
to vote. Under this interpretation one would not be 
entitled to vote until the moment when he enters upon the 
twenty-first anniversary of his birth. 

If a man is entitled to vote a moment before he enters 
upon this anniversary, he is entitled to vote at any time 

C. J. Smyth. 

H. J. Gunn, Esq., Lexington, Neb.: </seg>


            <seg id="p088">88 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

during the period between his twentieth anniversary and 
his twenty-first, because during all that time he is in his 
twenty-first year, and has not lived the full twenty-one years. 
The law knows no fractions of a day, consequently if a 
man's anniversary comes on the 7th day of November, he 
has not lived the twenty-one full years until the moment 
when the 7th day of November begins. This would be too 
late for him to vote at the election on the 6th. 

Yours very truly, 

Attorney General. 

By Paul Pizey, 

Assistant. 

Lincoln, Neb., November 15, 1900. 

Hon. IF. A. Poynter, Governor: 

Dear Sir — Replying to your esteemed favor of the 25th 
ult., wherein you enclosed certain papers sent you in the 
claim of W. O. Patterson against The State, for the sum of 
$200 offered by you as a reward for the arrest and conviction 
of the person that murdered Alois L. Standenmaier, in Sioux 
county, in May, 1900, in which you ask the opinion of this 
office as to whether or not Mr. Patterson is entitled to this 
reward, you are advised as follows : 

The facts as shown in your communication are as follows : 
On the 19th day of May, 1900, in a letter from Thomas Holly, 
sheriff of Harrison, Nebraska, you were apprised of the fact 
that a man was murdered in Sioux county on the 18th day of 
May, 1900, by some unknown party or parties. You were 
advised that if reward enough was offered, the party committing 
the murder could be secured. Under this advice, Your 
Excellency, on the 25th day of May, 1900, offered a reward of 
f200 "for the arrest and conviction of said person or persons 
for the murder of said Alois L. Standenmaier." 

W. O. Patterson now claims the reward offered by Your 

C. J. Smyth, </seg>


            <seg id="p089">89 

KEPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Excellency and in his statement of his claim sworn to before 
a notary public, he declares that on the 23d day of May, 
1900, he arrested one Chas. Russel, for the murder of Alois 
L. Standenmaier, and that said Russel was duly convicted 
for the murder and sentenced to the penitentiary for life. 
The county attorney of Sioux county and the judge of the 
district court wherein said Russel was convicted also made 
affidavits to the same effect. The question is, is Patterson 
entitled to the reward, having arrested said Russel on the 
23d day of May, 1900, the reward not being offered until 
the 25th day of May, 1900? 

It is the opinion of this office that the party claiming 
the reward is not entitled thereto. A reward is offered in 
order to procure the arrest and conviction of parties who 
have committed the crime. It is offered as an incentive 
towards the arrest and conviction of criminals, and it is 
given on the theory that all ordinary means have been exhausted 
in an unsuccessful attempt to secure the arrest of 
persons guilty of felonious offenses. On the advice contained 
in the sheriffs letter of May 19, Your Excellency offered 
the reward, not knowing that at the time you offered it, 

that the murderer had been arrested, and doubtless you 
would not have offered such reward had you known of the 

arrest of Russel. There can be no doubt under these facts, 
that the reasons for which rewards are offered do not exist 
in this case. 

In the case of City Bank vs. Bangs, 2 Edw., Ch. (N. Y.), 
pages 95-97, the court defines rewards as follows: 

"Rewards are ottered only when it is supposed the ordinary 
means of discovery and detection would prove ineffectual. 
They are voluntary offerings and adapted to what the party 
making the offer deems to be the necessity and urgency 
of the occasion. The object is to awaken public attention 
to the subject, excite vigilance, and call forth extraordinary 
individual effort for the accomplishment of the end proposed 
to be gained. All who choose to engage in it are at liberty </seg>


            <seg id="p090">90 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

to do so. And he who succeeds becomes entitled to the reward 
upon the ground of his superior vigilance or sagacity, 
or of his having used greater exertions or encountered 
dangers which others were disinclined or not in a situation 
to hazard." 

The party arresting the murderer in this case doubtless 
had no knowledge that any reward had been offered, and 
while I am aware that the authorities differ on the question 
as to whether or not such knowledge is required, and perhaps 
the weight of authorities in this country holds that it 
is not necessary for the one causing the arrest to be aware 
that any reward has been offered, yet that rule obtains 
doubtlessly only where the arrest has been made subsequent 
to the offer of the reward. 

In the case of Fitch vs. Skedaker, 38 N. Y., 248, a case 
similar to this is described and the court held that "such 
an offer proposes compensation for what shall be done thereafter, 
not for what has been done already, and, unless information 
be thereafter given which leads both to apprehension 
and conviction, the reward is not payable." In the 
present case the plaintiff, after the advertisement of the 
defendant's offer of a reward came to his knowledge, did 
nothing toward procuring the arrest nor which led thereto, 
for at that time Fee had already been arrested. 

These cases are decisive of this matter, and it is the opinion 
of this office that your Excellency would not be warranted 
in paying the reward. 

Yours very truly, 

C. J. Smyth, 

Attorney General. 

By Paul Pizey, 

Assistant. </seg>


            <seg id="p091">SCHEDULES "B," "C," "D," '%" "F.» 

STATE CASES— CIVIL. 

SCHEDULE B. 

at v. V 4 » t&gt; i t t i I state depository to recover 
Merchants' Bank of Lincoln ) f8T31 85^ Pe nding. 

21—69. 

&gt;l District Court, Lancaster 
ine btate county. Action on deposi- 
,r x. V ,., t, i * t- f or y bond- Ma y 5 &gt; 1899 » 
Merchants' Bank of Lin- Ju J dgment for plaint iff for 
coln J f9,903.36. 

'Z'Z — 125. 

-\ District Court, Lancaster 
The State county. Action to recover 
v r shortage as state treasurer on 
Joseph S. Bartley first term bond of $335,878- 
.08. Pending. 

10—15. 

District Court, Lancaster 
The State county. Action to recover 
v &gt; shortage of $3,527.90 as treas- 
Charles W. Mosher urer of relief commission. 
Pending. 

mu oi. x -\ Circuit Court U. S., Dis- 
lne fctate | trict Nebraska Action on 
,,. , ~7 ,. , „ , ... | bond as state depository to 
!• irst National Bank of Alma J MC0W 0fil2^ Pending. 

24—250. 

_, a , . » District Court, Lancaster 
Ihe tetate cruntv. Action on bond as </seg>


            <seg id="p092">92 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

No 

6068. 

District court, Otoe county. 
Action to correct bond. 
February 20, 1900, Judgment 
for plaintiff. 

The State 

v 

Otoe County 

No 

Injunction — Supreme Court. 
September 21, 1899, Affirmed, 
58 Neb., 823. March 7, 1900, 
Affirmed on rehearing. 59 
Neb. 737. 

Nebraska Telephone Co 

v 

John F. Cornell 

No. 10416. 

Pacific Express Co. 

] Injunction — Supreme Court. 
&gt;¦ December 19, 1899. Affirmed, 

v 

John F. Cornell 

To recover shortage. Dis- 
I trict Court, Otoe county. 
[April 24, 1900, Judgment 

The State 

v 

William Ebright 

J for plaintiff for $ 500. 

No 

Richard Blaco 

Supreme Court. Action on 
bond. May 3, 1899, Reversed. 
58 Neb., 557 

v 

The State 

No 

J. C. Goodell and 
A. J. Gallentine 

Two cases. Supreme Court. 
Action on depository bond. 
Error to District Court, Buffalo 
county. Pending. 

v 

The State 

No 

Mandamus. Supreme 
&gt; Court. April 6, 1899, writ 
J denied. 58 Neb., 451. 

The State ex rel. Agge Axen 

v 

John B. Meserve 

10417. 

59 Neb., 364. 

No. 5979. 
1 . * 

10461. 

10426. 

10549. </seg>


            <seg id="p093">93 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

No 

10586 

Supreme Court. Conversion. 
Dec. 19, 1899, reversed. 
59 Neb., 483. Feb. 1, 1900, 
mandate. Nov. 8, 1900, mandamus 
to District Court 
Douglas county to carry out 
mandate. Nov. 16, 1900, verdict 
for defendant in District 
Court Douglas county. 

The State 

v 

Omaha National Bank 

No 

5545. 

District Court, Buffalo 
county. Action "to recover 
shortage. Nov. 22, 1899, dismissed. 


The State 

v 

John T. Mallalieu 

No. 

10590 

Society for Home for the 

Ejectment. Supreme 
Court. Error, Lancaster 
county. Apr. 6, 1899, affirmed. 
58 Neb., 447. 

Friendless 

v 

The State 

No 

The State ex rel, Sprecher 

Quo Warranto. Supreme 
Court. Pending. 

v 

Charles W. Hoxie 

10626 

25—18. 

Mary Fitzgerald 
v 
fVilliam A. Poynter 

} Injunction. District 
Court. Lancaster county. 
December 21, 1899, dismissed 
without prejudice. 

264— S. 

jreenlief W. Simpson 
v 
[Jnion Stock Yard Co. 

Circuit Court U. S. Ne- 
braska District. Action to 
y prevent regulation of stock 
J yard rates under a legisla- 
tive act. Pending. </seg>


            <seg id="p094">94 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Circuit Court U. S. Nebraska 
District. Action to 
prevent enforcement of anticompact 
law. Pending. 

Niagara Fire Insurance Co. 

v 

John F. Cornell 

131—1. 

In re Patrick Gibbons, bank- \ District Court U. S. Ne- 

J braa ? :a. Pending, 

rupt 

393. 

"1 Supreme Court U. S. Emfbezzlement. 
Jan. 15, 1900, 

Henry Bolln 

v 

The State 

affirmed. 176 U. S. Rep., 83. 

"1 U. S. Circuit Court of Appeals. 
Action to recover 

John B. Meserve 

I money lost by Capital Na| 
tional Bank failure. Mar. 
19, 1900, dismissed. 101 
J Fed. Rep., 1006. 

v 

Kent K. Hayden 

1330 

U. S. Circuit Court of Appeals. 
Action to recover 
$236,361.83 lost by failure of 
Capital National Bank. 
Mar. 20, 1900, affirmed on appeal 
by McDonald. 101 Fed. 
Rep., 171. 

John W. McDonald 

v 

The State 

184 

T. 

Circuit Court U. S. Action 
to recover on bond as 
state depository. Mar. 20, 
1899, judgment for plaintiff 
for $15,825. 

The State 

v 

First National Bank of Orleans 


State of Missouri 

U. S. Supreme Court. To 
determine boundary dispute. 
Pending. 

v 

State of Nebraska 

115— T. </seg>


            <seg id="p095">95 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

62— Q. 

. Circuit Court U. S. Injunction 
against Board of 
Transportation. Mar. 23, 
1900, injunction denied. 
"May 21, 1900, judgment aflirmed 
by U. S. Circuit Court 
of Appeals. 102 Fed. Kep., 
¦&gt; 197. 

Henry L. Higginson 

v 

Chicago, B. &amp; Q. Kd. Co. 

Henry H. Parsons 

Injunction. 

District 

Catherine A. Lyons 

v 

P. C. Wade 

Settled and dismissed. 

417 

Injunction. District 
Court. Boyd county. May 
5, 1899, temporary injunc- 

John Brimmer 

v 

Nicolaus Sieler 

tion. 

Alfred G. Hopkins ~] Injunction. Lancaster 
v &gt; county. District Court. May 
William A. Poynter J 12, 1900, decree for plaintiff. 
16—196. 
McCormick Harvesting Ma-. District Court&gt; Adam8 
cmne i^o. I county Apr 7&gt; lg99? Judg . 
tt,™™ it T&gt; n ™^ a J ment released. 

&gt;¦ Court. Cheyenne county 

az — u. 

Chicago &amp; N. W. Ry. Co. 
v 
Donstantine J. Smyth 

&gt; Circuit Court U. S. To en- 
Moin Board of Transportation 
J from changing rates. Pend- 
ing. 

31— U.. 

Chicago, B. &amp; Q. Rd. Co. 
v 
Constantine J. Smyth 

¦^ Circuit Court U. S. To en- 
1 join Board of Transportation 
| from changing rates. Pend- 
J ing. 

O± 1 KA </seg>


            <seg id="p096">96 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Frank J. Bednor 

v 

Nicolaus Sieler 

Stephen Tanner 

v 

Nicolaus Sieler 

Art McCright 

v 

Nicolaus Sieler 

In re Cherry County Court "] 

Supreme Court. June 21 r 
1899, judgment of Lancaster 
county District Court for 
countv reversed. 58 Neb., 
734. 

House Bonds 
(The State 

v 

Cherry county) 

25—62; 

Habeas Corpus. Lancaster 
county. District Court. July 
19, 1899, writs denied. 

In re Bent 
In re Hayes 

Supreme Court from Lancaster 
county. Jan. 4, 1900, 
affirmed on rehearing. 57 
Neb., 711. 

The State 

v 

Thomas P. Kennard 

25 

Mandamus. District Court. 
Lancaster county. Sept 5, 
1899, dismissed. 

The State ex rel. 

v 

State Board of Health 

69—222 

Injunction. Trust case. 
District Court. Douglas 
countv. Pending. 

The State 

v 

Am. School Fur. Co. 

!; 25—64. 
S Hab&lt; 
&gt; county. 
J 19, 189 

11125. 

58.</seg> 


            <seg id="p097">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

97 

26—14. 

The State 

Action on contract bond. 
District Court Lancaster 
county. Pending. 

v 

Lincoln Cooperage Co. 

25—187. 

Appeal from State Auditor. 
Lancaster county. District 
Court. Dec. 27, 1899, 
finding for plaintiff. 

John M. Osborn 

v 

The State 

25—156. 

In re claim Mrs. A. M. Davis, 
Trustee, 

Appeal from State Auditor. 
Lancaster county. District 
Court. Pending. 

v 

The State 

Lancaster 

(¦ county. District Court. Dec 
J 2, 1899, demurrer overruled 

W. P. Porter 

25—207. 

In re claim Mrs. A. M. Davis, "I . 
Trillltpp District Court. Lancaster 
iiubtee, i , , „__ .. „_-- 

county. Dec. 1, 1900, dis- 

v 

missed by plaintiff. 

The State 

10929. 

Supreme Court from Lan&gt; 
caster county. Jan. 3, 1900, 

The State 

v 

Home Insurance C,o. 

10961. 

Quo Warranto. Supreme 
Court. Dec. 19, 1899, judgment 
for plaintiff. 59 Neb., 

The State ex rel. Cornell 

v 

William A. Poynter 

417. 

25—190. 

fhe State ex rel. Mrs. A. M.-. „ . 
Davis, Trustee. \ Ma » da T 1 " U f 
&gt;• county. Disti 

r easier couniy. j an. a, 
J reversed. 59 Neb., 524. </seg>


            <seg id="p098">98 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

1097 

i. 

Action on bond. Supreme 
Court, from Douglas county. 
Dec. 19, 1899, reversed. 59 
Neb., 460. Nov. 21, 1900, reversal 
adhered to on rehearing. 
84 N. W., 254. 

William A. Paxton 

v 

The State 

25—225. 

State Board of Agriculture ") „ ,_. . _ x 
I District Court. Lancaster 

county. Jan. 4, 1900, settled. 

John F. Cornell 

25—231. 

Omaha Cooperage Co. 

Replevin. District Court. 

Lancaster county. Nov. 13, 
1899, judgment for plaintiff. 

v 

John Hopkins 

25—235. 

The State ex rel. Omaha ~) Mandamus. District Court 

Cooperage Co. 

of Lancaster county. Nov. 
19, 1899, peremptory writ al- 

v 

John Hopkins 

J lowed 

Supreme 

The State ex rel. Omaha \ ? our * f r « m Lancaster coun- 
Cooperage Co. J *' 

25—259 

"^ Injunction. Lancaster 
&gt;- county. District Court. 

Benjamin F. Tolson 

v 

William A. Poynter 

Pending. 

11074 

The State 

1 Supreme Court. Trust 
f Case. Pending. 

v 

Standard Oil Co. 

j 

11020. 
John Hopkins, Warden, -. *, , 
_ r ' Mandamus. 
* I 1~* L M T </seg>


            <seg id="p099">99 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

The State 1 Receiver. District Court. 

For violating order Board 

I12G9. 

The State 

For violation of maximum 
freight rates. Supreme 
Court. Pending. 

v 

Missouri Pacific Ry. Co 

The State 

District Court. Saline 
county. Same as 11269. 

v 

Missouri Pacific Ry. Co. 

Chicago, St. P., M. &amp; 0. Ey. f^^X^ 11 - 8upreme 

v I Boyd county. Nov. 23, 1899, 
Farmers' &amp; Merchants' Bank [ Wilford Standiford appoint- 
of Butte, Neb. J ed receiver. 

11230. 

,„,.,„„ .. Injunction. Supreme 
Lincoln Medical College l Court from Lancaster coun- 
_.„. v . _ . fty. May 16, 1900, reversed. 
William A. Poynter J / 2 N W J g^ 

11271. 

The State For violation of maximum 
v [-freight rates. Supreme 
Union Pacific Rd. Co. 'J Court. Pending. 

11219. 

The State For violating order of 
v I Board of Transportation. 
Burlington &amp; M. R. R. Co. in | Supreme Court. Nov. 21, 
Nebraska J 1900, dismissed. 

11218. 

The State "J 
Fremont, E. &amp; M. V. Railroad J Same as 11219 ' 

Company 

11217. 

The State „ . ,_.. . _,_ «__ </seg>


            <seg id="p100">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

100 

11270. 

The State 

1 

&gt; Same as 11269. 

v 

Chicago, R. I. &amp; P. Ry. Co. 

The State 

District Court of Colfax 
county. Same as 11269. Dismissed. 


v 

Union Pacific R. R. Co 

John H. Miller 

&gt; Court Lancaster county 
J Jan. 5, 1900, allowed. 

v 

William F. Porter 

The State ex rel. Smyth 

Quo Warranto. Supreme 
&gt;¦ Court. June 7, 1900, writ 

v 

Frank A. Kennedy 

denied. 83 N. W., 87 

The State ex rel, Hibbard 

Mandamus. Supreme 
&gt;¦ Court. June 7, 1900, writ 

v 

John P. Cornell 

J denied. 83 N. W., 72 

11399. 

"1 Contempt. Supreme Court 

June 29, 1900, judgment 
against Bee Pub. Co. 83 N. 
' W., 204. July 12, 1900, judgment 
against E. Rosewater. 
83 N. W., 353. 

The State 

v 

Edward Rosewater 

The State ,1 -p.. , . . ~ 
y I District Court. Thayer 
Chicago, B. I. A P. Ry. Co. J count y- Same as 11269. 

26—26. 

1 Injunction. District 

11226. 

11220. 

11639. 

The State ex rel. Smyth j Trugt Cage Supremc 
Unite/starch Co. J Court - Pendin S- </seg>


            <seg id="p101">REPORT OF ATTORNEY .(JEXERAI 

101 

»,. a . i c, ., &gt; Trust Case. Injunction, 
fhe State ex rel. Smyth 1 Digtrict Court Vuglas 

v 

county. June 30, 1900, injunction 
denied. 

Reservoir Ice Co 

11455. 

Lozein W. Hilton 

i Supreme Court from Lancaster 
county. July 12, 1900. 
affirmed. 83 N. W., 354. 

v 

The State 

r| Action on bond of First 
National Bank of Orleans. 
District Court Rawlins coun" 
ty, Kansas. Fall Term 1900, 
transferred to U. S. Circuit 
Court of Kansas. Pending. 

The State 

v 

John W. Burton 

The State 

r Court Lancaster county. 
) Pending. 

National Biscuit Co. 

25—85 

Action to recover salary 
}as Supt. Feeble Minded Institute. 
District Court Lancaster 
county. Nov. 16, 1900, 

Charles G. Sprague 

v 

The State 

dismissed. 

i rm. j m i * 4- ) District Court Lancaster 
In re Theodore Clark for writ co M 2 writ 
of habeas corpus ' denied J 

26—148. 

District Court Lancaster 

In re Lew Kephart for writ c A 3 1900 wfit 
of habeas corpus j granted. 

27—100. 

) Trust Case. District 

26—187. </seg>

            <seg id="p102">
102 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

11641. 

The State ex rel. Mrs. A. M. 
Davis 

Mandamus. Supreme 
Court. Nov. 8, 1900, writ allowed. 
84 N. W., 87. 

v 

John F. Cornell 

The State 

Receiver. District Court 
of Furnas county. Apr. 10, 
1900, S. O. Simonds appointed 
receiver. 

v 

Citizens' State Bank of Cambridge 


STATE CASES— CRIMINAL. 

SCHEDULE U. 

No. 10472. 

Frederick D. Reynolds 
v 
rhe State 

Bigamy. Hayes county. 
)- Feb. 23, 1899, Reversed. 58 
j Neb., 49. 

No. 10476. 

Doote Mulloy 
v 
rhe State 

Assault and battery. Box 
&gt; Butte county. Mar. 8, 1899 r 
J affirmed. 58 Neb., 204. 

No. 10873. 

Gteorge C. Bailey 
v 
rhe State 

Rape. Douglas county. 
V Feb. 9, 1899, reversed. 57 
j Neb., 706. 

No. 10504. 

James Phillamalee 
v 
rhe State 

Larceny. Cedar county. 
&gt; Mar. 22, 1899, affirmed. 58 
j Neb., 320. </seg>


            <seg id="p103">103 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

No 

Alice Holmes 

Larceny from person 
Douglas county. Mar. 22, 
1899, reversed. 58 Neb., 297. 

v 

The State 

No 

Shooting with intent to 
[ kill. Dawson county. Mar. 
f 22, 1899, reversed. 58 Neb., 
J 356. 

Harley Atkinson 

v 

The State 

No 

Charles D. Tate 

Selling liquor to Indians. 
\ Cherry county. Mar. 8, 1899, 
J affirmed. 58 Neb., 296. 

v 

The State 

No 

Arson. Washington county. 
Mar. 8, 1899, reversed. 
58 Neb., 225. 

George Knights 

v 

The State 

No 

George Davis 

Forgery. Douglas county. 
Apr. 19, 1899, reversed. 58 
Neb., 465. 

v 

The State 

No 

Assault with intent to inflict 
great bodily injury. 
Butler county. May 3, 1899, 
reversed. 58 Neb., 531. 

Clinton Smith 

v 

The State 

No 

Murder. Douglas county. 
June 21, 1899, affirmed. 58 
Neb., 767. 

August Kastner 

v 

The State 

No 

Thomas Sullivan 

Murder. Douglas county. 
June 21, 1899, affirmed. 58 

v 

The State 

10520. 

10527. 

10542. 

10561. 

10566. 

10603. 

10G34. 

10641. 

Neb., 796. </seg>


            <seg id="p104">104 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

No 

10GT2. 

Coose Sutton 

Forgery. Washington 
county. May 17, 1899, re 
versed. 58 Neb., 567. 

v 

The State 

John Dunn 

v 

The State 

No 

10722 

Mary Baker alias 
quette 

Mary 

v 

versed. 84 N. W., 85. 

The State 

No 

10744. 

Frank Ward 

Assault with intent to kill. 
Jefferson county. June 21, 
1899, affirmed. 58 Neb., 719. 

v 

The State 

Edmon George 

v 

The State 

William J. Sweenie 

v 

The State 

Tames Latimer 

v 

The State 

11028. 

No 

Patrick Welsh 

Rape. Holt county. Apr. 
4, 1900, affirmed. 82 N. W., 

v 

The State 

368 

No. 10705. 
Rape. Greeley county. 
Y June 21, 1899, affirmed. 58 
J Neb., 807. 

Ineorrigibility. Lancaster 
&gt; county. Nov. 8, 1900, re- 

No. 10879. 
1 Cattle Stealing. Cherr 
&gt;¦ county. Oct. 18, 1899, r 
J versed. 59 Neb., 163. 

No. 10943. 
] Adultery. Butler county. 
Y Nov. 9, 1899, reversed. 59 
J Neb., 269. 

No. 10945. 
Robbery. Stanton county. 
&gt;¦ Dec. 2, 1899, dismissed by 
J plaintiff in error. </seg>


            <seg id="p105">105 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

( 

NO. 11097. 

"1 Rape. Kearney county. 
2, 1900, affirmed. 59 
J Neb., 655. 

Taeob Baer 

v 

The State 

No. 11130. 

\ndrew Hawkins 

*") Murder. Frontier county. 
20, 1900, affirmed. 83 
J N. W., 198. 

v 

rhe State 

No. 11190. 
Larceny. Hitchcock coun 

John Williams and 

Lewis 

&gt;- ty. Sept. 19, 1900, reversed 
83 N. W., 681. 

v 

The State 

No. 11277. 

Lloyd Cardwell 

~| Rape. Sheridan county. 
Y Sept. 19, 1900, affirmed. 83 

v 

The State 

N. W., 665. 

No. 11231. 

Vndrew McArthur 

Selling liquor. Sherman 
&gt;¦ county. June 20, 1900, af- 
J firmed. 83 N. W., 196. 

v 

Ihe State 

"] Burglary 

Kudv Hahn 

Lancaster 

&gt;¦ county. Sept. 20, 1900, af 
J firmed. 83 N. W., 674. 

v 

The State 

1 harles W. Little 

Osteopath practicing with- 
license. Nov. 21, 1900, 

v 

J affirmed. 84 N. W., 248. 

The State 

No. 11530. 

Burglary. Douglas coun&gt; 
ty. Oct. 18, 1900, reversed. 

Henry Leisenberg 

v 

84 N. W., 6. 

The State 

No. 11193. 

No. 11213 </seg>


            <seg id="p106">106 

HEPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. . 

i 

&gt; 

STATE CASES— CRIMINAL— PENDING. 

SCHEDULE D. 

No. 11365. 

Shedrick C. Burlingim 

Accessory to Forgery 
Douglas county. Nov. 20 
1900, submitted. 

v 

The State 

No. 11238. 

John W. Tatum 

Larceny. Buffalo countv 
Oct. 17, 1900, submitted. 

v 

The State 

No. 11407. 

Floyd Sandage 

Stealing chickens. Fill 
&gt; more county. Oct. 16, 1900 

v 

The State 

submitted. 

George Coil 

\ Nov. 20, 1899, continued t( 
) December 20, 1899. 

V 

The State 

No. 11259. 

Charles Sharp 

Larceny. Lancaster coun 
fty. Nov! 22, 1900, defend 
J ant's brief filed. 

v 

The State 

No. 11340. 

John W. Argabright 

v 

The State 

No. 11423. 

Selling liquor without li 
cense. Lancaster county 
Nov. 20, 1900, continued t&lt; 
Dec. 4, 1900. 

Fred Parsons 

v 

The State 

No. 11367. 
) Murder. Dawes county 

) Murder. Nemaha county 
\ Nov. 20, 1900, submitted. </seg>


            <seg id="p107">107 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

No. 11452. 

Rape. Madison county. 

Leland Spaulding 

v 

Oct. 17, 1900, submitted. 

The State 

No. 11470. 

Frank Dinsmore 

} Murder. Dawson county. 
Nov. 21, 1900, plaintiff given 
fifteen days to file briefs. 

v 

The State 

No. 11471. 

Cattle stealing. Cherry 
county. Nov. 7, 1900, plaintiff 
given thirty days to file 
briefs. 

Alexander Dobson 

v 

The State 

No. 11493. 

Cicero H. Thompson 

Murder. Cherry county. 
Nov. 20, 1900, continued 
thirty days. 

v 

The State 

No. 11634. 

Henry D. Rhea 

Embezzlement. Dawson 
Y county. Oct. 16, 1900, sub- 

v 

The State 

mitted. 

The State 

No. 11449. 

Lester M. Strong 

Assault with intent to com&gt; 
mit rape. Buffalo county. 
J Nov. 21, 1900, submitted. 

v 

The State 

No. 11691. 

Placing obstruction on 
(- public road. Burt county. 
J Oct. 17, 1900, docketed. 

Jonathan Lydick 

v 

The State 

No. 11651. 
1 Murder. Nemaha county. 
f Nov. 7, 1900, submitted. 

Charles B. Smith 
v </seg>


            <seg id="p108">108 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Falsely obtaining signature 
to note. York county. 
Oct. 29, 1900, docketed. 

No 

Patrick E. Cooney 

Liquor selling. Dawson 
}¦ county. Oct. 17, 1900, dock- 

v 

The State 

eted. 

No 

Edward Jerome 

Assault with intent to kill. 
\~ Dodge county. Oct. 23, 1900, 

v 

The State 

J docketed. 

No 

11714. 

George M. Howell 

1 Assault with intent to 
&gt; wound. Nemaha county. 

v 

The State 

Oct. 31, 1900, docketed. 

Rowland P. Hills 

v 

The State 

No 

11735. 

Practicing medicine with/?out 
i'mtiflcate. Custer coun- 
J ty. Nov. 12, 1900, docketed. 

Otis G. Sofield 

v 

The State 

District Court Douglas 
county. For violating antitrust 
law. Pending. 

The State 

v 

A. H. Bewsher 

.No. 11712. 

Samuel D. Roby 
v 
The State 

nosy. 

11702. 

No. 11721. 
~] Bigamy. Washington 
&gt; count v. Nov. 7, 1900, d&lt;&gt;ck- 
J eted. " </seg>


            <seg id="p109">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

109 

APPROPRIATIONS FOR OFFICE OF ATTORNEY 
GENERAL. 

SCHEDULE E. 

1897. Appropriations. 

1S98 SALARY ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Dec. 1. By Balance ? 1,000 00" 

To 6 month's salary — C. J. 

Smyth | 1,000 00 

$ 1,000 00 $ 1,000 0O 

1898 

SALARY DEPUTY ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Dec. 1. By Balance f 600 m 

To 4 month's salary — W. D. 

Oldham $ 600 00 

| 600 00 f 600 00 

1898 

SALARY STENOGRAPHER. 

Dec. 1. By Balance f 333 34 

To 4 month's salary — Geo. W. 

Corcoran f 333 34 

| 333 34 f 333 34 

1898 

STATIONERY AND POSTAGE. 

Dec. 1. By Balance $ 92 60 

To 4 month's expenses $ 92 60 

| . 92 60 f 92 60 
</seg>

            <seg id="p110">110 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

1898 

COURT AND OFFICERS' FEES. 

Dec. 1. By Balance I 44 40 

To expenses $ 34 50 

Lapsed 9 90 

$ 44 40 ? 44 40 

1898 

OFFICE EXPENSES. 

Dec. 1. By Balance f 65 

Lapsed ? 65 

5 

65 $ 

Go 

1898 

TELEGRAPH AND EXPRESS 

Dec. 1. By Balance $ 9 30. 

To expenses $ 9 30 

$ 9 30 $ 9 30 

1898 

FURNITURE AND REPAIRS 

Dec. 1. By Balance $ 102 70 

To expenses $ 78 65 

Lapsed 24 05 

$ 102 70 f 102 70 

1898 

TRAVELING EXPENSES. 

Dec. 1. By Balance $ 106 95 

To expenses $ 24 25 

Lapsed 82 70 

$ 106 95 $ 106 95 </seg>


            <seg id="p111">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

111 

USE IN PROSECUTIONS, DISBURSED BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR. 

1898 

Dec. 1. By Balance f 689 72 

To expenses $ 589 94 

Lapsed 99 78 

$ 689 72 ? 689 72 

1899 Appropriations. 

1899 

SALARY ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Apr. 5. By appropriation f 4,000 00 

To 6 quarters' salary — C. J. 

Smyth | 3,000 00 

Dec. 1. By balance 1,000 00 

f 4,000 00 $ 4,000 00 

1899 

SALARY DEPUTY ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Apr. 5. By appropriation $ 3,600 00 

To 20 months' salary— W. D 

Oldhani ? 3,000 00 

Dec. 1. By balance 600 00 

$ 3,600 00 f 3,600 00 

1899 SALARY ASSISTANT ATTORNEY GENERAL, 

Apr. 5. By appropriation f 2,400 00 

To 9 months' salary — Geo. F. 

Corcoran $ 900 00 

To 11 months' salary — Paul 

Pizey 1,100 00 

Dec. 1. By balance 400 00 

? 2,400 00 | 2,400 00 </seg>


            <seg id="p112">112 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

1899 SALABY ATTORNEY GENERAL'S STENOGRAPHER. 

Apr. 5. By appropriation $ 2,000 00 

To 20 months' salary Cath- 

erine A. Odell | 1,666 67 

Dec. 1. By balance 333 33 

$ 2,000 00 $ 2,000 00 

1899 

POSTAGE AND STATIONERY. 

Apr. 5. By appropriation $ 900 00 

To expenses $ 737 10 

Dec. 1. By balance 162 90 

| 900 00 $ 900 00 

USE IN PROSECUTIONS, DISBURSED BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR 

1899 

Apr. 5. By appropriation $ 5,000 00 

To expenses $ 4,003 16 

Dec.l. By balance 996 84 

$ 5,000 00 $ 5,000 00 

« 

1899 

TRAVELING EXPENSES. 

Apr. 5. By appropriation f 600 00 

To expenses 

$ 74 90 

Dec. 1. By balance 

525 10 

$ 600 00 $ 600 00 

1899 PRINTING BRIEFS. 

Apr. 5. By appropriation $ 800 00 

To expenses $ 310 30 

Dec. 1. By balance 489 70 

| 800 00 $ 800 00 </seg>


            <seg id="p113">113 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Note. — For detailed statement of expenditures of all above 

appropriations, Bee semi-annual statements on file in the 

office of the Governor. 

MONEY RECEIVED. 

SCHEDULE F. 

1899 

Sept. 5. Judgment — State vs. Hilton, 

case No. 11455 I 6,759 33 

Sept. 5. Paid J. B. Meserve, State 
Treasurer f 6,759 33 

1900 

June 4. Return of costs, case McDon- 

ald vs. State 6 10 

June 4. Cop. opinion, case Higginson 
vs. C, B. &amp; Q ¦ 3 50 

June 15. Fr. Exc. Bank, Atkinson, 

S. B. Howard, receiver . . . 1,442 81 

June 15. Paid J. B. Meserve 1,442 81 

July 31. Vol. 7 Gray's (Mass.) R. . . . 2 60 

Oct 24. 15 per cent dividend, case 

McDonald vs. State "35,454 27 

Oct. 24. Paid J. B. Meserve as per 
receipt, No. 17484 35,454 27 

Totals |43,662 51 $43,662 51 </seg>



            <seg id="p115">INDEX. 

Agricultural society 40 

Anderson, R. P., opinion 40 

Anti-trust law — 

standard oil case 11, 16 

&gt; 

insurance 8, 51 

¦&gt; 

intent of 78 

Appropriations — 

for bridge over Niobrara river 26 

claim presented before lapsing of 68 

for one fund — warrant drawn on another 84 

Banks and banking — 

are directors officers? 32 

assessment of stock 41 

what constitutes 55 

Birse, F. J., opinion 24 

Board, Secretaries, State Board Transportation, opinion 49 

Bond 3, 4 

depository, suit on 3, 4, 8, 9 

Conflict of laws — 

civil and military 35, 44 

'&gt; 

Clegg, J. F., opinion 34 

Cornell, John F., opinions 41, 51, 53, 57, 62, 68, 84 

r *7 7 ~**~ ™ w ~ ¦ ¦ "7 ¦~y 

of state treasurer — suit to recover on 

9 

surety, for saloon keepers 
depository, signed by officers 

29 
32 

of deputy county treasurer 
refunding railroad and court house 

43 
47 

allots — 

order of names on 

74 

printed in double columns 
ioyd, It. W., opinion 
tutler, W. K., opinion 

76 
86 
52 </seg>


            <seg id="p116">116 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

County — 

Garten, A. E., opinion 25 

Gunn, H. J., opinion 87 

55 

Hall, P. L., opinion 

Hammerly, J., opinion 24 

Hand, Joe, opinion 83. 

as applied to insurance o L 

Counties — 

formation of new lt&gt; 

clerks of — salary — fee book 24 

deputy treasurer of 43 
court house, refunding bonds for 47 

County seat — 
relocation of, submission of question of 73 

Courts — 

supreme — condition of docket 11 

Crops — 
tenant's right to 28 

Depository 3 

bond, suit on 3, 4, 8, 9 

Dort, J. G., opinion 77 

Elections — 

ballots — order of names 74 

printing in double columns 76 
certificate of nomination — requirements — time of 

filing 80 
retired soldier entitled to franchise 83 

meaning of "forty days" &gt; 86 

meaning of "twenty-one years" 87 

Embezzlement — 

by State Treasurer 4 

by City Treasurer 8 

by State Auditor » 

Fees 52 

insurance 53 

Felton, W. A., opinion 78 </seg>


            <seg id="p117">117 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Hartigan, John C, opinion ' 70 

Henderson, Col. W. L., opinion 19 

Highways — 

road district tax to exceed 15 mills 25 

Homestead — 

school land as — transfer 66 

Hostetler, B. 0., opinion 31 

House Roll No. 251 52 

Information and indictment 8 

Injunction — 

against State Board of Transportation 4 

to restrain prosecution of sureties on bond 6 

against regulating stock yards 7 

against enforcing insurance anti-trust law 8 

Insurance — 

anti-trust law 8, 51 

'&gt; 

fees — defalcation 9, 53 

&gt; 

reserve fund 41 

foreign — reciprocal tax 57 

withdrawal of security 62 

Introduction 3 

conclusion 14 

Johnson, Victor O., opinion ' 80 

Justice of Peace — 

number in county 24 

and assessor in one 25 

fines go to school district 85 

Legislature — 

journals of 13 

Leyda, Jas. E., opinions 39, 74 

&gt; 

License and occupation tax — 

distinguished 85 

collection of — costs 85 

McCartney, Frank,, opinion 29 

McCutchan, G. A., opinion 76 

McKillip, P. E., opinion 85 </seg>


            <seg id="p118">118 

REPORT OP ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Meserve, John B., opinions 25, 32, 73 

Military code — 

construction of 70 

Municipal bonds 3] 

redemption of, notice 3t 

Nebraska Industrial Home — 

power to relinquish children 60 

Nebraska National Guard 10 

Notice — 

to redeem water bonds of city 34 

Numerical indices — 

new set of 39 

Occupation tax and license — 

distinguished 85 

collection of — costs 85 

O'Neill, Hugh, opinion 26 

Opinions — 

Anderson, K. P 40 

Birss, F. J 24 

Board, Secretary, State Board of Transportation. . 4!&gt; 

Boyd, K. W 86 

Butler, W. R 52 

Clegg,J.F : 34 

Cornell, John F 41, 51, 53, 57, 62, 68, 84 

Dort, J. G 77 

Felton, W. A 78 

Garten, A. E 25 

9&gt;K 

Gunn, H. J 87 

Hall, P. L 55 

Hammerly, J 24 

Hand, Joe 83 

Hartigan, John C TO 

Henderson, Col. W. L # 19 

Hostetler, B. O , 31 

Johnson, Victor 0 80 

Leyda, Jas. E 39, 74 </seg>


            <seg id="p119">119 

ilEPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

McCartney, Frank 29 

McCutchan, G. A 76 

McKillip, P. E 85 

Meserve, John B 25, 32, 73 

'&gt; «*¦"&gt; 

O'Neill, Hugh 26 

Parker, J. T 41 

Poynter, W. A 35, 44, 88 

Rinaker, Samuel 64 

Root, Jesse L 42, 47 

Taylor, W. Z 29 

Walker, Lewis E 23 

Wilson, W. W 43 

Wolfe, J. V 28, 60, 66 

I, TO, 

Parker, J. T., opinion 41 

Penalties — 

actions for 10 

and fines 

Poynter, W. A., opinions 35, 44, 88 

Procedure — 

in Omaha National Bank case 4 

Railroads — 

regulation of 15 

refunding bonds of 47 

violating board orders 49* 

Residence — 

question of intention 23 

Reward — 

offered after arrest of murderer 88 

Rinaker, Samuel, opinion 64 

Boot, Jesse L., opinion 42, 47 

Schedules 3 

A, Opinions 19 

B, Civil cases — disposed of — pending 91 

C, Criminal cases disposed of 102 

D, Criminal cases pending 106 

E, Appropriations 109 </seg>


            <seg id="p120">120 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

F, Money collected and accounted for 113 

State Board of Transportation — 

suit to restrain 3 

validity of law creating 9 

regulating railroad rates 49 

Taylor, W. Z., opinion 29 

Taxes- 

preferred claim on personalty 29 

uncollectible delinquent 42 

reciprocal 57 

against telephone companies 64 

advertising land for sale for, charge 77 

Telephone and express companies — 

suit to reduce rates 3 

Walker, Lewis E., opinion 23 

Wilson, W. W., opinion 43 

Wolfe, J. V., opinion 28, 60, 66 

&lt;&gt; ««&gt; </seg>


            <seg id="p121">TABLE OF CASES. 

American School Furniture Co., State v 96 

Argabright v. State 106 

Atkinson v. State 103 

Baer v. State 105 

Bailey v. State 102 

Baker v. State 104 

Bank, State v 99, 102 

Bartley v. State 91 

Bednor v. Sieler • 96 

Bewsher v. State 108 

Blaco v. State 4, 92 

Bolln v. State 8, 94 

p &gt; 

Brimmer v. Sieler 95 

Burlington v. State , 106 

B. &amp; M. R. Rd. Co., State v 9, 99 

» 

Burton, State v 101 

Cardwell v. State 105 

Chicago, B. &amp; Q. Rd. Co., Higginson v 9, 95 

&gt; 

Chicago, B. &amp; Q. Rd. Co. v. Smyth 9, 95 

? 

Chicago &amp; N. W. Ry. Co. v. Smyth 9, 95 

i 

Chicago, R. I. &amp; P. Rd. Co., State t 100 

Chicago, St. P., M. &amp; O. Rd. Co., State v 9, 99 

Coil v. State 106 

Cooney v. State 108 

Cornell, Nebraska Telephone Co. v 3, 92 

Cornell, Niagara Fire Ins. Co. v 8, 94 

Cornell, Pacific Express Co. v 3, 92 

'» 

Cornell, State ex rel. v 100 

Davis v. State 103 

Dinsmore v. State 107 

Dobson v. State 107 

Dnnn v. State 104 </seg>


            <seg id="p122">122 

REPORT OV ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Ebright, State v 4, 92 

&gt; 

First National Bank of Alma, State v 3, 91 

First National Bank of Orleans, State v 9, 94 

&gt; 

Fitzgerald v. Poynter 6, 93 

F., E. &amp; M. V. Rd. Co., State v 9, 99 

Gallentine and Goodell v. State 92 

Hahn v. State 105 

Hawkins v. State 105 

Hayden, Meserve v 94 

Higginson v. C, B. &amp; Q. Rd. Co 9, 95 

i 

Hills v. State 108 

Hilton y. State 101 

Holmes v. State 103 

Home Ins. Co., State v 9, 53, 97 

Hopkins v. Poynter 95 

Hopkins v. State Board of Agriculture 98 

Hopkins, State ex rel. v 98 

Howell v. State „ 108 

Hoxie, State ex rel. v 93 

In re Bent 96 

In re Clark 101 

In re Cherry County Court House Bonds 96 

In re claim of Mrs. A. If. Davis v. State 97 

In re Hayes 96 

In re Kephart 101 

In re Patrick Gibbons 94 

Jerome v. State 108 

Kastner v. State 103 

Kennedy, State ex rel. v 100 

Kennard, State v 9, 96 

» 

Knight v. State 103 

Latimer v. State 104 

Leisenberg v. State 105 

Lincoln Cooperage Co., State v 97 

Lincoln Medical College v. Poynter 99 

Little v. State 105 </seg>


            <seg id="p123">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

123 

Lydick v. State 107 

Lyons v. Wade 95 

McArtliur v. State 105 

McCormick, H., Machine Co. v. Parsons 95 

MeCrigfat v. Sieler 96 

McDonald v. State 8, 94 

&gt; 

Mallalieu, State v 93 

Merchants Bank of Lincoln, State v 91 

Meserve v. Hayden 94 

Meserve, State, ex rel., v 92 

Miller v. Porter ICO 

Missouri v. Nebraska 94 

M. P. Uy. Co., State v 99 

Mosher, State v 91 

Mulloy v. State 102 

National Biscuit Co., State v 101 

Nebraska Telephone Co. v. Cornell 3, 92 

Nebraska, Missouri v 94 

Niagara Fire Ins. Co. v. Cornell 8, 94 

'&gt; 

Omaha National Bank, State v 4, 93 

i 

Osborn v. State 97 

Otoe County, State v 92 

Pacific Express Co. v. Cornell 3, 92 

Parsons, MeCorinick H. Machine Co. v 95 

Parsons v. State 10f&gt; 

Paxton v. State 9, 98 

i 

Phillanialee v. State 102 

Porter, Miller v 100 

Porter, State ex. rel. Davis v 97 

Poynter, Fitzgerald v 6, 93 

'&gt; 

Poynter, Hopkins v 95 

Poynter, Lincoln Medical College v 99 

Poynter, State ex rel. Cornell v 97 

Poynter, Tolson v 98 

Keservoir Ice Co., State ex rel. v 101 

Reynolds v. State 102 </seg>


            <seg id="p124">124 

BEPOBT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

Rhea v. State 107 

Roby v. State 108 

Rosewater, State v 100 

Sandage v. State 106 

Sharp v. State 106 

Sieler, Bednor v 9(5 

Sieler, Brimmer v 95 

Sieler, McCright v 96 

Sieler, Tanner v 96 

Simpson v. Union Stock Yards Co 7, 93 

Smith v. State 103, 107 

Smyth, C, B. &amp; Q. Rd. Co. v 9, 95 

Smyth, C. &amp; N. W. Ry. Co. v 9, 95 

Society Home for Friendless v. State 93 

Sofield v. State 108 

Sprague v. State 101 

Spaulding v. State 107 

Standard Oil Co., State v 98 

State Board of Agriculture v. Hopkins 98 

State Board of Health v. State, ex rel 96 

Strong v. State 107 

Sullivan v. State 103 

Sutton v. State 104 

Sweenie v. State 104 

State, McArthur v 105 

State v. McDonald 8, 94 

State v. American School Furniture Co 96 

State, Argabright v 106 

Srate, Atkinson v 103 

State v. Baer 105 

Slate v. Bewsher 108 

State, Bailey v 102 

State, Baker v 104 

State v. Bank 99, 102 

State v. Bartley 91 

State, Blaco v 4, 92 

&gt; </seg>


            <seg id="p125">REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

125 

State, Bolln v 8, 94 

State, Burlington v IOC 

State v. B. &amp; M. R. Kd. Co . .9, 99 

» 

State v. Burton 101 

State, Cardwell v 105 

State v. Cherry County 96 

State v. C, It. I. &amp; P. Kd. Co 100 

State v. C, St. P., M. &amp; O. Rd. Co 9, 99 

State, Coil v 106 

State, Cooney v 108 

State, Davis v 103 

State, Dinsmore v 107 

State, Dobson v 107 

State, Dunn v 104 

State v. Ebright 4; 92 

&gt; 

State v. First National Bank of Alma 3, 91 

&lt;i 

State v. First National Bank of Orleans 9, 94 

State v. F., E. &amp; M. V. Rd. Co 9, 99 

&gt; 

State v. Gallentine and Goodell 92 

State, George v 104 

State, Hahn v 105 

State, Hawkins v 105 

State, Hilton v 101 

State, Hills v 108 

State, Holmes v 103 

State v. Home Ins. Co 9, 53, 97 

'&gt; «*»! 

State, Howell v 108 

State, In re claim of Mrs. A. M. Davis v '. 97 

State, Jerome v 108 

State, Kastner v 103 

State v. Kennard 9, 96 

r » 

State, Knight v 103 

State, Latimer v 104 

State, Leisenberg v 105 

State v. Lincoln Cooperage Co ' 97 

State, Little v 4 105 

t </seg>


            <seg id="p126">126 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

State, Lydick v 107 

State v. Mallalieu 93 

State v. Merchants Bank of Lincoln 91 

State v. M. P. Ry. Co 99 

State v. Mosber 91 

State, Mulloy v 102 

State v. National Biscuit Co 101 

State v. Omaha National Bank 4, 03 

&gt; 

State, Osborn v 1)7 

State v. Otoe County 92 

Slate, Parsons v 10G 

State, Paxton v 9, 'tS 

State, Phillamalee v 102 

State, Reynolds v 102 

State, Rhea v 107 

State, Roby v 108 

State v. Rosewater 100 

State, Sandage v 106 

State, Sharp v 106 

State, Smith v 103, 107 

State, Society Home for Frindless v f*3 

State, Sofield v 108 

State, Sprague v 101 

State, Spaulding v 107 

State v. Standard Oil Co !»8 

State, Strong v 107 

State, Sullivan v 103 

State, Sutton v 104 

State, Sweenie v 104 

State, Tate v 103 

State, Tatum v 106 

State, Thompson v 107 

State v. U. P. Rd. Co 10, 99, 100 

, oj, 

State, Ward v 104 

State, Welsh v .• 104 

State, Williams v, 105 

/ </seg>


            <seg id="p127">127 

REPORT OF ATTORNEY GENERAL. 

State ex rel. v. Cornell 100, 102 

State ex rel. v. Hopkins i&gt;3 

State, ex rel. v. Hoxie 33 

State, ex rel. v. Kennedy 100 

State, ex rel. v. Meserve 92 

State, ex rel. v. Poynter 97 

State, ex rel. v. Reservoir Ice Co 101 

State, ex rel. Davis v. State 97 

State, ex rel. v. State Board of Health 96 

State, ex rel. v. United Starch Co 100 

Tanner v. Sieler 96 

Tate v. State 103 

Tatum v. State 100 

Thompson v. State 107 

Tolson v. Poynter 98 

Union P. Rd. Co., State v 10, 99, 100 

Union Stock Yards Co., Simpson v 7, 03 

i 

United Starch Co., State ex rel. v 100 

Wade, Lyons v 95 

Ward v. State 104 

Welsh v. State 104 

Williams v. State 105 </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>