<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0026</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Comparative Costs of Home-Produced and Commerically Produced Bread and Rolls</title>
               <date value="18??">October 1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 115 Comparative Costs of Home-Produced and Commercially Produced Bread and Rolls Edna B. Snyder Department of Home Economics LINCOLN; NEBRASKA OCTOBER 1939 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Purpose of Study "* Methods of Investigation 5 Results of Preliminary Survey 7 Results of Detailed Study " Quality of Home-Produced, Laboratory, and Commercial Bread '" Savings From Home Production of Bread 19 Discussion of Results ** Summary " </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Comparative Costs of Home-Produced and Commercially Produced Bread and Rolls ; EDNA B. SNYDERI Department of Home Economics During the last century the character of household production 2 has undergone significant changes. There has been a gradual transfer of pro - duction, particularly of material goods, from the home to outside agencies. Continually greater emphasis is being placed upon activities involving management and marketing or the assembling of goods so that they are available at the time, in the place, and in the combinations desired. To state it another way, the problem of the homemaker is becoming one of selection of goods rather than one of expenditure of time and labor for their production. Various influences have operated to bring about this change. Some of the influences which have been particularly effective are improved transportation facilities; the trend in population from rural areas to cities; the removal of households from convenient sources of raw materials into multiple dwellings where supplies, space, and facilities for production are limited; increase in number and availability of commercial products; regular money income; decrease in size of families, which tends to reduce the economic need for home production; increase in transportation facilities with a resultant increase in trade; and convenient standardization of such commodities as food, clothing, and household furnishings. Doubtless, as long as families desire to live in independent households, certain forms of household production will continue, as a result of factors that limit the time or distance between production and consumption. Certain other kinds of production which can easily be delegated to out - side agencies will consistently furnish problems of choice to the homemaker as they involve consideration of such elements as comparative quality, time and labor required for production, availability of commercial goods, pressure on money income, desire for a greater amount of time for leisure activities, enjoyment or satisfaction in production, and the market value of her time. ¦ : If we assume that "a thing costs us what we must give up to obtain it," then the saving from household production or. the cost of the house - wife's labor must be compared to the salary or wage she could earn in a paid occupation. The percentage of women whose abilities or training fit them for professional work is small. Outside employment for married women is often out of the question, because of factors such as lack of available work, community attitudes, or home responsibilities which make 1 The writer wishes to acknowledge the assistance given by the Nebraska Agricultural Extension Service and by the women who cooperated.in this study. ¦': ' ' 1 "Household production" las used here is intended to conform to the definition given by Reid, Ecpnomics of Hotuehold Production: "those unpaid activities which arc carried on by and for the members of the household* whic^h activities might be replaced.by market goods or paid services if circumstances such as income, market conditions, and personal inclinations permit, the service being .delegated to someone outside the household group." . </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 115 such an arrangement impossible. In spite of the rather prevalent belief that the increased mechanization of housework has made it less interesting than formerly, outside work available to the untrained woman is likely to be highly mechanized and poorly paid. 3 It would appear that a con - siderable portion of the economic contribution of the housewife to the home must at present and for some time to come be made through the use of her own time to produce savings by means of production in the home. Furthermore, any additional values to family welfare which might result from household production would probably be lost if such activity were not economically sound. Clearly any form of household production is economically sound if no alternative activity can be found which pays as well. It therefore follows that in making a decision as to what to make, the housewife should have available information on those forms of pro - duction which yield the greatest savings. By a cost comparison, it is possible to confine production to processes where savings are greatest and to avoid those where little or none occur. It is recognized that the goals of household production differ from those of commercial agencies, since in the former emphasis is placed upon outgo or expenditure and in the latter upon income, that household pro - duction is affected by values other than economic, and that a homemaker is not paid in money. Because of these differences, any study of costs of household production is involved with difficulties, and conclusions may hi* open to question. PURPOSE OF STUDY At present there is little definite information available regarding actual costs of various kinds of household production. One of the most recent studies dealing with the costs of home-produced bread is that by Muse and Liston, 4 of the Vermont Agricultural Experiment Station. This study was undertaken for the purpose of gaining information regarding the possible economy of home production of whole-wheat 5 and white bread, including rolls. Bread is one of the commodities whose production is being gradually shifted to commercial agencies. From 1933 to 1935 the per-capita pro - duction of commercial bread, rolls, and coffee cake increased over 9 per cent and that of prepared flour 20 per cent. A 15 per cent increase has been estimated for the period between 1935 and 1937. Bread is the most widely used baked product, the ingredients are more nearly standardized than for other baked products available through commercial agencies, and it is one of the most convenient and economical sources of energy. In spite of its universal popularity, figures show that the per-capita consump - tion of wheat flour in the United States has steadily declined since the 1 from 18W n, 1910 gainful occupations anions married wniiicn increased from 4 per cent to 11.7 per .rut. Kyrk: Etoiwmtt Problem, u\ lite Family. 19,». • Mananna Mine anil Margaret 1.. I.iston. Rclatiie economy of household production and of pur - ,ha.es „f white bread. Vermont .\«r. K\|&gt;. Sta. Bui. 392. Vtii. •The irrm "whole wheal" is used here to include liotli whole wheal and graham in accordance with &#132; Federal regulation which makes the icrms interchangeable —the product to include all of the lonsiilucnls of the cleaned grain. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Costs of Bread and Rolls beginning of this century as a result of a decrease in the use of bread. However, since 1933 there has been a slight upturn which may be related to the "depression" years with the necessity of purchasing less expensive foods. There are no figures available at present to show just how much of the total consumption of flour should be charged to home-baked pro - ducts. According to the 1931 census over 105 million barrels of wheat flour were consumed in the United States. Of this, somewhat over 2 per cent Was used for macaroni and allied products and 34 per cent by bakeries having a yearly production value of $5,000 or over, leaving over 60 per cent to be distributed among small bakeries and other consumers of flour, a considerable, portion of which was undoubtedly used in in - dividual households. There are indications that home baking increased during the "depression" period. In some localities in Nebraska the sale of wholesale bread products declined, but the drop may have been due to an increased.use of chain-store products rather than to an increase in home production. Only direct costs lof household production, which include costs of ingredients, fuel, and time required, are considered in this investigation. There are no transportation costs. Obviously there are certain fixed over - head costs, as for space and equipment, but since these costs have already been incurred they may legitimately be ignored. The costs of home-pro - duced bread are therefore estimated in terms of cost of materials and fuel, plus the housewife's time. These costs are compared to retail prices of commercial products available for purchase, which include a summation of costs of such items as materials, fuel, wrappers, direct labor, shop expense, administration, promotion and distribution, and deterioration of product. If transportation of a commercial product from the source to the home involves expense, there is an additional cost which must be added to the retail price. In evaluating results, other factors such as availability, relative nutritive value, and physical qualities are considered. While our knowledge of the relation of palat ability to the utilization of food by the human body is limited, we do know that consumption is affected considerably by the former. Therefore bread cannot be com - pared on the basis of nutritive value or cost alone. ; METHODS OF INVESTIGATION The method used in this study was a combination of survey and lab - oratory study. A preliminary survey was made for the purpose of secur - ing information regarding the baking practices of women in the state, such information to be used as a guide for more detailed study. The areas of the state used for the survey were selected oh the basis of types of farming represented in the state " and should therefore be fairly represent - ative. They include both farm and town families. Through the assistance of agricultural extension workers, the information was secured by means ' _, F. Garcy, Systems of farming and possible alternatives in Nebraska, Nebr. Aer. Exp. Sta. Bui. 307. 1937. </seg>
         <seg id="p006">6 Table I.— Halting practices of Nebraska women. r ~ j Tv ... „7_71.T.1^.Tl Women who balii-tl - Women win, purchased bread £ Group and women whti liaKetl , . - £ number of — ; ~ Wli.de; Olice-cakc No. r - wotnen A" ' :lrt N"ru' White wheat anil rolls women All Part No answer ffl ;',-, Pa. I'.cr. l'.ii. P.ci. r.ri. /'.&lt;/• /'."¦ Pel. g C"_o ' 33.8 "0.6 5.6 91.7 .2.1 51.3 212 8.5 88.7 2.8 2 '™97 32.8 61.2 CO 93.4 -18.-1 7H.f, 3.H 9.0 H8.9 2.1 £) '™1T ,7.9 -17.6 -1.5 95.3 51.5 63.3 162 B.fi 90.2 1.2 g Group 4 ° ,„.,.-.," 172 ,0.1 55.8 &#132;1 95.8 56.4 81.8 lUJ 6.8 87.-1 3.8 PC For all groups ?gfi R5 88.8 2.7 &gt; „ ___ . ¦ ¦ ¦ — r. 1 Two bakings per week was llie predominant practice. ........ r „.i . n„-„,i. 3Scvcmy-fivc per cent of the women who halted all bread anil 60 per cent of those who baked part reported baking white bread .post frequently. Records were made before hot weather. Most women met! m.,rc than one kind of fuel, ami cobs and w«m«1 were predominant fuels u«cd. c * Northeast Nebraska. ¦— * Lancaster county and neighboring areas. tn 5 Southeastern counties. C2 " South-central counties. Z H— </seg>
         <seg id="p007">¦ Costs of Bread and Rolls of questionnaires and included such items as residence, tenancy, family composition, availability of commercial bread, and kinds of bread pro - duced at home or purchased. Following the preliminary survey, six counties were selected for de - tailed study, namely: Otoe and Cass in the eastern general farming area where records were kept during April, May, and June, 1935; Thayer in the southern grain and livestock area, where records were kept during March and April, 1935; Logan in the range livestock and Lincoln in the cash grain and livestock areas during May, June, July, and December, 1936, and January, 1937; and Dodge county in the eastern general farm - ing and meat production areas, during May and June, 1937. The women were called together in groups by the county home extension agents. The research worker presented the study, explained the forms on which records were to be kept, and instructed the women with regard to their use. The forms provided space for information on economic status of the home as Well as detailed records of the kind, amount, and costs of ingredients, the amount and cost of fuel, and the time required in making bread and rolls. If ingredients were produced at home, the cooperators were re - quested to record the price that would have been obtained if the product had been sold, in case there was a market. Suitable scales were provided for weighing the ingredients used in bread as well as the baked product. They were also asked to keep a two-weeks record of all bread purchased, includ - ing kind, cost, weight in wrapper, and actual weight. In order that a comparison of nutritive quality of bread from different sources could be made, information from commercial bakers was obtained as to the ingredients used in their products. The types of bakers chosen ranged from a high-class specialty shop to those producing low-priced bread. RESULTS OF PRELIMINARY SURVEY Information regarding the baking practices of the women who co - operated in the preliminary survey is shown in Table 1. A total of 1300 women reported. Of those reporting, 68 per cent lived on farms, and among these owners and renters were about evenly divided. Almost 95 per cent of the women who reported baked bread and 38 per cent baked all of the bread used. Almost twice as many women baked white bread as baked whole-wheat and in all groups the frequency of baking white bread exceeded that of other kinds. Two bakings of bread per week was the predominant practice in all the groups, and the most frequent reasons given.for baking were economy and superior quality. There was little relationship between baking practice and residence or tenancy. A some - what greater number of women who purchased all of the bread used lived in town and a greater number were also owners. Of the women who purchased bread, only 8.5 per cent purchased all of the bread used. Commercial bread was available from either groceries and bakeries or both and was purchased from both sources. Only a small percentage of women lived a distance greater than ten miles from the source of purchase. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 115 Most of the women used more than one kind of fuel. Corncobs and wood were used by 70 per cent of the women reporting. Coal and kero - sene were used more frequently than gasoline or gas and a negligible number used electricity. In general, the baking practices of Nebraska women in different farming areas were found to be similar. RESULTS OF DETAILED STUDY In general, there were similarities in residence, tenancy, and other back - ground factors between the preliminary group and the women who co - operated in the detailed study. Seventy per cent of the women reporting lived on farms but owners predominated over renters in all groups except Otoe county. The average size of household was 4.24 persons. Both bakeries and groceries were available sources of commercial bread and in Table I.—Baking practices of women who kept detailed records. dumber Women who baked Bread used per week Cminty nt women All Part Nunc Max. Min. Med. Av. P.cl. P.ct. Pet. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. !¦.,» 2ii 75.0 20.1) 5.0 20 3 7 8.6 11,1,1k, 7 71.4 2K.5 24 5 8 11.4 Lincoln „ &#132; , &#132;n&lt;l Legal. 27 ...'.'» 26.0 11.1 ii 4 10.5 11.6 Otoe H 64,3 28.5 7.1 15 2 7 8.1 Tluwr S (.2.5 37.5 20 4 9 11.3 All 76 67.1 26.3 6.5 ii 2 8 10.3 Sort- v.iic mule itwii.il trips to limn f,,r lirr.itl. The roads were dirt, gravel, and paving;. Nine »..men used ilin roads entirely. The distance Irntn sources where hrcad could Ik purchased ranged ilolll 1j Hi H links. .Sources of bread were bakeries and groceries. No si -mIK.Mi! se.i.on.il i.in.ilion in Inking [ir.lclicc was shown by the records. (her olj |.er icnt used col.s and wood. lo c e.hcr or separately, (or fuel, and 35 per cent purchased .ill or part of the fuel used. no case were special trips necessary for the purchase of bread. The family preference was predominantly in favor of home-made bread, as was the opinion regarding keeping quality. Economy and superior nutritive quality were again the predominant reasons given for making bread at home. There was no significant seasonal variation in baking practice. Only a small percentage lived a distance greater than ten miles from a source where bread could be purchased. Table 2 shows the baking practice of the women who kept detailed records. Here again, as was shown in the preliminary study, over 90 per cent of the women baked all or part of the bread used. The median weight of bread used per week was eight pounds and the average 1014 pounds. The weight ranged from 2 to 33 pounds. The ingredients used per pound of bread were tabulated. More women (73 per cent of those baking) used water than milk. Since milk is a farm product, a wide use of it as the liquid in bread might be expected. How - ever, the sale of cream is often an important source of farm income, and </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Costs of Bread and Rolls the skim milk is sometimes fed to animals. Lard was used exclusively as shortening except in a negligible number of cases where butter was used for rolls. In a few instances no shortening was recorded. About the same number of women used compressed yeast as used dry yeast. Frequently both kinds were used and a relatively small number used a "starter." 7 There was considerable variation in the proportions of ingredients used, even by the same woman in different bakings. In some bakings where milk was used, the amount of milk in proportion to flour was too small. Apparently some water was used which Was not recorded. Using the median quantities of ingredients, which is,generally close to the average, a typical formula for bread as made by Nebraska women was de - rived. 8 The formula is as follows: Ingredients per pound of bread ¦.Liquid % cup Flour : .% pound lard Vi tablespoon Sugar &amp; tablespoon Yeast 'A cake (dry or compressed) A small number of women made whole-wheat bread and none made whole-wheat entirely. The proportion of whole wheat to white flour in the bread formula varied considerably, the percentage of whole-wheat to total flour used ranging from 4 to 36. As would be expected there was a wide variation in the amount and kind of ingredients used in rolls. ! In Table 3 are shown, costs per pound of ingredients of homemade bread as shown by the records. The costs are grouped according to kind of bread and to the liquid used. Of the total number of bakings of loaf bread, only 10.9 per cent were of whole wheat. The cost of ingredients ° for loaf bread made with milk was greater than that with water but costs Were also affected by ingredients other than milk. The costs for whole - wheat bread varied only slightly from those of white bread, depending upon the percentage of whole-wheat flour used. The retail price per pound of whole-wheat is generally greater than that of white flour. The greatest savings per pound in home baking was in Thayer county, where no milk was used for loaf bread. In most cases "starter" was used in place of com - mercial yeast, and wheat was exchanged for flour—thus eliminating the processing tax then in force. . The chief factors affecting the cost per pound of bread were: cost of flour, the kind and proportion of yeast, and the kind of liquid used. The cost per pound of flour tended to be less when purchased in 48-pound bags, the predominant practice of all women who baked regularly but did not exchange wheat for flour. Variations in the kind and amount of such '"Starter" is a portion'of the sponge that is saved to Mart, the fermentation of the next baking of bread, . ..'',' •The median is used to avoid errors from extremely high or low values. •It waf not possible to determine Iron, the records whether the milk used was whole or skim milk. In some cases the'cost given was sufficiently high for .whole milk. In these cases the women lived in town. However, the top milk may have been removed, and that; remaining used in bread making. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Agrici-ltvral Experiment Station Research Bulletin 115 ingredients as fat, sugar, eggs, fruit, and nuts caused considerable variation in the cost per pound of rolls. The rolls listed in the table are those where specially prepared dough was used. Table 3.— Costs of ingredients (per pound 1) of home-produced bread to Nebraska women for all groups. White loaf Whole wheat loaf White rolls Milk Water Milk Water Milk Water Cis. Cis. Cts. Cis. Cts. Cts. Maximum 5.52 5.51) 6.40 5.60 11.20 18.02-10.0 Minimum LOU 2.011 3.52 2.-II) 3.60 3.8 Malun 4.5* 3.00 3.X') 3.4K 6.-I5 5.5 Aieuec H.46 3.22 4.45 3.44 6.74 6.17—5.63 1 Tout number of bakings: white loaf iviili milk. 2"; while loaf with water, 126; whole wheat loaf uitli milk. 7; whole wheat loaf with water. 12: white rolls with milk, 7; whole wheat rolls with milk. I, white roll, will, water. 211. 1 With raisnu. Table 4. — Cost of fuel per pound of home-produced bread to Nebraska women} Nutural £m (iasi.linc Kerosene Cobs Coal Electricity Cts. Cu. Cis. Cts. Cts. Cts. M.IMIIIUIII 1.25 .(,5 M 1.00 .&lt;JO 1.37 Minimum .s') .511 .111 .22 .29 Moli.m .7-1 .5S .IK M A'l . ... Au-rjisc .Hi .57 .20 .4H .52 1 (tier 70 per icnt of die women used the stove for other purposes than linking bread. Over 60 per .cm used ...Is. or wood, together or separately: .15 per cent purchased all or part of the fuel used. \,. ,la'., nire 1:11111 ..11 ....t of wood. Weigh! of baking, with natural gas ranged from 2.81 to 6.25 pound, c.oolinr. 1. 10 a pounds: 10.11. Ii to 7.1 pounds: cobs. 5.25 10 13.75 pounds; kerosene. 3.25 l„ |o |„„„„!,. In Table 4 is shown the fuel cost per pound of baking bread. The data included in the table are those from records where actual amounts and costs were given. Some of the women gave estimates of the cost of fuel. These were obviously erratic and were therefore discarded. Seventy per cent of the women reporting used the stove for other purposes than baking bread, such as cooking other foods and heating water. Where fuel is produced on the farm and used for purposes other than baking, the cost for baking bread is negligible. The maximum cost per pound for fuel was the cost for electric energy, and the other fuel costs were in descending order (median values) as follows: natural gas, gasoline, coal, corncobs, kerosene. Obviously the size of baking affected the cost per pound. Even </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Costs of Breao and Rolls ¦..;' when these figures can legitimately be charged to the baking of bread the costs given in the table should be considered only as indications. Variations in fuel rates, differences in the construction and operation procedures that affect efficiency of ovens, and the limited number of bakings studied must be taken into account. Table s.— Time used by Nebraska homema\ers in preparation and atten- :'-•'.'.• tion given to bread during bakjng. 1 . . County :'¦ Weight of bread Time per baking Time per pound Pounds Minutes Minutes Thayer. Maximum 10.75 '. 45.0 12.50 Minimum 2.80 15.0 1.80 Median 6.50 '25.0 3.45 Average- -J.54 28.7 5.22 Cass " . - :.'•'¦'••' Maximum 14.00 55.0 11.20 Minimum 3.25 14.0 '1.00 Median 6.50 35.0 4.75 Average ¦.';. 4.75; -.'..' 32.5' 5.00 OtOC .;'.' .. '¦'¦ Maximum 10.00 . 50.0 11.00 Minimum '," "2.80 20.0 2.50 Median ;:;: 7.38 30.0 3.70 Average : 4.68,...- 313.". . 5.31 Lincoln and .Logan '¦¦'.-. Maximum : '. .18.00 60.0 13.00 Minimum . 3.50 15.0 1.80 Median 6.00 34.5 4.45 Average 4.79/; "-34.5. 4.29 Dodge '-.'.'¦.:"- Maximum: 12.00 75.0 17.10 Minimum 3.50 .20.0 2.00 Median ':¦ 8.25..-- . 30.0 ' . 4.00 Average : ¦ 5.28 40.7 6.41 All counties Maximum 18.00 75.0 17.10 Minimum 2.80 14.0 1.00 Median 6.60; 31.0 .'. 4.50 Average ''¦¦¦.;¦¦ 476 . --;¦;, 33.3 5.40 "For bakings between six and seven pounds, the predominant .weight of baking,, the time per pound ranged from _ to 10 minute, with a median of 5.5 minutes. Table 5 shows the time cost of making bread in Nebraska homes. AH of the bread was mixed by hand. The median and average weights of bread per baking were similar, or between six and seven pounds. The median time used per baking for all groups in preparation of bread was 31 minutes and the average 333 minutes. The median time per pound of. bread for all groups was 4.5 minutes and the average 5.4 minutes. Ob - viously the time used per pound was less for large bakings. The time used </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 115 in making bread as recorded might appear to be unreasonably low. How - ever, the women were asked to record only the time used in handling or caring for the bread. The time used for clearing up and washing utensils is difficult to determine since they are frequendy cared for along with other utensils used in food preparation. According to these figures (using the median which is close to the average time per baking) the time per week for household production of bread would be somewhat over an hour for two bakings per week, the predominant practice of the women cooperating. On the basis of six- to seven-pound bakings (the median and average weights per baking) the time per pound ranged from 2.3 minutes to 10 minutes with a median of 5.5. The time for two seven-pound bakings would be 1.28 hours per week, based on the latter rate. Table 6.—Weights and costs of bread purchased by homema\ers during a two-week period. Weight per loaf Cost per pound White Whole wheat White Whole wheat Oz. Oz. Cts. Cts. Maximum 32.00 32.00 10.60 10.00 Minimum 15.00 16.00 5.00 5.00 Median 17.00 24.00 8.90 6.60 Avcrajsc 1«.47 21.50 8.82 7.55 Table 6 shows the number and weights of loaves and the costs per pound of bread purchased during a two-week period by the women co - operating. There was considerable variation in the weights of loaves pur - chased. 10 The lowest-priced bread was obtained from chain stores where the distribution cost might reasonably be expected to be less than that of other bread bought at retail, since the wholesaler and retailer are the same and the bread is delivered in large lots directly to the individual retail stores. Other factors such as quality and kind of ingredients may, however, enter into costs. The maximum cost of white bread was 10.6 cents per pound and the median 8.9 cents. White bread was somewhat more ex - pensive on the basis of weight than was whole-wheat, but the cost per loaf was higher for the latter. Most of the bread was purchased from grocers rather than from bakeries. Only five women purchased rolls and the cost ranged from 10 to 30 cents per pound for fancy pecan rolls. Wider variation occurred in the cost of rolls than for loaf bread, as was also the case for rolls made in the home. The laboratory investigation included the preparation and baking of bread with various fuels by a standardized procedure which was adapt - able to home use. The stoves included used gas, electricity, gasoline, and 10 The Nebraska law requires lha! the Height in pounds or fractions o( a pound of commercial 10-ncs of bfead be not less than '/;. 1. l'i. or exact multiples of one pound. </seg>
         <seg id="p013">•¦' Costs oe Bread and Rolls kerosene. The gasoline stove was of the pressure type and the kerosene of the long-chimney type. All were of recent construction and recognized makes. The gas, electric, and gasoline ovens were insulated, the two former having thermostatic control. A household oven thermometer was used in the gasoline and kerosene ovens to check temperatures. The capacity of the ovens was similar. The electric oven had upper and lower units of 1500 watts each with a baffle over the lower unit and was operated with the vent open. The. gas used was natural gas having a heating value of approximately 1000 B.t.u. per cubic foot. The gas volume was measured by a 10-light wet test meter. The electric energy was measured by a type HC Sangamo watt-hour meter. The gasoline used in baking was measured by detaching and weighing the fuel tank before and after each baking. The pressure in the tank was kept constant for each weighing. A torsion balance was used for weighing—with weights to 1/16 ounce. The kerosene was measured as follows: the tank was removed and a mark was established in the pan which supports the tank and from which oil flows to the burners. At the beginning of each baking the pan was filled to the matk. At the end of the baking period it was again filled to the mark from a weighed container. The weight of the oil required to fill the pan to the mark at the end of the baking was equivalent to that used for baking. Preliminary to the laboratory investigation a formula and method were developed for making bread. The objectives of the preliminary work were the development of a formula and method which-would (1) produce -bread of desirable characteristics, (2) which could be repeated with comparable results in the laboratory, and which (3) was adaptable to house - hold use. Flour from different sources was used in the preliminary work, including that from several Nebraska mills and one nationally advertised product. Dry and compressed yeast, sweet and sour milk, buttermilk, and water were used for liquid.. Proportions of fat, sugar, and yeast were varied, as well as methods of manipulation. For the whole-wheat bread, various proportions of whole wheat to white flour were tried, as well as differences in manipulation of ingredients. Some differences in the quality of the baked bread resulted from the variations in ingredients, but since the study is primarily a cost study, a discussion of differences will be omitted except to note the method of combining ingredients for whole-wheat bread. With the whole-Wheat flour used in this investigation it was found that when the "sponge" was made with the whole wheat and the white flour added to make a stiff dough, a more desirable product resulted than when the "conventional" procedure was used, /. e., a sponge with white flour and whole wheat added to make a stiff dough. As a result of the preliminary work the following ingredients and method of mixing were adopted for use in the laboratory. 11: The formula and method present no significant departures from other basic formulas for bread made with general-purpose flour. The white flour used was a general-purpose flour, purchased from a Nebraska mill in barrel lots and was stored at low (45° F.) temperature to prevent changes in flour char- </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Aghh.ilti ral Experiment Station Research Bulletin 115 .ictcristics. The whole-wheat flour was from the same mill and was a finely ground product. The fat used was an open-kettle-rendered lard pur - chased in rive-pound lots and stored in an automatic refrigerator. Lard was chosen because it is one of Nebraska's important products, gave good results, and was the fat used by the women who cooperated. Furthermore, its use at least in part was reported by commercial bakers who gave in - formation in Nebraska. Compressed yeast was used because of con - venience and uniformity. Other ingredients were purchased from a local grocer. While bread made with water is less nutritious and differs some - what in physical quality from that made with milk, it is desirable in quality, convenient, and economical and results were easy to reproduce. Water was therefore used as the liquid in the tests to obtain fuel costs of baking. The following formula per loaf of bread was adopted for use in the laboratory: lor while hull bread: Fur whole wheat bread: H tiunio sifted Hour (approximately) K ounces whole wheat (lour s ounces liiiuid'- 6 ounces white flour '.- ounce l.inl .'-¦ cake compressed yeast . ounce sui^ar 1 * ounce sail ' i c.ikc compressed yeast '. nunci lard for pans The water was boiled and the lard, salt, and sugar added to the hot liquid. The temperatures of ingredients were kept between 80° and 85°F. When cooled to the desired temperature, the yeast was crumbled and added. When the yeast was well mixed, one-third of the flour was added and the batter beaten until smooth, with a wooden spoon. The "sponge" was allowed to stand for one hour in a covered container in the proofing uven. I:l As much of the remaining flour was added as could be manipulated with a spoon. The mixture was then turned onto a board, the remainder o, the flour added and the dough kneaded by hand until smooth and elastic. The entire time required for the process of mixing was about 10 minutes. The dough was placed in a lightly greased covered container and allowed to rise in the proofing oven until a dent from pressure re - mained m the dough, or about one hour. Following this, the dough was gently kneaded on the board and shaped into a loaf slightly rounded on top and placed in a greased pan 9Ya inches by 5% inches at the top, 4 inches by 8 inches at the bottom, and s'/s inches deep. The pan gave ample room for the dough to expand. It was placed in the proofing oven where it was allowed to rise until the volume had doubled, or about one hour. The "dent" test was used here also. For whole-wheat bread the same procedure was used; the sponge was made with the whole-wheat " Cans of mi. aluminum, and glass of the same capacity were used, fliffcrcnccs in fuel costs or ¦iualuy were not treat enough in be of significance. The liakcil loaf weighed approximately one and ..nc fourth &#132;o„n,i*. 11 When nillti was used as liquid the weight of liquid was kept constant and the amount of flour h.i. decreased slicdilly to compensate for ihe solids in milk. "rroolme. was done in an insulated oven which would maintain the required temperature ranee. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Costs of Bread and Rolls /lour and the dough was made stiff with the white. One-loaf, two-loaf, and six-loaf bakings were made. For two loaves the formula was doubled, for six loaves it was multiplied by six. The bread was baked for 45 minutes in a preheated oven at temperatures which were found correct for different ovens. Since the electric oven was pre-heated with the top unit "on", thus storing considerable heat in the unit, the thermostat was set at 400° F. in this oven. In the gas ovens the thermostat was set at 450°F. For one and two loaves it was necessary to reset at 350 °F. after the first 15 minutes. A household thermometer was used in the gasoline and kerosene ovens and the heat controlled by Table 7.—Costs per pound of loaf bread as affected by liquid used (full ¦ : costs not included). . Bottled: Bottled Bulk Powdered Kind of bread '; Water whole skim skim skim milk milk milk milk Cts. Cts. Cts. Cts. Cts. White 3.83 5.48 4.50: 4.20 4.28 Wholewheat 4.87 6.52 5.52 5.22 5.32 1 Whole milk is figured at 9. cents per quart, skim milk (bottled) :al -1 cents per quart, skim milk , (hulk) at 10 cents per gallon, powdered skim milk at 15 cents per pound. regulation of the flame as determined by' preliminary tests. It was at - tempted to keep the temperature as near 400°F. as possible in these ovens. For the one- and two-loaf bakings the pans were placed on a rack in the center of the oven. For the loaded oven, two racks were used, with three loaves on each rack. The pans were placed so that loaves on the upper rack were not directly over those on the lower. Since rolls, both home-produced and commercially produced, vary widely in ingredients, it is difficult to select formulas which are representa - tive; Two formulas, one for rich rolls with butter as the fat, and cinnamon rolls, which are frequently made by homemakers, were used to determine costs in the laboratory. Milk was used in both. These rolls would be con - sidered expensive and their use in this study is not intended to imply recommendation for the housewife who is carefully budgeting her income. They do, however, represent a type of roll which would retail at a re - latively high price by specialty bakers. Furthermore, it seemed possible that such rolls might be produced at home at a cost less or no greater than ordinary commercial rolls. In Table 7 are shown the costs per pound of ingredients of loaf bread made in the laboratory as affected by the liquid used. The costs are com - puted on the basis of the average weights of bread when baked. The kind and proportion of yeast used is an important item in costs. The use of compressed yeast results in a slightly higher cost per pound than would be the case if dry yeast were used. It should be recalled, however, that compressed yeast was used by as many homemakers as was dry yeast. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">16 Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 115 M *_ C — IV) X X « 1/1 r^o g S O«^ In. vO r- —- —• g j ¦ C U j cirir cT\m J^.*. jj g 5 rNl^ff' T t*t (No *^ i «7i .' _ r^ t rr\ rr\ (-1 _: O ~ d c .^ at oo cc — » ac w ?_: r^'O po' vo tn'o t__&gt; **; i _ z _¦. a . r I\_ -t o \_ - S I - *3 — "*! — l&gt;: T Is **¦¦». i_ *j -r Tin in —«" o 5 &gt;s|! ~ = *, ;: "S ii - _~s C nj m m mo "^ F *L_L y "" ' ' a 8 i -. &gt; i e vlscccac — x- es -J ¦51 j?:g Oee;^.^ "* 2 2 I c I "i. *t I "7= STiri OC7\ OM . — ;^— e-.^: in ~ eo„ § £ tj-r-r-r in" — o£ -S 's *-. ¦5 -S-2 0 1 i ¦/, r^ —ts aacv o m"n -&gt;. i ~ »- — -r « rooi en M ej 5 a u it is \ '- f - 9 ~ 2 . i .'. w reirfl^l ntO O3 !J s5 5 £ J: =°.°°- =c- ~ * 2"« tj. rj re, ro "1 m O 0= — S "• r: S S ¦ _ So 0 =.S V 2 .• «in"i 2 ~ !; .si « £ ~l ac m =2 =o ~S i. -Z U -f -r 1 in vo— _ 1 CT\ -* — •; -3 u *g Jl v ft 5 1 _ g = = « - hi jg 0 ,r- =¦ *¦ 5 _S a W"- „ t L ~ . -o -*1 "1 nt c 2 *Ss | £e &lt;j xatx -; x 2 ." I £f-.i ro ro r*i W"» -; — .= in ¦ 8 St I - * \ -z r- |^ .s § i . i ~S "315"3 u "g ~ S„ s| 1 £icn- j:n - c». • 2 Ii 15 &lt;2 0 3 </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Costs of Breao and Rolls The costs.per pound computed on the basis of Lincoln prices vary with the form of milk used—that made with bottled whole milk being greatest and that with skim milk purchased by the gallon being least. The cost of bread made with powdered milk at the rate of three tablespoons of powdered milk per cup of liquid is similar to that made with bulk skim milk. Since commercial bakers use the dry milk and since it is economical and convenient, the home baker might wish to consider the possibility of utilizing dried milk as a source of milk nutrients in bread. The use of bottled whole milk for making bread in the home is expensive. Other less expensive forms of milk provide a large portion of the nutritive factors in milk at a lower cost; If sufficient milk is otherwise allowed in the diet, bread made with water is satisfactory from an energy standpoint and is also palatable. Table B.— lngredients and costs per pound of white loaf bread made by the homemakers' formula and the laboratory formula. Flour Liquid' Lard. Sugar Yeast Fat for Salt Cost per pans pound . Water Milk Nebraska: Oz. Oz. . Oz. Oz. Cake . Oz. Oz. Ct.s Cu homemakers 12 '¦ ''. 7 .0.25 0.25 V» ;¦•'.'.. 0.2 3.64 4.97. Laboratory 11.2 6.4 0.40 0.40 -J- 0.3 0.2 3.83 4.20 ¦ ¦ ''''.' - -'¦ .•• to .¦-..-: ¦. .- _ ": : '-;- ¦; ;. ; :;.-.¦: ; ; ¦ ..- •... -' 5.48 It will be observed that the cost per pound of ingredients in bread baked in the laboratory differs from that of the women cooperating (Table 3). The difference is partly due to slight variations in amounts and costs of ingredients in Lincoln. The laboratory cost of whole-wheat bread is some-, what higher than of white, as was true for the women cooperating, again because of the higher retail price per pound of whole-wheat flour. A comparison of the formula derived from the amounts of ingredients used.by Nebraska women with the laboratory formula and costs is shown in Table 8. A comparison of the costs shows that they are similar to each other and to the actual costs as reported in Table 3. (The median is 3 cents and the average 3.22 cents per pound with water and the median is 458 cents per pound with milk). The median cost b£ milk to home - makers was used in computing that of homemaker's bread, while the range for laboratory bread is from that made with bulk skim milk to that made from bottled whole milk. In Table 9 is shown the cost of laboratory bread and rolls per pound as influenced by fuel. The basic cost of ingredients is used in this table for loaf bread. Fuel costs are computed on the basis of rates in Lincoln where gas and electric rates are relatively low. The figures for gas stoves are averages of several stoves used. The figures for kerosene stoves are averages of two stoves. The fuel cost was highest for electric energy and least for natural gas. Where kerosene and gasoline are purchased in large </seg>
         <seg id="p018">.\&lt;;RII7I LTIRAL ExPERIMI-.NT STATION RIiSEAROII BULLETIN 115 lots, as is the practice in many rural homes, the cost would be lower than shown in the table. Likewise rates for natural gas and electric energy vary and in most localities are higher than in Lincoln. The fuel cost of baking one loaf of bread is high as compared with the cost when the oven is used to full capacity and is obviously a wasteful practice if fuel tost is an important item in the budget. QUALITY OF HOME-PRODUCED, LABORATORY, AND COMMERCIAL BREAD Since factors other than time and money cost are important, the nutritive value and physical qualities of bread from various sources must lie considered. Inasmuch as bread is regarded primarily as an energy food, a comparison of bread from different sources may be made on the basis of calories furnished. The formula used by Nebraska households is some - what less rich in sugar and fat than is the laboratory formula, but the amount of flour is somewhat greater so that any difference in energy value is probably negligible. Any difference in the energy value of breads made with milk and water is also probably negligible. However, there are nutritive advantages from the use of milk which should be taken into ac - count. The quality of the protein, the minerals, and the vitamins con - tributed from milk justify its use where there is not sufficient milk in the diet otherwise. It will be recalled that over 73 per cent of the women cooperating in the study used water as the liquid in bread. Many women believe that home-produced bread is superior in nutri - tive value to commercially produced bread. Information in regard to in - gredients from commercial bakers in the state was used as a basis for comparing nutritive quality. It would be impossible to list formulas used by the commercial baker. However, there are certain differences in in - gredients which affect quality and nutritive value. In contrast to the bread made in the home, formulas used by the commercial baker include various yeast "foods." Except in the very "high class" products, powdered skim milk or water is used instead of whole milk. The commercial baker generally uses a "stronger" flour, or one richer in gluten-forming pro - teins than the general-purpose flour used by the housewife. This is necessary because of the more severe mechanical treatment given to the commercial bread. Although various fats are used, the use of lard, at least in part, was reported by all bakers in Nebraska who gave information. Corn sugar is frequently used instead of cane or beet sugar because of certain properties which are of importance to the baker. Some of the small, specialty bakeries use only the "highest grade" products—/.e., whole milk, butter, and fresh eggs, especially for the fancy rolls. Whole-wheat bread is likely to contain, in addition to yeast "foods," coloring and molasses. Commercial products made with milk are superior in nutritive value to home-made bread made with water. On the whole there is ap - parendy little justification for the belief that commercial bread in general is less nutritious than bread produced at home. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">¦'¦•'¦ i". Costs of Bread and Rolls It is probable that physical qualities of bread affect consumption to a greater degree than does nutritive value. Since individuals differ widely in preference^ as a result of habit, custom, and other factors, a measure - ment of quality of bread is difficult and considered by some to be without value. There are, however, standards which are fairly well defined and which may be used to compare quality— such factors as appearance and palatability, the latter having recently been defined as odor, taste, and "mouth-feel." j Because of various difficulties no attempt, to score all of the bread j baked in the laboratory was made; Some scoring was done, however, for the purpose of determining whether there was agreement among the judges as to quality. The judges chosen were from the Foods and Nutri - tion faculty and graduate students. The score card used was that devised by the American Institute of Baking. The judges were asked to score and to state a personal perference for breads baked in the laboratory from the flours used in the preliminary investigation. Results showed wide varia - tion in the scores for the same bread, in one case' ranging from 77 to 94. There was only 50 per cent agreement between scores and preference. The judges also scored bread from different sources, including home - makers' bread, laboratory bread, and bread from various commercial sources, ranging from an inexpensive bread to that' from a high-class bakery. Here again there was little agreement in total scores of different judges, and none in preference and total scores. One judge scored the laboratory bread highest; another gave an equal score to that of the lab - oratory and a commercial baker. In one instance the lowest score was given to the laboratory bread, in another to a homemaker's, and in still another to a chain-store product. In one instance the laboratory bread was given first preference and in another a homemaker's. The results of these scores indicate the difficulty in evaluating individual scores of bread quality. &gt;: •' ,'. However, lit must be considered that all of the bread scored was ac - ceptable in quality. The homemakers who contributed samples were care - ful, experienced bread makers. Moreover, bread from such sources is likely to he-identified by experienced judges even though all bread to be scored is unwrapped. Scoring may possibly be influenced by such know - ledge. Home-produced bread, otherwise of good quality, is frequendy scored low because of poorly shaped loaves. The age of the bread is a factor which affects flavor to a considerable degree. SAVINGS i_OM HOME I«ODUCnON OF BREAD The savings irom home production of white loaf bread are shown in Figures 1 and 2. Figure 1 shows the savings to Nebraska women from home production of Aoaf bread. The cost of bread available in local stores is used for comparison. The figure shows the cost of ingredients and total costs as affected by different fuels; the costs reported by the women (Table 4) and costs as calculated from the derived formula are used. In Figure 2 is shown the possible saving, as obtained from laboratory bakings, with different </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 115 liquids and fuels. Comparison is made with average costs at Omaha as reported in Consumer's Guide—l93s-1936. A glance at both figures shows the economy in home-produced bread. Even with bottled whole milk and electric energy representing the maximum cost for bread baked in the laboratory, the savings are considerable. CENTS PER. POUND I TL S A 5 6 *7 6 MEDIAN COST COMMERCIAL BREAD ¦¦ ¦¦ ¦¦ ¦¦ ¦¦ ¦¦ ¦¦ ¦¦ ¦¦ WATER BREAD -NEBQASKA FORMULA IMGREDIEWTS ONLY WITH ELECTRICtTY. PBB^B^—|—^Bj v NATURAL GAS )BBjBB^BB^Bfi » GASOLINE ¦¦¦BBIBB^BBJ " COBs"AND"wooD!...~V.7.^^^^^^^sr MILK BREAD -NEBRASKA FORMULA I I [ I INGREDIENTS ONLY PBj—iP—^B^—l WITH ELECTRICITY. PB^Bjßßl|—P—|— ¦ || NATURAL GAS IBIB^BBHBMBMBHBi • COM &lt; CDeS AND \NOOO. jIBBtaB^B^B^BJ WATER BREAD ¦ ACTUAL RECORDS 1111 INGREDIENTS ONLY. &gt;—|BBBMB4 WITH ELECTRICITY ¦¦M^BH ¦ coai ibbl^bb^bbS^ » GOBS AND wboDi"'"--taß^B^B^i MILK BBEAD-AT7WU. RECORDS I I 1 I INGREDIENTS OWLY- pBB|BB^B^B^Bi . WITH ELECTRIOTY- ...^¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦l 881 &gt; MATURAL GAS .aBMBMBMB^BBI ¦ a COAI ii COBS AUD WOOD t—^^^H^i^^^Hl » kEOOSEUE piHIHIHHBi Fie. 1. —Savings that result from home baking. The cost of commercial bread is compared wiih the cost of ingredients for home-produced white bread, and with costs of ingredients and various fuels. The savings from home production of whole-wheat bread as made in the laboratory are somewhat less than for white bread when compared with the Omaha average of 8.8 cents per pound, but there is a definite saving. The cost of rolls was between 10 and 12 cents per pound as com - pared with a range of 10 to 29 cents per pound for those purchased by the women. It should be kept in mind that the rolls made in the laD - oratory were of a fancy type, while those purchased ranged from plain to fancy rolls, including those made with nuts. </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Costs of Bread and Rolls In calculating the earnings of the women from home production of bread, it would seem logical to make comparisons as nearly as possible on the basis of nutritive value. Since information from commercial bakers specifies powdered milk at least in part of the bread produced, a fair comparison should be that made between bread from different sources C_t6 PER POUND I tt 3 A 5 6 7 ? OMAHA RITAU PRICE -___!__ _¦__!__! _¦¦_¦—¦ ¦ - - j . -. :v' ' - • . - - WHOLE MILK BREAD WITH E—CTR1dTY........... _¦ Bs_ 881 Hflß 881 BU ¦ GAS _-—.__!¦_!__¦¦¦¦¦¦ « GASOUNE ——I ¦_! I—B I—B ¦—I BB '«.' KEROSENE—........ _¦_¦_¦____! _i SKIM-MILK (Borneo) BREAD wrm ELECrmaTY. .... MB _¦¦_,_¦! 881 • GAS- .... ¦—I ¦¦ l—B _¦I ¦i • GASOLINE __l ¦_ ¦¦ l—B _1 • KEIW_NE ..-.. _¦ ___¦¦¦ ¦i ft_t«_) SMM-MILK BAEAD WITH aECTR1CTfY...........88i881«8i88881 • GAS -_¦__¦_!__¦ • -tSOLJME. I—B __¦___¦ » KER05ENE.......... s_B BBi sBB 881 ¦ SKIM-MILKVi?_A-y BREAD wrm EUCTBicrrv.—.—-¦¦__ _¦__¦¦ '.«. GAS - .'____„_¦ SSS—I—B 881 B .¦¦»• GASOLINE.. I_B _¦___¦ ¦ •KEROSENE.. . _¦_¦_¦ sss_ B WATER BREAD \wrm euECTßicrry fli BBi i_b ¦¦ ¦ "GAS.... .... 188 881 188 881 iSA_LINE._ _..___i__l__l__ll.:.' « KEROSENE ...... __1881188 ¦¦ \ hiiiii I 11 1 I Fig. 2.—_osts of baking with various fuels as determined in a laboratory—comr pared with Omaha retail price of white, bread. ..-.' made with milk. If the calculated cost of home-produced white milk bread made with the Nebraska homemakers' formula—4.97 cents per pound for ingredients plus the cost of cobs (0.38 cent per pound)—is com - pared with the cost of commercial bread available to her, she would earn the difference between 8.9 cents and 5.35 cents or 3.55 cents per pound by making her own bread. If one assumes that the typical baking is seven pounds and that bread is baked twice a week, the savings per week would be almost 50 cents and for a year would amount to $26.00. If the fuel is provided at home, or the stove used for other purposes than baking, thus making the cost of fuel negligible, the savings per pound would be </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Acßici'LTt'RAL Experiment Station Research Bulletin 115 ,9i cents per pound or $28.61 per year. If 5.5 minutes per pound is u.-quircd lo make bread in seven-pound bakings, 77 minutes per week would be required or nearly 67 hours per year. The housewife would then Ix earning 38.8 cents per hour. If bread making required 10 minutes per pound, which was the maximum time per pound for bakings between six and seven pounds, her earnings would be between 21 and 22 cents per hour. DISCUSSION OF RESULTS The results of this study show definitely that home production of bread and rolls is an economical practice. Bread and rolls having high nutritive quality can be made at home more cheaply than similar products iin lie purchased. The earnings computed on an hourly basis are probably as great as many women could earn either by other forms of household production or from employment outside the home. These results are in close agreement with those reported from Vermont by Muse and Liston (page 4), which showed a savings of 3.5 cents per pound for bread made with part milk and part water. The cost of purchased bread to Vermont women was slightly less (7.8 cents per pound) than that reported by women in Nebraska, as was the cost of home-produced bread (cost to Vermont women was 4J cents per pound). The time used per pound in Vermont was 6J minutes for 7.7-pound bakings, while that in Ne - braska was 5.5 minutes per pound for bakings between six and seven pounds. Vermont women earned 33 cents per hour for baking bread at home, while Nebraska women earned 38.8 cents when figured on the basis of the median time per pound and 21 to 22 cents if the maximum time per pound is used for six- to seven-pound bakings. The belief that home-made bread is more nutritious than commercial bread would seem to be generally without foundation. The amount of moisture in bread is a factor in determining the total nutritive value. No chemical analyses of bread or moisture determinations were made in this study. The Vermont study showed that the percentage of moisture in household bread was higher than in commercial bread. The factor of payability as it affects consumption of bread probably outweighs that of nutritive value. While Nebraska homemakers state a preference for home-produced bread, the preference may be a result of habit and custom. It is impossible to determine whether the amount of bread consumed in a family would be greater or less if all bread were purchased. While there is economy in producing bread at home, the total savings in many families would not warrant making it at home. Where the amount of bread used is large, where more productive work is impossible, and where the savings are vital to the family budget, there is justification lor the production of bread in the home. </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Costs of Bread and Rolls '.' SUMMARY ¦"¦- The purpose of this study was to determine the comparative costs of home-produced and commercially produced white and whole-wheat bread and rolls. Costs of home-produced bread were estimated on the basis of cost of ingredients and fuel, plus time. These costs were compared to costs of commercially prepared bread available at retail. Nutritive value was considered in interpreting results. The method used was a combination of survey and laboratoty in - vestigation. The survey included: (1) information regarding the baking practice of families in Nebraska, (2) detailed records of amounts and costs of ingredients, fuels, and time used in home-produced bread, (3) records of kinds, amounts, and costs of bread purchased over a two-weeks period, and (4) information from commercial bakers as to ingredients used in bread. The laboratory, investigation included the baking of bread by a standard - ized formula with ovens heated by electric energy, natural gas, kerosene, and gasoline, and with records of amounts and costs of ingredients and ¦fuel. ¦';';¦ - '."v¦'..'.; ;'. •;. '-'"'. Results of the study show the following: 1. Over 90 per cent of the women cooperating baked all or part of the bread used in the home. White bread was baked more frequently and in considerably greater amounts than was whole wheat. 2. The. most frequently listed reasons for home baking were economy and superior quality. The expressed family preference was predominantly in favor of home-produced bread. . 3. Approximately 70 per cent of the women cooperating used corn - cobs and wood together or separately as fuel and 35 per cent purchased all or part of the fuel. Seventy-one per cent used the stove for other pur - poses when baking bread. . 4. With the ovens used in the laboratoty, costs of fuel varied in the following descending order: electric energy, gasoline, kerosene, natural gas. Fuel costs to the women cooperating varied as follows: electric energy, natural gas, gasoline, coal, corncobs, kerosene. &gt; \ 5. The total costs of home-produced bread per pound varied with the cost per pound of flour, proportion and kind of yeast used, kind of liquid, ix. milk or water, and with the fuel used. Seventy-three per cent of the women reporting used water as liquid. 6. The savings to Nebraska homemakers from the home production of white loaf bread as calculated from the derived formula ranged from 2.56 to 5.26 cents per pound, depending upon the kind of liquid and fuel used. From actual records the savings ranged from 2.95 to 5.9 cents per pound. Bread baked in the laboratory showed possible savings ranging from 2.48 cents per pound to 4.47 cents, depending upon the kind of liquid and fuel used. Similar savings resulted from home production of whole-wheat bread but were somewhat less. Costs of ingredients.of white rolls made by cooperators ranged from 3.6 cents to 18 cents per pound. The </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bulletin 115 total cost of fancy rolls made in the laboratory did not exceed 11.8 cents per pound and ranged from 10.27 to 11.8 cents. Costs of those purchased bv homemakers ranged from 10 to 29 cents per pound. 7. The Nebraska homemaker's time is worth from 22 to 38.9 cents per hour for making bread, depending upon time required. 8. Information from commercial bakers regarding ingredients used in their bread products shows that they are not inferior in nutritive quality to home-produced bread and are frequently superior. 9. Household production of bread appears to be a sound practice in the economic sense. Economic necessity, market value of the time of the homemaker, family preference, availably of commercial products are factors in considering home-produced vs. commercial bread. |2'/,M| </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>