<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00027">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00027</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  ORGANIZATION OF NEBRASKA BOYS' AND GIRLS' CLUBS</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Extension Bulletin No. 10 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, Nebraska, U. S. A. ORGANIZATION OF NEBRASKA BOYS' AND GIRLS' CLUBS Kfhe Boys' and Girls' Club Work in Nebraska is conduclc' he University of Nebraska in cooperation with the United es Department of Agriculture. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION C. \V. Pl'GSLEY, Superintendent. DiatrilmttHl February M, 101:5. By Hildah Petkrson </seg>
            <seg id="p002">a 1 Alfalfa Management. I Cost of Growing Crops in Nebraska Testing Seed Corn. I Cooking and Sowing (Boys' and Girls' Clubs). Part I. — Judging Horses and Cattle (Boys' and Girl* Clubs). Part II.— Corn I Part III.— The Home Garden. Spraying Apple Trees. Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. I Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm. The Selection and Care of Seed Corn 10. Organization of Nebraska Boyi' and Girls" Club Ehe above bulletins will be sent free to residents of Nebraska request to College of Agriculture or NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">NEBRASKA BUYS' AND GIRLS' CLUBS Klhe purpose of the Nebraska Boys' and (iirls' Clul&gt; i* to rest boys and girls in the study of agriculture and domestic nee and thus help them in their preparation for life's work. I The Clubs had their beginning in the year of 1905. The rk at that time was undertaken by the State Department Public Instruction. In 1912 State Superintendent James E. Izell transferred the Club work to the Department of Agri - tural Extension, of the University of Nebraska. I Club members who have taken an active part in the work e found it not only very helpful but a pleasure. Boys and Is desire a part in some definite work. The club work gives m this privilege and if rightly undertaken it will result in cation, profit and pleasure. I We want wide awake and energetic boys and girls to become ■nbers of the Nebraska Boys' and Girls' Clubs. It is only industrious boy or girl who will take up the work, stick it, and make it a success. SUGGESTIONS FOR ORGANIZING CLUBS Local Club. There shall he no fixed geographical limit for the local club. It may consist of one or more school districts or of only parts of districts. The township is often a convenient unit for organization. Any community where boys and girls can con - veniently get together for club meetings may determine the territory of the local club. K teacher or any interested person appointed by the County rintendent or State Leader may act as local leader of the IK local leader shall call a meeting of the boys and girls for purpose of organizing a local club. The constitution the club with a general plan of the work should be presented le boys and girls at this meeting. Enrollment blanks should l be distributed and filled out by those who wish to become ibers. These blanks may be secured by writing to Depart- By lluldah Peterson. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">I Nebraska. E'he club may consist of any number of boys or girls between nd 21 years of age, but the best results are secured with 1 ten to twenty members in the girls' club and the same her in the boys' club. ■Each club should elect three officers, president, vice pres nt and secretarv-treasurer. the clubs should also decide work they will take up for the . The girls' club may take up successfully two courses, the boys' club would meet with better results in adhering ne line of work for the year. ("he names of the members and a list of the officers should eat to Assistant in Charge of Hoys' and Girls' Club Work, artment of Agricultural Extension, University Farm, l.in - , Nebraska, and a list should also be sent to the County erintendent. A lesson for each month will then be sent tc club member and suggestion for meetings to local leaders. I It shall be the duty of the local leader, or an assistant lointed by this leader, to be present at all local meetings both the boys' club and the girls' club. The leader shall 11 excursions, aid in the programs, and assist the members every way possible. I The leader should be a student with the club members and i:i interest of the club should seek the advice and cooperation practical farmers and home-makers in the community. Each club should meet at least one a month and oftener if possible. The local leader should at these meetings review with club members the lesson at hand for the month and should see that members make proper reports. ■ These meetings may be held at a school house or other cen I point, or the club may meet at the home? of its members. I The local leader should arrange for joii : meetings of the ,s' Club and the Girls' Club. These meetings should be 1 at least four times during the year. They should consist two parts, program and social. One meeting in the fall uld constitute the Local Club Contest and one meeting ing the summer may be a club picnic. Parents may take pan hese programs- Many special lines of the work will be - 111^ - ted from time to time by the state and county leaders. COUNTY CLUB. BThe county club shall consist of all local club members in county. Boys and girls between ten and twenty-one years </seg>
            <seg id="p005">of age living where there are no local clubs may be enrolled in the county club. The County Superintendent shall act as County Leader. j — L _ — — j The county organization shall have a president, vice pres - t and secretary-treasurer. These officers shall be elected le annual meeting of the county club. Ehis club shall have at least one meeting each year consisting contest and business meeting. The county leader may ge for other county meetings of the club. STATE CLUB. The State Superintendent of Agricultural Extension shall act as State Leader of the Boys' and Girls' Clubs. All members of local and county clubs are members of the State Club. Boys and girls between ten and twenty-one years of age living in counties where no county club is organized or in a community where there is no local organization, may become members of the State Club by applying for membership to State Assistant in Charge of Boys' and Girls' Club Work. The officers shall be a president, vice president and secretary - treasurer, elected at the annual meeting of the club. r'his organization shall have at least one contest each year, club members may exhibit at this contest. I An annual meeting or short course shall be held each year. :h county shall be entitled to send two delegates representing' boys' club and two delegates representing the girls' club to 5 meeting. NATIONAL CLUB. The United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Plant Industry cooperates with the State Agricultural Exten - sion Department in the futherance of Club work. Any active member of the State Club is also a member of the National Boys' and Girls' Club and is therefore eligible to exhibit at the National Club Contests and may represent the State or Count v Club in National Club meetings. I The club member winning first place in the corn club work 1 be eligible to membership in the "National All-Star Corn jb", and will have a life-time invitation to attend all social ictions, banquets, schools of instruction, etc., held in the erest of the "All-Star Club Work." </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 LOCAL CONSTITUTION ARTICLE I. NAME. This organization shall be known as the (Boys') (Girls') Club and shall be a part in the County organization known as the Count Boys' and Girls' Club, a part of the State organization known as the Nebraska Boys' and Girls' Clubs and a part of the Uniteil States National Boys' and Girls' Club. ARTICLE II OBJECT. The object of this organization is to encourage a type ol education which will equip Nebraska boys and girls to rendci the greatest service to themselves and to the society in which thev live. ARTICLK III MEMBERSHIP. Section 1. Any person between the age of ten and twenty - one years and a resident of may become an active member of the club, providing sucb person receives a majority of the votes of the active members present at any business meeting of the club. Section 2. Any person of the State of Nebraska may be made an associate member of this club by a majority vote of the active members present at any business meeting. ARTICLE IV. DUES Section 1. Membership in this club shall be free Section 2. An assessment may be made for any special work the club may wish to undertake by a majority vote of tht active members present at any business meeting, providing i motion to make the assessment has been presented to the clul at the last meeting before the vote is taken. ARTICLE V. PRIVILEGES AND DUTIES OF MEMBERS. Section 1. The members of this club are entitled to partici pate in Local and County Contests according to the rules ol </seg>
            <seg id="p007">&lt; ■ contest, and in State Contests held especially for the Bo\s Girls Clubs. Section 2. Members are entitled to all lessons and bulletins published by the State Department of Agricultural Extension in the interest of Boys' and Girls' Club Work. They are also entitled to all other bulletins issued by this department and also bulletins issued by the Nebraska Experiment Station. Ieetion 3. They are also entitled to any reasonable service •h can be rendered to the club by the Department of Agri - iral Extension, the County Superintendent of Public In - ction, the State Department of Public Instruction, and by Count v Farm Demonstrator. Section 4. Club members shall submit a report of work . whenever called for by Local Leader. County Superin - ent or State Leader of Club Work. Blanks for the^e rts will be furnished club members. ARTICLE VI MEETINGS. Bection 1. This club shall meet regularly on the fourth ay of each month and at any other time during the month ed upon by a majority vote of the active members present iv business meeting. Section 2. This club shall also meet with the (Girls') ( Hoys') Club of. four times each vear. ARTICLE VII. OFFICERS AND DUTIES Erction 1. The officers of this club shall be a president, a president and a secretary-treasurer. Their business shall ich as usually pertains to such offices. flection 2. The officers shall constitute an executive COOS' ee with power to act, subject to the approval of the club a* next business meeting. Section 3. The secretary-treasurer shall submit a report of ea li meeting, on blanks furnished, to the Local Leader, the County Superintendent and to the Department of Agricultural Extension, University Farm. Lincoln. Nebraska. ARTICLE VIII. LEADERS. Section 1. The State Superintendent of Agricultural Ex </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Section 2. The Coumy Superintendent shall act as the County Leader for the Club. Eection 3. Local Leaders may be chosen by the State er, by the County Superintendent or as desired by the ARTICLE IX. AMENDMENTS. This constitution may be amended by a majority vote of the active members present at any regular business meeting, pro - vided such an amendment has been presented at least one monih previous to such vote and providing it has received the sanction of the County and State Leaders. OUTLINE OF BOYS' CLUB WORK FOR 1913. Two courses will be provided for the Boys' Club this year, the Acre Corn Club work and the Potato Club work. One lesson will be sent each month to members of the Acre Corn Club. These lessons will be prepared by instructors in the Qollege of Agriculture. ■The Potato Club work will be arranged in one bulletin, ich will be sent to members who enroll in the Potato Club. CORN CL ,UB WORK. November Varieties of Corn December. .. Written Composition — "The History of Mv Acre of Corn." POTATO CLUB WORK. By J. R. Cooper. January State Contest February • General Instructions March Testing Seed Corn April ... Preparation of Seed Bed May (Corn Planting (Rainfall June ■ Cultivation July Insects August ... Study of Growing Plants September Selection of Seed Corn October Judging Corn </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Biods and Time of Planting, ivation. Insects, Diseases, and Methods of Their Control. Harvesting and Storing. Selecting Potatoes for Exhibit. OUTLINE OF GIRLS' CLUB WORK FOR 1913 It is urged that each club follow the work outlined for al. twirls clubs by the National leaders. For 1913 this will take np especially the growing and canning of tomatoes. The work will he covered by special bulletins. A two years' course in Cooking and also in Sewing will be provided for the (iirls' Club. The first year's course in Cooking will suggest some work in Home Gardening. \nv member of the (iirls' Club mav enroll for lioth the course in Cooking and Sewing. Twelve lessons in each subject are planned for the year. These lessons will be sent to club members each month during the year. COOKING— COURSE I By Orpha K. Nesbitt. Lesson No. 1 Lesson No. 2 Uses of Food and Their Preparation Home Gardening Lesson No. 3 • .* Spring Vegetables Lesson No. 4 Fruit — Canning and Preserving Lesson No. 5 Summer Vegetables Lesson No. 6 Canning Vegetables in the Home Lesson No, 7. Lesson No. 8, Lesson No. 9. Lesson No. 10. Lesson No. 11. Lesson No. 12. Variety in the Use of Cereals 1 read and Other Uses for Flour Substitutes— Eggs, Nuts, Cheese Meat Sugar and Its Uses Meat and Their Use in Our Daily Diet Simple Desserts SEWING COURSE I. By Mary Ellen Brown. Lesson No. 1 Dusting Cap Stitches and Principles of Sewing Regular Basting Hemming Overhanding Back Stitch Sewing on of Lace Joining ends of Lace </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Lesson No. 2 • Sewing Apron Stitches and Principles of Sewing Irregular Basting Featherstitch Gauging and Putting on Ruffles Putting on of Single Band Slipping Ties in Band Fitting Lessons No. 3 and 4 Towel Single and Double Hemstitch Cross Stitch — Border or Design Cross Initial Lessons No. 5 and 6 • Corset Cover Stitches and Principles of Sewing Halfback stitch French Seam Methods of Finishing Lesson No. 7 Repairing Hemmed Patch Overhanded 'Patch Lessons No. 8 and 9 Dressing Sacque Alteration of Boughten Patterns Machine Work Button Holes Lesson No. 10 Spoon Case Catch Stitch Blanket Stitch Long and Short Stitch Lessons No. 11 and 12 Napkin Stitches and Principles of Sewing French Hem Mitering Corners Embroidering Initial Outlining Padding Outline Stitch Chain Stitch Covering Satin Stitch </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">Boys' und dirls' Cluhs </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>