<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00021">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00021</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Home FOR THE FRIENDLESS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA.  FROM APRIL 14, 1899, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1900.</title>
		             <date value="1901">1901</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-05-29</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-05-24</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>

			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT 

THE 

Home for the Friendless 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. 

FROM APRIL 14, 1899, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1900. 

LINCOLN". NEB 

VTATE JOURNAL COMPANY. PEIST 

1901 </seg>


            <seg id="p003">-I 


Hon. W. A. Poynter Governor 

BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

Hon. J. V. Wolfe, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings 

President 

Hon. W. F. Porter, Secretary of State Secretary 

Hon. J. B. Meserve State Treasurer 

Hon. C. J. Smvth Attorney General 

ADVISORY BOARD. 

Mrs. H. J. W. Seamark Chairman 

Mis. L. W. Pomerine Secretary 

Mis. A. H. Weir Corresponding Secretary 

Mrs. W. M. Morning. 

Mrs. F. W. Hill. 

RESIDENT OFFICERS. 

Mrs. C. S. Jones Superintendent 

Lenore Perkv. M. D Physician 

Mrs. W. H. Hunter Matron 

Ernestine Lvons Teacher </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
REPORT. 

To His Excellency, Governor W. A. Poynter, and the Honorable 
Board of Public Lands and Buildings: 

Gentlemen — I have the honor to herewith submit for your 
consideration the report of the management and condition of 
the Home for the Friendless from April 14, 1899, to November 
:'.(», 1900. The number of inmates at that time was 43 — males, 25; 
females, 18. Number admitted to November 30, 1900, males, lfil ; 
females, 139; total. 300. The institution at that time was in a 
deplorable condition. As I look back now I wonder my heart did 
not fail me in the atetmpt to right such a dilapidated mass of 
property. My first work was to replace ninety broken window 
panes, the next was to send for the plumbers, as every water pipe 
in the building was leaking, and the sewer pipes clogged in five 
different closets. The sanitary condition can better be imagined 
than described. Many of the ceilings were wet and falling, and 
a musty, mouldy atmosphere filled every room. The children 
were in an unhealthy condition, from being crowded into a small 
dormitory on the third floor. 

THE HOSPITAL. 

The cottage used for a hospital was heated with soft coal 
stoves, which have been changed for steam heat; also one room 
converted into a drug room, where all the supplies for the hospital 
are kept. In the west ward the floor was badly worn. This 
ha« been replaced with a new one. and all the walls papered or 
kalsomined and the floors polished. 

:rekxhouse 

The greenhouse was a total wreck, as it had been abandoned 
and the plants all gone and almost all the glass broken out of the 

36 </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
562 

Uim COMMISSIONERS* REPORT. 

roof; the beds were filled with weeds, the floor covered with 
empty boxes and tin cans. This has been repaired and is now in 
excellent condition, filled with a collection of choice plants. 

SIDEWALKS, 

The back walks were entirely gone, and the front walks were 
in a condition to be unsafe to walk on, as almost every board was 
loose and many entirely gone. These have been replaced with 
white cement walks. 

All the machinery in the laundry was out of repair or broken 
so the washing had to be done with a tub and board for nearly 
two weeks. The holes in the floor were so large that one of our 
help came very near going into the boiler room below and was 
only saved by being a large woman. The floor has been replaced 
with a new one, and all the .machinery repaired, and three new 
stationary tubs put in. The sleeping rooms above the laundry 
had been abandoned: these have been repaired by plastering, 
painting, and papering, and are now pleasant and attractive 
rooms occupied by our help. 

BOILEF 

HOUSE 

The boiler house under the laundry could hardly be called a 
boiler house, as it was simply a hole in the ground to aceom 
modate one boiler, without wall or floor. The condition of boiler 
and machinery I will not attempt to describe, as some of you 
visited it before improvements were commenced. Excavation 
was made, and it is now a large square room with brick walls, 
and one new boiler has been added and one automatic feed 
pump. The old boiler has been reset and all is now in splendid 
working order. 

To make the improvements necessary the institution was a 
confusion of plumbers, plasterers, painters, and paper-hangers 
for many weeks. To do all of this and still keep within the 
limited appropriation has been my ambition, and at the same 
time to clothe, feed and care for our family in a creditable man 
ner. How well I have succeeded the following figures will verify: 

LAUXDRJi </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS 

563 

K1SBIRSEMEXT OF FIND! 

From April 14, 1899, to November 30, 1900. 

( (Ulcers' salaries f4,966 00 

Employees' wages 4,989 3J&gt; 

Maintenance 10,767 74 

Paid for labor on repairs and material for same 4,885 15 

Total |25,608 28 

Total appropriation $32,000 00 

Total expenditure 25 608 28 

Total $6,391 72 

November 

JO, 1900. 

Officers' salaries $6,000 00 $4,966 00 $1,034 00 

Employees* salarie 

6,000 

(Ml 

4,989 39 1,010 61 

Maintenance 20,000 00 15,652 89 4,347 11 

Total 

00 $25,608 28 $6,391 72 

$32,000 

ASH FOR 

BOARI 

From April 14. 1899, to November 30, 1900 

?tal received $1,901 48 

Paid into the state treasury 1,100 00 

\inoiint on hand $801 48 

fCTS AT 

MARKET PRICE 

Consumed from April 14. 1899 

to November 30, 1900. 

lue $298 49 

HOT gallons of milk, at li'ic per gal 1,000 87£ 

Total $1,299 364 

\vs i 

i 

HASE 

April lit. 1899, one cow $31 00 

April 27. 1899. one cow 40 00 

Mav 10. 1899. one cow 35 00 

Mav 12, 1899. one cow 35 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
564 

LAND COMMISSIONERS' REPORT. 

Nov. 29, 1899, one cow 4l* 00 

May 21, 1900, one cow 40 00 

Nov. 2, 1900, two cows 90 00 

€ash paid for tows '. |313 00 

April 14, 1899, one cow on hand. 

December, 1899, one cow died. 

Present value of eight cows £500 00 

Present value of one calf 10 00 

POPULATION OF H 

)ME. 

Number of inmates in the institution 
Male 

April 14. 1899— 

23 

Female 18 

Total 4S 

Number admitted from April 14 

1S9!» 

to November :&gt;(». 

1900 — 
Male . . . 

i«;i 

Female 

139 

::ni&gt; 

Total 

Number placed in homes 
Number adopted 

34 

21 

Number returned to friends 16&lt;&gt; 

Number of deaths 

Number of births 

Number of aged ladies in the Home. April 14 

t; 

Received since 4 

Number of deaths 1 

Number of adults found work 14 

Number sent to asvluni 1 

Total number 

:&gt;4:&gt; 

Total number dismissed 2K0 

Total number remaining &amp;'¦&gt; </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
565 

HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

NUMBER ADMITTED BY COUNTIES. 

Counties. Male. Female. Total. 

Antelope 1 . . 1 

Adains 5 . . 5 

Butler 1 1 

Buffalo 1 . . 1 

&lt; 'ass 12 6 18 

Oolfax 1 1 2 

t. v. 

&lt; 'uster 

Douglas 6 9 15 

I&gt;odge 1 1 2 

1 hmdy : 1 1 

Furnas 4 4 

Fillmore 1 16 17 

Frontier 

o 5 

.» 

flosper 1 .. 1 

&lt;lage 3 12 15 

» 

Hamilton 1 1 

Hitchcock 3 . . 3 

.; 

Holt 1 . . 1 

Jefferson 2 2 4 

Lancaster 68 26 134 

Merrick 1 1 

Xuckolls 1 1 2 

Xemaha 2 1 3 

.. 

i &gt;toe 1 

• &gt; 

I'olk 10 2 12 

I'ierce 1 .. 1 

Sheridan 2 1 3 

¦ ; 

Saunders 

.» 

Saline 4 4 

Seward 11 5 16 

Thayer 1 " 1 

&gt;\*ebster 1 1 

Wavne 1 . . 1 

York 1 1 2 </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
566 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

Number From Other States. 

Counties. 

Male. Female. Total 

Iowa 

o o 

EDUCATIOXAL DEPARTMENT. 

Our school has an average attendance of forty-five. This is 
one of the most: important departments in our work, and it has 
been very successfully managed by our most excellent teacher, 
who has given her undivided attention, and has been rewarded 
by the rapid progress the children are making. Our school is 
graded, the seventh grade being the highest, the oldest in school 
is 13 years of age. Our kindergarten includes the little ones 
four to five years of age. 

SABBATH SiHool 

Our Sabbath school is the most looked-for pleasure of the 
week; all are very much interested, and our school stands second 
to none in the city. A new piano has just been purchased, 
which is a great help in the institution, as children love music. 

AMUSEMENTS 

Amusements for the children are football and indoor games 
Our library has afforded some good reading for our boys and 
girls; but this department is in need of many instinctive and 
useful books. 

We are under obligation to many of our business men and 
friends for contributions of books and magazines sent the Home 
also to many children and Sabbath schools who so generously 
contribute candies and toys to our Christinas tree, and Thanks 
giving festivities. 

The general health of the inmates has been good the last year 
We have been very fortunate in escaping all contagious disease: 
that have been in the city. 

v;l ii&gt;;i - 

o 

¦2 

tlJHsoiiri 

1 

1 

S'ew York 

. 14 

.-, 

l!i 

Total 

. 161 

139 

300 </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
567 

HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

Much credit is due our physician and matron for their ever 

ready and efficient help at all times* 

RECOMMENDATIONS. 

I would recommend that a liberal appropriation be made this 

institution. Many improvements have been made and many more 

are needed which could not be made on account of shortage of 

funds. I would recommend that three bathrooms be added, and 

new tubs and fixtures be placed in the ones now in use. The 

school building should be painted on the outside, walls and roof. 

The main building roof should be reshingled. Floors in base 

nient of both buildings should be replaced with cement or tiled 

floor. That the ground west of the Home in this block be pur- 

chased for the use of the Home for buildings, playground, and 

vegetable garden. In the laundry a steam mangier is needed, as 

the old mangier with wooden rollers is entirely past use. 
We are greatly indebted to his Excellency. Governor \V. A 

Povnter, and to the Board of Public Lands and Buildings fo 

their valuable advice and help in many ways, also to the advi: 
01 v board of ladies who have so faithfully fulfilled all duti* 

assigned them. Mrs. 0. S. Jones. Superintendent. 

MATRON'S REPORT. 

1899, to Xuvember 30, 1900. 

Garments Made s'uur April 1 J 

I tresses for adults, wool f&gt; 

I Messes for adults, flannelette 7 

Dresses for adults, calico 31 

1 &gt;resses for children, gingham 14 

I tresses for children, calico 13 

1 trawers for children, pairs : 39 

I trawers for adults, pairs 14 

I'nder vests and waists 13 

Aprons 31 

Shirts 8 

Waists 19 </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
568 

I.AXD COMMISSIONERS* REPORT. 

Coat 1 

Night dresses 51 

Kheets ."k 

Pillow cases lfil 

Table cloths (old goods) 5 

Table cloths (new) !&gt; 

Neck ties (small) •. 11 

Tray cloths 

¦-&gt; 

Checked napkins for children, dozen 8 

Napkins, white, dozen 10 

Curtains (long) 50 

Curtains (short) 28 

Roller towels 77 

Single towels 4C&gt; 

Dresser spreads, bleached 12 

Dresser spreads, unbleached 

Didies lti.-» 

Comfortables 32 

Dish towels 06 

Bed ticks 

AXNBI) FRVIT. 

Peaches 40 

Pears 12 

Quince and sweet apples f!0 

Jelly and jam 20 

Pickles 

::n 

PHYSICIAN'S REPORT. 

To Mrs. C. S. Jones, su]&gt;erintpndent of the Home for the Friend 
less: 

As medical officer of this institution, I hereby beg leave to sub 

mit my report from the time I entered upon the performance of 

my duties. April 14, 1899, until the present time. During this 

time we have had, besides the ordinary affections incident to </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
569 

HOME FOR THE KR1EXDLE8S. 

•hildhood and old age, epidemics of tonsilitis in severe form, 

whooping-cough. German measles, chicken-pox, and tinea ton- 

uraus. 

Lobar pneumonia, seven cases; all recovered 
Hroncho-pneunionia, six cases; three deaths. 
Rheumatic fever, four cases; all recovered. 

Chorea, three cases; one recovered, one case improved before 

leaving, and one case early taken home for treatment. 
Congestion of the brain, one case; recovered. 
Asthma, chronic, one case; marked improvement. 
Septic ]M&gt;ison, two cases; recovery. 
Epilepsy, two cases; one removed to Hospital for Insane, one 

fo home. 

Hernia, two cases; fitted with trusses. 

Adenitis, two cases; one cervical terminated in resolute reovery; 
one axillary, terminating in suppuration, recovery. 

Circumcision, three cases. 

Curvature of the spine with semi-paralytic condition of the 

inilis. two cases; recovered. 

Severe scalp burns, brought to us, two cases; one recovered, 
li' improved but removed home before recovery. 

Curetted uterus, one case. 
1 Hslocated shoulder, one case. 

Fracture, surgical neck of humerus, one case. 
Fracture, olecranon process, one case. 

&lt; Obstetrics, two cases 

The conditions met with here are peculiar, in that the persons 

to be found in This institution are very largely from among three 
classes. They belong to the two extremes of life and those suffer- 

ing from some constitutional dyscrasia. Have had: 
Births— 2. 

Deaths — Aee. 

No. Yre. Mos. Dys 

Premie poison 1 80 

1'remic convulsions, twins, mother died of 

uremia 2 .. 1 8 

•&gt; 

2 14 </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
570 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 

A 

Deaths — No. Yrs. Mos. Days. 
Whooping-cough 4 .. 4 8 

o o-» 

15 

Tuberculosis • 3 . ¦ . ¦ 1 1 

13 11 

1 

Enteritis 

1 

i a 

Enteritis, one born at 7 months 4 

Intestinal indigestion 1 .. .. 17 

During the prevalence of smallpox in the state last summer, 
and after it had invaded our city, it was deemed best to practice 
general vaccination in the institution, which was done with the 
best result. The fact that we have been spared a visitation of the 
more serious contagious diseases I feel is largely to be attributed 
to the fact that when scarlet fever, diphtheria, and smallpox have 
been prevalent in the community, visitors have been excluded 
from the institution. 

Since entering upon my work here I have been greatly pleased 
to note the many improvements made, especially in the matter 
of cleanliness, repairs to the plumbing, and improvement and 
extension of the heating plant, the same having been extended 

Broncho-pneumonia 

:? . 

o 

2a 

7 

12 

. 12 

16 

Malnutritiuu 

7 

l'i; 

Malnutrition, premature birth and jaundice 

O 

Malnutrition, twins, mother died of uremia 

• &gt; 

ti 

• I 

1 1 

21 

Malnutrition, following cholera infant inn 

¦ » 
• » 

in 

Malnutrition, mother had Potts' disease. . 

•5 

IT. 

Total number of deaths 

24 </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

571 

over to the hospital, which was formerly heated by stoves, but 
which has now the advantage of steam heat. The above improvements 
have greatly benefited the sanitary conditions of the institution. 


I have been gratified to observe the home-like atmosphere 
which has pervaded the Home, the uniform kindness and affection 
which has been manifested toward the children, and the 
sympathetic care extended to those who are spending their declining 
years in this place. 

Lexore Perky, M. D. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>