<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00039">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Influence of Number of Daily Milkings on the Production of Dairy Cows</title>
               <date value="1931-09">1931-09</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 59 The Influence of Number of Daily Milkings on the Production of Dairy Cows R. F. MORGAN AND H. P. DAVIS Department of Dairy Husbandry LINCOLN, NEBRASKA SEPTEMBER, 1931 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY 1. High-producing Holstein, Jersey, Ayrshire, and Guernsey cows of various ages milked three times daily produced from 39.69 to 52 20 per cent more fat and from 44.98 to 65.18 per cent more milk thin cows milked twice daily. 2. When high-producing cows of all breeds milked four times daily were compared with cows milked twice daily, the fat production for the several age classes varied from 110.19 to 127.53 per cent and the milk production from 149.08 to 160.31 per cent greater for those milked tour times. ' . 3. Milking high-producing cows four times as compared with three times daily showed an increased fat production ranging from 44 70 to f)'.).81 per cent, while comparable increases for milk ranged from 51.99 to 71.79 per cent. 4. There was a slight tendency for additional daily milkings to in - crease the percentage of fat in the milk. 5. The influence of additional milkings was greatest when carried through the entire lactation period. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">The Influence of Number of Daily Milkings on the Production of Dairy Cows It. F. M'OItGAN AND H. P. DAVIS Milking cows more frequently than twice a day has generally been considered as likely to increase their milk now.. Ihe practice of so doing is a very old one in certain sections. An early writer (5) indicates that at the begin - ning of a lactation period many Dutch farmers milked their cows three times daily, although apparently this practice did not continue throughout the entire milking period 1 he tact that milking cows more than twice a day is likely to result. in increased milk flow is recognized by several of the breed associations in the United States. For example the Holstem-Friesian Association of America (16) has established separate classes in their Advanced Registry for cows milked twice daily as compared with those milked . three or four times daily. The American Guernsey Cattle ( lub (1) recognizes a separate class for cows milked only twice a day, assuming apparently that other cows on Ad - vanced Registry test are milked more frequently The Register of Merit of the American Jersey Cattle Club lists the number of milkings used during the year together with the figures for milk and fat production, in order that readers may judge the influence of the number of milk - ings. • ■ • According to Eckles (8), "Heavy producing cows will in - crease their yield by an additional milking, while small or medium milkers show no appreciable increase. Few cows will produce over 50 or 60 pounds, at the most, with twice - a-day milking. For the Channel Island breeds (Guernsey? and Jerseys) 35 to 45 pounds mark the same limits. With cows of this grade a third milking makes it possible not only to make use of the full capacity of the animal but also apparently to hold up the production to a higher level for a longer period. ... Seventy or eighty pounds of milk daily for a Holstein or 50 for a Jersey is near the upper limit for three milkings daily. If the animal has a capacity above this, four milkings are necessary to obtain a maxi - mum yield." Riford (21) changed 50 cows averaging 45 pounds of milk daily from two- to three-time milking and stated that the average increase was four pounds of milk daily. He also compared a group of 25 cows milked three times daily with their past production when milked twice. The in - crease varied from 9.1 to 13.2 pounds of milk daily, the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 59 largest increase being from fresh cows. He stated that milking three times added about 10 per cent to the produc - tion of cows giving between 40 and 60 pounds daily, while there was an increase of about 20 per cent from cows pro - ducing above 60 pounds of milk a day. Woodward (28) reported that the increase in milk flow - due to milking three times daily. as compared with twice was about 12 per cent over a short period and for a longer period the increase varied up to 18 per cent. The change from three to four, daily milkings increased production slightly more than 6 per cent. Turner (26) reported that cows milked at eight-hour intervals and others milked at six-hour intervals produced respectively ten and sixteen per cent more milk than cows milked every twelve hours. Dean (7) stated that during one month an Ayrshire and a Holstein cow were milked three times daily and during the following month they were milked twice daily. He concluded that, while three-time milking produced more milk, it did not pay in the case of cows producing 42 and 52 pounds of milk daily. Brody (4) indicates that there is a marked difference in the production of cows milked twice, three times and four times daily. Atkeson (3) reported that three cows that had complete records under different systems of milkings showed 100 per cent milk production for four-time milking, 75 per cent for three-time milking, and 60 per cent for twice-a-day milking Among thirteen cows that were milked both three and four times daily, the increased production due to the extra milk - ing was 25 per cent. The peak of production for cows milked twice daily was reached before the end of the third week while with three- and four-time milking, the peak of milk production was not reached until the end of the sixth week Dahlberg (6) reported that for- a Jersey herd, the net result of three-time feeding and milking was 22.3 pounds of butterfat yearly for cows that produced about. 375 pounds of fat yearly on twice-daily feeding arid miiking. There is a cumulative effect due to developing the producing ability of the cow that is brought about by the extra milking that may be important from the breeding standpoint. In this experi - ment the twice-a-day cows were milked only 10 months while the cows milked thrice a day were milked 12 months According to Huynen (17) the milking of cows three times as compared with twice daily showed an increase of 1 per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Influence of the Number of Daily Milkings for cows milking 10 liters daily, and 10 per cent for thoso milking 30 liters daily, or an average for the herd of between 6 and 7 per cent. Swett (24) demonstrated that pressure in the udder has an inhibiting effect upon milk secretion; consequently there is logical reason to believe that more frequent milking would result in increased production. According to Smeyers (23) a trial with 34 cows whose production ranged from 8.5 to 17 kilograms of milk daily under twice-a-day milking showed an increase of 8 per cent in milk and 13 per cent in butterfat production when milked three times daily for a week. Fleischmann (10) stated that three-time showed an in - creased yield over twice-a-day milking of between 6 and 7 per cent. Woodward (27) in a later report showed that cows milked twice and three times daily for alternate 30-day periods fol - lowing 10-day transitional periods, produced 11 per cent more milk and almost 10 per cent more fat when milked three times daily. When longer periods, 217 to 365 days, were compared, the extra daily milking caused 20 per cent more milk and 21 per cent more fat production. Alternating periods of 30 days, with a 10-day transitional period, to compare three-time milking with four daily milkings showed an increased pro - duction for the latter system of 7 per cent more milk and 6 per cent more fat. Additional milkings over twice daily served to reduce the rate of decline of milk production, or, in other words, increased the persistency of lactation. The effect of milking cows more than twice daily may be three-fold. It may increase the milk flow, it may have an effect upon the percentage of butterfat, and it may in - fluence the persistency of lactation. Any of these effects may be measured by means of experimental trials or by the tabulation of past records. In an effort to determine the influence of the number of milkings daily,' the available records of the dairy herd at the University of Nebraska were carefully tabulated and arranged by breeds and by ages. Only records that exceeded 304 days were included and all animals were excluded where abortion might have had an influence upon production (18). In the University herd four breeds of dairy cattle have been kept, Holstein, Jersey, Ayrshire, . and Guernsey. A larger number of. records of the first-named breed were available for study, but all records for each breed have been presented where comparison was possible. Since it is a generally accepted fact that the production of dairy </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 59 cows is affected by their age, particularly when immature, it was necessary to group the data under different age classifications (1, 2, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 18, 19, 25, 26). Consequently ali animals calving between the ages of 24 and 35 months inclusive were grouped as two-year-olds (25) ; those calving at between 36 and 47 months inclusive were listed as three-year-olds ; those calving at between 48 and 59 months were considered as four-year-olds; and all animals calving at 60 months or older were considered as belonging to the aged-cow group. Records of cows over 10 years of age were omitted in order that senility might not have an effect (11, 12, 15, 26). The tables in - clude data on the following: the average age; the number of days that the animal was milked two, three, or four times daily; the pounds of milk; the pounds of fat; the per - centage of fat; and the relation to maturity. In Table 1, Holstein cows milked twice daily are listed by age groups. A total of 75 animals are included in the table. The relation of the production of the younger animals to the mature animals is approximately the ac - cepted relationship as determined by various investigators (11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 18, 19, 25). The production shows a regular progression from the younger to the older group: In making up this table, the range of milkings was as fol - lows: for 305-day records, 610 to 792; for 365-day re - cords, 612-912. It is believed that this is a fair vange of milkings for the respective milking periods. The average age was 5 years and 1 month and the 75 cows were milked an average of 344 days. Table 1 A is comparable to Table 1, except that it re - presents a tabulation of Holstein cows milked three times daily. Here again the production relationship of the im - mature animals to the mature is very close to the gen - erally accepted relationship (25). The average age in this - group was 4 years and 6 months and the average number of days in milk was 354. . The number of milkings daily is listed together with the range. The difference of seven months in the average age of the cows milked three times daily as compared with those milked twice (shown in Table 1) does not have any effect upon the comparison of the tables. In Table IB, Holstein cows milked four times daily are compared in age groups. Here again the production ac - cording to age is approximately the accepted standard as shown in Table 7. The 109 cows averaged 5 years of age, were in milk 357 days, and had an average of 1,413 milk- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Table 1. — Production of Holstein cows milked two times daily Range of milkings: for 305 days, 610-792 ;_ for 306-365 days, 612-912 ,__ _J_ _'■ Days milked -. &gt;-t . Relation to 2 Number Age Days Four Three Two Total Milk Fat, Fat maturity, J3 of cows groups in time.; times times milkings based C Yrs.-Mos. milk daily daily daily . . on fat M Av. no. Av, no. Av. no. Av. no. Av. no. Av. lbs. Av. lbs. Av. p. el. P. cl. § 32 7-8 336.5 0.94 42.0 293.4 716.7 10585.7. 356.04 3.36 100.00 _ •" ;•■ 13 4-4 344.3 0.77 35.2 308.2 729.2 9622.3 332.25 3.45 93.31 2 12 3-3 354.3 ... — 354.3 708.5 .8682.3 299.35 3.45 84.07 18 2-1 350.7 ... 11.0 339.6 712.5. 8292.8 273.33 3.29 76.76 g Tot. 75 Av.- 5-1 344.1 0.53 26.6 316.8 716.7 9563.8 323.07 3.37 ....■■ Table 1A. — Production of Holstein cows milked three times daily g J Range of milkings: -for 305 days, 853-1217; for 306-365 days, 913-1277 . B 34 7-1 346.3 62.2 242.5 41.7 1059.7 15707.2 565.26 3.60 100 ; 00 o 13 4-5 357.5 7.9 318.3 31.3' 1049.2 15144.9 529.68 3.50 93.70 % 15 ■ 3-7 358.5 80.9 222.0 54.8 1099.7 14542.4 518.84 3.57 91.78 33 2-3 359.6 27.1 311.0 20.4 1084.3 12757.3 445.41 3.49 78.79 O Tot 95 Av. 4-6 354.4 57.7 273.4 ' 34.9 1074.5 1442L6~ 511.43 3.55 Table IB. — Production of Holstein coivs milked four times daily g Range of milkings: for 305 days, 1218-140; for 306-365 days, 1278-1460 P 51 7-1 356.4 344.3 9.8 0.25 1401.0 21972.5 788.97 3.59 100.00 ? 15 4-7 360.0 350.6 8.4 0.93 1429.9 21495.8 783.92 3.65 99.35 w 15 3-5 349.0 339.8 10.1 3.00 1395.5 18001.8 690.41 3.83 87.50 28 2-4 351.1 354.4 6.8 1.96 1397.8 16642.1 606.63 3.44 76.88 Tot. 109 Av. 5-0 | 357.8 347.1 8.8 1.10 1413.0 20129.6 733.44 3.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 59 . ings. In Tables 1, 1A, and IB, the greatest variation in days in milk was 13 days, and this did not have any appre - ciable effect upon the results. It is evident from studying Tables 1, 1A, and IB, that there was a considerably larger production of milk and fat in the groups milked more than twice daily. The average percentage of butterfat for the cows milked twice daily was 3.37, while for the Holstein cows milked three times daily it was 3.55 and for the cows milked four times daily, 3.64. It seems reasonable to conclude that the additional daily milkings added materially to the milk production, and there is an indication that the ad - ditional milkings increased the percentage of butterfat. It might be well to state that all the three- and four-time milk - ing records were made under advanced registry conditions with the percentage of butterfat determined 'by samples tested for each milking for one or two days in the middle of the month. Part of these milking records were obtained by the testing of weekly composite samples of milk. In Table 2, comparable to Table 1, data for Jersey cows are presented. The relation of production at younger ages to maturity is not according to the accepted scale as was the case with the Holsteins in Table 1. What this is due to is not entirely apparent. The three- and four-year-old groups deviate materially from the expected ratio,' and in fact both groups exceed the mature production in fat. The effect of a higher fat percentage in the younger ages will account for part of the large fat production at the imma - ture ages as compared with the production at maturity. If the cows at the different ages had produced milk con - taining the same percentage of fat that the mature cows produced, the two-year-old cows would have produced 301.10 pounds of butterfat or 88.91 per cent of the mature production. The three-year-old cows with the same per - centage of butterfat would have produced 324.53 pounds of fat or 95.84 per cent of the mature production. The four-year-old Jersey cows with the same percentage of fat as the mature cows would have an average fat production of 341.23 pounds or 100.77 per cent of mature production. Even eliminating the factor for percentage of fat, the Jersey cows in this tabulation vary materially from the anticipated relationship between mature and immature cows. It will be noted that the number of milkings for each of the immature groups is larger than for the mature group. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">TABLE 2. — Production of Jersey cows milked two times daily __ Range of milkings: for 305 days, 610-792; for 306-365 days, 612-912. ■ Days milked . &gt;-&lt; : • Relation to 2 Number Age Days Four Three Two Total Milk Fat '■ Fat maturity, £3 of cows groups in times times times milkings based C Yrs.-Mos. milk daily . daily daily on fat w Av.no. Av.no. Av. no. Av.no. Av.no. Av.dbs. Av. lbs. Av.p.cl. P.cl. H 75 8-2 344.9 25.3 318.2 714.2 6714.7 338.61 5.04 100.00 14 4-5 345.7 40.3 304.5 731.0 6772.4 351.80 5.19 103.89 . § 28 3-4 354.3 2.3 35.6 316.1 748.9 6439.1 343.15 5.33 101.34 47 . • 2-2 354.1 11.0 19.8 323.5 751.6 5974.3 318.18 5.33 93.96 g Tot. 164 Av. 5-3 349.2 3.5 26.8 318.2 732.2 6460.6 334.65 5.17 _. , __ , Table 2A.— Production of Jersey cows milked three times daily S Range of milkings: for 305 days. 853-1217; for 306-265 days, 913-1277 W JO. ■ 17 6-8 358.2 20.1 271.0 67.0 1027.9 9566.7 517.51 5.41 100.00 o 10 4-5 361.5 33.7 219.7 107.1 1009.0 9033.9 491.49 5.44 94.97 *j 8 3-5 357.3 59.9 200.2 97.2 1035.1 7653.8 435.97 5.70 84.24 M 9 2-2 333.0 33.1 291.3 8.5 1023.5 6992.5 394.30 5.64 76.19 " ° Tot. 44 Av. 4-7 353.9 33.0 250.6 69.6 1024.0 8571.2 471.57 5.50 ■■■■.. £ TABLE 2B. — Production of Jersey coivs milked four times daily g Range of milkings: for 305 days, 1218-1400: for 306-365 days, 1278-1460 P 4 9-0 365.0 329.5 34.5 0.75 1423.2 13186.2 725.56 5.50 100.00 § 2 4-5 364.5 361.0 1.50 1448.5 10982.0 700.95 6.37 96.60 w 2 2-2 335.0 335.0 1340.0 9440.0 517.04 5.48 71.26 Tot. 8 Av. 6-2 357.3 338.7 17.2 0.63 1408.7 11698.6 668.53 5.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 59 T» w rS l y A C ° WS I ?- ilked three times daily are tabulated in T?wL ?t ? cco ? dl 1 n f . to a * e - This table is comparable to S ™ ♦ ?u ls i 61^ COWS - While " there is a variation Sp P rS?f? *£- pf butterfat between the different age classes, the relationship between immature and mature production is reasonably close to the expected. There appears to be a wider range of butterfat percentage variations between various groups of Jersey cows than between correspond - ing groups of Holstems. There was a uniform increase in production as compared with twice-a-day milking. lable 2B shows the Jersey cows milked four times daily and is comparable to Table IB f6r Holsteins. While onlv a few animals are presented, the table correlates well with ?S er to 5 /' fables 2 A and 2B show that cows milked three and four times daily produced materially more than those milked twice daily and that they averaged higher in butterfat. Tables 3, 3 A, and 3B present data regarding Avrshire cows comparable with data presented in the previous" tables for Holsteins and Jerseys. The small numbers represented do not permit the drawing of any conclusions but are pre - sented for comparative study. Here, too, the cows milked three and four times daily produced more milk, and fat than those milked twice a day, but showed no appreciable increase in the percentage of butterfat in the milk In Tables 4, 4A, and 4B figures for different age groups of Guernsey cows under different systems of milking are P ™ eS iw t' — £ ag ? in the numbers represented are too small to be significant. In Table 4 there is a very uniform progression in the age groups. Throughout all the tables the relationship of production at younger ages to mature production is quite uniform where there are sufficient num - bers to be in any way significant. Since the progressive re - lationship is comparable to the figures presented by Turner and co-workers (25) on the relationship of immature pro - duction to mature production, it is. believed that the data presented m Tables 1 to 4B are of significance. Cows £n£ e ? H S t and , fou . r times daiJ y had materially higher milk and fat production and in some cases a higher ner - centage of butterfat than cows milked twice a day It is obvious that in studying the influence of the number 2,^ mi !J? n g? upon Production the best comparison would be with the same cows. Since age is a factor in - fluencing production, all animals would have to be mature if the comparisons were to be valuable unless corrections for age were used. Various factors have operated to pre- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Table 3. — Production of Ayrshire coivs milked Uvo times daily Range of milkings: for 305 days, 610-792; for 306-365 days, 612-912 ■ - ' Days milked Z Relation to J3 Number Age Days Four Three Two Total Milk Fat Fat maturity, e, of cows groups in times times times milkings based k Yrs.-Mos. milk daily daily daily on fat g .Ar. no. Ap. no. Av. no. Av. no. Av. no. Av. lbs. Av. lbs. Av. p. cl. P. cl. _ 17 9-9 342.0 1.3 61.5 . 278.4 747.4 9564.9 370.46 3.87 100.00 2 3 4-6 346.6 98.6 248.0 792.0 8156.3 322.06 3.95 86.93 4 3-3 360.5 18.5 342.0 739.5 7461.3 300.98 4.03 81.24 g 13 2-3 346.9 40.1 305.7 733.0 6253.6 272.32 4.35 73.50 g Tot. 37 Av. 6-0 346.1 0.6 | 52.4 292.4 745.1 8059.9 325.35 4.03 2 . , . , c . Table 3A. — Production of Ayrshire cows milked three times daily S Range of milkings: for 305 days, 853-1217; for 306-365 days, 913-1277 • g» 12 6-6 354.0 ..... 311.0 42.6 1018.6 11342.9 450.93 3.97 100.00 ° 7 4-4 342.7 270.2 72.4 955.7 9704.4 396.73 4.91 88.02 _ . 3 3-3 344.3 35.0 236.6 72.6 995.3 10990.0 404.48 3.68 89.69 O 7 2-3 356.5 327.1 29.2 1040.0 7189.8 312.43 4.34 69.28 £ Tot. 29 Ay. .4-7 350.8 3.6 297.3 49.9 1006.5 9942.2 399.58 4.01 K . : . : 1 , ■- . g Table 3B. — Production of Ayrshire cows milked four times daily p Range of milkings: for 305 days, 1218-1400; for 306-365 days, 1278-1480 2 4 7-2 365.0 328.0 37.0 1423.0 14683.2 600.33 4.08 100.00 w Tot. 4 Av. 7-2 365.0 328.0 37.0 . ., . . 1423.0 14683.2 600.33 | 4.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Table 4. — Production of Guernsey cows milked two times daily Range of milkings: for 305 days, 310-792; for 306-3G5 days, 612-912 Diya milked —— — _ Number Age Days Four Three Two"" Total Milk Fat Fat mturity 40 a of cows groups in times timas tinus milkings based &gt; _ Yra.-Mos. milk daily daily daily on fat % , , _ , Av ; no - Av. no. Av. no. Av. no. Av. no. Av. lbs. Av. lbs. Av. p. ct. P. ct l \ Ji o! 5 - 6 ••' 34 - 8 309 - 6 725 -° 7340 - 8 339.41 4.62 100 00 £ a o'o H •••• 87 ' 2 250 -° 764 - 6 6809 -7 306.36 4.49 90.26 SO * 3-2 355.5 63.2 287.2 779.2 6007.2 287.22 4.75 84.26 I 2-4^ 342.3. 3.1 39.1 302.1 728.0 5570.4 253.84 4.55 ' 74.78 H Tot. 33^ Av. 5-1 | 345.1 0.8 47.4 295.8 ~ m3~l~ 66I5X ~3oT74" 4^ ...;.. •** Table 4A.—Productian of Guernsey cows milked three times daily £ . Range of milkings: for 305 days, 853-1217; for 306-365 days, 913-1277 5 6-8 365.0 63.4 212.6 83.4 ■ 1058.2 10053.3 492.61 4.89 100.00 | 3 4-5 359.3 73.0 189.6 96.6 1054.3 8483.2 408.04 4.80 83.03 &gt; 3 3-3 360.6 ..... 301.6 59.0 1023.0 8447.3 424.35 5.02 8614 » 4 ,2-1 320.5 308.0 3.2 948.7 6566.5 359.26 5.47 72.'90 g Tot. ; 15 Av. 4-5 351.1 35.7 251.2 59.8 1021.2 8488.2 426.48 5^02 . W. ,~ ' ■ — Table 4B.— -Production of Guernsey coivs milked four times daily r Range of nuHri^gA^o'L 305 days, 1218-140(k_for jOG-365 days, 1278-1460 . " . : = : g 1 4-7 365.0 360.0 1.0 4.0 1451.0 12257.3 614.20 5 01 oi 1 3-3 365.0 347.0 18.0 ..... 1442.0 13149.4 626.60 4.77 '.','..'.] «» Tot. 2 Av. 3-9 365.0 353-0 9.5 I. 2.0 1446.5 12703.3 ~ 620.40 4.88 ■ ..... ..~ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Influence op the Number of Daily Milkings vent the actual accumulation of such data. For example, the general practice has been to milk cows four times daily only when their production was much above the average, lnree-time milking has been practiced at times for all the herd, and at other times has been used only for exceptional cows. Records are available from eight mature Holstein cows under both twice-a-day and three-time milking. That each of these cows had the ability to produce much above the average is shown by the records. Table 5 shows the milk and fat production of each cow under each system of milking, together with the increased production that may be attributed to the extra milking. Where several records are available, all are given and the average used in determ - ining the increase due to frequency of milking. While the numbers are very limited, this table confirms other tables in that there is a marked increase in production due to one extra milking each day. The average increase was 57 93 per cent in milk and 62.95 per cent in fat production. There is a very slight increase in the percentage of butterfat but it is not believed to be significant. A similar comparison of individual cows when milked three and four times daily is given in Table 6. Only nine cows are included but a number of records are listed. ' Here again there was a uniform increase due to an extra milk - ing amounting to 38.76 per cent in milk and 34.88 per cent in tat. Not enough animals were available to justify a comparison of two-time with four-time milking. It should be noted that the animals listed in Tables 5 and 6 were high-producing cows. . Whether comparable increases in production could have been obtained with cows of lower inherent producing ability is doubtful. Unfortunately there were only a very few cows of other breeds upon which like comparisons could have been made. Because of the limited numbers these were omitted. The data presented in Tables 1, 1A, and IB for Holstein cows have been rearranged and regrouped in Table 7. Here for comparison are advanced registry data tabulated by Turner (25).. Since that work represents large popula - tions it may presumably be considered as indicating the true relationship of fat production at immature ages to maturity, especially since it agrees with other material bearing on the subject (11, 12, 13, 15, 16, 18, 19, 26). Con - sidering mature fat production as 100 per cent, then four - year-old cows produced 94.03 per cent of mature produc - tion, while three- and two-year-old cows produced respec - tively 87.15 per cent and 77.67 per cent. Nebraska records </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Table 5.— Influence of number of milkings upon production of mature individual Holstein cows I — three vs. four times &gt; ■ number Two Three Two Three " Tw0 Three ' O Kaan Marie Clothilde 2nd , 49,529 9,844.9 IS.Wl 316.62 426.95 3605.8 36.34 104.63 32.46 3.25 3.16 * - - o,\Wb.o 260.52 • „ t 11,889-5 390.82 r/5 12.761J 15,666.7 438.10 657i93 • K » ren2nd • 5B ' 816 J1.663J 17.810.9 374.25 601.87 5174.6 40.95 184.24 .44.11 3J0 3J7 ft) ' *"* Gerbe " 68 ' 099 ftefj } fi .?52| 264:40 558.98 7742.8 87.61 273.04 98^4 3.14 3^8 'g o.o^-.J 1 J,I «l .&amp; . Z (7.51 665.14 m - . ■ 8,892.4 13.656J 301.89 428.80 • S Susanna Gerben 148,639 9,441.9 14,475.5 357.70 -619.87 6521.0 8K97 228.40 78JJ6 3.66 3.69 W 8,897.4 303.72 m '„,,', . 5,986.9 211.75 . W Me.. Lincoln ,26,168 13,174 J 12,037.5 460.58 428.21 665.8 6.05 57.70 12.52 3.49 3.74 W i^,jii.j 527.68 XT 17,001.4 644.29 r Mfa, Gertrude Cornucopi. DeKol . . . 181,981 11,027.7 lliwA 395.43 654^ 6012.6 61.03 207.78 69.99 3.51 3.49 'E Aver »g e ■ 9,907.9 15,6)8.0 337.16 549.43 5740.1 57.93 212J7 6^95 SAO 3^ 3 ■• . . ■ , to </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Table 6. — Influence of number of milking 8 upon prodiiction of mature individual Holstein co-ws 3 — two vs. three times ' § Milk records Fat records Fat percentage fed Milkings daily . . MUkings daily Increase in Increase in Daily milkings Name Registry milk fat . O number Three Four Three Four Three Four •*! Lbt. Lbt. Z&amp;7 Lbt. Lbt. P.ct. Lbt. P. ct. P. cl. P.ct. H La Verna Lincoln 227.3G5 19,352.3 29,556.0 645.47 1048.50 7288.2 37.66' 277.11 42.93 3.33 3.47 X 23.726.0 796.66 . M Eve Lincoln 262,616 13,985.3 19,6992 452.35 611.16 6153.9 45.43 170.96 38.83 3.21 3.10 13,1 05 .3 . 428.05 • 2 Allie Lincoln 178,368 17,070.2 22,157.4 692.12 846.22 2983.9 18.89 110.30 17.72 3.94 3.90 7l 16,577.0 15,395.6 699.95 619.26 3 14,730.6 575.23 g Quinet Lincoln 339,507 15,150.9 18,445.5 661.10 709.89 4323.8 29.69 161.92 27.13 3.84 3.76 5 15,271 3. 19,322.7 690.08 713.81 • H ■ . 13,259.0 628.61 , » Quality Lincoln 348,248 18,813.1 23,893.5 631.16 818.8.5 5978.2 31.77 227.16 35.99 3J5 3.46 o 23.294.1 801.18 2 27,668.0 963.01 ■ • 24.309.8 850.19 . i_i Varsity Derby Esther 472,944 14,684.7 31,925.9 613.85 762.02 6794.2 39.45 222.76 43.36 3.49 3.69 V 19.031.9 72121 . &gt; Varsity Piebe Fontiac Karma 719,087 16,659.1 19,146.0 630.05 727.71 3534.1 21.34 12625 20.03 3.80 3.76 H 21,040.4 784.90 kI Varsity Derby Georgia 476,484 16,957.4 20,356.5 658.05 719.94 3399.1 20.04 61.89 9.40 3.88 3.60 Varsity Derby Celia 381,325 13,231 3 21,959.5 505.81 782.58 6522.2 49.06 200.28 39.59 3.80 3.66 !&gt; 17,673.6 629.60 £&lt; Average 16,657.8 21,588.9 57227 772.03 6031.1 38.76 199.76 34.88 3.67 3.68 a </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 59 were tabulated according to age without reference to num - ber of milkmgs daily. In this tabulation with the mature cows as 100 per cent, the four-year-olds produced 92 48 per cent, the three-year-olds 85.43 per cent, and the two - year-olds 76.80 per cent of mature fat production The variation from advanced registry figures is 1.55 per cent for four-year-olds, 1.72 per cent for three-year-olds, and 0 87 per cent for two-year-olds, all of which indicates that the cows studied were normal as compared with the breed. When the cows milked twice a day were compared the variations from advanced registry figures were as follows - for four-year-olds, 0.78 per cent; for three-year-olds 3 12 per cent; and for two-year-olds, 0.94 per cent. In the com - parison of cows milked three times daily with the advanced registry data, the variation is as follows: for four-year - olds, 0.33 per cent; for three-year-olds, 4.63 per cent - and for two-year-olds, 1.12 per cent. When the cows milked four times daily were compared with the ad - vanced registry data, the differences were as follows- for four-year-olds, 5.32 per cent; for three-year-olds, 0.35 per cent; and for two-year-olds, 0.79 per cent. These com - parisons have been presented in order to indicate that the cows whose records are presented were normal in the relation of their immature production to mature production and that age as a factor affecting milk and fat production had been eliminated. Table 7 shows that three-time as compared with twice-a-day milking showed differences in fat production varying from 58.68 per cent to 73.32 per cent, while for milk production the range is from 48 38 per cent to 67.49 per cent. The mature, four-year-old, and two-year-old cows showed a maximum variation of 4 32 per cent from the average, while the three-year-old cows showed a greater variation. Four-time milking when com - pared with twice-a-day milking (see Table 7) showed a fat production ranging from 121,48 to 135.97 per cent and milk production ranging from 100.03 to 123.39 per cent higher for the four times. When cows milked four times were compared with those milkfed three times, the fat ranged from 33.06 to 48.00 per cent higher, while the milk increase ranged from 23.78 per cent to 41.93 per cent * k !* iH a S ° mdic . ate that a slightly higher percentage of butterfat accompanies the more frequent milking practice. In Table 8 data comparable to Table 7 are presented for Jersey cows When grouped together by ages, irrespec - tive of number of milkings, the Nebraska cows do not agree </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 Table 7. — Influence of number of milking s upon milk and fat production of dairy coivs — Holsteins § Nebraska cows milked daily llclation lo maturity . Increase due to milkings Ago Adv. Ncbr.. Adv. Ncbr. Milked daily 1} at . Item Registry cows, . Kcgis- cows.all Thrice ■ Four times Four times calving ' data, all Four try milk- Four over twice over twice over thrice H Holstcin rmlkings Two Three times data inns Two Three times ■ K P. cl. P. cl. P. cl. P. cl. P. ct. Lbs. P. cl. Lbs. P. ct. Lbs. P. cl. Cows, No. 3390 117 32 34 51 . y Mature Milk, Lhi. 17O37J 10585.7 15707.2 21972.5 100 100' 100 100 100 5121.5 48.38 11380.8 107.50 (12(i5J 39.88 Z? Fat.P.ct 3^5 3J6 ■ 3.60 3.50 ... S Fat, Lbn. 654 605:61 350.22 505.20 788.97 100 100 100 100 100' 209.04 58.68 432.75 121.48 223.71 39.57 S Cows,jVo. 1238 41 13 13 15 ...... . • .. .. M Four Milk, Lbt 15717.4 9022.3 15144.9 21495.8 92.25 90.89 90.42 97.83 5522.0 57.39 11873.5 123J9 0350.9 41.93 W years Fat, P. cl 3.56 3.45 3.50 3.65 • _ Fat, Lbs. 015 560.08 332^1 529.68 783.92 94.03 92.48 93.25 93.70 99.35 197.47 59.44 451.71 135.97 254.24 48.00 § Covt.So. 1523 42 12 15 15 M Three Milk, Us 14103.6 8682^ 14542.4 18001^ 82.77 82.00 92.58 81.92 5860.1 07.49 9319.5 107J3 3459.4 23.78 O years Fat, /'. cl. .... 3.07 3.45 3J7 3.83 : &gt; Fat, Lbs. 570 517.40 299.35 518.84 690.41 87.15 85.43 84103 91.78' 87.50 219.49 73.32 391.00 130.03 171.57 33.06 p Cows.A'o. 2454 80 18 33 29 Two Milk, Lbs 13141.6 8292.8 12757.3 16588.5 77.13 78.33 81.21 75.49 4464.5 53.83 8295.7 100.03 383.12 30.03 ts&gt; years Fat, P. ct 3.54 3.29 3.49 3.65 ... S Fat, Lbs. 508 465.14 27333 445.41 006.03 77.07 76J0 76.73 78.79 76.88 172.08 63.00 333.30 121.94 161.22 36.19 p I— I CO </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Table 8. — Influence of number of milkings upon milk and fat production of dairy cows — Jersey &gt;J&lt; Nebraska cows milked daily Relation to maturity Increase due to milking: £&gt; Age Adv. Nebr. Adv. Ncbr. Milked daily § at Item Registry cows, Regis- cows, all 1 Thrico Four times Four times calving data, all Four try milk- Four over twice over twice over thrice m Jersey milkings Two Three times data ings Two Three times ■ h 1 •.. • P.ct. P.cl. P.cl. P.cl. P.cl. Lbs.. P.ct. Lbs. P.ct: Lbs. P.cl. I* Cows.Jv'o. 4730 00 75 17 4 r - Mature Milk, Lbs 7480.4 0714.7 0500.7 13180.2 100 100 100 100 100 2852.0 42.47 6471.5 80.37 3619.5 37.83 \Q Fat.P.rt. .... 5.15 5.04 5.41 5.50 g Fat, Lbs. 511 386.41 338.01 517.51 725.50 100 100 100 100 100 178.00 52.83 380.05 114.27 208.05 40.20 &gt; Cowt.No. 1087 20 14 10 2 £d Four Milk, Lbs 7900.0 0772.4 9033.0 10982.0 lOC'lii 100.85 94.43 83.28 2201 .5 33.30 4209.0 62.15 1048.1 21.56 H years ' Fat, P. ct. .... 5.42 5.10 5.44 6.38 W Fat, Lbs. 480 432.38 351.80 491.40 700.95 05.10 111.89 103.80 04.97 06.00 139.00 30.77 349.15 90.21 209.46 42.61 M Cows.JVo. 2263 30 28 8 ; W Three Milk, Us. .... 6709.0 0439.1 7053.8 89.57 95.89 80.00 1214.7 18.86 G years Fat, P. ct 5.42 533 5.70 ...:. W Fat,U&gt;. 443 363.77 343.15 435.97 86.09 04.14 10U4 84.24 92.82 27.04 ,_, Cows.JVo. 4000 58 47 0 2 ' ' C Two Mllk.Itj. .... 0251.8 5074 3 6992.5 9440.0 83,47 88.97 73.09 71.58. 1018.2 17.04 3405.7 58.01 2447.5 35.00 C yars Fat, P. cl 5.38 5J3 6.04 5.47 : P Fat, Lbs. 383 330.84 318.18 394J0 517.04 74.95 87.17 93.1)0 76.10 71.20 70.12 23.02 108,86 62.40 122.74 31.13 W ■ ■ . *° </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Influence of the Number of Daily Milkings in all age classifications with the advanced registry data, the four-year-olds and the three-year-olds being above the mature cows in production (see Table 4). For Jersey cows, the percentage increase due to three-time milking over twice-a-day milking ranged from 23.92 to 52.83 for fat and from 17.04 to 42.47 for milk. . When four-time milking was compared with twice-a-day milking, the increase in fat ranged from 62.49 per cent to 114.27 per cent, while the increase in milk ranged from 58.01 to 96.37 per cent. Four - time when compared with three-time milking showed an increase in percentage of fat production ranging from 31.13 to 42.61, while for milk the increase ranged from 21.56 to 37.83 per cent. As in Table 7, for Holsteins, this table shows that Jersey cows show materially higher milk and fat production when milked more frequently than twice daily. There appears to be also a higher percentage of butterfat from cows milked more frequently than twice daily. Additional milkings do not increase the production of milk and fat for Jersey cows as much as for Holstein cows, which may be due to the difference between the breeds, to the fact that the Jerseys were on the average lower in production than the Holsteins, or to both factors. Table 9 presents figures for Ayrshire cows comparable to Table 7 for Holstein and Table 8 for Jersey cows. The Ne - braska data are meagre but this table shows the same re - lationship that the others showed except that the additional milkings are not accompanied by the higher percentage of fat in the milk. The increased production due to the extra milking ranged slightly lower in percentage than was the case in the other breeds. This may have been due to the lower inherent producing ability of this group of cows. Table 10, comparable to Tables 7, 8, and 9, shows the data for Guernsey cows. The paucity of the data precludes much discussion, but here as in every other case, the in - creased number of -milkings materially increased the pro - duction. While not true in every case, the additional milk - ings tended slightly to increase the percentage of butter - fat. In Table 11 a recapitulation of previous tables is made so as to present a summary of all records of all breeds in one table. It is true that in such a tabulation the Holstein cows, being more numerous, naturally would have a greater effect upon the results, but since tables have been presented showing the separate breeds it is believed that a combina - tion of all data is worth while. In the combined data there are enough numbers to smooth out individual inequalities </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Table 9.— Influence of number of milkings upon milk and fat production of dairy cows— Ayrshire w Nebraska cows milked daily Itclalion to maturity Increase due to milkinEB Ase -■ ■ A*r ; Nebr. ~~' ~AdT Nel.r MilMdab__ Fourtimc. §d S ■ Item Re««try cows. H£» &lt;^.»» „,.,., , wicc ovcrtwicc „«. ralvlIlg Ayribirc milkings Tun Three times data in B s Two Three times ; H ■ — ; _ /'. cl. V. ct. I'.ct. I'.ct. l'.ct. Lbs. J'.cl. Lbt. I'.ct. Lbs. P.ct. Q Three Milk,'"": " 8973.6 7461 J I09-J0.O V".::.: "".:. ffi^ '7M0 %.is |;«jj' '_«? «* j;"|j»j; |j|j|; --^ " ::: 8 T»o M7k/w°: 17 !° m!m "«»■« nsL. :::;:::: ::::•;: »i7 «« e^ ■:;:::: w |«2 :::::::; ;::::; :::;::: :;'.:: « ■ . ■ . 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Table 10. — Influence of number of milking s upon milk and fat production of dairy coivs — Guernsey a . . . _ . . . n Nebraska cows milked daily Relation to maturity Increase due to milkings Ace Adv. Ncbr. Adv. Ncbr. Milked daily g at Item Registry cows, Rck'is- cows.&amp;ll 1 Thrice Four times Four times calving data, . all Four try milk- Four over twice over twice over thrice j Gucr'Bcy milkings Two Three times data ings Two Three times m P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.cl. P.cl. Lbs. P.ct. Lbs. P.cl. Lbs. P.cl. H Cows.A'o. 3457 20 15 5 ,_, Milk, Lbt 8018.9 7340.8 10053.3 100 100 100 100 100 2712.5 30.95 55 Mature Fat, P.ct. .... 4.71 4.62 4.80 d Fat,Li«. 517 377.71 339.41 492.61 100 100 100 100 100 153.20 45.13 g Cows,.Vo. 1977 9 5 3 1 ...'..' S Four Milk, U) 7972.8 6809.7 8483^ 122573 99.42 62.76 84.38 1673.5 24.57 6447.6 79.99 3774.1 44.48 M years Fat, P. ct. ■ .... 4.09 4.49 4.80 5.01 : . Fat, Lbs. 492 374.47 300.30 408.04 614.20 95.16 99.14 90.26 S2.83 101.68 33.18 307.84 100.47 206.16 50.52 O Cows.A'o. 2506 8 4 3 1 ' .' '. Three Milk, Its. .... 7815.0 6007.2 8447.3 13149.4 97.45 81.83 84.02 2440.1 40.61 7142.2 118.89 4702.1 55.66 O years Fat, P. cl. .... 4.87 4.78 5.02 4.77 &gt; Fat, Lbs. 452 381.07 287.22 424.35 626.60 87.42 100.88 84.62 80.14 137.13 47.74 339.38 118.16 202.25 47.00 ■ p Cows.A'o. 5554 13 9 4 *&lt; Two Milk, Lbs: .... 5876.9 5570.4 6506J5 73.28 75.88 65.31 990.1 17.88 years Fat, P. ct 4.87 4.55 5.47 : g Fat. Lbs. 409 280.27 253.84 359.20 79.11 75.79 74.78 72.82 105.42 41.53 M CO </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Table 11. — Influence of number of milking a upon milk and fat production of dairy coios — com- % bination of four breeds W Nebraska cows milked daily Relation to maturity . Increase due to milkinga t 1 * Age Registry Ncbr. Adv. Ntbr. I Milked daily ~ W «hL ' T' ■ r ll.Tis-c.mMl- — Thrice Four times Four times •a"'"* . a ". .»'.' _ , Four try milk- Four overtime over twice ovcrlhrico M j breeds rmlkings Two Three times data inns Two Ttaw limes ' • . »»rinrico lj u. bmPSi 1 *! ' l2l4 Im 802 :l 13000!l , 20882 - &lt; i '■•■■■■ ' 0() ' 1(l0 I(IU '' !() «?M ti2-ots i 2800.0 " iibij' nu'j' 60.62 h Altitun* I'lit, 7 . ft. .... 4-Ul 4J2 -i.il&gt; 3.CJ !• . *^ Fat, Lfcu. 540 487.28 340.04- 527.80 771.88 100 1110 100 i()0 100 ' isV.lO 52.20 "425.24 i22.b" 244.08 4fl!24 " Cows, An. 0224 8(1 35 33 18 ' ; : " W ■ K l' Ur WWF", " 8I ?-?» 7^ 4 ''. ilmi . IM1 . 4 '-': ' Jl ~ 2 M.1B ''88.71 U4.88 3578.5' 44.98 iigSSJ' uim 828(1.8 ' 71.79 S jfurs r ui, / . ctt .... 4.IW -I.'Jl' 4.1t'» 3.8(i . . . . . Jif Fat, /A... 5IHi 480.80 . 33H34 478.84 71^5.28 87.30 08.68 97.02 11(1.72 '99,14 "142.50 42J0 "428.94 127.53 '280.44 59.81 &gt; Cows, .Vo.' 8017 9.1 48 29' 18, ...... ;... ~ . . ' 2 *'"'l /-'"• •JC5 433.25 824,02 474.37 j 088.42 80.11 'sS.SM 93.47 89.87 '88.09 "l50.35 4(U(I ' 302.40 ill .84 '212.05 44.70 td Com, JVe. ' 16005 170 ; 87 53 ) 30 ..... ~ ' Cj •~5S' Fat.Vrt: ' " " '^408 W5 4'57 """'ill ' "*'"'■) r&gt; • " 78 ' 5 '' S ' M5 8U&lt; "™-«° (13.80 io2il';6' issii OOsil'.o' 57:58 r _1 Fm| /./.«. 408 3S!IJ'J I 29.V3l')| 4I2X.4 : C2(I.S8 75.55 i 79.01 85.21 i 78.18 'sil.j.i "l'lV.gS 39.M "3g5.i;) iio.il) '208.24 5O.4(i H ■.■.'.■. ■'. Z </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Influence of the Number of Daily Milkings so that when compared, under two-, three-, and four-time milking under the different age groups the variation from the advanced registry data is slight in any particular case, which indicates that the Nebraska cows are a normal group. When three-time milking is compared with twice - a-day milking, the increase in fat ranges from 39.69 to 52.26 per cent, while in milk production the increase ranges from 44.98 to 65.18 per cent. In the comparison of four - time milking with twice-a-day milking, the fat increase ranges from 110.19 to 127.53 per cent. The milk increase ranges from 149.08 to 160.31 per cent. When four-time milking is compared with three-time milking, the increases in fat range from 44.70 to 59.81 per cent while the milk increases vary from 51.99 to 71.79 per cent. It is not fair to draw any conclusions from this table with reference to the percentage of fat, since high and low testing breeds are represented and are not in equal proportions. From the data presented the influence of more frequent milking daily upon yearly milk and butterfat production appears to be greater than most writers have stated, at least when cows of potential high production are con - sidered. There is some evidence that more frequent milk - ings tend to increase the average percentage of fat in the milk. Whether the increased milk flow is due to a larger production of milk evenly distributed throughout the lac - tation period or whether added milkings daily tend to main - tain milk flow at a higher level for a longer period has not been determined. ' </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 59 literature cited 1. American Guernsey Cattle Club. 1930. Rules and Requirements of the Advanced Registry of Guernsey Cattle. Peterboro, N. H. 2. American Jersey Cattle Club. 1923. Register op Merit, consolidated.- New York 3. Atkeson, F. W. 1929. Dairy Husbandry. Idaho Agr. Exp. Sta. Ann. Rept., Bui. 164. 4. Brody, Samuel, Turner, C. W., and Ragsdale, A. C. 1924. The Relation Between the Initial Rise and the Sub - sequent Decline of Milk Secretion Following Parturi - tion. Jour, of Gen. Physiol. 6:541-545. 5. Colman, Henry. ■ • '.;. 1848. European Agriculture, quoted in Holstein Herd Book, 1:9. 6. Dahlberg, A. C. 1924. New York Experiment Station, Jerseys. Two versus Three Milkings. Hoard's Dairyman 68:436. 7. Dean, H. H. 1898. Annual Report, Dept. of Agr., Ontario, Canada. 8. Eckles, C. H. 1929. Dairy Cattle and Milk Production, rev. ed. ; Macmillan, New York. 9. , and Palmer, L. S. 1917. Influence of Age of the Cow on the Composition and Properties of Milk and Milk Fat. Jour. Agr. Research, 11:645-658. 10. Fleischmann, W. 1920. Lehrbuch der Milchwirtschaft. Aufl. 6, Neubearb., p. 633, Berlin. 11. Gowen, John W. 1920. Studies in Milk Secretion V. On the Variation and Correlation of Milk Secretion with Age. Genetics 5:111-189. . 12. 1920. Studies in Milk Secretion VIII. Influence of Age in Milk and Butterfat Yield in Holstein-Friesian Cattle. Maine Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 293. 13. 1920. The Correlation Between the Butterfat Percentage of one Lactation and the Butterfat Percentage of Suc - ceeding Lactations in Jersey Cattle. Maine Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 291. 14. 1923. Studies in Milk Secretion XIV. The Effect of Age on Milk Yield and Butterfat Percentage of Guernsey Ad - vanced Registry Cattle. Maine Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 311. 15. Graves, R. R., and Fohrman, M. H. 1925. Effect of Age and Development of Butterfat Produc - tion of Register of Merit Jersey and Advanced Registry Guernsey Cattle. U. S. Dept. of Agr. Bui. 1352. 16. Holstein-Friesian Advanced Registry Year Book. 1924. Vol. 35. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Influence of the Number of Daily Milkings 17. Huynen, E. 1923. CONTRIBUTION A L'ETUDE DEB VARIATIONS DE LA COMPOSI - TION DU Lait. World's Dairy Congress, Syracuse, N. Y., Proc 2:1067. 18. Morgan, R. F. . 1929. Some Economic Phases of Abortion in Dairy Cattle. Thesis presented for partial fulfillment of the Master of Science Degree, University of Nebraska. 19. Pearl, Raymond. 1914. On the Law Relating Milk Flow to Age in Dairy Cattle. Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol. and Med. 12:18-19. 20. , , and Miner,. J. R. 1919. Variation of Ayrshire Cows in Quantity and Fat Con - tent of Their Milk. Maine Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 279. 21. Riford,' Lj S. 1922. Does it Pay to Milk Three Times a'Day? Hoard's Dairy - man 63:661. 22. Roberts, Elmer. 1918: Correlation Between the Percentage of Fat in Cow's Milk and the Yield. Jour. Agr. Research 14:67-96. 23. Smeyers, F. 1909. LflNFLUENCE DU NOMBRE DES TRAITES SURLA PRODUCTION du Lait et du Beurre. Laiterie 19:58. 24. Swett, W.| W. 1927. Relation of Conformation and Anatomy of the Dairy Cow to the Milk and Butterfat Producing Capacity. Udder Capacity and Milk Secretion. Jour. Dairy Sci. 10:1. 25. Turner., d. W. F Ragsdale, A. C, and Brody, S. 1924. ThE Relation Between Age and Fat Production in Dairy Cows. Mo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 221. 2G. 1928. Factors Affecting the Percentage of Fat in Cow's Milk. Mo. Agr- Exp. Sta. Bui. 222. 27. Woodward, T. E. : 1T&gt;31. The Production of Dairy Cows as Affected by Fre - quency and Regularity of Milking and Feeding. U. S. Dept. of Agr. Circular 180: 28. , and Dawson, J. R. 1926. Care and Management of Dairy Cows. U. S. Dept. of Agr. Farmer's Bui. 1470. [3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>