<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00079.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT of the State Treasurer to the GOVERNOR of the State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1936-10-21">1936-10-21</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT of the State Treasurer to the GOVERNOR of the State of Nebraska JULY 1, 1934 to JUNE 30, 1936 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">REPORT OF TREASURERS OF NEBRASKA TERRITORIAL B. P. Rankin Term of office began March 16, 1855 William W. Wyman Term of office began November C, 1855 August Kountz Term of office began October 8, 18G1 STATE August Kountz From February 21, 1867, to January 11, 1869 James Sweet From January 11, 18 CD, to January 10, 1871 Henry A. Koenig From January 10, 1871, to January 11, 1875 J. C. Mcßride From January 11, 1875, to January it, 1879 George M. Bartlett From January 9, 1879, to January 4. 1883 Phelps D. Sturdevant From January 4, 1883, to January 8, 1885 Charles D. Willard From January 8, 1885, to January 3, 1889 John E. Hill From January 3, 18;9, to January 13, 1893 Joseph S. Bartley From January 13, 1893, to January 7. 1897 John B. Meserve From January 7, 1897, to Januaiy 3, 1901 William Stauffer From Januaiy 3, 1901, to Januaiy 8. 1903 Peter Mortenson From January 8, 1903, to January 3, 19of" Lawson G. Brain From January 3, 1907, to Januaiy 5, 1911 Walter A. George From January 5, 1911, to January 7, 1915 George E. Hall From January 7, 1915, to Januaiy 9, 1919 Daniel B. Cropsey From January 9," i9i9, to January 4, 1923 Charles D. Robinson From January 4, 1923, to January 6, 1927 Willis M. Stebbins From Januaiy 6, 1927, to January 8, 1931 T. W. Bass . From January 8, 1931, to January 5, 1933 George E. Hall From January 5, 1933, to January 3, 1935 George E. Hall From January 3, 1935, to OFFICE PERSONNEL H. J. Murray _ Deputy Treasurer Ed Westering Bond Clerk E. A. Dosek Bookkeeper Paul Ldewer Bookkeeper Ernest Arnold, Jr. Bookkeeper Arlene Moon Stenographer </seg>
            <seg id="p005">STATE TREASURER REPORT OF STATE TREASURER June 30, 1934 to June 30, 1936 . i STATE OF NEBRASKA TREASURY DEPARTMENT State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska, October 21, 1936. To His Excellency, Governor of Nebraska and The Fifty-Second Session of the Legislature. Dear Sirs: Pursuant to the requirements of the Constitution and the laws of the State of Nebraska, I herewith submit my biennial report of the State Treasury for the biennium ending June 30th, 1936. During the biennium no warrants were registered against any of the funds. All lawful claims were paid m cash as soon as presented and audited. At the beginning of the biennium there was a total balance m the several funds of the Treasury m the amount of 34,899,753.02 of which 5904.695.92 were federal funds and $3,995,057.10 were state funds. At the close of the biennium there is left a total balance m the several funds of the Treasury m the amount of $6,533,944.83, of which $2,711,835.08 are federal funds and $3,822,109.75 are state funds. This shows an increase of federal funds m the amount of $1,807,139.16, and a decrease m state funds m the amount of $172,947.35. During the biennium there was disbursed and transferred from the general fund $12,067,862.03. During the previous biennium, (June 30, 1932 to June 30, 1934), there was disbursed and transferred from the general fund $12,463,504.15, or a decrease for this biennium of $395,642.12. During the biennium the taxpayers of the State paid into the general fund from the state tax levy $8,814,061.94, and during the previous biennium $9,779,161.33, or a decrease for this biennium of $965,099.39. At the close of the biennium the State owes no debts, either bonds or warrants, and all current bills are paid. It should be, and no doubt is, a matter of great pride to all </seg>
            <seg id="p006">REPORT OF Nebraskans that the State's financial affairs are m such excellent con - dition, and that those responsible for this satisfactory condition are en - titled to the commendation of the taxpayers of the State. During the biennium there were some new and increased disburse - ments from state funds as compared to the former biennium, which were clearly justifiable, to a few of which I call your attention, viz: Disbursements for Biennium ending June 30, 1931 June 30, 1936 Gasoline Tax Fund Refunds to dealers $ 177,629.43 S 299,636.25 Apportionment to County Treasurers 5,029,598.91 6,382,266.08 Building and maintain - ing roads 10,294,943.65 11,785,506.90 State Assistance Fund (New) 1,333,627.95 Liquor Commission (New) 183,416.72 Temporary School 1,723,782.33 2,040,925.03 Agriculture &amp; Inspection Ports of Entry (New) 53,915.17* $17,225,954.32 822,079,294.10 •Furnished by Department of Agriculture and Inspection and which has practically stopped bootlegging of gasoline. LICENSES, PENALTIES AND FINES Section 5, Article VII of the State Constitution provides. "All fines, penalties and license, or ("Whatever they are called." — State vs. Aitken 61, Nebr. 490), monies, ♦••♦shall be appropriated exclusively to the use and support of the common schools m the respective subdivisions where the same may accrue." License monies, or ("Whatever they are called"), are not beinp so appropriated. They are being diverted and appropriated for other purposes. The Statute should direct all such monies collected by the State into the temporary school fund for the use and benefit of all the common schools of the State. USE OF CASH FEES BY ANY DEPARTMENT IS AN ABUSED PRIVILEGE AND A WASTE OF PUBLIC FUNDS. I wish to repeat my message of 1916, viz: "The people of Nebraska have tried for over forty (now sixty) years to get away from the waste and abuse of giving to any public official or employee for himself or for </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATE TREASURER others the use of the fees derived from his services or by his department. With the adoption of the State Constitution of 1875, the State's executive officers were denied the use of any more fees and m lieu thereof, were given a fixed salary. The Clerk of the Supreme Court, County Treasurers and other officers have been changed from fees to fixed salaries. The use of fees m many departments of the State government is being permitted by the Legislature. In many instances, this privilege is being abused and more money is being used and spent than is necessary. The Legislature should abolish the use of any and all fees or cash funds; should direct their payment into the Treasury and into the general fund, and should appro - priate a fixed salary for each person employed m the various departments and a fixed amount for the incidental expense of the various departments aside from salaries. In every instance, if there is a general need for a department or a board or officer, the Legislature should appropriate the necessary salaries and expenses whether any fees, much or little, be derived for such services." Respectfully submitted, GEORGE E. HALL, State Treasurer </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">STATE TREASURER STATEMENT Showing balances m various funds as of June 30, 1936. Current Revenue Funds General Fund $ 630,724.95 Capitol Fund 206,706.74 Game, Forestation &amp; Parks Commission 34,225.06 Motor Vehicle Fund 141.531.T4 Gasoline Tax 1,588,058.37 Miscellaneous Cash 386,295.33 State Assistance Fund (Old) .__ 895,633.19 State Assistance Fund (New) 922,828.97 Federal Assistance Fund 234,702.27 Federal Public Health 33,484.13 Federal Vocational Education 84,357.62 U. S. Employment Service 9,793.75 Federal Aid Road 52,910.76 University Cash 488,260.56 Federal University Fund 54,681.47 Normal Cash and Library 34,745.05 Institution Cash '. : 149,396.20 Compensation Court 43,622.25 Aviation Fund 9,328.52 Liquor Control Fund 109,214.98 Trust Account — National Industrial Recovery Highway Fund 423,442.92 Total $6,533,944.83 Current Trust Funds Temporary School $ 609,865.79 Soldiers Relief Income 31,372.10 University Income 318,041.46 Normal School Income 9,848.79 State Hail Funds 4,833.70 Total S 973,961.84 Permanent Trust Funds Permanent School Fund $ 262,112.48 Permanent University Fund 6,654.61 Agri. College Endowment Fund 25,071.24 Normal School Endowment Fund 4,146.46 Soldiers Relief 68,905.38 Bessey Memorial Endowment Fund 128.14 Total $ 367,018.31 GRAND TOTAL _ $7,874,924.98 Cash Account Checks and Drafts $ 280,695.18 U. S. Government Bonds 2,876,482.44 Due from Banks 4,718,847.36 Total $7,874,924.98 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">SCHEDULE I. Showing the Receipts and Disbursements of the Nebraska State Treasury for the Biennium, July 1, 1934 to June 30, 1936. A. Current Revenue Funds Receipts Disbursements Balances and and Balances FUNDS June 30, 1934 Transfers Transfers June 30, 1936 1. General Fund $1,328,702.68 $11,369,884.30 812,067,862.03 $ 630,724.95 2. Capitol Fund 218,276.64 4:!,223.92 54,793.82 206,706.74 3. Game, Forestation &amp; Parks Comm. ___ 32,942.43 322,525.15 321,242.52 34 225.06 4. Motor Vehicle Fund 37,209.58 1,324,201.24 1,219,939.08 141,531.74 5. Gasoline Tax 1,368,236.73 20,730,511.26 20 500,689.62 1,588,058.37 6. Miscellaneous Cash 394,703.52 1,020,117.95 1,028,526.14 386,295.33 7. State Assistnnce Fund (Old) 1,19U,175.42 300,542.23 895,633.19 a 8. State Assistance Fund (New) 2,256,166.92 1,333,627.95 922,828.97 H 9. Federal Assistance Fund 787,670.65 552,968.38 234,702.27 o 10. Federal Public Health 34,016.16 532.03 33,484.13 fd 11. Federal Vocational Education 37,404.14 255,541.42 208,587.94 84,357.62 H 12. U. S. Employment Service 9,793.75 . 9,793.75 O 13. Federal Aid Road 284 320.28 718,567.55 9J9.977.07 62,910.76 "* 14. University Cash 429,680.12 2,475,644.50 2,417,064.06 488,260.56 15. Pcderal University Fund 23,027.81 81)5,297.91) 773,644.24 54,681.47 16. Normal Cash &amp; Library 60,085.27 219.744.66 245,084.87 34,745.05 17. Institution Cash . 125,160.13 620,901.27 605,665.20 149.396.20 18. Compensation Court 06,1)71.14 23,348.89 . 43,622.25 19. Aviation Fund 21,672.51 12,343.99 9,328.52 IK). Liquor Control Fund ..-_ 1.39(1,212.17 1,280,997.19 109,214.98 21. Old Atfe Pension Fund 130,919.64 130,919.64 22. Trust Account --Nationnl Industrial Recovery Highway 559,943.69 8,445,878.116 8,582,379.13 423,442.92 Total -— $4,899,753.02 $54,304 927.83 ."552,670,736.02 $6,533,944.83 B. Current Trust Funds 1. Temporary School . $ 540,221.03 $ 2,110,. r &gt;(;9.79 $ 2,040,925.03 $ 009,865.79 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Receipts Disbursements Balances and and Balances June 30, I'M Transfers Transfers June 30, 1936. 2 Forest Reserve 2,!)03.10 2903.10 3 Soldiers Relief taSS "IIIi::-™ 52,129.10 159,243.00 180.00u.00 *W»™ 4. Univeisity Income 240,131.45 90,453.19 12,843.18 31 g.M1.46 5. Normal School Income 4 261.23 7,587.56 2,000.00 0.848.79 6. State Hail Funds 21,553.39 . 21,399.20 38,118.89 4,833/70 Total $ 858,596.20 S 2,392,155.84 $ 2,276,790.20 $ 970,961.84 C. Permanent Trust Funds 1. Permanent School Fund S 167575.60 $ 4,042.559.78 S 3,948,022.90 $ 262,112.48 H 2. Permanent University Fund 26,234.66 78,576.90 98,156.95 0£6«4.61O £6«4.61 H 3. A R ric. College Endowment Fund 21,240.96 206,921.91 203,091.63 25 ' 07 HI H 4. Normal School Endowment Fund 4,285.68 58,349.06 58,488.28 4,146.46 _, 5. Soldiers Relief 103,416.34 888,186.24 922,697.20 68,905.38 £) 6. Bessey Memorial Endowment Fund _._ 128.14 128.14 j£. Total $ 322,881.38 S 5,274,593.89 $ 5,230,456.96 $ 367,018.31 g GRAND TOTAL $6,081^30.60 $61,971,677.56 $6!),177,983.18 $7^74,924.98 g </seg>
            <seg id="p012">REPORT OF DETAILED STATEMENTS EXPLANATORY OF THE BALANCE SHEET OF SCHEDULE I Schedule A-l. GENERAL FUND Balance June 30, 1934 S 1,328,702.68 To Departmental Receipts Supreme Court Fees S 23,051.65 Governor 149.00 Secretary of State 328,303.03 Estate Tax 232.289.34 " Tax Commissioner 103.72 Com. Pub. Lands &amp; Bldgs. __ 8,520.69 Railway Commission 1,396.69 Car Line Tax 87,815.55 Securities Fees 110.00 Dept. of Roads &amp; Irrigation 21,430.76 Beverage Tax 272,177.07 Liquor- Commission 398,174.10 Compensation Court 82.80 $ 1,373,604.40 To Miscellaneous Receipts Sale of Books, (State Library) 3,486.60 Miscellaneous Refunds 617.68 Suspense Account 3,102.87 7,207.15 To Interest on Deposits with Banks $20,221.77 U. S. Gov't. Bonds carried as Cash 578.901.64 99,123.41 Bank Charter Fees 555.00 Insurance Premium Tax 1,071,885.63 Taxes 8,814,061.94 Redemption Taxes 3,446.72 9,989,072.75 11,369 884.30 „ m _. c. 812,698,586.98 By Transfer to State Assistance Fund (Old) 300,000.00 By Warrants Paid 11,767,862.03 12,067,862.03 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 630,724.95 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATE TREASURER Schedule A-2. CAPITOL FUND Balance June 30, 1934 S 218,276.64 To Tax Collections S 42,970.56 Capitol Commission 253.36 43,223.92 261,500.56 By Warrants Paid 54,793.82 Balance June 30, 1936 S 206,706.74 Schedule A-3. GAME, FORESTATION &amp; PARKS COMMISSION Balance June 30, 1934 _. S 32,942.43 Receipts — Administration of Game Laws 285,153.54 Receipts — Maintenance State Parks 31,683.21 Receipts— Arbor Lodge 193.23 Receipts— Chadron ' Park 5,197.35 Receipts— Victoria Springs 297.82 Receipts — Stolley Park Receipts — Niobrara Island Receipts— Ft. Kearney 322,525.15 S 355,467.58 By Warrants Paid 321,242.52 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 34,225.06 Schedule A-4. MOTOR VEHICLE FUND Balance June 30, 1934 S 37,269.58 Receipts — Highway Maintenance 1,170,035.31 Receipts — Highway Supervision 99,918.04 Receipts— Drivers' Licenses 12,750.39 Receipts — Bus Licenses 41,117.50 Flare Testing Fees from Dept. of Roads &amp; Irrigation 380.00 1,324,201.24 $1,361,470.82 By Warrants Paid 1,219,939.08 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 141,531.74 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">REPORT OF Schedule A-5. GASOLINE TAX FUND Balance June 30, 1934 $ 1,368,236.73 Receipts — Dept. of Roads &amp; Irrigation__S 1,375,139.17 Receipts— Gasoline Tax Collections 19,405,372.09 20,780,511.26 $22 148,747.99 Refunds to Dealers 299,636.27 Monthly Apportionment to County Treasurers. (See Schedule II) 6,382,266.08 One-fifth (representing one cent per gal - lon) to State Assistance Fund 2,093.280.37 Warrants Paid. (Regular) ... 11,785,506.90 20,560 659.C.2 Balance June 30, 1936 S 1 558.U58.37 Schedule A-6. MISCELLANEOUS CASH FUND Balance June 30, 1934 S 394,703.52 Receipts from — Military Cash 2.00 Grain Warehouse &amp; Miscellaneous Fees (Railway Commission) 35,272.60 Fire Marshal 31,286.68 Stock Brands, (Secretary of State) 8,198.00 State Real Estate. (Secretary of State) _ 9,482.00 Readers of Examinations (State Supt,) _ 13,116.00 Nurse Registration, (State Supt.) 6,773.00 Foods, Drugs &amp; Oils, Etc. (Agriculture) 370,928.65 Bovine, T. B. Inspection, (Agriculture) _ 7,417.04 Bee Inspection, (Agriculture) 3,912.28 Plant Inspection-Nursery, (Agriculture) 3,940.33 Hay &amp; Potato Inspection, (Agriculture) 5,296.00 Sales Pavilion Licenses, (Agriculture) __ 364.00 Examining Boards, (Welfare) 41 H66.31 . Div. of Athletics, (Welfare) 14,720.18 Professional Fund, (Welfare) 5,339.00 Barber Division, (Welfare) _ 16,782.50 Cosmetology, (Welfare) 33,589.13 Bank Assessments, (Dept. of Banking) _ 102,956.19 Examination Expense, (Dept. of Insur - ance) 35.620.86 Fees, — Agents' Li-censes, (Dept. of In - surance) ________ 112,818.49 Securities — Broker's Licenses, (Dept. of Insurance) 5,766.30 Cash Aid Road, (Dept. of Roads &amp; Irri - gation) 68,768.90 Revolving Fund, (Supplies) . 75,106.71 Metropolitan Water, (Auditor) 457.33 Fees, (Bur. of Roads &amp; Irrigation) 9,811.44 Child Welfare 4.6.03 $ 1,020,117.95 1,414,821.47 By Warrants Paid 1,028 526.14 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 386,295.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE TREASURER Schedule A-7. STATE ASSISTANCE FUND (New). Balance June 30, 1934 Transfer from— Old Ape Pension" Fund" ~l~ 463 580 93 Transfer from— Liquor Control Fund 700 COo'oo Tni ' from ~ State Assistance Fund (Old) _ _ 300 000 00 Transfer from— Gasoline Tax Fund _I™-~ 787.875.94 2 256,456.92 By Warrants Paid . " " 1&gt;333&gt;627 . 95 Balance June 30, 1936 • g 922 8 9 8 97 Schedule A-8. STATE ASSISTANCE FUND (Old). Balance June 30, 1934 Transfer from— General Fund" ZZZZZZZ &lt;jnn"nnn"nrt Transfer from-Gasoline Tax Fund 111 oKIK By Warrants Paid .. I.XOS.XTB^ By Transfer to State Assistance Fund 1,195,633.19 (New) 300.000.00 Balance June 30. 1936 $ 895,633.19 Schedule A-9. FEDERAL ASSISTANCE FUND Balance June 30, 1934 Receipts— United States Treasurer'ZZZZZ 8""787,~67~0~66 * By Warring Pniri 787,670.65 ay warrants raid 552,968.38 Btlance June 30, 1936 $ 234,702.27 Schedule A-10. FEDERAL PUBLIC HEALTH Balance June 30, 1934 Receipts— United States TreasurerZZZZZZ 34~01~6"l6 By Warrants Paid /. »WM Balance June 30, 1936 33,484 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">REPORT OF Schedule A-11. UNITED STATES EMPLOYMENT SERVICE Balance June 30, 1934 _! Receipts— United States Treasurer 9,793.75 9,793.75 By Warrants Paid Balance June 30, 1936 S 9,793.75 Schedule A-12. FEDERAL VOCATIONAL EDUCATION Balance June 30, 1934 8 37,404.14 Receipts— United States Treasurer 255,541.42 292,945.56 By Warrants Paid 208,587.94 Balance June 30, 1936 S 84,357.62 Schedule A-13. FEDERAL AID ROAD Balance June 30, 1934 S 284,320.28 Receipts— United States Treasurer 718,567.55 1,002,887.83 By Warrants Paid 949,977.07 Balance June 30, 1936 S 52,910.76 Schedule A-14. UNIVERSITY CASH Balance June 30, 1934 S 429,680.12 Receipts from — University of Nebraska S 2,475,000.00 Investments on Bessey Memorial Fund 634.50 Child Saving Institute, Omaha 10.00 2,475,644.50 2,905,324.62 By Warrants Paid 2,417,064.06 Balance June 30, 1936 S 488,260.56 Schedule A-15. FEDERAL UNIVERSITY FUND Balance June 30, 1934 $ 23,027.81 Receipts — United States Treasurer 805,297.90 828,325.71 By Warrants Paid 773,644.24 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 54,681.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE TREASURER Schedule A-16. NORMAL CASH AND LIBRARY Balance June 30, 1934 60,085.27 Receipts from — Chadron Normal S 44,953.60 Kearney Normal 41,979.61 Peru Normal 58,876.33 Wayne Normal 73,935.11 219,744.65 279,829.92 By Warrants Paid 245,084.87 Balance June 30, 1936 S 34,745.05 Schedule A-17. INSTITUTION CASH Balance June 30. 1934 S 125,160.13 Receipts from — Feeble Minded Institute, Beatrice 82,636.23 Girls' Industrial School, Geneva 3,542.04 Soldiers &amp; Sailors' Home, Grand Island 18,721.01 Hospital for Insane, Ingleside 84,703.32 Boys' Industrial School, Kearney 17,781.59 Hospital for Tuberculosis, Kearney 4,245.26 Hospital for Insane, Lincoln 71,891.21 Men's Reformatory, Lincoln 114,906.92 State Penitentiary, Lincoln 78,307.34 Handcraft Furniture, (Penitentiary) Lincoln 7,602.12 Prison Employment, (Penitentiary) Lincoln 39,163.54 Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 3,458.07 Girls' Industrial Home, Milford 1,904.99 Soldiers &amp; Sailors' Home, Milford 10,504.33 School for Blind, Nebraska City 1,705.50 : School for Insane, Norfolk 52,410.83 School for Deaf, Omaha 9,153.83 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln _ 13,793.02 Women's Reformatory, York 3,625.30 Genoa State Hospital 9,844.82 629,901.27 755,061.40 By Warrants Paid 605,665.20 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 149,396.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">REPORT OF Schedule A-18. COMPENSATION COURT Balance June 30, 1934 Receipts from — Bureau of Insurance 61,899.45 Compensation Court 5,071.69 66,971.14 By Warrants Paid gjgjj Balance June 30, 1936 S 43,6°° °5 Schedule A-19. AVIATION FUND Balance June 30, 1934 Receipts from — Dept. of Agriculture 21,590.41 Aeronautics Commission j. 82.10 21 67 9 51 By Warrants Paid .. llf£H Balance June 30, 1936 3 9j328 52 Schedule A-20. LIQUOR CONTROL FUND Balance June 30, 1934 _ Receipts from — Governor 70 j 0 Liquor Control Commission „_._! 1,390,142!07 1,390,212.17 By Transfer to State Assistance Fund 1,390,212.17 (New) 7QO Qog qq By Transfer to General Fund "" 397|680!47 By Warrants Paid 183,416.72 1,280.997.19 Balance June 30, 1936 S 109,214.98 Schedule A-21. TRUST ACCOUNT - NATIONAL INDUSTRIAL RECOVERY HIGHWAY FUND Balance June 30, 1934 Receipts from-L 559,943.69 Dept. of Roads &amp; Irrigation inn n?7 97 United States Treasurer . L=— gjgfflS 8,445.878.36 By Warrants Paid . ggggß Balance June 30. 1936 S 423,442^ </seg>
            <seg id="p019">STATE TREASURER Schedule B-l. TEMPORARY SCHOOL Balance June 30, 1934 $ 540,221.03 Receipts from — Interest on Bonds 878,161.11 Warehouse Licenses 86.10 Employment Agencies' Licenses 2,200.00 Insurance Agents' Licenses 20,917.00 Liquor Dealers' Licenses 296,720.07 Interest on School Land 133,257.58 Lease on School Land 779,227.93 2,110,569.79 2,650.790.82 By Warrants Paid 2,040,925.03 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 609.865.79 Schedule B-2. FOREST RESERVE Balance June 30, 1934 _ --"-" Received— United States Treasurer § 2,903.10 2,903.10 By Warrants Paid - . 2 903.10 Balance June 30, 1936 :- Schedule B-3. SOLDIERS' RELIEF INCOME Balance June 30, 1934 52,129.10 Receipts — Bond Investments 159,243.00 211,372.10 By Warrants Paid 180.000.00 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 31,372.10 Schedule B-4. UNIVERSITY ENDOWMENT INCOME Balance June 30, 1934 240,431.45 Receipts from — Interest on Bonds 75,064.62 University Land Interests 3,952.01 University Land Lease 4,90653 Agriculture Land Interest 2,607.02 Agriculture Land Lease 3,923.01 90.453.19 330,884.64 By Warrants Paid 12,843.18 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 318,041.46 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">REPORT OF Schedule B-5. NORMAL SCHOOL ENDOWMENT INCOME Balance June 30, 1934 S 4,261.23 Receipts from — Interest on Bonds 7,421.24 Normal School Land Lease 166.32 7,587.56 11,848.79 By Warrants Paid . 2,000.00 Balance June 30, 1936 S 9,848.79 Schedule B-6. STATE HAIL INSURANCE FUND Balance June 30, 1934 21,553.39 Receipts — County Treasurers 21,399.20 42 952 59 By Warrants Paid 38,118.89 Balance June 30, 1936 S 4,833.70 Schedule C-l. PERMANENT SCHOOL FUND Balance June 30, 1934 167,575.60 Bonds Redeemed 3,973,553.73 School Land Principal 68,673.42 Escheats 332.63 4,042,559.78 4,210,135.38 Bonds Purchased 3,948,022.90 Balance June 30, 1936 S 262,112.48 [ Schedule C-2. PERMANENT UNIVERSITY FUND Balance June 30, 1934 S 26,234,66 Bonds Redeemed 78,475.93 University Land Principal 100.97 78,576.90 104,811.56 Bonds Purchased 98,156.95 Balance June 30, 1936 S 6,654.61 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">STATE TREASURER Schedule C-3. AGRICULTURE COLLEGE ENDOWMENT FUND Balance June 30, 1934 :__ 21,240.96 Bonds Redeemed 203 179.45 Agriculture College Land Principal 3,742.46 206,921.91 228,162.87 Bonds Purchased 203,091.63 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 25,071.24 Schedule C-4. NORMAL SCHOOL ENDOWMENT FUND Balance June 30, 1934 4,285 68 Bonds Redeemed 58.349.00 2 - 62,634.74 Bonds Purchased 58 488.28 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 4,146.46 Schedule C-5. SOLDIERS RELIEF FUND Balance June 30, 1934 $ 103,416.34 Bonds Redeemed 888 186.24 991,602.58 Bonds Purchased 922,697.20 Balance June 30, 1936 $ 68 905.38 Schedule C-6. BESSEY MEMORIAL FUND Balance June 30, 1934 128.14 Bonds Redeemed _ — 128.14 Bonds Purchased Balance June 30, 1936 $ 128.14 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">REPORT OF SCHEDULE 11. GASOLINE TAX DISTRIBUTION TO COUNTIES Representing three-eighths of gasoline tax receipts from June 30, 1934 to June 30, 1936, less transfers to State Assistance Fund. June 30, 1934 June 30, 1935 to to Total June 30, 1935 June 30, 1936 Adams County S 54,339.29 $ 57,898.51 $112,237.80 Antelope County 33,724.59 35,851.67 69,576.26 Arthur County 2,405.61 2,809.91 5,215.52 Banner County ._ 4,793.42 5,085.10 9,87852 Blame County 3,199.04 3,508.20 6,707.24 Boone County 30,859.87 31,866.53 62,726 40 Box Butte County 26,633.58 28,105.03 54,738.61 Boyd County 13.189.83 13,517.97 26,707.80 Brown County 12,002.07 12,373.38 24,375.45 Buffalo County 57,731.33 61,347.13 119,078.46 Burt County 30,912.13 32,266.89 63,179.02 Butler County 34,289.18 35,877.66 70,166.84 Cass County 43,698.20 47,112.59 90,810.79 Cedar County 32,102.86 32,475.78 64,578.64 Chase County 13,050.37 14,132.64 27,183.01 Cherry County 21,239.10 22,013.23 43,252.33 Cheyenne County 27,012.99 27,684.89 54,697.88 Clay County 33,286.61 33.891.06 67,177.67 Colfax County 28,254.26 29,410.26 57664.52 Cuming County 33,874.66 35,887.01 69,761.67 Custer County .. 56,120.44 56,778.54 112 898.98 Dakota County 22,938.38 23,251.52 46,189.90 Dawes County 23,097.03 24,260.66 47,357.69 Dawson County 43,748.61 45,700.39 89,449.00 Deuel County 12,567.23 12,019.37 24.586.60 Dixon County 23,384.00 24,651.94 48,035.94 Dodge County 63,757.03 66,598.77 130,355.80 Douglas County 449,940.46 474,779.14 924,719.60 Dundy County 12,372.65 13,402.79 25,775.44 Fillmore County 32,636.75 31,842.94 64,479.69 Frankhn County 21,191.52 21,229.32 42,420 84 Frontier County 17,955.82 18,975.63 36,931!45 Furnas County 27,193.77 28,471.84 55,665.61 Gage County 71,608.65 74,028.14 145 636.79 Garden County 10,891.50 11.253.84 22,145.34 Garfield County 6,392.12 6,906.57 13,298.69 Gosper County 10,944.41 11,093.91 22,038.32 Grant County 3,390.21 3,466.44 6,856.65 Greeley County 15,129.46 14,986.61 30,116.07 Hall County 68,497.04 70,724.51 139,221.55^ Hamilton County 29,344.38 29,759.96 59,104.34 Harlan County 19,002.03 19,677.22 38,679.25 Hayes County 7,609.26 7,861.13 15,470.39 Hitchcock County 15,645.18 17,461.52 33,106.70 Holt County 31,484.71 33,474.24 64,958.95 Hooker County ___ 3,087.92 3,220.01 6,307.93 Howard County 22,334.58 23,018.40 46,352:98 Jefferson County _._ 39,352.00 40,967.01 80,319.01 Johnson County 22,846.25 23,841.07 46,687.32 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE TREASURER June 30, 1934 June 30, 1935 to to Total June 30, 1935 June 30, 1936 Kearney County 20,948.45 21,837.12 42,785.57 Keith County 17,353.80 19,706.41 37,060.21 Keya Paha County 6,728.17 6,223.09 12,951.26 Kimball County 13,733.51 14,670.35 28,403.86 Knox County 35,858.50 37,601.74 73,460.24 Lancaster County 235,623.07 252,214.60 487,837.67 Lincoln County 50,385.86 59,133.57 109,519.43 Logan County 4,448.03 4,652.65 9,100.68 Loup County 3,657.28 4,123.36 7,780.64 Madison County 57,327.60 59,558.79 116,886.39 McPherson County 2,538.16 2,951.81 5,489.97 Merrick County 25,474.93 26,019.80 51,494.73 Morrill County 20,193.35 21,240.81 41,434.16 Nance County 20,077.60 20,655.64 40,733.24 Nemaha County 29,306.86 31,786.60 61,093.46 Nuckolls County 27,935.75 28,523.34 56,459.09 Otoe County 52,174.26 56,189.76 108,364.02 Pawnee County 21,587.11 22,543.61 44,130.72 Perkins County 15,922.05 16,790.21 32,712.26 Phelps County 25,890.20 26,269.82 52,160.02 Pierce County 24,772.79 26,061.42 50,834.21 Platte County 47.519.81 50,908.69 98,428.50 Polk County 26,560.29 27,720.59 53,280.88 Red Willow County 39,628.25 43,392.14 83,020.39 Richardson County 45,413.95 48,885.76 94,299.71 Rock County 6,447.76 7,049.31 13,497.07 Saline County 43,414.68 44,919.11 88,333.79 Sarpy County 27,873.70 30,530.34 58,404.04 Saunders County 51,544.39 54,615.26 106,159.65 Scotts Bluff County 75,935.34 80.669.02 156,604.36 Seward County 41,726.73 42,923.46 84,650.19 Sheridan County 24,419.32 25,896.67 50,315.99 Sherman County 18,98053 19,461.84 38,442.37 Sioux County 10,007.43 10,468.53 20,475.96 Stanton County 18,346.99 18,941.25 37.288.24 Thayer County 32,020.37 32,296.47 64,316.84 Thomas County -2,890.17 3,132.90 6,023.07 Thurston County 18,027.21 18,252.23 36,279.44 Valley County 20,415.68 20,883.98 41,299.66 Washington County 31,233.10 34,29737 65,530.47 Wayne County 26,919.63 27,619.04 54,538.67 Webster County 22,850.48 23,177.11 46,027.59 Wheeler County 4,795.29 5,131.09 9,92638 York County 41,976.63 43,573.11 85,549.74 TOTAL $3,111,947.44 53,270,318.64 $6,382,266.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">REPORT OF SCHEDULE 111. DEPARTMENT EXPENSE Showing unexpended balance of appropriations as of Jnn? 10 icm - amount of appropriations for biennium beginning July 1 1935- amount funiS d l 93 U 6 nng tHe tW ° yearS&gt; 8 " d the balanCe oj!^PPropriaffi onXnd Balance Appropriation Balance , n o c ,. 30 ' July h Amount June 30, 1934 1935 Expended 1936 Premium on Surety Bond *1.50) Pre^umorSur^Bo-nd---- * n °' 000 - 00 4 9 99- 9 6 W00.04 (Deputy Treasurer) "237.50 237.50 TOTALS $16,156.28 :539 817.50 837,536.09 518.437.69 •Lapsed to General Fund. ♦•Appropriations carrying the emergency clause. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>