<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00039">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00039</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Co-Coperative Associations A Survey of the Co-Coperative Associations in Nebraska for the Year 1920</title>
               <date value="1920">1920</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE BUREAU OF MARKETS AND MARKETING LINCOLN BULLETIN NO. 109 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS A SURVEY OF THE CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS IN NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR 192O LEO STUHR Secretary of Agriculture W. C. ANDREAS. Chief of Bureau J. E. FATE. In Charge of Statistics </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CO-OPERATIVE CONCERNS INTRODUCTION Because market conditions have shown the violent changes lately recorded, the average consumer has reached the conclusion that the marketing problem it, the most important of problems. Producers and consumers alike have decided that the ultimate solution of this problem lies in co-operation. When business is organized on a co-operative basis the greed for gain is eliminated and thus the margin between price and cost is lessened. As a result there is at present an unusual interest in co-operation, its causes and its effects. From the standpoint of finance the co-operative organization is promoted in order that the patron may - have returned to him, in the form of dividends, any surplus which may accrue as profit above the expenses of running the business and the amount which must be set aside to cover unlooked for losses or natural depreciation. But analysis sometimes shows that in eliminating the individual greed for profit the individual initiative is also eliminated. Too many times the owners of stock forget their ownership and go where the higher price is paid temporarily, regardless of the fact that they may be helping to ruin themselves. Upon a study of the Rochdale plan, it is shown that true co-operation involves three features: First — One man, one vote, regardless of the stock held, Second — A division of profits on a patronage basis, and Third — A limit on the rate of dividends on stock. The Rochdale pioneers went further than this and co-operated in the truer sense of the word. They realized that a co-operative society was their society and that any lack of patronage on their part meant that they were not patronizing themselves to that extent. In order to aid any movement facts concerning this movement must first be secured- These facts must bring to light the progress secured in the past and the methods of securing the progress together with the plans for the future and the obstacles which may retard or prevent the successful completion of these plans. For these reasons a survey of co-operative concerns in Nebraska was made in 1920. This covered the calendar year 1919. The results of this survey were published as Bulletin 108. The nature of the replies and the information thus secured served as an aid in preparing a new questionnaires. This was sent out to 740 Nebraska organizations which, by nature of the name, appeared to be co-operative. A letter was enclosed requesting that the concern fill in the questionnaires and return at once. The information gives was to be from the 1920 record. Table I is a copy of the blank sent to each of the organizations. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS TABLE I State of Nebraska Department of Agriculture Lincoln QUESTIONNAIRE— CO-OPERATIVE CONCERNS 1. Name of Company 2. Place of Business (Town) 3. Incorporated (Yes or No) Date 4- President Address Secretary Address Manager Address Total shares Of Stock sold Total No. of Stockholders 5. 6. Par value of shares 7. How many shares can one person hold 8. If Farmers Association, do you sell shares to other than farmers— 9. What is you fixed rate of dividend on stock 10. Are profits distributed on patronage basis 11. Has each stockholder one vote regardless of shares held by him 12. Is your business property and equipment owned or leased 13. If owned, state value If leased, annual rent__ 14. Average amount of capital borrowed during year 15. Average rate of interest paid on borrowed capital 16. Give largest and smallest amount of borrowed capital during the year and time when each is borrowed: a. Largest amount Date borrowed b. Smallest amount Date borrowed.- Give average amount borrowed continuously— 17 J8. Volume of business for the year 19. How many dollars total income from each $100 volume of business 20. Name commodities handled: As a selling organization As a buying organization 21 Give estimated per cent of volume of business: As a selling organization As a buying organization 22 Estimate amount of capital for each purpose 23. Do you set aside a reserve fund How much 24 In what way can co-operation be furthered in Nebraska— (Date) (Signed _..- Secretary or Manager JILL OUT AND RETURN AT ONCE </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 5 The commodity or commodities handled has quite an influence on volume of business. It also influences the margin of profit since some articles can be handled on a narrow margin while others represent a much larger margin as a necessity for successful business operation. Table 2 gives the classification according to commodity handled. This varies somewhat from the classification given in Bulletin No. 108 and shows that the co-operative concerns have branched out more during 1920 and are handling a more varied supply of goods. As those who responded are not always the same as those who responded to the ques - tionnairs on 1919 business, this would also cause a variation in the classification following. This is minutely classified as it is evident that a difference in commodity affects volume. Grain and livestock do not represent the same profit in respect to volume as grain and machinery, although elevators handle these things. For this reason Table 2 contains the subdivisions of elevators according to commodities sold or bought. For the purpose of comparisons, both with other concerns and with 1919 figures, the tabulation made in Tables 3 and 4 shows number and average capital. Both average credit and average continous credit arp given in Tables 3 and 4. In figuring average credit, all amounts borrowed were considered. In figuring average continuous credit, amounts borrowed for a short time only were not considered. A ref - erence to Table 1 will show that through the questionnaire, figures were secured on the average credit and the average continuous credit. . By adding the continuous credit to the capital, as stated in the tables, the result shows actual capital used during the year which should be capital stock, rather than borrowed funds aside from capital stock. In Table 3 both volume and ratio are given. The ratio is computed by dividing the volume by the capital or the volume by the sum of the capital plus continuous credit, which is the actual capital used since the continuous credit represents the amount borrowed continously and does not include exceedingly large amounts borrowed for very short periods. The ratio of volume to total average credit is also given and is of use in interpret - ing the business- By studying Table 3, one is able to determine to some extent the class which is the more prosperous. Compare those who handle grain only with those who handle grain and coal. Coal does not appear to increase the volume of business materially, nevertheless the answer to question 19, Table 1, tells an interesting story. It is found that, on an average, those answering this question report a low income when Handling grain alone, but a much, higher rate when handling coal in addition. During the past year, when grain prices tumbled over night, the elevator which handled side lines of coal, etc., was the one which was tided over the situation more easily. In the handling of coal, idle capital was used and the profit made on coal balanced in part the loss on grain. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS TABLE 2 — CO-OPERATIVE CONCERNS (Separated according to commodity handled) Elevators Grain 38 Grain (Flour &amp; Feed) 10 Grain and Coal 63 Grain, Coal and (Flour) 6 Grain, Coal and (Peed) 10 Grain, Coal, (Flour and Feed) 22 Grain, Coal and Machinery 9 Grain, Coal, Machinery, (Flour and Feed) 24 Grain and Livestock 16 Grain and Machinery . 4 Grain, Coal and Livestock, (Flour and Feed) 12 Grain, Coal and Livestock 14 Grain, Machinery and Livestock 2 Grain, Coal, Machinery and Livestock 9 Grain and Farm Supplies 5 244 Elevator and Lumber Yard Grain, Coal and Building Material 26 Grain, Coal, Machinery and Building Material 8 Grain, Coal, Machinery, Building Material and (Flour) _.. 3 "Grain, Coal, Livestock and Building Material 11 Grain, Coal, Livestock, B'ld'g Material (Flour and Feed) 2 Grain, Coal, Machinery, Livestock, Lumber and Cream 3 Grain, Livestock, Machinery and Building Material 3 56 Lumber Yard Building Material and Coal 4 4 Implements 5 5 Creamery 13 13 Store Merchandise 74 Merchandise and Machinery 40 114 Store and Elevator Grain and Merchandise 8 Grain, Coal, Machinery and Merchandise 16 Grain, Coal, Machinery, Merchandise and Livestock 15 39 Livestock 1 1 Social 1 1 Elevator, Store and Lumber Yard Grain, Coal, Merchandise and Building Material 2 Grain, Coal, Building Material, Merchandise and Livestock 4 6 Telephone 2 2 485 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 7 In a comparison on capital tied up in the business, it is found that in a large percent of cases, the business property is owned. This of course, is as it should be, but we find in this, as in the survey of 1919 conditions, the capital is totally inadequate, as in many cases it does not cover the value of the property when actually it should provide for a working capital to be used in buying and selling the commodity handled. This cannot be explained by stating that it would result in much idle capital as the amount of capital borrowed continuously shows the contrary. And since it is necessary to borrow this amount contin - uously (Table 3) would it not have been better had this been in the form of stock, thereby avoiding a possible call for payment of borrowed funds, which call, invariably in the economic relation of things, comes when the money is most needed in the operation of the business? Due to the fact that some concerns had changed ownership or from some cause were not in operation, and that others, although farmer companies, stated that they were not co-operative, it was necessary to discard many replies. When the work of tabulation was begun, there were on hand five hundred questionnaires. Of these, seven were dis - carded as not being co-operative and eight were new companies which left 485 which were considered sufficiently representative to be of use. The results of the work are given herein with such explanations as may be deemed necessary. DEFINITION OF TERMS The terms used in this article are defined below in order that there may be no confusion in ideas- Patronage — By this is meant the patronage dividend which is a dividend declared on the basis of goods bought from the concern or sold to a concern by a customer. In some cases this dividend is paid only to stockholders while in others it is paid to all patrons. Non-Patronage — This refers to a business which apportions its divi - dend only on the basis of stock and not at all on the basis of patronage. All truly co-operative concerns should declare a patron - age dividend. Capital — This is the money secured from the sale of stock and does not represent any surplus or reserve. Credit — Total continuous credit is the total of the average amount borrowed continuously for use in conducting the business. Total average credit is the total of the average amount borrowed during the year, including amounts borrowed for both long and short periods- Volume — This refers to the amount of business for the year in terms of dollars. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 0 ° eH "3 I oqoON«si&gt;to«fiiflOMi-joooio«q o 508 .«* hS . • 'c "3 oo q o; ■* in oq q -; io ■* co q e; to BjjJjWQ'' i-H r-1 i-l iH i-l iH i-H iH i-H i-H S •,- — a to Tt ia m co ih m_ p 05 eo © t^ oq to «^*3r5 il i! — tooi-ioc-t-oooNoont-wwio ! i, &lt;u * "a E O e iP. e S.°^.®_ e£ J. o i'^. li ?.®. u ?. e^. a i 0( i S &gt; m | H ® c~ c l'1 l? i c 'I' 5 l c 'l &lt;3 l r l'^' c i. 00 .. T ~ l f"! 05 §Wj J&gt;^ OO^OMMMOt-OiOOOlOO IS i -^ 6»*i ioo«on»i»««ot-oooio •rf ' s «ti «i 0 i T] l l o. 0 o. e i. l ».'^.'»,'n, 0 i'0.o.oi. c i. Em o S Ji ei oi oi oo to n£ &lt;6 \a \a ii ao ao t^ Q i PS "* E- i H ft ; Pu "S»J-— ©ocioooo-Hooc-oomm O ' 5 s "5 »t*."l°. l8 . l&gt; l o . o . o .«.t o . t -. lf l COO. ' U « io .:- -^ eo ;-; r- « &lt;M _ _ o o^ W O || i •• J I lOiaoo^oooooiOLnootD S5 — ' *~ '^'o'-^'o'o'c^'co^ia''— 1 1-^ t--" t-^" co^ co" c--" H 0 (8«ftlSM00l«nNMNHHa^ i i i i i i i *5 i i -o i i i i I I I I I I I V I I 9 I I I I I I I I I I 1 ,* I I « I I I I ! 1 ! ! ! ! fc ! !&amp;• ! ! ! ! 1 1 1 1 1 1 ll I tl I l-i i ! ! IS !E ! IE ! !3 ! ! ! ! :|^ ! !~ '*.« ! i itsilJ elf lit &gt; q c" c g c" g" c" g" c c g" sf c" c" c j '§ 'S 'H 'a 'a 'a '§ 'a 'a 'a 'a 'a 'S a a </seg>
            <seg id="p009">CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 9 .2 Oc3« i-HCO^OirJcicieoci'^ coco i/j z C r- 5 2i ffl i5i If— OOOU50000MO O© © S ' *h ■ "5 Sf-- ifl©ot-ifl©©©w© o© © OS q 5 2"° t^.' / 5. 5^. o . &lt; H u ?. c i c ?. c^.' = 2. &lt;= i. o ~ °_ E^ « e u £ o'^-Tc-^'^cc't^c^'-^' io"oo" Ato of ;/! HTi o«omco-*_ t i-H — in© © t&gt; iflO o o eo o o© © -5? 5^ — %t: *f? _.•" O OiOOOOOO © O C~ o — '-S lO ol-ooooo o o © OU5OOOOO © © 32 lOOCiC U5OO CM © 5§2 §2 HUcj oo« eo « eo P a. 9p -:/=- H " J^- ) -^.^ TTU3XC: C.tONt-X'- XN O TjinMCCltONt-X'- XN O «S H^ ■S'S ■h'io m O © NlOrlHMM ■&gt;» H a 2. - « 58 O NH-^rtN-*(NH^^ CO^H t-H r- 1 &lt; a ■— ~. X U i i i i i i i i i i i i"9 i i "p i i i i I I I I I I I V I I &lt;b I I I I I I I I I I I -*&gt; I I V I I i I I I I I I I I &amp;-, i i r£. i i I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I s^S-^ n &gt;h 03 oi -i i&gt; m t-" ei «o cot-' d Sji 10010H«10«)0^« OO CO — ~Z = t-U3r4NCCOXOQ0(0 OO [r- ! ! ! ! ! !* !!«!!!! t ! I Mil Kill! c .c"_c _s.S.S.B.S.S .£ .s".£".S^.£".S woooooooooouoooo </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 •p* -w w . o • C « ■ I •5 s Q © 5 u — &amp;«■£ 5 5-9 -c 3 -*_' ii? e £ 5g? »5 £ a f-Qu o Q H P3 "— IS 23 z c CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS * °3 "a "? 00 . ei ? c 7 * "2 °5 *"? . . »? oseocoo *'&gt;'-; "? ►o°g ** W rt i-H r-( MiOHCi O -H O O5 O O &gt;2 &lt;OMt-t- COO500 •»* t- ■* oi" co '-I' n S*^j OC&amp;OOOOO OO —• M.-S oimoc- oioo ioo 03C8-C 0«OOK&gt; CJ."?.'l. N 00 — o o o o ooo o o ■ijr ooooc- ooo o© 5S^ O HO00 0.0,-^ O5. US. O * hi hNOCO "-■ &gt;-l &gt;-i O 00 f&lt;yn jjNM^ eo io co eo oo OOOO OOiA OLO __«a cooooo oot- «o t- **-a o""'«*''t'eo coefc^ "5 t- ,oft t-iet-H coco HjS IO (N CO &gt;-i &lt;M O C^ 00 CO O NMCC "5 O i u : is : i i ! IS IE !« ! ! ! i 2'*ill^# si J i S 22 22 2 2 2 I =3 | g i in 1 h^ </seg>
            <seg id="p011">CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 11 |.as**ssi «^|5|! d si d 1 5 © — &gt; Z Ed •» o 3?| II II 5 — j -ts S 2 o o § li's 8 i § § I « g !« o o •35 « « g g I If |S ill I i i I l :i s P 111 ! ! |s-gi;-§isi a " IllallJlJ i€ i I | i4444*44 1 1 3 1 l! ii I, </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 RATIVE ASSOCIATIONS .2 =«875 . T-&lt; t-; O •&lt;* CD a&gt; .4. co co ci co — r — r-l CO MOt" to oi '-I rH CO Cft Oi 00 00 t- "5 CO CO «C O 00 a i 0) II ooh (Oho m m co oo us \aci t£ tS tN Wist- 00 tO eg " 1 ail »» ocoo o o ON ODOiS O O oq^ onh o o ■*m &lt;ohn io oo I SO Ci O O© O O lO CO OOlO O S cooo" t-^oo'o' o" on" •a 3 C-rt OtOffi O0 050 OO-^ CJCftt- Tt OOliS &lt;N oo co"co"d" ui" eo" ICO (MOO'H lO CO corn e»(Nico »h 6 OJCO t-lO-* rH IM ■* «O CO iH rH ;; ■ !&gt;M i ii II I I V I I ■ I i \t \ I i g i J i i | &gt;&lt;r» j ■ i u -c i BB . « i || gl 68^ ! g«S ! is Sw M |plL g II p'§22 e s aii a. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 13 .2 »&lt;« i 5 HIM 5| Ml — &lt; «&gt; —1 — 1« 1-1 •2_: A ■g o e « fc ~ £ - s E ll Si ho I CO t- CC O CO »Ol': co 06 00 C-U3 O 00 O O © rto o coo o 5 CS O WHO 1 ;j •4 &lt;u s IP 25 Ll 1 ' S - ia «(9- Tf CO OOO 00-* OOO oj 00* u^cT T CO © © © 00 -* ©00 ■^^ lO^O © 00" c^ 00 i^cT CO ■»!• ae- I : ll *6 © UO © © © © © NrH © © © © O0 «O_ CS_ ©_ 5O © CO © 00"t-" SOt-ToJ {vf ■MX WH «(9- H i (M t— -H -H »H 1— I 5v| 01 1 i i i 3 I 3 as I 08 ! I i i- 8 i i SsJ i i i i i !| i i l s s; ; is as 'si i *«- i g^-g ea c c c g s &gt; cctS w g|| g'ggg &gt; g 311 £ </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS INTERESTING AND VALUABLE DATA SECURED The answers to many of the questions asked (Table 1) are both interesting and valuable. In checking up the answers to question No. 5, it is found that 485 co-operative organizations in Nebraska have sold o-'er 213,351 shares of stock and these shares are held by 57,756 stock - holders. This is a good index to the spirit of co-operation prevailing and shows that especially among the fanners the idea of joining forces for the purpose of cutting down marketing costs has gained a much gTeater foothold. Of the total stockholders, 50,665 own stock in 401 con - cerns which declare a patronage dividend while the balance own stock in organizations which do not declare a patronage dividend. The elevators have 27,162 stockholders owning 79,762 shares of stock. The patronage elevators have issued 69,321 of these shares to 23,159 stockholders. Of the stores a large per cent declare patronage dividends. (Table 3) Stock in these patronage stores is distributed among 11,421 stock - holders which is the greatest proportionate number, averaging more than 120 stockholders to each of the 95 stores. It is of interest to note that these stores, averaging 120 stockholders each, had a total volume of business of $8,076,989. (The patronage elevators have a total volume of business of $42,702,953). These figures have an important bearing on the question of co-operation, its advantages and the obstacles to its success. A LARGE PER CENT OF STOCKHOLDERS ARE FARMERS In answer to the question "Do you sell shares to other than farmers", 179 answered in the affirmative, the balance answering "No", thus making it clear that the majority of the stockholders of co-operative companies are farmers. Of those who restrict their stock to farmers only, there were 261 of the patronage concerns and 45 of the concerns not declaring a patronage dividend. In the organizations classed as elevators 65 or 33% 9^ of the patronage concerns sold stock to other than farmers. This is interesting to note in view of the fact that with a patronage dividend there could be no hope of securing more than a normal return on the investment in stock, if the owner was in no way interested in farming. Apparently the explanation lies in the fact that many belong to these concerns who are farm owners and wish to help sustain the co-operative organization in order to provide a better market for their share of crops than might otherwise seem to be probable. Of those elevators not de - claring a patronage dividend 40.4 per cent sold shares to other than farmers. The per cent is not surprising in view of the fact that dividends are declared on a stock basis. STORES VS. ELEVATORS As the store is primarily a consumers organization compared to the elevator which is primarily a producers organization, it was expected </seg>
            <seg id="p015">CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 15 that the stores would show a much larger per cent selling shares to other than farmers. Of stores declaring a patronage dividend, 25 or 40% of those handling merchandise only, sold shares in the patronage con - cerns to other than farmers, while 7 out of 12 of the non-patronage con - cerns sold shares to other than fanners. Of those handling merchandise and machinery 13 out of 33 patronage concerns sold shares to other than farmers. The totals show that of the concerns classed as stores, 46 sold shares to other than farmers, while a majority limited their shares to farmers, and of all stores handling merchandise only, 42 sold to farmers only. Of stores selling merchandise and machinery, 35 per cent sold to other than farmers. The approximate number of those other than farmers was only slightly less in elevators than in stores. These figures seem to point to the fact that the co-operative organiza - tions are composed largely of farmers whether these organizations are of consumers or of producers. AVERAGE RATE OF DIVIDEND The average rate of dividend varied very little, it being eight per cent in practically all cases, altho some went as high as ten per cent and others as low as three per cent. Neither was there any appreciable variance in dividend as concerned the commodity handled, thus showing that the spirit of co-operation guided the stockholder rather than the return on the investment or the degree of risk. The highest rate of fixed dividend was ten per cent and the lowest was three per cent. VOTING POWER Until the adoption of the amendments to the constitution which went into effect January 1, 1921, co-operative concerns could not legally, by articles of incorporation or through by-laws, limit the voting power of the stockholder to a one man, one vote policy. However, in many cases the members of many companies voluntarily limited themselves to one vote per man. Men owning more than one share could, if they wished, cast one vote and although they could have cast more if they had desired, they could not legally be compelled to do so. As a result the answers indicated that in 296 of the organizations declaring a patronage dividend each stockholder exercised only the power of one vote. Of those which do riot declare a patronage dividend, 58 indicate that they operate on the one man, one vote plan. These figures further bear out the fact that the co-operative spirit prevails even in the non-patronage concerns and when by means of education and legislation the way is made clear we may see many more cross to the side of the patronage dividend and true co-operation. In answering question 11 (Table 1) the tables showed 189 elevators giving each man one vote regardless of shares held. Of these, 35 were </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS lion-patronage concerns and although not showing the co-operative spirit when declaring stock dividends, yet they appeared to be willing to limit themselves in their voting power in view of the fact that this could not be brought about by compulsion. Some of both patronage and non - patronage concerns have made note that in some cases the stock vote was allowed although commonly it was not used. TOO SMALL A WORKING CAPITAL Question 13 called for the value of business property. The average amount of money invested in the business property is shown in the table given below. Patronage — Non- Patronage Value of Value of No. Capital Property No- Capital Property Lumber Yard 6 185,397 126,780 By comparing this table with tables showing total capital it is evident that in many instances the amount invested in business property is too large a per cent of the total capital. In fact, with many of the organizations of this survey, the capital as shown by shares of stock, did not equal the value of the buildings and necessarily a loan was carried continuously, no part of which was available as working capital. In considering the capital invested, due emphasis must be placed on the reserve fund. Of the patronage organizations, 291 replied that they set aside a reserve fund and 30 of the non-patronage concerns replied in the affirmative. The total reserve reported was $296,263 by 72 con - cerns. An average of 8 per cent of profits was the amount which 168 concerns reported they endeavored to set aside as reserve. TRUE CO-OPERATIVE SPIRIT SOMETIMES LACKING Of those answering question 24 (Table 1) over fifty per cent ex - pressed the idea, some in very forcible terms, that the main need in furthering co-operation in Nebraska lay in a greater and truer co-op - erative spirit among stockholders of the organizations. From the state - ments made by managers, it is evident that too many people organize in order to secure better marketing facilities or better prices for them - selves, and when these facilities or prices were offered by the competitor, the stockholder forgot the real purpose of organization, forgot that the Elevators Elevator and Lber. Yd. Lumber Yard Implements Creamery Store Store and Elevator Elevator, Store and 197 I 51 5 10 95 36 $2,573,503 $2,226,237 1,460,985 735,648 38,860 14,265 237,775 237,561 1,371,289 411,163 817,955 515,756 47 : 5 4 3 19 3 $451,145 $455,088 66,750 39,586 43,750 22,500 22,206 24,400 216,535 86,499 29,600 32,227 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 17 co-operative concern was his store or elevator and sold or bought where he could get the most for his goods or buy the most for his money regardless of the fact that by so doing he was defeating the purpose of his own organization, and by his lack of patronage discouraging others. Others expressed the opinion that education was the vital point providing this was along the line of the principles of co-operation, as the stock idea prevailed among many. Ten per cent of the answers indicated that those answering considered the legal restrictions too severe and consequently more or less detrimental to the best interests of co-operation. A little over ten per cent of those replying to this question considered that the best method of furthering co-operation in Nebraska lay through the establishing of terminal facilities through teats on the exchanges and the terminal elevator. It is noticeable that the main suggestions of the managers for tHe i nprovement and further success of co-operation came as a request for greater co-operation among the members, either through direct appeal or by a campaign of education along co-operative lines. No one person can make a co-operative organization a success as by its very nature it depends upon the many rather than the few. Merely electing a manager does not insure success although the manager has the greatest of authority conferred upon him. The stockholders must do their part. ANALYSIS BEFORE CORRECTION Before an effort can be made to correct an error that error must be located and its effects analyzed. In social, religious or business life all measurement is made according to surrounding or prevalent standards or units. With a co-operative organization the natural process of measure - ment of the individual concern would be by comparison with the average of other co-operative concerns which were working under somewhat similar conditions as regards commodity handled. In Table 3 is con - tained much material which, when properly used, may serve as a unit of measure and analysis. It may be that the concern is handling grain and coal and the directors are anxious to know how this particular business lines up with the average. The tables also show the number of elevators operated on the patronage plan and the total capital, con - tinously borrowed credit and total volume of business. This means an average capital of $11,323 each, average credit of $4,449 and average volume of $187,104. Possibly the business in question has more capital ond less volume. Further comparison, however, may reveal the fact that when average continous credit is added the ratio of volume to capital is larger than the ratio of average volume to average capital, or the reverse may be true. Possibly a larger per cent of capital is invested in business property than is the average case. Since the average investment in business property represents too large a per </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS rent of the total capital at the present time this would mean that the working capital was entirely too small for successful business operation. A comparison can be made between patronage and non-patronage concerns. In many cases it is found that the ratio of the average volume to the average capital or the capital plus credit, is as great or greater in non-patronage concerns than in patronage concerns. This would give rise to questions concerning managers efficiency. Are the managers of non-patronage concerns more efficient, and if so, why; or is there a lack of co-operation among stockholders? The best manager in the world cannot run a co-operative business successfully if the members fail to co-operate. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 19 © pa 5 5 E o B. Oc m I on TC O IOM00O I I O IN [j E | » t-_ i o os h o i -« •* O - i O " »" ' M »" M O tt" r H t- t* Ci CO IO &gt; "*. °°. °° ! ih 05 mi | eo "5 £L "-"" i «-? i i in &amp;*ji MOO IOOO I I I I 'to "C^rt^i 000 IOC1O I I I IO Q u f &gt;• M » ItO'-i'to' ' ■•;" g, &lt; i a r S_.*&gt; US O O I O t- © I I I I M : a 4)2 noo locio i i i i in J5 c j »qq ioou) i l ia ■S [S r'? " ' N °° °° ! » &lt;O M ]!■*■ « H U n ' w « to ooog tji CU 'Si ' ' !-* — K 15 5 i SJ MM DO u © MM 5 I es a u s a &gt; H M a 2. O T21000 IOlCOO I 1© I© 5r ■j 5 -&gt;*mio i©k&gt;o© i i oo !e I $ £ Ht;l; I &lt;N leion I O_ I eo oS" -h" » os ! n" « oT !e&lt;ri*r H r^U3(O'&lt;'NMHM CO O J* ' (M I I 00 O tr-lO-^&lt; ICOCSCO*-H I ICM-ri* &amp; -O 1 I »H I I 00 OSO I 0) O Q t&gt; I I © lt~ aj ia h i ia oo t- i i © i eo ■3 e e» t; i os, h es h i t~ico *» s Oj" c-^ I tjT ca to •»&lt;■■ co" ! ioT o_z ©■»»•»* t- t- en mio E-io c-o5;&lt;M-fl&gt;©-H, ©,i5o &gt; n m n« ci i to" i ci" w- ~ ' ' ' ' r -h«o i o on] n i i © i!m -a be X eo to i « to is i i © i _j J 1 g g S8 iSSSS i i 9 i 8 5 &lt; * G^to I©©lO© I I © I© «&gt; _ •■"■ t-lO I O O Cl 19 I 1 © 100 g ' n S CVI TT CO 00 U3 ?- "-I 1" g H « [_) N [- »co rt|,N ■m&gt; -H i ii i eo M IO I O "3 O us I© t- l-^r _ S ©00 I ID t- OO io 100 O I ■3^ io a i oo &gt;-. n a i co i*i "5'S. » o I io" t- h tT I us" "»! |oo~ r°St t- «e eo os t- mh oooo H^ us -* j cm cq ao h I « NmH* I H I I « rj C*~ I U3 O L^3 iD I i-H $0 1 vH »X C5 IO I H O CO I I O U i i I I ! I II i I i | S j j j i J I | - i i ! Ij I ill 121 !1S, I | H ! In u i ! 2 Z g &amp; [ i « iiif ' to « j ti B v « a s a J a t illiliHii i^ i i i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS In Tables 3 and 4 it is shown that in some lines the volume ratio to the capital or capital plus credit is greater with patronage concerns while in other lines the reverse is true. A study of these tables brings out the fact that the patron in selling apparently goes where the price is the highest. In the tabulation of stores the following figures serve as an index: STORES •Patronagi •Non-Patronage- Average Average Average Cont. Average Cont. No. Capital Credit Volume No. Capital Credit Volume 95 $14,435 $6,861 $85,021 19 $11,396 $4,263 $63,073 It is here noticed that the ratio of volume to capital is greater in case of patronage concerns than non-patronage. When capital plus continuous credit is considered the ratio of larger volume in patronage concerns is even more marked, even when the capital involved in the patronage concerns is much larger than in those not declaring a patron - age dividend. It becomes clear that when the patron is buying, the patronage dividend is a mighty force in securing his trade. The inter - pretations and analyses which can be made from this tabulation must necessarily vary according to the application which each manager may make to his particular situation. NECESSITY FOR STANDARD ACCOUNTING METHODS There is a need for standardization of accounting methods if com - parisons are to be made and conclusions drawn for the benefit of co - operation. By use of standard accounting systems the different con - cerns would be able to draw conclusions through averages applied as a unit of measure to each business. A leak cannot be remedied unless it is first found. If the method of bookkeeping is poor there is always a chance for an undiscovered loss. The manager of a large factory knows exactly the cost of each piece of work or material that goes into a manufactured article. This is done through the medium of accurate accounting methods. If one is in doubt as to the reliability of a measure or weight, this measure or weight is compared with a standard unit. In case of doubt in running the affairs of a factory or other business concerns the manager compares his business with the average of those with which he comes in contact. By using this method the manager is able to find out where his business stands with reference to the average; both as a whole and in its separate parts. By this method he discovers where he stands above the average and why and where he falls below the average. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 21 REPORTS SHOW GROWTH IN CO-OPERATION A few comparisons of 1919 business with 1920 business bring out some data and some important changes. Although the number of elevators reporting is practically the same, a much larger per cent report patronage dividends. The average capital reported for patron - age elevators in 1919 was practically the same as in this report. The average credit, however, is about 91 per cent as great in 1920 as the year before in spite of the fact that credit conditions were greatly in - flated in the early part of 1920. Average volume reported was $214,038 for 1919 and $216,766 for 1920. Stores have also shown a growth as 17.7 per cent of the 1919 reports were so classed while 23.5 per cent were classed under stores according to the last report. The increase in their volume of business of 1920 over 1919 is noticeable in view of the fact that there was not the same relative increase in capital and credit. Further evidences of growth may be observed from the summary following which gives some total figures for each year for the purpose of comparison. CONCLUSIONS 1. The largest proportionate number of the co-operative concerns reply - ing were classified as elevators. The next largest were stores, of which 40 per cent more replied in 1920 than in 1919. 2. The percentage of gross income varies widely with commodity handled. This shows that large volume does not necessarily mean large profit. 3. Although a large per cent set aside a reserve fund this reserve is not proportionately large enough to offset the need for additional capital. As a result, too many are depending on too large an amount of capital borrowed continuously. 4. The working capital is too small in proportion to the total capital- 5. Continuously borrowed funds form too large a per cent of the working capital. Additional stock would decrease the need for borrow - ing and thus eliminate the risk which always comes when depending too largely on borrowed funds. 6. The large number of stockholders in co-operative concerns means a strong tendency toward co-operation in Nebraska. That so many of these are farmers is evidence that the strength of the co-operative movement lies in rural communities. 7. Too many fail to realize that a stockholder in a co-operative organ - ization is aiding himself when he patronizes his own company. 8. In general, of the patronage concerns classed as elevators, the largest Lumber recorded grain and coal as the commodities handled. This in </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS itself is an index pointing to the business which produced the most profit. Further investigation showed that these concerns had proved to b? the most profitable in 1920. This is due in a large part to the fact that profits on coal offset, to some extent, losses on grain and goes to prove that the largest volume of business does not always indicate the most profit. 9. Considering capital invested, volume of business and necessary credit those handling merchandise appeared to realize more actual profit than those which were classed as" stores but handled machinery in addi - tion to merchandise. 10. The continuous credit forms too large a percent of the money used as capital. 11. Under 1920 conditions a large volume sometimes meant a large loss. It must be remembered that 1920 conditions were abnormal. TABLE 5 — SUMMARY OF REPLIES RECEIVED FROM QUESTIONNAIRES SENT TO FARMERS CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS 1920 1919 Number of questionnaires sent out 641 740 Number of replies received 520 566 Number of replies used in subdivision on basis of commodity 494 485 Number further tabulated 485 485 Number who returned profits on stock basis only 111 84 Number who returned profits on patronage basis 374 401 Total capital stock, non-patronage firms $ 886,260 $ 832.360 Total capital stock, patronage firms 6,491,886 6,688,244 Maximum interest paid on stock, 485 firms 20% 10% Minimum interest paid on stock 3% 3% Average interest paid on stock 8% 8% Total borrowed capital, patronage firms $ 4,358,487 $ 4,020,165 Total borrowed capital, non-patronage firms 1,385,481 574,305 Total volume of business, patronage firms 87,147,404 79,659,637 Total volume of business, non-patronage firms 25,222,665 13,354,472 Maximum interest paid on loans 10% 11% Minimum interest paid on loans 5% 5% Average interest paid on loans 7%% 7%% 'r Number who have reserve fund 369 321 Number not having reserve fund 116 164 Lowest par value per share $ 5 $ 1 Highest par value per share 225 200 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>