<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00006.00004">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>npd.00006.00004</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1900</title>
		             <date value="1900">1900</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-26</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-05-31</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-12-15-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1900 v Prepared by S. C. BASSETT Secretary Nebraska Dairymen'* Association • FREMONT. NEB PRINTED BY THE FREMONT IRIUI'.IK </seg>
            <seg id="p003">• </seg>
            <seg id="p004">.1 Nebraska Dairymen'* Association, I Secretary's Office, Gibbon, Neb., Jam aky i, 1901. \ His Excclltncy, Ckas. II. Dietrich, Governor of Nebraska : Sir: — In compliance with the law in this case made and pro vided, I hereby transmit the annual report of the Nebrask Dairymen's Association for the year 1900. Respectfully yours, S. C. BASSETT, Skoiktaky. </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">TABLE OF CONTENTS. Officers and Directors 8 List of Members 9 Program 14 Dairy Exhibit 16 Proceedings Sixteenth Annual Meeting 19 The Skimming Station 20 The Hand Separator 21 The Babcock Test 22 Report of Treasurer 24 Report of Auditing Committee 27 Dairy Exhibit „ 27 Butter Making 28 Discussion 36 Awnless Brome-Grass for Dairymen 44 Farm Rations for Dairy Cows ' 5 2 A Comparison and Analysis of the Different Systems of Handling Milk 62 The Raw Material for the Butter Factory 77 The Social Importance of Rural Interests 84 Sampling and Testing Milk 88 List of Creameries in Nebraska 96 List of Cheese Factories 101 </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">OFFICERS, 1900-1901. President J. H. Rushton, Fairmont Vice-President E.' S. Snivel y, Lincoln Secretary and Treasurer S. C. Bassbtt, Gibbon DIRECTORS B. R. Stouffer J. K. Honeywell Charles Harding C. A. Clark </seg>
            <seg id="p009">« </seg>
            <seg id="p010">LIST OF MEMBERS. HONORARY LIFE MEMBERS. J. H. Monrad Winnetka, IU. C. L. Gabrilson New Hampton, Iowa W. D. Hoard Fort Atkinson, Wis. A. C. Tupper Osage, Iowa J. G. Lumbard Omaha, Neb. LIFE MEMBERS. Elijah Allen Omaha, Neb. D. P. Ashburn . . Gibbon, " Mrs. D. P. Ashburn Gibbon, " J. Dixon Averj'. . . .Corner Clark and Water Sts., Chicago, 111. L. J. Babcock Gibbon, Neb. S. C. Bassett Gibbon, " Bates, Wilcox &amp; Streeter Omaha, " John Baumer Omaha, u J. M. Bayley Gibbon, " G. W. Bemis Sutton, « J. M. Bennett Hebron, " R. Bingham &amp; Co Omaha, " Henry Bolin Omaha, " W. L. Bovee Gibbon, " W. H Buck Gibbon, " W. A. Carpenter York, " H. C. Carter, box 241 Buffalo, N. Y. H. G. Clark Omaha, Neb. L. S. Coffin Ft. Dodge, Iowa T. D. Curtis 899 North Clark St., Chicago I. N. Davis Milford, Mass. J. H. Davis Gibbon, Neb. J. B. Dinsmore Sutton, " a </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. W. C. Drury Gibbon, Neb Henry Eicke Omaha, " Frank T. Emerson 422 South Fifth St., Omaha, " Germantown Cooperative Creamery Ass'n, Germantown, «• H. Fieldgrove Shelton, " Chas. Finch Omaha, " T. J. Fisher Gibbon, « H. F. Flint Gibbon, F. S. Fulmer Gibbon, " R. W. Furnas Brownville, H. C. Glissman box 685, Omaha, " E. W. Gunther Albion, " J. W. Harrell Gibbon, « Chr. Hansen 17 Dearborn St., Chicago, 111 E. J. Hainer Aurora, Neb Louis Heimrod Omaha, " E. F. Howe Fairmont, " S. W. Hoyt 3-5 Harrison St., New York, N. Y W. H. Ijams Omaha, Neb P. E. Her Omaha, » A. Jones Madison, " H. B. Kelley Inez, " Thomas Kirk ' Gibbon, « Kirschbraun &amp; Sons Omaha, " S. H. Knight 218 La Salle St., Chicago, 111 F. W. Lessentin Omaha, Neb Otto Magenau Fremont, " Markel &amp; Swobe Omaha, " Martyn Bros Omaha, " J. C. Merrill Sutton, Max Meyer Omaha, " Dr. Geo. L. Miller Omaha, Frank E. Moores Omaha, " W. T. Mount Omaha, " M. H. Noble Gibbon, " R. O'Keefe Omaha, " </seg>
            <seg id="p012">LIST OF MEMBERS. 11 Peycke Bros Omaha, Neb. Henry Punch Omaha, " Riddell &amp; Riddell Omaha, «* Allen Root Omaha, 1 J. H. Rushton Fairmont, ** Geo. Schroeder &amp; Co Omaha, " Louis Schroeder ... ; Omaha, ** Wm. Sievers Omaha, " Geo. H. Silvernail . , Gibbon, * J. G. Southwick Bennett, " Chr. Specht Omaha, " J. T. Stanhope Dubuque, Iowa B. R Stouffer South Omaha, Neb. Otto Stuben Omaha, " Wm. Sutton Table Rock, " Julius Treitschke Omaha, ** Troxell &amp; Williams Omaha. " D. H. Wheeler Omaha, " D. H. Wheeler, Jr Omaha, " W. G. Whitmore Valley, " Whitney &amp; Co Omaha, « Wideman &amp; Co Omaha, " H. H. Wing Ithaca, N. Y. Ed. Whittig Omaha, Neb. C. E. Woodruff Gibbon, " T. G. Furgason Beaver Crossing, " Haskell &amp; Bosworth Beatrice, " F. II. Vaughan ...Fremont, **■ J. J. King West Point, • Chas. W. Stevenson Fremont, " ANNUAL MEMBERS. J. K. Honeywell Lincoln, Neb. J. S. Temple Cheney, » J. E. Cullings Wahoo, « August Leader Papillion, " </seg>
            <seg id="p013">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION* 12 P. H. Kennedy Lincoln, Neb V. A. Lagen Star Union Line, Omaha, i. W. M. Bucknum Star Union Line, Omaha, N. N. Bundz Carleton, (i Wm. Ulrich Princeton, &lt;&gt; F. W. Graham 1505 South 26th St., Omaha, Chas. A. Crate Lincoln, &lt; Morris Friend Lincoln, « A. C. Jones Blair, J. R. Housh Fairbury, Ravenna Creamery Co : Ravenna, 4 I. L. Strong Holdrege, ,&lt; F. M. Housh Neligh, E. Rector Crete, J. N. Buck 918 South 31st St., Omaha, H. J. Edholm 1007 Jones St., Omaha, A. M. Priest Lincoln, * C. F. Schwager Ft. Calhoun, Ed. Lytle Omaha, L. D. Stillson York, E. H. Schulte West Point, John Weitzel Malcolm, J. Hess Newman Grove, R. A. Carpenter York, W. J. Colvin Omaha, E. Samzelius Schuyler, Frank E. Moore Schuyler, 1 John McDonald Sutton, Prof. E. A. Burnett Lincoln, 1 Jos. F. Lamb Tecumseh, E. E. Place Albion, A. F. Hartwell Inavale, F. A. Leighton New Hampton, Iowa C. H. Ganson Cedar Rapids, J. F. MacLuman Sioux City, </seg>
            <seg id="p014">LIST OF MEMBERS. 13 J. H. Grommon Manchester, Iowa L. J. Nelson Sioux City, •• M. G. Koepsell Wilson, Minn. Albion Creamery Co Albion, Neb. D. J. de Hoogh Boyden, Iowa L. C. Norton Ft. Crook, Neb. W. Z. King Norfolk, » Guy E. Klumb York, " Herbert Craven Pierce, " E. Sudendorf Elgin, III. G. W. Kelley Afton, Iowa Life membership 95 Annual members • ■ 50 Total 145 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">PROGRAM OF SIXTEENTH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION, LINCOLN, DECEMBER l8, 19 AND 2O, I9OO. J. J. King, president West Point J. E. Cullings, vice-president Wahoo S. C. Bassett, secretary Gibbon PROGRAM. TUESDAY, DECEMBER l8. 7:30 p. M. — This session will convene in the large committee room of the Lindell hotel. Address of president. Report of secretary and treasurer. Appointment of committees. "Merits and Demerits.of Food Commission Law." — Frank R. Hibbard, deputy food commissioner. WEDNESDAY, DECEMBER 19. SESSIONS HELD AT DAIRY BUILDING ON STATE UNIVERSITY FARM. 9:30 a. m. — "Awnless Brome Grass for Dairymen," Prof. T. L. Lyon. 10:30. — "Supplying Milk to City Customers," W. L. Hunter. 1 1 x&gt;o. — "The Social Importance of Rural Interests," Chan - cellor E. Benjamin Andrews. 1 130 p. m. — Governor W. A. Poynter "Buttermaking," Prof. G. L. McKay. THURSDAY, DECEMBER 2O. SKIMMING STATION DAY. — SESSIONS HELD AT DAIRY BUILDING ON STATE UNIVERSITY FARM. 9:30 a. m.— "Farm Rations for Dairy Cows," Prof. E. A. Burnett. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">15 PROGRAM "Raw Material for the Butter Factory," H. F. Mclntosh. "A Comparison and Analysis of the Different Systems of Handling Milk," J. H. Rushton. 1:30 p. M. — "Sampling and Testing Milk," Prof. A. R. Haecker. "Is There Need of a Skimming Station Course at the Dairy School?" S. C. Bassett. GENERAL REMARKS. The package of butter awarded sweepstakes will become the property of the association. For the sessions held at the State University farm, parties will take the Havelock car on O street, running every thirty min - utes, to Holdrege street, where a conveyance will be provided to take all persons to and from the University farm, the convey - ance running to connect with the Havelock car. Persons attending the sessions at the farm are requested to bring their noon lunch with them; hot coffee will be provided for all. At the University farm are many things of interest — a fairly well equipped dairy school, a profitable herd of dairy cows, as well as the various departments of the United States Experiment Station. In discussing "Buttermaking" Prof. G. L. McKay, of the dairy department of the Iowa Agricultural College, will take up the subjects of "Starters — Flavors" and the various methods of determining the acidity of cream. It is desired to make "Skimming Station Day" of real benefit to the operators of skim - ming stations, and Prof. A. R. Haecker in discussing "Sampling and Testing Milk," will make practical demonstrations of sampl - ing and testing, making use of the apparatus of the dairy school for this purpose. Dairy supply men desiring space to exhibit their goods are requested to notify the secretary that ample accommodations may be provided. There will be no session on Wednesday evening, giving traveling men an opportunity to get acquainted and do business with their customers. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">18 NEBRASKA DAIRVMEN's ASSOCIATION. DAIRY CLASS. To dairy scoring highest .....$ 5 00 To dairy scoring second highest 3 00 In addition to above if sweepstakes are secured, $20. Also: To the butter-maker securing the highest score that may be awarded at all of the regular Dairy or Creamery Association State meetings held during the present season, on butter regularly entered as colored with Alderney Butter Color, $100. In case of a tie, or several securing the same score, the $100 will either be divided or drawn for as may suit the pleasure of a majority of the interested parties during the next national meeting at St. Paul, Minnesota. Francis D. Moulton &amp; Co., 169 Jackson Boulevard, Chicago. To the creamery making the best butter salted with Moulton's Cadillac salt, exhibited at the meeting, ten barrels Moulton's Cadallic butter salt; and to the butter-maker making butter winning first prize, $10 in gold, if such butter is salted with Moulton's Cadallic salt. The Sharpies Co., A. W. Rockwell, manager, 28-32 S. Canal St., Chicago. To creamery man securing highest score on butter, if made from cream separated by a Sharpies Separator, one All - over butter printer. To the dairyman scoring highest for butter, if made from cream separated by a Sharpies Separator, one 6-bottle No-tin Babcock tester. The Lindell hotel has kindly placed at the disposal of the association two large sample rooms on the ground floor for the exhibit of dairy products and dairy supplies, and the officers of the association are very desirous of making, at this time, a cred - itable display of dairy products, and urge creamerymen and dairymen to bring with them to the meeting samples of their goods for exhibition or competiton, as they may prefer. Exhibits may be sent — express charges prepaid — to b. C. Bassett, Lindell hotel, Lincoln, Nebraska. Such exhibits will be placed on exhibition and at the close reshipped to the owner. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">PROCEEDINGS OF THE SIXTEENTH ANNUAL MEETING IiF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION AT LlNDELL HOTEL, LINCOLN, NEB., DEC. 18, 1900. Annual meeting, called to order by J. H. Rushton, President King not being present. REPORT OF SECRETARY. Returns from the creameries of the State show that 9,093,706 pounds of creamery butter were manufactured in the year 1900, the greater per cent of which finds a market outside the borders of our State. It is estimated that 6,000,000 pounds of dairy or farm butter produced in the State, has, under the commercial term of "Ladle" butter, been shipped to markets outside our S.ate, making the exported butter product of the State for the year approximately 15,000,000 pounds. This amount is but a small per cent of the butter which might be produced for export from the State or that would be so produced if fraudulent, imita - tion butter products were compelled to be sold on their merits and honest butter had only fair and legitimate competition in the open markets. Until within the past three years, it was thought dairying could only be pursued in a commercial way in the agricultural portions of the State, but it has already been demonstrated that eve'n in the "range" portions, devoted almost entirely to live stock, that dairying can be most successfully and profitably pur - sued. Since the introduction of dairying into this portion of the State it is found that "on the range" are many conditions favorable </seg>
            <seg id="p019">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 20 o the industry. The owner of a herd of cattle has the cows, and as he does little or no farming, he has time to milk, to feed the calves and to haul his milk to the skimming stations. In some instances they do not feed the calves, so to speak, but at night separate the calves from the cows, in the morning milk the cows and during the day allow the calf to follow its mother. To the owner of a small herd, or for instance a couple jus making a start in the world, the annual returns from the increase of a small herd might not be sufficient to support the family, but by milking the cows and selling the butter produc and feeding the skim-milk to the calves, there is a regular monthly income from the dairy for the support of the family while the yearly increase of the herd is in no wise diminished, anc if the "ranchman" keeps a few hens as well as a dairy, the returns are at once so quick and satisfactory as to place the beginner "on the range" in a more independent position than is the beginner in, what are by many deemed, more fertile an&lt; favored portions of our State. THE SKIMMING STATION. Dairying "on the range" does not mean that butter is her manufactured to any extent. In the past thi ee years there hav been established what are termed skimming stations, wher milk from the various dairies is brought, the cream, by mean of a separator, separated from the milk, the skimmed mil returned to the farm or ranch and the cream sent to som central factory, there to be manufactured into butter. Not many years since there were in our State one hundrec fifty or more creameries, engaged in the manufacture of butter and when the annual output of one of these creameries amounted to two hundred thousand (200,000) pounds of butter, it wa thought to be an enormous amount. To-day there are less than fifty creameries in operation. The least amount reported a being manufactured at a creamery for the year, being 27,26 pounds, while one creamery reports as its output for this yea </seg>
            <seg id="p020">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL. CONVENTION. 21 2,250,000 pounds. Tributary to our less than fifty creameries are some three hundred skimming stations, some of these stations being four hundred miles from the central factor] where the cream is manufactured into butter. These last men - tioned stations being in the "range" sections of the State; am that the dairy industry is taking a firm hold in that section is best shown by the fact that the business is rapidly increasing the increase for the year being from twenty- five to fifty per cent over the previous year. THE HAND SEPARATOR. Even under the skimming station plan, the hauling of the whole milk from the dairy to the station and the return of the skimmed milk home is a matter of considerable expense, reduc - ing the price received by the dairyman for his product, as well as materially lessening the feeding value of the skimmed milk. To obviate both of these losses to the dairyman, the hand separa - tor is coming more and more into use. That there was a great loss to the dairyman of butter fat under the old, deep-setting plan as compared with the separator plan is no longer questioned; the saving to the dairyman under the separator plan being from fifteen per cent to fifty per cent, and in numerous instances even more. It is also true that from the standpoint of the dairy - man having ten or more cows, the separation of the cream from the milk at home by means of the hand separator is by far the most practical and profitable plan to pursue; not only is there a lessening of expense in the hauling of cream instead of milk, and an increase in feeding value of the skimmed milk, but there is an independence in the matter of marketing the product that does not exist when the whole milk must be delivered at some central point. Separated cream is a condensed product, and can be shipped to a market hundreds of miles distant if a satisfactory market cannot be found nearer. To the owner of ten or more dairy cows, the hand separator is well worth investigation. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 22 THE BABCOCK TEST. While all well-informed dairymen concede that the Babcock method of determining the per cent of butter fat in milk or cream is eminently practical and correct in principle, and milk or cream should be bought and sold on the basis of its butter fat contents, yet it cannot be denied that there is much dissatisfac. tion and irritation in the use of this method. It would seem that the time has arrived when there should be some legal requirements as to the use of this method. The law is fixed and definite as to what constitutes a bushe or gallon, a pound or an ounce, a yard or a foot, but while the principle upon which the Babcock test is operated requires tha a certain quantity of cream or milk shall be used in making a test, and that a certain measure on the test bottle shows a cer tain per cent of butter fat in the sample; yet no one will con tend that all pippets or test bottles are exact in their measure - ments. Very slight variations in this respect are a sufficien cause for dissatisfaction and criticism, and there is no question that if the law should specify definitely as to what constitutes one measure or one weight, it should for all measures or weights, and it further seems that it would be best for all parties concerned that the law should specify that where the butter contents of milk or cream is bought or sold by the Babcock test it be on the basis of pounds of butter fat, instead of a pound o butter. There is something quite definite as to what constitutes a pound of butter fat, but there may be manufactured from one hundred pounds of butter fat, anywhere from one hundred ten to one hundred twenty pounds of butter, according to the method of manufacture — what might be termed a standarc article of butter, containing from twelve to fifteen per cent o water. There are many other matters of interest to dairymen, which might be mentioned did time permit. The passage of the Food Commission Law by our last Legislature, the almost certain </seg>
            <seg id="p022">23 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. passage of the Grout Bill by Congress, make it plain that dairy - men, like people engaged in any business or profession, must be organized and alive to their every interest if they would succeed and secure their just dues and rights. The finances of the association are in good shape. There is the utmost harmony and good feeling among the members, and the outlook for the dairy industry in. the State is more bright and hopeful. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 24 REPORT OF TREASURER. To the Officers and Members of the Nebraska Dairymen's Asso- ciation : I herewith submit the financial transactions of 'the association for the year ending December 17, 1900: RECEIPTS December 19, 1899, cash on hand • 105 15 Membership fees 40 00 State appropriations 1,031 17 • 1,176 32 EXPENDITURES. December 19, 1899, expenses at annual meeting, 1899 • 600 December 22, Robs L. Hammond, postmaster, postage 4 00 December 22, J. H. Rushton, expense in interest of Food Commis- sion bill 100 50 December 30, attorney's fees, £. J. Hainer and A. M. Post 200 00 January 1, 1900, F. H. Vaughan, secretary, incidental expenses . . 4 75 February 1, F. H. Vauehan, secretary, salary 150 00 February 13, F. H. Vaughan, secretary, expenses incurred at National Buttermakers' meeting, Lincoln 143 82 March 31, J. W. Brewster, stenographer 4 00 March 31, F. H. Vaughan, secretary, salary 75 00 July 21, S. C. Bassett, secretary, salary 75 00 July 27, Fremont Tribune, printing annual report 281 00 October 1, S. C. Bassett, salary as secretary 75 00 November 3, Aurora Republican, printing 9 00 October 5, F. D. Reed, stationery and printing 4 50 November 3, W. A. Rodgers, postmaster, postage stamps 2 00 November 6, Gibbon Gazette, printing 7 10 December 1, Shelton Clipper, printing programs 8 55 December 15, Whitehead &amp; Hoag Co., badges 14 76 December 15, W. A. Rodgers, postmaster, postage stamps 9 85 December 17, cash to balance s vt • 1,176 32 S. C. Bassett, treasurer. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 25 The report of the treasurer was referred to an Auditing com - mittee, consisting of Morris Friend, W. A. Carpenter and B. R. Stouffer. The following committees were appointed: Committee on Resolutions. — J. R. Rushton, George E. Has - kell, J. E. Cullings. Voted to have a Committee on Nominations as follows: A. M. Priest, W. A. Carpenter, J. S. Temple. J. H. Rushton offered the following resolution, which was unanimously adopted: "7ot/te Hon. C. H. Dietrich, governor, Lincoln, Nebraska: The State Dairymen's Association in convention assembled hereby unanimously ask you to appoint to the office of deputy food commissioner of the State of Nebraska, Mr. S. C. Bassett, of Gibbon. Mr. Bassett would bring to the execution of this law a large fund of information, gathered as secretary of this association during the past eleven years; also a wide acquaintance with the dairy conditions in this and other States, and a thorough knowledge of the law under which he would be called to act. We believe further that the execution of this law should be placed in the hands of its friends, and if so placed, we believe that it would prove of great good to the dairy interests of the State." By unanimous consent the following message was sent to Hon. W. V. Allen, Washington, D. C: "Lincoln, Nbbr., Dec. 18, 1900. Hon. Wm. V. Allen, Senate Chamber, Washington, D. C. In the name of seventy thousand cow owners of Nebraska, we ask you to report the Grout bill from committee and become its special advocate on the floor of the Senate. (Signed) Nebraska State Dairymen's Association." Mr. C A. Clark offered the following motion, which was unanimously adoptfd: "That a committee of three be appointed by the chairman to solicit subscriptions to help Mr. Knight in his fight for the Grout bill in the Senate of the United States." 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 26 Pursuant to said motion, the chairman appointed the following gentlemen: A. M. Priest, chairman; J. M. Buck, B. R. Stouffer. On motion a recess of fifteen minutes was taken, to enable the Committee on Nominations to report. The Committee on Nominations reported as follows: "We would respectfully present the following names for nomi - nation : For president — J. H. Rushton. For vice-president — E. S. Snively. For secretary-treasurer — S. C. Bassett For Board of Directors — J. J. King, J. H. Honeywell, C. A. Clari, B. R. Stouffer, Charles Harding. ( Signed ) A. M. Priest, W/ A. Carpenter, J. S. Temple." The chairman suggested that the meeting proceed to the election of each officer in regular order. Mr. J. H. Rushton nominated for president for the ensuing year. Motion seconded and carried, unanimously. Moved that Mr. E. S. Snively be elected vice-president. Motion seconded and carried by unanimous vote. Chairman: We will now proceed to election of secretary and treasurer. Mr. Bassett has been recommended by the committee. Moved that Mr. Bassett be elected. Seconded and carried unanimously. On motion, J. J. King.J. K. Honeywell, C. A. Clark, B. R. Stouffer and Charles Harding were elected directors for the ensuing year. On motion, meeting adjourned to meet at the dairy building, State University farm, Wednesday, 9:30 a. m., December 19. DECEMBER 19 AFTERNOON SESSION. Held at dairy building on State farm. (No session held in the forenoon.) </seg>
            <seg id="p026">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 27 Meeting called to order by Mr. Bassett, who stated that he expected the president would arrive a little later, and asked the meeting to choose some one to preside. Moved that Mr. C. A. Clark should preside. Motion seconded and carried. Mr. Clark: Gentlemen, I thank you. What is the pleasure of the meeting? REPORT OF AUDITING COMMITTEE. Your committee to whom was referred the report of the treas- urer, beg leave to report that they have compared the various items in said report with vouchers on file, and find receipts for all monies expended, and that the expenditures were for the best interests of the association. Morris Friend, W. A. Carpenter B. R. Stouffer. » On motion, the report was received and placed on file. DAIRY EXHIBIT. The following are the scores of entries in the butter exhibit: DAIRY BUTTER. Mrs. J. S. Temple, Cheney 92i D. J. de Hoogh, Boyden, Iowa 944 J. K. Honeywell, Lincoln 96 J. C. Norton, Ft. Crook 92 A. C. Jones, Blair 86 August Leader, Papillion M* E. E. Place, Albion 73* CREAMERY BCTTER. Herbert Craven, Pierce, Neb 934 W. A. Carpenter, York 93 G. W. Kelly, Afton, Iowa 9B| R. A. Carpenter, York 93 W. Z. King, Norfolk M* </seg>
            <seg id="p027">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 28 Guy E. Klumb, York 95* N. N. Bundz, Carleton, Neb 89* E. H. Schulte, West Point 90 M. G. Koepsell, Wilson, Minn 94 E. Samzelius, Schuyler 92 John Weitzel, Malcom 90 J. Hess, Newman Grove 92* Ravenna Creamery Co 93 J. E. Cullings, Wahoo 92 Albion Creamery Co 90* E. E. Place, Albion 73* BUTTER-MAKING. PROF. G. L. MACKAY, OF IOWA AGRICULTURAL COLLEGE. During the past ten years many changes have been made in the "butter business. Many old theories have been laid aside and many new ones taken up. Milk in its natural state is one of the most perfect foods known to man. It contains all the elements necessary to sustain life. It is also one of the most susceptible foods to changes, or, I might say, it is one of the best mediums I know of for the action of good or bad bacteria. If proper care is not observed in regard to cleanliness in all the little details, we cannot expect to have perfect flavor, no matter what methods are adopted at the creamery. If milk is quickly cooled after it has been drawn from the cow, and care has been observed to have all the vessels properly cleansed, it will invari - ably arrive at the creamery in a condition to make the highest grade of butter, providing the maker understands the changes that should take place in ripening. The question of flavor is an important one, especially with butter makers. This is not to be wondered at, as flavor counts nearly half the total in scoring. Now we have no way of deter - mining the flavor except by taste and smell; that is, we have no chemical test by which to measure flavor. Flavor is a very important factor in governing the price of all dairy products; so everything that has any bearing on flavor is very important. At certain periods of the year very little difficulty is experienced in </seg>
            <seg id="p028">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 2 9 producing high-flavored goods. June has been singled out by many as the ideal month. Some have analyzed the grasses at this period to find out what nutrients they contained, so as to substitute these at other periods of the year, but so far there has been nothing definite found to show that feed governs flavor. Not many years ago the cheese-makers in the East selected June as the ideal month for making cheese, but now September and October chee?e sell higher than that made in any other month ; so we find that opinions differ as to what are the ideal months. I do not contend that feed has no effect on flavor, but I do contend that fermentation has a greater effect. A few years ago, when discussing this subject with some dairymen at Topeka, Kansas, one gentleman seemed to think that I did not give June grass due credit for its influence on flavor. Prof. Cottrell, of the Kansas Station, told his experience with ex Governor Morton's herd in New York State. He said he had made butter in Octo - ber that was scored 100 points by Orin Douglass, of Boston, who is considered one of the best judges in America, and the cows had not been on grass for three years. In this case it would seem the June flavor was not what it was supposed to be. I am well aware that certain foods, such as wild onions, leeks and turnips, have a decided effect on flavor unless the cream has been pasteurized. These seem to be charged with volatile acids, as during pasteurization their obnoxious products pass off or evaporate. Pasteurization does not seem to have the same effect on tainted milk, which is caused by putrefactive bacteria, for the reason that the products of these bacteria are undoubtedly non - volatile and do not evaporate. Experiments were conducted in England at the Southeastern Agricultural College, where cotton seed oil cake has been fed o cows to the proportion per cow of from two to seven pounds. Jutter fat gave cotton seed oil reaction twenty-four hours after eeding with the cake, and continued several days after stopping. Amount of cotton seed oil present in butter from cows fed with cotton seed oil cake, less than one per cent. This would indicate hat some feeds have an influence on the fat. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 30 When cows are on dry feed there is a period during the winter months when the average butter and cheese-maker has been unable to make fine goods. This has been attributed by many to the food consumed by the cow and by others to the advanced period of lactation. I remember attending a conven - tion in London, Ontario, Canada, some years ago, when they were discussing the advisability of shipping winter-made cheese to the English market. A prominent buyer and exporter, Mr. Caswell, who was present, got up and opposed the proposition of sending to England winter-made cheese. He said he had never seen but one lot of cheese made in winter that possessed that high summer flavor. He said he was so interested in this lot of cheese that he drove out sixteen miles to find out the secret of this flavor. The only information he got from Mr. Chapin, the dairyman who made the choese, was that he had fed his cows on clover hay and corn meal. Now I was personally acquainted with Mr. Chapin, and knew that this cheese was made from milk of cows well along in period of lactation. While the food used was excellent, I think this high flavor was due to the proper fermentation, as Mr. Chapin from a sanitary point of view, was an ideal dairyman. His stables were light and airy. All manure was scraped into the gutter the first thing morning and evening before the milking was done. The udders were carefully brushed, also, before the milk was drawn. Milk was conveyed to the cheeseroom at once, thus avoiding many of the obnoxious stable germs. This room was usually kept at a moderate temperature, and undoubtedly the germs that got in from the dairy were of the kind that aid in producing flavor instead of injuring it. The germs that get into milk from the stable are far more injurious to the flavor than those that get into the milk when the cows are milked out of doors. I think possibly this is the reason that Denmark has adopted pasteurization of milk so universally, as they stable - feed their cows most of the year. They use a lactic acid ferment for a starter. At our school we made a number of tests of samples of dif- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 31 Ient patrons' milk at different times of the year. Early in ireh a hundred samples of milk were taken, and only I2# r cent showed a pure acid. Flavor 48 per cent impure acid, vor 39^4 per cent rapid decomposition of the curd. Samples ten on April 8th, showed 50 per cent pure acid, flavor 27.7 r cent impure acid, flavor 23.3 per cent rapid decomposition the curd. Samples taken May 10th showed 90 per cent pure id flavor, 10 per cent impure acid, and again on July 10th milk Dwed the same as May milk as regarded pure acid flavor. We also found a lot of milk during the winter that seemed to contain bacteria that had the power to coagulate the milk without souring it. A lot of this difficulty might be obviated if the patrons exercised more care in brushing the udders before milk - ing, and saw that the milk was removed from the stables as soon as drawn from the cow. Many of the conditions that I have just mentioned are largely responsible for the lack of flavor in winter months. The improper ripening of cream is another cause. In the natural ripening of cream the fermentation is due to a variety of organisms that gain entrance into the milk and cream from the time the milk is dnwn until the cream is churned. When cream is ripened by a starter we attempt to control the fermentation by adding a large number of bacteiia of a kind that we expect will give us the desired flavor. Lactic acid seems to be an important factor both in butter and cheese-making. In good cheese we find about 96 per cent of the germs to be of the acid bacteria. In well-ripened cream we find from 90 to 95 per cent. The butter that scored the highest on flavor at the National convention held at Topeka, Kansas, was made at our school, and scored 48.5 out of a possible 50 on flavor. The cream showed 94 per cent of the germs to be of the lactic acid species. In that contest we had a tub of butter from each day's make for four consecutive days. When the judges had scored four days, and selected fifty of the best tubs from which to select the sweepstakes, the four tubs from Ames were among the fifty. When the number was reduced to eleven for the finals, three of the eleven were from Ames. This would indicate that our boys </seg>
            <seg id="p031">32 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. had flavor largely under their control. This phenomenal show - ing would indicate that the boys had the right kind of a starter, and that the cream was ripened to about the right degree of acidity. The temperature at which cream is ripened is not a very important factor, at least not as important as is generally supposed. We have made excellent butter ripening at 90 degrees, and again had equally as good butter ripening at 60 degrees. If I were to give any set rules for temperatures for ripening cream, I should say about 65 to 7° degrees for the summer months and from 70 to 75 degrees for the winter months. It is not so much the temperature at which the cream is ripened, as the degree of acidity to which it is ripened. I would advise ripen - ing to .60 or .65 of 1 per cent of acid. When ripening is car - ried beyond .70 of 1 per cent, we are approaching the danger line, and sour butter may be the result. This will depend some - what on the thickness of the cream. For instance, 40 per cent of cream would contain twice as much fat as 20 per cent cream and less milk serum; consequently could not develop as much acid without endangering the flavor. I saw possibly one of the best butter-makers in the West fail at the National meeting with butter of this kind. He had carried the ripening to .75 of 1 per cent. Butter fat has no flavor in itself, so to speak — possi - bly not more than tallow fat has. We depend largely on devel - oping our flavor from the milk serum in the cream. The high aroma is possibly due to the breaking up of the milk sugar by the lactic acid species, and is possibly a by-product of the same. We use what may be called the fermentation test for selecting milk for starters and for our cream. We take fifteen or twenty samples in glass jars of about a pint each from different patrons' milk and heat them to a temperature of 80 degrees and allow them to sour. Good pure milk will coagulate solid without any pinholes, and sour with a pleasant acid taste. When we find milk of this kind we are satisfied that we have the right kind of bacteria present to produce a good flavor. I prefer a 25 to 30 per cent cream in the winter for making high-flavored butter. Another essential point in the winter is to have a good </seg>
            <seg id="p032">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL. CONVENTION. 33 starter. It is about as important to have good starters as it is to have good seed to sow. The common theory of preparing a good starter is to select a can of good milk and skim the cream from it, and let it stand at a temperature of 85 to 90 degrees until it sours. This would be all right provided you could tell the kind of bacteria present in the milk, but this you cannot do. Hence you do not know what kind of flavor it will produce. The only difference between this and our method is that when we find a sample that sours with a pleasant flavor and is free from taint, we pasteurize a can of our best milk by heating it to 155 degrees, and after keeping it at this temperature for twenty minutes, we cool it back to 80 degrees, and then inoculate it with the best sample we have among the number selected in the different jars. Starters of this kind can be carried forward for a month or so without danger by pasteurizing the new lot each time and then adding some of the previous day's starter. Butter - milk can also be used for a starter for a week or so at a time, when a good starter has been added to the cream in the begin - ning. The principal objection to it is, that if there is any taint in the cream it is transmitted to the buttermilk, and increase* from day to day as the buttermilk is added. The Douglass or Keth culture has given better results than any other commercial starter we have ever tried. If you have a good starter do not be afraid to use a good per cent of it. I would advise using from 15 to 20 per cent. The common theory used to be that when cre'am assumed smooth, granular appearance it was fit to churn, but this is not always correct. I will say, however, that when cream is read to churn it will always have that smooth, granular appearance I presume that some of our prominent butter-makers hav observed the condition of their cream when they have mad some extra fine butter, and found it to have a nice, smooth granular appearance, so this has been handed down to us as test when cream is ready to churn. I have seen cream have this same appearance when it was not near ripe enough to churn. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 34 Good ripened cream should have a sharp, biting, acid taste, but pleasant. The majority of you, I presume, are familiar with the princi - ples of the acid, or alkali test. To those who are not, I will try to explain. We have two tests on the market, the first by Prof. Mann, where a one-tenth normal solution of caustic potash is used. The other is in the form of alkaline tablets, and was first introduced June 3, 1891, by A. W. Stokes, of England. These tablets or pellets are composed of carbonate of soda and phenol - phthalein. The number of pellets used gives in tenths of per cent of lactic acid, the acidity of the milk. The principle of the alkali test is an old one, that an alkali will neutralize an acid or that an acid will neutralize an alkali. By adding one to the other we can bring them to a neutral state, where they are neither acid nor alkali. This is what chemists call titration. Some liquids are acid; vinegar is an example. Others are alkaline; limewater is an example. Others are neutral, neither acid or alkaline; distilled water is an example of these. Now if we take a given quantity of vinegar, which is an acid, and slowly pour in the limewater, which is an alkaline, the alkaline limewater will gradually neutralize, that is, overcome the acid, and a point will be reached where the mixture is neither acid nor alkaline, but neutral. If we continue pouring on the lime - water, the mixture would of course become alkaline. Now if we wished to know the amount of acid in the vinegar, we could find out if we know the strength and the amount of limewater used. If we had two kinds of vinegar we could tell which was the stronger by the greater amount of the alkali required to neutralize the acid in it. In other words, we can measure the amount of acid in one liquid by the amount of alkaline liquid of constant strength required to neutralize it. It is necessary, however, to be able to tell when just enough of the alkali has been added to neutralize the acid. There are some substances that are of one color when in the presence of an acid and another color when in the presence of </seg>
            <seg id="p034">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 35 an alkali. By using some of these we are enabled to determine the exact time when a liquid is being changed from an acid to an alkaline condition. One of these is phenol-phthalein. In the form of a liquid this chemical is neutral and of the color of water, but when exposed to an alkali it changes to a red color. If a few drops of pheno-phthalein solution are placed in a liquid con - taining acid, and if then an alkaline liquid is slowly poured in, as soon as the mixture becomes slightly alkaline it will turn pink, because of the pheno-phthalein contained. With the Mann test a burette holding 50 or 100 c.c. is used. There is a scale on the side of the burette something like that on the neck of a Babcock test bottle. The basis of the test is to take 50 c.c. of cream, add a few drops of the phenol-phthalein and slowly mix in the alkaline solution. When the cream assumes a permanent pink color, rea&lt; the scale on the burette and see how much of the alkaline solu tion it has taken. The reading does not indicate the per cent o acid, but the number of c.c. of the solution it has taken to neu tralize it. If the per cent is desired, multiply the number of c.c. of alka - line solution it has taken to neutralize the acid in the 50 c.c. of cream by .009, and divide by 50 and the quotient will be the per cent of acid. In 1894 Prof. Farrington, of Wisconsin, introduced a table that is very simple and quite practical. With this test five tab - lets are used in a glass cylinder. The cylinder must contain 97 c.c. of distilled water after the tablets have been added and dis - solved. These tablets contain the phenol-phthalein, which act as an indicator so as to give the solution a pink color. The solu tion is mixed in a glass cylinder that has a scale on one side Each c.c. on this scale represents .01 of 1 per cent, so when th cream assumes a pink color, by reading the number of c.c. it ha taken to neutralize the acid, you have the per cent at once. Fo this test, 17.6 c.c. of cream is used instead of 50 c.c. as with th Mann test. If this test is used, I would advise using two cylin ders, as it would take from 60 to 65, or about that, to test th </seg>
            <seg id="p035">36 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION. cream of a morning The remaining solution could be poured into the other cylinder and corked tight for the next day. In using any of these tests, great care should be taken that the solution be kept air-tight, as it weakens very rapidly when exposed to the atmosphere. With the Mann test we usually use a 25 c.c. pipette and multiply the reading by two, which gives the same result, thus saving half the amount of alkali solution. We have found some little variation in the tablets. If some of our chemists would compound a large tablet of carbonate of soda that would be equal to 100 c.c. of one-tenth normal solution, and use a burette with the number of c.c. marked on one side and the per cent on the other, it would be an improvement for practical purposes over the solution or the. small tablets, as there would be less chance for an error with on large tablet than when so many small ones were used. W would get closer reading with the burette than when we used cylinder, as the diameter is much smaller in the former. Th test is sure to come into general use. The progress of dairyin demands accuracy all along the lines. DISCUSSION. Chairman: I would be glad to hear any remarks on this question. The Professor has given us a very thorough and complete exposition of the question of testing the acidity o cream, and to start this discussion I would like to ask th creamerymen here how many used this alkaline test to deter mine the acidity of their cream. I want to find out whether 1 is common to test the acidity of cream in this way. If any us it, will they volunteer to say so — makes a practice of using i Mr. Priest, do you use the alkaline test? A. Yes sir. Q. Do you consider it essential to determine the acidity of cream to have that test? A. Yes sir. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">SIXTEENTH A.NNUAX* CONVENTION. 37 Q. Now it used to be the fact we would dip our finger in and test it that way? A. This test is as essential as in using a thermometer to tell the temperature. Q. I expect that is correct. I have used it some, but not all the time. Any one is privileged to ask any questions of the Professor in regard to this matter. Mr. Leighton: There is one question I would like to ask. How many days does it take to make this starter, and whether he makes a new one every morning? McKay : They usually prepare a starter once a week. Some times can carry a starter for a month. There is little danger of over-ripening a starter. As long as you can ripen it an&lt; keep it at a moderate temperature you can inoculate it with a previous starter each day. Whenever we find a starter gets rank we resort to the old samples and prepare a new starter Mr. Leighton: You say a pound of starter will pasteurize a gallon and a half of milk? A. We pasteurize ten or twenty gallons of milk, as the case may be. We pasteurize as much milk as we need. Now the importance of flavor I don't think is thoroughly understood or realized by creamerymen, particularly when you are shipping your butter to the West. The Hazlewood company, probably the largest in the world, are realizing the importance of flavors. They have engaged two men from our school. One by the name of Mortison to go to Sioux City, and they pay him $1300 a year. His work is to prepare starters and look after the ripening of the cream. They have been so pleased with his work that they have taken another one of our men, and put him at Spokane, Washington, doing the same work, using the alkaline test, and using starters, and watching the question. of flavors. Mr. Brown, the manager of that company, informed me last summer that if their business increased the way it had been doing, they were prepared to pay Mr. Mortison more salary than any college could pay him as professor. Chairman: How much do you think you can increase the </seg>
            <seg id="p037">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 38 flavor of butter, taking, say ioo gallons of cream— divide it into two parts, and take one with a starter, and one without, what would be the difference in the flavors of the two butters, the handling being the same? A. It would depend altogether, or largely, on what the condition of the cream was to commence with. Q. I assume the ideal condition ? A. In the winter-time I think it would make a difference of five points; in the summer-time I would not say it would make any difference. The natural condition without the starter might possibly beat the one with the starter, but I think it is safe to use a starter at all times. In using the commercial starter we have used the Douglas and Keith — one is as good as the other; but some times we can catch a natural starter, by taking a num - ber of samples, as I have suggested, and when we find a sample with a pleasant taste, we are satisfied the right kind of bacteria are present. Q. I would like to ask another question of the Professor. What makes the fishy flavor in butter? A. Have you ever had any fishy flavor here in the West? Q. Yes sir. A. I am not prepared to state just what it is. I have seen but one lot of butter that had a fishy flavor. Q. It is characterized as such? A. There are a great many characterized as such that I thin are due to filth. It is sometimes laid to the salt. I have see such a case in Canada. I scored some butter for Mr. Robert son, of Nova Scotia. It had a fishy taste, and I asked him th cause. He said that the cleanings of fish were put on the lane as fertilizers, and that the cows grazing there had that flavor i their milk. He said all the butter they made there had tha peculiar fishy odor. I think it is usually from a lack of cleanl ness; sometimes the cream is over-ripe, and it gives it a pecu - liarly rank flavor ; it is sometimes termed a fishy flavor. It 1 pretty hard to tell by even examining butter just what causes i Chairman Clark : I want to ask a question in regard to this </seg>
            <seg id="p038">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 39 matter. The Professor has told us that our creamery butter has cored low in this State. Now it occurs to me that possibly this tarter business might help us to ge over this trouble. I would ike to ask the creamerymen here how many use the starter, make a business of using it in their creamery right along. I am asking this for information. I live a good ways west, and when I come down into civilization I would like to find out what he rest of the people are doing. Who uses the starter? It is advertised in the paper 3 a good deal; somebody must be using t. I suppose Mr. Rushton may use it altogether. Mr. Rushton: No sir, I don't. Chairman Clark: Mr. Carpenter, do you use it? A. No sir, not as a rule. We have done some experiment - ing, but never could make it appear to any advantage. Mr. King: I am thoroughly satisfied that we will never occupy an advanced position in the dairy world until we do. Chairman Clark: That is an ideal view of yours. Mr. King : No sir, it is a practical view ; it is a practical thing. It is the thing we are short of in this State. Chairman Clark: I used a starter at one time for two months. I got the Cams bacteria, the first that was used in the East. I used it for about two months. I thought that was just the stuff. I got hold of some that didn't look right and I quit using it. My butter was going to Boston. There was never any difference made in the price. It seems to me that it has got to be like this: a man has got to be a professor in order to make butter. It seems to me we ought to have butter-makers who can tell when cream is ripe enough to churn without having to go through this alkaline process. There is no starter that will take the place of cleanliness properly observed in handling the cows, and the proper kind of food used. We can make good butter.winter or summer. We don't want to get to be too scientific; we want to be practical at the same time. Mr. Rushton : This word "practical" that you use is indefi - nite; anything is practical that will bring money, and flavor will bring money. Now we, of course, had something of an unfor- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 40 tunate experience in the earfy days with the bacteria you have mentioned. Whether it was all due to the bacteria or the man behind the bacteria, I don't know. I have used it myself, will tell you what appears to me to be the condition of things in this country to-day and in this State in particular. There is no enough brains used among butter-makers. Now you say that a butter-maker has to be a professor. Hail the day! Butte is worth twenty-five cents a pound to-day. Where in the commercial world, or where in the industrial world is there to be found anything worth that much that is handled as butte is handled to-day, in the length and breadth of this land.'' You are handling a product that is valuable in which qualit counts. Do you suppose in a large manufacturing establish ment they would allow the finest kind of steel to be handled b a man the way butter is handled — by incompetent people — who bring to bear upon that product of human skill, so little skill Now I believe the time is coming, and I agree with Professo Mackay that the Hazlewood Company have struck a basis tha is killing, but must be followed by every man who wishes to excel in this business. A butter- maker should be a reader, student and a philosopher, for he is handling a valuable foo&lt; product, and the very last tenth part is of just as much impor tance as it is in the quality of the steel spring in the watch you wear. Chairman Clark: That is very true, but there is no educa tion like that of experience. You can take all the young men out of school and put them into practical business, but they have got to get practical education from having the corners rubbw off right in the business. Prof. McKay : The best illustration of the value of a starter is the Sands Creamery Co. We found at the Iowa convention this fall that the three highest scores went to the Sands Company. At the State fair in Iowa the highest also went to the same company. They iise starters in all their creameries. I went into an office in Chi - cago some time ago and spoke about Kansas butter, where Sands </seg>
            <seg id="p040">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 41 tad creameries, and said, "Where do you get all your fine but - er?" They said it didn't make any difference about the States; t is the intelligence displayed by the butter-makers. They told me that if Sands had a man who would not use a starter he would fire him immediately. Chairman Clark: Anybody else any remarks to make on this subject? If our butter score is low in this State, we want to know why. I would like to hear from Mr. Carpenter, as to how their sweepstakes butter was made. Mr. Carpenter: I was not present when the young man prepared it. Chairman: I don't wish to antagonize the educated butter - maker. We must have them, but I stand up for practical knowledge, and I think the creamerymen and butter-makers here do the same. I would rather have a man that is successful in making butter, whether he learned it from his mother or from the Iowa Dairy School, than to have the man who has all the theory in the world and doesn't know how to use it. It takes practical common sense behind education to make a dairyman. We are apt to make too strong statements. We think this is the right way and we state it sometimes a good deal stronger than we ought to. In some places, if not all places in this State, it is impossible to get our cream and milk gathered every day. What is the situation. I know of some creameries where the cream is gathered only once a week. Now it strikes me that the care in handling of this product is worth more than your scientific bacteria and testing. Prof. A. R. Haecker: I think we have an object lesson here in the fact that creamery butter scored low and our hom dairy butter scored high. Our conditions here in Nebraska, a we all know, are very much different than further east, or in som localities North and South. Our dairies are more scattered here and as the President has said, a great deal of the cream is gath ered once a week and brought from long distances. One of ou creameries right in town here is making cream up into butte which has been brought from as far as western Nebraska or even 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 42 Colorado. This is a long distance for shipping, and conse quently a long time for the cream to be on the road, so that th very fact of the condition of factory butter is different than in Iowa or Minnesota, where they gather daily from the patron around a creamery the product brought in every day and mad up while jt is fresh. I don't know as we can lay the blame a the door of the butter-maker who has not used the starter fo poor butter. Il may be true, and likely it is to some extent, bu I don't know as we can say that is the reason. We can undoubt edly improve the flavor of our butter by using starters, becaus we have so many varied conditions — cream that has undergon a great many different kinds of fermentation, some spoiled, am some just right to make up into butter. It is almost impossibl under such conditions to make first-class butter. If this fer mentation has not gone too far I believe cultures could be usec to advantage. Professor Mackay has done a great deal of inves tigation in the use of starters. I suspect no man in this countr has done as much work in this direction as he has. I hav watched his bulletins with a great deal of interest, but I ough to tell you, in my mind I doubt the advisability of establishing small home dairies using starters unless they are obliged t through conditions that are not perfect. I believe that the bes starter is the natural starter. I believe Wisconsin showed som very valuable things along that line. At the same time thei conditions might not have been exactly right. How about that Prof. Mackay: I believe they report the natural starters the best. It seems to me we should U3e starters in our creameries. I am convinced of that. I believe we have to make a strong fight for clean milk before it reaches the creamery. Cleanliness in the barn from the word go. I believe that is the most impor - tant point. If you can make up poor milk into butter at once, I believe you can make better butter than you can a week later on. The remark has been made that cleanliness is of more impor - tance than bacteria. When we have cleanliness we have the right kind of bacteria. When we have filth we have putrefac - tion bacteria. If we have the right kind of bacteria, we will </seg>
            <seg id="p042">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 43 get the right kind of flavor. We depend for the flavor upon the fermentation we develop, and if we have the right kind of bacteria we get the right kind of flavor. With all bacteria, they are destroyed after being developed to a cer - tain point. We might have a right starter and have the milk in the right condition, and providing it ripened to the right point, we might get the right flavor, but if not we get some over-ripe or rank flavor. Professor Haecker has men - tioned the gathered cream system. Of course, the starter will not have the same effect there if the product is already greatly injured. The only method that I have found where I could reclaim was where I could dilute the gathered cream with water, and pass it through the separator. In this manner I removed the casein and added five points to the flavor. Mr. McIntosh: Professor Mackay's last remark seems to cover all the objections the chairman has made to a professor in the manufacture of butter. When the professor could get thi cream, of all conditions and character, take it and wash the casein out of it and mix it with milk and apply the starter an&lt; raise the product five points, does not that prove to you that edu cated brain in butter manufacture is infinitely valuable? You school is nothing but the result of education. What would you starter be worth in my hands in the manufacture of butter, who know nothing about starters. But let me go to your college fo a certain part of the time until I both know the theory and prac tice of using your starter — which is education — and I will gran you, put a starter in my hands, and 1 can do something with it And if an emergency arise, my educated judgment enables me to do what he has done, and your butter-maker to do the same thing; hence the necessity of a professor in the butter factory and the necessity of getting all the science you can into you practical affairs. Chairman: Very true, and I am very glad that we have the professor, an educated man, to give these points. I have made the same test myself in regard to gathered cream, and </seg>
            <seg id="p043">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION. 44 afterwards dilute, and finds it takes out a good deal of the rank flavor. Mr. Bassett: We are very grateful to Professor Mackay for his presence and help, and I move that a vote of thanks be extended to him for his assistance. Carried unanimously. DECEMBER 20— SECOND DAY. AWNLESS BROME-GRASS FOR DAIRYMEN. PROF. T. S. LYON, STATE UNIVERSITY. It is not likely that any plant will ever be found or developed that will in itself fill all the requirements for forage demanded by the dairyman. His wants can only be met by a number of dif - ferent plants, each adapted to the production of feed for certain times of the' year. It is not to be expected that awnless brome - grass will do more than provide one other plant among those adapted to the maintenance of dairy stock, but its relative impor - tance among these plants, especially in central Nebraska, prom - ises to be considerable. This grass has been known in Europe for more than a cen - tury, but its value as a forage crop has not been realized until recent years. Experiments conducted by Stebler and Schroeter at Magocs, in Hungary, and continued through a period of thirty years, have demonstrated that it had the ability to withstand greater degrees of drought than any of the other grasses with which they experimented. Awnless brome-grass, or more specifically, Bromus inermis, is doubtless a native of northeastern Europe and western. Asia. It is found growing at the present time all through that region, where the extremes of dryness, cold and altitude are not exceeded in any of the so-called semi-arid portions of this coun - try. The fact that it maintains existence under such adverse conditions has led to the hope that it would prove of value in </seg>
            <seg id="p044">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 45 portions of this State where the ordinary cultivated grasses do not thrive. In Europe it does not seem to be grown in regions where other cultivated grasses of value luxuriate. Whether this woulc indicate an enonomic inferiority for the grass under conditions generally favorable for grasses, is doubtful, as it is quite possible that its value may not have been appreciated out of its natura habitat. Awnless brome-grass was first sown at the Station in the spring of 1897. A one-tenth acre piece of land was seeded to the grass. It made a fair start, but was soon overshadowed by weeds. The weeds were mown twice during the summer, set - ting the cutter bar high, and raking up the weeds after mowing. The plot was apparently captured by weeds, with a very poor prospect for a stand of grass. It was not until late in the fall, and after the weeds had ceased to grow, that the grass began to thicken. It grew, and remained green late into the fall, and started growth very early in the following spring. Growth began fully as early as with blue grass. By the time weeds made their appearance the stand had thick ened to such a degree that very few noxious plants secured a foothold. On June 23 one-half of the plot was cut for hay. The yield from one-twentieth acre was 349 pounds, or at the rate o nearly three and one-half tons of hay per acre. The remaining one-twentieth acre was cut for seed on July 5. The yield of seed was 37 pounds, or at the rale of 740 pounds per acre. The soil during the winter and early spring of 1899 was extremely dry. The brome-grass did not make a strong growth when it first started, and this seemed to affect it after sufficient moisture fell later on. The grass became green about the latter part of March, and it was not until June that there were any abundant rains. On June 17 the one- tenth acre plot was cut, yielding 300 pounds of hay, or at the rate of one and one-half tons per acre. In 1900, a very favorable season for grasses, the stand was </seg>
            <seg id="p045">4 6 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. thick, but the growth was less and the color lighter than near-by plots sowed the ytar before. The plot was cut June 27 and yielded 580 pounds of hay, or at the rate of a little over two and one - fourth tons per acre. Another plot in the same field, and sown in the spring of 1899, yielded at the rate of 38 tons per acre. On April 23, 1898, Browns ittermis was sown with a number of other grasses and clovers, the mixture being in each case brome and one other grass or clover seed in about equal propor - tions. The mixtures were: Awnless brome-grass and white clover. &lt;t « " " " blue grass. " " " red clever. U (C " " " Russian red clover " " " timothy. " " " alsike clover. « « .« « These grasses all started about equally well, but the clovers made the best showing during the first year. By the second year the brome-grass had crowded out all the other grasses and clovers except the red clover, which has held its own fairly well. Brotnus ittermis, when sown in mixtures, would probably better be used only in small proportions. Its very slow growth the first year gives the other plants abundant opportunity to make a start, but after the first season the brome-grass spreads rapidly A mixture of alfalfa and Brotnus inermns sown April 21, 1899, when cut, June 27, 1900, yielded at the rate of four tons of hay per acre. A plot of alfalfa sown in the spring of 1897, and on which brome-grass seed had been harrowed in after discing in the spring of 1899, yielded at the rate of three and one-half tons per acre when cut, June 13, 1900, being from one-fourth to one-half ton more than that from contiguous plots of alfalfa not having the brome-grass growing on them. The second and third crops of alfalfa were lighter on this plot than on adjacent ones, although this had not been the case in previous years when there was no brome-grass on the plot. For hay production, therefore, a mix- &lt;« t( </seg>
            <seg id="p046">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 47 ture of Bromits inermis with the alfalfa would not seem to be desirable. On the plot where brome-grass and alfalfa were sown at the same time, the brome-grass predominated. Where the brome - grass was harrowed in two years after the alfalfa had been sown, it has not yet become very well established. If the presence of other grasses in the alfalfa field really nul - lifies its tendency to bloat cattle, as has been stated, this mixture should make a very valuable one for pasturage. In the spring of 1898 fifteen acres were sown with brome - grass at the Station. The seeding was done at two differen times; the first on April 2, the new on April 27. There is bu slight difference in the appearance of these different sowings The latter is, perhaps, somewhat the better, but it is doublfu whether this can be attributed to the time of sowing. The weeds were cut three times during the summer. In the following spring a portion of the field was fenced off and included in a pasture which was originally composed of prairie sod, but in which blue grass and while clover had obtained a foothold. The cattle at first preferred the mixed grasses, but later on they showed an increasing relish for the brome-grass. The poorer portion of the remainder of the field was cut fo hay on June 29. It yielded one and one-quarter tons per acre Another portion was allowed to go to seed. It was cut for seet July 24. This was done with a self-binder, setting the cutte bar about sixteen inches high, so as to remove as little grass a possible with the heads. The bundles of heads on short stem were stacked and threshed. The yield of seed was 177 pounds or 12.6 bushels per acre. After the seed and hay had been cut, the aftermath was pas - tured. Thirty-two head of cattle were allowed access to the twelve and one-half acre field on August 4, and it was open to them until August 29. During this time they also had access to an adjoining field of mixed grasses. It is probably fair to say that the field carried one-half the number for that period. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">48 NEBRASKA DAIRYMKN's ASSOCIATION. On September first twelve head of horses were turned on this field exclusively, where they remained until September 18. For three days during that time seven additional head were pastured. It is fair to conclude that this field of twelve and one-half acres carried twenty-four head of stock for six weeks. In order to test the value of the grass for pasture, a known area of land on which the grass was growing was fenced and pastured by one cow. A record was kept of the length of time this plot afforded pasture, and the amount of milk and butter- fat the cow produced while she was on the pasture. The grass thus pastured was the aftermath of that cut for hay, and, as before stated, the stand was not very good. Two separate tests were made. In one case a one-fifth acre plot of land was used, and in the other, a two-fifths acre plot. A different cow was used in each test. Previous to the test, both cows were on the same pasture, which was a prairie sod on which considerable blue grass and white clover had come in, the seed having been sown on the disced prairie sod some years since. A record of milk and butter-fat produced by each cow was kept during the month preceding and that following the period she was on the brome-grass. A comparison of the daily milk flow and butter-fat production on the mixed grasses and on the brome-grass serves to show the relative values of the two as a pasture for dairy stock. PASTURE TEST. Name of cow Fannie 2d Bess Breed Grade Jersey Grade Jersey Area of land pastured 1-5 acre 2-5 acre Began test July 9 July 30 Finished test July 16 August 10 Length of time pastured 7 days 10 days Length of time pastured 7 days Average daily milk flow on mixed grasses be- fore test 13. 25 lbs. 26.87 lbs. Average daily milk flow on brome-grass. .12.17 lbs. 19.93 lbs. Average daily milk flow .on mixed grasses after test 10.87 lbs. 19.56 lbs. Average daily butter-fat production on mixed grasses before test 0.76 lbs. 1.20 lbs. Average daily butter-fat production on brome-grass 0.71 lbs. 0.88 lbs. Average daily butter-fat production on mixed grasses after test 0.67 lbs. 0.87 lbs. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 49 The first test would go to show that brome- grass is equal to the mixed grass pasture as a milk and butter producer. The second test does not give results so favorable to the brome-grass. While it is probable that the brome-grass does not furnish quite such good pasture as blue grass and white clover, yet these tests certainly demonstrate that it does furnish a good quality of pasture. The fact that the pasture during the early portion of July gave better results than during the first part of August may indi - ate a lessened value during the hot, dry period of summer, 'he appearance of the grass, however, during that time would ot contribute to the conclusion that it deteriorated to as great n extent as the mixed grasses. The qualities that Dromus inermis has to recommend it are, arly and late growth, admitting of early spring and late fall pas - urage; prolific seed production, and a large seed, thus increas - ng the chances for germination; ability to withstand long periods of drought without losing its green appearance, and much longer without being killed; extreme hardiness against cold; palatability s a feed, and a fair degree of nutritiousness. There is no other grass with which this Station has experimented that possesses all of these qualities in such a marked degree. On the other land some of the native grasses have advantages not shared by brome-grass. The quality of curing on the ground into a nutri - ious hay does not seem to be a property of brome-grass. Its Irought-resisting qualities are not perhaps so great as some of he grasses of the southwest. The native grasses as they exist at &gt;resent are practically debarred from cultivation by the small amount of seed they produce, thus making it impracticable to jarvest the seed in the ordinary manner, and ridiculously expen - ive to seed down any amount of land to them. It is possible that by selection and cultivation some of these native grasses may have their qualities so changed that a suf - ficient amount of seed may be produced to make their seeding possible. Tall oat grama shown at this Station on cultivated 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 50 land has produced a fair amount of seed, so that there is now nearly a half acre seeded to the grass. The extreme tardiness in spring growth is another undesirable quality in the native grasses. This is especially objectionable to the dairyman, as is likewise the characteristic of drying up early in the year. In other words, the period through which suc - culent feed is furnished by the native grasses is entirely too short. It must not be forgotten, however, that the dry grass as it stands dry upon the prairie, furnishes a very palatable an&lt; nutritious feed, and if supplemented with succulent forage makes an excellent milk and butter producer. It would not seem wise at the present time to destroy a prairie sod for the sake of seeding to brome-grass, but it certainly is desirable to seed a portion of the land already in cultivation. During the past few years there has been a steadily growin tendency among farmers, and especially dairymen, in this State towards the substitution of annual forage plants for the grasses This is an attempt to decrease the cost of producing feed, and a far as present results are concerned, is doubtless successfu The greater amount of feed produced by an acre of land whe planted to these crops apparently more than justifies the adde yearly expense for soil preparation, seed and sowing not entailec by the maintenance of more or less permanent pasture o meadow. In considering the cost of feed production by thi means, one item of expense is commonly overlooked. It is th greater value of the fertilizing material removed when land cropped continuously than when it is periodically seeded down t grasses. The time that the land lies in pasture is practically period of rest, and allows it in some manner to recuperate from the exhausting effect of continuous cropping. Where tillage is given year after year, the added waste is due not only to the greater amount of fertilizing material removed in the crops, but more largely to the loss of vegetable matter in the soil. The presence of decaying vegetable matter in the prairie soils is in great part the reason of their great fertility, and is the constituent most concerned in their water-holding properties. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 51 The supply of vegetable matter in the soil may be maintainet even against constant cropping, byuhe application of barn-yar&lt; manure to the land. But unfortunately the region most given to the production of annual forage crops is the one where the decomposition of manure in the soil proceeds slowly, and where its use is often attended with unfortunate results. The solution of this difficulty is, of course, to be found in the use of well rotted manure and the application of small quantities at any one time. Such practice, however, limits the amount of vegetable matter that it is possible to incorporate in the soil, and renders very desirable the possibility of seeding down to some grass. The liability to humus depletion in the soils of the wester plains is the most serious danger that confronts the agricultur of this region. It is the condition under which much of the lam in the southern states is now suffering, and the result there i sufficiently disastrous, as anyone who has experienced it wi testify. In the South, however, the possibilities for recuperatio are much greater than here, owing to the greater humidity of th atmosphere. The restoration of the humus on the western plains would be a much more difficult operation. If, therefore, awnless brome-grass finally proves itself to be so well adapted to maintain existence and furnish feed in central and western Nebraska, as it now promises to do, its value will be twofold, for not only will the generation who harvests the hay and pastures its cattle upon it be benefited, but still more, com - ing generations whose land has its fertility maintained or perhaps improved by the humus-building power of the grass. [NOT«.— Professor Lvon bad arranged for exhibiting specimens of brome-grass as well as numerous specimens of native and cultivated grasses. There was an interesting discussion of their value as forage plants, which discussion it is not possible here to produce] </seg>
            <seg id="p051">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 52 AFTERNOON SESSION— DECEMBER 20. FARM RATIONS FOR DAIRY COWS. Professor E. A. Burnett, of the State University, spoke on this subject as follows : I do not anticipate that we will see a revolution in the feeding of dairy cattle in this State, but I do expect as the dairy interests become more important that more study will be given to the subject, and that in consequence better methods of feeding will be introduced because they lead to larger and more profitable results. I am not inclined to recom - mend that he should at once change all the methods he has practiced in the past. Much as approved methods of feeding will do for the production of milk or butter, the ration is not th only thing on which the cheapness of production depends. It useless, or nearly useless, to say to the farmer that only a balanc ration will produce cheap butter, when he neglects many of th other things tending to cheap production. In endeavoring t induce a farmer to use good rations and good methods of feeding I think that the question of feed is secondary to the question o management. That not until you have induced the farmer tod many other things which are essential to cheap production, wi you be able to change his methods of feeding very largely. Now as I look upon the dairy cow, and as I believe the farmer shoul look upon the dairy cow, she is purely and simply a machine fo the converting of food into milk and butter products. She is t be looked upon as a mill or factory is looked upon; a machin which is able to use the raw material and convert it into a mor concentrated product, leaving a margin to the manufacturer, we look upon the cow in this sense, then we must recognize th fact that an efficient machine is necessary. If we look over th various milling plants of the State of Nebraska, I have no doul we will see those of various degrees of efficiency ; some o which are old style; some of which are up-to-date; some o which are of good capacity; some of which have not th proper capacity in comparison with the cost of the machine Now what we want in a dairy cow is an animal which ha </seg>
            <seg id="p052">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 53 capacity to do work; a cow which will produce but ioo pounds of butter a year, on good feed, is not a dairy cow. She should not be in the dairy business. The sooner she is discarded the better it is for the man who has owned her. I There is no use talking balance rations for a cow that has not pacity for doing work. On the other hand, you cannot tell nether or not a cow has capacity for doing work until you have ven her an opportunity to do work. Now very few farmers ve their cows a sufficient opportunity to work. What I mean ■ that is regular work every day in the week for at least ten onths in the year. Ten months , is a long enough milking ason for cows in this Stale, or for most any cow. The majority cows in this State, I fancy, produce milk about six months in e year. I wonder if that is high enough. Is it, Professor aeckerr tA. On the average; some of the better ones a little more, rhaps nine mouths for the very best, barring a very few herds as good cattle as there are in the United States. Now if it comes to the question of working the cow up to her capacity, then we are obliged to study foods much more care - fully than we did before. In the Hrst place, the question of the relation between the concentrated foods and roughness is one of great importance. Ordinarily that is given but little attention by the farmer. He is not certain how much grain he feeds. The character of the grain depends upon the ease of securing any particular kind. Mostly corn; sometimes a mixture of corn and oats; sometimes a mixture of corn and bran. Now all of these foods are good. It is only a question in my mind to get a proper relation between these foods in order to get the best results. You are well aware of the fact, for example, that the .production of milk requires work in the cow. If you feed her wholly upon roughness, she is not able to do the work which is required to reduce that rough food to milk, or at least not able to do enough of that work in one day. She has expended too much labor and energy upon producing every pound of milk. What then, are we to do? We are to add to her ration a certain amount of </seg>
            <seg id="p053">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 54 concentrated food, which does not require as much work to reduce it to the condition of milk. That is to say, we pick a grain ration. A grain ration varies in its digestibility, being from 50 per cent to as high as 70 or 80 per cent, depending upon the character of the grain. The rough foods vary in their digestibility from 30 to 70 per cent. Now if you take away half the roughness, which has 30 per cent nutrients, and add the same weight of concentrated food, which has 60 per cent of digestible nutrients in it, you will see that you add material to the matter whtch the cow can draw upon for the manufacture of fhe desired product. We believe, from a great deal of study of the matter, that a cow is able to consume about 30 pounds of food per day, per haps 28 Or 29 pounds of dry matter. This 28 or 29 pounds o dry matter should supply about 15 pounds of digestible nutrients and upon these digestible nutrients, the cow is able to do a max imum amount of work. We are able to supply that amount o digestible nutrients if we feed from ten to fourteen pounds o grain per day to the cow, and the balance in a good quantity o roughness. The trouble with the farmer is that he gives too little care to the amount of grain supplied daily, and too little attention to the fact of supplying exactly the same amount day after day and week after week. He also gives too little atten - tion to the quality of the grain. There is a very great amount of difference in the amount of nutrients supplied by the differ - ent kinds of grain, especially when you feed them by measure. Prof. Kennedy ,of Illinois Experiment Station, in a recent issue of the Breeder's Gazette worked out the digestible nutrients in some three or four of our food stuffs, using a measure instead of weight as the standard. He says that four quarts of bran weigh two and one-fourth pounds; that four quarts of oats weigh four pounds, if the oats are of stancard grade; that four quarts of corn-meal weigh five pounds; that four quarts of oil - meal weigh six pounds. Now look at the variation : From two and one-fourth to six pounds in four of the ordinary food stuffs of the farm; throw out oil-meal and take the corn- meal, oats </seg>
            <seg id="p054">SIXTF.KNTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 55 nd bran, two and one-fourth pounds in one case, four pounds in nother and five in another. Suppose we feed these by meas - ure. You will see the great variation in feed which the cow eceives per day without our appreciating the fact that we are varying the ration. Now what is it necessay to do in order that we get this ration right? Figure out some combination of corn, oats and bran, which will give you the proper weight of food, •"ind out how many quarts are required to make up this desired ation of, say fourteen pounds, and if you do not vary in your measure day after day, and week after week, then your ration is accurate enough. You feed the same ration day after day. It s also apparent when you come to study the chemical composi - ion of these foods, that there is a greater variation in the diges - ible nutrients than would appear from the weights merely. I am not inclined to force upon the farmers this idea of feed - ng a balance ration, from a chemical standpoint, and still no man can contradict the fact that a balance ration will produce better results and a larger milk flow, from a given amount of food, than a much wider ration, as we speak of, so that -the dairyman who s in the business for the largest profit, cannot afford to ignore this question of a balance ration, or approximately a balance ration. In calculating the flesh-forming elements in four quarts of bran or oats or corn, or oil-meal, we find that four quarts o bran contains twenty-seven one-hundredths of a pound of this flesh-forming material, which is so essential to the rations of a cow. Four quarts of oats contain a little more — thirty-seven one-hundredth pounds — and four quarts of corn contains forty one one-hundredth pounds of flesh-forming material, while fou quarts of oil meal contains one and twenty-seven one-hundredtl pounds of flesh-forming material, exactly a pound more than wa contained in the bran. Now we have been led to believe tha corn is a very bad food for milk production, and that bran wa a very excellent food for milk production, and we have seldom taken into consideration the greater bulk of the bran. We fine upon comparison that four quarts of corn-meal contain mor flesh-forming material than four quarts of bran. Don't under </seg>
            <seg id="p055">56 NEBRASKA TVMRYMFN's ASSOCIATION. stand me from this that I believe corn the better ration. I onl insist on the fact that we must feed by weight and not by meas ure, if we are to get accurate results. When you take a give weight, then bran has much more flesh-forming material than corn. Now the question might arise what kind of ration can a farmer afford to feed; can he afford to buy expensive food when he has a surplus of corn. Well, if he is in the dairy busi ness for the sake of producing milk cheaply, he cannot afford to ignore those classes of food which contain large percentages o flesh forming material. He will certainly be obliged to fee&lt; liberally the bran or oats, or sparingly of oil-meal, unless he ha alfalfa as roughness for his dairy" cattle. I have compoundec two or three rations which are about as follows: One of them is made up of prairie hay, corn fodder, corn-meal, oats and bran. Feed one-half corn-meal, one-fourth oats and one-fourth bran, giving 12 or 14 pounds of grain for a day's ration. I hav added to this about what prairie hay, corn or fodder a good cow would eat in a day, and it does not make a bad ration. It fur nishes one and six-tenths pounds of protein, where it ought t furnish at least two pounds; it is low on protein. It is a bette ration, however, than nine-tenths of the farmers of this Stat feed to their dairy cows. If they could be induced to feed tha ration in the place of what they are now feeding, and to giv the other attention which is essential to get milk production, yo would see the milk product per cow increase more than fift per cent in one year in the State of Nebraska. I think I know what I am talking about when I make that statement; that i you could induce the farmers of this State or the dairymen o this State to feed a ration of one-half corn meal, and a quarte each of bran and of oats, feeding approximately twelve pounds a day per cow, if she would consume twelve pounds, and more if she would consume more, and the character of roughness which I have stated, you would increase the milk and butter produc - tion more than fifty per cent in this State per cow, and the ration named is not anywhere near to balance ration. As careful </seg>
            <seg id="p056">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 57 feeding as that indicated would mean that very much more care would be given in many other respects; that more regularity in feeding would be practiced; that more regularity in the milking of the cows would be practiced; that a great deal more attention would be given to all the details of the business, and that is what makes the dairy profitable in any locality. !I have compounded another ration here which contains practi - ally the same amount of dry matter, but is made up of one - lird corn-meal, one-third ground oats and one-third bran as a rain ration, using barley and oat hay as roughness. This fur - ishes a good deal nearer a balance ration than the first, because ou have reduced the corn. You have replaced fodder corn nth oat hay, which contains more flesh-forming material Vith twelve pounds of grain, and in addition prairie and oat ay, whatever the cow would consume, it would certainly be a reat improvement over the rations now fed. Either of these ations might be improved by the man who is working for large roduction. I am not very sure that this second ration could be improved greatly by adding oil-meal to the ration; i. e., I am not sure that you would cheapen the cost of the milk. I think, perhaps, you might increase the quantity, but 1 fear you would not cheapen the Now I figured out another ration this morning, in which alfalfa hay is used as the roughness for dairy cows. The facts of the case are that you can hardly fail to feed enough protein to a dairy cow. If you feed plenty of good alfalfa hay, you can feed any old thing for grain and get a balance ration. I don't believe, however, that clear corn-meal is a good grain ration for a dairy cow, even when she is on alfalfa. It is too heavy. It wants to be lightened by some other kind of food. In feeding any of these rations, the essential thing is to feed enough and feed with regularity. In my own experience I have increased the milk product of the cow 3,000 pounds in twelve months,by improving her ration, and she had a very good ration before. I have increased from 7,000 to 10,000 pounds in twelve 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">58 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. months by increasing the amount of the ration and giving a little care to the kind of food she got. I don't know what her butter production was before, but I forced her butter production to 420 pounds of butter-fat on a pure bred short-horn cow of good milking quality, simply by a little attention to the character of the food, and feeding her as much as she required. Now that cow gave evidence of capacity. There are plenty of cows in the country with good dairy qualities, which have not that capacity, and they would not consume as much feed. I am firmly con - vinced of the fact that you must have cows with large capacity for consumption in order to get the most profitable cow. When you have that sort of a cow, you can well afford to -give the study which is necessary to feed her the best kind of a ration. I don't know that I have more to say on that subject, unless there are some questions. President King: Have you experimented with ensilage.' A. Yes, and I believe it will always increase the milk pro - duction, where you give the other attention which is necessary Now the trouble with most farmers who are producing som milk, is that they are in the business on an entirely too sma scale. They are milking two or three cows as a side issue They cannot afford to have an expensive plant. A man that ha three or four cows as a side issue does not want to go to muc expense. A man that has twenty good cows, and is in the bus ness for the profit there is in it, can well afford to invest in a silo If he has forty or sixty cows, he can better afford to invest in i because a slight increase in the expense of the plant is all that 1 necessary. Mr. Bassett: Can he afford it if he has alfalfa? A. 1 am not so sure. It does not require the same invest ment in a plant. The trouble with a great many farmers (the creamery men who are here will appreciate that fact) is tha they change their minds too often as to what they want to do. A man builds a silo and puts $300 or $500 in th plant, and uses it one year, and decides that he wants to go into the hog business. It is not good feed for hogs; his plant is </seg>
            <seg id="p058">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 59 waste for that business. It is as good as ever for the dairy bus - ness, but he has decided to go out of the dairy business. A man who is not practically certain of the kind of business he wants to stay in, had better not make too large investment in that business. He cannot sell it to some other man for the money he put in it. There is not a question as to the fact that ensilage will increase the milk flow. I have never tested it in com - parison with alfalfa. I have never seen a region where alfalfa could be secured abundantly until I came to Nebraska, and never had the opportunity here, but I fed ensilage for a good many years before coming here. This short-horn cow that made 420 pounds of butter-fat, had forty pounds of ensilage daily during the winter, and some other succulent food. Mr. King: Is that an average feed, forty pounds? A. It is a pretty large feed for an average cow; this was large cow and of large capacity. Mr. Doubt: Nearly every cow will eat a different ration ; you can't judge of that by the size of the cow. A. I would not like to make the statement that a different ration is required by every cow, although a little variation might be an advantage to most cows. Mr. Doubt: Is it not necessary for a dairyman, if he is to make a success of dairying, to have as much succulent food as possible? A. I think so. Corn ensilage is cheaper than beets, after vou get the plant established. But a five hundred dollar plant is not necessary for root pro - duction. I think you can produce just as much milk per day and per month, with plenty of roots, as you can with corn ensilage; they cost more money. I don't find it necessary to feed oil meal when I feed beets. Mr. Doubt: What ration do you feed? A. Well, about six or seven pounds of beets cut up, for a ration once a day, and feed them every evening. I raise a good deal of corn, and have stalk fields, and I feel that it is necessary to use them. You hire your corn shucked, and there will </seg>
            <seg id="p059">60 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. lways be nubbins left, and I turn my cattle in the stalk field for n hour or so; I never lost but one young bull in a stalk field in my life. I use it for half an hour the first day, and an hour the ext day, and then turn them in on rye as much as possible, or ven wheat, which I had this year, and when they are eating orn out in the field, I feed them bran every night, and alfalfa lay, or clover hay. I find that I can get a good flow of milk. cut a half bushel of beets and divide them between three ows. Q. Do you think you get more feed out of your stalk fields than you could to put it in the silo? A. I have never used a silo; have always intended to for the last ten years. Mr. Burnett: Sixteen tons of ensilage would furnish all the roughness that four cows could eat all winter, or more. This amount of silage would be produced on one acre. Voice: You would have to have hay along with it. A. You ought to have hay, yes. LMr. King: What is your idea about grinding feed? How out the fineness of the corn? tA. I cannot say that I have had any experience that would definite in that regard. I believe I would grind it reasonably e. Mjre than they crack it for steers in the feed lot. Mr. King: Have you ever taken into consideration shorts? A. I think shorts could be fed as a substitute for bran. There is probably a little more digestible protein, and probably a little more digestible carbo-hydrates, and I am inclined to think you could pay a little more for it. The amount of protein is just about the same. I have never had much experience in feeding shorts to dairy cattle, but in feeding shorts and bran to swine, I have some experience, bran not being valuable for swine, and shorts being one of the best foods we have. LMk. King: Have you ever had any experience with rye orts? A. I have not. I have not a very good opinion of rye in any way, except as green forage; it is the best in the spring. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">61 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. Mr. King: Do you know anything about barley? A. It is a pretty good feed for hogs. Mr. Temple: I don't believe I am ready to hang my cows just yet. You made a statement that if a cow only made a pound of butter a day, the sooner the farmer hung her the bet ter. What does that mean? You say a cow milked for ten months in a year, that means 300 pounds of butter at twenty-five cents a pound, which amounts to $75.00, and I would consider that a pretty good cow, though there are lots of cows that do better than that, while at the same time I think she is paying you well. But I cannot agree with that statement of yours, and don't believe I will hang mine yet. Mr. Burnett: I mean a pound a day when she is on full flow, which would not mean an average of a pound a day for a year, or 300 pounds a year ; nearer 200. I am ready to concede that the kind of feed certain cows get, that 200 pounds of butter at the market price of twenty-five cents a pound would more than pay for the feed. The trouble with cows of low production is that you put too much labor into them for a little money. I have to pay someone, may be you, twenty-five cents a pound for butter, but they put a whole lot of labor into that. You must not count the feed only against the cow, and all the rest as profit; but you must charge the labor of one man for every twenty cows in addition to the cost of feed before any profit can be figured. Mr. Temple: I would like to ask Mr. Bassett what the amount of butter was that Mr. Vaughan's cows made? Mr. Basseti*: There were about thirty head, counting heifers and all. The yield was an average of 275 pounds of but - ter per cow per year. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">62 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. A COMPARISON AND ANALYSIS OF THE DIFFER - ENT SYSTEMS OF HANDLING MILK. J. H. RUSHTON, FAIRMONT, NER. [Mr. Kushton presented this subject in an able manner, taking his manu - script home for revision. He writes that it has been lost, and that he has not time to reproduce it. The discussion is herewith published, as it con - tains much of interest regarding this important subject.] DISCUSSION. Mr. Haskell: I want to ask. Mr. Rushton a question Granting that the farm separator is the right way from the standpoint of the farmer; from the standpoint of the man who manufactures the butter can we maintain the quality of our but ter by the hand separator system? M*. Ri/shtox: I don't know that my article touches tha question. I simply say the question of the quality of the sepa rator cream is a matter that will have to go through a proces of evolution, in my judgment. I don't think that you will find a fine quality of cream from hand separators ready-made, think you will have to educate lots of people, and it will cos money to educate them, as it has cost lots of money to do lots o things; in the matter of quality of hand separator cream, the difficulty is not in the cream, it is the fellow behind the cream Mr. Haskell: Is it not easier to control one man than it is forty? Mr. Rushton: Well, that depends on the fellow. ( ) : Isn't it easier to control the bacteria in the cream from forty patrons than to control the bacteria in the milk from forty patrons before the cream has been separated? Mr. Haskell: W&lt;; cannot separate milk when sour. We have to have it come to the station in pretty sweet condition. That is a little protection. I suppose if we could separate sour milk, we would take it. Mr. Burnett: Don't you take a good deal of milk that is sour? </seg>
            <seg id="p062">63 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. Mr. H\skbll: We cannot get it through the separator very sour. Chairman: Pretty sour? Mr. Haskbll: Might be a little tainted. That is the point I want to bring out. Tnere are forty men separating milk on the farm, and one man at the station. After the cream has been separated from the milk, there is one man to take care of it at the station. Now with the hand separator there are forty men to take care of it on the farm. It seems we have a little more control when one man has control of it than where forty have control of it. Mr. Rushton: I did not touch on that point at all. My own judgment is, however, that there is a great deal of bad milk at the factory, and with the hand separator there will be the same kind of difficulty. A butter-maker, according to an address made by some one in Iowa, said "you will have to have the genius of Webster to comprehend all the minute details of the business from the Atlantic to the Pacific. The butter-maker is a kind of general Moses, located in the center of a little territory, to lead them all into the promised land." That is the veriest rot, for vou to expect a butter-maker to do that and make butter too. You have got to educate the people. But in this matter of cream, seriously speaking, hand-separator cream separated from the milk, five, ten, fifteen or twenty minutes from the cow, is the basis for the finest cream, the finest oil that there is under the living sun; you have the ideal conditions there, and if the after treatment is bad, it is not the fault of the cream; it is the fault of the people. You have the finest skimmed milk there is on earth fifteen minutes after the milk comes from the cow. If there is anything in it that the calves' stomach can digest, you have got it. I don't anticipate any trouble from the hand separator. Mr. Haskell: I don't like to take this question too seri - ously into consideration. I remember quite a number of years ago (interrupted with laughter) — we used to gather cream from cans submerged in water, and from the hand separators. Mr. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">' 6 4 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. Rushton used to gather, too, both of us. He and I decided, after a consideration of this matter, that we got the finest cream from these cans that were submerged in water. The hand separator cream is not very good. We decided that really the first-class cream came from those cans submerged in water. I want to ask Mr. Rushton how about that now; where did we get the best cream from ? Mr. Rushton: I remember the incident; I plead guilty. The hand separator cream that we had to deal with in thos days when you and I were in that business, was the produc received from farmers who had no education at all in th handling of their cream. Now there was some of this cream we had in cans that came from farmers who had no education but the most of it came from those who were fairly well edu cated in the necessity of keeping the milk in cold water, and th cream was better than the cream from the hand separator whe you put hot milk of the evening separation into the cold milk o the morning separation. If there is anything that will kill man's failh in human nature, and your ability to educate him, 1 is to have hot cream from evening milk poured into cold cream from the morning milk, and a few days after try to make goo&lt; butter from it. That was the trouble. I don't know as w knew it then, but I have learned much since. Mr. Haskell: My idea in asking this question is to get at the facts in the case. Mr. King: I want to ask you, can we make better butter from the hand separator cream than we can from the cream skimmed from the submerged milk? Aren't we getting right back to where w e were ten years ago, as a general system ? Mr. Rushton: We can get just as good cream from the power separator as the hand separator ; as far as the cream is concerned some of it is very fine, but the trouble with that sys - tem is the loss part of it. Mr. Haskell: We are speaking as manufacturers. Mr. Rushton: Yes, we are. If I have got 100 patrons, and they are producing only five pounds of oil a day under one </seg>
            <seg id="p064">SIXTKBNTH ANNUAL CONVKNT1ON. 65 system, and under the other system they will produce eight pounds a day, I am interested in changing it. Mr. Haskell: You misunderstand my question. Can we make as good butter from hand separator cream as we can from cream skimmed from submerged milk? Mr. Rushton: As a whole, better. Mr. Chairman: You remember "the world do move," and I think our president will keep in the front of the procession. A wise man will change his mind. I would like to hear from Brother Carpenter on this proposition. Mr. Carpenter: My preference would be with a separato at the Station, decidedly, but we are having trouble the last yea or two, as the patrons do not seem to be satisfied to do the hau ing. If you refer to quality, my impression is that you can ge the very finest quality of cream from the submerged system although that is a pretty hard thing to inaugurate, and I thin the greatest loss in that system is caused by the manner o taking the cream from the body of the milk. The greater per centage of loss is made there, rather than by setting in moder ately cold water. I do not advocate that system if any arrange ment can be made to haul the milk to the creamery. I am afraid the conditions are liable to get back to where they were few years ago, from the fact that if this milk is going to be allowed to stand a few days, we will have conditions that cream used to have when we gathered it at intervals. Mr. Haskell: We still consider that Mr. Rushton has the floor. I would like to ask if we are not getting right back to where we were a few years ago on this creamery proposition. Mr. Rushton: Suppose we are, what are you going to do about it. As far as I am concerned, I never had a horror of the gathered cream system, but I have a great deal more horror o the fellow that is hauling the milk. He is a more expensive fellow. He has a big expense account. As far as the logic of facts is concerned, the problem of getting this cream to the central factory, and of getting it there in as good quality a is needed for the purpose, is a practical question that will have to </seg>
            <seg id="p065">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 66 be worked out, for you can just remember this, that it will prove forever true that the farmers will patronize the system that gives them the largest return per pound of oil for what they produce, and the creamery system will have to bend to that proposition. Mr. Stillson : I don't think that my style of work would do any good to this audience, because I use the hand separator, but I sell my milk all quite sweet. We are supplying our customers with bottled milk and bottled cream. So far as the getting it to the factory, I don't know anything about that. So far as the hand separator is concerned, I would never milk cows a day if we had to go back to the old system, because I can get so much more butter-fat out of my milk by the hand separator, and then I can feed my milk sweet to my calves arid pigs fifteen minutes after milking. Prof. Mackay: I would like to ask Mr. Rushton if he would advocate running the hand separator by hand or power. Mr. Rushton : We are trying to induce the use of hand separ - ators. We will let the farmers figure that out for themselves. When they have a large dairy they will use power; when they have a sm-ill dairy they will get along by hand. Mr. Haskell: It seems to me the main question before the house is this: Between the power and hand separator can we maintain the quality of our product in the hand separator plan equal to what we could on the power plan? I ask Mr. Rushton that in all fairness. Mr. Rushton: I believe I answered that question before. That is largely a matter of detail that has to be worked out. I can answer it by saying that I have seen better cream from a hand separator than I ever saw from power separator cream. It is a matter of detail and your experience will be a sorrowful one in working out the details of any system; you have had lots of trouble in your station system in taking in milk; the gathered cream fellows have a lot of trouble in shortage as well as quality, and it is expensive. But answering your question: If you ask me what I think can be done, I think in the future that you will get better </seg>
            <seg id="p066">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 67 / cream for butter-making from hand separator cream on the whole than you ever did from power separator cream, and that the introduction of the hand separator cream system in the United States generally will give us a higher grade of butter than from the power system. Prof. Mack ay : It is better to use a tread power so that even power can be had all the time. Mr. Rushton: The hand separator depends for its power to perform its duty on the amount of centrifugal force employed. In the gathered cream business, if the driver goes to work and plunges his dipper into the can, he knocks down about half of the cream into the milk, and is taking in lots of milk in the cream ; the natural tendency is to do that. The remark that 1 made is, that the skimmed milk experiment was done by one of the best skimmers in this country, and in the other it was done by four of the best skimmers we had in our employ. They went down deep to get the stuff. Chairman: This is a vital question. It has been said a hundred times that dairying does not pay — cannot get money enough out of it. Still, we creamerymen are figuring how to get the most money out of it; it would be best to stop and figure for the other fellow a little. We have got to do it. I tell you you cannot interest the farmer in anything unless he can see money in it. There is no use of talking; this proposition of hauling milk is a serious thing. It is a serious thing 'back East where they have to haul it only two or three miles. In this State, where they haul it ten or fifteen miles, what is it going to be? I believe the farmer can haul his cream ten or fifteen miles and deliver it to the creamery as well as he can haul his whole milk three miles. My idea of the proper way to handle this subject is for the farmer to have a hand separator and separate his milk, and deliver his cream, and he will do that when he knows there is money in it. They do it back East; they deliver their milk two or three miles. He can deliver his cream here ten miles just as easily as he can deliver his whole milk two or three miles, if he can get the pay for delivering that </seg>
            <seg id="p067">68 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. cream so that he can get his money out of it. He can have sweet milk for his calves just as good as it separated at the station. Mr. Stillson: I wish to say a word in regard to the creamery business. Any person running a few cows can, with a very little care, take care of cream for two or three days, and bring it in to the creamery in good condition, when they could not keep the milk that length of time, because it occupies s much less space. If you want the cooling system, put you cream in a can and submerge it. Here comes now anothe point. I know there are a good many creamerymen here, an if I can hit them a crack, it is all right, and I will do it. believe that any man that is running a creamery could we afford to give a little time to the instruction of how to take car of cream, and how to. run the hand separator, and make it pa for them, that is, they could instruct the patron a little and ge them to do better business. I know the farmers, as a class, ar pretty hard to teach. If the creamerymen themselves woulc help along in the instruction to the farmer, I believe it woulc pay them to do it. Mr. Rushton: You are touching that sore point. Tal about instruction to patrons, you can instruct a man if he i willing, but when he turns you down cold — when you try to te himafewthings.it is a pretty hard thing; he objects. Th old lady will likely say: "Young man, when did you learn t make butter? I made butter back in Vermont that brought 4 cents a pound, and for you to come out here and tell me how t set milk" — and he gets the cold shake or the marble heart. O the other hand a farmer will look at this proposition in business-like way. Why don't he go and instruct himself — g and do something himself? Secretary Bassett: I would like to say a word in regard to this question. I am not only interested, but I have a little satisfaction growing out of it. I remember some few years ago that I invited a gentleman down to the convention to discuss the use of hand separators, and some of the creamery boys sat </seg>
            <seg id="p068">69 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. down on me pretty hard, and afterwards they said I wasn't doing the dairy business any good. I want to say that one of the boys who sat down on me the hardest seems to be a very strong advocate of the hand separator system to-day. I think that really the creamerymen ought to look at this matter in a broad way, and not with the view as to what their immediate profits are going to be. I believe the use of hand separators on the farm will have a tendency to enlarge the dairies. The man who keeps two or three cows cannot afford a separator, but the chances are he will think he had better keep more cows, and for that reason have one ; the result will be more cows will be kept on the farm. The great drawback to-day with the develop - ment of the dairy industry in the State, is that the dairies are small and scattered. Every one agrees with me to-day, that the large expense in the creamer}* business is. in getting the pro - duct from the farmers to the factory. I think all of you will admit that from the standpoint of the dairyman, the hand separators would bring him the greatest returns from his dairy. If that is true, if you help to get the dairyman better returns, you will build up the business. I remember a discussion at one time between an old banker and a young one. It was at a time when they used to loan money for two and three per cent a month in this State. Some men didn't seem to think it anything out of the way when they paid two or three per cent a month for money. They were discussing the matter. The young banker argued if money was worth that and he could get that rate of interest, it was the proper thing to do so. The older man said, "If you are going to stay in the banking business in this country you are doing an unwise thing in doing it. The men must make money from the money they borrow of you or they will soon go out of business. You had better build up around you a class of customers that can afford to borrow your money at eight per cent or ten per cent a year, or perhaps less, and in the end you will be a richer man, take less risk than you are taking to-day, and do a much safer business." In the immediate future, possibly the introduction of hand separators </seg>
            <seg id="p069">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 70 will not be as beneficial to the creamerymen of this State as it would be to continue the present system. But if it be true that the dairymen can get more money out of the business by the u»e of the hand separator, and that it will tend to increase the size 6f their dairies, it will benefit the creatneryman in the end. He will secure cream, from the hand separator, from the farmer, at his station in good condition. Any trouble of that character will be overcome. As to the other proposition, Mr. Haskell has tried to make it a strong point whether you could make as good a quality of butter. Of course, it is desirable to make the best quality of butter. I live in the vicinity of a skimming station, and the question of the expense of hauling the milk is a nightmare for the men that engage in the business. I know the company operating the skimming station; they have had to put up a mar - gin to get the milk hauled. I used to do institute work. I had never fed any separator milk. They often asked me the ques - tion, "Will it kill calves?" As a general proposition, I said, "No." I had fed skimmed milk to calves all my life, and that was all there was to separator milk. There is nothing to the question whether separator milk will kill calves, but the stuff that you sometimes get from the skimming station will, if fed to calves, kill them. Now as to the question of hauling milk : there was one route where they hauled milk ten or twelve miles. The person who hauled the milk came in the morning with a load of milk, and after he had loaded up his skimmed milk he would bum around town all day and let the milk stand in the wagon in the hot sun, and would not go home until sundown. That skimmed milk would kill a calf or any other any animal that it was fed to. Voice: He needed a starter. Secretary Bassett: Creamerymen should look at this question in a broad-minded way ; not just what it brings you in dollars and cents to-day or this year only. The use of hand separators will, I fully believe, build up the business and make larger dairies, and it will pay all parties better in the end. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 71 Mr. Haskell: I want to say one word more. I think Mr. Bassett is right from the standpoint of the farmer. The hand separator is the most profitable way to conduct the milk business for the farmer. But from a broad-minded point of view, take it in the case of the United States in competition with the world, can we maintain the quality of the butter on the hand separator plan? Prof. Mackay : Reports from Australia show that their but - ter is falling off in the English market in quality, as due to the introduction of the hand separator. But I can see no reason why, if the farmer is educated to care for the cream, why the same grade of butter cannot be made from the hand separator. But the farmer has not time, we are told, to go to the creamery with his cream, and it is kept at home three or four days, and after it has changed so far, it is almost impossible to reclaim it. If we are going to introduce the hand separator, we have got to educate the farmer as well. Mr. Burnett: I am greatly interested in this process of educating the farmer. I would like to see these creamerymen do as much of it as they will. I am interested because, as you know, 1 have charge of the Institute work in this State, and I believe the question of the method by which the farmer can get the most money out of the cow, or a given quantity of cream, is one which the creamery men have got to come to if they ever develop a large business in this State. There is no question but that Nebraska has as cheap food products as any State in the Union. It has all the conditions for producing as cheap butter as can be produced anywhere and at as much margin of profit. I have in mind two localities in the State north of here, which you all know contains a banner creamery — South Dakota — where there are no skimming stations in connection with it. I doubt if in that particular locality it would be advisable to intro - duce hand separators. On the other hand, the more skimming stations we have the better, perhaps. But going ioo miles west of there, I know of </seg>
            <seg id="p071">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 72 a locality where the amount of milk produced is so small, or the dairymen are so scattered that it seems practically impossible to get a skimming station, or at least that the hand separators go into the field first. In that locality there are a very large num - ber of hand separators, and they produce good butter — I thin in one instance having the butter manufactured at a central fac tory, and in a great many instances manufacturing it themselve — but in that locality I seriously question if a skimming statio could be put in. In this State, it seems to me that with the grea expense of a plant installed in every locality, it is a question i they had better change that plan. You are not by any mean certain that a change to the hand separator process will be sue cessful. You have got outlying patrons who could deliver the cream, but would not deliver their milk. I don't know but tha you can run the two systems in connection. I don't know — I am not enough of a dairyman to know. H ask ell: We have them both. Q. And they work all right? A. Yes. Mr. Burnett: I believe that the creameryman, to be suc - cessful in this State or anywhere, must look to the greatest profit to the patrons. It is a difficult matter to get out of a cow what it is possible to get out of her. It is a question of feed, care and selection of the cow, and caring for the milk after it is produced. I don't suppose any creameryman can educate his patrons to do all these things. There is one thing I want to know. I presume there are some men in this audience who can help me. It seems to me if a creameryman would gather the statistics showing the money produced per cow by the different patrons, that he could stimu - late to a larger production than in almost any other way. If you could show that one man produced forty dollars worth of butter - fat, another thirty and another twenty, and another fourteen, it seems to me there would be a great deal more encouragement to the fourteen dollar man to do better, or get out of the bus- </seg>
            <seg id="p072">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 73 iness. I don't know as it would make much difference which he did do. He would do more harm by the kicking he would do than he would by going out of the business. I will ask if any creamery man here has some statistics of that sort. I would like to use them. How is it, Mr. Rushton? Mr. Rushton: We have not anything of the kind that could be used, except in this way. We can figure how much the farmer gains by the hand separator system, but we have not seen our side of the profits yet. Chairman: One point, that is, educating the patrons. The question has been raised here whether it is safe to put these sep - arators out among the patrons, whether they would take the proper care of them. If you can get patrons to come into the creamery so you can show him the business, you can teach him something. He would go away from there a better and a wiser My idea is for a farmer to increase his business so that it will he an object for him to deliver his cream, and when he comes to the factory with his cream, you can ask him inside, and you will very soon have an educated patron. We would like to hear from Mr. Vaughan. I Mr. Vaughan : I had got started to go out. I thought pos - bly I might say a word on hand separators that might be of terest. I have had more experience from the standpoint of a liryman than from the standpoint of a creameryman. I think put in one of the first hand separators that was put in in the tate, as long ago as 1892. I know that I was very much eased with it, and used it in my dairy as long as I kept it up. am free to say now, from the standpoint of a farmer, that I ;vp r would haul my milk forty rods. We had the hand separa - r in the stable and ran it with power, and could get the cream 1 the creamery in very nice condition, just as good as from jwer separators. On the other hand, from the standpoint of e creameryman, the kind of creamery that we are running, I irink to think of the trouble we have before us, if we put out Hid separators. We are getting cream at the present time, I 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 74 presume, from fifty hand separators at our different stations: some of the stations have perhaps a dozen separators, and we are getting quite an amount of this hand separated cream. I presume half of the the time the cream goes into the second grade. It is almost impossible to get cream which we can make into as good butter as from power machines. I know our man at Fremont used to roar about the hand separators. He kicked about it. It is a faci. which we have got to meet. At the same time we are putting out machines as opportunity offers, but we are not crowding them. If the times demand it, we intend to supply hand separators. Voice: Have you any trouble in getting the farmers to keep these hand separators clean — to keep them perfectly clean? A. I think they take better care of the separators than they do of the cream. I have had a good deal of experience with hand separators, because I have sold ioo I presume, but I think there is more difficulty with the slovenly care they give the cream than there is with the machines. Dr. Peters: Can you tell how many of the hand separators are located in the stables? A. Very few of them in the stables, I think. The larger portion of them are in dwelling houses. Q. How near the pantry ? A. Well, I could not tell about that. Mr. Vaughan: For three or four years I ran my hand sep - arator right in my stable. I had a nice little place partitioned off, and we had forty cows, and would milk three or four gal - lons of milk, and then start the separator, and in ten minutes after milking our milk was separated. Voice : You made butter, didn't you ? A. Yes, sir. Q. Didn't have any creamerymen criticising your cream,, did you; didn't know whether it was good or not? A. I know it always used to sell pretty well. Mr. Priest: It doesn't seem to me that we are giving this, hand separator question a fair show. I think if you will look. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 75 over your semi-monthly report*, you will see your hanc separa - tor patrons are all self-delivering patrons, and the majority of them deliver their cream about twice a week. Some of them seem to deliver it about when they want to come to town. ( ) : They cannot run as heavy cream with hand separator as they can with a power machine. Voice: From my experience with a hand separator they can n as heavy cream as with a power machine. Prof. Mackay: I think the question of thickness of cream is one which will help the hand separator along. The great mis - take is in skimming too thin cream. All these machines can be adjusted for thick or thin. The thinner the cream the sooner it will sour. Mr. Rushton : What would you consider a fair per cent of acidity coming into the factory? A. What would run about fifteen degrees. Q. How on Farrington test? A. Twenty hundredths of one per cent. Mr. Burnett raised le question some time ago in regard to returns per cow. A ear ago last fall I was in South Dakota, and in conversation with President James Armstrong, he informed me that he got a eturn of $67.00 per cow from a herd of twenty-five cows. We ave cows at our college, and have kept an accurate account, nd they have given u! $50.00 net profit. I was in Canada a ew years ago, and a gentleman made this statement: He said, I believe I have the best cow in Canada; that she produced 7707 pounds of milk in nine months, out of a herd of cows hat gave an average of 12,000 pounds." I went to see his ows. I found Mr. Tillson had an ideal herd. He looked pon the cow as a machine. Q. What breed? A. A cross between a shorthorn and a Holstein Q. What was the herd? A. Holsteins. Q. The returns from your cows are about $50.00 per head ? A. Not on an average. We figured out our profits on the </seg>
            <seg id="p075">76 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. average price of butter. We have cows that run $50 net. In a general way I think they would average somewhere about $50 on the average price of butter. Q. Could a farmer make that average amount of money per per cow as you do? A. Certainly, I don't see why he could not get the same price. You are supposed to have more knowledge than he does. Mr. Moore: I have been very much interested in the hanc separator question, for the reason that it has been considerabl) agitated in our locality. I had hopes and misgivings. I don' know which I have to-day, after hearing this discussion. I hav felt that the day of the hand separator is near at hand, for th reason that it is something that will give the patron the greates return for his feed and labor expended. But touching on th question of profits from the cow, I think the gentleman who jus spoke answered it thoroughly. It would be hardly fair to publish these figures. I think I could come as near to doing that as anyone. I think in nine - tenths of the cases of our patrons I could give it complete, pro - vided our patrons would answer a few questions I ask them. At the close of 1899 I sent to each of our'patrons a list of questions very similar to the numerous ones that were published in the various dairy publications, and I think 6\n of 125 sent out I go about a dozen returns. They didn't say so to me, but a great man\ of them did say to the station operators, "What business is it o that company what I am doing here on my farm in a private waj I cannot see that it is any of their business at all." In some o my work before in trying to find how many cows each patro had, a great many of the patrons flatly refused to tell how man cows they owned or milked, for the reason, it seemed to then that it was not any of the company's business what they wer doing. I am satisfied if we could get these figures complet and make statements showing what the return of each cow was some of the showings would be so low that many of them woulc quit the business. Whether it would be for our interest for them </seg>
            <seg id="p076">77 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. to do so, I don't know. But speaking along that line, ami knowing what those showings per cow would be, I have to say we have a great many patrons that are patrons simply because they get a little more out of their butter-fat than if they made butter at home, with less labor, and it being shown to them that it is less work, they stick by us. But it is not as much better for the patrons as it ought to be. We have patrons who, through their patronage of our company, are doing well; 10 per cent of our patrons are satisfied with their business. THE RAW MATERIAL FOR THE BUTTER FACTORY. H. F. MCINTOSH, EDITOR OF NEBRASKA FARMER. The "raw material for butter manufacture" you will readily ondense in your minds into the word "milk," and while milk s one of the simplest products of human affairs, in its natural tate, it has got us into a great deal of trouble in the modern, ntricate dairy industry. The struggle we are making to bring his indispensable article of human food, butter, up to the high tandard that people have set for everything they desire for con - umption, has taxed the ingenuity of the producing class, I think, as high as we find it taxed in any of our industries. So, the man that can make butter of the quality now demanded by the consumer, every day in the year, and put it before the consumer n the way that he demands it, is achieving something that is by no means inconsiderable, and not unworthy of the highest praise, when we reach the ideal. To do those things, the butter-maker must of course have raw material; and, unfortunately, as butter-making is now conducted, he producer of the raw material is a different man, situated differently, and looking at the business from a different point of view from the butter manufacturer. Unfortunately, also, for he butter manufacturer, the producer of this "raw material" has control of the situation. Unless the butter manufacturer can get milk in sufficient quantities and in proper condition, he cannot </seg>
            <seg id="p077">78 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION. meet the demands of the butter trade. Hence the importance of the subject. Every man who has studied this question asks himself, the first thing, "Why is it that the farmer will not produce the raw material for the butter manufacturer as the manufacturer desires to have it?" There is only one answer to this question, in the light of what we know of human affairs. That answer is: As the farmer views the matter, it does not pay him to produce milk. Of course, when we speak of the question of pay, it is always relative. It pays him something to produce milk; but the farmer feels that it does not profit him as much to produce milk as to produce pigs or corn, or some other product in the handling of which less skill is required, and much less detail. And, so, the farmer has, I think, sacrificed his financial oppor - tunity for simplicity in conducting his business. And I hope to show you by some statistics gathered from men who produce milk, that this may be a profitable business. In anticipation of this meeting, I sent inquiries of a very per - sonal character to a number of men I know to be engaged rather extensively in the production of milk. A few of these replied frankly, and honestly, I think, to the inquiries. With the permission of the persons furnishing the information, I place it before you. The inquiries were as follows : (I). How many acres in farm? (II). How many cows do you keep in milk? (HI). Do you practice winter, summer or all the year through dairying? (IV). What is the general breed character of your herd? (V). What is the value of your annual sales of butter or butter- fat? (VI). Do you sell, annually, any other products than butter or butter-fat? If so, what products mainly, and their total value? A Sarpy county, Nebraska, farmer who makes butter for private customers in Omaha, gave the following answers: "(I). </seg>
            <seg id="p078">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 79 150 acres. (II). Twenty. (III). All the year round. (IV). Jersey. (V). $1000.00. (VI). No." II happen to know, in this case, that the farmer is a large pro - icer of poultry products, and that he has many acres in orchard, e certainly left out important items of income. At any rate he es in a style impossible on twice one thousand dollars in e city. A farmer in central Nebraska who sells cream to a coopera - ve creamery, gives the following replies: "(I). 680 acres. II). Twenty. (HI). Grade shorthorns, some full blood. IV|. All the year through. (V). Sales of butter-fat for the &gt;ast twelve months were $467.31. Aside from that we made quantity of butter for family use in a family of eight persons. VI). We sell cattle, $1200; hogs, $1000; oats, $300; hay, &gt;3&lt;x&gt;. Total of sales, $3267.31." This farmer remarks, "You will probably figure out that our cows do not pay for their keep - ng, but it must be remembered that dairying is not our main bject in keeping the cows." A farmer in South Dakota replies to the inquiries as follows : "(I). 320 acres. (II). Sixteen. (III). All year, but most of my cows calve in early winter. (IV). I select cows of good dairy form, regardless of breed, and use a good short - orn bull. (V). This year it will be close to $900. (VI). ieside the cows we keep fifty head of pure bred shorthorns. Our annual sales from those, and the calves from the milk cows, vith some hogs and wheat, $2500. The total sales from this lalf section of land is $3400." t Another Nebraskan says: "(I)- 320 acres. An average of O. (HI)- Any cow that will test 3.8 per cent fat, and give lenty of milk. All breeds represented. (IV). All the year. (V). Have figures for only the past four months. August, $120.23; September, $111.03; October, $1x6.22; November, $130.00. Average for four months, eighteen cows. (VI). Calves, hogs and corn, estimated, $2,000." (Adding the estima - ted sales of butter fatter at $120 per month as above, we have ■$3440 as the income from this half section.) </seg>
            <seg id="p079">80 NEBRASKA DAIRVMEN's ASSOCIATION We now come to an Iowa farmer who not only answers our questions, but furnishes some interesting comment. The answer are as follows : "(I). 332 acres. (II). Twenty. (III). Short horn. (IV). The year through. (V). $500. (VI). No othe product than the calves from these cows, which are sold as beei at about 24 months old. These beeves weigh 1100 to 1200 pounds each. Their increase in value per year would probiiblj be about $500 per annum, although we do not sell them unti ready for the block." This gentleman offers the "following interesting report on his farm methods: "1 am not making much of an effort in the dairy line at present, but give most of my time to feeding cattlt Have now 220 head on feed. I do not make butter now. We milk the cows, separate the cream, which is sold at 18 cents per inch to the creamery. The price runs down to 13 cents in summer. There is sure money in dairying, and plenty of fer - tility to give back to the soil. A man with twenty cows of the right kind, rightly handled, can come as near being independent as any person on earth. He has no use for the bankruptcy law. His credit is gilt-edged. You may wonder why I do not make a specialty of the business. I don't know, unless it is a desire to get money faster, or a desire to invest more heavily than dairy - ing will permit. I like the business of feeding cattle, and only cling to the dairy because / am afraid to go oh without it. The work we do in dairying can be done in connection with feeding, and thus find employment for our time all hours of the day. In other words, the dairying does us no harm in the feeding division, and pays all expenses. So, if there is anything made in the feed - ing venture, it can be saved, not eaten up by the family." We may be pardoned for calling attention to this dairy of 20 cows which is maintained as the assurance of prosperity, against the risk incident to feeding eleven times as many beef steers. It will be observed that none of the farmers reporting above devote all their resources to the dairy industry. In each case the dairying is a side issue, whether supporting a herd of pure- </seg>
            <seg id="p080">81 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. bred shorthorns or a lot full of beef steers. None of the men are living up to their dairy resources. It is easily within the range of possibility for any one ownin a 160-acre farm in the eastern half of Nebraska to maintain, o that farm, besides other stock, a herd of fifty cows in milk, capa ble of producing an average of 5,000 pounds of milk per co\ per year. This herd should produce 10,000 pounds of butter-fa worth $1,500. This is only $30.00 per cow, a record about a low as the lowest reported above. The cows should produc forty calves (why not fifty?) worth $18 each at one year old, o $720. The surplus milk and feed — waste should support hundred pigs, worth $800, making a total product annually o $3,020. I call this a three-man plant. It represents a $10,000 invest - ment. Allowing $1,000 of the income for wear and tear and labor, there is left a net profit of 20 per cent on the investment. This is a modest estimate of the possibility of a dairy farm. It is a business proposition on which a man can wear diamonds. Mr. Bassett: Is not the estimate you make too high? The Speaker: I do not think so. Mr. Bassett: My own experience and observation, and the best statistical information I can get are to the effect that a farm which, as an investment, pays 4 per cent is doing well. Now, when you come to say 20 per cent, that must represent the owner's living and compensation, too. The Speaker: I do not include his living. I represent the net profit of a 160-acre dairy farm, managed on a business basis, to be 20 per cent per year on an investment of $10,000. Mr. Bassett: There is something wrong with your figures. The Speaker: No, sir, my figures are correct. I grant that 4 per cent as farms are operated, is a good income. But the object is to inspire men with a belief that they can do greater things. You think my estimate of the stock-carrying capacity of a 160-acre farm is too high; but let me call your attention to what is actually being done at this time by David Brown, of Dodge county, Neb. : and Mr. Brown's operations are not an </seg>
            <seg id="p081">82 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. experiment. This is the third year he has been following his present system, and what he is doing.any man similarly situated may do. In a November issue of the Nebraska Farmer, Mr. Brown writes: "We have kept on this 240-acre place, during the entire summer, our herd of cattle with their increase, num - bering in all no; 15 head of horses, our flock of 200 sheep, and the hogs and pigs above mentioned (about 100 head). We have on hand, for we have just finished putting up our feed crops, enough forage to keep for eight months to come, double the number of sheep and cattle we have on hand, and carry our horses and hogs also. In this forage we have not got all our corn crop. Twenty-two acres of corn became two dry before we got to it, and we did not cut it up; that we left over to husk, and must allow that much fodder to go to waste." This report justifies the claim I make for the live stock sup - porting capacity of a 160-acre farm. Not my figures are wrong, but the farmer's conception of the resources of his land are wrong. His ideals are too low. Creamerymen must take this matter in hand. While perhap you cannot teach an old dog new tricks, it seems to me you ca get hold of young men in your various neighborhoods, and by patient system of direction, you can make dairymen out of th young men. The farmer cannot come to the modern dairy sys tern by reading of journals, or by the teaching of schools tha he cannot attend. He must come into personal relation withth new order of things if he is to become inspired with the possi bilities which are before him. That is one reason why I think these schools (reference was directed to the Nebraska Dairy School, in which the meeting was held) ought to be built up. You can sugar the bait here so as to bring some hundreds of the farm boys in here to give them a glimpse of the possibilities of agriculture. The idea we have that farming must be something that unfits a man to asso - ciate with business men and tidy people; that it makes a man grimy and thick-skinned, wants to be got out of people. You get farming on a paying basts, and the man has capital; he has </seg>
            <seg id="p082">83 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. resources; he has liberty to go from home and to meet people, and to grow in other ways. You must give a consciousness of this to him, and in this school is the place where the ideal of the farmer's life and the possibilities of the farmer's life may be shown, and a high ideal of the farmer's life may be instilled into the boys. The more boys we can get in here, the more exalted the ideal of the farmer's life we can give them, the more we are discharging our duty to the State of Nebraska and our fellow- The dairymen can learn something from the sugar beet men n the solution of the problem of raw material for the butter fac - ory. The manufacturers of beet sugar and the manufacturers of butter stand in exactly the same relation to the agricultural lass. The sugar beet men have taken the wise course of contract - ng in advance for a specified amount of raw material from the armer, barring only the accident of crop failure. They have endeavored all along the line to have that raw material produced under the immediate and direct supervision of the factory. The manufacturers buy the seed for the planter, in order that farmers may make no mistake in the seed. They see that he has the right kind of machinery for cultivating the crop. They see that lis crop is tilled and shaped up at the right time, and that it is dug and delivered according to specified rules. That is a busi - ness proposition between the manufacturer and the producer of raw material. I believe the application of the system to the dairy industry is very largely possible. It ought to be fully pos - sible. A butter manufacturer is not justified to-day in accepting these little dribs of cast-off products of the farm; and unless he can get a number of farmers to contract to produce the kind of milk he wants, in the way he wants it, the butter maker is not justified in dealing with them at all. This contract system is in operation in the Elgin, 111., dairy district, where they manufacture con - densed milk, and with reasonable modifications it is applicable to every district where dairy operations on a large scale are practicable. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">84 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. To use a slang phrase, it is "up to" the butter manufacturer to put his business on a business basis with the farmer — a course equally beneficial to both. President King: It is with great pleasure that I introduce to you Chancellor Andrews, of the State University. THE SOCIAL IMPORTANCE OF RURAL INTERESTS. CHANCELLOR E. BENJAMIN ANDREWS. Two great movements are now progressing in the Unitec States, which have extraordinary social importance. One is the rush of population into cities-, the other the syndicating of mos wealth in a manner which threatens to lower the fortunes of the rural classes. These classes, being among those who canno combine, have to sell their products competitively, whereas fo most things which they buy they must pay syndicate prices These two movements are so sweeping and in their effects so decisive that some thinkers regard them as destined to reduce the rural population of America to ignorant peasants such a we see and pity in most European lands. That result every true American would wish to avoid. Whether or not the danger is so great as alleged we need not inquire. One thing is certain, that the welfare of the rural com - munities is no mere affair of those communities alone, but is important to the entire republic. For its continuance and strength the whole naiion requires that ihe rural classes should thrive. As those classes are so is the State. A vigorous country population is a necessity in order to attain the highest physical health throughout the total body of citizens It is equally necessary to the finest character and integrity of ih whole people, and also for the richest development of commot sense, sincerity, large views and patriotism. These qualitie spring from Mother Earth. They are found in cities, of course but usually because they are brought there. The stronges instances of them are not indigenous to towns. It is generall </seg>
            <seg id="p084">85 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. recognized that town life would soon grow pale and sickly as well in moral as in physical regards, but for the incessant importa - tion of blood and character from the country. It is a matter of common knowledge that nearly all of the men and women in the most commanding positions in society, business, literature and life, were born and reared in the country. Over and above the preceding considerations, which apply to other countries as well as our own, there is a special reason for conserving and strengthtning rural interests here in the United States. Europe was settled mainly under military motives, so hat all over Europe even to-day the great land-owner is a more significant person than the great townsman, manufacturer or &gt;anker. Socially, land-owning counts there more than wealth in other forms. The blooded aristocracies of European lands all stand in some sort of connection with the proprietorship of and. It is easy to see that in the countries named there is an immense influence other than that of wealth operating against mere wealth. In the United States, unfortunately, we as ye possess no such counterpoise against the dead weight o Mammon. We need to raise up such, and the only apparen way, at least the best way, apparently, to accomplish that result is to cultivate rural interests. Build up and keep up a country population both worthy and able to determine our nationa character. How can such a country population in the United States be reared? How can the landed interests be put in a condition to be felt as a solid factor in American civilization, always to be reckoned with, opposing in every way the rule of brute Mammon and the sway of those decadent and effete elements always so active in great municipalities? How can we establish countrj life and character so that it shall be a beneficent safety valve fly- wheel, or governor to our vast social machine? 1. Good legislation is called for, directed not to the financial profit of the farming class, which would be class legislation and therefore wrong, but calculated in a large and enlightened </seg>
            <seg id="p085">86 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. manner to render stronger, happier and more cheerful the people who live out upon the land and furnish the bone and sinew, also, in great part, the brain and character of the Ameri - can people. Laws in this spirit would not deserve condemnation as class legislation. Their fundamental aim would not be the welfare of a class. They would not have in view the good of the country for its own sake, but country prosperity for the sake of the entire nation, the idea being that the character, morality, ability and consequent safety of the nation would immensely sink should the country population fall to the level of serfs or peasants. 2. Perfect roads. The advantages to rural districts from this source would be incalculable. The time is coming when in all well populated sections, travel will be so swift and comfort - able that the entire population of the country can, day-time or evening, gather at the center as easily as such a crowd now forms in any city; when country centers will have churches, music halls, opera houses, schools, and all similar agencies of culture, as good as there are in the world. 3. Country free delivery of mails. This will come immedi - ately after roads are made good, so that newspapers and other intelligence by mail will not only speed across the country at the most rapid rate so far as railways extend, but reach destina - tion from post-offices with equal expedition. 4. Country High schools. Efforts for the establishment of these have been making for a number of years in this State. The need is a pressing one. Those interested in the cause are in earnest and may be counted upon to continue agitation until every boy and girl in the country parts of the State can obtain first-rate school preparation for the University or for life without tuition cost and without being obliged to leave hcme. 5. Vastly improved primary and grammar as well as High schools. When rapid and easy travel over country roads is the rule, schools will be concentrated at county and township centers so that grading can be made much more complete than now. A </seg>
            <seg id="p086">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 87 higher order of teaching talent will also be employed. Far beyond this in importance, grading and administration being equally good, country schools can be mflde immensely more instructive and inspiring than city schools. Nature, the centra) object of attention in modern schooling, city pupils can approach only with travel and expense, but it lies, in all its departments* open and ready for inspection, under the eyes of country pupils without money and without price. 6. Build up country home life. Encourage all who can to - build and live in the country, even if a part of their life must be in the city. The above improvements will go far to produce this encouragement. A reflux of population from city to coun - try will certainly occur when country roads are perfect, mail facilities greatly bettered, schools, concerts, churches and other means of culture as good in the country as in the city, and so on. But aside from these considerations there ought to be a richer, deeper and more general appreciation of the country than now exists. The country is beautiful, healthful, and in every wise desirable on its own account. If people think otherwise or do not think on the subject at all, it is due to their lack of culture. They ignore the works of God as stupid people might walk through the Louvre and not think of the matchless art creations, upon the right hand and the left. This subject, the glory of the country, ought to be taught, written up, and preached upon until enthusiasm for country living becomes deep and general. 7. Farmers themselves can assist to strengthen and enrich country life by doing farm work in a more systematic manner than is now usual. Too much farming goes on by mere routine and tradition, without the slightest application of scientific principles. How few farmers for instance keep books so as to know what profit accrues from such and such an animal, herd, crop, or parcel of land. This methodless and unintelligent farming is responsible for much of the disposition shown by your boys and girls to rush to the city. Young people with intelligence wish to cultivate their minds and are determined to do this. Much of the farming which they have known doesn't </seg>
            <seg id="p087">88 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. supply them with that motive. Farming might be so carried on that young people's mental faculties and sense of art would be addressed by it far more than can be done by city occupations. Gentlemen, I thank you for your attention. SAMPLING AND TESTING MILK. PROF. A. L. HAECKER, NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION. The subject of milk testing has been written and talked abou so much at our dairy meetings, that I feel it is getting to be a very old story to some of you. Still, I believe there is some room for improvement in all matters pertaining to our industry and in my visits to creameries throughout the State I find the milk testing quite far from what it should be. The true value of milk is its per cent of butter-fat, whether it is to be used for cheese, butter or home consumption. The fat content should be its standard. We have standard weights for all our grains, and nearly all are sold by weight, but the base value of milk is its per cent of but - ter-fat. This should be as carefully and fairly weighed as our No. i wheat. The Babcock Test is no doubt the best scale we have for measuring the value of milk, but this scale is quite complicated, and if not worked properly will give incorrect results. I do not wish to be understood that the Babcock Test is a very difficult one to operate, but rather it is a simple operation. Still we cannot afford to be careless and neglect any of the principles. The sampling, whether from composite bottles or new milk should always represent as nearly as possible the whole lot o milk from which it is taken. To mix fresh milk, pouring once or twice from one vessel to another will be sufficient, but in com posite samples where a thick,tough cream has gathered on the sur face and sides of the bottle, warming is necessary. This may be done by placing the bottles in a hot water bath for a minute o so and then mixing thoroughly. Composite samples shouk </seg>
            <seg id="p088">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 89 - never run over two weeks. One week would give much better results than two. Here is where many operators are careless and fail to obtain good results. An old, tough composite sample is a hard one to mix as well as to test. It is much better to test often, thus depending on several for the monthly average, instead of one or two. For example, say the composite tests are run in a certain factory for a month. A patron, Mr. Brown, finds on his monthly statement that he has delivered to the factory during April, 7500 pounds of milk, which tested 3.5 per cent of butter - fat. This would give him 262.5 pounds of butter-fat, which, at 18 cents per pound, would give him $47.25. Suppose the test was a difficult one or some little mistake made, so that the result read 3 per cent instead of 3.5, then his check would be $40.50 instead of $47.25", or a difference of $6.75. On the other hand, suppose the test read 4 per cent fat instead of 3.5 per cent, then Mr. Brown would get $54.00, or $6.75 more than was due him. Such mistakes are likely to occur when a single, old, tough com - posite sample is used to find the monthly average, and when it requires but little extra work to run one each week, it seems to me a much better and purer system. The task of sampling milk is not a difficult one — thorough mixing, a good pipette, and a clean conscience is all that is neces - sary. When it comes to sampling cream we have a more difficult task, and really we are in great need of a practical, reliable test for cream. Cream is lighter than milk and more viscous; being lighter per volume it requires a larger measure or pipette, and how much larger we are not able to tell, for the richer the cream, the more is required for a sample. We can get exact results by weighing the cream, using just eighteen grams for a sample. If a pipette is used at all, it should be an 18 cc and not one intended for milk which is 17.6 cc. If the latter is used the result in testing average cream will be from 1.5 to 2 per cent too low. An 18 cc pipette will give very close results in average cream. Cream being very viscous, it is difficult to get </seg>
            <seg id="p089">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 90 fhe sample mixed; pouring and stirring are necessary, but care hould be taken not to churn the sample. Diluting the sample with skim-milk or water is sometimes practiced. When this is done the test is made in a whole milk bottle instead of a cream bottle. In diluting great care should be used in getting the ratio exact for a slight mistake will be multiplied when this system is used Skim-milk is better than water for diluting, as it is heavier, and thus makes a mixture nearly the same as whole milk. The ratio should be one part cream to three parts skim-milk, in which case the per cent fat of the test must be multiplied by four. The largely increased use of the hand separator is making cream testing a very important feature in our industry, and it is getting more and more so each year. In regard to adding the acid there is little difficulty found except in getting the proper amount when it varies in strength and temperature. Use enough acid to burn or destroy all solids in the milk except the fat, which in a good test should have a rich straw color. If the fat has black clouded clots mixed in it, or floating at the bottom, it shows over-burning, in which case use less acid or coo both acid and milk. On the other hand when white or cloude&lt; clots appear in the test it shows a weakness of acid or no enough used. The reading of the test should be done with the use of dividers, thus lessening the danger of mistakes. All glassware connected with testing should be well cleaned and perfectly free from grease. Sal soda and "gold dust" are good for this purpose, being strong in alkali. Regarding machines, we should always aim to use a substan - tial kind which will neither tremble nor shake while running. The heavy, well-made machines are better than the cheap tin ones, which soon wear out. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 91 tThe turbine testers give very good results in all kinds of eather, being well regulated by the steam which keeps the )ttles at an even temperature. / As to the glassware, the best is none too good. Not often are bottles found with poor or incorrect graduation, but when they are it is nearly always among the cheaper goods. A good qual - ty of glass will not break as easily, and in the end is the cheap - est to buy. A butter-maker or skimming station operator should be well provided with all necessary equipment for milk testing, and this part of his work ought to be done with great care. On the other hand, patrons should be considerate of the operator's skill and fairness. Milk with a low per cent of butter-fat cannot be made to test higher by kicking. The milk not only from individual cows, but also from the entire herd, will vary from day to day, week to week, and month to month. This fact has been carefully demonstrated by many experiments and tests. Secretary Bassett: Mr. Chairman, I desire to offer the following resolution : "Whereas, At this date there are some 300 skimming stations in our State tributary to less than fifty creameries, making the skimming station a most important factor in our commercial dairying, Resolved, That the Regents of the University be requested to establish a skimming station course in connection with the dairy school, with an equipment sufficient to furnish complete instruc - tion in regard to the control and operation of a skimming station as well as that of a farm dairy." One of the most prominent creamery men in the State remarked the other day in speaking in regard to the topic that Professor Haecker has discussed, said that he personally instructed his own skimming station men. I do not just agree with the proposition as he stated it. I think he is right in a measure from a business point of view; </seg>
            <seg id="p091">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION. 9 2 that is, whenever you employ a man you should instruct him in your system of business. If you are a banker, you have a certain method of doing business; that is, all bankers do not keep their books in the same manner. They do not conduct the details of their business in the same way, and therefore when a person who has taken a complete course in bookkeeping, goes into the office of a banker or mercantile establishment, he has to be instructed in their method of carrying on business. There - fore, if a man had taken a complete skimming station course in a dairy school, and was competent to opeiate the whole station from receiving the milk to taking the test, yet the men who employed him might have methods whereby they wished their business conducted that they would have to instruct him in. I take it for granted that the man who had received such a course in school would be much the better man, easier to instruct, fall quicker into the ways of conducting the business, and would be a more useful and better man. The man that conducts your skimming station, is the man who stands between the owner of the creamery and the patrons. He is the man that meets them; he can best do missionary work, and induce patrons to pursue methods that would be a benefit to the company if he understands the principles underlying the whole business. If he does not know any more about the test that we have been talking about than only in a mechanical way, and does it as a Chinaman would do it, and you have to tell him what "he is to do, first this and then the other, he cannot be a very efficient man. He is a machine. When he gets switched off the regular routine, he is lost, as it were. We are interested in developing the dairy interests of the State. We are not interested in this man making money or that man making money, but to develop the dairy resources of the State. We are interested in what the farmer makes out of the dairy business and the creamery man makes out of the dairy business, but above all the dairy resources of the State ought to be developed that all the people may be benefited. Now if that is true, and as the skimming station has devel- </seg>
            <seg id="p092">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 93 ped wonderfully in the State lately, and it is my judgment that it will to a still larger extent, then we are interested as a people in his State to make the most out of that which will best develop le resources of the State in a dairying way. To that end we lave established a dairy school and an agricultural college to fur - ish education to those who engage in agriculture in the State. We have established to a certain extent a dairy school. I think lis was one of the first states where the skimming station plan vas adopted to any considerable extent. Our conditions almost emanded it. It has a promising outlook, and it seems to me lat we might take up here in this dairy school and establish a ourse of instruction in a skimming station work, while it might ot be advisable to do it in butter-making. We have at this lme six times as many men engaged in controlling skimming tations as in operating creameries. A butter-making course would be a great deal more expensive than a skimming station ourse. I am inclined to think that the individual who wishes to earn butter-making, that is, the principles of it, that given by school of that kind, better go to Ames, Iowa, or Wisconsin or Minnesota, than for us to attempt to do it in this State. There re a good many things connected with the establishment of a chool for butter-making. You must keep a large number of ows, or buy milk and have it brought to the school. In teach - ng anyone to do that kind of work, there is not any certainty n the beginning, at least, of producing a good, first-class article o go upon the market. A young man may ruin a batch of butter, or it may be he may make an inferior article. These schools are not run to make money. They can only be run t a financial loss. The larger plant is a more expensive plant nd our conditions do not warrant it. I think we most neec nstruction in the line of the operation of the skimming station think if the skimming station operator understood the manipu ation of the test, and all the reasons that Professor Haecker has xplained to us, so that he could explain it to the patrons, there would be less irritation in regard to the test. It need not be a very elaborate course. We ought to keep </seg>
            <seg id="p093">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 94 here the different breeds of dairy cows. There is just as much ducation in knowing the different breeds of dairy cows — in the tudy of them — as it is to have your text-books, or anything con - nected with the work of education. We learn as much or more &gt;y the eye, as in any other way. I think we ought to adopt this esolution and press it upon the regents to give us more in this espect. They gave us a farm dairy course, and it would not be expensive for them to add to that the course required for the skimming station. If we are to have skimming stations in the State, we want men competent to operate them. Some of you vere here yesterday when Professor Mackay spoke, and remember quite well at the Omaha Exposition dairy exhibit — he first exposition — I was in charge of its exhibit, that a large number of students from the Iowa Dairy School took advantage of the list scoring that was made in October to send over sam )les of their butter product to have them scored. I was quit nterested in the result. It was all of a very high grade, ant hey were among the top winners in that exhibit; they were in competition with the best butter-makers of the West, i Nebraska, Minnesota, Iowa, Wisconsin, Illinois, Ohio, ant Indiana, and from the far East, New York, and some of th New England states. All sent butter there to be scored, ant there was no poor butter came from the Iowa station. Professor Mackay mentioned yesterday that one of their me was employed at the Sioux City factory, Iowa, at $1300 per year and his work is largely the receiving and ripening of the milk — getting it ready for the churn. No one doubts to-day that th educated "man is the valuable one. Why not have here some thing along that line — something a little more practical. This is not presented with the idea of finding fault with what has been done. The time is ripe now for something more of a practical nature; therefore I move the adoption of the resolu - tion. Seconded byj. C. Doubt. Motion carried. Mr. King: This is the end of the program, I believe. </seg>
            <seg id="p094">95 SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. Mr. Stouffer offered the following resolution, which was adopted : Wherkas, The Nebraska Dairymen's Association, in session at the University Farm, has been well entertained at that insti - tution; and Whereas, We, as members of the said Association, feel a high degree of interest in agricultural education, and believe that it is of the greatest importance to this State; therefore be it Resolved, That we, the members of the Nebraska Dairy men's Association, desire to tender our thanks to the Uni versity authorities for the use of the University building and many other favors shown, and, furthermore, that w express our desire to the Regents of the University that th University farm be equipped with all that is necessary to teac practical agriculture. B. R. Stouffer: I move that we hold all or a part of our next session here. Motion seconded and carried. J. J. King: I thank you for your attendance; the meeting stands adjourned. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">96 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. LIST OF CREAMERIES IN NEBRASKA. i. } KAMI OF CRIAMEKT i I HAM! Or CBIAMIKT MAHAUEB OB PRO- PRIETOR I POST-orFICE UUUJHI i I 1 Albion Separator Creamery Co. 8 Allen Creamery Co 3 Amelia Creamery Co 4 Ansley Dairy Association 5 Arcadia Creamery Co 8 Adams Center Creamery 7 Atkinson Creamery Co 8 Bancroft Creamery Co 9 Blackbird Creamery lOi Blair Creamery Co I!] Blue Hill Creamery 12| Boone Creamery Co lSj Bismark Creamery U Blue Point Creamery Co In Beatrice Creamery Co. 1«« ■ 17* " ' lx» - ■ If* •M • • •j I • ■ ■ • ' 22 • ■a* ■w •• ■ 2:, • *• ■■ ■ «• '■ ■ 2 . * »• ■' ■ 311 • ' ■ :tl • ■ :i-j« ■ ■■ Xt« • 14* «• m* ■■ ■ 37* • - it* - ■■ : &amp;»* ■■ • 40* " . .. 41 • " • 42* ■■ ■ «• " ■ 44 • • 4S» ■ ■ «• ■ ■ 47» ■ ■ 4» • ■ - 4!.« ■ ■■ 50 • ■ M • H* ra* ■ ■ M* ■ ■ Sn» ■ ■ hli* - " "&gt;7» ■ • ■§• - ■ »• ■ ■ 6ll» ■ «1 • ■ ■ ii-.' • " •• «S« ■ »»• ■ «• • • w ■■ 67» •■ " I 1 I 4 S • • M W. Ladd. Mgr C W. Moss C. H. Whitman Hansen &amp; Templin — J. J. stlllson J. J. Klkin Harry Spindler EdMoBride F. H. Rozell H.B. Heed Geo. E. Haskell. Pres' -. :: :: ;; :: :: '.' '.: : ': M Albion Allen Amelia Ansley Arcadia. Archer Atkinson Bancroft Blackbird Blair Blue Hill Boone Columbus Petersburg.... i Lincoln 'Adams lAinsworth ... 'Alliance 'Alma Ansley Arago Arapaboe. .. 'Ashton lAtlanta 'Axiell Amherst Bee [Brady Butte I Beatrice. iBox Butte. .. j Hroken Bow . . Beaver City. . iBerlrand Bartlett Banrd Belmont lien kel man . .. j Bennett Bloominaton.. ,Burwell Cortland jCallaway .Comstock Cambridge jCrawford jCreston jCampbell Champion iCulbertson ... Ifhappell Curtis iClarkson j Denmark Denton Danbury Dunbar Eustis Kimwood Kddyville Eagle Elm Creek Elsie El wood Falls City Franklin Farnam Boon. Dixon Holt Custer Valley Merrick Holt Cuming Holt Washington Webster Boone Plane Boone Lancaster Gage Brcwn Box Butti Harlan Custer Richardson Furna&gt; Sherman Phelp&gt; Kearnev Buffalo Sewuni Box Hutte Custer Furnas Phelns Wheeler Cheyenne Dawe&gt; Dumly Lancaster Franklin Garti. Gage Custer Custer Furna^ Dawes Platte Franklin Cluise Hitchcock Deuel Frontier Colfa.x Lincoln Lancaster Red Willow Otoe Frontier Cass Dawson Cass Buffalo Perkins Gosper " Richardson Franklin Dawson •Ski imini .ationv </seg>
            <seg id="p096">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 97 •Skimming Stations. 0 HAMS Or CBBAMBRT M1IUGU OB PBo- PRI1TO* ft.ST-orn.E I'OCRTT m 'Beatrice Creamery Co m* ■■ •• TO* " " 71 * " ■ 72* - ■■ 73* •• ■ T4 • " ■ 75* " " 78* ' ■ 78* - ■ '.'.'.'.".'.'.".' 79* - ■ m* •• •• 81* ■ . • 82* •' H3* • » M* - ■ KB* ■' ■ 86* ■ ■ w&gt; ■• •■ (•&gt; - - «0&gt; ■ " »!,* ■ ■ Hi» - ■■ 93* •' •' 94'* ■ • !»S « " •' »6» ■ - »7« ■ - &amp;«,• •• ■ 99* • • l(«l* " l&lt;ll • ' 1(K.» " • •in 1 * ■■ ■ ... 104* • • KB 1 * ■ 106* ■ " • 07* ■ ■ II** •■ 109* ■ ■ 110* ■ Ill* ■ - 112* •• •■ 113* ■ ■ 114* '■ " us 1 * ■ ■ iiel* • ■ 117* " •■ 119!* • " ia&gt;* •• ■■ I. 1 '* ■• •• 122* • ■ nil* ■■ •■ i-'4* •• ■ ; 1** ■■ MK« ■• ■■ l?:* •■ 128* ■ ■ .... l-&gt;9* •■ " 130,* • " 131* ■ " 132 • • 188* ■ ■ 134* ■ • 186* ■ • 136* - - IJ7* - • Geo. E. Haskell. Pres. , Greeley Gross Gothenburg ... Gibbon Grant Goaper Gordon Guide Rock. .. Hemingford. .. Huntley Humboldt Holbrook Holdrege Haigler Havelock Hildreth .... Hay Springs .. Hayes Center Hooper Imperial Indianola Kearney Lanham Long Pine Lawn Lodjre Pole . . . Lynch Lamar Lexington Lindsay Llnwood Mascot Merna Maryland Maywood MoOook Miller Xaper North Platte .. Orleans Oconto Oxford " Overton Princeton.. . Palisade Pleasanton ... ' Petersburg . . Republic'nC'y Rushvllle Sanrent Sidney 8»cce»» Spencer Stratton Syracuse Scribner Sutherland . . Silver Creek .. Sparks sterling Stuart Spaulriing . . . Trenton Turlington .. . Taylor Upland Verdon Venango Valentine Wilson vine.. Greeley Boyd Dmwson Buffalo Perkins Gosper Sheridan Webster Box Hutte Harlan Richardson Pumas Phelps Uunily Lancaster Franklin Sheridan Hayes llOdKf Chase Red Willow Buffalo Gage Brown Box Butte Cheyenne Boyd Chase Dawaon Platte Butler Harlan Luster Dawes Frontier Red Willow Buffalo I Boyd 1 Lincoln Harlan Custer Furna&lt; Oawson Lam Hitchcock Buffalo Boone Harlan Sheridan Custer Cheyenne Seward Boyd Hitchcock Otoe DodKe &lt; Lincoln i Merruk Cherry Johnson Holt Greeley Hitchcock Otoe Loup Franklin Richardson Perkins Cherry Furnax </seg>
            <seg id="p097">98 NRBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. NAME OF CREAM EKT KAM.OrCBBAM.BT " '"^pUf^oR "°" •* ■*T-orriC» COCRTT arice Creamery Co 138 'Beatrice Creamery Co Geo. K. Ha-kell Pro- Wauneta... Chase Haskell. Pres Wauneta ... Ichase 139 « • " Wallace Lincoln Wallace Lincoln 140 • *?! ;; - " . Wellfleet ... Lincoln Welltieet Lincoln 141 ♦ Mr ■ ■ • Wolbach Ureelev Wolbach . .'.'.. IGreeley M*&lt;* \ 4 .Z'. : ' - •• Atwood KawlinV-.K Atwood R»wlinV&gt;.Ka- 143* Baker Brown. Baker. ........ | Brown. 144* Bremen I Marshall. Br.men I Marshall, 14ft • *5 • Blue Rapids .. Blue Rapids 1*1* " " Harnes Waahgtn 148* Barnes Bern Wash 'Km IJ:! " ••■ " •' »«"» Nematm. i4r Nemabu. 148* •■ •■ Cuba Republic. Cuba Republic, Herndon Rawlings. 149. **• [I " Herndon Rawlings. IS?!: :: :;•... :; :: %%™ *«*•■*•-. ISO. Hanover Washgt'n. ■ 151 . Haddam S: :: :: :; lami::: Pha " ps - \bt* ■ " Long Island .. Phillips. ™i* ■' • •• Lu.-tor Morrill Brown. ' •■ *t Francis... Cheyenne. 153:. Morrill Brown. Brown " •■ *t Francis... Cheyenne. Waterville... Marshall, Washington .. Washgtn. Washington .. Washgt'n Julesburg Sedgwlck. ■■ " Julesburg Sedgwick. C .Col 16" • ,t. " ■ Brush Morgan, :; :: •■ ■■ Hoiyoke Phmips, '" * •• •■ Haxtun « fiimphell Creauiorv t ■&gt; Campbell. Franklin N 63 (-arroll Crpamery I M. L Merrill Carrol Wayne M Carleton Creamery Oo W. L. Osborn &lt; arleton Thayer S r, h , am , bers r reamerv O&gt; H L. Kimrslev (.hamber Holt M Coleridge Creamer\ O .John Hayne ('oleridge Cedar » Clear Springs Creamer\ i ., Waterbury . Dixon * Dannebrot? &lt; 'reamery . .lens Jensen! Ihmnebrog Howard * David Pity Creamery f&gt;eo. Schwesser David City .. . . Butler Dixon Creamery Co a. F.. Sparks. Manair'r Uixon Dlxon -i Emerick Creamery Wm. Mclntosh Kmerick Madison 72| Farmers' Co-op. Creamery A&gt;- n F . s . Pexton. Secv Neligh Antelope 7] Fontanelle Creamery i. k. Cahoon Fonianelle .... Wasbingun Brush Morgan. ISO. Holyoke Phillips. Hi! • Haxtun ]«2 Campbell Creamer . - ' Campbell! "" Franklin Neb w (-arroll Crpamery I , M. L Merrill Ciirrol Wayne '** Carleton Creamery c. i W. L. Osborn ......... &lt; arleton B I.. Kinirsley Chamber Thayer IS Chambers creamery O&gt; ....'.'.' b.L. Kimmley .'..'! ".'.'. chamber .'.'.' '.'.'. Holt «« C olendee Creamer\ O .John Hayne C'oleridRe Cedar » Clear Springs Creamer\ i ., Waterbury . Dixon * Dannebrot? Creamery . .lens Jensen! Ihinnebrog Howard * David City Creamery f&gt;eo. Schwesser David City ... Butler i'O Dixon Creamery Co A. E. Sparks. ManaL'r Dixon Dlxon -i Emerick Creamery Wm. Mclntosh Kmerick Madison 72| Farmers' Co-op. Creamery Am'n F. s. Pexton. Secv Neligh Antelope 7j Fontanelle Creamery I. K. Cahoon . . Fontanelle .... Washington ■■ LrBuiiruruK ' . rettoierv '* David Pity Creamery ., 170 ui xon Creamery Co . J"l Emerick Creamery Madison Antelope 174 • ]!*' •■ ■• Hooper Dodge Hooper .1 H.-^s N'ewmanGrve Dodge 1"t. Farmers Creimery Co Ivfj Fairmont Creamery J7b&gt;. Farmers' rreimery Co j. Hess Newman Gr've Madison Newman Gr've Madison IW Fairmont Creamery J. H. Rushton. Pres.! Fairmont... Fillmore ■ • J. H. Rushton.Pres! Fairmont .... Fillmore Crete Saline Crete Saline 178 '• •• Fairbury Jefferson Fairbury DeWitt Jefferson '2 '" " UeWitt Saline 17V. Saline 180* '■ - " Ohiowa Fillmore Ohiowa Fillmore 181 « |l* •• Tobias saline ■''obias Saline 182. •J* ■• •• Dorchester... Dorchester . . 1X3 • " •• Saline Center. Saline Center 184. I** 1 * " " •• Wilbur •• Wilbur Western '**■• » •• Western 18V* INS. " » Beaver Cros'g Seward Beaver Cros'g Seward li&lt;7« {£■• ■ " ■' Milford Milford 188. " •• Pleasant Dale Pleasant Dale 1H». !?!,* " " Plymouth ... Jefferson Plymouth I Jefferson lie IJ. * •' •• Jansen Jahsen Bower "&gt;' • •• •■ Bower «• ■ • •■ &gt;teeleCity....; ».'• I! - Holland Lancaster »** ' ■■ •• Hickman £• ' ' •• •• saltillo H"&gt;* " ■ •• •• Firth !'.".".". I." '.'.'.'. ~ " - Alexandria !.! Thayer 1(*;» ■ ■• . . •• .. Kiowa 1*1 Olenville Creamery Association M. Rasmussen Glenvilie'.'. . '.'.'. Clay » Graf ton Creamery Co Geo. H. Warren. Sec . Graf ton , Fillmore BOermantown Co-op.Cream'ry Co E. H. Kock Oennantown Seward Grand Island Creamery O. Roeser Grand Island. Hall Golden Rod Creamery E. L. Ross Emerson ' Dixon Hampton Creamery Joshua Cox Hampton Hamilton Hartington Creamery Hanna &amp; Swanson... Hartington .. . Cedar _,' " " " " Kohl •• awl * " •' • Constance...! " ♦Skimming Station* IV&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p098">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 99 • MAHAGBK OH PRO 7. HAM! or CHEAMBBT PKirroR r«TT : »* Harrington Creamery Co 'Hanna &amp; Swuiwn . .KaMBow .. Cedar »* Harrington Creamery Co • West Bow Dlxon West Bow....! Dlzon !™|* " „ • " St. James.... Cedar vlei-sonc n-amery Con. Reiger. Mgr Henderson ... York St. James.. .. Cedar Hallan i 'Con. Reiger. Mgr Hendf rson .... York Halliin O. H. Allison. Mgr . . Norfolk Hallan Lancast Lani-a-i*r v Co O. H. Allison. Mgr .. Norfolk Madison ' Battle Creek Madison ' ■ Clear Water .. Antelop. I ■ Verdigre Knot I ■ Union Tp Madison ' Stanton.. Stanton Madison t!4 »&lt; Battle Creek . Madison Clear Water ..Antelope Verdigre Union Tp Knox Madison Man ton [Cumlng LoiraD Cumlng LOgaD Meadow (in Creighton I Knox Creighton. .Knox ' Foster Pierce Hoskins Wayne j'ireen Garden. Madison Foster Pierce Hoskins Wayne I'ireen Garden. Bancroft fctadteon ' " Bancroft Cumlng Belden Cedar Humphrey Platte jfuminif Belden Cedar Humphrey Platte " Bismark tp . Cuming Bismark tp Cuming '-■34 :a*el &amp; Stevenson Creamery . .'. Hagel &amp; Stevenson . .. Columbus. '.'.'.. PUtte*"' Nellfjh tp ... Cumlng Hagel &amp; Stevenson . Columbus iPUtte at-el &amp; Stevenson Creamery -;. ■' i;.-n,,.i Genoa " ■ Sherman I Sherman tp. H " ' Bismark Rismark Lsaaka 5£ . : ' Loaeke 2M Grund Prairie. Grand Pruirie. JJi ' " . ' ' Clarks Merrick ••■a Creamery Co Churle- llanlim: Omaha Douglax -'41 i.'larks M.rric-k Churles 1 1 anlimr Omaha UougUui 2«- ll.vgeia Creamery C&lt; 4.: ' .Herman Washini ■ ' Kennard Washim • Herman Washington .44 Kennard N. Nelson Jackson ... . . Washington ■• kson Creamery. iikson Creamery N. Nelson Jackson iw Creamery Co Kenesaw ".. Adams Jackson .'4- 1 Ki-tD-saw Creamery Co Kenesaw L. r. Tolle*. Mgr ... Laurel Adams .aurel Butter Co U c. Tolle«. Mgr . .. Laurel " Cedar urel Butter Co '.'. it'h Creamery Cedar .eitth Creamery V. V.. Beattv. See Lel K h . .' .' . . . Coif ax C. E-. Beattj S- Leich ..'.'.■■.".'.".■ Ooltex i ins Creamery Co. 90 LeKKe Creamery Co. Al, Lawrence Creamery. .yons Creamery Co W. H. Lyon. Sec Lyons Burt W. H. Lyon. Sec Lyons ..... '. '.'.'. J. Folda. MifT Kovers Burt &lt;-K»ce Creamery Co J. Folda. Mgr Rogers Colfax Creamery K. McBride Lawrence. ... Nuckoll iColfax E. Mr Bride Lawrence '.".'.. Nuckolls E. Mr Bride Lawrence . . . . .1 K Shultz Martinsburi.'.. Ji2 : Martinsburv Creamery Ai MartlnHburn Creamery' J. E. Shultz Miirtinsburi-'.. Dixon Martinsburi;.. j Dixon 3S3 Millard Creamery Association 253 Ml I lard Creamery Association... A. B. Detweiler. Se&lt;- . . Millard ... Douglas A. B. Detweiler. Se&lt;- . . Millard Douglas Mi shop A Withrow... Central City. .. Merrick 264 Meade Creamery Bishop A WUhrow. .. Central City. Merrick iS4 Meade Creamery. 2S6 Malcolm Creamery E. Deltch. Sec Malcolm. Lancast a&gt;S Malcolm Creamery . . E. Deitch. s&gt;. .laleolm. 'Lancaster «« Newport Creamery p. K. Fisher Newport Rock 2S6 Newport Creamery c. uciwu, o«Ti: .»iau-oim. . . P. E. Fisher Newport Rock 22 « e , wcas H e Crei «nery Newcastle Dlxon 287 Newcastle Creamery. Newcastle Dlxon -5« Nelson Creamery Nelson Nuckoll i£8! Nelson Creamery. Nelson I. Kri man Nysted Nuckolls A» Nysted Creamery I. Friman Nysted Howard -ted Creamery Howard ago Fender Creamery Pender ThurMo 280 Pender Creamery. Pender Thuraton J. G. Finney Pllger Stan ton \V. F. Robinson. &gt;ie&lt;- Ponca lMxon J5i l^'ffer Creamery J. G. FinMy Pllger Stanton 261 Pilfer Creamery *!S Pont "» Creamery Co W. F. Robinson. Sec . Ponca lMxon 3fl2 Ponca Creamery Co HS £,''■!•«" .Oeamery Wm. Bechtor Pierce ...... Pierce M3 Pierce Creamery. Wm. Bechtor Pierce .'..'.'.'.'.' Pierce W. Courtnage Plainview. . . Pierce 284 Plainriew Creamery w. Courtnage Plainview. .. Pierce 2S4 Plain view Creamery.. 2« Prairie Flower Creamery J. C. Hass Wausa Knox 3«S Prairie Flower Creamery ... .. . Jfl« Pleasant Dale Creamery J.C. Hass.. Wausa . JKnoi 3*5 Pleasant Dale Creamery C. T. (Jray Pleasant Dale. Sewanl ('. T. (iray Pleasant Dale. Sewanl Ruben Lipp. Sec Pawnee City.. Pawnee C. A. Clark Ravenna Buffalo Ord Valley I.oup City Sherman M. N Winebrenner . Randolph.. . Cedar T N Moon. Sec Riverton Franklin •m Pawnee Creamery Co Ruben Lipp. S«-c. Pawnee City . . Pawnee 'X! Pawnee Creamery Co. 208 Ravenna Creamery a«« Ravenna Creamery C.A.Clark Ravenna Buffalo 2* I " ' ■ Ord Valley -■*. £™ * ,', w ' " LoupHty Shermai !JW "Zl Ranil olPh Creamery M. N Winebrenner .. Randolph.. . Cedar 271 Randolph Creamery -TJ Riverton Creamery . . . ■-T3 Rising City Creamery -"74 Raymond Creamery . . £72 Riverton Creamery T N Moon. Sec Riverton Frankli ?73 Rising City Creamery Edgar Fox Rising City. . . Butler x . »■■ luinpu. o^v mvcnuu . . . EdKar Fox Rising City. Butler "2 Ra . vmond Creamery Jonn Weilzel Raymond.! Lanca-t Jonn Weilzel Raymond. '...'' Lanca-t.-r WS Savage Creamery C. E. Dawson Savage Antelop WS| Savatre Creamery. . C. E. Dawson Savage Antelope Frank E. Moore. Mgr. Schuyler Colfax 'JW Schuyler Creamery Frank E. Moore. Mgr. Schuyler. Colfax 'J7*i Schuyler Creamery 1T7 Seward Creamery -71 Se*»n&gt; Creamery Seward '. Sewanl Seward Silver Creek . . ISewanl J78 si lver Creek Creamery Si Wer Creek Merrick Merrick ■-"7» Stromsburg Creamery s. S. Nelson. Sec stromsburg Polk -•80 Superior Creamery &amp; Pro. Co ...iF. N. Henningren .. Superior Nuckoll Nuckolls »1 Sutton Creamery Association ... J. C. Merrill Ssutton " Clay jClaT 3*2 Spring Lake Creamery Geo. A. Hrooks Bazlle Mills .. Knox •Skimming Stations. Knox </seg>
            <seg id="p099">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 100 "-.orcu.Mnr I ™VZ£&amp;™ phietok. posT-orruit &lt; ouktt poar-omca &lt; ouhtt — 2K3 South Platte Creameries. Iw. A Carpenter. Mi •utn Platte Creameries. 284 ' ' . W.A Carpenter. Mgr. Aurora Hamilton Marquette Hamilton ■ " Arborville York Vork York L'lysses Butler Hnidshaw York Iiica Seward Thayer York Q re-ham Yock Stromsburtf . . . Polk Beulah Polk Island Polk Stark Hamilton Osceola Polk W. A Carpenter. Mgr. Aurora Hamilton Marquette Hamilton 284 ' ' ■5 •J**7 285 " Arborville York a* ■ York ; York L'lysses Butler »7 BrUdshaw York 288* MBi* 2»» »l* are* MS* SM'* «: »7» ~* - 300* 288« • Utica Seward MB* '■ - a»» • - Thayer York Gresham Yock »i* - «,* " - StromsburK . . . Polk MS- " " Beulah Polk «w» • Island Polk «: ;: :: Stark Hamilton lOsceola Polk van* ■■ ....'.'.'.'.'.'.'.' Ong Clay Clay S: :; : :::!:H::::: = = Shickley Fillmore Shickley Fillmore jSt. Paui Howard St. Paul Howard Howard St. Liborj . Howard J. W. Bush iTilden Madisor 301 Tildeo Creamery J. W. Bush 301 Tilden Creamery .. ... 3U2 Talma^e Creamery . . * a Union Creamery :«M West Point Creamery J. W. Bush [Tilden Madison ITalmaue Qtoe Madison Madison jTilden Madison 308 Taltna».'r Creamery ITalmaue Qtoe Madison Madison . J. J. Kini; West Point... Cumins Si 3 Union Treamery 304 West Point Creamery J. J. Kin* . J. J. Kin* West Point... Cumins Beemer Cumins Snyder ....... Dodije lOmeW P... Cumlnit 9 m se \V. P Cumintr l»m s w W. P CuminK 305» ■ 3K« *M* Beemer Cumins •08* " 4. Snyder ....... Dodtce W7» ■ ■ W7» soe* 300* 10 in e W P... Cumins S08» - ■ y m s e W. P Cumins 300* - ■ l»m s w W. P CuminK J K. CulinKS Wahoo Saunder&gt; 110 Wahoo Creamery i E. Culintnt ., 310 Wahoo Creamery 111* . |JE. Callnci \V;ihoo Saunders Prague . Ill* • Prague 31S» ■ " ... - SIS* 313* SHI* MM* Oadat Bluffs ;.ir Bluffs . in SIS* Yutan . . su* - - I \W&gt;ton IIS* • " Vnterloo Crenmery BurtB.Corl: Valpraiso Burt B. Corliss Omaha Douulas Valpraiso A uterloo Creamery. Burt B. Corliss Omaha Douirlas Waterloo . . Douglas Benmnffton .. . Douglas Springfield .. Sarpy V;illey Douglas Cretnii Sarpy st-hnf iWayLe Wayne Waterloo . . Douglas 3I»|* SiO* 321* Benninif ton . . Douglas 31»* Springfield .. Sarpy s*» ■ - Valley Douglas «1* - c;retri;i Sarpy -i-huf Wayte Wayne 3ttl Wayne Creamery Tim Wayne Creamery |C. Wischof •SkimminK Stations. •Skimming Stations. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">SIXTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 101 LIST OF CHEESE FACTORIES. MANAGER OB PBO- ■ AMI or KAl-TuKT PR1CTOR POST omCB COUNTT Clover Dale Cheese Factory W. M. Thomas Plattsmouth . . Cas.s Inavale Cheese Factory A. F. Hartwell Inavale Webster Loreito Cheese Factory U. C. Hallstead Loretto Boone Streblow Cheese Factory Streblow Cheese Factory F. A. Streblow Tekimah Burt Swiss Cheese Factory J. R. Jenney. If an&amp;x'r Neboville Platte Wilson Cheese Factory Leigh Plane . iv jcuuc} . ammumi r ncuuviuc * mi«^ Leigh Plane Avoca Cheese Factory Amsdel Sheldon Avoca |Caa« Uunlap Cheese Factory .'.... B. Fendrlch DunUp Dawex </seg>
            <seg id="p101">• </seg>
            <seg id="p102">. </seg>
         </p>
      
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>