<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TWENTY-FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Hospital for the Insane TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>   
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">ti i </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OK THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Hospital for the Insane TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1912 B. BENJAMIN F. WILLIAMS, M. D SVrtllNTENDIKT </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Hon. E. B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands and President Buildings rresmem i AnnisnN Wait. Secretary of State Secretary Hon. Addison Wait, Secretary of State Attorney General Hon. Grant Martin State Treasurer Hon. Walter E. George RESIDENT OFFICERS Superintendent Eiamin F. Williams, M. D. RENCE B. PlLSBURY, M. D LE L. EWING, M. D . . First Assistant Physician Second Assistant Physician Pathologist tiRENCE Emerson, M. D. E. Bennett, Esq. Steward Matron Mrs. M. K. Bennett NON-RESIDENT </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
        
            <seg id="p005">IN MEMORIAM It seems fitting that we preface this report with a word in memory of the late Dr. John T. Hay. Dr. Hay died on the twenty-eighth day of September, of the first year of this biennium. By his death the state sustained a great loss. His life was one of usefulness, being devoted al - most entirely to earnest and diligent effort in behalf of the unfortunate wards of the state in this institution. He had served the state for many years and won for himself a record of honesty and efficiency. He first entered the service in the early eighties as first assistant physi - cian. He had been connected with the institution either as first assistant or as superintendent a large part of the time from that date until the time of his death. The death of Dr. Hay occurred at a transitional period of the institution's history. New buildings were being plan - ned and many of the details were not yet completed. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">96 SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT Hon. Chester H. Aldrich, Governor of Nebraska and the Honorable Board of Public Lands and Buildings: Sirs: Another biennial period has been added to the history of this institution, and it becomes my duty as well as privilege to present my first and the institution's twenty-first biennial report of its progress and needs. With the close of this biennium we find that the hospital has grown far beyond the proportion anticipated. With the added responsibilities of a constantly increasing population has come the burden of providing for them suitable accomodations in our already overtaxed wards, and proper grouping of cases has been next to impossible. By act of the legislature of 1910 an appropriation of $100,000 was made for the construction of two hospital buildings. The buildings decided upon by the Board of Public Lands and Buildings provide housing for 200 additional patients. When the overcrowded condition of our present hospital building is depleted, there will be room for a limi f ed number of new cases. The appropriation has provided the bare buildings, but no provision was made for furnishing or connecting with light, heat, water and sewer. tOn December 1, 1910, there were 601 patients in the house, •ing the biennium there have ben admitted 505 new patients 32 have been returned to the hospital from parole. There e been under treatment in the hospital during the biennium \S; 100 have been paroled; 273 discharged; 101 have died; have eloped; 157 patients carried on the books of the in - ution, but not in the house, have been discharged. I On the date of December 1, 1912, there were 619 patients the house and 100 on parole. The maintenance per capita ■ing the biennium has been $14.10 a month. During the biennium the value of products of the farm, garden and dairy, estimated at market value, amounts to $39, - 403.65. Of this amount $14,844.16 has been converted into cash and placed in the cash fund. The balance of the products has been consumed and has help ad to decrease the maintenance expense. Permanent improvements have been created from the cash fund to the amount of $3 699 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Eie Barn and Campus, formerly a part of Hog Lot. Center Walk to Car A Walk in Campus. Onion Patch. A View of Hog Breeding Pens, nel and his Flock. </seg>
           
            <seg id="p008">97 Physical Condition of Patients The general health of the patients has been exceedingly good during the biennium. There have been no contagious or infectious diseases, save a few cases of erysipelas during the winter months, and a few cases of mild diphtheria. There have been, however, a number of cases of tuberculosis. In this con - nection, the frequent occurrence of active pulmonary and in - testinal tuberculosis among insane hospital patients is shown by autopsies held during the biennium. There was evidence of tuberculous process either in the form of pulmonary or intes - tinal in a large percentage of the cases. This evidence clearly indicates the importance of segregation of tuberculous patients in a hospital for the insane and emphasizes the importance of suitable provision for said isolation. tA brief examination of reports from various institutions in ird to the frequency of tuberculosis discloses this disease as the ntial cause in 38 of 184 deaths, or 17.5 percent. The pathol - t's report of necropsies shows that a proportion of 152 to or 69.9 percent, have tuberculous lesions which are un - btedly contributory factors. In our institution in the last biennium of the 44 patients who died previous to October 15, 14 or 61.6 per cent, died as a direct result of tuberculosis. The infrequency of necropsy permits by relatives make it impossible to determine the frequency of associated tuberculosis in those who died from other causes, but the clinical examinations reveal a proportion at least as great as that in other institutions. Housing and Paroles I It has been the policy of this administration to release to care of their families as many patients as seemed expedient, staff meetings the history, present condition of the patient, ir home surroundings and the possibilities of the patient lg the liberty with good results are discussed, and if deter - led favorable, an effort made to instruct the relatives in the ividual peculiarities of the case that they may anticipate iculties before they occur and in every way co-operate with hospital in securing the greatest amount of liberty possible the benefit of the patient and the relief of the state. The iical staff fully appreciate their limitations in entering far </seg>
            <seg id="p009">98 into the home life or aftercare of patients released from the hospital. There is a field for development along this line and many patients might be returned to their homes if proper super - vision could be instituted by competent person or persons, whose duty it is to inspect and instruct those who have charge of con - valescent patients on the outside. We have experienced two unfortunate accidents during the biennium, and in each accident it was purely the result of the overcrowded condition of the institution. A male patient on the violent ward on the night of May 21, 1911, almost under the eye of the night watch, stealthfully secured a portion of the bed clothing and constructing a noose of this, deliberately strangled a fellow patient to death without making any sound or dis - turbance sufficient to awaken two other patients who were sleeping in the same room. This accident would not have been possible had sufficient room been afforded to place this patient in a room by himself. Patients on the violent wards should of course be slept singly, but during the past biennium it has been necessary to sleep two patients in a bed, and the fact that other accidents have not occurred is the result of sheer luck and The second accident was the suicide of a patient who secured a knife from the operating room in some unknown manner and barring the door to his side room prevented the nurse reaching him until he had inflicted a bodily wound from which he died. Official Organization There have been two changes among the officers of the hospital during this period, occasioned by the death of Dr. Hay. Dr. August Anderson was appointed first assistant physician to serve from the first of October until the first of January. On the first of January Dr. Lawrence Pilsbury was made first as - sistant physician and Dr. Clarence Emerson was made pathol - ogist. The official organization has been most harmonious. Their co-operation in all things for the good of the institution has been in evidence, and by reason of this harmony much has been accomplished. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">99 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, LINCOLN The medical staff has conducted clinics regularly and each patient is taken before the hospital clinic for careful examination and analysis. The clinic is composed of the entire medical staff. Each case is carefully reviewed and a comprehensive record prepared. At this time a tentative diagnosis is made, the case kept under observation and carefully reported for a period of one month, after which the patient again appears before the clinic and diagnosis confirmed or altered, as the case may be. By this method all the physicians on the staff have an intimate knowledge of the condition of each patient in the The Nurses' Training School tThe change in the nurses' training school was occasioned the resignation of Miss Lillian B. Stuff, formerly super - ndent of nurses. Miss Mary Ruth Swann, form the Colum- Hospital at Washington, D. C, was appointed as super - ndent of nurses. She took charge of the school May 1, 1912. school was never more satisfactory than at present. I All nurses entering the employ of the state at this institu - are required to take training regardless of the length of ice in any other institution not giving training. The male ndants are not required, but are urged to take training. It been the policy to rotate the nurses on duty on the various ds, thereby securing for each nurse the full measure of ex - ence the hospital affprds. The value of the training school never more apparent than at the present time. By its in - nce the standard of employees is greatly elevated. Only ,e nurses who are manifestly interested in the training are loyed and only those who demonstrate temperamental ?ss for the work are retained. By the influence of the training school and the training school alone is the institution able to secure that class of em - ployees who treat patients kindly and considerately and who become skilled and tactful in the art of caring for and controlling the insane. No better expenditure of money could possibly be made in the interest of our state wards than an appropriation to perpetuate the nurses' training school. It is gratifying to report the keenest interest on the part of the nurses and attend- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">100 ante and the most painstaking effort on the part of the instruc- tors who conduct the course of training. The course of training offered by the training school is as follows: JUNIOR CLASS Monday and Thursday from 3 to 4 P. M Anatomy and Physiology Dr. H. L. Ewing September 23 to October 31 Examination November 4 Materia Medica Pharmacy and Laboratory Work Dr. C. Emerson and Mr. E. H. Swallow November 11 to December 19 Examination December 23 VACATION Hygiene and Bacteriology Dr. C. Emerson January 6 to February 13 Examination February 17 Contagious, Infectious and Children's Diseases Drs. L. B. Pilsbury and C. Emerson February 24 to April 3 Examination April 7 TEXT BOOKS Anatomy and Physiology Kimber Materia Medica Stoney Text Book of Nursing Stoney Obstetrics and Gynecology Davis Psychology Bun- Medical Dictionary Dorland Hygiene and Bacteriology Hiss and Zinsser Dietetics . Pattee Surgery Stoney SENIOR CLASS Tuesday and Friday from 3 to 4 P. M. General Nursing and Practice of Medicine . . Dr. L. B. Pilsbury September 24 to November 1 Examination November 5 Surgery and Bandaging Dr. H. L. Ewing November 12 to December 20 Examination December 24 VACATION Obstetrics Dr. B. F. Williams Gynecology Dr. H. L. Ewing January 7 to February 14 Examination February 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">101 Nervous and Mental Diseases and Psychology Dr. B. F. Williams and Dr. L. B. Pilsbury tThe Friday night dances continue to be popular amuse - is. Occasionally a lecturer or entertainer favors us with a ram. An effort is made to supply a variety of entertainments ell as to give abundant opportunity for inside games or out - or lawn sports. Religious Exercises Dr. Stuff, the chaplain, has conducted regularly Sunday morning services. His long experience and contact with the insane has rendered him highly competent for service as chaplain of the institution. He is especially tactful and able to interest his audience, and has won the love and esteem of the patients. The chapel is filled each service and the patients look forward with anticipation for the Sunday morning hour with Dr. Stuff. The music is supplied by a choir under the leadership of a chor- Fire Drill The fire drills have been conducted regularly. When the alarm is sounded every person in charge of a ward immediately assembles the patients on the ward, ready to leave the building. When all patients are so assembled and a census taken, the one in charge of the ward reports to center that everything is in readiness. A record is kept and it is surprising to see what development has come from practice. It is estimated that the building can be emptied completely in six minutes. Two fire companies were organized; the one composed of attendants 'ebruary 25 to April 4 Examination April 8 Metetics Miss M. R. Swann tuary 26 to April 5 Examination April 9 tical Nursing and Bedside Instruction Throughout the Year Miss M. R. Swann SPECIAL LECTURES lurgery Dr. J. M. McLeod lye, Ear, Nose and Throat Dr. A. P. Furgason lydrotherapy Dr. B. F. Williams &gt;ral Hygiene Dr. M. E. Vance Amusements </seg>
            <seg id="p013">102 and the other of the outside departments, who are in competition in responding to a call. Library I The library commisssion, created by the last session of the slature, in their distribution of books and periodicals, granted &gt; institution 270 books and 22 periodicals. By a system of jipting the books are obtained from the librarian on Satur - r of each week; the charge nurses, or attendants, returning ;he library upon this day all books and periodicals upon their •ds. By this method no books or magazines are lost, or troyed. The charge nurse, or attendant, is made responsible each book or periodical, and in case of loss the same is charged the nurse, or attendant, having charge of the ward. By i method a full circulation is obtained and each patient show - interest in any book or magazine is permitted to make his ■ction at the library. tThe class of books which seem in greatest demand among patients are books of fiction. The next in demand are the jnt magazines and popular periodicals. The least in demand the historical works. Some donations have been received there are now about 500 volumes in the library. I The experiment of establishing a library in this institution been most gratifying. Much good has resulted and it is to hoped that future legislatures will continue to appropriate, lenishing and expanding our library, that it may yield the est measure of good to our patients. Improvements During the past biennium a number of changes about the farm, the garden, on the campus and about the buildings have been inaugurated. The following is a summary of improve - ments: The Wards The wards have been repainted, the floors in some of the dining rooms replaced, and the wainscotings removed and re - placed with cement. Further remodeling is needed upon the violent wards. The arrangement of these wards is not good in that they do not admit of a sufficient amount of sunlight. The woodwork on several of the wards has been grained and fur - nishes a relief to the ordinary white wall of the ward. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">103 Campus The dairy lot and hog houses which have occupied a promi - nent position in front of the barn, have been torn down and re - constructed on a plot of ground back to their old location. The buildings have been reconstructed, using mostly old materials and rendered more efficient, while the plot of ground formerly occupied by these unsightly structures has been sown to alfalfa, and a portion of the old feed lot given to the cultivation of flowers, adding materially to the general aspect of this portion of the campus. A water pipe has been laid through the campus, conveying drinking water for the use of patients during the summer months, while on the campus. A triangular cement fountain has been constructed for water plants and special at - tention has been given to the artistic arrangement of flowers and shrubbery. t Ornamental lamp posts have been placed on the campus, same being manufactured under the direction of our head enter and assisted by patients. The same are quite orna - tal and made at small expense. 325 feet of storm sewer have been constructed which will carry the water accumulating in front of the annex and women's hospital building, passing beneath the new corridor and empty - ing at a point below the laundry. This prevents any possible overflow which might damage the foundation of the corridor and new buildings. Several hundred feet of new curbing have been constructed using the materials which were found in out - of-the-way places about the institution. Poultry House iA well ventilated and lighted poultry house 20x80 feet been constructed which affords ample room for a laying it of one thousand hens. A cement duck pond has been con - cted, and the general poultry yard enlarged. Power Plant Two new boilers were installed to provide additional ca - pacity to care for the new buildings. One new dynamo of in - creased capacity has been installed together with a Jones Under- Feed Stoker to supply the new boilers. The smoke stack which was not tall enough to furnish draught for the stokers was extended a distance of thirty-five feet. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">104 Laundry Twelve electric irons have been installed and are doing good service in the laundry room. Two rotary washers were installed and the building piped for steam heat to replace the soft coal stove which was formerly used to heat the building. Farm I The ice-house, which has been out of use since the installa - a of the cold storage plant, has been torn down and moved the west farm and reconstructed and is now used for a calf One hundred ten acres of alfalfa have been sown making a total of one hundred sixty-five acres of alfalfa on the hospital farm. Observations taken during the past history of the in - stitution would favor an increased acreage of alfalfa and a de - creased acreage in corn. The orchard has been cultivated, carefully pruned and all vacant places in the orchard have been reset with Ben Davis, Jonathan, Winesap and Wealthy apples. A vineyard of two thousand grape vines has been planted and the vines have made excellent growth. I The cottage formerly used by the chief engineer has been ed to a position adjacent to the new hospital building and d for a nightwatchers' cottage. Arts and Crafts I The department of arts and crafts organized during the st summer has been self-sustaining. All kinds of needle-work i basketry have proven profitable to the state and to the pa - nts. Patients who have steadfastly refused to be interested their surroundings have after persistent effort taken up some e of industrial work and advanced to a remarkable degree of iciency to the relief of many mental symptoms — the value this work can not be over-estimated in connection with the epital for the Insane. Open Air Pavilion An open air sleeping pavilion has been constructed which accommodates the tuberculous patients and the infirmary pa - tients. The roof of gravel is provided with a guard and a wooden platform constructed thereon that the roof may also be used for </seg>
            <seg id="p016">105 I open air pavilion. The first floor has been converted into ining room which enlarges the general dining room and will mit of all patients in the new woman's hospital building being red in the general dining room. A corridor has been con - icted connecting this dining room with the new woman's pital building and by means of this patients may be passed n the hospital building to the dining room without exposure I The State Association of Graduate Nurses presented to the I a sanitary drinking fountain. The same was installed position in front of the main entrance, securely anchored cement base and afforded great relief to the multitudes of )le who visited the institution during the past summer. The e is of great benefit to the patients who are on parole about grounds. It delivers an abundance of clear, cold water free 1 any possible infection. This act on the part of the nurses i be commended, and the institution has been greatly ben- Employees' Dining Room The employees' dining room in its present location was greatly crowded. It was not possible to serve the food in an appetizing way. The floor was badly worn. The room has been remodeled and enlarged; a new floor laid and new tables pro - vided. The dining room adds materially to the comfort of the employees. Hospital Cemetery During past years no attention has ever been given to the hospital burying ground. The same has been carefully leveled and sown to grass; a cement block placed at the head of each grave and a plot prepared so that an accurate record may be had of the place of burial of each patient. The trees have been trimmed, and in the future this part of the hospital grounds may be rendered sightly by planting of shrubbery and plants. General Kitchen The general kitchen has been repainted and an exhaust fan placed in the side wall, greatly adding to the comfort of the employees and patients who are on duty there. The escaping steam from the cookers during the hot weather rendered the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">106 Eerature almost unendurable; by use of the exhaust fan all i is extracted from the room and the cool air from the de replaces it. IMPROVEMENTS NEEDED Grounds I Since the street car line has been extended, the passengers delivered at a point ten rods north of the main entrance of hospital grounds. Visitors to the hospital wear paths, ng the most direct route across lots to the hospital main ■ance. Others traveling from the stock yards, back of the aital, intersect this path at other angles, cutting across grass s. The institution grounds are greatly damaged by this scriminate traveling. Efforts to direct the stream of visitors ;he main entrance of the hospital grounds seem futile. An imental iron fence similar in construction to the one surround - the University grounds should be constructed. Cement Walks I The general contour of the hospital campus is such that cinder walks which circumscribe the grounds and are used exercising patients are subject to great wash and damage ng rainy seasons. It is impossible to keep this walk packed lly during certain seasons of the year. The result is that surface is always being renewed with fresh cinders. The ring of these cinders upon the shoes of patients exercising it this ring daily is great. A cement walk should be con - cted. This would permit of outdoor exercise during rainy ons as well as dry with a minimum amount of damage to The Buildings The old main building houses approximately 450 patients. The construction of the wards used for violent patients is not all that is desired. Remodeling of these wards which will permit of an increased amount of air and sunshine together with new floors and electric wiring are greatly needed. The electric wiring in the old building has been condemned by the inspector of the city of Lincoln, and several |small blazes have ocurred about </seg>
            <seg id="p018">107 I? institution as a result of the defective wiring. The danger m fire by reason of this is so great that the light circuit the main building is cut off at ten o'clock, and the only light m that time until five in the morning is the light furnished by items used by night watches and nurses. This arrangement far from satisfactory, but appears to be the safest considering iditions. The new wiring should be so constructed as to per - t of a night circuit, should of course be conduit and in every y up to the specification of the national underwriters. The nodeling of the interior of the wards of the main building ;ether with the rewiring would involve an expenditure of ap - )ximately $9,000. Laundry tThe laundry and equipment are very defective. The increased ulation of the hospital will necessitate new laundry provision. s almost impossible to do the work for the hospital in the sent quarters. That portion of the building now used for isement hall directly above the laundry will afford sufficient :e for the laundry finishing room. There should be an ap - jriation of $10,000 to provide new equipment and remodeling building to fit it for use. Amusement Hall An amusement hall should be provided of such dimensions as to permit all patients who desire to attend amusements or chapel services to do so. Therefore, an appropriation should be made for one new building; the first floor of this building to be used as an industrial room. In this room the repairing of cloth - ing, manufacturing and repairing of mattresses, and general industrial work of the institution could be performed. The top floor would be used as an amusement hall. A suitable structure would cost approximately $40,000. Bake Shop IThe oven of the present bake shop has collapsed at two irate times during the past biennium. It has been patched and made to do until it has reached that point where relief it be had. An appropriation of $5,000 should be had to equip build a new bake shop. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">108 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT A special appropriation of $20,000 should be granted to purchase furniture and equipment for the two new hospital buildings. An appropriation of $6,000 is required to connect these r lings with sewer, water, electric light and steam. An appropriation of $5,000 should be granted to equip the hydriatic rooms in the two hospital buildings. The roughing-in for all equipment is completed and with the purchasing of the equipment the buildings will be ready for The present dairy barn is located in the basement of the general barn, underneath the horse barn. It is unsaintary, badly ventilated, impossible for sunlight to reach, and in every way is objectionable, and an appropriation should be had to build a new dairy barn. Appropriations The amount of appropriations desired is divided into small amounts. No single one amounts to any great sum. The ex- penditure of this amount of money in the way outlined will greatly add to the efficiency of the institution. The new buildings make additional demands upon every department, and the appropria- tions asked for in each instance are to afford relief to the already overburdened departments. To summarize, the appropriations requested for the next biennium are as follows: Regular Appropriation Officiers' salaries $19,700 Employees' wages 85,000 Maintenance 188,300 .General repairs 12,000 $305,000 Special Appropriation Dairy barn $5,000 Laundry 10,000 Bake shop 5,000 Industrial building and amusement hall 40,000 Remodeling and rewiring old building. . . . 9,000 Cement work : . 9,000 78,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">109 Appropriation to Complete and Equpt New Buildings Furniture and equipment for new build ings. $20,000 Connecting steam, sewer, water and elec tricity 6,000 Equipping hydriatic rooms 5.000 31,000 Total $414,000 Clinical Records The sterotyped form of clinical book affords insufficient data for the intelligent study of the individual cases. There - fore, the clinical book has been abandoned and a system of case records substituted which permits of an unlimited expansion in the accumulation of data and information concerning each individual case. Soon after commitment to the hospital the patient is pre- |«d to the medical staff for clinical analysis. All data received :onnection with the case from the county board of insanity ;ther with the information gleaned from the family and per - il history sheet are submitted to the medical staff. The ;t known as the "Mental Status" constitutes the summary deductions based upon the examination. Record of this mination is taken in shorthand by the clinical stenographer. I questions and answers constitute a part of the record and filed with the other data. By this system any person re - ving the record of any individual case is able to form his own lion of the patient's mental state and base said opinion upon evidence presented at time of examination. The clinical ;ts, copies of which appear, are upon different colored paper to render identification more simple. FAMILY AND PERSONAL HISTORY Full and complete answers to the following questions are requested so that we may know as much as possible about all patients who are committed Name of patient (in full ) ■__. Address of friends Number of brothers living. . . dead Number of sisters living dead Which in order of birth is patient?. _ . . Number of patient's children imale) living dead ...Number of patient's children (female) living dead Date of birth of youngest child Date of patient's mar- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">110 riage, if married What relatives have been insane? .. (a) On father's side (b) On mother's side Have any relatives suffered from epilepsy, St. Vitus's dance, hysteria, any other nervous diseases or in- temperance? HISTORY OF PATIENT Age at teething . Walking Speech General nutrition in childhood Diseases of childhood Any residuals, deafness, deformities, paralysis, etc (a) Contagious diseases (b) Other diseases (c) Injuries, head etc. Was there unconsciousness? (d) Convulsions. Age at onset, character, etc. Age at first menstruation Any abnormalities Mention mental or physical peculiarities at puberty Date of change of life Mental peculiarities Character of labors. Condition during pregnancies Has patient or patient's wife had miscarriages? Number .. Mention uterine or other diseases peculiar to women Have there been any surgical operations or diseases since puberty Has there been any veneral disease? Aptitude for study Where- educated Aptitude for work Early occupation Was patient social? Solitary? Egotistic? Religious tendencies . Was patient naturally mild? Irritable? Steady? . Rambling? Was patient eccentric? If so, in what way? Was patient temperate? If not, what forms of liquor were used and to what extent? Has patient ever had delirium tremens? Did patient use tobacco, and to what extent? Did patient use morphine, opium, cocaine or other drugs? HISTORY OF INSANITY Previous attacks of mental disease — give dates, duration, symptoms, where and how treated Supposed cause of insanity, such as habits, shock, misery, jealousy, disappointment, grief, overwork, occupation, intoxica- tion, injuries, organic or nervous diseases How long has patient been insane? Was the onset sudden or gradual? When did changes of character occur in habits?.. Morals? Disposition? Conduct? What physical symptoms were there, such as loss of weight . .. .Appetite . ... . Constipation Changes in speech Gait Sleep .. ...... Menstruation Has patient been dangerous to others? _ If so, how? Has patient been suicidal? If so, how? Has patient been destructive? Filthy? Noisy? Stupid? Excitable? Disorderly? Restless?. . Talkative? Indifferent? Was memory good or impaired? For recent events?, For remote events? For both? Has patient seen or heard things which do not exist? If so, what and when? Has patient had delusions (false ideas)? Describe fully Were delusions permanent or changeable? What did patient talk about? Did patient refuse to talk or eal? For how long?.. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">111 Did patient know he was insane? Did patient recognize his sur- roundings? His friends and relatives? Has disease been increasing? . If not, when was this first noticed? Have there been lucid intervals? If so, for how long? Did patient appear natural at such times? . . Signature Address. _ ..Remarks . Remarks REPORT OF RECEIVING NURSE REPORT OF RECEIVING WARD Case No. Name of patient.. .Received.. _M .19 Ward Report rendered hours after admission. Height Color of Eyes Complexion Color of Hair Recent injuries Old injuries Eruptions Condition of body as to cleanliness Restraint used at time of admission .Condition of clothing as to cleanliness and value Voluntary statements and general attitude at time of admission Received by LABORATORY REPORT Date Name URINALYSIS Specific gravity ..Transparency . Reaction Albumin Sugar Casts Pus Epith. cells Bile Acetone STOMACH ANALYSIS Test breakfast Amount of G. J Odor Undigested food Mucus Blood Total acidity Free HC1 Lactic acid Yeasts Sarcinae . Oppler Boas B Pepsin THROAT Diphtheria bacteria Other bacteria SPUTUM Character Tubercle bacilli Elastic tissue Other bacteria PUS Bacteria.. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">112 BLOOD Haemoglobin - Leucocytes total Small mononuclear Large mononuclear . . Transitional forms Polymorphonuclears Myelocytes „ . Eosinophiles Mast cells Basophilic stippling Parasites Culture SERUM Widal Waasermann Noguchi Butyric acid FECES Amount Consistency .. Color Odor .. Food Mucus Blood Pus Parasites Ova PHYSICAL EXAMINATION Name Date By Dr._. GENERAL APPEARANCE Height Weight Nutrition. Pulse Respiration Temperature RESPIRATORY SYSTEM CIRCULATORY SYSTEM ABDOMINAL AND DIGESTIVE ORGANS PELVIC ORGANS NERVOUS SYSTEM Eyes and vision 1 Hearing Smell.-. Taste Cutaneous sensibility Deep sensibility Co-ordination Muscular power Reflexes Movements Convulsions Speech . Right or left handed Paralysis, tremors or local spasms Vaso-motor or trophic disturbances Writing Remarks i SUMMARY— MENTAL STATUS Name Date Examiners GENERAL OBSERVATION Conduct upon time of admission Restlessness Voluntary complaints Demeanor toward those in authority Profanity Co-operation Irritation or depression DertructiveneBB Coherency </seg>
            <seg id="p024"/>
           
            <seg id="p025">113 GENERAL MENTAL ATTITUDE Ideas of reference Ideas of persecutit Ideas of persecution Delusions Hallucinations Illusions STREAM OR MENTAL ACTIVITY Flight of ideas Spontaneous product Spontaneous production Elaboration on things seen or heard Relevant answers Retardation ORIENTATION Identification of self Of those present Place Time Season Direction Insight and understanding of situation MEMORY Remote past Recent past Retention of word, number, etc EDUCATION AND GENERAL EXPERIENCE Calculation Geography History Current Topics Remarks MONTHLY RECORD Case No Monthly Chart for 191 Patient Nurse. Ward NOURISHMENT Appt. exaggerated Appt. normal . . Appt. poor Tube feeding Private tray Liquid diet SLEEP Approx. No. hours Hypnotic Dreams pleasant Dreams unpleasant Drowsy during day EXCRETIONS Normal Laxative or Enema Catheter Habits clean Soiled Wet Smearing, etc. OCCUPATION Reading Writing Games Ward Work GENERAL TREATMENT Bed Isolation Restraint Tub Hydro Therapeutic Outdoor exercise Parole GENERAL BEHAVIOR Resistant Passive Talkative .... Co-operative Polite Abusive . . . Aggressive Quiet Mute Sociable Seclusive Obstructive Excited Meddling Destructive Decorative Masturbation Inert .Attempted homicide Attempted suicide .. Attempted escape ..... . </seg>
            <seg id="p026">114 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT GENERAL DISPOSITION Happy . Sad Indifferent Affectionate Angry Homesick Laughing Crying Shouting Profane _ Obscene Prayerful Erotic Fearful Complaining SPECIAL SYMPTOMS Headache Seizures . . Hallucinations, Sight Hallucinations, Hearing Hallucinations, Touch Hallucinations, Taste Hallucinations, Smell Delusions Menstruation Temperature . Pulse ....... Respiration Financial Statement During the biennial period the appropriations made by the legislature were $358,567.57, which includes $75.25 lapsed in 1910 appropriation. There was spent from this fund $317,498.16, as follows: Officers' salaries $19,699 . 99 Employees' wages 55,429 . 04 Maintenance 130,228 41 General repairs 9,646.73 Laundry 450.00 Dynamo and boiler for engine room .... 2,100 . 00 Engine house new boiler 1,299 . 99 New buildings 98,644 . 00 In addition to this there was expended from the cash fund $27,054.54. Of this cash fund $8931.10 were received from the county boards for the care of inebriates, and the balance was obtained from the sale of farm products. The expenditures for the biennium for officers' salaries, employees' wages and maingenance were $205,357.44. The average number of patients present during the two years was 607 and the per capita cost was $338.31 or $14.10 per month. The usual tables of statistics are included in this report and respectfully submitted. Dr. B. F. Williams, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">To the Superintendent: The Legislature of 1905 passed a law providing for the de - tention and treatment of inebriates and drug addicts in one of the State Insane Hospitals at the expense of the respective coun - ties. Later an agreement was made whereby these individuals were to be cared for by the Insane Hospital at Lincoln. The first man was received July 8, 1905, and the first woman Aug. 26, 1905. At the date of this report there have been received altogether fifty-two women and 1172 men, most of whom re - mained in the hospital from 80 to 90 days. These patients are committed for a maximum period of three years, but it was deemed best by the Board of Public Lands &amp; Buildings to actually keep them in confinement for ninety days. From this ten days are usually deducted for good conduct. It will be seen that this arrangement savors somewhat of a sentence with forcible re - straint, but it does not seem possible to avoid this under the cir - cumstances. Unless an individual comes to the hospital volun - tarily, which is somewhat exceptional, he naturally regards his commitment very much as he might a jail sentence and as a matter of fact he may have been repeatedly in jail and may have spent some time in jail waiting to be sent to the hospital. Some Ehave spent nearly the entire time of their commitment in i county jail, owing to the overcrowded condition of the ital. PThe law specified that a separate ward should be provided dipsomaniac patients, but this is clearly impossible in the case of women, as there are seldom more than one or two such patients in the house and sometimes none at all. During the last several years it has been found equally impossible in the case of the men because there were too many insane patients who needed to be cared for on the dipsomaniac ward because of lack of room else - where. This is far from being a satisfactory arrangement from the standpoint of anybody concerned. Not only do the dip - somaniacs constantly complain and make this evasion of the law a ground for habeas corpus proceedings, but it is much harder to maintain discipline on a ward of this mixed character. There are usually from 12 to 20 dipsomaniacs on the ware) and from 25 to 30 insane patients. Moreover, the ward in question is one </seg>
            <seg id="p028">116 Ei it is necessary to use for a semi-disturbed class of patients a considerable proportion of epileptics who are notoriously ble. Of the results of treatment given to dipsomaniacs it is diffi - cult to speak, as our knowledge of their after history is scanty and casual. As a rule nothing more is heard of them unless they happen to be recommitted, which is not so very unusual. In such a case the results of treatment have obviously been only temporary, though it may be noted that one man who was re - committed recently is said to have abstained for four years after leaving here. Several years ago the plan was tried of sending out queries in regard to discharged dipsomaniac patients, but the results of this attempt were so unsatisfactory that the plan was abandoned. Often all trace of patients was lost after their leav - ing here. Some were transients in the first place and did not remain permanently in the county from which they were sent. In the beginning it was thought that patients who left here could be paroled, kept under surveillance and made to be on their good behavior, but the attorney general gave it as his opinion that when a patient left the hospital his liberty could no longer be restricted under the commitment in question. It has been the practice for some time now to discharge absolutely all dip - somaniac patients leaving the hospital. When a man runs away he is later discharged unless he is returned within a reason - able time. Since the beginning there have been 208 escapes, some patients having escaped more than once. Of these forty - eight were returned. Of the men seven have died while in the hospital and one of the women. There has been no attempt to administer any medication resembling the so-called "chloride of gold" treatment. The Igs employed promote elimination and stimulate the appetite, symptoms of illness are of course treated as they arise. The ie is examined in every case admitted and a physical examina - i made as a routine measure. When acute symptoms of al - olism are present these nearly always subside within a few s and it is almost never found necessary to administer alcohol, i only specific treatment employed is the Towns' -Lambert »tic treatment which is given to practically all drug addicts to a few alcoholic patients. The results have been very i indeed in the morphine cases, but the method seems less </seg>
            <seg id="p029">117 applicable to alcoholism. It is often possible under this treat - ment to withdraw morphine immediately and absolutely, even though the amount taken habitually may have been quite large. A clinical chart is kept during the administration of the narcotic specific the patients being kept temporarily on the infirmary It would be very unfair to say that all dipsomaniac patients are troublesome. Some of them work faithfully from the time of their admittance, conform to all the rules of the hospital and cause not the slightest concern. On the other hand many are sullen, discontented and continually plotting to escape from the time they first arrive at the institution. It can not be doubted that some have benefited permanently by the treatment given them here, but on the whole it is open to question whether the enterprise is a profitable one for the state. At any rate, there is no question but that this class of patients should be cared for at some other place than an insane hospital. A compromise arrangement would be to have them housed in a separate building, perhaps in a remote part of the grounds, but best of all would be a farm colony such as Iowa has had for some years and New York is about to have. The same might be said of the epileptic patients, many of whom are able-bodied and at most mildly insane and who might better be segregated in a separate institution. Such institutions are to be found in several of the states. Con - sidering the overcrowded condition of this hospital it is much to be desired that our wards might be kept for the insane alone. Respectfully, L. B. PlLSBURV, First Assistant Physician. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">To the Superintendent: I The pathological work during that part of the biennium end- Jan. 1, 1912, was done by Dr. L. B. Pilsbury. After that : Dr. C. Emerson has performed this service. The routine work has consisted in the examination of urine from every patient at the time or admission. The water supply has been subjected to frequent bacteriological and clinical exami - nation with favorable findings in all but a very few instances whereupon the reservoir was cleaned and disinfected with copper sulphate. Necropsies have been performed on all cases when the consent of relatives was obtained. The various sera, pus, blood, sputum, stomach, throat, exudate, and cerebrospinal fluid exami - nations have been made when clinically indicated. The laboratory work may be summarized thus: New Features A new animal house has been constructed and while not pretentious is of sufficient size for our purpose. It is now well stocked with rabbits and guinea pigs. An electric incubator has been manufactured by the pathologist at small cost. A serviceable blood-pressure apparatus was also made by the pathologist. Serum has been produced by rabbit experiment Jnnalyses 678 Iputum 86 66 Itomach 28 Hood 45 Vidal 16 Joguchi wasserman 29 Jutyric acid 11 3 Jecropsy 7 &gt;us 14 "erebrospinal 12 Hood culture 17 teraghty-Rowntree test 35 frobilinogen test : . . . 56 •uantitative ammonia 73 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, LINCOLN 119 Ether material prepared for the performance of Noguchi it it has been available when desired. The laboratory has made more sanitary by the use of oil cloth on laboratory , and the application of paint. I Some research has been done and two articles published the pathologist in the Journal of the American Medical As - ation, with the following titles: a. Clinical Incubator at Small Cost. b. Glycosuria Among the Insane. A third dealing with "Liver and Kidney Function among the Insane" is being worked out by the staff. Recommendations It is recommended that the laboratory floor be improved by the application of a hard non-absorbent surface since the pres - ent cement floor is porous and unsightly. The necropsy build - ing, an unheated bare room, is inadequate for proper examina - tions and should be replaced by one equipped with heat, running water, a necropsy table and instruments. An autoclave or pres - sure steam sterilizer is needed in the laboratory. C. Emerson, Pathologist. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">120 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Population for the Year Ending November 30, 1911. Men Women Total Number of inmates present at the beginning of the fiscal year 242 359 601 201 82 283 Number admitted during the year . Number returned during the year . . . Number paroled during the year .... Number discharged during the year Number eloped during the year Number died during the year Number transferred to Hastings .... Number present at end of fiscal year Average daily inmates present 61 10 71 78 30 108 98 23 121 53 0 53 28 27 55 2 2 247 369 616 244 361 605 Average daily number officers and employees 44 47 91 Population for the Year Ending November 30, 1912 Men Women Total Number inmates present at the beginning of the fiscal year 247 369 616 161 62 223 33 27 60 38 47 85 106 27 133 24 1 25 Number admitted during the year Number returned during the year Number paroled during the year Number discharged during the year . . Number eloped during the year Number died during the year Number present at end of fiscal year . . Average daily number inmates present 23 23 46 250 360 610 242 368 610 Average daily number officers and employees 43 50 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">TABLE NO. 1 iENERAL TREATMENT FOR THE FORTY-TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1912. (INSANE ONLY) 1 i? ] 1 2 H I I : J 1 g &amp; c -o % .a o z a a I 5 1 I] 1871 87 ... 87 8 1872 66 29 85 20 1873 49 38 87 14 1874 56 17 73 15 1875 46 46 92 20 1876 61 72 133 30 1877 93 52 145 24 1878 99 83 182 38 1879 120 117 237 42 1880 160 114 274 44 1881 193 124 317 48 ' 1882 230 164 394 71 1883 273 206 479 74 1884 282 204 486 74 1885 360 185 545 81 1886 358 202 560 97 1887 374 202 576 96 1888 400 219 619 72 1889 392 194 586 72 1890 309 I 201 I 513 83 1891 326 I 189 4 519 81 1892 346 200 4 550 67 1893 273 242 3 518 92 1894 317 269 1 587 90 1895 341 255 2 598 115 1896 348 225 573 101 1897 351 216 5 572 93 1898 360 226 586 73 1889 330 253 6 589 106 1900 369 250 619 90 1901 365 358 9 i 732 80 1902 531 476 5 1012 105 1903 516 530 16 1062 166 1904 513 524 17 1054 113 ' 1905 588 455 19 1062 121 1906 559 339 19 917 57 1907 508 255 21 784 75 1908 500 167 15 | 682 37 1909 511 185 66 ! 762 33 1910 555 130 91 776 21 1911 570 154 16 740 1912 599 I 96 I 8 703 , I i i i 4 1 1 1 i 4 4 2 6 2 2 1 1 2 4 2 4 2 2 I 1 I 1 1 1 3 2 2 2 2 3 3 1 7 4 4 1 ' 7 4 10 3 11 2 6 1 3 3 a i 1 36 1 2 34 7 f 5 2 5 2 3 13 11 14 15 17 : 25 23 20 36 21 31 25 I 19 32 27 31 21 24 30 19 23 30 36 28 27 66 61 54 63 71 48 40 41 46 55 45 12 41 4 14 1 17 : 34 19 2 ■5 66 17 80 19 77 13 56 132 131 44 33 97 392 131 809 86 100 273 26 317 42 341 61 30 (51 57 360 107 330 32 531 182 516 186 513 109 588 181 559 130 508 91 501 3 510 1 570 2 599 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">122 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT MOVEMENT OF POPULATION INSANE Summary for Two Years 1911 1912 In hospital at beginning of year 211 359 570 230 369 599 211 359 570 Admitted 76 78154 43 53 96 ! 119 131250 Returned I 6 10 16 3 5 8 9 15 24 Under treatment 293 447 740 276 427 703 339 505 844 Discharged 19 17 36 16 18 34 35 35 70 Discharged, not insane 1 2 3 1 1 2 2 3 5 Transferred to Hastings 2 2 2 2 Paroled 14 30 44 8 25 33 22 55 77 Died ..'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'■ 28 ' 27 55 22 23 451 50 50 100 ■ i Total removed i 63 78 141 53j 68 121J116 146J262 Remaining November 30 230 369 599 223 359 582 223 359 582 Average number treated 219 360 579 221 366 587 220 363 583 Pnt on parole or elopement November , and later discharged without re- , rning to the hospital 73 59 132 5 14 19 78 73 151 Paroled or eloped during 1911 and later discharged without returning to the </seg>
            <seg id="p035">123 INEBRIATES AND DRUG HABITUES Summary 1911 1912 for 'Two Years m I w t m|w!t|m w|t In hospital at beginning of year 31 31 17 17 31 .. 31 Admitted 124 4 128118 9 127 242 13 255 Returned 5... 5 3 3 8 . . . • 8 — — — — I— j ;— I— Under treatment 160 4 164 138 9 147 281 13 294 Discharged 87 4 91 104 8 112 191 12 203 Paroled 23 23 23 U Eloped 33 33 6 6 39 .. 39 Died ! 1 1 ••■ ! Total removed 143 4 147 HI 8 119 254 12 266 Remaining, November 30 17 17 27 1 28 27 1 28 Average number treated 25 1 26 21 2 23 23 tt on parole or elopement November 1910, and later discharged without rning to the hospital 3 3| 91 ... 91 91 3 94 Paroled or eloped during 1911 and later discharged without returning to the hospital ,.l.| 53 53 53 . 1 53 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">124 Average Number of Employees for Twenty-four Years Employees Biennium Monthly Average 8 1888 62 9 1890 56 10 1892 60 11 1894 52 12 1896 55 13 1898 59 14 1900 61 15 1902 77 16 1904 87 17 1906 86 18 1908 86 19 1900 . 80 20 1912 80 Eight biennium beginning December 1, 1886. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">125 Tablr No. 2. Type of Disease of Patients Admitted Men Women Exhaustion psychoses 2 Toxic psychoses Alcohol 5 Delirium a Thyroid 1 Uremia 1 Dementia praecox Catatonic form 2 22 Hebephrenic form 20 8 Paranoid form 6 15 Paresis 26 5 Organic dementia 2 1 Involution melancholia 5 6 10 Senile dementia 14 Manic-depressive insanity 12 46 Paranoia 3 Epileptic insanity 9 4 1 Hysteria 10 2 Imbecility Moral imbecility 1 Constitutional inferiority 1 I Not insane 4 Total 119 Inebriates and Drug Habitues Men Women 223 6 Alcohol 6 Drug habit 19 7 Total 242 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">126 Table No. 3. Counties from which Patients were Admitted Burt 1.1 Butler 1 .. 1 Cass 5 3 4 . . 12 Cherry 1.1 Cheyenne . . 2 o Clay Coif ax Cuming . . 1 • Custer .. 4 1 5 Dakota . . 5 . 5 Dawes .. 2 1 3 Dawson . . 2 . . 2 Dixon Dodge 5 4 12 21 Douglas 32 36 29 2 99 Fillmore . . 4 . . 4 Franklin . . 2 . . 2 Frontier 1 . . 1 Furnace Gage 7 8 15 1 31 Garfield Greeley . . 2 . . 2 Gos f er 1 1 Hall 14 1 15 Hamilton . . 2 . . 2 Insane Addicts Total Men i Women Men Women 3 1 4 Antelope 1 1 Blaine Boone 4 4 Box butter 2 2 Brown Buffalo 5 5 Boyd 4 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">127 Inebriates and Drug — Continued Insane Addicts Men Women Men Women Total Harlan Howard . 2 1 3 Holt 1 .. 1 Hooker 1 1 Jefferson 1 .. 3 4 Johnson 1 2 1 .. 4 Kearney .. 3 3 Knox 3 3 Keya Paha 1 1 Lancaster 37 33 23 2 95 •&gt; Madison 13 13 Merrick .. 1 .. 1 Morrill Xemaha 4 4 7 .. 15 i Nuckolls .. 4 . 4 Otoe 6 2 8 o Pawnee 2 2 4 Phelps 1.1 Polk 1.1 Pierce 4 4 Platte . . 4 . . 4 Red Willow .. 1 1 2 Richardson 9 8 2 1 9 2 Rock. Saline 4 9 2 .. 15 Sarpy 2 1 3 •&gt; Saunders 3 9 4 16 Seward 3 9 . ■ 12 Shei man . . 1 . . 1 Sioux Stan ton Scott Bluff .. 4 4 Thayer Thurston Valley 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">128 Inebriates and Drug- — Continued 3 8 IK 7 13 19 3 15 36 1 IS 32 2 14 33 ■■; a 11 34 1 10 31 7 15 8 9 1 2 5 7 4 1 2 3 3 4 1 1 2 20 131 242 13 505 Insane Addicts Men Women Men Women Total Washington . . 5 . . 5 Eie . . 4 . . 4 ter . . 2 1 3 ler ______ Totals 119 131 242 13 505 Table No. 4. Ages of Patients Admitted Inebriate and Drug Insane Addicts Age Men Women Men Women Total Ac ere 15 to 20 5 20 to 25 8 25 to 30 11 30 to 35 23 35 to 40 13 40 to 45 16 45 to 50 8 50 to 55 11 55to60 7 60 to 65 4 65 to 70 9 70 to 75 2 75 to 80 1 80 to 85: .. 1 1to90 to 95 to 100 &gt; to 105 Unknown Totals 119 </seg>
        
            <seg id="p041">\ 1 ! i i 1 \ \ </seg>
            <seg id="p042">129 Table No. 6. Nativity of Patients Admitted Inebriate and Drug Insane Addicts Men Women Men Women Total Table No. 5. Civil Condition of Patients Admitted Inebriate and Drug Insane Addicts Men Women Men Women Total darned 50 64 143 9 266 lingle 55 33 69 1 158 Vidowed 6 20 14 2 42 )ivorced 6 12 6 1 25 Jnknown 2 2 10 . . 14 Totals 119 131 242 13 505 Asia Minor Austria ... Bohemia 2 Canada ... China Denmark 2 England . 2 France Germany. 9 Greece Holland ... Ireland... 5 Moravia . . . Norway.. Poland 1 Russia 4 Scotland . . 1 9 6 •■ 1 7 » 1 « 2 « 11 14 u •• ■■ 1 i 5 1 i 3 3 3 4 3 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">130 Nativity of Patients Admitted— Continued Inebriate and Drug Insane Addicts Total Men Women Men Women Sweden 3 6 4 1 14 Switzerland 1 . . . . . . 1 Wales United States 85 96 184 11 376 Unknown 4 1 15 . . 20 Totals 119 131 242 13 505 Table No. 7. Occupations of Patients Admitted Inebriate and Drug Insane Addicts Men Women Men Women Total Agents 1.1 Barbers . . 10 . . 10 Bartenders 1 . . . . . . 1 Blacksmiths 2 .. 1 .. 3 Carpenters 7 .. 11 .. 18 Clerks 1 . . 6 7 Conductors, R. R 2 2 Cooks 1 .. 2 3 Dentists 1 .. 2 .. 3 Domestics 9 . . . . 9 Dressmakers 1 . . . . 1 Druggists . . 2 . . 2 Electricians . . 1 . . 1 Elevator operators 1 .. .. .. 1 Engineers, civil . . 1 . . 1 Engineers, locomotive ... 2 . . . . . . 2 Engineers, stationary 1 .. 2 .. 3 Farmers 36 . . 58 . . 94 Fireman, stationary . . 1 . . 1 Gardeners 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">131 Occupations of Patients Admitted — Continued Inebriate and Drug Insane Addicts Total Men Women Men Women Horse- trainers 1 1 Hotel-keepers •&gt; 9 House-keepers 93 9 102 Insurance agents 2 1 3 Iron-moulders 1 1 Jewelers 1 1 2 Laborers 25 48 73 1 Laundrymen 1 Linemen 1 1 Liverymen 1 1 Machinists 2 9 Mail-carriers 3 1 4 Masons 7 i Mechanics 1 1 Merchants 6 6 12 Nurses 1 1 12 Painters 3 0 Paper-hangers 1 1 Peddlers 1 1 Physicians 2 1 3 Plasterers . 3 3 Plumbers 2 9 4 Printers 2 4 6 Prostitutes 1 1 R. R. Employees 2 2 1 Railway mail-clerks 1 Real estate agents 1 2 3 Restaurant-keepers 4 4 Salesmen 1 9 Saleswomen 1 1 2 Saloon-keepers 1 1 Seamstreses 3 8 Shoemakers 1 2 I Stenographers 1 3 4 2 Students 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">132 Occupations of Patients Admitted — Continued Inebriate and Drug Insane Addicts Total Men Women Men Women Teachers 1 7 .. .. 8 Teamsters . . 1 . . 1 Tinners 1 . . . . . . 1 Tailors 4 .. 4 Wagon-makers . . 1 . . 1 Watchmen .. 2 .. 2 Watchmakers . . 1 . . 1 Well-diggers . . 1 . . 1 N T o occupation 5 10 1 2 18 Unknown 2 2 20 24 Totals 119 131 242 13 505 Table No. 8. Causes of Death Insane Men Women Acute cardiac insufficiency 1 Acute miliary tuberculosis 1 Apoplexy 1 1 Arterio-sclerosis 1 Arthritis deformans 1 Cerebral softening 2 Exhaustion 2 2 Inanition 1 1 Organic brain disease 1 1 Organic heart disease 2 2 Paraplegia 1 ♦Paresis 23 3 Pneumonia 2 6 Pulmonary hemorrhage 1 Pulmonary tuberculosis 3 16 Self-inflicted wound 1 </seg>
            
            <seg id="p046">u c pa 1 "c - 8 c 'S 2 T C ■ ai c c &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p047">133 Causes of Death — Continued Insane Men Women Senility 6 10 Senile epilepsy 1 Sepsis 1 Status epilepticus 4 Strangulation 1 Uremic poisoning 1 Totals 50 50 "Several of the paresis cases had pulmonary tuberculosis. Dipsomaniacs Men Women 1 Cerebral softening STEWARD'S REPORT Cash Fund Cash on hand December 1, 1910 $ 2,256 64 E received for care of dipsomaniacs. $ 8,931 . 10 received for sale of live stock 9,715 65 received for sale of hides 1,985 . 12 received for sale of bread 574 48 Cash received from all other sources ... 5,602 42 26,808 . 77 Total $29,065.41 r expended from December 1, to November 30, 1912 $27,054 54 ron deposit with state treasurer November 30, 1912 1,453 61 Cash in bank November 30, 1912 211 44 Cash on hand November 30, 1912 345 82 Total $29,065 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">134 FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCTS Corn 4,300 bushels Oats 1,715 bushels Oat straw 25 tons Wheat 1,320 bushels Prarie hay 18 tons Alfalfa hay 300 tons Tame hay 162 tons Cane seed 925 bushels Cane hay 175 tons Ensilage 350 tons Apples 783 bushels Asparagus 2 bushels Beans, string 115 bushels Beets, blood ; turnip 275 bushels Cabbage 114,748 pounds Carrots 323 bushels Cauliflower 266 heads Celery 75 dozen Cherries 132 bushels Corn, sweet 312 bushels Cucumbers 47 bushels Egg plant 6 dozen Green spinach 334 bushels Horse radish 40 pounds Lettuce 351 bushels Musk melons 1,197 Onions, dry 360 bushels Onions, green 13 bushels Onion sets 54 bushels Parsnips 430 bushels Parsley 169 quarts Peas 233 bushels Plums 17 bushels Potatoes 2,715 bushels Potatoes, sweet 248 bushels Radishes 90 bushels Rhubarb 208 bushels Ruta baga 16 bushels </seg>
            <seg id="p049">135 Farm and Garden Products — Continued Salsifv 81 bushels Strawberries 60 bushels Squash , 2,185 t Tobacco 350 pounds Tomatoes 984 bushels Turnips 348 bushels Watermelons 5,398 DAIRY Total number gallons milk 81,244 Monthly average, gallons milk 3,385 Daily average gallons milk Ill Daily average for each cow 2.313 Daily average number cows milked 48 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">136 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT „, « noon &lt;o© o — 2 ll^a !g§S : " ' : S 2 It] " x I _ a E i °? ®. ■* ® ■&gt;: °&gt; 5 ® S 0% 3 §§§§§§§§ i 2T |"!s §§§§§§§§ s jg r g ij -a I ooote i-H • ■ ■ &gt;a E&lt; &lt;-&gt;O« • t- ■ • ■ M kiu g. o ■» :^ : : ; » . _, WO400 N ■ *£ ooeot- •* ' ' ' t 3n w i-i 00 : «d ' ' ' as 3S g- &lt;» 00 «T ■ ■ ■ • mi g S s ■ ■ I d Q I : : : :. 0 I^IS^- S2gg : S ; ; : Si Q ::::::::: 1 ffillli! * &lt; ;hSqohjz </seg>
            <seg id="p051">3pen Air Pavilion from Corridor, built from Cash Fund, 1912 View of the Camnu </seg>
          
            <seg id="p052">137 rH RECEIVED FOR SALE OF FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCTS Cane seed $ 880.20 Cattle ' 295.00 Hogs 9,420.65 Hides 1,985.12 Millet seed 109.63 Wheat 1,009.44 Pasture 30.50 Melons and cantelopes 44.19 Cabbage and tomatoes 99.45 Rags and old iron 188.48 Tomatoes, cabbage, and sweet potato plants 207.02 Bread 574.48 $14,844.16 Total CATTLE AND HOGS Beef butchered (purchased) 168 heads 94,090 pounds Beef, butchered (raised on farm). . 124 heads . 50,080 pounds Veal butchered (raised on farm).. . 60 heads . 9,950 pounds Hogs butchered (raised on farm). .137 heads. . .20,920 pounds Sheep butchered praised on farm) . . 8 heads . . . 390 pounds Six cattle, killed, and condemned. POULTRY Eggs </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>