<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00031">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Breeding Winter Wheat for Resistance to Stinking Smut</title>
               <date value="1930-12">1930-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 51~ Breeding Winter Wheat for Resistance to Stinking Smut (Tilletia levis and Tilletia tritici) T. A. KIESSELBACH and ARTHUR ANDERSON Department of Agronomy Lincoln, Nebraska December, 1930 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY Several productive lines of hard red winter wheat which are highly 'resistant to both species of stinking smut (T. levis and T. tritici) have been isolated from the Turkey variety. Artificial-smut and stem-rust epidemics and controlled freezing have been found useful supplements to field-performance tests. In response to inoculation in the seedling stage with four physiologic forms of black stem rust (Pticcinia graminis tritici), all of these Turkey selections gave indications of superior rust resistance. When subjected to low temperatures, three of them appeared to be as cold - resistant as Nebraska No. 60, a standard and extensively grown wheat in Nebraska. These same three selections, in duplicate field plats in 1930, ranged from 4.3 to 4.8 bushels higher in yield per acre than Nebraska No. 60 and ripened from one to three days earlier. In the nursery the average yield from ten replications ranged from 1.9 bushels less to .9 bushel per acre more than the parent variety. - ■ Some segregates of hybrids between standard susceptible and re - sistant varieties have given such favorable reactions to inoculation with various collections of smut that this method of obtaining new resistant lines seems to give much promise. All collections of smut from Nebraska and other central states of the hard red winter wheat belt proved to be T. levis. Four other collections used in these tests were T. tritici. Differential reactions of the new Turkey .selections and a number of hybrid selections and established resistant varieties to collections of bunt from a number of states give definite evidence of the occurrence of mild and virulent physiologic forms of both species. Certain selec - tions have proved very resistant to some of the smut collections and rather susceptible to others. Some of them are so resistant to all col - lections tested that annual seed treatment for the prevention of smut would appear unnecessary. In case continued yield tests substantiate present indications, one or more of these new selections will merit ex - tensive trial. . . </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Breeding Winter Wheat for Resistance to . Stinking Smut (Tilletia levis and Tilletia tritid) T. A. KIESSELBACH and ARTHUR ANDERSON Thru the use of control methods of selection and testing, a number of promising new lines of hard red winter wheat which are extremely resistant to the stinking smut or bunt disease caused by Tilletia levis Kiihn and Tilletia tritid (Bjerk.) Wint. have been established at the Nebraska Agri - cultural Experiment Station. These investigations were undertaken because of the growing prevalence of this disease and the great financial loss caused thereby to wheat growers. Even tho effective means for its control thru seed treatment have been developed, the persistence of smut is apparent from the data in Table 1. Table I.— Percentage of wheat grading smutty in terminal inspections of car load receipts at four Nebraska markets seven years ( 1923-1929 J 1 Terminal 1923 1924 1925 1926 1927 1298 1929 ir f' *'• P- ct - P- Ct. P. Ct. P Ct P Ct P rl Kearney 4.7 35.0 53.6 27.5 12.5 35 2 35 9 ftSsS?:-:::: :::::::::: ■ ,\i &amp;? ? 9 $ SI. «« I I Sehnyler 17.5 26.5 19.5 20.9 1M 11 .1 fals Statistics compiled by the U. S. Department of Agriculture indicate that 28 per cent of the cars of wheat received at Omaha during a seven-year period, 1923 to 1929 graded smutty. The price paid for such wheat is discounted because of its reduced milling value. This, together with the fact that the loss in grain yield has been found in unpublished Ne - braska tests with local hard red winter varieties to be nearly proportional to the percentage of heads infected, stresses the advantages of a smut-resistant wheat. In any attempt to produce new varieties that are resistant to smut, the importance of combining other desirable agronomic characteristics should not be overlooked With this m view, the more resistant- selections have also been tested in the field for yield and vegetative type and under controlled greenhouse conditions for reaction to low tem - peratures and black stem rust (Puccinia graminis tritici (Pers.) Enkss. and Henn.). The use of control methods to insure disease epidemics and winterkilling is one of the newer aids in an effective winter wheat selection program. The opportunity for the determina- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 51 tion of relative cold endurance may be long delayed when it is dependent entirely upon seasonal conditions in the field. This may be illustrated by the loss of 82 per cent of the entire Nebraska winter wheat acreage during the winter of 1916 - 1917 by winterkilling, whereas since that time stand losses due to cold have been relatively small. Losses from occasional widespread stem-rust epidemics are well recognized. Such losses occurred in Nebraska in 1917, 1920, and 1923. Since the most productive varieties now commercially available in this region are more or less rust susceptible, the development of a productive wheat that is resistant to the prevailing physiologic forms of rust would seem highly desirable. FOUNDATION VARIETIES Improvement was undertaken by selection within com - mercial varieties and within hybrid populations. The tests by the former method have reached a somewhat more ad - vanced stage. Varieties for selection.-, — In planning a program of selec - tion, it seemed desirable to begin with varieties whose general superiority had been established. Two such varieties of hard red winter wheat were available. These were Crimean (C. I. 1435) and Turkey (South Dakota No. 144). They had ranked second and fourth in yield, respectively, when compared with 42 other varieties and strains during an eight-year period, 1915 to 1922. (Kiesselbach, 1925.) This group of wheats included the best varieties obtainable from the experiment stations of the hard red winter wheat states and from the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Varieties for hybridization. — The outstanding smut-re - sistant varieties available at the time these hybridization studies began were Regal, Sherman, Hussar, and Ridit. None of these had given evidence of being well adapted to this locality. They were crossed in 1924 with two standard local hard red winter varieties,. Nebraska No. 6 and Kanred, which had proved very productive but susceptible to smut. A num - ber of plant selections have been made from each of these hybrids, beginning in the third generation. INITIAL SELECTION UNDER BUNT AND STEM-RUST EPIDEMIC CONDITIONS A special planting was made in the fall of 1923 with seed of the Crimean (C. I. 1435) and Turkey (South Dakota No. 144) varieties which had been heavily inoculated with T. levis collected locally. The following spring an artificial epidemic of stem rust (Puccinia graminis tritici) was created in these </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Breeding Winter Wheat plats. Potted wheat plants heavily infected with 10 dif - ferent physiologic forms of stem rust were distributed about the nursery in time to permit spread of the disease. 1 A water suspension containing spores of a number of physio - logic forms of rust was also sprayed over the growing plants. Fairly severe epidemics of both rust and bunt developed. Four hundred and fifty-three heads were selected from smut-free and relatively rust-free plants in the case of the Crimean and 397 such selections were made from the Turkey variety, making a total of 850 selections. Fifty-one of these are still being grown because they have given, some evidence of superior rust resistance. ELIMINATION OF SELECTIONS SUSCEPTIBLE TO T. LEVIS COLLECTED LOCALLY (1925-1930) After being inoculated with a local collection of T. levis, these 850 selections were planted in head rows in the fall of 1924. Thereafter plantings were made in 8- or 16-foot rows at normal rate. Except in cases of high resistance, where the entire row was carefully examined for bunt, the percent - age of smut has been based on the number of smutted or partially, smutted heads found in three to five lots of 100 con - secutive heads. Table 2. — Relative distribution of 420 selections of winter wheat with reference to degree of infection when uni - formly inoculated ivith T. levis collected locally (1926 and 1927) ,. . Percentage of infection " Variety and year . . . ■ 0-9 10-19 20-29 30-39 40-19 50-59 60-69 70-79 80-89 1 90-100 \P.cl. P.cl. P.cl. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P. ct. P. ct. P ct (1) I «&gt; (3) (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) (io) (il) NUMBER OF STRAINS IN EACH GROUP Crimean (C. I. 1435) 1926.,..- ..I 0 1 2 I 3 I 33 I 48 I 56 I 42 I 25 I 8 1 1 1927. ....| 0 I 1 | 3 | 5 | 11 [ 12 | 38 | 68 I 65 25 Turkey Red (So. Dak. 144) 1926 I 32 I .26 I 33 I 29 I. 35 I 23 I 18 I 5 I II 0 1927 I 33 | 33 I 19 | 24 I 29 I 22 [ 23 I. 5 I 9 | 5 Weather conditions in 1925 were not favorable for severe epidemics of bunt. To illustrate, five relatively bunt-suscept - ible varieties which had been similarly inoculated averaged but 15 per cent infection. At harvest, only head rows 'This rust material was supplied by M. N. Levine of the Minnesota Agricultural Experiment Station and the potted plants used in the field were infected by G L Peltier, Station Plant Pathologist. ' ™ </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 51 entirely free from smut were saved for continuation. Of the Sections continued, 235 were from the Crimean and 222 fr °iStho%he r mf y ection averaged only 15 per cent for five susceptible varieties in 1925, it am^.to 47 and 49 per cent for the same varieties, respectively, in 1926 and 1927. The distribution of 218 selections of Crimean and 202^selec - tions of Turkey with respect to their degree of infection is s^wn in Table 2 for 1926 and 1927. These results show. verTdeaVly that this particular importation of Turkey CO n tains lines that are resistant to smut found locally. The Crimean, on the other hand, showed no such resistance. Be - cause^f these results, all the Crimean selections were dropped f?om the smut nursery and ° n * 2 VoV^aTeTon^S Turkey selections were continued in 1928. Based on the l»£» results, only the 17 most smut-free lines were grown in 1929 and the number was reduced to 12 in 1930. . Results summarizing the comparative reactions of these 12 remaining selections and a number of variebe s to the local collections of smut are shown in Table 3, tor the neriodfrom 1924 to 1930. During the last four years, these 12 sdections averaged 1.3 per cent infected heads, as com - bed witHsT^ for the original Turkey and 40 per ?ent as an average for four standard productive varieties. COMPARATIVE RESISTANCE TO COLLECTIONS OF SMUT FROM VARIOUS SOURCES Several investigators, including ; Faris ( 19 f)' n^^ nh! a s^ and Stakman (1927), Gaines (1928), Reed .(1928), and Roeme? (1928) have reported concerning physiologic forms SbSSL Differential varietal response to these forms is now eenerally accepted. In view of the marked resistance of a 5um£ of ?he?e new Turkey selections to local collections of k fc8S 1^K. S fSSrif states supplied the coUec - tions of smut used in these tests. Microscopic examination revved that both species, namely T levis and T. tritici were represented. All collections from the central states, except one from Minnesota, were T. levis. All but one. collection of T tritici came from Pacific coast states. This is in agreement Stephens and Woolman (1922) who re - port that in the United States T. levis is i commonly found last of the Rocky Mountains while T. tntici is largely re - stricted to the more westerly states. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Breeding Winter Wheat Table 3. — Comparative resistance of varieties and selections of winter xoheat to T. levis collected locally (1924-1930) ■ Percentage of infection Selection or variety , , . .___^ 1924 1925 1926 1927 1928 1929 1930 P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P.ct. 0) ■ , (2) (3) (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) STANDARD VARIETIES Orig. So. Dak. No. 144 ; 10.0 61.0 37.0 37.0 34.0 25 0 Crimean (C. I. 1435) : . . 30.0 42.0 57.0 Kanred 21.0 48.0 53.0 4l'.o' ' ' ' 39'.6' ' ' ' 27.6 ' ' Nebraska No. 60 13.0 51.0 54.0 50.0 18.0 30 0 Nebraska No. 6 3.0 45.0 43.0 76.0 37.0 30.0 NEBRASKA SELECTIONS FROM TURKEY RED (South Dakota No. 144) Selection No. 4300 0.0 0.0 4.0 6.0 02 1.7 4.5 Selection No. 4301 0.0 0.0 4.0 1.0 1.0 0.2 1.6 Selection No. 4303 0.0 0.0 1.0 0.5 1.7 4 0 Selection No. 4304 0.0 0.0 2.0 1.0 03 0.6 0.4 Selection No. 4305 •.. 0.0 0.0 5.0 3.5 02 12 3 0 Selection No. 4311 0.0 0.0 0.0 2.5 0.0 1.0 3.5 Selection No. 4317 . .- 0.0 0.0 2.0 0.1 0 0 2 0 Selection No. 4318 0.0 0.0 . . .■ 0.0 0.4 02 0.5 Selection No. 4319 0;0 0.0 0.0 1.0 0.1 1.3 1.5 Selection No. 4322 0.0 0.0 4.0 2.5 0.5 0.6 0.5 Selection No. 4324 0.0 0.0 3.0 1.5 0.5 4.7 3.5 Selection No. 4325 0.0 0.0 3.0 0.5 0.1 1.5 1.0 Where data are lacking no tests were made or stands were not secured. ■Methods. — Twenty-eight varieties or selections of winter wheat were uniformly inoculated with smut spores from 17 sources prior to planting in the fall of 1928 and with smut from 12 sources in the fall of 1929. The seed was given a standard formaldehyde treatment before inoculation, to guard against foreign infection. That such contamination was largely avoided was made evident by the fact that 22 of the 28 control rows were entirely free from bunt in 1929, while the infection in the other six rows ranged from only .2 to .8 per cent. In 1930, 24 of the control rows had no bunt while the other four contained from .5 to .7 per cent of infected heads. , Hands and utensils were thoroly cleansed whenever a change of smut collection was involved during the preparation, inoculation, and planting of the seed. Sufficient seed was weighed out in each case to plant an eight-foot row at normal rate. The seed and spores were carefully rubbed together so that each seed might carry sufficient spores. The 28 wheats treated with any one smut collection were planted in adjacent rows. The degree of infection was judged by the percentage of smutty heads. Two hundred heads were examined in each row except that where the infection was low all heads were carefully inspected. Special care was used in guarding against the possible in - troduction and spread of new physiologic forms into this </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 51 locality. The seed was prepared for planting away from all other wheat and planted in an isolated nursery. After the head counts were made in the ensuing crop, the wheat was cut and burned in the field. As a further precaution against possible spread of some new virulent form, only those smuts secured from neighboring states between which, a free seed exchange occurs have been grown in field cultures after the first year. Other collections are now being confined to the greenhouse. The 28 wheats planted in the field included two standard susceptible and six established resistant varieties, the twelve new resistant Turkey selections repoi'ted in Table 3, and eight hybrid selections originating in the F : , generation of crosses between susceptible and resistant soi'ts as previously described. The Minturki and Oro varieties have become available since the other four resistant sorts were used as parents for these eight hybrids. They were included because of their known resistance and other relatively desirable agronomic characters. In fact they are regarded as the best suited for this region of any of the ' established resistant varieties and for this reason are especially valuable for com - parison. Owing to the limited amount of space available, only 12 wheats were grown in the 1930 greenhouse tests for differ - ential reactions. These included nine of the outstanding new Turkey selections and Nebraska No. 6, Minturki, and Oro. Fifteen planting samples containing fifty seeds each were prepared for each variety. These were inoculated individually with smut collections from 15 different sources and planted in 30-inch rows spaced 4*4 inches apart. The. method of pre - paring and planting the seed was the same in the greenhouse as has been described for the field tests. The percentage of infection is based on the total number of heads per row. Results. — -Tables 4, 5, and 6 show the detailed results of the reactions in the 1929 and 1930 field tests and the 1930 greenhouse tests. A relatively high degree of infection of the susceptible varieties resulted in all three tests. Several striking differential reactions were obtained among the varieties, selections, and hybrids. Some of the wheats proved extremely resistant to all of the collections. The degree of resistance, however, was somewhat variable. In 1929, as an average for reactions to smut from 17 dif - ferent sources, Nebraska No. 6 and Kanred averaged 27.9 per cent infected heads. Ridit and Minturki averaged most resistant of the resistant varieties, with .2 and 1.2 per cent of smut, respectively. Five of the Nebraska Turkey selec - tions averaged less than 1 per cent of infection. Of the </seg>
            <seg id="p009">TABLE 4. — Comparative resistance of 28 varieties and selections of winter wheat to T. levis and T. tritici from 17 sources, 1929 Species, source of collection, 1 and jicrccntaRe of infection Tillttia kris . ■ Tillttia tritici Varieties-and ! ■ '- : '- —. selections Lin- North Mit- Man- Fort Brook- St. St. La Moc- Cor- Pull- Water- St. Cor- I'rncl- Hcpp - coln, Platte, chcll, hattan, Collins, ines, Paul, Paul, Fiyrttc casin, vallis, man, villc, Paul, vallis, Irton, ner, Ave- Ncbr. Ncbr. Ncbr.. Kans. Colo. S. Dak. Minn.' Minn. Ind. Mont. Oreu. Wash.' Wash.' Minn. Orcg. Orcg. Orcc. 1 raci- . /'. rt. P. rt. P. rt. P. ct. P. ct. P. el. P. rt. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. /'. ct. P. ct. P. cl. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P, rt. P. rt. (1) (2) (1) (4) (5) • (6) (7) . (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) (13) (Ml (15) (10) (17) (IS) (19) ' . STANDARD SUSCEPTIBLE AND RESISTANT VARIETIES . w Ncbr. No. 6 37.0 49.0 .10.0 .16.0 40.0 31.0 17.0 27.0 6.0 52.0 17.0 | 30.0 28.0 17.0 23.0 17.0 65.0 30.7 E? Kanrcd 39.0 43.0 28.0 37.0 35.0 35.0 9.0 21.0 3.0 26.0 23.0 30.0 36.0 4.0 |7.O 1.0 38.0 25.0 K Minturki 2.7 2.9 12 0.8 0.8 fj 1.6 2.1 0.2 0.8 0.2 0.4 0.4 0.2 1.4 0.2 2.9 1.2 m Oto... 1.9 . 12 0.8 0.4 0.6 0.8 0.4 1.3 0.0 19.0 0.0 0.2 1.2. 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.8 1.7 a Regal 0.6 0.0 0.4 0.6 0.2 0.2 2.1 22.7 5.2 2.6 2.5 17.4 1.6 3.8 10.3 0.0 30.3 5.9 — Sherman 0.2 1.2 6.1 0.2 0.4 0.2 8.8 21.9 lfl.O 6.7 2.4 16.1 7.6 10.4 41.5 0.0 31.3 10.7 Z Hussar 010 0.6 1.6 0.0 0.0 0.2 0.0 15.2 0.4 3.4 2.4 8.2 0.2 1.3 0.0 0.0 8.6 2.5 O Ridit 0.0 0.8 0.2 0.0 0.2 0.0 0.0 O.Q 0.0 0.2 0.0 0.6 0.4 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.2 0.2 ■. NEBRASKA SELECTIONS FROM TURKEY RED (South Dakota No. 144) Selection No. 4300 1.7 2.4 5.3 0.4 1.0 0.9 4.1 2.4 0.7 10.9 0.8 1.1 1.6 1.3 1.2 0.2 1.3 ' 2.2 2 Selection No. 4301 0.2 2.2 0.8 0.2 1.1 0.2 1.8 0.0 0.0 5.4 0.2 0.6 0.4 0.0 0.8 0.0 0.2 0.8 3 Selection No. 4303 1.7 1.2 1.7 • 0.4 1.1 0.8 0.8 0.6 1.3 6.3 0.0 0.4 0.4 0.6 1.2 0.0 1.2 1.2 2 Selection No. 4304 '. 0.6 0.2 0.6 0.2 0.6 0.0 0.4 0.4 0.0 5.8 0.0 0.2 0.0 0.2 0.0 0.0 1.2 O.ii E Selection No. 4305 1.2 0.6 1.8 1.1 0.8 0.0 1.6 1.0 1.8 7.4 0.2 0.4 0.4 0.4 0.0 0.0 1.4 1.2 Selection No. 4311 1.0 0.2 6.0 0.0 0.6 0.0 19.9 36.8 20.7 5.6 3.7 8.5 21.0 32.0 23.7 .0.0 30.9 12.4 ** Selection No. 4317 0.0 0.2 0.4 0.0 0.6 0.0 0.8 0.4 0.0 13.5 0.4 0.0 0.4 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 I.I) &lt; Selection No. 4318 0.2 0.2 0.2 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.6 0.0 0.0 6.2 0.0 0.6 0.8 0.2 0.0 0.0 ■ 0.2 0.5 ffi Selection No. 4319 1.3 0.2 0.8 0.0 0.0 (I.I 0.2 0.0 O.8 5.7 0.0 0.0 1.2 0.2 0.0 0.0 0.9 0.7 m Selection No. 4322 0.0 2.5 2.4 0.4 1.2 0.0 8.2 18.0 7.8 3.2 3.9 11.(1 12.9 0.7 14.1 0.0 21.0 6.9 &gt; Selection No. 4324 4.7 7.0 2.5 1.4 4.2 1.1 9.9 2.4 4.1 8.9 0.0 0.8 12.0 7.8 4.4 0.0 3.2 4.4 . h Selection No. 4325 1.5 0.2 0.4 0.0 0.0 0.8 O.4 0.2 0.2 7.9 0.2 0.0 0.6 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.7 NEBRASKA HYBRID SELECTIONS Sherman x Ncbr. No. 6 0.0 0.0 0.6 0.0 0.2 0.0 5.5 10.9 9.7 3.3 5.7 14.0 21.7 4.8 7.3 0.0 15.2 5 8 Hussar x Nebr. No. 6. .. 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.4 8.7 2.5 4.0 13.3 10.8 11.4 1.2 0.0 0.0 20.9 4,1 Hussar x Kanrcd 0.4 0.0 0.4 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.2 19.5 0.6 6.3 10.2 11.9 5.6 0.4 0.4 0.0 34.1 5.3 Kanred x Ridit 2.1 2.3 1.1 0.0 0.8 0.4 0.0 0.4 0.8 1.1 0.2 2.1 0.4 0.0 0.4 0.2 2.4 0.9 Nebr. No. 6 x Ridit .... 2-3 3.1 1.8 5.6 2.5 2.1 1.2 2.3 2.8 1.5 4.3 0.4 3.5 0.4 2.2 0.4 3.0 2.3 Nebr. No. 6x Regal.... 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.2 0.2 5.6 0.2 2.0 14.7 10.2 4.9 0.6 0.0 0.0 30.6 4.1 Kanred x Regal 0.0 0.0 0.2 0.2 0.0 0.0 0.0 8.1 1.8 4.0 s.3 13.9 8.0 0.4 1.4 0.0 31.7 4.7 Sherman i Kanred 0.8 0.4 4.9 0.8 0.0 0.8 13.9 273 41.6 8.1 24.8 20.1 10.7 18.6 29.8 1.2 43.7 14.6 ■The collections listed in Columns 2 to 8 were secured directly from the Agr. Exp. Stations at the points indicated; those in Cclimns 9 to 18 were obtained from E. N. Bressman of the Oreg. Agr. Exp. Sta., who previously had secured them from the designated locations. 'These St. Paul, Waterville, and Pullman collections contained 10 and 5 per cent and trace of T. Iritiei, respectively. ■Contained 20 per cent of T. Init. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Table 5. — Comparative. resistance of 28 varieties of winter wheat toT. levis from 12 sources, 1930 Source of collection 1 and percentage nt infection Varieties and selections Nebraska Kans. Colorado S. D. N. D. Minn. Montana 1 1 , Average 2 North Mit- Man- Fort Brook- St. Moc- Boie- £* Lincoln Lincoln Platte chell hattan Collins' Akron ings Fargo Paul 1 caain&gt; man (XJ P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. J* (1) (2) (3) (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) (13) (14) w STANDARD SUSCEPTIBLE AND RESISTANT VARIETIES • W Nebraska No. 6.. 27.6 25.0 36.0 23.5 40.5 ' 13.8 29.5 25.7 6.3 30.5 36.6 26.8 Kanred 22.5 9.5 29.5 23.5 33.5 28.0 21.5 12J5 6.5 30.5 22.0 21.8 l_, Minturki 0.0 0.5 2.0 3.0 1.0 • 3.5 4.0 3.0 22 1.0 0.6 1.9 gJ Oro 0.0 0.0 0.5 0.0 1.5 0.0 1.0 1.5 0.0 1.8. 1.0 0.7 2 Regal • 0.5 0.0 1.5 2.0 0.5 2.9 3.5 0.7 0.7 9.8 0.0 2.0 y Sherman 5.5 6.0 .6.0 5.5 6.3 10.6 8.0 3.0 7.6 9.3 11.7 7.0 Hussar '. . . 2.9 0.9 2.1 0.0 3.4 1.8 6.5 0.0 0.0 7.1 0.9 25 CO Ridit 5.3 13 13 0.5 1.9 0.5 4.0 0.0 0.0 2.4 0.6 2.2 H NEBRASKA SELECTIONS FROM TURKEY RED (South Dakota No. 144) . T Selection No. 4300 0.0 OlO 0.5 0.0 2.0 2.0 1.5 • 1.5 1.0 0.5 1.6 1.0 l_i Selection No. 4301 0.0 0.0 1.5 0.5 0.6 1.8 0.1 1.0 0.6 2.5 0.-0 0.8 •" Selection No. 4303 22 2.9 1.0 0.5 3.5 4.6 1.0 1.0 1.1 6.7 0.5 22 M Selection No. 4304 0.0 0.0 0.5 0.1 0.0 1.6 0.0 1.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.3 2 Selection No. 4305 1.0 1.5 0.5 0.0 4.0 1.0 0.0 1.5 0.6 3.5 0.0 1.2 § Selection No. 4311 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 1.0 0.6 0.5 0.0 1.8 6.5 0.5 1.C £ Selection No. 4317 3.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.5 0.0 1.0 0.0 1.5 0.5 0.6 £ Selection No. 4318 0.5 . 0.0 0.5 0.0 0.0 0.0 1.0 2.0 0.5 0.0 2.0 0.0 0.6 J, Selection No. 4319 0.5 0.0 0.0 0.0 1.0 0.5 0.5 0.0 0.5 0.0 0.5 0.0 0.3 * Selection No. 4322 '. 0.0 0.0 0.0 1.0 1.0 0.5 3.2 0.0 1.1 9.0 9.4 0.6 23 ■_, Selection No. 4324 3.1 3.8 1.5 1.5 1.6 4.0 1.0 2.8 2.8 1.2 1.9 0.0 1.9 W Selectiort No. 4325 0.6 0.0 1.0 0.0 0.5 0.0 1.5 1.0 0.0 1.5 0.0 0.0 0.5 C NEBRASKA HYBRID SELECTIONS £ Sherman x Nebr. No. 6 1.1 2.3 0.0 0.5 0.0 0.0 3.7 0.7 1.0 6.8 11. :i 2.9 2.8 W Hussar x Nebr. No. 6 0.0 0.0 0.0 1.6 1.0 0.0 3.9 0.6 0.0 1.8 6.0. 0.0 1.3 H Hussar x Kanred 0.0 0.0 0.6 1.0 0.6 . 0.0 4.7 2.1 0.0 1.9 9.0 3.1 2.1 2 Kanred x Ridit 5.6 0.0 2.5 2.0 6.0 3.6 2.5 5.4 0.0 0.0 2.0 1.0 2.5 •* Nebr. No. 6 x Rldit 6.1 33 2.5 4.0 8.5 0.5 12 1.8 0.0 4.1' 2.4 1.7 3.2 q, Nebr. No. 6 x Regal 1.0 0.0 0.0 0.5 0.0 0.0 1.6 0.0 0.0 2.1 19.5 0.5 2.3 Zi Kanred x Regal 0.6 0.7 0.0 0.0 0.0 . 0.0 2.1 12 0.7 ' 3.8 17.0 0.0 2.4 ■ Sherman x Kanred 0.0 4.4- \2 0.5 0.0 0.5 3.0 0.6 0.0 21.1 6.5 0.0 3.3 •All of the smut collections were taken from th ■ 1929 differential nursery at Lincoln except those reported in Columns 2 and 10. Those listed in Columns 8 12 and 13, were originally supplied by the Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases, U. S. D. A. 'First 14 rows were not inoculated with smut from Fort Collins due to insufficient supply. This collection is omitted from averages. •The smut from St. Paul and Moccasin contained 25 and 5 per cent of T. Iritici, respectively. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 TABLE 6. — Comparative resistance of 12 varieties and selections of winter wheat to T. levis and __ T. tritici from 15 sources. Greenhouse, 1930 . Species, source of collection 1 and percentage of infection Tilletia Inii Tillctia trilici W Varietiesand : 1 — &gt; ; 1 &lt; 5 ■elections Lin- St. LaFa- Moc- Cor- Full- Water- Czech- St. Crcig- Cor- Pend- Red- Hcpp- S coin, Paul, yette, casin, Idaho vallis, man, ville, oslov- Paul, mont, vallis, leton, mond, nor, Average S Nebr. Minn. Ind. Mont.' Oreg.' Wash.: Wash.' akia Minn. Idaho Orcg. Oreg.: Oreg. Oreg.&lt; m P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ci. P.ct. P.ct. P.d. P.ct. P.cl. P,ct. P.cl. ■ P.cl. P.ct. P.O. O (1) ■ (2) (3) (4) (6) (6) (7) . (8) (9) (10) (11) (12) (13) (14) (15) (16) (17) Nebraska No. 6 48.1 4.0 52.4 90.0 30.0 65.6 20.0 8:1.7 27.3 23.0 14.8 25.0 63.8 45.0' 63.8 41.7 "? ' Minturki 3.4 0.0 0.0 22.0 3.7 6.5 0.0 0.0 2.7 O'.O 4.2 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 2.6 3 Oro 6.4 0.0 8.9 45.6 8.3 4.7 12.3 3.9 0.0 1.7 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 2.2 6.8 2 Selection No. 4300. ... 1.7. 0.0 6.6 8.9 6.3 1.9 0.0 0.0 6.6 6.3 7.3 3.1 3.4 0.0 2.0 3.3 „ Selection No. 4301 „.. 3.6 0.0 2.0 4.4 0.0 1.7 2.5 4.5 0.0 2.3 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 ' 1.3 U Selection No. 4303. ... 4.7 0.0 3.0 23.7 0.0 6.3 0.0 6.7 6.4 21.7 7.7 3.3 7.3 0.0 2.4 5.8 * Selection No. 4304.... 0.0 0.0 1.8 25.0 0.0 3.7 0.0 4.7 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 2.2 &lt;&lt; Selection No. 4305.... 2.6 0.0 16.6 7.5 0.0 4.9 9.0 1.6 0.0 6.3 0.0 0.0 1.8 1.8 3.6 3.4 &lt;j Selection No. 4317.... 0.0 0.0 0.0 232 0.0 0.0 2.0 0.0 0.0 . 4.6 0.0 0.0 0.0 4.8 8.6 2.7 R Selection No. 431S. ... 0.0 0.0 1.9 21.7 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 42 0.0 0.0 . 0.0 0.0 0.0 1.7 m Selection No. 4319.... 0.0 0.0 0.0 6.1 0.0 0.0 1.6 0.0 0.0 3.8 1.6 0.0 0.0 1.4 0.0 0.9 &gt; • Selection No. 4325. ... 1.5 0.0 0.0 2.1 2.4 0.0 0.0 1.6 4.0 0.0 2.0 13 0.0 0.0 9.2 1.6 H 'These collections of smut were supplied by E. N. Bressman of the Oregon Agr. Exp. Sta., who had previously secured them from the designated sources. 'Contained traces of T. tritici or T. font. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 51 hybrids, a selection from Kanred by Ridit was the most re - sistant with only .9 per cent smutty heads. In 1930, in the field (Table 5), Nebraska No. 6 and Kanred averaged 24.3 per cent smutty heads. Of the resistant varieties, Oro and Minturki contained the lowest amount of smut, with .7 and 1.9 per cent respectively. Six of the new Turkey selections averaged less than 1 per cent bunt. The Kanred by Ridit selection averaged 2.5 per cent infection, as compared with 1.3 per cent for the most resistant hybrid selection, Hussar by Nebraska No. 6. The fifteen collections of smut used in the 1930 greenhouse test were supplied by E. N. Bressman of the Oregon Agri - cultural Experiment Station, who had selected them from among 78 different lots of bunt because of their wide range of specific differential reactions on a number of varieties of wheat These included the various physiologic forms reported by Bressman (1931). In reaction to all of these collections, the susceptible variety, Nebraska No. 6, averaged 41.7 per cent smutty heads. Minturki and Orq showed averages of 2.6 and 5.8 per cent of infection, respectively. Four of the Turkey selections aver - aged less than 2 per cent smutty heads. NEBRASKA RESULTS FROM THE U. S. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE UNIFORM BUNT NURSERY In addition to the -field tests with bunt, rather similar tests were conducted in 1929 and 1930 in co-operation with the Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases, U. S. Department of Agriculture. The results are here presented because in addi - tion to the regular varieties included in the U. S. Department of Agriculture uniform bunt nursery at the Nebraska Agri - cultural Experiment Station, one of the new Nebraska Turkey selections, No. 4319, was similarly inoculated in 1929, and nine of the Turkey selections were similarly treated in 1930 The results are given in Tables 7 and 8. This U. S. Department of Agriculture collection of wheats included three recognized resistant varieties and seven sus - ceptible sorts. All were inoculated individually with smut from each of nine sources. It is of interest to note that the Nebraska Turkey selection No. 4319 averaged only .1 per cent of infection, as compared with 1.9 per cent for Minturki and 1.5 per cent for Oro in 1929. In 1930, this same Turkey selection No. 4319 averaged 1 per cent infection for the nine collections of smut compared with 2.5 per cent for Minturki and 1.2 per cent for Oro The nine Turkey selections averaged .4 per cent smutty heads in contrast with 25 per cent for the average of seven susceptible varieties. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Table 7.— Comparative resistance of 11 varieties of winter wheat to T. levis front nine sources. Conducted in co-operation with the Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases, JJ^.JJjJ^19zQ__ Source of collection and percentage of infection 5j ' Variety North Man- ~ Red- St. Moc- Boze- M Lincoln, Platte, hattan, Hays, Akron, field, Paul, casin, man, Average g Nebr. Nebr. . Kans. Kans. Colo. S. D. Minn. Mont.' Mont.' £. g (1) • '(2) (3) (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (11) g SXno/go: :::::::;: S3 i« « w 25.9 2.5 im iu i« 1.5 g •Contained a trace of 7". In'lici. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Table 8. — Comparative resistance of 19 varieties of winter wheat to T. levis from nine sources. Conducted in co-operation with the Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases, U. S. D. A., 1930 Source of collection and percentage of infection g Variety North Man- Red- St. Moc- Boze- £ Lincoln, Platte, hattan, Hays, Akron, field, Paul, casin, man, Average 2 Nebr. Nebr. Kans. Kans. Colo. S. D. Minn. 1 Mont. 1 Mont. &gt; P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.cl. P.ct. P.cl. P.cl. pTet. P cl g 1 (1) (2) .(3) (4) (5) (6) (7) (8) (9) &lt;\o) (il) jg Kharkof 38.8 29.3 13.6 27.0 44.3 10.3 6.6 22.9 211 23 8 W Karmont.... 38.6 27.3 14.6 31.3 33.1 17.4 11.4 45.0 20.6 26i6 -g Newturk 22.0 15.1 28.2 29.2 28.5 24.1 19.6 35.1 30.0 25.8 *" Kanred 36.3 18.2 7.2 26.6 58.1 5.6 9.1 27.0 36 9 25 0 fcrj Blackhull 46.1 26.7 31.8 52.2 60.3 21.6 28.7 32 0 311 36 7 W Tenraarq. 27.0 22.7 8.3 10.8 32.1 11.3 8.0 19.6 21.3 17 9 S Nebraska No. 60 40.3 6.5 10.3 29.5 13.9 8.4 17.8 10.8 33.1 19 0 £ Mint, x Bel.-Buf 0.7 1.7 0.0 2.2 0.0 0.5 0 7 15 05 0 9 » Oro--; 0.0 2.8 0.0 2.5 0.0 1.3 0.7 3.'o 0&gt; 12 S Minturki 5.9 1.8 .0.6 5.1 3.1 1.9 2.0 0 0 2 5 2 5 W Nebr. Sel. No. 4300 0.0 0.0 0.8 3.4 0.0 0.0 0.0 o'o 0 6 0 5 W Nebr. Sel. No. 4301. 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0 0 00 00 00 £ Nebr. Sel. No. 4303 0.0 4.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.8 5 9 0 0 0 9 13 E Nebr. Sel. No. 4304 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 00 0 0 00 00 a Nebr. Sel. No. 4305 0.0 0.0 0.0. 1.4 1.3 0.0 o'o 4*8 o'o 0 8 H Nebr. Sel. No. 4317 0.0 1.4 0.0 0.0 2.0 0.0 00 0 0 00 04 2 Nebr. Sel. No. 4318 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0*0 14 00 02 Nebr. Sel. No. 4319 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 1.2 00 0 0 00 0 1 S Nebr. Sel. No. 4325. 0.0 2.3 0.0 0.0 _0.9_ 0.0 , q.q q% j.p 05 •Contained a trace of T. Iritici. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Breeding Winter Wheat In conjunction with the two U. S. Department of Agri - culture uniform bunt tests, the Nebraska Turkey selection No. 4319 was entirely unaffected by smut from six different sources during both years. It was entirely smut-free in 41 of the 69 instances reported in the preceding tables and aver - aged but 1.3 per cent infection in the 28 remaining cases. Maximum infection was 6 per cent as compared with 90 per cent for Nebraska No. 6. SUPPLEMENTARY TEST FOR RESISTANCE TO STEM RUST The nine smut-resistant selections from Turkey (South Dakota No. 144) (Table 8 and preceding tables) , together with Kanred and Nebraska Crimean Nos. 12 and 50, were tested in the seedling stage in the greenhouse for resistance to stem rust during the winter of 1929-1930 by Geo. L. Peltier, Station- Plant Pathologist. The reactions of these wheats to the four physiologic forms of stem rust found by him to be prevalent in Nebraska in 1929 were determined in duplicate tests. As shown in Table 9, all of the Turkey selections have given evi-* dence of being relatively resistant to all four forms, whereas the Kanred and Crimean selections were susceptible to them. Table 9. — Comparative reactions l of 12 strains and varieties of winter wheat to four physiologic forms of Puccinia graminis tritici - Physiologic forms Variety or selection '■ 1 18 34 39 56 ' (1) (2) (3) (4) (5) Kanred S S S S Crimean No. 12 S S S S Crimean No. 50 S S S S Selection No. 4300 . S- S- R S- Selection No. 4301 S- S- S- S- Selection No. 4303 S- S- R S- Selection No. 4304 S- S- S- S- Selection No. 4305 S- S- R S- Selection No. 4317 S- S- S- S- Selection No. 4318 . . . . S- S- S- S- Selection No. 4319 S- . S- R S- Selection No. 4325 S- &amp;; R S - 'Explanation of symbols: S, susceptible; S-,' slightly susceptible; R, resistant. 'Acknowledgment is made to G. L. Peltier, Station Plant Pathologist, for the determination of these reactions. COMPARATIVE COLD RESISTANCE In view of the work of Steinmetz (1926), Hill and Salmon (1927), Akerman (1927), and investigations in progress with alfalfa at' this station by Peltier and Tysdal, it seemed desir- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 51 able to compare a number of the promising selections with respect to cold resistance under controlled conditions. The freezing equipment installed in 1927 in the greenhouse was made available thru the courtesy of the Department of Plant Pathology for such studies. Planting. — The wheat to be compared was planted on October 17, 1929, in soil-filled boxes 5 x 17 x 19 inches. These boxes were placed contiguously in a shallow excavation in the wheat field with their tops level with the soil surface. They remained in the field until removed to the freezing chamber. The wheat, therefore, was subjected to such hardening-off as occurred naturally in the field. FlO l«r Ml Bi n h r t ° wSTT"* Wlr A eI , Whe ? t , varieties in flh «* for controlled cold-endurance testa. R'Kht. Wheat removed from field to . greenhouse January 31 and photouraphed February 22. without additional freeiinR. Left: Correspond^ wheat 20 .lavs tomn»r« e t'.r it S !J bj&lt; w d n a° h °" TI ' '" the frcrain * chamber to a minimum air temperature of —30 C. and minimum soil temperature of -29° C. The seeds were spaced at approximately one-half inch in - tervals in rows 2i/ 2 inches apart. Seven rows were planted in each box. The first, fourth, and seventh rows were planted as checks to Blackhull, Nebraska No. 60, and Min - turki, respectively. These three varieties were known to differ m relative winterhardiness. ' Twelve strains, including nine new Turkey selections which had proved resistant to bunt, two new high-yielding Nebraska Crimean (C. I. 1435) selections, and Oro, were planted in rows 2, 3, 5, and 6 for comparative testing. Three boxes were thus required for a complete set. In addition, a number of control boxes for determining proper exposures and technique were planted to </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Breeding Winter Wheat two rows each of Blackhull, Nebraska No. 60, and Minturki and one row of Crimean No. 50, a Nebraska selection from Crimean C. I. 1435. A field count of the plants on November 12 indicated good and comparatively uniform stands in all of the boxes, with a relatively small amount of growth due to delayed planting. The soil iii the boxes was kept well watered until it became frozen in November. Following a thawing out of the soil in late December, it was again watered. Hardening-off temperatures in the field. — The mean out - door temperature for November was 2.6° C. below normal, the minimum of -18.3°. C. occurring on the 22nd. The mean temperature for December was .8° C. above normal with a minimum of -19.4° C. on December 18. The last week aver - aged 9.4° ;C. above normal. The January mean, on the other hand, was 4.9° C. below normal. The minimum temperature of -26.7° C. occurred on January 17 with a range in minimum temperature from -18.3° C. to -26.7° C. from January 14 to January 23. Temperatures maintained in freezing chamber. — One or two complete sets of the wheat varieties under test were frozen by; control methods on eight different dates between December 2 and January 31. The average results from 12 comparisons are reported in Table 10. Soil temperatures as measured ! by thermocouples imbedded approximately three - fourths inch deep in the individual boxes ranged in the var - ious tests from -.5° C. to -16.3° C. at the beginning of the freezing and from -21.3° C. to -29.1° C. at the time the boxes were removed from the freezing chamber. With the exception of one eight-hour period, the boxes were retained in the freezing chamber from 30 to 35 hours. An average air temperature of -25.5° C. was maintained in the freezing chamber.j with an average minimum of -30.7° C. The dura - tion of freezing was gauged by the minimum soil temperature. Comparative recovery from freezing. — Upon removal of boxes from the freezing chamber, they were placed on a table in the greenhouse for recovery under favorable growth con - ditions with a mean temperature of about 22° C. Final read - ings of the percentage of survival were made at the end of approximately four weeks. This length of time was re - garded as necessary, since some plants gave early evidence of recovery i but later succumbed as a result of the freezing. In Table 10, Columns 4, 5, and 6, are recorded the per - centages of survival for each of the three check varieties grown in conjunction with each of the selections listed in Column 1. In Column 7 is recorded the survival for each of the selections listed in Column 1. The ratio of this survival </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Table 10. — The survival of new winter wheat selections in comparison with that of three standard 2 varieties of known relative hardiness after being exposed to low temperatures under con- » trolled conditions 1 £ . to Percentage of survival &gt; Range in soil — : Odds compared w Selection temperature Standard Varieties with Nebr. X centigrade Selection Ratio to No. 60 (student's **&gt; Nebr. (Col. 1) Nebr. method) ' Max. Min. Blackhull No. 60 Minturki No. 60 % . (1) (2) (3) (4) (5) ' (6) (7) (8) ~(9) ■ " Selection No. 4300 -9.6 -26.3 36 68 76 70 1.03 3 W Selection No. 4301 -9.0 -26.4 33 67 76 52 0.78 109 " Selection No. 4303 -9.5 -26.5 30 68 79 48 0.71 1444 M Selection No. 4304 -9.7 -26.4 30 69 79 51 0.74 4999 t Selection No. 4305 -9.7 -26.5 33 63 73 51 0.81 40 o Selection No. 4317 -9.5 -26.4 38 72 78 63 0.88 16 . B Selection No. 4318 -9.3 .-26.4 36 70 79 58 0.83 104 Selection No. 4319 -9.3 -26.3 34 66 76 64 ■ 0.97 4 £?• Selection No. 4325 -9.4 -26.5 28 64 76 60 0.94 . 3 S Crimean No. 12. -9.7 -26.4. 34 68 74 67 0.99 1 £• Crimean No. 50 -9.7 -26.4 34 68 74 72 1.06 9 S Pro ■• -9.4 -26.5 29 67 7(3 59 0.88 40 g 'Avprage of 12 comparisons, frozen on eight different dates from Dec. 2. to Jan. 31. Average duration of freezing period 30 hours, mean average and minimum air temperatures in freezing room — 25.5 and —30.7° C, respectively. ' CH </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Breeding Winter Wheat Table 11. — Comparative cold survival of three varieties of tvinter wheat under controlled freezing conditions and in the U. S.\ D. A. uniform winterhardiness tests Kind of Test U. S. D. A. winterhardiness nursery — average for 9 to 23 Variety Controlled stations per year freezing 1930 . Nine-year average, 1930' 1921-1929' ■ P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. (1) (2) (3) (4) Minturki 1 76 68 65 Nebraska No. 60 68 61 59 Blackhull L 33 46 42 j • . 'The unpublished 1930 U. S. D. A. data were supplied by J. A. Clark and K. S. Quisenberry. 'From U. S. D. A. Circular No. 141. to that of Nebraska No. 60, grown and frozen comparably in the same box, is shown for each selection in Column 8. It may be concluded from these results that the Turkey selections Nos. 4300, 4319, and 4325, and Crimean selections Nos. 12 and 50 are as winterhardy as Nebraska No. 60. There is satisfaction in knowing this, since Nebraska No. 60 is recognized as a comparatively hardy • variety for Nebraska conditions. Dependability of controlled freezing tests. — It is of interest to know how the foregoing controlled freezing results com - pare with those secured under actual field conditions of winterkilling. The three varieties used as controls exhibited rather similar degrees of hardiness and ranked the same as under field conditions in the U. S. Department of Agriculture uniform winterhardiness nursery during a nine-year period, 1921 to 1929. (Quisenberry and Clark, 1930.) In this gov - ernment field-survival test, in which northern states and Canada were represented, the mean survivals for Blackhull, Nebraska No. 60, and Minturki were 42, 59, and 65 per cent, respectively, as compared with averages of 33, 68, and 76 per cent for these controlled comparisons. (See Table 11.) This similarity of survival is evidence of the reliability of this con - trolled procedure. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska* Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 51 -i &lt;*£ ■ ! ■ 1 13 • . = -u „ 2'i 1 — r 1^- — 1 r ».l :— — 1 1 s "~ '■' ' £- 1 ' 1 B •2 5| K I •' ■ ■ s _ 05 S I S £ w : i i r— -. — : 1 a a «. "** I r ■ ' ' I "a = a I §•:■:: 2Sg"-2 I g | "o"S - _ g ■ " : : : "7 " I li » ■* g -i ; ; — : — — £■ a = § g " : ;~ 1 ..§■ . c ' ■ - ■ - t to v. 2^ | ■ | ?:5.1§!lls!li||s [ Is i| ! * |.ygg 2 w i ■ 3 : 2 v *-' wf'2 ; 5 &lt;2 : 1 '- S II |! || lull Ji.3 .^aaaaiS35-| *] *-^ I! s| j i £ &amp; * "Si "»" "Sal t--;» : '!»'! = '!tei-"! S |^ [. || &gt;gl' &lt;S;-- j-a-o..— o J || S if "' -. ■ st a 4 &amp; Sc .^^ qqoujknO'tqqiflioq g c &amp; * ! -r i ;? 1 • frA/a 4! : : " 3 £ «2» ,. ' .£ S£° *"^ ' ' "^ °1 °9 °"3 *^ "? "? °9 ■« * p ■ g | "i ZS.2 * ® — S S-t 1-38. i j.. j • ' s S = 5 P sill 3 S SS.?!5?5?5?^55 S « | I -S ; : : ■ 5 Si &lt;n ! . : : s ;;;;;;;;; «a £ | m a"! SS ~ . -'BBiMnBOBB **_ d « </seg>
            <seg id="p021">: Breeding Winter Wheat comparative yields of new smut-resistant selections Prior to 1930, the investigations with the new selections made from South Dakota Turkey No. 144 were concerned primarily with the development of bunt-resistant lines. All discarding following the first selection was on the basis of re - action to bunt. After nine selections with a very favorable smut-resistance record during a period of years had been isolated, it became desirable to learn their general compara - tive value with respect to other agronomic characters. These complete data for 1930 are assembled in Table 12 in compari - son with the three standard varieties — Nebraska No 60 Kanred, and the parent Turkey variety, South Dakota No. 144. In duplicate one-thirtieth-acre plats, all of these selec - tions yielded two or more bushels per acre above Nebraska No. 60 and Kanred, which are now regarded as the two most productive varieties grown extensively in this state In the nursery, the nine selections ranged from 1.9 bushels below that of the parent variety to .9 bushel above. A straight average of two smut inoculation tests shows 1 2 per cent infection for the nine new Turkey selections as compared with an average of 25.3 per cent for Kanred and Nebraska No. 60. In a similar comparison with Nebraska No. 60 in four independent tests representing a rather large number of smut collections, these nine Turkey selections averaged 1.4 per cent smut in contrast with 29.4 per cent for the Nebraska No. 60. Altho the nine do not average as winter - hardy as Nebraska No. 60, three of them, Nos. 4300 4319 4 • ' S lve evidence of being about as hardy. The No. 4319 ripened three days earlier and was somewhat shorter strawed than Nebraska No. 60. In a test with smut-free seed NT S averaged 4.3 bushels higher in yield than Nebraska No. 60. It also developed only .9 per cent bunt, as com - pared with _29.4 per cent for No. 60 in the four tests when artificially inoculated with smut from a number of sources. Its lodge and shattering resistance and other qualities ar&gt; - peared satisfactory. p «, tt seem . from th ? data available that a number of these Turkey selections give distinct promise of favorable production and should prove attractive as parents in a breed - ing program. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 51 literature cited Akerman, A. 1927. Studien uber den KSltetod und die Kalteresistenz der pflanzen nebst untersuchungen uber die wlnterfestigkelt des Weizens. Veroffentlichungen der Knut und Alice Wellen - berg-Stiftung, X. 232 pages. Berlingska Boktryckeriet, Lund. Bressman, E. N. 1931. Physiologic Forms of Bunt op Wheat and Varietal Resist - ance. Phytopathology 21:108 (abst.) (Read in manuscript.) Faris, J. A. 1924. Factors Influencing the Infection of Wheat by Tilletia tritici AND TUletia levis. Mycologia 16:259-282. Gaines, E. F. 1928. New Physiologic Forms of Tilletia levis and TUletia tritici. Phytopathology 18:579-588. Hill, D. D., and Salmon, S. C. 1927. The Resistance of Certain Varieties of Winter Wheat to Artificially Produced Low Temperatures. Jour. Apr. Res. 35:933-937. Kiesselbach, T. A. 1925. Winter Wheat Investigations. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 31. 149 pages. Quisenberry, K. S., and Clark, J. A. 1930. Hardiness and Yield of Winter Wheat Varieties. U. S. Dept. of Agr. Circular 141, 30 pages. Reed, G. M. 1928. Physiologic Races of Bunt of Wheat. Amer. Jour. Bol. 15:157-170. Rodenhiser, H. A., and Stakman, E. C. ' 1927. Physiologic Specialization in Tilletiu levis and tilietia tritici. Phytopathology 17:247-253. . Roemer, T. 1928. GlBT ES BlOLOGISCHE TYPEN VON STE1NBRAND {Tilletia tritici) des Weizens? Kiihn Arch. 19:1-10. Stephens, D. E., and Woolman, H. M. 1922. The Wheat Bunt Problem in Oregon. Oreg. Apr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 188. 37 pages. Steinmetz, F. H. 1926. Winter Hardiness in Alfalfa Varieties. Minn. Agr. Exp. Sta. Tech. Bui. 38:1-33. [3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>