<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Bulletin of the University of Nebraska TWENTIETH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BOARD OF REGENTS TO THE GOVERNOR PART ONE, Laid Before the Legislature at its Thirty-second Session, 1911</title>
               <date value="1911">1911</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">\ •&lt; ATHLETIC FCLD r 10 // IZ \ \ I I o I I I II I 1 \ ' "*^ C \\ v ./~ ' _ \ k \ i : 1 ' » u ii &gt; \ *»_•_. i -— I A ADMINISTRATION BUILDING ME MCCH ENGINEERING LAB Bli BOILER HOLBE VI MUSEUM a BRACE LABORATORY L LIBRARY C CHEMICAL LABORATORY N NEBRASKA HALL E ELECTRICA1 LABORATORY O OBSERVATOR&gt; C GRANT MEMORIAL HALL T THE TEMPLF OH CREEN HOUfiLH 8 8OLDIERB MLMOHIAL HALL VIA MECHANIC ARTS HALL L UNIVERSITY HALL </seg>
            <seg id="p002">! n i II L -fl K i r C / ) — «. i 8 L jrt s\ II o s ■ ■ t • 1. 1 1 y ilil iilli flMJ s ililiiliSlS|liiii i </seg>
          
            <seg id="p003">Bulletin of The University of Nebraska TWENTIETH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BOARD OF REGENTS TO THE GOVERNOR PART ONE Laid Before the Legislature at its Thirty-second Session, 1911 January 1, 1911 PBINTH) BY THS UNIVBMITY Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p004">2 The Bulletin of the University of Nebraska is published semi-monthly between January 1 and October 1 of each year by the University of Nebraska at the University of Nebraska. Entered at the Post-Office at Lincoln, Ne - braska, as second-class matter under act of Congress, July 16, 1894. One number is issued for each of the following: the Graduate College, the College of Arts and Sciences, the Teachers College, the College of Agriculture, the College of Engineering, the College of Law, the College of Medicine, the School of Pharmacy and the schools of Art, Agriculture, and Music, the High School Manual, and the Biennial Report of the Board of Regents to the Governor. They are furnished gratuitously, postage paid, to all who apply for them. In asking for a bulletin, name the department of the Uni - versity concerning which information is desired. Address THE REGISTRAR, The University of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">3 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN OFFICE OF THE BOARD OF REGENTS To the Governor, Hon. Ashton C. Skallenberger: Sir: In accordance with the law, I have the honor to present herewith the twentieth biennial report of the Board of Regents of the University of Nebraska, covering the biennium ending November 30, 1910. In the report is included a general survey of the progress of the University, the estimates by the regents of its needs for the coming biennium, and the financial state - ment of the secretary. Respectfully submitted, Charles S. Allen, President of the Board of Regents. January 1, 1911. MEMBERS OF THE BOARD ■ Frank Louis Haller* Omaha Term expires January, 1912 Victor Gerald Lyford Falls City Term expires January, 1912 Term expires January, 1916 OFFICERS OF THE BOARD Hon. Charles Sumner Allen, President James Stuart Dales, Secretary CHANCELLOR OF THE UNIVERSITY Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D. •Elected in 1909 to serve unexpired term. !on. Charles Barney Anderson Term expires January, 1914 ■ George Coupland Term expires January, 1914 :on. Charles Sumner Allen — Term expires January, 1916 !on. William Gunn Whitmore </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">5 GENERAL SURVEY OF THE BIENNIUM Colleges of the University. The University of Nebraska now com - prises the following colleges: The Graduate College The College of Arts and Sciences, including the School of Fine Arts and the Affiliated School of Music The Teachers College, including the Summer Session and the Model High School The College of Engineering The College of Agriculture, including the School of Agriculture The College of Law The College of Medicine, including the School of Pharmacy. In addition to these, the Board of Regents is the governing board for E&gt; Agricultural Experiment Station for Nebraska and of the Experiment bstations at North Platte, Valentine, and Scottsbluff. It also has en - isted to its care the superintendency of Farmers' Institutes. EBy act of the state legislature of 1909, the Industrial College ceased to as such, being erected into the Colleges of Engineering and Agriculture; Graduate School became the Graduate College: the same legislature :ed the Teachers College. Sianges in Membership of the Board of Regents. On July 8, 1909, Frederick Hiram Abbott of Aurora resigned and Hon. Harvey Ells- Newbranch of Omaha was appointed to succeed him. At the first general election, Hon. Frank Louis Haller of Omaha was elected to serve out the unexpired term. In November, 1909, Regents Allen and Whitmore were reelected. Regent Allen was elected to succeed himself as president of the Board. Changes in Membership of the Teaching and Administrative Staff of the University.* On November 6, 1908, Dr. E. Benjamin Andrews resigned the chancellor - ship of the University, being assured by able medical advisers that he could not continue without grave and immediate danger to his health. The resig - nation was accepted and became effective December 31, 1908. In appreciation of his efforts for the University and as a mark of esteem, the title of Chancellor Emeritus was conferred upon him. On December 8, 1908, Dr. Samuel A very, head of the department of Chemistry of the University, was elected Acting Chancellor, succeeding Dr. Andrews. On May 20, 1909, Dr. A very was elected Chancellor of the Uni - versity of Nebraska. •Only the names of those of professorial rank are given. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">6 Henry Baldwin Ward Dean of the college of medicine and head of the department of zoology George Purcell Costigan, Jr. Dean of the college of law and professor of law Mrs. Edna M. Barkley Dean of women K December 11th, 1908, the Board of Regents issued the following nial on the death of Dr. George H. Bicknell, adjunct professor of lology and otology: "In the death of Dr. George H. Bicknell, adjunct professor of opthalmol - ogy and otology of the Omaha medical college, we recognize a severe loss to the University. In arranging the details and carrying out the plans of the affiliation between the University and the Omaha Medical College and in solving the difficulties which have arisen since then, Dr. Bicknell, as secretary of the board of trustees in Omaha has displayed marked ability and has performed an invaluable service to the University and the state." The following promotions or changes in title have occurred: NAME FORMER TITLE PRESENT TITLE Samuel A very Head professor of Chancellor chemistry Charles Edwin Bessey Dean of the industrial Head dean of the colleges college of the University Charles Russ Richards Associate dean of the Dean of the college of industrial college engineering Edgar Albert Burnett Associate dean of the Dean of the college of industrial college, agriculture and director head professor of an- of Nebraska experiment nimal husbandry and stations director of Nebraska experiment stations William Granger Hastings Professor of law Dean of the college of law Villiam C. Webster ames E. LeRossignol Professor in the department of political economy and commerce Professor in the department of political economy RKeyser ;er G. Vernier Ferdinand C. French »aul G. WooUey Lnnette C. Philbrick rhomas B. Sears tobert C. Ashby )aniel Ford llfred Boyd toland Elisha Stone and commerce Professor in the department of soils Professor of law Professor of philosophy Associate professor of pathological anatomy Associate professor of home economics Assistant professor of civil engineering Adjunct professor of animal husbandry Adjunct professor of rhetoric Adjunct professor of civil engineering Assistant professor of agricultural botany and assistant botanist in the experiment station </seg>
            <seg id="p009">7 FORMER TITLE Professor of anatomy PRESENT TITLE Acting dean of the col - lege of medicine Harry K. Wolfe Professor of philosophy Head professor of phil - osophy Howard R. Smith Professor of animal Head professor of animal husbandry husbandry Archibald L. Haecker Professor of dairy hus- Head professor of dairy husbandry bandry Frederick J. Alway Professor of agricultur- Head professor of agri - cultural chemistry al chemistry Prosser H. Frye Professor of rhetoric Head professor of rhet - oric G. W. A. Luckey Head professor of the history and science of education Head professor of educa - tion George R. Chatburn Professor of applied mechanics and ma - chine design Head professor of applied mechanics and machine design Albert A. Reed Associate professor of secondary education Professor of secondary education John E. Almy Associate professor of experimental physics Professor of experimental physics William A. Willard Associate professor of zoology Professor of histology and embryology Edward G. Montgomery Associate professor of field crops Experimental agronomist in the college of agri - culture and crop agron - omist in the experi - mental station Professor of law Samuel J. Tuttle Joseph H. Powers Lecturer Assistant professor of zoology Professor of general and experimental zoology James H. Gain Associate professor of animal pathology Professor of animal path - ology Leon W. Chase Professor of farm mechanics Professor of agricultural engineering Charles W. M. Poynter Adjunct professor of human anatomy Professor of anatomy ■ B. Ensign E. Persinger Assistant registrar Adviser to women Assistant professor of American history Associate professor of American history Guernsey Jones Assistant professor of American history Associate professor of American history William C. Brenke Assistant professor of mathematics Associate professor of mathematics Franklin D. Barker Assistant professor of Associate professor of zoology zoology </seg>
            <seg id="p010">8 FORMER TITLE Adjunct professor of agronomy Instructor Adjunct professor of political science Associate professor of political science and sociology Leon E. Aylsworth George A. Loveland Assistant professor of meteorology Associate professor of meteorology Amanda Eeppner Adjunct professor of the Germanic lang - uages and literatures Assistant professor of the Germanic languages &amp; literatures Charles L. Dean Adjunct professor of mechanical engineer - ing Assistant professor of mechanical engineering Charles M. Heck Adjunct professor of physics Assistant professor of physics Louis B. Tuckerman, Jr. Adjunct professor of physics Assistant professor of physics Hiram W. Orr Adjunct professor of the history of med - icine Assistant professor of the history of medicine Myron H. Swenk Adjunct professor of entomology Assistant professor of en - tomology Andrew D. Schrag Instructor Assistant professor of Germanic languages Adjunct professor of animal husbandry Adjunct professor of Assistant professor of an - imal husbandry Elda R. Walker Assistant professor of botany Raymond J. Pool Assistant professor of botany Nels A. Bengtson Assistant professor of ge - ography and economic geology Alfred Boyd Adjunct professor of civil engineering Lynn A. Scipio Adjunct professor of mechanical engineering Albert Bunting Adjunct professor of practical mechanics Vernon V. Westgate Adjunct professor of hor - ticulture Percy B. Barker Sarka Hrbkova Adjunct professor of soils Adjunct professor and acting head of the de - partment of Slavonic languages Alice Howell Adjunct professor of Adjunct professor of el - ocution rhetoric Robert S. Trumbull Instructor Adjunct professor of ag - ricultural chemistry </seg>
            <seg id="p011">9 FORMER TITLE Flora Bullock Instructor in English Adjunct professor of Eng- in the school of agri- lish in the school of culture agriculture Claude K. Shedd Instructor in farm Adjunct professor of ag- mechanics ricultural engineering George H. Walker Assistant in anatomy Adjunct professor of an- atomy Laurence B. Pilsbury Instructor Adjunct professor of bac- teriology and pathology James F. Stevens Instructor Adjunct professor of ma- teria medica The following new members have become connected with the teaching Charles W. Pugsley Professor of instructional agronomy and farm manage- ment George O. Virtue Professor of political economy and commerce Charles A. Robbins Professor of law Herbert Brownell Professor of physical science in the teachers college Harriet Folger Associate professor of home economics Philo M. Buck Associate professor of rhetoric William L. French Adjunct professor of dairy husbandry Olenus L. Sponsler Adjunct professor of botany and forestry G. Herbert Coons Adjunct professor of agricultural botany George A. Stephens Adjunct professor of political economy Lockwood J. Towne Adjunct professor of civil engineering LAND ACQUIRED Drill Ground and Athletic Field, 10th and T Streets, adjoining the city campus $35,900 Four acre tract near the University Farm 3,750 College of Medicine Campus 20,000 Experiment Substation tract, 160 acres, title held by Federal Government ralentine Experiment Substation tract, 40 acres donated by city of Valentine; 1000 acres of military reservation under perpetual easement from Federal Government. PERMANENT IMPROVEMENTS Euipment of new Mechanical Engineering Laboratories $49,139 ating and Power-house equipment, etc., on campus (in city) . . 20,000 er-feeding barn at University Farm under construction 4,844 Walks, and University Farm road 1,500 Building and improvements at Valentine Substation 5,352 Building and improvements at Scottsbluff Substation 1,555 Building and improvements at North Platte Substation 11,150 New plant houses (farm and city campuses) 7,329 Shops and sheds 1,569 Water plant (on University Farm) 5,394 Veterinary Building (completion of) 5,909 New Mechanical Engineering building (completion of) 78,155 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">I ■• O5 • 00 •* N CT&gt; t- IO CO -i-ilNt-O&gt; to oo ■ co in co os co oo as coasasi-H i-i ©_ ' COCOCO T)&lt;CO lOi-li-lCM \w4 \ \ coi-iN ui'fHeo' &gt; o ST. ! t- eo • i-i e» «» us tji o co -t-oi-it- CO IS ■ CO CO &lt;3i ■&gt;» i-H i-H CO 1-100 IO • IOMH i-l • I en co co C5_CO t-^ 1 2 i « ! — ' 2 Q s ■s &lt; 5 i 6 a i S u 2 S I " O) [V] ■§ K § g Is ■= % ■° « cd oq 0 3 1 « ( 8- s en »-i j | j I I t- -co t-u5»T|inioo "^cicoc^ oo -co ■ i— i co io us co oo ■ co as oo co ■IO ■ i-l i-l '^HriH •00 • 00 Ol O&gt; »-h ■ ■ HOl^N ■ ■a&gt; ■ us t-ooea • ■ -oscooocd • •CO »-* ■ • ■ *-* »© r-i *-&lt; : : :| ::::::::: ! : \ . . .^3 ...::::::::: :: :g :«: : g ::::::: :: :g :§: :| ::::::: i-Jei^; ii Mil :~Jl1l -it ■ Si :• : : S s-g a) OS &lt;*&gt; C ° C fee ° « °&gt; * CO — = W -&lt; -g t/3 W v- — &lt;UWv_»_ &gt;. r g&gt;rH h h h h g&gt; yr h « g&gt; | 09— 9) 3S 53- ►&gt; O JS O O O O C •U5 ■iH»»O«J • O5O5005O ■ • i-i • o&gt; us eo eo • • cm_"5 t-i i-i ■ ■CO OOlOHOOtJ . ■ -HHH1S ' ■«O lOt-00«5IN ■ ■ OVO ■*ooco t-coco O&gt; t-CM t-COi-C O5 00rH lO^OS Cp_ •w co" t-eo-&gt;» MOJCO OO5MU5 i-T i-T on t- t-eoo 5 +i s I 'S 01 M •s If 1 ! 8 •o ai i i S £? * 2 t -g s § - o •&lt; ** H in O 3 | I i - ° i "o 0 •s 8 ill I I </seg>
            <seg id="p013">11 RESIDENCE OF STUDENTS— STATES AND COUNTRIES 1908-9 1909-10 NAME Alabama 0 1 Arizona 0 1 Arkansas 3 1 California 1 I Canada 0 1 Colorado 11 U Georgia 1 o Germany a l Idaho 3 2 7 10 1 o 0 4 70 74 Japan 3 1 Kansas 28 27 Kentucky 1 0 Korea 1 1 Louisiana 0 •2 Massachusetts 1 1 Michigan 2 0 Minnesota Missouri Montana Nebraska New Jersey New York North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Persia Philippines South Dakota Tennessee Texas 2 3 Utah 1 0 Washington 3 1 Wisconsin •&gt; Wyoming 15 14 Total I 3,611 3,992 Total for biennium 7,603 SIGNIFICATION OF THE DATA ON ATTENDANCE Eng the past four years the average increase in attendance has been annually. This means that we are now caring for over one thousand more than four years ago. Inasmuch as the total attendance at the y did not exceed five hundred during any year of the first twenty years of its existence, the enormous increase in the demands upon our re - sources is apparent. This evidence of the increasing confidence of the people of the state in their institution is gratifying, yet the burden of adequately caring for the ever increasing numbers has become a serious one. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">12 In order to care for the students seeking admission, the resources of the University have been conserved to the utmost. During the past two years very little building has been attempted, and the Board has followed the policy of adding nothing new in the way of subjects taught, or expansion in any department, unless such a step was actually forced upon us by conditions prevailing in the state, or by the general progress of education. The members of the faculty have been urged to limit the electives offered, and to retain nothing except what might be fairly attributable to the needs of the students and to the demands of higher scholarship. In carrying out this general policy the Board has met criticism from those who advocated new substations, new schools of agriculture, and other activities worthy in themselves but which help to swell the total appropriations spent under the direction of the Eents without contributing directly to the purpose for which the Board, legal provision, exists, namely, to administer the affairs pertaining to ler education provided for by the state. CONDITIONS OF STUDENT LIFE Since the last report was submitted, conditions of student life have steadily advanced, and are in all respects in a most wholesome condition. The admirable civic conditions prevailing in the city of Lincoln have tended to this result. Cases of students committing acts unbecoming to young gentlemen or young ladies are exceedingly rare. Thru the establishment of a delinquent student committee, with a secretary in active charge of the work, scholarship has been markedly improved. A somewhat closer super - vision of the students' work has been acceptable to the students, and espe - cially so to the parents. No serious student disorders of any sort have oc - curred. An investigation conducted by the Y. M. C. A. employment bureau indicates that the young men having their principal work at the city campus, are earning an aggregate of nearly $100,000.00 a year. The University is to be congratulated that so many of its students are wholly or partially self - supporting, and that the city furnishes such facilities for self-support. THE GRADUATE COLLEGE During the biennium the University of Nebraska has been admitted to the Association of American Universities, a group of twenty-two institutions selected on the basis of their maintaining efficient graduate schools. The enrollment in our graduate college this year will reach probably two hundred. ehis increase has been in part accelerated by the abolishment of fees in the ■aduate college. Since a large number of our graduate students are giving some instruction to the undergraduates, the Board deemed it undesirable to place a tariff on the scholarship which they represent, and which is of great value in encouraging ideals of scholarship among the undergraduates. k While private foundations are receiving their millions in donations for uate instruction, and while one state university has a large -appropriation ifically for its graduate work, the University of Nebraska has never been </seg>
            <seg id="p015">13 ments which contribute their quota of work towards making up the college. The Board regrets that it has not been able to appropriate $10,000.00 a year to be devoted to the advancement of the graduate college in providing fellow - ships and scholarships, in adding to the means and appointments for research, and in securing more effective library investigation. THE COLLEGE OF ARTS AND SCIENCES The college of Arts and Sciences must always remain the central college in our University organization, since the cultural subjects are grouped here. Hence whether the student is studying agriculture or law, his general edu - cation must be cared for by this college. In accordance with our policy of retrenchment the only expansion strictly within this college has been the establishment of a department of Slavonic, to meet the needs of our Bohemian speaking people. The work of this department has been rapidly developed, is affording one of the few opportunities for the study of one of the noble, but rer known, literatures of Europe, and is greatly appreciated by our citizens Bohemian descent. Embracing, as this college does, all the departments of knowledge not especially assigned to one of the professional colleges, it must be always the center of academic influence and learning. It is, in a sense, the soul of the institution. It can no more be neglected for technical pursuits than can the higher life of the individual be neglected to increase his capacity as a bread winner. Many of its departments are now very inadequately sheltered. It would be highly desirable to have in the near future a worthy building in which those departments not requiring laboratory facilities could be housed. At the same time more adequate laboratory facilities should be provided, especially for botany, chemistry, and geography. As an example, it may be cited that the department of chemistry, which is housed in a building valued at $40,000.00, has a total enrollment in all courses, of approximately 600 unrepeated names. An addition to the south of the present building, involv - ing an outlay of $40,000.00, would equip this department for satisfactory work, altho the plant would still be more modest than that enjoyed by many sister institutions. In the department of botany, physical conditions are exceedingly bad. It is almost inexcusable to permit one of our most distinguished professors to repeat his lectures to several sections because no adequate lecture room has been provided, capable of holding all the students at one time. The department of geography occupies rooms in the basement formerly used for the storage of janitor supplies and of lumber for the carpenter shop. All departments of this college, practically without exception, are in cramped, crowded, unhygienic quarters. This condition of affairs should be remedied at the earliest possible moment. THE TEACHERS COLLEGE In 1908 the Board of Regents erected the department of education into a teachers' college, an institution of collegiate standards ranking with the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">14 into seven colleges. The aim of this college is to prepare superintendents, principals, teachers in secondary schools, professors in normal schools and smaller colleges, as well as to provide supervisors in such special lines as agri - culture, domestic science, manual training, and the fine arts. It has no desire to encroach upon those fields which have long been recognized as occupied by the normal schools; namely, the preparation of teachers for the grades, of principals for the small high school, and for other lines of teaching where the schools are not in position to pay the salaries commanded by graduates of the full college course. The college has established a practice high school for the benefit of its students. This school has been placed on the accredited list of four-year secondary schools which prepare for the freshman grades of the various uni - versities. The purpose in maintaining it is to afford an opportunity for the students in the teachers college to do practice teaching. The school is housed in the basement of the Temple, and is supported very largely by tuition fees charged. The pupils are not listed in the catalog of university students. E would be highly desirable to have a special building to house this Not only is there urgent need of the room in the Temple for other s, but the teachers college high school should occupy a model building, having proper offices, recitation rooms, gymnasium, laboratories and work Cops for manual training and domestic science. In short, there should be building that could be exhibited to superintendents and school officials as presenting the most desirable features of school architecture and appoint - ments. Such a building with its equipment could be erected for about $80,000.00. THE COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING The act of the last legislature in providing for the organization of the college of engineering, formerly a part of the old industrial college, has had much to do with promoting the welfare of engineering and increasing the efficiency of the work done in the college. During the latter part of the past university year the new mechanical engineering laboratories were occu - pied. These laboratories are housed in one of the finest buildings of the University group. The building is practically fire proof, and is highly credit - able to the dean of the college, who acted as architect, and who, with the superintendent of construction, supervised its erection. Few changes have been made in the personnel of the faculty. The enrollment of students in - creases, and the demand for the graduates is fully maintained. Bfhe erection of this building has made the department of mechanical eering one of the best equipped in the country. The next step forward d be to equip adequately the department of electrical engineering, department occupies what was originally a wooden shed, but which was veneered with brick and otherwise improved a number of years ago. It has secured some relief thru occupying space vacated by the department of mechanical engineering. Tho not pressing the needs of this department upon the legislature at the present time, and recognizing that other interests must </seg>
            <seg id="p017">15 $100,000.00. During the past year the title of the department of farm me - chanics has been changed to that of agricultural engineering. As this depart - ment has for its special duty the teaching of farm mechanics and a certain amount of engineering work to the students in agriculture, its needs will be mentioned under the latter college. THE COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE In accordance with the plan of reorganization mentioned under engineer - ing, the work in agriculture was reorganized into a separate college. It includes courses in general agriculture, a course in forestry, and a course in home economics. The secondary school of agriculture heretofore attached to the industrial college, has now become an organization articulated with the college of agriculture. The attendance in the college of agriculture shows a healthy increase, and its graduates are in great demand. The school of agriculture, with a constantly increasing attendance, continues to do its admirable work in the training of practical farmers. The agricultural ex - periment station is investigating problems of plant diseases, studies in hog cholera and swamp fever, studies in soils of the transition region, methods of determining humus, transpiration studies with plants to determine types which are economical in the use of water, degrees of the saturation of soils to promote optimum growth of plants. Among the more popular lines of investigation of this kind are, the development of corn, wheat, and other cereals; a study of the effect of fertilizers, and the distribution and growth of bacteria upon alfalfa; a study of food stuffs to determine economical rations, and the use of silage in the production of beef and dairy products. Hog cholera serum is being produced for distribution to farmers thru veterinarians; and the work of the insect pest and plant disease bureau within the station is progressing. This work, with that of the serum, is being carried in part by special state appropriations. Substations: The North Platte experimental substation continues to do efficient work, and enjoys the appreciation of the people in the western part of the state. The legislatures of 1907 and 1909, each appropriated $25,000.00 for the maintenance of this station, the appropriation coming out of the state general fund. The appropriations have been supplemented by the sale of produce from the station which, under the careful management of the superintendent, has amounted during the biennium to approximately $15,000.00. It is highly desirable that a boarding house for laborers, as well as other buildings, be erected. For this purpose and for maintenance the Regents request that not less than $30,000.00 be taken from the general In accordance with an act of the legislature of two years ago, a sub - n designed to serve the sandy country of the state was located, by a tittee of the Regents, at Valentine. It includes 40 acres of deeded adjoining the town, together with about 1,050 acres of land from the try reservation, which is to remain under easement from the govern - in the possession of the University as long as it is used for experimental </seg>
            <seg id="p018">16 with an endeavor to demonstrate the feasibility and economy of concrete construction in the sand hills region of the state. The legislature of two years ago provided for a substation which was located about seven miles from Scottsbluff. This station has been conducted in cooperation with the federal government. The latter has a dominant in - fluence in its control. The state appropriation has been expended largely for barn and machine shed, fences, horses, machinery, and incidentals. With adequate maintenance the station is now in position to do excellent work during the coming biennium. Karmers' Institutes: The work of fanners' institutes has so outgrown propriation that two-thirds of the appropriation was used during the ear of the biennium, and still institutes were refused in some localities. Many states are adding departments of agricultural extension, and while Nebraska has made a beginning in this respect, the work has been done largely without funds. While the Regents are formally requesting only $25,000.00 out of the general state fund, $5,000 more than appropriated two years ago, they realize fully that this amount is entirely inadequate to meet the demands of the people. Their reason in not asking for a larger sum is that they feel that this is not strictly one of the University activities, but rather a state enterprise administered by the Regents for the welfare of the state. In many other states it is administered by the state board of agriculture. The Regents believe that the Nebraska method is efficient and economical, and would welcome an increase in this amount at the hands of the legislature. As many of the members of the legislature are farmers, and in view of the E needs of the institution in other respects, it does not seem to the Regents hey should be required to urge this item upon those who are informed ard to the subject. THE COLLEGE OF LAW The college of law, under its new dean, is enjoying a period of unexampled prosperity. Not only does it show the greatest proportional and actual in - crease of any of the colleges of the present year, but its work is of such a character as to receive the general endorsement of its patrons and the bar generally. However, the college is more seriously handicapped for room, the class rooms are more crowded, ventilation poorer, and general physical eon - rons less favorable, than those that exist in any other college of the Uni - rity. THE COLLEGE OF MEDICINE E&gt; total attendance of the college of medicine during the last annual was 197, as compared with 185 during the preceding session. The d entrance requirements to the college previously announced have been put into effect, involving the presentation of two years of college work above the thirty points of high school work. The most worthy fact in con - nection with the material equipment of the college has been the purchase of </seg>
            <seg id="p019">17 11 1 Wll y-il •! ground has been purchased and thus a start has been made. The Child Saving Institute of Omaha has been giving a perpetual lease to certain lota belonging to the state. On these a building will be erected to serve as a children's hospital. Tho the work of the two final years of the college of medicine is under the full control of the Regents, the financial direction of these clinical years given in Omaha is under the management of a board of directors representing the joint stock company which owned the Omaha Medical College before it became a part of the University. Owing to the great increase in the cost of adequate medical education, and to the fact that the high standards of the University have reduced the numbers, the Omaha part of the work is conducted at a loss which members of the faculty make good by private contributions. The time has come when the legis - lature should make a specific appropriation for the maintenance of the work at Omaha, and take over the full financial control of the same, collecting all tuition fees and paying all bills, thus placing this college on the same baaia at the other colleges of the University. For this purpose the Board urges an item of $20,000.00 out of the state general fund, to be expended during the biennium for the maintenance of the work in Omaha. While certain citizens of Omaha have expressed a desire to contribute funds for the erection of buildings on the medical college campus, and while the Regents, as authorized by law, welcome contributions to the University's various enterprises, the time has come when the state, at public expense, should erect a clinical laboratory and administration building on its Omaha campus to cost not less than $100,000.00. This building, with the affiliated children's hospital, would serve as a nucleus of the medical plant. Other hospital facilities may be expected in the future, and while the medical college has ample facilities, it would be highly desirable to have certain hospitals under its own direct management. The Board is especially desirous of in - creasing the plant at Omaha, owing to the fact that the best authorities on medical education regard the course of six years above the high school as the most desirable. Of these six years, four are now given in Lincoln and two in Omaha. At the earliest possible moment a readjustment should be made so that two will be given in Lincoln and four in Omaha. This can be brought about only by the state's taking over the financial control of the work in Omaha, and the building of an adequate physical plant. Echool op Pharmacy: The School of Pharmacy is entering upon the year of its existence. The registration of the first year was 16; of the 1, 27; and the number at present is 33. The great need of the school of pharmacy at present is more room. The school is housed in the basement of University Hall and Nebraska Hall in rooms not designed for class room purposes. There are no hoods for gases; the ceilings are low; the light is bad. It is exceedingly important that better quarters be provided as soon as possible for this school. THE SUMMER SESSION In accordance with the referendum vote of the students in attendance at the summer session of 1909, and upon the recommendation of the faculty. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">18 the length of the term of the summer session was extended to eight weeks. The management was under the direction of the chancellor, who was largely relieved of routine work by a very efficient committee. Professor Grummann, formerly director of the school, requested to be relieved. Four important innovations marked the summer session of 1910: the school of superintendence, the model high school, model grade school, and the special courses of in - struction which were given in agriculture, education, home economics, and industrial training. The total enrollment for this session was 511, the largest in the history of summer sessions at the University. The summer session has now been recognized as equivalent in instruction and credit to a half semester of the University, and in the opinion of the Board the time has come to abolish the enrollment fee, and charge only the matriculation fee and such incidental and laboratory fees as are charged during the regular university year. This might mean a loss of about $3,000.00 in fees, but there would seem to be no logical reason why the summer session should not be supported in the same way that other sessions are supported. The ex - tension of the work during the past summer was accomplished without ap - propriating funds in excess of those granted during the preceding year. UNIVERSITY EXTENSION When the printed volume of this report is ready for distribution, the work of the department of University Extension will have completed its second year. The work has been planned along four lines: correspondence study, instruction by lectures, debating and public discussion, information and general welfare. This work has been carried on without expense to the state other than the salary of the director and the stenographer of the de - partment. Actual expenses have been met by small fees. It will be im - possible to greatly extend the work of the department without direct ap - propriation out of the state general fund. Inasmuch as the fees charged are very low, most of the work must be done gratuitously by professors in ad - dition to their regular work. It would be highly desirable if this legislature would appropriate $50,000.00 out of the state general fund for university ex - tension work, including agricultural extension. By throwing part of the work now cared for by the Farmers' Institute fund onto agricultural extension, and making the superintendent of farmers' institutes director of agricultural extension, the amount given for farmers' institutes could much more adequately sustain that part of the work. As conducted during the past two years, the department, without any support other than that already mentioned, has been able to reach thru its lectures at least 100,000 citizens, and has had an Eate audience of 300,000. There should be a closer relationship between sity extension work and agricultural extension work, and the Board ideavor to solve this problem to the satisfaction of all interests if a : appropriation is made. THE LIBRARY During the last biennium 11,150 bound volumes have been added as, •gainst 10,150 during the preceding two years. Of the volumes added 1562, </seg>
            <seg id="p021">19 were by gift. The total number of volumes now in the library is 90,510. The most urgent needs of the library are as follows: A reading room for professors and graduate students where it will be possible for them to work under better conditions than in the crowd of several hundred undergraduates who use the library almost constantly during its open hours; a reading and study room other than the library reading room. The library reading room is so crowded with students who are using their own text books, that those who come to consult the library are frequently unable to find seats. More working space is needed for the library staff. Sufficient space was not provided in the [inning, and as the working staff has been enlarged its quarters have become re and more crowded. PEVELOPMENT OF THE CITY AND THE FARM CAMPUSES The four city blocks, including the space which would have been occupied by the city streets extending thru the plot, served as a site for the greater part of the University's activities until the development of the farm campus, and the taking over of the medical college work at Omaha. Even under present conditions four-fifths of the students receive the greater part of their instruction on the original location. The legislature of two years ago in appropriating money out of the state fund for a drill ground and athletic field, endorsed the policy of the Board in their plan to acquire more ground in the neighborhood of the present tract. With part of this appropriation the Regents purchased one block north of the city campus for a drill ground and athletic field. As this proved to be too small for a satisfactory field, Messrs. J. E. Miller and J. W. McDonald purchased three lots on the block east of the recently acquired tract (see diagram of city campus). This land has been turned over for the use of the University, interest on the investment being paid by the athletic board of the University out of the proceeds of tickets sold for athletic contests. The University should reimburse Mr. McDonald and Mr. Miller for their investment, taking over the ground at cost, and should acquire the rest of the block. This will permit the Uni - versity to enclose a compact plot of six blocks, the city having previously ordered the streets vacated as soon as all of the two blocks north of the city campus are acquired. While this represents a small campus, it contains adequate room for new buildings to aggregate several hundred thousand dollars, and is comparable in size with the original Harvard yard. The future development of the University can then take place by acquiring neigh - boring building sites in precisely the same way that the plant at Harvard has been developed. The suggestion has been made that since there is ample room for building on the University Farm campus, future building activities should be confined to those needed by the college and school of agriculture. While the Regents have always considered the development of the agricultural work of the institution as a matter of great importance, yet among the most pressing needs for relief at the present time are those in connection with some of the other colleges of the University. These cannot be neglected. The develop- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">20 tnt of all the colleges of the institution, and of the several campuses where y are located, should proceed simultaneously. kAt the University Farm campus great congestion exists in certain depart - its. While we cannot look upon our seven weeks' short course in agri - ure as of sufficient permanence to justify building for its especial accom - modation, aside from this course chronic congestion exists in a number of the departments giving work in the school of agriculture. Particular attention should be called to the inadequate facilities in horticulture, agricultural botany, agricultural engineering, and dairying. An urgent need is felt for armory and gymnasium facilities. It should be remembered that the second battalion is now nearly as large as the first battalion, since very few of the school of agriculture students secure exemption from military drill. Students coming from the active outdoor life of the farm suffer more from lack of proper exercise than other students. The Regents recommend the con - struction of a building which may be termed the Plant Industry Building, having in mind the use of the basement of this building for purposes of an armory and gymnasium, also providing a large assembly room. This build - ing would house the departments, or most of them, having any relations to the plant industry, and would afford relief to other departments in vacating rooms for their use. The next most urgent need would be relief along the line of farm mechanics for the department of agricultural engineering. A railroad switch should be built to avoid the necessity of hauling coal and building material. It would pay for itself in a short time. Altogether, it is highly desirable to spend during the biennium in the neighborhood of $200,000.00 at the State Farm, not only to give immediate relief for the congested condition of certain depart - ments in the school of agriculture, but also to develop the work of the college of agriculture. RECAPITULATION OF THE NEEDS OF THE UNIVERSITY Pr forty years the University has steadily grown upon its present sites oring always to keep pace with the growth and educational needs of te and the general advance of the educational movement in the mid- With limited resources it has met the demands upon it in a reasonably iesful degree. With the spread of culture and increase of wealth in the state, some citizens, doubtless, would like to see a more magnificent physical plant — more imposing and elegant buildings, ample and attractive grounds. That there is great educational value in such environment there can be no doubt. The Regents share in the desires of the most ardent advocates of good things for the University. But whatever ideals might be entertained for the future, the Regents are now, more than ever before, confronted with immediate needs of such mag - nitude and kind as preclude in large measure an ideal expansion of the phys - ical plant. Considerable building must be undertaken at once, and should feof such a character as to afford immediate relief to unsatisfactory con - ons. If relief is not to be provided for, the Regents would request the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">21 farm and city campus, to the present enrollment. It is not fair to students seeking an education to permit greater congestion. If the legislature does not feel that the condition of the state warrants the construction of permanent buildings, strictly temporary wooden structures might be provided. An equally urgent need of the hour is more teachers of the higher rank. The Regents deem it their first duty to emphasize these needs. The statistical tables accompanying this report show the ratio of students to teachers of all ranks from deans to scholars, to be about 18 to 1. This is nearly double the standard recognized by the leading institutions of the country. Inability to remedy that condition in some measure is a serious handicap tending to lower the position of the University among institutions of its kind. The real test of the need, however, is not shown by merely comparing the number of teachers with the number of individual students. The extent, character, and diversity of the student's work is an important factor usually overlooked. The registration statistics of the last two university years show that the teaching force touches the student body at about 30,000 points annually. The present tendency of demands is toward increased diversity and amount of university educational activity. To divide overcrowded classes means more teachers and more class rooms. EXPLANATION IN REGARD TO THE SOURCES OF THE UNIVERSITY'S REVENUES It should be borne in mind that only requests made for appropriations out of the state general fund represent additional drain on the state's re - sources, or burdens to the tax payers. When the mill rate was passed it was assumed that the revenues from this fund would be ample to care for the needs of the University indefinitely. It should be remembered, however, that practically the University consisted at that time of the activities on the Uni - versity campus, with a little agricultural work done at long range on the University Farm. No one could at that time foresee the demands made upon the institution by the people of the state. As announced two years ago, the mill rate is nearly exhausted in caring for the salary roll and for current expenses at the city and farm campuses. The other demands made upon the institution must be provided for from other funds. As an instance of the unforeseen demands made upon the institution by the people of the state, and the progress of education, the Regents would mention the great agricultural awakening of the country and of the state, resulting in the ex - penditure of money for agricultural instruction and experimentation (to a large extent funds donated to the institution by the Government), amount - ing to nearly six times as much as the cost of the college of engineering, nine times as much as spent for the college of medicine, and so on. Farmers in - stitutes, the substations, special appropriations for seed, hog cholera serum, and other activities illustrate the development of agricultural activities not sought by the Regents or by the professors engaged in agricultural work. The Board of Regents was constituted originally, by law, as a board to care primarily for higher education. The handling of such funds as the farmers' institute fund, the substations, even the experiment station itself, must be </seg>
            <seg id="p024">22 regarded aa duties laid upon the Regents by the people of the state, and should not be charged to higher education in Nebraska. If the members of the legis - lature, and the people of the state will bear in mind the things that have been delegated to the Regents to administer not at their request, and sometimes C their wishes, they will see the unfairness of looking at the grand totals inistered by the Regents as representing the money used by the Uni - of Nebraska. Bit should be remembered, further, that only about two-thirds of this »y in the grand totals represents money drawn from taxation. The rest s from invested funds, as a government donation, from the sale of produce, from student fees. Iinally, in the analysis of the use of money, it should be remembered rhereas the sum of over $200,000.00 appears as University cash, only a i this is paid by students. Thus, for instance, if during the next bien - the text book fund should contain $10,000.00 left over from the sale of in the preceding year, this might be turned over twice each year and as $40,000.00 in our grand total in our next biennial report, whereas nothing whatever has been added to the fund. On this basis it would appear perpetually as $40,000.00 a biennium. Money used in feeding live stock, and replacing the fat animals with feeders, might figure perpetually in a similar way. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">SPECIFIC LEGISLATION REQUESTED Formal appropriations of funds belonging to the institution: Appropriating to the use of the University 90 per cent of proceeds of the mill tax for 1911 and 1912, (estimated) $792,000 00 240,000 00 Appropriating the University Cash Fund (estimated). E;IATIONS FROM THE STATE GENERAL FUND, ING ITEMS CARED FOR IN THE PAST FROM FUND AND REPRESENTING ONLY SLIGHT ONS AND INCREASES: Farmers Institutes $25,000 00 Substations : North Platte 30,000 00 Scottsbluff 5,000 00 Valentine 10,000 00 70,000 00 KPRIATIONS FROM THE STATE GENERAL FUND IESENTING MARKED INCREASES OVER COR - •ONDING ITEMS GRANTED TWO YEARS AGO: EPhe bills authorizing the new substations, as originally passed con - ed by error a charge to the temporary university fund instead of to state general fund. This error was corrected, but the correction waa ed by the governor. The university fund should be reimbursed as an of justice. 23 For additional land and permanent im- provements at the city campus $150,000 00 For permanent improvements at the Uni- versity Farm campus 150,000 00 300,000 00 PPROPRIATIONS FOR NEW ITEMS FROM THE rE GENERAL FUND: ) enable the state to assume complete financial control of the medical work at Omaha $20,000 00 to reimburse the university for the substations at Scottsbluff and Valentine; to be used for general maintenance 20,000 00 40,000 00 1&gt;r general repairs to university property in lieu of expenditure from temporary university fund, to restore fire loss on mechanic arts hall $15,000 00 ir clinical laboratory and administration building on the Omaha medical campus . . 100,000 00 115,000 00 t. S. grants, trust funds not requiring re- appropriation 240,000 00 240,000 00 $1,797,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">24 Two years ago (Nov. 1908) the Regents estimated the proceeds of the university mill tax for 1909 at $400,000.00 and for 1910 at $410,000.00. The figures proved to be, in round numbers, for 1909, $398,985.00, and for 1910, $412,138.00. Thus the Regents' estimate of the mill tax resource for the current biennium appears to have been soundly made. The statute of 1909 setting aside the mill tax proceeds for University support, authorized the use by the Regents of 95% of the University mill levies for 1909 and 1910. The aggregate amount so made available is found to be, in round numbers, $770,568.00. That statute also appropriated to University uses $30,000.00 of delinquent taxes of former years, making a grand total of $800,568.00 from the mill tax resource for usual University purposes. From that total available resource the Regents have apportioned to vmrious University needs for the two years ending March 31, 1911, thesum of $765,855.00, leaving unapportioned the sum of $34,713.00. That balance together with the 5% reservation from the face of the levies ($40,556.00), would have made a total reserve of $75,269.00 for the protection of the fund But later in the session of 1909, after the appropriation of 95% of the mill levies to ordinary University purposes, the legislature passed acts ap - propriating $20,000.00 for the establishment of two experimental substations In form, those acts were substantial copies of legislation eight years precedini and made the appropriations payable from the temporary university fund Still later the legislature transferred the substations appropriation to the general appropriation bill to be paid from the state general fund. The Gover nor vetoed the items so transferred. Upon application to the Supreme Court it was held in State ex rel. Bushee vs. Regents, on re-hearing, that the $20, 000.00 substations appropriation was payable from the mill tax portion o the temporary university fund in addition to the 95% already set apart for the University generally. The effect of the proceedings just stated was not only to delay steps to start the substation work until the second year of the biennium but, also, to reduce the total reserve named above for protection of the fund to the sum of $55,269.00. On the morning of November 12, 1910, while this report was in preparation, occurred the heaviest loss by fire in the University's history. The roof of the mechanic arts building was destroyed fire of unknown origin, the building and its contents being damaged to extent estimated at a minimum of $12,000.00. In this emergency the Regents were obliged to draw again upon the depleted reserve sum last above named reducing it to $43,000.00 approximately. Besides, if it happen that all of the $30,000.00 appropriated against delinquent taxes of former years, be not collected in this biennium, the reserve is further reduced by so much of tax of former years as remains uncollected. There has also been paid interest on outstanding university fund warrants from April 1, 1909, to November, 1910, approximately $10,000.00, which stands charged against the mill tax portion of the temporary university fund in addition to all other charges. It is possible that the reserve may fall as low as $20,000.00 — a lower stage than usual in recent years. To prevent recurrence of this con - dition and to add further protection to the temporary university fund, the </seg>
            <seg id="p027">25 vereity mill levies for 1911 and 1912 be set apart for University uses. They ilso ask that at least the $20,000.00 sub-stations draft upon the temporary university fund and the fire loss be made good by appropriations from the state general fund for some general University purpose in the next biennium. Items are accordingly added to the formal estimates of expenditures from the state general fund, for the next biennium. !'wo years ago the Regents estimated the total income to the university Fund for the present biennium at $225,000.00. It has already reached e more than $238,000.00 with every indication that there will be a sub - al balance in the state treasury on March 31, 1911. This is in keeping the long established policy of the Board of Regents to preserve this continually upon a strictly cash basis, as its name indicates and the law requires. The two funds — the temporary university fund, composed of the mill tax and income from permanent endowments, and the university cash fund, composed of moneys collected at the University — are the only ones requiring special comment. They are the only resources the amount of which cannot be definitely known in advance and which vary from year to year. All others — the United States "Morrill", the experiment station fund and special appropriations from the state general fund — are fixed amounts annually or biennially for definite limited purposes. Under the rigid methods of dis - bursing money for University support there is no probability of the three latter funds or appropriations being overdrawn at any time. All are plainly set forth each biennium in the Regents' estimates with the purposes specified to which they must by law be applied. On the pages immediately following appear, first, the Regents' estimates of the usual resources of the University for the two years ending March 31, 1913, with amounts and general purposes of expenditures stated. Second, financial statements by the secretary exhibiting all expenditures for the two years ended November 30, 1910, the general purposes of said expenditures, the portions thereof charged to the different funds, the status of the several funds on November 30, 1910, the cash collected at the University and paid to the state treasurer for the same period. The formal financial statements have been improved in several par - ticulars. An entirely new table has been added classifying total expenditures by departments of instruction, administration and special activities. There has also been added a statistical table showing the total number of semestral registrations of students in the various departments of instruction for the two school years ended August 12, 1910. It is thought that these two com - plementary statements present the magnitude and efficiency of University activity in a manner readily understood and more clearly outlined than here - tofore. Their value for comparative purposes is apparent and they add much to the importance of the usual "per capita cost" argument, which merely divides a gross expenditure by the number of individual students in attendance for a given year. Part two of this biennial report is the usual detailed statement showing </seg>
            <seg id="p028">26 every item of expenditure by the University and the purposes of the ex - penditures for the two years ended November 30, 1910. PROPOSED CHANGE IN FORM OF OFFICIAL REPORT KFor the two years beginning December 1, 1910, it is proposed to change method and form of the Regents' biennial report and the semi-annual rts of the Board to the Governor. From the establishment of the Uni - versity to the present the law requiring biennial reports to be made "in detail" has been strictly followed by presenting to the Governor and the Legislature printed reports setting out each and every item of expenditure as made. The report has become voluminous and costly. It is believed that some of the most important advantages of that method are lost in its multiplicity of detail. For example: If John Doe is paid a salary of one thousand dollars a year in monthly payments, the spirit of the law is as well kept and more direct information given by reporting $2,000.00 in one item for the two years' service rather than repeating monthly payment to John Doe twenty-four times. The like is true in the case of supplies bought each month or frequently from the same person or dealers. For a number of years it has been necessary to publish the biennial report in two parts in order to secure delivery within the time required by law. Under the new plan the report can be reduced to one part giving all the information now embodied in two parts, in more convenient form and at less cost for printing. ESTIMATED ORDINARY RESOURCES AND EXPENDITURES (Not including requests for land and permanent improvement.) E owing is the Regents' estimate of University resources, all funds, two years ending March 31, 1913, with contemplated expenditures during the same period. EThe Board of Regents request the passage of an act by the legislature ar to that of 1909, separate from all other appropriation measures, setting t 90% of the one mill tax levy for the next biennium, for the support ie University in its ordinary educational activities. The Board asks for appropriations from the general fund of the state, as heretofore, for support of farmers' institutes and the North Platte sub - station. It also asks appropriations from the state general fund for main - tenance and improvements for the new substations at Scottsbluff and Val - entine and aid in support of the Omaha branch of the medical college, and addition to building site in Omaha. The income from endowment lands and permanent fund investments and the cash donations by the United States in further aid of the college of agriculture and for support of the agricultural experiment station connected therewith, are held by the Supreme Court of the state to be trust funds sub - ject to expenditure by the Regents for the special purposes prescribed in the acts of Congress creating said funds respectively, without further action by the legislature than the original acceptance of the terms of said grants. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">27 THE TEMPORARY UNIVERSITY FUND (Mill Tax) Resource One mill levy for 1911, on estimated assessment of . 1420,000,000 420,000 00 One mill levy for 1912, on estimated assessment of. 460,000,000 460,000 00 $880,000 00 Less 10% for delinquencies and depreciation 88,000 00 Available for the biennium net $792,000 00 Expenditures Payable from the temporary university fund (mill tax) For salaries and wages $560,500 00 For general maintenance, including departmental expenses; farm expenses; freight, express and cartage; fuel, gas, light, power and water; furniture and fixtures; incidentals; labor; live stock; library books; printing; postage and stationery; publications; re - pairs and up-keep; special equipment; stu- dent text books; traveling expenses 220,000 00 Reserved for emergencies 11,500 00 $792,000 00 792,000 00 THE TEMPORARY UNIVERSITY FUND (Income) Resource Interest on lease and sale contracts of agricultural college and university lands and interest on investments of the per - manent endowment funds, for the two years ending March 31, 1913, estimated (trust fund) $80,000 00 Expenditures Payable from the temporary university fund (income) : For salaries and wages and facilities for in - struction in subjects related to agriculture and the mechanic arts, as limited by the act of Congress of July 2, 1862, and sup- plementary acts 80,000 00 $80,000 00 80,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">28 Resource 6 donation by the United States in further aid of the college I agriculture and the mechanic arts for the two years nding June 30, 1913, under the act of Congress of August 0, 1890, and supplementary acts (trust fund) $100,000 00 Expenditures Payable from the united states "morrill" fund E salaries and wages and facilities for in - itruction in the subjects indicated only in ;he act of Congress of August 30, 1910, and supplementary acts $100,000 00 $100,000 00 $100,000 00 THE UNITED STATES AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION FUNDS Resource Cash donation by the United States to maintain the agricultural experiment station in Nebraska for the two years ending June 30, 1913, under acts of Congress of March 2, 1887, and March 16, 1906 (trust funds) $60,000 00 Expenditures Payable from the U. S. agricultural experimental station Er salaries and wages, supplies and facil - s for scientific investigations and experi - ntation and the publication of results as required by the acts of Congress $60,000 00 $60,000 00 60,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">29 THE UNIVERSITY CASH FUND Resource E received at the University as tuition fees, sales and dry other sources and to be paid over to the state isurer as custodian of the university cash fund; estimated the two years ending March 31, 1913 $240,000 00 Payable from the university cash fund: For salaries and expenses in the schools of agriculture, fine arts, professional schools, summer school, teachers college high school and university extension courses; advertis - ing; chemical supplies; farm up-keep; farm departments supplies; foodstuff; incidental expenses; labor; laboratory apparatus and supplies; library books; livestock; services (expert); specimens; substations (No. Platte, Scottsbluff , Valentine) ; student text books, and all other purposes for which fees or other moneys are received at the Uni - versity $240,000 00 $240,000 00 240,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">30 Resource Eve appropriations asked from the general fund of the e for the purposes specified below, for the two years ng March 31, 1913 $105,000 00 Expenditures Payable from the state general fund: upon direction of the Board of Regents, For maintenance of farmers' institutes including salaries of superintendent, assistants, stenog - raphers, clerks, freight and express, office expenses, services of lecturers and speakers and other workers, traveling expenses of lecturers and officers, telegraph and tele - phone $25,000 00 E services and expenses, aid in support of the Omaha branch of the medical college, ad - ditional land for building site, street grad - ing and other improvements 20,000 00 t support of experimental substations; im - provements, services, supplies, stock, labor, At North Platte 30,000 00 At Scottsbluff 5,000 00 At Valentine 10,000 00 For general repairs of University property, in lieu of expenditure from temporary uni - versity fund to restore fire loss on Me - chanic Arts Hall 15,000 00 $105,000 00 105,000 00 RECAPITULATION Total of available resources and special appropriations asked for general support only, for the biennium $1,377,000 00 From the one mill university tax and state general fund 897,000 00 From sources other than state revenue $480,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">a « i i I 00 i-t I to" g si 82 co oo I eo" o ctT eoooio ■^•OJeo f-H CO si o^oo e^o&gt;_ i o • to - co *♦ : llj » 1 I i S3 8 s§ s o oo oo ■ • ■* t- o ■ ■»?) i s a* O 00 iO 00 CO oo IO i-l 00 ■■ ISO eo 5&gt; oo • • ■♦•* eo o&gt; m" ; ; oTeo" a i o I i II § o 1-1 s CO 1—1 s o H ■ ji - ■ ji I IJ i to I 00 2 00 1 3 I 2 It S-2 s E od" 1 ! i! 1 ill o 8 8 S3 S o t I 00 § © s to o eo cc o oio coco ao oo M oo to CO t~lO tj" 00 kO N«eo no'o" «-H CO t-&lt; 1 I a S ! i * i &amp;**.•.!&amp; '■ *«§ ill : in JL &gt; ■ a &gt;&gt;.2 1= 111 &lt;i 2 « a 5 * " Ij I y 1 1 1 life S«! f Sl:l i# Ell i i </seg>
            <seg id="p034">» 2 si I sis 5 l-H l-H CO MoJ_oo_ to'rt'eo' II ■"^i-i" eo s co tOi-l &gt;-l&gt;O00 •*oo en^-He*) I IO ■ ■ CO ■ • ?3 : : co ■ ■ e» : : S3 S : : oeo © ' ■ O 00 O - - - i I 8 1, t-o»eo 00 COM (MN00 esfio^-T CO lOffl H ■ rf 00 Oi ■ t- 00 «o -ir co - • N • • w4 • ■ o ■ ■ CO . . «o : : O5O5 CO A S8S eo ! OOl • coco - e»eo oooo - ■^"* ■ : : :§ : : : : : :fl : : : . . t- ... i a I z c i ii C eo*"^ S H i 5 * -S3 1 I •sii I 3 g . . . -ooe* eo© • • ■ eot- OCQ ■ • • M9&gt; t-O» • ■ • • t-O CO 00 ■ * * • O&gt; 00 eo . . . . to t- i-i oo °i. m 00 ■ f-H !ob" CO CD C4 r-t to 00 ! I I I gH h "1 &amp;: 11 : «:| : : il: :| : Git\k I I ii iif] Hi!- * L Mil : t||S :;:|il: «||2 g *|||ff Jf ill? lift ti h T Sfbcc 2 S a. I c c oj-g i sfiilsJ </seg>
            <seg id="p035">§ SI ' I o M 38 CON "5 ?) OJCO oo 00^ QO-*f is 52 _ ? i g§ too CON § : o ■ ITS § : : :§ 2 : : :§ 2S 91U3 OS 00 1SU3 — : g : : : : CO C4 - ■ . 3 I : I : : : : '. co : : : ■ 3 : — - I ; !: : : M : o 1-4 ■ CO CO &lt;D M £S£3 IS co^o&gt;o us iO'OOt'O l-T t-WN i to •00 .oo" OCOOrH USiOOJl ii-J'id'ui' s § r &gt;o 8 8 2 s S. ao T I P.; S7 o Sec-" tl ' li 1 ' I ■ "I * s-12'3 c : 2 III 5 Mjj i :S :U :g| :.. : : :§£ li II Iiil II Jjfif i I! a j I! * * ■sii i | s. : 1 :§ •■s! f I iliiiiii :l||i|fj -a 1 c 5 I </seg>
            <seg id="p036">I 2s I_U : : i&gt; S S. —^ - 13 be NVIONSO00HNNHHH — ( ■g oonnNtOHot-coutsio c- o oo us o» t- ■* to © oo ■** tn co eo t- . Csl W3 t^ O CC O5 O U5 c*l O^ *D a CO "S e^oo_co_o^c^m to i-i to ■£ H v)eio&lt;£oi&lt;orZ&lt;ous-&lt;fo&gt;m eS =s HHM CO t «O 3 •» o- -w ■ . C o • oooeo • ■ 3 Jj » 00 ■ MOO) • js ' ..!..[_: iusoeo ■ -I «o ■ •«&gt;■»&gt;■(- ■ ■ « ° 5, c» ■ e»«e-«f ■ t;, &lt;ta a : :B : : ta r^ — ■ '■ ] ,o. a, m oo oo m io oo oooonio - *{£ S 0) UJN91KKOM c^iOCO^JiO - &lt;° &lt;*&lt;*«!»!eoo cneoent-eo J3 cs wcotcooost- oOTfTfooco ■ "O JJ .S'C "- 1 "5 "&gt; °o &lt;*,*. ■ oo^o«o us ■ "g i ! .5 Jll | If I I I 1 11 * I! I 5 i nisiaoinnoixsooo t- ' ooHocctcnoisnoiaic co u3t-oo»nNOnHO&lt;oo a&gt; : O^tO^rH^e^eO^OO^^tC^ &lt;O^ t-H *-H »— ( •— t i j ; 1 1 miiN i J '■'■'■'■ PC 1*9 • ■ M ■•^ &gt; ; ; ; ; :£i«J - g c -£ • ■ • - S-| bo^o S J :Sg ipfil iiiiiUIi I llllfll^Illii- U0QSSft,K'6tJ&lt;OjSOwW "1m » Oi • c j= So o t rj o _ « «t ® "c ° " J U m C x - *13 S .a 3 - : B! </seg>
            <seg id="p037">a 3 — . 1 ■£ | _ z 3 a? t-coN»0!Oso-»5Dtecow ten^NNOMn ' .5 3 i. C c o I • OS OS CO &gt;-l &lt;M &gt;-l CO C- p BOwoBt-'XinrtHt. toiaiooocoNioSbjj _? .5 S CO i-&lt; OS 00 IO CO OS «O ■* O N0ONt-O9N*» w c 0. S Tf005 L M"t- ; 'M"'&gt;oco''NTi&lt;'©' i-Tt-"'ei5iotoos''oo*©' • c I , S ji £ J g g oo ■* (m o «o -h o) t- oo oo o eg us a&gt; oj ?j im i-l g-c a 3 '13 OOOC&gt;)Tfi&lt;ecO-5&lt;DCOCO-* OSOIMCOCOOIMOS a «*S r#s n.'^ HHOtDWrtlOHOOO O&gt; X CO U3 O N -m" 52 0/3 0 i u ?.'T. 00 . ao . 10 . t ~. 00 ."* t^ e i. Soi8?»«rt a, j&lt; Z C/2 pt( •*■ i-Hi-H H * S 2 *» ft W ~5-o . « .-h 5 . 2 1 — "° $ £ - p» n S 13 c &gt; ° o 2 S o,aj ■* o (M rn t- os ro o «o cm to a 05 00 1- .5 K § « -3 u «•&lt;) w §-2 »ooaiou3NNt-t-w osmooooww^us-b'S.S 'aS ■■§ £ 5 J-S -^^^-si^ Isi 111 !- Jss iN Q « t- m "xonownnoOMWS oeoSo£ooo« C^ _; H 04 -2.H H&lt;e00H&lt;O05TKXHH» U3CO^"05000eO»oap£ OS &lt; a? fioujgc-rtt-oooam ownonmSx ®§P £ c a •7 ft, &gt;3 mE, a»rtO!Ot-H5ausoo t-oooiooNoousco T3°c o» S J bm os t- «o 00 o 00 c- cnenoo"io" ~c6r+-*iam-«&lt;3i 5*~ 5 o'5 3 Z j r—^^—- «2^ ago go ::::::::::: ::::::: ||2 1-IJ Wg ::::::::::: :::::::: 8j| | S 5 £5 II : : : : : : : : : : : J i : : : i ! *p B^l g 5S ::::::::::: | ::::::: "gg« 2 1 g g S3 :.: :f ::::::: I : : : Saa §.=s S5 §« :: :| ::::::: 3 j" g-^i 3 Ib 1 I* 111 JP . . . 8 : 03 :::::::: «3= -g g.» St :: ; s ;;;;;;; || ;;;:;;:; JU 15^ I BHiiili iflsSlliiJ </seg>
            <seg id="p038">i •&lt;^TOt-eoeo •«*eo^'&gt;-i ■NHCOHr-neMHlOtCF-w-. (2 - t-Nos^i!eojiOf&lt;iecN*0'*oi«NiOiHfO&lt;eoMio - Sisnu3icNAONiiono«nau9N&gt;au3'40oooon .1 §voo:ie9is&gt;Nt-a&gt;riHooecao&gt;ao&gt;u3MiHM9i^'Ot&lt; 01NN'Ot-fl'OCOU5iO'*«'&gt;tUJaN«!OCCOni'N(C «•■•* ■* CO 00 D5 O&gt; O» Oi -* O -*^0Ortt-&lt;CC^-*S-&lt;)i?i O3y~l «D (M Oi «O CO_N i-H Tf t-_M_O&gt; H^noOOO N 1 s i rtt-O5[-M t- U5 » "•»• « O t~ &lt;D CO CT&gt; ■* t- 3* I 5 2 c corate&gt;oo!fiu3nwient-&lt;eiiOMOoc-teoooecoN tsisnunOHCcnoentsionoooteviooenH Mi it N ! \\ |! jj ! I N Ms I j M M j| : : : : : : : : : : : : : : :| :| i i i • \ \ ] :i:J : j : | j j il : j _Jf |l it I I I i: ■ c ,-." fe ■ • c2 ■ • • a ■ • • • • :k : : : 'W9 '■ :.c--§ :'j :-S.§ : :&gt;»S §l|l|!.^;||ill!l|i|l:J- Illtl § j E h ! 2 illlllllllH^ ! c 8 j eg If g I ! ! I </seg>
            <seg id="p039">3 ,2 - - l-^i^i-l(O I ; i ~ ! oisssnx § i •! « ooioiooa « ■*■ « ■f oo NOHt- O ccoao 8 ' s IU w § — r *§! i ll ■ O&lt;-lC-&gt;O00 'Hdnooo «»&lt;-&gt; O0 g : : :J 2 : : :l ■ «; : t- o so ro oo tooiocoa § i 5 • BOHMOl XNOhO t-^oTocT cT fH t-H i :S^-^ : lilt I •a- 2 ! : ■g Si b Hill M '■ °* * I 1 : ■g Si b liill 1 Si ii i I* * m o :=3 ; § ! ijf i | ftl iii 111? J </seg>
            <seg id="p040">38 General expenses (Benefiting all departments) Advertising rrmitory (for women) Assistance Supplies and equipment 9,041 73 Fuel, light, power and water Furniture and fixtures 60,987 16 10,355 96 Incidentals (all expenses not otherwise classified) rnitor's supplies (brooms, brushes, floor sweeping and finish - ing compounds, toilet paper, towels, soaps, etc.) 19,506 88 Erturers and speakers (services and expenses) blications (catalogs, bulletins, journals and studies) nting and postage (cards, blanks, programs printed station ery and postal supplies) •ss; Regents' expenses (traveling in discharge of duties) Repairs and up-keep (repairs of property and up-keep of grounds 31,893 04 tcial services (legal, expert accountants, sanitary expert) tioner's and office supplies 947 45 5,470 86 4,483 91 Kegraph, telephone and messenger service It books (for sale to students) 31,069 98 SIS Traveling expenses (University officials, delegates) Redemptions (2d year only) — fees returned to students ■ experimental srr.sTATioNS (Maintenance) orth Platte Salaries, regular service Labor 8,101 65 6,268 14 Other expenditures (supplies and equipment) Scottsbluff (2d year only) 19,945 46 Salaries, regular services, supplies, equipment and labor Valentine (2d year only) 1,972 38 Salaries, regular services, supplies, labor and equipment 5,608 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">39 Land and permanent improvements rind purchased (for drill ground, farm use and medical college site in Omaha) 59,650 00 78,155 42 Engineering building (completion of) riuipment of engineering building (heavy machinery placed on foundations) 49,139 17 5,909 60 3,712 03 Veterinary building (completion of ) . . Special equipment of other buildings Permanent improvements At North Platte substation At Scottsbluff substation At Valentine substation Other permanent improvements Heating and power equipment New plant houses Shops, sheds . Steer feeding plant Water plant (on farm) Walks, drives and minor improvements :al activities Corn exposition i Lincoln, January, 1909 Farmers' institutes Superintendent and clerk, salary Lecturers, services and traveling expenses Supplies and apparatus Hog cholera investigation ramp fever investigation (first year only) berculosis (hogs) investigating i first year only </seg>
            <seg id="p042">40 Snowing the condition of all university funds on November 30, 1910 The temporary university fund (Mill Tax Account) Balance, November 30, 1908, of regents' apportionments from mill tax of 1907 and 1908 (salaries, current expenses, farm departments, farm and city cam pus improvements) $193,828 11 Additional apportionments by regents, December 1, 1908, to March 31, 1909, inclusive 7,734 42 Regents apportionments from mill tax of 1909 (95%, all apportioned) 379,036 47 Regents' apportionments from mill tax of 1910 (95%, $391, - 531.63) 356,818 53 Legislative appropriation 1909, from prior delinquent taxes . . 30,000 00 Legislative appropriation 1909, additional to 95% of mill tax for 1909 and 1910 (for two new substations) 20,000 00 $987,417 53 r:penditures for the two years ended November 30, 1910 (see statements No. 1 and 2) 806,194 94 Balance, regents' apportionments unexpended Nov. 30, '10. $181,222 59 The temporary university fund (Endowm't Income Account) Balance, November 30, 1908, of regents' apportionment of income for 1907 and 1908, from endowment lands and funds $28,460 23 Regents' apportionment of same for 1909 and 1910 73,000 00 $101,460 23 Expenditures for the two years ended November 30, 1910 salaries only (see statement No. 1) 80,085 23 Balance, regents' apportionment unexpended Nov. 30, 1910 . . $21,375 00 Thb "morrill" fund (United States) Balance, November 30, 1908, in state treasury, of install - ment for the two years ended June 30, 1909 $26,850 00 Installments for the two years ending June 30, 1911 85,000 00 $111,850 00 rcpenditures for the two years ended November 30, 1910, salaries only (see statement No. 1) 79,700 00 r dance, unexpended November 30, 1910 (Congressional appropriation) $32,150 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">41 1 1^^ Tr \ me i"^_y j 1^1 ■ ir a^f 1 1 qji xu iT^s^^5 1 1 jf i vi ntifcS a^i s?y m i u^?r * a i^ a^* The AGRicuLTimAL experiment station fund (United States) r dance, November 30, 1908, Congressional appropriations (Adams and Hatch bills) for the two years ended June 30, 1909 19,349 92 Congressional appropriations (Adams and Hatch bills) for the two years ending June 30, 1911 58,000 00 The university cash fund Balance, November 30, 1908, in state treasury $45,449 34 Paid to state treasurer by the secretary of the board of regents for the two years ended November 30, 1910 236,892 34 $282341 68 Expenditures for the two years ended November 30, 1910 (see statements No. 1 and 2) 222,456 52 Balance, unexpended on November 30, 1910 ($13,800.00 now unapportioned) $59,885 16 $77,349 92 Ixpenditures (under Adams act) for the two years ended November 30, 1910 (see state- ments No. 1 and 2) $26,333 12 Ixpenditures (under Hatch act) for the two years ended November 30, 1910 (see state- ments No. 1 and 2) 30,206 03 56,539 15 balance of Congressional appropriations unexpended on November 30, 1910 $20,810 77 (Adams, $9,815.40. Hatch, $10,995.37) </seg>
            <seg id="p044">42 STATEMENT NO. 3— Continued Showing the condition of all university funds on November 30, 1910 The state general fund Balances, November 30, 1908, of legislative appropriations of 1907, for the university: Engineering building Farmers' institutes. . $9,783 24 6,754 62 Swamp fever investigations (horses) Tuberculosis investigations (hogs) . . £2 rslative appropriations of 1909, for the university Farmers' institutes Hog cholera investigations Land and permanent improvements North Platte Substation 20,000 00 5,000 00 120,000 00 25,000 00 $187,671 42 Expenditures for the two years ended November 30, 1910, for the several purposes named above (see statements No. 1 and 2) 182,289 74 Balance, unexpended on November 30, 1910 $5,381 68 (Farmers' institutes, $4,866.75. Hog cholera, $514.93. BALANCE SUMMARY Temporary university fund Balance, mill tax account as above $181,222 59 21,375 00 32,150 00 20,810 77 Balance, endowment income account as above Morrill fund, balance as above - Agricultural Experiment Station fund, balance as above University Cash fund, balance as above 59,885 16 State General fund, balance as above $320,825 08 Deduct University Cash fund item (State Treasurer's accounts) unapportioned by regents on November 30, 1910, as above 13,800 00 Total regents' apportionments (all funds), unexpended November 30,1910 $307,025 08 To the above total of $320,825 08 Add amount of mill tax unapportioned by regents, Nov. 30, 1910 34,713 10 Total balance in State Treasurer's accounts, appropriations ap - portioned and unapportioned, November 30, 1910 $355,538 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">43 STATEMENT NO. 4— CASH Receipts and disbursements by the secretary of the board of regents for the two years ended November 30,1910 Receipts Balance, November 30, 1908 $4,245 45 Agriculture, school of, incidental fees 4,592 00 Animal husbandry, department sales 9,201 28 Animal pathology, department sales 635 94 Certificate fees (teachers and others i 474 00 Crop agronomy, department sales . . 2,362 15 Dairy husbandry, department sales 19,262 25 Diploma fees 3,885 00 Dormitory (women), board and lodging charges 10,786 70 Drill grounds, sales of old houses 2,560 00 Examination fees (general colleges) 104 00 Farm, department sales 1,908 41 Fine arts tuition fees 2,995 75 Forestry, department sales. 268 00 High school (teachers' college), tuitions 3,590 50 Horticulture, department sales 265 91 Incidental fees (general colleges: 22,299 00 Laboratory fees 41,670 79 Law college fees (tuition and special 17,398 00 Library fees 3,417 00 Locker rentals 817 05 Matriculation fees 13,630 00 Medical college, tuition fees (at Lincoln 4,770 00 riscellaneous — botanical high school supplies $510.74, library penalties and losses $343.45, stenographic bureau service $217.80, freight refund $138.00, sundry items unclassified $1,830.34 3,040 33 Museum (C. H. Morrill donation for specimens 1,000 00 Non-residents of the state, tuition fees Pharmacy, school of, tuition fees Registration fees (general colleges) Rentals (use of buildings and grounds) Substation (North Platte\ live stock sales Summer school, tuition fees l!347 65 591 00 510 90 20,918 64 4,789 00 Teachers' bureau, registrations Text books, sales to students. . . University extension, tuition fees ions 152 90 ts. 35,471 35 n fees 1,538 11 Disburse menta Fees redeemed by students I. . . . $1,152 68 rid to the state treasurer by the secretary of the board of regents, for the university cash fund 236,892 34 Balance, November 30, 1910 4,284 04 $242,329 06 $242,329 06 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">44 STATEMENT NO. 4 — CASH— Continued SUMMARY Student fees: Diploma, incidental, library, matriculation, tuition and other general fees named above . . $87,251 01 Laboratory fees 41,670 79 128,921 80 Other collections: All items named above except student fees 109,161 81 $238,083 61 Balance, November 30, 1908 4,245 45 $242,329 06 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">45 STATEMENT NO. 5-CONSOLIDATED Showing total available resources of the two years ending March 31, 1911;* the regents' apportionments therefrom; total expenditures from April 1, 1909, to and including November 30, 1910; and apportion - ments balance unexpended at close of business on November 30, 1910. Resources Temporary university fund (Mill Tax Account) 95% of mill tax for 1909 $379,036 47 95% of mill tax for 1910 391,531 63 Special appropriation of prior delinquent tax 30,000 00 Special appropriation for substations, additional to 95% of the mill tax of 1909 and 1910 20,000 00 Total available from mill tax resource $820,568 10 Income from endowment lands and permanent funds .... 73,000 00 Total temporary university fund resource $893,568 10 MORRILL FUND (United States), for 2 years ending June 30, '11 . . 85,000 00 Exper. station fund (U. S.), for 2 years ending June 30, '11. 58,000 00 University cash fund (fees and other cash receipts) 232,018 45 State general fund (special legislative appropriations of 1900, see statement No. 3) 170,000 00 Total available resources $1,438,586 85 Apportionments By the board of regents, from Temporary university fund (Mill tax account), for salaries $506,000.00, current expenses $209,661.43, permanent improve - ments $50,193.57, substations $20,000.00, total $785,855 00 Endowment income account (salaries). . 73,000 00 orrill fund (U. S.), salaries 85,000 00 Experiment station fund (U. S.), for sal- karies $33,065.00, other purposes $24,935.00 . 58,000 00 ate general fund (see statement No. 3) . . 170,000 00 University cash fund 218,218 45 1,390,073 45 Unapportioned November 30, 1910 (mill tax $34,713.10, university cash $13,800.00) $48,513 10 Total apportionments by regents, as above $1,390,073 45 Total expenditures from the same to November 30, 1910 1,083,048 25 Total apportionments balance unexpended on Nov. 30, 1910 . . $307,025 20 •The balances in the several funds on November 30, 1908, from the </seg>
            <seg id="p048">46 preceding bienni urn's resources (shown in statement No. 3), were exhausted within the first few months beginning December 1, 1908. They are ex - cluded from this statement except in the case of the university cash fund, which has had a continuous credit balance. The above statement is designed to show, separately, the amount and application of funds made available for university support by legislation of 1909, with special reference to the mill tax resource of the years 1909 and 1910. The period for which legislative appropriations are made ends March 31. The state fiscal year ends Novem - ber 30. The fiscal year for United States appropriations ends June 30. It is obviously impracticable to make a single statement, in brief form, synch - ronous in all items for all funds. The balance shown above of $307,025.20 is the residue of regents' apportionments from all funds, accruing in the current legislative biennium only, for support of the university from November 30, 1910, to March 31, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">47 STATEMENT NO. 6 — STATISTICAL YEAR 1908-9 YEAR 1909-10 TWO DEPARTMENTS Agriculture, school of •Agricultural botany •Agricultural chemistry •Agricultural engineering .... 'Animal husbandry 49 •Animal pathology •Crop agronomy •Dairy husbandry 8 'Home economics 114 •Horticulture 20 •Soil agronomy 51 American history 436 Anatomy (includ. in medical) Applied mechanics 451 Astronomy 121 Bacteriology and pathology. . 22 Botany 336 Chemistry 668 Civil engineering 266 Education 170 Education, agricultural Education, secondary Educational theory and pract . 40 Educational psychology 78 Electrical engineering . 177 English language and lit 565 Entomology 32 European history 156 Fine arts 73 G*on»phy 214 •The figures opposite are college course registrations only. These departments are entitled to distribution among them of 4484 registrations by students in the school of agriculture. See explanatory foot note on following page. 1st sem. 2d sem. \ 1st sem. 2d sem. I 49 8' 114 20 51 590 "4" 2 33 12 28 17 146 12 7 4 2 21 67 68 10 161 26 48 531 6 7 16 33 4 32 139 18 436 422 435 506 u. 451 121 22 336 668 266 170 40 78 177 565 32 155 73 51 214 300 185 45 304 516 261 185 11 97 112 237 584 25 115 122 33 170 392 157 32 365 733 350 280 20 62 44 191 691 21 181 80 56 161 294 191 37 312 586 245 225 10 75 49 228 628 21 135 84 28 214 1" 1,317 2,503 1,122 860 21 20 274 283 833 2,468 99 586 i </seg>
            <seg id="p050">48 STATEMENT NO. 6— STATISTICAI^-Continued Registration statistics for the two school years ended August, 1! ended August, 1910 Total, course registrations II to difficulty of securing exact figures, the numbers placed &gt;oeite the school of agriculture, the college of law, the college nedicine, the school of music and the summer school represent individual students only, attending those departments. To ng them conservatively to the registration basis (by courses) whole number 3,760 should be multiplied by 4 and added above m Total of unrepeated names (students) 1908-9 3,611 Total of unrepeated names (students) 1909-10 3,992 7,603 908-9 YEAR 1 &gt;09-10 TWO 2d aem. total DEPARTMENTS lstsem. 2d sem. 1st sem. Total brot forward Germanic languages 205 688 126 148 572 116 105 751 133 35 650 158 4 Greek Histology and embryology (included with zoology) Jurisprudence and public law . Law college Mathematics Mechanical engineering Medical college (Omaha in- Military science Music (affiliated school) Philosophy Pharmacy and pharmacology. Physical education Physics Physiology ■. . Political economy Political science and sociology Rhetoric Roman history and literature. Romance languages Slavonic languages Summer school University extension 250 506 288 "Hi" 322 31 683 399 61 156 378 898 289 274 34 142 185 435 311 167 383 560 319 25 678 300 48 253 568 687 239 233 41 345 57 227 184 ' 491 325 483 374 54 677 375 78 166 490 I 1,134 313 347 53 i68 138 192 419 372 197 451 654 345 81 707 306 55 213 602 1,019 277 326 65 399 225 195 I I 1,734 1,214 1,360 191 2,745 1,380 272 788 2,038 3,738 1,118 1,180 193 8 204 - </seg>
            <seg id="p051">49 Instructional, administrative and all other services, November 30, 1910 Number Maximum Minimum Average TITLES Instructional Salary Salary Salary Deans eans 7 $3,000 $3,000 Acting 1 $2,600 2,600 Associate 1 1,000 1,000 $3,000 1 1 1,000 1,000 Head professors IS 2,500 2,300 2,361 Professors 36 2,400 1,500 1,968 ♦3 1,000 500 Associate professors 11 1,600 1,200 1,491 *1 200 Assistant professors IS 1,500 1,100 1,335 •1 100 Adjunct professors 26 1,300 1,000 1,176 •9 800 600 Instructors 36 1,200 500 *3 400 250 Assistant instructors 1 450 Assistants 43 850 50 317 Fellows 18 400 100 278 Scholars 12 250 100 156 2 200 150 183 235 Assistance — laboratory and other helpers, paid by the hour — ap - proximately 98 Total instructional 333 *These are not included in the averages. They are cases where a part only of the person's time is given to university service. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">50 CLASSIFIED SUMMARY OF UNIVERSITY EMPLOYEES Continued TITLE NUMBER SALARY Administration Chancellor 1 $6,000 Secretary Board of Regents 1 2,500 Assistant Secretary 1 1,800 Purchasing Agent I 1 1,800 Director University Extension 1 2,000 Inspector Accredited Schools. I 1 2,000 Assistant Inspector Accredited Schools 1 1,200 Superintendent Construction, etc 1 1,800 Assistant Superintendent Construction, etc 1 1,300 Assistant Superintendent Construction, etc 1 1,100 Adviser to Women 1 1,200 Registrar 1 1,600 Librarian 1 2,200 Assistant Librarian 1 1,100 Superintendent North Platte Station 1 2,200 Assistant Superintendent North Platte Station 1 500 Superintendent North Platte Station Superintendent Valentine Station 1 1,320 Superintendent Farmers' Institutes 1 1,600 Landscape Gardener 1 1,380 Farm Superintendent 1 1,000 Engineer Heating Plant 1 1,320 Assistant Engineer 1 1,080 Assistant Engineers 2 840 Assistant Curator Museum 1 900 Mechanics 6 av. 840 Gardeners 2 600 Firemen, Heating Plant 7 av. 600 Janitors and Watchmen 28 av. 684 Office and Library Assistants 24 1 av. 608 Stenographers 10 av. 606 Foremen, herdsmen, stablemen, dairymen; teamsters, Office Assistants, paid by hour, approximately 15 av. 250 Assistant Janitors, paid by hour, approximately "" 13 av. 150 Administration 148 Instruction 333 Total employees 481 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">51 $1,432,310 00 PROPERTY SCHEDULE REAL ESTATE ■located under act of Congress of 1862 for agricultural Value liege endowment, 90,000 acres at constitutional minimum of $7.00 $630,000 00 ■located under enabling act of Congress of 1864 for state niversity endowment 46,080 acres at constitutional mini- mum of $7.00 322,560 00 These lands are under the management and control of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. The proceeds (principal) from sales constitute the permanent endowment funds. Lease, rentals, interest on sale contracts and interest on permanent fund investments are paid to the state treasurer for the temporary - fund. A quantity of the land has been already deeded to pur - chasers and what remains is practically all under contracts of lease or sale. On Nov. 30, 1910, the permanent endowment funds had reached a total of $690,234.61, all bearing interest at about 4%. Until the lands are entirely converted into an interest bearing fund it is most convenient to retain them in the above form on this brief property schedule. P blocks of ground, 11.9 acres, reserved 1867 in the original own site of Lincoln for a university campus. Estimated Lots 4, 5 and 6, block 26, original plat of the city of Lincoln, site of the Temple, obtained in 1903. Cost $5,300.00. Esti- Kll, city of Lincoln. Purchased 1905-9 for drill ground d athletic field. Cost 41,000 00 College and experiment station farm, 320 acres, bought in 1874, three miles northeast from center of the city of Lincoln. Cost $22,000.00. Estimated value 200,000 00 Etnan tract." Four acres in township 10, range 7, Lan - ter County, south of Holdrege street, adjacent to Uni - sity farm: Purchased 1909. Cost 3,750 00 ■mental substation farm four miles south of the city of orth Platte, Nebraska, 1,920 acres. Title obtained in &gt;04. Cost with improvements $16,000.00 (partly donated). Estimated value 60,000 00 ■al college campus at Omaha. Lots 16 to 21, inclusive, lock 2, Potter's addition; lots 1, 2 and 3, Leavenworth errace addition; Mocks 2 and 3, Ralph Place addition. Valentine experimental substation farm. Forty acres of land adjacent to the town of Valentine, Nebr., donated by citizens of Cherry County, as a site for the farm buildings. Estimated value 1,000 00 1,040 acres adjacent to Valentine, Nebr., held under perpetual lease from the United States Government, conditioned on use for experimental use. value 150,000 00 mated value 14,000 00 Cost 20,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">52 o LJ IljiJl^i Cjo Kjrs (_ 1 1 1 OAAlx US University hall — old central building— city campus. Common Present brick, native sandstone foundation and trimmings, slate Value roof. Built 1870. Foundation replaced — north wing re - modeled. Cost $140,000— depreciation, 40 years, $100,000 — estimated present value 40,000 00 E stratum hall — city campus. Common brick, terra cotta nmings, temporary metal roof. Built 1905-6. Cost i,000 — depreciation, 4 years, $1,400. Estimated present ue 33,600 00 The Temple — city campus extension. Omaha dark iron spot pressed brick, Bedford limestone trimmings and exterior basement walls, tile roof. Built 1906-7. Cost $95,000 (donated). Basement finished 1908, $6,000. Total cost $101,000— depreciation, 2 years, $2,020. Estimated present E building— city campus. St. Louis pressed brick, red idstone trimmings, slate roof, fire proof book rooms, ilt 1891-5. Cost, with fixed tables, $110,500—de - ciation, 15 years, $16,575. Estimated present value. . . . 93,925 00 ■laboratory of physics— city campus. Omaha grey pressed ick, terra cotta trimmings, slate roof. Built 1904-5. Cost ith fixed tables and cases, $75,000 — depreciation, 5 years, ,750. Estimated present value 71,250 00 Chemical laboratory — city campus. St. Louis pressed brick — limestone foundation and trimmings — slate roof. Built 1895. Cost, with laboratory tables and other fixed working equipment, $40,000. Remodeled 1904, $21,250—depreci - ation, 25 years, $22,969. Estimated present value 38,281 00 Nebraska hall— general science building — city campus. Common brick, sandstone foundation and trimmings, slate roof. Built 1887-8. Cost $41,000— remodeled, 1908, $6,000—de - preciation, 22 years, $25,850. Estimated present value. . 21,150 00 B memorial hall— armory and men's gymnasium — city cam - is. Common brick, sandstone foundation and trimmings, ite roof. Built 1887-8. Cost $25,000- : -depreciation, 22 are, $5,500. Estimated present value 19,500 00 Memorial hall annex (to Grant Memorial Hall) auditorium and women's gymnasium — city campus. Common brick, sand - stone trimmings, slate roof . Built 1899-1900. Cost $30,000 — depreciation, 10 years, $3,000. Estimated present value. . 27,000 00 Museum building (one wing) — city campus. Common brick, sandstone trimmings, slate roof, fireproof construction. Built 1906. Cost, with display cases, electric elevator, and laboratory tables, $50,000 — depreciation, 4 years, $2,000. Estimated present value 48,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">53 PROPERTY SCHEDULE— Continued BUILDINGS ON CITY CAMPUS— Continued Estimated Ec Arts Hall (north wing) — city campus. Chipped Present mon brick and Omaha red pressed brick, sandstone Value mings, slate roof. Built 1897-8. Cost $30,000 — de- preciation, 12 years, $3,600. Estimated present value $26,400 00 (Damaged by fire November 12, 1910. Estimated loss $10,000. In process of repair.) Bering building — city campus. Lincoln iron spot pressed ick terra cotta trimmings, steel and re-inforced concrete nstruction, tile roof, copper cornice. Builtl908-9. Cost... 115,000 00 Strical laboratory and carpenter shop — city campus. Chipped brick veneer, shingle and metal roof. Built 1893-5. Cost $10,000. Depreciation, 15 years, $3,000. Estimated pres- ent value 7,000 00 Boiler house and stack — city campus. Common brick, sand- stone foundation and trimmings, slate roof. Built 1887-8. Cost $27,000— engine room added in 1906, $3,000. De- preciation, 22 years, $9,900. Estimated present value 20,100 00 Greenhouse — city campus. Wooden frame — built 1890-1. Cost $1,000. Razed, 1909. Greenhouses — city campus. Steel frame. Built, 1909. Cost. . 4,800 00 Carpenter shop — city campus. Wood, shingle roof. Built about 1896. Sold 1910. Foundry — city campus. Wood, metal roof. Built about 1898. Estimated present value 700 00 Observatory — city campus. Stucco exterior, shingle roof. Built about 1896. Remodeled 1909. Estimated present value 600 00 $666,286 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">54 PROPERTY SCHEDULE— Continued IMPROVEMENTS OTHER THAN BUILDINGS ON CITY CAMPUS Estimated Equipment boiler house — city campus. Heating and power Present boilers (nine), with settings and steam, water and smoke Value connections; stokers, engine, fan, pumps, air conduits, valves and piping in boiler house. Installed 1889 and 1894 ($27,500), added to in 1905-6 ($5,500), and 1910 (boiler and stokers, $8,800). Estimated present value $32,000 00 K equipment — in library building. Old book stacks, shelv - and cases. Estimated present value $1,000. Two story 1 book stacks and cases, 1908, cost $6,000 7,000 00 Ennels — city campus — with steam, water and gas supply ss, pipe covering; hydrants. Built 1895 and 1904 ($28, - i) and added to in 1906 ($1,500). Estimated present ue 25,000 00 Electric light and power equipment — city campus. 100 K. W. generator and engine, transformers, motors, switch board and wiring. Installed 1907-8 ($4,000). 400 H. P. Corliss engine and 300 K. W. generator, connected, new switch board and piping, installed 1910 ($13,000). Estimated present value 16,800 00 Sewers, connecting buildings on city campus with city sewer system. Estimated present value 900 00 K paving around city campus. Brick, grouted. R street d 10th street repaved, and 12th street newly paved, 1906. timated present value 9,500 00 B driveways on city campus. Old driveway laid 1890-1891. stimated present value, $2,000. New driveway to Ad - inistration Hall. Brick, grouted, laid 1906. Cost $1,033. stimated present value, $1,000 3,000 00 Iron fence around city campus. Built 1889-90. Cost $14,000. Estimated present value 10,000 00 Stone and cement walks around and on city campus. Estimated present value 10,000 00 Iron railings and oak benches on city campus. Estimated value 100 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">55 BUILDINGS ON UNIVERSITY FARM Estimated Agricultural hall — school, laboratory and office building — farm Present campus. Omaha grey pressed brick, Bedford limestone and Value terra cotta trimmings, slate roof. Built 1904-5. Cost $60,000 — depreciation, 5 years, $3,000. Estimated present value 57,000 00 Ei building — home economies and women's dormitory — i campus. Omaha grey pressed brick, Bedford limestone mings, slate roof. Finished 1908. Cost, with fixed ratory tables, $64,500 — depreciation, 2 years, $1,290. Estimated present value 62,210 00 Experiment station building — farm campus. Common brick, sandstone trimmings, slate roof. Built 1899-1900. Cost $27,500 — depreciation, 10 years, $4,125. Estimated present value 20,875 00 K\ pavilion — stock and grain judging — farm campus. mmon brick, sandstone trimmings, slate roof. Built )8. Cost, $30,000 — depreciation, 2 years, $900. Esti- mated present value 29,100 00 ■iery hall and shops building — farm campus. Common ck, shingle roof. Built 1904. Cost, $10,500 — depreci - on, 6 years, $945. Estimated present value 9,055 00 Kltural building and greenhouses — farm campus. Wood, ngle roof — greenhouses, metal frame. Built 1904. Cost 500 — depreciation, 6 years, $780. Estimated present value 5,720 00 Dairy building — farm campus. Common brick, chipped veneer, shingle roof. Built 1896-7. Cost, $5,500 — depreciation, 13 years, $1,430. Estimated present value 4,070 00 Veterinary building — farm campus. Common brick, limestone trimmings, slate roof. Built 1908. Cost, $12,500 — de - preciation, 2 years, $375. Estimated present value 12,125 00 Insectory and pathological greenhouse — farm campus. Steel frame, and glass, brick foundation. Built 1907-8. Cost $3,300 — depreciation, 2 years, $66. Estimated present value 3,234 00 Plant houses — farm campus. Steel frame. Built 1909. Cost.. 2,900 00 Steer feeding plant — university farm. Hollow brick, stuccoed exterior feeding barn, with silo, steel stalls, cement floors and corrals. In process of construction. To cost 9,000 00 Farm machinery laboratory — farm campus. Frame, on brick foundation of old boiler house. (Temporary.) Built 1909. Estimated value 2,200 00 Water plant — university farm. Steel tower and tank, well and pit, electric motor, pump (old), piping, valves, and con- nections with city water main. Constructed 1909. Cost . . 5,600 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">56 PROPERTY SCHEDULE— Continued BUILDINGS ON UNIVERSITY FARM— Continued Estimated Boiler house and stack — farm campus. Common brick, lime- Present stone trimmings, slate roof, fire proof coal bunkers. Built Value 1907-8. Cost, $11,250— depreciation, 2 years, $337. Esti - mated present value 10,913 00 ■superintendent's dwelling — farm campus. Frame, shingle »of. Built 1877. Cost with improvements $4,000— de- preciation, 33 years, $2,000. Estimated present value. . . . 2,000 00 Old stone dwelling — farm campus. Built about 1870. Esti - mated present value 1,000 00 Hog barn — university farm. Wood and cement. Built 1906 Cost $2,500 — depreciation, 4 years, $500. Estimated pres- ent value 2,000 00 $253,982 00 &gt;tiry barn — university farm. Wood, shingle roof. Built 1904. Cost with silo and stock scales, $10,000— depreciation, 6 years, $1,200. Estimated present value attle barn — university farm. Wood, shingle roof, with silo. Built about 1889. Cost $3,500, remodeled 1906. Depre- ciation, 11 years, $770. Estimated present value •Id horse barn — university farm. Wood, shingle roof. Built 1877. Cost $7,500 — depreciation, 33 years, $4,950. Esti- mated present value "wo machine sheds — university farm. Wood, metal roof. Farm and farm mechanics departments. Estimated present value $8,800 00 2,230 00 2,550 00 1,500 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">57 IMPROVEMENTS OTHER THAN BUILDINGS ON UNIVERSITY FARM Estimated Equipment boiler house — farm campus. Two 350 horse power Present Atlas water tube boilers, automatic stokers, engine, fan, Value pump, water heater, piping and valves in boiler house, breeching and foundations for boilers and machinery. In - stallation finished 1908. Cost $13,500 — depreciation, 2 years, $270. Estimated present value $13,230 00 rck tunnels, boxed steam piping in trenches, brick junction pits, farm campus. Installed in part in 1903-4, added to in 1908. Estimated present value 8,000 00 Etric power transmission line from city campus to buildings on farm campus, transformers, switch board, motors. In - stalled 1908. Cost $4,700— depreciation, 2 years, $470. Estimated present value 4,230 00 Walks and drives — university farm. Cement walks, macadam drives with cement curbs. Completed 1908-9. Cost 8,000 00 Pie and horse sheds, corn crib, corrals, feeding racks, wagon and stock scales, and watering tanks adjacent to horse barn, university farm. Estimated present value 3,000 00 K sheds, corrals, feeding racks and watering tanks between iry and cattle barns, university farm. Estimated present lue 1,000 00 Three wind mills — university farm. Estimated present value . . 250 00 Sanitary sewer, connecting buildings on university farm with Salt Creek. Laid 1905-6. Cost 8,803 00 Water mains, connecting farm and its buildings with Lincoln city water system. Laid 1905-6. Cost 3,867 00 r mains, connecting buildings on university farm with gas mains of Lincoln Gas and Electric Light Co. Laid 1905-6. Cost 1,500 00 ri fencing on university farm. Approximately 1,800 rods. Cost about $1.00 per rod set. Estimated present value. . . 1,200 00 Steel culverts on university farm. 80 feet. Estimated present value 80 00 rrtable hog sheds (16), feeding racks, watering troughs and hog scales. Estimated present value 350 00 Quarantine hog houses and pens, and crematory, university farm. Estimated present value 300 00 $53,810 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">58 BUILDINGS AND IMPROVEMENTS — SUBSTATIONS NORTH PLATTE, NEBRASKA Superintendent's dwelling. Two story, eight room, wood, Present shingle roof. Built 1905, $3,500. Plumbing added 1907, Value $900. Depreciation, 5 years, $440. Estimated present value $4,060 00 Kn's dwelling. Two stories and finished attic, 11 rooms, me, shingle roof, cement block foundation. Built 1910. «t 4,40000 Herdsman's dwelling. One and a half story, six room, wood, shingle roof. Old house moved and repaired 1905. Esti - mated present value 1,200 00 Ban's cottage. One story, four room, wood. Built 1907. it $1,400 — depreciation, 3 years, $84. Estimated pres - value 1,316 00 Cattle barn. Built 1907. Cost $2,600— depreciation, 3 years, $152. Estimated present value 2,444 00 Horse barn. Built 1905. Cost $2,300 — depreciation, 5 years, $230. Estimated present value 2,070 00 ■house. Two story, wood, shingle roof. Built 1907. Cost 12,200 — depreciation, 3 years, $132. Estimated present alue 2,068 00 Machine shed. Wood, iron roof. Built 1907. Cost 500 00 Beds. Two stationary sheds and six portable. Built 1907. at $1,050 — depreciation, 3 years, $32.00. Estimated sent value 1,018 00 B cattle sheds. Four, built 1905-7. Cost $800. Destroyed y fire 1909. B service. Three cisterns, pressure tank, three wind mills, d piping to houses, barns and hog lots. Installed 1907 1,400) and 1909 ($2,100). Estimated present value 3,400 00 ■concrete cattle and hog sheds. Galvanized iron roofs, luilt 1910. Cost 1,760 00 Horse shed and granary. Built 1910. Cost 400 00 Wire fencing. Woven wire and barbed wire fencing. Estimated value 2,000 00 Chicken houses, granary and coal bin. Estimated value 600 00 Corn crib. Built 1910. Cost 400 00 Stable. Built 1910. Cost 250 00 VALENTINE, NEBRASKA Superintendent's dwelling. Cement block construction, 8 rooms. Built 1910. Cost 4,200 00 Horse barn. Cement block construction. Built 1910. Cost... 2,500 00 ■fencing. 640 rods woven wire fencing. 1,920 rods barbed .ire with posts. Cost, with labor of setting 1,400 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">59 BUILDINGS AND IMPROVEMENTS — SUBSTATIONS — Continued SCOTTSBLUFF, NEBRASKA Frame barn. Built 1910. Cost 1,000 00 Frame Machine shed. Built 1910. Cost 500 00 Wire fencing. 680 rods woven wire fencing. Cost, with setting 575 00 $38,051 00 CHATTEL PROPERTY The inventory of chattel property, corrected to November 30, 1910, including the substations at North Platte, Valentine and Scottsbluff, covers apparatus, books, chemicals, fur - niture, implements, laboratory and shop materials, live stock, machinery, tools, specimens, utensils, vehicles, and articles of every description owned and used as facilities for instruction, experimentation and special activities of the university. Its total aggregate is $549,937 00 RECAPITULATION Endowment lands and real estate $1,432,310 00 Buildings on city campus and extension 666,286 00 Improvements other than buildings on city campus 114,300 00 Buildings on farm and farm campus 253,982 00 Improvements other than buildings on farm and farm campus. . 53,810 00 Bugs and improvements on experimental substations at orth Platte, Valentine and Scottsbluff, Nebraska 38,061 00 Value of all real property $2,558,739 00 Chattel property 549,937 00 $3,108,476 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">60 TABLE OF CONTENTS Biennial Review (general) Changes in board members, faculties and employees 6 to 9 Colleges, reorganization under legislation of 1909 5 Agriculture 15 Arts and Sciences 13 Engineering 14 Graduate college 12 Law college 16 Medical college 16 Teachers college 13 &amp; 14 College campuses (city and farm), development of 19 &amp; 20 Land acquired and permanent improvements 9 Library, needs of 18 &amp; 19 Revenues and general needs 20 to 23 Special appropriations requested 23 Student attendance 10 &amp; 11 University extension 18 Financial Review 24 &amp; 25 Cash, statement for the two years ended November 30, 1910 43 &amp; 44 Estimate, of resources and usual expenditures for the two years ending March 31, 1913 26 to 30 Expenditures, general, for the two years ended November 30, 1910.31 to 33 Expenditures, by departments, for two years ended November 30, 1910 34 to 39 Funds, statement of condition on November 30, 1910 40 to 42 Funds, consolidated statement of all (current biennium only) 45 &amp; 46 Property, schedule, real and chattel 51 to 59 Reports, biennial and other, proposed change of form 26 Statistical Employees, instructional and other, classified summary 49 &amp; 60 Student registrations by courses, two years 47 &amp; 48 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>