<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SIXTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT AND BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb FOR THE YEARS 1907 AND 1908 TO THE GOVERNOR HON. GEORGE L. SHELDON</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">. &gt;1 111) SUPERINTENDENT AND BOARD OF TRUSTEES hi iiii Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb FOR THE YEARS 1907 AND 1908 * ru mi GOVERNOR HON. GEORGE L. SHELDOX </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb, Omaha, Nebr., December 1, 1908. Hon. George L. Sheldon, Governor: Dear Sir — In compliance with Sec. 12 chap. 22, of the Com - piled Statutes the Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb have the honor to transmit herewith the sixteenth biennial report of this institution, embracing the progress and work accomplished during the period ending December 1, Very respectfully, .1. O. Detweiler, John W. Steinhart, R. B. Windham. Board of Trustees. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">I.. BOARD OF TRUSTEES J. ( ). Dktwkii.k.k. Prendent. Jmo. \Y. Stkixhaht. Secretary R. H. WlNDHAM OFFICERS &lt; . K. White, M. A. Superintendent and Steward Omaha. Nebr. Nebraska City. Nebr. Plattsmouth, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">454 M A Ml AT OF TEACHERS Teacher Librarian Literarv SocieU Christian Endeavor Societj (iirls' Christian Endeavor Society Editor «&gt;f -Tli*' Nebraska Journal" Physical Culture (Girls) ical Culture (Bovs) man r \ i. ( i \&gt;-i ■•tli all. I 10th &lt;■ Grade) .1. \\ . Sowell, M. A. ('. H. Eldridqi H. 1). Drake, B. A. Knl Class (7th Grade) irth &lt; 6th Grade) H. McFarlank, B. A. Mi-- M \Kiii\ Finch Fifth Class Cird and 5th Grad&lt; OHM. ( i : rtfa &lt; il a h Grade) Third Class (5th Gra Fourth Class (4th Grade) Fifth Class (3rd Grad 2nd Grade) &lt;;. H. Putnam, B. S. Mi-- Alberta A. Regnier M u&gt;. Ida (i. RcNDEI Miss Emma I.. Anderson Mi&gt;~ Minnie M. Rupley, H. A. Mis- Edna Shomber I 1 1(1 MAIM ( OK A 1 Third Year Class Mi Anna Ii. Kikkpatbick, M. S. Mis-. M\kv N. Wuodkon FirM Year class (Beginner Miss Lillian Mamfohd I INDTSTKl \ I DEPARTMEN twing. Designing and Art iting Mh. Lloyd Blankenship Mil. C. K. Comp ■•■iitry Mk. 0. H. M&lt; Mii.lkx Mr. Samuel Goveia -making Painting Mr. J. F. Rogers Sewing Miss Willa T. Campbell .'lice Eman of Farm and Grounds culture and (iardeninp ing Mk. W. H. Chapman MlM Anna BYRNE Miss Haihel Hemvig Laundrv Mh. G. H. I'i inam Mis&gt; Marion 1-inch Mb. H. I) Dun If a. J. H. McFarland Mi-- M MfKiN Pinch Ml(. J. \V. SuWKLL Mi&gt;&gt; Marion Pinch Mk. \\ E. Sahin </seg>
            <seg id="p005">455 Nebraska [nstitute rou the Dea.p \nd Dumb Omaha. Nebh., December 1. HK)s. »The Hoard of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf Dumb has the honor to submit the following report. ■ The following table shows status of appropriations made hy Legislature for the biennium. 1907 and 1906. Appropriated Expended Balance Kry of superintendent rv of matron $36(M) (M) $:«KK).(M) $600.00 1600.00 1333.33 26667 Biries of teachers, etc ployes' wages 29000.00 22285.00 6715.00 11000.00 9223.74 177ti 28 T&lt;&gt; His Excellency, Governor George L. Sheldon: DOMESTIC DEP (■ PARTMENT Matron and Housekeeper Mi^~ Nuba &lt; &gt;. Joh s» &gt;n &lt;** Mi&gt;&gt; Audrey Holsclaw Girls' Supervisor Mi-^ Carrie .(. Wilson Girls' Supervisor, Assist ani Mi&gt;&gt; Clara .1 i:\-kn Boys' Supervisor Mrs. Aw Richards Supervisor (small) Mi» Jennie H wihki. Supervisor, Assistant Mk. \Y. I-:. Sabin Supervisor Assistant (small) M i;. Hen ri J. Porter Physician ('. C. Morison, M. D. N II rse Mrs. Clara F. Adair Engineer Mr. H. E. Glad win Assistant Engineer and Nisrhtwatch Mk. H. B. Gladwin Fireman Mr. B. M. Palmer Janitor Mr. John S to do la .-....,. Mi» Am and \ Kline 2(1 Cook : Mi^~ Albertina Kim kson Laundress Mi&gt;&gt; Helen Kinder Laundress Mrs. Nora Phillips Dining room girl Ml&gt;^ Ml N MK 0 Dining room girl Mi--&gt; Johanna Spencer House girl Mis- K\ \ S( HILTZ House girl Miss M v &gt; BELL Boon House girl Ml-&gt; 8l LVIA TROXEL TRUSTEE8 1 I REPORT </seg>
            <seg id="p006">456 Repairs and improvement mdet students $3800.00 13485.55 *314 45 300.00 244. 06 55 94 34275.00 26045 39 822 lfaintenanc&lt; I \STITUTION (ASH \&lt;V»il Nl Balance un hand from last report $279 mi Cash received since from the sale of farm products, tuition of non-resident pupil, receipts from industrial shops. etc. 229! Total $257! ■"46.61 Amount expended Balance on deposit with state treasurt 333 us ESTIMATKD EXPENDITURES Kill! BIENNICM PROM A PHI I.. l'.»0&lt;» TO KI'KII. 1, 1911. Salary of superintendent and steward $360o un Salary of matron and housekeeper 1B00 no Salary of teachers, physicians, nurse, supervisors, Btenog rapher. and all employe 4350d no Repairs and improvements 3S0M (M) Gallaudet student 300 no Maintenance 36000 &lt;M&gt; SPECIAL APPKOPKIATION tnew building to include auditorium, library, mu seum. domestic science room, hoys' study room, and dormitories S50000.00 f toxin (ordered by commissioner of Health of the City of Omaha. Nov., 1907 263 05 ing 45th Street for street car (ordered by the City of Omaha. Fall of 1907) 230.00 Cement sidewalk (ordered by the city of Omaha M:iv l!M)s </seg>
            <seg id="p007">457 SUPERINTENDENT'S REPOR1 To the Honorable Hoard of Tru Gentlemen— I have the honor to submit to you the sixteenth biennial report of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb, covering the period from December 10, l'.NKi to December 1. l'.to.x. I During this bienniaJ we have enrolled 217 pupils. Of these ) were hoys and !I7 were girls. Thirty-five new pupils have been initted since the last report. Kight have been graduated, rteen found incapable of receiving further instruction arid •refore did not return, seven removed from the state, five have her been transferred or recommended for admission to the Institute for Feeble Minded Youth at Beatrice, and one was trans - ferred to the School for the Blind at Nebraska City. This leaves our present enrollment lls. This school was founded in 1869 and since that time 769 pupils have been enrolled. Of this number 7fi have been awarded diplomas of graduation. 1 he several I counties ol tl he stale have sent pupi ile i s to tins se! to th 118 se ehool hool as follows Adams 14 Furnafl 11 11 Antelope 3 Gage 12 12 Banner 1 Gosper I I Boom 17 (ireeley 4 Buffalo 12 Hall 14 Hurt 12 Hamilton H Butler 13 Harlan •&gt; Box Butte •_&gt; Hayea 4 Boyd . . 2 Hitchcock • ) Brows 1 Holt &lt;l 16 How aril 4 «- 13 Jefferson 10 Chase 1 Johnson 8 ,-hen,v 2 Kearney 11 Cheyenne 1 1 Kno\ 11 Clay Culfax 10 Lancaster 12 Lincoln 42 I Cuming. . 9 Madison 1 8 Merrick </seg>
            <seg id="p008">s i. ■'■ </seg>
            <seg id="p009">459 Nance Daw son Deuel N'emaha Nuckolls Otoe 1 Dixon :? Dodge Pawnee Perkins Phelpa Pierce Douglas Dundv i:«» Emorc nklin k . 9 Platte •&gt; 11 Sherman Stanton Thurston Thaver El Willow hardgon •k ■ &gt; 21 1 Saline 21 Yallex Washington Wayne Sarpv 9 Kndera anl IN n Webster York Total From ot i ■ &lt; irand total The causes of deafness, as n ported by parents, are shown in the following table. Apoplexy 1 LaGrippx Brain fever 44 Lung fever. Bronchitis o Membranous croup Malaria i i rrh 13 ( atarrhal fever. 1 Measle Mumj).- 31 Cholera infantuni 4 ■&gt; Cold... 13 Paralysis Congenital 200 Pneumonia Quinsy . . . . (ramps 1 1 gestion of lung* 1 Scarlet fever Scrofula Diphtheria 11 S Dropsy of brain 1 Spasms 1 Diabetes 1 Spinal meningitis Si 1 1 a 1 t M Kail (in infant \ 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">460 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 4(&gt;0 LAND 0OMMI881 er (kind unknown) 17 r i^kind unknown) 17 Sunstroke 1 Sunstroke 1 4 4 Typhoid fever Typhoid fevei 16 t6 i hurt (in cyclone) 1 1 hurt (in cyclone) 1 Tul&gt;erculai affliction. 1 Tubercular affliction. . . 1 Whooping eougfa l'.t Inflammation of brain 2 Inflammation of brain 2 Whooping cough 19 Inflammation of ear 30 Inflammation of ear 30 Yellow fever Yellow fever 1 1 Intermittent fevci 1 Intermittent fevc; 1 Unknown 128 Total Mutes Total. 7 £ Mutes Grand total Grand total LIST OF (IKADl \TK&gt; Name &lt; lass Ell* M Rudd. IM Attended (iallaudet College two years, taught in her alma mater. Married L. A. Divine in 1K97. died in Ifl Louis A. Divine MM Graduated from Gallaudet College in taught in the Montana. Nebraska and Ten- nessee schools for the deaf. Now teaching in the Washington sohool at Vancouver. Married Belle Stout of Philadelphia, Penn. Mewart lss't Married James Cain, an ex-pupil of the Ne- braska school, who is said toliea prosperous cotton grower and a highly res|&gt;ected citizen '■ola. Oklahoma. Lucy Butterick 1880 Taught several years in her alma mater. ried Mr. Coulter, an ex-pupil of the Mi- school — fill ranchman in Redington. Nebraska. Ella Conii.-h 1X&lt;)1 Was buy-' supervisor for several years in the Colorado school. Married Alvis L. Hurt, an ex-pupil of the Kansas and Colorado schools, now engaged in the cattle bn in Venial. I'tah. Ida Kerr 1S91 Married Arthur Boat right, who is an industri- ous, frugal farmer in Osceola, Nebraska. Alfred Waugh Mil Lives in Washington, fisherman. Married an ex-pupil of the Illinois school. Edward Higgin.- ls&lt;U Made a name for himself as an artist i ifornia. Never marrietl. Killed by a train. OU B. Crawford 1891 Attended ( iallaudet College two year- several years a teacher in her alma mater. Married Lloyd Blankenship. art teacher in the Nebraska school. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Ella Ream . ls'.M Married Abraham OmJ— t, ■ graduate of the New York City School for the Deaf, ■ one of the successful, hard-working tanners of Arapahoe. Nebraska. Porter 1893 luperior at the Nebraska - He is considered one of tlie Ix'st (Uper in the land. Unmarried. LeRoy Johnson 1n!»:&lt; A tonsorial artist in Cofiage View, Nebraska- Married Amelia Miller, a former pupil of the Nebraska schools. A~;i Bealmi 18M In Montana in the cattle bu to !«■ doing well. lioirix- 18*3 Photographer in California, unmarried. Died suddenly in HHI7. - Kluge !V»:i A successful farmer in Saltillo, Xeh Marrie&lt;l Kniina I.uhii. an &lt;&gt;x-|&gt;upil of the Nebraska school. Fred Parli I8M A well-to-do farmer living in l'awne. Nebraska. After his graduation he att&lt; Kendall (Ireen school, a preparatory school, but did not enter college. Fred Beck 1889 Self-sustaining, lives in Portland, Oregon. Mar- ried Belle Fitch, an ex-pupil of the Nel school. Harry Mercer 1881 A master of the printing trade. Married Mary Donnelly of the dai &lt; ;\\. F.Mella KorU- lf'9o Attended Gallaudet College. Taught la year at her alma mater. Married I Jmies. an ex-pupil of the day school for the deaf at St. Louis, who is an employe in the St. Louis. III., postoffice. Mary Donnelly ls'.i.i Attended (lallaudet College Married Harry llercer, '93. John Flood 1895 A government employe in Washington. 1). C. Married an ex-pupil of the Missouri school. Cora Rexford 1896 Soon after graduation married B. Y. Round, a graduate of the Wisconsin school and of (iallaudet College, who ably edit paper for the hearing. Nettie Burrows 1896 Living at Ord, Nebraska, with her parents. Busy with her art work Lloyd Blankenship. . . .1897 Art instructor in his alma mater. Married Ota Crawford, a graduate of the Nebraska school. Wayne Thiernian 1897 Master carpenter in a door and w indow .sash factory in Portland. Oregon. Married Mar- garet Turner, a graduate of tin </seg>
            <seg id="p012">462 ing for his widowed mother. John Zadina An employe in ;1 packing 1 utfa Omaha. Married Jennie Prentice, an e\-|&gt;ii|&gt;il of the ool. Martin Kennealley Farming in Cnxik .ra&lt;k:i. Little known of him since hi- graduation. William Kiper 1897 I to make ;i hoimI living from poultry farming in Portland, Oregon. Marrie.; Jojr, :&lt;n ex-pupil of the OlUgoa school. Jane Ixwkhart 1 897 Mai lied John Hautnan of Omaha Nebraska a fir^t riasa i &lt; ker. Marion Hall 1897 Bertha Bauman Married an t-x pupil of the Wisconsin - ■ Hiplove in a packing houi &lt; taaa 'Brien August KolxTstfin Patrick Regan id Jenkins ol the same class I fanner in 1'latte ('enter. Nebraska Kmma Morsr Graduate from ( lallaudet ( 'otlege in 1(05, n the dapw B. A. Married l'erry Smtf a graduate of the Nebraska school. Graduate from (iallaudet CoBege in I9M receivinp a H. A. Now at home at Ha Nebraska. ktaptBf Ihhi~&lt; for her father. Married John Zadina of tin Died in 1906. Jennie Prentice 190(1 Katherine Peterson Kinploye in her alma mater upon graduation. Married Bert Kllis of ( (klahoma. an eft-pupil of the Iowa school. 1900 Mary Smrha 19&lt;i2 Spent four f% illaudet College, taught one year at her alma mater, several months at the South Dakota school when 4 forced to give up work because of ill health. Devotes much of her time to sewing and painting at her home in Milligan. Nebraska. Maude Marshall 1902 Besides with her mother at Lincoln, Nebraska, where she make- practical use of her for art work. Clara Truhlar 1902 Married a hearing man. Little is heard of her since her graduation. Ifaairr Willmao 1902 Attended Gallaudet College two years. at home in Nebraska City with her parents, keeping up her art studies. In Pitt-Jim _• i the capacity of hoMB- kt^per. \\i»rk&gt; in ■ l»&gt;\ faotory in Omaha, Nebraska, ■Mni 1 Vt^ </seg>
            <seg id="p013">463 Dean W. Smock 1902 An employe in the U. 1'. Railroad Maud Zweifel Hattie Bell Ken * 1903 A (iallaudet College graduate. Teacher in the ( Oklahoma School for the Deaf. Pern Attended (iallaudet College two years. painter by trade. Married EaM of tin- el i Frances DavU John Opfer. . . I9U Married an ex-fgpil of the Texas school. 1904 Was an employe in tut alma mater one Now fanning in K.r Richard Bingham . 1904 Works for contractor Harte, Omaha, cars ing at good \v .:. Harold Lee MM A swift and sure hand at carpentry. I at I duneil Bluffs, Iowa. Isaac Wittwer ItM A graduate from the college of barbed. Now engaged in that line at Council Bluffs, Iowa. Bert Pilsbry 1904 Fanning at l'lattsmouth, Nebr 1905 Junior at (iallaudet College Home. Lincoln. Maude E. Roath . . Anna Johns MM A (iallaudet College girl, (lave up her si to keep house for her father at Minden Nebr., after the death of her mother 1905 (irand Island, fanning with hit father Earl Haller Laura P«terson 1905 At her home in Friend, Nebr., doing work for her mother. Takes pleasure in fancy work and painting. 1905 A rising young farmer of ability Harry Myers Helen N'orthrup 1905 Finished the course at (lallaudet Coll. three iching in tin Dakota School for the Deal. 19O.&gt; Employed in the Nebraska school a year, girls' supervisor in the South Dal "1 one year. At present keeping house for her father at Sjn '""• Margaret Stilhnan 1906 Housekeeping at Miss Bamford's home, Oi El Marshall. . . Jensen es Macek... h Morehouse 1906 Assistant girls' supervisor at alma mater. 1906 Working with his father in South Omaha. 1906 Attended (iallaudet College one year edited a magazine for the deaf, named "The Silent Success,'' now working on a paper for the hearing at Da»es. Nebr Wilber Stichler 1906 Worked two it printer at Havi Nebraska, now helping his father on tin Rudolph Schupbach 1906 Works in hi- Anna Kinnier 1907 At home with \i- .vhere sh. &lt; &gt;in:ih:i, NefarMk*. 1902 Married IH-an W. Smix-k </seg>
            <seg id="p014">464 Cora Pillard H«l7 Helping her mother at bone i Hampton. N&gt;|,r. and doing art work at which she is quite exiwrt . Harry Kellner 1907 i rit i hand at Kuskin. Nebraska _-!• Thomaen l!*07 At work on his father's farm. Cedar Blurts. [ A. I&gt; Strain 1908 \~ a ion gift he received a farm of liio acres from his parents and is now M t ilU-r of the soil at Niohrara. Nebraska. Eugene 1 Ingle Htos A freshman ai (lallaudcl College. Jacob Zeilir urns [M|ia hia fatlmi iwi taxi farm al Hastings md finds time for his art work, which i~ hi- HEALTH Our location and surroundings uc conducive of good health and the general health of our pupils has been good. We had the misfortune to l&gt;e quarantined for diphtheria for three weeks in ember, 1907. the genus of the disease having been first d: - ered in the throat of a pupil who had just returned from a visit to her bome. Prompt action was taken by our school physician and the health authorities so thai no serious results followed. Wi in epidemic of whooping cough la.-t spring which was brought to the school in a similar manner. We have bean extremely fortunate in having had but three cases of serious illness during the past two years, all of which were pneumonia. Two of them were carefully nursed back to health in our own hospital and the other one. after becoming convalescent, was taken home. All have entirely recovered and are now in school. No deaths have occurred since the last report, no serious accidents have happened. and no one has been maimed or crippled in any way. tWe are in need of a room for systematic physical training. ,-iuni should l&gt;e provided and equipped to furnish regular c drill and amusement when out door sports cannot be ilged in. This could easily l&gt;e arranged in a new building ch is much needed. EDUCATION A 1. UK PA HTM E N 1 The educational instruction comprises two distinct depart - ments, viz; the manual and the oral. This plan is called the "Combined System." Kach pupil that enters our school is given a chance during his first year to learn speech and lip-reading. If sufficient prO| made to justify it, he is retained in the il talent. WMl l!«t* liwistani boy'a Miperviaor at lii- alma I </seg>
            <seg id="p015">465 department throughout his entire course. Otherwise, he ie placed in a manual elaas. In the manual department the medium of communication is finger spelling and writing. "Signs' are not not taught in any of our el The children are taught the English language and how to use it. We do not encourage the t signs, except in chapel services or at public gatherings where finger spelling, writing and lip-reading would In- too difficult. Every deaf person is happier from his knowledge of the language and we have no desire to deprive him of its use, except in the school room. About two-thirds of our pupils are in oral class* In order to meet the entrance requirements to (iallaudet College, another year of work was added to our course of study this fall. We now have ten grades, requiring an average pupil twelve years to complete. If lit satisfactorily, he will !&gt;e admitted laudet College) at Washington. I). complete the course of study there completes our course of study to the federal institution ('. anil after five years lie may and receive a bachelor's degree. &lt;.AI.l. U DET STIDEX1 Five worthy deaf young people were assisted in securing a college education by the appropriation of $/}&lt;)(). &lt;M) made two years ago. We earnestly recommend that the same amount lx&gt; appro - priated for that purpose during the coining liiennium. INDl'STHI U. DEPARTMENT As Mated in our ••School Guide for 1908-1908" published last summer, our aim is to give the deaf children of Nebraska tin possible training, mentally, morally and physically, and our methods are baaed on the following principl 1st The essence of all training is action, being able to do something .and to do it in the very l&gt;est manner. 2d The fundamental basis of all good citizenship trained intelligence which will enable The individual to earn a living and become a self-supporting nieml&gt;er of society. Accordingly, pupils old enough to l&gt;e admitted to the industrial shops are instructed in carpentry, printing, shoe-mending, painting. baking, free-hand drawing, laundering, dressmaking and fancy needle-work, anil some of the boys are given some practice in farming and gardening, but we are sadly handicapped in doing all we would like to do in the industrial department for lack of room and equipment. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">WHITE. SUPERINTENDENT </seg>
            <seg id="p017">467 UK I.1IIHAHV The small room which we call "The library" wi mly used as a make-nhifi be&lt; - miodate ton intended for that purpose, l&gt;u wo have no other. It i.- onl or twelve persons at a time \ library properly provided with books suited to thi of deaf children would be of inestimable worth. No adjunct to our institution would be of greater value and in the appropriation which is made for a new building, we recommend that the same shall include sufficient funds to equip one room for a library large enough to meet our actual needs V LA HIES It is our custom to employ teachers ami other employes under a gradually increasing scale of wages. Experience, counts for so much in teaching and caring for the deaf that even the most successful teachers in public school work are helpless among the deaf. It requires special training and several years of mingling and working with the deaf to make really successful teachers. There - fore, strictly as a business proposition, it does not pay the state to hire cheap, inexperienced teachers nor to train new ones every year. Teachers of experience and ability are sought by superin - tendents of state schools all over the country. We have been very fortunate this year in gathering a very excellent corps of instructors into the Nebraska school, but in order to keep tlrem. we must pay salaries in proportion to those paid in similar schools in other states. At the National Convention of American Instructors of the Deaf held in Ogden, Utah, last summer, the following resolution was adopted unanimously. "Whereas, The profession of Agriculture is becoming more and more a science which needs special training, and inasmuch as it fundamental importance to the welfare of this nation, and Whereas. It is apparant that the profession of agriculture with its kindred occupations is one of the very best callings for the deaf, therefore l&gt;e it Resolved-, That it is tin "f this Convention that agri - cultural instruction should )&gt;e added whenever possible to the curriculum now provided in the Schools for the Deaf, and every effort be made to impart to pupils u practical knowledge of rural occupations." i </seg>
            <seg id="p018">468 i) commissioner's hkpokt We need an extra teacher in the educational department, a teacher of domestic science, a teacher of agriculture, and a regular night watchman to guard the buildings and premises throughout the entire year. We must pay more for nearly every class of labor than we did a few years ago. In view of all the foregoing facts, we have asked for $3500.00 more for salaries for the next biennium than was appropriated two years ago. Considering the numl&gt;er of pupils in school and the number of industries taught, our scale of wages is low. The office of steward formerly carried a salary of $1200.00 a year and since his duties have been a-sumed by the superintendent this amount has been saved by the state each year. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS Considering the length of time our buildings have been en they are all in good condition. None of them has any modern in of ventilation not even the school building. No s\ whatever for ventilating the closets in the basement of the school house had been devised until September, l ( .*07. These el were thoroughly ventilated at a cost to the state of about 130.00. In the report of two years ago we find that the steps and approaches to the various entrances (which were in bad condition) were recommended to l&gt;e rebuilt of iron. Six were needed. The best bid on the cost of one, in iron, was $725.00. This was consid - ered too high and bids were taken on a plan to have them built of oak. The lowest bid was 1175.00. That l&gt;eing considered too high, the foreman of our carpenter shop d to take the measurements for materials upon which bids were taken, and with the aid of the deaf boys who are learning the carpenter's trade, the first new set of stairs was constructed at a cost to the state of $25.50. Then we proceeded in the same way with the other approaches until our carpenter boys had finished four new complete, and from the old lumber selected enough good material for the construction of the other two, which look as good as new, at a total cost for the six of about $150.00. ■ A new ice house was built by our boys at a cost which was than had actually been paid out for ice in one year. New tile flooring has been placed in the kitchen, pantry, and washing room, satisfactory adjustments of the plumbing made in this connection, needed repairs of the plumbing was </seg>
            <seg id="p019">469 dining rooms were repainted and redecorated, also the kitchen and several other rooms and dormitories, ■ general overhauling of all the rooms in alt the buildings waa made patching the plaster - ing, repainting, etc.. wherever needed. A window was placed in the bathroom on the lower floor of the hospital, a new outside stairway to the hospital has been built by our hoys so that the first and second floors can he isolated from each other in case of contagious di new cement floors were put into the bakery and laundry and a new cement sidewalk was built from the hospital to the street, and a new cement walk is now being constructed from the front (east) entrance of the main building and school house to connect with the new walk already built extending to the .street. M A I N T E X AM K We have sought to keep within the limits of our appropriation, making all expenditures with the utmost care and economy. Therefore, we do not expect to have any deficit at the end of the present biennium. Anticipating an increase in attendance and considering the increased cost of food products, coal and other materials, we have asked for an increase of 11725.00 over the amount appropriated two years ago. MANNERS AND MOKAI The school discipline is good. Pupils are taught to respect authority and are encouraged by wholesome advice from teachers and officers alike in right ways of living and nobility of character. (Jenerally our pupils respond willingly so that by kindness and firmness there is seldom need for punishment. We insist that pupils remain in the institution continuously through the school term as homegoers disturb the discipline and order of schoolroom work and endanger the whole institution to contagious dise i CHANGE IN NAME We desire to be recognized as a part of the great educational system of the state. To this end we recommend that our legal name, "Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb," l&gt;e changed to "Nebraska School for the Deaf or "State School for the Deaf." Several other states have made this change and the deaf of our ■ • would heartily appreciate it. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">r /. /. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">471 SEEDS I The legislature of two years ago recognized our need building and appropriated 135000.00 for that purpose. The ropriation. however, was vetoed by the Governor on the grounds the state should first l&gt;e out of debt, so we did noi ding that we so much need. We again ask for an appropriation a new building, which with the equipment needed will require: expenditure of $50(M)().IM). This new building should contain, vnmasiuni which could be used on special occasions fo itorium as our present chapel, for instance, is not large en teeommodste nrore than about half the people who would like ittend our commencement exercises. It should also cm n-ary. reading room, and a study room large enough to act late 125 boys, a dormitory and a museum where specimens of sorts could lw&gt; collected and exhibited and where those now have could l&gt;e properly taken care of. t\Ve need more land. Our play grounds are not large enough. • is as necessary for growing children as food. There ts of land adjoining the state grounds which may lie bought the city is fast absorbing these tracts for building pur] i it will be impossible to buy advantageously. t\Ye have leased 40 acres which joins us on the east fffl rs. This provides us with sufficient grain and provende stock. We have also rented during the past season 10 eh joins the states grounds on the south. This was use lening purposes and furnished us about 300 bushels of pot numerous other garden vegetables. We need a new fence around our premises. Next to the street on the west, it should lie something especially substantial ami permanent which would lie a credit to the state. On the other three sides, it should l&gt;e less a expensive pattern but of suf - ficient strength and durability to protect our orchard and garden! from all prospective intruders. We have asked that the amount for repairs and improvements be allowed that was granted two years ago. ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS In submitting this report of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb for the years 1907 and 1908, I wish to thank gentlemen of the Hoard of Trustees, for your wise counsel which I have frequently sought and for the honorable and business-like </seg>
            <seg id="p022">472 &gt;ils wliicli have characterised the discharge of all your duties lor the cordial support given me at all times during the short period of my connection with the management: I wish to thank all of our friends for the assistance and encouragement that they have given to our work from time to time; I wish to thank our Governor for his efforts to remove political preferment from its management and make efficiency alone I* 1 the test for a position in an educational institution of this kind: I thank the Legislature for the generous appropriations accorded us. without which nothing could have bees accomplished; I thank the Federation of Women's Clubs of Nebraska for the kindly interest that they have shown in our work: I extend niv heartiest thanks to all teachers, officer MM) employes for their faithfulness and loyalty to duty through se united efforts our school may rank with the Ix-st on the continent: I thank the parents and patrons who have given us their support in enforcing the necessary rules, and acknowledge with humility and gratitude the kind Providence whose watchful I and guidance has guarded the safety anil welfare of us all. ( . K. White, Superintendent. I.IVI OF I'IPIl.s ENROLLED DURING THK HIKNMIM 190, 1908. Age Name Residence Nativity Admitted , Peter Minden Dan- Am. . . Sept. 1807 \ndrewjeski. Frank. Elba Swed-Am. Dee. 19(K) \rnett. Harvey Hartingtun American. Sept. 1906 \nderson. Tena. Minden Dan-Am.. Sept. 1905 7 Ariderson. Klla Minden Dan-Am.. Sept. 1908 11 Anderson. Edith. . Arcadia.. Kng-Am. Oct. 1(104 12 Alexander. Bernice... Johnson. American. Oct. 1902 11 Arndt. Helena Harvard Germ- Am.. Oct. 1 ( .»()7 krndt, Frieda Harvard . Germ-Am.. Oct. 1907 If Heegle. Austin Grand Island.. American. Sept. 1896 Germ-Am. .Feb. 1899 19 Broekeineier. Frank. . Stanton. 9 Broekeineier. Kddie Stanton. Germ- Am. .Sept. 19()6 » Biasing, Charles South Omaha American ..Sept. 1897 Brown. Arthur. IMainview . Dan- Am. Sept. 1905 6 Brown. Walter l'lainview Dan- Am. Sept. 1906 19 Brown. Fred Sheridan, Wyo American. Sept. Is9s 14 Blackwell, Henry Omaha Negro Fel&gt;. 1907 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">473 lit Bender, Joe Milfonl Germ-Am. Oct. 17 Brant, Gerald Omaha American .Sept. \'2 Beers. All&gt;ert Alexandria. American. Oct. !!•(»&gt; 18 Butterbaugh Vernon Fairbury. . . American. Sept. 21 Ha.~&gt;. \c&gt;la Wilsonville. American. Sept. Jo Belgum, Guatave .Albion Nor- Am . Sept. Is Byers, George .South Omal 8 Babeock, Arc-hie North Loup South Omaha North Loup. Martinsburg. . Martinsburg. Sinithfiel'l. . . . Stamford American. Sept. Babcock, Archie American. .Sept. s I'.t Bauman, Hattie Martinsburf Baunian. Hattie 1!. ( ierni-Am. .Nov. 14 Bauman, .lessie Martinsburf 14 Baunian. Jessie ( ierm-Am. .Sept . 1904 1'.. 19 Bun. Ruia. . SmithfieW. . Burt . Kuia. . . American. Sept Hi U&gt; Burt . Mabel . Stamford Hurt. Mal&gt;el American. Oct. 1 Vt'.t 10 Birk. Cecelia. .Grand Islan 10 Birk, Cecelia Grand Island. Grand Island Albion. . Dan-Am. . Sept. 1905 1 ■"&gt; Brain. Mary Grand Islan 8 Belgum, Tena Albion Bram, Mary Hus-Am Sept. 1900 I.", s Belgum, Ten Nor-Am Oct. 12 Bohrer, Mary... . Riverton 12 Hohrer. Marv Irish-Am. .Sept. 1908 13 Brown. Margaret ('larks 7 Buinaim, Helen. . . Wausa 13 Brown. Margarei Germ-Am. Sept. 1907 Bumann, Helen. Germ- Am.. Sept. 1908 &lt; 17 Babeock, Kate North Loop 17 Babcock, Kate American. IVK&gt; 15 15 Christensen. Christian . Minden. Christenaen, Christ i Dan-Am.. Sept. 10 Chiistenseii. Harry. . Minden 10 Christenaen, Harrv Minden Omaha Hooper Fremont Benson Aurora Omaha Dan-Am. Sept. 1905 If. lf&gt; Cuscaden. Scott Omaha Cuscaden, Scott American. Sept. 1 VHi l.S 13 Cooper. Glenn Hooper Cooper, Glenn Scotch-Am Sept. 1903 20 Claussen. William. Fremont Claussen. William. Germ-Am. .Oct. IS99 20 _'(&gt; Chappell. Arthur .. Benson Chappell, Arthur . American. ( )ct. 1 VKi Id Cox. Arthur Aurora 10 Cox. Arthur American ..Ian. 1907 10 Cobb, Herold Omaha 6 Chase. Archie . Crofton Cobb, Herold American ..Ian. ';; I Chase. Archie ('line, Bessie Cowen, Klla Clawges. Alice Clark, (iladys Cummings. Marion Debus, Peter Crofton American. Oct. 1908 12 ('line, Bessie Louisville Germ- Am. .Sept. 1904 1.") Cowen, Klla Hebron American . Sept. 1902 10 Clawges, Alice . .Bridgeport . American. Oct. 1!MI4 13 Clark. Gladys Herman 8 Cuinniings. Marion ..Omaha American. Sept. 1907 Omaha American.. Sept. 1908 13 Debus, Peter Lincoln Lincoln Russian. . Feb. IDelehov, Bennie DeGrofft, Charles Day, Cliff(.rd Hi Delehoy. Bennie Blue Hill Blue Hill . Eng-Am Sept. 1WI6 I". DeGrofft, Charles Blue Hill Blue Hill American. Oct. 1899 13 Day, Cliff «tnl Fairtield American. Sept. 1904 13 Davis. Edith Lincoln B Dyer. CaMM . Loomis Lincoln American. Jan. 1902 Looniis A roeric an. Sept. 1908 in Dewitt, Kthel Dakota Citv. Dakota Citv American. Nov. IMOs </seg>
            <seg id="p024">!) COMMISSIONER'S KKl'ORT 474 14 Ellingha Hooper Gem- Am. . .Sept. Marv Lincoln America. Sept. 1908 Enters, Bertha Chapman Germ-Am.. May I'.miT 11 Fahrenholz. Arthur Norfolk Germ-Am .Sept. 1!MI4 Huhl&gt;en 21 Forell, Frank American .Sept. iv.i:&lt; 17 Fry. Eugene Omaha American . Sept. 1898 1 1 Flanagan. Francis South Omaha Irish-Am. .Jan. 1902 alk. Charles.. Omaha Bwed- Am . . Oct. 1908 17 dottier. William Rushville Swiss-Am. Sept. 1898 in Gomme, James F.ddvville Eng-Am Sept. 1905 21 Gilson. O. E. Plattsmouth American. Mch. 1 v"&gt; \'.i Ciaeth. Lvdia Fremont Germ-Am. .Oct. 1 899 American. Sept. 1900 Barking. Ralph Valley 1!» Higbv. C: Oconto American. Nov. 1 Vt."&gt; 1 1 Harri.-. ( llenn Rising City American. Sept. 1904 Hladik. Kmil Plainview Boh- Am. ...Nov. 1 898 10 Herman. Frank Walnut Germ-Am .Sept. 1905 17 Hogle. Eugene Omaha American. Nov. 1895 Swedish Sept. 1904 21 Hells-ten. Joel. . .. &lt; Mnaha 1(1 Hartz. Willie American. Sept. 1905 17 Hefner. &lt; ■ • Coleridge Germ-Am. Sept. 1900 1 1 Harris. Charier Newcastle. American. Sept. 1908 13 Hooper, Roy Odell Eng-Am. Sept. 1907 20 Hurt. Jerrv Dwight Bohemian.. Sept. 1908 7 Hawkins. I Beaver Crossing American.. Oct. I'm is Fiaurigan. !■ Fremont Irish- Am. ..Oct. I'.mis 16 Hanson. Minnie Stanton. . Swed-Am. Se]&gt;t. l'.MI4 14 Horn, (lertrude Randolph. Germ-Am. Sept. li»oi -'(I Hanel. I'auline Clarkson Boh- A in Nov. 1895 12 Henzler. Minnie Pierce Germ-Am. Sept. l*t()6 2(1 Holmes. Florence Arcadia American. Sept. 1903 Ih Holmes. Oliver Arcadia American. Sept. 1903 12 Hanehett. Bessie Omaha American. Sept. 1901 14 Hefner. Frieda . Coleridge Germ-Am. Sept. 1901 \ellie Newcastle American. Sept. HMlti 1 1 Haves. Mallei Morrill.. American. Apr. 1908 16 Isoin. \*f Eng-Am.. Feb. 1903 Concord 16 Jenkins. Claude Beavei Crossing American. . Nov. lohnson. Wilson Springfield Swed-Am. Sept. 11 Johnson. Albert.... Newcastle I- Am. .Sept. 1908 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">475 16 Jenks, Viola Fullerioo American. Sept. 1^ American. Sept. 11 Johnson, Cora O'Neill Germ-Am. Sept. 1905 9 Jensen, Mine Hampton .Dan-Am.. Sept. ( term-Am. Sept . 1905 Dan-Am.. Sept. I'.mi:&gt; 19 Kellner, Theodore. . Omaha Jewish- Am Nov. Tewish-Ani Nov. I s '.' 1 20 Kirkpatrick. Ralph. . Coleridge . American Mch. l!&gt; American Mcli. 20 Kirk pa trick. Ralp Hi Kyucl. Joseph Clarkson. Bohemian.. Jan. 1902 8 Kennedy. Alvin Minden American Sept. I IKyncl. Joseph Kennedy. Alvin Kuster. Bonnie Kreifies, Paul... Kxohn. Albert Bohemian. Jan. 1902 American .Sept. 11 Kuster. Bonnie. Hickman Germ-Am. Sept. 1904 ( term-Am. Sept. 1904 !_' Kreifles, Paul.... Pmul Germ-Am. Sept. L903 8 Krohn, Albert Wan Germ-Am. Sept. l 8 Kalina, Joe Culhertson ..Boh-Am Sept. 1907 Germ-Am. Sept. l l &gt;o:&gt; Paul Wall Germ-Am. Sept. 1907 Boh-Am Sept. 1907 13 Killham. Delia... Omaha . Irish-Am. .Sept Irish- Am... Sept. 14 Kinnier. lil-ie Spakting . Irish-Am. . .Oct . Irish- Am... Oct. 12 Kikjoyne, Catherine. South Auburn. Irish-Am... Sept. 1902 Irish-Am... Sept. 1902 19 Kuta, Btacia Columbua Aus-Am Oct. Columbus Columbus Aus-Am Oct. 1S9N 17 Kuta. Sophia Columbua .Aus-Am Oct. I \m Oct. 14 Kindred. Hattie Blair American. .Ian. Blair American. Jan. l'.'Oi 11 Kindred. Lettie... Blair American Ian. 1901 s Kindred. Helen Blair American Sept. American Jan. I'.'iM American .Sept. lit Koehler. France Lincoln Germ-Am. .Oct. 1901 Germ-Am. Oct. lMiil 10 I.ee. Fred Lincoln American.. Sept. 1905 American. Sept. 1905 13 Lamlireeht. Willie Blair Germ-Am. Sept. I Germ-Am. Sept . 1902 20 Leach, George Edgar American. Sept American. Sept. 1897 Hi Lanphear. Luke Ord American. .Ian. s Lanphear. Willie Ord American.. Nov. 1908 American. Jan. l'.'OO Lanphear, Luke American. Nov. Lanphear, Willie Ord s ■_'&lt;&gt; Lewis. Charier Waterloo American. Nov. American. Nov. 12 Larsen. Hilda Wayne Dan-Am. Sept Dan-Am. . Sept. 1903 12 Lewis. Lela Clay Center American. Sept. 1WM American. Sept. 1904 1") Lewis. Bessie. . Huskin American. Sept American. Sept. 1901 11 LaBrie. (irace Omaha American. Apr. American. Apr. 1906 14 Morter. Silas Lyont American. Jan. 1900 Ki McLane. John Florence . American. Sept. 1904 American. Sept. 1904 10 Me Lane. John Florence Norfolk. 18 Muller. August Norfolk.. German — Sept, 1903 German. . Sept . 1903 Muller. August is 24 Mura. Mike St. Iibory Bohemian.. Dec Mullin. Robert. ... Omaha American. Oct. Bohemian.. Dec. Mura. Mike St. Libory Omaha. 24 American. Oct. Mullin. Rolxrt 18 1^&gt; Macek. Jaines South Omaha . Boh-Am. .. Sept. Boh-Am. Sept. 10 McFaddan. Paul Hastings American. Sept Mayfield. Jay Neshit American. .Sept. 10(12 American. Sept. American. Sept. 1902 Irish-Am. .Nov. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">476 I.McKnight . .'■ Miles. Harvey Martin. Lueinda Menu. Lenora 20 Me Knight, Jesse .Peru American America Apr. 1.S9S 12 Miles. Harvey Omaha America Martin, Lueinda Shubert America American Oct. n»(is American Nov. l'.Mki 16 Menu. Leaora Dodge (Jenn-Ai 7 Menu. Helen Dodge (lerin-Ai (ienn-Ain Nov. 1895 7 Menu. Helen derm-Am l'.HIS Sept ■ Mitchell. Ethel Mikolajezk. Annie Myers. Ruth 11 Mitchell. Kthel Omaha America! American \WA Sept 17 Mikolajezk. Annie ... Elba Pol-Am. Pol-Am. Sept HHHi 1.") Myers, Ruth Blake America (fuller, Ernestine Norfolk Germaa. American Oct. 1899 I.Mullei. Krnestine Meyers, Mabel McGonigal, Annie Macek. Sophia 1903 Sept 16 Meyers, Mabel Arapahoe America] American 190*2 Sept 11 Mc(!onigal. Annie . Wisner Irish- An Irish-Am. Sept I'M 14 1") Macek. Sophia Smith Omaha .... Boh- Am Boli-Am Sept 11 MuhL, Katie Lincoln Russian. 11 Muhl. Katie Russian. Jan. 1906 IMichaelis. Pearl.. McMillan. Nellie Nelson. Arthur Netusil. Anton . . Newman, Harold Nystioin. Sophia Neal. Alta 12 Michaelis, PearL. Howells. . America Howells Lincoln Valley American 1903 Sept 1^ McMillan. Nellie Lincoln .Irish- An Irish-Am. Sept 19 Nelson. Arthur Valley Swed-Ai Swed-Am Dec. 1895 10 Netusil. Anton ... Omaha Boh-Am Kewman, Harold Laurel America Omaha Laurel Omaha Tobias. Mem a Boh-Am Sept I'M):. American Oct. IV. IM 21 Nvstrom. Sophia Omaha S\ved-Ai Swed-Am 1902 Sept l."&gt; Neal. Alta Tobias... America American Sept l'.tOl 14 Neve. Annie Merna America '.i &lt; KLeary, Margaret Hastings Irish- An American Apr. P. MIS Irish- Am. .Nov 1905 12 O'Connor. Delia Bloomfield Irish-An Irish-Am. Oct l'.HHi 13 Olson, Regina Herman Nor-Ain Nor-Am Dec. I'M 17 19 Patteraoa, George Primrose. America I Patterson, (ieorge Pospisil. J.ouis Pospisil, Henry Pospisil. Barney Pospisil, Ernest. Parkins. Frank Patterson, Lulu Pillard. Cora Primrose. . Plainview. . Plain view. . Plainview Prague American Nov. 1895 1.") l'ospisil. Louis Plainview.. Boh-Am Boh-Am Feb. is'.t'.i 11 1'ospisil, Hemy l'lainview. . Boh-Am Boh-Am. \WA Sept 1(1 1'ospisil. Barney 1'la.inview Boh-Am l'ospisil, Krnest. Prague . Boh-Am Boh-Am 1905 Sept Boh-Am Jan. 1006 is Parkins. Frank (iothenburg. America American l'.Hto Sept 21 Patterson, Lulu Primrose America I'illard. Cora Hampton French-. American lN'U Sept French-AmSept American. May Boh-Am. .Ian. Swed-Am. . Apr. Germ- A in. Sept .American.. Oct. American. Sept Germ- Am. Sept IParkhurst. Addie Pospisil. Olga. . . Pearson. Kllen Peterson. ]■}■ Quillin. Sanders Roberts. George Rush. Fred 12 Parkhurst. Addie South Omaha. . America 190(1 11 l'ospisil. Olga. . . Prague Boh-Am 1&lt;K)6 16 Pearson. Kllen Tekamah Swed-Ai ISMS 15 Peterson. Rosa Bennington Germ-Ai 19CK) 17 Quillin. Sanders .. (irand Island America 14 Roberts. George South Omaha . . America 1«M»4 16 Rush. Fred Minatare. . . (ierm-A 1900 1 1 Roirlit7 Frpd </seg>
            <seg id="p027">477 INSTITUTE FOR THK DEAF \\1&gt; Dl'.MH 19 Redinon. Eva ( hnalia American Oct. ls'.t'.t 14 Rutledge. Nellie Red Cloud \merican 1902 Oct. 17 Hotter. I Plattsmouth. Aus-Am ls ( .t7 Sept fi Roedcr, Irene Loomu Germ-Am Loomis Germ-Am Oct. l'.KIS 17 Saajtboff, Clans Diller Germ-Am Oilier Feb. 1901 22 Sabin, William. V... Tecumseh American Sabtn. William. E American Se|)t 1893 16 Seth, Elmer Bertrand. . Swed-Am 16 Seth, Elmer Bertram!. Swed-Am Feb. 1901 '22 Smith, Thomas Button.... American oo Smith, Thomas American 1897 Sutton Sept 20 Strain, A. I). Niobrara American. American. Sept IN'. 14 11 Stark, Harry Pierce Germ-Am Simpson, Harold . . Grand Island \merican ( lerm-Am 1905 Sept American 1907 Sepi 21 Sturgeon, Frank Fairbury. . American American 190s Sept 12 Stillahn. Johanna Syracuse Germ-Am Stillahn, Johanna 12 Syracuse ( lerm-Am Sept 1902 12 Sealer, Florence... Battle (reek. American 12 Sealer, Florence. Battle Creek American Sept 1 !»(»:{ 15 Btrobridge, Ella Norton American. 15 Strobridge, Ella Norton American. ..Sept. 1903 Columbus Swiss- Am. Sept. 1902 22 Schupbach, Hedwig. Columbus. Swiss-Am Schupbach, Hedwig Swiss- Am 1902 Sept 27 Spencer, Johanna. Omaha American. Omaha American is', tl) Sept Ill Toxwonl, ('In ■ Pender American Fender American 1X98 Sept 20 Tatum, Ralph. Bloomfield American 20 Tat urn, Ralph Bloomfield American Sept IS'. 14 ■ Treuke. Oscar Omaha Germ-Am Thomas. Lloyd South Omaha. Irish-Am. In Thayer. Orin Cheyenne, Wyo. . American !) Tesar, Fred Clarkson Boh-Am it; Treuke. Oscar (lerm-Am Oct. 1899 Thomas, l.lovd Irish- Am. 1902 Sept Thaver. Orin American is Sept 1896 Boh-Am Sept 191)6 ITer}X&gt;iining. (lieeley.. Arnold American Thomsen, Louise Cedar Bluffs Germ-Am Tikalskv, Viola. . Verdigre Boh-Am . Urbach, Conrad. ... Lincoln Germ-Am Wright, John Naper American \\ Yssels. John . Hickman Germ-Am Watehorn. Robert. Leigh Irish-Am. Wiltrout, Daniel . Wauneta. American American Jan. 1908 Germ-Am Mdi 1898 Tikalskv, Viola Verdigre Boh-Am 190S Sept IT, Urbach, Conrad Lincoln ( lerm-Am Oct. 1899 Wright, John American Xov 1895 (ierni-Ain Oct. 1902 Irish-Am. 1S94 Sept American Oct. 1899 16 Wieseman. Christie ■ Whitlock, Blanche Welch, Margaret 13 Wiltrout, Ida 16 Wieseman. Christie . .Oaeeola derm-Am lti Germ- Am Sept 1900 *Whitlock, Blanche Ong Germ- Am Welch, Margaret Omaha. Irish-Am. One ( lerm-Am Sept 1902 Omaha Irish-Am. 1894 Sept l.S Wiltrout, Ida Wauneta American Wauneta American Sept 1903 IWedmore. Kva Omaha American. Yelinek, James Plattsmouth Boh-Am. . Zeiler, Jacob Hutting! Russian. . Zabel, Walter Davkin Germ-Am, 8 Wedmore. Era 15 Yelinek, James 22 Zeiler, Jacob ... 15 Zabel, Walter. . Omaha American Sept 1906 Boh-Am. Jan. 1902 Russian. Sept 1894 (Jerm-Am 1904 Sept I ' MIS •)■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p028">1M)K\ Kortionments to Schools ropriations, 1907-8 Appropriation, estimated, 1909-10 nn for the Incurable Insane, Hasting meeting d of Public Lands A Building; : count v conte I t and rental ii mrveyiaf 1 missioner Complaints nn file iparison of interest and rental collected yearly i Concl K&lt;l lands s-old art nieiit &lt;&gt;f surveying rational lands B mated expenditures next biennium I appropriations 10 11 : Home for the Friendless, Lincoln Interest and rental -1 Itemized work of the hiennium. ute for the Deaf and Dumb. Omaha 461 Institute for the Blind. Nebraska City. 4-7 Lands sold, appraised at 20—21 Letter of Transmittal . . 4 Location of institution ami superintendent in charge 9 Nebraska Hospital for the Insane. Lincoln 131 Nebraska Institute for Feeble Minded Youth. Beatrice. . tal for Crippled Children, Lincoln 377 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford Nebraska State Hospital. Ingleside Norfolk Hospital for Insane Official roster, land office Official roster, state. 1909 11 s Kianent school fund, how secured lanent school fund, investment of [ Knpraisement lands held under leas tal and interest Rental on lease contract Recommendations lands sold s State penitentiary Soldiers' and Sailors' Home. Grand Island Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Milford s tte Industrial School. Kearney al collection.- i il rentals collected on lease contri Total interest collected on sale contract- Table securities permanent school fund Temporary school fund tl ate educational land le, work of the biennium Tpmnorarv &gt;1 fuiul aDDortionnionts » &gt;f </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>