<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0071.0003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION TWENTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT 1929</title>
               <date value="1929">1929</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION TWENTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT 1929 John C. Trouton _J state plre Marenal L. J. Butcher .... Assistant State Plre Marshal Sigrid Rasmussen 1 Secretary E. E. Hayduk ..... Deputy State Fire Marshal Thomas L. Wilson Depuiy State Fire Marshal Ray E. Eaton Deputy State Fire Marshal M. H. Mockenhaupt Deputy State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p002">York Blank Book Co., York, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">TWENTY-FIRST ANNUAL REPORT Of the STATE FIRE MARSHAL Letter of. Transmit tal To His Excellency, Arthur J. Weaver, Governor of the State of Nebraska. Your Excellency: In compliance with the law governing this department, which provides that a report of all business transacted, orders issued, and acts performed by the State Fire Marshal, his deputies and others constituting the Department he made to you annually, I take pleasure in submitting to you, this the Twenty-first Annual Report, covering the activities of this Department which you have placed under my direction. The Department has been operated in a business like manner and well within the funds at its disposal, and whatever measure of suc - cess has been obtained has been due to the courteous, loyal and united efforts of everyone connected with the Department, the volunteer fire department organizations, and the public. ■ Assistant Fire Marshal, Lynn J. Butcher; Deputies, Ed E. Hayduk, Thomas L. Wilson, Ray E. Eaton, and M. H.j Mockenhaupt, and our secretary, Miss Sigrid Rasmussen, have worked earnestly and con - sistently in an effort to reduce fire hazards, and I am pleased to re - port that their efforts in this direction have been rewarded in a very gratifying manner. Respectfully submitted,. - JOHN C. TROUTON, State Fire Marshal. Lincoln, Nebraska, January 1, 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">■ • / FIRE-PREVENTION-WEEK PROCLAMATION For many years it has been the custom to set aside a week during the autumn months to be known as Fire Prevention Week. The prin - cipal object of this week is to direct attention to the unnecessary loss caused by fire and to impress upon the public the necessity of such action as would greatly minimize future losses. That great benefit accrues from such an annual educational cam - paign is shown by the fact that there was a reduction of $6,021,052.00 in the fire losses of the United States in 1928 over those of 1927. Curing this period Nebraska reduced her fire losses approximately $400,000.00. Believing that fire prevention is a patriotic as well as economic duty of every citizen of Nebraska, I hereby proclaim October 9 to 15th, 1929, as Fire Prevention Week and urge every citizen to make a special effort to reduce fire hazards. I especially request that a por - tion of the day, Wednesday, October 9th, be devoted to fire prevention educational exercises, especially in schools. The public press, educat - ors and other civic leaders are respectfully asked to discuss the im - portance of this educational work. Concerted action on the part of all. our citizens for the elimination and prevention of fire risks will result in the saving of human lives and property. Furthermore, I respectfully direct the attention of the public to the necessity for the passage of Buch laws by the state and local sub - divisions as will conserve human life and property by a better control of explosives such as firecrackers and fireworks. Frequently in the hands of children and inexperienced persons they are a menace to the individual and the public. In testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand and seal this 27th day of September, 1929. ARTHUR J. WEAVER, j Governor. (SEAL) </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 1929 TAX Aetna Fire Insurance Company $ 684.22 Agricultural Insurance Company „ J 131.84 Allemania Fire Insurance Company . .... 4.06 Alliance Insurance Company of Phil 121.53 American Alliance Insurance Company J.... 40.51 American Auto Fire Insurance Company J 8.71 American Central Insurance Company J.... 67.35 American Druggists Fire Insurance Company .J 5.13 American Eagle Fire Insurance Company J 61.44 American Equitable Fire. Insurance J... 31.17 American Insurance Company of Newark J 362.01 American Merchants Marine Insurance Company .' 4.86 Atlas Assurance Company, Limited, of London _ 20.12 Automobile Insurance Company of Hartford ...J 65.31 Baltimore American Insurance Company L .15 Bankers and Shippers Fire Insurance Company 7.91 Boston Insurance Company 66.83 British American Assurance Company L 23.66 Buffalo Insurance Company L 30.54 Caledonian of Scotland L 78.71 California Insurance Company L 4.52 Camden Fire Insurance Association : 1 67.98 Carolina Insurance Company L 2.21 Central Manufacturers Mutual Insurance Company 10.33 Chicago Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company I 26.74 Citizens of Missouri Insurance Company .'. ...I 29.75 City of New York Insurance Company 1 44.51 Columbia Insurance Company j 1 8.74 Columbian National Fire Insurance Company ...1 .47 Commerce Insurance Company i : 9.86 Commercial Union Assurance Company :i 128.18 Commercial Union Fire Insurance Company 6.41 Commonwealth Insurance Company 113.05 Concordia Fire Insurance Company 61.43 Connecticut Fire Insurance Company , 629.04 Continental Insurance Company 384.23 County Fire" of Philadelphia 12.93 Detroit Fire and Marine Insurance Company ..: 15.87 Druggist Mutual Insurance Company J 14.62 Dubuque Fire and Marine Insurance Company J 85.10 Eagle Fire Insurance Company J 2.37 Eagle Star &amp;. British Dominions Ins. Co 1... 26.46 East and West Insurance Company J 15.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">STATE OP NEBRASKA Empire State Insurance Company „ 2.72 Employers Fire Insurance Company 85.48 Equitable Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 40.37 Eureka Security Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co :. 3.44 Farmers Fire Insurance Company 24.17 Federal Insurance Company _ 26.35 Federal Union Fire Insurance Company 20.89 Fidelity-Phenix Fire Insurance Company 430.31 Fire Association of Philadelphia 85.74 Firemen's Insurance Company 168.78 Firemen's Fund Insurance Company 95.27 First American Insurance Company 10.57 Fitchburg Mutual Fire Insurance Company 8.39 Franklin Fire Insurance Company 156.65 Franklin National Insurance Company . 13.66 General Exchange Insurance Company 141.02 General Insurance Company of America 128.55 Girard Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 54.25 Glens Falls Insurance Company 232.72 Globe &amp; Rutgers Fire Insurance Company &#132; 1,267.53. Grain Dealers National Mutual Fire Ins. Co 171.62 Granite State Fire Insurance Company 49.41 Great American Insurance Company 429.46 Great Lakes Insurance Company .4.75 Guaranty Fire Insurance Company . 40.81 Hanover Fire Insurance Company 116.86 Hardware Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 155.50 Harmonia Fire Insurance Company „ 1.88 Hartford Fire Insurance Company 763.40 Henry Clay Fire Insurance Company .., 21.30 Home Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company „ 11.84 Homeland Insurance Company of America 6.87 Home Insurance Company ; 962.90 Hudson Insurance Company ■. 28.54 Imperial Assurance Company i....'. ■ 10.90 Implement Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Co.. 28.02 Importers &amp; Exporters Insurance Company '. 40.69 Independent Fire Insurance Company 5.68 Insurance Company of North America 766.69 Insurance Company of State of Pennsylvania 37.87 Inter-Ocean Reinsurance Company . 31.39 International Insurance Company 296.11 LaSalle Fire Insurance Company ' 5.48 Law Union &amp; Rock, Ltd. Insurance Co 89.91 Liverpool-London &amp; Globe Ins. Co. 315.11 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION -. - . London Assurance Corporation 33.37 London &amp; Lancashire Insurance Company J 107.65 London &amp; Scottish Assurance Corp., Ltd ! 1.95 Lumbermen's Mutual Insurance Company J..... 5.83 Maryland Insurance Company 1 7 62 Massachusetts Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co. ...J 9.97 Mechanics Insurance Company of Philadelphia 95.50 Mechanics &amp; Traders Insurance Company _ 27.05 Mercantile Insurance Company of America 292.95 Merchants Fire Assurance Corporation i 86.58 Merchants Fire Insurance Company 35.27 Merchants Insurance Company [ 41.15 Mercury Insurance Company [.„' 37 45 Michigan Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co j. 3.45 Michigan Millers Mutual Fire Insurance [ 40.43 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Association [ 38.28 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company j 15 75 Millers National Fire Insurance Company I ,, 50.14 Mill Owners Mutual Fire Insurance Company ...1 97.05 Milwaukee Mechanics Fire Insurance Company 153.54 Minnesota Implement Mutual Fire Insurance Co. .... 53.15 Mohawk Fire Insurance Company J ] 88 National American Fire Insurance Company ...J.... 584.51 National Ben Franklin Fire Insurance Company 100.80 National Fire Insurance Company of Hartford 1 2,079.99 National Implement Mutual Insurance Company 15.75 National Liberty Fire Insurance Company ....... 124.62 National Reserve Insurance Company 33.96 National Retailers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 3l!l6 National Security Fire-insurance Company 1 450^83 National Union Fire Insurance Company 1 478 74 The Netherlands Insurance Company. j 41 45 Newark Fire Insurance Company „ 31.06 New Brunskick Fire Insurance Company 28.45 New England Fire Insurance Company 8.42 New Hampshire Fire Insurance Company 152.49 New York Underwriters Insurance Company 289.67 Niagara Fire Insurance Company , 83.42 North British &amp; Merchantile Insurance Co. Ltd 213.35 North Carolina Home Insurance Company . 9.85 Northern Assurance Company Ltd „: 47 38 North River Insurance Company . 106.48 Northwestern Fire &amp; Marine. Insurance Company :.... 72.99 Northwestern Mutual Fire Association 1 16.90 Northwestern National Fire Insurance Company 131.93 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">STATE OP NEBRASKA Norwich Union Fire Insurance Company 48.64 Occidental Insurance Company . . 76 Ohio Farmers Insurance Company 90 Ohio Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Company 48 97 Ohio Millers Mutual Insurance Company 1 82 Old Colony Insurance Company 14 77 Orient Insurance Company 141.09 Pacific Fire insurance Company ; jjj 60 Palatine Insurance Company „... 14.70 Patriotic Insurance Company of America 14.75 Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Company 142.34 Pennsylvania Millers Mutual Fire Ins. Co. 11.24 Peoples National Fire Insurance Company .15 Philadelphia Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company 53.28 Phoenix Assurance Company Ltd. of London 56.24 Phoenix Insurance Company .-. 396.67 Potomac Fire Insurance Company 68.34 Preferred Risk Fire Insurance Company 17.42 Providence Washington Fire Insurance Company 116.79 Provident Fire Insurance Company .78 Prudential of Great Britain ". 47.74 Queen Insurance Company ;.... 185.55 Reinsurance Company Salamandra 1 113.25 Reliance Insurance Company of Phil ; 8.79 Retail Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Company 105.62 Rhode Island Insurance Company 99.60 Rochester American Insurance Company 2.23 Rocky Mountain Fire Insurance Company 5.73 Royal Exchange Assurance Company 22.38 Royal Insurance Company •. 351.84 Safeguard Insurance Company . 17.75 Scottish Union &amp; National Ins. Co ■. 109.57 Security Insurance Company 188.54 Security Mutual Fire Insurance Company 18.02 Sentinel Insurance Company . '_ 8.27 Springfield Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co 742.73 Standard Fire Insurance Company 7.25 Star Insurance Company 64.76 State Assurance Company Ltd. of Liverpool 13.51 St. Paul Fire and Marine Insurance Co 669.13 Sun Insurance Company of London . 148.04 Superior Fire Insurance Company :....'... 8.96 Svea Fire &amp; Life Insurance Company Ltd. 30.67 Transcontinental Insurance Company ■ 4.78 Travelers Insurance Company 183.52 </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">STATE OP NEBRASKA EXPENSES INCURRED IN INVESTIGATION OP FIRE Temporary Services 22.50 22.50 TOTAL EXPENDITURES FOR 1929...... $21,686.99 SUMMARY OF THE ACTIVITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT Inspections made .,...■ 16,117 Orders issued 16,475 Orders complied with while inspectors were in town 7,100 Buildings demolished by order of this department 166 Buildings ordered repaired by this department...... 692 Public buildings changing doors to swing outward, (churches, hotels, schools, hospitals, lodge halls, dance halls and theaters) 139 New fire escapes installed:. Schools (Tubular 3; Spiral 10; Iron 10) 23 Apartment houses, dance halls, lodge halls and theatres IS Iron fire escapes on schools lowered to floor level and doors placed as exit to escape in place of windows 26 Schools extensively repaired 30 Moving picture theatres extensively repaired 120 Moving picture theatres closed on second floor (2) and on first floor (11) — Total i 13 Public buildings receiving extensive electrical repairs 144 Panic bar locks installed on public buildings 131 Kerosene tanks removed from store buildings .-. 685 Fires investigated : 159 Persons arrested for arson : 4 Persons convicted of arson . . 3 Persons complaint dismissed 1 Persons bound over from 1926 and cases still pending 7 CAUSES OF FIRES AS REPORTED DURING 1929 Balance •■;•■• Omaha Lincoln State Total Unknown causes 163 43 159 365 Sparks from chimney on roof 196 40 140 376 Defective chimney ' .30 3 86 119 Gasoline and kerosene stoves : 27 4 112 143 Oily rags, paint rags, and mops 9 0 5 14 Short in auto wires , 8 3 19 30 Gas stove explosions 9 3 5 IT </seg>
            <seg id="p013">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION Balance of Omaha Lincoln State' Total Oil Lamps 4 0 3 7 Overheated stoves and furnaces 61 7 75 133 Communicated .... 8 3 18 29 Defective electric wires . 36 3 63 102 Spontaneous combustion 12 5 24 41 Children and matches ■. 35 0 23 58 Cigarettes, cigars and pipes 38 8 36 82 Inflammables too near stoves 14 -3 24 41 Bonfires and burning grass :. 24 1 19 '44 Incendiary 9 0 20 29 Gasoline explosion 10 2 28 40 Hot ashes against wood 17 3 13 33 Oil burners 19 2 13 34 Lightning .'. 1 0 16 16 Stills overheating 4 0 0 4 Brooders and incubators . 3 3 4 10 Oils and greases on stoves 8 2 7 17 Starting flres with kerosene and gasoline ] 0 0 10 10 Motor back fires .*. _ 2 0 14 16 Mice and matches „ 7 0 9 16 Electric curling and flatirons , 15 2 9 26 Motion picture films „ .0 0 11 11 Fireworks 2 0 6 7 Smoking in bed 8 0 3 11 Thawing out water pipes ; * 11 3 7 21 Washing clothes with gasoline 3 2 4 9 Rubbish in basements 30 9 5 44 Careless use of matches _ „ 16 2 13 31 Miscellaneous 19 4 21 44 Total number of flres . 848 160 1,022 2,030 Less communicated flres _ i 8 "3 18 29 840 167 1,004 2,001 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 STATE OP NEBRASKA FIRE LOSSES BY COUNTIES County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Adams $129,900.00 $ 76,800.00 $ 16,217.00 Contents [. 94,950.00 54,200.00 16,240.00 Antelope ; . 43,780.00 26,700.00 12,570.00 Contents .24,650.00 13,000.00 7,280.00 Boone 51,435.00 41,385.00 7,950.00 Contents 62,777.00 50,812.00 7,735.00 Box Butte 124,700.00 81,500.00 13,559.00 Contents 86,200.00 41,100.00 12,003.00 Boyd 21,950.00. 10,000.00 16,950.00 Contents 55,800.00 9,000.00 13,300.00 Brown 9,200.00 2,500.00 3,700;00 Contents 5,000.00 6,500.00 7,700.00 Buffalo 100,200.00 67,700.00 17,955.00 Contents 54,950.00 55,050!00 16,585.00 Burt 24,800.00 17,800.00 4,605.00 Contents 32,100.00 28,800.00 2,500.00 Butler _ 79,250.00 39,950.00 22,561.00 Contents .'. 60,900.00 40,150.00 20,269.00 Cass 27,200.00 19,700.00 7,827.00 Contents .- 13,900.00 9,600.00 5,120.00 Cedar 38,240.00 30,450.00 12,064.00 Contents 13,410.00 8,100.00 1,540.00 Chase „.... 4,300.00 2,900.0a 4,300.00 Contents..... , 7,300.00 5,700.00 7,300.00 Cherry 22,300.00 15,000.00 3,490.00 Contents 10,975.00 4,500.00 1,510.00 Cheyenne 18,950.00 16,050.00 1,593.00 Contents 13,470.00 11,550.00 1,214.00 Clay 49,850.00 25,150.00 10,351.00 Contents 28,025.00 14,109.00 6,729.00 Colfax ....... 750.00 500.00 750.00 Contents 1,000.00 none . 1,000.00 Cumlng 33,300.00 19,000.00 8,645.00 Contents 16,050.00 3,600.00 9,740.00 Custer 125,800.00 80,800.00 36,357.00 Contents _r. 53,800.00 .33,240.00 3,141.00 Dakota C. 38,350.00 23,950.00 12,555.00 Contents 13,490.00 4,300.00 4,625.00 Dawes 18,500.00 5,300.00 2,650.00 Contents ■ 5,200.00 2,000.00 2,200.00 Dawson 46,850.00 34,200.00 5,785.00 Contents 38,300.00 24,995.00 ■ 5,010.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION County Value of Elders. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Cbnteni" •■'"• 26 ' 62500 5-00000 420.00 Dixon ' 6&gt;00 °- 00 1 ' 700 - 00 100.00 Contend 28.800.00 17,275.00 9,200.00 Dodge 13,450.00 8.400.00 4.840.00 ?:"^; : 249.450.00 157.950.00 32,698.00 DougtaB 133.450.00 80.150.00 21,907.00 Content's 20.130.00 16.125.00 11.455.00 PHlmore "' 2l812 °° 2 ' 00000 2 ' i92 -00 ConTe'ita • 32 - 9 25.00 18,100.00 14,825.00 FraSun 3 °' 5750 ° 2 °' 1500 ° 15 ' 497 - 00 ContentB 6&gt;07 °- 0 ° 5 ' 40000 2 &gt; 6200 ° Frontier 2&gt;3050 ° 2 ' 700 - 00 2 '185.00 Contents' 3&gt;3 ° 000 1 ' 700 - 00 1 ' 350 - 00 Furna« 4&gt;5 °°- 00 3 ' 40000 3 ' 6 °000 FUr " aS ;"V " 26,350.00 20,200.00 14,264.00 „ Contents 10.100.00 5,500.00 4,295.00 • 296,335.00 209,300.00 26,884 00 °° ntelUS " 146.675.00 | 87.500.00 18,OO6.'oO Garden „; 4.22B.00 none 345 00 Gar^ O " tent8 • ■•• 1.800.00 none i &gt;500 .00 Cont,;; a 7 ' 5000 ° 3 ' 70000 7 °0.00 „ Contents . LBBO.ffO 300.00 300 00 HaI f° ntentS : " 1.375.00 1.465.00 925.00 Hail.... .... 186,600.00 131,100.00 26,156.00 HamiT * 95.125.00 1 80,510.00 18.522.00 HamlltOn 50.700.00 30,600.00 35,630 00 Contents ,_ 20,100.00 6,500.00 7,530.00 " amn 22.900.00 19,750.00 7,995 00 Hitoh° nt l nt8 ■ M2 °- 00 5 ' 65000 3.034.00 Hlt^ COCk :- 6,025.00 4,000.00 115 00 Contents 6.050.00 5,000.00 3.005.00 HO "" 20,540.00 13,800.00 9,890 00 Contents ; 13.405.00 6.900.00 2,720 00 - Oker 1,500.00 1,000.00 60 00 Contents - 300.00 ! none none Howard...... 5,200.00 4,200.00 50.00 Contents......;..... 1.500.00 500.00 75.00 Jefferson , 99,360.00 79,480.00 7,034 00 Contents,....; 70,750.00 52,600.00 10.316.00 JOll " 8On ■ 86,250.00 '40,400.00 14.145.00 Contents 44,520.00 27.405.00 11,525.00 Ke " ney 76.160.00 1,350.00 Contents • 16.925.00 9,145.00 595.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">STATE OF NEBRASKA County Value of BIdgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Keith ,. 6,500.00 4,500.00 525.00 Contents 2,000.00 1,200.00 none Kimball - 2,500.00 1,000.00 1,250.00 Contents 1,775.00 400.00 1,575.00 Knox 41,100.00 26,500.00 14,337.00 Contents. ; 15,705.00 11,175.00 6,810.00 Lancaster 178,415.00 64,197.00 13,606.00 Contents „ 50,862.00 25,750.00 11,733.00 Llncoln 32,350.00 30,850.00 7,900.00 Contents...: 30,125.00 17,700.00 14,965.00 Madison 69,900.00 45,000.00 27,421.00 Contents 35,800.00 23,800.00 17,290.00 Merrick 98,685.00 66,750.00 6,157.00 Contents * 59,360.00 37,250.00 7,400.00 Morrill .- 26,400.00 15,550.00 16,634.00 Contents _ 32,350.00 18,700.00 18,975.00 Nance 52,550.00 31,750.00 21,938.00 Contents 82,400.00 57,600.00 60,470.00 .Nemaha , 31,600.00 . 21,800.00 3,225.00 Contents 9,550.00 8,850.00 2,070.00 Nuckolls 32,225.00 21,135.00 4,285.00 Contents..: 24,550.00 17,310.00 2,960.00 Otoe 23,500.00 14,700.00 1,938.00 Contents 10,850.00 . 6,650.00 1,015.00 Pawnee 30,700.00 22,300.00 3,270.00 Contents 14,300.00 10,750.00 1,560.00 Perklns - 10.850.00 5,200.00 1,765.00 Contents 6,575.00 4,900.00 4,651.00 PneI P a 9,500.00 6,000.00 3,125.00 Contents 5,100.00 4,100.00 1,525.00 Pierce -.- 66,190.00 46,140.00 9,404.00 Contents 55,045.00 38,260.00 5,141.00 Platte : 170,600.00 104,950.00 6,148.00 Contents ;...... _ 88,900.00 62,450.00 ; 5,578.00 Polk - 8,900.00 3,900.00 699.00 Contents 3,200.00 1,600.00 . 400.00 Red Willow _ 151,575.00 70,300.00 48,345.00 Contents.. . 354,800.00 291,300.00 38,785.00 Richardson 313,525.00 258,600.00 . 63,265.00 Contents 195,925.00 161,650.00 63,445.00 Rock 1,200.00 none 100.00 Contents 800.00 none none Sallne 48,000.00 27,400.00 27,700.00 Contents 86,585.00 48,400.00 14,328.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION County Value of Bldgs; Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. bar^ y : 12,750.00 I 8,600.00 2.358.00 contents 20,300.00 | 16,400.00 10,720.00 SaU " de " ■•» 9.0.200.00 44,500.00 19,432.00 1^ * 80,910.00 22,075.00 18.110.00 Scotts Bluff 207.150.00 192.777.00 28.749.00 q« * 138.728.00 91,438.00 15,614.00 *, " "-• 99.750.00 38,750.00 14,355.00 ,, h^° ntent8 • 62.400.00 24.063.00 7,910.00 ,, . 54.700.00 24.018.00. 11,305.00 Contents. 24,060.00 I 10,000.00 2.245.00 Mierman.... 14.100.00 10,000.00 2.640.00 «,»Z° n ; U.500.00 6.000.00 2.050.00 SU " tOn - ' 17,750.00 11.000.00 740 00 Tha^ ntentS 16.015.00 12.300.00 1.065.00 lllayer - • 30.400.00 9,250.00 13,757.00 _ Contents..... 47,160.00 32,050.00 27,925.00 nU^ StOn 79.750.00 51,450.00 10,025 00 Contents ..; 19,400.00 10,500.00 3,595.00 val ' ey • 1.500.00 700.00 75.00 Contents..... 1,000.00 700.00 34.00 Washington 22,200.00 14.700.00 7,300 00 Contents 8.300.00 5,500.00 3,950.00 yne 40,800.00 25.000.00 11 170 00 We °2T ts " — 18i4750 ° 6 ' 40000 5 - 515 '- 00 e^ Ste t r 15,200.00 9.150.00 4.500.00 Wh e e T er e S 9 ' 95000 4 - 95 0-0" 5.905.00 Wll !, eIer 3,500.00 2,000.00 500.00 YorS° enU " "" • 1 ' 5000 ° n0De "O-OO " V 251,150.00 130.000.00 22,119 00 C ° ntentS " 254,850.00 182,350.00 62.356.00 FIRE LOSS FOR 1929, VALUE, INSURANCE, AND LOSS AS REPORTED BY COUNTIES n . _. Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Out-State ? 4.677.550.00 $ 2,901327.00 $ 868,129.00 „ t - 6 . , Value of Cont. Ins. on Cont. Dam. on Cont. ° Ut " State « 3.204.739.00 $ 2.092 202.00 $ 732.730.00 n , Value of Bld 6s. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. ° maha " $24,725,070.00 $16,286 058.00 $ 533,639.00 _ • Value of Cont. Ins. on Cont. Dam. on Cont ° maha 112,234,579.00 $10,345:773.00 $ 621,378.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">STATE OF NEBRASKA \ ■Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Lincoln .$ 2,101,250.00 $ 1,626,250.00 $ 69,358.00 Value of Cont. Ins. on Cont. Bam. on Cont. Lincoln $ 925,885.00 $ 722,350.00 $ 120,632.00 Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. GRAND TOTAL $31,503,870.00 $20,713,635.00 $ 1,471,126.00 Value of Cont. Ins. on Cont. Dam. on Cont. $16,365,203.00 $13,160,325.00 $ 1,474,740.00 TOTAL DEATHS FROM FIRES Men ...; _ 19 Women jg Children ..„ 13 Total 48 CAUSES OF DEATHS Kerosene explosions ....'. .". 3 Starting fires with kerosene ; 6 Gasoline explosions .-. 7 Clothing caught fire from stoves 5 Cigarette '. _ _ _ 1 Film fire ..; . j Cleaning clothes with gasoline 1 Bon fires 1 Playing with matches . 4 Electricity 2 Fire Works 2 Dynamite ; . g Heating combustible liquids 1 Miscellaneous , g Total _ 4 g TOTAL INJURIES FROM FIRES Men ; i llt Women _ 3 5 Children 26 Total 172 CAUSES OF INJURIES Cleaning clothes with gasoline ; 8 Kerosene explosions 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">. DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 19 Starting flres with kerosene Gasoline explosions ' 12 Starting fires with gasoline ....." [ 33 Fire Works J | 2 Torpedos and dynamite caps ■ I " 6 Firemen fighting fires ----- - 41 Elecricity „. " | ; * 3 Filling kerosene lamps and stoves Heating oils ' j 9 Film fire " 1 3 Stove blaze Igniting clothing ....'......". I f Bon fires ' ■■ 1 " *» J 0 Ammonia explosion Playing with matches ...Z"""!'"Z" 3 Miscellaneous " • ;-•--• 10 Total ... ■ - 172 DEATHS FROM FIRES Alexandria— Alvin Vostrez, 4, and DonivL 2, died of burns re ceived when the mother sought to fll, the lamp while it was burning hrse n an^ .T" 103 '", ""' "*" k h»™ throughout the house and all over the occupants. (See injured.) Auburn— Mrs. Roy Brinkley, 33, died frJm burns received when cleaning clothes with gasoline that exploded! ,„ °^l ral . Clty ~ BUrnB resultln S fron &gt; explosion of a kitchen stove l Soi::rr s^v::.r h kero r caused the — - her C c^hf eW ~ MI L 8 - J6BS Dunkebur « er - s &lt;&gt;. Jas fatally burned when w:rsSn g g C a aU fowl. flre fr ° m th6 kUCUen "^ *™™ b » ™° Culbertson— Mrs. Rea Matson was burned almost to a crisp when the kerosene can exploded with which she was starting the kiSen Deshler^-Mrs. Claude Rainey and two daughters, 1 and 3 years died of burns when the gasoline cook stove exploded. a lSe e d S °an^ M t rB tf T rd&gt; 3 °' ° f burns i recel^d when she took Vrl f, \ I he basement t0 see caused the lighting sys - ?u?ea°&gt; Dg gaS WM lgnlted by the lamp flame - &lt; s * 8 *- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">STATE OF NEBRASKA Friend — Burned to death, the body of Charles Davis, 40, farmer, was found in smouldering ruins of his home. Fremont — Mrs. Vina South, colored, died of burns suffered by the explosion of kerosene which she poured on a smouldering fire in the kitchen range. (See injuries.). Grand Island — Neal Oren Thayer,' 4, was trapped in a blazing barn, while his mother, held back by the flames/watched the build - ing burn. The. boy is believed to have been playing with matches and started the lire himself. Lexington — Burns resulted in the death of Mrs. Alfred Pearson and her 2 year old daughter. The child's clothing became ignited when she came in contact with a stove, and the mother was fatally burned in attempting to extinguish the flames. McCook — Mrs. Carl D. Summers, 35, died of burns, when spraying the kitchen fire with kerosene. The can exploded. (See injured.) North Platte — Jimmie Poulos, 20 months old, died of burns re - ceived when his flimsy clothing caught fire while playing with a match. Ogallala — Jens Ker Jensen,' 23, was burned to death in a fire of unknown origin thaf destroyed his shack. Omaha — "Old Dad" Heinle Hanseri, 72, hermit and war veteran, was found burned to death in his shack on the banks of the Missouri river. Omaha — In an attempt to keep a weed and grass fire from reach - ing her house, Mrs. Josephine Prusha, 70, received fatal burns, re - sulting in her death. Omaha — Mrs. Dorcas Aitken, 43, died of burns, when her negligee caught fire from a gas stove while preparing breakfast. Omaha— Bobby Stanek, 3, died of burns received when his cloth - ing caught fire presumably from, the kitchen stove. His mother had wrapped him in flannel after greasing his chest for a cold. Omaha — Faulty piece in fireworks is thought to be the cause of the fireworks explosion, causing two deathR and partially destroying the 4 story building of Brinn &amp; Jensen, Harney Street. Harry H. Jones, general manager, of the company and Myron Jensen, 20, son of the president, were both killed, after being trapped in the blazing building. Omaha — Trapped by flames in his home, Jacob Scholting, 67, was burned to death . </seg>
            <seg id="p021">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION Omaha— Arlyene Lotus Peterson, 2%, was fatally burned when' her clothing ignited as she played with matches. (See injured.) Omaha— William Gresham, 1.4, died of burns suffered when a gasoline torch exploded spraying him with the flaming liquid. Plattsmouth— Trapped, with his clothes n flames in an air tight shaft, 35 feet below the surface of the Missouri river, John Stepp 23 received fatal burns, caused by a cigarette setting his clothes on'flre! Ravenna— Rose Hankins died of burns received when attempting to pour kerosene on the kitchen flre.causing an explosion. Scottsbluff— Roy Sugano died of burns when films caught fire that were being shown in a little church school building. No booth (See injured.) Scribner — Arthur Jackson, 40, was severely burned by a charge of 6,600 volts of electricity, causing his death Scribner— In the dynamite explosion, 6 men were killed, 5 of which were members of the Scribner fire department. (See injured.) Shubert— Miss Bertha Werner, 30, died of burns received when a can of kerosene exploded while she was pouring the oil on live coals in the kitchen range. Tekamah— Carl Rhoades. 3. and 16 months old brother, were burned to death in a fire which destroyed the Rhoades home. Upland— Mrs. Hannah Ouster died of burns received when gaso - line and wax she was preparing to put on the floor caught fire. Verdigre— Edward Chocholousek, 35, was burned to death in a fire of undetermined origin that destroyed his farm home. Western — Mrs. George P. Sawyer was burned to death in a fire which destroyed their home, resulting from defective wiring. Wilsonville— Ora Washburn, 45, died of burns he received when gasoline fumes in his cleaning establishment became ignited (See injured.) Winslde— Henry Wacker, 42, was burned to death when an oil stove into which he was pouring kerosene exploded. Wisner — Dr. J. Sievers, 33, and Miss Eunice Meyers, 21, were burned beyond recognition when the car in tarhich they were riding crashed thru a bridge railing and burst into flames. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">STATE OF NEBRASKA INJURIES FROM FIRE Alexandria — While Mrs! Will Vostrez -was filling a burning lamp, an explosion occurred, throwing burning oil on her father, and Bister', Miss Gladys Frank. (See deaths.) Alliance — Mrs. Ralph Stevens suffered severe burns when a lamp exploded. Alliance — Mrs. Gerald Estes, 27, was burned about the face when a small oil heater exploded. Amherst — Mrs. A. T. Reynolds was seriously burned when an oil stove exploded. Beatrice — Rev. William Layman, pastor of St. John's Lutheran church, suffered severe burns about the face and hands when a gas - oline lamp exploded in his home. Beatrice — Mrs. I. E. Walker burned her hands and face when a gasoline stove exploded. Beatrice — John West, a fireman, sprained his ankle at a fire, cause of fire unknown. Bellwood— Mrs. J. M. Romshek was badly burned on the right side, under the arm, and on her chin and chest, when her dress caught fire as she was burning some oil paper in the kitchen range. Her clothing was nearly all burned off her body. Blue Hill — Vernon Karsting was injured in an explosion when he threw a lighted match into a supposed empty gasoline tank. He may lose the sight of one eye. Brainard — Lucile Litty, 9, was injured on the left leg by a flre cracker. Brainard— Buford Wrede was injured on the left cheek below the eye when a bomb exploded. Bridgeport— Mrs. R. B. Strohl was severely burned about the head, neck and shoulders when a kerosene can turned over on a hot stove causing an explosion. Bridgeport — Mrs. Elmer Casson was badly burned about the face, body and hands when a quantity of linseed oil she was heating boil - ed over and ignited. Bruning— Mrs. Wm. Hasselbrings, and a son, 11 years, were badly burned on the face and arms, when a kerosene stove exploded. Cedar Bluffs — When drawing gasoline from a barrel, the lighted </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION lantern ignited fumes, slightly burning William Veck about the hands and face. Central City— Hazel Henthorn was slightly burned on hands and face while. filling the container of an oil store while the stove was lit, causing the kerosene fumes to ignite. Central City — Mr. John Orendorf was badly burned about the hands when he tried to extinguish the fire, caused when the kitchen stove exploded. His wife started the fire with kerosene. Two chil - dren were also burned. (See deaths.) Central City — Mrs. C. L. Fox was seriously burned on limbs, hands and face, when the gasoline stove exploded. Scribner — Thirty-five persons injured, 9 of which were firemen, in the dynamite explosion. (See write-up on Scribner disaster.) Crete— Joe Brabec, 50 year old volunteer fireman, will probably lose the sight of one eye as the result of a,blaze which destroyed the Crete Mills power house, due to an explosion of a blow torch. Crete — Stanley Sebek was slightly burned on hands and face when gasoline exploded with which he started a fire in the kitchen range. Dalton — Kenneth Morgan was badly injured about the head and face by the explosion of a truck motor. Dwight — Frank Patocka, Jr., had his hands severely burned when he caught hold of a live wire while at work. The wire was a worn drop-cord which was short circuited. Ellsworth — Donald DeFrance was seriously burned when fighting a prairie fire. Emerson — Mr. Edward Rohde was painfully burned while tearing the burning clothing from his wife's body, following a lamp explo - sion. Fairbury — Paul Shepherd, Orvllle Simpson and John Slater, work - men at the Fairbury Ice company, were badly burned by an ammonia explosion at the plant. Fairfleld— Mrs. T. H. Gay and her 8 year old son were slightly burned when the kitchen range exploded. Falls City — O. W. Finney and R. M. McClain suffered burns while working on the new bridge spanning the Nemaha river when a kero - sene fuel tank exploded. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">STATE OF NEBRASKA Falls City — Lila Hollens, 10, was perhaps fatally burned, when her clothing caught fire while standing near ,a heated stove. She rushed out into a high wind, and her clothing was burned from her body. Fremont — Mrs. A. C. Khineworth, mother; and Mrs. Wordell Cash, sister; were seriously burned when the kerosene lamp exploded caus - ing the death of Mrs. Vina South. Fremont — Frank Hammond, veteran Fremont newspaperman, was badly burned about the face and neck when the furnace at his home exploded, caused by an accumlation of coal gas. Grand Island — Myron Robb, Nelson, Neb., and Orville Wittwer, Red Cloud, Neb. aviation students, were killed, and Harold Wilson, Lebanon, Kansas, was badly burned, when their plane went into a tail-spin and crashed to the ground. Grand Island — Mr. Wm. Schutz had his hands and head burned in a fire. Cause unknown. Grand Island — Hans Priess, 26, farmer, suffered severe burns about the hands and face as the result of a carbide explosion. He was holding a gasoline lantern in one hand and attempted to thaw out a frozen gas valve, part of the farm lighting equipment. Gas escaping from the valve to the lantern flame caused the explosion. Havelock — Jack Bennett, 15, was burned and narrowly escaped death due to an oil heater that was left burning after he had gone to sleep, setting his bedding on fire. Hartington — When starting the furnace fire with gasoline, Harry Stockwell was severely burned. Hemingford — Marion Hayes, '26, was overcome by smoke and w . Beverely burned about the back and lower limbs, when fire broke out in his apartment, caused by an explosion of a gas stove. He was revived by firemen. Kearney — Mrs. Bertha Cornish was severely burned about the arms and face when gasoline, which she was heating for cleaning purposes, exploded. '■'... Kearney — Fred Pietgen was badly burned about the arms and face when a fire started while a tank truck was unloading gasoline at the station. The fire was caused by static, resulting from gasoline pour - ing into the tank. Kearney — B. F. Harvey was severely burned when his home was destroyed by fire. Kerosene was used to speed up the fire, causing an explosion. </seg>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION Kearney — While washing auto parts in gasoline, Lawney Stokes was badly burned, when the gasoline ignited. Lincoln — Mrs. L. G. Saunders, while lighting a gas stove, sustained painful burns about her face and arms and a deep burn on the thumb of her right hand when escaping gas in the oven exploded. Lincoln: — Wenona Fannsburg, 7, suffered very severe burns, when her clothing caught fire lighting candles. Lincoln — Dorothy Winchester, 18, accidsntly set off three small torpedoes in her dress pocket, exploding them, injuring her hand and limb. Lincoln — Dona Kabat, 4, was badly burned about the chest, abdo - men, and left arm, when her clothing caught fire from a sparkler. Her mother attempted to tear the burning tjlothing from the child's body thereby burning her hands. Lincoln — Joe Lowroy was severly burned while piloting his plane to earth with a dead motor and the machine; on fire. The plane was completely destroyed. Lincoln — Mrs. Garfleld Sedoris was burned about her left hand when some gasoline with which she was cleaning ignited. Lincoln— Peter Dittenber, 19, was injured by an explosion while soldering a can he thought was empty, but decided it must have con - tained a little gasoline. Lincoln — Claire Hull received burns when his truck caught fire, caused by defective wiring. Lincoln — John Hergenrader was severely burned on both hands following a gasoline explosion in the garage! He lit a match to see if the gas line of his truck was leaking. Lincoln — Frank Cajek suffered severe burns on both hands when trying to save his home from destruction by lire. Lincoln — R. E. Cecil sustained a severe burned left arm when he struck a broken high voltage wire. Lincoln— Andrew Biby, 23. was seriously burned about his face, arms and chest while attempting to fight a blaze which started from an overheated oil stove. Lincoln — When coal oil, with which he was lighting the kitchen stove, exploded, Frank BurgeBS was badly burned on the face and hands. Captain Henry Steffensmeyer and Charles Kidney, Junior Captain, suffered burns to their feet while carrying out furniture. </seg>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028">STATE OP NEBRASKA McCook — Miss Elizabeth Schafer received painful burns on her arms and hands, when gasoline with which she was cleaning clothing caught fire suddenly. McCook — The little Fair Boy was burned, but not seriously, when Mrs. Carl Summers started the fire in the kitchen stove with kero - sene. (See deaths.) Milford — Mrs. Helen Mundohenke, 24, was badly burned when her clothing became ignited as she attempted to remove a can of blazing varnish from the kitchen stove. Norfolk — William Kemp of Wayne and Fred Koch of Winside may each lose an eye as a result of being struck by torpedo fragments during the Fourth of July celebration. ' North Platte — Louise Winters, 12, was badly burned on the arm when an oil stove overturned. North Platte — Mrs. Sam Poulos was burned about the limbs when endeavoring to smother the flaming clothing of her 20 months old boy. (See deaths.) North Platte — Mrs. Nels Forstedt and daughter Lila were both severely burned when gasoline exploded while doing some cleaning. Omaha — Hait Kendley was burned on the lower limbs. Cause unknown. Omaha — Willis A. Buck, federal dry agent, was severely burned when a tank of gasoline exploded in a cave which he and two other agents were raiding. Forsling, in pulling Buck from the fire, was burned on the face. Omaha — Mrs. Albert Peterson suffered severe burns on both hands while rolling her 2% year old child on .the ground to extinguish the flames, which burned all the clothing from Arlyene's body. (See deaths.) Omaha — Carl Breci was severely burned when an explosion oc - curred resulting from starting a fire with kerosene. Omaha — Harold Williams, 5, was badly burned about the face and hands, when pulling out a rag that served as a cap to a gasoline tank, and unable to see what was inside, he lighted a match, resulting in an explosion that blew the bottom out of the tank. Omaha — Sam Newman, owner of a wholesale paint and wall paper concern, was saved from possible suffocation by his wife when a blow torch with which he was experimenting exploded in his hands, burn- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION ing his hands, neck and hair, stunning him, and setting fire to his store. Omaha — Miss Clara Harte was slightly burned while conducting a laboratory experiment at the Creighton medical college, when five gallons of alcohol became ignited. Omaha — Betty Jean Jespersqn, 5, stepped too close to a bonfire, which ignted her clothing, badly burning her about the back and head and her condition is said to be serious. Omaha — Mrs. H. D. Christen, suffered severe burns when her clothing caught fire from a cigar lighter, after she had refilled the lighter with a cleaning fluid. ■ Omaha — L. J. Clark was burned on the hands when he endeavored to extinguish his bed clothing which had caught fire from the flames in the fire place. Omaha — Robert Knack was burned on "the left leg and 3 other persons suffered from shock when a clothes dryer exploded at a south side cleaning plant. Omaha — Trapped by fire in her room, Miss Tillie Kapanek and her rescuer, Mrs. Arthur Irvine, were severely burned about the face and arms, and their hair was almost singed off. Fire started in the basement.. Omaha — Jack Smiley, 13, was badly burned on the face by a fire cracker thrown in front of him. Omaha — Al Smith, 32, was temporarily j blinded and suffered severe burns when a fire cracker was thrown into the car in which he was riding. Omaha — Arthur Westergard, fire commissioner, Capt. George W. Gates, Dan Bailey, Joe Nichols, Harry Hodgeton, Joe Saitta, Albert Newton, were injured while fighting the $160, 000 blaze which gutted the Sommer Grocery store at 4822 Dodge Street. Omaha — Bobby O'Keefe, 13, and Virginia Dolly, 7, were injured when Frank G. Mellinger, Jr. 9, dropped a lighted match into a glass jar filled with gunpowder, saved since July \i, resulting in an ex - plosion which caused Frank's death instantly. Omaha — H. A. Meils was burned on the face when a pan of gas - oline caught fire. Omaha — One fireman was slightly injured at a fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">STATE OP NEBRASKA Omaha— Chas. Mann was burned on the hands when grease on the stove caught on flre. Omaha — Mrs. Rosa Stein was burned on the hands when cleaning fluid ignited from the pilot light. Omaha — Fred Jepsen was burned on the right hand when flre started in the garage from an unknown cause. Ord — Playing with matches may result in the death of Clifford Worm, 6. He ran into the house with his clothing ablaze. Ord — E. O. Carlson, an employe of the Ord Cooperative Creamery, sustained very severe burns about the forehead, face and arms, when he attempted to throw some waste kerosene and water into the furnace, causing an explosion. Pawnee City — George Goldsberry received slight burns on his hands while extinguishing a blaze which resulted due to the driver of the closed coupe smoking a pipe while having his car filled with gas - oline. Potter — E. M. Nelson was seriously burned as a result of an ex - plosion of a carbide plant. His son, Allan, was slightly burned. Plattsmouth — Mrs. P. A. McClary was severely burned on the hands while attempting to throw the oil heater out of doors after it had exploded. Ravenna — Mrs. Fred Hankins, 45, was badly burned in an explo - sion of a kitchen stove. She was preparing breakfast and used kero - sene to hasten the flre. Ravenna — Henry Eckel, 15, was struck in the center of the fore - head by a torpedo, apparently thrown from the opposite side of a street, injuring his head, face and one eye. Rising City — James Van Matre, Sr., had his feet severely burned one night while extinguishing a fire of unknown origin which had broken out in the house. Scottsbluff — K. Shimado and Mrs. K. Endo suffered burns on face and arms when films caught flre in a small church school building. (See deaths.) Shelton — Ah explosion of gasoline in a service station resulted in five persons being injured, one seriously. John 1 Dally, employe, was burned seriously, and Hugh Graham of Gibbon, Fritz Williams, Shel - ton, and Mrs. John Claus and daughter of Kearney, were injured. Mrs. Claus was blown 15 feet against a pump by the blast. The women were severely burned. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION Sidney — Raymond Olbrecht, Vernon Stiverson and Fred Stockton, high school students, were severely burned when their automobile overturned into a ditch and caught fire. So. Sioux City — Fire Chief, Geo. W. Sheets, was cut on the face by flying glass while lighting a fire of unknown origin. Spalding — The 4 year old son of Mr. and Mrs. Harold Smyth was badly burned when he apparently attempted :o stir up the fire in the cook stove during his parents' absence. When they returned they found part of his clothing burned oft and hej was rushed to the hos - pital, but was not expected to live. . Spencer — Oil wagon driver- was burned on the face and hands when static spark ignited gasoline he was putting in the tank. Surprise — Mrs. O. W. Slaughter narrowly escaped serious Injury when gasoline with which she was cleaning some clothing ignited, burning her neck and hands. Syracuse — Mrs. W. K. Keathely was seriously burned about the face and arms when gasoline exploded in which she was cleaning clothes. Tecumseh — Sam Kilbourn was burned while housed in jail. The jail caught on fire. Tekamah — Walter Rhodes was burned about the face and .shoulders when his home was destroyed by fire. (See deaths.) Wymore — Lyle Homer, 5, and 4 year old son of Tom Long, Have - lock, were burned when Lyle placed a lighted candle in the opening of the gas tank on the car. Scarcity of gasoline in the tank of the auto probably saved their lives. York — When Mrs. Albert Thompson removed the lid from the kitchen stove, flames from the fire ignited fumes escaping from an oil can in the room, and an explosion followed. Two children, Robert, 3, and Jeanette, 10 months, were slightly burned. Yutan — W. N. Miller, fireman, fell, breaking one of his legs, and Fred Puls sustained some fractured ribs while fighting a roof fire. INVESTIGATION OF SUSPICIOUS FIRES During 1929 the Fire Marshal's office made investigation of 159 suspicious fire. Of this number investigated it was believed that 47 of these fires were, without doubt, of incendiary origin. Four men were arrested and charged with arson;, three confessed and were sentenced to the penitentiary; one, the complaint was dismissed. Of </seg>
            <seg id="p032">STATE OF NEBRASKA the remaining 44 cases, up to date, no charges have been preferred, as the collecting of evidence still continues. Fifty-nine of the fires investigated proved not to be of incendiary origin, but in most cases carlessness on the part of the occupant in allowing fire hazards to exist. The other fifty-four were listed as unknown or. doubtful. In the investigation of these fires the utmost care -was taken to avoid publicity and reflections being cast on any innocent party or parties. It is a greater satisfaction to the investigator to be able to exonerate the suspected ones than it Is to bring charges of arson against them. DORCHESTER — Stanley Vodicka operated a shoe store. He had an old out-of-date stock, so he insured it heavily and then hired Joe Berounsky of Omaha to come to Dorchester to touch it off. The fire occurred February 9, 1927, at 2:15 A. M., and the final evidence was not procured until two years after the fire. They were arrested and plead guilty on April 2, 1929, and were sentenced to 15 months, each, in the penitentiary. • OMAHA — Sabastino Millitti, an Italian boy, 14 years of age, living at 1935 So. 12th Street, set fourteen fires during the period of April 12 to 15, 1929. He was captured by the deputy fire warden and police, and was tried before an insanity board; he was sent to the insane asylum. INCENDIARY FIRES BUIiliETIN FOB FIRE DEPARTMENTS It is desired to call the attention of the members of the fire de - partments throughout the State of Nebraska to the ever increasing number of fires of suspicious origin. Some officials are on record as making a positive statement that more than 30 per cent of the' fire loss is incendiary. This is undoubtedly an extravagant statement, but it is consercatively estimated that 10 per cent of fire show evi - dence of incendiarism. It occurs to me that by cooperating together and thoroughly investigating every fire of suspicious origin we may materially decrease the fire waste in this state and make the crime of arson so unprofitable and so unpopular that it will be seldom attempted. Arson has always been considered one of the most serious crimes and has been classed with murder and treason, and in. some states, even now, a conviction of arson carries with it the death penalty. In - cendiary fires can, for ordinary purposes, be separated into five classes, according to motive: 1. To conceal evidence of some other crime. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION 2. Malice or revenge. 3. Malicious mischief. 4. Pyromania or some other form of insanity. 5. Desire to defraud the insurer. Every, fire is presumed to be of accidental origin, and as the fire - men are the first to reach the scene of thd fire, it 'is usually within the province of these men to overcome the presumption of accident and to discover evidence to show that the lire was incendiary. One ot the first and most important steps in an arson trial is to prove what the lawyers call the "Corpus Delecti", or the body of the crime. In other words, before evidence of a motive, or even a confession, can be introduced in a criminal trial it must first be proven that the specific crime charged has been committed. In a case of arson the specific charge is the burning of a building or other property. In the investigation of a fire care should always be taken to ascer - tain the character of it, in what part of the building it originated, how it burned, and other facts and circumstances which may be sug - gestive of the nature of the fire under investigation. The ince'ndiary origin of a fire is sometimes shown by direct and positive evidence, such as the saturation of the premises with kerosene or some other explosive compound. It may be shown by the fact that there are two or three separate fires, one having no connection with another. It sometimes manifests itself to the firemen by the manner in which if burns, or by the presence of dense smoke, indicatfng the use of oil. The appearance of the interior of a b aiding frequently shows whether a fire is the result of accident or design. The articles of furniture may be so placed as to retard the work of the firemen, or there may be evidence that a considerable part ot the furniture, fix - tures, or stock had been removed previous to the fire. The Supreme Court of a western state, in commenting on an arson case, said, "Where the same person has a series of fires and collects insurance it furnishes a basis for an inference of more or less strength that the fires are not accidental." In the investigation of a supposed incendiary fire it is frequently thought important to eliminate insofar as is possible all the accidental causes which might possibly be put forward as the probable cause for the fire. It is highly important to inspect the heating and the electrical equipment of the building, to see (whether such equipment could possibly have been the cause of the fire. It is thus Important to know, that the electrical equipment is intact or that there is no electric wire near the origin of the fire, as some of these things will undoubtedly be advanced by the defense as the probable cause. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">STATE OF NEBRASKA Any of these things and many others not here mentioned, may tend to excite the suspicion of the firemen that the fire was not acci - dental, and in such a case a thorough investigation as to its cause should be immediately made. If any. physical evidence of incendiarism is found it should be immediately taken possession of by the officer in charge and held for the Fire Marshal, or his deputy. It frequently happens that the remains of .a "plant" arranged by someone to start or accelerate the fire is found in the building after the fire is extinguished. It is highly important, in the event candles or oily bottles, or things of that character are discovered, that they be left exactly as found until they can be photographed. If the candle is to be picked up. lift it by the wick and turn it over to the fire marshal's office for examination for fingerprints. The same care should be exercised in handling any other ar - ticles which were plainly used by the incendiary, for their examina - tion for fingerprints. AH cases of suspicious fires should be immediately referred to the State Fire Marshal for further investigation, but the members of the fire department should bear in mind that, being the first at the scene of the fire, it is their duty, if the fire is incendiary, to collect and develop the evidence to support this fact. Of course it is impossible to properly investigate the cause of a fire during its progress, but where the circumstances are suspicious, as soon as the fire is ex - tinguished a watchman should be placed in charge of the building until such time as proper investigation can be made. (Signed) JOHN C. TROUTON, State Fire Marshal. STANDARD EQUIPMENT OF FIRE DEPARTMENTS The hose couplings of all fire departments in this state should be brought to a standard. The standard for hose couplings established by the National Board of Fire Underwriters is known as seven and one-half threads to the inch. National Standard. It is essential that this standard should be adopted by all cities towns, and villages, so that in case of a big fire occurring, and a call for help being sent out. other fire companies responding to the call can couple on the fire hydrants wherever and whenever neecssary. At the Baltimore fire. Washington and Philadelphia sent their equipment to assist, but their equipment, was useless for they could not connect onto the fire hydrants. The fire loss was forty million dollars. This might have been greatly reduced had all equipment </seg>
            <seg id="p035">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION (ANDERSON COMPANY, OMAHA, NEBRASKA, has standard dyes changing hose couplings to standard.) ATTENTION: FIRE CHIEFS &amp; FIREMEN John C. Trouton Falrbury, Nebraska. State Fire Marshal, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Sir: We have a drill tower at Fairbury, and ve will start drill school as soon as the weather moderates. Our drill tower is fifty-two feet high, and we expect to put on aU the drills that are used in any first class fire department. Our fire - men will be drilled in this tower. They will be instructed in pumping, and layouts of hose, as well as ladder and rope work. In fact, we are using the Kansas City, Missouri, drills. - Our drill master took his schooling from the Kansas City drill school last summer under Chief Hardwick of that city. All we ask of those who attend is that they obey our rules, and furnish their own laundry. We will furnish the rest; a good place to sleep and a good bed. THIS DRILL, SCHOOL WILL BE FREE TO ALL PAID AND VOLUNTEER FIREMEN. All firemen wishing to take this schooling must notify us in ad - vance, so reservations can be made. If you are for this kind of schooling, please advise your men, so that they can notify the different departments over the state. Very truly yours, F. C. BROWN, Chief. 'COMMENT. This is the first opportunity we have had In the State of Nebraska whereby the Volunteer firemen can be educated In drill work of this kind, and I sincerely hope that at least one member of each fire de - partment will avail themselves of this opportunity. Mr. Brown, Fire Chief, is to be highly complimented on his ef - forts in making this possible. Of twenty-three fires reported last year for Falrbury, the value of buildings and contents, estimated, was $135,250.00, with a total loss </seg>
            <seg id="p036">STATE OF NEBRASKA of only, $6,840.00. This, fire loss is less than in any city ot its size in our state. During last December the city of Fairbury presented the fire de - partment with a new 1,000 gallon, LaFranze pumper, and the In - spection Bureau gave the city a new rating of 10% less on all busi - ness and residential districts. (SO! YOU SEE IT PAYS.) JOHN C. TROUTON, State Fire Marshal. WHAT PRESSURE SHOULD BE MAINTAINED ON THE PUMPING ENGINE? THESE SUGGESTIONS WILL HELP YOU TO SOLVE THIS PROBLEM PUMPING ENGINE PRESSURES It is evident that a short method which will enable an operator of a pumping engine to determine the pressure suitable under various ordinary conditions would be quite welcome, and with that in mind the following, has been prepared as a guide. It should always be borne in mind that a few pounds variance either way makes but little difference in the amount of water that reaches the fire. There is an old saying that any stream that does not make a black spot where it hits is of little, if any, value. A good stream is one that will enter thru a window force, and at this point not lose continuity of the stream by dividing into a shower of spray, and should appear to shoot 90% of the whole body' of water inside a 15-inch circle, and 75% of it thru a 10-inch circle. It is generally considered that an effective nozzle pressure is ap - proximately as shown in the following table which also shows the dis - charge in gallons per minute at such pressure: Size of Pressure Nozzle at Nozzle Discharge %-inch 50 lbs 120 G. P. M. %-inch.. 50 lbs 160 G. P. M. 1 -inch , ...50 lbs 209 G. P. M. 1 %-inch 50 lbs '. 265 G. P. M. 1 %-inch 50 lbs 326 G. V. M. 1 %-inch 60 lbs 434 G. P. M. 1 %-inch 60 lbs 515 G. P. M. 1 %-inch— 60 lbs 600 G. P. M. 1 %-inch ...60 lbs... 700 G. P. M. 2 -Inch 65. lbs :...'. .960 G. P. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION A nozzle of any certain size is not suitable in all cases. For example, a 34-inch or a %-inch tip is best suited for small fires; 1 - inch and 1 %-inch tips are effective on fires of ordinary magnitude; 1 Vi -inch tips should be used on single lines directed upon large fires; larger sizes are used in connection with large stream appliances, such as deluge sets, deck pipes, monitors, turret pipes, and ladder nozzles. The following methods may be used to roughly and quickly cal - culate the pressure at which to operate the pumper, remembering that one or two pounds either way make no noticeable difference. These formulas are based upon the assumption that there is little or no difference in ground elevation between the fire! and the location of the pumper. Where there is a difference, add 5 pounds to pump pressure for each 10 feet the pumper is lower than the fire and subtract 5 pounds for each 10 feet the fire is lower than the pumper. Also, add 5 pounds to pump pressure for each story the nozzle is used above the ground. The pressure added for each 100- feet of hose in the line is equivalent to the approximate pressure lost due to friction in the hose with the amount of water flowing that would result with the given size of nozzle and the pressure at the *tip as indicated in the table. FORMULAS (1) %-inch NOZZLE: SINGLE LINE: Pump pressure equals 50 lbs. plus 5 lbs. for each 100 feet of 2 %-inch hose in the line. Example: 300-ft. line would require 50 plus 5 plus 5 plus 5 equal 65 lbs. pump pressure. (2) %-INCH NOZZLS; SINGLE LINE: Pump pressure equals 50 lbs. plus 7 lbs. for each 100 ft. of 2 %-inch hose in the line. (3) 1-INCH NOZZLE; SINGLE LINE: Pump pressure equals 50 lbs. plus 10 lbs. for each 100 ft. of 2 %-inch hose in the line. (4) 1 %-INCH NOZZLE; SINGLE LINE: Pump pressure equals 50 lbs. plus 17 lbs. for each 100 ft. of 2 %-inch hose in the line. (5) 1 %-INCH NOZZLE; SINGLE LINE: Pump pressure equals 50 lbs. plus 25 lbs. for each 100 ft. of 2% inch hose in the line. (6) 1 %-INCH NOZZLE; 2 LINES of 2%-IN^CH HOSE OF EQUAL LENGTH, SIAMESED. Pump pressure equals 60 lbs. plus 10 lbs. for each 100 feet in one line. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">STATE OP NEBRASKA (7) 1%-INCH NOZZLE; 2 LINES OF 2% -INCH HOSE OF EQUAL LENGTH, SIAMESED. Pump pressure equals 60 lbs. plus 15 lbs. for each 100 feet in one line. (8) 1%-INCH NOZZLE; 2 LINES OF 2% -INCH HOSE OF EQUAL LENGTH, SIAMESED. Pump pressure equals 60 lbs. plus 20 lbs. for each 100 feet in one line. (9) 1%-INCH NOZZLE; 3 LINES OF 2% -INCH HOSE OF EQUAL LENGTH, SIAMESED. Pump pressure equals 60 lbs. plus 13 lbs. for each 100 feet in one line. (10) 2-INCH NOZZLE; 3 LINES of 2%-INCH HOSE OF EQUAL LENGTH, SIAMESED. Pump pressure equals 65 lbs. plus 25 lbs. for each 100 feet in one line. These pressures give good average streams but are not the maxi - mum nozzle pressures permissible. Under certain conditions higher or lower pressures may be more desirable and the officer in command will give instructions to the pump operator. Care should be taken that the layout will not require the pump to operate at a greater capacity or pressure than that for which it is designed. Published by the KANSAS INSPECTION BUREAU, W. C. Hodges, Mgr. E. J. Stewart, Chief Engr. Topeka, Kansas. Permission was given this Department to print this in our Annual, for the benefit of all fire departments. DANGER IS ALWAYS PRESENT: GUARD AGAINST IT The most frequent cause of fires and the one that calls the fire department out at all hours is the roof fire; a dirty flue, a cold night, a dry shingle root, and a hot fire is the finest combination tor such a fire. It causes the local fire department to make more mileage than any other one fire hazard. The remedy is simple. Before starting fires in the fall of the year, be sure the chimney is clean, and that the stove and furnace pipes have been cleaned out. See that the pipes are properly cemented in the flue, as this will give better control of the fire and will mean a great saving in fuel. If the furnace door Is left open during the summer it will prevent the condensation which occurs when the furnace is not in use and prolong the life of the pipes. It creates an air circulation which minimizes condensation. If any </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION bricks are loose in the chimney and the mortar is gone, danger is pres - ent. Repair all defects at once. You may be saving a life. THE TRAGIC STORY OF BABB'S SWITCH "Babb's Switch" is the name of a rural community schoolhouse not far from Hobart, Oklahoma. Before its destruction by fire on the night before Christmas, December 24, 1924, it was used for school purposes and as a meeting place for parents and children in their social gatherings and entertainments. The schoolhouse was a one - room building. Its only door opened in instead of out. Over every window heavy hail-wire screening had been fastened to the outer frame with staples. A Christmas tree had been installed on tl c teacher's platform at Babb's Switch. The committee in charge had decorated the ever - green tree with tinsel. Cotton from nearby fields was used to rep - resent a covering of the branches with snow. There were no electric lights at Babb's Switch for illuminating the tree. The community schoolhouse was lighted with kerosene lamps. It was a cold night. Parents and children filled the one large room. Then the members of the committee proceeded to light the candles used to illuminate the Christmas tree. The tragedy of Babb's Switch may be told in a few lines. The open lights of the candles quickly ignited the cotton, tinsel and presents, and soon the flames had spread to the building. The parents and children rushed to the one door, but it opened' in. As they massed against it there was no possibility of escape. The windows, too, were covered with heavy wlrej screens stapled to the frames. Thirty-five persons, mostly children,' were burned to death in that schoolhouse, and seventeen of them vrere buried in one long grave. It was a tragedy that should be an object lesson to every teacher, pupil and parent in Nebraska. — THE COLLINGWOOD SCHOOL DISASTER Collingwood is a little town near Cleveland, Ohio. A few years ago its schoolhouse was destroyed and nearly 200 children were burned to death. Mr. T. Alfred Fleming, now, in charge of Conserva - tion Department, National Board of Underwriters, was one of the .first two at the scene of this school disaster. Mr. Fleming, in describ - ing the horror, said: "When I got there I found about twelve or fourteen of the little </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATE OF NEBRASKA children who had been huddled together at the front of the building, standing there in the snow and sleet. Looking at the building there wasn't anything that could be seen but a sheet of flame coining from every window and front door. Somewhere in that building there must have been tied up about one hundred and fifty to two hundred children who had been unable to make their escape. "The fire started in the center in the front of the building over by a radiator where the pipe was up against the woodwork. This was a steam system of heating and the woodwork, had no protection what - soever. The heat simply drew out the sap from the wooden sash and the intensity of the heat sapped it more and more until it carbonized the wood and it only needed' an extra fire down in the furnace to cause the carbonized wood to break out in flame. When it was first discovered the blaze was smaller than the size of a match flame. The report was sent all through the schoolrooms and immediately a fire drill was sounded, but this particular blaze caught on a substance used to keep the floors clean, and was highly filled with a rosin sub - stance, a preparation that may be found in 67 per cent of the schools of today. It immediately flashed across the doorway, where it was fed by oxygen from underneath, and in that way cut off the front exit in less than three minutes. By the time the children came down from the upper rooms in the usual way to the front they found themselves confronted with a flame like a prairie or forest fire. "The children rushed to the rear door, breaking their formation. There were about six steps down to the rear door and naturally they pushed each other down the landing. When we broke open those rear doors we found them not only opening inward, but locked while school was in session. The fire department was a volunteer depart - ment and consumed valuable time in coming from the various shops. "After the doors were broken we found children piled above the top of the doors. I don't know how much farther. It was a pile of dying children twelve and a half feet high. We tried to pull them out from underneath but only found that the weight of those above them was too great. While working heroically, the chief of the Collingwood fire department heard the voice of his only child, a eon ten years old. from that pile of pershing children.; This big, strong fire chief put his massive weight on the two arms of that little boy to pull him out. He pulled an arm entirely out and the other so far that he simply turned his face away from the horror of the scene and his child burned to death. Turning the other way he saw mothers and citizens running to this terrible scene. The old chief was com - pelled to marshal those who first arrived to keep away that onslaught of crazed individuals. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION "After it was all over we carried one hundred and seventy-three little children, headless, armless and legless knd laid them in a row in the Lakeshore machine shops for identification. We identified as many as possible by a Bhred of clothing, by a button, sometimes by an old-fashioned ten-cent watch that never would run in the world, never was intended to run, that some boy had. There were many little bodies we could not identify. Those you will find buried in Lakeview cemetery, Cleveland, in little circular rows. You will find at the entrance of that cemetery these graves of school children, the victims of carelessness in the handling of fire." (Is it any wonder that we are trying to carry a message of safety along flre prevention lines all over the country?) A NEBRASKA TRAGEDY A tragedy in the loss of human life and the destruction of prop - erty was vividly brought to our attention in the Scribner dynamite explosion of March 4, 1929. Scribner was dealt a distressing and sorrowful blow when dyna - mite exploded in a shed at the Carl Hollander place west of Scribner during the process of a flre, that was discovered ten minutes previous, believed to have originatd in a car, supposedly due to defective wir - ing. The car was in a leanto shed adjoining the building. Members of the Volunteer Fire Department and citizens being unaware of the 250 pounds of dynamite stored within, pressed close in around the burning structure, and the explosion sent their bodies thru the air and rolling along the ground for distances estimated as far as 150 feet. In that part of the barn the dynamite was kept, there was also stored a quantity of nails, wire, tool boxes and other iron materials. This iron and steel was sent in all directions imbeddirfg itself into human bodies in its path. Six men were mortally wounded and passed away from injuries within eighteen hours of the dreadful accident. They were Fred Fei - gner, 22; Gus Pittack, 26; Harry Wibbles, 23; Guy E. Clark. 39; . William F. Strube, 34; and Arthur Schoeneck, 25. These were all members of the fire department with the exception of Wibbles. Thirty-five persons were injured, nine of! which were firemen. Those most seriously injured and confined to the hospital were: Fred Pscherer, fire chief; Elmer Steil, John Lamberty, Sid Spurling, E. J. Moeller, W. J. Shorten, G. P. Johns, John Thorp, Henry W. Meier, Joe Rumery, Henry. Rich, Elmer Hershberger, John Valk, William Hen - ricksen, William Harder, Melvin Rexin, Otto Rink, John Steil. Much </seg>
            <seg id="p042">STATE OP NEBRASKA credit is due those in charge of the hospital and also those who so willingly assisted, and the mere fact that a hospital was available and so completely equipped is without doubt due to the mortality among the Injured being held so low. Those injured in a minor degree were: Wm. A. A. Welgand. , Lester Ehlers, Wm. Fahk, Clarence Zucker, Asst. Chief; W. C. Nutt, Wilmar Wapelhorst, M. A. Hpstrup, Jr., Van Rich, John Steil, Otto Rink, Henry Benne, Ray Johnson, Clarence Broeker, Carl Meyer, Louis Iske, and others. The final cost of this explosion, measured in money, is approxi - mately $85,000, exclusive of property damage. Property loss does not compare to the annual life loss of human souls. This is a supreme challenge to the conscience of the nation, and it is simply staggering in its black conception, for many innocent lives are sacrifled every year on the pyre of carelessness. The responsibility for safeguarding life and property rests not only on the fire chief and his brave men, but also upon each person in - dividually. There Is no more efficient way of keeping down to a minimum the annual fire waste of a city or town than by instituting a regular and systematic inspection of all buildings and their sur - roundings, and people should be educated in the art of preventing flre and eliminating unnecessary hazards. NEBRASKA BOY SCOUTS AND CAMPFIRE GIRLS Great credit is due to the members of the Boy Scouts and Camp Fire Girls organizations, as they are taught from the time they become members to be careful in all things, and particularly so in regard to the prevention of fires. These boys and girls have rendered great service to the cause of flre prevention in seeing that waste papers are removed from the homes and in noting just what disposi - tion is made of rubbish, weeds, and other Inflammable trash In or around the home, and to see that such disposition is a safe one; also telling their parents about pilot lights for electric irons; how danger - ous an oily mop can become; in giving warnings about the use of gasoline for cleaning purposes, and in warning their home folks not to use kerosene in starting fires. It cannot be stated in figures what the value of this service really is, but it can safely be said that these things accomplished by the little members of both of these organiza - tions has aided greatly in the now steadily growing decrease in our State's flre losses. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION CLEANUP Clean up your basements, yards, alleys and closets. Rid them of all rubbish. Whitewash all you can. There are several good ■white - wash preparations on the market that will render wood flre resistive to a very perceptible degree, and the result is FEWER FIRES, BETTER HEALTH, and a CLEANER CITYl A clean city Is a safe city. CLEANLINESS is next to GODLINESS j get as close as you can and keep close. "DO IT NOW", is a good slogan. • SMOKING AND ITS DANGERS One hundred billion cigarettes are lighted and consumed every year. Every one of them are a potential' fire hazard. Th'e cigarette butt and the cigar stub cause many fires. One careless smoker year. Every one of them is a potential fire hazard. The cigarette ignited some rubbish on the floor of a shirt waist factory in New York causing the death of one hundred and forty-five persons and destroyed the building. NEVER smoke near a gasoline filling station; some one might have to open the cemetery gate. Remove all benches from the vicinity of gasoline pumps and filling stations; they invite the careless, ones. Screen all street gratings to prevent rubbish from accumulating under them; a match, a cigar, or a cigarette may find its way into the rubbish and the flre is started. The State Fire Marshal will willingly furnish you with "NO SMOKING" signs to place in dangerous places. SOME OF THE UNDERLYING CAUSES OF FIRE GAS OILS ASHES LITTER MATCHES GASOLINE FIREWORKS EXPLOSIONS ELECTRICITY CARELESSNESS DON'TS DON'T use make-shifts Instead of proper fuse s in your electrical cir - cuits; the fuse Is the safety valve of the system. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">STATE OF NEBRASKA DON'T leave electric flatirons or other heating devices turned on while attending to something else. DON'T look for a gas leaks with an open flame light; you will be sure to find them. DON'T use gasoline or other volatile liquids to remove spots from clothing or for other purposes. It is cheaper to pay for dry cleaning than for a funeral. DON'T throw your matches or lighted smoking material where they can possibly start a fire. DON'T smoke in bed; even if those guilty of this practice are too green to burn, the beds are not. DON'T let the children play with matches or bonfires. DON'T fail to have your defective chimney and flues mended; they cause numerous fires in our state. DON'T forget to have your smokepipe cleaned of soot; if clogged it may overheat and start a fire when you operate the furnace. DON'T neglect to protect walls, ceilings and partitions from the over - heating of stoves, furnaces and pipes. DON'T put hot ashes into wooden boxes or barrels. DON'T fill oil lamps or stoves by open flame lights; many lives have been lost : by this form of carelessness. DON'T let rubbish accumulate; uncleanliness and fire go hand in hand. DON'T fail to keep a bucket of water and a bucket of sand in a con - venient place for use in case of fire; they may save the lives of your family. DON'T fail to purchase a good fire extinguishing chemical (one or . more) for your home. . ■ DON'T save your burnt out fuses; they have no value. DON'T fail to look after chemical extinguishers; see that they are immediately charged after being used. A 2% or 3 gallon turnover chemical can be used by man, woman or child and one or more should be installed in every home. REMEMBER, IN CONCLUSION, "FIRE IS A DANGER THAT NEVER - SLEEPS", SO BE CONTINUOUSLY ON YOUR GUARD. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">DIVISION OP FIRE PREVENTION SLOGANS America never has been licked — except by flames. A match has a head, but no brains. When' you use its head, use your brains. A fire extinguisher on hand is worth two in the store. Fire loves a disorderly housekeeper. A tree will make a million matches, but a match will start a fire which destroys a million trees. Clean property seldom burns. A man steals a few dollars and is sent to prison, but when a man through carelessness and indifference causes a fire which results in the loss of thousands of dollars worth of property, and sometimes the loss of life, he is not punished. Which 1b the greater criminal? I Careless smokers burned over millions of dollars worth of prop - erty last year. Do not smoke where smoking is forbidden. Fire prevention protects your home and family. Fire waste is not paid by insurance companies; they only distribute the money that is paid by the people when they buy merchandise. The cost of fire tax is concealed in the price of the goods. If we all use precaution and teach our boys and girls the hazards of fire, it won't be long until the fires will be reduced to a minimum. Fire is not the only form of waste, but it is the most malignant. If we are careful in all things we will avoid waste, and careful - ness does not cost a cent. From little sparks may burst a mighty flame. Courting Danger. "'How'd they come to bounce the fire chief?" asked Abe Hinkle, who had been out of town! for a couple of days. "He took too many dad-blamed risks," answered Joe Mudge. "Why he even wore his celluloid collar to fires." If your fire insurance rates are too high, see that your city con - forms to the state law the state marshal is called to enforce and then watch the results. (Kansas State Fire Marshal's Bulletin.) A tumbledown wooden building cob webbed and trashbedecked In the rear of a block of business houses is more expensive luxury than a perpetual marble fountain bedecked with yari-colored lights by night, set in the public square. (Kansas State Fire Marshal's Bulletin.) </seg>
            <seg id="p046">STATE OF NEBRASKA FIRE DEPARTMENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX "Section 4469. Compiled Statutes for 1922. FIRE DEPART - MENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX. All cities of the metropolitan, first or second class or village, organized under the laws of the State of Nebraska, shall have power and authority to levy a special tax of not more than one and one-half (1%) mills each year upon all tax - able property in said city. Such special levy shall be made by the same officers or board and shall be levied in the same manner as In the case of general city taxes. Revenue raised by such special levy may be used only for the purposes of purchasing equipment for a fire de - partment of such city or for installing and equipping a fire alarm sys - tem, or in payment of bonds as hereinafter authorized. Note. Sections 5820 and 5910 C. S. Neb. 1922 now fix levy at twenty per cent of one and one-half mills actual valuation.) "Section 4470. BONDS— AUTHORIZED. Any city or village hav - ing levied a tax as herein authorized may anticipate the collection of such tax so levied, and for that purpose may issue bonds with interest coupons attached, in a sum amounting to 90 per cent of the tax so levied. Such bonds may run for a period of not more than five years, and may bear interest at a rate not to exceed 5 per cent per annum. Bonds so issued shall be secured by such tax so assessed and levied, and shall be payable only out of the funds derived from such tax. In any case in which bonds are issued as herein authorized, it shall be the duty of such city, on receipt of such tax paid, to hold the same as a separate fund to the amount of the bonds, so Issued, and the interest thereon, for the purpose of paying or redeeming such bonds." </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>