<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00077.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-Fourth Biennial Report Labor and Compensation December 31, 1932 to December 31, 1933</title>
               <date value="1934-01-10">1934-01-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Twenty-Fourth Biennial Report Labor and Compensation December 31, 1932 to December 31, 1933 1 —P^W" ""^**^\_^lr v .^^^T_J^*^J^'J CHARLES W. BRYAN, Governor CECIL E. MATTHEWS, Labor and Compensation Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STAFF Department of Labor Charles W. Bryan Governor Cecil E. Matthews : Commissioner Dorothy Miller Secretary George A. Norman , Inspector Britt Pryor Special Factory Inspector Bertha Johnston. Special Pile Clerk Department of Compensation Charles W. Bryan .....Governor Cecil E. Matthews Commissioner Stephen Vail + Chief Investigator Frank A. Dutton Assistant Investigator Dorothy Miller Secretary Claire Bradford „.: File Clerk </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL To His Excellency, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Ne - braska : In compliance with the laws of the state of Nebraska, I have the honor to submit herewith the official report of the Department of Labor for the years 1932 and 1933. Respectfully yours, Cecil E. Matthews, Labor and Compensation Commissoner. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Lincoln, Nebraska, January 10, 1934. To His Excellency Governor Charles W. Bryan, Capitol Building, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Governor: I have the honor of reporting to you herewith, the records of the Department of Labor and Compensation as provided by law for the year 1933 and comparative year 1932. I am happy to report that this department's operating costs arc showing net savings of over $1,600.00 per annum under the appropria - tions granted this department 'for the past year. The appropriation to which I allude, is the regular appropriation made for salaries and main - tenance and does not include the special appropriation under which special help is now employed. , The labor situation is very much improved over that of a year ago. At that time the unemployed m this state were m the throes of despair. The future did not contain a single ray of material comfort at that time The great drive to the end of providing work for the unemployed had not taken place. The charity organizations of Nebraska were being diawn upon as never before. And then later, began thy great drive, m which government and state has played a magnifiicent part. Employers working under the NRA have had a part m the reeni - ployment program. Joining forces with other agencies of both state and nation, we now behold a major portion of the unemployed of Ne - braska once more employed and the future is indicative of continued employment and a lessening of the ranks of the unemployed That we may understand the extent of the unemployment within this state a year ago and appreciate the progress that has been made m providing jobs for the jobless the past twelve months, I herewith present a report of the survey as taken by the Federal Re-employment Division which has been graciously provided this department by Hon. George Hodge, Director of the National Re-employment Service, whose mission m this state has been to care for the orderly and efficient selec - tion of applicants for work upon our highways and public works, con - structed from funds made available under the National Recovery Act This organization was designed to be temporary m character and tyas born of necessity, arising out of the labor policies formally adopted by the special Board of Public Works. DIRECTOR GEORGE HODGE'S REPORT • August 1, 1933, initial registration unemployed 60.000 November 15, 1933, placed m temporary employment 15,000 November IS, 1933, additional registrations 40,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">jE'-EE eE;7-::..it' EeyEe Total registrations 105,623 Legitimate unemployed 65,000 November 15 to date, placed in permanent and temporary employment .35,000 January 1, 1934. Total reemployment 69,315 Thus we have cause to feel that everything possible has been done in a short space of time, to alleviate the distress of the unfortunate un - employed, which at the beginning of the year 1933, was in numbers, without precedent in the history of this state. COMPENSATION COMPILATIONS The following compilation from the records of this office afford an interesting study. It shows that the injured employes are holding their own in compensable benefits per injured man. On the other hand it . shows a great saving in the ultimate cost to the employer over previous years, in the matter of the medical, hospital and surgical expense. The new medical fee schedule did not go into effect until July 1, 1933, therefore the showing in reduced medical costs has the benefit of the fee schedule saving for a period of only six months of the full year. There can be little complaint of, on the part of the employer, or the in - surance carrier, relative the campaign this department has waged to place the medical burden upon a fair and just basis to all parties concerned. Medical Compensation 1932 Lard Record $248,914.89 $471,975.22 1933 Card Record $151,592.00 347,940.99 Reduction 97,322.89 124,034.23 1932 Total Accidents 14,081 1.33 Total Accidents 12,027 Reduced accidents 2.054 1932 Compensation average injured man $33.57 1933 Compensation average injured man $28.92 1932 - Total numbers fatalities 40 1933 - Total number's fatalities 26 1932 - Average medical expense per injured man $17.67 1933 Average medical expense per injured man —.$12.77 Average reduction per man $ 4.90 1932 - Lump sums and other settlements $195,504.79 1933 .- Lump sums and other settlements $189,603.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">These sums are included in the total of com-* pensation payments listed above. 1933 - Petitions Filed . ...475 Awards Made 252 Appeals from Awards _ 138 Dismissals 272 Appeals from Dismissals 56 1932 - Total liability per injured man $37.31 1933 - Total liability per injured man -.25.76 Net decreased liability 11.55 1932 - Lump sums and other settlements charged to average injured $13.88 1933 - Lump sums and other settlements charged to average injured $15.76 1932 - Total cost per injured man to employer or insurer &lt;;5I jq 1933 - Total cost per injured man to employer or insurer : 7 $41.53 Net reduction over previous year per I injured man * q i — — —— — — SAFETY CAMPAIGNS PROFITABLE a . The most profitable campaign that an employer can wage, is a safety campaign. It is profitable to the end of reducing the hazards and the human element of distress accompanying all accidents, but it has also behind it the possibilities of greatly reducing the cost of liability insurance. A certain employing agency within this state permitted seemingly. a free reign of carelessnese of its men last year and as a result the in - surance company that carried that company's risk paid out over $18,000 in compensation insurance claims. Finding themselves unable to buy compensation insurance any longer, this concern sought the rights of a self-insurer, which privilege was granted under certain conditions, and that was that such an uneconomic loss must be abated. A safety campaign in charge of a man employed to do nothing else other thaii promote it, was put under way. As a result the first six months tinder such supervision resulted in compensable losses aggregating less than Another employing agency that has around forty truck drivers, put on a safety campaign last July. Recently awards were made by the com - pany to the drivers who had driven their truck six months without an accident of any kind. All but four of those forty men received silver medals. Those four were unable to keep other vehicles from hitting their trucks, hence they lost out in securing a medal, for that .was pan </seg>
            <seg id="p007">of the campaign — to not only not hit the other car or truck, but to keep others from hitting theirs. At that, the total damages that resulted and chargeable to their record, was in the small sum of $20.00. Three years ago this same concern paid out annually in compensable benefits a total of $10,000. Last year it paid out $150.00. Here is a picture of what safety work will do when employers once adopt it as a set policy of their institution or business. FEMALE LABOR LAW BEING ENFORCED ' - ■ ■ ■ ■ Only in rare instance, is there an attempt upon the part of employer to ignore the provisions of the female labor laws. In only one instance the past year has an employer refused to recognize .the right of the state to govern the employment of female labor and this case is to be passed upon by the courts in the not far future. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>