<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF The Soldiers' and Sailors' Home LOCATED AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA BIENNIUM ENDING, NOVEMBER 30th, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Of Soldiers and Sailors' Home 10( AThD AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA BIENNH M hSDISG, SOI EMBER MM*, 1901 COL. J. H. PRESSON COMMASDAST </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">To the Governor ami Board of Public Lands and Building* of the State of Nebraska: Gentlemen — I have the honor to submit the Kighth Biennial Report of the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home. Milford, Nebraska. tin beginning this report I wish to express my gratitude to an wise Providence for His goodness in preserving the members of 5 Home, and the property of the same from all serious accident, I that no contagion or malignant disease lias invaded our pre - ct8. The conditions existing in the Home and among the niem - ship are the best I have ever known. I have had the privilege some other Homes during the past year, but did not find my of them as much social life as exists here. PHYSICAL CONDITIONS We have an abundant supply of the very best water, a whole - some atmosphere, an excellent drain. I beds and pure food. We maintain regular hours for sleep, free from noise and other dis - turbance, so that the old people who compose the inhabitants have the best of conditions and opportunities surrounding them enabling them to spend in peace their declining years. A number of stantial improvements have l&gt;een made, an addition has been built to the laundry, new boxes placed for the clothing, a new extractor in the place of an old worn out wringer, steam and hot water direct from the boiler so that we are having clean and white clothing every week. I have had the hospital, stand pipe and smoke stack re - painted at a cost of $280.00. I have bought some new. and re - paired the old closets, and put them in a sanitary condition. Many minor improvements too numerous to mention have been ma that the Home generally is in good repair. A new building for officers' quarters and for office work is now well on toward completion, and when done will relieve the main building so that there will be room for twenty-five more members. The hospital is under the management of Dr. J. (J. Muir, who is very successful in treating the ailments of the members and who holds thei? confidence and respect. His offici nent it made </seg>
            <seg id="p004">420 DISCIPLINE The proper administration of discipline in an institution is \ s more or less difficult. Especially in one composed of men of habits, appetites and tastes, together with the predjudir many years. No two cases though they may l&gt;e similar can he • d exactly alike for the reason t hat there are different degrees of responsibility. The inordinate use of intoxicants is the serious disturbance we find in the Home; and is the cause of many being here who would otherwise have homes of their own. There .any worthy men and women in the Home who appreciate all that the state and the nation is doing for them, and they do all they can to make the Home a haven of rest, while others who had as good a home complain of everything and everybody. Il is the old condition of the tares and the wheat. I have l&gt;een com - pelled to discharge eleven during my term of office, some of tl readmitted on the written statement that they would be :ent to the rules and l&gt;e decent ever after. SEEDS &lt;iK THE HOME »1 have recommended to the Auditor that the following amounts .ppropriated to meet the necessary expenses for the Institution the next biennium. Including fuel and lights, furniture and bedding, drugs and medicines, hospital supplies, stock, feed, electrical supplies, laundry, stationery, printing, postage, telegraph, telephone, transportation burial expenses, including the services of a Chaplain and the pur - chase of sixteen lots in the cemetery, the improvements of grounds. i and clothing M follow Total $51,100.00 II would also recommend that the sum of eight thousand dollars 000.00), or so much thereof as may be necessary to install a pressure boiler and to sink an additional well, this would be e economical in furnishing heat, and do away with the necessity MAINTEN \M E Maintenance $34,200.00 Offic riM 5,580 00 8,900 . 00 General repairs 2.420.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">421 of maintaining a dam for the storage of a water supply. The a| priations made by the last Legislature have been ample to all demands, and there will l&gt;e no deficiency in any of the fun The following amounts have l&gt;een expended during the bien- mutn: Maintenance $32,612.22 Officers' salaries Employes" wages ■ s7 Total $46,718 72 (ieneral repairs ''117 ''7 I NS'll I IT1ON A I (ASH KIND On hand at close of last liiennium Received since 1.7J- Total S 1 . / 9 1.574 18 Expended Balance on hand November 30. l'.Mts The pay roll for the month of November 1906 as follows 1 Bookkeeper $35 . (M) I Hospital cook | 1 Hospital steward. 1 Assistant steward 1 Laundryman. . . 1 Hospital waiter... 20 (K) 30 00 3 Waiters. $1L&gt; each 24 00 .SO. 00 1 Fireman 1"&gt; (M) 1 Laundn 1 Head cook. 1 Second cook. 15.00 60.00 1 Fireman 1 Teamster _'4 imi 25 00 1 Com. Sergeant is (H) Male Female Total Xuml&gt;er of members December 1 1906 171 12 183 Xumljer received since 94 6 Xuml&gt;er discharged or died 1J-J 10 Number on rolls November 30, 1908 143 § 151 This, institution does not attempt to do any farming. 1 am of the opinion that farming by old soldiers would prove an un - profitable business, and I think the cost per capita is greater where the experiment has Iwen made than it is where it is not. We have Population </seg>
            <seg id="p006">422 a garden each year and produce early garden stuff such corn. peas, pot. rly cabbage, evewnbers, lettuce. I etc. In favorable seasons we have peaches, cherries Strawberries and papas. We keep a sufficient number of cows to furnish milk for our use. anil pigs to eat the refuse of the tables. The hogs are sold and the money goes into the cash fund of the Home. The amount realized from this source (milk and garden) in th&lt; 11,960.60. I part of the pcinsioa of the members is taken. The pen - is range in amount from $10.00 to $30. (H) per month. One of inconsistencies we note is that some who are entirely helpless ;ive 112.00 while others who are quite active receive $24.00 and (K). It is quite gratifying however, to observe that those who helpless and thosewho receive meager pensions are more content appreciate the blessings they receive more than those wli ;e pensions and can go and come at will. I wish to acknowledge nnection the receipt of gifts to the men in the hospital and he Home of good things from the \V. 1{. ('. at Lincoln. Seward. Is City, and other Corps. These things are always thankfully ■ived and appreciated. In closing this report 1 wish to thank the Governor of the Hon. (leorge I.awson Sheldon, for the courtesy he lias at all ■ wn me as Commandant of this Home and the interest lie has taken in the general superintendence' of the institution, to the menders of the Board of Public Lands and Building rig after the supplies that have at all times been furnished and in granting every request that I have asked at their hands. In taking my leave of the Home I do so with the conviction that it will never receive letter attention by any State Board than it has during th lennium. I wish also to thank the officers of the &lt;■. Dr. .1. (I. Muir, Surgeon. Mrs. Hena M. Walsh. Matron and 3. 1). Myers, Kngineer. for their loyal support and uniform kindness in the management of the affairs of the Home. Not an unkind word has ever passed between us, and I take pleasure in Mending them to my successor or to any institution that is in need of efficient help. I am also under obligations to the subordi - nate officers and employes for the faithfulness that they have shown in the discharge of their duties. This is in a particular sense true of those who have labored in the hospital. They have done the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">423 iirbo have l&gt;een the beneficiaries of their care. I expect to re on the advent of the incoming administration without a ;le regret, and leave to other hands the care of my comrades who facing the evening of life; there are many worthy ones among in and these cannot receive too much, and the other class will a,vs have more than they deserve. 1 have the honor to be very truly yours. .1. H. Presson, Commandant. RKl'OKT OF SURGEON To Col. .1. H. l'resson. Commandant S. &amp; S. Home, Milford, Nebr.: Sir — I have the honor to report at the close of this biennium the following matters connected with this institution. In keeping with my commission from Governor Geo. Lawsoo Sheldon. I as - sumed the charge of this department of your Home on the 1st day of May 1907. Then has l&gt;een an average of twenty patients in the hospital during my incumbency, three of these are incapable of helping themselves, l&gt;eing wholly paralyzed, a number of others receive their meals in their rooms on trays. I visit the hospital at least once each day. at which time those who are sick in quarters and need attention come to the dispensatory and are examined and given medicine as their cases require. I also visit those who ck in quarters and if their cases become serious 1 have them removed to the hospital. I have had two cases of surgery. In one case the leg was taken off just below the knee, in the other case the thumb was removed. In the former case gangrene was developed and the pa - tient died, in the latter the wound healed and the patient recovered. The care of the patients is in the hands of the hospital steward and tant, the present force are doing their duties well and I com - mend them to you as capable men and worthy of your confidence. The food is prepared by an experienced cook and is such as quired by the inmates. The building is kept clean and free from tfl and vermin; there is no complaint of executives only such as you might expect in an infirmary or other such place. I Yourself and other officers and members of the Home have thanks for the uniform courtesy shown me during my con - ion with the Home. Respectfully yours. .1 . (I. Mt'iH. Surgeon. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">424 NAMES OF MEMBERS WHO DIK1M. THE H1KNMIM Name Cause of death Heart failure William H. Johnson William H. Nichols John F. Phillip* Joseph Schallowbaugh Isaac Henry Heart failure Apolexy 76 Old age 86 Pneumonia Pneumonia Paralysis Old age E. \Y. Hutchinson William 1). Rawle- James \Y. H; Thomas Skeede i 5 S6 S4 74 Paralysis I . Bruce uel Hetrick .1) Eddy Consumption Consumption Calvin S. Howe i Husted... Killed R. R. accident Heart failure William T. (ireshain. James Fraziei Disease of stomach Cancel- stomach .der 1). Phinney Edward Healev Strangulation Paralysis Wiley H. l.angford John L. Bboup. . Dropsy . Dropsy . Paralysis (iangrene Samuel Alhin. John McCullough. . James C. Packard. William H. Carte William H. Kyle Henry Eaton Heart failure Alcoholism Diabetia Wcnnen Hester Baldwin 71 Heart failure Consumption Mary E. Bromwell. 70 BKTICS IN THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FKOM « UK II MEMHEKS A\E BEEN RE( EIVED TO THJ HOME. MI1.EOHD NEBR. Men County NuiuIk?! Women Present Women Adam.- 6 •) Antelope 1 1 Banner 2 HAYK 1)1 K I) Age 72 74 .")() M H7 Paralysis BS Consump 7&lt;l 74 75 7s &lt; i 80 72 f&gt;7 ♦i4 70 78 (is (&gt;N 71 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">SOI.DIKHs' AND SAILORS' ROME, IIILFORD 425 i Box Butte 1 Buffalo A 1 1 6 3 Butler 13 4 • ) Cherry I 1 1 1 Cuming ■ &gt; 1 Colfax 1 1 &lt; 'lister -&gt; I) awes 1 Dawson ■&gt; I),,.l K e A 1 Douglaa 71 •&gt; &gt;- _'. Furnaa •&gt; Fill inure 3 Franklin.. 1 Frontier •&gt; 11 ,\ Gosper 1 Hall _'4 * &gt; .") 1 Hamilton. . 1 Harlan 1 Howard 1 Jefferson 4 1 Johnson 9 .&gt; Kearney. . 1 ■) 3 •&gt; Lancaster... 163 2 55 &lt; Madison 1 Nemaha 1() 1 2 Nuckolls. 3 A Otoe... 5 .) Pawnee. •) 1 2 1 :&lt; l Polk 1 Hichartlson &gt; 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">&gt; ■&gt; SillllH' . . s Saundei&gt; 4 . . 1 rd * s 1 Sheridan . ' Stanton 1 Thaver ■&gt; Thomai 1 •&gt; Washington. Webster N 9 York... 12 1 8 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>