<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Tax System of Nebraska with Special Reference to Its Relation to Agriculture</title>
               <date value="18??">October 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">The Tax System of Nebraska with Special Reference to Its Relation to Agriculture COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 105 | L. B. Snyder Department (if Rural Economics ¦¦ I'- ¦:¦¦' ¦ ' V;- ' COMMISSIONER COUNTIES SUPERVISOR COUNTIES MeUSEO IN THIS STUDY Hi 4 USED IN THIS STUDY ' ?sa OTHERS | fZ223OTHERS Counties in Nebraska by types of organization. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OCTOBER, 1938 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Chapter Page I. Introduction * 11. Assessment 9 111. Levies 18 IV. Receipts 33 V. Expenditures 43 VI. Delinquency 66 VII. Summary '° </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Tax System of Nebraska with Special Refer - ence to Its Relation to Agriculture Chapter I—lntroduction Relatively heavy fixed charges such as interest and taxes, when coupled with ceclining prices of farm products, create an interest among farmers in the agencies that tend to maintain these charges at a high level. People hecomi extremely tax conscious during depressions and eventually demand that re factions be made in their taxes. This demand becomes more insistent when i axes fail to respond to the need for reduced spending the same way expenc itures of the individual respond. Several features of public expendi - tures Operate to prevent quick adjustments in taxes. In the first place certain salaries of public officials are fixed by statute and others are estab - lished &gt;y contracts which may run for several years and prevent reductions until tie statutes can be changed or the old contracts expire. A second condition that tends to keep expenditures and taxes high is the fact that officials are elected for terms of several years. In periods o£ declining prices these men feel obliged to carry out the program the public elected them to fulfill. A third factor that prevents prompt reductions is the added burden of relkf when unemployment is widespread and incomes are low. In the fourth place, certain citizens who-are being benefited by governmental expenditures resist efforts to lessen their personal gains. Fifth, payments of interest and principal must be met during depressions as well as in periods of prosperity. Whjen taxes are not reduced as quickly as the public desires, remedies are frequently sought through legislative action or through the ballot. Popula • resentment over faijure to reduce local taxes often leads to the election of a new set of officials upon the expiration of the terms of the old ones. These newly elected officers are often unable to make good on their ampaign promises of economy until they have become familiar with their ntw duties. Voters dojnot insist upon economy in the use of state and federal funds and often elect the candidate who promises the greatest liberalii.y in their use. ) Public spending cannot take place without raising funds or incurring debts. Citizens of the territory that became Nebraska had seen the evil consequences of excessive state and county debts in older states. In an effort tJ avoid similar misfortune for their state they included a section in the state constitution limiting state debts to JIOO.OOO. 1 The state constitu - tion al:;o limits county levies to 50 cents per $100 of assessed value of property and makes it necessary for higher levies to be approved by the voters. 2 These constitutionaljrestrictions haveforced;the state to adopt a pay-as-jou-go policy and prevented heavy county expenditures. : Altr ough there has been much agitation for relief from heavy taxes on the part of Nebraska property owners, neither sales taxes nor income taxes hive been.used in this state. The public has been told repeatedly that such taxes would simply mean additions to present taxes without equalizing the tax burden or furnishing extensive relief. This statement has been - 'The (oiutiiuiian of Kcbriiki. An.-Xlll. See: 1. . 'Ibid., An. VIII, See. 5. . . I :. ', . </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bel. 105 accepted by many people. Contrary to this belief is the opinion that the proper use of an income tax would tend to relieve farmers and other small property owners of part of their tax load since the incomes of many of these people would be too low to be taxed, while persons with large in - comes would pay more taxes than at present. Sales taxes are criticized because they require the payment of part of the costs of government by those with low incomes and little or no property. Inasmuch as sales taxes would tend to make this group of the public tax conscious and less ready to vote for high expenditures by governmental agencies, they may be desirable. The favorable position of Nebraska from the standpoint of property taxes is shown in Tables 1 and 2. The first of these shows farm real estate taxes per acre for the United States, for the West North Central region, and for the seven states included in this region. These taxes per acre were higher in this region than in the entire United States. Of the seven states in this region, Nebraska occupied a middle position with lowa, Minnesota, and Kansas having higher taxes per acre and North Dakota, South Dakota, and Missouri having lower taxes per acre during most of the period. Ne - braska had lower taxes than North Dakota six of the 21 years, South Dakota eight of the 21 years, and Missouri eight of the 21 years. Higher assessed values per acre will not entirely explain this situation. Nebraska had lower farm real estate taxes for each $100 of assessed value than the other six states of the region during most of this period as shown in Table 2. The exceptions are the years 1913 to 1923 when Missouri had lower taxes and 1913 and 191-1 when South Dakota had lower taxes for each $100 of assessed values. Progress in governmental affairs calls for constant study of matters pertaining to government. The recent agitation for moratoria on debts and taxes and the many tax reforms suggested are evidence of the need for such study. Before satisfactory reforms can be made, information on receipts and expenditures by governmental agencies must be secured. The expense connected with collecting, tabulating, and analyzing such data has prevented private agencies of the state from doing this. Because it was felt that such information would be useful and could be obtained by the College of Agriculture, this study was undertaken. The study is divided into seven chapters. The first chapter contains the introduction. In the second chapter assessments are discussed. In the third chapter levies are discussed. The fourth chapter takes up govern - mental revenues. The fifth chapter deals with expenditures by public agencies. The sixth chapter is concerned with one of the effects of taxes and expenditures, namely, tax delinquencies. The seventh and last chapter is a summary of the findings in the earlier chapters. A complete study of all the counties of the state would have involved more time and money than was available and probably would not have provided much more information than could have been obtained from a smaller sample. In selecting the twelve counties used in this study, an effort was made to select counties whose officials would cooperate, counties </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Tax System of Nebraska Table \.—Farm real estate taxes per acre')or seven West North Central I states and for\the United States, 1913-1933} Y"r 1 us- 1 &lt;S1 &#132;&amp;- 1 Mil"--; 1 M°- 1 ¦&amp;• [.'-A 1 &gt;"• 1913 $.24 $.24 $.19 $.56 $ JO $.14 $ .15 $ .15 $ .21 1914 .24 .25 .19 .56 .34 .15 .17 .15 22 '915 .26 .27 .19 .60 .35 .16 .20 .17 23 »16 .28 .28 .20 .64 .39 - .16 .21 .18 24 1917 .31 .32 .22 .74 .46 .18 .21 .22 .27 »1» -33 .34 .23 .76 .4» . .19 .25 .26 28 »»¦ ••" •« : .28 .94 .64 .25 .43 .35 .35 920 .51; .54 .42 1.10 .76 .28 .44 .45 .42 1921 .54 .59 .47 1.20 .79 .38 .45 .41 SO 1922 .54 .57 .41 1.26 .77 .40 .43 .41 .45 1923 .55 .58 .40 1.25 .84 .40 .38 43 .48 1924 .55. .57 .39 1.23 .75 .41 : .38 .43 M J925 .56 .58 .42 1.15 '.78 .43 .37 .44 .52 192« .56 .58 .42 1.14 .80 .44 .37 .44 .54 1927 .57 .59 .46 1.14 .81 .45 .39 .44 .56 1928 ,58 .60 .46 1.15 .85 .47 .39 .45 .57 1929 .58 .61 .45 1.22 .86 .47 .38 .46 .58 9|? •" •&lt;¦&gt;• .44 1.24 .87 .45 .38 .44 .55 "I .53 .56 . .42 1.13 .84 .41 .33 .35 .5J »M ¦ .«, .47 .36 1.02 .67 .37 .29 .32 .41 '933 .39' .42 . .30 .90 .67 .32 .27 .20 .36 'Yearbook of Afiticullurc. 1935, U. |s. Department of Aisricullure, pp. 688 and 689. 1 rreJir iinaiy, based on figures for 35 slain. Table :!.—Farm real estate taxes per $100 of value by states for seven West \North Central states and for the United States, 1913-1933. 1 West Year U.S. North Nebr. la. Minn. Mo. N. S. Kan Central . Dak. Dale. t'ou Si s 5.43 5.38 $.50 $.54 $.25 5.48 $J5 $ .51 m* .56 .44 .38 .46 .61 .27 .55 .36 51 I»|s -57 -44 .37 .44 .55 .28 61 38 5 '916 .57: .44 .37 .45 . .55. .26 .61 .38 5» 1917 .58 .46 .35 .48 .58 ' 27 59 43 53 J»'B -57 •« .32. .44 .56 26 .67 51 919 .59 .47 .32 .41 .59 .28 1.05 49 56 «? H ¦&lt;« -52 .52 .70 .34 1.11 .66 68 1922 M .76 .60 .75 .86 .58 122 82 83 1923 1.01 .84 .64 .80 98 63 122 93 94 1924 1.03 .86 .65 .83 .94 .67 1.28 . .96 96 »« .07 .90 : .70 .81 1.00 .75 . 1.30 1.05 106 1926 1.12- .96 .72 .86 1.09 .80 1.39 1.17 110 1927 1.15 1.00 .80 .88 , 1.14 .83 149 9 5 1928 1.18 .1.02 .80 .90 1.20 .86 153 24 1.17 1929 1.19. 1.08 .81. .98 1.25 .89 154 jo 20 1930 1.28 .. 1.20 .84 1.14 1.45 98 72 HO 124 1931 1.42 1.3! .95 ! 1.28 ; 1.65 : 1.06 1.75 .38 38 1932 1.50 IJ6 1.05 1.59 ,1.64 1.17 1.71 I« ¦". 35 1933 1.22' 1.20 .85 1.28 .1.56 .97 ; 1.54 . .96 . 1.16 'Vearhnk of AKricullurc,.U.*S.'Dqanin«it i of Agriculture, p. 690.- ' ¦¦ , 1 Prelin mary, based on figurct for 351 states. • "..¦¦'. that rej resent the different areas of the state and provide information con - cerning the two types of county government found in the state. Popular vote of the residents of a county determines whether a county is operated under tie supervisor system and has township organization and a board of supervisors 3 or under the precinct system with a county board of com - 'Compled Satutcs of Nebraska, 1929, Sec. 26-201, 592. . ' </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricixtcral Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 missioners. 4 At the present time 27 counties have township organization and 66 have precinct organization. The 27 township counties all lie east of a line drawn north and south through the western border of Custer county. The map on the cover shows the distribution of the two types of counties in the state and the counties selected for detailed study. The location of the 12 counties selected for this study as well as the population per square mile and the rainfall are shown in Figure I. Cuming, Gage, Harlan, and Valley counties arc the township counties selected for this study. In these counties responsibility for local roads and minor affairs is delegated to townships. To attend to these duties each township elects a township road supervisor, a township clerk, and a town - ship justice of the peace. These three representatives operate as a township hoard tor administrative purposes. The county board of supervisors has charge of those roads designated as county roads and the administration o£ county business. POPULATION PER SQUARE MILE H ABOVE 40 W 201 TO 30 E3 5.1 TO 10 38 JO I TO 40 10.1 T0 2C &lt;Zi UNDER 5 l'n.. I. —l'n|iul:iii(in per M|iun- mile and rainfall fur Nebraska. The eight precinct or commissioner counties selected are Boone, Cass, Dakota, Dawes, Frontier, Hamilton, Lancaster, and Thomas counties. Of these, Boone, Cass, Frontier, and Lancaster are designated as near-by com - missioner counties for case in distinguishing them from the other commis - sioner counties. In these eight commissioner counties the county board of commissioners has charge of all of the road work that would be controlled by the township boards of supervisors in the township counties and the functions performed by the county unit in the supervisor counties. A majority of the citizens of any county feel that the type of county organization found in that county is superior to the other type. In order to determine whether any marked difference exists, the four supervisor counties are compared with four commissioner counties. Comparisons arc 'Ibid.. Sec. 26-297, 601. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Tax System of Nebraska made between a supervisor county and a commissioner county situated in simila!' areas so far as rainfall and population are concerned. In each of the foi lowing pairs the commissioner county has been named first and the supervisor county second: Gass and Cuming, Lancaster and Gage, Boone and V alley, and Frontier and Harlan.. . -. :. Data for the section onj assessment and levies were taken from the reports of the state tax commissioner. Another source of information used to a limited extent was the files of the newspapers published in each count). For legal provisions the state statutes have been used. Ths annual reports of the state auditor are the source of data upon state r:venues, while the county treasurer's reports published in the county newspipers have furnished most of the information upon county revenues. Towm hip revenues were obtained from the township clerk's records and checkdd by figures obtained from the county treasurer's office. State expenditures were taken from the auditor's biennial reports. These reports' are based upon reports from the different state agencies and upon the records of expenditures found in the offices of the state treasurer and state auditor. Each county treasurer is required by law to publish semi - annual reports of his office! These reports show expenditures classified accord ng to the different funds rather than according to the purpose of the expenditure. This made it necessary to secure the data from the records found in the county clerks' offices. Since these records show only claims allowed and do not break dc wn these expenditures, it was found necessary to consult each voucher and separate the items into the desired categories. For this purpose two representatives from the College of Agriculture visited each county. Each voucher was examined and the items found on it wen; classified according jo the following classifications. ¦~. RoAd, bridge, arid road-dragging expenditures were divided into labor for roid and bridge building and for repairs, contract expenditures for roads and bridges for which no itemized statements could be secured, repairs on road machinery | and equipment, gasoline for county-owned tractor; and trucksiused for highway work, materials and supplies for roads, bridges, and! culverts, purchases of equipment, freight on road materials and equipment and miscellaneous road expenditures. Expendi - tures from the general fund were distributed to accounts for salaries of elected officers; salaries of clerical help, including deputies; janitor service; office expense; office supplies; printing; office equipment; repairs; officer's bond;; ail and deputy sheriff; law enforcement and court expense; mileage; elections; agriculture (county fair and county agricultural agent); insur - ance (6f courthouse, jail, etc.); relief; mothers' pensions, and miscellaneous expenditures from the general fund. After these data were transferred to work ;heets the items were totaled and tabulated in the offices of the Department of Rural Economics at the University of Nebraska. Each township of the four supervisor counties was visited by the same field workers. Township expenditures were tabulated on the form used for county expenditures. Tabulation was done by the same staff in the Rural Economics Department. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Ac.ruxltiral ExptRiMENT Station Research Bul. 105 School figures were taken from the records on file in the office of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction at Lincoln. Representatives of the College made the tabulation in the office of the superintendent. The data on tax delinquency were collected by a corps of workers under the supervision of the Department of Rural Economics cooperating with the federal government in CWA Project F-23. These data were worked over in the department in 1934 and additional work done on them in </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Chapter ll—Assessment Tangible property serves as a satisfactory measure of tax-paying ability in a new country, where the ownership of such property corresponds very closel' with incomes of citizens. As soon as the country becomes older and the ux burden heavier, larger percentages of investment funds are placed in intangible property, such as bonds, mortgages, and stocks. This class of property is easily concealed from the tax assessor. Many personal in - come: are derived from such investments or from personal services and are not directly related to the ownership of tangible property. Older regions have found it advisable to employ taxes based upon income or pur - chase: of goods in order to relieve tangible property owners and to reach those people who do not own tangible property. Nebraska has not resorted to a general sales tax nor to an income tax but relies upon the property tax fcr most of the revenue for the subordinate taxing bodies of the state such is cities and towns, townships, schools, and counties. Tfjie first step in determining the tax to be paid by each owner of tangible property subject to the tax is the assessment of property. Real estate is assessed every fourth year by county assessors. 1 Prior to 1926 the c uadrennial assessment was made April 1: of. those years evenly divisible by four. In 1925,1 the year of assessment was changed to 1926 and every fourth year thereafter. 2 Each year the county assessor is required to add to the value of each tract of real estate enough to show the increased value due to the addition of new improvements or to subtract enough to offset losses of buildings and land through fire, flood, or wind. Since 1930 county assessors have been elected every fourth year: 1 Personal property is assessed as of April 1 each year by local officers knowi as precinct or township assessors, who are elected every even - numb :red year. 4 They are under the supervision of the county assessor. After the local assessor has listed all the property in his precinct or town - ship, this list must be turned over to the county assessor not later than the last Monday in May." The county assessor, then examines and corrects the errors in these lists." The corrected local lists of property are next reviewed by the county board of equalization of which the county board of supervisors, in a town - ship county, or the county board of commissionrs in precinct counties, the county assessor, and the county clerk are members. 7 The county board of equalization makes any adjustments in assessed values that seem just. Wher the county lists have been adjusted so that property in each precinct or township is valued on the same basis they are sent to the state board of equalization at Lincoln. 8 Thils state board reviews the lists of the differ - ent counties and increases the value of any class of property ior of all 1 Sin « 1934 assessment of teal estate his been every olbcr year instead of every fourth year. ' Cor ipilcd Statutes of Nebraska. 1929. Sec. 77-1601.' - . 'Ibit., Sec. 32-211. .- I' - ¦-.-.- - ¦• -..¦¦ '¦¦ ¦;¦¦. . ¦¦¦ 4/»«'., Sec. 32-212. ¦¦!-': f; . ¦ --¦ -¦-.'¦¦ ¦:..; .'¦¦¦¦ • tt/i 1., Sec. 77-1601. ¦&#132;.-:"..¦ .-:.¦'¦¦..¦¦¦¦ - :" - : -¦¦ : '/»;}. ¦ ;¦¦.. : ; .¦/..• ¦: ¦ ' ¦ ¦¦'¦¦ : - - 1 KM., Sec. 17-1609.' : . ' ' •Itii., Sec. 77-1001. : 9 </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 property of a county in which undervaluation appears to have occurred or decreases the value of any class of property or of all property in an over - valued county. The corrected county lists are then returned to the differ - ent counties, where the county assessor or the county clerk revises the assessment roll to make it conform to the .total county valuations established hy the state board of equalization." Table 3.— Assessed valuation oj tangible property in Nebraska. 1 Value in millions of dollars I'cr ccnl of all properly \&gt;,, Total Town Farm , Town Farm „ , VC" tangible real real P""""1 real real *«"&gt;"*! p»,;,,, v estate «uic Pr°Pcr" r wait ame I™! 1"'? p.ci. p.ci. P.ci. I»r S3.HI 5613 $1,778 5750 19.51 56.61 23.88 IMS 3.126 621 1.780 725 19.87 56.94 23.19 ,929 3 167 627 1.783 757 19.80 56.30 23.90 1930 3 102 621 1.737 744 20.02 56.00 23.98 1931 3 046 622 1.737 687 20.42 57.03 22.55 193; 2:521 530 1.436 555 21.02 56.96 22.02 1 Nebraska Tax Commissioners' Reports. Review and equalization of assessment rolls are necessary to distribute the burden of the property tax as equitably as possible. There is a tendency for each local assessor to under-assess the property in his territory. By so doing he hopes to enable his constituents to escape part of the county and state taxes and insure his own re-election. Without review by county and state boards of equalization, one precinct or township might not pay its fair share of the county and state tax. Inequalities of assessment of proper - ties within a township or precinct means that the owner of the under - valued property would escape some of his share of state, county, township, and school taxes. Table 4.— Assessed valuation 0/ tangible property in 12 Nebraska counties. 1 Value in millions of dollars Per cent of. all properly property esta.e estate P'°P"'y estate estate P"?"'? /&gt;.&lt;¦;. P.cl. P.ct. 1927 5 544 5124 S 297 5123 22.70 54.61 22.69 1928 541 126 297 118 23.30 54.88 21.82 1929 550 129 298 123 23.44 54.14 22.42 1930 544 128 294 122 23.50 54.08 22.42 1931 537 128 295 114 23.92 54.85 21.23 {j)32 444 109 242 93 24.65 54.45 20.90 1 Nebraska Tax Commissioners' Reports. Property assessment lists vary from year to year as shown in Table 3. From 1927 to 1931, the value of tangible property in Nebraska exceeded three billon dollars. In 1932, it declined to a little over two and one-half billion dollars. Farm real estate comprised a little more than 56 per cent of the total grand assessment rolls of the state. Personal property was never valued at more than 24 per cent of the total and town real estate never more than 21 per cent. Personal property assessments dropped more • Ibid., Sec. 77-1002. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Tax System of Nebraska rapid y than either farm or town real estate because of easier liquidation of such property by the owner and quicker adjustments in assessments to meet changing price situations when property-is assessed each year. Tible 4 shows the total assessed value of tangible property in the 12 coun ies studied to be greatest in 1929 and least in 1932. Farm real estate was 54.14 per cent o£ the total assessed value in 1929 and 54.88 per cent in IS2B. All three classes of property, farm real estate, town real estate, and |&gt;ersonal property, were assessed at much less in 1932 than in 1931. The jreatest decrease from! the highest point, $123,000,000 to $93,000,000, amounted to 24.4 per cent and was shown by personal property. Farm real estate) was second with a decline of 18.8 per cent, $298,000,000 to $242,000, - -000, "rom 1929 to 1932. Assessed values of town and city real estate fell less than either of the other two, being only 15.5 per cent lower in 1932 than in 1929. i ¦ Tible 3 shows that from 56 per cent in 1930 to 57.03 per cent in 1931 of th: total assessment roll for the state was farm, real estate. From 54 to 55 per cent of the assessment roll in the 12 counties of this study was farm real estate according to Table 4. As large as these percentages seem, they do not represent all of the property upon which farmers pay taxes. Farmer-owned tangible personal property must be added to farm real estate before a true picture is secured. As Nebraska assessment rolls have been made it is impossible to divide the 80 personal-property items listed, between farm and non-farm portions of our population. State reports do not si low how much of the assessed value of farm machinery, household goods, motor vehicles, livestock, grain, and other items are owned and the tsxes upon them paid by farmers. Such division is made more difficult because railroads, Pullman lines, j telephone and telegraph lines, and electrcal transmission lines pass through town and farm areas. Each taxing unit in which such [properties lie includes a portion of their value in its assessment roll. ! . ' In order to determine the assessed value of tangible property owned by farmers the method illustrated in Table 5 was used. Gage county figures have been used in! this table. The percentages of the different classes of property to farm areas and to towns were determined upon after consulting the tax commissioner and the county assessors in the 12 counties studied. Values of railroad property lying in farm areas were found by multiplying the number.of miles of each branch of each railroad found in farm territory by the assessed value per mile as deter - mined by the state board of equalization. The same process was followed for Pullman lines running the various counties. Necessary mile - ages were taken from the |tax commissioners' reports and from railroad time tables. Because Lancaster and Gage counties have larger percentages of town and city population than the other counties, franchises were divided 90 per cent to towns and 10 per cent to farm territory instead of the 80 per cent and 20 per cent used in the other 10 counties. ' The figures found in fable 6 were secured by applying the method outlined in Table 5. Since taxes levied for any year are based upon assess- </seg>
         <seg id="p012">12 2. TO &gt; ... o Table s. — Values used in determining the percentage of total tangible property owned by Gage county farmers. 5 I'rrn | 1927 | VII* | 192* | 1930 I 1931 [ 1932 _j - - , . - 1. Grand lolal of all tangible properly 570.383.4nM 569.ri56.1159 570.871.034 570.293.120 569.976.001 $58 457 445 ? 2. Value of tangible properly in cities and lowns . . 15.337.9(H) 14,723,940 15,278,030 15,261,0411 14,623,765 121408*280 P 3. Value of the part of railroads in farm territory ' (excludes terminals) 4,921.248 4.922.666 4.957.223 4,947.907 4 781962 4 083 064 5 1 4. Value of Pullmans for farm territory 17,403 18,409 20,537 19,410 16,743 '14474 . 5. Pipe lines in the county . 019*525 t_ 6. 80% of value of electric lines in county 189,096 244,572 254328 « 7. 80% of value of telephone and telegraph line, in '2 county 169,868 169.220 171.328 236,416 231.736 216,260 M 8. 70% of foreign-incorporated corporations 119,186 120,943 141.974 941,175* 28 980 *^ 9. 10% of the franchises for the county (used by 20% ' -1 all other counties except Lancaster) 1,078 906 14.018 12,752 12,056 12,644 tf&gt; 10. Non-farmer owned tangible properly (sum items 2 _; 'o 9) 20.566,683 19.956.084 20.585.110 20,666,621 20,852,009 18,037 555 R 11. Farmer-owned tangible properly (item 1 and item 10)... 49.816,800 49,699.975 50.285,924 49,626,499 49,123,992 40,419 890 3 12. Per cent of property owned by farmers (divide ' ' 2; item 11 by item 1) 70.78 71.35 70.95 70.60 70.20 69.14 __, 1 Includes pipe-line values. J_ X r </seg>
         <seg id="p013">'_.. . ¦:;." . Tax System of Nebraska ments made the preceding year, assessments for the years 1927 to 1932 arc used. They are shown for the state in Table 4. The last row of figures in Table 6 shows the percentages for all 12 counties for the period 1927 to 1932. The differences between these percentages and the corresponding figures found in Table 4 represent the part farm personal property is of the total assessment roll. The 12 county percentages found in the thirteenth line of Table 6 are lowej- than those for any counties except Thomas. Dawes, and Lancaster. The same reasons for the low percentages of farmer-owned property do not hold for these three counties. The presence of the City of Lincoln, with its large property assessment roll and the large mileages of valuable railroad property indicate why farm property makes up a relatively minor part of the total in Lancaster county. In 1927 city and village property ™™ JL^ CCnt of ¦»Blt?u«iMe property; in 1928, 69.27 per cent; in 1929, 68.95 per cent; in 1930, 69.10 per cent; in 1931, 68.49 per cent; and m 1932, 69.24 per cent of the total assessed value of tangible property in Lancaster county. 10 Table 6.—Percentage of tangible property owned by farmers in 12 \counties, 1927-1932. County IM7 [ | 1928 | 1929 | 1930 | 1931 | 1932 . ¦ State and County Taxes *&lt;*"* ........ 82.68 81.91; 80.93 ' •' 81.25 82 02 8690 Ca» ............... 76.48 77.60 77.43 77.39 7654 7535 Cumins 88.67 89.49 i 89.48 89 09 89Jfi MM " £*°« ¦•• • 'I- 81 n£* 70J3 71 OS 7W7 7152 £"»« 5339 54.84 54.53 .54.03 53 69 5145 £"&gt;""«¦ •••• 80.24 81.74 81.74 82.18 8225 8148 £**&#132; ,70.78 71.34 7055 70.60 7020 6914 H«mlfon &#132;..: . 81.06 .; 81.74 81.63 81J8 8173 8035 v coupria.:::::::: et.is i 62.71 6o."o S ; ifil I Township Taxes Cuming .......:..... 94.74 i 95.48 95.63 9538 9573 055s g»«f • •-¦ 90.H 90.49: ¦»« - M.46 90.78 90J4 Hirhn ............ 67.80 169.37 69.67 69.62 6952 6811 V'"&lt;* •¦• 76-52 j 76-88 77.07 77J1 76J3 wjl High values for city and village property do not explain the Thomas county situation. In this county, three conditions help in such explanation. First, the county is small, and over 79,000 acres of its total area are in - cluded in the Bessey National Forest, thus exempting it from property tax. In the second place, farm lands of the county are assessed at low values: $331 an acre in 1927; |3J2 in 1928; $334 in 1929; $337 in 1930- $338 in 1931; and $2.82 in 1932." The third reason is the large percentage of the value of tangible property,represented by railroad property. In 1927, 46.62 per cent of all tangible property in Thomas county was railroad "Bawd upon city and village valuations found in ihe abstract of assessment books in the Slate Tar O.mmm,oncr', office at Lincoln and upon the grand total of the tangible propcXtti roll found in Statement I of thn Annual State Tax Commissioner,' report! for 1927 to 1932, inclusive "Nebraska Tax Commissioners' Reports, 1927 to 1932, statement I. </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 property; in 1928, 43.35 per cent; in 1929, 43.75 per cent; in 1930, 42.56 per cent; in 1931, 42.27 per cent, and in 1932, 44.52 per cent. 12 Although Dawes county lands are valued at considerably more per acre than Thomas county lands, they are among the lowest acre values in the state. In 1927 they were assessed at $10.14 an acre; in 1928 at (10.15; in 1929 at $10.20; in 1930 at 510.16; in 1931 at $10.17; and in 1932 at $8.44.'' City and village property values in Dawes county varied from 27.91 per cent of the total assessed tangible property roll in 1927 to 30.55 per cent in 1932. v The railroad property ranged from 16.11 per cent in 1929 to 18.55 per cent in 1927. I*'1*' The last two classes of property accounted for from 45.09 per cent in 1929 to 47.53 per cent in 1932. Table 7. — Assessed value of tangible farm property per capita farm population for county and state taxes} i j j — Hank 1127 I I9M 1929 ( 1930 1931 1932 1 ! : l 1. Cuming' Cumins* Can Can Can Can 55.14H 55.14* 55.125 54.919 54.529 53,861 2. Cast Can Cumins' Cuminw* Cuming" Cuming* 5.1"! 5.» M 5.110 4.876 4.771 3,827 \. Lancaster Hamilton Lancaster Hamilton Hamilton Lancaster -t. I&lt;Jl 4.306 4.37H 4.336 4.311 3,477 ¦I. Rimillon iMihJ.irr Hamilton Ljncailer Ldttcaiter Hamilton 4.175 4.2H 4.3 M 4.336 4.306 3,475 5. (iJBC* C,a s c* Cage 1 Gage' Gage* Gage* 4.1*1 4.1127 4.(161 3.994 3,937 3,227 6. Bimne Dakota Dakota Dakota Boatte Dakota 3.834 3.RMI 3.703 3.656 3.647 3,091 7. Dakota ttaune Rontie llootie Dakota Boone 3.543 t.75n 3.6211 3.623 3.616 2,954 8. Valley- Valley" Valley- Valley* Valley* Valley* -'.716 2.75! 2.780 2,801 2,718 2,186 9. Dawcs Dawcs Dawes Dawes Dawes Dawei 2/.7(&gt; 2.664 2.631 2.573 2.484 1,965 10. Marian" Harlan* Harian" Harlan" Harlan* Harlan* 2.41' 2.461 2.485 2.474 2,41] 1,947 11. Frontier Frontier Fiontter Frontier Frontier Frontier 2-I'VI 2.H5 2.25J 2,348 2,328 1,895 12. Thnmai Tlinm.is Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomas 1.930 1.97) 2.024 2.021 1,893 1,470 I Bjird upon values found in arriving at percentages used in Talile 6 and farm population. Stjrrcd counties art the four supervisor counties; italic type indicates near-by commissioner counties. The values of farm property assessed against farmers of the twelve counties not only vary between counties but are different for each county from year to year. In Table 7 is shown the average value of tangible farm property assessed against each farm person in each county. These counties are arranged in order from the county with the highest average value of farm property for each person to the county with the lowest average value for each person. The table presents data for the years 1927 to 1932. Supervisor counties are designated by asterisks and the near-by com - " Ihid. Otitjincil by ifiuiling item 78 by the grand total for the county. II Ibid.. Statement I. "See f.x.Uioit 10. v Nebraska lax Commissioners' Reports. 1927 to 1932. Obtained by dividing item 78 by the graml lutal fur the counts. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">.-.,.. Tax System of Nebraska . missioner counties to be compared with the supervisor counties by italic type- - . ;; ". :'..¦ ; . ...¦•. , . . ¦:. ; Vjalues of tangible property per farm person in each county were lower in 1933 than in the earlier years of the period. The decline in values was very great from 1931 to 1933. Less property is owned per person in the four counties located in the western half of the state and in which one - crop farming prevails. Harlan county was the only supervisor county whose farmers consistently owned more property than its paired commis - sioner county. ¦:¦;¦ : . Table 8 shows the average values of farm lands per farm person. Changes in rank of the different counties did not occur very readily when Table B.— Assessed value offarm land''pet-farm person for county and state taxes} , Rank 1927 1928 ¦ 1929 1930 1931 1932 '• C°" c"&gt; Cats Cats Caa Ca,, $4,678 ..; M.fi» .: $4,626 $4,408 $1,398 »3,W1 2. Ciiming* Coming* Cumins' Cumins' ..Cumins' Cuniing' 4,563 , .4,524 4,487 1228 4.260 3,529 3' *?«?" Li"£{'"' U»«"«r UncMer Hamilton 3,959 3,953 3,972 3,983 3,944 3,228 .&lt;.. Hamilton Hamillon Hamilton Hamillon Hamillon Uitcatur 3,7/2 3,832 3,889 3,916 3,943 3 056 5' %"-;--". "?S!? Dakou Ga ß c« Gage' Gage' ¦3,665 3,616 3,570. 3,519 3,535 2 952 "' ¦¦'?35* ¦'¦¦¦««' :ft B C Dakota .! ;; Dakota Dakota ¦ 3,548 3,535 . 3,527 . . 3,471 3,476 2,914 7" ?°f.°,f B?"A S&lt;""" Botmc . ' Boont Boonc ¦.: 3,389 3,347 3,306 3.259 3,283 2,745 8- -^*S: .¦¦;YJ"g 1 Valky' . Valley' ¦' Valley' Valley ¦ • . , 2,307 2,318 2,330 2,336 2,299 1952 '" i'liu' '?^ ¦-' ¦¦"¦•'?,'!? Dawcs ¦¦¦¦•Dawn Dawcs : 2,304 2,259 2,219 2,166 2,161 1,792 10. H"rjan« H"'a"* Harlan' - HarUn' Harlan' Harlan' 2,156 .2,124 ..-.. 2,124 2,084 2,092 1,734) 11. Frontier FrentiVr Frontier Frontier Frontier Frontier 1,668 1,649 1,709 . 1,861 1,870 1,558 ' n. .Thomai Thomas: Thomas. Thomas Thomas Thomai 1,521 .1,506 1,493 . 1,486 1,429 l.l™" 1 Based _upon values found in arriving at percentages used in Table 6 and farm population. Starred counties are the four supervisor counties; italic type indicates near-by commissioner counties. farm land was used alonej Three reasons seem to explain the greater constancy of rank: (1) farm population changes very slowly, (2) farm real esate is assessed but once in four years, and (3) numbers of the different farm personal property items and values per item fluctuate more than the number of acres assessed. For two of the four pairs of counties the commissioner county had higher values of tangible farm property per person than did the super - visor county. In one pair the reverse condition held. For the fourth pair the supervisor county ranked above the commissioner county in two years and below it in four years.] Commissioner counties appear to have more tangible farm property per tapita of farm population than do supervisor counties. In but one case (|Harlan and Frontier) did the value of farm </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 land for each farm person in the supervisor county exceed the corresponding ; value for the commissioner county for the period. The other three pairs show greater values for the commissioner county. The percentages of farm tangible property represented by farm. land {' are shown in Table 9. When this table is considered in connection with ' Table 8, a partial cause of the changes in percentage of value represented by real estate is shown. Values of land remained relatively constant for , the first three years or until land was re-assessed in 1930. The 1930 land I assessments were reduced in eight of the twelve counties. The exceptions i are Lancaster, Hamilton, Valley, and Frontier counties. The continuance : of the depression after 1930 led to further reductions in assessments and s by 1932 farm real estate assessments had been lowered a great deal. Re- ¦ ductions in land valuations were not as great as those in the various items \ of farm personal property. Nebraska cattle were assessed at about $10.00 , Table 9. — Percentage of assessed farmer-owned tangible property that is { represented by farm real estate (subject to county and state taxes). \ County 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 Boonc 88.39 89.25 91.10 89.95 90.02 92.92 \ Can 91.71 91.61 90.26 89.61 91.07 92.75 I Cumins «B.M 87.88 87.81 86.71 89.29 92.21 : Dakota 95J7 93.68 96.41 91.91 96.13 94.27 i Dawci . 86.21 84.80 84.34 84.18 87.00 91.20 '[¦ Frontier 82.21 78.74 75.85 79.26 80.33 82.22 ' Gage 87.60 87.78 86.85 88.11 89.79 91.48 i Hamilton . 90.35 88.99 89.14 90.31 91.46 92.89 i\ Harlan . K9.13 86.24 85.47 84.24 86.77 89.06 i Lancaitcr 90.16 93.83 90.73 91.86 91.59 87.89 C Thomai 78.81 76.29 73.76 73.53 75.49 77.96 { Valley 84.21 84.26 83.81 83.40 84.58 89.30 i 12 counticj . 89.05 89.15 88.39 88.28 88.54 91.20 j" per head less in 1931 than in 1930 and $11.00 per head less in 1932 than j in 1931. During this period the numbers of cattle fluctuated very little. • The assessed values of hogs in Nebraska were $22,000,000 in 1930, $17,000,- I 000 in 1931, and $8,000,000 in 1932, or $10.78 per head for hogs in 1930, \ 58.77 in 1931, and only $3.92 in 1932. Other items of personal property % owned by farmers fluctuated almost as much as cattle and hogs but were f;i less important. The changes in values of farm personal property were much t greater than for farm land and hence land assessments assumed more ;. importance in the total value of the farm property in 1932 than in 1930. f That part of the tangible property of township counties owned by \ farmers and subject to county and state taxes is shown in the upper part j of Table 6. Where all city and village property in a county is levied upon i for township purposes, the percentages found in the upper part of this •!' table apply for the township levies. However, that condition did not exist \ : in Gage and Cuming counties, where the property in the city of Beatrice in | Gage county and of West Point and Wisner in Cuming county is exempted [, from township taxes. Property in all other towns of these counties is &gt;; subject to township levies. The assessed value of property exempted from £•' township levies in these three towns must be subtracted from the total M </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Tax System of Nebraska value of property in the county before it is possible to determine the part farmer-owned property is of the total property subject to township taxes. Removal of the exempted: town property in these counties caused a marked increase in the relative importance of farmer-owned tangible property. Percentages in the lower part of Table 6 show how much of the property that was taxed by townships was owned by farmers. Fanners of Gage county pay from 19,15 per cent to 21.40 per cent more of the township tax than they pay of the county tax and those of Cum ing county from 5.99 to 6.73 per cent more. Farmers residing in township counties own most of the property that is subject to township taxes. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Chapter lll—Levies I Making the tax levies is the second step in taxing procedure. The levy | tor each taxing unit is prepared independently of the others. Before a f levy can be made, it is necessary to determine "the amount of revenue re- ; quired and not provided from some other source." * This amount is then ; divided by the total value of all property subject to the tax, which amount } is secured from the tax lists that are prepared by the county clerk from the assessors' rolls. The resulting quotient is the rate of the property tax j for the taxing unit involved and is expressed as mills on the dollar. Farm I property may be subject to levies by four taxing units—state, county, school districts, and special tax districts. Farms in supervisor counties have a : fifth levy—the township levy. .! The framers of the Constitution of Nebraska thought it wise to curb j the power of subordinate tax units in making levies. County officials can- i not levy in excess of 50 cents on each $100 of assessed valuation without j submitting the proposed levy to the voters of the county. 2 Township I officials cannot levy more than 3 mills for all purposes. 3 j Levies are seldom the same for the different taxing bodies. Table 10 .j and Figure 3 show the amounts levied by each of the taxing units from j 1927 to 1933. Throughout this period Nebraska schools were responsible •] for more of the levy on property than any other tax unit and for almost j as much as all others combined. School and state levies were lower in 1928 j than in 1927, those for counties and cities and villages higher and town- i ship levies about the same. City and village and township levies decreased in 1929. All the other levies increased until total levies were $1,500,000 j above 1928. Reductions of approximately $500,000 each by the state, | counties, and schools more than offset increases by township and city and village units, making a total reduction of about $750,000 in 1930. All tax - ing units over which farmers had much control began to show sizable reductions by 1931. State levies for that year were reduced more than j 51.000,000, those for counties over $500,000, school levies over $1,000,000, \ and townships $100,000. People in cities and villages had not begun to j (eel the depression as much as farmers in 1931 and increased their levies ( more than §1,000,000. Without exception every taxing unit reduced its i taxes in 1932 and 1933. Schools made the greatest reduction, decreasing I from 25.9 millions in 1931 to 18.7 millions in 1933. Heavier reduction in i the levies by the state had occurred earlier in this period; hence less re- | duction was possible for this unit. Counties did not make as large cuts as f schools or the state but did make rather large reductions. The heaviest \ percentage reduction took place in township levies, where less than 37 per f. cent as much money was levied in 1933 as in 1927. ?• - ¦ is 'I, o Virtue. The L'nitmily nf Nebraska Tax Primer, Chapter V, page I!, October, 1932. Ncbrajka '•', Agricultural Experiment Station. Lincoln. Nebraska. #' 'Compiled Statures of Nebraska. 1929. Aritcle 8. Section 5. p. 54. '''¦¦ 1 lbtd.. Chapter 2ft. Article 2. Secticin 26-259, p. 598. fc- 18 </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Tax System of Nebraska Table 10.— Governmental subdivision levies. 1 . Tangible : ~" - snd in* •inglblc '«'' '«« 192? 1930 1931 1932 1933 property :' Tout $63,914,948 555.744.612 557,225,596 $56,525,535 554.894.848 $48,306,170 $41,417,767 Slate ••• 11,862,474 6,567,268 7,879.329 7,461,204 6.393,936 6,128,000 5 081,779 County ...... 11,017,263 11,141,247 .11,456,280 . 10,894,030 10,311,386 8,696,221 8170,934 School 30,351,819 26,444,500 27,127,274 26,894,992 25,902,030 22,625,361 181760,559 City and -, ¦ village .... 9,061,253 9.970,316 9,163.493 9,589,016 10,695,041 9,706,921 8803432 Towiuhip ¦¦¦¦ 1,622.139 1,621,281 1,599,220 1,686,293. 1,592,455 1,149,667 60l!()63 1 Nebraska Tax Commissioner's Reports, 1927 to 1933. Judging by the results shown in Table 10 and Figure 2, property-tax reduction was more speedily accomplished for the state than for other units. Much of this reduction was made possible because of the yield of the increased gasoline tax during the years following 1928. This was also MILLION-"--.. ."'" ' 'DOLLARS ¦¦-. 35 ¦¦—! ' : ¦¦---' ;' 30- '' ';';' "-'.' ¦2a" - I 7r?Zui_LToNS 1928 1929 ,93° *93, 1932 1933 '"* of dollars 639 55-7 57? 56* 54i9 48.3' 41.4 ? township Estate __ city and village __ county ¦ school Fig. 2.—Property tax levied by taxing units. true for the county units, which shared in this tax after 1928. The other taxing units were unable to tap any such productive source as the gas tax. Nebraskans postponed heavy reduction of school levies as long as it was reasonably possible, yet when convinced of the necessity for such reductions, made heavy cuts. Township levies remained fairly constant until 1931, although they declined almost one millon dollars during the next two years. This heavy reduction probably meant almost no road work on many miles of township roads. Levies for cities and villages did not decline as fast or as much as those for any.other taxing units. They employed no especially productive new sources of public funds and probably had demands for relief as the depression lengthened and increased in severity. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 School levies accounted for between 45 and 48 per cent of the total property tax for the 93 counties of the state according to Table 11 and Figure 3. County levies were second in importance, being 17 to 20 per cent of the total levy. City and village levies made up 14 per cent of the total in 1927, then gradually increased to 21 per cent in 1933. The PCHCtNT 100 -I i —l | 1 | 1 ¦ 1 | 1 | , | 1 90 ;':•: y.y !¦:'¦; :•':'• ;):j: :'•:&gt; ;|v 60 Ig H B| so - B H H ¦ H H _H 40 - H H H H H jo H H H H H co - H I H H H io- H H H H H Q j __¦—^b—^h—^i—§¦—^B_J__i 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 H SCHOOL __3 COUNTY ? TOWNSHIP --i-CITY AND VILLAGE (HI STATE Fig. i. —Percentages of property tax levied by taxing units. importance of township levies decreased even more than state levies, being 5 per cent of the total in 1927 and 2 per cent in each of the four years, 1930 to 1933. Table 11.— Division of the property tax dollar among governmental-sub - division levies. 1 city Year State County School a*:d Township Total village P.cl. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.cl. P.a. 1917 19 17 45 14 5 100 1928 12 20 47 18 3 100 i 1929 13 20 48 16 3 100 I 1930 13 20 48 17 2 100 ¦ 1931 12 19 48 19 2 100 ! 1932 13 18 47 20 2 100 •' 1933 12 20 45 21 2 100 !. 1 Nebraska Tax Commissioners' Reports, 1927 lo 1933. . f </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Tax System of Nebraska Table 12.— Percentages of levy for each taxing unit of the 27 township . counties. 1 . -"'-'"-/..'.- Year State County School. I Cit,»nd I Towll , Mp • I I I .- - ¦ | village | ¦ P-a. Pm, Pxt. "¦¦'•¦; Pm. Pjtt, low ?i«l 16&lt;B . •?I.TO -11.82 : 8.58 MS 13.07 18.80 45.59 12.93 9 61 1929 13.43 . - 16.58- 40 26 2158 «15 I^o 14.31 18.29 4459 13 08 9 73 '«' 13.12 17.06 45.91 14.04 9 87 1932 14.69 . 16.70 45.83 14 38 840 "&gt;33 14.37 18.26 46.82 15J28 5.27 mi«^5 b™o^l9ll^93?™i"'°933 S' RcPOr"- S'alCmC"' M'" 1927 ' 1928 ' 19M- »"&lt;! 1930, and State- Table 13.—Percentages of levy for each taxing unit of the 66 non-township counties. 1 ,: .'.-¦ year Suic I County School Cityand 1 - - - village p-«- P-«. P.n. p.n. "27 17.45. 17.46 ' 4993 15 16 J928 .; • 11.22 20.50 4824 2004 . 1929 13.95 : 21.81 51.13 1311 2?? !?•'! 1"1 48M 8.68 !J3l 11.03 19.50 47.72 2175 ¦1931 11.89 18.52 4724 nil ¦ - »33 . ¦¦• iM7. axil g^ Hil m cm^ffoM9j"l9?2?ald i l9n3"f RCP°"i- S'a'™C"t " /or 1H7 ' )M8 ' »».-»d .WJO, and Srate- Table 14.— Levies for 27 township counties and 66 non-township counties 1927t01933y ¦¦¦¦¦' Year | State | County | Schools | City and villa B e | Towiuhip' | Total : -' Levies for 27 Township Counties |::::;: USSS'-.^SiS .-.SJffig life gg r&lt;gf I S"« ( County [ School. | Xity and vilh E c ( T0,,! Levies for 66 Non-Township Counties ' f» 8 204805.37 19 233 866.31 1932J9692 P'K'S 1930 ...... 4^81^734 7.J8.025.94 19166515S S MlMWeli '"3 3,441,151.11 ..¦f.WilmW 13,'421,'6«J5 7.'061,'ti0,a lo.'oif.jzlj? mcn^^^l^atjfe^^ SB': ITC"' "for 1927- 19M- IM9- and IHO- a"" S»«- Grouping the counties of the state according to the type of county organization before considering the relative importance of the various taxing units furnished a good picture of the relative importance of town - ship units in those counties having this form of organization. Such </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 INOM ' NUMttM t 120 r ¦ 1 "° ' /^""^ V TAX PAYING ABILITY (00 C- rr^ \ 90 ¦ \-—\V i . \ \ —TOTAL TAX \\\ 70 ¦ \ \ \ \\ / '! GROSS FARM INCOMt ) \ / i OF NEBRASIVA FARMS \ \ / i \ v i 40 \ *- | ' ! i 30 I 1 L_ l I I I ! 1927 1928 1929 1930 19.31 1932 1933 j 1-u.. 4.—lndex ut uix-paunn ability of Nebraska farmers (in- \ iU-x o( toui! taxes divided by index oi jjross farm income) \ O {&gt;27= UW). j. separation and grouping is made in Tables 12, 13, and 14. Township f levies in the 27 supervisor counties were 5.27 to 9.87 per cent of the total f, property tax levy for these counties. Other taxing units were of less im- !' portance for these counties than for the entire state. State levies have £ about the same relative importance for the 66 commissioner counties as «' for the entire state. Counties of this group show a slight increase when * the percentages found in Tables 11 and 13 are compared. Schools and : cities and villages were relatively more important for commissioner counties i than for all the counties of the state. County units in commissioner counties perform practically the same functions performed by the county and township in those counties with ¦.;: supervisors. Table 15 shows the part of. the total levy required to perform ' these functions. In those 66 counties having commissioners, from 17.46 | ; . per cent to 21.81 per cent of the levy was needed. Twenty-seven supervisor i' counties required from 23.27 per cent to 28.41 per cent of the total levy, f Commissioner counties require a smaller portion of the total levy for f </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Tax System of Nebraska "TV \ COUNTY —-^ \ \ \ \ TOTAL rV \V 60 V SCHOOL—"^VV \ ,^-x.^ TOWNSHIP—\ \S. ¦;.¦::•; V -n \ - .' ':- -. so :- - - ¦:¦. ¦ ¦.-.¦¦¦¦¦."""-v \ '¦¦¦•; STATE—X^ 1»27 1121 «» M IMI |932 1933 Fig. s.—lndexes of tax levies by taxing units (1927 = 100). .: these functions than do supervisor counties. It is impossible to make comparisons of the services rendered the people by each type of county. Citizens are vitally interested in knowing how tax levies have kept pace with their individual incomes. Table 16 and Figures 4 and 5 show indexes of taxes for the different taxing units and indexes of gross farm income, and a ratio of index of gross farm income to total tax. The index of gross farm income is used as a measure of the economic condition of tanners of the; state. The, base year for these indexes is 1927. Gross farm income was down 4.5 points in 1928, then rose 5.7 in 1929. From 1929 income of Nebraska farmers fell until the low point, 36.8, was reached in 1932. Improved prices of farm products resulted in a rise of 4.0 points in As farm, products lose their ability to purchase the. things farmers wish to buy, farmers can do one of two things: cither quit purchasing certain articles or substitute less expensive goods for them. They did some of both from 1927 to 1933. Reducing taxes is just a way of decreasing expenditures for services obtained. The ratio of the index of total taxes to the index of gross farmj income is a means of measuring the ability of farmers to </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Table 15.— Comparison of county and county-township levies, based upon percentage of total levies. 27 rownship counties Sixly-six commis- Year I _. .. I County and jioncr Cnumy | Township [ low nship counties I&lt;)&gt;- 16.69 8.58 25.27 17.46 1928 18.80 9.61 28.41 20.50 1929 16.58 5.15 24.73 21.81 1930 18.29 9.73 28.02 19.71 1931 17.06 9.87 26.93 19.50 1912 16.70 «.« 25.10 18.52 I'm 11U6 5J7 23^ 10.18 pay taxes from their income. This index shows farmers had 9.5 per cent more tax-paying pwer in 1928 than in 1927 and 13.1 per cent more in 1929 than in 1927. By 1930, gross farm income had fallen so much faster than total taxes that farmers possessed 5.7 per cent less tax-paying ability than in 1927. The low point in this index occurs in 1932, when gross farm income was but 36.8 per cent of 1927 and when farmers had but 48.7 per cent as much tax-paying power as in 1927. Further declines in the total tax index combined with an increase in the index of gross farm income raised the tax-paying power of farmers by 14.3 points for 1933. Table 16.— Indexes of tax levies by subdivisions and farmers' ability to pay, Nebraska, 1927-1933. 1927 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 Governmental subdivision 1 Total levy 100 87.2 89.6 88.4 85.9 75.6 64.8 State levy 100 55.4 66.4 62.9 52.3 50.4 41.8 County levy 100 101.1 104.0 98.9 93.6 78.9 74.2 School levy 100 88.2 88.2 89.1 84.6 73.4 60.4 City and vtlla S e levy 100 110.0 101.1 105.8 115J 105.0 95.5 Township 100 100.0 98.6 104.0 98.2 70.9 37.0 Rural elementary school d.strict 1 100 101.3 101.1 100.1 87.6 71.0 57.2 Farmers' ability to pay Gross farm income &gt; 100 95.5 101J 83.4 55.9 36.8 40.8 Purchasing power of Nebraska farm products' 100 98.9 102.1 88.3 69.2 57.4 58.5 Ratio of index of gross farm income of Nebraska farm - ers to index of total taxes levied 100 109.5 113.1 94.3 65.1 48.7 63.0 1 Nebraska Tax Commissioners' Reports, 1927 to 1933, Statement 15, Governmental Subdivision Levies and Taxes. ' Computed from figures obtained from the office of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction, Lincoln, Nebraska. J Computed from "Gross income from farm products by Hales," U. S. Department or Agriculture * it. C. Fillcy, Effects of Inflation ajid Deflation upon Nebraska Agriculture, 1914-1932. Nebr. Agr. Eip. Mi Res. bul. 71, 1934. Basal on Table 4. pace 12. A study of the indexes shown in Figure 5 shows how each taxing unit reacted to the condition of farmers. During this period the index of city and village levies remained above 100 with the exception of 1933, when it fell to 95.5. This happened at a time when farm income was falling rapidly. Unemployment among city laborers did not become a major problem for some time after farm income declined. Gradual increases in </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Tax System of Nebraska the numbers of unemployed in towns led to increased expenditures and heavier taxes for relief by towns. Because so much of the school levy is for high-school purposes and because most high schools are located in cities and villages and are under the control of the same group of voters who levy city and village taxes, total school levies might be expected to remain fairly high even in face of reduced farm income. The index of gross farm income reflects conditions during the entire year. Before any reduction resulting from decreased in - come can take place, voters must have a chance to act upon the school budget for the following year. This means a lag of at least one year be - fore the effect of lower income is reflected in reduced levies and several years before there is an effect on taxes paid. Farm income was reduced from 1929 to 1930. The school budget for 1930 had been approved the previous June and the amount so approved levied as a tax upon the property of the district. 5 . . ™ ' The trend in rural school levies is shown by the data in Table 16. During the years 1927 to 1930, rural school levies remained at 100 or slightly above. The index of gross farm income and the index of pur - chasing power of Nebraska farm products remained close to 100 for the years 1927 to 1929. In 1930 both of these indexes fell, the former to 83.4 and the latter to 88.3. As a result of the reduction in their well being, farmers voted lower rural school levies for 1931. Each year of decline in the two indexes of fanners' ability to pay resulted in decreased rural school levies for the year following. When the index numbers of purchasing power of Nebraska farm products are compared with the next year's index of _rural school levies a remarkably close relationship is shown. The two indexes were as follows: purchasing power for 1930, 88.3, and rural f ht™» ' *n 3l ' 5 716; Purchasing P°wer for 1931, 69.2, and rural schools Sw wo7LO; and PurchasinS Power for 1932, 57.4, and rural schools for County levies remained at 100 or more until 1930. In 1929 the county began to share in the revenue from the gasoline tax. At the time the levy was made for 1929 the gasoline tax law had not been changed to permit county participation in this tax. After 1929 county levies were reduced both because farm incomes were low and because the gasoline tax was proving a good source of revenue. ; r ¦ f Township levies are made mainly for the purpose of providing a system or local highways for farmers. The maintenance of a good local highway system must seem quite essential to farmers, if the way they continue high township levies after farm incomes decline is any indication of values placed on governmental services. When farmers decided to cut their levies, townships were cut more severely than any other unit. ¦'¦"'.: 1nJ927 the state levy was much larger than those for the years 1928 to 1933. State levies for each of the years from 1923 to 1926, inclusive, were too small to meet the obligations incurred by the state during these years. Creditors of the state were forced to carry these unpaid balances as </seg>
         <seg id="p026">i Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 open book accounts. Unpaid accounts from the previous year were paid § out of the first collections of the state during the succeeding year. Because \ state levies were not large enough to cover expenses each year, the amount \ carried as unpaid accounts increased. "To take care of this, a redemption &lt; tax of 1.50 mills was levied for 1927, which increased these receipts during \ 1928 by more than ten millions."" Three factors operated to make possible a reduction in state levies after 1927: j 1. Removal of the deficit by the heavy collections in 1928, J 2. An increase in gasoline taxes, and i. 3. A reduction in spending forced upon the different state offices. Table 17.— Rant\ of 12 counties in per capita levies. ¦'11l I ¦ Hank ' 1927 1928 1929 I 1930 1931 1932 ! I / ! I 1. Cuming' Cuming* Valley* Cuming* Cuming* Thomas 515.12 515.511 5H.44 514.93 513.69 Sll.BB 2. Valley- Valley* Cuming* Thomas Valley* Valley* 14.53 13.94 13.84 14.73 13.59 10.35 I. Harlan* Harlan* Thomas Valley* Thomas Cuming* 1292 12.59 13.49 14.58 13.51 10.21 4. Thnnu- Thomas Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* 12.38 12.75 12.64 12.77 12.26 9.00 5. Gage* Hamilton Frontier Hamilton Cass Cass 977 1071 12.00 10.81 10.42 8.33 6 Hamilton Gage* Hamilton Frontier Frontier Hamilton 9.49 9.20 11.48 10.25 10.15 7.73 7. Dakota Dakota Gage* Gage* Hamilton Gage* 9.32 9.17 9.98 10.18 9.76 7.45 8. Boone Baone Dakota Cass Gage* Frontier I 9.09 9.00 9.11 9.95 9.05 7.37 9. Cast Cass Boone Boone Dakota Dakota | 8.96 870 8.93 9.23 7.57 6.04 10. Frontier Dawes Cats Dakota Boone Dawes i 8.64 8.24 8.89 8.99 7.06 5.24 11. Dawes Frontier Dawes Dawes Dawes Boone '{ 5.75 6.24 8.33 5.92 6.61 5.16 j 12. Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster I 3.59 1.56 3.40 3.55 3.63 4.39 i Started counties are the (our supervisor counties, and Ihe levy includes township and county levies; i iulic type indicates four commiisioncr counties which arc near-by and compared wilh supervisor counties. The reduction in levies must have been too great, because the 1929 k state levy was raised to 66.42 per cent of 1927. The year 1930 found the ' downward trend of the state levy resumed. Its low point came in 1933 at 41.82 per cent of 1927. '¦ In general it seems as though those levies over which farmers have the most prompt control respond to changes in farm income most prompdy. People show less reluctance about reducing levies for those taxing units that are more remote from them and whose spending may affect them less. After farm income has been reduced, a lag of one year will ensue | before a corresponding reduction in a farmer-controlled levy can take place. | Yearly rankings of each of the twelve counties in levies per person are $ shown in Table 17. Those counties that are starred are the supervisor (v counties. In these counties the per-capita figure beneath each county name f; " Slate Auditor', Report, 1928, Nebraska, p. 4. C </seg>
         <seg id="p027">: . Tax System of Nebraska is based upon the combined county and township levy. For the other counties, only the county levies were used in determining the levies per capita. The counties whose names are italicized are near-by commis. sioner counties being compared with the supervisor counties. In, the first hve years a supervisor countyhad the heaviest levies per person. In every year three of the first four counties were supervisor counties and in no year was one of the four near-by commissioner counties included in the four counties with the heaviest levies. The fourth supervisor county, Gage had lower levies than the near-by commissioner county, with the heaviest peropita levies in four of. the six years. During the next to the last year, Table 18.— Ran{ of 12 counties in total property taxes levied per acre, county levies only. Rank 1927 1928 ¦¦¦ 1929 1930 1931 Ml 1. Un^r &lt;_ &#132;_ =7 LfT ¦21 •:• :- Dakota Dakota Dakota . Dakota Can Cos, f* •"¦ -55 .55 . .54 .43 &amp;':¦¦ *&amp; . *&amp; Cak :¦ ¦.B*s:];':.: ?*s ¦*" G*Si Ham"9°" Hamij}J n : G% . C'&lt;*' G^« 5, HamUuin G&gt;^ ; ¦ GajjJ . H.miUon ¦ . Ihraiton Hamih'n 6. Curnrng- [. Boon^ Cimbg. Cumin,;' .: ' Cuming* 7 r ¦¦; a,™.-¦•; -...a-y . ¦ c um^. Bo^ : Bo&lt; J Bm " 8, V a l^ V Val^,. VaUy- yjg. yj^. y^. 9. Ha^- Harian- Hartan- . ; HaWan- HaiL HarW - ¦io.-v..-ft.«ftr:...¦.; : .d&gt;«« ¦..¦¦¦¦ KB,;*,. . F«,»;&amp; f ¦•¦;¦¦¦ fnw^r ¦•-¦ ,„„;", Starred counties arc the four iupeivitot counties, and the levy include! county !«•!,« ™I.' Julie we indicate / m , commoner counties which are ncar-hy and compared wiil,™SentaJ Su«fa! two of the near-by commissioner counties had larger levies than Gaec courity. Lancaster county had the lowest levies for each person through - out the period. In both Lancaster and Gage counties, the two that had the lowest lewes for each person in their group, large cities, Lincoln and Beatrice, and a great deal of corporation property are found. None of the other counties.has much corporation property. By statutes a minimum number of county officials must be provided. This necessitates hieher levies to pay the costs of county government in those counties where the assessed value of property is low. During the years 1927 and 1928, all four of the near-by commissioner counties studied were among the five counties with the lowest levies for each person. In 1929, 1930, and 1932, three of the four commiss oner counties were among the five counties with lowest per-capita levies. </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 \ Frontier and Cass counties were the only two near-by commissioner coun- [ ties ranking above eighth. Population per square mile has a direct bearing upon tax levies per acre. : This is brought out when county tax levies per acre, shown in Table 18, j are compared with population per square mile, as shown in Figure 1. Those counties with the greatest population density have the highest levies per acre. Lancaster county had more people per square mile and the high - est property-tax levy throughout the period. Thomas county had the fewest people per square mile and the lowest tax per acre. Table 19.—Ran{ of 12 counties in total property taxes levied per acre, total county and township levies. Kink ' 1927 1928 1929 I 1930 ! 1931 1932 1 Lwt-iMlfr Lutuj.irr lancantr Lancaster Lancaster Lancjsta 5 .67 5 .07 S .65 S .69 S .72 S. SS 2. Cuminc* Cumins* Gape* Cuming* Cass Cass .59 .60 .56 .59 .54 .43 3. Dakota Dakota Dakota Gage* Cuming* Gage* .54 .55 .55 .57 .54 .41 4 Gacc* Gjcc* Cuming* Dakota Gage* Cumins* .54 .51 .54 .55 .51 .40 5 Cats Cj« Cass Cass Dakota Dakota .47 .45 .46 .52 .47 33 6. Vjllrv* Hamilton Hamilton Hamilton Valley* Valley* 39 .39 .41 .39 36 .28 7. Hamilton Valley* Valley* Valley* Hamilton Hamilton .35 .37 .39 .39 .34 .27 8 Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* .33 .32 .32 .32 Jl .23 9 Boonc Boone Boojte Boone Boone Boon? .30 .30 .30 .31 JM .18 10 Frontier Dawci Fmniicr Frontier Frontier Frontier .12 .11 .16 .14 .14 .10 U. Dawes Frontier Dawes DaweJ Dawes Diwcs .08 .09 .11 .08 .09 .07 12. Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomai .OS 06 .06 .06 .06 .05 Starred tourMici are the four supervisor counties, and the levy includes township and county Itv'ro; italic npc indicates (our commissioner counties which arc near-by and compared with supervisor counliej. The inclusion of township levies with those of counties in supervisor counties changes the rank of several counties according to Table 19. The data in this table do not run counter to those of Table 18 although increased costs are shown for all supervisor counties. It can still be said that counties with the most people per square mile have the greatest levies per acre for i local roads and for county use. j Comparisons of the various groups of counties in Table 19 show two of the near-by commissioner counties and two of the supervisor counties among the first five counties every year. Two of the near-by commissioner and two of the supervisor counties are in the next five ranking counties five of the six years. Since the same state and county mill levies apply to all property in a ; county regardless of whether it is located in town or country, agriculture | would bear the same proportion of the county levy as the assessed value | </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Tax System of Nebraska ¦¦•-. •'¦¦ " ' '.'•••' ' - ' ¦¦-¦¦ -: .. ¦ ¦ .'•¦ ¦ ¦ ¦" . - ' " '".. ': '- ¦ .;.['• \ of farmer-owned tangible.property was of the total assessment roll. By multiplying the amount of the county levy by the percentages found in Table 6, the amount of the county levy made against farmer-owned tangible property was determined. This figure was then divided by the farm popula - tion to secure the values found in Table 20. In this able counties are arranged in descending order for each year. Dakota county remained first Table 20.—Per-capita levies against farmer-owned tangible property, county __ ¦ - levies only. '. . . Rank 1927 1928 I 1929 1930 1931 1932 1. Dakota Dakota Dakota ' Cass Cass ¦" Cass $15.41 $15.43 ;. $14.98 : $16.17 : . $16.67 $13.05 2. . Cass .; Ctttt Hamilton • Dakota Dakota Dakota 14.89 14.51 14.97 . "" 14.98 12.76 10.63 3. Hamilton Hamilton Cass Hamilton Hamilton Lancaster 12.10 .13.85 14.61 H.OB . 12.71 10.22 4 Gage* Dawcs Frontier Thomni Frontier Hamilton . 11.91 . 13.54 13.70 12.55 11.71 9.91 5. Boone Cuming* Dawcs Gage* Thomas Cage* 11.77 11.67 13.46 11.93 10.86 8*57 6. Valley' Boonc Gage' Frontier Gage' Thomas 11.05 11.49 :" . 12.19 11.82 10.58 ; 8.52 - 7. Cuming* .- Thomas ' Thomas Boane . Dawes Frontier .10.64 IIJI 11.80 11.58 10.50 8.41 8. Thomas Gage* Valley* Valley* Valley* Valley* 10.58 10.86 11.26 11.47 10.27 8.18 9. Harlan* Valley* Boone Cuming* Harlan* Dawcs 10.01 10.25 11.21 11.22 9.22 8.03 10, Frontier Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* Cuming* Boone 9.58 9.81 9.83 9.70 .9.74 7.14 U. Dawcs Lancaster ' ¦'¦ Cuming* .Dawcs . Boone Cuming* 9.19 . 8.04 . 9.50 939 9.08 7.78 12." Lancaster Frontier. Lancaster - Lancaster ¦ Lancaster . Harlan* . 8.27 7.43 --.¦¦-¦ 7.89 8.35 8.67 6.80 Starred counties are the' four supervisor counties, and the levy includes county levies only; italic type indicates four commissioner counties which are near-by and compared with supervisor counties. or second during the six years, 1927 to 1932. Cass county ranked third in 1929 and iirst or second throughout the other years. Lancaster county had the lowest per-farm capita county levies during four of the first five years and then jumped to third place in 1932. Increased levies in. Lancaster county and only, slightly reduced percentages of farmer-owned tangible property meant larger per-capita levies against farmers. This increase came at a time when per-capita levies for all other counties declined and boosted Lancaster from twelfth to third place. Dawes county also showed great variability in its rank. From 1927 to 1928 its levy increased 49 per cent and the percentage of the assessed tangible property owned by farmers in - creased one per cent, resulting in a per-capita increase of $4.25 for each farmer of the county. - . : '[ . :: ¦ When the part of the township levy which each farmer bears is deter - mined in the same manner and added to the county levy against each farm person as in Table 21, marked increases take place in amounts for the supervisor counties. This changed the ranking of all the counties of the group. All of the supervisor counties were among the high-levy half of </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 the group every year except the last, when Harlan county dropped to seventh and Lancaster advanced to sixth. In 1928 and 1929, all four supervisor counties ranked above the near-by commissioner counties. In 1927, 1930, and 1931 three of the four super - visor counties ranked above Cass, which was the highest near-by com - missioner county. Harlan county, the fourth supervisor county, ranked above the remaining three near-by commissioner counties. Two of the supervisor counties ranked above Cass, the highest near-by commissioner county and a third supervisor county ranked above Lancaster, the next highest near-by commissioner county for the last year, [n no case was the near-by commissioner county of a pair above the supervisor county paired ivirh it. Table 21.— Per-capita levies against farmer-owned tangible property — county and township levies. i i i i i Rjnk i 1927 . 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 I j i I 1 1. Cumins* Cumins* Cumins* Cumins* Cuming* Cumins* 521.115 521.6( Hl.ll 520.54 519.15 $14.34 2. (ia«c # (iJtlc' Gage* Gage* Valley* Gage* 18.29 17.H 18.65 19.05 17.01 13.69 ). Valle&gt;* Valley Valley* Valley- Gage* Cast 17.71 1T.1.i 17.85 18.14 16.84 13.05 ¦I l)jk..u !&gt;jk,.u Dakota Cj,! Call Valley* 15-11 15.4.! 14.18 16.17 16.67 12.72 5 Cut Ilarlan* Hamilton Dakota Harlan' Dakota 14.W 14.77 14.97 14.98 14.23 10.63 6 Harlan* Tj.. Harlan* Harlan* Dakota Lancaster 14m 14.51 14.81 14.H9 12.76 10.22 7 Hamilton Hamilton ('a&gt;. Hamilton Hamilton Harlan" 12.11) H.KS H. 61 14.08 12.71 10.21 S. Hoqiic Dawci Frontier Thomas Frontier Hamilton 1177 U. 54 1.1.711 12.55 11.71 9.91 1 I homjs Hnnne IJawes Frontier Thomas Thomas Ill.W 11.49 IIAI, 11.82 10.86 8.52 in. Frontier 1 hom.i&gt; 1 hnmas Roone Dawcs Frontier 9.5K ll.il 11.8(1 11.58 10.50 8.41 11. Dawrt Lantjtter Bnone Dawcs Hoone Dawes 9.29 8.04 11.21 9.39 9.08 8.03 12. Ldtniattet Fnmtiej Lancaster Lancaiier Lancaster Boane 8.27 7.4 i 7.89 BJS 8.67 7.14 Starred counties are the four supervisor counties, and the levy includes loivnship 2nd county levies; italic type militate* four commissioner counties which are near-by and compared with supervisor counties. Since there is a fairly direct relationship between population and the expenditures in a county, the counties with the largest population ordinarily have the largest expenditures. A county with the largest population accord - ing to area is, therefore, likely to have the highest levies per acre. Acre levies made against farm property for county use only are shown in Table 22. Data in this table do not show such direct relationships to popula - tion as was shown in Table 18. It is quite evident that the large amounts of property owned in towns reduced the county tax per acre and that the larger the value of property not owned by farmers, the greater the reduction has been. During this entire period Cuming-county levies per acre for county purposes were lower than those of its paired commis- </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Tax System of Nebraska sioner county, Cass. Valley county ranked below Boone, its paired com - missioner county for the six years, and Gage county below Lancaster county in 1932. Harlan county had higher acre levies than Frontier, the com - missioner county of that pair, for the entire period; Gage-county levies were higher than Lancaster county during the first five years of the period. Of the 24 comparisons that can be made between a supervisor county and its paired commissioner county, 13 show the supervisor county having lower levies than the commissioner county and 11 show the reverse situation. No marked superiority is shown for either type of county organization. ¦..'¦¦-: ¦¦¦ -..:.¦'¦¦ Table 22.— Per-acre levies made against tangible farm porperty — county levies only. Rank 1927 -1928 1929 1930 ¦;. 1931 1932 1. . Dakota Dakota • Dakota Cats ¦ . ¦ Can ' ¦ Catp ' . $ .39 . S .40 S .39 5 .40 S .41 5 32 2. Cast ¦ ' Cast Cant Dakota - : Dakota Dakota v .;¦ 36 35 36 ,39 ¦. ¦ '. 33 .28 --3. Hamilton Hamilton Hamilton .' Hamilton ¦ Hamilton Lancaster .28 , .32 34 31; .28 .27 4. Cumine* Cumins' Gage* Cuming* Cumins* Hamilton .27 30 . .28 .29 .25 .22 5. . : Gage* . - Booitc Cumins* - Gape* . Gacc* .. Cuming* ; .27 ¦ .25 .25 . .27 .24 .20 6. Boone Gage* ' Boone Boone ¦ Lancaster Gage* .25 , .25 .24 .25 ; .23 .20 7. Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster . Boone Boone .21 ¦ .21 . . .20 ¦ .21 _20 .15 8. Valley* Valley* Valley* Valley* Valley* Valley* .19 .17 .19 .19 .-.;.; .17 .13 ' 9. Harlan* Harlan' Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* .15 .15 .15 .15 .14 ,10 10.. Frontier- Frontier . Frontier ¦ Frontier Frontier Frontier .10 . .07 .13 .12 .11 .08 U. Dawes . Dawes Vawes ' Dawes Dawes Dawes .04 . .06 .06 .04 .05 .04 12. Thomas Thomas Thomas ' Thomas . Thomas Thomas .02 .02 .03 .03 .03 ' .02 Starred counties are, the four, supervisor counties, and the levy includes county levies only; italic type indicates four commissioner counties which arc. near-by and compared with supervisor counties. When that part of the township levies that fanners, pay is added to the county levy paid by farmers before determining a county and township levy for each farm acre, all of the supervisor counties show increases, according to Table 23. : v ; ; ' ;. •¦ .. . Combining county and 1 township levies against farmer-owned tangible property makes possible a comparison of the supervisor and near-by com - missioner counties for practically the same services of government. Each supervisor county has heavier levies for each acre against farm, land than the near-by commissioner county of the pair. Supervisor county levies exceeded those of the commissioner county paired with them by from five cents an acre for.Gage and Lancaster counties in 1932 to 22 cents an acre for the same pair in 1929. The presence of township units adds materially to the levies. . .-¦"'.¦ . ¦•;..¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Table 23. — Per-acre levies made against tangible jarm property — county and township levies for 12 counties. B.nk I&lt;&lt;2: 1928 I 1929 1930 1931 1932 J. Ciiming' Cumins' Cumins' Cumins' Cuming* Cumins' S 54 S 5(. S .50 S .53 S .50 S 37 2. Cace' Dakota Gape' Gage* Cars Cats .42 .40 .42 .42 .41 31 3. Dakota Gacc* Dakota Can Gage* Gage* .39 .40 .39 .40 .39 .32 4. Can Cms Can Dakota Dakota Dakota .36 .35 .36 .39 .33 .28 5 Valley* Hamilton Hamilton Hamilton Hamilton Lancaster .30 .32 .34 .31 .28 .27 (&#132; Hamilton Valley- Valley- Valley' Valley* Hamilton .28 .29 .30 .30 .28 .22 7. Boone Boone Boone Boone Lancaster Valley* .25 .25 .24 .25 .23 .21 8. Harlan* Harton" Harlan* Harlan' Hatlan* Boonf .22 .22 .22 .22 .21 .15 9. Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Boone Harlan* .21 .21 .20 .21 .20 AS 10 Frontier Frontier Frontier Frontier Frontier Frontier .10 .07 .13 .12 .11 .08 11. Dawc* Djivm Dawes Dawxj Dawes Dawes .04 .06 .06 .04 .05 .04 12 Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomas .02 .02 .03 .03 .03 .02 Starred ounncs -ire the four supcrvi&gt;or counlics, and the levy includes county levies only; italic type indicates four commissioner counties which are near-by and compared with supervisor counties. </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Chapter IV—Receipts By statute, county treasurers of Nebraska are made collecting agents for the different taxing units. 1 For this service the county receives fees that vary with the amount collected and the unit for which collections arc made. 2 Prior to the amendment of Section 2392 of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922, only the excess fees above the amounts necessary to pay the salaries of the treasurer, his deputy, and clerks were turned over to the county. Since the amendment of this law, fees have been turned over to the county and all county officers paid out of the general county funds. ""¦;.'¦¦ ; Two statutory exceptions are made in the collection of city taxes. Omaha and Lincoln 3 are permitted to collect their own city taxes on property through their city treasurers. For all other first-class cities 4 and for second - class cities and villages 6 of the state, county treasurers are made city treasurers ex officio for the purpose of collecting taxes upon property sit - uated within the city or village.: Every elected official who has anything to do with raising money for public purposes hopes to find a source of public money that will be less painful for the voters than the property tax and will be productive of much revenue. The state of Nebraska has been fairly successful in securing revenue from sources other than the general property tax, according to Tables 24 and 25 and Figure 6. Of these the most productive source has been the so-called gasoline tax. In 1927-28 about $3,000,000, or 12 per cent of the state's revenue came from gasoline taxes. An increase in the tax per gallon from two cents to four cents in 1929 resulted in 50 per cent more revenue in 1928-29 and more than 100 per cent more revenue in 1929-30. By 1931-32, the high point of the six-year period had been reached with over seven million dollars collected by the state from gasoline taxes. This was 24.9 per cent of the total state revenue for that year. While the gasoline tax was assuming more importance as a source of state revenue, the property tax was being called upon to furnish less revenue. In 1927-28, 41.73 per cent of the state's revenue came from this source and in 1932 - -33 but 20.87 per cent. Property taxes yielded 10.5 million dollars in 1927 - -28 and 4.8 million in 1932-33. Contributions from the federal government in the.form of educational grants and highway:aid amounted to three million dollars and 11.84 per cent of the state's revenue in 1927-28. Receipts from this source had increased to five million dollars and 22.12 per cent of the state revenue by 1932-33. Reduction in automobile license fees" cut revenues from that source from over $1,000,000 to $500,000. 1 Compiled Statute! of Udmdn, 1929, Sec. M-551. i .... »l»M.,Stc. 33-118. -";...¦- ;¦:'¦¦• 'lUi.,Scc. 15-811. : ; . • ? Ibid., Sec. 15-317. . --.-.; : :. , : •Hid., Sec. 77-1901. •Uwi of Nebraiki, 1933. Home Roll No. 243, pp. 417-419. • 33 </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 \, Table 24—State receipts, 1928-1933. t Cuncnt rotnufi | 1927-28 • | 1928-29' | 1929-30' j 1930-31 ' ( 1931-32' ( 1932-33" ( crjn.l ».ul J25.365.328 521.882.216 527.879.902 527,933,759 528.H9.849 523,022,591 j Current revenues I (.ener..! |.r.,|.cn&gt; 10.553.575 7.618.798 7.327.357 7,402.638 5,807.593 4.804.U0 [ feline i.091.2«» -t.720.965 6.467.930 6.876.842 7.008,371 5.723.627 I s ...ninhuiioni 3.003.284 1.6H.318 2.377.660 2.931.770 5,211,982 5.092,667 ! &lt;„!., l,«n^ 1.217.817 1.354.211 1.283.772 1.176.864 1.084,646 519,591 t''""&gt;'i''i'uMcm 1 1.426.922 1.444.062 1,681.791 1.542.696 1,499,459 1,198,542 """&gt;c"u"i" 1 2.W1.444 2.013.509 2.749.285 2.234.713 2,244,496 1,692,721 "'Tu&gt;t"funls" '" 1128 775 1.102.218 1.136.364 1.107,192 987,862 901,078 Sorwcirnuc receipts 1.992.223 2.U13.835 4.855,743 4,661,044 4,305,440 3,090,255 1 !WX Auditrir'k Report, p. 20. * 1932 Auditor's Report, p. 20. 3 I'Hlt Aminor\ Report, p. 211. s 1932 Auditor's Report, p. 22. 3 IWI \u000dr* Report, p. 22. * 1934 Auditor's Report, p. 22. Table 25. — State receipts in percentage, 1928-1933} '"'""&lt; I 1927-28 1928-29 1929-30 1930-31 1931-32 1932-33 rc\cnuet 1 1 I I I ' , &#132;„,! &#132;,ul W 100 100 100 100 100 ''"", &#132;„„.,„¦ 41.71 34.82 26.28 26.50 20.63 20.87 ".' ' ' 12.19 21.57 23.20 24.62 21.90 24.86 ¦ „,, ]u . n&gt;&lt; . 4.8H 6.19 4.60 4.21 3.85 2.26 iduc.il .rul uiuiiuium 5.62 Ml 6.0S 5.52 5.35 5.21 I s Z,,Z i"n» H M 738 8.53 10.50 18.52 22.12 • &gt;,he, ; u ",r, nt - 11.52 9.20 9.86 8.00 7.97 7.35 lnt;;r, ','• T""'" 1' 4.45 5.04 4.08 3.96 3.51 3.91 S.,"rr'cnut rci-cipi. 7.85 9.20 17.42 16.69 15.29 13.42 1 \nnujl reports of State Auditor. Fees paid by students of the four state normal schools and the state university, together with returns from the sales of goods and services from these institutions and the substations at North Platte, Mitchell, and Valen - tine amounted to 5.62 per cent of the total revenue of the state in 1927-28 and 5.21 per cent in 1932-33. Actual collections were $1,426,922 in 1927-28 and $1,198,542 in 1932-33. Money collected by the various state institutions is turned over to the state treasurer by whom it is placed in the general fund. Payments from the general fund must be authorized by legislative action. During the fiscal year ending June 30, 1933, $4,024,195 in warrants was authorized and issued in payment of the expenses of the university, its suhstations, the school of agriculture at Curtis, and the four normal schools. The receipts from these institutions amounted to 29.78 per cent ¦ of the money paid out for their maintenance. Of the 70.22 per cent de- j rived from other sources, a pan came from federal funds and from in- ' vestments and the remainder from the property tax. (I Receipts from temporary trust funds were but $200,000 less in 1932-33 than in 1927-28. Other current revenues declined from 2.9 million dollars or 11.52 per cent in 1927-28 to 1.69 million dollars, or 7.35 per cent in M2-il. Non-revenue receipts produced J1,990,000 in 1927-28 and $3,000,000 in 1932-33, which amounts were 7.85 per cent and 13.42 per cent of the revenues of the state, respectively. By 1932-33 property tax revenues were ? </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Tax System of Nebraska PERCENT. ¦ . ¦-. ."¦¦¦.¦.. ioo-i t- —i p—| [—| I—-, I—. '.... - :¦¦''. '• 90- ;; . 80- . " L_ 70' _ W: ¦••?¦•¦¦ # #:" 60- J, ::-&gt;V :•;•;: :':J: S *•: 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 : ; ¦ NON-REVENUE RECEIPTS : S TEMPORARY TRUST FUNOS ;¦ ¦¦:'.¦..¦ . OTHER CURRENT REVENUE .¦;.¦¦¦¦¦'.'¦ . V .^ U.S. CONTRIBUTIONS "-., . . El EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS S AUTOMOBILE LICENSE ; } (wj GASOLINE TAX ' ? GENERAL PROPERTY .';'¦ ..¦.:.•. : ; Fic'S.—Sources of state receipts, 1928-1933. largely displaced by revenues from gasoline taxes, contributions from the U. S. government and non-revenue receipts and amounted to but 20.86 per cent instead of the 41.73 per cent produced in'l927-28. The sources of receipts for the 12 counties used in this study are shown in Tables 26 and 27. Property taxes yielded 67.73 per cent of the total county revenue during the calendar year 1928 and 54.99 per cent in 1933. In these 12 counties motor vehicle taxes ranged from 14.76 per cent of the total revenue in 1930 tolB.oB per cent in 1928. Greatly reduced taxes upon automobiles resulted in yields of only 10.21 per cent or $223,439 in 1933. Following the passage of the 1929 gasoline tax law, counties be - gan to share in the gasoline tax to the extent of one-fourth of the revenue that remained after the administration, costs were deducted. 7 By 1933 these 12 counties were receiving 19.40 per cent of their revenues from the tax upon gasoline. In Table 26 receipts from fees as shown were lower than was actually true and receipts from "other sources" unusually high because it was not possible to separate fee collections from collections from 'Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1929, Sec. 66-til. </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 other sources in Lancaster county. Had this been possible it is not likely that other collections would have yielded over one per cent of the total, while fee collections would have been approximately 10 per cent of the total. Townships receive their revenues from two sources: the property tax and the poll tax. Table 28 shows the amount received from each source. Table 26. — Sources of receipts for 12 Nebraska counties, 1928-1933. Source IMS j 1929 1930 1931 1932 I 1933 I'rnoem ux ... 51.812.847 51.874.224 51.840.362 51.554,866 51,342,018 $1,203,060 Mrnor vehicle m . 483,983 516.271 453,341 445,066 414,741 224,593 Ci«,hnr ux ... ... 299,443 398,215 406,295 341,815 423337 I'i.ll mi 36.8-10 34,972 29,437 28,995 28,468 28,224 Fm 155.404 158.506 152.886 148.409 140,352 119,239 o.her source! 195.251 220.328 218.125 193,407 167,526 183,784 loul receipt. 2.W14J25 3.103.444 3.092,366 2.777,038 2,434,920 2,182,237 Table 27.— Percentage of receipts from different sources, 12 Nebraska counties, 1928-1933. i Smirce I 192» • 1929 1930 1931 I 1932 1933 J'r.ipem i" '¦"'' «&gt;.39 59.51 55.99 55.12 55.13 Mi.mr vehicle ux 18 01 16.64 14.66 16.03 17.03 10.29 i.ju.linc vi 9.65 12.88 14.63 14.04 19.40 h.ll v, . 1.37 1.13 .95 1.04 1.17 1.29 Fee- 5.79 5.09 4.94 5.34 5.76 5.47 Other source* T. 28 7.10 7.06 6.97 6.88 8.42 1..U1 receipt. ll«i.i»l 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 In the four supervisor counties under consideration township revenues did not change much during the first four years of the period. From 1931 to 1932 a reduction of $62,046 took place. The receipts the last year of the period, 1933, were 53.08 per cent (Table 29) of what they were in 1929. This table shows the percentage of the year's revenue derived from each source. During the first four years but little change occurred in the im - portance of each source of revenue. During the next two years township taxes on property were reduced by more than 50 per cent, resulting in a decline in total revenues from $286,232 to $151,937. Because poll taxes are fixed by statute 8 they have proved less responsive to economic condi - tions and their yield has been relatively constant in amount although it has increased in importance. In 1928 this tax produced $20,110 and in 1933, 518,501. Nebraska schools receive support from but few sources, the principal one being the property tax as indicated in Tables 30 and 31. Of the total revenue of the schools of Nebraska, approximately 80 per cent came directly from the property tax. In addition, from 7.1 per cent in 1928 to 9.54 per cent in 1933 came from tuition paid by the county out of funds secured from a levy upon property in those districts not maintaining public high schools. Since this tuition money came from a tax on property, it 1 Compiled Sututci of Nebraska, 1929, Sec. 77-1802, p. 1509. </seg>
         <seg id="p037">• . Tax System of Nebraska Table 28.— Township revenue for four counties, 1928 to 1933. Tax 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 Valley County : '¦•'...' - ¦¦ Property ......;. $54,809 $53,673 J50.986 «9,823 $42,938 $28,869 Mi.&lt; 3,295 2.846 2,818 - 2,727 2656 2542 Total 58.104 ¦ 56,519 53.804 5255 D 45^4 3MII Cuming County * ; ¦ '.-¦- ;;...¦'". Property ........ 93,690 93.373 90,023 89.418 61,505 23,426 I"0",-- •• 5,115 . 5,000 5,106 5,175 5,100 5212 Total ...... 98,805 , 98,373 95,129 94593 .. -am 28,538 Harlan County - Property ........ 33,147 32,994 , 33,003 32,921 23,588 18,055 Poll 2,370 2,516 2,522 2,465 2,518 2598 T0u1..... 35,517 35,510 35,525 35.386 -26.106" 20!653 Gage County Property ........ 86,530 90,646 86,551 94.756 77JM 63,086 Poll ............. 9,330 9,701 9,342 8,947 8/577 8149 To"l •••••• &amp;.S6O 100,317 95,893 103,703 85,881 71,235 Four Counties rropmy 268,176 270,686 260,563 266,918 205,335 133,436 5»", ,20.110 20,063 19,789 19,314 18 851 18,501 T°»' 288,286 290,749 280.352 286,232 224,186 151.937 Table 29.— Percentage of the revenue for four township counties from property and poll tax. ; Tax 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 Valley County ' Property 94.33 W. 96 94.76 94.81 91.17 9191 : Poll ............. 5.67 .5.04 5.24 5.19 5.83 8.09 Cuming County : ¦ Property 94.82 94.92 94.63 94.53 92.34 81.80 P"« • ¦ ¦ 5.18 : 5.08 5.37 5.47 7.66 18.20 Harlan County ¦ ¦'. Property ........ 93.33 92.92 92.90 93.03 90.36 87 42 Poll ;. 6.67 7.08 7.10 6.97 9.64 12.58 Gage County Property ........ 90.27 90.33 9036 91.37 90.01 88.56 P"» • •"•••• 9.73 9.67 9.74 8.63 9.99 11.44 Four Counties Property-...; 93.02 93.10 92.94 .93.25 91.59 87.82 P°" ¦¦• ¦¦¦¦ 6.98 6.90 7.06 6.75 8.41 12.18 seems fair to assume that Nebraska schools secured from 86 to 89 per cent of their revenue from taxes' upon tangible property as shown in Table 31. City schools ol the state were less dependent upon the direct property tax than were the elementary schools of the slate but were fully as dependent upon the property tax if the property tax and tuition are considered to - gether. School income from tuition fluctuated less than from any other source because the charges per pupil were fixed by statute at not to exceed $3.00 per week 0 for each high school student, and $1.00 per week 10 for each student in the elementary grades^ . . .. • Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1929, Sre. 79-902. ¦ 10 Hid., Sec. 79-504. . .¦¦¦¦¦ ¦ ; ' ' :: </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Nebraska Ac.rualtiral Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Table 30.— Income of Nebraska schools, 1928-1933. x 1 I-*' I rt\T y 1 "tF' 1 Tuiii"n 1 ™"« Element! ry I»'H 51.971(126 5f.086.K7H 5600.309 524.098 SM).74t I'J'O 7 007.584 (&#132;091.218 641.264 23.418 251.684 |'i«) hQW") I, OKI 972 624,600 25,127 207,530 1111 (,m\Mh (..021.92) 633.W1 25.479 210,733 11(2 MH7.850 5.269.911 596,5*1 26,084 155.291 ,„!! 4919411 4 270.652 499.227 23.244 136.300 s, t MM.HV. 5.6)7.1197 599.221 24.575 203,713 Hich Schools and C'iiy and Town Elementary |Qi« 2(Ii'OIO IT.W2.7'* 957.248 2.114.232 2,087,762 !»:¦) 211-t»7IM 1(0)18.708 978..(.(2 1.983.042 1.507,102 loin ?1&gt;.794.6i0 lA.l2ft.Mt 786.H08 2.086,446 1,795,493 ]iill :iumo»7 11, 1122 IKK) 855.274 2.062,072 1,549,741 |&#132;t; 1k'451451 14 4KS.HH 7=5(1.(7(1 2.110..88 1,113.545 1911 H -gl ir 111989(1 M6.lfi7 1.859.257 888,978 \, B li'.Ws'.9H( 15.(40.70S 828.9H 2.035.908 1.490.437 All Schools I^2B «M24(l(r, 24.079.M6 1.557.557 2.1.(8.3)0 2.348.503 pic, 27 494 7M 22 1119 921. 1.61W96 2.006,460 1.758.786 luiir 27-1(859 22 2118 6iS 1.410.608 2.111.573 2.003.023 |9(| '7(80r,1i 22.04(.92( 1.488.665 2.087,551 1.760,474 19(i 14 507(01 19 755.079 1J46.904 2.136.482 1,268,836 1911 \t':illU&gt; 1i.M.9.587 1.145.594 1.882.501 1,025.278 tog ih.Ml.im 2i1.977.502 1.428.154 2.06 D.483 1,694,150 Table 31. — Percentage oj total income, Nebraska schools, 1928-1933. \ CJ , Stale and online Inul I'rcjpcMv ( riicra | Tuition Olhcr lunr W '^2. "'*' Rural Elementary I9ij 100 87.30 8.61 .35 3.74 mM iimi 8692 9.15 .34 3.59 I gin lIXI 87.65 9.00 .36 2.99 \9(\ 1110 87.(8 9.19 .37 3.06 |9(i IW 17.14 9.86 .43 2.57 ]uu lim 8(..M lII.U -47 2.76 A,,. 100 87.20 9.27 .38 3.15 Hinh School anil City anil Town Elementary 198 100 77.72 4.13 9.13 9.02 1^29 10H 78.19 4.77 9.68 '.36 19(0 100 "55 3.78 10.03 8.64 ]i&gt;U 100 78.20 4.18 10.06 7.56 1912 100 78.47 4.07 11.43 6.03 19(1 100 77.05 4.37 12.57 6.01 to e 101) 77.89 4.21 10.34 7.56 All Schools 1928 100 7993 5.17 7.10 7.80 1929 100 80.41 5.89 /.30 6.40 19(0 WO 80.08 5.09 7.61 '-22 |9(l 100 «0.5 l 5.44 "«2 M 3 19(2 100 80.61 5.49 8.72 5.18 19JJ 100 79.45 5.81 9.54 5.20 Ul! . 100 KOI") 5.46 7^BB 6.4/ The division of receipts from each source between town and rural schools is shown in Table 30. Town schools averaged 75.29 per cent of total receipts, while rural schools averaged 24.71 per cent of the total. The reports in the office of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction do not separate receipts intended for high-school use from those for the </seg>
         <seg id="p039">Tax System of Nebraska elementary schools of the towns. However, it was possible to determine the percentage of the pupils enrolled in rural schools. In 1927-28, 33.66 per cent of the students in the public schools of the state were listed as rural; in 1928-29, 32.83 per cent; in 1929-30, 31.81 per cent; in 1930-31,. 31.43 per cent; in 1931-32, 30.70 per cent. 11 These percentages, indicate that rural schools of the state do not receive as.much for each pupil as do town schools. Town schools secured 73.13 per cent of the property tax while rural elementary schools secured' 26.87 per cent. Schools in town received 87.98 per cent of the revenue from other sources while rural elementary schools received 12.02 per cent. In but one case did rural elementary schools'receive more than 30 per cent of the income from any one source. Rural schools received 41.96 per cent of the state and federal aids which amounted to a very small part of their total revenue. A summary of the property tax situation in the different units' affecting farmers, namely state, county, school, and township, is shown by Figure 7. Property taxes declined in importance for state, county, and townships, P£B CENT - 100 r — : ; : 1 90 -1 U rn ..¦¦¦'¦ 80 70 . i. . 60 . .0 ' 40 ¦ Itlllll ¦ ¦-..¦ _, o, o—nj ro _.o&gt;O —IM —• 0)0,0 — IXI rt *»0-Nfl NNnnnn nmninnri WNnnnn wrjnriflfl g, 0.0,0, o. O. et, epot q, ep o, enenotenefia a. mo, O, _J _» ~lf ATE ~ "COUNTY ~ "SCHOOL TOWNSHIP Fig. 7.—Revenue obtained from property tax by taxing units. '¦¦'¦'¦'The cross-hatched portion of the school bars represents . ':...' tuition paid by the county from funds collected from the property tax. and retained about the same importance for the schools of the state at the end of this period as at the-beginning. The greater success of the state in tapping other sources of revenue such as the gasoline tax and federal grants has enabled it to rely upon property taxes for less of its revenue. The proportion of the state revenue from property tax in 1933 was but half as large as in 1928. 1 ¦ 11 Nebraska Educational Directory, Nebraska Department of Public Instruction, Lincoln, Nebraska, 1929-30 and 1933-34. </seg>
         <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Although the county units of the 12 counties studied have not been as successful as the state in finding other sources of revenue, they have shown some ability along this line. By 1933 the percentage of their revenue secured from property taxes had fallen from 67.93 per cent in 1928 to 55.46 per cent as shown in Table 27. In 1933 the gasoline tax returned to those counties $423,336 for county use, which was doubtless not available in 1928. The property tax seemed to stabilize at about 55 per cent during the last three years of this period. Table 32. — Percentage of total income from each source going to rural elementary and town schools, 1928 to 1933. Stale and Ujr Total Property (cdcral TuUion Other taxes a j flj sources Rural Elementary 1928 23.H 25.28 38.54 1.13 11.10 1929 25.49 27.55 39.59 1.17 14.31 1910 25 02 27.39 44.28 1.19 10.36 19)1 25.17 27.32 42.55 1.22 11.97 1952 24.68 26.68 44.29 1.22 12.24 I 9« 24 99 27.25 43.58 1.23 13.29 H B . 24.71 26.87 41.96 1.19 12.02 Town Schools 1928 76 86 74.72 61.46 98.87 88.90 1929 74 51 72.45 60.41 98.83 85.69 mil 74.98 72.61 55.72 98.81 89.64 Wl 74 81 72 68 57.45 98.78 88.03 1912 75)2 73.32 55.71 98.78 87.76 1933 75.01 72.75 56.42 98.77 86.71 ÜB.U B . 75.."1 7). l) 58.04 98.81 87.98 Table 33.— Per-capita receipts from property tax for 12 Nebraska counties. (..unties I'l2B 1929 ¦ 1930 | 1931 1932 1933 F"U c™,m c "'"" 58.23 58.05 58.73 57.84 55.93 55.17 i „„,,„.. 9.74 11.29 11.31 9.39 5.40 6.43 G JC e 6.77 5.91 7.49 6.39 5.56 4.55 Hjrhn c».(,7 9.40 8.32 9.12 6.72 5.00 Vjllcv ''.18 8.69 9.15 8.90 7.17 5.35 Four nejr h\ aininmMnncr counts 7.06 7.20 6.70 5.27 -f.BB 4.59 Boonc 9.69 9.31 9.53 8.36 5.85 4.06 (;.,„ 9.17 8.98 9.03 8.58 8.42 7.13 K,,,niir, Ki.OI 16.45 15.39 15.73 13.91 9.34 LimtUT 5.49 5.80 5.17 3.41 3.43 3.88 Four other cnrnnmMunei tnuntio 9.18 10.56 10.00 8.90 7.58 5.96 IMkou . 9.15 11.26 10.77 8.77 6.56 5.05 Ujuo 7.7) 9.04 8.04 6.60 6.57 5.10 Hamilton 10.4f, 11.14 10.« 10.75 8.92 7.43 ThMiui lI.K 12.90 12.150 13.03 11.71 7.26 Tntil nf 12 counties (cum. u«- Mih i .. 7.71 7.91 7.71 6.47 5.55 4.94 The direct property tax returns to schools remained constant at about 79 per cent during this period. This is shown by the black portion of the bars in Figure 7. In addition to this money obtained by schools by direct levy on the property in the districts, they receive money for tuition. </seg>
         <seg id="p041">Tax System of Nebraska This comes from the county funds derived from the property tax. Thus schools of Nebraska benefit indirectly from the property tax levied by the county. Tuition money received by schools is represented by the cross - hatched portion of the school bars. Nebraska schools receive about 90 per cent of their revenue from the property tax. : ' Substantial reductions in the amount of property tax levied and rela - tively fixed returns from poll taxes resulted in less dependence upon the property tax by townships in 1932 and 1933 than in the years 1928 to 1931. During the five-year period from 1928 to 1932, property taxes yielded from 94.17 to 94.96 per cent of the township revenues, and then dropped to 91.91 per cent in 1933. Statutory restrictions upon their taxing powers have kept townships from using other sources of revenue and have pre - vented reductions in the poll tax by them. Per-capita receipts from the property tax are shown for each county in Table 331 In this table they are arranged in the three groups. The four other commissioner counties as a group showed the highest receipts per Table 34. — Per-capita receipts jrom property tax jor 12 Nebraska-counties (township and county purposes). Coumies ; . 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 Four supervisor counties ' ... . - ¦ - (county and township * - . .... ¦ . : ' --¦'¦; . . .: purposes) .512.49 512.34 512.86 $12.07 $9.18 57.28 Cumins ........i.i 16-33 17.84 ; 17.59 15.60 9.66 8.05 Cage 9.66 8.91 10.35 9.52 8.11 6.63 Harlan ............ 1335 13.08. 12.01 12.81 9.37 7.03 Valley ..,....:...; 14.89 .14.30 14.50 14.14 11.71 8.41 Four near-by commissioner ¦ ' ¦ . - counties ;;¦....... 7.06 . 7.20 6.70 5.27 4.88 4.59 Boone 9.69 9.31 9.53 8.36 5.85 ¦ 4.06 Cas 9.37 8.98 9.03 8.58 8.42 7.13 Frontier -16.03. 16.45 15.39 15.73 13.91 9.34 Lancaster .......... 5:49 5.80 5.17 3.41 3.43 3.88 Four other commissioner ¦ counliei 9.38 10.56 10.00 B^9o 7.58 5.96 Dakota 9.15 11.26 10.77 8.77 . 6.56 5.05 Dawcs 7.73 9.04 8.04 6.60 6.57 5.10 Hamilton 10.46 lliM 10.93 10.73 8.92 7.43 Thomas ........... 13.92 ; 12:90 12.60 13.03 11.71 7.26 Total of 12 counties . ' ' /. - (county and township ¦ . ¦ . purposei) .............. 8.85 9.06 8.81 7.58 6.39 5.49 person with a range of from $5.96 to $10.56. The four supervisor counties ranked second with a range of $5.17 to $8.73 per person; and the four near-by commissioner counties ranked last with receipts ranging from $4.59 to $7.20 a person. The presence of the city of Lincoln in the near-by com - missioner county group and the city of Beatrice in the supervisor county group tend to reduce per-capita receipts for these groups. Lincoln, which is the larger city, showed greater tendency to lower per-capita taxes than did Beatrice. : V ¦ .....-¦.. -; '..'¦'.'¦':.''¦,".¦ : Per-capita receipts from the property tax by county and township when the two are combined for the four supervisor counties are shown in Table 34. This combination materially raises the per-capita revenues from the </seg>
         <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 property tax for the four supervisor counties, which group now takes first place away from the other near-by commissioner county group. Compari - son of the pairs of counties shows the supervisor county of each pair well ahead of the commissioner county paired with it. Higher levies were necessary in supervisor counties in order to provide sufficient funds for the services rendered by county and township. Indexes of per-capita receipts from all sources, with 1928 used as a base, show income from some sources increasing while that from others declined. When county and township incomes were combined for the different groups of counties the index of total receipts rose to 113 for 1929, and dropped to 112 for 1930, and to 101 for 1931. In 1932 a further drop took place and the index was at 87. For 1933 this index was 76 per cent of 1928. During this time, income from the property tax failed to in - crease as much as the general index for 1929, fell to 100 in 1930, was 86 for 193], 72 for 1932, and 62 for 1933. Counties received no money from the gasoline tax in 1928. When 1929 is used as a base, this source of revenue shows increases to 133 in 1930, 134 in 1931, a drop to 114 for 1932, and a recovery to 141 for 1933. The increase in revenue for this one source which alone remains above 100 for the period, is responsible for total revenue remaining above 100 until 1932 and not going below 76 for the entire period. Of the three groups, the four near-by commissioner counties showed the greatest increase in gasoline taxes, going from 100 in 1929 to 140 in 1933. The second group was the four supervisor counties, whose index was 139 in 1933. The four other commissioner counties were last with an index of 123 for 1933. The leading group owes its showing in gasoline tax collections to the presence of Lancaster county, which had an index of 144 in 1933. None of the other three counties which make up this group had such high indexes. The index number for Frontier county was 134, for Cass county 139, and for Boone county 120 in 1933. The four super - visor counties showed less variation than the near-by commissioner counties. The Cuming county index was lowest with 134, Gage county next with 140, Valley third with 141, and Harlan highest with 142. They clustered closely about the group figure of 139. The four other commissioner counties were the lowest of the group. Dakota showed a greater increase than any of them. Its index was 136 while Dawes county with 129 was second, Thomas county third with 119, and Hamilton last with 113. The presence of the city of Lincoln in Lan - caster county in the first group doubtless contributed to its greater increse in gas tax. Lancaster county showed an increase in numbers of auto - mobiles and trucks amounting to more than 10 per cent which was about three per cent more increase than was shown by Gage, the county with the next highest registrations of automobiles and trucks. More automobiles and trucks in a county mean more gasoline sold in the county. During most of this period gasoline was lower in price in Lincoln than in surround - ing towns. </seg>
         <seg id="p043">Chapter V—Expenditures Public money may be paid out only when properly drawn warrants are presented to the treasurer of the particular governmental unit con - cerned. These warrants must be made out by the clerk of the body and approved by the board in charge of the funds drawn. upon. 1 In cases where insufficient funds are available in any fund against which a warrant has been drawn, payment may not be made from any other fund. Such unpayable warrants must be recorded by the treasurer in a warrant register in the order of their presentation. Upon every warrant so presented the treasurer shall indorse "Registered for payment," with the date of registration and shall sign such indorsement. 2 In this way payments by county treasurers are restricted to those, warrants issued against funds con - taining sufficient money to cover the warrant. In cases of emergency, the county board may vote to transfer money from the general fund to another fund.? . ; .• ¦:•.;¦¦. -.¦;..¦.¦ Registered warrants must be paid in the order in which they are registered. When, sufficient money has been collected in the fund against which an unpaid warrant is drawn the holder shall be notified in writing 4 by the treasurer. Registered warrants draw seven per cent interest from the date of registration until they are paid. 8 Expenditures by the State of Nebraska are shown in Tables 35 and 36. Total expenditures for the fiscal year beginning July 1, 1927, and ending June 30, 1928, were 22.4 million dollars. The lowest expenditures by the state came in the next year and amounted to 19.4 million dollars. The largest amount of money spent by the state, 29.8 million dollars, was in the fiscal year 1931-32. Of the seven items listed, expenditures for roads and bridges was the largest every year of the period, ranging from 27 per cent in 1928-29 to 47 per cent in 1931-32 of the total expenditure by the state. Educational expenditures ranked second in importance with a low per cent of 15.9 in 1931-32 and a high of 24.3 in 1928-29. The low expenditure for education occurred in 1932-33 when 4.2 million dollars were spent. Educational expenditures include those for the state univer - sity and those for the four state teachers colleges at Chadron, Peru, Wayne, and Kearney. I For the institutions ° administered by the state board of control, expendi - tures ranged from 2.4 million'dollars in 1932-33 to 2.96 million dollars in 1930-31. Expenditures by the state board of control ranked third in relative importance during the entire period with the highest percentage of the state expenditures, 11.49, taking place in 1927-28 and the lowest, 8.55 per cent, in 1931-32. These data are summarized in Table.36. 1 Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1929, Sec. 26-1003. : i ' Ibid., Sec. 77-2-W3. , .-.; : -»/*«.. Sec. 26-717. .-¦¦"¦ !. ".--:• ¦.¦.:..- .. i *ltU;. Sec. 77-2-HH. • ¦ .. : ¦ 5 Compiled Statutes of KcbrasW 1919, Sec. 26-1302. ¦"." ' The institutions arc: Feeble Minded Institute, Beatrice; Girls' Industrial School, Geneva; Soldiers and Sailors Home, Grand Island; Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside; Hospital for Tuberculosis, Kearney* Lincoln Stale Hoipital, Lincoln; Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln; State • Penitentiary, Lincoln; Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford;' Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk; School for Deaf, Omaha; State Reforma - tory, York; Slate Reformatory, Lincoln; Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln; State Industrial School, Kearney; Soldiers and Sailors Home, Milford; and School for the Blind, Nebraska City. 43 </seg>
         <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Table 35.— Slate expenditures by fiscal years, July 1 through June 30 * (000 omitted). EiiKtulini! jßccic, ! 1927-28 192829 1929-30 1930-31 IMI-32 1932-33 Avmie Department «pcn.l,.urc« .. Sl.Sfcn 52.056 51.%6 52.215 51.747 51,726 51,929 Rol.li jnd br.leri 8.535 5.260 10.079 10.477 14,080 10,483 9,819 Motion 4 600 1.717 4.902 5,053 4,750 4,205 4.704 f.L,,l of c,.n.,0i 2 578 2 226 2.653 2.964 2.551 2,447 2.570 V". Ml diZ^tncnr:.: 1.130 1.220 1.179 1.221 1135 960 .141 fi.hir i..&gt;u caih exoend 1939 1.576 1.587 1,601 1,312 833 1,475 m : S:::: iws 17:055 22.355 23.532 25.575 m&amp;s zi,«B \,.n-i.".w rxpemliLi. I 7SB 2 .14.1 4.506 4.901 4.264 2.500 3.550 l.fZ ."II . .. 22AJ6 19.398 26.871 28.433 29.839 24.154 25.188 1 Sale juiluori' rcporli. Table 36.—Percentage of total state expenditures Jor each item. Ex P endin ß aß encie, ' 1927 28 ! 1928-29 1929-30 1930-31 1931-32 1932-33 Avcrasc Department expenditure. . 8.32 10.60 7.32 7.79 5.86 7.15 7.66 Roads and bridge. 38.04 27.12 37.51 36.85 4/.19 43.40 39.98 Equation 20.50 24.32 18.24 17.77 15.91 17.41 8.68 Board of control 11.49 11.47 9.87 10.42 8.55 10.13 10.20 Tm.t fund d.sbur.emem 5.0-1 6.29 4.39 4.30 3.80 3.97 4.53 Other f o,t. c.h expend. 8.64 H. 12 5.91 5.63 4.40 3.45 5.86 Total govl "ih expend. 92.03 57.92 83.23 82.76 85.71 85.51 85.91 Noncrnt expcndimres 7.97 12.08 16.77 17.24 14.29 14.49 14.09 (irand loul 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 100.00 None of the three remaining divisions accounts for as much as 11 per cent of the state expenditures. In 1928-29, departmental expenditures were 10.6 per cent of the total, and other governmental cash expenditures were 8.12 per cent, while trust-fund disbursements were last with 6.29 per cent. Included in departmental expenditures are those by the legislative departments, judiciary departments, executive departments, departments under the direction of executive officers, and code departments. Expenditures for sundry departments and the capitol commission and miscellaneous appropriations make up "other governmental cash expendi - tures." This was highest in 1930-31, when it amounted to $1,601,000 or 5.63 per cent of the total expenditure for the state, and lowest in 1932-33 at $833,000 or 3.45 per cent of the total. Nongovernmental expenditures ate made up of revolving-fund expenditures such as state hail insurance losses and expenditures and bonds purchased for permanent trust funds. This item was lowest in amount, being $1,788,000 in 1927-28 or 7.97 per cent of the total. It increased until 1930-31, when it was $4,901,000 or 17.24 per cent of the total. The data in Table 37 show indexes of state expenditures with 1927-28 used as a base. Departmental expenditures remained above 100 until 1931 - -32, when they fell to 94. They were 93 in 1932-33. Much of this failure to reduce was due to the inelasticity imposed by salaries established by action of the state legislature. Road and bridge expenditures fell to 62 per cent by 1928-29 but rose again the next year and were 118 per cent of 1927-28. Road and bridge expenditures were 123 per cent of 1927-28 in 1930-31 and reached the high point of the period at 165 per cent in 1931-32. </seg>
         <seg id="p045">¦ . Tax System of Nebraska Table 37.— Index of state expenditures—l927-28=100. Eiptmiinff accncici 1927-28 1928-29 1929-30 1930-31 1931-32 1932-33 DquTlmcnl expenditures,. 100 11(1 105 119 in m Road, and bridges. .. 100 «2: 118 m 165 133 ' Etluralion .;.. 100 103 107 110 nY Bl Board of con.ro! . :.. 100 *Sfi 103 ? '$ ?| Trim fund dUliuricmcnis. 100 . 108 104 108 inn « O,hcr so,-., ca.h expend.. 100 8? . „" Sj M S! Totnl B ovt. caih cjpcml. . 100 W 108 114 m lm Kon-Bovernmcn. expend.. 100 131 252 274 23S 9? Cnnd .wa1..;..,....... 100 8( j 120 .fg g {» 2'3i thcy ad f fallen t0 123 and were approximately the same as in iyJU-31. Demands for economy were recognized by the state board of control during the second year of this period. During the third and fourth years, expenditures by the board were much higher, reaching 103 in 1929-30 and 115 in 1930-31. The board's expenditures dropped to 99 in 1931-32 and 95 in 1932-33, Other governmental cash expenditures showed the greatest change of the governmental cash expenses. For the three years 1928-29, \^T6^h ±7&lt;r il Bl&gt; 82&gt; and 83 per cent, respectively, of 1927-28. In 1931-32 they fell to 68 and in 1932-33 to 43 per cent of 1927-28. ¦. Non-governmental cash expenditures showed more change than any of the government cash expenditures, increasing rapidly until 1930-31 when they were 274 per cent of 1927-28. From this high point they fell to 193 in 1932-33. Funds for these expenditures are derived from non-tax sources; hence an increase in this division does not mean added tax burdens. When the non-governmental expenditures are disregarded, a better notion of state governmental cash expenditures can be obtained. Total governmental cash expenditures reflect the influence of the heavier expendi - tures, such as those for roads and bridges, and education hence remained above 100 during every year of the period after 1928-29. The index of grand total state expenditures is much higher than that for total govern - ment cash expenditures, because as much as 17 per cent of the total expenditure was from a source whose index stood at 274 per cent of 1927-28 during the period 1930-31 and at no time represented less than 12 percent of the total, with an index of 131 per cent of the base year. Schools of Nebraska take first place among the public spending agencies in amount of money spent. The data upon which this chapter is based were taken from the reports for the fiscal years, July 1 to June 30, on file in the office of the state superintendent of public instruction. During the six fiscal years from 1927-28 to 1932-33 for which school expenditures were tabulated, total school expenditures ranged from $20,977,795 to $29,713,996. The decrease was heaviest from 1931-32 to 1932-33, when schools spent $5,175,189 less than a year earlier. • When index numbers of total school expenditures, given in Table 38, are calculated with 1927-28 as-a base, some decline is noted for the entire period. In 1928-29 the index for all schools was 94.22; in 1929-30, 95 49 - -in 1930-31, 96.71; in 1931-32, 88.01; and in 1932-33, 71.19. Rural ele - mentary schools were more directly controlled by the farmers of the state. </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 The index of rural elementary school expenditures remained above 100 for the first four years and then fell to 89.05 after farm income declined. The greatest reduction occurred in expenditures by city and village elementary schools, whose low point, 67.32, came in 1932-33. The few rural high schools of the state are reported with those of cities and villages. Their numbers are small and their removal from the list would make no appre - ciable change in the total index. The controlling influence for the high schools of the state is the same population group that control city and village schools, namely, the non-farm group. Less reduction took place in the expenditures by high schools than took place for village and town elementary schools. City and village schools reduced their expenditures by removing the so-called frills. Music, art, and dramatics were removed before anything else; then followed reductions in vocational training. None of these had been very extensively introduced among the rural elementary schools of the state; hence cuts could not be made by reducing the size of the instructional force in rural elementary schools. Table 38. — Index of total expenditures by Nebras\a schools. Elementary Years i " High school '"" Rural | Village and town 1917.18 IIHI.OO 110.00 100.00 19.1..29 101.27 88.14 95.80 1919-30 loo.nri m.m 97.71 1910.11 111122 91.84 98.72 1911-I' 89.115 83.51 92.03 1912-3.1 73.39 (.7.32 73.22 Table 39. — Percentage division of expenditures for all school of Nebras\a. Fisc.il Ccncral Teachers' T™'' School Opcr- Main- Capital Debt All other year, oinirol salaries books supplies aiion tcnancc outlay service expenses 1927-28 Th 5T75 im 2T3 O4 57Tk oi Tuis 4J2 1918-29 I 16 57.59 2.01 2.31 9.16 3.61 6.77 9.55 4.62 1919.V1 4.18 57.43 2.04 2.42 9.43 3.711 7.36 8.42 5.02 19111.31 4 15 57.24 1.86 2.38 8.96 3.64 7.94 8.68 4.95 1911-11 4 75 611.75 1.73 2.22 9.43 2.91 5.04 8.26 4.91 1912-n 5.38 64.87 1.59 2.03 10.32 2.43 1.62 7.31 4.45 Data in Table 39 indicate the relative importance of school expenditures for different purposes. The major item for all schools was salaries of teachers. The proportion which teachers' salaries formed of the total expenditures for school purposes ranged from 53.75 per cent in 1927-28 to 64.87 per cent in 1932-33. General control, which went from 3.84 per cent of the total in 1927-28 to 5.38 per cent in 1932-33, and operation, which was 8.54 per cent in 1927-28 and 1032 per cent in 1932-33, were the only other single items for which increasingly larger parts of school expenditures were made each year. Expenditures for capital ouday and debt sen-ice became relatively less important during this period. New buildings were not provided and the payments for buildings erected dur - ing the boom years immediately after the World War were reduced. In cases where serially numbered bonds had not been issued, redemption was discontinued. </seg>
         <seg id="p047">. Tax System of Nebraska Enrollment in each of the three types of schools of the state shows that high schoo]s had the fewest pupils, with from 19.95 per cent to 23.42 per cent of the pupils of the state. City and village elementary schools had the largest enrollment, with 46.3? per cent for the school year ending June 30, 1928; 46.71 per cent in 1929; 46.99 per cent in 1930; 47.01 per cent in 1931; 46.40 per cent in 1932, and 45.88 per cent in 1933. Rural elementary schools enrolled. 33.66 per cent of the pupils of the state in 1928; 32.83 per cent in 1929; 31.81 per cent in 1930; 31.43 per cent in 1931; 31.01 per cent in 1932; and 30.70 per cent in 1933. Enrollment in the high schools of the state increased during this entire period. In 1932-33 the enrollment in high schools was 15.68 per cent greater than in 1927-28. The increase had been quite steady as shown by the index numbers in Table 40. The tendency for young people to continue in school when it is difficult for them to secure gainful employment was quite evident. En- Table 40. — Index numbers of school enrollment. School 1927-28 1928-29 1929-30 1930-31 1931-32 1932-33 Total ;.•..... 100 99.67 99.6 ft . 99.57 99.38 . 98.53 Well school : 100 102.25 105.92 107.62. 112.51 115.68 Elementary city anil village 100 100..15 100.96 100.89 99.39 97.44 Elementary rural. 100 97.22 94.22 92.99 91.55 89.87 rollment in city and village schools remained about the same as in 1927-28 for the first five years of the period. A decline to 97.44 per cent was shown for the last year of the period. The index for rural elementary school enrollment shows a steady decline from 100 to 89.87, or a drop of 10.13 per cent from 1927-28. There is no way of determining the numbers of farm boys and girls attending city and village elementary schools or of telling how many of the high school students reside on. the farms of the state. Enrollment of farm youths in high schools is quite a factor for some oi our smaller schools. The decline in the rural elementary index of enroll - ment is evidence of the trend toward smaller families on the farms of the state. Some of the rural districts may have closed during the latter years of the period and sent their children to city and village schools although there is no proof of such action. ' : Table 41 shows the percentage of the total spent by the three types ot schools of the state for each item. High schools spent from 35.11 per cent of all money spent by schools upon the 19.95 per cent of students enrolled in all schools of the state in 1927-28; rural elementary schools spent 25.64 per cent of the total upon 33.66 per cent of the students of the state; and city and village elementary schools spent 3932 per cent upon 46.39 per cent of the'pupils. The percentage of: the total spent upon high school pupils continued to increase until 1931-32. During that year high schools spent 37.02 per cent of the total spent by schools upon 22.59 per cent of the students of the state. City and village elementary schools spent 37.37 per cent of the total upon their 46.4 per cent of the students, while rural elementary schools spent 25.61 upon the 31.01 per cent of the pupils enrolled in the country schools of the state. Both high schools and city, and village </seg>
         <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 elementary schools spent relatively less of the total in the last year of the period. Trie former spent 36.71 per cent of the total on 23.42 per cent ot the students and the latter, 36.97 per cent on 45.88 per cent of them. Expenditures by rural elementary schools of Nebraska have never made up as large a part of the total school expenditure as their share of the school enrollment would indicate they should spend. Longer class periods, more equipment, and fewer subjects taught by each teacher, together with Table 41. — Percentage division of school expenditures for Nebraska. F.pcn.iiiurc 1927-28 1928-29 1929-30 1930-31 1931-32 1932-33 Rural Elementary Cencr.il control 11.45 11.7-1 11.90 IMB 11.-tl 11.23 Teachers' salaries 30.53 30.19 29.8-1 29.44 28.59 27.36 Text hooks 29.12 26.86 28.77 25.01 26.50 27.73 School supplies 32.03 31.54 30.23 28.94 29.28 31.42 Opcraiion 18.48 18.20 18.64 17.83 16.37 16.74 Ma.nifn.incc 36-63 35.06 34.43 36.51 32.44 29.53 Capital outlay . 17.40 22.04 19.59 18.56 13.80 42.63 Debt service 13.90 25.84 24.10 26.65 25.28 27.24 All other expenses 23.31 22.66 24.27 24.38 25.54 39.69 Toi.il 25.64 27.21 26.74 26.50 25.61 26.32 City and Village Elementary General comrol 44.27 44.13 44.05 44.26 44.28 44.39 Teuton' salaries 38.21 36.91 36.48 36.84 37.00 37.09 Text books 36.49 36.54 35.30 37.17 35.80 33.60 School supplies . 29.49 28.51 30.25 29.43 29.59 27.66 Operaiion 45.66 43.41 43.11 43.82 44.55 43.66 Maintenance 34.80 33.03 33.48 31.72 33.54 33.85 Capii.il outlay 35.28 25.55 33.95 37.77 29.46 34.52 Debi sen ice 43.05 37.0H 37.95 36.68 37.36 31.38 All oiher expenies 46.13 42.71 39.35 39.14 39.03 20.53 Toial 39.32 36.85 37.09 37.41 37.37 36.97 High School Genetal control 44.28 44.13 44.05 44.26 44.29 44.38 Teachers' salaries 31.26 36.90 33.68 33.72 34.41 35.55 Tot books 34.39 56.60 35.93 37.82 37.70 38.67 School supplies 38.48 39.95 39.52 41.06 41.13 40.92 Operation . W.KTi W..W M.25 38.35 39.08 39.60 Maintenance 28.57 31.91 32.09 31.78 34.02 36.62 Capnal ouilay 47.32 52.41 46.46 43.67 56.74 22.85 Debt service 43.05 37.08 37.95 36.67 3736 31.38 All other expenses 30.56 34.63 36.38 36.48 35.43 39.78 Total 35.11 35.94 36.17 36.09 37.02 36.71 demands for more preparation by high school teachers were responsible for this condition. High-school officials have little opportunity to modify high-school curricula because of the entrance requirements of the colleges and universities and the system of accrediting high schools of the state by the university or other educational agencies. Of the various items of expenditures for which index numbers have been determined, salaries, as shown in Table 42, are the most important. While the index of salaries for all the schools increased to 102.99 in 1930-31, that for rural elementary schools dropped to 99.32 per cent and city and village elementary schools to 99.01. The index for high schools increased to 111.47 per cent of the base year. After 1930-31 all indexes of salaries paid teachers showed declines, rural elementary salaries going to 7635 per cent in 1932-33, city and village elementary salaries to 82.71 per cent in 1932-33, and high school salaries to 96.96 per cent of 1927-28. </seg>
         <seg id="p049">Tax System of Nebraska Table 42.— Indexes of school expenditures for Nebraska. . .. : . . ¦. . . = Expenditure 1927-28 1928-29 1929-30 1930-31 1931-32 1932-33 Rural Elementary General control . 100 - 104.87 107.74 109.98 108^3 97m Teachers' salaries 100 99.85 99.71 99.32 93.15 7635 School supplies 100 100.60 102.32 97.71 84.04 66 01 Operation..: 100 101.63 106.32 97.78 86.04 7733 Maintenance 100 102.98 104.64 110.61 71.44 43 52 Captlal outlay 100 97.29 95.19 , 98.62 42 35 3371 .f. bt: JOO 119.10 99.34 114.50 94 10 7197 AH other expenses........ 100 99.72 118.75 118.29 110.56 12054 City and Village Elementary General c0ntr01...... 100 101.98 103.15 109.72 109.09 99 U Teachers' salaries 100 97.53 97.41 99 01 9634 «? 7 J-?"r k»-;. 100 95.54 94.93 9-0 75 20 5201' School suppltes ;. - 100 98.77 111.18 107.93 92 26 6309 Operation 100 98.10 99.51 97.29 94 74 8165 Maintenance 100 102.10 107.07 101.14 77 75 82 97 Capital outlay. JOO' 55 . 63 BU _ jg.oi #S . ¦ Soje ¦_•*' ':-."'¦ 100. 55.18 50.53 50.88 4492 3104 All other expenses... 100 94.96 97.26 95.95 05.39 25.83 High School General control 100 101.98 103.15 109.72 109.09 99 11 Teachers' salaries 100 106.20 109.98 111.47 109« 9.96 J? ,b?° kl •;. ¦•--100 101.56 102.54 99.19 8382 6359 School supplies... 100. 106.10 111.35 117.04 9828 7156 OP™''™ •• '.. 100 110.49 112.45 108.46 10590 9430 Maintenance:..;.......... 100 120.16 124.99 123.37 ; 9604 6918 Capital outlay.... 100 85.05 83.00 8532 MO4 664 ?5 bt ; •••¦ 100 55.18 50.53 50.88 4492 3104 All other expenses........ 100 116,27 135.82 135.07 .117 X. 92.49 All Schools General c0mr01...;....... 100 102.31 103.68 109.75 109 04 98 96 S','"a\ tc*h"' ...100 100.95 102.02 02 99: 99 48 85 20 I„" b?° ks -,-. ...100 95.42 98.14 96.13 7636 5656 School supplies... 100 102.17 .108.40 108.16 9194 0729 Operation 100 103.20 105.41 101.39 9716 8539 Igg ,g_:g| ,!;.-] r?ll ,Sg JB Schools made very heavy cuts in expenditures fortext books and school supplies. Text-book expenditures for the three classes of schools dropped to 56.56 jier cent of 1927-28 by 1932-33. Rural elementary schools spent but 53.86 per cent of 1927-28 for text books, city and village schools spent 52 08 per cent, and high schools 63.59 per cent of 1927-28 in 1932-33. Less reduction took place in school supplies, the index for all the schools being 67.29 per cent of 1927-28 in 1932-33. Rural elementary schools were 66.01 percent of 1927-28, city and village schools were 63.09, and high schools 71.56 per cent. ¦:. The index ot high-school expenditures for capital outlay declined more than any other index. In 1932-33 but 6.64 per cent as much was spent for capital outlay as in 1927-28. Rural elementary schools spent 33.71 per cent as much in 1932-33 as in 1927-28, which was relatively more than city and village elementary schools, with an index of 20.35. Extremely heavy reductions took place in expenditures for debts. Less reduction took </seg>
         <seg id="p050">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 place for rural elementary schools during this six-year period than for cither of the other classes of schools. City and village elementary schools had index numbers of 31.04 in 1932-33. Only 27.24 per cent of the total of the payments for debt service were for rural elementary schools. City and village elementary schools and high schools each accounted for 3138 per cent of the total. As a consequence, the comparatively high index of rural elementary schools had little influence upon the index for all schools. The other items were of minor importance and their indexes followed the same general pattern as the index for total expenditures. These minor items are not discussed separately. Table 43.— Annual school expenditures per pupil for Nebraska. Klcmcniary \r.ir i High school Rural | City anil village s i'&lt;:::» SM.-to 577.31) 5161.20 IQ2K-2O 71.15 f&gt;T.l2 151.23 IW-ffl 7U2 (MS 148.87 lilo-U 7-l.iri 7IMO HB.lO I'm (2 MM M.97 132.15 1012 31 55.'i! 52.59 102.30 Per-pupil costs are shown in Table 43. Rural elementary schools had higher costs per pupil than city and village elementary schools after 1927-28. During this year they had lower costs per pupil. The increased enrollment in high schools in 1932-33, together with reductions of $2,790,136 in total high-school expenditures, resulted in annual expenditures per pupil of 5102.30, which was a reduction of §58.90 when compared with $161.20 in J 927-28. Numbers of high-school teachers remained about the same for the six-year period, yet almost one-sixth more pupils were given instruction in high schools in 1932-33 than in 1927-28, indicating more economical use of funds with the larger enrollment. Comparison of rural school expenditures in supervisor counties with those in commissioner counties had little significance because of the number of consolidated high schools found in the different counties. There are five such schools in Gage county, four in Cass, two in Lancaster, and none in Cuming, Boone, Valley, Frontier, or Harlan counties. Con - solidation of schools removes the farm land found in the consolidated district from the area that supports rural elementary schools. Comparisons of rural-school expenditures of two counties in which the amounts of land included in consolidations differed would mean almost nothing. There should he very little relationship between type of county organization and rural school expenditures. Of the governmental units for whose support farmers pay taxes and over which they exert a large measure of control, counties ranked next to schools as spending agencies. Because county expenditures for the whole state are not available, this discussion will be limited to expenditures by the 12 counties included in the sample taken. Table 44 shows total expenditures for the 12 counties by calendar years rather than by fiscal years. Average yearly expenditures for Lancaster were more than one- </seg>
         <seg id="p051">Tax System of Nebraska third of the total for the 12 counties and were much more than for any other county. Examination of the data found in this table will show that in general those counties with the largest population had heaviest total expenditures. .-. , ;. Table 44.- Total expenditures of 12 counties by calendar years, 1928 to Co-nic [ 19 28 [ »29 193 0 193 , 1932 1 933 | Mmsc I fI111I! "&amp;r:::::,,« if; jg ,jj j| Jg ,« rh F°( puF* es oi analysis, county expenditures have been separated into those for highways, including expenditures from road, bridge, and road - dragging funds, and those for general administration paid from the general iund. H lg hway expenditures have been divided into labor, contract con - struction, repairs, gasoline, materials and supplies, equipment, freight, and miscellaneous. General administration expenditures include sallies of elected officers, office help, and salaries of all deputies except the deputy sheriff, day labor and wages of janitor, office expense, printing, office equipment, repairs, officers' bond, jail and deputy sheriff, court and other law enforcement, mileage of county officers, election expense, expense for agncutural development including county fair, insurance, relief, and imscellaneous expense not pertaining to highways. It was necessary to include contract construction as: an item, because some of the counties followed die policy of letting contracts for road work. When such work vouchers were drawn and filed ,in the office of the county clerk. These vouchers made no division oi the amount into labor, materials and supplies, gasoline, etc. To obtain this division would have required the examination of the books of each company doing such work which was prohibited by the expense involved and the difficulty in ob^ taming their consent. c Results showed some of these items to be relatively unimportant, such items are not discussed in detail. Highway expenditures were rela - tively more important than those for general administration. Table 45 shows that the 12 counties spent 56 per cent of the total spent upon high - ways and 44 per cent upon general county administration. Five of the 12 counties used more than 56 per cent for highways, while the other seven used less than 56 per cent for the same purpose. Each of these 12 counties decreased the percentage of their total expenditures used for high - ways and increased the proportion for general administration during this </seg>
         <seg id="p052">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Table 45.— Percentages of county expenditures for highways and for general administration, 1928 to 1933 Per cent 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 " Avenge County ~ Z, m •• m » •» I l g I! g II s II s Il g II s I I 5 sr s s s s s 3« s 3 5 s f 3 s s p g i? {££„ 46 5-1 61 39 57 43 50 50 39 61 24 76 « 51 VjiicV « «&gt; 59 41 62 38 52 48 57 43 33 67 52 « Boon? « II 73 27 69 31 63 37 67 33 43 57 65 35 C 3lt 70 30 70 30 70 30 64 36 63 37 57 43 67 33 Frontier 65 35 64 36 64 36 59 41 62 38 57 43 62 38 IZ""Z, 53 47 (A 36 65 35 58 42 49 51 37 63 55 45 n aloca 44 56 55 45 54 46 40 60 35 65 21 79 43 57 w. 36 64 50 50 46 54 41 59 40 60 39 61 « 58 Hamilton 61) 40 6S 35 69 31 62 38 63 37 56 44 63 37 Thoma, » 59 33 67 56 44 55 45 41 59 38 61 f « All 12 counties 5° ** period. In 1929 Cuming county spent 71 per cent for highways, which includes construction of highways, building bridges, and maintaining them after built. In 1932 highways used but 39 per cent of the total. Even heavier reductions were made in Dakota county where 55 per cent had been used for highways in 1929 and 21 per cent in 1933. Cuming averaged 63 per cent for highways while Cass used 67 per cent. Gage county used 49 per cent and Lancaster 55 per cent for the six - year period. Valley used 52 per cent and Boone 65 per cent of the total county expenditure for roads. Harlan averaged 49 per cent for highways, while Frontier had an average of 62 per cent. In every comparison the commissioner county of the pair used a larger percentage of the total for highways than the supervisor county used. The most important item of highway expenditures was labor, according to Table 46. This item includes payments for horse work and man labor but does not include payment for the use of trucks or tractors. It was im - possible to separate man labor from horse work on many vouchers where the vouchers read "for work on roads." When tractors were used the county officials were able to inform the enumerator of that fact. The largest percentage of the county expenditures for labor on highways oc - curred in Thomas county, where it amounted to 35.06 per cent. This was due, in part, to the extensive use of horse-drawn county road machinery. Contract construction, the next item listed, was not generally used and where it was employed its importance varied from 0.11 per cent in Thomas county to 19.39 per cent in Lancaster. Thomas county had less mileage of roads requiring the use of large highway machines and more work of the type that could be done by men and horses than the other counties of this study and hence did not follow the practice of letting contracts for highway work. Cost of repairs on highway equipment was low in all the counties but unusually low in Thomas county. This fact reflects the importance of horses as a source of motive power for road machinery. </seg>
         <seg id="p053">Tax System of Nebraska Table 46.—Percentage distribution of county expenditures by items for highways in 12 Nebraska counties, average for 1928 to 1933. — ' ¦ " ¦ -. Materials County labor Contract Repairs. Gasoline and Equipment Freight .Miscell- ' " . . Supplies aneous l°° m — 3J-90 •'; 6.83 2.68, 4.87 12.20 „24 1.73 100 £¦".• V.l°. KM 2« «•''' l«-«« ' i«2 131 L 65 ¦ .?"»"«• • 31.51 5.79. 2.89 6.15 8.57 5.62 27 116 Lancaster 17.17 19.39 2.37 3.73 7.37 3.29 100 28 ¦£ m'»e . ?9.06 •.-!«. US 3.52 15.52 ' 1 '2XH ,3M *•?-••••• ?J-g ••• t.48 335 15.30 2.18 I.H 151 H". 1; 1"1 • »-3? ¦ "•« "3 4.70 11.58 3.78 M 28 Valley ........ 22.24 .8.52 2.02 4.80 .... 5.71 5.01 224 1.7 Baiota ....... 12.25 14.67 133 5.84 3.93 370 "l 91 t&amp;wes 18.73 .73 2.04 5.28 7.71 5 00 112 168 ft™"''" 26.42 15.02 2.54 425 1079 -97 207 14 ™°™» • 35.06 .11 .13 .05 8.58 l'l9 .08 M Gasoline for use in county trucks and tractors ranged from 0.05 per cent in Thomas county Ito 6.19 per cent in Cass county. Here again is shown the influence of horses as motive power in Thomas county. In a few counties; the amount spent for gasoline showed an inverse relationship to contract construction, indicating that work done with county-owned machines in other counties was performed by contractors in the counties being considered. Materials and supplies varied in relative importance from 3.93 per cent in Dakota county, where the percentage spent on contract work ran high, to 16.88 in Cass county, which is a county where expendi - tures for contract construction were relatively low. Hamilton proved an exception to the usual rule and had a comparatively high percentage of expenditures for contract construction and for materials and supplies. Thomas county vouchers included, with surprising frequency, such items as prairie hay. A few questions led the field workers to class these expendi - tures as materials and supplies for highways since the custom is to build side roads by using coarse hay on the loose sand. In no other county was this practice general. Those counties with largest expenditures for equip - ment were those with heaviest expenditures for gasoline, indicating that most of the expense was incurred upon motor-driven equipment. The remainder of the items were comparatively unimportant. Expenditures for general county administration from the general county fund were more inelastic than those for highways. As a consequence of the relatively greater fixity in the amounts of many items for general administration, the percentage of the whole going for these items fre - quently increased, although the actual dollars spent may have remained the same or even been reduced. One of those items with the greatest fixity is salaries of elected county officers. Although no two counties show the same average expenditures, remarkable uniformity in amounts spent from year to year for salaries is shown by each county. Much variation in the percentage of average expenditure for each item of general administration for the different counties is shown by the data of Table 47. Expenditures for salaries of elected officials were most important, 26.05 per cent, in Thomas county and least important in Lan - caster county, where 5.70 per cent of the total was for that item. In </seg>
         <seg id="p054">54 z Table 47. — Average percentages of total expenditures for items of general county administration in 12 counties, 1928 ¦&gt; to 1933. 2 . -—. — - n ¦ ¦ - Expenditure. Boone Cass Frontier l_,iiLastcr Cuming ciagc Harlan Valley Dakota Dawes Hamilton Thomas _] •— ¦ • Cl"' ed 11.61 8.13 14.36 570 16.52 11.44 19.18 16.79 16.22 17.06 10.66 26.05 _\ Office help deputies: : 2.94 3.37 2.68 7.it, 3.48 6.67 3.40 2.93 2.48 6.25 2.40 0.81 P1 Labor janitor; etc.. 0.68 0.63 0.25 11.59 1.52 0.44 0.87 0.88 (1.39 1.32 0.61 1.14 * Office expense ... 1.86 1.58 1.23 1.24 2.29 1.61 1.94 2.94 2.98 3.40 1.27 3.62 £ Office suppHe, .... 2.75 3.10 4.36 2.32 3.76 3.81 5.21 5.27 3.51 3.44 3.78 5.27 _&gt; Printing 132 0.25 0.78 (1.36 1.81 0.53 0.89 0.43 1.92 2.32 0.69 2.56 _• Office Muin'rncnt '".'. 0.60 0.33 0.06 0.24 11.76 0.18 0.44 1.08 0.36 0.73 0.43 0.11 m En 113 0 22 0.48 0.30 0.33 1.00 0.05 0.51 0.29 0.61 0.17 0.23 _ officers-bonds':":::: 0.09 o.h 0.21 0.10 «.m 0.18 0.36 0.41 0.72 o.i« 0.2s 0.33 1 ail deputy sheriff 0.84 1.07 1.02 1.96 1.27 1.64 1.29 0.93 1.35 2.48 1.72 0.94 crt Law enforcement . 134 1.86 3.35 5.38 (1.72 3.20 2.87 1.28 1.02 2.69 1.53 2.73 *4 Mileage 0.40 1.21 1.22 0.22 1.42 1.83 1.79 1.09 0.52 1.16 1.25 1.88 % Election " " .. .. 0.53 0.58 0.83 0.50 0.78 0.46 0.43 (1.62 0.68 0.79 0.49 0.92 g Aerl county fair .. . 1.77 0.25 2.70 0.73 2.35 1.53 0.81 3.00 3.46 3.83 2.97 0.03 § Insurance . 0.86 0.59 0.29 0.53 0.93 0.91 0.96 1.49 0.68 0.84 (1.92 1.11 * „'.?_? 3.56 6.45 2.38 14.56 3.95 12.08 7.36 7.12 16.24 6.95 5.34 4.56 !» Mothers'' "nensidii'.'.'.'' 1.66 1.54 1.15 2.69 2.36 2.67 1.55 ... 1.84 2.35 1.40 1.25 " M^c/llaneou. ...... 0.61 0.53 0.65 0.60 2.03 1.19 2.54 0.80 1.96 1.26 0.88 0.48 M . ¦ _, f O </seg>
         <seg id="p055">Tax System of Nebraska general, those counties with the larger populations spent the lowest percent - age on salaries. This is largely due to the statutory provisions made for officers in the various counties whereby both the number of offcers and their salaries are fixed by law. Some opportunity to combine offices in the smaller counties has been offered by law. In Thomas county the county clerk serves as county assessor, clerk of the district court, and registrar of deeds. In spite of this combination of offices, salaries of officials re - quired Jarger part of county expenditures in Thomas county than in any other county of the study. Salaries of office help and deputies showed great variations in the relative importance among the expenditures by the counties. The range was from 0.81 per cent in Thomas county to 736 per cent in Lancaster county. Those counties in which a large part of the county money was paid for salaries of elected officers spent a smaller percentage upon salaries of offce help. This was true of Thomas, Dakota, Cuming, Frontier, Harlan, and Valley counties. Dawes county proved an exception to the rule with high percentage for salaries of elected officers and also for office help and deputies. Whenever density of population is accompanied by a large enough total population; a smaller percentage of the total expenditures is used for salaries and office help. This indicates some increase in efficiency for the more populous counties. Relatively small percentages are accounted for by such minor items as Jabor and janitor, office expense, office supplies, printing, office equipment, repairs on court house, and officers' bonds. The most important of this group was office supplies, which ranged from 232 per cent for Lancaster county to 5.27 per cent for Valley and Thomas counties. The larger counties appear to be able to buy supplies more advantageously than the smaller ones. : Combination of the items of jail and deputy sheriff gives a fairly good picture of the importance of maintaining law and order in the various counties. Salaries of county judges and sheriffs are included in salaries of elected officers. The cost was relatively greater in Lancaster than in any other county, 7.34 per cent being used for that purpose in Lancaster county.' The lowest percentage used for these two items in any county was 2.18 in' Boone county. The presence of larger cities contributes to the cost of law and order in the various! counties. f j A range of from 0.22 per cent to 1.88 per cent of the total for mileage paid to county officers does not indicate very great burdens for this item. Sparseness of population is responsible for the larger size of this percentage. Although the problem of relief was of increasing importance in these counties during this entire period, it did riot reach serious proportions until after the end of the peribd.Three counties, Dakota with 18.08 per cent, Lancaster with 17.25 per cent, and Gage with 14.75 per cent, spent more than any other counties I for relief and mothers' pensions. Lancaster and Gage counties have the largest cities, which probably contribute to the heavy percentages for support of those who are unable to care for them - selves because of old age or lack of income. Dakota county has no large city but does have a large population that is regularly employed in the </seg>
         <seg id="p056">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 factories, railroad yards, packing houses, and other industrial concerns of Sioux City, lowa. As the depression increased, many of these people were discharged and became a burden upon Dakota county after their savings were exhausted. Such expenditures in Dakota county were $11,811 in 1928, $14,641 in 1929, $16,231 in 1930, $21,850 in 1931, $26,886 in 1932, and $22,819 in 1933. In the last year of the period, Dakota spent over 50 per cent more money on relief than on its highways. Although poverty doubtless existed in dominantly agricultural counties, it was cared for locally and the county was not called upon to assume the load to such an extent as in the counties with relatively more non-farm population. Table 48. — Rant{ o/ 12 counties in per-capita county expenditures, 1928 to 1933. Rank i 1928 ! 1929 I 1930 1931 1932 1933 1. Can Frontier Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomas 514.02 515.H6 522.63 528.77 521.42 $12.84 2. Boone Cass Frontier Can Cast Hamilton U. 62 15.76 19.36 14.73 14.58 12.01 3. Thoma* Roone Cast 22 Frontier Hamilton Cass 1355 15.59 19.33 13.59 13.65 11.39 4. Hamilton Thomas Hamilton Cuminß* Frontier Frontier 12-16 15.50 17.51 13.45 12.35 10.34 5. Frontier Hamilton Boone Hamilton Valley* Gage* 12.24 14.63 15.22 13.10 12.04 8.72 6. Dakota Cumin);* Dakota Boone Boone Lancaster 10.02 13.96 14.46 J2.81 10.62 7.83 7. Dawcs Dakota Cuming* Valley* Dakota Dawcs 9.81 12.87 13.72 11.52 10.62 7.80 8. Cuming" Harlan* Valley* Harlan* Case* Valley* 9.67 12.47 13.41 11.01 9.55 7.47 9. Gape* Valley* Harlan* Dakota Harlan* Dakota 9.59 11.07 12.84 10.79 8.88 7.31 10. Valley* Gage* Gage* Dawcs Lancaster Harlan* 8.80 10.42 10.52 9.82 8.61 6.M 11. hiarhn' Dawcs Dawes Gage* Dawcs Boone 7.93 9.72 10.36 8.19 7.78 5.90 12. Lancatlfr Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Cuming* Cuming* 6.18 8.07 9.60 8.13 3.47 5.M Surrcil counties arc the supervisor counties; italic type indicates the near-by commissioner counties. The rank of the 12 counties in per-capita total county expenditures and the amounts spent per person are shown in Table 48. Each year of the six shows the commissioner county of three pairs having heavier per-capita expenditures than its paired supervisor county. These pairs show Cass with heavier total expenditures per person than Cuming, Boone heavier than Valley, and Frontier heavier than Harlan. The supervisior county, Gage, of the fourth pair always spent more for each person than Lancaster, the near-by commissioner county. Because the same services are rendered by the county in commissioner counties and the county and township to - gether in the supervisor counties, more detailed comparisons will be made after townships have been discussed. Highways are responsible for most of the expenditures by the town - ships of Nebraska. Of the four counties with supervisor organization, Gage county townships ranked first, Cuming second, Valley third, and Harlan </seg>
         <seg id="p057">'¦ Tax System of Nebraska fourth. These townships spent from 83.94 to 96.28 per cent of the town - ship money upon highways. The percentage spent by Harian county townships, 83.94 per cent, was lower than that for any of the other three counties. In the records for Harian county townships many vouchers were found that were so itemized as to be unclassifiable. Some of these may have been for highway f purposes although they were classed as miscellan - eous general-administration or general-fund expenditures. Average annual per-acre expenditures of 22 cents places Cuming county first for the six years as indicated by data in Table 50. This was divided into 21 cents for roads and one cent for general administration. Gage county _had average annual per-acre total expenditures of 17 cents, road expenditures 16 cents, and general administration one cent, and ranked second. Valley county; ranked third with average annual total per-acre expenditures" of 13 cents, road 12 cents, and general administration one cent. Harian county was last with total expenditures of 8 cents an acre, highway expenditures of seven cents, and general administration of one cent.-. • .. ¦,'.-. ' i ¦ . :. . , ¦'¦;- .:¦'¦'. '•¦¦. . ¦¦¦;. Comparisons based upon individual years show the four counties hold - ing the same rank from. 1927 to 1932 as they held when ranks were based upon average annual per-acre expenditures. In 1933, Gage county spent ten cents an acre, nine of which were for roads and one for general adminis - tration. Cuming county spent nine cents an acre, eight for roads and one for general administration, to rank second. Valley continued in third place and Harian was Jast in 1933. When township expenditures are reduced to a per-capita basis (Table 51) the four counties do not continue in the same relative position as in Table 50. Cuming county had average annual township expenditures of $5.64 per person, Valley $4.54, Harian $3.36, and Gage $3.04. Harian county townships spent 54 cents per person for general administration, which placed that county ahead of Valley with 29 cents. Cuming, with 21 cents, continued above Gage, with 11 cents per person. Two factors seem of major importance in determining township expenditures of the different counties. They are average annual rainfall and population density as shown in Figure 1. Those counties situated in areas where average annual rainfall is heavy will be forced to spend more money to drag roads and repair damages due to floods than will be necessary in counties with less rainfall. The presence of more people in a given area results in more miles of roads, heavier travel per mile, and greater expenditures for; road construction and maintenance. Harian and Valley counties are located where population density during the years covered was 10.1 to 20 per square mile, Cuming county 20.1 to 30, and Gage county 30.1 to 40. j Average annual rainfall varied for Harian county from 22 to 24 inches, for Valley county from 24 to 26 inches, for Gage county from 30 to 32 inches, and Cuming county about 30 inches. Gage county is more fortunate than Cuming in that more o£ the roads of the county are federal and state highways, which are under the control of the state highway department and are not maintained from county or township funds. ¦'" ¦'. ¦' ! ¦ v •¦¦'.'¦'¦ '¦ ¦ :¦.'¦',--¦¦'. ¦'.'¦¦ ¦•-.•¦¦¦ ¦.'•¦¦'." • </seg>
         <seg id="p058">58 Table 49. — Highway expenditures by counties, 1928 to 1933 (tournships only). County [ Material. General PI and Labor Contract Repairs Gas and Kquipment I-'rright Mlsccl- adminis- _ year I supplies lanenu. tralii.n &gt; 1928 541867 518.168 S 2.11H S 3.1112 5111.526 S 8.189 S 65 S 88 $2,014 -&gt; 1929 4(1.610 17.1H0 1.552 3.158 7.880 11.978 28 310 3.701 O 1910 51 2118 H. 716 1.825 5.181 17.926 X.7411 61 619 2.882 _&gt; 1911 46 814 16.799 1.878 5.149 19.517 7.124 48 919 2.915 fl 19(2 41617 7.901 2.1,28 (..519 lll.2(.8 1.1815 45 25(1 3.199 J_ 1911 17.025 2.544 1.178 1.117K 3.6811 572 14 295 2.417 _] As B . . 40.527 12.1,78 1.944 4.181 11.616 6.101 41 424 3,010 - 1928 66.790 7.670 412 5 13.893 1.108 984 2.634 1929 . .. 74.549 10.611 57(1 . . 19.514 1.846 803 3.455 gl 1910 ... 77.763 14.265 454 210 19.601 2.513 627 3.591 3 1931 67.706 2.811 494 211 12.796 3.429 1.022 3.751 tn 1912 .. .. 60.710 5.924 341 14(1 11.539 2.655 12 948 3.548 2 19H 14.668 5116 248 8.077 2.189 328 3.530 V ay,,.. ::.::.:;:.. 63.698 6.884 41.3 n« 14.237 2.12.1 2 ?ss 3,41s m Harlan H 1928 16.650 5.604 353 841 3.244 1.177 7 ... 1.799 _" 1929 14,913 6.804 267 573 2.251 2.202 4 ... 3.287 &gt; 1930 19.269 4.636 306 900 3.145 4.444 29 ... 6,751 H 1931 :..::..::.. 16.571 8.435 «h 965 2.321 1.124 26 ... 6.872 o 1932 15.107 3.129 198 572 2.816 515 ... 4.977 Z 1933 5.971 2,770 167 457 1.912 400 ... 5.314 j- Av B 14.747 5,230 292 718 2.615 1,647 11 0 4,833 g* Valley &gt; 1928 22,902 8.848 190 472 6,742 2.196 Z 654 1.813 » 1929 29.492 9.628 260 417 7,046 2.411 1 1.077 3.938 _. 1930 27.660 9,266 168 575 7.352 1.690 7 599 2.913 1931 25.436 5.929 232 195 4,961 139 2 559 2.662 W 1932 30.001 4.347 519 228 5.157 430 3 384 2,646 C 1933 18,602 1,874 253 208 3,756 97 241 2.545 Avg 25.682 6.649 270 349 5^836 U6l 2 586 2.753 _ </seg>
         <seg id="p059">Tax System of Nebraska Table 50— Per-acre township expenditure in four supervisor counties of Nebraska, 1928 to 1933. County ~~ "~ ; """ ' ; . ¦'¦'-. al"1 Total road fund Total general Grand total Cuming 1928 ..... ....... !; 5.23 $.02 125 1929 .: .23 \ot M 1930 .27 SI ;i_ 181 :........- .27 Mr '_? 1932 .; .20 0 i? 1933... ; .08 .01 « Average annual.: ..... .21 . . - ,01 ' - *22 Gage .... 1928 : .j, .17, ¦"• .. 17 ' 1929 .20 .6 ii 1930 '.' : ..I . jj 1931 ..-..; .16 0 - '» 1932 . .15 01 7Z 1933 : .!-¦ .09 .01 10 Average annua1........... .16 '.01 17 Harlan ' 1928 ..................;. ! .08 .01 09 1929 .08 0 'cl 1930 ! .09 02 U 1931 '-! .08 . .02 10 1932 ...; I .06 ol ¦_! 1933 03 -.:¦¦..-.¦¦ m i..-.-. ;g Average annual ,07 ,01 08 Valley . '! ¦'.'" Z. 1928 &#132;¦,: ; .12 .01 13 1929.... ; .14 : o ii 1930 ,1 .13 0 , 14 1931 .................... .11 .01 ..•{_¦' 1932 , .12 01 'a P j .07 - .01 : OS Aycrage annual : . .12¦¦'¦--¦. .01 .13 Of Cuming county's 96.28 per cent spent for roads, on an average 50.06 per cent was spent for labor, 15.66 for contract construction, 14.37 for materials and supplies, 7.78 for equipment, 5.41 for gasoline, for road machinery, 2.40 for repairs on equipment, and the remainder, 0.16 per cent, for freight and other miscellaneous road expenditures. Gage county spent 69.28 per cent for labor, 7.49 per cent for contract construction, 0.5 per cent for repairs on equipment, 0.15 per cent for gas - oline, 15.48 per cent forlmaterials and supplies, 2.53 per centlfor equip - ment, and 0.75 per cent for freight and other miscellaneous expenditures to account for the 96.28 per cent spent for highways. Expenditures for highway labor for townships in Harlan county were 49.01 per cent of the total, for county construction 1738 per cent, for repairs on equipment 0.97, for gasoline 239, for materials and supplies 8.69, for equipment 5.47, arid for^freight 0.03 per cent. 1 Valley-county town - ships spent 5933 per cent for labor on highways, 1536 for contract construction, 0.62 for repairs on equipment, 0.81 for gasoline, 13.48 for materials and supplies, 2,68 for equipment, and T36 per cent for freight and other miscellaneous road expenditures. Labor on township roads is the largest single item of township • expenditures in every county, with </seg>
         <seg id="p060">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Table 51.— Per-capita township expenditures in jour supervisor counties of Nebraska, 1928 to 1933. Cumins Gage Ycir General I General lllßh' adminii- Toul Hle°- I adminU- ToUl v tyi rrjiion w*y* I (ration 1928 56.07 $.20 $6.27 $3.02 5.09 $3.11 1929 5.78 ¦ .26 6.04 3.57 .11 3.68 1930 6.94 .20 7.14 3.82 .12 3.94 1931 6.85 .20 7.05 2.92 .12 3.04 1932 5.00 .22 5.22 2.71 .12 2.83 1933 1.97 .17 2.14 1.51 .12 1.63 Averse 5.45 .21 5.64 2.93 .11 3.04 Marian Valley Vcar General General '"&gt;¦¦" ailminis- Total H|Sh" adminii- Total rrjn.in ;"!* tr.ilion 1928 53.09 5.20 53.29 54.38 5.19 54.57 1929 3.01 .37 3.38 5.26 .41 5.67 1930 3.65 .75 4.40 4.96 .31 5.27 1931 3.35 .77 4.12 3.94 .28 4.22 1932 3.51 .56 3.07 4.33 .28 4.61 1933 1.32 .60 1.92 2.65 .27 2.92 Avcracc 2.82 .54 3.36 4.25 .29 4.54 percentages ranging from 35.14 in Harlan county for 1933 to 73.41 in Gage county for 1931. Vouchers showing items for labor frequently read "for work on highways or roads." Much of this labor was for a man and team but this was not always clear and no effort was made to separate man labor from horse labor. Contract construction frequently meant roads or bridges built by the county highway department under contract with the township. Where this was the case the county was not charged with expenditures made on such contract work. This item was second in importance for the townships in three of the counties and third for the fourth. Contracting with the county for road work indicates that township officials realize that a larger operating unit can do the work more cheaply than the township. These four township counties varied a great deal in the average annual percentage of the township expenditures that were used for materials and supplies, which includes such items as gravel, cement, bridge materials, posts, and snow fences. The largest percentage was spent by Gage count) 1 and was 15.48; Cuming county was second with 14.37, and Valley third with 13.84 per cent. Harlan county spent less of the township money for this item than any of the three other counties. Its average was 8.69 per cent. For three of the four years Harlan county townships spent 10 per cent or more for materials and in the other three years spent from 631 to 7.97 per cent. Cuming county townships ranged from 9.13 to 19.26 per cent for materials and supplies. Relatively low expenditures by townships for gasoline were possible because townships accept work upon the highways in lieu of money pay - ment of poll taxes. When this is done a man and team work as a unit in payment of the poll tax. Such road work would be reported under labor. </seg>
         <seg id="p061">Tax System of Nebraska The heavy road machines were owned by the county or by construction companies, and the work done under contract. Gage county was the only county whose townships made fairly large purchases of road equipment in 1933. Its expenditures for equipment amounted to $2,189 in 1933. Cuming county townships spent $11,978 for road equipment in 1929 and only $572 in 1933. From $4,444 in 1930 Harlan township purchases of equipment fell to $400 in 1933. Townships in Valley county cut their equipment purchases from $2,411 in 1929 to $97 in 1933. Because township governments were dominated by farmers, their expenditures for equipment were reduced to the minimum during 1933 when farmers were short of funds. Combining county and township expenditures before calculating the per-capita expenditures for roads, and arranging the counties according to rank in Table 52, changes the relative positions as shown in Table 48. Table 52.— Per-capita expenditures for roads and bridges (county and '. -. :¦ \ township),l92B to 1933. Rank I 1927 1929 1930 1931 1932 : 1933 1. Cuming* ¦ - Cuming* ' ; Cuming" Cuming'- Valley* Hamilton $12.01 $15.68 : $15.87 $16.25 $11.18 $6.78 2. Cast Valley* Cast Thomas Cast Cast 9.75 11.75 13.52 15.76 9.18 6.46 3. Boone Boone . Valley' Valley' Thomal FroiM'tr 8.73 11.35 13.35 9.88 8.78 5.88 4. Gage* - Cast . -Thomas ' Cast Hamilton Gage* 8.01 11.02 12.68 9J6 8.60 5.47 5. Frontier Harlan' Frontier Harlan' Cage' Valley* 7.95 . 10.64 12.34 8.84 7.76 5.14 fi -Valley' Frontier Hamilton- Bcone Frontier' Thomas ,7.94 10.14 12.14 8.13 7.60. ¦»•«&gt; . 7. . .Hamilton Hamilton Harlan* Hamilton Boon? Cuming* 7.53 9.49 10.97 . ¦• 8.11 7.08 , 4.10 B. Harlaii' . Gage' Boone Frontier Cuming' Dawes 6.75 8.68 10.50 7.96 6J7 3.05 . 9. Thomas - Dakou Gage. - Gage' - Harlan* Lancaster 5.57 : 7.09 9.03 633 5.99 2.86 10. Dakota Lancaster- Dakota ' .Lancaster - Lancaster ' Harlan* 4.45: 5.18 7.76 4.71 4.21 2.79 11. Dawei Thomas Lancaster Dakota Dakou Boone '.'.,-¦¦ 3.56 5.06 6.26 4.31 3.68 2.53 12. Lancaster Dawes Dawci Dawei Dawej Dakou 3JO . 4.88 4.73 4.06 3.11 1.52 Starred counties arc the supervisor counties; italic type indicate! the near-by commissioner counties. Cuming county now ranks first during the first four years, displacing Cass, Frontier, and Thomas counties, which shared first place in Table 48. When county and township expenditures are combined, Cuming county moves from last Jin 1932 to eighth (see Table 48), and from last in 1933 to seventh. Valley increased its rank four places and was sixth in 1928. Township expenditures increased the rank of Valley county to second in 1929, third in 1930 and 1931, first in 1932, and fifth in 1933. Gage county increases its rank and fluctuates between fourth in 1928 and 1933 and ninth in 1930. Per-capita expenditures in Harlan county increased while </seg>
         <seg id="p062">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 the rank of the county fluctuated quite widely, varying from eighth in 1928 to fifth in 1929, sixth in 1930, fifth in 1931, ninth in 1932, and tenth in 1933. Uniformity in rank of counties for road expenditures is noticeably lack - ing. When the pairs of counties are compared, Cuming county has higher expenditures per capita for roads, than Cass county during the first four years, while Cass exceeds Cuming county the last two years. Boone county had higher per-capita highway expenditures than Valley county in 1928 and lower the last four years. Gage county per-capita expenditures exceeded those of Lancaster county for each year of the six. Frontier county had higher per-capita expenditures than Harlan county in 1928, 1930, 1932, and 1933 and was surpassed by Harlan county in 1929 and 1931. Of the 24 comparisons that can be made, seven are in favor of the supervisor counties of the pairs and 17 favor the commissioner. In providing highway services commissioner counties do the work with lower expenditures per person than do supervisor counties. The inclusion of township expenditures for general administration with expenditures of the county for the same purpose adds relatively little to the per-capita expenditures of the four supervisor counties and makes Very few changes in rank. Table 53 shows the average expenditure for the county and township in the supervisor counties and for the county only in the commissioner counties and shows the ranks of the different counties. Thomas county spent more money per capita for general administration than any other county. From $7.98 in 1928, the amount this county spent increased to $13.01 in 1931. Lancaster county ranked below the other counties during the first four years of this period. Its rank increased in 1932 and 1933 after the heavy increase in relief expenditures had taken place. Further details are given in Table 53. In general the most populous counties spent less per capita for administration than did those counties with fewer people. Valley county spent more for general administration than Boone throughout the entire six-year period. This was offset by Cass, whose expenditures exceeded those of Cuming county for the six years. Gage county spent more per person than Lancaster county during five years and less the sixth. Frontier ranked above Harlan two years and below it four years. Measured from the standpoint of the greatest number of combina - tions favoring either type of county, the commissioner counties appear to spend less per capita for county administration in a ratio of 15 to 9. The combination of per-capita expenditures for highways and general administration of both county and townships in Table 54 changes the ranking of the counties. Cuming and Thomas share first place throughout the period. The former ranked second in 1930 and 1931. Heavy expendi - tures for highways during the first four years are responsible for the high rank of Cuming county, while relatively heavy administrative expenditures kept Thomas high in the ranking. Lancaster remained low in the rank - ings five years and rose to eighth the sixth year after relief and highway expenditures had both increased. Low expenditures for roads in Dakota county partially offset heavy relief expenditures and kept the county low </seg>
         <seg id="p063">Tax Svst£M of Nebraska . 1.1 •••'.-' : '" ¦. ¦: in the rankings. In general, high road expenditures by supervisor counties can be blamed for their higher ranking in total expenditures. The total expenditures per capita in Cuming county for the first four years were larger than in Cass county the same years. The services per - formed in the two counties were approximately the same. For the last two years the reverse situation held true and Cass county had heavier Table sl.—Per-capita expenditures for general administration of county | and township, 1928 to 1933. Rank; 1928 .1929 . 1930 ¦ 193J 1932 1933 ' ¦ ' I '' ¦ ¦• I :- --. I ' I.'. .Thomas Thomas.. . 'Thomas , Thomas Thomas Thomas S 7.98 510.44 S 9.95 513.01 512.64 S 7.94 2. Dawes Dakota Frontier Dakota Dakota Dakota !¦¦¦ 6-25 , 5.78 ' 7.02 6.48 6.94 5.79 3. Dakota Frontier Dakota Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* 5.57 5.72 6.70 6.29 5.95 5.26 4. Valley* Gage* Harlan* Valley* Valley* Valley* 5.42 . 5.43 6.28 5.86 ...... 5.47 5.25 5. . Vlamiltun Harlan* Cass Dawes Cast Hamilton .1.93 5.21 ... 5.81 - . 5.76 5.40 .; 5.23 6. Boone Hamilton' Dawes Frontier Hamilton Lancaster .4.89 5.14 . 5.63 -¦ 5.63 5.05 4.97 7. Gage* Valley* Gage* Cast Frontier Cass 4.69 4.99 5.43 5J7 4.75 4,93 8. Harlan* ' - Dawes ; Hamilton "' Hamilton Daivcs Gage* .4.48. 4.84 5.37 4.99 4.67 4.88 9. Frontier Cast Valley" Gage* Gage* Daivcs ¦1.29 4.74 5.33 4.90 4.62 4.75 10. Cast Cuming? Cuming* Boone Lancaster Frontier 4.27 ¦:¦... 4.32 5.00 4.68 4.40 . 4.46 11. .' Cuming* Boone Boone - Cuming* '.-:¦ Boone Boone 3.94 4.24 ; 4.72 4.25 : 3.52 3.37 12. Lancaster '¦:¦; Lancaster Lancaster : Lancaster Cuming* Cuming* 2.88 2.89 3.34 3.42 2.33; I 3.25/ Starred counties arc the supervisor counties; italic type indicates the near-by commissioner counties. expenditures per person. In 1928, Boone county ranked above Valley but in the last five years Valley was above Boone. Frontier spent more per person in five of the six years and less than Harlan the sixth year. Gage spent more than Lancaster county during each of the six years. Seven of the 24 yearly county comparisons in favor of the supervisor county and 17 in favor of the commissioner county of the several pairs is a margin that indicates superiority of the latter. . .- Lancaster county ranks' above all other counties in average annual total expenditures per acre with $1.58 as shown in Table 55. Cass county was second with 77 cents an acre, which was less than half as much as Lan - caster county had 1. Gage county averaged 70 cents an acre, Dakota 68 cents, and Cuming 61 cents to rank third, fourth, and fifth, respectively. Hamil - ton ranked sixth with 49 ccntsj Valley seventh with 41 cents, Harlan eighth with 34 cents, Boone ninth with 33 cents, Frontier tenth with 19 cents, Dawes eleventh with 13 cents, and Thomas last with 7 cents. When comparisons of the paired counties are made from Table 55, Lancaster spent more than Gage each year and Harlan more than Frontier. Cass </seg>
         <seg id="p064">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Table 54.— Toted expenditures per capita jor county and township, 1928 to 1933. Rank j 1927 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 1. Cuming* Cumins* Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomas 515.95 $20.00 $22.63 528.77 $21.42 $12.84 2. Cats Valley* Cuming* Cuming* Valley" Hamilton H. 02 16.74 20.87 20.50 16.65 12.01 3 Rttone Frontier Frontier Valley* Cast Can 1362 15.86 19.36 15.74 14.58 11.39 4 Thomas Marian* Can Harlan* Hamilton Valley* 13.55 15.85 19.33 15.13 13.65 10.39 5 Villev* Cast Valley* Can Gaßc." Gage* 13J6 15.76 18.68 14.73 12.38 10.35 r&gt; G-ikc" Boone Hamilton Frontier Frontier " Fronrier 12.70 15.59 17.51 13.59 12J5 10.34 7 Hamillnn Thomas Harlan* Hamilton Harlan* Harlan* 12.45 15.50 17.25 13.10 11.94 8.05 8 Frontier Hamilton Boone Boone Boone Lancaster 12.24 14.63 17.22 12.81 10.62 7.83 9. Harlan* Gage* Gape* Gape* Dakota Dawcs 11.23 14.11 14.46 11.23 10.62 7.80 JO. Dakota Dakota Dakota Dakota Cumins* Cumins* 10.01 12.87 14.46 10.79 8.70 7.34 11. Daives Dawes Dawes Dawcs Lancaster Dakota 9.81 9.72 10.35 9.82 8.61 7.31 12 Lancj'tcr Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Dawcs Boone 6.18 8.07 9.60 8.13 7.78 5.90 Starred counties arc the supervisor counties; italic type indicates the near-by commissioner counties. Table 55.— Per-acre expenditures of total funds (county and township) 1928 to 1933. K.mk 192: I 1929 1930 1931 1932 1933 \ I 1. Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster S 1.17 5 1.54 5 1.8" 5 1.61 S 1.72 5 1.59 2. Ca's Cast Cass Cuming* Cast Cars .73 .82 1.00 .81 .75 .58 3 Gage' Gape' Dakota Cass Gage* Gage" .71 .79 .89 .76 .70 .58 4. Cuming* Cuming* Cumins* Dakota Dakota Dakota .62 .78 .82 .68 .67 .48 5. Dakota Dakota Gape* Gage* Hamilton Hamilton .59 .78 .81 .63 .48 .42 6. Boone Boone Hamilton Hamilton Valley* Cumins* .45 .52 .62 .47 .45 .29 7 Hamilton Hamilton Boone Boone Boone Valley* .45 .52 .52 .44 36 .28 8. Valley* Valley' Valley* Valley* Cumins* Boone .36 .44 .50 .42 34 .21 9. Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* Harlan* .29 .40 .44 .38 JO .20 10 Frontier Frontier Frontier Frontier Frontier Frontier .17 .22 .27 .19 .16 .14 11. Di*cs Dawci Dawcs Dawcs Dawcs Dawcs .13 .14 .15 .14 .11 .11 12. Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomas Thomai Thomas .06 .07 .09 .13 .09 .05 Starred counties are the supervisor counties; italic type indicates the near-by commissioner counties. </seg>
         <seg id="p065">Tax System of Nebraska exceeded Cuming every year except 1931. In four of the six years, Boone county spent more than Valley and less the two years that remained. Nine yearly comparisons show the commissioner county spent less than the supervisor county and 15 comparisons show the supervisor county spent less per acre than the commissioner county. Per-acre expenditures are greater for those counties with dense popula - tion. The presence of the city of Lincoln in Lancaster leads to greater per-acre expend tures and to lower per-capita expenditures. Although Gage county has one city of over 10,000 population, the population density for the county is no greater than that or Cass or Dakota counties. Some advantage in per-acre expenditures was shown for the supervisor group of counties. : </seg>
         <seg id="p066">Chapter Vl—Delinquency Prior to 1933, real-estate taxes were due May 1 of the year following trie levy of the tax. If not paid by that date, they were considered delin - quent and 10 per cent interest was charged on the unpaid tax. 1 In many instances the period during which taxes were delinquent was relatively short, yet delinquency had actually occurred and was so recorded for this study. For example, a farmer who has a herd of hogs partially fat or whose hogs are fat but who considers the price too low may prefer to allow his taxes to become delinquent and pay interest rather than sell his hogs at the prevailing price. In the wheat areas of the state, payment of the taxes for the year may depend upon the harvest of a small-grain crop and may be delayed until after combining or threshing in July or August. In neither case do such delinquencies indicate particularly dis - tressing conditions, but rather poor timing of tax-paying dates to accommo - date farmers. An attempt was made to remedy this condition in 1933, at which time the date of delinquency was made July I. 2 In 1935, the law was again changed so that real-estate taxes are now payable in two install - ments, the first of which becomes delinquent May 1 and the second September 1. An exception is made in the case of counties with 150,000 or more population where delinquency dates are March 1 and August I. 3 In 1953, tax-delinquency data were collected by a corps of workers employed by the federal government and supervised by the Rural Econ - omics Department of the Nebraska College of Agriculture. This work was done under Project F-23 of the Civil Works Administration. These data furnish the material upon which this chapter is based. No claim of completeness of data is made for the individual counties, although it is felt that these data are representative of conditions in the state. In work - ing over the figures found in the county offices, it was quite generally the practice to begin tabulation with the most recent year and to take up the year immediately preceding after the first was completed and so on until all years had been tabulated. This project was suspended by orders from Washington before the field workers in several counties had com - pleted the survey. Consequently the last year of the period, 1932, should be more nearly complete than any of the others. It is, therefore, used in preparing the map, Figure 8, showing distribution of tax-delinquent farm lands of the state for 1932. More delinquencies were found in some counties in 1931 than in 1932. Two counties, Morrill and Rock, have no delinquencies indicated, not because there were none but because no usable records were secured from those counties. Reports for Nemaha, Deuel, and Sioux counties were quite incomplete. Data for the other counties are more nearly complete and make a better basis for consideration. No part of the state appears to be exempt from tax delinquency nor does there appear to be any close relationship between the length of time the land has been in farms and 1 Compile! Suiuro iif Xcbrj&lt;ka. 1929, Sec. 77-1907. ' U»i ..( Nebraska. TOJ, p. 590 1 Ljw, o( Nebraska, 1933, p|i. 557-558. 66 </seg>
         <seg id="p067">, . i Tax System of Nebraska tax delinquency.! Counties in the western or more recently settled parts of the state had as much delinquency as those in the eastern or older parts. Of the 91 counties for which data were obtained on delinquencies on farm real estate, eight had $100,000 or more in delinquent farm real-estate taxes in 1928. For the following year, 13 counties had as much as $100,000 and in 1930, 18 counties had this amount. The high point in amount at delinquent farm real-estate taxes came in 1931 when 100,000 acres or more were delinquent in each of 32 counties of the state. The situation improved for 1932 when but 18 counties showed $100,000 of taxes delinquent. Cherry county had the largest acreage of farm land tax-delinquent ac - cording td Figure 8. This county had 1,927,135 acres delinquent in 1932. • • • iiJlLj..'¦~??v iF - • h?? fPa S^ *xQi: £M itl [4 j£ %.. m ns ::: J^S, £•!••:...•:....::..... .%; : j Uj/U . .1: :i;VML -S^r T7T . Iff ..... gg! &lt;5g4~ .w:. ::: ra^ .•v• • • ;^; Tsi S^^TTTij^E s;i •::T^rTnTssTTT^lTT77}j"7iwr - ;..':::; .:. ". ..;.•-. zftooo-acres ¦" ; .-.''. :-.-'¦ ;. •••¦¦ Ficj. B.—Acres of farm land tax delinquent for 1932. This was over 56 per cent of the 3,453,888 acres assessed in the county in 1931 for taxes payable in 1932. Even low valuations per acre failed to prevent heavy tax delinquency in Cherry county. Farmers in Cherry - county rely upon sales of cattle for most of their income. These sales seldom are made before calves are weaned in the fall. In many cases, cattle have been sold and the proceeds spent before May 1 of the following spring, when taxes are due. As a result, farm real-estate taxes have quite generally been permitted to become delinquent. Farmers preferred to pay the 10 per cent interest on past-due taxes to arranging for a loan at the bank even though interest rates on bank loans were lower than 10 per cent in many cases. Additional loans could not be secured upon personal property or farm lands in many cases and farmers found permitting taxes to become delinquent the easiest way to secure additional, loans on their already heavily encumbered assets. : During the entire period for which the delinquency data shown in Table 56 were obtained, 113,689 different farm properties were reported delinquent one or more years. Of these 33,644 were delinquent only one of the five years; 27,115 two years, 20,654 three years; 16,709 four years, and 15,567 all five years. These numbers cannot be compared with the number of farms shown in the census as a farm frequently includes several </seg>
         <seg id="p068">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Table 56.— Tax-delinquent farm properties for 91 Nebraska counties, 1928 to 1932. Number of years delinquent ? number ¦""""• O- I T.o | TW | Four | Five g£ Adam. ... 367 409 365 330 411 1,882 Anlrlopr. 677 531 792 51 24 2,075 Arthur .... 1(M 62 85 95 97 443 Ranne, HO 100 74 25 9 348 Maine 45 72 81 105 209 512 Boonc 414 417 384 314 358 1,887 Boi Buttc 189 215 215 236 314 1,169 Boyd 187 202 181 264 311 1,145 Brovn . 279 253 211 229 160 1.132 Buffalo .... 958 731 374 144 ... 2,207 Burt 37S 386 276 246 219 1.505 Butler ".'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 477 382 223 185 106 1,373 Ca.i 631 482 356 253 164 1,886 Ccilar ' 251 334 359 358 375 1,677 Chaw 149 131 200 231 284 995 Cherry 1.120 441 ... ... ... 1.561 Cheyenne 472 168 90 17 2 749 Clay 346 345 286 266 250 1,493 Colfax 347 275 156 141 154 1,073 Cumins ¦¦¦¦ 555 346 204 140 79 1.324 Cusicr 596 381 378 412 332 2,099 Dakota 85 90 82 121 202 580 Dawc. 190 224 258 275 270 1,217 Damon 411 369 353 350 348 1,831 IVucl . 196 223 253 12 3 687 Duon 350 390 317 257 127 1,441 DoJbc 722 516 331 227 171 1,967 Douelai 35.' 313 220 225 262 1,372 Dundy 226 221 168 87 30 732 Fillmorc .. 572 419 278 229 209 1,707 Franklin 706 95 31 4 ... 836 Frontier 297 311 251 287 304 1,450 furnaj 1.107 583 331 205 168 2,394 (,a ß e 396 223 76 16 5 716 Garden 251 196 169 164 257 1,037 Garfiel.l 115 131 120 99 102 567 (,mper 230 168 123 97 123 741 Crjnt 39 47 41 34 16 177 Grcclo 16) 244 430 C 73 1,042 2.552 Hall 199 274 164 148 80 865 Hamilton .... 626 421 281 265 219 1,812 Harlan ... 324 277 214 186 168 1,169 Hajo 249 161 130 87 69 696 farm properties according to the assessors' classification. When a property is delinquent but one out of five years, it may have been due to an over - sight on the part of the tax payer or to his temporary shortage of funds. Such cases do not indicate distress on the part of the tax payer. Two years of tax delinquency out of five may not show real distress. However, when taxes on the same piece of property are not paid for 60 per cent of the time, distress is quite evident. The 16,709 properties delinquent for four years and the 15,567 delinquent for five years certainly do not appear to be in the best financial condition. Thirteen counties, Antelope, Buffalo, Custer, Furnas, Greeley, Holt, Knox, Lancaster, Madison, Otoe, Saunders, Scotts Bluff, and York, had more than 2,000 farm properties on which taxes had been delinquent at some time during this five-year period. These counties are scattered throughout all sections of the state and include counties from the corn - hog section, the wheat section, and the grazing areas. Fourteen counties </seg>
         <seg id="p069">: Tax System of Nebraska Table 56.— Tax-delinquent farm properties for 91 Nebraska counties, 1928 to 1932 (Contd.). . Number of yean delinquent Tool On. | Tw. | Three | Fot | Fite Hitchcok 262 292 .202 164 124 1044 Holt 466 417 434 530 442 2289 Hooker. 28 41 84 84 118 355 Howard 393 321 338 282 154 i &lt;v Jefferson 579 .446 329 208 215 'm lohnson 357 291 199 157 123 1127 Kearney 213 222 178 208 237 1058 Keith 78 125 167 231 374 975 KeyaPaha ........ 167 162 175 . 157 150 811 Kimball 152 208 ; 205 ¦ 98 461 1224 Knox : . 440 602 572 519 424 2557 Lancaster ......... 690 542 393 324 2« 2 198 Lincoln... . 650 475 216 20 5 1366 f°F»&gt; ..-: 110 .. 128 118 105 43 504 Loup , 120 138 131 119 105 613 Madison -;..:; 788 491 350 268 205 2 McPherson 184 103 75 ' 49 . 42 453 Merricfc ......... 269 159 53 11 ?i • «v Nance.... 528 506 283 37 34 1 lij Nemaha .......... 220 .103 13 10 9 355 Knolls •• 427 332 . 210 172 129 1270 °&gt;« 879 562 336 268 202 2247 P»»-nee 367 273 230 152 123 IHS £""•" -•• 32': 21? 167 , ,158 !«.. iJOK ™«'P» •• &#132;. 276 233 195 203 208 1115 P««c 308 .351 246 ¦ 255 222 1382 Plane... 354 218 60 22 13 667 Jed Willow. 138 242 179 114 147 820 Rtehardwn ....... 678 427 263 144 92 1604 fine--- ¦ 174 304 225 219' 337 259 Sarpjr ............ 312 114 78 49 79 . 632 Saunders ......... 565: 577 518 431 249 5 3411 Sc«m B1 U « 634 : 869 266 149 141 2.059 Scward 570 384 189 144 84 1371 Shcidn 413 408 I-' 27i: 260 219 1571 Sherman ......... 355 395 .394 384 82 1,610 Swux 329 191 137 61 94 «12 Stanton .......... 271 208 175 124 114 892 Thayer .......... 462 344 282 237 148 1473 Thomas .......... 67 78 98 106 198 547 J"""" 1" • 288 355 342 288 . 233 1.506 Valley 309 279 .295 235 217 1315 Washington 226 149 58 23 41 497 W'ync 362 264 197 155- 127 1105 Webster 404 351 309 188 5 1257 Wheeler "... 292 162 143 99 84 780 York ¦¦¦¦¦¦...... 681 496 365 298 232 2,072 TOTAL ¦¦¦¦¦¦¦ 33,644 -27,115 20,654 16,709 15.567 113,689 had more than 300 properties that were delinquent for each of the five years. They are Adams, Boone, Box Butte, Boyd, Cedar, Custer, Dawson, Frontier, Greeley, Holt, Keith, Kimball, Knox, and Saline. These counties do not include any counties east of Cedar and Saline. Counties from all other parts of the state are found in this list. L ¦¦¦ Tax delinquency for 91 counties of the state is summarized in Table 57. From 1928 when 41394 farm, properties were delinquent to 1931 when 73,940 were delinquent, a steady increase was shown. Conditions improved after 1931 and only 71,104 farm properties were tax delinquent in 1932. Column 3 shows the acres on which taxes were delinquent. The smallest number of tax-delinquent acres, 10,862,589, occurred in 1928. The largest number of tax-delinquent acres came in 1931 when 18,514,564 acres were </seg>
         <seg id="p070">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 so classed. A slight decrease to 18,072,389 acres occurred in 1932. Column 4 shows the amount of taxes levied against these delinquent acres. In addition to the delinquencies for the current year considerable amounts of taxes for earlier years were due in each of these years. Columns 5, 6, and 7 give an idea of this situation. In Column 5 are shown the numbers of properties on which taxes had been due and not paid for over a year. Twelve hundred such properties were delinquent in 1928. This number was more than doubled, 2,528, in 1929. In 1930 the numerical increase was about the same although the rate of increase was only half as great. The number of delinquent properties was 3,783 in 1930. More than twice that number, or 7,862, properties were delinquent in 1931. The largest number of such properties occurred in 1932 when 18,897 were delinquent. Table 57.— Tax delinquency of farm property for 91 counties of Nebraska, 1928 to 1933. Taxes Icvicil during former Number .• i i' *") &gt;ca" aml "nPa'"l &gt;urrmer Number Irwi-if Year if »n these Number Average proper- J( . rfs j Jfll | s am | &#132;f amount •'" ilelini|ueni proper- Amount tor nc |, mcs property !«;„ 4| «4 111.81,'5m 54.490.81tl 1.200 S 187.976 $156.64 1929 4N 772 12J40.15.&lt; 5.399.529 2.528 170,191 67.32 IWO 55 434 13.252.605 6.419,345 3,783 316,454 83.65 I9JI 71 940 15.5H.564 7.754.020 7.862 732,199 93.13 1932 71.104 18,072.389 6,154.712 18,897 2,019,482 106.87 The total amounts of such old delinquencies and the average amount due on each property are included in Table 57. Taxes amounting to 5156.64 were owed on each property on May 1, 1928, in addition to the unpaid current taxes. Substantial reductions in total taxes past due for more than one year occurred in 1929 when a total of $170,191 or $67.32 per farm had been delinquent longer than one year. The heavy increase in total amount due was not offset by a corresponding increase in numbers of delinquent properties and the amount of taxes delinquent on each farm increased to $83.65 in 1930. More than double the total amount of delin - quent taxes in 1931 was accompanied by slightly less than double the numbers of properties delinquent and, as a result, the average amount increased almost $10.00 —to $93.13 —for 1931. The average delinquency per tract increased in 1932 until $106.87 was owed on each delinquent tract and a total of $2,019,482 was past due more than one year. State, county, township, and school units of government had been forced to continue to carry owners of farm properties for $2,019,482 in taxes that had been due for more than a year. Table 58 shows the situation in the 12 counties of the sample. In this table, the first main column, "Years in which delinquency occurred," is divided into five sub-columns, one for each year. This should be read from left to right. Where an X appears in the sub-column under a year, the number of properties shown in the line under the county name were delinquent for that year. If X appears for two years, the number of prop- </seg>
         <seg id="p071">71 '•".'' Table 5%.-—Delinquency by years. Years in which delinquencies '¦•'..-' occurred •'¦¦¦'.: '¦¦'.«'¦ ¦ ' *.- " ¦- _.'- -' fe ''.".' • —•— ; - - -*. ¦ . j_, ' .-....¦,__. '._.¦. c_&gt;''n 3 ' a ¦ x xM:zzzizs,Zi. 's •!?.'¦ :}_¦ .J? ; ¦:'{,:¦'¦;: S "._'•.':'¦ '! i . 4 5 _ V 3.6 XXX X92fS6sil M S 22 '.'¦'¦¦ '•• :'¦»¦¦ .« 31 447 XXX XX 358 217 .64- ;»_ 304. &gt;«. 249.: 5 2-2 270 2,9 19. 2.433 : H X X X - 4 3? ?r t? •? - 2&lt;i ]2 15 14 . 12 4 164- 5 .— XX .4 ..... -7 • ... 16 ... . 12 11 ¦ 7 28 ....... 2 ' 7? 17 . in ** X X X X . 37 42 : 34 27 49 27 57 4 23 33 J] 2? IS V&gt; - .Z^.:iZ;,.Z:/X;,--Z-!.vZ-:_SZ ?_Z:-,;:-¦.¦¦¦ _8 ii 1.:1 Si 'ii- ¦¦¦¦¦Zi ZZ.i:-;:vs:.ZZi{-..V'_!-.-' T,'„ii„ - i' i 2 |z ¦,; f I XX ,¦'¦ X -..".'¦., 36' ,22 .14 14 12 334fi 14 ..... ,_? O X vv. J ]?, : ',? Jl 2218 5 . 10 1.3 34' ;. 115 __ X X |Z i« « _5 21 27 .31. 2 22 12 22 . 13 231 W XX 19 24 7? in ¦'¦'¦'¦¦}? ?1 5? 35 : 6 28 69 3 . 483 g .xx„ i? : .&amp;.¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦; 1 : .g,-.. * ;. ¦':_.. .--¦ 1' II ]„ 1 - ill -I X XXX .07 70 .„.56 1? |. . , £ Z 42 14. • 1 ii™ A 111 | XX X39\i7-?aif ' J„ ' - ¦¦'¦J? 4940 3 189 * ¦ 2; XX f9 33 ....... 27,. 24 24 10 64 10 12 24 39 9 315 xx x iIS 11' lU\l , .-..¦»¦¦.¦- ?s- j j ¦»¦• .:.» ¦"_ ; :-.-¦ „ x ¦¦¦ • ¦¦_¦ • ¦¦_?¦ ',; .? .? a ¦ i ¦ '-•¦»• * » "¦¦¦ s« a ,__.¦,¦ -.5 17 —.H 14 ¦¦ ¦¦ ¦¦ 2i 20 "3. 29 fi 1 '« ¦ l '* *&gt;jft X 102 74 165 193 65 70 274 66 3 6 211 14 1 2M XX . 162 110 218 164 156 135 237 129 39 100 174 30 !'«_ X 145 93 194 207 104 129 196 185 42 60 20' 2? ¦ l'S. _____ 1.887 1335 1.886 1.324 1.450 1,169 2,198 716 580 1.217 l.I?l 547 i&amp;l.l Starred counties are the four supervisor counties. Italic type indicates four near-by commissioner counties. </seg>
         <seg id="p072">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 crtics were delinquent both years. For example, the first line of the table shows the number of properties on which taxes were delinquent May 1, 1928, only. Boone county had 85, Valley 57, Cass 109, etc. Line 2 shows the number of properties on which taxes had not been paid May 1, 1928 and 1929, but for which payment was made on time for the other three years. Line 6 shows the number of properties on which taxes had been delinquent in 1928 and 1930 but had been paid for 1929, 1931, and 1932. The last column of the table shows the total for the 12 counties. In these J2 counties, 665 properties were delinquent in 1928 but had their taxes paid when due all the other years; 326 were delinquent in both 1928 and 1929, 447 in 1928, 1929, and 1930, 656 in 1928, 1929, 1930, and 1931, and 2,4333 for each year of the five-year period. A total of 6,342 properties were delinquent three or more successive years of the period. Sixteen hundred and eight of these were delinquent for four successive years. Three or more successive years of tax delinquency indicate distress on the part of tax payers of the counties. Lancaster county with 2,198 parcels of farm property delinquent had the largest number and ranked much ahead of Gage county with its 716. Of Lancaster delinquencies, the largest number occurred for the single year 1931 when 274 properties were delinquent. The next largest number was in the class showing five years of delinquencies. There were 249 in this class. For the two years, 1931 and 1932, 237 properties were delinquent. On May 1, 1933, taxes on 196 Lancaster county farm properties were delinquent. Four consecutive years, 1929 to 1932, of tax delinquency were shown for 122 properties in Lancaster county. Three consecutive years of tax delinquencies, 1930 to 1932, occurred for 106 properties. A total or 726 properties were delinquent for three or more consecutive years. In 1932, 185 farm properties were tax-delinquent in Gage county. One hundred and twenty-nine were delinquent for both the years 1931 and 1932. Only 64 Gage county properties were delinquent three or more consecutive years. Boone county had 1,887 properties against Valley county's 1,335 delinquent one or more years. In Boone county, the largest class was that for five consecutive years of delinquencies, 358. The number of properties on which taxes were delinquent for three or. more consecutive years was 863 for Boone county and 568 for Valley county. Total delinquencies for Cass county were 1,886 and exceeded those for Cuming, 1,324. Cass had 614 and Cuming 314 delinquent for three or more consecutive years. More farm properties, 1,450, were delinquent in Frontier county for the period than in Harlan county, which had 1,169. Seven hundred and eighteen Frontier properties and 314 in Harlan county were delinquent for three or more years in succession. The smallest number was found in Thomas county although the situation was probably as bad in that county as in any of the state. Parcels of land that are assessed against individuals in Thomas county are larger than for the other counties and the county has fewer acres assessed. Table 59 shows the number of delinquencies for the 12 counties by years. More properties were tax-delinquent in 1931 when there were </seg>
         <seg id="p073">Tax System of Nebraska 10,589 than in any other year; 1932 was second with 9,891; 1930, third with 8,364; 1929, fourth with 7,388, and 1928 last with 6,661. Lancaster county had more delinquent properties than any other county for the period and had more delinquencies during each of the last two years. Thomas county had fewer delinquencies than any other county in 1932. It remained fairly constant with delinquencies ranging from a low of 363 in 1929 to a high of 406 in 1931. Harlan, Gage, and Dakota counties each had more properties delinquent; in 1932 than in 1931. All other counties of the sample had more delinquencies in 1931 than in 1932. Table 59.—Number of delinquencies by years, 1928 to 1932. County . ".'..'¦¦¦ 1928 1929 1930 ! 1931 1932 Boom ¦•• 912 965 1,054 1,308 1,207 Valley.... 651 . 722 754 873 777 Cm» 639 704 959 1,115 1,078 Cuming 342 449 460 826 737 £° nli" • • 704 769 871 1,034 962 HsriM 521 536 598 702 747 Lancaiter ••• .809 910 1,025 1,506 1,243 G»p ••••••••••••• 89 105 224 300 441 Dakou ¦'¦ 365 374 394 397 475 gawa .......; 603 717 796 932 814 Hamilton •• 651 774 831 1,190 1,020 Thonu. 375 363 398 405 390 Toal ¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦ 6,661 7,388 8,364 10,589 9,891 Table 60.— Acres of farm land on which taxes were unpaid May 1. County 1928 1929 1930 1931 1932 Boone ..... .....164,250 165,857 184,471 227,444 213,340 Vallej 134,761 144,706 158,775 176,859 161,791 Cw 82,729 87,812 124,639 133 865 132 814 aiming 55,852 69,590 71,234 128,133 123,572 ?«"&gt;"« '. 231,974 : 259,111 287,160 372,215 340870 Harlan 108,158 106,727 - 121,492 147997 156713 Lancaster 104,215 U8.885 134,728 200,675 163 610 Sp •""• 9,161 11,249 28,666 42,725 58876 ¦£*&lt;«» ••••• 55,729 56,080 57,886 61,111 74,807 g™™ •.— ••• 395,783 478,561 479,162 560,162 485642 Hamilton 87,300 104,530 103,557 151,413 127694 Tfcomai ..-.; 217,468 206,601 229,390. 227,820 215,676 Tht numbers of acres on which taxes were unpaid for each year are shown in Table 60. Dawes county, which is one of the largest counties, had more acres delinquent than any other of the sample counties. Gage county, which is another large county, had the fewest delinquent properties for each year. Frontier had next to as large numbers as Dawes throughout the period. Thomas, which was one of the smallest counties in the sample, was third in number of delinquent acres: Wide variations in size of counties make the percentage of the assessed acres that are tax-delinquent a good indication of the tax situation. The figures in Table 61 are obtained by dividing the number of acres that were tax-delinquent in a county for any one year by the number of acres that were assessed the preceding year. The counties are then arranged for each year in descending order from the county with the highest percentage to that with the lowest. The greatest distress is shown in Thomas and </seg>
         <seg id="p074">Nebraska Agriciltlral Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 Dawcs counties. Farmers in these counties rely upon cattle for the largest part of their revenue and may have waited to pay their taxes until their young cattle ivere sold in the fall and early winter. The situation did not improve for Thomas county and grew worse for Dawes as the depression continued. Frontier, which was third in rank the first year and the last three years and was fourth the second year of the period, showed delin - quencies ranging from 39 per cent in 1928 to 63 per cent in 1931. Poor wheat crops and low prices for grain were probably two of the main causes of the distress in this county. Roone and Valley counties had about the same percentages of their lands delinquent throughout this period. The same general type of farm - ing prevails in these two counties with livestock feeding and grain pro - duction found on nearly all farms. Low prices for farm products and dis - tress due to drouth conditions can be blamed for the situation in these two counties. The increase in rank of Dakota county during this period Table 61. — Rant{ of counties in percentage of assessed acres that were delinquent May 1. Rank 1928 1929 1930 193! 1932 1 Thfjni.i* Thorn.i» Thomas D.uvcs Thomas (,2 59 66 67 62 2 Ojwo Uauo [Jatves Thomas Dau-cs 47 57 57 65 58 I Frontier Dakota Frontier Frontier Frontier 39 45 48 63 57 ¦) Boone Frontier Valley* Boone Boone 38 41 45 52 49 5 Valid" Valleyl Boone Valley* Dakota 38 41 42 50 48 (. lJakou Bofjiir Dakota Hamilton Valley* Mi 38 38 44 « 7 HarUn- Hamilton Cjis Harlan' Harlan' 31 )\ 37 42 44 8 Hamilton Marljn' Marian' Dakota Cast 21, m .15 39 39 9. Cjii Cj« Hamilton Lancaster Hamilton 24 Id 30 39 37 10. l*jniditer Lancaster Ljncjtter Cdfs Cumins* 20 23 26 39 34 11 (umiriK* Cumins' Cuming* Cuming* Lancaster 15 19 20 37 32 12 &lt;&gt;JKc" &lt;mkc" dage" GaKc" Gage' 2 l_ 5 8 II Marrnl tountir* arc the su|x:r\ isor counties', italic type indicates the near-by commissioner counties'. was probably due to increased relief expenditures and to low prices of farm products. Gage county had the smallest percentage of its lands delinquent of all the sample counties, although delinquencies increased a great deal during the period. The two per cent of the land that was delinquent in 1928 and 1929 and the five per cent delinquent in 1930 indicate no distress. Eight per cent in 1931 and 11 in 1932 show no particular distress. Gage county is situated in that part of the state in which delinquencies were less important. Even among the counties of southeastern Nebraska, Gage </seg>
         <seg id="p075">-.¦,'. Tax System op Nebraska appears to be very favorably situated from the tax-delinquency standpoint. Gage county has several large settlements of Germans who are members of the Mennonite or Lutheran churches and many settlements of Danish and Bohemian farmers whose love of the land and thrift have prompted them to keep their titles to the land free from tax or mortgage liens. In three cases where a supervisor and near-by commissioner county are compared, the former has shown lower percentages of tax delinquency. Frontier county had more farm real estate tax delinquency than Harlan county, Cass more than Cuming, and Lancaster more than Gage. In 1928 Boone and Valley counties each had delinquent taxes on 38 per cent of their farm real estate. A greater percentage of the farm real estate was tax-delinquent in Valley county than in Boone county in 1929 and 1930. During 1931 and 1932 the percentage of farm land which was tax delin - quent was greater in Boone county than in Valley county. Although this comparison shows the supervisor county in better condition than the commissioner county of the pair, the actual difference was less than 10 per cent in 10 cases out of 20 where comparisons were made. In the case of Frontier and Harlan counties when comparison was made for 1928, a difference of only 8 per cent was found. For Boone and Valley, the differ - ence was three or less in every year although two comparisons showed conditions more favorable to Boone, the commissioner county. Differences in favor of Cuming county of nine per cent in 1928, seven per cent in 1929, two per cent in 1931, and five per cent in 1932 do not show great superiority of the supervisor county. However, a difference of 12 per cent or more in ten of the comparisons indicates less distress among the supervisor counties than among commissioner counties. Taxes that are not paid when due become a first lien on the property and endanger the title of the owner of the property. If not paid by the first Monday of November after taxes become delinquent, real estate against which such delinquent taxes have been levied is subject to sale/ 1 If a tract of land has been offered for tax sale three consecutive years and not pur - chased for want of bidders, the county commissioners are authorized to direct the county attorney to start foreclosure proceedings in the same manner as if the lien were a mortgage. 3 For this reason, accumulated delinquent taxes on a property seldom run for more than three years nor do they amount to a large sum on a single property in Nebraska. ; Taxes that were past due by as much as one year in the 12 sample counties are shown in Table 62. Dakota and Thomas counties were the only ones for which such delinquencies were reported in 1928. The iotmet had two such properties upon which $20.00 in taxes had been due for more than a year and the latter five properties delinquent for $486.00. All counties showed some such delinquencies in 1929. The 12 counties had 215 properties delinquent for $12,916 in 1929, 377 for $12391 in 1930, 934 for $80,340 in 1931, and 2,295 for $264,113 in 1932. When the pairs of counties are compared, two cases show the near-by commissioner counties with more properties delinquent for larger amounts 'Compiled Statutes of Kcbraika,, 1929, Sec. 77-2001 *JWA, Sec. 77-2030. .': "¦ ; </seg>
         <seg id="p076">76 Table 62. — Property-tax delinquencies of more than one year's standing. p [^2~8 1929 ioiii '911 1932 H C"un,» No. Amouo. N„. | Ami.v.ii N... | An.ounl N... | Amount No. Am.mM &gt; „ , 6 5189 16 SI .11111 72 58.312 260 531.672 tj 1 ""J"'. '• ! V, 4 524 12 3.521 196 23.860 £ Valle&gt; 10 215 II 807 32 2.235 124 13.178 m i"",:-; 5 201(1 17 1.824 511 6.297 173 24.971 £ Cuming* 4 liSl 27 3.892 IMI 10.025 271 32.164 2 r™"'"-; , 281 5 284 11 912 253 24.401 - ,a lan J 26 I 51 II 493 45 3.049 Z Lancaster '«¦ g 4|) . H„„ „ r , In . MH H f'J'f, , S2O 11 721 25 1.027 41 3.213 99 12.274 up l™'"* '*" ,6 ISM 151 8.795 257 21.809 380 44.280 H S*"^ 22 4247 39 7.385 78 13.867 207 29.450 5 "a"" 1'"" i a„6 96 2 888 70 6.905 176 8.823 191 13.956 S h,T._i:::::::: 5 so. 2T5 i.:™ 377 32.991 934 w,..*.. 2.295 204.1 v § Starred counties are the fur supervisor counties. Italic type indicates the four nearby commissioner counties. £- a r: r 0 </seg>
         <seg id="p077">Tax System of Nebraska than the paired supervisor counties had, and two cases where the reverse situation was true for 1929. Boone and Frontier counties had more delinquency than their respective paired supervisor counties, Valley and Harlan. Gage and Cuming counties were ahead of Lancaster and Cass. Dakota, Dawes, Hamilton, and Thomas counties had worse conditions than the others in 1929. Heavy increases in numbers of properties and amounts of taxes delinquent for more than one year did not alter the standing of the four pairs of supervisor and commissioner counties. When comparisons are made between the percentages in Table 61 and the values in Table 62, some relationship is shown. Thomas and Dawes counties, which had the highest percentages of their land delinquent each year, accumulated past-due tax delinquencies more rapidly than the rest of the counties. Thomas had a high percentage of its land delinquent in 1928 and had some taxes that were more than a year overdue. Their annual delinquency remained high in 1929 and the accumulated more-than-one - year-old taxes increased more than 400 per cent. In 1930,! the percentage of annual delinquencies remained high and the amount due on year-old delinquencies was much greater. The same was true in 1931 and 1932. While not so pronounced as in Thomas county, the tendency for tax delinquencies to accumulate also appeared in the eleven other counties of the study. Some of the annual taxes that are not paid tend to ac - cumulate and help swell the total of those not paid for more than a year. This, situation does not indicate a complete tendency to pay taxes when livestock or grain is sold. Much of Thomas and Dawes counties is owned in units too small to be operated successfully by a tenant. Many of the absentee owners of small tracts have been unable to sell their land or to collect the rent from it. After a certain time some of these owners tire of paying taxes out of other income and permit the taxes to become delinquent and the land to be sold at tax sale. Land sold in this manner is frequently added to other holdings to form more economical operating units. To some extent a similar transition from smaller units to larger was taking place in the wheat area and in such counties as Harlan, Frontier, and Hamilton. Throughout much of these areas the size of homesteads was too small for present-day operation and changes have not been made very rapidly. . . .. V Table 63 reveals another aspect of tax delinquency, namely, the per - centage of the taxes that were levied against farm real estate and not paid by May 1 of the year when due. The percentage of farm real-estate taxes that were delinquent increased throughout the period. Thomas was the only county whose percentage of delinquent farm real-estate taxes reached a peak in 1930. Boone, Dakota, and Gage counties reached the peak in 1932. The remaining eight counties had the highest percentage of delinquency in 1931. Two counties, Thomas and Frontier, had more than 50 per cent delinquency throughout the five-year period. In 1928, Dawes county also showed over 50 per cent delinquency. These three counties, together with Boone, Valley, Harlan, and Cass, made up the seven counties with more than 50 per cent of delinquencies in 1930. Nine counties, including the seven that were delinquent in 1930 and Lancaster </seg>
         <seg id="p078">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 nnd Hamilton had one-half or more of their farm real estate taxes unpaid in 1931. Of these nine, Lancaster and Hamilton reduced the percentages of real-estate taxes that were delinquent in 1932. Tax delinquency in Dakota county increased to over 50 per cent in 1932. This county and Boone, Thomas, Dawes, Frontier, Harlan, Valley, and Cass made up the eight counties that had 50 per cent or more delinquency in 1932. In but one case did the supervisor county of a pair show greater percentage of farm real-estate tax delinquency than the commissioner county of the pair. The difference in this case was but three-tenths of one per cent. Fifteen of the twenty comparisons between supervisor and commissioner counties showed differences greater than ten per cent in favor of the supervisor county. In counties where farmers receive most of their revenue from a single product such as wheat or cattle, a higher percentage of the farm real-estate taxes are likely to be delinquent if that particular farm product is not marketed prior to May 1, which was the tax-delin - quency date during this period. Table 63.— Percentage of property taxes levied against farm real estate and delinquent in 12 counties, 1928-1932. Rank 1928 1929 1930 1931 1)32 1. Thorn ji Thomas Thomas Thomas Boone 73.J 75.6 90.0 87.1 72.2 2 Pawes Frontier Frontier Frontier Thomas 55.9 62.2 64.0 81.2 70.9 3 fmnuer Valley' Boone Dawes Dawes 55.1 49.7 56.6 80.7 70.6 4 Boone Boone Valley* Boone Frontier •. 46.3 49.4 56.2 67.8 65.9 f Marian 1 Harlan' Dawcs Harlan' Harlan' 44.6 46.8 56.2 67.1 61.1 6 Valley* Dakota Harlan* Valley" Dakota 44] 41.9 51.8 61.1 54.9 7 Dakota Dawes Cass Hamilton Valley" 40.5 41.7 51.5 58.9 54.4 8 Hamilton Hamilton Dakota Cass Cass 37.0 40.5 44.0 56.8 51.7 9 Cats Can Hamilton Lancaster Hamilton 35.2 36A 40.9 56.3 47.1 10 Lancaster Lancaster Lancaster Dakota Lancaster 28.0 31.0 37.9 43.9 45.8 11 Curajnc* Cuming* Cuming* Cuming' Cuming' 17.3 20.4 22.6 41.2 36.0 12 Gage* Gjgc' Gage* Gage' Gage? 23 3.0 7.3 11.2 14.3 Starred counties are the supervisor counties; italic type indicates the near-by commissioner counties. Farm real-estate tax delinquency appears to be a problem of major importance for the state as a whole and for the twelve counties of the sample. When judged by the percentage of the assessed land on which taxes were delinquent and the cumulated back taxes the same counties show distress. Evidently much of the year's taxes remain unpaid each year with resulting heavy accumulations of back taxes. </seg>
         <seg id="p079">Chapter Vll—Summary The importance of local real-estate taxes in the tax situation has not been given as much consideration as state and school taxes yet undoubtedly they have great importance. Nebraska farm real-estate taxes were lower dur - ing the period 1913-1933 than those of the most of the West North Central group of states. This favorable situation does not preclude the necessity of study of the real-estate taxes of the state. The.cost of a detailed study of the relative importance of state, school; county, township, and other taxes for the entire state would have been prohibitive and necessitated the use of a sample when this study was planned. The counties selected included Boone, Cass, Cuming, Dakota,-Dawes, Frontier, Gage, Hamilton, Harlan, Lancaster, Thomas, and Valley counties. Four of these—Cuming, Gage, Harlan, andl Valley—had townships instead of precincts and a board of supervisors instead of a board of commissioners. Each of these counties was compared with a commissioner county located near at hand and designated "near-by commissioner counties." Where they would apply, data for the entire state were used. Assessments.—Assessment of tangible property is the first step in deter - mining the tax that must be paid by the owner of property. In Nebraska, assessing of tangible property is done by county and township or precinct assessors. The tax lists prepared by these officials are received and adjusted by a county board of equalization before being sent to the state board of equalization at Lincoln for comparison with similar lists from other counties. The state board reviews these lists and orders any changes that seem necessary in order for assessments to be properly equalized. The value of all tangible property was $3,141,000,000 in 1927 ant&gt; $2,521,000,000 in 1932. About 57 per cent of this was farm real estate, 20 per cent city real estate, and the remainder personal property. No separation is made of personal property into farmer-owned and tbwn - or city-owned personal property. It was necessary 'to calculate the value of tangible property owned by farmers before it was possible to find the percentage of the tangible property of the counties that was owned by farmers on which they paid taxes. Wide variations in the importance of farm property were found for the 12 counties of this study. Farmers in Boone, Cuming, Frontier, and Hamilton counties owned more than 80 per cent of the tangible property of the counties, while those of Dawes county owned 54 per cent, Thomas county 43 per cent, and Lancaster 31 per cent of their respective counties. The percentages for the entire group ranged from 57.42 per cent in 1930 to 62.71 per cent in 1928. Town pro - perty in West Point arid Wisner of Cuming county and Beatrice of Gage county is not subject to township levies. The removal of this property from the total tax roll of the county before figuring the percentages of the property subject to township taxes and owned by farmers increases the percentage greatly. About 90 percent of such property is owned by farmers of Gage county and 96 per cent by farmers of Cuming county. The total per-capita value of tangible property owned by farmery and 79 </seg>
         <seg id="p080">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Blx. 105 the per-capita value of farm land were greater in commissioner than in supervisor counties for three of the four pairs considered and lower for one pair. The value of farm property per person was lower for the western - .Nebraska counties than for those in the eastern part of the state. Levies.—Making of the levies follows assessment of property. The rate of the levy is determined by dividing the amounts of money that are to be raised by property taxes by the total assessed value of all property found in the unit for which the levy is being prepared and are expressed as mills on the dollar. The amounts levied are determined by multiplying the value of the property against which the levy applies by the mill levy. The same piece of property will be subject to state, county, school, and sometimes special levies such as drainage or paving levies. Property-tax levies were greatly reduced for all taxing units of Nebraska from 1927 to 1933. In supervisor counties farm property is subject to township levies. The levies made in 1927 totaled 563,914,948, of which $30,351,819 was lor schools, SI 1,862,474 for the state, $11,017,263 for the counties, $9,061,253 for cities and villages, and $1,622,139 for townships. In 1933 total levies were $41,417,767, with $18,760,559 for schools, $5,081,779 for the state, 58,170,934 for counties, $8,803,432 for cities and villages, and $601,063 for townships. School levies accounted for 45 to 84 per cent of the total property tax for the 93 counties. About 20 per cent was for counties and the same amount for cities and villages. Between 12 and 13 per cent was for the state. The remainder was levied by townships. Of the total property tax levied in 27 supervisor counties, townships were responsible for from 5.27 to 9.87 per cent of the tax. Combined county and township levies were about 25 per cent of the total in supervisor counties and the county levies about 20 per cent of the total in the six commissioner counties. Performance of the same functions required 5 per cent more of the levy - in supervisor counties than in commissioner counties. The income of Nebraska farmers and the purchasing power of. farm products did not keep pace with tax levies for the different taxing units of the state during the period 1927 to 1932. The index of tax levies for such units as rural schools, townships, and counties, which were subject to close control of the farmer voters, showed greater conformity to the index of farm income than was true for those taxing units whose control was farther removed from the farmers. The allowance of a one-year lag in the index of tax levies reveals a fairly close fit to the index of farmers' income and the index of purchasing power of Nebraska farm products. Per-capita levies for county use in supervisor counties were lower than per-capita county levies in commissioner counties. Neither type of county had any marked advantage over the other in county levies against each acre of farm land. The combined per-capita township and county levies for supervisor counties were higher than the county levies for com - missioner counties. Receipts.— State receipts ranged from $21,882,216 in 1928-29 to $28,149, - -849 in 1931-32. Of the total receipts of the state, general property taxes supplied from 20.63 per cent in 1931-32 to 41.73 per cent in 1927-28, </seg>
         <seg id="p081">Tax System of Nebraska : gasoline taxes from 12.19 per cent in 1927-28 to 24.90 per cent in 1931-32 and U. S. contributions from .7.38 per cent in 1928-29 to 22.12 per cent in 1932-33. . ; County receipts for the 12-county sample ranged from $2,182,237 in 1933 to $3,103,44* in 1929. From 55.13 per cent in 1933 to 67.53 per cent in 1928 came from the. tax on tangible property. The addition of the gasoline tax to county revenue sources in 1929 made possible rather sub - stantial reductions in the county tax on tangible property. The tax on gasoline produced from 9.65 per cent of the county revenue for these 12 counties in 1929 to 19.4 per cent for 1933. Heavy reductions in motor - vehicle license fees for 1933 resulted in decreased county income from this source, from 18.03 per cent in 1928 to 10.29 per cent in 1933. Town - ships received 90 per cent or more of their revenue from property taxes. The largest part of the remainder came from the poll tax. School money was derived from relatively few sources, the most important of which was the tax on tangible property, 87 per cent of the total. Rural schools collected from 23.14 per cent to 25.49 per cent of all school revenue and from 25.28 per cent to 27.55 per cent of the property tax. County and township receipts per capita were higher in the four super - visor counties than were county receipts in the four near-by commissioner counties. . . •• Expenditures.—Taxes collected by county treasurers can be paid out when properly drawn warrants are presented and when sufficient money to cover the warrant is in the fund drawn;upon. : State expenditures for highways exceeded all others for the state with expenditures for educational institutions such as the state university and the four state teachers' colleges second, and! the expenditures for the institutions under the state Board of Control third. State highway expendi - tures increased 65 per cent from 1927-28 to 1931-32, while those for educa - tion and the state institutions under the Board of Control remained about the same until 1932-33. Total state expenditures were 8 per cent greater for 1932-33 than for 1927-28. : l! -: Expenditures for the. public schools of Nebraska are almost as great as for all the other governmental units. From 53.75 per cent to 64.87 per cent of the money spent for schools was for teachers' salaries. Enrollment in the high schools of Nebraska ranged from 19.95 per cent to 23.42 per cent of the total in public schools of the state. (Elementary schools of Ne - braska cities and villages had from 45.88 per cent to' 47.01 per cent and rural elementary schools from 30.70 to 33.66 per cent of the students of the public schools. High-school enrollment increased from 1927-28 to 1932-33, during which time enrollment in city and village elementary schools declined to 97.44 per cent and that of rural elementary schools to 89.87 per cent of 1927-28. City and village elementary schools spent from 36.85 per cent of total school expenditures in 1928-29 to 39.32 per cent in 1927-28; high schools from 35.11 per cent in 1927-28 to 37.02 per cent in 1931-32 jand rural elementary schools from 25.61 per cent in 1931-32 lo 26.74 per cent in 1929-30. Larger high-school enrollment helped reduce </seg>
         <seg id="p082">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Research Bul. 105 expenditures per pupil for high schools. Decreased enrollment in the other types of schools tended partially to offset the effect of reductions in salaries of teachers upon costs per pupil. Highway expenditures by counties accounted for about 60 per cent of the total for the counties. Labor on highways required most of this 60 per cent. Salaries of elected county officials were responsible for a large part of the general county administration expenditures. Statutory pro - visions for the numbers of county officials and their salaries prevented substantial reductions in salary expenditures by very small counties. Variations in payments for office help and deputies were great, ranging from 0.81 per cent in Thomas county to 7.36 per cent in Lancaster county. Relief was not a major problem for the more rural counties, although it was important for those counties with larger urban population. Townships spent practically all of their funds upon the local highway system. From 48 to 69 per cent of the township funds were spent for labor on highways. Townships frequently contracted with the county for the construction of township roads when large machines were needed. County and township expenditures were combined for supervisor counties before expenditures for the two types of counties were compared. Per-capita costs of providing loca! highways were lower in the near-by commissioner counties than in the supervisor counties. Size of county and the number of people in the county were important in determining the county and township administration costs per acre and per capita. Administration expenditures were somewhat lower for commissioner counties than for supervisor counties. Tax delinquency.—Much real-estate tax delinquency indicates poor tim - ing o£ tax-delinquency dates with dates when farmers receive income, rather than actual distress. Repeated delinquency on the same real estate year after year probably indicates actual distress. Tax delinquency increased from 1928 to 1932 for the 91 Nebraska counties for which data were collected. Cumulated back-tax delinquencies are better indicators of distress than current delinquencies. Increases from $187,976 in 1928 to 52.019.482 in 1932 means much more distress in 1932. Slightly less distress was found in supervisor than in commissioner counties. This was indicated by the fewer delinquencies of three or more years out of the possible five years, the lower percentage of the acres of the county on which taxes were unpaid, and the smaller amount of cumulated unpaid back taxes. Three of the supervisor counties had failed to collect a smaller percentage of their tax money than their paired com - missioner counties. For the fourth pair no advantage was found for either type of county organization. </seg>
         <seg id="p083"/>
         <seg id="p084"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>