<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00024">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00024</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  COOPERATIVE VARIETY TESTS OF CORN IN 1902 AND 1903.</title>
               <date value="1904">1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">E3 U L 1^ KT I N or the AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XVI, Article IV. COOPERATIVE VARIETY TESTS OF CORN IN 1902 AND 1903. By T. L. Lyon. Distributed April 21. 1904. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (the mm or m mtMm) JOHN L. TEETERS, President, Lincoln EDSON P. RICH. Omaha ELISHA C. CALKINS, Kearney CARL J. ERNST, Omaha CHAS. S. ALLEN, Lincoln WM. G. WHITMORE, Valley THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director mid Animal Husbandman T. L. LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial ikcrttary WM. W. MARSHALL, Executin THE WORKING STAFF H. H. SMITH, B. Sc, Animal Husbandman A. T. Peters, D. V. If., Animal Pathologist Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist S. Avery, Ph. D., Cheviot A. L. Haecker, B. Dairy Husbandman Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomologist Erwin H. B arbour, Ph. D., Geologist R. A. Emerson, B. S ulturist O. V. P. STOUT, I igatuyii Engineer O. D. Swezey, M. A., Meteorologist J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Associate Animal Pathologist W. P. Snyder, M. S 5 lUendent Experimental Substation North Platte Perin, Farm Fortmtm </seg>
            <seg id="p003">1(V T. L. LYON Cooperative variety tests were undertaken because of a lack of definite knowledg iing the types of corn I to different sections or localities in i corn at the Experiment Station is of only limited valu&lt; sons wishing to know what type of corn t Erom the station. The more widely these tests a the more accurate is our knowledge concerning the value of the different varietii R'liially important to the grower of pun [ to the grower of corn for feeding or for ma: of corn best suited to his locality. DIVISION OF THE STATE INTO SECTIONS. The botanical survey of the State has shown that i collection of plants differing markedly from • in other regions, indicating a cliff* I the condi: wth in the the same plants are found in all a the pr&lt; greatly. I For these experiments the State has been divided int . the boundary lines of which correspond more or lesB sely with those marking changes in the natural vegetation. . vari. in any one section included the same i varieties in all were tested but the maximum number any one section was twelve. The larger varieties were used in sections and the late maturing varieties in the itheast, earlier maturing varieties were used in the north and st, and smaller eared varieties in the west. The following &gt;le gives the name of each variety, the locality in which the id was raised, and the section or sections in which testt BULL. 83, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBB. VOL. XVI, ABT. IV. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">I 'ariety Teats of Corn in 1902 and 1903. 4 Years of test, origin, and location of test of each variety. Section In which Years tested Name of variety Seed raised Boone County White Central Illinois Section I Reid's Yellow Dent Central Illinois Sections 1, i. Silver Mine Central Illinois Sections 1, S Riley's Favorite Central Indiana - rtions 1 Mammoth White Pearl Washington Co., Nebraska . . | Sections 1. 1 Mammoth Golden Yellow Washington Co.. Nebraska . . i Sections 1 Snowflake White Southwestern Iowa Sections 1, 1. S, 4 Early Yellow Rose Southwestern Iowa Sections 1 , S. S, 4 Nebraska White Prize Washington Co., Nebraska . . ! Sections i i ; olden Row Washington Co.. Nebraska . . j Sections 1, *, S 1908- 1908 Learning lHM-ian Hogue's Yellow Dent 19W-19O1 Pride of the North... (Vntral Illinois '.ions 1.2.3. Saline Co., Nebraska Sections 1, », S. 4, 5, 6 Pride of the North. . Minnesota Sections 4. S, 6. Calico . Washington Co.. Nebraska . . Sections Minnesota No. 13 Minnesota Sections 4.5. B. Karly Cattle King Washington Co., Nebraska. . . Sections 5, A. Golden Cap.. Legal Tender Dodge Co. Nebraska sections 1. 1, 3. Washington Co., Nebraska . . Sections I, 3. Washington Co.. Nebraska . . Sections !. 3. 4 lan-isn Iowa Gold Mine Each certain nties as foil comprises Section I. Richardson, Pawnee, Nemaha, Johnson, Otoe Section 2. Sarpy, Douglas, Washington, Dodge, Bart, ( ing, Thurston, Dakota. Eetion 3. Gage, Lancaster, Saunders, Jefferson, Sali Butler, Thayer, Fillmore, York, Polk, Nuckolls, Clay, Ham - , Merrick. Section 4. Colfax, Stanton, Wayne, Dixon, Cedar, Knox, PlaMe, Madison, Pierce, Antelope, Boone, Nance. Ketion 5. Webster, Adams, Hall, and all count i. pt Lincoln and Perkins. Section 6. Howard, Greeley, Wheeler, Holt, Boyd, and all counties west. fPhis can best be seen on the accompanying map of the State, which the section boundaries are marked with heavv Li </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 METHOD OF CONDUCTING THE TEST. t little more than half the varieties are raised within the e, and the remainder from States as far or farther north. ng, however, to the greater altitude of central and western i, a given variety does not ripen so quickly in that an as it does in Illinois or Indiana. Iorn grown at a great distance from the locality in which it is &gt;&lt;1 is always at a great disadvantage in a variety test. The cal change in climate and soil which is generally experi - d by seed carried a great distance is almost sure to cur - the yield the first year at least. It is hoped that seed of y of these varieties may soon be produced in Nebraska, as t of them are highly prized varieties of corn in other sec - 3 of the corn belt, and promise to be well adapted to raska when bred here for some time. tis planned to repeat the test of each variety for a series of i in the hands of the same experimenter. The number of rimenters will be increased as rapidly as means will per - but must, of course, be selected with reference to their </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 sary to do this, as the varieties being planted side by side mix and hence are valueless for seed. Inough seed is sent to plant at least a quarter acre of each ety. All varieties are planted in the same manner and on same day, the land prepared in the same way and the same ivation given throughout. Each variety is picked separately an accurate estimate of the yield of the corn on the srmined. The proportion of corn to cob on ten rej ears of each variety is also determined. CLIMATIC CONDITIONS IN 1902 AND 1903 I he season of 1902 was a very unusual one. In almost all ions of the State there was a larger rainfall than the normal, accompanying this was much cool weather throughout all corn growing months, followed by killing frost in the fall y three weeks earlier than usual. Except in the - -tern ion of the State, a large proportion of the ordinary field corn not fully mature at the time the killing frost occurred. It ither to be expected therefore that the late maturing vari tiese experiments should be at a disadvantage in the orded. The season of 1903 also was unusually cool and wet, but stern portion of the State a killing frost did not r so early. In spite of the delayed frost, corn did not mature so well as in 1902 owing to the great rainfall and attendant floods in the early part of the summer, which greatly del planting, and also to the cold, damp fall weather. GERMINATION TESTS OF SEED USED germination test was made of the seed of each variety before it was 6ent out to the experimenters. The sample for the was obtained by taking kernels from one hundred t are of each variety. The results were as folio </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Germination test of each variety. IPer cent of kernel Variety. germinating. 1902. Boone County White 8« Reid's Yellow Dent 80 sw Silver Mine If Riley 's Favorite M Mammoth White Pearl H -uaujujinu vv uivc i cai i .*•» ■« Mammoth Golden Yellow 99 W&lt; Snowflake White 100 Early Yellow Rose 98 M M m Nebraska White Prize 99 &lt;«* Golden Row H !«:t Learning I U Hogues^ Yellow Dent 95 99 Pride of the North «3 Calico 98 !*4 Minnesota No. 13 I M Early Cattle King I M H Golden Cap 98 W Kl Tender !*i Gold Mine 99 Iowa Gold Mine The yields reported by eacli experimenter are herewith g the tests being classified by sections, and stated for 1 ratel v Section 1 Te*U in 1902, Name cf experimenter. Post office. (1) William Ernst Graf. (t ) H. R. Coles Pawnee Yield in bushel* per acre. (») 2 Reid's Yellow Dent I 33 Learning oo Boone County White Silver Mine ... 21 Riley's Favorite 20 Mammoth Golden Yellow. . Nebraska White Prize I Mammoth White Pearl Golden Cap . . j :« Snowflake White Early Yellow Rose TO Hogue's Yellow Dent T2 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Section l. — TetU in 1903. Name of experimenter Post office illiam Ernst Graf. (f ) C. F. Chase Pawnee Section 2.— Tat* in 190S. Name of experimenter Post office (i) D. F. Stouffer Bellevue. (t) Joseph Hall Tekamah. (3) Lee Smith De Soto. nd Echtenkamp Arlington. (5) Charles Thompson West Point Yield in bushels per acre. (») 2 &lt;»&gt; Reid's Yellow Dent 23 64 M 42 25 Learning 17 67 44 48 64.5 Legal Tender 25 Silver Mine 21 25 72 58 28 Silver Mine 21 59 4!t 45 37 Iowa Gold Mine 23 66 47.5 Mammoth Golden Yell- 26 57 39 ■ix Nebraska White Prize. ... 20 63 M 32 Mammoth White Pearl ... 20 Golden Cap 24 :i* 4&lt;i fi7 77 60 it «4 47 Snowflake White 17 75 44 41 Early Yellow Rose 23 64 32 Hogue'g Yellow Dent I 21 71 43 40 ■'.• B. Liphardt B. Cleghorn. (5 ) Ben Maiben Graf. Manley. Palmyra. Yield in bushels per acre. |(f) 3 Yellow Dent 75 in* 70.3 e County White 66.5 • Mine 68 's Favorite 52 QOth Golden Yellow. 64.6 kska White Prize.... 76.5 noth White Pearl . . 62 m Cap 60 flake White 54 Yellow Rose 69.5 -How Dent 60 e Variety 2 72 4 48.7 33 3 53.6 58.2 48.3 59 62.1 43.7 66.7 53.7 65.9 68.2 3 54 51 2 51.2 46.6 59.6 58.6 50 57.8 61.7 51.2 61.7 (4) 45 35 40 38 35 35 38 38 38 40 3.5 &lt;40 45 T 29 35 32 29 33 33 25 34 30 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Iie's Yel. Dent en Row .White Prize, en Cap ling f Yellow Rose 1 Tender . Gold Mine . . rflake White . (f) 52.5 60 55 60 57.5 57 55 53 57.5 50 (*&gt; 61 76 55 70 61 70 70 61 70 58 (9) 58.4 52.1 48.9 49.9 49.8 49.8 50.1 508 "45 V &lt;*) 20 22 20 16 22 20 22 17 ltf 20 a 75.4 63.6 62.7 65.7 59.6 65.4 60 65 58.9 (•) 70 58 54 67.5 45 58 45 54 ! SECTION 2.— Tuts in 1903. Name of experimenter. Post office. ( i ) Fred Echtenkamp Arlington. ■ W. H. Hoegeme yer Hooper. C. Y. Thompson West Pc West Point. (l) Stouffer Bros. Bellevue. (5) Joseph Hall Tekamah. Yield In bushels per acre » 2 &lt;*) (4) (•) a s.. 5 2 M -o S 6 Reid's Yellow Dent 39 49 4 4* Learning 36 51.9 HO Legal Tender 44.4 45 Silver Mine ' 34 48 5 4* Iowa Gold Mine '&lt; 44.2 42 Kmoth Golden Yellow. 39 46.4 aska White Prize ... 36 47.1 83 51 Mammoth White Pearl . . .! 41 44 6 4.". GoldenCap j 33 55.4 HO Snowflake White ! 34 44.9 4* Early Yellow Rose 33 43.6 M Hogue's Yellow Dent '.'.'.'.'] 34 48^3 4:'. Native Variety I I 52 2 Section 3.— Tats in 190i. Name of experimenter. Post office. ■ D. E. Ritchey Rising City Anton Kuska Milligan. Milligan. (*j L. A. Love . . -Valparaiso U) C. G. Nootz Raymond. (5) Experiment Station Lincoln. (6) J. C. Doubt Bethany. (7) E. B. Stauber Stoddard. Yield in bushels per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Section 3.— Test* in 190S. Name of experimenter. Post office. S. R. Hall Havelock. Hogue Crete. laleigh Wilder Central i .xperiment Station Lincoln. A. Gait Edgar. S. L. Johnson Edholtn. Miner Friend. [8) John D. Hasik Abie. L. A. Love Valparaiso. IJ. H. Hu D. E. Hi J. If. Woods D. J. Wood Charles B. Camp Rising Ulysses. Fairbury. Chen Held In bushels per acre. Hones Yellow Dent Golden Bow Nebraska White Prize 56 53 OoMenCap 63 43 Learning Karly Yellow Rose S8 4t Calico LegBl Tender 56 » lows Gold Mine 58 30 Snowflake White . . . ■ 44 NatlTe Variety (») M&gt; W 69.1 » 59.9 35 68.7 33.5 61.0 25 «.l 30 59.8 B.5 08.1 10 61.1 S 70 " \ («) («) (7) (8) i » 6Z 57.3 42 0U 34 50 « 53 32 .... 36 :* -' M 50 :u i » 43 31.8|jW 30 4* 17 46 30 311 34 54 .... 38 19.7 40 34 5C 19 56 4 38 45 18 40 33.7 » 5c 33 .... IS 37 30.144 57 33 ! 30 163 * SO .... 59 .... 40 ...|fl» Section 4.— Tests in 1902. I! of experimenter. F. J. Houtz L. M. Heesacker D. M. Decamp Postoffle*. Albion. Lindsay. Clearwater. Yield In bushels per acre. Ie's Yellow Dent »n Row iska White Prize esota No. 13 Gold Mine of the North flake White ■ Yellow Rose Cattle King (f) 35 50 40 40 45 35 56 Not matured. 54 Not matured. Not matured. 33 20 49 Not matured. 37 20 54 Not matured. 44 Not matured. 44 Not matured. 34 Not matured. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Section o.— Test* in 190*. Name of experimenter. Post office. (i) I. D. Evans Kenesaw. (t) G. A. Prime Arapahoe. (3) A. C. Bischel U) W. H. Gasaway . Bertrand. (5) J. H. McLaughlin Doniphan. C. Bassett . Gibbon. (7) J. S. Cobeldick Alma. Yield in bushels per sere. (»&gt; (4&gt; (•&gt; (•&gt; I &lt;r&gt; ( f ) (*) (f) (*) Early Cattle Kin? .. Not matured 8 Early Cattle Kin* .. Not matured 8 Hogue's Yel. Dent. Not matured 18.5 Not matured 37 17.5 a 60 Not matured 37 17.5 31 «) Not matured 30 31 41 flu Hopes Yel. Dent. Not matured 18.5 Not matured 3D 31 41 M 43 33 18 31 30 Minnesota No. 13 ... Matured I Minnesota No. 13 ... Matured £5 33 18 31 50 Not matured 37 18 40 ■ Calico Not matured 14 Calico . Not matured 14 Not matured 37 18 40 Pride of the North .. Matured 7.5 Pride of the North .. j Matured 7.5 30 » 18 30 « Not matured 34 ».5 36 40 Not matured 38 X 30 flu Not matured 38 M 36 ! «u so ss 18 » aa Nebr. White Prize.. Not matured 7 Nebr. White Prize.. Not matured Not matured 34 » 5 38 40 Early Yellow Rose.. Not matured IS Not matured 36 X 30 «0 Early Yellow Rose.. Not matured 16 Golden Row \ Not matured I 17 Golden Row Not mature Not matured 38 M 30- Name of experimenter. Post office. (1 ) G. A. Prime Arapahoe. (i ) I. D. Evans Kenesaw. Yield In bushel* per men. (f) 2 Early Cattle King M) \ Hogue's Yellow Dent Calico :« 30 Pride of the North H 20 Nebraska White Prize 14.5 i &amp;&gt; Early Yellow Rose M Golden Row 34 Native variety Yield in bushels per acre. Early Cattle King Not matured 30 Not matured Not matured Minnesota No. 13 30 25 Not matured Not matured Calico Not matured 30 Not matured Not matured Pride of the North 35 SO Not matured Not matured Nebraska White Prize Not matured 40 Not matured Not matured Early Yellow Rose Not matured 10 ! Not matured Not matured Hogue's Yellow Dent Not matured ».=&gt; | Not matured Not matured Hopue's Yellow Dem All of the foregoing varieties were tested on the Experiment Station farm and gave the following yields: Sections.— Tests in 1903. (f) (*) (*) &lt;«&gt; Section 6.— Tests in l90i. Name of experimenter. Post office. (1) D. C. Konkel ...Weissert. (t) G. F. Smith. ... Ewing. (3) L. V. Humphrey Atkinson. U) T. W. DeLonp Ainsworth. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Variety tests on the Experiment Station farm. •The poor yield of this variety in 1903 was due to the failure of the seed to germinate Eie following is an explanation of the characteristics of each ty together with a brief history and statement of the source e seed used in these experiments: HOGUES YELLOW DENT. Standard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Improvers' Association. Shape of ear, slightly tapering; length of ear, 8 to 9 inches; circumference of ear, 7 to 8 inches; color of kernel, yel - low; shape of kernel, wedge; indentation of kernel, rough; num - ber of rows, 16 to 20; size of shank, medium; size of cob, med - ium; color of cob, red. Ised of this variety was obtained from Mr. R. Hogue of Crete, le county, Nebraska, who has grown it since 1885. The was obtained originally from Mr. Shrader, who lived in the bern part of Lancaster county, Nebraska, and from whom Hogue purchased it in the year named. The history of the previous to that time is not known. Mr. Hogue has care - r selected the seed each year, having particularly in view ining a deep kernel. The result is an ear with deep ker - , deeply indented and fairly late maturing. One character- Variety. Source of seed. Yield in bushels per acre. 1902. 1903. Av'r'ge. i Yellow Dent I's Yellow Dent al Tender den Row den Cap. wflake White ly Yellow Rose raska White Prize ming Mammoth Golden Yellow . Calico Early Cattle King Iowa Gold Mine Boone County White . ... Mammoth White Pearl . . . Silver Mine s Favorite Pride of the North Minnesota No. 13 Saline Co., Nebr »-4 75.1 75.2 Illinois 6* 70.5 Washington Co.. Nebr. 65.0 t 68.1 66.5 Washington Co., Nebr. 63.6 69.1 66.3 Dodge Co., Nebr 65.7 ; 66.7 66.2 Iowa 58.9 168.7 63.8 Iowa 65.4 (B.I 63.7 Washington Co., Nebr. 62.7 59.9 61.3 Illinois. ».6 61.6 60.6 Washington Co., Nebr. 54 3 86:1 60.0 Washington Co., Nebr. 60.0 59 8 59.9 Washington Co., Nebr. 56.8 i 62 5 59.6 Washington Co., Nebr. 57.9 ! 60.9 59.4 Illinois 5&gt; 59.0 Washington Co., Nebr. 54.3 61.8 58.0 Illinois 50.0 58.1 54.0 Indiana 53.2 51.0 52.1 Minnesota 52.5 31. 4« 41.9 Minnesota 43.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Kof the corn is a thick, medium tall stalk with long, broad is, giving a large amount of foliage. The variety has never i intentionally crossed since Mr. Hogue obtained it. It is a erately late maturing variety. REID'S YELLOW DENT. Standard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Improvers' Association. Shape of ear, slightly tapering; length of ear, 9 inches; circumference of ear, 7 inches; color of kernel, light yellow; shape of kernel, long wedge; indentation of kernel, medium smooth; number of rows, 16 to 18; size of shank, small; of cob, medium; color of cob, red. Seed of this variety was obtained from Mr. James L. Reid of East Lynn, Illinois, whose father, Robert Reid, originated the variety by selection from a cross of Gordon Hopkins' corn from Ohio and what was called "Little Yellow corn" that was raised in central Illinois. The corn has not been intentionally crossed by Mr. Reid since 1847, and has been improved by selection since that date. It is a moderately early maturing vari' LEGAL TENDER. mdard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Improvers' Association. Shape of ear, cylindrical; length of ear, 9 to 10 inches; circumference, 1\ to 8 inches; color of kernel, lemon yel - low; shape of kernel, long wedge; indentation of kernel, rough; number of rows, 18 to 20; size of shank, small; size of cob, small; color of cob, red. Seed of this variety was obtained from Mr. Fred Echtenkamp of Arlington, Washington county, Nebraska. It is moderately GOLDEN ROW. Standard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Impro 1 Association. Shape of ear, cylindrical; length of ear, 10 inches; circumference of ear, 7£ inches; color of kernel, deep yellow; shape of kernel, long wedge; indentation of kernel, rough; num - ber of rows, 20; size of shank, medium; size of cob, medium; Seed of this variety was obtained from M.JH. Smith A </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 De Soto, Washington county, Nebraska. It was brought from northeastern Indiana by Mr. M. H. Smith in 1879, and had been carefully selected for throe years previous to that time. Since 1876 it has not been intentionally crossed. The ear has increased in size illy in length, since coming to Nebraska. i moderately late maturing variety. GOLDEN CAP. mdard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Improvers' Association. Shape of ear, slightly tapering; length of ear, 9 inches; circumference of ear, 6 to 01 inches; color of kernel, deep yellow with light golden cap; shape of kernel, Ion. ; in - dentation of kernel, medium; number of rows, 14 to 16; size of shank, very small; size of cob, very small; color of c ■ red. I this variety was obtained from Mr. J. M. Usher of iont, Dodge county, Nebraska. He originated the variety in 1889 by g Mammoth II b with a corn from Hiving a long, slim ear. The kernels of the Mammoth -etooth corn were very deep but far apart, while the Kansas had short ken wiled i .ther. In selecting from this cross, ears showing as nearly as pi medium een the characteristics of the two variei d for seed. The result was a variety having kernel &gt;ther than the Mammoth Horsetooth corn and deeper than the Kansas variety. When Golden Cap was first established the kernel was light colored with a golden cap. In 1892 Mr. Maher made a cross of the corn above described with a red variety which has given the kernel a reddish yellow color underneath the golden colored cap of the kernel. Again in 1898 another cross was with a yellow variety of corn having a smooth, shallow kernel, the intention being to make the variety earlier. The process of crossing continued for two yean. The result is a fairly deep grained and moderately early maturing variety of corn. SNOWFLAKE WHITE. iiidard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Improvers' » • . e 1* lit! * ♦. " -1 rrfVi t ft tf\ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 K;hes; circumference of ear, - color of kernel, e; shape of kernel, medium I indentation of ium rough; number of rows, It of cob, medium; color of cob, whit. Seed of this variety was obtained from J. B. Armstrong &amp; Son, Shenandoah, Iowa. It is a late maturing variety. EARLY YELLOW ROSE. mdard for type adopted by the . Impro Association. -lightly tapering 9 inches; circumference of i I kernel, yellow; shape of kernel, medium wedge; indent I kernel, rough; number of rows, 1' uk, medium; of cob, medium; color of cob, red. tif this variety lined from J. B. Armstrong &amp; Shenandoah, Iowa. It is a late maturing corn. NEBRASKA WHITE PRIZE. mdard for t pted by the Nebraska Corn lmpro Association. of ear, cylindrical; length of ear, D in circumference ol r of kernel, white; sha] kernel, medium wedge; indentation of kernel, rough; numb rows, 10 to 18; size of shank, medium; si mm; color of cob, white. {eed of this varii obtained from M. II. Smith A Wash i i ith from' nort i Indiana in iown e by Mr. Smith since 1874. The ear has increased in ming to Nebraska. It is ring ietv. LEAMING. Standard for type adopted by the i lmpro Association is somewhat different from that adopted by the Illi - nois Association. As seed of this variety was obtained in Illi - nois the standard for that State is given. Shape of ear, taper - ing; length of ear, 10 inches; circumference of ear, 7 inches; color of kernel, deep yellow; indentation of kernel, rough; shape </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 of kernel, medium wedge; number of rows, 16 to _M shank, medium; size of oob, medium; color of cob, &lt;:&gt; f this variety was obtained from Mr. E. E. Ch&lt; -. who purchased the seed from Mr. Learning of Wilmington, Ohio, in 188.1 Mr. Learning origi - irietjr, it is said, in 182G. Be began select from the ordinary yellow coin grown on the Little ■r five years he constantly selected his corn to conform to a definite type, and his son lias been carry - ing on the selection of late years. The strain of thi - that ted in tl. i rougher ear than that ordi - narily raised in this State. It shows a tendency, hoi ■otli type. It is a moderately early maturing variety. MAMMOTH GOLDEN YELLOW mdard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn In, Association. of ear, cylindrical; length of ear, 10 to 11 inches; circumference of ear, 7 to 8 inches; color of kernel, yel - shape of kernel, medium wedge; indentation of kernel, n; number of r ze of shank, large; size of medium; color of cob, red. Seed of this variety was obtained from M. H. Smith &amp; Son. in a cross between li olden Row and Hogue's Yel - low Dent. The cross was made in 1889. It has never been tionally i since that time, but has been carefully ed for type. It is a late maturing variety. CALICO. mdard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Impro Association. Shape of ear, tapering; length of ear, 7 to 8 inches; circumference of ear, 6£ to 7£ inches; color of kernel, mixed; shape of kernel, medium wedge; indentation of kernel, slightly rough; number of rows, 16 to 20; size of shank, med - ium; size of cob, medium; color of cob, mixed. Eed of this variety was obtained from Mr. James Sully, oto, Washington county, Nebraska. It has been grown by since 1894, when he obtained the seed of John Martin of a, Iowa, as seed of Calico corn. He has grown it since that </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 time without intentionally crossing with any variety and has 1 the seed each year. It is an early maturing variety of corn. EARLY CATTLE KING. mdard for type adopted by the Nebraska ( ■iation. of ear, slightly tapering; length of ear 9 inches; circumference of ear, 7 inches; color of kernel, reddish yellow; shape of kernel, broad wedge; indent I kernel, slightly rough; number of rows, 14 to 1 &gt;f shank, 1. size of cob, small; color of cob, red. E?ed of this variety was obtained from M. II. Smith &amp; f obtained the seed from Illinois in 1000. The ear is small, with a fairly deep grain. It is a moderately early maturing etv. IOWA GOLD MINE. iiidard for type adopted by the Corn Impru iation. Shape of ear, slighty tapering; length of ear, 8 inches; circumference of ear, 6? to 7 inches; color of kernel, yel - shape of kernel, wedge; indentation of kernel, rough; num - ber of rows, 16 to 20; size of shank, medium; size of cob, medium; color of cob, n E}d of this variety was obtained from Mr. Fr 'likamp lington, Washington county, Nebraska. It is a well-known ty of corn. It is a moderately early maturing corn. BUONE COUNTY WHITE. iltandard for type accepted by Nebraska Corn Improvers' ociation. Shape of ear, cylindrical; length of ear, 10 inches; ■umference of ear, 7^ inches; color of kernel, pearl white; pe of kernel, medium wedge; indentation of kernel, rough; nber of rows, 16 to 22; size of shank, medium; size of cob, iium; color of cob, white. Seed of this variety was obtained from. Mr. A. P. Grout of Winchester, Illinois, who obtained the seed several years ago from the originator of the variety, Mr. James Riley of Thorntown, Indiana. Mr. Grout has been growing the corn for seed with - out any intentional crossing. Mr. Riley began selecting seed </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 I this variety in 1876, starting with a large variety with taper - ailed White Mastodon. He has not crossed it with any rn, but has brought about a radical improvement in the ) by careful ion of seed. It is a late maturing etv." MAMMOTH WHITE PEARL. iidard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Impro ■iation. Shape of ear, cylindrical; length of ear, 10 i ircuinferem &lt;v of kernel, whit. of kernel, medium wedge; indentation of kernel, h; number of r&lt; hank, 1, olor of cob, whit iiiety was obtained from M. 11. Smith t V Son. It Mated in a c i Nebraska White Prize and V White. The latter was a variety from Shawnet It had a medium short, thick ear, with m lined kernels and was very late maturing. 'I made in 1 3 which time it has fully for type, and no forth* intentionally le. It is a late maturing variety. SILVER MINE. tndard for type of thi- adopted by tl Association is not the same as that adopted by the Illinois Asso - ciation. As the seed was obtained in Illinois, the tat iven. i ear, cylindrical; I f ear, 9 in&lt; 7 inches; color of kernel, cream white; indenta - h; shape of kernel, broad wedge; lnim - if rows, 16 ze of shank, small; size of rob, small; . white. is obtained from Mr. Warner of Illinois, who obtained the seed from Mr. J. H. l'&gt; Illinois, who raised it from seed selected from a prize-winning exhibit of white corn at the Ford county (Illinois) Farmers' tute in 1890. Its history before this date is not known but it has not been intentionally crossed since that time. It is a moderately early maturing varic </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Cooperative Variety Tests of Corn in 1902 and 1903. 19 RILEY'S FAVORITE. Standard for type adopted by Nebraska Corn Improvers' Association. Shape of ear, slowly tapering; length of ear, 9 inches; circumference of ear, 7 inches; color of kernel, deep yel - low; indentation of kernel, rough; shape of kernel, medium wedge; number of rows, 16 to 20; size of shank, small; size of cob, small; color of cob, deep red. &gt;d of this variety was obtained from Mr. Marley Riley of T horntown, Indiana, whose father, James Riley, originated the variety in that locality in 1885. It is the result of a cross of a late corn (Golden Yellow) with a small early corn (Pride of the North). It is a fairly early maturing variety. PRIDE OF THE NORTH. liulard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Improvers' viation. Shape of ear, cylindrical; length of ear, 7 inches; circumference of ear, 6 inches; color of kernel, orange yellow; shape of kernel, broad wedge; indentation of kernel, slightly rough; number of rows, 16; size of shank, small; size of cob, small; color of cob, red. Reed of this variety was obtained from Northrup, King &amp; npany of Minneapolis, Minnesota. It is a small eared, early :uring variety, and is widely grown over the United States, characters differ greatly in different portions of the country. MINNESOTA NO. 13. tndard for type adopted by the Nebraska Corn Improvers' Association. Shape of ear, tapering; length of ear, 8 inches; circumference of ear, 7 inches; color of kernel, yellow; shape of kernel, oval cap with medium depth; indentation of kernel, smooth; number of rows, 14 to 18; size of shank, medium; size of cob, medium; color of cob, red. Seed of this variety was obtained from Northrup, King &amp; Company of Minneapolis, Minnesota. The variety was origi - nated by the Minnesota Experiment Station, and is a small eared, early maturing corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Cooperative Variety Tc*t» of Omm in 1902 nn&lt;l 1903. 20 SUMMARY. t»rn brought from outside of the State did not yield so well as from seed raised within the State. A notable exception to is Reid's Yellow Dent. tirly maturing varieties did not yield so well as later matur - ones. Kellow varieties gave, on the whole, better yields than white The proportion of corn to cob did not bear any relation b I of corn per acre, neither did the size of the ear. ne of the varieties of corn brought from othei ugh not yielding remarkably well in these trials, give evi - dence of becoming vary valuable varieties after they have raised in this region for a sufficient number of well adapted to the climate. Of these Reid's Yellow Dent, iv White, 1 /earning, and Silver M irtic- </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>