<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0082.0023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Study of Farm Families and Their Standars of Living in Selected Districts of Nebraska 1931-1933</title>
               <date value="1935-07">1935-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 78 ! A Study of Farm Families and Their Standards of Living in Selected Districts of Nebraska 1931-1933 MARGARET FEDDE AND RUTH LINDQUIST Depart meni nf Home Economics LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JULY, 1935 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Pace Summary 3 Introduction 5 The Cooperating Families and Their I- omes 7 Extent of farm ownership 7 Composition of families 7 Composition of households '. g Age of operators and homemakcrs -....■ 8 Birthplace of family members jj Educational background ... 8 Reading interests 9 Distance from community services. . 10 Telephones and radios 10 Family membership m organization:; 10 Housing 10 Economic status of families 14 Economic services of farm women . 16 The Money Value of Family Living an I Its Distribution 1G Average yearly money value and its distribution 17 Relation of value of living supplied by farm to living purchased 17 Average value of living for owners, part-owners, and tenants 18 Comparison of levels of living jy Average value of living for families of different size 21 Value of living and age of homemaker 22 Comparison of present study with o:hcr Nebraska studies 24 Comparison of present study with selected studies of farm families 27 Changes m the Distribution of the Valte of Living during 1931, 19.52, and 1933. 28 Findings for the entire Igroup 28 Findings for twenty-five families who kept records for three years. . : 32 Other effects of lean years upon families 3(5 Recent studies of the depression anil farmers' standards of living 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY The findings in this study arc based upon the home accounts kept by 100 farm families in three counties of Nebraska during at least one of the years 1931, 1932, and 1933. Approximately half of the group lived on farms which they owned. The size of the family was 4.2 members. The size of the household was 4.4. The aver - age annual value of living was $1,071.32. Of the total, -41.6 per cent was provided by the farm. To Nebraska farmers these years brought low prices for grain and livestock and the farm was often operated at a loss. Obligations assumed in better years became in - creasingly difficult to meet. The annual value of living for the group of tenants was approximately two-thirds that of the owner class, and part-owners had a higher value than cither. Families in which the operator and homemaker were between 40 and 45 years of age had an average value of living that was approximately three-fourths that of the group 45 years and over. Size of family appeared to affect total value of living less than other factors related to the age of the homemaker. A comparison of the average value of living by year showed §1,226.36 for 58 families in 1931, $1,008.58 for 69 families in 1932, and $988.06 for 56 families in 1933. The average cash expenditure in 1932 and 1933 decreased more than §150, partly because of a change in prices but also because of restricted purchasing. Housing showed a slight increase in value from 1931 to 1932, for the annual cost of housing cannot readily be altered when it is so directly associated with the farm business, even though the pressure on the cash income is increased. The value of food dropped more than one-fourth of the 1931 value. In 1933 the value of clothing, operating, and development increased slightly over the value in 1932. Savings, hous - ing, and health had a lower value in ]')ii than in 1°32, while food showed no appreci - able change. Accounts kept by 25 families throughout the three-year period showed a 21 per cent decrease in the average value of living in 1932, when compared with the 1931 average, and a further decrease of one per cent in 1933. The decrease in cash ex - penditures was twice as large as the decrease in value of the living provided by the farm. In order of size of percentage decrease in 1932, church and charity ranked first: and gifts to persons outside the family, supplies and equipment, clothing, and purchased food followed in the order listed. The largest decrease in value of a single item was in food. In 1933 there was a further percentage decrease in church and charity, supplies and equipment, and water and telephone. The expenditure for health was greater in 1932 and less in 1933 than in 1931. The decrease in the net cash income lowered the amount for savings in 1932 and a further decrease occurred in 1933 which, translated into family practice, meant allowing insurance policies to lapse. Other effects of the depression upon these families do not lend themselves to exact measurement. Alternating periods of depression and prosperity had occasioned adjust - ments of different types in many of the families. Attitudes changed during the length - ening depression and an increasing uncertainty of the future for agriculture also had its effects. Additional facts regarding the 100 families and their homes help to describe the standard of living and the backgrounds of the group. A majority of the farm operators and homemakers were born in Nebraska and slightly less than half were born in the county in which they lived at the time of the study. More than two-thirds of the operators and three-fourths of the homemakers were under 45 years of age. Thirty of the mothers and fifteen of the fathers had had one or more years be - yond high school. For all of the families in which there were children who had reached the adolescent years', high-school graduation appeared to be an accepted goal and many were making college attendance possible. Reading matter in the home, as shown by subscriptions to papers and magazines, consisted largely of a daily paper, one or more farm journals, and a woman's magazine. Community libraries provided many families with books. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">The case with which business and social contacts can be maintained is indicated m part by thc distance trom communi y services. Two-thirds of thc families were less than five miles from a center. There was a tendency m many families to go to urban centers to supply a part of thc needs. Telephones and radios were found m three - fourths of thc homes. More homemakers than farm operators belonged to organiza - tions m thc community and thc average number to which they belonged was larger For sons and daughters thc 4-H Club was thc one m which membership was most frequent. The majority of farm dwellings were valued at less than $3,000. They averaged 6.3 rooms and 3.6 bedrooms. Fifteen per cent were completely modern and fifty-eight per cent had no modern improvements One-fourth were more than fifty years old. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">A Study of Farm Families and Their Standards of Living in Selected Districts of Nebraska, 1931-1933 MARGARET FEDDE AND RUTH LINDQUIST ' This study of farm families in selected districts of Nebraska was under - taken in order to obtain information regarding the total money value of family living and the proportion of the total used for each of the principal groups of goods. A further purpose was to measure the adequacy of the living provided. The study was begun in January, 1931, and continued through the year 1933. The districts selected included Cass and Fillmore counties through - out the three-year period, and to these Buffalo county was added at the beginning of 1932. There were two reasons for the selection of these areas. The first was the advantage to be gained from the farm account project, which had already been begun in these counties, and through it both infor - mation and interest could be more readily secured. A second reason for the choice was the type of farming area which each lepresented. Cass county, on the eastern border of the state, ranks among the more prosperous counties of the state. In 1925 slightly more than half of the farms were owned by the operators and the average acreage per farm was 167.2. a Sources of farm income are principally corn, winter wheat, other small grains, hogs, beef cattle, and dairy and poultry prod - ucts/' Fruits and vegetables are grown in greater quantity than in either of the other counties. Farms in Fillmore county averaged 181.1 acres in 1925 and at that time less than half of the operators were owners. 4 It is a part of the southern cash grain and livestock area of the state, in which families look principally to corn, wheat, hogs, and dairy and poultry prod - ucts for their cash income. Buffalo county, in the south-central section, had an average acreage per farm of 228.3 in 1925 and a percentage of ownership practically the same as that of Cass county."' In Buffalo county corn is the most important crop, but a large percentage of land is used for pasture, and beef cattle are of major importance as a source of income. High yields of alfalfa, in addition to the corn crop, encourage the produc - tion of beef cattle. Dairying and hog production are also important. Added advantages which these three counties had were the ease with which they could be reached from Lincoln and the interest of the extension workers located in the counties. 1 Thii study mi hcrfun under the direction nf M. Ruth Clark, formerly Associate Professor of Research in Home Economics, and Ihc field work was done by Lucy S. Hoff. Ruth Limlquist m\ employed during the early part of the year 19.15 to complete the study. Margaret Fcddc is Chairman of Ihc Department of Home Economics and has given the study general supervision since it was begun. Credit is due to Muriel Smith, of the Extension Service, and to members of the Departmen - of Rural Economic! for aid Ritejl. a L". S. Census of Agriculture: 1925, Nebraska. Statistics by Counties. 1926, p. 9. 3 The comparison of counties with respect to sources of income is based upnn the areas described in Types of Farming in Nebraska, Nel.r. Art. I'-*P. Sia. Bui. 2+t. by Harold Hedna ami F F Elliott, May. 1930. *V. S. Census of Agriculture: 1925. Nebraska, Statistics by Counties, 192(5. p. 11 '- 1H.1., p. 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agr. Exp. St\. Research Bulletin 78 The method used was the analysis o£ home accounts. Forms for record - ing items of family living were fu nished to homemakers who expressed a willingness to cooperate in the ;tudy. c In most of the families farm accounts were already being kept. Additional information regarding each family was secured through the use of a family history schedule. The initial contacts with the families were made through the county extension agents. These were followed by visits to the homes for the purpose of explaining the study and the help needed from families. Later visits were made at intervals of three or four nonths to give assistance and to sustain the interest of the cooperators. Another help in sustaining interest was the promise of an annual summary for :he individual family and a comparison with other families. These summa ies were prepared and returned at the beginning of the new year. A total of 183 annual records, returned by 100 different families, were completed satisfactorily for analysi: . This total consisted of 58 records in 1931, 69 records in 1932, and 56 Records in 1933. Forty-eight of the 100 families kept records for 1932 and 1933 and 25 families completed accounts for the three-year period. An attempt to analyze and intc rpret the value of family living during 1931, 1932, and 1933 without a consideration of the effects of deflation upon Nebraska agriculture would give at best an inadequate description of the situation. The value of faUi property in the state fell from an average of $33,771 per farm in 1920 to $22,672 in 1930, or a decrease of Table 1. - Comparison of farr,, L° the paces and purchasing power % f tTom i m ,° to 19 « * further farm products 1929-33 x decrease in land values approached ' 40 per cent. s It was not the fall in v« %£££• SSCSS 1 ' the value oi fa ™ Property alone: farm prices by farmers for that constituted the economic Droh - . . commodities t r i r ~ , 929 ~ — 'em of the farmer. A fall in the 1930... .;;:.;; m h 4 selling prices of farm products was 1932:::::::;::; » \lj intensified by a less rapid decline in mi &lt;*&gt; 1Q9 the prices of purchased goods and 1 h. ciyiic Filiey, Effect of inflation ami i&gt; '- services regarded as essential for the farm f ami!y. The comparison of S-tfdKSs «f 52r£j£yfcirii index numbers shown in Table l is five-year base: i9io to i9H=ioo. in.iei nun-.h.- s pertinent in this connection. ot pr:'cs paid by farmers for commodities. pr&lt; . T »U J L • i • t pared by O. S. Dept. of A B riculture. arc on i ln ot nCT Words, the prices which five-year ba,e ; A US ust. I9 09. to JuI ,. m4=m Nebraska farm products brought ;„ 1929 were 46 per cent higher than the average for the basic years 1910-14. In the same year the prices paid or purchased commodities by farmers, nHdi^ilS'Sf K "~ prc ™ rc:l in cooperation »■ ih ibe Extension Service for use both in this project .ind_ in the Extension nroiecl in home accounu A^rt' CI&gt; c C F L" Cy " n E ? CCIS "' Infl -" inn an&lt;l Delation upon Nebraska Agriculture. 19H to 1932, Ncbr • KB f i. V?" " ' Unc&gt; 1934&gt; p - 5 - Dat:l usei1 wcrc akcn from lhc Hftecnth Census. n. K. Mauber, The Farm Real Estate Situati &gt;n. 1932-33. L". S. Dcpt. of Agr. Cir. 209. 1934. p. 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living according to index figures of the U. S. Dept. of Agriculture, were 52 per cent more than those of the basic period. By 1931 the prices of farm prod - ucts had fallen 66 points as contrasted with a fall of 28 points in goods purchased with the farm income. For 1933 the situation was but little uitterent from the preceding years. In relative terms, a dollar's worth of tarm products bought 96 cents' worth of purchased goods in 19"&gt;9- in 1931 it bought 63 cents' worth; and in 1932, 54 cents' worth. Changes'in prices of specific products show the effect upon the farm family's purchasing power. From $1.19 per bushel for potatoes in 1930 the price had fallen in 1932 to 46 cents per bushel. In 1929 eggs sold for 27 cents; in 1932 thev brought 13 cents to the producer." Another measure of the rapidly changing economic condition of Table 2. — Comparison of average Nebraska farmers in the 1929-32 annual labor income per farm, period is the annual labor income of 1929-32. 1 the farm. Some of the results of a j NoTol j Averse — study of farm records kept by farm rc '"' r ' s ' ' Jb " r inc "™ owners are shown in Table 2. The \™ \% ."'US capital value of the farms ranged [^'^.'."'.'.'.'."'.'.'.1, 225 -2.084 from $25,000 to $34,000, and a 5 " 2 - 1 -"' per cent interest charge on the in- ' H - cl &gt;' llc Fillc &gt;- Effects of inflation and i&gt; c vestment has been deducted. SuT -R '"»?*' Asricu " urc&gt; 19U to I932 ' THE COOPERATING FAMILIES AND THEIR HOMES Of the 100 families who cooperated in this study 46 lived in Cass county, 32 in Buffalo county, and 22 in Fillmore. Had the number from each county been larger, the findings for each county might have shown interesting and significant comparisons. No attempt has been made to present the facts regarding each county separately. Extent of farm ownership.— The cooperating families consisted of 54 farm owners and 46 tenants. Eighteen of the owners used additional land which they rented. In 14 of these 18 cases, the landlord was a relative. Twenty-six of the 46 renters lived on farms owned by a relative. The average acreage for the owners was 230 and for part-owners 278. Rented farms averaged 216 acres. Composition of families.— In all but three of the families both husbands and wives were living at home. In these three, the wives were widows. The number of members in the families varied from 2 to 10 with an average of 4.2 when only the dependent children were considered. The total number of children in each family was 2.5, which includes those who had died and those who no longer lived at home. Table 3 classifies the number of families by the number of children. The ages of the children ranged from less than a year to more than 30 years. One-fourth of the entire number were under 5 and another 15,*p H '35.' Vde F '" C&gt;1 EffeC ' 5 ° f Inflalion aml D &lt;*»'™ "P"n Nebraska Apiculture, 1914 .o 19*2. Tahfc </seg>
            <seg id="p008">• Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 fourth were between 13 and 18 Jears. Sixteen per cent were over 18, and fnd^i?;^ r ,t lwecn 5 an r ycars - Hal£ of thc number ™ **• uJS 0 ?* 0^** 0 * h ° USeholds — f he average size of the household, a term used to .nclude guests, employees, and boarders, was only slightl" Table 3.— Classification of 100 \o- l arger th . a P that of the family. 0 But operating families by number of ■ families had additional persons children at opening of the study '" homes throughout the year. Families- Families ir u n ° "^ '^ m ° re than One No. of children Mc h !£«" "ch class throughout the year and in 81 (3 " chilllrcn)1^ggg!, homes was no additional •v«,,,^ ~^ r ~ member at any time. A hired man *° nc 9 ii wa s present for a part of the vear in ?wo ::::::::::::: \l f 9 27 of the homes. fo™ .::::::: 10 2 i A S C oi operators and home- Fi Tou°, r n o m r m ifi;; ,iS l I0 g two-thirds av. no. children luo °' the men and three-fourths of the per fani | y .... 23 women were between 25 and 4 _ ■Lf, , ge J Very nolrl » °™-lhird wtre over 25 but undn 30 ilirtitpi 73 l o . r native JNeUraskans. Four were fore gn -born 10 irwl Fo . • 7° rted °" e ° r m ° re Children »»™ in a "°ther state Formal education of operators, -The amount of formal education of 10 Denmark, Germany, m Sweden. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living college. Only one was a college graduate, but 14 had had one or more years in college. Formal education of homemakers.— In comparison with their husbands, the wives had had more formal education. Only one of the women in the group had stopped school before completing the sixth grade and five others had left before reaching the eighth grade. Only six operators and home - makers had dropped out of school in the grades. Thirteen women were graduates of the e.ghth grade only, as compared with more than twice that number of men for whom schooling had ceased with the completion of the eighth grade. Very nearly half of the homemakers had had one or more years in high school and one-fourth had graduated. Four had re - ceived training in a business college. Twice as many women as men had attended college and six of the women were college graduates. Formal education of children.— The importance attached to education by a family is reflected in the educational status of their grown children Compulsory school laws, however, tend today to raise the number of years spent in school attendance and may account for the difference in' the amount of education received by parents and children. Since more than 1&lt;U per cent of the children in these families were under 13 years of age at the beginning or the study, it is the comparison of only the older children that is of .merest in th.s connection. Ten out of 97 had left school without completing high school and two of these had not gone beyond 'the eighth grade. Of the 41 who had completed high school, nine were attending C C nd e d e tn n 3 an , J f 2 ' and 32 WCrC n ° '° ngCr in Scho ° L Seventeen had ended their formal education with graduation from high school. Two had had a business course and 13 had attended college. Six of the 13 had con - tinued in college until graduation. Reading , interests.-The interest of families in reading is indicated by he ownership of books, the use of school and community libraries, and the borrowing ot books trom friends and neighbors. In these 100 families only one ment.oned the use of "a good family library". Very nearly half of the group used a community library with more or less regularity Books were borrowed more often by the children than by the parents. Sixteen iamihes read books belonging to neighbors and , relatives Subscriptions to papers and magazines provide an index to the type Tn.CTTu ( I" 8 L ma , ttCr that is avaiIable in the home - More than one-half of the families had one daily paper and ten had more than one A state newspaper surpassed all others in popularity and a daily stock Zror S o eqUemly f ° Und i , T ' le aVeragC " fam ' lies was sHghtlv S mn, £ ° r m ° re WCekly ne ™P a P e 's, which were more often county papers than any other type, were subscribed for by half of the families Magazines averaged slightly less than five per family. Of these period - icals two were farm journals, 1.8 were women's magazines, and 0.85 fell into the class of all other types which included religious, boys', nature, and general. The range in number was from none to fourteen. Some had </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 access to magazines of friends and relatives, and these were not included. Apparently the price of a magazine and the length of the subscription period affected the regularity from year to year. Information available regarding the changes in the thr;e-year period showed that general maga - zines in the $3.00-per-year class tvere less likely to come into the home a second year than were the less ex sensive ones and those for which the term of subscription was more often several years than one. Distance from community services. — Nearly two-thirds of the families lived five miles or less from the renter which they regarded as their home town. Only five were 16 to 20 miles away. These towns provided the high schools, churches, banking services, and grocery stores which were used. For medical service a majority of the families depended upon physicians at a distance not greater than 11 miles. Furniture and clothing were pur - chased in larger and more distant centers by half of the group, while 10 to 15 per cent used mail-order houses for a part or all of these purchases. Telephones and radios. — In tne past a telephone has been regarded as of considerable importance, and often indispensable, by many farm families. Of the 100 families, 79 had this service. A few had had their telephones taken out or their service discontinued as one means of lowering expendi - tures. No information concerning the number of families who had had a telephone earlier was available. To present-day farmers the radio has both a business and a recreational service to offer. The importance attached to it in this group is shown by the fact that very nearly every family who had a telephone also had a radio. The total was 74 telephones as rompared with 79 radios. , Family membership in organizations. — If organizations to which mem - bers of the family belong can be used as an index of activity in the com - munity, then the women were the most active. The average number of clubs per woman was two, while the number for the men averaged one. Thirty-nine men and sixteen worien belonged to no organization. Thirty - one women and sixteen men belonged to two. Six women listed five. Among the men, the type most frequently mentioned was an association of farm operators interested in one or several phases of the farm business. The Farm Bureau was listed frequently. Church auxiliaries, community clubs, and extension classes were most frequent among the women. Lodges were listed but rarely by either. The extent of church membership was not learned, but religious affiliations were recorded by each family. Ninety-five were Protestant and four were Catholic. Only one family of the entire group had no affiliation. Information regarding the exient of membership in clubs by the chil - dren was confined largely to the group of adolescent age. The type re - ported most frequently was the 4-H Club, though others were mentioned occasionally. The average number per child above the age of 12 was 1.2. Type of housing. — A frame dwelling varying in size from three rooms to fourteen, in value from $200 to $18,000, and in age from two to sixty- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living five years suggests the range in type of housing. All but two dwellings were fully screened and all but nine had been painted, though many were in need of new paint. More than half had been remodeled at least once. Trees were recorded by 95 of the families, lawns by 84, and yards fenced from the stock and poultry by 74. Valuation of dwellings.— The wide range noted above in valuation of the farm house presents the extremes. Table 4 shows that more than 80 per cent of all the homes were in the lower brackets. Approximately one- Table 4. — Range in value of housing. Value of dwelling | *£.£ Value of dwelling " I *°:.£ £ n ™&lt;;VoT 5 frt.0O0.5-t.W9 ' •iSSftw 3 2 t «»r-'t^ :::::::: &gt; 3.0Q0-3.999 ..:::::::::::::::;:::: , Tola , — fourth were valued at less than $1,000; one-third were in the $1 000-$l 990 class; and one-fourth in the $2,000-52,999 class. A total of nine were valued at $5,000 or above. In comparison with the findings of the Nebraska farm home survey of nine counties " made in 1934, these figures are of interest. They show that the average amount of $2,000 which 447 families, who were contemplating building in 1934, planned to use, is not different in terms of dollars from the present value of dwellings. Table_5. — Age of farm dwellings. [ Nyj^Jg. A -,, fdwcl , in(; | 20-29 years 24 ■ 8^" 7 30-39 years 7 «"»i«" ::::::::: m T .,ui ~^&gt; Age of dwellings.— One-fourth of the farm dwellings had been built more than fifty years ago and very nearly as many from 20 to 30 years ago. Only 8 per cent were less than 10 years old. Table 5 gives additional information dn this point. Table 6.— Size of farm dwellings— total number of rooms and number ____^ ofbedroo ms. No. of ream. I • Vu '" hCT »"».!S»iS_ ,. . Numbe. ,,f familieT^ , I*""-™ I ""'room, j * &gt; -° {r *"- AH room, j Bedroom, I.EEEE ' is HE=E: ~H ~~ 4 :::::::::::::::::: « 3 2 \ ln rir m&gt;rc 5 5 20 17 7 " V" i? I Total families... 100 100 ■ \- H &lt; ' Av. tin, per family 6.3 36 Size of dwellings.-In Table 6 the variation in size of dwellings is shown. Halt of the homes had seven or more rooms. The average for all was 6.3 rooms per family and 1.5 rooms per person. The number of bed - "Luella Selover, A Summary of ,|,e Federal Farm.Hou.ing Survey in Nebraska. 1934 (unpublished). </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 rooms varied from one to seven with very nearly half of tjfe families having four or more rooms for sleeping, tor an average of 0.8 bedroom per person. If the standard for health and decency, established by the U. S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1 - of one room per person, exclusive of bath, is used as the measure for adequacy of space, then overcrowding did not exist among these families. The amount of space available for sleeping was also high. An allowance of at least one room for the parents and one for the children of each sex is a standard freque tly quoted for sleeping space. A com - parison of the dwellings with thos: in other rural studies is made in Table 7 and shows that the amount of ;pace was similar to that found in more extensive surveys in Nebraska. Orily the study of Vermont owner families shows a greater average in numbtr of rooms per person. Table 7. — Comparison of average size of farm dwellings of 100 Nebraska families with average size in other rural studies. Stare tir section I Years I Families I Size of I Ronmc I,™.-!,,.! i I ~~ J I reporting | household | m pcr """"""M | Rooms per person No - 'Vo. Total Bedrooms Total Bedrooms Nebraska 1931-1934 100 4.2 6 3 3 6 M ni Nebraska' 193-1 14,916 4 4 6 1 4 Nebraska' 1923-192-1 342 4 4 65 30 15 07 North-Central States * 1923-1924 1,439 4 6 69 ') \l Iowa 4 1926-1929 • 147 4.8 74 5 Y" mont * 1927-1930 74 4.9 10.0 4.6 2!o 09 Arkansas • 1933-1934 6.613 : 4.4 4 6 1 05 6.940" 4.8 3.9 ['. 0.81 \ I' Ue JL b f do , VCr- -\ Summar &gt; "f &lt;he Federal Farm Housin K Survey in Nebraska (unpublished), 19M Bui 264 Nx,v" 1931 ' an '' HOUSC Opcr; " i " n Costs on N&lt;*n»ka Farms. Nebr. Agr, Exp. Sta! ! I' i" K' rk P atr 'f k - The Farmer's Standard of Living, The Century Co.. New York, 1929 • m "r, Ho &gt;'- J aluc of Family Living on Io va Farms. Iowa A K r. Exp. Sta. Bui. 281, lunc, 1931 Su Bui 34o' Uine S 193' '' L "''"'' "" St C&lt; - ific Owner-Operated Vermont Farms, Vt. A B r. Exp. June D T934 °" Ca " Cr " Arkan "» Farm Hou.in^ O.n.lilion. and Needs. Ark. Art. Exp. Sta. Bui. 305, ' White owner families. - 9 White non-owner families. The amount of privacy possible for the child or adult in the 100 homes included in the present study was actually less than the number of rooms would indicate. In the winter months, the difficulty of heating all of the house, or the cost of heating it, resulted in the use of only a part. In many families not all of the bedrooms w( re used during any part of the year and, fewer were used during the winter. Frequently the living room or dining! room, or both rooms, were not used until summer temperatures again made them more comfortable. Particula ly in families with adolescent children, the lack of an attractive and warn living area often becomes a handicap in entertaining friends and may d scourage recreation at home. In twelve of the homes the kitchen was. use J for the living room a part or all of the year. In more than half of the entire number, the dining room served this purpose through the winter, if not throughout the entire year, and for very DccencfMomh.? TSSS ££?. Ma™0."' * ""*"'* ° C "" '" H "" h and </seg>
            <seg id="p013">7:175.7„!" i ' 1932.' S C " nfcrcnCC on H " mc Buil&lt;li "« »»'' Home Ownership, Farm and Village Housing. Farm Families and Their Standards oh Living nearly three-fourths of the group the kitchen was used for eating at least a part of the time. One-half of the families used their dining rooms for eating all or a part of the time. Extent of home improvement.— These Nebraska families were more ortunate than many other rural families in the matter of home improve - ments. Table 8 shows that fifteen had completely modern homes For them, central heat, electricity, and a r „ _ water system, which included both S.—txtent of home improve - hot and cold running water in tnent. kitchen and bath, were a part of the Nature ,,f improvement | Kumbcr of lilies comforts of life. Twenty-seven had &gt;&gt;mpi«ciy modem is one or more of these improvements,' 'S£iT£ S^EKS .. * and the remainder, 58, were with- ' out any of them. A total of one- wa( " »y««n 4 -.L- i I , , , . , Central heat only 4 third had a bathroom, although Klcctricity and water .system 1 some were without a part or all of N " ' n&lt;Klcrn imi&gt;rmcmcn 58 the plumbing fixtures that make a T "' al jo? bathroom modern. Two families had a second bathroom. Showers were reported by only two. More than three-fourths had an outdoor toilet. Frequently both indoor and outdoor toilets were found for the same home. The explanation was that of expense. Often the cost of maintaining the needed pressure for flushing the toilet seemed excessive. Recommendations of the President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership include those dealing with the health of rural families: "Provision should be made for the comfort and privacy of the occupants, protection against extremes of temperature, protection against rodents and insects, and for the installation of equipment in or about the premises which will provide a safe water supply and a sanitary method of disposal of human excreta and other wastes." l:l The degree to which the dwellings in this study measure up to these recommendations is seen in part by the data presented. In the use of the available improvements is seen one of the effects of the depression upon this group of families. The cost of heating the house with the furnace seemed excessive in several cases and the practice of heat ing only a few rooms was common. In one home the use of the furnace had been discontinued. Because the cost of electric current seemed pro - hibitive in some instances, the family had returned to another method of lighting and appliances were no longer used. The electrical labor-saving devices owned most frequently were those that make laundering less irksome. Six homes with electricity were with - out an iron and nine were without a washer. Eighteen had an electric vacuum cleaner. Additional pieces of small equipment, such as a perco - lator, grille, or popper, were owned by 20 families. There were three </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 mechanical refrigerators. Some pwer equipment, most often a washing machine, was found in one-half of the homes. In a recent study of the use of electricity on 780 Nebraska farms, it was found that a larger number of irons and washing machines w;re being used than of other appliances. Eighty-five per cent of the families had electric irons and 81.8 per cent had washing machines as compared With 29.7 that had toasters and 27.3 that had vacuum cleaners. 14 Two-thirds of the houses had kitchen sinks, although only one-fifth were equipped with running water. In urban homes this piece of equip - ment serves primarily as a place fir the preparation of vegetables and for dishwashing. In rural homes thatj are without running water its purpose is often that of a lavatory for the family and farm workers and it is little used in other ways. Particularly i¥ the house is one in which there is no hot water piped to the sink, the homemaker may still find it more con - venient to wash dishes on the coakstove where the contents of teakettle and reservoir can be used as needed. If there is no kitchen pump, a pail of water and dipper at one side of t e sink, with mirror above, make wash - ing in the kitchen before meals a convenience, and a pail either at one side or beneath the sink to hold waste water is used if there is no drain. The methods of sewage disposal showed considerable variation. Over half of the entire number used eilher a surface drain or carried all water out in a pail. Twenty-two had a cesspool and the remainder were divided equally between the use of a septit tank and a deep tile drain. Uses of the farm dwelling.— OJ ten the farm dwelling is used for activ - ities not found in the daily routire of the urban family. In 86 of the homes in this study all dairy utejisils were washed in the kitchen Ten used a washroom or milk house for this purpose. In 25 of the homes the separator was used in the kitchen In half, the separator was kept in the basement or in a room used for t at purpose. In 26 homes there was an incubator in the house; in 11 of ihese homes the incubator was kept in the basement. No information wks obtained regarding the place where laundering was done. Economic status of families.— In the introductory section of the bulletin loai^oT 10 Pl ' ght ' n Which Netraska farmers found themselves during jyil, 1932, and 1933 is discussed briefly. The situation which existed in Cass, tillmore, and Buffalo counties during this period may be seen in part in Table 9. This comparison of the farm business in the three years is based upon a summary of all th farm accounts which were kept in the counties and is not limited to the keeping home accounts. It shows a net return to the operator afteS inventory changes in equipment and stock were made that reached a high point of $2,172 in Cass county for iinT l a P 01 " 1 in FilImor e and Thayer counties of —$356 in 1932 When the earning of the operator was determined for the three years, after Exp"!u E B U B l"289. t p a . nd 44. E Jun- e . I^34: "" ° f ] Elc """T « Nebraska ?»»•. 1920-1934. Nebr. Agr. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living first deducting wages for all unpaid labor other than his own and allowing 5 per cent on the investment, only Cass and Buffalo counties in 1933 showed a margin available. In neither case did the labor and management wage reach $600. One index to the economic status of families of farm owners is the net worth of their farms. For 93 of the 100 families information was available Table 9. — Condition of the farm business in Cass, Fillmore, and Buffalo counties, 1931-33} llem Cass | Pillmore 2 Buffalo 3 1931 AVERAGES Number of farms avcragCf*. 6° 25 48 Cash income 53.007 53,377 52,574 Cash expenditure 1.566 1,805 1,423 Net cash gain 1,441 1.572 . 1,151 Inventory gain or loss —1.55? — I.38K —1,077 Net return — 112 184 74 Labor anil management wage * — 1,954 — 1,542 — 1,283 1932 AVERAGES Number of farms u\craecd.. 48 33 34 Cash income S2.534 S2.1O9 S1.930 Cash expenditure 1,605 1,357 1,002 Net cash K ain 929 752 928 Inventory Kain or loss — 1,180 — 1.108 — 834 Net return -251 —356 94 Labeir an.l management wajjc ' '. — 1.834 — 2.046 — 967 1933 AVERAGES Number of farms averaged 43 '•* 56 Cash income 53,123 S2.467 $1,914 Cash expenditure 1 1,402 1.512 1.013 Net cash gain 1,726 955 901 , Inventory gain or loss 446 405 &gt; 354 Net return 2172 1.360 1.255 Labor and management wage 4 597 — 44 265 1 Dased upon annual analyses of farm account! prepared by the Nebraska Agricultural Extension Service and the Rural Economics Ocpartmenl ot the College of Agriculture, University of Nebraska. 5 In the summaries, returns from Fillmore rounty are reported with Thaycr county, which borders it on ihe south. 3 Non-irrigated farms (irrigated not used). 'This is the earning of the operator after first deducting wages for all unpaid labor other than his own, and secondly, after deducting an assumed 5 per cent on the investment. on this point. For 35 owners the average was $26,932 and the range from less than $10,000 for three owners to $80,000 for one owner. Included in the net worth are the land, buildings, equipment, and livestock. For 16 part-owners the average was $39,714 and the range from $16,000 to $84,000; Unfortunately the number and amount of mortgages are not known. In contrast, 42 tenant families lived on farms with an average net worth of $26,253 and a range from $5,500 to $63,000. Information regarding the net worth of the equipment and livestock owned by them was not listed; hence their financial status, as measured by their business investment, can not be given. Another index of the economic status of the 100 families included in the study is the net cash income from the farm business. This information, </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agr. Exp. S-a. Research Bulletin 78 summarized in Table 10, shows that 28 of the 58 keeping home accounts in 1931 had a cash return of less than $1,000, as compared with 51 of the 69 in 1932 and 40 of the 56 in 19J3. In 1931, 14 families had $1,500 or more, and in 1932 and 1933 the ni mber was seven. Economic services of farm women.— The economic contribution made Table 10. — Net cash income from tnese arm women is seen partly farm business of cooperating ' n tne activities which they listed. families, 1931-34. \ Table 11 compares the findings of '•Amount ,c n« I, No. of f ar m opI^T *c present study with those of an ca»h income j i93i i 1932 i 193J earlier study of routine and sea - uotojsoo:::::;;::::: la ,| bm1 work - °niy two of the 100 si!om!su99- 12 2 ° '&lt; vvomen took no part in outdoor SU500SI.999 '.'.'.'.'.'..'. 9 6 2 activities. Ninety -seven regarded Unknown .T!?.'.'".'.'.'. 4 5 'the care of chickens as a part of to»i number...... m w 56 the ' r '° b and 96 did the gardening. , " The amount of help received from other members of the family was not given. Less than one-third of the women helped with the milking i nd one-fifth worked in the fields at some time during the year. Eight a;sisted with the chores and other work ot the farm. Thus the division of Isbor between husband and wife is seen Table 11.— Nature of assistance r° ** d [ fferent in this selected group given by homemakers in out- rom ' , Sltuatl °n which exists in door activities. many urban homes where husbands t often provide the money income and homemfkers women direct the use of it. In these " Cm famiL '" arm homes the abilit i«, skills, and in J i93i' C 33 1^1927-28 ' interests of the wives affect very care of chickens 97 g2 directly the size of the cash income Mti r kinT E m and the amount of food which the work in fields! '.'. '.'.'.'.'..'. 19 38 5 farm can be made to furnish. In- Ch °wo,k n&lt;1 .. ol . hcr . fa . rm ... 8 125 d «rectly they affect it, as do urban None -j_ homemakers, by their ability and 1 M. Ruth Clark and Greta Gray, The Routine willingness tO provide home-manU - sL^TBZ°t^Tntu" m mo omzn - fa^ tured g° ods £or consumption. . . Churning, baking, canning, and the making and remaking of wearing :ipparel may conserve appreciably the cash income which is available for family living. THE MONEY VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING AND ITS DISTRIBUTION In this section money values are used to describe the standard of living which prevailed for the cooperating farm families during three years of depression. Comparisons are made vdthin the group with respect to farm ownership, size of family, level of living value, and age of homemakers. These are factors which appear to be of importance in determining the standard of a family. The standard for this group is also compared with </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living the standards found in other rural studies. Unless otherwise indicated 183 yearly records of 100 families are the basis for the comparisons. Average yearly money value and its distribution. — These Nebraska farm families had an average money value of living in 1931 of $1,226.36. In 1932 it was $1,008.58, and in 1933 it was $988.06. No attempt has been made to adjust 1932 and 1933 values to the 1931 price level in Table 12. Table 12. — Distribution of average yearly value of family living among principal groups of goods. 58 families, 69 families, 56 families. Item av. 517-c 3.9 — av. size 4.2 — av. size 4.3— 1931 1932 1933 Savings S 134.18 S 104.14 5 86.43 Food 382.26 283.81 283.54 Clothing 108.51) 83.47 90 15 Housing 249.41 254.68 235.04 Operating 182.38 147.69 157.12 Health 42.67 42.58 39.48 Development 126.96 92.21 96.30 Total value of living 11,226.36 51,008.58 S 988.06 Per cent Per cent Per cent Savings 10.9 10.3 8.8 Food 31.2 28.1 28.7 Clothing 8.8 8.3 9.1 Housing 20.3 25.2 23.7 Operating 14.9 14.7 15.9 Health 3.5 4.2 4.0 Development 10.4 9.2 9.8 Total 100.0 100.0 100.0 The value of food was greater than that of any other principal group and in each year it made up more than one-fourth of the total value. Housing was second in order of size and ranged from one-fifth in 1931 to one-fourth in 1932. The money value of operating was approximately 15 per cent, and that of clothing 8 per cent. For health, 3.5 to 4 per cent was -used. Development varied from 9.2 to 10.4 per cent. Savings, which were 10.9 per cent of the total in 1931, fell to 8.8 per cent in 1933. Relation of value of living supplied by farm to living purchased. — The years 1932 and 1933 showed a decrease in the average value of living supplied by the farm and in the average cash expenditure. In all three years, however, the farm provided approximately two-fifths of the total value of living. In this study the money value of foods and fuel supplied by the farm shown in Table 13 have been based upon records of the quantities actually used. Unit prices which each product would have brought if sold at the farm were used in preference to the plan of taking current retail prices in the locality, since so often the latter include services which the farm family does not perform before using the product. The bottling of milk, packag - ing of butter, grading of vegetables, and transportation are examples of these services, and the cost of the labor and materials must be included in </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Ack. Exp. S -a. Research Bulletin 78 Table 13. — Average money value of goods supplied by the farms and average casp expenditures. Item I 1931 j 1932 ! 1933 Food supplied 5 226.74 S 168.71 S 171.21 Fuel and ice supplied 25.81 25.37 29.7t Housing supplied 234. 119 239.3V 217. -i9 Total supplied \alue -1S(&gt;.M 433.47 418.41 Cash expenditure 739.72 575.1 1 569. (&gt;5 Total value of living 51.226.36 Sl.008.58 s 988.06 Per cent Per ctnl Per cent Food supplied ■ 18.4 16.7 17.3 Fuel and ice supplied 2.1 2.5 3.0 Housing supplied 19.0 23.7 22.0 Total supplied value 39.5 42.9 42.3 Cash expenditure 60.5 57.1 57.7 Total 100.0 100.0 100.0 the retail price. This difference in the method of computing values is im - portant to note, particularly when comparisons are made with money values which are based upon retail prices. Housing, in this study, consists of two items. The one is the annual value of the dwelling and the other is the cash expended for repair and upkeep. In Table 13 only the firs) item is included. It is based upon 9 per cent of the total value of the 'dwelling in order to cover interest on investment, depreciation, insurance and taxes. The total value was that used by the family in the farm account book, or estimated by them and later checked in the research office.! Average value of living for owners, part-owners, and tenants. — In Table 14 a three-year average is used ;is a basis for comparing owners, part - owners, and tenants with respect to the average value of living and the value for each of the principal grou as of goods. Part-owners are those who rent land in addition to that whict they own. Table 14. — Distribution of average value of living among principal groups of_ goods. ltcm Owners | Part-own :rs | Tenants Owners | Part-owners! Tenants Yearly records 63 35 85 63 3! 85 Av. size of family 4.2 4.2 4.0 4.2 4 2 4 0 Av. age of operator 45 41. J 34.8 45 41 .1 34^8 Value supplied by farm... S 550.47 S 538.0(2 S 334.96 43^9 39"' P 40*8 Cash expenditures 704.91 819.8) 486.10 56.1 60 8 59'2 Totjl $1,255.38 $1,347.8! S 821.06 100.0 100.0 loo' Savings S 103.45 S 168.2' S 87.07 S3 lil 106 food 344.02 334.43 285.34 27.4 24.8 347 Clothing 105.87 115.5) 75.17 8.4 86 92 Housing 342.99 321.63 145.13 27.3 238 177 Operating ; 182.30 188.(5 2 135.05 14.5 140 16~4 J™ 41.45 65.55 32.04 3.3 4.9 39 1 Development 135.30 153.8! 61.26 10.8 114 7'5 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living The part-owners had an average value of living of $1,347.82. The owners had $1,255.38, and the tenants had $821.06 or approximately two - thirds of that for the owner group. The percentage of the total living which was supplied by the farm was slightly higher for the owner group than for either of the other two. In terms of money value, that supplied by the farms of owners was more than $200 higher than for tenants. A comparison of the value of the seven principal groups of goods in the three classes showed a lower value for all groups among the tenants, but a higher percentage for food and operating. The percentage for doth- Table 15. — Distribution of average value of living among principal groups of goods, by value-of-living level. Item Under $500 j S500-S999 j SI.000-SI.499 | S1.500S1.999 | $2,000 and over Yearly records 5 99 -18 20 11 Av. size of family 4 4.1 -1.2 4.0 4.2 Av. age of operator 32.0 38.3 43.0 47.4 51 Value supplied by farm.. 5 169.25 S 318.52 S 434.45 S 677.12 51.345.39 Cash expenditures 210.98 420.42 779.88 1.036.94 1.222.68 Total value of living.. 380.23 738.94 1,214.33 1,714.06 2.568.07 Savings 8.11 68.10 154.75 196.71 151.16 Food ... 184.98 '274.98 341.49 414.87 435.90 Clothing 32.43 69.57 111.49 134.36 173.85 Housing 52.28 131.25 227.34 441.01 1,103.32 Operating 70.16 120.96 183.92 259.75 292.46 Health 8.09 22.91 59.46 65.01 108.17 Development 24.18 51.17 135.88 202.35 303.19 P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. Value supplied by farm 44.5 43.1 35.8 39.5 52.4 Cash expenditures 55.5 56.9 64.2 60.5 47.6 Total 100.0 100.0 100.0 100.0 100.0 Savings 2.1 9.2 12.8 11.5 5.9 Food 48.7 37.2 28.1 24.2 17.0 Clothing «.5 9.4 9.2 7.8 6.8 Housing 13.7 17.8 18.7 25.7 43.0 Operating 18.5 16.4 15.1 15.2 11.3 Health 2.1 3.1 4.9 3.8 4.2 Development 6.4 6.9 11.2 11.8 11.8 ing was also slightly higher among the tenants. The average number per family was approximately the same in the three classes. The average age of the operator was 45 years for owners, 41.8 for part-owners, and 34.8 foi tenants. Comparison of levels of living. — The lowest total value of living in the three-year period was $296.56. for one family of three members in 1931. The highest value, $4,475, occurred in the same year for a family of three. More than one-half of the entire number of records showed less than $1,000. Eighty-four per cent showed less than $1,500. Only six families had a total value of $2,000 and above for one or more years. Table 15 compares five different levels with respect to the money value and percentage of the total which was used for each of the principal groups of goods. For all levels the size pf family was approximately the </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Si a. Research Bulletin 78 same. The average age of the farm operator, however, varied. For those living on less than $500 the average age of the operator was 32 years In the next highest class, $50fl-$999, the age was 38.3 years, and on the highest level the average was 51 years. The most striking difference in the money values was in the item of housing. On the lowest level, $52. 8, or 13.7 per cent, was the average housing value. Both in dollars and percentage this item increased until it reached an average of $1,103.32, 43 per cent of the total value of living for the level of $2,000 and above. Families on the highest level averaeed considerably more than twice as muih as those on the second highest level An explanation cf the wide range is found on pages 11 to 14. where the size, age, and extent of home improvements in the dwellings are discussed. VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING 0 10 20 30 40 50 SO 70 80 80 100 | PERCENTAGE E3D &amp;m FOOD CLC 'THING HOUSING OPERATING ■■ iTTTTTT] m^\ HEALTH DEVELOPMENT SAVINGS Fie;. 1.— Pcrccnta K cs of average value of living used by families on different levels for principal groups of goods. Just as housing was the most important single item in family living on the highest level, so food occupied (the central place for the lowest levels and made up more than one-third -of the whole for more than one-half of the entire group. However, the iverage money value of food on the highest level was more than twice as large as that on the lowest level. Clothing showed an increase in value with each level but it constituted a decreasing percentage of the whole for the levels of $1,000 and above The average for the level of $2,000 and above was $173.85 as compared with $32.43 for the level of less than $50C, but the small number of families on these levels makes this comparison less significant. Operating items also increased i i money value with each increase in average value of living but only on the lowest level did the proportion 1 of the whole approach one-fifth. For he $1,000-11,499 level the percentage was 15.1 as compared with 11.3 for he level of $2,000 and above. Health expenditure averaged $22.91 yearly for more than one-half of the entire </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living group. On the highest level it averaged $108.17. On no one of the levels was as much as 5 per cent due to this item. In both value and percentage, development was of increasing import- Tc-^T the 1OW tO the h 'S h lcveIs - The ave «ge of $51.17 for the level or |o00-$999 was one-sixth of that on the level of $2,000 and above The percentage of the total value of living used for development ranged from b.4 to 11.8. Figure 1 shows the ditfercnces in the distribution of the aver - age value on the different levels. Average value of living for families of different size.— Table 16 com - pares the value of living in families of different size. Families of two and Table 16.— Distribution of average value of living among principal groups of goods, by size of family. Item I m Tl ™ I Th ' ee F '""- V^i I More than 1 members I members membra members | 5 members Yearly records 24 41 „ 7j ~ Av. a K e of humemakcr. . . 37.8 37. k 3r,.s 374 Value supplied by farm... % mj50 S 542.79 5 4V3 76 5 3jq ,5 TTmoo Cash expenditures 6M.HS 5 64.4f. 595.1* (l v\\ ?«« Total value of livini;. , 1.105.35 1.107.25 1.029.09 I.0I&amp;-U 1.170J6 Savin « s I?"'" 90.22 87.61 107.56 155.62 F "'"[. •■■ 289.72 276*1 315.00 326 40 387 9&gt; CJotWng ?4.78 80.20 101.12 9402 11H44 Housln B ■ 2».(» 3WI.4O 240.29 18141 162 17 """ a /' n K "«&gt;•« 164.H 151.97 nfijo 78 98 '" U . h «■» -10.17 40.01 48.27 36 87 Development 123.22 95.40 93,09 102.30 130.3fi Value supplied by farm... 39.9 49,11 42V 17^' Sfi? Cash expenditure! 60.1 51.0 57^9 f,2 i 53 « T"'" 1 100.0 100.0 100.0 100.0 looio Saving! 12.6 h.l K~5 \ii}, UJ '•■° O&lt; 1. M.2 25.0 30.fi 32.1 Ul clothln E 6.8 7.2 9.8 9.2 • Kil Housin K 24.3 32.6 23.3 17 9 139 Operalinc 15.3 14.9 14.8 15 4 15', Health 3.7 3/, 3.9 47 3*2 Development 11.1 S.6 9.1 ] 0" 1 |'|j three members used approximately $1,100 annually for living. In families of more than five members, the average was $1,170.36. Families of four members averaged $1,029.09 and families of five averaged $1,016.46. The value of goods supplied by the farm was largest in families of three and represented 49.0 per cent of the total. In all other classes the percentage was less than 43. In no class did the average for cash expenditures reach $750. Food and housing combined were responsible for approximately 50 per cent of the average value of living in each class. This relationship is shown in Figure 2. As the value for food increased in the families of four, five, and more members, the value of housing decreased. The percentage for clothing varied from 6.8 for families of two members to 10.1 for </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 families of more than five membe s. Operating costs, though varying in amount, showed little variation in percentage and approximated 15 throughout. Families of two and six or more members had a higher value for development than did those o: three, four, or five members. The largest families had the highest average for savings, $155.62; families of two were second with $138.70. In tiis connection the average age of home - maker for each class is important tc note. MEMBERS _________________ 0 O 20 30 40 50 60 70 80 90 100 PERCENTAGE t~~ __ FOOD CLOTHING HOUSING OPERATING ■■ ~~ C~~l HEALTH DEVELOPMENT SAVINGS Fie. 2. — Percentages d£ average value of living used by families of different sizes for principal groups of goods. Value of living and age of homemaker. — Table 17 shows the variation in average value of living for families when they are grouped by age of homemaker. The average value oi living was $1,553.94 in the class of 50 years and over as compared with ! 5 1,509 .51 for those 45 to 50 years. The average size of family in both groups was smaller than in the classes with the hoinemaker 30 to 40 years of age. For the class from 40 to 45 years the average value was $1,109.20, and in each of the others it was less than $1,000. The small number of case; included in the average of $657.51 for women under 25 years makes the igure less significant than if more were included. The average value of living supplied by the farm was very much higher for the two upper age classes. In tr e 50-year-and-older class the amount was very nearly half of the total. The explanation for the wide range is seen when the values of housing are compared. Families in which the women were in the two upper age classes had 31 and 37 per cent of the total value in housing as compared with 15 to 19 per cent in the lower age classes. A comparison of average cash expenditures in the several classes </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living Table 17. — Distribution of average value oj living amdng principal groups of goods, by age of homemaker. Item | anVmcr [ «-49 &gt;"■ | 40-44 its. | 35-39 yrs. | 30-34 yrs. | 25-29 yr&gt;. ; Yearly records 18 28 27 29 31 44 6 Av. size of family... 4 3.5 -i.6 5.0 4.6 3.6 2.5 Value supplied by farm 5 757.04 S 661.84 5 31G.09 S 345.79 5 404.25 S 333.89 S 251.98 Cash expenditures 796.90 748.07 723.11 509.47 556.76 519.56 405.53 Total value of living 1.553.94 1,509.91 1,109.20 855.26 961.01 853.45 657.51 Savings 120.68 158.52 117.09 71.95 108.94 90.30 99.92 Fof.il 311.55 346.79 339.38 324.70 331.40 279.92 190.84 Clothing 106/r* 125.12 104.86 89.76 89.45 73.39 40.34 Housing 574.75 467.70 170.33 146.97 184.86 151.98 119.18 Operating 201.44 196.66 165.63 136.57 145.41 152.95 127.28 Health '10.54 32.54 42.13 24.33 33.11 45.07 43.81 Development 148.34 182.58 169.78 60.98 67.84 59.84 36.14 /'. n. /■ &lt;•/. /'. &lt;•/. P. cl. I: a. • P. a. P. a Value supplier) by farm 48.7 43.8 34.8 40.4 42.1 39.1 38.3 Cash expenditures 51.3 56.2 65.2 59.6 57.9 60.9 61.7 Total 100.0 100.0 100.C liW.O 100.0 100.0 100.0 Savings 7.7 10.5 10.6 8.4 11.3 10.6 15.2 1-oc.l 20.0 23.0 30.6 38.0 34.5 32.8 29.0 Clothinc 6.9 8.3 9.4 10.5 9.3 8.6 6.1 Housing 37.0 31.0 15.4 17.2 19.2 17.8 18.1 UpcraiinK 13.0 H.T 14.9 15.9 15.2 17.9 19.4 Health 5 8 2.1 3.8 2.8 3.4 5.3 6.7 Derdopriwnt 9.6 12.1 15.3 7.2 7.1 7.0 5.5 showed more than $700 for those in which the homemaker was 40 years or older. The average was less than $600 for all others. Operating values for the classes of older women were higher than those of the younger classes: this resulted in part from the difference in AGE UNDER 25 O 10 20 30 40 50 80 70 00 SO 100 PERCENTAGE P%Z3 R^^3 t^M FOOD CLOTHING HOUSING OPERATING ■B Illllllll bv^vKI HEALTH DEVELOPMENT SAVINGS Fie. 3. — Percentages of average value of living used for principal groups of goods in families classified by age of homemaker. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agr. Exp. 5ta. Research Bulletin 78 housing. Average clothing values were above 5100 for the three older i classes and below $100 for all others. The average total for development was more than twice as high for the three older classes as it was for the younger classes, due in a measure to the cost of educating older children. The amount saved was also higher in the three older classes, and in each case was greater than $100. In only one of the four younger classes— the Table 18. — Distribution of average value of living among principal groups of goods in studies t f Nebraska farm families. ! Present home ~ Item account study. Home account Home account Estimate study 1931-33 project. 1933 project, 1934 1923-24 (A) (B)« (cy (D)« Number of families 100 ' 164 239 342 . Av. size of household.. 4.2 4.0 3.9 43 Value supplied by farm. 5 445.71 S 330.80 S 341.87 S 750.00 Cash expenditures 625.61 588.06 714.11 93100 Total value of living, 1.071.32 918.86 1,055.98 1,681.00 j Savings I0H.24 86.18 91.48 50.00 I Food: Purchased 127.06 130.71 161.14 1 -,, ™ Supplied 187.87 149.42 155.24 / lZbW&gt; Clothing 93.45 93.17 118.64 250.00 Housing: Supplied 231.00 158.92 163.45 204 00 Cash expended 15.99 10.77 10.25 Operating 161.57 165.06 206.02 282 00 Health 41.66 45.20 . 52.79 73.00 " Development 104.48 79.43 96.97 96.00 I P. ct. V. cl. l: cl. /'. ct. , Value supplied by farm. 41.6 36.0 32.4 44.6 Cash expenditures 58.4 64.0 67.6 55.4 Total 100.0 100.0 100.0 100.0 Savings 101 9.4 8.7 3.0 Food: Purchased . .. 11.9 14.2 15.2 ) .,7 Supplied .... 17.5 16.3 14.7 Housing: Supplied 21.5 17.3 15.5 12.1 Cash expended 1.5 1.2 1.0 Clothing 8.7 10.1 11.2 14.9 Operating 15.1 18.0 19.5 16.8 Health 3.9 4.9 5.0 4.3 Development 9.8 8.6 9.2 5.7 1 One hundred eighty-three records were fn nished by these families. * Muriel • Smith. Nebraska Summary of H imc Account Records, 1933, Nchr. Agr. Ext. Service, Circular 11-112. 3 Muriel Smith, Nebraska Summary «f Hume Account Records, 1934, Ncbr. Agr. Ext. Service. Circular 11-113. 4 f. O. Rankin and Eleanor H Hinman. A Summary of the Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes, Nebr. Apr. Exp. £ta. BlI. 267, Jan.. 932. 30-34-year class — did the amount exceed $100. Figure 3 shows how the \arious age classes distributed the value of their living. Comparison of present study with other Nebraska studies. — Table 18 compares the averages of the present study with those of other studies of farm families in Nebraska. For tlie year ending in June, 1924, which was regarded as a "good" year, a schec ule was used to collect data on the value of living, and farm families estimated the amount used for their various needs. The findings in both of tie recent studies of the Agricultural Ex - tension Service are based upon summaries of home-account books. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living The average value of living found in the 1923-24 study was $1,681, more than half again as high as that of the present study, which was $1,071.32. In 1933 the Agricultural Extension Service found an average of $918.86, and in 1934, $1,055.98. Both of these summaries show less than 40 per cent from the farm, while the 1923-24 estimate study and the present study show slightly more than 40 per cent. The most striking differences in the distribution of the value of living are in food, clothing, and operat - ing. These changes are shown graphically in Figure 4. $700- | HOMC ACCOUNT STUDY H &amp;6OO- 5 — — HOMC ACCOUNT PROJCCT-1933 B=l ».„ HOME ACCOUNT PROJECT -1934 Pj£'S3 9 5OO" '/ ' ~ i "* J ~ ESTIMATE STUDY E^^j $400 - °ABCD ABCD ABCD ABCD ABCD ABCD ABCD FOOD - CLOTHING -HOUSING-OPERATING-HEALTH-DEVELOPMENT-SAVINGS Fig. 4. — Comparison of money value of principal groups of goods in four Nebraska studies of farmers' standards of living. The estimate study (D) represents the year ending in June. 1 924. There are several factors which need to be considered in interpreting these differences. Of major importance is the method of study. With the estimate method, which arrives at quantities and value by means of a schedule filled out in conference with the family at the close of the year, it is probable that averages for food, operating, and development may lepresent less accurately the actual values used by the group than those for clothing, cash expended for housing, health, and savings. The latter item* are fewer in number and more easily recalled, particularly in cases where iheck stubs or canceled checks are available and in studies where sufficient time is allowed to discuss these items with other members of the family. In determining the value supplied by the farm the estimate method is likely to be less accurate than the home-account method. A comparison of the two methods of study has led to the following conclusions which are pertinent at this point: </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 "In conclusion, the results from tl ic small samples of families included in this study indicate that \yith families similar in education and in purchasing procedures to the professional group cooperating in the present study, the schedule apparently can lie made a satisfactory method of sccu ing data on family expenditures and savings. If an analysis of the nutritional content of the diet of such a group is to be made a part of. the project, the results of this in .estimation indicate that the schedules should be supplemented by records of food const mption. With farm families similar to those coo|ierating in this study, the schedule lould perhaps be made a satisfactory method of securing data on family expenditures and savings. However, for the purpose of obtaining satisfactory data on the value nf family living furnished by the farm, and on the quantities of foods consumed by firm families, it is apparent that accounts kept for short periods at different seasons in the year should be used to check the accuracy of the schedule data." 1" A second factor to be considered is the change in the level ot prices. In 1931 the prices paid by Nebraska farmers for commodities were 83 per cent of those for 1923 as indicated by a change in index numbers. For 1932 and 1933 they were 72 per ent. 1 " In a comparison of housing supplied by the farm the difference in the estimates of the annual value should be noted. In the 1923-24 investigation 10 per cent of the total value of tr e dwelling was used, whereas 9 per ceni. was used in the three more recent studies. The contrast in this item be - tween the present study and the earlier one is therefore grater than the averages indicate. A third factor should be nottx in interpreting the increase in the aver - age and in the percentage for s: vings which occurs in the three recent studies. The form of saving reported in all of the studies was almost wholly insurance. In many farm families a single policy of $1,000 or more is carried by the husband as a r. rotection to his family in the event or illness and death, but it is not commonly regarded as a form of in% - estment to be increased as the margin between cash income and outgo is increased. Rather is there the tendency to invest available money in the farm business. Purchase of additional land, new machinery, or stock is common. These increases are seen in the farm inventory but do not appear in the savings column of the home account book. On the other hand, the home account book often shows savings when :he farm business shows a loss. The savings are usually life insurance ind the loss may be due quite largely to a decrease in the farm inventory. Of special interest is a comparison of the changes in value and per - centage in the present study (A) ind the summary of 1934 home account books (C) of the Agricultural E (tension Service. In the latter were in - cluded many of the 100 families who had kept accounts in study A. Cash expenditures in 1934 were almost $100 higher, though the total value of living was slightly lower. The drouth reduced farm production — notably gardens. Purchased food, clothing, operating, and health were all higher in value than in study A. Savings, development, and cash expended for "Chase Going Woodhouse and Faith WilliLms. Comparison of Schedule anil Account Methods of Collecting Data on Family Living V. S. Dept.lof Aj;r. Tech. Bui. 386, pp. 4(M1. 1931. H. Clyde Fillcy, Effects of Inflation and Deflation upon Nebraska Agriculture, 19M to 1*&gt;32. Th*" percentage are derived from index numbers iti Table ■), paRc 12. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living housing were less than in study A. A slight increase in farm prices toward the close of 1934 and government payments to farmers explain the upward trend in cash expenditure. Comparison of present study with selected studies of farm families. — Table 19 is a comparison of the present study made during the depression Table 19. — Distribution of average value of living among principal groups of goods in selected studies of farm families. Present home Iowa home Wisconsin csti- Vermont home N. Central Item account study, account study, 1 mate study 3 account study 3 estimate study * 1931-33 1926-29 1929-30 1927-30 1922-24 Number of families 100 147 900 95 1,439 Av. si;c .if household.. 4J 4Ji 4J; 4;!) 4.6 Value supplied by farm S 445.71 5 692.23 S 497.00 S 753.00 S 671.00 Cash expenditures 625.61 932.72 957.00 1,728.00 942.00 Total value of living 1.071.32 1 .624.95 1.454.00 1.K81.IK) 1,613.00 Savins! 108.24 82.82 38.00 h6.00 44.00 Food: Purchased 127.1/6 241.17 289.00 318.00 220.00 Supplied 187.H7 399.69 231.00 372.00 403.00 Clothing 93.45 153 S7 194.00 159.0" 232.00 Homing Supplied .... 231.00 267.12 221.00 248.0*1 233.00 Cash expended 15.99 Operating . .: 161.57 284.87 275.00 398.00 263.00 Health 4166 46.46 75.00 59.00 72.00 Development &lt; 1O4.4S 195 41 131.00 241.00 146.00 /'. i/. /'. &lt;■/. /". a. i: a. l: a. Value supplied by farm 41.6 42.6 34.2 40.0 41.6 Cash cxpendituics 58.4 57.4 65.8 60.0 58.4 Tolal 100.0 100.0 100.0 100.0 100.0 Saving. 10.1 5.6 2.6 5.0 2.7 1-ood: Purchased 11.9 15.0 19.9 18.0 12.2 Supplied 17.5 24.5 15.9 19.0 26.4 Clothing ... 8.7 9.5 13.4 8.0 4.4 Housing: Supplied 21.5 16.4 15.2 13.0 14.4 Cash expended 1.5 '.Vi 1 Operating* 15.1 17.6 18.9 22.0 16.3 Health 3.9 2.9 5.1 3.0 4.5 Development" 9.8 9J W) 1^0 9.1 ' F.. E. Iloyt, Value of Family LivinE on Iowa Farms. Iowa Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 281, June. 1931. ■ E. L. KirVpatrick. P. E. McNall. and May I.. Cowlcs, Farm Family Living in Wisconsin. Wil. Agr. F.xp. Sta. Kcs. Bui. 114. )an.. 1933. ... c c. ' M. Muse, The Standard 'of Living on Specific Owner-operated \ crmont harms, \ t. Agr. fcxp. sia. Uul. 340. June, 1932. ' . . •E. L. Kirkpalrick, The Farmer's Standard of Living, The Century Co., New 19Z9. '- Includes fuel, ice, telephone, household service, supplies, equipment, and automobile. "Includes education, church and charity, . recreation. K ifts, organizations, personal, and any un - classified items.. with four studies of farmers' standards of living made in other areas in the preceding decade. The Vermont and Nebraska studies are similar in the number of families included, but the latter is based upon 183 yearly records of the 100 families. Both the North Central estimate study and the Wisconsin estimate study have very much larger numbers, and differ from the other three, also, in the method of study. The size of the household in the five studies varies but slightly. In total value of living the present study revealed less by several hundred dollars than any of the other four. There was but little variation </seg>
            <seg id="p028">. Nebraska Agr. Exp. S-a. Research Bulletin 78 in the percentage of the total furnished by the farm, and for both Nebraska and the North Central states the percentage was 41.6. The value and percentage for savings were higher in the present than in any of the earlier investiga ions. The tendency of farm operators to invest cash reserves in something other than insurance has already been indicated. This tendency is seen n the averages for the studies made during more prosperous years. An analysis of the investment expenditures of 226 farm families in 'Minnesota.- in 1927-28 provides interesting infoi - mation in this connection. Of an average total of $1,058, 26 per cent was used for interest on debts for real property, 22 per cent for payments on farms or mortgages, and 19.8 per ceht was reinvested in the business. Only 6 per cent was used for life and ac :ident insurance. Interest on operating or personal debts accounted for 2.8 (per cent, while the remainder, 22.4 pci cent, was used for all other investments. In the upper income groups the proportion of the total used for li e and accident insurance was smaller than that in the $2,000-$4,000 class :s. 17 The present study was lower than any of the others in value of all principal groups of goods, except savings. In percentage, farm-supplied housing was higher for the Nebraska study and represented 21.5 per cent of the total. The Iowa home account study of 1926-29 was second in order with 16.4 per cent. As is suggested in the next section, the annual value ot farm-supplied housing is not easily altered, and therefore years of depres - sion show but little change in value from more prosperous years. CHANGES IN THE DISTRIBUTION OF THE VALUE OF LIVING DURING 1931, 1932, AND 1933 In Table 12 a comparison is mkde of the yearly value of each of the principal groups of goods with the total value of living. In the following section the changes will be discussed and further details given for all of the families and also for the 25 fa nilies whose records were complete for the three-year period. Findings for the entire group.—TThe principal form of savings was life insurance. For the three counties the average per family fell from S134.18 in 1931 to $86.43 in 1933 and the percentage dropped from 10.9 to 8.8. In 1931, seven of the families saved lothing. In 1932, 13 families reported nothing saved, and in 1933 there w:re 14 without savings. Several families dropped insurance policies after 193 1 because they were unable to meet the premiums or because loans on theirt policies left little of the cash value. As has already been stated, farmers had small incomes during this period. The price of farm products fell more rapidly than the cost of pro - duction. An additional reason why farm families had difficulty in saving was the necessity of making interest payments on investments. Reports on obligations for the year 1933 showed that 39 of the 56 families had made </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living interest payments on loans or mortgages and that 20 had made payments on notes. The payment of interest is unquestionably an expense but the reduction of principal is ordinarily made from savings. Fifty-two reported no new investments. The proportion of the average value of living used for food approxi - mated 30 per cent in each of the three years, though the value for the year 1931 was $382 as compared with $283 in both 1932 and 1933. For a family of four the daily average fell from $1.05 to 77 cents. A fall of 13 per cent in the retail prices of food in 1932 helps to explain the decrease. roOO CLOTHING HOUSING OPERATING HEALTH DEVELOPMENT SAVINGS Fig. 5. — Changes in the money value of principal jJ r()U l&gt;s (if jjoods for 25 families in 1931. 1932, and 1933. Out of each dollar used for food, 60 cents was the value supplied by the farm. The method used for estimating the value of home products resulted in a lower total than would have occurred had retail prices been used. The slight variation in the average size of family from year to year makes interesting a comparison of the quantities supplied by the farm. In Table 20 both quantities and money values are given. The latter arc less comparable than the former because of the change in prices which occurred. In the use of eggs there was little variation, and the weekly average was 3!4 dozens. Milk consumption rose from 939 quarts in 1931 to 996!4 quarts in 1932 and remained practically the same during 1933. The average amount used daily was between 2 Y z and 3 quarts for families averaging four members. Both cream and butter were used more genei-" ously in 1932 than in 1931 and a further increase occurred in 1933. The average weekly consumption of butter rose from 2 pounds in 1931 to 2 l / 2 pounds in 1933. The amount of cream used daily increased slightly. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 Although the value of home-produ:ed meat was lower for 1933 than 1932 tne number of pounds used was greater. The pounds of poultry used in - creased very nearly half in 1933 ever 1932. For fruits ™d vegetables weights were not available, but in each of the three years their value was irom 16 to 19 per cent of the value of all food supplied by the farm. Corn wheat, and miscellaneous products such as cheese, nuts, and honey pro - duced on the farm, were little use!. Table 20.— Average quantity, moniy value, and portion of total food value of various foods supplied yearly Ay the farms of all cooperating families. Item 1931-58 families 1932-69 families ' 1933—56 families __^ Am.. | Value | P. c i. Ami. | Value | P. ct. Am., i Value I P. c. IiMifil toui bod suppiici:::: .:: 2»:n »:» ::: 1-0.75 v»i ::: , 7 !-g lo s-s Inventory adjustmen. 0 37 7nj "V A"51 To.al food med 226J74 "j "i 16 lfl \\\ \\\ 17 ?ff »T The adequacy of the diet in 19:3 for 49 of the 100 families is the sub - ject of a special study to be reported in a separate bulletin. The findings are summarized in the following statement: inn'n!.r t&gt; " S T n **L Centf -°; 33 ° f thc fanilirs studicd&gt; wcre usin s ««e«s which scored 100 per cent or above w.th respect to c; Icium and phosphorus; 91.8 per cent or 45 were udng d.ets scoring 100 per cent o- above in protein: with rcspVct to calories, " 5 £™' « . g inn P&gt; WCrC a^ mte ° r m ™ *»n adequate; and for iron, 77.5 per cent, or 38. scored 100 per cent or more. Of thc 4&lt;&gt; families, 22, or 45 per cent, were consuming diets inadequate or one or more nutrients, there bcinp 58 deficiencies ot various kinds among these.' Calcium and phosphorus, both available in large quantity from milk were inadequate most often and alsjo fell farthest short of adequacy when measured in terms of percentage of the requirement. Inadequacy in pro - tein was found less frequently than were inadequacies in any other nutrient i«i expenditure for clothing was less in 1932 than in either 1931 or 1933. From a high point of $108.50 it fell in 1932 to $83 47 and rose m 1933 to $90.15. Included in this group were expenditures for per - sonal appearance such as haircuts, shaves, and any cosmetics used. The average for the husband in the family was lower each year than the aver - age tor the wife, and for other members of the family it was higher Because many of the more costly articles of clothing are purchased less often by farm families than once in three years, the yearly costs found are probab y somewhat below an average annual cost. The need for making a small cash income purchase the essentials for family well-being also lowered the amount spent. 8 The average value of housing w s second only to that of food in each ot the three years and represented ore-fifth to one-fourth of the total value. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living Nine per cent of the valuation of the farm dwelling was used throughout the study as the amount needed to cover interest on investment, deprecia - tion, insurance, and taxes. In addition, the actual cash expenditures for repair and upkeep were included. The average annual value of the two items was $249.41 in 1931, $254.68 in 1932, and $235.04 in 1933. For farm owners, lean years make sacrifices necessary, but housing costs can - not easily be altered from year to year; hence they are more stable than those of other goods and services. The dwelling that has been bought or built continues to be used, and only in the upkeep can the amount be regulated. The average expenditure in cash was $15 to $18 per year — an amount which left over many needed repairs, including painting, until the farm would again "p a y"- Table 21. — Changes in the average yearly value of operating items. llcm 1931 |- 1932 1933 Purchased light, fuel, anil ice S 29.02 5 34.20 S 26.85 Supplie.1 fuel anil ice 25.81 25.37 29.71 Water and telephone 10.30 7.9ft C.28 Supplies and equipment 71.90 42.55 49.65 Automobile 15.35 37.61 44.63 Total value of operating S182.38 S147.69 S157.12 Percentage of total value of living 14.9'.' j 14.7', O 15.9^1 The average operating cost was 15 per cent of the total value of living and showed little variation from year to year, though the amount was less following 1931. In Table 21, the individual items are given. Household iupplies and equipment, both new articles and replacements, amounted to $71.90 in 1931 but less than $50 in the two succeeding years, quite prob - ably indicating one of the items where families practice economy as the need arises. The expense of the automobile showed relatively little change from year to year, though it was somewhat lower in 1932. A decrease after 1931 in the average for water and telephone, though not large, occurred because telephone service was discontinued in some of the homes. No expense was recorded for water in these farm homes, but the account book used in the study combined the two items. Fifty-five to $60 was the average value of all light, fuel, and ice. In 1933 home-produced fuel and ice exceeded the average value of purchased light, fuel, and ice, a change which was due to greater use of wood and cobs for fuel and lessened use of coal. The average expenditure for health was slightly lower in 1933 than in 1931 and in 1932. The variation in percentage for the three years was 3.5 to 4.2. The range in this item among the cooperating families was very wide, a point which is concealed in the use of averages. For one family of two members who kept records throughout the three-year period the ex - penditure per year was less than one dollar. Another family spent $590 in a single year and $215 the following year. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 Met t Ce t r r PaM ITT 1 10 - In d ° llarS . "ducarioT! chfnged bu nH 1Q* *f three y ea , rs ' while the iverage for church and charity in 1937 and 1933 dropped to less than one-lfalf of the $41.54 average in 193 This SSTtE " P l ° 3 VCly gfeatly reduCed -^nditure bv one S^Jor IqTth' """H sHghtly h^ her in ™* than in JET . ■ am ° Unt ° r glfts to friends and relatives outside Table 22.— Changes in the av\ra Re ye ariy value of development. !S I &gt;«i I i«: ! ,933 = Fducation . . . ' ' ■ Church and charity.;."! „•?! S 37.S9 S 38.«3 Recreation ■ | '- 54 20.92 17 r ,7 Gifts ...■".".; ; ;?'? 22n " 26.98 : 2 '- 22 11.40 13.02 Total value of development sikw. ■ „. , . Percental of ,.,,:.| value ,,f \W me ."[WWW \\\ _ .*'$•$, S 92.9J $ 96JO _ Findings for twenty-five familieL who kept records for three yearH The changes from year to year wh ch have been discussed in the preced - we g re P s a u ffi faP H '" the aVerageS ° f aH famili « wh ° s ™2 tTere wS 9S f T P u 'T a " alyS S '" a " y ° ne y ear " In the group Th s fir \ £amiheS , t , hat kept reCOrds throughout the three-year ptiod ratine the h" P° SSlbI^. a " ™^f &lt;&gt;i their records for the purpL of eTonornic'Lt" 8 " •"&gt; du^ of pj" T , able 23 the . cnan g« in valul for each of the items is given and in total value ot $1,500 or more; in 1932 there were 10 and in 1933 there </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living was only slightly more than two-thirds of the 1931 total. Church and charity showed the greatest decrease and gifts were second. The decrease in education in 1932 was less than for any other item with the exception of light, fuel, and ice purchased in 1933. Education was slightly higher in 1933 than in 1931. Interpreted in terms of family practice, this meant some change in subscriptions to magazines and newspapers, but sons and daughters in college continued with their courses. Lowered cash expendi - ture for church and charity and gifts to those outside the family did not Table 23. — Changes in the distribution of average yearly value of living for twenty-fife families. 1 I'cm I9.?l 19.12 1933 Value supplied hy farm 5 588.03 S 509.54 5 509 H Cash expenditures 844.59 626.94 612'll Total value of living 1,432.62 1.13(1.48 I.121J5 Savings 5 H5.iV, S 123.89 S 104.17 Food: Purchased 163.99 105.28 IoTtI Supplied 242.22 176.64 179 93 5406.21 S28I.92 S283.64 Clothing! Father 25.59 15.17 20 25 Mother 49.42 31.50 33.78 Others 44.64 10.45 UP 119.65 77.12 " 87.35 Housing: Supplied l&gt;y farm 31S.R3 309.21 299.81 Cash expended 10.14 14.14 2133 328.97 323.35 321.14 Fuel, light, ice: Purchased 33.60 37 61 33 16 Supplied 26.98 23.69 29.40 Water and telephone 10.24 H.62 7.41 Supplies and equipment 88.42 49.73 4fi.75 Automobile 45.91 37.07 37 56 205.15 156.72 154.28 Health 47.11 61.01 42.9C Education • 60.76 57.01 62.96 Church and charity 68.18 21.09 18.88 Recreation 23.90 2O.2M 28.97 Gifts 27.63 14.IW 16.96 1K0.47 112.47 127.77 1 The families averaged 3.8 memhers each year. always mean a lessened contribution, for frequently home products were given instead of purchased gifts — a value which was probably recorded somewhat less accurately than other values. The average per family was approximately ten dollars yearly. Wood, for example, in one family helped to meet the annual pledge to the church and the services of the farm operator paid the balance. Neither item was recorded by the family. An interesting comment on purchased recreation may help to account for an increase in value of this item in 1933 over that in 1931. The year 1932 brought so many hardships and sacrifices that an expenditure for recrea - tion was necessary to build up morale. In the group were some who made trips to the World's Fair. Several suggested that the use of the car for family recreation helped to relieve the strain that came with everything going wrong. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 The second highest percentage decrease in 1932 was in clothing. For husband, wife, and all others, the average value was lower than in 1931. This was due in part to the amount on hand and, particularly, to the con - dition of the more costly garments, such as coats and suits, which could be made "to do" until there was a margin in the cash income. A 10 per cent decrease in retail prices of chthing is another explanation. Undoubt - edly, however, there was a tender cy on the part of these farm families to let the standard for clothing, as measured by number of articles, their state of usefulness, and the cost per item, fall when demands upon a smaller income increased. In this connection, the degree of skill and interest in garment-making and remaking on the part of the homemaker was an important factor in deter Timing the economic service which she Table 24.— Average quantity ami money value of food supplied by the farm for twenty-five families during three years. haa '"' 1932 1933 Amt. I Value Ami. | Value Aim. | Value Ekrs ('«.). 177 24.18 172 19.07 160 16 65 Milk iqis.) 831 38.61 910 27.64 966 25 05 Cream (««.) 110 23.62 123 18.99 118 ISM Butter (/Ax.) 103 27.06 108 20.49 108 19 47 Poultry (/*/.). ... 26.95 15J 16.01 212 17 46 Fruits, vegetables ... 40.75 34 29 33'm Corn, wheat 4.2i ... 2 77 6 '72 Miscellaneous .; ... .^^ ... 0.69 . .. o'69 Total value of supplied : " , food"---; 2 «- 2 •■■ 175.29 ... 176.63 Inventory adjustment. ... ; . . \ 35 2 20 Total value of fowl "«*1 242.22 176.64 179.83 could render and the change in the standard which was necessary. The year 1933 showed an increase in the value of clothing due in large part to the necessity for replacing wholly worn-out apparel. Unfortunately, there is no information regarding the ttitude of adolescents toward a lowered standard. A decrease of more than one -third in the value of food purchased occurred in 1932 and 1933 for these 25 families as compared with a de - crease of slightly more than a fourth in the value of farm-supplied food. A 13 per cent change in price h=lps to explain the decrease in value of purchased food, just as lower prices for farm products explain the change in value of home-supplied food. There was no evidence of fewer guests for meals. An effort to use more home products is seen in the increased consumption of milk, meat, and poultry shown in Table 24. Conditions such as drouth, over which the arm family has no control, affect, how - ever, the amount that can be mate available from the farm. The value of operating items decreased approximately one-fourth in 1932, largely because of fewer purchases of supplies and equipment. The new rug or table which had been hoped for was not purchased and the supply of curtains, table linen, bedding, and kitchen equipment was made </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living to do. Fuel, light, and ice, both purchased and supplied, changed rela - tively little. In 1932, a poor year for cobs, more fuel had to be purchased. Less coal and more wood were used when possible after 1931. In the 25 families, as in the larger number, the smaller value for water and tele - phone was the result of discontinuing telephone service. Old cars were used sparingly in order not only to avoid the cost of gas and oil but to delay expenditure for costly repairs. One family sold the car in order to lessen expenditure, and arrangements were made to pay lor gas and oil when a neighbor's car was shared for trips to town. An - other family did not purchase a new license. Horses and buggies were used by a few of the group. Table 25. — Yearly percentage changes in average value of living and of principal groups of goods for all cooperating families and for twenty - jive families that kept records during three years (1931=100). Percentage decrease Ilcm 69 families, 25 families, 56 families, I 25 families, 1932 1932 1933 j 1933 Supplied value 10.9 13.5 14.0 13.7 Cash expended 22.3 25.6 23.0 27.5 Total value of living 17.K 20.7 19.4 21.9 SavinRS 22.4 14.6 35.6 28.2 Food 25.8 30.6 25.8 30.2 Clothing 23.1 35.5 lfi.9 27.0 Housinc 2.1 ' 1.7 5.S 2.4 Operating 19.0 • 23.7 13.9 24.8 Health 2.0 29.5 J 7.5 8.9 Development 27.4 37^7 I 24.1 29.2 1 An increase. Although they showed a smaller percentage of decrease than the other items, savings were less in 1932 and a further decline occurred in 1933. This change was the result of allowing insurance premiums to go unpaid and policies to lapse, as has been indicated earlier. Borrowing on a policy was necessary in at least one family, in order to pay for a tonsil operation advised for one of the children. A comparison of the differences between the large and small groups of families is seen in Table 25. For the smaller group, development, clothing, food, and operating decreases were all greater both years than for the larger group. The decrease in savings was smaller in the 25 families than in the entire group. These contrasts may be due to the fact that the 25 families represented a group more highly selected on the basis of financial interest and conscious desire to use their money income and farm products to attain their goals. The differences may lie explained, also, by the fact that the larger group of families cooperating varied from year to year. Sharp differences in percentage decreases between the two groups arc also due to individual cases. For example, a high expenditure of one family for health in 1932 resulted in a marked increase in the 1932 average. A greatly lowered contribution to church and charity was made by one of </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agr. Exp. &gt;ta. Research Bulletin 78 the three-year families in 1932. T e effect is seen in the 1932 average. In 1933 very nearly one-half of the larger group were the three-year families; in 1932 they constituted approximately one-third of the group. Other effects of lean years upjn families. — The effects of lean years upon these farm families are shoyn only in part by a comparison of the items which make up the value o: living. Other adjustments were made which cannot be seen in graphs aid tables, yet they did affect the happi - ness and well-being of families. Moving was one type of adjustment which was made by several families. Some moved to less desirable farms and dwellings, hoping that they could manage to make both :nds meet and thus avoid an increasing amount of indebtedness. One owner lost his farm as a result of fore closure. Others succeeded in delaying the day when they would again become tenants, but there was no assurance that it could be postponed for long. One young man and his wife gave up a rented farm and went to live with relatives after deciding t lat they could not continue to be inde - pendent. Three families in the younger age group had moved from town to farm and into a new vocation at an earlier period in an effort to get started. One operator filed a petition for bankruptcy in the courts in order to get a fresh start. Several families had reached n iddle age and had accumulated posses - sions designed to provide the comforts of life during old age. With the very great decline in the value of farm land and the earlier losses of capital, accompanied by a lowerec and uncertain cash income, not only was their security for the future erldangered, but their present standard of living was beyond their means. They had known and enjoyed better times; now their earlier habits hal become a cause of worry and strain. Some families needed loans but s:curing them was humiliating to their family pride and regarded as out of harmony with their financial standing in the community. The fear of further and unpredictable loss was ever present for some. Others in the group had recently started in the joint enterprise of farming and homemaking. For them the first years had been difficult because of the economic strain, and desirable goals seemed further and further removed. If illness occurred, the strain was double. Restlessness had resulted for some. Others found spending a wiser choice than saving, because they had seen money values wiped out. For some the recent years have meant only more struggling. A large family, frequently moving from farm to farm, an inability tD accumulate, or other limiting factors had made all years of responsibility difficult. For them the depression brought a difference only in degree. Changing attitudes were apparent among many of the adults. Dis - couragement was greater and mo e frequently observed in 1932 than in 1931. For example, of the 58 families who cooperated in the first year of the study, only 40 continued durirg the second year and the reason which </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Farm Families and Their Standards of Living most of them gave was that since they had so little money to use there was no point in recording expenditures. Further, attention given to selling and buying only made them more conscious of present inequalities and of future problems. There were those who had reached the stage of re - garding all individual attempts at economic soundness as futile. To many, a policy of saving even a small part of the cash income was out of the question, for at best there was not enough to take care of present essentials. In some of the families a critical attitude regarding public expenditure: had developed. This was expressed by indifference and unwillingness to cooperate in community activities in some instances, but also by bitterness and cynicism in others. The disparity between farmers' obligations, par - ticularly taxes, and the prices of farm products was a matter of frequent concern. This attitude was brought out in connection with the request Table 26. — Average quantity and money value of food furnished by the farm for twenty-five families. "«™ 1931 »" 1933 Ami. 1 Value Ann. | Value " Ami. 1 Value &amp;£;#*?•■? l77 sun m SI907 i«o sices Milk {qls.t 831 38.61 910 27.64 966 -&gt;5 05 Cream («lt.) 110 23.62 123 18.99 118 1814 !'.""",!,""• ' I03 27Ofi 108 20M Ins ii'v Meat (//,/.) Sfi.79 705 35.10 834 39 35 Poultry &lt;«.,.) ... 26.95 155 16.01 ' 212 17 46 Fruits, vegetable! ... 40.79 ... 14 29 Vi'lO Corn, wheat ... 4.23 ... 2.77 ... 672 Miscellaneous ... .... , .. om nm Total value of furnished f"d 242.22 ... 175.29 ... 17663 Inventory adjustment ... .... ... 1.35 20 Total value of food used.. 242.22 .. I7fi/i4 179 83 for accurate records of farm products used at home. To many, the attach ment of a money value described but inadequately the value of the con - tribution made by the farm to the living of the family. Uncontrolled spending and the high cost of local, state, and federal government occa - sioned widespread concern. Whether or not this attitude continued after cash payments to farmers were begun by the government is a point of interest but one which cannot be answered, for the study closed before any payments were made. There were also those in the group who were still hopeful that better times would come. Courage and perseverance marked their approach to the problems of each day. Some found comfort in recognizing that they were not alone in looking for solutions, while others summoned all of their intelligence to meet the crisis. Many women commented on the difficulty they had in deciding what things were, after all, of primary importance and what they could afford to let go. Several expressed the opinion that record-keeping was a help in making the income purchase the essentials, and they continued with accounts in order to be more watchful of small and large leaks. An understanding and an appreciation </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 78 o£ the problems which farm operators were meeting grew out of the ex - perience of those women who helped keep the records of the farm business. Undoubtedly this did much to pro note harmony in financial matters. The effect, upon homemakers especially, of having little or no money for making needed repairs on the house or for buying equipment was not always the same. There were tho:e who accepted inadequate housing as a temporary measure to be remed ed after the farm would be clear and prices had risen. Others were urdoubtedly somewhat less interested in keeping their homes attractive because everything had been allowed to run down and there was little pro: pect of a new purchase or an improve - ment. For them keeping house w.is only a part of their job and brought less satisfaction than did the roul ine in more prosperous years. There were some who found in community activities an opportunity for self-ex - pression that had been lessened in their recent experience in homemaking. An attitude of increasing uncertainty regarding what the future held for agriculture interrupted conscicus planning toward desired goals by these farm families. Unfavorable weather conditions complicated the struggle for existence. To those ir the earlier stages of life, the first years following marriage did not bring the opportunity to accumulate a reserve but necessitated the use of reserves accumulated before marriage by both husband and wife. The possibility of home and farm ownership became less rather than greater. Families tiat had reached a later stage were likely to accept a lowering standard in 01 der to provide the essentials for a larger number of members. Paid service ind the help which commercial agencies had given in more prosperous yeais were used sparingly, if at all, by farm operator and homemaker. Hired lands were the exception instead of the rule and only eight of the 100 fanilies had a hired man all of the year. Only two families had a paid helper in the home. Bread and butter were again made in the home. For the older family the period was one of frugal living if they were able to avoid loss. Unfortunately information was not available regarding the : mount of financial assistance that was received from self-supporting sons ind daughters among the older families. A leveling of income and a recognition of common problems appeared to reduce to a minimum any tende icy toward class distinction or a division between more and less successful families. The futility of depending upon individual effort and the need for group endeavor were apparent. Interest in farm accounts grew and with ii an appreciation of the value of pooling the knowledge gained with refcre ice to farm management. Recent studies of the depression and fanners' standards of living. — Similar studies in other states havi: been conducted, but unfortunately few are available for comparison as thi: ; report goes to press. In Illinois a study of 429 farm records kept during 1931, 1932, and 1933 includes the follow - ing findings: "The average realized income of th: 111 families in 1930 was $2,190, of which $635 was the money value of commix ities and services furnished by the farm. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">i ■'■'.■.. ■• ' ' ■ ■■■'■.. Farm Families and Their Standards of Living 39 "The 159 families in 1931 had an average realized income of $1,791, of which S645 was the money value of the home-produced food, fuel, and rental value of the farm dwelling. "The 159 families in 1932 had an average realized income of $1,308, of which $560 was the money value of the commodities and services furnished by the farm. "There was a tendency over the three-year period to use savings to offset a declin - ing income and to supplement income by obtaining work away from the farm." "On the basis of purchasing power of the dollar, the percentage of retrenchment in expenditures from 1930 to 1932, on the average, for all families studied was great - est in recreation, next in gifts, then in automobile, savings, education, repairs and furnishings, church, operating, personal items, health, and the least in clothing. Food consumption increased, the increase consisting entirely of home-produced food."! 8 The situation in three counties of Wisconsin in 1933 as compared with 1929 is the subject of a bulletin which deals primarily with the methods farm families used to meet the problems of lowered and uncertain income from the farm business. In addition to the comparison of money values, attention is called to the social implications of decreased purchasing power. "The study indicates that all the families have had to retrench in their home and community standards of living. Unfortunately, die data presented do not portray the full significance of this retrenchment. Yet they do suggest that there is a minimum standard of living for agriculture — a standard below which families cannot go without involving the typical rural community in too great risks for public welfare. This I minimum must take into account production resources, furnished living, purchased goods and services, social facilities and activities, and organized institutions and agencies. In addition to the material necessities, any satisfactory living must have a non-material emphasis dealing with family and larger group relations.! Even minimum standards of living must be filled with definite objectives or ideals to strive for, ability to man - age resources and spend incomes, inclination toward common interests, and participa - tion in neighborhood and community affairs, for an economic and social life that is .stable and satisfying. Lacking these material and non-material attributes in their stand - ards of living, farm families readily become marginal witli respect to economic and social welfare." I!l / • :'■ ■'. •.':'•.: ' ' . ': : ■■■■ : " :■ V' .I - ' '-■■;.. : . ■ ■■/ ' ■ . . ■ ■ . /.-■■■"•, . . . ' ' . ■ ■■.'.'.■■ i 18 Ruth Crawford Freeman, Living Expenditures of a Group of Illinois Farm Families. 1930. 1931. 1932, 111. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 406, pp. 404 anil -106, Sept., 1934. '• E. L. Rirkpatrick, Rosalind Tough, and May L. Cowlcs. How Farm Families Meet the Emergency. Wis. Agr. Exp. Sla. Res. ltul. 12fi, p. 34, Jan.. 1935. [3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>