<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FORTY-NINTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1936-02-01">1936-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1935-1936 VOLUME 5 i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY 16852B ASTOR, LENOX AND TILDEN FOUNDATIONS R 1939 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS i ■ — VOLUME 5 1. Agricultural Experiment Station, Annual Reports, 1935, 1936. a. Bulletins, Nos. 290-301. b. Research Bulletins, Nob. 73-83. c. Circulars, Nob. 50-53. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FORTY-NINTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA H Presented to the Governor February 1, 1936 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, R. L. Cochran, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska, approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith to submit the 'Forty-ninth Annual Report of the Agri - cultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. W. W. Burr, February 1, 1936. Director. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State oh Nebraska, Executive Department Mr. W. W. Burr, Director Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station: Sir: I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Forty-ninth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. R. L. Cochran, Lincoln, February 1, 1936. Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Earl Cline, Lincoln, President Term expires January, 1937 Arthur C. Stokes, Omaha Term expires January, 1937 Stanley D. Long, Grand Island Term expires January, 1939 Frank J. Taylor, St. Paul Term expires January, 1939 Marion A. Shaw, David City Term expires January, 1941 Charles Y. Thompson, West Point Term expires January, 1941 E. A. Burnett, D.Sc, Chancellor L. E. Gunderson, 1 Finance Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS W. W. Burr, B.Sc, Director . W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service R. T. Prescott, A.M., Agricultural Editor THE TECHNICAL STAFF C. W. Ackerson, Ph.D., Assistant m Agricultural Chemistry M. Afanasiev, M.F., Assistant m Plant Pathology M. A. Alexander, M.Sc, Assistant m Animal Husbandry S. W. Alford, D.V.S., Superintendent of the Serum Plant Arthur Anderson,* Ph.D., Assistant m Agronomy A. E. Baragar, M.Sc, Assistant m Home Economics Marvel L. Baker, M.Sc, Assistant m Animal Husbandry, North Platte M. J. Blish, Ph.D., Agricultural Chemistry {Chairman) E. E. Brackett, B.Sc. m E.E., Agricultural Engineering (Chairman) E. M. Brouse, B.Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine L. K. Crowe, M.Sc, Assistant m Dairy Husbandry H. P. Davis, M.Sc, Dairy Husbandry (Chairman) P. A. Downs, Ph.D., Associate m Dairy Husbandry Margaret Fedde, A.M., Home Economics (Chairman) H. C. Filley, Ph.D., Rural Economics (Chairman) A. L. Frolik, M.Sc, Assistant m Agronomy L. F. Garey, Ph.D., Associate m Rural Economics Samuel Garver, 2 B.Sc, Research Associate m Agronomy . R. W. Goss, Ph.D., Associate m Plant Pathology H. J. Gramlich, B.Sc, Animal Husbandry (Chairman) Lionel Harris, 4 M.Sc, Acting Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell I. L. Hathaway, M.Sc, Assistant m Dairy Husbandry Eleanor Hinman, A.8., Assistant m Rural Economics F. D. Keim, Ph.D., Agronomy (Chairman) T. A. Kiesselbach, Ph.D., Agronomy E. B. Lewis, B.Sc. m A.E., Assistant m Agricultural Engineering W. J. Loeffel, M.Sc, Associate m Animal Husbandry W. E. Lyness, M.Sc. m Agr., Assistant m Agronomy H. A. McComb, B.Sc, Assistant m Horticulture, North Platte C B. McGrath, B.Sc, D.V.M., Assistant m Animal Pathology and Hygiene R. A. Mapes, Manager Union Fruit Farm, Union A. W. Medlar, A.M., Associate m Rural Economics R. F. Morgan, M.Sc, Assistant m Dairy Husbandry F. E. Mussehl, B.Sc, Poultry Husbandry (Chairman) J. F. Olney, D.V.M., M.S., Assistant m Animal Pathology and Hygiene IBy an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska, approved and m effect February IS, 1899, the State Treasurer became ex officio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1, 1899. lOn leave. 1 Detailed from Division of Forage Crops and Diseases, U. S. Department of Agriculture. ♦Detailed from Division of Western Irrigation Agriculture, U. S. Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">G. L. Peltier, Ph.D., Plant Pathology (Chairman) E. L. Reichart, M.Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry Raymond Roberts, M.Sc, Assistant in Entomology J. C. Russel, 5 M.Sc, Associate in Agronomy R. M. Sandstedt, M.Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry George Schmid, B.Sc, Manager Box Butte Experimental Farm, Alliance Edna B. Snyder, M.Sc, Assistant in Home Economics L. B. Snyder, M.Sc, Assistant in Rural Economics Leland Stott, Ph.D., Assistant in Home Economics C. A. Suneson,* M.Sc., Research Assistant in Agronomy M. H. Swenk, A.M., Entomology (Chairman) R. R. Thalman, M.Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry H. M. Tysdal,' Ph.D., Research Associate in Agronomy L. Van Es, M.D., V.S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene (Chairman) H. E. Weakly," M.Sc, Assistant Agronomist, North Platte R. M. Weihing, Ph.D., Assistant in Agronomy M. D. Weldon, M.Sc, Assistant in Agronomy H. O. Werner, Ph.D., Associate in Horticulture D. B. Whelan, M.Sc, Assistant in Entomology C. C. Wiggans, Ph.D., Horticulture (Chairman) W. W. Yocum, A.M., Assistant in Horticulture C. L. Zink, B.Sc, Tractor Testing Engineer L. L. Zook,* B.Sc, Agronomist and Supt., Experimental Substation, North Platte CHANGES IN STAFF Harold Hedges, assistant in rural economics, granted leave of absence January 25, 1934, resigned effective July 1, 1935. Eleanor H. Hinman, assistant in rural economics, resigned effective August 1, 1935. R. M. Weihing, assistant in agronomy, resigned effective July 1, 1935. C. A. Suneson, detailed from Division of. Cereal Crops and Diseases, U. S. D. A., transferred to Davis, California, February 1, 1936. Samuel Garver, detailed from Division of Forage Crops and Diseases, assumed duties here April 5, 1935. Leland Stott, assistant in home economics, appointed September 1, 1935. M. Afanasiev, assistant in plant pathology, appointed June 1, 1935. L. F. Garey, associate in rural economics, appointed September 1, 1935 (on leave from University of Minne - sota). R. T. Prescott, agricultural editor, appointed July 1, 1935. . '••■■ ■■■'.' '■•'■'• ■■■'■' "..'.' ■ ■'-.,•■■ ■';■;• CONTENTS Introduction 5 Rural Economics 30 Agricultural Engineering 5 State Serum Plant 32 Animal Diseases 6 North Platte Substation 33 Chemistry 7 Scottsbluff Substation 36 Dairy Husbandry 9 Valentine Substation 37 Field Crops and Soils 11 Box Butte Experimental Farm 38 Fruits and Vegetables 17 Land, Buildings, and Equipment 38 Home Economics 18 Publications 39 Insects, Rodents, and Birds 21 Financial Statement (Federal) 40 Livestock Feeding 23 Financial Statement (Exclusive of Plant Diseases 28 Federal Funds) . . 42 Poultry 29 * On leave. * Detailed from Division of Cereal Crops and Diseases, U. S. Department of Agriculture. 7 Detailed from Division of Forage Crops and Diseases, U. S. Department of Agriculture. * Detailed from Division of Dry Land Agriculture, U. S. Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Forty-ninth Annual Report In this report the work of the Experiment Station is briefly summarized on the basis of the calendar year 1935. The financial statement at the end of the report covers the fiscal year ending June 30, 1935, thus conforming with the fiscal year of the state and federal governments. The progress of the Experiment Station program is shown in brief statements on the various projects: Where a project has been completed, or has progressed to the point of the data in the publication are briefly summarized; thus the annual report becomes a convenient guide to publications of the Experiment Station, as well as a progress report. In carrying forward the Experiment Station program the problem to be solved, rather than the departmental field, is considered. Several depart - ments may cooperate on a given project. The work reported under a par - ticular sectional heading may be, but is not necessarily, the work of a single department. Cooperation within the institution is not shown in this report. Cooperation between the Experiment Station and several bureaus and offices of the United States Department of Agriculture is mentioned. Satisfactory progress was made on many lines of work during the past year. Over a considerable part of the state, including the Experiment Station fields and plots at Lincoln, crop yields were seriously reduced by continued drouth. Therefore, those projects depending on climatic condi - tions suffered accordingly. On the program as a whole there was some continued slowing down because of emergency programs. A few members of the Experiment Station staff were loaned for temporary periods to dif - ferent government agencies. During the year the Experiment Station cooperated with other states of the Corn Belt and with the federal government in procuring data on land use. There is a marked increase in the tendency to consider problems from a regional basis which will involve more cooperation among the states and with the Department of Agriculture. AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING Tractor testing. — Tractors are tested in accordance with the Nebraska tractor testing law. The results of these tests are published and requests for this information have come from all parts of the United States and many foreign countries. The fees paid by the manufacturers ($500 for each tractor tested) pay a considerable part of the cost of testing. Bulletin 296, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1920-1935, January, 1936, 32 pages and large summary sheet, summarizes the tests on machines that are now on the market. Seventeen tractors were tested during the 1935 season. Six were of the Diesel type; three were tested on gasoline and eight on distillate. Two were operated under complete drawbar tests to obtain comparative data on steel-wheel and rubber-tire equipment. One garden tractor was tested. Since 1920, 238 tractors have been tested, of which 80 are on the market at the present time. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Pneumatic tires on farm tractors.— Results of comprehensive tests under this project were published in September, 1934. During the past year five sizes of tires were tested on a tractor, on the testing course and also on two plowed fields. This work indicates that diameter of tire cross-section alone has little effect on tractive ability of a tire. Where traction is not limited by engine power, it appeared also true that the effective diameter of a wheel has no direct relationship to tractive ability of the tire. Electric power on Nebraska farms. — Progress was made on a sub - project dealing with the heating of water for livestock. In tests with animals it has been found that temperatures higher than 60° F. are not justified. The adaptability of electrically heated hotbeds to farm use.— Studies have been carried on through one season, with four heating devices em - ployed in starting and growing garden plants. This work is new and will be continued. The adaptation of insulated electric brooders in uninsulated poultry houses.— A special type of insulated electric brooder has shown promising results in economical brooding of chicks and turkey poults. This work will be continued. Methods of cooling milk on farms.— Studies of the cooling of bottled milk by spray and cold diffusion and of milk in cans by hydro-vacuum and spray equipment, along with studies of cream line, bacteria count, and flavor, near completion. The data will be prepared for publication soon. Bindweed-eradication machinery and other farm equipment.— Several types of equipment for bindweed eradication have been constructed and used in tests during 1934. Fallowing that was begun in 1934 will be continued during at least a part of the 1936 growing season. One new device was built during the past year, a straight blade mounted on a tractor in such a way that it could be run at various depths and could be made to run close to fences and into corners. A tight-bottom buncher was designed to make it possible to cut very short grass and to hold all of it until a quantity large enough. for con - venient handling has been accumulated. This equipment can be attached to the sickle-bar of a mower. Blueprints are available. Frequent inquiries regarding the "automobile hay sweep" made it desirable to design, build, and try out one in a field. The conversion of old automobiles to this purpose has been done in the Platte valley for years, and the one built is used to study design and to supply first-hand information. ANIMAL DISEASES The influence of environment on poultry diseases. — This project has received considerable attention in the past few years, and certain phases will be continued during another year. The purpose is to measure the influence of various sorts of equipment and other environmental factors in poultry yards and houses on the spread of disease, and to obtain infor- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Forty-ninth Annual Report mation on modes of dissemination and on methods of control. Bulletin 290, Diseases of Poultry — Their Nature and Control, published in 1934, contains some of the results of the work, and another preliminary report was made by L. Van Es and J. F. Olney in the Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 86 (N. S. 39):390-406, March, 1935. The latter report covers bacillary white diarrhea, blackhead, tuberculosis, fowl cholera, coccidiosis, and fowl typhus. Work on bacillary white diarrhea, fowl typhus, and fowl cholera was completed in previous years and work on coccidiosis was completed during the past year. For the latter certain types of equipment are effective and some further improvement in design of chick feeders, which were espec - ially helpful, will be ' attempted. Sanitary equipment for the control of blackhead of turkeys will be put to another severe test in 1936. It seems advisable to repeat this work with the exposure of the poults to direct and indirect contact with common fowls. Other results of this investigation have caused fowls to be regarded as primary carriers of the causative factor of blackhead. Ground that had remained idle 35 months after serving as a yard for fowls was found to be hazardous as a place for poults. Obser - vations on tuberculosis will also be continued another season. A survey of erysipelas among Nebraska swine. — Since this work was begun 281 outbreaks of acute swine diseases have been investigated. In 69 cases, or 24.2 per cent, of the outbreaks erysipelas was identified as the cause. Results from this study will be prepared for publication soon. Immunity studies on hemorrhagic septicemia. — Work on the last phases of this project were concluded two or three years ago. Pressure of other work has delayed the analysis and publication of the results. Diagnosis of material submitted by farmers and veterinarians. — During the year 1935, 8,373 specimens were examined and information about them was supplied to those interested. CHEMISTRY Preparation and study of the cereal glutelins. — Considerable work has been done involving the use of sodium salicylate as a dispersing agent for the cereal proteins. This offers a decided advantage in that sodium sal - icylate is a neutral solvent, in which the entire gluten of wheat can be dispersed without the danger of irreversible alteration in properties that is always involved when the proteins are in an acid or alkaline environment. Such a dispersion can be made the starting point for fractional precipita - tion studies. Fractional precipitation can be accomplished by several dif - ferent methods, including the addition of progressively increasing quan - tities respectively of salt, water, and acetone. Some "fractional solubility" studies of the flour proteins have been made. Complete dispersion of all protein requires a sodium salicylate con - centration of about 10 per cent. Only partial dispersion occurs at lower concentrations. Concentrations varying from 1 to 10 per cent were used. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station In all fractionation experiments the chemical compositions (products of hydrolysis) as well as the amounts of protein of the various fractions re - spectively were studied. The results continue to support the view that protein of wheat gluten is composed of many "dissociable components", varying slightly and systematically in composition and properties, in oppo - sition to the former belief that gluten is an intimate mixture of two dis - tinct individual proteins, glutenin and gliadin. The number of these com - ponents remains to be determined. Some of the work is being organized tor early publication. Enzymes of wheat flour as related to flour grade and baking character - 1At!rCST^, S , tudy ° £ Catalase activit y of commercial flours was published (M. J. Blish and C. E. Bode. "Catalase Activity in Wheat Flour," Cereal Chem. 12:133-42, March, 1935). Catalase activity appears to be a single and not a multiple factor. It is closely correlated with flour grade (degree or. refinement) for any given lot of wheat. Systematic regional variations in catalase-activity range were observed. A report was published in 1934 showing that diastatic activity in a flour - m-water suspension closely parallels that in a dough from the same flour - therefore determinations with water suspensions are highly informative as well as being far more convenient than determinations with the dough itself. B The starches of cereal grains were found to be more susceptible to attack by diastatic enzymes than are other starches (potato and arrow - root). Efforts to establish the fundamental nature and cause of wide varia - tions in the diastatic properties of different flours have thus far failed to disclose the underlying factors involved. Differences in starch susceptibility are doubtless involved, but a study of these differences is made extremely difficult and complicated by the fact that starches probably undergo irre - versible changes during various treatments that may be used for isolating thern and preparing them for study. Another complicating feature is that the diastatically active factor in flour is relatively insoluble in water No method of isolating it in an unchanged form, for detailed study, has been made available. A number of publications related to this project have been made: "A Collaborative Study of the Manometric Determination of Gassing Power" by R M. Sandstedt, Cereal Chem. 12:517-19, Sept., 1935; "Factors Affect - !!l g w « alueS in the Ferr 'cyanide Method for Diastatic Activity", by H W. Putham, M. J. Blish, and R. M. Sandstedt, Cereal Chem. 12:494 - 504, Sept., 1935; "Definition and Measurement of 'Flour Strength' as an Inherent Property of Wheat", by M. J. Blish and R. M. Sandstedt, Cereal Si" 1 ™- i I 653 " 64 ' N ° V " 1935; " Rc P°^ on Diastatic Value of Flour", by M. J. Blish, Jour. Assoc. Offic. Agr. Chem. 18:566-69, Nov., 1935; "Baking lest as a Method of Measuring Quality in Winter Wheat", by M. J. Blish, Northwestern Miller 184 (No. 2, Sec. 2):10-ll; "Baking Strength of Hour , by M. J. Blish, Southwestern Miller 14:21-41. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Forty-ninth Annual Report The nature of herbicidal toxicity. — A study of the rate of decomposition of sodium chlorate in the soil, with varying conditions of temperature, organic content, etc., is well under way. Sodium chlorate is highly resistant to decomposition in the soil, as has been shown by others. Spraying bind - weeds with gasoline carrying other substances in solution gave promising results in preliminary greenhouse trials but was unsatisfactory under field conditions. Preliminary field trials with an acid-arsenic spray treatment developed by A. S. Crafts of California gave promising results and will be continued. • Comparative efficiency of various proteins in poultry feeding. — The work on the comparisons of animal and vegetable proteins when fed as the source of the concentrate in baby chick rations was completed. The results showed that the lot whose ration contained the animal concentrate (1) made a greater gain per weight of feed or nitrogen fed, (2) retained more of the nitrogen fed, and (3) retained less of the calcium and phos - phorus fed than the lot receiving the vegetable protein concentrate. The hand method of feeding resulted in a low coefficient of variability in the final weights of the chicks in each lot, largely because all were fed identical weights of feed. It seems that by this method trustworthy results may be secured with comparatively few birds in the lot. A comparison of meat scraps as the source of the protein concentrate with a combination of equal parts of meat scraps, fish meal, and dried buttermilk as the concentrate in a growing-chick mash is in progress. The rations are pressed into pellets and hand-fed in equal amounts daily to each chick — a procedure that is essentially a comparative slaughter test. The lot fedythe concentrate made from the three animal proteins made a slightly greatfcifvgain in weight per unit of feed or nitrogen fed than did the other lot. Research Bulletin 80, The Utilization of Nitrogen, Calcium, and Phos - phorus by the Growing Chicly, by C. W. Ackerson, M. J. Blish, and F. E. Mussehl, September, 1935, 16 pages, reports a study of the net retention of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus, determined by comparing the gain of these elements with accurately known amounts ingested. Data on the composition of 127 newly hatched chicks and 30 chicks fed the experi - mental ration are presented. DAIRY HUSBANDRY Study of vitamins. — Studies are being made of the effect of methods of preserving silage upon its vitamin A content. Corn silage made in the usual manner is being compared with corn silage to which cane molasses has been added before fermentation has taken place, and also with corn silage preserved by the addition of mineral acids. These silages are being fed to rats and also to cows. Later the milk from these cows will be fed to rats to determine the effect of the molasses and mineral acids upon the vitamin A content of the milk. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Preliminary studies have been made of the vitamin content of cheese, and further studies will bejnade with various types of cheese. Since the last Annual .Report, Research Bulletin 79 was published. Research Bulletin 79, The Vitamin A Content of Sour Cream Butter, Sweet Cream Butter, and Margarines, by I. L. Hathaway and H. P. Davis, August, 1935, 8 pages. In this study 19 samples of margarine were ob - tained from Illinois, Ohio, and Nebraska. They were analyzed chemically and the vitamin A content of each one was compared with that of either sour-cream or sweet-cream butter. The fat content of the butter samples varied from 80.2 to 81.5 per cent, while the fat content of the margarine samples varied from 78.3 to 89.2 per cent. From the results it was evident that these samples of margarine were very poor sources of vitamin A when compared with butter. One of the margarine samples caused an average gain of 10 grams per rat and another caused an average gain of 25 grams per rat when fed at the rate of one cc. daily for eight weeks. In every other case the rats fed margarine showed a final loss in weight and most of them did not survive the experiment. Butter was fed at a daily rate equal to one-tenth or one-twentieth of the quantity of margarine fed in all cases but one, and the rats survived and gained, the smallest gain averaging 45 grams and the largest 111 grams during the eight- weeks period. Growth studies of dairy cattle. — Data are being obtained regarding the rate of growth as determined by various anatomical measurements for four breeds of dairy cattle. Preliminary studies indicate that the rate of growth is a very smooth curve, and the maximum skeletal development is reached at approximately sixty months of age. Reproduction in dairy cattle. — Studies have been made of bulls and cows of various ages to determine if age is an important factor in regularity of breeding. Data for more than eighty bulls and several hundred cows are being prepared for publication. Studies have also been made of the influence of pregnancy upon the gain in weight of lactating dairy cows. A research bulletin on the latter subject will be published during the coming year. Ripening of cheddar cheese in cans. — Studies are being made of the factors affecting the success of the process of ripening cheddar cheese in cans. Cheddar cheese is placed in cans after coming from the press and the entire ripening process is carried on under controlled conditions. The use of a patented can allows escape of gas and moisture, but does not permit the cheese to have access to the air. Fermentation in milk, with particular reference to curd character. — This study is designed to obtain information regarding the effect upon curd character of the following factors: individual cow, breed of cow, age of cow, inherited characteristics, season of the year, stage of lactation, udder diseases, chloride content of milk, titratable acidity, and relation of chloride to other ingredients of the milk. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Forty-ninth Annual Report Studies of the operation of the Babcock test. — This study is an effort to determine the influence of various factors which may affect the accuracy of the test as applied to various dairy products. The effectiveness of different methods of cooling milk for farm use. — Studies have been made of various methods of applying air and water currents to milk in order to determine their applicability and effectiveness for farm use. Milk quality as affected by the individual cow in a herd. — In this study the effect of abnormal conditions in the mammary glands is studied to determine their effect upon composition and quality of the milk produced. FIELD CROPS AND SOILS Corn improvement. — The development and testing of superior corn hybrids has continued to be the outstanding phase of the corn-improve - ment investigations. Improvement has been effected and the best hybrids now available merit further testing and use in eastern Nebraska and on the irrigated lands of the central part of the state.. In cooperation with the Agricultural Extension Service, 27 hybrids and seven standard varieties were compared on farms in five different counties in eastern Nebraska. The results are reported by P. H. Stewart, D. L. Gross, and T. A. Kiesselbach in mimeographed Agronomy Circular 34. 9 As an average for the five tests, the five best hybrids yielded 9.2 bushels or 21 per cent more than the five best varieties. All hybrids averaged 14 per cent higher than all varieties. The three Nebraska commercial double crosses, Nos. 238, 252, and 362, averaged 20 per cent higher yield than Krug, a widely grown standard variety. As a three-year average these have surpassed Krug with the following yields: Krug, 47.6 bushels per acre; Nebr. 238, 52.7; Nebr. 252, 55.7, and Nebr. 362, 54.2. In addition they have excelled in lodge resistance. An extreme difference of 9 bushels per acre was noted between var - ieties in these 1935 tests. During four years throughout eastern Nebraska, Cattle corn has averaged 16 per cent less in yield than the next lowest variety. As reported by T. A. Kiesselbach and R. M. Weihing in the Journal of the American Society of Agronomy, 27:538-41, July, 1935, the root systems of Fi single-cross hybrids have been found to be decidedly larger than those of the selfed-line parents, while intermediate development occurs in the F-j. Thus the root systems exhibit hybrid vigor similar to that of the aerial parts. The striking differences in root development of corn in relation to its regional adaptation and vegetative size have been summarized by R. M. Weihing in the Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. 27:526-37, July, 1935. The root systems were found to differ in size in somewhat the same degree as did the above-ground parts. • Obtainable by writing to the Department of Agronomy, College of Agriculture, Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Small-grain improvement — This project has to do with the breeding and testing of wheat, oats, and barley. The wheat-improvement work is cooperative with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. An unusually late harvest, together with exceptionally humid weather and widespread lodging, served to bring Nebraska its worst wheat stem rust epidemic since 1916. Even such partially resistant varieties as Turkey (winter) and Ceres (spring) were seriously affected. Varieties such as Nebraska 60 and Cheyenne have been known to be rust-susceptible and became heavily infested. Two varieties grown in limited areas in the state excelled this year, because of moderate rust resistance and early maturity. One of these, Blackhull, should not be grown because of lack of winter - hardiness. The other, Nebraska 1069, is a Station development regarded as the best available early wheat, but not otherwise fully proved. The rust resistance of Thatcher (spring) as established in various tests in the state demonstrated the feasibility of breeding for rust resistance. A total of 370 near-immune strains were isolated in the winter-wheat nurseries this year. A considerable number of resistant strains were noted in materials being tested. Definite plant-breeding advances giving earlier maturity, greater hardiness, and resistance to lodging, rust, smut, and Hessian fly are evident in Station nursery stocks of winter wheat. Technical wheat investigations included studies of floret sterility in - duced by chilling, and the effect of seed source upon the hardiness of seedlings. Sterile florets appearing after chilling were shown to be normal except for the male flower structures, since foreign pollen produced hybrid seeds. The relationship of winterhardiness of seedlings to seed quality has not been fully established; but good seed has never been at a disadvantage, while shrunken, weathered, or broken seeds often produce plants which are at a great disadvantage. The Experiment Station was host to a winter-wheat improvement con - ference attended by 33 workers from nine states other than Nebraska. The mimeographed Report of the Third Hard Red Winter Wheat Im - provement Conference, Lincoln, Nebraska, April 11-12, 1935, was pre - pared by C. A. Suneson. While 26 varieties of oats tested in field plats averaged about 40 bushels of grain per acre in 1935, the extreme range was from 18.6 for Markton to 51.1 for Brunker. Among the better varieties were the standard Iogold and Nebraska 21, with yields of 8 bushels per acre above Kherson. The late-ripening varieties were at a distinct disadvantage and yielded only about 50 per cent as much as standard early sorts. Of the 19 varieties of barley under test, Spartan and Wisconsin 38 were the highest in yield with 28.8 and 28.7 bushels per acre, respectively. Both are smooth-awned. Spartan has recently been introduced into the state from Michigan as a certified crop. It is especially early-ripening and lodge - resistant. Alfalfa improvement. — Two chief phases have been continued, the testing of various alfalfas and the improvement of existing varieties. The </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Forty-ninth Annual Report work is in cooperation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. It has been well established by experimental tests that southern-grown seed is undesirable for Nebraska conditions, but among the standard northern strains and varieties no clear-cut differences have been obtained. A detailed test involving four standard varieties — Grimm, Northwestern Common, Ladak, and Hardistan — indicates that there is considerable difference be - tween them, depending on conditions under which they are to be grown. On Nebraska uplands there is not much choice between the four varieties. If bacterial wilt is prevalent, however, as in subirrigated valleys, Hardistan is the most satisfactory variety; while if the crop is to be grown in the drier sections where one or two cuttings constitute the total crop, Ladak will produce decidedly more hay. Tests in the central Platte Valley where bacterial wilt is severe have substantiated these conclusions. As a result of six years' work on the selection of alfalfa for wilt and cold resistance, a number of strains have been isolated which are sufficiently resistant for this region. It now remains to test these for commercial pro - duction and possibly to recombine them to take advantage of hybrid vigor. During the past year several methods of natural and artificial crossing were attempted, including the use of honey bees, bumble bees, and leaf-cutter bees (Megachile sp.) in cages. The greenhouses have proved indispensable in this program and, during the past summer, seed was produced in a large commercial greenhouse in addition to those at the Experiment Sta - tion. In 'addition a plan has been worked out whereby seedlings can be started in southern California during the winter and transplanted to Ne - braska in the spring for seed production under isolated conditions, as for example in irrigated cornfields in western Nebraska. A number of such plantings have been made this winter at the U. S. Western Irrigation Sub - station, Bard, California. The following publications appeared during the year: "An Analysis of Soil and Seasonal Effects in Alfalfa Variety Tests", by H. M. Tysdal, Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. 27:384-91, May. 1935; and "Alfalfa Wilt Control by Breeding Making Remarkable Progress", by H. M. Tysdal, U. S. D. A. Yearbook for 1935, pp. 119-20. Sweet-clover improvement. — Sweet-clover improvement was inaug - urated in 1935 in cooperation with the Division of Forage Crops and Dis - eases, U. S. Department of Agriculture. The investigations include: (1) improvement of sweet clover through selection and breeding; (2) studies to determine the best methods of planting small seed lots in limited field areas to secure accurate comparative data; (3) tests of varieties for com - parative hay, pasture, and seed yields; (4) effects of cutting treatments in first and second years on hay, pasture, and seed production; and (5) seed increase of promising varieties. Data are not yet sufficient to justify con - clusions. This crop has come to be extensively grown in this state for pasture and soil improvement. Grain and forage sorghum. — Interest is developing in grain sorghum as a grain crop in this state, especially in the South Platte territory. Corn </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station yielded only 7 bushels per acre in 1935 compared with 31.5 bushels for Early Kalo, a recently introduced variety which would normally ripen too early in eastern Nebraska, but fared especially well this year. Pink Kafir, which is regarded as the standard variety for the Experiment Station Farm at Lincoln, has averaged 43.8 bushels per acre compared with 32.5 bushels for corn during 7 years. This is 35 per cent above corn at 56 pounds per bushel for both. It has also yielded 26 per cent more silage. Under the exceptional conditions of the past year this variety failed to ripen grain. Atlas has yielded 98 per cent more silage than corn during 8 years. Reing late in maturity, Atlas cannot be depended upon to ripen grain regularly this far north. Of the varieties now available commercially for grain production, Pink Kafir excels for eastern Nebraska, Kalo for central Nebraska, and Early Kalo for western Nebraska. Among the forage varieties, Atlas and Orange rate as the best late sorts suitable for eastern Nebraska, Early Sumac for central Nebraska, and Black Amber for western Nebraska. Comparative forage yields of sorghum and corn have been published by W. E. Lyness and T. A. Kiesselbach under the title Annual Fodder and Silage Crops for Nebraska, Station Circular 52, 8 pages, March, 1935. Soybeans. — Renewed interest in soybeans for feed and industrial use has resulted in the production of several thousand acres in this state in 1935. A further increase in acreage for grain will doubtless depend upon an expansion of the industrial requirements. It is doubtful if 'soybeans should replace alfalfa, red clover, or sweet clover to any extent in this state, although they have proved satisfactory as an annual hay crop when grown in cultivated rows. As an average for the past 27 years soybeans have averaged 16.5 bushels per acre on the Experiment Station Farm, compared with 38.6 bushels of corn and 45.0 bushels of oats. The most promising varieties are Illini and Manchu. As an average for the last six years the Illini has yielded 22.1 bushels per acre, Manchu 20.2, Aksarben 19.4, and Virginia 15.4. Management of permanent pastures and native meadows. — The pasture - renovation experiments conducted cooperatively with farmers during 1933 and 1934 were discontinued in the spring of 1935 because the extreme drouth and heat of 1934 had killed much of the grass. Efforts to eradicate the more serious pasture weeds by mowing at various intervals are being continued. Indications are that buckbrush may be eradicated by annual mowing during the latter part of May over a period of several years. Blue vervain has been eradicated by annual mow - ing during the middle of June over a two-year period. Seed-germination studies are being conducted with a number of pasture weeds to determine the importance of sted in the spreading of these weeds in pastures. Studies concerning the introduction of cultivated forage species into the subirrigated prairie meadows of the Elkhorn valley and sandhills have given favorable results and will be concluded in 1936. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Forty-ninth Annual Report Weeds. — Studies indicate that bindweed can be eradicated from lawns by means of sodium chlorate without materially injuring Kentucky blue - grass. Several applications of one pound of sodium chlorate per square rod at intervals of not less than three weeks have been found to eradicate bindweed. It is highly essential that such applications be immediately followed by thorough watering. A systematic effort at bindweed eradica - tion upon the Experiment Station lands has been carried on during the last four seasons with significant results. Both chlorate application and clean tillage have proved effective. In cooperation with the Division of Forage Crops and Diseases of the U. S. Department of Agriculture, the effects of bindweeds upon corn yields and upon the subsoil moisture supply were studied throughout eastern Nebraska in 1935. As an average for the state, the infested areas of corn fields yielded only about one-third as much as the weed-free areas. Estab - lished stands of bindweeds exhaust the subsoil moisture far deeper than do annual cereal crops and compete with alfalfa for deep-seated subsoil moisture. The restoration of organic matter in Nebraska soils. — The field work and soil sampling have been completed in an investigation of the rate and nature of decomposition of various organic materials when added to soil. A study of the effects of various continuous crops on the organic matter and nitrogen content of the soil is being continued. Three hundred soil and plant samples have been taken and part of the analytical work has been done on 100 of these. A paper on "Relation of Root Distribution to Organic Matter in Prairie Soil," by J. E. Weaver, V. H. Hougen, and M. D. Weldon, was published in the Botanical Gazette, 96:389-420, March, 1935. It was shown that in virgin grassland, 60 to 68 per cent of the underground parts of the native grass were found in the surface 6 inches of soil. Below this level, an approximately linear relation was found between the amount of root material and the amount of soil organic matter in the various soil horizons. Some twelve hundred soil samples have been obtained from the old and new crop-rotation plats of the North Platte Substation. Nitrogen de - terminations have been made on 600 and organic matter on 100 of these samples. This work has been done in cooperation with the U. S. Depart - ment of Agriculture, Division of Dry Land Agriculture. Nitrification in soils. — The. sixty-one small-grain, potato, and sugar-beet plats of Field K of the Scottsbluff Field Station were sampled to the depth of five feet at the beginning of the growing season and again immediately after harvest, for the purpose of studying the influence of rotations, alfalfa, and manure on the ability of the soil to supply nitrate to the crop. Manur - ing once in a two- or three-year rotation seemed to be as effective in main - taining the nitrate supply as growing alfalfa two years in a four-year rota - tion, or three years in a six-year rotation. The soil under the potato rota- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station tions maintained a higher nitrate content than that under the sugar-beet rotations. The nitrate supply and the yield were generally much higher in the four-, six-, and seven-year rotations, all of which included alfalfa, than in the shorter rotations in which there were no legumes. Weed con - trol was much betteij on the longer rotations. The samples taken for the nitrate determinations are also being used in a study of the nitrogen, organic matter, available phosphorus, and pH under these rotations and soil treatments. Laboratory studies are being made of the nitrification rate in the first and second six-inch sections of these soils. The investigations at the Scottsbluff Field Station are in cooperation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture, Division of Western Irrigation Agriculture. Phosphorus studies on alkaline soils. — Laboratory studies have lieen continued on the availability of phosphorus in alkaline soils as determined by leaching them with a dilute alkaline buffer reagent adjusted to the pH of the soil. A number of soils from Scottsbluff county of known and varying response to applications of phosphate fertilizer were studied. The results obtained were in close agreement with phosphorus availability as indicated by growing crops. This method is also being used to study the availability of phosphorus in several experiments. A laboratory investigation is in progress to determine the effect of organic-matter decomposition upon the availability and fixation of phos - phorus by alkaline soils. Various types of organic materials such as alfalfa, sugar-beet tops, potato tops, manure, and straw are used. Upon the de - composition of the organic matter considerable phosphorus is released in the available form. The calcareous soils fix this phosphorus more rapidly than the non-calcareous soils. The samples taken on the rotation plats of Field K of the Scottsbluff Field Station were also included in the phosphorus studies. The available phosphorus and pH were determined to the depth of five feet on the 61 plats. The ability of these plats to supply phosphorus to the crop was indicated by the phosphorus content and yields of tops and roots of the plants. Very little available phosphorus was found below a depth of one foot except in the manured plats. The pH values increased with depth to a pH of 8.5 but very little available phosphorus was found when the pH was above 8.0. More available phosphorus was found on the rotation plats than on the continuous-cropping plats but the most significant increases were on the manured plats. For example in a rotation of oats and sugar beets with manure, the available phosphorus in the surface six inches of soil was more than five times as great as in a similar rotation without manure. Field work has been continued in cooperation with the U. S. Depart - ment of Agriculture, Bureau of Chemistry and Soils. Further data have been obtained on the phosphorus absorption by sugar beets on phosphate - deficient soils and their response to the application of phosphate fertilizers. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Forty-ninth Annual Report FRUITS AND VEGETABLES Orchard culture. — The orchard-culture studies are concerned .with cultural methods, soil fertility and moisture, and other problems of the orchardist. Investigations are carried on at the fruit farm at Union and also in the orchard at Lincoln. During the season of 1935 moisture was plentiful and temperatures low early in the season, but the opposite ex - tremes were encountered later. Measurements were continued and emphasis was placed on soil-moisture determinations, which show that 40 to 60 per cent of available soil water, down as far as 30 feet, has been used by the trees in 17 to 18 years, and that even greater depletion has occurred in the filler-tree area. Preliminary tests indicate that little of the variation can be traced to differences in treatment of the soil. In the vineyard, soil sampling to a depth of 15 feet in cultivated and mulched blocks indicates that mulching conserves the soil moisture. The mulch, however, may have had an adverse effect on growth and yield, as indicated by observation. Records kept have not been summarized. The root systems of apple trees. — Marked variations in root growth are now apparent after three years of growth with various types of mulch and cultivation. The greatest depth of rooting under straw so far noted has been less than 8 feet, while under cultivation it has been over 16. Data and drawings are being prepared for publication. Paper mulch, straw mulch, clean cultivation, corn planted 5 feet from the tree, and corn planted 9 feet from the tree are being compared, as well as other factors. Fruit breeding. — The 1935 season affected variety tests adversely. Strawberries failed almost completely, as did some varieties of gooseberries and currants. Little or no extension of tree-fruit plantings was made. Pruning. — Data on apple-tree pruning have been taken the past two years in accordance with earlier plans, but their significance has been made doubtful by the severe drouth. Raspberry yields were good and the control of number of canes per acre and number of laterals per cane seems to have had some significance. Orchard spraying. — This project makes available information on new spray materials as they are developed, and on new pests and other troubles. No experimental spraying was done in 1935; the disseminating of information was continued and was helpful in controlling various orchard pests. , Fruit stocks.— The season was unfavorable to fruiting and tempera - tures did not put the stocks to a severe test. This project includes a study in a top-worked orchard at Lincoln and in a scion-rooted orchard at Union. ■ Apple storage. — Continued inactivity on this project is attributable to lack of suitable fruit to use. Russeting. cracking, small size, etc., in 1935 made selection of suitable fruit impossible. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Experiments with vegetables. — With asparagus, the manure and straw mulches continued to retard the season and reduce yield but resulted in increased size of spears. The addition of salt has not controlled weeds. A cutting season ending June 1 in 1934 resulted in better yields in 1935 than a shorter or longer season. Soil-moisture studies in asparagus beds are being made but no reports can be made at present. The season of 1935 was ruinous to tomatoes. The absence of fruit setting was evidently due to heat and dry air, for it was not altered by irrigation. Studies of carrots have shown that the ratio of inner to outer portion varies with variety and season and that it can be influenced by cultural practices. The middle of February proved better as a planting date for spinach than late March. Seed value of potatoes. — A research study will be available for publica - tion shortly on three years of experimentation with storage of Triumph potatoes at the Box Butte farm. Early or fall cold storage is not as desir - able as cellar storage because of more rot but spring cold storage is desir - able because of the delay of sprout growth. Feathering causes more loss than other types of injury, with cuts and cracks following in order. Wounds healed quickly in a warm, humid atmosphere, satisfactorily in a humid cellar, less so in a dry cellar, and poorly in cold storage. Exposure of damaged potatoes to sunshine caused increased losses of weight in stor - age and interfered with the healing of wounds. Field tests show that seed value is greater when sprouts are just emerging and least when tubers have sprouted excessively. Publications during the past year were made as follows: Bulletin 294, Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska, by H. O. Werner and L. L. Zook, April, 1935, 16 pages; "Is There Any Difference in the Productivity of Dry Land and Irrigated Seed Potatoes?" by H. O. Werner, Amer. Potato Jour. 10:64-67, March, 1935; and "Seed Value of Potatoes Grown in Different Crop Rotations with Irrigation," by H. O. Werner, Amer. Potato Jour. 10:118-25, March, 1935. Nutritional conditions influencing tuberization of the potato. — The response of two strains of Triumph potatoes was studied under continual low temperatures with long and short days and when subjected to rising temperatures and increasing day lengths (Southern conditions) as com - pared with the opposite (Northern conditions), and also with high and low nitrogen supplies at different parts of the growing season. Conditions favoring vegetative development brought out strain differences more than did those favoring tuberization. In addition to Research Bulletin 75. pub - lished in 1934, a report was made by H. O. Werner in the American Potato Journal 12:274-81, October, 1935, on these studies. HOME ECONOMICS Family economics. — The major part of the results of this study are included in Research Bulletin 78, A Study of Farm Families and Theifl Standards of Living in Selected Districts of Nebraska, 1931-1933, by </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Forty-ninth Annual Report Margaret Fedde and Ruth Lindquist, July, 1935, 40 pages. This study gives us needed information about farm incomes and expenditures during three depression years. One hundred families kept accurate records in three selected counties representing different agricultural areas. Among the observations were the following: In all three years the farms supplied about two-fifths of the total living; the greatest retrenchments were made in development, which includes education, church and charity, recreation and gifts; and the next greatest were in clothing and purchased food. Other effects of these lean years upon families are also discussed. A de - tailed study of the adequacy of food consumption in these families has been made and is now ready for publication. Family life studies. — The first objective of this project will be a com - parative study of young people from farm, village, and city homes in re - gard to certain possible relationships between character and personality adjustment, and home and family influences. The project was drawn up during September, 1935, and hence work of a preliminary nature only has thus far been accomplished. Before work on the project proper could be begun it was found necessary to develop three tests in the field of attitude and character. One, a scale for measuring attitude toward work as opposed to leisure and play, has just been subjected to an experimental try-out, and an analysis of the data for purposes of validation and standardization is now in progress. An experimental form of a test of self-reliance, resource - fulness, industry, and conscientiousness is about ready for trial and stand - ardization. Another scale for measuring attitude toward home life is also in the early stages of development. Home equipment. — Two studies are in progress, one on types of gas stoves and another on steam pressure cookers. Six stoves embodying dis - tinct types of burner design have been completely studied to determine the performance of surface burners and ovens. The results for these stoves are being prepared for publication in a technical bulletin. To complete the study, seven stoves are being investigated at present. Many of the tests used were similar to those of the American Gas Association Testing Laboratory. Surface burners were tested for both short- and long-time efficiency, heat distribution, time of heating, and flue-gas analysis, includ - ing CO;., CO, and boil-overs. Included in the surface burner tests was a test of automatic lighters. Oven tests consist of preheating, cooling, ther - mostat calibration, heat loss from empty oven, open-door heat loss, tem - perature distribution within the oven and on exterior surfaces, and flue - gas analysis. To supplement the technical tests actual cooking was per - formed on the surface burners and in the oven. Records were kept so that cost of operation could be determined. The results show that the thermal efficiency will vary with the size of the pan used, a large pan having a higher efficiency than a small pan. For a five-quart pan, having a bottom 8% inches in diameter, efficiencies were found to vary from about 45.5 to 33.5 per cent for the same quantity </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station of water when a gas rate of 9,000 B.t.u. per hour was used. (Highest efficiencies were obtained with this pan.) Similarly for a one-quart pan efficiencies were found to vary from 32 to 15.5 per cent. (This represents the lowest efficiency.) On one stove when the burner was operated at 9,000 B.t.u. per hour, an excessive amount of carbon monoxide was found but when this same burner was operated at 7.000 B.t.u. per hour or less it was satisfactory. For the five-quart pan mentioned above, this same burner operating at 5,000 B.t.u. per hour gave an efficiency of 52.4 per cent. Boil-over tests showed that some burners and some automatic lighters are easily clogged. With the exception of the burner previously mentioned, all of the burners were safe with respect to CO. Although the surface burners on the modern gas range are superior to those of the old gas stoves, there is still need of improvement. At present the principal fault with gas ovens is burner design. Low temperatures of 250° and 300° F. can not be obtained with most present - day gas-range ovens and this is almost entirely due to poor burner design. Complete results of this study will be published in the near future. The aim of the project on steam pressure cookers is to study the accuracy of pressure gauges, both new and old, used on steam pressure cookers. A primary gauge such as a mercury manometer will be used as the standard gauge. Temperatures in the cooker will be measured by thermocouples and compared with the pressure-gauge readings. Other technical features about the cookers will be investigated. This project has just been started and no data are available. However, a few preliminary tests indicate that even a new gauge may be in error by as much as two pounds per square inch. Food studies. — Three projects have been in progress in this field, one on the cooking quality of Great Northern and navy beans, another on comparative costs of home and commercially prepared bread, and a third on the use of lard in making cakes. Results of the study show that the cooking quality of Great Northern and navy beans is determined almost entirely by the physical and chemical characteristics of the seed coat and the micropylar region. Hydrochloric and acetic acid, sulphates and chlorides of calcium, magnesium, and aluminum harden the seed coats. They are softened by ammonium salts of organic acids and sodium bicarbonate. They are not affected by sul - phates and chlorides of sodium and potassium. The seed coats contain relatively large amounts of pectic substances, such as pectates or pectic acid, and relatively large amounts of calcium; the Great Northern varieties analyzed contained almost twice the amount of calcium contained in the navy variety. The seed coats contain relatively low amounts of pro - tein. Storage under laboratory conditions developed hard shell while beans stored in sealed jars at 72° to 80° F. and others at 45° F. actually improved in cooking quality. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Forty-ninth Annual Report Detailed records of cost and ingredients of bread and rolls have been obtained from two counties in the state. A sufficient number of counties will cooperate to give representative data on baking practice and costs of the entire state. Bread has been baked in gas ovens in the laboratory. A careful record of all ingredients and costs has been made. The work will be repeated with other fuels. From the records to date, the actual cost per pound of home-baked bread is approximately half that of commercially prepared bread. The major part of the project on lard consists in studying the relation - ship of methods of mixing, temperature of ingredients, and mixing time as related to final cake scores. A satisfactory cake could not be obtained with lard as the shortening with the standard, conventional method of mixing, but by modifications of technique, lard was used successfully in cake making. Approximately 1,600 Nebraska homemakers reported on the shortenings used in their homes, together with the reasons for such preferences. The results show that 50 per cent use butter, 25 per cent use cream, and 20 per cent use lard; whereas 65 per cent prefer using butter, 18 per cent cream, and 3 per cent lard. Flavor, texture, and availability are the most important reasons given for using the various shortenings. Nutritive value, creaming qualities, and cost are of secondary importance. The results of both of these studies will probably be published in a research bulletin this year. INSECTS, RODENTS, AND BIRDS The chinch bug, Hessian fly, and other injurious pests. — The extreme drouth and heat of the summer of 1934 were exceedingly detrimental to the development of the second brood of chinch bugs, and relatively few of them went into hibernation that fall. As a result there was no 1935 chinch-bug outbreak in Nebraska, and the studies of chinch-bug barriers carried on in 1934 had to be suspended. These same weather factors like - wise reduced the Hessian-fly population even below the 1934 level, and no Hessian-fly field-observation stations were maintained in 1935. A special study on the life history and control of the boxelder plant bug was carried on during 1935. This study revealed that this pest has a much wider range of host plants than had previously been known to be the case, that in its life history it passes through more than the four instars usually attributed to it, and that the ordinarily recommended methods of chemical control are relatively ineffective. Further studies will be carried on in 1936 for better means of chemical control and also a search for successful mechanical control measures. Grasshopper control. — Grasshopper injuries were materially abated in 1935. as compared with the several seasons preceding, especially those of 1933 and 1934, but there were still sufficient grasshoppers in 1935 that studies of the composition and distribution of grasshopper baits could profitably be continued, as well as other methods of fighting these de - structive pests. The grasshopper egg survey made in the fall of 1935 indi- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station cates a probable increase in the grasshopper population for 1936, and it is expected that this project will be continued through that season. Distribution, life history, and means of control of the common Nebraska cutworms. — Studies made on the identification of the species of cutworms under this project led to the publication in June, 1935, of A Key to the, Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms that Attack^ Corn, as Research Bul - letin 81 of the Nebraska Station, by Don B. Whelan. This bulletin sum - marizes a considerable amount of research along this line. Further data on the distribution, food habits, life histories, and natural enemies of Ne - braska cutworms were accumulated in 1935. The light trap at Lincoln was continued for its third season, and, as a check on the species of cut - worm and armyworm moths in western Nebraska and theii abundance and periods of flight, a similar light trap was conducted in Scotts Bluff county. Control of potato flea beetles and potato psyllids. — This project was begun in 1935. The results obtained in 1935 gave some promise of control in the form of a spray program. Several plats in Scotts Bluff county were used to test different kinds of sprays, and observations were made on the seasonal abundance and distribution of the pests concerned, as well as their effect upon the plants. In 1935 the psyllids were about two weeks late in making their appearance, but by the middle of August severe damage was observed in unsprayed fields in the territory from Kimball and Bushnell north to Morrill and Scottsbluff, with some damage around Alliance. A more intensive study of the problem is projected for 1936. A brood study of the codling moth in southeastern Nebraska. — The season of 1935 was very different from that of 1934, and consequently the codling moth reacted quite differently to these changed conditions in the matter of its life cycle. The great decrease in the codling-moth population brought about by the drouth of 1934 and the unfavorable fall preceding the 1934-35 wintering of this pest, was followed in 1935 by a marked recovery in its numbers and a more normal development of its various broods. Spring brood emergence began on May 28, having been retarded by the cool, wet second half of May, and reached its peak in mid-June, with an oviposition period extending from June 10 to July 6, with a high percentage (over 76 per cent) of fertility for the eggs. First-brood moths were flying from July 11 to August 28, with the peak in late July and early August, and an egg-laying period extending from July 13 to Sep - tember 24. the longest egg-laying period for this brood recorded in any of the eight years of work on this project, no doubt induced by the period of cool, wet weather of late August and early September. Second-brood moths were flying from August 16 to September 30, with the peak during the second week in September, and the egg-laying period extending from August 20 to October 3, with about 77 per cent of the eggs fertile. In the fall of 1935 there was a normal population of hibernating larvae, much in contrast to the conditions obtaining in the fall of 1934, with fall weather </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Forty-ninth Annual Report conditions favoring a heavy survival and a strong codling-moth population in 1936. Principal biological factors determining the population level of the Bob-White Quail in Nebraska. — During 1935 further study was made upon the present distribution and abundance, food, parasites, and natural enemies of the Bob-white Quail in Nebraska, under this project, which was begun in 1934. Some preliminary publication will probably be ready during 1936. Control of rodents and other injurious mammals. — Further work on pocket gophers, prairie dogs, and ground squirrels was carried on in 1935, but the greater effort was made in a study of the common mole, and this effort will be continued through 1936. LIVESTOCK FEEDING" Cottonseed cake, tankage, and 22 per cent protein cubes as supple - ments to a silage ration. — This was a 150-day experiment with steer calves fed silage and the above-named supplements. The silage contained no grain, having been made from the drouth-affected corn crop of 1934. The gains made 'by the three lots were as follows: 219 pounds, 228 pounds, and 201 pounds respectively for the cottonseed, tankage, and cubes. Though there was not much difference in total gain between lots, there was considerable difference in economy of gain. Based upon replacement values, cottonseed proved to be worth 65.98 per cent as much per ton as tankage and the cubes 64.88 per cent as much per ton as cottonseed cake and 42.82 per cent as much per ton as tankage. Both cottonseed cake and tankage produced fatter calves than 22 per cent protein cubes. (Mimeo. Circular 15(4.) Grainless silage, cottonseed cake, and a half-feed of corn for yearling and calf heifers. — The purpose of this experiment was threefold: (1) to compare yearling and calf heifers when fed silage, cake, and a limited amount of corn, (2) to determine the advisability of wintering well heifers that are to be summer-fed, and (3) to test the beef-making qualities of grainless silage. Two lots each of yearling and calf heifers were used. One lot of] heifer calves and one of yearling heifers were fed limited amounts of corn (4.13 pounds for the calves and 5.79 for the yearlings) with a full feed of silage and 1 pound daily of cottonseed cake. The other two jots received silage and 1 pound of cottonseed cake. They were fed 150 days. Heifer calves receiving no corn gained 75 per cent as much as heifer calves receiving 4.13 pounds of corn daily. Yearling heifers re - ceiving nojcorn gained 87 per cent as much as yearlings fed 5.79 pounds of corn daily. Heifer calves receiving 4.13 pounds of corn daily gained 87 per cent as much as yearling heifers receiving 5.79 pounds of corn daily. 10 In the section on livestock feeding at Lincoln, reference is made to mimeographed circulars by their numbers. These circulars may be obtained from the Department of Animal Husbandry, College of Agriculture, Lincoln, Nebraska, by anyone who wants a detailed report. The titlrs of the circulars arc the same as the titles of the experiments; the authors, unless given otherwise, are as follows: for cattle experiments, R. R. Thalman and H. I. Gramlich; for hogs, W. J. Locffcl; for sheep, M. A. Alexander. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Both lots of cattle fed limited corn rations were too fat for the feeder buyer and might have been classed as "near-beef." Grainless silage proved /5 per cent as valuable as normal silage for calves and 87 per cent as valuable for yearling heifers. Limited corn feeding was more practical for calves than for yearlings. (Mimeo. Circular 155.) Finishing yearling and calf heifers after a wintering ration of silage, cottonseed cake, and limited amounts of corn.— This experiment represents the finishing period or Phase II of the experiment reported in Mimeo. Circular 155. All lots were similarly fed but marketed at different times As in Experiment 155 (Circular 155) there were two lots of yearling heifers and two lots of heifer calves. During Phase II both lots of calves and both lots of yearlings performed about alike except that the gains were slightly more efficient in the lots fed no grain during the winter. The cost of gain favored the calves. Both calf lots and the yearling lot fed a limited corn ration during the winter were in about the same condition when sold, grading strictly choice. Lot 4 (yearlings, no grain during winter) should have been fed approximately 80 days instead of 67 L.ot 1 was fed 81 days; Lot 2, 67 days; and Lot 3, 53 days. (Mimeo. Circular 15o.) Long alfalfa, alfalfa meal, and alfalfa meal and cottonseed cake for fattening yearling steers.— This is the second trial in which long alfalfa and alfalfa meal have been compared as roughage for fattening cattle. This is also the second test to determine the advisability of adding a protein supplement to a corn and alfalfa ration. Three lots of yearling steers were fed 195 days. The lot getting long alfalfa hay gained 0.06 pound more daily than the lot getting alfalfa meal. As in Experiment 150, there was little difference in corn requirements but some hay was saved by feeding alfalfa meal. The addition of 1 pound daily of cottonseed cake to the ration resulted in an increased gain of 0.16 pound daily. All lots sold for the same price when marketed. (Mimeo. Circular 157.) The seeding and carrying capacity of temporary pastures.— This is the fourth trial of a series scheduled to continue over a period of years. The tests were planned to secure data on the comparative value of temporary and permanent pastures and to obtain general information regarding their management. As in previous tests, second-year sweet clover gave the most pasturage. Rye, followed by Sudan grass, was second, first-year sweet clover third, Sudan grass fourth, and permanent pasture grasses (sown 1934) fifth. The native bluegrass sod was killed out entirely by the 1934 drouth. Rye gave considerable pasturage during April and May, and again in October and early November. (Mimeo. Circular 158 by R R Thalman, H. J. Gramlich, W. E. Lyness, and T. A. Kiesselbach.) The Red Polled steer for beef production.— Experiment in progress. Five head of Red Polled steers are being fed individually. In addition to keeping a record of feed-lot performance, detailed carcass studies are being made. Each steer is slaughtered when he weighs 900 pounds. Results will be published in Mimeo. Circular 159. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Forty-ninth Annual Report Cottonseed cake, tankage, and 37 per cent protein soybean cubes as supplements to a silage ration. — Experiment in progress. Lots 1 and 2 are duplications of experiment reported in Mimeo. Circular 154. Lot 3 was introduced into this test in place of the lot receiving 22 per cent cubes. The results will be published in Mimeo. Circular 161 in April, 1936. Limited corn rations for yearling and calf heifers. — Experiment in progress. A duplication of experiment reported in Mimeo. Circular 155. Trial to be published in Mimeo. Circular 161, together with two-year average. Growing pigs on Sudan-grass pasture. — Pigs self-fed corn and tankage gained twice as rapidly as those receiving 2 l /i pounds of the same ration daily. Pigs on self-feeders required less feed and less forage to make com - parable gains. In comparing growing rations of corn, 9 parts, and tankage 1, fed at the rate of 2 pounds daily as compared with 2 Vz pounds, slightly larger gains but less efficient feed utilization was noted at the higher level of feed intake. When fed as a growing ration, standard wheat shorts pro - duced larger and more efficient gains than an equal daily allowance of corn and tankage. (Mimeo. Circular 255.) Full-feeding pigs on Sudan-grass pasture. — Eight lots of 73-pound pigs were fed in Sudan-grass lots for 85 days. Pigs which were self-fed corn and tankage gained almost twice as rapidly as those receiving only corn. Where self-fed, each pound of tankage saved 1.67 pounds of corn. Where tankage was limited to one-fourth pound per head daily, each pound of tankage saved 2.4 pounds of corn. Larger gains were secured, however, where the daily consumption of tankage was not restricted. Low-grade tankage containing 30 per cent of crude protein was quite unpalatable and only one-third as valuable as the standard 60 per cent protein tankage. No advantage was apparent in this test from dividing the pasture and rotating the halves every week, because the pasture was not grazed closely enough. A supplementary mixture of cottonseed meal and tankage, equal parts, proved very palatable, and produced slightly larger, though no more eco - nomical, gains than straight tankage. A supplementary mixture of equal parts linseed meal and tankage was the least palatable of the oil-meal - tankage mixtures. Smaller and slightly less efficient gains were secured where this mixture was fed than where tankage alone comprised the sup - plement. Substituting new-process soybean oil meal for half the tankage reduced the daily gain below that of the check lot, which received only tankage as a supplement. (Mimeo. Circular 254.) Protein supplementary mixtures for dry-lot pig feeding. — Four lots of 123-pound pigs were fed in dry lot for 85 days in a trial to compare tank - age as a supplement with equal-parts mixtures of cottonseed meal and tankage, linseed meal and tankage, and new-process soybean oil meal and tankage. The linseed-meal-tankage mixture proved slightly less palatable than straight tankage, and the cottonseed-meal-tankage mixture markedly </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station more palatable than straight tankage. Where linseed meal and where soy - bean oil meal were ted with tankage, equal gains were secured as with tankage alone. Marked increases in gain were noted where cottonseed meal was fed with tankage. Where new-process soybean oil meal made up half the supplement, the oil meal proved equal to tankage. Where linseed meal and cottonseed meal were substituted for half the tankage, more feed was required to produce each hundred pounds of gain. (Mimeo. Circular 253.) Supplementing the corn and tankage ration for pigs in dry lot. — Ten lots of 9 pigs each were fed in dry lot for 67 days. Various combinations were made of tankage with each of three oil by-products: cottonseed meal, linseed meal, and new-process soybean oil meal. In each case the oil by - product was mixed with the tankage in the following proportions: equal parts tankage and oil meal; one part tankage and three of oil meal; and one part oil meal, one alfalfa meal, and two of tankage. The protein mix - ture was self-fed free choice with yellow shelled corn. The essential data are presented in the following table: ____ i ! Feed for 100 pounds of gain Supplement fed j Daily gain ; c^ | Supplement | Tola! II ! Tankage | 1.70 339 41 380 Tankage 1, cottonseed meal I.... 2.03 298 74 372 Tankage 3, cottonseed meal 1 .... 1.99 313 66 379 Tankage 2, cottonseed meal 1, alfalfa meal 1 1.81 328 61 389 Tankage 1, linseed meal 1 1.65 345 -18 395 Tankage 3, linseed meal 1 1.66 334 55 389 Tankage 2, linseed meal 1, alfalfa meal 1 1.98 318 55 373 Tankage 1. soybean oil meal 1... 2.00 316 52 368 Tankage 3, soybean oil meal I... 1.79 329 52 381 Tankage 2, soybean oil meal 1. alfalfa meal 1 1.69 | 334 ! . 45 379 The addition of the oil by-products improved the palatability of all the rations. Six of the lots fed the mixed supplements gained more rapidly than the lot fed only tankage as a supplement. In every lot save one, less corn was required for 100 pounds of gain where a mixed supplement was fed. However, more mixed supplement was required than tankage in every instance. In four of the ten lots, less total feed was required per 100 pounds of gain with the mixed supplements than with tankage. Both cottonseed and soybean oil meal appear to be most efficiently utilized when mixed with an equal weight of tankage. The addition of alfalfa meal to both the soybean and the cottonseed meal mixtures lowered their efficiency. This situation was reversed in the case of linseed meal. The efficient utilization of tankage by pigs in dry lot. — Six lots of ten 83-pound pigs were fed in dry lot for 94 days. Shelled corn was self-fed </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Forty-ninth Annual Report to all lots. Tankage was fed at the following levels to the first four lots: self-fed, 0.4 pound. 0.2 pound, and 0.1 pound per head daily. Lot 5 re - ceived 0.4 pound tankage per head daily for 40 days, then no tankage. In Lot 6 the situation was reversed, no tankage being given for 40 days, after which a daily allowance of 0.4 pound was fed. The essential data are presented in the following table: Av. daily ration , , ., Feed tor 100 pounds of gain Lot No. Av. daily Corn Tankage gain Co rn Tankage | Total — 1 5.70 0.70 1.63 351 43 394 2 5.22 0.40 1.43 364 28 392 3 4.41 0.20 1.09 403 18 421 4 4.09 0.10 0.91 446 11 457 5 4.15 0.17 0.97 427 18 445 6 4.26 0.23 ! 1.06 402 22 424 It will be noted that appetite and rate and economy of gain varied directly with the allowance of tankage fed. Slightly larger gains and more efficient feed utilization were secured where 0.20 pound of tankage was fed daily throughout the test than where double the daily allowance of tankage was fed during either the first or the last half of the test. Fattening lambs without hay. — Six groups of western feeder lambs were used. A corn and alfalfa-hay ration was used as a standard for a comparison with silage rations fortified with cottonseed meal, bone meal, tankage, and meat scraps. In one lot wheat straw ; made up the roughage. Very satisfactory results were obtained when silage made up the roughage in the ration if it was supplemented with proteins and minerals. (Mimeo. Circular 328.) Short-tailed Hampshire sheep study. — This study was begun on January 30. 1933, when a Hampshire ram lamb was dropped with a tail about half normal length. He sired 11 ewes and 3 rams in the 1935 lamb crop. One of the ewe lambs had a twisted, kinky tail. The average tail length for the 14 lambs was practically the same as for the other Hampshire lambs dropped in the flock but sired by a different ram. Eight of the ewe lambs will be mated to their sire in the fall of 1936. The project is being continued. Efficient corn and alfalfa-hay rations for fattening lambs. — This is the second trial of a test in which eight groups of western feeder lambs are fed rations varying in amounts of corn and alfalfa hay. The test is now in progress and will terminate about the first of March. The first trial is reported in Mimeographed Circular 327. Farm flock performance. — A flock of 79 aged western ewes were bred to Southdown rams in the fall of 1933. Data were collected covering one year of production. Records of the feed consumed, days on pasture, </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station products produced, and other pertinent facts are available in Mimeo - graphed Circular 329. 6 r PLANT DISEASES The pathological and physiological aspects of alfalfa failures in Ne - braska. — The work on wilt and cold resistance of alfalfa selections, co - operative with the U. S. Department of Agriculture, has advanced to the point where seed of some of the selections is being increased for dis - tribution. Heaving of soils by frost exerts a severe effect on alfalfa fields and winter-grown crops and an effort has been made to produce the same effect under controlled conditions. Heaving and the production of ice plates was produced by open systems, or with an excess of water available to the soil below and the freezing of soil above. Plants will be subjected to tests later. Studies of cold resistance of winter wheats continue, and also of factors that influence the activation of seed. A study of the soil-borne diseases of the potato. — The effect of different crop rotations on the occurrence of potato scab under irrigation has been studied at the Scottsbluff Substation and the results are being prepared for publication. A similar study is being niade under dry-land culture at the Box Butte Experiment Farm. The relation of weather conditions, crop rotations, date of planting, and infected seed to the occurrence of Fusarium wilt has been studied and the results are being prepared for publication. Experiments are being continued in the field, greenhouse, and laboratory, to determine the effect of soil conditions as modified by crop - ping systems, cultural treatments, and weather upon the occurrence of potato scab, Rhizoctonia, and Fusarium wilt. Spraying potatoes for the control of flea beetles, psyllid yellows, and early blight. — Spraying experiments were conducted during the past season but because of the slight amount of early blight present the results were not conclusive regarding this phase of the project and further tests- will be needed. Virus diseases of the potato. — This project, which has been inactive for some years, has been reopened for the study of a previously undescribed disease of potatoes that is causing considerable loss to the seed-potato industry. A description of the trouble is being prepared for publication and experiments are being conducted to determine the nature and means of controlling the disease. Diseases of field and garden beans. — The search for varieties or strains of the common bean resistant to the bacterial blights is being continued by inoculation tests in the greenhouse and selections in the field. Only two bean varieties have shown any degree of resistance and further selection and hybridization work will be needed. A number of German varieties reported as resistant are being tested at the present time. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Forty-ninth Annual Report POULTRY Incubation of turkey eggs. — Approximately 2,400 turkey eggs were used in an effort to determine the effect of humidities of 40±2, 59±2, and 80±2 per cent, during the first 24 days of incubation, on the subse - quent hatchability of eggs and growth rate and stamina of the poults. No significant effect of this variation in relative humidity was noted. The tests support an earlier conclusion that the critical period is the last few days of incubation, so far as humidity is concerned. Nutritive requirements of growing turkeys. — Over 1,000 poults were used in a test on calcium utilization. The results indicate that calcium in the form of sulphate is used more efficiently than that in the form of carbonate. The advantage in each of four experiments was consistently for the sulphate salt, but this advantage was not sufficient to justify a high premium in price for one product over the other. These experiments suggested the possibility of acid-base relationships as a factor affecting calcium utilization. The principle involved was studied by altering the acid-base relationships of a standard ration with additions of ammonium chloride at one and two per cent levels. The addition of this salt depressed the growth rate distinctly. Ash analysis of the tibias of repre - sentative birds from each lot, however, indicated normal calcification for all lots. A comparison of the availability for growing poults of the calcium in dolomitic limestone, as compared with that in high calcium limestone, was made. The dolomitic limestone used contained 43.50 per cent magnesium carbonate and 51.25 per cent calcium carbonate. Both products were pulverized to the same degree of fineness, and the same level of calcium was provided for both lots. The growth rate of the poults receiving the dolomitic limestone was slightly higher than that of the high-calcium limestone group. There was no significant difference in the ash content of the bones of representative poults in the two lots. The magnesium in the dolomitic limestone ration, which was the equivalent of 1.65 per cent of magnesium carbonate, apparently did not interfere with the assimilation or deposition of the calcium. Nutrient requirements of growing chicks. — One phase of this protect has had to do with the relationship of protein level in the growing ration to the subsequent stamina of the laying flock. With the increase in laying ability that has come about as a result of breeding, there has also occurred an increase in mortality of laying birds, especially during the first year of production. Work at Cornell University has shown that increasing speed of maturing has resulted in shorter life. The rations of two lots used were the same except for protein, which was 2'/l times as great in one lot as in the other. A comparison of the growth rate of the two lots of pullets until the twenty-fourth week indicates a material stimulation of the growth rate of the high-protein lot until the twelfth week, when the low-protein lot began to recover the comparative </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station loss, and no difference at the end of the twenty-fourth week. No differences in mortality during the first year and no significant differences in produc - tion have been noted. The study will be continued with double the num - ber of individuals. Another phase has had to do with the antirachitic value of the cod - liver-oil by-product, stearine. formerly used in soap making and recently in animal feeding. Results from 11 lots of 30 chicks each indicate that there is a material difference in the antirachitic value of cod-liver-oil stearine, crude cod-liver oil, and the refined oil. Ash data on the tibias from 15 chicks in each lot were also taken. Estimations on comparative values, as obtained from these lots, would be as follows: refined cod-liver oil 100, crude cod-liver oil 85, and the stearine by-product 40 units. Determinations of sex of day-old chicks. — Considerable success in de - termining sex of day-old chicks has been obtained with the method adopted in the United States from the Japanese and Circular 51, Determining the Sex of Day-old Chicks, by H. E. Alder, March, 1935, 8 pages, has been published. This circular describes and illustrates the method. RURAL ECONOMICS Nebraska farm land prices. — One part of this project, which treats of farm mortgages, was completed in 1933 with the publication of Research Bulletin 67; a second part, which was concerned with land-price history, was completed in 1934 with the publication of Research Bulletin 72; the third part of the project was completed in 1935 and the project was closed with the publication of Research Bulletin 77. Research Bulletin 77, Sales Value and Assessed Value of Nebraska Farm Land, 1921-1934, by Eleanor H. Hinman, July, 1935, 24 pages. The bulletin compares the assessed value of Nebraska farm land per acre with the price at which the land actually sold. Statistics are given for counties, for districts, and for the state as a whole. Nebraska farm land prices fell much more rapidly than assessed valuations during the 12 years ending March 31, 1933. Land values declined, but the assessed valuation of farm land remained approximately constant from April 1. 1921, up to and including the year ending March 1, 1929, in the western part of the state, and up to and including the year ending March 31, 1932, in the eastern part of the state. The assessed valuations of individual Nebraska farms commonly varied widely from their potential sales value in such a way that a disproportionate amount of the tax burden was placed on the poorer farms. In every geographic district as shown by this study, the least valu - able farms were seriously overvalued by the assessors, and the more valu - able farms were undervalued in relation to the average assessment ratio for the district. The rather serious assessment situation revealed in this study indicates the need of a much more careful consideration of assess - ment problems than has yet been made in Nebraska if our tax laws are to be administered with equity. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Forty-ninth Annual Report Cost of marketing corn and wheat in Nebraska by different methods. — Financial and marketing data have been secured from country grain elevators for 1934. It is anticipated that these data and those secured in previous years will be tabulated sometime in 1936 and a manuscript pre - pared for publication. The study will show the financial status of the elevators from 1920 to 1934 and the factors influencing the operating results during these years. Farm organization and farm costs. — This project utilizes the farm account book as a source of information upon the profits obtained from various types of Nebraska farms. Fourteen hundred books were sum - marized for 1934 and probably nearly as many will be summarized for 1935. Two manuscripts based on parts of the data secured during the past 20 years are in progress. One of these shows the relationship which has existed between size of farm and the return which the farmer receives for his labor. The other manuscript gives information upon farm ex - penditures. Cost of producing farm crops. — Some of the farmers who keep farm record books keep a detailed cost-of-production record for one or two crops. This makes possible a comparison of production costs in different parts of the state and under different systems of management. Records were com - pleted in 1934 as follows: wheat 119, corn 99, potatoes 61. Farm real estate tax delinquencies and public expenditures in Nebraska. — A large amount of data gathered under a CWA project during the past three months of 1934 is available for this project. Complete data have been obtained from Dakota, Cuming, Boone, Valley, Thomas. Dawes, Frontier, Harlan, Hamilton, Gage, Cass, and Lancaster counties for the years 1928 to 1933. Good progress has been made in tabulating the data and it is anticipated that material progress will be made during the year in prep - aration of a manuscript. Farm mortgage foreclosures in Nebraska. — Some information was secured upon farm real estate transfers in 19 selected Nebraska counties under a CWA project for the years 1928-33. The data were comparatively complete for 12 of these counties. Each of these counties has been visited, the CWA data checked, and additional data secured. A study of adjustments in farming by regions and type-of-farming areas from the standpoint of agricultural adjustment and planning, includ - ing land conservation. — This project is cooperative with the Bureau of Agri - cultural Economics of the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Data secured by Nebraska assessors were tabulated and additional data were obtained from census reports, corn-hog contracts, and farm account books. Soil and climate were considered in. working out possible adjustments. A great deal of work remains to be done on this project before the results can be published. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station state serum plant Because of the decrease in hog population in the state, the demand for serum and virus decreased during the year. The advancing hog market however, stimulated vaccination somewhat. There was little cholera until September and October and even then the disease did not gain epidemic proportions, but was confined to localities. Past experience has shown that when vaccination is at its lowest ebb the possibility of a severe epidemic is greatest. The swine industry is at present, then, in danger of attack All orders were filled promptly and a liberal supply of serum was kept in storage to provide for emergencies. The policy of buying serum subject to retest and of making virus has been continued. With little additional expense for equipment, the plant could produce serum. Serum has con - tinued to retail at 55 cents per hundred cc. and virus at $1.50 per hundred cc. A report of the sales by months follows, together with a financial state - ment for the year ending January 1, 1936. Scrum and virus sold by months during 1935: Serum Virus January ■ 22^000 1,415 February 24.250 1,245 Mar 5, h 6,250 395 1 18,375 1,365 Ma &gt; ■•• 81,625 " 6,650 J u . ne 45,375 3,535 J . u 'y 60,875 4,895 Au S" st 218,500 13,725 September 100,375 5.930 °?*° b " 1,642,625 34,190 November 126,250 7.370 Pi"!! , •■"•" 348 - 375 2 -795 Used at plant 3,000 2,500 2,694,875 86.010 Scrum on hand January 1, 1935 5,263 895 cc Serum purchased in 1935 ...!!.'!!!! 3^588*050 cc Total handled for year g,851 945 cc Serum on handjanuary 1. 1936 "'!'!"! 6]l57io~O cc Number of pigs used in making virus and testing scrum 94 Total gross sales from all sources cit Qfin 3&lt;c Money collected and receipted for '.'.'.'.'.'."' 1211726 Outstanding accounts (University of Missouri) . . 1050 00 Assets Cash balance January 1, 1936 573 451 24 Estimated value of scrum stock 24*628 28 Accounts receivable ] 050 00 Miscellaneous stock ....... 300 00 Total assets $99,429.52 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Forty-ninth Annual Report NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION The experimental work was continued much as in previous years. The principal change was the suspension o£ much of the dry-land crop work, which is cooperative with the Division of Dry Land Agriculture of the U. S. Department of Agriculture, because of the transfer of land to the Platte Valley Power and Irrigation District. Total precipitation for the year was above normal but it was erratically distributed. The winter of 1934-35 was dry and soil-blowing caused considerable damage. Then followed heavy rains and low temperatures; and in late June hot, dry weather came on and persisted during the remainder of the summer. Rust was prevalent in small grains but rust damage was less than that caused by the hot, dry weather. Dry-land crops and tillage.— The relocation of dry-land work prevented the securing of continuing results. All of the old plats were sampled in the fall of 1934 for organic-matter and nitrogen determinations. Land for the relocation consists of 320 acres comprising the west half of the section immediately southeast of the original area. Three fields have been laid out in 390 plats of one-tenth acre each for crop-rotation and tillage studies. One of the fields had been seeded to winter wheat, and one was seeded to oats and another to barley. These wete harvested by plats in order to obtain information on the variability of the land. Yields of the 108 plats of winter wheat ranged from 9.8 to 35.3 bushels per acre, oats from 34.4 to 64.1, and barley from 17.3 to 52.7. Average yields were: winter wheat 23.8, oats 48.6, and barley 32.6. The crop rotations planned include those in use by the Great Plains stations co - operating with the U. S. D. A., Division of Dry Land Agriculture, and a number of other rotations particularly applicable to Nebraska conditions. Crop varieties. — Tests were continued with winter wheat, barley, oats, corn, and sorghums. All small-grain yields were above normal. Winter - wheat varieties ranged from 32.7 to 41 bushels on stalk ground and from 44.7 to 56.0 on fallow. The highest yield was made by the rust-resistant Turkey 10016. Some rust-susceptible varieties with previous high records were very low. The highest-yielding barley varieties were Ezond with 52.3 bushels per acre and Short Comfort with 47.1. Both have had good records for several years. The highest-yielding oats varieties were Burt 293, Trojan, Kherson 459, and Iogold, all above 60 bushels per acre. Of 16 corn varieties and crosses on dry land, six outyielded Substation White checks 5 to 21 per cent, and 10 yielded 5 to 36 per cent less than the checks. All but two of the 18 single crosses between pure lines out - yielded the checks from 3 to 96 per cent. Of sorghum varieties, Early Kalo appears to be outstanding for both maturity and high grain yield. Its 1935 yield was 35.2 bushels per acre in comparison with 21.9 for corn. For the 3-year period 1933-35, the average yield of Early Kalo was 170 per cent of the yield of corn. For forage and ensilage, Atlas sorgo has produced yields of high tonnage and quality. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Pump irrigation. — On account of the heavy spring rainfall, the irriga - tion pump was not started until July 10. A higher water table permitted the pump to operate more efficiently than during the previous year. The average discharge was 1,140 gallons per minute. An average of about nine inches of water was applied to 134.6 acres at a cost of approximately $5.00 per acre. Because part of the irrigation was for annual pastures and preparation for seeding alfalfa, from which cash returns cannot be figured, and because increases resulting from irrigation were lower than usual, a total net profit cannot be shown for pump irrigation for the 1935 season. Irrigation costs per unit of production for certain crops were as follows: potatoes 3 cents . per bushel, corn silage 34 cents per ton, Atlas silage 64 cents per ton, and alfalfa hay $3.14 per ton. Wintering and fattening cattle. — Steer calves which had been well wintered were grazed on native grass for 84 days and then finished on ground corn and alfalfa hay in dry lot in comparison with similar steers fed in dry lot for the entire period. As in former years, the steers grazed on native grass, whether given a full feed of grain, a half feed of grain, or no grain during the grazing period, and then finished in dry lot, made more economical gains and were more profitable than the steers fed in dry lot for the entire period. Although the three methods of handling steers on grass all have a place in beef production in southwest Nebraska, it seems that the more grain fed during the grazing period, the more ex - pensive the gains. In a comparison of 0.67 pound of 60 per cent digester tankage and 1.0 pound of cottonseed meal as supplements when fed with a full feed of shelled corn and silage to fattening calves, the tankage produced more rapid and more economical gains. Likewise, the addition of 0.1 pound of ground limestone to the ration in which 1.0 pound of cottonseed meal was fed as a supplement proved profitable, resulting in more rapid and eco - nomical gains. In a test of supplemental feeds for calves wintered on silage, there was little if any advantage in the addition of 0.1 pound of ground limestone to the ration in which 1.0 pound of cottonseed meal was fed as the supple - ment. A mixture of 0.5 pound of cottonseed meal and 0.33 pound of 60 per cent digester tankage satisfactorily replaced 1.0 pound of cottonseed meal as a supplement to a ration of silage for wintering calves. Each ton of tankage fed in this manner replaced 3048 pounds of cottonseed meal. Gains and silage required per unit of gain were not affected. One pound of cottonseed meal proved to be more palatable than 0.67 pound of the tankage used in this test. As a result the calves fed the tankage as a sup - plement ate less feed and made slightly smaller and slightly .more expensive gains than the calves fed cottonseed meal. Bulletin 294 (North Platte Series No. 37), The Use of Wheat and Rye for Fattening Calves, by Marvel L. Baker, April, 1935, 16 pages, reports the results of three trials in 1931-33. The two grains were tried alone and </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Forty-ninth Annual Report in combination with corn. All rations produced satisfactory gains but those including corn resulted in a better finish than did the' others. The development of breeding cattle. — This was the second year for this long-time project involving a study of the effect of cottonseed cake and steamed bone meal when fed with prairie hay on the development and reproduction of range cattle. Soybean oil meal and tankage fed with ground wheat to fattening hogs. — Pigs fed ground wheat and expeller-process soybean oil meal plus ground limestone (all full-fed free choice) made as rapid gains as similar pigs fed ground wheat and tankage. One hundred pounds of soybean oil meal replaced 40 pounds of ground wheat and 50 pounds of tankage. Apparently the addition of ground limestone resulted in more rapid and more economical gains. Pigs fed the expeller-process soybean oil meal ate more than three times as much supplement and gained more than l'/i times as rapidly as similar pigs fed the solvent-process soybean oil meal. The apparent difference between the two oil meals may be due to palatability. The Nebraska flock-testing project. — This project has been continued in cooperation with the Poultry Department and the Extension Service of the College of Agriculture at Lincoln. It will be continued another year. Horses. — Continued progress was made in improving the type and quality of the Percheron horse herd. Holstein cows. — The Holstein herd was maintained on the same basis as in former years. No losses occurred from pasturing the milking herd on new, succulent alfalfa, although some danger from bloat did exist. Aside from this, the alfalfa provided excellent grazing. It is possible that more bloating occurred than will usually be true because of the extreme succulence of the alfalfa used and the prevalence of rainy weather during the early summer of 1935. Horticulture. — The table-land orchard and forestry plantings were eliminated by the previously mentioned transfer of land. In the old bench orchard a fair crop of apples was produced. A new variety orchard has been started south of the poultry plant. Injuries from hail, drouth, and severe winters in recent years have caused losses and required renovating and replacements. The 1935 season provided favorable conditions and plantings made an encouraging response. In the canyon plantings Scotch and Austrian pines have withstood the 1934 drouth better than the Western Yellow, although the latter have shown better survival in previous years. In the landscape plantings Black Hills spruce made a good recovery from the burning of 1934. A lot of 110 seedling peonies came into bloom for the first time. About half of these were single, several of which showed very good quality. . Potatoes. — A report on the possibility of producing seed potatoes in central Nebraska was made in Bulletin 294 (North Platte Series No. 36), </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska, by H. O. Werner and L. L. Zook, April, 1935, 15 pages. The field work was done earlier; the results have shown that with the application of certain managerial practices, seed production is feasible. SCOTTSBLUFF SUBSTATION This substation is maintained in cooperation with the Division of Western Irrigation Agriculture, U. S. Department of Agriculture. The most extensive project carried on is that concerned with crop rotations, although important projects are under way on field problems and on prob - lems related to livestock. A great deal of other work is also carried on here, such as the production of foundation seed of certain strains of Tri - umph potatoes for the Nebraska Certified Potato Growers' association; the studies on water requirements of crops by the U. S. D. A., Bureau of Agricultural Engineering; tests on sugar-beet varieties and cultural methods for sugar beets carried on by the Division of Sugar Plant Investigations of the U. S. Department of Agriculture; studies of twin-row planting and of varieties of potatoes by the University of Nebraska, Department of Horti - culture; the increasing of seed of wilt-resistant varieties of alfalfa by the U. S. D. A., Division of Forage Crops and Diseases; the studies of the effect of crop rotation on plant food elements in the soil, by the University of Nebraska, Department of Agronomy; and the study of the effect of crop rotation on diseases of potatoes, by the University of Nebraska, De - partment of Plant Pathology. The Pathfinder dam was filled only to half its capacity by the latter part of June, 1935, and as a result less than half the normal delivery of water was made during the year. Rainfall was almost normal in quantity but unevenly distributed. Heavy winds in February and March caused a great deal of erosion. The growing season was longer than usual — 142 days — as compared with an average of 133. Crop rotations and fertilizers. — Yields in the rotation plats were normal, in spite of the small amount of available irrigation water. Forty-eight rotation systems are in operation, of which 31 were established in 1°12, three in 1920, ten in 1926, three in 1931, and one in 1932. The coming into prominence, in this section, of beans as a crop caused the introduction of the latter two, and the prominence of sweet clover caused the introduc - tion of those in 1920 and 1926. One of the important results has been the information on beneficial effects of alfalfa and manure. U. S. D. A. Tech - nical Bulletin No. 483, Effect of Alfalfa and Farm Manure on Yields of Irrigated Crops in the Great Plains, by Stephen H. Hastings, Division of Western Irrigation Agriculture, U. S. D. A., Washington, D. C. Septem - ber, 1935, includes data on work at the Scottsbluff substation. Data from the last 18 years show that the average increase in yield of beets due to applications of manure was 8.39 tons an acre and due to alfalfa in the rotation 5.65 tons. For potatoes the increase due to manure has been 105.0 bushels, and to alfalfa 133.8 bushels per acre. The figures for </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Forty-ninth Annual Report oats, respectively, are 22.8 and 33.8 bushels. The increase in corn yield due to alfalfa has been 24.7 bushels and in wheat yield 9.9 bushels. Sweet clover as a pasture crop in rotations has given large returns, and appears to be a sound means of maintaining the soil fertility over a long time. In 1926 an experiment was begun to determine the immediate and residual effects of different quantities of manure and to determine whether or not to apply a given quantity all at one time or in portions over a five - year period. Residual effects since 1930, when the five-year period ended, have been studied. The results show that heavy applications may be profitably made. Recently obtained information indicates that heavy applications of manure preceding sugar beets are attended by reductions in sugar content, and as a result it may be found that moderate applications fl2 to 16 tons) are best. Dairying. — Ten of the poorest cows of the dairy herd were culled out during the summer and seven choice heifers were obtained from the sub - station at Valentine. For a number of years one lot of cows has been fed roughage with grain and the other lot roughage without grain. The lot without grain has produced milk at a considerably lower feed cost but the death loss has been greater in this lot, the cows have had greater trouble in calving, and their general constitution has been poorer. Since July the cows remaining in this lot have been fed roughage and bone meal, with improvement in general health but not in production. Variety tests of vegetable crops. — Cabbage, cauliflower, tomatoes, onions, sweet corn, string beans, and peas of different varieties are being tested for production and adaptation to the North Platte valley. Hail early in the season and drouth later on damaged a great many of the plantings. VALENTINE SUBSTATION The work of the Valentine Substation was continued with some changes in the dairy and beef-cattle work. The effects of the drouth of 1934 lasted over into 1935 and severely affected yields of crops. Crops. — Spring grain attained a height of from 12 to 16 inches, but because of drouth failed to produce grain and was cut for hay. The winter wheat and rye plots were abandoned on account of poor stands resulting from insufficient fall moisture. Corn was a failure as a grain crop and the stalks were too short to cut with a binder, as were also most of the sorghum varieties. Dwarf Freed was the most drouth-resistant grain sorghum. As silage crops, Amber and Atlas sorgo produced two tons per acre from plots adjacent to corn that was too poor to cut. Meadow improvement. — The water level during the winter of 1934-35 was the lowest during the twelve years in which readings have been taken in this area. Spring rains, however, brought the level up to about normal and made favorable conditions for the seeding of clover on the subirri - gated meadows. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Tree plantings.— The older windbreaks suffered the greatest loss since being planted in 1913. A ten-year-old planting of Russian olives and a seven-year-old planting of Chinese elm, however, survived almost 100 per cent. Beef cattle.— A project is now being conducted for the purpose of studying the effect of winter ration on the development of range heifers that calve as two-year-olds, and also the effect on the birth and weaning weight of their calves. Another phase of the project is a comparison of wintering in dry lot as against wintering with access to range Lot 1 receives prairie hay alone the first winter and hay plus one pound of cottonseed cake daily the second winter. Lot 2 receives prairie haVplus one pound of cottonseed cake the first winter and hay alone the second winter. Lot 3 receives prairie hay plus one pound of cottonseed cake daily each winter. Lot 4 receives the same kind of ration as Lot 3 but has access to range which has been summer-grazed. The first winter gains in Lots 1 and 2 were comparable to gains made by steer calves similarly fed. The summer gains, however, were smaller because of poor pasture. When weighed off the grass in the fall the heifers in Lot 2 averaged 60 pounds heavier than those in Lot 1. Lot 4 consumed almost 25 per cent less hay than Lot 3 and gained 17 pounds more. Dair £7;!c C d f ify herd ° f P urebred Holsteins was dispersed in the spring of 1935 and a project with general-purpose cattle was started in co - operation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. BOX BUTTE EXPERIMENTAL FARM The winter wheat crop failed because of winterkilling, and spring wheat was severely injured by rust. The yields of other crops were res - tively good. The yields of standard varieties were approximately as fol - n7n T I u *? aC ?' ° atS 33 ' k'fcy 15 ' g fain sor ghum 12, spring wheat 5, soybeans 7, and safflower 8 bushels per acre Differences in the yield of potatoes in the various rotation plots were less than last year, because of abundant moisture in the spring which re - sulted , n the potato roots penetrating down to five-foot depths and being able to withstand the dry weather of August. The yield of potatoes on the farm was about normal or slightly above. The production of disease-free seed and potatoes for use as foundation stock tor certified-seed growers is being continued and the sale of such seed constitutes the chief source of revenue for the farm. Aside from the production of such seed and the rotation experiments, the remainder of the larm is devoted to experimental work conducted by the Departments of Agronomy, Horticulture, and Plant Pathology in the College of Agricul - ture, University of Nebraska. ADDITIONAL LAND, BUILDINGS, AND EQUIPMENT At the North Platte Substation a cottage, barn, machine shed and well on the new. land acquired for the dry-land agronomic work cost about </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Forty-ninth Annual Report $6,000. In an exchange of land with the Platte Valley Power and Irriga - tion District at North Platte, the substation received 320 acres adjacent to the land exchanged. PUBLICATIONS OF THE CALENDAR YEAR 1935 ANNUAL REPORT Forty-eighth Annual Report, presented to the Governor February 1, 1935. 1,500 copies. BULLETINS No. 292, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1920-1934. Board of Tractor Test Engineers. January, 1935, 3,500 copies; reprinted September, 1935, 2,000 copies. No. 293, Cultural Practices in Corn Production. T. A. Kicsselbach, Arthur Ander - son, and W. E. Lyness. January. 1935. 10,000 copies. No. 294, Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska. H. O. Werner and L. L. Zook. Bulletin 36 of the North Platte Experiment Substation. April, 1935. 5,000 copies. No. 295, The Use of Wheat and Rye for Fattening Calves. Marvel L. Baker. Bulletin 37 of the North Platte Experiment Substation. April, 1935. 5,000 copies. No. 296, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1920-1935. Board of Tractor Test Engineers. January, 1936. 5,000 copies. RESEARCH BULLETINS No. 77, Sales Value and Assessed Value of Nebraska Farm Land, 1921-1934. Eleanor H. Hinman. July, 1935. 3,000 copies. No. 78, A Study of Farm Families and Their Standards of Living in Selected Dis - tricts of Nebraska, 1931-1933. Margaret Fedde and Ruth Lindquist. July, 1935. 3,000 copies. No. 79, The Vitamin A Content of Sour Cream Butter, Sweet Cream Butter, and Margarines. I. L. Hathaway and H. P. Davis. August, 1935. 3,000 copies. No. 80, The Utilization of Nitrogen, Calcium, and Phosphorus by the Growing Chick. C. W. Ackerson, M. J. Blish, and F. E. Mussehl. September, 1935. 3,000 copies. No. 81, A Key to the Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms That Attack Corn. Don B. Whelan. June, 1935. 3,000 copies. CIRCULARS No. 50, Bindweed Eradication. T. A. Kiesselbach, P. H. Stewart, and D. L. Gross. February, 1935. 25,000 copies. No. 51, Determining the Sex of Day-old Chicks. H. E. Alder. March, 1935. 5,000 copies. No. 52, Annual Fodder and Silage Crops for Nebraska. W. E. Lyness and T. A. Kiesselbach. March, 1935. 10,000 copies. TECHNICAL PAPERS Because the technical papers published by Station workers are mentioned throughout this report, no list of them is included. 1G852B </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF MONEY RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT HATCH FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1935, under act of Congress approved March 2, 1887. Total S15.000.00 Expenditures For salaries $15,000.00 TotaI S15,000.00 ADAMS FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1935, under act of Congress approved March 16, 1906. Total \ $15,000.00 Expenditures For salaries $15,000.00 Total $15,000.00 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON, January 22, 1936 Finance Secretary. PURNELL FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1935, under act of Congress approved February 24, 1925. Total. $60,000.00 SALARIES Expenditures Regular $39,738.93 Temporary 3,755.33 Total $43,494.26 SUPPLIES Office Supplies $ 31.40 Laboratory Supplies 2,301.22 Fuel (Coal) 9.75 Educational and Recreational 78.91 Janitor and Barn Supplies 32.23 Feeding Stuffs 4,964.75 Agricultural Supplies 1 17.47 Total 5 7,535.73 EXPENSE Office Expense and Postage $ 2.64 Freight, Express, and Drayage 65.22 Water, Heat, Light and Power 41.20 Public Printing and Advertising 148.33 Traveling Expense 1,969.1 1 Rentals 87.38 Special and Temporary Services 3,836.00 Miscellaneous 1 1.06 Total , $ 6,160.94 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Forty-ninth Annual Report REPAIRS Building $ 41.33 Lands 48.31 Equipment « 83.77 Total $ 173.41 EQUIPMENT Furniture and Fixtures $ 531.90 Apparatus (Labor and Equipment) 1,672.89 Livestock , 56.03 Machinery 328.50 Books, Magazines, and Maps 5.50 Total S 2,594.82 LANDS AND BUILDINGS Land Improvements. $ 40.84 Total S 40.84 GRAND TOTAL $60,000.00 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON, " January 22, 1936 Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station FINANCIAL STATEMENT EXCLUSIVE OF FEDERAL FUNDS Statement of expenditures for the Agricultural Experiment Station of the University of Nebraska for the year ended June 30, 1935 (exclusive of Federal Funds), including expenditures for central station at Lincoln, and substations at North Plattc, Scottsbluff, Valentine, Union, and Alliance. SALARIES Regular $59,526.36 Temporary 2,709.20 Total S62.235.56 SUPPLIES Office Supplies 5 798.03 Laboratory Supplies 6,722.17 Fuel (Coal) 1,005.59 Food Stuffs 1,5-46.9-1 Educational and Recreational 117.41 Janitor and Barn Supplies 826.95 Feeding Stuffs 33,722.-! 1 Agricultural Supplies 4,560.63 Total S49.300.13 EXPENSE Office Expense and Postage S 1,534.78 Freight, Express and Drayage . 768.97 Water, Heat. Light, Power and Fuel 5,147.87 Public Printing, Advertising and Photography 2,462.09 Traveling Expense 2,132.21 Rentals . 206.60 Special and Temporary Services 21,254.20 Miscellaneous , 860.82 Total $34,367.54 REPAIRS Building $ 2,616.63 Lands 273.76 Equipment ■ ■ 4,662.94 Total S 7,553.33 EQUIPMENT Furniture and Fixtures '. $ 1,216.67 Apparatus (Labor and Equipment) 2,178.32 Live Stock 8,194.39 Machinery 1,264.26 Books 270.91 Total S13.124.55 LANDS AND BUILDINGS Land Purchase $ 6-40 Land Improvement 200.65 Original Construction 1,557.28 Additions and Improvements 78.03 Total. .... $ 1.84236 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Forty-ninth Annual Report FIXED CHARGES Refunds S 104.35 Total S 104.35 GRAND TOTAL S168.527.82 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON, January 22, 1936 Finance Secretary. [UiM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>