<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SEVENTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Institute for the Blind TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE YEARS 1907 and 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">SEVENTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Institute for the Blind TO THt GOVERNOR FOR THE YEARS 1907 and 1908 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">»* r* ■&gt; f\ *\ W -A X J^ I If- ■»' F\ I H f * I ' 1 ' I » I * , Nkbr. City. Nkhh.. Dec. 1. 1908 Hon. (ieorgo I.. Sheldon, (iovcrnor. tSir In eompfianee with Section 12, Chapter I'd. of the &gt;. of 1S9(), the Hoard of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for Blind have the honor to transmit here wit li the seventeenth nial report for that institution upon the work accomplished ng the period ending November ■«&gt;. 1008. Respectfully. Johh 0. Dktwkii.kk John W. Bteinhabt </seg>
            <seg id="p003">BI". Mokkv, Superintendent. NABEL R. MoRKV. Matron. I.1TKK AKY DEPART MEN lVi BC Cook. History and Literature ;mk Johnson, Primary MUSIC DKPAKTMKN V LoEB, Hand. Orchestra and Violin ;::::: ElMTH C. CHANDLER, Pianoforte. Chorus and Pipe &lt; &gt;rg&amp;n 1 Mil- I Kl U. DKPARTMKN1 Bkk Bruce, Piano tuning. Broom making, ete. ik Campbell, Sewing. Beadwork, Domestic Science. . Banner, Typewriting, Librarian 35.00 Jo. tK) .'.V. Ml Bertha Jensen, Assistant Matron, boy M. JENNIE Ebb, Assistant Matron, girls I . M I 1 1.( ) V KS It. Cakmodv, Kngineer. . ' . YOWELL, Teamster, etc. S. Waltkks. Niglit-watcli an Wilson, Laundret 60.00 A ist ant Engineer. Vk.kna Wilson. Assistant Laundress . 15.00 Ctnthis Pugh, Cook _'."). (M) Annv Stewart, Assistant cook l.V(M) Stella Gunn, Domestic 15.00 MaTTIE McCanN, Domestic I.").lMk Minnie Giffen, Domestic l.").(K&gt; Maude Mookk. Domestic. 1").(K» Mabel Lindeen, Domestic lo.oo Grace Pugh, Domestic l.'&gt;.()0 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nkhr. Citt, Nkhh.. Nov. 11. 1906 To the Governor The BoaH of Trait— of the Nebraska Institute for the Blind •he honor to submit the following report BThe management of the school has not changed during the The general health of the school lias been {r&lt;&gt;oil. The relations of pupils, teachers and officers has been har - moni : the efficiency of the school has steadily advanced. ■ The report of the superintendent, giving in detail th- affairs •f the school, i.s made a part of this report. Respectfully submitted, John 0. Dk.twk.ii.kk. President John W. Sik.inhakt. Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Nebraska City. Nebraska, Dec. 1. l To the Board of Trustees. Nebraska Institute for t he Blind: (lentlemen — I herewith present the 17th biennial report of the affairs of this institution. t During the past two years we have had but little sickiu rfere with work of the school. The pupils have !&gt;een inter. heir work, and as the teachers, for the most part, have shown same disposition, I feel that we have made commendable | IAt the time of writing this report several cases of scarlet f&lt; mild type have developed, hut I hope we shall not h:r us time. I Last June there was graduated from the school a datt and one hoy; Clara Holdeman. Hose Husa. Kdna K&lt;&gt; a Linstroni and (lien Lewis. LAs all are of good natural ability, and are ambitious, 1 H in why thev should not make a success in life. IAs is well known to you. our schoo' is of a threefold nature. des the usual work of the public schools, pupils here are taught ic and industrial occupations. IThe work of the literary department is practically that of the ic schools of the state, making allowance for work sueli y requires sight — drawing, for example. In the music department pupik learn to play the piano, organ, violin and various band and orchestral instruments. Vocal cul - ture is also looked after particularly when pupils show any s| aptitude in that direction. The industrial department teaches our boys and girls to do things. Boys showing the requisite talent for the work a thorough course in the principles and practice of piano tuning, at which trade numerous of our graduates are making a good living. in making, carpet weaving, hammock netting and cane seating of chairs is also taught. The girls are taught several of then cupatiom sewing, both by hand and on the sewing machine, knitting crocheting d'irninp - ind mending The older ?irls f. .11, &gt;•- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">432 LAND &lt; o.MMISsIoNKK's KKPORT I ell planned and definite course in domestic science, including ;ing and a study of its principles. This department is designed &gt;e of practical use to the girls in their homes. The kitchen isils are such as are found in the average home. The work is done in chafing dishes over gas jets or alcohol lamps, hut on od old-fashioned cook stove. The girls are taught to build the and care for the stove. They sweep and scrub the floor, and t the windows clean. Many have already learned to get a meal plete from preparing the potatoes to baking the bread. I eon - - our girls' kitchen one of the most useful features of the school. IThe requested addition to the main building for kitchen and :uv purpose* vm generously granted by the legislature and l&gt;een erected. I desire to express my appreciation of the ■ough and honest manner in which the contract was fulfilled the bulkier, Mr. .lames Welch, of this city. I consider this cture the l&gt;est and most durably built of the entire building. While the need for better kitchen and library facilities had l&gt;een felt, now that we have enjoyed these advantages for a ■nonths it is hard to understand how the old conditions were long. With numerous windows placed high in the mi!' new kitchen has an abundance of light and ready means «&gt;f ventilation, in strong contrast to the dingy room which so long - the important place for the preparation of the meals of the household. The room on the floor above the kitchen, also light and airy, contains our school library, and as it directly adjoins the school room is much more convenient than the old library room. which was situated off in one of the wings of the building, incon - venient of access. However, a small appropriation is nece - the plans drawn for the new building. These plans call for partitions on the third floor, which will provide more sani - -leeping rooms for the kitchen and dining room girls. In order to store sufficient hay to last the cows through the winter more barn room is needed. An addition to the frame barn that is necessary and would not cost much. As it now i&gt;. a portion of the hay must be stacked, or hay must be bought during the winter. Hither way entails greater expense than as though the i amount could be properly stored at the time it is Aside from these slight additions, I do not. at the present time, see any reason for thinking more buildings will l&gt;e i i r </seg>
            <seg id="p007">433 The heating plant will soon require overhauling. and 1 would suggest that in the DO distant future a modern vacuum system of heating he installed. Minor repairs are being made constantly and, of course, must continue to be made. tTwo years ago I suggested the desirability of the state's pur- B of a small piece of land adjoining our grounds, hut when came for action the owner had changed his mind, and declined t any price on it. »The returns from the few lots I have been able to rein t advantage a few acres would l&gt;e. With hardly any additional ■use these lots have furnished an abundance of fresh vegetable - ng the summer, and nearly half enough potatoes to last through school vear. II desire to express my appreciation of the support ren&lt; at all times by our Governor, as well as by the various members ■our honorable bodv, the Hoard of Trust' Respectfully submitted. .1. S. MoREY. Superintei: </seg>
            <seg id="p008">434 KKHS AND TEACHERS, NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR BLIND I : ibge I.. Sheldon tiuvprnor Ho\liL&gt; ()K THUS E\ (&gt;. Uetweilek \ W. Stkinhaht. EKT B. WlNDHAM. President Secretary OFFICERS R. MOBB1 . A. M. ! I'nion) ABEL R. MOREY Superintendent and Matron Matron TBACB1 Literary Department Nebr. Institute for Blind) History and Literature me .Jon Nebr. Institute for Blind) Primary Music Department ■Loeh (Heidelberg, (Jermany) .... Violin. Orchestra and Band th ('. Chandi.kh (Chicago Musical College) Pianoforte. Pipe Organ. Chorus work. etc. Industrial Department Clahk Bhice (Ohio Institute for Blind) Piano tuning. Carpet weaving, etc. Ekfie Campbell (Illinois Institute for Blind) Sewing. Beadwork. Domestic Science c. .1. Hammer (Grand Island Business College) Typewriting, Librarian Bertha Assistant Matron — Boys </seg>
            <seg id="p009">435 ENROLLMENT FOR THK BIENNIUM December 1, 1 «&gt;&lt;)&lt;; to November 30, H»()s k Pupils Age 1'. O. Address Nativity Date of in-. Maurice.... 12 Norfolk, Neb Iowa Sept. Hi erson. Edward 15 Omaha, Neb... Nebraska .Oct. "&gt; Auhrecht. Klsie Rrinson. Nellie Brown, George. Burns, Joseph Cave, Herbert Conies. Emma Coaad, Albert.. Coiad, (ieoii; Ouster, Elisabeth Davis. Grace 17 So. Omaha, Neb... Nebraska. Sept. 17 24 Dunbar, Neb. .Indiana Jan. 2 .") Lincoln. Neb Sept. ll&gt; l(i Lincoln. Neb Nebraska. Jan. 7 17 Basile Milk, Neb. Nebraska .Oct. 2 13 Mason City. Neb. Nebraska. Oct. 30 11 Lincoln. Neb .Nebraska .Sept. 10 16 Lincoln, Neb Nebraska Sept. 10 ii Omaha, Neb April 31 Franklin, Neb.. Illinois. Sept. 17 20 Omaha, Neb. Missouri Jan. 30 20 Havelock. Neb. .Nebraska. Sept. 2 13 Omaha, Neb. .. .Nebraska. Sept. 20 15 Pawnee Citv. NebNebraska Nov. &lt;» 1905 MM 17 1907 1899 I '....7 1902 1902 1907 MMI7 Ellis, Ruth 1«M)7 Eder. Frank eke. Ludwig iey. Fern ism; 1«HW Fleming. Kenneth Flo.,,1. Axel 9 Kearney. Neb . Nebraska Sept. 19 33 Pender, Neb Sweden... Sept. 22 In Omaha. Neb . Nebraska .Sept. 16 17 Springview. Neb. Nebraska Sept. 19 27 Blair, Neb Ohio . . Sept. 16 23 Nelson. Neb. Illinois. Oct. 2 28 Lawrence. Neb . . Wyoming.Feb. 14 10 Friend. Neb. Nebraska .Sept. 30 40 Butte, Neb . . Nebraska. Meh. 2 12 DuBois, Neb Nebraska. Sept. l(i 15 Rush City, Minn. Nebraska. Nov. :i 10 Heaver City Neb. Nebraska .Sept. 19 10 Arcadia, Neb ..Nebraska. Oct. 10 1 * M M ' hart. Bruce Giereau, Henry (lish. Clarence Gordon, Bessie i:g. Hubert en, John 1903 1902 ls'C 1 N,M ) 190.* 1907 (Iriffith. Irene UM&gt;7 Hauilow. Edward Harris. Lvle 1004 Hawlev. Leo Hendricks. Delia. Hill. Ethel. 7 Omaha, Neb. . Nebraska. Feb 27. Ifi So. Omaha. Net). Nebraska. Nov. 25, ."}."&gt; Nebr. City. Neb Nebraska. Nov. 2!t. 21 Callaway. Neb. Nebraska. Sept. !t. 17 Albion, Neb Nebraska. Sept. 14, 13 So. Omaha. Neb Nebraska Sept . 20. 23 Omaha Neb Nebraska Sent 12 KM IS MMMi Eabaugh, \V. E lenian. Clara, on. Lloyd . . ISDN 1!M)2 1903 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">I. AM) &lt; OMM1SS1ONKKS KEPORT 436 ion. James 17 Lincoln Noli Nebrask t. 10 Nov. 13 30 12 Lincoln. Net) it. 16, 1906 Sept. 16 Journey. Wallace. Kempley. Karl 17 Arapaboe, Neb. ..Iowa Jan. l. 1901 .Jan. 1 l'MU 13 Grand Island. Neblowa . Oct. 12, 190s itton. Nel). ... Nebraska .Sept. 23, 1905 Oct. 12 I '.HIS E. William tz. Kdna *ler. ' i Sept. 23 is College View. Neb. Nebraska. Jan. 4. 1MI7 i Jan. 4 1897 15 Deabler, Neb Nebraska. Sept. 28, 1907 15 Deshler, Neb Nebrask I Sept. 2s 19 Rain. Neb Nebraska Sept . (i. 1899 1«.) Rain. Neb Nebrask 1 899 Leake. Tommy (ilen ... 12 Klin Creek. Net) NebraskaSept.lt&gt;. 1907 12 Kim Creek. Neb Nebrask I Sept. 16 1907 20 Beatrice. Neb Nebraska .Sept. 13, 1899 20 Beatrice Nel. Nebrask i Sept. 13 20 Hershey. Neb Nebraska Nov. 10. 1897 in Fairbury, Neb pt. 16, 1907 Hershey Nebrask i Nov. 10 Linstrom. Anna Lilley. Elena. 20 1897 Sept. lti 1907 Iiard. Klizal»etli wick. Lew une. Walter... nig. Beulah . . ford. Henry lips. Lab 11 IMattsnmuth. Neb. Missouri .Mch. 3, 1902 Missouri . Mch. 3 17 MeCook, Neb Nebraska Feb. 27. 1901 Nebrask ».Feb. 27 l'.tOl 14 Omaha. Neb Iowa . Sept. is. I9M S .Julian. Neb Nebraska Oct. 31, 1906 Omaha. Neb Iowa 14 Sept. is H.04 Nebrask i.Oct. 31 15 Ashland. Neb Nebraska Sept. 10, 1901 Nebrask a Sept. 10 19 Kenesaw. Neb Nebraska Nov. 10. 1906 Nebrask i Nov. 10 l'.MK E. Minnie. . nson. (iail. . u'ch. Matilda le. Harr\ is Wvmore. Neb . Missouri . Sept. 10. 1902 I Omaha. Neb Nov. 10, 1906 Missouri .Sept. 10 1902 Nov. 10 1'tON Hi Button, Neb. Nebraska .Sept. 18, 1906 Nebrask i Sept. 18 li»OS 26 26 Lushton. Neb. Nebraska May li. 1904 Lush ton, Neb Nebrask i. May (. 1««)4 Rothery. (leorge Rupencamp. Nina. Sawyer. Bessie. . . . Schneider. Henry . Sheekler. Harry. Smith. I^na 18 Omaha. Neb . Nebraska Sept. 16, 1905 Nebrask ;t Sept. Hi Hi Omaha. Neb Nebraska Sept . 23. 190&lt;&gt; Nebrask i Sept. 2-i loot; 13 Fairbury. Neb. Nebraska .Sept. 13, 1904 Nebrask ;i Sept. ].i. 1904 23 MeCook, Neb. Russia Nov. 19. 1903 Russia Nov. 19. 1903 11 Nebr. City. Neb. Nebraska Oct. 24. 1904 Nebrask i.Oct. 24 1904 22 Lyons, Neb Nebraska Sept. 13, 1904 Lyons. Neb Nebrask 1904 •x Sept. 13. 15 Omaha. Neb Nebraska. Oct. •"&gt;. 190s Lyons. Neb Nebraska Sept. 21. 190s (i Dodge. Neb . Nebraska Sept . 2S. l«»07 Smith. Harry Smith. Walter . Snyder. Mary Swab, Jacob Tatum, Ralph. . Taylor, Dorothy iell. May ' . Waldren, Charlotte ;. "Walter. . . 15 Omaha. Neb Nebrask a. Oct. "). Lyons. Neb Nebrask ii Sept. LM L908 (i Dodge. Neb Nebrask ii Sept. 28 1907 41 Hastings. Neb. . Kansas. . .Jan. s. l ( .t07 41 Hastings. Neb. Bloomh'eld. Neb Lincoln. Neb. Kansa .Jan 19 Bloomfield. Neb Nebraska Jan. 4. 190s ."&gt; Lincoln. Neb Nebraska. Sept. lti. 1907 Nebrask a. Jan. 4 1908 \\\ t .Sept. 10 L907 21 So. Omaha. Neb. So. Dak Sept. 20. 1906 Sept. 20 10 Carroll. Neb. Iowa Nov. 3, 1905 Nov. 3 17 Omaha. Neb Nebraska. Sept. 17 1905 •ulski. Fred :&gt; Valley. Neb Nebraska Sept. Hi </seg>
            <seg id="p011">437 GRADUATES OF THK NEBRASKA INSTITUTE I BLIND Year Name Gradu - ated in I'. O. Addic taming Aaberg. Albert.. L 1886 Kazile, Net) Adams. Nellie.... L. 1890 Nebr. City. Neb.. Tecumaeh, Neb... Battle Creek. Mich Nebr. City. Neb.. Jacksonville, 111 Omaha, Nel&gt; 1),,, Bail. .lames B. ('. 1898 Baker. Alice V. P. T. 1898 Bell. Bertram... . Y. 1S«»7 Beuter. Harry. . B. 1897 Botsford, Anna . L ls'.ts Lawrence. Kansa.- Nebr. City. Neb.. Madrid. Neb. Bruce. Clark L 1886 Brown. Gertrude. I- 1890 Burns. James T. 1898 Keneeaw, Neb. Marquette. Neb ( Iraf, Neb 1). Bush. S. .1 T. B. 1&lt;)(M) Campbell. Lucy.. L. 1886 Clark. Roy. L. I*. 1899 Lincoln, Neb.. Coiad, Harry.. . L. T. is ( .i4 Nebr. City. Net). . Long Island. Kane Brock, Neb. Coiad, Sarah.. . . L. 1894 a Coryell, Levi L. 1888 dim, Emma L. Neniaha. Neb. Lincoln. Neb.. Lincoln. Neb. . . . Alexandria. Neb. Rapid City. 8. I) Stella. Neb Crowder, William B. 1898 Curtis. Frederick. L. 1894 DeLong, Clara. .. L. 1886 Deraiileau. Renii. P. T. 1899 Duncan. Sylvia. . L. 1899 Duehohn. Christian L. Louisville. Neb.. Blair. Neb.. Gillette. L. B T. l'.M)7 (iish. Clarence.. . L. I. 1907 Nelson. Neb Lincoln, Neb.. Gregg. William.. L. 1886 Harmon. Mary... L. 1886 Buffalo Gap, 8. 1). Omaha. Neb Haynes, Frank... I'. 1903 Hegel. Paul T. 1899 Hexthausen. Hans L. T. 1'. B.l'tOl ■leman. Clara. L. I. 1906 abaugh. Wm. T. B. 1902 ingsworth. Ferd. L. B. 1898 Nebr. City. Neb.. North Plane. Neb Diller. Neb Hollingsworth, Nora L. IMM) Helmut. Isabella. L 1894 Omaha, Neb. Callaway, Neb </seg>
            <seg id="p012">\I&gt; COMMISSIONER'S KKI'ORT 438 Genoa. Neb Fremont. Neb. . . Xebr. City, Net).. Nebr. City. Neb.. Nebr. City. Neb. Wilber, Neb i; College View. Neb Cozad. Neb. I Clarence B. 1897 Red Cloud. Neb Beatrice, Neb. Hershey. Neb. Herehey, Neb. Lewis, Glen. L. I.T. 1!M)S Erom, Anna. L. I. 1908 rum. Christina L. I. 1M06 . Delia.. L. I. 1904 L. I. HMM Burr. Neb Mathews. Golds I Bo. Omaha. Neb .Nebr. City. Neb. Madison. Neb Nebr. City. Neb. Rogers. Neb . . 1). .is,- 1 Miller. Stella L 1896 c( Martin. Nora L 1'. V. 1901 !.. P. 1806 L 1". 1899 Mullins. Julia. 1 I Noble. Bell i useil •&gt;. Ida L 1901 .larie.. . L P. 1898 Page. Adalbert... L T. B. 1899 ish, Mer. . L. T. 1898 Stromsburg, Neb Burress. Neb L. T. 1896 1). Quandt. Gustav I ice Regelin. Minnie 1 KB, John. L. T. B. V.1902 Anna. L. I. 1908 MOB, Arthur. B. 1900 Shike. Ray. L. V. T. 1900 Stinger. May.. Deceased Deceased Eater. Kft] L. 1894 ick. Maud.. L 1890 . Nona L 1'. I- 1908 Yes L. P. 1. lfHHi White, Owen L B. H»04 Yes Battle Creek. Mich Omaha. Neb Yes n. Austin... L 1MM na, Charles L. P. C. 1908 Ye3 L — Literary Dept.; B Broom-making ; V — Violin; P— Piano; -p p- . ninp- C Cl- rinet • I Industrie' DeDt Johnson, Ingwald B. Johnson, Jennie L. P. L8M Clarence T. L. France- L. 1898 Josephine L. 1S&lt;)4 Knapp, Anna.. L. P. 1901 nta, Kdna. L I. 1'. l ( .t0^ Lanham, Alma L. 1896 1896 is'*; M, Aulev. .Mary 1.. P. 1898 Miller. E. J. L. 1894 1894 Guide R.uk. Ncl -alem. Neb lS'.M Grant, Neb 1899 Omaha, Neb. 1888 Beatrice, Nel&gt;. Grand Island. Nel 1902 Los Angeles, Cal 1906 Wolbach. Neb... 1900 Peru, Neb... L. 1899 Gering, NH Nebr. City, Neb Omaha. Nt-1 Albion, Neb </seg>
            <seg id="p013">439 NEBRASKA INSTITUTK FOK THE BLIND EJufing the past two years pupils have us subjects and trade? as follows: ing, New York point }&gt;een I in true t« j Heading, Line letter tting. New York point ewriting Language Grammar Arithmetic Geography Kted States History ient Historv s Mediaeval History Rhetoric ' l'hvsics II Chemistry Kcunomv Zoology 4 Physiology Algebra 6 11 &lt; ;; 15 l» 4 Cornet i Other hand instruments Voice culture i Eus singing 1 theory uonv l'oint music Piano tuning Broom making Carpet weaving Hammock netting I 4 In. met ry Eoforte Organ </seg>
            <seg id="p014">440 LAND 0OMMI88IONER'8 KK1MRT KFour pain hoots, 1 cap, '.i fascinators, 1 handkerchief bi receivers. 4 jackets. 7 yards lace. 1 pair mittens. 1 shawl. A .slippers. 1 scarf. 2 set mat:-. Raffia and Reed Work Thirty-eight baskets, .i hags. 2 frames. 15 hats. L3 mat Head Work t Eighty baskets. «.t hall holders, 42 bracelets. '.V2 boxes, 45 brooni - 27 candle sticks. 17 chairs. 28 cups. 4 sets doll furniture 18 gobletfl, '_' guards. 2 letter cams, 15 mats. 4S necklaces. lapkin rings. 7 pitchers. 2 pockets. 2 purses, '■'&gt; pair sandals. ."&gt; 2 vases. .'&lt; watches. 8 watch ca ■ ti caps. 2 curtains. 1 doll suit, 2 dresses, 12 dust cloths, 2 flags. 31 mops, 4 ( ,t pillow I 4 skirts, ti pieces underwear. 10 towels. 4S tea towels. rash cloths. Brooms, Hammocks, etc §(&gt;ne hundred and eight dozen of brooms. 150 yards of carpet. a large number of fly nets and hammocks; besides, a consider - mt of cane seating chairs was done by this department. Sewing Sewing (nann 1! tng (machine) ting heting 1'. Raffi;i Bead work Domestic Science ARTICLES MADK BY PUPILS Ul KIM. THK BIKWIVM ENDING NOV. HO. l'.IUS Knitting and Crocheting </seg>
            <seg id="p015">-|«q psjBiuns'^ ■/- 6061 IC jbj^ 'Xouaioy 7- L ' Z i - rcz- I l~ 71 Z i n / 5 c c. ■■: S c — - tr — -m n m x •" 5 5 — 5 ■" — • — i Vl55;:-S5 ?.5 :§S§|| | papoadxg M x-x / [' : »'M. ■M C. I- X X X KHil uoiivudaiddy £--■ -/ i()6I I uoiiBudojd -&lt;1b 'AauaiagaQ r^s^^H^iiisg^^iii* r i- / X S r — — ~ ~ — — r: n — s. — x. "i i- &gt;" "5 -r * w tl-JZI-h-'iriC-- '" - - — I- ~ M 9061 'pw*n 5§i'ir§~[i— •" V"! ?i -2 £ ~ rl ri Vi U 9061 I SS£8 1 ** -i — i - 21 S £: r: ,1 = g .^ 5 § S S SS5SSSSSSS 5 '"Ofil uoiiBud aace us — i- ~ ■" x x. n ■" z — -r -i — i- = ■* | ,),)([ 'MMpg •• n — re re </seg>
            <seg id="p016">442 TABLI SHOWING CLASSIFICATION OF ALL EXPENDITURES Y.-:ir ending Rot. 30, 1907 Classification- Salaries and wagM latuffa 110,156 21 362 85 473 40 29. hi Bt — fresh, dried and canned t. fish and poultry 142.51 829.87 JOCS 246.91 including beans, rice etc 282.07 Er and syrup and coff« 'llaneou^ 207.30 4(1 57 349 35 tationery and printing Bhing, bedding, dry goods and furniture I and light 175.65 2,707.37 Kcal attendance, medical and surgical supplies id improvements 1.470 20 Paints and oils 97.30 Tubular fire eat ape Water rent NOO.OO 344 35 Telephone S4 25 '■. musical instruments and supplies k feed S3 79 Etion to main building 'llaneous 3.701 OO 524 64 $24,018 33 Year ending Nov. 30, 1908 Salaries and wages ;&lt;tuffs (4.30 390 . 03 sr 335.56 16.58 Fruit — fresh, dried and canned Meat, fish and poultry 172.85 848.80 151.85 including beans, rice ip and sugar etc 221 . 35 253.49 Tea and coffee </seg>
            <seg id="p017">443 Miscellaneous Books, stationery and printing Clothing, l&gt;edding, dry goodfl and furniture Fuel and light Medical attendance, medical and surgical supplies. Repairs and improvements 228 4(1 177 07 Paints and oil Addition to main building r rent Telephone Music, musical instruments and supplies Stock feed I'llaneou STATEMENT SHOWING THK AMOUNT OF CASH RECEIVED AND PENDED DCHING THK BIENNIAL TERM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908 1(F.( EIPT Balance on band Dec. 1. 1&lt;M)6 BroonH sold. . Twine and rings 55 IS Els and beadwork ipts from scales t slates 95 21 Carpet weaving Carpel warp Hammock Point and typewriting paper AppL 105 &lt;k&gt; Hugs 1S6.00 Calves 10.50 Car fare and clothing for indigent pupils from counties . . 13.89 er rental 10.00 itoes '26.30 Cane seating.. 3 25 ellaneous articles 32. 44 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p018">444 I. AM) COMMISSIONERS HKl'oKT EXPENDITURES •uoc-k eord and rings Jit and expreaa 115 00 1 1 supplier (1 bead wive grinder. 31 U Ket junior tlrill len cultivator shelter 7.00 ■ fries ing Printing i state fair exhibits ■ • for chain 1 . 35 Breeding stock 12. (K) tur on grounds tal of lot 12.60 9.25 Car fare, official t rips of superintendent.. Exchange 17 17 1 05 •llaneous articles ss Balance on hand Novenil&gt;er 30, 1908. rOLLOWJNG PIMATE OK REQUIREMENTS KUK THK ENSUING HIKNNlr M y of su|&gt;erinten(lent »o.O&gt;"i U" v of matron 1.000 (Id laries &lt;).000.00 ■ loves" wages 7.500.00 Maintenance 19,800.00 General repairs 3.000.00 Addition to barn and completing new wing as per plans sOO.OO 144,700.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">445 BTATEMENT SHOWING RECEIPTS 20 qts. blackberries at 5e 1 (M t Sweet corn. ... 2.00 Grapes 2 00 5 . 00 bu. tomatoes at 50c • &gt; 1908 1!&gt;()N To rent 5.25 160 bu. potatoes at 62e.. 19.25 'A tons beel 5.00 L'O bu. tomatoes at *1 00. JO (Ml 10 liu. peat-lies at 50c 5 00 Sweet corn 2 oo Cucumbers and squash 5 00 To balance 1*3.20 Cabbage 5 00 1198.70 18 70 fTKMKNT OF NEBRASKA INSTITUTE KOU THE BLIND IN M ( I ITH THK AMEKICAN PRINTING HOUSE Kim THE BLIND, DINNING JUNE 1, 1907 AND ENDING NOVEMBER M). 1908 tutor ■ 1, To balance.. $:«.2l : l. To imlse . . . 115.00 . 6. To mcb 4.80 1907 1907 1907 Dr. June 1, To balance.. $33.21 By quota, 1908 07 II By quota, 1906 07 June 1. To incise... 115.00 . 6. To indse.. 4.80 28, To tncbe... 60. K&gt; 1908 Dec. 28, To nwlse. HO 10 1908 1908 HI0N Jan. 13, To mclse. . . 13 75 13, To mdae. . . 13. 75 By quota, 1907 08 1 By quota, 19(17 06 121 26, To mrtfi . . 7. 7"&gt; April 2. To indse 40 25 1 2, To mdsc 46.25 By balance By balance 9 24 $290.10 ■ 10 May 1, To balance... 9.24 Nov. 14, To nulse 44.55 By quota. 1908-00 120 Nov. 30, To balance.. 67.01 AND EXPENDITURES &lt;&gt;\ TWO KCBEfl Of LAM). RENTED, K)l&lt; THE 1'EABB 1!MI7 \ N : I) 19 rent 15.00 ■"&gt;&lt;&gt; bu. potatoes at sn&lt;- 140 00 Is 6.00 1 ton cane .', ihi </seg>
            <seg id="p020">446 CHADl'ATINd EXERCISES HK)7 Friday. June 14th. at Two O'clock ■ure — Lustspiel . Keler ■■ Bela Orchestra eation Piano Quartette — Zampa Herolcl Edna Kooats, Leona Jenning:-. Glen Lewis, Henry Schneider ing by touch • ieen of the Earth. Pinsuti Henry Schneider letrv of the Horizon Edna Koontz Serenade The Old Church Organ. W. Paris Chambers Band Song — The Nightingale's Song Nevin Kdna Koontz tiomic \ alue Anna Linstrom Spring Flowers Waltz Song Schamann Senior Chorus Industrial Exhibit School Organ — Andantino . L. H. Salome (has. Zadina lution of the Piano Clarence Gish Presentation of Diplomas John O. Detweiler, President Board of Trustees Hymn — The Spacious Firmament School Benediction </seg>
            <seg id="p021">447 ANNUAL CONCERT Thursday Evening, June 13th. r.»()7. at F.ight O'eloek ssional March &lt; leo. I.. T Orchestra n — Triumphal March Dudley Buck Edna Koonti Violin—Bohemian GW W. i'alfe Willie Currie a, Boat Song. Neidl ripay I.ove Boaf Victor Herheti Hoys' Chorus n — Introduction to 3rd Act of Lohengrin W Charles Zadina Trio — I.e Reve Goltermann Helen Morey, A. Loeb, Jessie 1). Knierick Bong — Carmena W Edna Koonti Jupiter Symphony — Allegro Vivace Mozart String Orchestra Piano Quartette — Der Freischutz \\ Edna Koonti, Miss Emerick, Cnaa. Zadina. Miss Wolfe Toy Symphony Hadyn Allegro Deciso. Minuetto. Trio. Finale Mixed Choi </seg>
            <seg id="p022">448 GRADUATING KXKRC1SKS Wednesday Evening, June I Oth, 1908 at Kight O'clock n Festival March Ralph Kinder Edna Koontz Essay A Little I^eaven Clara Holdeman Piano spring Song Mendeli (ilen I^ewis :iti«ni The Chimes of Amsterdam. Ml*. George W. Paull Husa iination — Stand for Something. 0. S. Marden (ilen Lewis A Gyp«y Maiden. 1 Henry Parker Edna Koontz Essay -The Quest of the Unknown Anna Luutrom Essay- A Hridge from Dreamland Kdna Koontz Trombone Calvary P. Rodney (lien Lewis - History Clara Holdeman Piano \ alse Hrilliante. Op. M, No. 1 Chopin Kdna Koontz Class Prophecy Husa Class Poem Anna Linstioni Presentation of Diplomas by Pres. John 0. Detweiler Class Song </seg>
            <seg id="p023">449 ANN I A 1. ( ( &gt;N&lt; I. HI Tuesday Kvening, June 9, 1908, Eight O'clock American Fantasia Theo. .M . Tocani Orchestra Piano— Valae de Concert M Lewis Ludwick Adoration M. Telrna Kdna Knout z Violin — Legende . \\ ieniawski Helen Morey Chorus The Miller's Wooing.. K. Fanning Senior Chorus Organ — Torchlight March (niili Kdna Koontz Cornet Duet — The Mermaids Pinsuti I^wis Ludwick, Mr. Loeb The Great White Throne . \\ . M. 8. Brown String Orchestra Vocal Duet— To Our Boat Frances All Henry Schneider, Lewis Ludwick Concerto in D minor — Allegro .Mozart Kdna Koontz, Miss Wolfe </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>