<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SECOND BI-ENNIAL REPORT Nebraska Forestation Commission APPOINTED BY THE GOVERNOR</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Nebraska Forestation Commission APPOINTED BY THE GOVERNOR DECEMBER 1916 IIACON FKCSS LINCOLN. •»■■■ </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Bers of Nebraska Forestation Commission Appointed by the Governor, 1915 Terms expire 1917 CARL ROHDE, Chairman Columbus, Nebraska A. H. METZGER, Rolf, Nebraska WOODRUFF BALL, Secretary Valentine, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT Hon. John H. Morehead, Governor, and Members of the Thirtx - fifth Session of the Xebraska Legislature: We, your Commission of Forestation. have the honor to sub - mit for your consideration, the following re]xirt with recommen - dations and outlines of such legislation as we deem timely and expedient, accompanied by explanations thereof. During the past two years, we have endeavored to keep in touch with forestry work within our State and do such publicity work as the opportunity afforded. The publicity work we have done has had to do with the preparing of articles to appear in our State papers and attend meetings where we have interested citizens and organizations in the needs for this work and showing them the results that might accrue to our citizens and state, were forestry more widely practised. Two distinct areas now remain in the Xebraska National Forest. One area located in Thomas County was designated as the Loup River Division and the area in Cherry County was designated the Xiobrara Division — both of the Xebraska Xational Forest. The creation of the Xebraska Xational Forest was pri - marily due to the persistent and untiring efforts of the late Doctor Charles E. Bessey of the State University. To Doctor Bessey be - longs all the credit for their creation and during his life time, he t(X)k a keen interest in the successful outcome of the work con - ducted thereon by the Xational Government. In view of the fore - going facts, we felt that Doctor Bessey's labors should receive recognition. Wherefore, we suggested to the Bureau of Forestry that they officially change the designation of the Loup River Divis - ion and Xursery thereon, to the Bessey Division and Bessey Xurs - ery. thus providing a most befitting memorial and pcq&gt;etuating the memory of Doctor Bessey. We are pleased to advise that the change suggested has been made. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT Acting upon our further suggestion, the Bureau of Forestry this past summer has seen fit to rename the Xiobrara Nursery, and it is now officially designated as the Morton Nursery, a memorial to the life work of the Honorable J. Sterling Morton. We are pleased to say that the additional appropriation secured from our National Congress thru the efforts of your Commission in 1914, has been continued. With these additional funds, the Gov - ernment has erected and completed a second nursery. During the past Spring, the first seeds were planted at this, the Morton Nurs - ery, and shortly the seedling trees available thru this second nursery, will enable the Government to double its afforestration operations. During the past season upon the Bessey Reserve, the C'vernment transplanted and set out in the hills eight hundred res of coniferous trees. When one considers the successful out - come of the afforesting operations of the Government whereby they have conclusively proven that they can and are growing trees upon these reserves upon a strictly commercial basis, it behooves our citizens to impress their members of Congress that ample funds should be provided for carrying on this work. Since the creation of the Nebraska National Forest, the ques - tion has been agitated as to whether or not these reserves contained agricultural lands and that the progress of our State was being hindered by reason of the fact that homesteading and the settle - ment of these lands was prohibited under the rules of the Bureau of Forestry. That this question might be equitably settled, your Commission induced the Government Iiureau of Soils to make a soil survey of both the Bessey and Xiobrara Divisions. This report has been filed and is to the effect that neither one of these Divisions contain land that can be classified as agricultural. We take this opportunity of calling the attention of our citi - zens to the fact that the Bureau of Forestry is conducting forage grass experiments upon many of their Forest Reserves in the West with a view to increasing the live stock grazing capacity of these Reserves. Such work might well be undertaken by the Bu - reau in this State to the material benefit of the entire Sand Hill region, which covers practically one-fourth of Nebraska's area ; and were our members in Congress surficientlv urged to provide the </seg>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA COMMISSION ON FORESTATION 5 necessary funds, there can be no question but what the Bureau would gladly attempt these experiments in this state. I'rior to this year, no authentic data has been compiled rela- tive to the acreage of standing timber in this State. This Spring, at the request of your Commission. Mr. Mellor, Secretary of the State Board of Agriculture, had included upon his forms used by the Precinct Assessors for the gathering of agricultural statistics questions that will in the future give us this information. These ques - ii&lt;ms pertain to the number of acres of native standing timber and the number of acres of planted timber. In time, this information should prove of value and interest. As with other questions, so with that of forestry Our present antiquated State Constitution forbids the enactment of much salu - tary forestry legislation. With a revised or amended Constitution, provision could be made for the exemption from all taxes were lands planted to forest trees. This exemption to apply to these lands and their products until the forest trees thereon became merchantable timber. Then as marketed, be taxed as personal prop - erty, thus encouraging the individual in the production of forest trees. Much could be done and should be done in this State in pre - serving the native standing timber upon what is termed the Pine Ridge of Nebraska, for were protection afforded these timbered lands under State ownership, it would go far in regulating the flow of those streams having their sources in Northwestern Ne - t.raska. In fact, this State might well consider the establishment of small State Forest Reserves in this Pine Ridge Section, as is done by so many of our Eastern States. In addition to the value of the standing timber upon these areas, there is the fact that thev would serve as recreation grounds and a habitat of small game and birds: and with the cooperation of the State Fish Commission, ideal haunts for our disciples of Isaak Walton. Such legislation as we have to propose you will find appended to this report. There is nothing new, sensational or unusual in what we are asking. It is the result of a painstaking survey upon the part of your Commission and in submitting it, we sincerely </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT hope that this L put the State of Dated at Y .egislature by the passage of our proposed Bills, will Nebraska upon the forestry map of this Nation. Respectfully submitted. State Forestatiox Commission Cari. Rohde, Chairman, Columbus, Nebraska. Rolf, Nebraska. W'iKioRiFF Ball, Secretary, Valentine. Nebraska. akntine. Nebraska. December I, 1916. A. H. Mf.tzgkr, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">A BILL For AX ACT TO provide for the creation of a State Forestation Com - mission and defining its duties. Be it Enacted by the People of the State of Xcbraska: Section i. There is hereby created the State Forestation Com - mission of Nebraska, to consist of three members to be appointed by the Governor. Persons so appointed shall be such that have a knowledge of and an interest in forestry work and development in Nebraska and shall serve without pay or compensation for their time spent in fulfilling the purposes of this act. Within thirtv (30) days after this Act shall have become effective, the Governor shall appoint three persons as members of said Commission for terms of one, two and three years, respectively, designating the term each shall serve, and thereafter, appointments shall be for a term of three! 3") years each. The Governor shall be ex-officio member of the Commission. Sec. 2. It shall be the duty of the Commission to studv forestry conditions and methods of development thereof throughout the State; collect information and data pertaining thereto; cooperate with and assist all citizens, organizations and communities within the State in forestry work : disseminate forestry information thru reports, recommendations and such publicity methods as the Com - mission may deem expedient. The Commission shall, on or before the 31st day of November preceding the meeting of the Legisla - ture, prepare and file with the Governor a full and complete report of its work during the preceding bienimm. Sec. 3. Within sixty (60) days after their appointment, the Commission shall meet with the Governor and organize by select - ing one of their number as Chairman and one as Secretary. There - after, meetings of the Commission shall be held at the call of tb* Chairman. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 EXPLANATION- OF COMMISSION' P.ILL In presenting for your consideration the foregoing P.ill that provides for the creation in this State of a permanent Forestration Commission, we do so, fully recognizing that there is a sentiment among many of our citizens antagonistic to the creation of am and all State Commissions. Nevertheless, they continue to multiplv in numbers, not only in our own State, but in all the States and the National Government, for there are and will be new problems aris - ing that must be met and solved as a matter of public policy : and under our present form of Government and bur present antiquatei! Constitution a Commission provides the sole solution. The question of scientific forestrv is older than our Nation. hence, we are not asking the creation of this Commission in b?half of a present day fad — rather your MppOft is solicited in behalf of a policy that among all the progressive people of our Nation, is recog - nized as a necessity. With our rapidly diminishing timber lands, the question of their replenishment becomes of vital interest. Time is the principal factor that has to do with the growing and maturing of merchantable timber. We cannot hope to make Nebraska a large producer of timber, but if properly encouraged and abetted, we mav hope for an increased area of standing merchantable trees, which will accrue to the material benefit of our State. At the present time, thirty-two of Nebraska's sister states have seen the need and wisdom of providing for the care of their stand - ing timber and the planting and maintenance of additional tim - bered areas. These states all maintain a Forestrv Commission under diversified titles with a State Forester. There are now approximately twenty million acres of land owned and adminis - tered as State Forests. South Dakota, to the North of us, Iowa on the East and Kansas, on the South, now maintain State For - estrv Commissions and State Foresters. In the creation of a Forestration Commission, we present to you a question that has to do principally with the future. This generation can hope to derive but small direct benefits. However, has riot the time arrived, when we should legislate to advance the interests of this same future ? </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NEBRASKA COMMISSION ON FORESTATION 9 We know that this proposed legislation merits and has the active support of a large number of our individual citizens and organizations within our State. The need of a State Organization, that may serve to direct and foster the efforts of those citizens engaged in forestry work, is apparent, if their labor is to be brought to a successful consummation. . </seg>
            <seg id="p010">For AN ACT TO authorize the State Hoard of Educational Lands and Funds to exchange any State Educational Lands within the lim - its of any L'nited States Forest Reserve in this State for lands of equal acreage and value held by the L'nited States Govern - ment in such Reserves, and to provide for the leasing of such lands thus acquired. Be It Enacted by the People of the State of Xcbraska: Section i. The State Board of Educational Lands and Funds is hereby authorized and empowered to enter into agreements with the officers and agents of the L'nited States Government for the exchange of any State Educational Lands lying within any Fed - eral Forest Reserve within this State for other lands of equal areas and value belonging to the L'nited States and within anv Federal Forest Reserve. And the said Board of Educational Lands an&lt;l Funds is hereby authorized to convey any such lands to the L'nited States by deed as provided in Section 5851 of the Revised Statutes for 19 1 3. upon the execution by the L'nited States Government of a patent to the State of Nebraska for the United States lands so exchanged. Sec. 2. Any lands so received and patented from the L'nited States shall be held as a part of the Educational Lands of this State and shall be subject to all existing laws pertaining to Mch lands. Provided, that such lands so received in exchange shall onlv be subject to lease for terms not exceeding five 1 5 ) years with the privilege of renewing for a like term at the option of the Board. Such leases may also include the right to the lessee of removing all improvements he may have erected on the land. Sec. 3. The Board of Educational Lands and Funds is further authorized and empowered to secure from the holders of anv leases or sale contract of any Educational lauds lyir.jj in anv Federal Forest Reserve surrenders, relinquishments or cancella - tion of such leases or sale contracts. If the Board and the holder </seg>
            <seg id="p011">NEBRASKA COMMISSION ON FORESTATIOX 11 of any such leases or sale contract cannct agree upon the term for such surrender, relinquishment or cancellation thereof, th Board is hereby empowered and authorized to take over the inter est of such holder by appropriation as provided for the comlemna tion of private property for State Institutions as set forth in Ari 14, Chap. 74 of the Revised Statutes for 19 13. EXPLANATION OF RILL FOR EXCHANGE OF LANDS. This bill is submitted for your consideration and enactmen by reason of the fact that within the boundaries of the presen two Divisions of the Nebraska National Forest, there are locatc&lt; sixteen State School Sections of 640 acres each and lieu se'.ec tion lands of 308 acres. Due to their arbitrary location, unde the law, these sections are isolated one from the others. L'nde the Presidential Proclamation setting; aside these Forest Reserve the contiguous lands are all directly under the management am supervision of the Government Bureau of Forestry. The Bureau pursuing its established policy of afforesting these lands, will in time to come, plant to trees all the Government lands surrounding the State School Sections. The Bureau of Forestry being withou jurisdiction over the State Lands, will perforce be compelled to fence these sections each to itself. With a full understanding of the character of the soil and topography of these sections, it will be readily understood that such action upon the part of the Government represented by the Bureau of Forestry, will materially reduce the leasing value of these State lands, if it does not entirely destroy it. Again, without policing, these areas will prove a constant men - ace the afforesting operations of the Government, owing to their unguarded condition, the growth of grass thereon and its resultant liability to prairie fires. On the other hand, the State, by effecting this exchange o lands, will acquire a compact body of land of such an area (ap - proximately 10.000 acres) that its leasing value needs must b«. greatly enhanced. Safeguarded as is this proposed exchange b the provisions of this act. the State can lose neither quality no </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT quantity of land, and the State School Fund will, in time to come, be augmented by this proposed exchange. To those who would plead delay in the passage of this legis - lation, we would most respectfully submit, that, the Government hav - ing passed thru the experimental stages of afforestation in Ne - braska, is now entering upon an aggressive and extensive campaign of tree planting from its nurseries : one each upon the Ressev and Xiobrara Divisions, and the earlier this exchange can be effected, the more favorable will be the conditions therefore, for with each season's planting, the area available for this exchange becomes more restricted. Again, the exchange perfected, the ( iovernment may, to better advantage, pursue its work. Similar conditions have arisen in every State in which there are both National Forest Reserves and State School Lands. In some of these States, these exchanges have already been legally provided for upon the part of the individual State. In fact, in South Dakota, even tho the title has not passed, jurisdiction has. The final consummation of these exchanges is now awaiting the passage of a bill thru our National Congress, which authorizes the exchange upon the part of the Government, and makes pro - vision for the exchange in title. This Bill has alreadv passed the House of Representatives and is now pending before the Com - mittee in the Senate. Favorable action upon the part of the Senate may be expected at this session. This Bill is a matter of mutual concern to the Government and our State. The Government Bureau of Forestry, thru its accredited representatives, has endorsed this Bill and joins with our State Commission in respectfully praying that this session of he Nebraska Legislature enact this legislation. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">A BILL For AX ACT TO provide for the Areas by counties, all cities all villages, and to provide and payment thereof. establishment of Forest Reserve of the first or second class an- 1 for the acquisition, maintenance Be It Enacted by the People of Section i. Even count v, c the State of Xcbraska: tv of the first or second class and every incorporated village is hereby authorized and empowered to establish and maintain Forest Reserve Areas, and for that pur - pose is hereby authorized and empowered to receive in fee bv titt. grant, devise, purchase or condemnation, any lands having nat - ural timber thereon or suitable for reforestation or afforestation and to hold, improve, protect and plant such areas by reforesting and afforesting and manage the same on approved forestry principle - for park and public purposes, including the protection of their potable water supply. Provided, That any such city or village may acquire such Reserves within a distance of fifteen (15) miles of the corporate limits. Provided, That the acquisition of any proposed Forest Reserve* shall have first received the approval of the State Forestation Com - mission as to its adaptability for the purposes intended. Sec. 2. Any of the forementioned governmental subdivisions are hereby authorized and empowered to acquire lands suitable for the purposes herein provided by the condemnation of private property for such public uses where the same cannot be fainv and equitably acquired by purchase. Such condemnation or appro - priation shall be had by the County Board or the Mayor and Council or City Commissioners, as the case may be, under the form and procedure provided for by Sections 1092 to 1096. inclu - sive, of the Revised Statutes for 1913, providing for the condem - nation of private lands for County purposes. Sec. 3. Upon the filing of the petition with the County Board or the City Council or Commission, as the case may be, signed bv </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT t least ten per cent (icA) of the voters of the governmental ubdivision effected describing the lands proposed to be acquired nd requesting the Board or Council or Commission to acquire le described tract for Forest Reserve purposes, it shall be manda - orv upon the County Board or the City Council or Commission. s the case may be, to submit the proposition at the next general r special election called for that purpose whether or not the escribed tract shall be purchased or acquired for such Forest Reserve purposes. And if the municipal subdivision is without unds available for completing the acquisition of the proposed ract, the County Board or City Council shall, at the same election, submit the question of issuing negotiable funds to the voters of the District for the purpose of providing means for the acquisition of said land. Such election and submission to be held in conformity to the provisions of Sections 405 to 409 of the Revised Statutes for 19 1 3, providing for the issuance of internal improvement Sec. 4. The police power of such County or City is herebv extended to and over the lands acquired under the provisions of this Act and the County Board and the Mayor and Council or City Commissioners, as the case may be, is hereby authorized and empowered to enact laws, rules and ordinances for the regulation and protection of such Reserves as may be deemed proper and expedient. Sec. 5. Provisions of this law are hereby made applicable to all such real estate as may have been or which shall hereafter be acquired under the provisions of Section 51 19 of the Revise! Statutes for 1913. Sec. 6. Two or more counties thru the joint action of their several County Boards are herebv authorized and empowered to ex - ercise all the powers, privileges and duties set forth in the several sections of this Act. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NEBRASKA COMMISSION ON FORESTATION 15 EXPLANATION OF HILL FOR COUNTY AND MUNICIPAL F&lt; )REST RESERVES In explanation of the preceding proposed law, we have deemed it proper to include herewith a copy of an article pre - pared by our Commission and read before the 19 16 annual meet - ing of the Nebraska State Association of Commercial Clubs held in Omaha, Nebraska, on the 25th day of May last. Mr. President and Members of the Xebraska State Association Commercial Clubs: I come before you representing the State Forestation Commis - sion of Nebraska to invite your attention to, and support of, certain proposed legislation which we have in mind, to be taken up at the coming session of our State Legislature. The particular phase of this proposed Legislation to which I shall, today, confine mv remarks, should appeal to you, one and all, as the representatives cf our municipal corporations. Our proposed laws will readilv be classified under your head of constructive legislation. We are ask - ing the passage of laws that will permit of the Counties. Cities of all classes and Villages of this State, creating and maintaining forest reserves. In Europe such forest reserves are commonlv termed communal forests and I believe that term more apropos than that of municipal forests as used in this country. These proposed laws will give the right to the above mentioned political units of our State to acquire by gift, purchase or other - wise, tracts of land adapted to forestry purposes, with the power to vote bonds for the pr. .ment thereof and levy taxes for the bonds and maintenance purposes. While such laws as these are of * constructive character, yet it is no easy matter to interest the people of one generation in a work f*om which they may not hope to derive direct benefits or, to put it otherwise, build for the genera - tions of this country to come, but, Gentlemen, not one of vott can deny the necessity for such work and the sooner we plant the seed, the sooner shall be the harvest. That the United States is a great and wonderful nation, that the State of Nebraska is a great and wonderful State is true, it must be true for we all admit it, but is not our greatness due in no small measure to the fact that we have been burning the candle at both ends without thought of the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT future. Mother Xature tadewcd our country and our state with wonderful resources and we have used them as if thev were with - out limit. Until today every thinking person within our country has come to recognize the fact that there will be a dav of reckon - ing and that we must make preparations therefor, for it is not far distant. Today, I shall endeavor to show you, without entering into loo great detail, what has been or is being accomplished in the world along the lines of work that we propose and the needs of such work in Nebraska. In this present day age, to make a propo - sition appeal, it trust be demonstrated that it is practical, feasible ;.nd at least eventually may become self-sustaining, if not a great pecuniary success, and who of us will gainsay that what has been accomplished elsewhere cannot be duplicated by our citizens if their minds be set to the task. We live in what we are pleased to term a most enlightened age, but I shall ask you to go back into the dark ages to the year 1306. This year of 1306 marks the establishment of the communal t'.rest of the city of Zurich, in Switzerland, and from that dav to this it has been under the control of and managed bv the citv authorities. It comprises an area of 2,840 acres, 2,560 of which are covered with standing timber. This forest returns an annual net income per acre of about $8.00. or 820,000.00 per annum. The Swiss forests occupy 2o c { of its total land area. Of this the State owns 4/)^ and the communals 6&amp;9^( or 1431,000 acres and, while I have not the figures, we cannot doubt, knowing the Swiss people, that out of this area there are many comnnmai forests quite as successful fiiianciallv as that of the citv of Zurich- Perhaps in Germany, the science of forestry has been carried to the nth power. In the German Empire at the present time, there is a total of 34,989,675 acres devoted to forestry purposes. The State forests comprise 3 1 .9 */i of this and the communal for - ests 16.1%, or a total of 5.645.227 acres. Germany, taken as a whole, has a larger forest acreage and a much larger forest pro - duction today than she had 100 years ago. One of the most suc - cessful communal forests financially, is that of Forback. in Alsace- Lorraine on the edge of the Schwartzwald, or Black Forest. The City of Forback has a population of approximately 1,900 and owns </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NEBRASKA COMMISSION ON FORESTATION 17 a forest of 1.482 acres, which returns an annual net income of $12.14 per acre to the City. Its citizens pay no taxes and nearlv ? 1 0,000 are divided yearly among 275 of its families, oldest in time of residence. The city of Baden-Baden in Baden has a com - munal forest of nearlv 13.000 acres, which netted the citv la-t year over $67,000. Heidelberg, Frankfort, and Pforzheim main - tain communal forests, as do some 1.500 other villages and cities of the German Empire, all of them returning an annual net profit or income, ranging from $1.70 to $12.40 per acre, which pays all or a great part of the taxes of these municipalities. These conditions as to communal forests prevalent in Switzerland and (jermanv are duplicated throughout Europe to a greater or less extent, as in France with its 5/100,000 acres of communal forests. Austria, with over 14% of its forests owned by municipalities, Hungarv. with its 4,000,000 acres, and Sweden, with over 2,000.000 acres of communal forests. And, speaking of Sweden, the town of Orson has a communal forest and the revenue derived therefrom is said to pay all its taxes, support its public schools and libraries and, in addition, operates a free street railway. The municipalities of Japan today own nearlv one-tenth of the total wooded area of the nation, or over 4,000,000 acres of communal forests. These few figures and illustrations cited will give vou a faint idea of what the old world is doing towards the upbuilding of its communal forests-. In the United States, at the present time, com - munal forests are in somewhat of an embryotic stage and reliable figures and data thereon are difficult of compilation. However, we now have not less than eight states which have passed laws with express provisions for the creation and maintenance of municipal or communal forests. Those of which I have definite knowledge are Illinois, Indiana, Massachusetts. Minnesota, Xew Hampshire. New Jersey, Xew York, and Wisconsin. In addition, there are other states in which we find municipal forest reserves or wood lots created, not for forestry purposes solely, but for the additional purpose of protecting the water sheds, or the sources of their potable water. According to one table, we find thirteen different states with a total of ninety-seven municipal forests. Another table cites ten states as having sixty-nine municipal forests devoted principally to the protection of their respective potable water </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 ipply. Doubtless were statistics available they would show that n the United States, to date, the benefits derived from these orests are principally indirect, for the policy of scientific foresta - on as it is known in Europe, is not as yet well developed. These arious State laws provide for the establishment of municipal for - sts and their management under a definite forest policy, to be evised by experts in the matter of forestry, usually specifying the tate Forester, which includes the commercial marketing upon a scientific basis of standing timber and the planting or reforesting F cut-over lands and the afforestation of lands more suitable for le growing of timber than any other present known purpose. ! There can be no real reason urged against the passage of trs permitting of the organization of municipal or communal ests and, on the other hand, there are many reasons why thev juld be permitted. Speaking for Nebraska, there are few com - mities in our State but what could, to their advantage, create d maintain communal forests to the everlasting benefit of their ipective citizens. Many of our communities have available ste lands that could be devoted to forestation puqx&gt;ses, for :se lands would eventually be made to return a net income. rreby materially reducing the tax levy, furnishing employment ring certain seasons of the year or times of commercial depres - m when the question of the unemployed is vital and a menace to r communities. Under proper rules and regulations, they would ord a natural outing place for all citizens and a sanctuary for ds and small game. The sources or water sheds of the potab'e iter for every municipality should be protected against contami - tion. The creation of a municipal forest provides for a practical lization of such areas and last, but not least, the forestation of :se waste places will enhance the value of the surrounding lands. The work of the National Government during the past twelve years upon its forest reserves in this State, has paved the wav for others and made possible similar forestafion work. The experi - mental stage of afforestation is past for the government has con - clusively demonstrated that trees can be artificially planted an-1 grown to return a net profit. However, it does not appeal to the private citizen, and it therefore must devolve upon our local gov - ernments. Many of you may have noted by the papers that thru </seg>
            <seg id="p019">N fc.BR ASK A C OM MISSION ON FORESTATION 19 the good offices of Dr. Clifford of the City of Omaha, a start has been made by the Fontenelle Forest Association, in its acquisi - tion of land along the Missouri River. This land to be held in perpetuity for forest purposes. Wherefore. I ask you, cannot the State of Nebraska that gave to our Nation the Honorable J. Sterling Morton, be induced to get in line and assist in the solution of at least this one of our manv conservation problems, for. Gentlemen, accordingly as we attack and solve these problems, so will we be held in judgment favorably or otherwise, by the future generations of the State of Nebraska. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>