<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>MESSAGE OF Ashton C. Shallenberger GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE 32d Session Nebraska Legislature 1911</title>
               <date value="1911">1911</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">MESSAGE Ashton C. Shallenberger GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE 32d Session Nebraska Legislature 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">3 Ientlemen : I congratulate you because of the honor erred upon you by the people of this commonwealth iving into your hands the law-making power of the b. You are the only means through which the will 3ur fellow -citizens can be crystallized into law. Since initiative in all matters of legislation must come from the responsibility of your position is very great ■ed, and I am sure that you are assembled here, lved to act with the highest regard for the general are of those who have given this great trust and ar into your hands. In conformity with constitutional requirements, I shall recommend certain measures for your consideration that I believe are of particular importance at this time and which if molded into the laws of this state will make for the common good of us all, and my judgment upon them is based largely upon the experience gained in serving for two years as the chief executive of the state. The legislature which just preceded you enacted a number of laws, dealing with matters essential to the best interests of the people, some of them new in principle and going directly to the foundation of good government and calculated to protect the rights and the property of the citizen. I am glad to know that the great majority of the measures that I refer to are still in force and are vindicating the wisdom and the judgment of the legis - lators, who enacted them. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 The guaranty of deposit law was one of the most im - portant measurse ever formulated by a Nebraska legis - lature. The people have been denied the benefits of its provisions during my term of office owing to an injunction issued against the governor of this state out of the federal court. This law has been at issue before the supreme court of the United States for final judgment, and I am glad to report to you that a decision upon it has been reached and the law sustained. I will not recommend any additional bank legislation, since it is my deliberate judgment that the law enacted by the previous legis - lature is the most advanced in its regulatory provisions and the best calculated to benefit the people generally that has yet been adopted by any state. The injunction served the purpose of preventing the administration responsible for the law from putting its provisions into effect. Although the governor who advocated the measure and who made his campaign and was elected upon this issue has been denied the right to inaugurate his policy, I shall be satisfied now that the final result will be to the people of Nebraska the benefits of the law and the added safety and stability which it is calculated to bring to the banking business in Nebraska. NON-PARTISAN JUDICIARY A bill was enacted by the last legislature to change materially the manner and method of nominating the judges of our state courts and the superintendents of our public school system. This law has also been declared unconstitutional by our state supreme court, because of certain limitations which it contained, relative to the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">5 petitions required of candidates who desired to file under the provisions of the act, and for the further reason that it also restricted political conventions from endorsing party candidates. I believe that the law would still be effective as a non-partisan measure if it was to be reenacted, leaving out the provisions that were declared unconstitutional by the court. The most essential point in the law that was nullified was the one providing that the judges, and the superintended our public schools were to be nominated by petition and not by party primaries. These positions are purely non - partisan in their duties and it does not seem to me that there can be serious objection to the requirement that candidates for these offices shall seek election because of their known merits for the place desired and not because of any party approval. » believe that our constitution should be so amc: &gt; provide for the election of six supreme judges from rate districts, these districts to correspond at present Iie different congressional districts of the state. The justice should be elected from the state at large, this plan because it will give each section of the ! representation on the supreme bench and for the ler reason that in states where this rule now prevails is been found to be a powerful factor in preventing courts from being made up entirely of members of political party. POPULAR ELECTION OF UNITED STATES SENATORS Ky enacting what is commonly known as the Oi i for the election of United States senators by direct ■, the last legislature took a distinct step forward he direction of real popular government. The g </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 and governor at the last election, shows that the people will make use of the power given them and vote in - dependently and intelligently as to their choice of men for the high office of United States senator. A great majority of the legislative candidates of both parties at the late election subscribed to "Statement No. 1," and it is interesting Lo note that those candidates who did not vote so were generally defeated at the polls. This shows that the voters are quick to choose in favor of e who are willing to abide by the will of a majority of the people. The sentiment in favor of popular elections for United States senator is rapidly growing throughout the nation and,, Nebraska has added another impeti. the public sentiment for this reform. INCOME TAX AMENDMENT I recommend that a joint resolution in conformance with constitutional requirements be enacted by this legislature authorizing an amendment to the national constitution granting the right to the federal government to levy a tax upon incomes when found necessary by the congress of the United States. By so doing we should not relinquish the right of the states to levy taxes upon incomes but the federal government may need this authority at any time and no tax can be more equitable than one assessed against incomes because only those who can afford to pay the tax will be charged with it and this can be said of no other form of federal or state taxation. Both houses of congress have asked for this authority by large majorities and the president of the United States has also recommended that it be granted to the national government by the states of the Union. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">7 ELECTIONS Iir present constitution provides for too many elections ebraska. An amendment should be adopted to pro - for biennial instead of annual elections. I would recommend that the term of office of the governor other state officers should be changed fronr two to years and that they should be eligible for only one , this would give them a term of service sufficient laugurate a policy of administration and to render le state the benefit of valuable experience gained in ?. It would also prevent an official from being &gt;ted into playing selfish politics in order that he t improve his chance for reelection. STATE RAILWAY COMMISSION The physical valuation of railroads is a measure of vast importance to the people of the state and to the railroad corporations as well that was inaugurated by the previous legislature. The report of the state railway commission, which is included herewith, shows that satisfactory progress is being made in the appraisal of the railroad properties in the state. It is the opinion of the commission that the work of appraisal will be ac - complished without exceeding in cost the amount ap - propriated for the purpose of physical valuation by the last legislature. However, the work is of such magnitude and detail, that the biennium may end before the work is finished; and if such is the case, the balance of the ap - propriation at that time available for the expense of this department will be turned back into the treasury and it will then be necessary for this legislature to reappropriate such an amount as will finish the undertaking. I believe </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 I he act requiring approval by the commission of the ance of stock and bonds and other evidences of in - tedness of public service corporations was prepared submitted by me together with a special message to legislature. The purpose of the law is to prevent the ing upon the market of securities of a questionable ■acter, or that do not represent real values invested lublic service corporations. Since its passage applications to issue stocks and bonds to the amount of $194,848,030.00 have received the official sanction of the commission. The knowledge that the requests for stock and bond issues must stand the test of strict investigation, is sufficient to discourage the formation of schemes of doubtful character, which in the past have often been exploited at the expense of the public. As a result of this law the watering of stock of public service corporations in Nebraska has become a thing of the past. I believe that the procedure as to appeals from orders of the commission should be so amended that such cases should be carried directly from the commission to the supreme court upon the record and evidence produced before the commission. I would recommend that the office of public weigh - master and scale-inspector be created for the purpose of obtaining correct and official weights upon all shipments. That other industries in addition to grain elevators be provided for in the equal facilities act, in order that suitable side track connections with public carriers may - be obtained upon reasonable terms. The demurrage act passed by the last legislature should be so amended as to invest reasonable discretion - ary powers in the commission. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">9 of contraband commodities, should be so amended as to include within its terms and apply, as the case may be, to shippers as well as to carriers. Imbodied in the report of the railway commission are ■r recommendations for legislation which are not lout merit. I believe, however, that the specific ndments which I have pointed out are sufficiently artant to engage your attention. I would respect - r refer you to the valuable report of the commission general information as to the work and scope of this Y which is one of the most important boards under scheme of state government. CORPORATION TAX LAW The corporation tax law, enacted by the legislature of 1909, has proven a very material factor in adding to the revenues of the state. Its constitutionality has been sustained by the court and it is proving a very valuable revenue producer for the state treasury. Most of the corporations subject to its provisions have complied with its requirements and have paid promptly the tax levied under the bill. The total tax collected up to date amounts to $130,502.15. A number of corporations, however, have refused to comply with the law and are therefore delin - quent. The attorney general should at once proceed against those corporations which have failed to obey the law and if the tax required of them is not paid promptly thev should have their charters declared forfeited. LEGISLATION RESTRAINING THE LIQUOR TRAFFIC The thirty-first session of the Nebraska legislature enacted a number of bills placing further and more </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 the state. These several laws and amendments are all proving to be wise and salutary measures, especially the so-called daylight saloon bill, which because of the novelty of its restrictions was at first bitterly assailed. This law, however, has been vindicated by the unanswer - able logic of experience as the best regulatory liquor law yet enacted by any state. The salient principle and provision of the law that the sale of liquor shall be con - fined practically to the hours of daylight only is rapidly finding favor in other states as well. Indeed, the idea of limiting the hours of sale and the number of saloons in accordance with population is a feature in the control of the evils of the liquor traffic that is being adopted in some form by almost every nation of advanced civilization. Under the operation of this law as well as the other provisions of the Nebraska statute dealing with the same subject this state has accomplished results in minimizing the evils of the liquor question to an extent that challenges comparison with the showing made by any other state in the Union. But in my opinion much more can still be done along the same line if we can secure a proper ob - servance and obedience to our laws upon the subject. Nebraska has a splendid reputation as a law abiding commonwealth along most lines, but enforcement of liquor laws has always been difficult to secure in any country. I can find no other commonwealth in the republic that has less of poverty, ignorance, crim. drunkenness than our own fair state of Nebraska. But we in common with all of our sister states are lacking in public sentiment that shall insist upon a decent respect for and obedience to the laws, which the people enact through their legislature. I know there are some who </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11 succeeding legislature, but a comparison of our law en - forcement with that of other nations and an observance of the tardiness with which justice often lays its hand upon the malefector must force the careful student of the problem to admit that our weakness is not so much in our lack of laws but rather because of our failure to enforce their provisions after they are written upon the statute books of the state. I am not a lawyer, but if I cared to take the time I could easily cite a hundred statutes, now encumbering the law books of the state, which are never enforced and are a reflection upon the effectiveness and the forcefulness of our civilization. What is needed most at present is a healthy public sentiment that will compel a decent respect for and obedi - ence to the laws we now have and also men in office with the honesty and the courage and the determination to enforce them. It is futile to pass laws if men may dis - obey them with impunity and especially is this so of laws limiting or controlling the sale of liquor. Realizing this weakness in our present administration of law and justice a previous legislature enacted what is commonly known as the Sackett law. Under this statute, if an official empowered with the enforcement of law refuses to do his duty, the governor is authorized to instruct the attorney general to commence action in the supreme court against the offending officer. The court may in its judgment appoint a referee to take testimony to ascertain if there is any ground for such action. After a hearing is had and testimony taken, the referee shall make his report back to the court and the court may take such action as it shall deem just. This law has been much talked about and I think the governor's </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 to law-enforcement has yet to be proven. It has been invoked by an executive but once, since it was adopted by the legislature and that time by myself. Because of the time required, under the necessary court procedure as indicated above, its value as a remedy for the evil it was presumed to correct is greatly impaired. It takes too long to get results by this act under present methods. It seems to be somewhat the rule of late to elect governors of this state for but one term, and unless the executive shall commence an action against a derelict official soon after he is elected, he is very likely to go out of office himself before he can hope to secure a decision as to the delinquent officer. If power over an official who shall fail to do his duty is to be in any manner vested in an executive then I believe that the governor should be given the right to hear complaints against officers em - powered with law-enforcement and upon a satisfactory showing being made to him that the official complained of is guilty as charged the governor should have the power to suspend the delinquent official, pending an al to the supreme court. At the governor's con - ference held in Washington, D. C, January last. Gover - nor Hughes of New York, now Mr. Justice Hughes of the United States supreme court, and many distinguished executives of other states, expressed themselves as believing that this power should be lodged in the ex - ecutive. Wherever it has been given to a governor there is no record that it has ever been abused. The hearings would be held in the office of the governor under the "Fierce light" that beats about the executive office, the governor's reputation and that of his administration </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 urors to sit upon the justness of his action and if the Hutive is to be charged with responsibility of law - rcement he should be given every means compatible vith justice and in conformity with the constitution to hat the laws are strictly obeyed. If this is thought oo great an authority to vest in the governor, and I idmit it is in a certain sense an arbitrary power, then the )resent act should be amended so as to provide for im- nediate trial and decision by the court in giving preced- ence to these matters over all other questions before that KI, perhaps, ought to observe in passing as evidence efficiency of the Sackett law, that since the attorney Bil has commenced to take testimony in the ouster gainst the chief of police of Omaha, I am reliably nformed that the police force of that city has suddenly crewed down the lid so tight that ginger ale is now con idered strong drink in the metropolis aft'^r eierht o'clock EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS The several departments that because of constitutional limitations, are made adjuncts to the executive office, have all made their reports for the biennium to the governor, and I have included them with this me - for your consideration. Rnew department was created by the last legislature, of fire warden, to have charge of the problem of fire waste and the enforcement of the laws pertaining to that subject. The expenses of the department are pro - vided for by assessments against the premiums collt-* by the fire insurance companies of the state. Then KIRE WARDEN </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 this office has entailed no additional burden upon the taxpayers. Under the present efficient chief deputy warden and his assistants, the office has been organized and the work systematized, and I think that a very useful public service will be found to result from this new legislation. OIL INSPECTOR The department of oil inspection has grown in im - portance during this biennium because of new legislation passed by the 1909 legislature. This office has now become a revenue producer for the state of considerable rtance, and has at this date paid into the state •ury $40,412.09, in excess of all expenses, and the amount for December is not included in these figures. GAME AND FISH I he fish and game department is one of considerable rest and importance to the state. I am glad to be to say, it has been well administered under the ent chief deputy warden and his assistants, and if recommendations made by Warden Geilus to you enacted into law, this department can also be made sustaining. BUREAU OF LABOR The bureau of labor should have a more liberal ap - propriation than has heretofore been allotted to it. It can be made a powerful force in advertising the resources and advantages of this state as well as the bureau of statistics and labor. I recommend, therefore, that you encourage this department by giving it an appropriation commensurate with its needs. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">15 Iie department of pure food is one of the most im - int of these connected with the executive office. &gt;als with many commercial, as well as administrative lems, and I am glad to state that, under the present nissioner, it is attracting the attention of other ■s because of the ability that he has shown in its agement, and the wisdom of the laws dealing with subject, which have been enacted by Nebraska The veterinary department is one of peculiar im - portance to Nebraska because of the tremendous value of our live stock production and investments. Much valuable work establishing additional quarantine reg - ulations against the importation and spreading of con - tagious diseases among our various breeds of live stock has been accomplished by this department under the able management of Dr. Paul Juckniess during the past two years. A quarantine against tubercular animals has been established, and during the biennium, 15,645 animals have been tested and 1,301 found infected and slaughtered. Fifty-six are still in quarantine. A con - siderable area in the western portion of the state that infected with scabies has been cleaned up and relieved of quarantine restrictions. The amount of money ap - propriated for this department is not in proportion to the importance of the live stock industry in Nebraska. The previous legislature increased the meager appropri - ation that had been heretofore alloted to this department, and as I have pointed out, very material benefits to the live stock interests of the state have resulted therefrom. TATE VETERINARIAN </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 property reaching in value into the millions. A sufficient sum should be awarded to the veterinary department by you to provide every possible means for the prevention of the spread of this dread swine disease. The state veter - inarian recommends that the legislature should provide for a live stock sanitary board to have control of the animal quarantine and sanitary regulations of the state, and I join in his recommendation. BOARD OF HEALTH I he state board of health is one of the most important irtments of the state, as it cares for the health of the ent as well as the future of our commonwealth. I advised that Nebraska will be admitted into the .tration area of the United States this year, sho ked improvement in all health matters. The deaths or state for the last year were 10,352, births 25,171. last legislature added to the already large duties of board, the responsibility of collecting and compiling sties of all marriages and divorces in the state. 62 marriages and 1,807 divorces have been recorded ng 1910. Ine of the most dangerous epidemics that has threat - i Nebraska in recent years appeared in the form of bro-spinal meningitis or polio-myelitis. The Xe - ika board of health was the first health department le United States to recognize this disease as contagious at once ordered it quarantined. As a result of this npt and vigorous action on the part of the board, e was stamped out one of the most threatening and astating epidemics that has ever stricken the state, cause and nature of this disease has not been defin- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17 board should be armed with every facility for inves - tigation to the end that future epidemics be prevented. I would recommend that you deal liberally with the board in a special appropriation to be used in original research and investigation of this and other similar diseases, be - sides the regular appropriation for gathering vital sta - tistics and regular inspection of the health conditions of state THE STATE BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS Ie state board of charities and corrections is in a cer - sense a department under executive advice and ol. The state is looking after the welfare of its s and cattle and its live stock fi^herally, and I am to be able to report that this board is doing an im - e amount of good in looking after the poor and un - nate men and women and children of the state, and ommend that you give it the financial support to 1 its efficient service in a most worthy cause justly REPORTS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS irie reports of the superintendents and the various ds and executive officers having charge of the different ? institutions are herewith transmitted to you for • information and guidance to assist you in framing i legislation as you shall deem necessary. The reports full of valuable matter that you should study and nine with care. These reports show that the several tutions are being well and economically managed, that the control of the state's business affairs has </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 only comment upon such recommendations made by the various departments reporting to me as I think call for special mention, and which I believe should receive legislative action at your hands. Most of the state institutions are going to finish the present biennium without a financial deficiency. The soldiers' homes at Grand Island and Milford and the boys' industrial school at Kearney will not be able to maintain their institutions for the biennium upon the appropriations made for them by the last legislature. But it must be said in fairness to their superintendents that your predecessors reduced the amount of appro - priation for the maintenance of these three institutions $36,000 below that which was appropriated for them for the preceding biennium. Owing to the increased cost of living it evidently was impossible for these institutions to be properly conducted for the present biennium, with due consideration for the welfare of those dependent upon the state, with so reduced a maintenance fund as that provided two years ago. I, therefore, recommend to you that you take this into careful consideration when you come to make appropriations for these institutions for the coming biennium. PENITENTIARY The state penitentiary will also show a small deficiency. It is not so large in amount as that of two years ago and if this institution was credited with a fair amount of remuneration for the light and power it furnishes to other state buildings including the state house, the governor's mansion and the orthopedic hospital, it would be self- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">19 the income paid by this institution into the state treasury that the warden is warranted in his claims that he has succeeded in putting the prison upon such a sound business basis that it now is no longer a charge upon the tax-payers of the state. The warden recommends in his report the establish - ment of a state reformatory for first offenders and those young in years. It is surprising to learn how many of those confined at Lancaster are of immature years and guilty of crimes committed largely because of improper education and environment. The first duty of the state should be to try and reform these men and boys and to leave nothing undone to prevent their becoming con - firmed and persistent criminals. A state reformatory could be combined with the institution for juvenile offenders at Kearney under one management without much additional expense to the state. The older offenders should be entirely segregated from the boys and if th done I believe a real reform in our prison work can be instituted and that with little added cost to the tax - payers. If this is not done the present prison will ulti - mately have to be enlarged. To establish a state reform - atory at this time will be found in the end to promote financial economy as well as to conserve humanity, honesty and law observance among our citizens. In the wide discretion granted to our courts, under the salutary parole law, enacted by the last legislature, the selection of those to be sent to the reformatory can safely be left to the wisdom and judgment of the courts of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 The general management and administration of the institutions of the state should be placed in the hands of a non-partisan central board of control, authorized by constitutional enactment to take from the board of public lands and buildings the labor and duty of managing and directing the various state institutions now under its control. This board should consist of three or five mem - bers to serve for not less than five years and to be ap - pointed by the governor. It should be made their plain duty to see that efficiency and not political pull should determine, as far as possible, the personnel of the employes and officers of the state institutions. The members should not be all of one political party and in order to make this latter requirement effective, a civil service commission can be created to examine and certify can - didates to a place upon the waiting list of those desiring employment of the state and the board should be required to fill appointments from those who have passed a satis - factory examination. Unless this is done in my judg - ment it would be just as well to leave the responsibility of appointments in the hands of the governor as at present as otherwise we will only change from the selection of state appointees by the leader of one party to that of appointment by a party majority of a board of control. The chief necessity for a board of control is not because the management and work of the present board of public lands and buildings is unsatisfactory but for the reason that the labor and time required of them in this respect is an unfair load put upon men who are elected for other purposes and who have plenty of other duties that require their full time and who now fulfill the task of serving as a board of control without any additional remuneration </seg>
            <seg id="p022">21 whatever. All state institutions whose maintenance is furnished from the public treasury, should be subject to the board of control. I want to here acknowledge my ap - preciation of the unfailing courtesy and consideration El me by the other members of the various state s of which I have been ex-officio a member. Though allegiance to a different political party from that of my fellow workers, I and my appointees have been accorded absolute fairness and even generous treatment at their hands and from them I have found the state has had service and business ability of such high order that it has commended my admiration, and I am sure that the state generally little appreciates the high sense of personal and business honor and devotion to public duty that is rendered to it by the members of the board of public lands and buildings and the members of the other e boards of administration. STATE FINANCES The state's finances are in excellent condition. The treasury is showing a satisfactory balance in the different funds and the state has no unpaid bonds or obligations of any kind. For the first time in its history at the date of the assembling of the legislature Nebraska is out of debt. The salaries paid to the state officers who admin - the affairs of government are fixed by the con - stitution. This document was adopted by a convention assembled at a time when the state was young in years, poor in property and short on income. Nebraska is now rich and prosperous; we are entirely out of debt. The amount of wealth piled up each year by the people of the state is now larger than that produced by a like number of citizens in any other commonwealth of the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">22 particularly in the executive branch because of the creation of so many new departments which because of itutional limitation have necessitated their being made adjuncts of the governor's office. A quarter of a century of state expansion and development has produced conditions, and, therefore, it is unfair and unjust to ct men the state at personal loss to them - 8 because of the low salaries paid and the demands placed upon them by reason of the positions which they and which they cannot escape. The state can and should provide fair and adequate salaries for its sen ; Thi responsibilities of the governor of this state and the demands made upon him are greatly in excess of those of a congressman or a United States senator and the dignity of the state ard justice to the executive demands that the governor should at least receive a salary equal to that of a member of the national house or senate. The at - torney general of this state should be a lawyer competent to combat the best counsel that the bar of this state or any other commonwealth affords. Corporations pit against him the brightest and keenest legal minds that money can hire. Questions involving millions of the people's money are oftentimes staked upon his ability and judgment. He should be paid a salary of at least $5,000 per annum, and the state treasurer should receive a like salary- because of the responsibilities of that office and the great business judgment needed there. The other state officers should have their salaries increased in a degree commensurate with their responsibilities and duties. I recommend that an amendment to our con - stitution be submitted to the people for their approval, </seg>
            <seg id="p024">23 ecessor, Governor Sheldon. I believe the people of Nebraska will sanction a reasonable increase of salary to their officers if given the opportunity to do so. TATE HOUSE AND SUPREME COURT The present state house is inadequate in room for the la of the seat of government. If this legislature is not ready to undertake the problem of the erection of a new state house, something should be done at once to relieve the congestion and crowded condition of the present building. The state historical society has ac - quired a lot of ground fronting the southeast corner of the state house park. The state has already expended $25,000 in building a foundation for a proposed historical museum building, located upon this lot. I vetoed a sub - sequent $25,000 appropriation for the same purpose, made by the legislature that just preceded you, be&lt; I believe it a wasteful and improper way to erect a public building to do so by piecemeal. I would advise that the title to this property be placed in the stai Nebraska and upon this site a building erected, suitable to house the supreme court of the state, the attorney general's office, the state library and the state historical society. This would vacate enough rooms in the present state house to provide accommodations for all the officers needed for many years to come. I, therefore, recommend that an appropriation be made by this legislature adequate to erect and equip a building suitable for the purposes above described. To provide sufficient funds for the improvement above sted I would recommend that a levy of one mill be </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 authorized for this purpose for the coining biennium which would produce a sum of approximately $800,000. This would be more than sufficient to build the court and historical building proposed and with the balance of the fund so raised I would advise the rebuilding of the south - east side of the east wing of the state house, where we are at this moment. It should be torn down and re - builded upon a proper foundation. The house and senate chambers should be remodeled and redecorated, as should also the corridors and offices. With the ex - penditure of such a modest sum, an amount not to be compared with that now being spent by other states for capitol buildings, the present state house can be remodeled and made up-to-date and entirely sufficient to fulfill e need of Nebraska's seat of government for a generation. The cost of the one mill levy to the average tax-j will be so small as to be scarcely felt. The present state house is artistic in appearance, of proper dimension, elevation and design for its situation and surroundings and it will be the part of economy us well as conserving an artistic and historical building to carry out the plan of improvement which I have here outlined. LINCOLN MONUMENT I he last legislature appropriated funds to erect a ument to the martyred president Abraham Lincoln, i the capitol grounds in this city, which bears his :&gt;red name. I understand that the artist, George ster French, who has been assigned the work, has tared his model and will soon submit it to the com - ee in charge for their approval. I hope this statue be of such artistic merit as to become a monument alone to the memory of the great statesman it repre- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">25 it and to the public spirit of the legislature and citizens of Nebraska who have made it possible for it to be THAYER MONUMENT The Vicksburg Military Park commission is very desirous that a proper monument to Nebraska's soldier statesman, General Thayer, who was one of the heroic figures in the historic siege of Vicksburg shall be erected in the military park at the point where the brigade under General Thayer won undying fame for its bravery in that great struggle. Nebraska will honor itself by so honoring General Thayer and the troops who fought under him, and I recommend that a suitable ap - propriation be made by the legislature to provide for a monument to him to be erected upon the Vicksburg battle field under the direction of the park commi- STATE UNIVERSITY The state of Nebraska has a very great university in an exceedingly small situation. It is tightly wedged in between business blocks, street car lines and railroad tracks, until it has been squeezed into all sorts of shapes both as to the style of the architecture of its buildings and as to their places upon the campus. The university should expand and spread out mightily in the near future if it is to meet the expectation of its friends and the hopes and the wishes of the people of the state. To acquire sufficient ground for an adequate addition to the present campus will cost from three-quarters of a million to a round million of dollars. Adjoining the outskirts of the citv. the state has three hundred and twenty acres of </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 land, which is ideally located for university campus, and upon this splendid site plans of university develop - ment can be achieved of an unequal beauty and utility. Eighty acres of this land should be devoted to the purpose of a university campus. The colleges of arts and sciences should be removed to this new campus as rapidly as possible. The law, medical and engineering colleges can remain for a time as at present located. If desired the present location could ultimately be disposed of to the city of Lincoln and would make a first-class site for a city high school building. The cost of maintaining in separate situations two great educational plants as is at present done is greatly in excess of what it would be if the two institutions were combined under one general scheme. We have now reached a period of growth and development in Nebraska when we can look with courage and understanding into the future, and we should begin to build for all time in matters such as the permanent development of this our great central educational in - stitution, the university of Nebraska. Competent archi - tects should prepare a plan for such magnitude and beauty as will make this work when completed a mon - ument to our devotion to education, and a source of pride and continued benefit to future generations. The legislature from session to session should with judgment and generosity provide the funds necessary to carry - forward and finally complete some such a plan of uni - versity development when once it has been adopted and approved by the legislature and the board of regen F! money that would be needed to alone buy the ary land adjoining the present campus would go ward erecting the buildings designed for the farm If the state needs more ground for experimental </seg>
            <seg id="p028">27 I ling, because of the setting aside of a portion of the ent farm for the university campus, such land as Id be needed can be purchased at a short distance 1 the present farm for a mere bagatelle compared i the price of a single city block in the heart of Lin - . The university is measuring up to the expectations desires of the people as an intellectual center and eadership in all educational matters is unquestioned, iring and effectual. You should provide liberally ;ts needs and at the same time with judgment ■ manner of the expenditure of the funds provided by legislature. NEW BUILDINGS NEEDED A number of new buildings for different institutions of the state were provided for by the last legislature in their several appropriation bills. They were all necessary to the public service and the money is being judiciously expended. I do not think so large a building program will be needed for this biennium, but I recommend to you that you provide for an additional wing for the b hospital for the insane at Lincoln, as recommended by the superintendent of that institution. I regret to have to state that our state insane hospitals are still crowded and that the additional room that will be provided when this building is erected is sadly needed. Another wing for the Kearney normal school should be erected to correspond with the one authorized two years ago, and to complete the plan for the main building, designed for this growing state normal school. The last legislature was very generous in the matter of appropriations for educational purposes. They author - ized the expenditure of several hundred thousand dollars </seg>
            <seg id="p029">28 more of the state's money in that direction than had been done by previous legislatures. The state can well afford to be generous in sustaining our system of public education. Practical education should be made as easily to be obtained as possible and the standard of our schools raised as high as human hands can build or our best brains conceive. To accomplish this we need good teachers and the best instructors must necessarily come from those schools devoted to the special purpose of pedagogic education. Realizing this fact the 1909 legis - lature established two new normal schools in Nebraska, the one in northeastern Nebraska at Wayne and the other at Chadron in the northwestern portion of the Both of these new schools should be treated generously by you as they will need every possible a - ance in getting organized and under way and on the road toward effective service in furnishing additional educators to train the youth of our state. GOOD ROADS A state road law that will produce practical results in improving our highways beyond their present condition should be adopted by the legislature. A comprehei bill should be prepared embodying those provisions which have proven satisfactory in other states. Nothing will add more to the value of property nor to the welfare and profit and pleasure of the general public than will a m of well-built, first-class highways throughout the state. Good roads can be built and maintained at less cost both as to money and labor in Nebraska than in almost any other state of which I have knowledge. A few hundred dollars per mile spent upon our dirt roads produces results almost the equal of that accomplished </seg>
            <seg id="p030">29 results. I believe that in most counties the county Id be made highway commissioner a.&gt; well, and the powers and duties of that office be added to those he now has. His engineering knowledge and skill surveyor should make him the logical man for the position and the additional expense to the county would no* be very great. I he automobile is becoming more and more the vel ipid transit upon our public highways. This machine lires a good road bed to make possible its hi_ :tiveness. A small registration tax is now cha owner of each automobile in the state. R importance of good roads to the automobile indi. for the satisfactory use of these machines, a nu: states have already passed laws levying a small annual pending as many thousands upon the high favored regions. Anyone that has observed the splendid roads that can be built in Nebraska from our mother earth when engineering ability and experienced workmanship are combined with the advantage that nature has freely given us can easily see that we have the natural conditions granted us by a generous Providence for building and maintaining the very best of roau the lowest possible cost. Nature has done her sharo but we must have intelligent leadership in designing and constructing the highways, and the funds must b&lt;? pro- vided to carry on the good work. A county highway commissioner should be authorized for each county in the state who should have general supervision of all the road- building done in his county. This will make for unity of plan and design, the establishment of proper grades, the building of suitable bridges, and the general intendency essential to the accomplishment of la </seg>
            <seg id="p031">30 owners. In some states this tax is a flat rate per machine and in others it is prorated according to the rated horse - power of the automobile. A tax of $10.00 per annum per machine in Nebraska would at present turn into the treasury about $125,000 per year. Several of the eastern states where the maintenance of roads is very costly have given this matter of vehicle tax legislation a great deal of attention. In the state of New Jersey, in 1909, the automobile owners paid inio the road fund of the state treasury about $245,000. The legislature added an ap - i iation of $300,000 to the automobile tax fund and created a general road fund to be expended upon the improvement of the state highways. The $550,000 thus raised was proiated among the several counties of the state with the proviso that in order to obtain its share of the state fund any county desiring it was required to appropriate out of its own treasury a sum considerably in excess of that asked for from the state. Under this plan starting with a nucleus provided by the automobile tax. the state expended in the year mentioned more than $1,300,000 upon its roads. If it can be done in con - formity with the constitution I believe it would be well if the automobile road tax should be in lieu of any other tax upon these machines, and thus the owner of the average automobile would be required to pay no heavier tax than at present and would have the satisfaction of the improvement that it would bring to the state high - - and the public would receive the full benefit of the tax as well. Our present inheritance tax law can be used as a model for the manner of the distribution of the funds and I hope that a bill embodying the general plan herein indicated will be enacted by this legislature. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">31 The national guard under the efficient leadership and management of the present adjutant general has become a military organization of which the state may well be proud and upon which the nation can depend for efficient service in time of war. The national guard must be our real reliance for military protection in time of great national danger. A large standing army will never be possible in this republic. It is, therefore, all the more uial that the efficiency of the organized militia be held at the highest possible standard. The federal govern - ment recognizing this fact is giving liberal aid in the matter of financial assistance as well as expert advice and inspection. The legislature should also be generous in its appropriations for the support of the guard and lend them every possible encouragement because of the patriotic duty which its members take upon themselves hev join its ranks. PAKDONS, COMMUTATIONS AND PAROLES Iie matter of pardons and paroles of those cont le penitentiary at Lancaster is one of the most trying laborious duties that the governor of this state is ron ted with. We have no board of pardon .en the labor and the entire work and responsibility i upon the executive. This is getting to be a loa y that the legislature should provide for a board of Ions to deal with all matters of this kind, and I recom - d that you take such action as will establish such a I have had many applications for clemency at hand and held a great many investigations of cases that </seg>
            <seg id="p033">32 believe it is unwise to interfere, except in extreme cases, with the judgment of the court and jury, who have the best opportunities to know and consider all the facts in such matters. I have been liberal with paroles, since I believe that this system of granting an opportunity for first offenders to have one more trial to show that they can become good citizens is a scientific and humane way to deal with the problem of reformation for those who have gone astray. I have found it necessary to pardon or parole a number of convicts who were afflicted with incurable disease and whose presence in the penitentiary a menace to the health of the other inmates of the Ei and I think some law should be made \vl tion should be allowed the executive or the bo )1 upon a proper showing being made upon the 1 e prison physician and the warden. Klist of all pardons and commutations will be found nded to this message. PRIMARY ELECTION LAW The previous legislature changed very materially the primary election law of the state. The original law adopted by Nebraska provided for what is commonly known as a closed election. It sought by stringent pro - visions to keep the voters of one party from determining who the candidates of another party should be. This is a requirement that the student of party primaries has found to be essential to good government and political honesty and to worthy nominations not only in Nebraska but in every state where primary nominations prevail and two or more parties exist. The law now in force </seg>
            <seg id="p034">33 to be an open primary, but is in effect open for professes K political pirates to clandestinely vote for a candidate im he has no intention of supporting at the general tion, while at the same time the honest voter is bound time the honest voter is bound ■ominating primaries lirst came in favor becau - popularity of this plan in a number of southern But the fact, as everyone knows, is that in of the states south of Mason and Dixon's line bui one party exists that has any chance to put its nominees into office. At the conference of governors at Louisville, K\\, recently, the question of party primaries was very fully discussed. It was quite generally admitted that in states with two parties fairly evenly matched in num - and where the character and personality of the candidate of a party would largely determine its success, the one point necessary to achieve, in order to make by the provisions of the law and his own sense of party honor and votes in the column provided for the party whicli claims his allegiance. Nominations by primaries is still in an experimental stage in this state. For more than a hundred years our national government has Etained its high standard of efficiency by party govern- . The responsibility and organization due to men ing themselves into political parties that stand for those things in popular government which they honestly believe are essential to the general welfare of the state or of the nation has been the chief factor in the develop- ment of Anglo-Saxon civilization. If we had only one tical party then the making of a primary law would simple thing. With two parties struggling for control t standing for principles more or less the opposite in , a satisfactory primary measure becomes a different question. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">34 To permit the members of one party to participate in the nominations of another will invariably bring about one of two results. If the contest is close between the parties it will result in the nomination of poor candidates. If one party is known to have a large majority, it will result in the gradual elimination of the minority party. The building up of parties and the nomination of strong candidates by both parties requires that the members of each party must only be allowed to participate in the nomination of their own party candidates. In states where there is practically but one party, as a rule, the minority party having no chance of electing its own candidates, will ordinarily support the best candidates of the majority party. At the last governor's conference an executive of a southern state said that his commonwealth had nom - inated its candidates in party primaries for twenty years and that this had been an entirely satisfactory system to his people, but in answer to a question by a northern governor he admitted there was practically only one party in his state. The fact of the matter is that in most southern states the primary is the decisive contest and the election in November is merely a form. If we have a wide-open primary with no party lines drawn then any primary is a useless expense. The candidates should be placed upon the ballot by petition and the November election would decide whom the people desire for their officers. If men are not to stand for some principle that represents an organization, then the idea of nominations either by primaries or conventions is folly. But organization has always been essential to the </seg>
            <seg id="p036">35 or business, and the idea that governmental reform or the selection of worthy candidates for office can be ac - complished without the aid of this, the greatest force in modern civilization, has no foundation either in ex - perience or in reason. There are certain inherent a nesses in the practical working of the primary idea that cannot be entirely gotten rid of, but which should be eliminated as far as possible. In primaries there is little lection, deliberation or leadership. The eandi&gt; • themselves, instead of being chosen to go on the ballot by others competent to act in the matter. Under the convention system many hundreds of r utive citizens of a party are gathered together with a sense of pride and responsibility because of their long association 11 the organization which they represent and with lie regard for the responsibility which they ow. party and to the state, and a candidate that can mn gauntlet of criticism and win the approval of a ority of such an assemblage must have at least a licum of merit. But under the primary system it is n difficult to induce worthy men to file for offices of ortance, and thus the voters are forced to choose veen men of whom they know nothing, and some - ?s, perhaps it is well for the candidate that such is case. Inder our first primary act it was found that the ? position of the names upon the ballot, the accidental abetical index of one's name, was often the deter - ing factor in winning success in a state-wide primary, lizing this we have provided for the rotation of ies upon the ballot, but this of itself is an admission the whole matter is largely a gambler's chance. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">36 so as to give everybody an equal chance in the lottery. This vital weakness comes because of the indifference of the voters or lack of knowledge as to the merit of the candidates upon the ballot. It can only be remedied by in some way increasing the interest of the general public as to the importance of the primary. Recognizing the force of this point the state of Colorado recently enacted a law which provides for a convention to select names to go upon the primary ballot. Xo candidate's name is permitted to be printed upon the primary ballot who does not receive a certain per cent of votes at the selection convention. Another objection to the primary is the expense that itails upon the state and the candidates for nom - inations. Because of the fact that the average citizen seems indifferent as to the result of the primary, the nominations are most likely to go to those who put money and organization behind their candidacy. In i his state the corrupt practice act keeps down the ad - on df the amount of money spent in the interest of the several candidates, but in other states where these provisions do not prevail, and the entire matter is laid bare, a better picture of the growing expense of primaries is presented. In a southern state two years ago a governor was defeated in a party primary. He was a candidate for re - nomination and his opponent apparently made no effort in, and the governor supposed that he was to be easily renominated. But his opponent had an organ - ization behind him with plenty of money that got its voters to the polls on primary day with the result that the governor was defeated. This fall the same can- </seg>
            <seg id="p038">37 campaign expense statement shows that he spent over $39,000 to win the victory. The point to be noted is that he could just as easily have been nominated at the previous primary if he had expended the $39,000 at that time. The governor of a great northern state, in dis - •ng the cost of primary elections with me, when in - formed that it was rumored that his primary cost him $60,000, he immediately replied that he had only spent $30,000, but that his opponent's primary exp&gt; amounted to $80,000. A governor-elect of an ea~ state filed an election expense account this fall of $35,000 — he was nominated in a convention. Had he been nom - inated in a primary where the fight was as fierce as it was at the election, and often the primary is the most election, and often the primary is the most Iely fought of the two battles, his primary expense Id no doubt have been as large as his late election was certified to be. Congressmen have certified to lary expenses of from $15,000 to $20,000 and $25,000, United States senators to sums exceeding $100,000. expense account of one side in a recent senatorial iary fight in a certain state has been certified Ii the late primary in Nebraska il defeated candidates expended more money hiring automobiles and ecting an organization, there is no doubt but that results could have been changed, providing always : their opponents did not also hire more automobiles more party workers. The candidate who hires 1,000 jmobiles on primary day will vanquish him who hires 500 automobiles. Napoleon Bonaparte said, "Vic - r goes to him who has the heaviest battalions." In </seg>
            <seg id="p039">38 pr iiTicii y CicCtioris success win 01 lcugsl porcfi upon trip banner of him who has the largest automobile brigade. There is still another feature which must be taken into account in dealing with the party primary in states like Nebraska, and that is that the centers of population will generally dominate the primary although they may not control at election time. The indifference and careless - ness of the voters at the primary as compared with the interest shown at the general election makes this possible. A few of the most populous counties in the state can easily dominate any primary because their centers of population are congested, their voters are easily gotten to the polls and they understand the value of organ - ization. This has been observable in both the primaries that have already been held in Nebraska and will con - tinue to grow more evident as these centers of population see the tremendous advantage that they have. The matter of control of primaries by centers of pop - ulation probably will trouble us as little in Nebraska as in any state in the Union so that point may be passed over. To impress upon you the importance of these features which I have touched upon, I shall quote from the recent remarks of several distinguished governors whose states have had the primary law in practice to show you that these problems are confronting the people of every state where the system is in force as well as our own. The governor-elect of Oklahoma says, "There are two things connected with the primary law that are not entirely satisfactory, and that must be remedied. Pro - visions must be made to prevent the members of one party from voting in the primary of another and some method must be devised for the arranging of names on a ballot, so that one candidate will not have the ad- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">39 to participate in the nominations of another will result either in the nomination of poor candidates, or the Kical elimination of the minority party. I feel that lethods so far adopted have not been entirely satis - ry and that our efforts should be to secure such modification in the existing primary laws as to accomplish this result." Governor Deneen of Illinois says, that his state has not had a long experience with primaries but ■as had more different laws on the subject than all other states combined. He said that they had had difficulty in Illinois in preventing men from voting in nore than one party primary. Upon the points above mentioned, Governor Fort of New Jersey says in part. as follows: "The direct primary system will not prove satisfactory except under strict regulation in the follow - ing respect; a system of enrollment at least a year ahead Ke election is necessary to keep the primary of one ' from being voted in by members of another party, method of petitioning for candidates to run at the iry should be simple and easily understood. Re- count by order of courts should be authorized." I have put these points, which experience has shown is essential to a successful and satisfactory primary' law before you at some length, hoping that they may assist you in framing a law that I trust will be not only a satis - factory measure for Nebraska but a model for other states to follow. The basic idea of the individual voter having the right to express his wishes as to the nominees of his party by direct vote is fundamentally a correct theory of popular government and the people will not lightly give up che party primary because it is at first </seg>
            <seg id="p041">40 shall protect the integrity of party organizations, and this must be done or the whole system will be condemned as a failure. 1 shall close my observations upon this question by ing from the statement of an Iowa statesman upon subject which I consider a strong summary of my views upon the matter: "There should be a system of registration provided so that it would be impossible for a democrat to vote for a republican candidate or a republican to vote for a dem - ocratic candidate for nomination at a primary election. No republican should desire to be nominated by dem - ocratic votes and no democrat should depend upon republican votes for his nomination. If the matter of selecting candidates is left strictly to the party which the candidate represents the best man in each party will usually be nominated, and every candidate's nomination will stand upon his merits and on his party's platforms and come before the people as the choice of the organ - ization with which he affiliates. This applies to all parties and I only refer to the democratic and republican parties because they are the two leading parties in the state and nation." THE PROPOSED INITIATIVE AND REFERENDUM The legislature should submit to the voters of the state an amendment to our state constitution reserving to the people the right to initiate legislation by petition and to exercise the power of the referendum which is, in effect, reserving to the citizens of the state the power to veto legislation by popular vote. The initiative is designed to place in the hands of the </seg>
            <seg id="p042">41 I ile the power to make laws for themselves when latures through indifference or ulterior influences refuse to enact the legislation they desire. The itive and referendum combined will insure popular rnment not so much because of laws that may be ted under the right conferred in the proposed amend - t but rather because of the latent power which the ibers of the legislature will know is in the possession le people ready to be exercised whenever the house senate shall fail to enact the laws demanded of them he electorate of the state. The right of the referendum has long been exen in this country as to constitutional amendments and it has also been one of the fundamental principles of the English constitution for more than two hundred j and under it the British ministry exercises the rigi: appeal to the country for its judgment, whenever they shall elect to do so upon a parliamentary measure. Afl il known the referendum has for years been one of the basic principles upon which the liberty and lav the Swiss republic have been founded. The wisdom of reserving this right to the people has been vindicated wherever tried. It is never called into action until after the legislative branch has acted upon some policy of government and hence preceding its invocation is al deliberation, debate and legislative responsibility. Both by reason and experience it is safe to assume that this power will rarely if ever be abused and the requirements preliminary to its being exercised by the people should not be made too difficult to be easily complied with when occasion demands that it should be invoked. Kpular initiative in matters of legislation is a power difficult to deal with intelligently and with a cer- </seg>
            <seg id="p043">42 referendum. For reasons that are apparent to everyone, the principle of representative government and the delegation of powers to a greater or less degree has been found to be essential to the development of good govern - ments among men. Debate, deliberation and continued study of important questions of government are ab - solutely necessary before satisfactory and efficient laws can be framed and enacted. For this reason, for many centuries the people have delegated to chosen representa - tives the power to enact the laws which they desire. In political campaigns and platforms the citizens express the general principles of government which they wish embodied into laws, leaving to their chosen servants the duty of determining the form and provisions of the statutes which shall give force to their commands. This practice of centuries, based upon reason and ex - perience, cannot be changed in a moment with the cer - tainty that the people will at once take upon themselves the duty and responsibility which they have heretofore trusted to their representatives. It has been proven in this state, by repeated experience, that the average voter is slow to express himself by voting directly upon matters of legislation. The subterfuge of counting ballots, marked in party circles as being cast for or against constitutional amendments because of party ex - pressions upon the measure, has been found to be a legal necessity to the adoption of such amendments because of the unwillingness of the voter to register his judgment upon matters about which he has not sufficient informa - tion or is lacking in interest. Because of these facts which I have stated and which we know are fundamental and based upon the unanswerable logic of experience, </seg>
            <seg id="p044">43 upon such questions as the public mind has been focused upon for a considerable length of time, so that public ntiment upon the proposed measure has crystallized nto concrete form. The student of the question of direct ition resulting from popular initiative is at once truck with the fact that but few measures of any kind. ubmitted by this means, have been enacted into laws his or any other country. In twenty years the . public has submitted only twenty-nine measur popular approval and of this number mear n were rejected and only thirteen adopted. In the ouri two amendments h n submitted ■ both of them were defeated. The state of Montana constitutional provisions for this form of legislation, but no measures or amendments have been adopted by this method in that state. South Dakota has had this &gt;n in its constitution for some time, but no law n adopted which was initiated by popular ion, and at the last election all questions submitted under the referendum as well were defeated save one This legislature should study well the experiences had jnd the results obtained under the initiative and refer- ndum in other states and profit from their example in &gt;rder to adopt an amendment free from their mistakes ind containing those provisions proven by experience as •ssential to a satisfactory law. \s far as possible the amendment adopted should dis- ourage the submission of questions that should more properly be left to legislative action, and thus prevent uch a deluge of measures being offered under its pro- visions for popular decision that the mere flood of num- </seg>
            <seg id="p045">44 that I have consulted has agreed that this is a point that must be guarded with care. The officials whom I quote are warm advocates of direct legislation and the opinions expressed are given in the light of the experience had in their respective states. Governor Vessey of South Dakota in dealing with this question states, " I hardly know what plan to suggest to prevent too many measures being submitted at one election, but I think if there could be a limit established we would get a more intelligent vote. I am firmly of the opinion that we are placing before our voters too many candidates and too many propositions for their consider - ation at any one election. I think the chief objection to the operation of our law is the small number of petitioners necessary to referend or initiate a matter, being only 5 per cent. I believe it should require at least 15 per cent, and I am inclined to think that 20 per cent would be better. ipon the same point Attorney General A. M. Crawford 'regon writes: "I would suggest several amendments ur laws, however. One, that more than 8 per cent of voters be required to sign a petition to invoke the ative. Then it will not be resorted to by designing ons to promote some private enterprise. I would :est from 10 per cent to 15 per cent and in no than 10 per cent." Illinois enacted a measure limiting the number of bills to be submitted at one election to three in number and the selection of the measures to be submitted to be determined by the order of their being filed in the office of the secretary of state. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">* 45 declared adopted. I think it will at once be admitted that no amendment to the constitution should be declared adopted without a majority of all the votes cast at the election being registered in its favor. To provide that a minority and perhaps even a small minority of the voters of the state could change the fundamental law of the commonwealth, which even the supreme court i is not allowed to disturb, would be dangerous in a very marked degree, in my judgment. to statutory measures the case is much different. A statute can be repealed or amended at any time, provided it is done so in a constitutional manner. Stat - utory laws are subject to judicial construction and can be set aside by the courts, if found in conflict with the constitution. This is a government by majorities, and in no case does our law permit the adoption of any bill or amend - ment, except by a constitutional majority. To amend the constitution requires a favorable majority of all the f&gt; cast at the election at which the amendment is litted. To secure the legal passage of a bill by r the house or senate of this legislature you must d in its favor not only a majority of those voting also a majority of all those entitled to vote upon it under the constitution. In my opinion, the amend - ment to be adopted should provide that before a law shall be approved under its provisions, the total vote cast upon any certain measure should be a substantial majority of all the votes at the election before it shall be declared adopted, that is, a bill to be adopted should receive a majority vote of a majority of the votes cast. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">adoption by but a minor fraction of the total electorate of the state through the power of organized wealth and concentrated effort. Unless care is taken to prevent organized special interests from using to its advantage the power conferred by the amendment you submit, the results flowing from it may be radically different from that anticipated by some of its ardent advocates. This measure has been urged by some as a general panacea and in lieu of all other enactments or political action dealing with the liquor question. The fact is, however, that no radical temperance legislation has been achieved by this method in any state in the Union. On the other hand, a prohibition amendment has been defeated under its provisions in one state by a majority of more than two hundred thousand votes, and in two other common - wealths by invoking the power conferred by such an amendment, the liquor interests have been able to nullify and kill county option measures after such bills had previously been adopted by these states. Experience would seem to indicate that the liquor interests are much more in danger of hostile laws from legislative action than by reason of the adoption of the initiative and the referendum. You gentlemen of the legislature must cast your votes upon measures with the bright light of public opinion beating upon you when the roll is called. You cannot dodge or ask that the question at issue be referred to the secretary of the polling booth. The man whose name is signed to this message is a living example of the efficiency and power of the organized liquor interests when working behind the bulwark of ballot-secrecy and irt </seg>
            <seg id="p048">47 I [any states are seeking to prevent minority nom - ions in party primaries where a large number of men for a certain office. The law in these states requires . before a candidate shall be declared the nominee of party he shall have received a substantial percentage .11 the votes cast in his party primary for that par - lar office. When a number of worthy candidates file party primary they may divide the vote of the better lent of a party to such an extent that an undesirable iidate may win though the element behind him may fiuch in the minority for the reason that their votes be easily bunched and thus a candidate be nom - d who represents but a small minority in his party s some such safeguard as I have indicated is pro - 1. If this is necessary as to candidates, it is much ■ so as to measures, as selfish interests can easily ! this power one by which the people can be robbed eir rights rather than a means for their protection if a loophole is provided, because of the fact that the amendment has been carelessly drawn. I relieve that with the adoption of this amendment you Id provide that votes in a party circle upon the &gt;t should not be counted for or against a measure riitted for popular approval under its provisions. No r state has such an unscientific, illogical and danger - provision of law. In my judgment it is not sound ic policy to count men's votes in this manner for or nst candidates but I deem it a much greater perver - of the fundamental principles of popular government ermit laws to be adopted by such means. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">48 We have no bad effects from the practice of this policy as yet, because the amendments to the constitution adopted by reason of it had been long debated before the bar of public opinion and attention concentrated upon them for years. Before their submission to the voters they were debated and approved by a constitutional majority of both the house of representatives and the senate and after this had still to run the gauntlet of ap - proval by representative conventions and party primaries in order to secure the counting of party votes in their favor. These conditions, all to be overcome prior to popular vote had insured prolonged discussion, debate and deliberation and party responsibility, preceding sub - mission. The number of measures submitted at any one election has never been more than two in number. Failure as to any one of the requirements I have men - tioned has always defeated such measures in Nebraska. The fact that one political party failed in the last primary by 1,462 votes to approve the amendment to the con - stitution proposed by the last legislature undoubtedly defeated this measure at the general election. The rule that votes in the party circle were to go as the primary decreed empowered these 1,462 votes cast in the August primary to deliver more than 50,000 democratic votes against the amendment in November. It cannot be known what the actual intent of the voters of that party was in this matter. More than 100,000 votes were counted for the amendment and less than 5,000 votes cast at the party primary in August delivered the great majority of these to the support of the amendment. If this rule is to continue in force in this state, those interested in special legislation will soon learn that con - ventions and primaries will really determine the defeat </seg>
            <seg id="p050">49 interests to work in for the purpose of punishing or rewarding those who aspire to political power. The same selfish interests will be quick to take advantage of this same possibility as to laws and measures if legislation is Become a matter dependent upon the control of cal machines and party primaries. Another very important matter for you to con - in the drafting of an effective amendment dealing with direct legislation is as to the form of the ballot, to be used in submitting questions to the voters. If you blunder in this particular alone, you may easily render the whole amendment of no effect. I cannot find a - amendment or law which has been adopted by the people of any state where the law provides that the me voted upon must be submitted to the voters upon a separate ballot from the one containing the names of the candidates for office. Also you must determine whether the entire bill to be voted upon shall be printed upon the ballot for the information of the voter or only a descriptive ballot title. You must determine how extensively the ballot title shall be and who shall have the right to frame it. I think the very size of the South Dakota ballot where the law requires that the entire measure shall be pn upon the ballot has a strong tendency to cause the voter to ignore the whole matter because of the fact that he has not time to even read it, let alone digest it. On the other hand, if the ballot titles are obscure or the number of measures submitted too numerous when only the title is printed upon the ballot, the same confusion and diffi - culty upon the part of the voter to vote intelligently is encountered. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">50 I would recommend that the amendment to be adopted should require a petition of more than 10 per cent of the electorate of the state to initiate legislation and not less than 8 per cent of the same vote to invoke the referendum. This represents the concensus of opinion of the author - ities which I have gathered from every state that now has the law in operation and from those who are warm advocates of the idea. E amendment should provide that only a limited r of measures could be submitted at any one elec - a satisfactory rule for preference can be deter- Eat a majority of all votes cast at the election at i a constitutional amendment is submitted should quired to be cast in its favor to secure its adoption. That at least 75 per cent of all the votes cast at any election be required to be cast upon a statutory measure submitted to the people under the initiative, before it shall be declared carried. The measures to be voted upon should be printed upon the same ballot as that upon which the candidates for office appear and should be described by suitable ballot title to be drawn under the direction of the attorney general reserving the petitioners the right to appeal to the supreme court if dissatisfied with the descriptive title furnished by the legal authority of the state, they to submit to the court a ballot title satisfactory to the proponents of the law and the court thereupon to promptly decide as to which title will best inform the voter as to the meaning and object of the proposed law. I [formation as to the measures to be submitted, under initiative or referendum, should be furnished to the rs by advertisement in the newspapers of the state </seg>
            <seg id="p052">51 and also by printed arguments, pro and con, offered by those for or against any such measure, the same to be printed by the state and distributed to the voter - their information and guidance. I would strike the party ring from the present ballot form as provided by statute, but in any event the proposed amendment should expressly provide that votes shall not be counted either for or against any amendment or statute unless the voter shall indicate his will by marking in the proper square upon the special ballot opposite the measure sub- I have gone to considerable length to give you my views upon the primary question and the initiative and referendum, because these are matters dealing directly with the fundamentals of government. I approved the present primary law against my better judgment because I have a well-grounded objection to the exercise of the veto power by the executive except in grave cases and I had not expressed my views fully upon that matter in my message to the former legislature, and, therefore, I hesitated to disapprove a bill that had passed both houses by a considerable majority and upon which I had not plainly stated my views in a constitutional manner. The opinions that I have expressed to you in this message are based primarily upon the iron logic of experience and the knowledge that I have gained in the office that the state has honored me with, and after diligent and earnest study and consultation with the executives of many other states of the Union, and others in authority, whose judgment I believe valuable, because of the opportunities they have had to gain knowledge at first hand. I have every confidence that vou will use the </seg>
            <seg id="p053">52 utmost care and consideration and exercise your best judgment in these questions as well as every other matter that shall come before you pertaining to the welfare of the state. I wish to express to you and to the people of the state my appreciation of the great honor done me in entrusting to my care the high office which I am about to leave and to say to you, gentlemen of the legislature of Nebraska, that I hope your duties will prove a pleasant task to you personally and that the session may result in satisfaction and honor to the members here assembled and to the welfare of the people of the state. Respectfully sub- fSigned) Ashton C. Shallenberger. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>