<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ELEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Norfolk State Hospital TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1910</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Norfolk State Hospital TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER. 30. 1910 Bt J. P PECIVAL, Superintendent Claflin Printing Co. »jg* Cnlversity Pl»o«. »br </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE BOARD OF CONTROL Hob. K. B. Gowles, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings, Chairman Hon. George C. Junkin Secretary of State Hon. L. G. Brian Treasurer of State Hon. Arthur M"ullpn Attr».r.mr n. &gt;««..., 1 Attorney General RESIDENT OFFICERS J. P. Pecival. M. D W. D. Guttery, M.D M. H. Newman, M. D Elizabeth Leeee Superintendent First Assistant Physician Second Assistant Physician Superintendent of Nurses Herman Grei-kt Steward </seg>
            <seg id="p003">407 1 O I I IS K\C'l lt'Ill'V. . \N'lt * &gt;I1 ' . tMlit 1 I ' Wl.r I). 11 compliance with tin- stEtutory renuiremei have tin biennial repori i&gt;f the Norfolk State Bos- •eriod of twenty-four months, commencing IV mber 1. 1908, to November :in. 1910, inclusive. Also i- atioiis and present conditions embracing at this tun charge of the institution February 1. 1909, with h; the following ot1i&lt;-i-rs in charge: Dr. -I. I'. Pecival, Kupt-rin- &lt;-nt : Dr. W. I), (lottery, first assistant physician: Dr. K Kelley. second assistant physician ami pathologist ; Miss BelW (lark superintendent of nurseH; Herman Gereeke, steward; I Itzmer, clerk. Miss Brace Kidder. matron. Miss ('lark, superintendent of nurse*, resigned June 1 was sue led by Miss S. If. Sliatto. who resigned 1909. and was imeceeded by Mi&gt;s Elizabeth Leec ident of nurses. Miss Kidder resigned November 3, 1909 s Hueceeded by Miss Theresa Kriz. as matron. Mr. Laun &lt; r resigned May 15, 1910, and was succeeded t&gt;y Boy C. Hutehi - i. as clerk. Dr. E. KeHey resigned May 26, 1910. and :eeeded by Dr. M. 8. Lombard. Dr. Lombard resigned No - mber 10, 1910, and was succeeded by Dr. M. H. Newman, as &gt;ond assistant physician, November in. 1910. MOVEMENTS AND POPULATION. At the last biennium the hospital had 2v2 patient* e .-ml of the present biennium we have 309 patients, receiving tients from thirty-one counties north of the Platte river. We v, paroled and discharged 14&lt;&gt; patients during this biennial*, ,i iiinl mii iiicnasc of '21 patients. i!t ami was succeeded bv Miss Elizabeth !.■ supenn- endent of nurses. Miss Kiil&lt;l.r resigned November :!. 1 i&gt; succeeded bv Miss Theresa Kriz. as matron. .Mr. Laun LMicd May 15, 1910, and was sueceeded by Boy C. Hutehi Dr. E. Kellev resigned May 26, 1910, am! seeded by Dr. M. 8. Lombard. Dr. Lombard resigned No in. 1910. and was succeeded by Dr. M. II. Newmai November in. 1!»1 MOVEMENTS AND POPULATION ■ &gt;..■&gt; \t r bv havintr ings completed. The present population -Moii of this new • ■lit </seg>
            <seg id="p004">408 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT ing, and the old building that was vacated, was taken in pos - session by the female patients, as it was necessary to relieve the two female buildings. Each of these cottages were built for the ultimate capacity of forty, and we had as many as seventy-five, so you can see the new building completed, only relieved the congestion and the increase of thirty patients, is about the limit that we can accept, and we are anxiously waiting to have the large female hospital building completed, which has been delayed since 1907. and will not be complted. until the next legislature passes a deficiency. This building not being completed, cripples the institution, beyond comprehension, and will not be able to relieve this conp mdition until the Imilding is completed. HOSPITAL S-.iic Hospital is a crying necessity, that cannot be ignored, umanity demands it. This hospital never has been provided with hospital accommodations, to treal the insane according to modern methods, and with all the unfortunate surrounding such a situation. We simply d&lt; ditions should l&gt;e property red&lt; Nebraska should provide for the the best we can, but the con - eraed, and the great state of unfortunates. Insanity is increasing, as pop ings should be provided for, in i all the insane in this state. At insane person to every 510, and ulation is increasing, and build - id vance. to give care and treat the present time, we have one not later than ten years from now we will have one to every 410. as the older the state gets the more insane we have. The problem is not so much the care of the present insane, as the causes of insanity are found in our social habits, customs and tendencies of our times. A hospital is a place where an effort is being made to cure, or at least improve the conditions of every patient. The insane are a lot of unfertu uuch more dangerous to themselves than to any. . Furthermore, while only some forms of insanity are curable, according to the present medical kowledge. More patients who have suffered injury to their intellectual fac - ulties, through a destructive mental disease, more properly a brain disease, are not the helpless and useless lot of people, as they were formerly considered. They are capable of considerable re-education. On the basis of these fundamental considerations, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">409 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK i ncdiril problem of the Norfolk State ll» me appears sub-divided u follows: (A) The insane (B) The care of the physically ill pat* u-s sub-divided u follows: (A) TIk B The eare of the physically ill patients, ihronic patients. al and practical work has clearly d&lt; A Experimental and practical work has clearly d&lt; ible recovery from many forms of mental disi sovery from many forms of mental di&gt;' iscd in their intensity, by earl - nits in less actual harm. It is equally iv be decreased in their intensity, by early M, care, therefore results in less actual harm. It is equally that in early care, it is necessary to rely upon meas ;are. it is necessary to rely upon meat raight chair, and heroic doses of Hyoaeme, to be looked upon as liiirmfnl. rather than 1 upon as harmful, rather than 1, eatment of the insane, and has be&lt; isaiie. ami has bei itinent oi monstrated as being unnecessary. The excellent resul' g unnecessary. The excellent recall nt of acute insanity by employment of Hydro f acute insanity by employment of Hydro- ires, show the methods to be followed: Hj show the methods to be followed: Ilydro- reful feeding, out-door exercise, fre ful feeding, out-door exerci ,uent fitment in bed. All the indicated additional n bed. All the indicated additional I in earl} I insanity, to get tli trlv • insanity, to get the o every hospital naideraW* spital fin patients who are physically ill. and vho arc physically ill. and so weak. cial attention. In man insanity is nothing 1. In many cases, insanity is nothii or malnutrition, affecting mot- nutrition, affecting more icularly the brain. All such eases must lie properly provided for Ul such eases must be properly provid areful nursing. About .")(» per cent of insan and in hospitals er eeni of insane, as found in hospit, ited to a certain extent, meaning that theii rtain extent. meaning that their nt.-d to a ure impaired, and are still able of acquirin| impaired, and are still able of acqui • along industrial lines. ; alone industrial lines, bj nd repeated instructions. They can be taught very many structions. They can be taught very leful occupations, and in this way. they can prove then nd in this way, they can prove then support. m leave the institution, and return to leave the institution, and return to thei a living for thei reliev uniti' are, and there is no reason why 1&gt; n btained in carefully planned indust ijis established in hospitals for insane. Idl iv in a normal individual, therefore, the in dustrial re-education and their usefulness, is in my opinion th vital problem in the chronic insa: </seg>
            <seg id="p006">410 V There lias been installed in this hospital, a system of record the loose leaf type, with a vertical filing case, which wil promote, and in fact, require the A typewriter has been in areful individualization of each ailed in the physician's offices, an. I all records have been madi in typewriting by the use of tmanent black type. This system has entailed more work than &lt;&gt;ld. but the results have I n verv rrntifvina i&gt;, ti,..t ti... ■n very gratifying, in that tin records will he complete, and will afford data in years I- statistical compilation. The 1; as far as the meagre facilitie ivision has been made in th npleted. for a laboratory of tli •rapeutio measures have been ■d results. Provision for the large hospital building for Irotherapeutic plant . boratory work has been carried now available will allow, ami new hospital building when most approved type. llydro - irried into effect ft |y with the future h-is also been made women, for the eqoipmeni of a NURSING DEPARTMENT Our training school for nurses was organized in 1907 but during the changing of administration. February 1. 1909 the outgoing officers disbanded the training school, and I im diately reorganized the training: It has a course of two years. work, in some of the large h&lt; nurses. .Miss Leece, has made h •hool. and it is now on firm ftnd six months" poct-graduat&lt; piials. The superintendent o rself very useful in the promo lion of this work, which all the sin has been due to her irts. The training school is ils of training schools of the members of the American i ■ and practice 1&lt;&gt; obtain oi nt rv. and accept only those Millions, who possess the pi now registered under the stan State of \ew York, and w Association. It has been our pur - ur pupils from our surrounding • who have not worked in other roper requirements of character. and fair education. It has take n much work on the part of tin superintendent of nurses and physicians in the way of instrih tions and lectures, but the results have been verv food Tli n very good. The training school has also attended to the industrial class, and embroidery has made great advance among our female patients. I nursing course has been working under many difficulties. chief one has been poor living quarters, and it is desirable special quarters should be furnished for them, to which </seg>
            <seg id="p007">411 they may be able to retire after their work is doi njoy the privacy and &lt;|iiietness whieh is now impossible. For this purpose 1 believe an Appropriation should be made sufficient to build the nurses and attendants a home, large enough for at i^t forty-five people. We have been handicapped by the phy rounding country, who have been knocking Mciiitls of m our training school, and influenced the nurses not to take hospital. I believe this is pure ignorance t r.nmiiL: in Kthe physicians" part, as none of them ever visited this insti - on. and therefore are not able to criticise the valuable work e in the institution. rGESTED CHANGE IN OUR STATUTES, RELATING TO OUR INSANE HOSPITAL. There appears to lie widespread sentiment in favor of ehang- tthe name of the "Insane Hospital" to the single title "State pital." It is said that the very name carries with it a stigma, to those who have relatives among the patients, and it is injury n confined in this hospital, seeking to those who ha ild up their careers anew, and this sentiment is one that should diverted, and there is no reason why the name should be changed. Frequently those that recover, atv sent to their ittives or communities, and a person like that is always aded by the neighbors and everybody shuns him. and in this y do not give the unfortunate person a chance to show that he well again, and has to find a home for himself in another I At the present time all the epileptics are committed to the UM Hospital, and no doubt they contribute to the over-erowd - all the insane hospitals, and I believe that there should be tate institution built for the epileptics, as many of them are insane, and it is not justice to rank them among the insane, st of the states have an institution for the epileptics, and I be - e the state of Nebraska should also have an institution for the leptl NEEDS OF THE INSTITUTION I Laundry and the drying room is inadequate for the needs the institution, and there must be new machinery installed mnniiiity. where In- lias been unknown </seg>
            <seg id="p008">412 rooms I have made larger, also enlarged the assorting room. I have bought a body ironer, also a new fifteen horsepower motor, and all the machinery is run by motor. All the irons have heated on the stove, and I have installed lately all electric iron*, which are quite important in our laundry. Also one new wash - ing machine, as the institution is enlarging, and so machinery has to be enlarged. ENGINE ROOM tWe have installed several motors, 1 250-horsepower boiler, il also ■ new direct connected engine and generator. Also a new switchboard, which was very much needed in the insti - tution. Our coal question is quite important, as the coal has to be hauled three miles to the institution, and it is very expensive to us. so I believe that it is absolutely necessary to have the auto - matic stokers installed. Also our chimney is only eighty high, and the draft is not sufficient, therefore the stack should be raised fifty feet, and that would make quite an item in our coal bill. Our heat and electric plant, is at present in the be ondition, and I am in hopes that in the near future we will have our own storage battery for lijrhtin^r the institution at night in place of baying electricity from the city plant. That would Ik -SOO every year. TELEPHONES At the present time we have a telephone system installed by the Bell Telephone Co. It is the old button system, and it is not very satisfactory in our institution. We pay big money tor renting these phones, and some of them are not in use part of the time. 1 should recommend that the state institution should install its own automatic telephone system, which would cost us about $1,500. This would save us s2."&gt;.on a month in telephones, and •*4&lt;Hiu a month for a telephone operator, as the automatic s\ no switch board. I believe this would lie quite a saving, and not only this, when we want the phones, we could use them, and repair them ourselves whenever it may be necessary. A NEW ELECTRIC LINE 'ther long standing want, is a side track to the institution. We pay out annually £4.000 for hauling supplies and coal to the </seg>
            <seg id="p009">HOSPITAL FOR I NORFOLK 413 We have been using our influence to have a sidetrack put in from the Omaha. Minneapolis &amp; St. Paul R. R.. and have not succeeded, so I would recommend that the state build its )wn track from the institution to the city of Norfolk, and there with the Chicago North-Western R.R., and over onn this tr iltl use an electric car. run by it- borage 1 with the city electric plant. In this way very handy com .yam-. • for the employe !-Y and the visitors, going to and from the institution, and in this wav we woul ible to haul all of our coal to our bins and lpplies. and I am sure that this car would pay for itsdf. and would save this $4,000 a year. I have figured it \v 000 to build this line to the city, and it would pay for itself in four vear ited institutions in the state of Kentucky, and a have their own electric lines, running to and from n nd tiny not only pay. hut they make money for Either have ;i side track put in by the railr- - 1 its own electric line. BUSINESS DEPARTMENT nance of the hospital, the sum of $80,000 was i 1 by the last legislature. The pn ri through the physical hiennium without A i deficiency, and I think we will save about one of the large buildings was no' pleted as promised, and I thought it my duty to save all tht money possible for the state of Nebraska. We also had a] jriated $40,000 for employes 1 wages, and I think we will e Hit ahead on this appropriation. The last biennium shows, that it cost the institution ••r27() a year for each patient. In the pn I'M for each patient, to run th iving &lt;r capita head, which are gratifying HYDROTHERAPEUTIC OUTFIT it in&lt;: insane pat. iry that the hospital be equipped with l proper apparatn ivintr tin- patients water treatment </seg>
            <seg id="p010">414 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT baths, stimulating baths, shower, sponge, etc. Before the new female hospital building is completed, all these appara' should be installed, as we have a room arranged where the ap - paratus could be used. This will cost about $4,000. Also a new itor should be installed in this building, as everything is arranged for it. This will cost about $1,500. PAINTING AND OUTSIDE IMPROVEMENTS Ewill be necessary to paint all the roofs on the buildings imiiKT. Also paint all the buildings internally, and this e done, as the walls look uncleanly, and the roofs must painted, as the paint is peeling off, which will cost about GREEN HOUSE Elt will be necessary to enlarge our green house, at 1 ake it 0OC« as large as it is at the present time. For the ?r we are unable to provide for raising flowers, and in the ig time, to commence early vegetables to grow. For that m we sometimes have late vegetables, and as the institution larging, so ought the green house be enlarged. This will about $1,000.00. SUBWAYS le years ago they have built subways, connecting one building to the other, so in case of very cold weather, or unpba&gt; - ant weather in the summer. It is necessary to carry all the food to each cottage and dining room, from the kitchen, through these subways. All these subways need repair, as they are leak - ing, and after a rain, or when the snow begins to thaw, the m - through the cement walks into the subways, and all thes&lt; - subways must be repaired, and if not repaired before long, they cannot be used. It will also be necessary to connect the new fe - male building with an extension subway. This is estimated to about $2,000.00. AMUSEMENTS Nothing is better appreciated than amusements, by *our chronic insane patients. During the wMnter months, we have dances for the patients, every Friday night. I have also made runt* nt s wit h im &gt; vm ** Dicturcs a rid I \\n \ t* sh t isfit j &lt; 1 ni vm* 1 1 tnnt </seg>
            <seg id="p011">IOSPIT tin- patients enjoy these shows, mi 1 boughi n moving machine ;ind r.-nt of films .mtv week. This way we give moving picture show every Sunday night. During the MKltltl mpiis. and during th.- winter months, in oui iiu.Miii.-nt is appreciated by all th wonderful gedatory effeet, and is very in* ting to these patients. We abo take tl ■&gt;r am. re-educating to these patients. \\V also take th,- pi iin-nts. thai are (it for them, to the city, i.-ii n. to the city, t hi at may \»- able to enjoy it. We also have a zoological ex 0 enjoy it. We also have i zoological ga roeneed hi build, and in this, the patients tak« in this, tin Tli, ropriated $4,000.00 to build ■ barn. I , 4.1 MM I.I Ml to | ml. that the barn would noi be large enough •n would not be large enough i-t. and I suggested to them thai they i iggested to tli&lt;-iu that they : ii. and in this way. purchased our own . H.l my own barn, and in this way. purchased our own eemeni il the patienta make the cement block* them patients make t! ,,t hi hese we build the barn, and in this way. w. uild the barn, and in this wi 1 a large barn for horses. The six. nd hereafter, all small building will !»,■ This will be ■ large saving, and a new in HOSPITAL GROUNDS AND LAWNS \\ an Ua ivc h.-.-n planting trees, shrubs, and beautifying th,- trroun&lt; v w i FARM AND STOCK &gt;-n ur manure, and haul lurinu- th,- winter, all the manure we can ire.1 from » }, i,i..i, n ,* • '• UP II 18 ullltf 6XDCD8ive t u Us \Yh ;i Isi » fi'iit Ififl </seg>
            <seg id="p012">416 Kr land, but this year we were fortunate in having favorable ther. and received a good crop of corn. KThe hospital as it develops, needs a larger dairy herd, and will be necessary to replace the pasture sod with tame gram, this will meet the requirements. This institution is in need of land, that is. good land. At 160 wres, where corn can be raised. This institution has always been handicapped, by being built on a very poor pieee of land, called the sand hill. &gt;The stock has done well during the past year. We have at nt time three hundred hogs, and eighty-two cattle. We e told two carloads of bogs this year. The dairy herd has 1 improved by a thoroughbred Holstein bull, and before Ion-. will have a full Holstein herd. We have plenty of milk to the herd w nq&gt;ply us. and as the institution incr . . and therefore, milk will 1 plenty. We were unfortunate in our herd, to have a disea herd wi-re damaged. All i-tmeiit of agriculture for tub from this disease. t. but only a few of tin cattle were tested by the depa sis. and were found to be free fur the next biennium is oe ambler, one mangier, one ex LThe following appropriation irv. For laundry, one dry Ietor and one washer, approximate $2,700.00. Repairs and im - vemeats, consisting of laundry repairs, machinery, paints and i. Repairs and improvements general $7,000.00. Hydrotl itic apparatus $3,000.00, new subway to new building $1,000.00, fining walla $1,000.00, tire escapes and removing iron bars, and lacing them with wire screens $1,000.00; 160 acres of land ,.ii()(i.(K). home for nurses $15,000.00, new elevator in building 500.00, complete building $20,000.00, employes' w;l i.(io. maintenance $90,000.00, consisting of board, clothing, fuel, •turning patients, burial expenses, telephones, telegraphs. tjonery, , freight, chaplain, amusements, drugs, ,ks. instruments, horses, harnesses, and farm machinery, super - endent $5,000.00, first physician $3,000.00, second phyi 400.00, superintendent of nurses $1,800.00, clerk $1,800.00 and ward $2,400.00. This institution is so situated, that it adjoins a small t rav better wages to our help, than in any other insti </seg>
            <seg id="p013">ITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK 417 tution in the state. There are other reasons for this. Every man in the land feels and knows that the cost of living has incn in the last five yean, and more so. in the last two years. K thing that must he used, touched or consumed, has advai I \ slight degree, but advanced very much. This advanee been steady up today, and they have come to stay. This ; true, and it unquestionably is true, what we could have bought two years ago for *l"i(l will now cost *-_&gt;i&gt;o. It may be stated, if per capita must be increased in our state institutions. 9 prices are already high, why do we advocate in. way of increasing a number of attendants, and in. lswer is. that the very increase in commodi increased salaries and wages all along the Hm ts the physician more to maintain his family, educate. ide for it. All these attendants in effect hav • or connections dependant upon them, ami it port and provide for such dependants. The attend- nnot meet their ex] n small salaries ood help seek larger pay elsewhere, and thu inc. The better salaries , u r h expect. STATISTICAL REPORT OF MOVEMENTS OF POPULATION TX. Male Fein Patients remained, December 1. 1908, during biennium 154 128 Admitted during biennium 112 71 Total patients treated during biennium 266 Total patients paroled dun biennium -7 ~&gt;4 Died during biennium .:i» 14 Transferred during biennium l 5 Returned during biennium 22 Escaped during biennium Remaining during biennium Recovered during biennium e </seg>
            <seg id="p014">418 &gt; t 14 1 12 l 10 i • t 4 4 &gt; &gt; &gt; 1 ) : : Mai. Female T Improved during biennium No change during biennmm u; 32 Out on parole Not insane ■&gt; COUNTIES AND NUMBER OF PATIENTS ADMITTED ( ounty Holt Kiiox Stanton ( !edar Thurstoii Madison Coif ax I'latte Cherry Boyd Wayne Pierce Dixon Antelop Sioux Priming! Hurt Key a Pali Boone Washing Morrill Dakota Dougla Sheridan Duell Brown Rock Dawes Box BMtte Valley ! Thomas </seg>
            <seg id="p015">419 Malt' Female i i 1 i 21 'i 4 4 ! ■ » Epilepsy i Hnntington's Chorea Involutional Psychosis Involutional Melancholia Imbecile 1 13 4 Imbecile Moral •&gt; Manic Depreauvi •&gt; 1 Paranoia Senility Sant 11 1 Paralyti 1 1 ; Secondary Syphilis Hysteria Alcoholic Hallucinona Amentia Demeutia Precox Dementia Precox Katatonic Kmentia Preeox Hebephrenii mentia F*reeoz Paranoid Kxliauston Psychosis Polynouritic (Eomtkow Neurasthenia Psyi-liasthenia Paretic Cerebral Hemorrhage Tabes Dorsalii Infection PsychosM Organic I\v&lt; h&lt;»is </seg>
            <seg id="p016">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 420 BIRTHPLACE OF PATIENTS Male Female T'tl Male Female T'tl Iowa 11 10 21 Wales 3 New Hamp 1 1 2 Austria Hun. 2 2 4 Ohio 4 4 8 Germany England 11 9 20 Pennsylvania 4 4 n New York 448 Maim o 9 Bohemia 2 10 Kansas ■1 Denmark 1 1 Don't know •"&gt; 2 Illinois ."» 4 9 New Jersey. 112 Switzerland .... 1 1 1 Virginia 1 Scotland 1 1 Michigan Norway 112 Canada Sweden Q Minnesoti Missouri ti Rus Indiana 4 1 5 Philippine Ts Ireland Wisconsin 2 5 1 &gt; Georgia Kentucky Maryland Nebraska 20 16 36 OCCUPATION OF PATIENTS Male 1- M;iNi!ii Farmer Laborer (IT Watchman Clerk l'i 19 Carpenter Gardener Attorney 1 Saloonkeeper 1 1 Bookkeepei i Fireman 1 Tailor 1 Laiindryman. 1 Schoolteacher Harber 1 Uanehman 1 Contractor 1 Showman 1 1 1 1 (i ( House wif Engineer 1 iii Dnn't know 1 4 Waitres 1 Confectioner 1 arnlll </seg>
            <seg id="p017">HOSPITAL FOR II \ORFOLK 421 ALLEGED CAUSES OF INSANITY PATIENTS ADMITTED Male Pemah Total Not stated Grief M 4^ •) 4 Alcohol Family Senility 1 ■* •&gt; •&gt; turaatism o 10 &gt; i ( 'i»nsan&lt;ruinity 1 : 1 1 : Masturbation Predisposing Masturbation 4 Predisposing 1 1 Hard work ! Secondary syphilis 1 Sunstroke .&gt; Women 1 1 Brain lesion lira in lesion Typhoid ■&gt; o •&gt; Worry Worry 3 Bad literature 1 i Paralytic stroke 1 1 Congenital defect Disappointed love Tabes dorsalis ■i 1 1 1 1 •&gt; I Eiigion anism redity 9 1 1 4 ■i &lt; linement ■ 5 Painful menstruatioi Kt'tlex female organ Pin-rperal infection Tuberculosis n 1 • &gt; 1 1 1 1 Sexual excesse •&gt; Monopause 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">422 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT IN CONCLUSION Ring tin/ past two yean, I have put in many extra hours, lg the conditions of the Norfolk State Hospital, with of tlie officers and employes, who have been Loyal to to the state. tOur patients are clothed better than they have ever been. i-y receive mure entertainment than they have heretofore. ce a week we give a picture show, which they enjoy very much. The patients are better treated and receive more attention than heretofore. This is not all my work, but Your Excellency is also &lt;1 ing of credit, in giving me your kind assistance and support. in my good work in the hospital, and I cannot too earnestly express my appreciation of your kindness in this matter. I will turn over a saving of about $12,000 to the state, which will show that it is not always necessary to spend all the money that is appropriated. I heartily recommend to you that the merit system alone ed be considered in our state institutions, and the radical res have taught me that the patients are the ones that suffer, just like breaking up a family and getting acquainted with I also thank the Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings for their kind co-operation with me. for the good of the hospital, and I also thank the officers and employes for their kind assistance given me. during my term of office. Respectfully submitted. J)K. -I. P. "hi 1\ AL. Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p019">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. NORFOLK 423 rTRON'S REPORT FOR BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1910. Preserves, Jellies Pickles, Etc. ■Jn:{ pilous Apple 'M gallons Apples, era! 4nti gallons Beans, salted Beets, pickle 500 gallons 142 •rations ( Vim. swi lined 1 1 it i gallons lted ( urn. swt 21 gallons Corn, relish t lions Catsup, tomat Chili sauce ti gallons 1!,»") gallons Cherries, canned Cucumbers, pickled 12,^ gallons :ili gallons 2ni) gallons Cucumbers, salted Currants, canned gallons Currants, spiced Dill pickles • ! gallons KM) gallons 14 gallons Dutch pickle 8 gallons Fruit juii Grape marmalade 4!t gallons India relish Jelly, in Mang 8 gallons 1-il) gallons .Minct !'-, gallons ( Hived cherri 1!) gallons Onions, pickled Piccalilli lo:i gallons 14H gallons Hum preserv 1826 gallons Saucrkra :{ gallons 4H4 gallons Fomatoes. preserv 25 gallons Tomatoes, pit Watermelon preserves Klcs. buttei is. pickle* ."&gt;:&gt; gallons 2 gallons -&gt; gallons Cucumbers, ript r&gt; gallons 1788 id Str iwhrrrifs Tomatoes, ripe, cann ti:&gt;!) gallons 177 gallons l'2~&gt; gallons </seg>
            <seg id="p020">424 Articles Manufactured. Aprons, bleached muslin Aprons, unbleached muslin Aprons, kitchen ticking Aprons, kitchen gingham Aprons, oilcloth s 147 58 3 Bed pads s Bed pan covers Bibs, oilcloth Bandages s Burial robes Broom covers Camisoles I Camisoles strings Candy bags Chemise 8 Clothes bags 32 Curtains, swiss and scrim Drawers, men's canton flannel Drawers, ladies' canton flannel Dresses. r;ili.-. .-&gt;37 203 ■M 200 -er scarfs 69 Iron holders, dozen Mattress covers _ &lt; Muffs, canvas Napkins, made of table linen Napkins, hemmed 84 Napkins, sanitary Nightgowns 241 410 Night caps Pillow &lt; Quilts 9 4 Bestnint bands Sheets, unbleached Sheets, bleached _ Sheets, restraint 4.'. : Shoe bags Skirts 69 Strong suits </seg>
            <seg id="p021">425 Table cloths Ke covers made of old linen i'Is. bath 7^4 Towels, hand Eels, Turkish els. roller ... els. dish 4.". 529 2410 Trav cloth 112 B strainer form- 2n •24 (Tnderwaisti Wash cloths •&gt; 10 Window shades 13 Articles Manufactured for Patients From Private Material 14 A i irons, white Chemise 0 Drawers ■M 12 Bht gowns rtwaists Nijrhtgrowns 9 Shirtwaists 9 5 o Shirtwaist suii Shirtwaist suits Skirts Ties Ti,s Mending. 260 Aprons Apron Blankets Blanket Bed tieki B.-d ticks 1 162 &lt; 'amisoli- &lt; 'atnisol 82 20 Drawers ElWCT e 527 1 39 ( 'lotlies bags . (lotlies basrs Jackets 162 Muffs, canvas 18 Xijrht shirts ... oo Overall Pants 551 435 Pillow case '1 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">426 LAN!) COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Skirts Eimg suits III-- cloths ta S tappers, altered eta : Towels I iiiun suits Quita 2 &lt; "urtaius .) Vapkinx E spreads strainers 4 •&gt; Material Used in the Sewing Room. Bed ticking, yds {tons, pearl, jrross tons, bone, jrross tons, pants, yross tons. coat, irrnss co. vards &lt; anton flannel, yards -h toweling, yards Curtain, scrim and swiss Denim, blue, yards ss "77 zu Gingham, apron, yards 144 191 s 332 20 Kin. bleached, yards in. unbleached, yards |OitO net. yards 282 3135 &gt;4 Napkin, table, dozen i Bon haftintr. rolls v;is. yards Kham. blue and stripes, yards iiiii'ts. groaa Etiiitf cotton halls n. table, yards . yards </seg>
            <seg id="p023">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK 427 Needles, machine, dozen Oilcloth, table, yards Pillow tubing, yards I 'in Scissors Sheeting, bleached, yards Sheeting, unbleached, yard Tape, rolls Thread, cotton Turkish toweling, yards Window shade material, yards Toweling for dresser scarf, yard STEWARD S CASH REPORT FOR THE BIENNIUM Disbursements. 1908 I 51 47 Dec. 1 ('. &amp; X. \\\. freight, car brick 1 I'. P., switching charges .') IK) 5 (M&gt; II. L. McCormick, corn stalks J. R. Hayes, stamps 15 00 7 Western I'nion Telegraph Co.. messages 11 Millard Langfeld If. 1). Ty.. cultur. 17 I". P.. freight switching charges :{ Tti 2 00 .-&gt; IK) .It; :W i:&gt; (M) '.) :.:! 22 I). ('. Kegan. returned patient 30 V. P.. freight, car brick 2 :&gt;o 41 SO :i&lt;) American Express Co., exp :{ (I.") 15 (K) 3 35 .") Western I'nion Telegraph Co.. messages (i I. M. Maey, photographs ti A. L. Killian. radse (i Parker Urothers. beet seeds 3 36 •2ii 50 1 I).') 1 DO li &lt;;. II. Burton, repairing clock _NtMM|lt*&gt;. &gt;t ' \\ 111*;. |(*l|M*I S 17 C &amp; X. W.. car hriek 19 J. R. Ilayt's. stamps 22 C. &amp; N. W., freight l!l()!t. •Ian. 5 •). K. Hayes, postage stamps </seg>
            <seg id="p024">428 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT C. H. Frey, flowers is 6 6 G. M. Dudley, hack hir Hoffman &amp; Ville. dishes re. M H. E. Hardy, scale book 6 6 6 Norfolk Furniture Co., mds P. S. Sprecher, stationery E. H. Oury, express 4 75 6 s 10 L8 J. R. Hayes, postage stamps E. J. Rix, straw and milld F. &lt;). Boyd &amp; Co.. 45.90 alcohc H. M. Eaton, invoice hospital J. R. Hayes, postage stamps 15 00 20 11 25 28 ■&gt;r, 2:, 1 63 90 15 00 4 4 Western Union Telegraph Co., messages Union Pacific R. R., freight 1 02 6 7 26 I . ft X. W. R. R.. freight 11 5 ol 15 D. C. Regan, returned patient (Chas. Bache J. R. Hayes, postage stamps 23 4 95 26 J. W. White, 55 gallons C. oil American Express Co., express Union Pacific R. R. Co., freight E. H. Oury. stabling team 27 •27 25 27 4 Western union Telegraph Co., messages L. G. Brian, State Treasurer, deposit W. C. Babcock W 1,164 7.; it; 5 00 is J. R. Hayes, posta^ J. E. Rix, 1 straw stack 15 00 23 5 00 23 Agent C. &amp; N. W. R. R. Co., freight Wm. Wagoner, 6 loads of sand P. M. Barrett, 1 gal. whiskey 23 :J0 :*(&gt; C. Schmeiderberg, separator repairs Sugar City C. Mills, 200 lbs. flour L. G. Brian, State Treasurer, deposit Box rent and express to E. H. Oury C. &amp; N. W. R. R., freight 30 :n 1.039 32 Apr 3 2 4."&gt; 1 98 i 12 J. R. Hayes, stamps 15 00 17 Theo. Barnhardt, 105 bushels corn Standard Oil Co., oil 59 20 20 Standard Oil Co., oil 22 E. Rattler, 2 tons ha.v 24 C. E. Sallad 25 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">429 I C. &amp; X. W. R. U.. freieht J2 E. II. Oury, freiehi and pxpn ■) I. Gutzmer, returned patient M..i L. &lt;;. Brian. State Treasurer, ilepos May 3 J. R. Hayes, post 1.") (Ml 4 Robert Lamm, 9,025 ll». corn Western I'nion Telegraph Co.. m&lt; I'. Won J. -I. Clemments, rctun tin rintin 1~&gt; 00 17 J. R. Hayes, postage stamps 17 J. R. Hayes, postage stainr 20 P. A. Hardy, optical supplier 11 2:? &gt; F. A. Hardy, optical suppli 31 K. II. Oury, express charges + 4 78 3] L &lt;i. Brian, State Treasurer, deposit 1,145 29 L (I. Brian State Treasurer, d r&gt; 2!t June 4 I). ('. Regan, returned patient (John K&lt;&gt;pp 15 -I. R. Hayes, postage 1"' 00 1t&gt; ( '. S. Hays, repairing wateh - tM1 Iti John Knantz, rarriage anil team for I'&gt;. I'. L. ft B. -' ll(l 1fi Singer Sewing Machine &lt; irs 3 75 •&gt;-, lime- 4 D. ('. Reean. returned patient (John Kopj •I. R. Hayes, i 1.-&gt; of) 2 tMI i:» S. TI njr ,\ John Knantz, parriage ami team for I'.. I 2 nil &amp; I'. Sinirer Sewing Machim n; • iiairs i •&gt; 2ti J. P. Peeival, returned patient 26 J. P. Pecival. ret iti !&gt; 93 29 II. O. Drebert, freight &lt;&gt;n paini II. &lt;). Drohort. freight •&gt;') ii pan 29 Standard Oil Co., oil Standard &lt;Ml Co., oil 2fl 20 J. P. Peeival, returned patient •T. P. Pecival, return* 2!i I 1 iticnt 30 E. IT. Oury. expi E. IT. Oury. expre &lt; 30 Western f'nion Telegraph &lt;'&gt;.. m&lt; 2 14 Western 1'nioii Telet li ( !0 ipl III! July :{ William I. Kinan 2 7". fi L. (i. Brian. State Treasurer, deposil 51 90 posit 7 J. R. Hayes, postage 1&gt; i)t) J. R. Hayes, posta 14 Danxseb ft Land Optical Co. 1 : '&gt;T 14 Dauxsr-li &amp; Land Opti ( 14 Expense, returned patient (Schaffer 3 42 :) 42 14 if 1-") Freight on sewer pipe 14 30 I.') 20 Freight on carryall 27 56 Freiirht on earrvall 20 20 Transferring Mrs. MeNish 1 1° Xish 1 10 2d T 22 Returning Leonard Weber 4 0.") Returning Leonard AV 4 or, 24 Peiiefold and Co., supplies ■"&gt; 47 47 31 E. II. Onrv, express ehargea E. II. Oury. pxpn irir 1 10 n E. II. Oury. expr ■T. R. Haves, stami 21 )■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p026">430 LAND COMMISSIONER RKPORT Weekly Press, subscription Vcra Oarlock, patient advaneed J. H. Shimm. moving pietun E. H. Oury. exprea 11 6 mi 13 20 (HI 5 7(i Sept 6 Norfolk Furniture Co., drawer II. .1. Penefol Co., supplies i 4 (id •I. P. Pecival. drugs, etc. P. If. Barrett i i Bd. Bruggeman. 1 electric fan Lowe Brothers, seeds &lt; 1 K(l i F. ( '. Cantwell, stall rent for team •John Hopkins Press, journal rabseription (1. H. Stechert Co., book, medicine s 6 (Mi * . ) (Ml •") 2c 15 00 30 (Ml L. (i. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit Western Stoneware Co., jir rubbers Gerrao Manufacturing &lt;&lt;&gt;.. 2(i gal. Qern Kiesau Drug Co., books 21 21 20 (M» 23 23 Truax Greene Co., buckles 16 -() 23 Midland Paint and (ilass Co., glazing Norfolk Butter Co., butter 23 •y-A Asa K. Leonard, office supplies Bd Hammond, street plants A. ( '. Vranderbery. band concert _■&gt; ■21 2( 27 E. II. Oury. express and post office box rent Peoples Department Store, jars 7 02 i 11 •I. R. Hayes, postage 2: 25 Jacob Rohwer. •% bus. Spuds 26 L. (J. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit ('. W. Landers, freight on onions II. A. Drebert. freight on Pole catcher Freight on concrete machine 885 00 11 in 26 26 28 1 Brian, State Treasurer, deposil 17 K. H. Oury. cxprcv* •'51 Hoffman an&lt;l Vicllc. crockery, ei ■U K. II. (Miry, express 31 .1. I'. lV&lt;ival 19 7-2 2 47 £2 1 95 7 95 22 &lt;i&lt;t 11 (i. K. Stecheri Co., Imok. n 21 -I. H. Hayes, postage 21 .1. II. Sliiimii. picture show 21 L. (i. Brian. State Treasun J. K. Hayi's. postage ). V. l't'cival. hospital association tV&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p027">HOSPITAL FOR INSANK. NOKKOLk 431 2 .1. II. Shimni. :{ picture shows 6 T. ('. Cantwell. stall rent for team Sept. and Oct. 6 Western Inion Telegraph Co.. n 7 81 281 n» 11 I,. (J. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit 17 II. A. Drebert, freight on pallet of conerett machine 30 ('. W. Landers, freight on en 22 ('. P. link, returned patient 27 Weekly Tress for blanks n einrint 2!) Kxpress eharjrf 29 Freight on laundry machinery 1 Freight charees 1 M. II. Farley, dehorning 44 eattli 1 Russ &amp; Owen for drills 2 Corbin and Co.. master keys 2 Aleon and French. 1 entertainment 1.") Edwards and Bradfo rd Lumber Co.. sewer 2&lt;l K. H. Ikes for union 20 L. (i. Brian. State Treasurer. Deposit 1) .}. P. IVrival, returned Joseph Trimmer, patient lit J. H. Ilayi-s. postal Hi Freight ,:: E. II. Oury. express charges for November 7 J. II. Khimm. 2 ihowi -1 IMI 9 J. K. Hays, postage 1 :&gt; IMI 10 Freight on l&gt;rick. $75.89, &lt;&gt;n lumber -f 1 "&gt;--.-i&lt; • 2-i-i 1!» pipe 16 &lt;'. W. Lander*, freight on l-beanu for barn 20 J. K. Hayes, postage Btani] 21 II. A. Divert, freight 21 Henry Ferris, mm stack itrmw -" (MI 23 C W. Landers, balance freight &lt;&gt;n .nirin lllllll). 14 1S 2'A II. H. Drebert, freight &lt;&gt;n candy 44 cent* pip*. $3.63 31 J. P. l'f'ival. coat hann»'r&gt; 31 II. A. Drebert, 6 window n </seg>
            <seg id="p028">432 1910 .[an. 6 on E. II. Oury, e\| 1 I).-. T. ('. Cantwell, sliill rent, X i 14 John Friday, hardw 2 4.") 1 .-)() 1&gt; B. II. Walters, old carp 2o \V. A. Wagner, pasturing 14 head of cattle 42 00 42 (M) 15 (Ml Til 7(1 2o \V. A. Wagner, pasturing 14 •22 John R. Hayes, stamp- 15 &lt;&gt;o John R. Hayes, stamp 29 II. A. Drebert, freighi "ii generator. 70 7&lt;&gt; •_'!&gt; II. A. Drebert, fi •J'i Norfolk Weekly Press. 2,000 reqanition blanks 7 00 Norfolk Weekly Pn &gt; quisition •)i| blanks 7 (Ml 2!i L. &lt;■. Brian, State Treasurer, denosil 758 i- 29 L. &lt;i. Brian, 758 72 :!1 .1. I'. Pecival, returning -I. I.. Davis, patient ti !):{ ti !):{ :i1 .1. P. Pecival. reti , is. patient paid :;] K. II. Oiuy. express and freight paid 4 ; W 2 Western I'nion Telegraph Co., message*, Nov. Dec. and -Ian. 1"&gt; 64 4 lirht N(iv Western ["nion Telegraph ( 111 Dec. and Jan 15 (14 2 Geo. II. Burton, one clock 1 - )(l 1 50 2 I". .M. Barrett. 2 &lt;Mll&lt;&gt;ns brandy ; 3 00 ulv 2 (fas. A. McKiinm, veterinary servieet 4 "o •&gt; (fas. A. McKiinm, v 4 DO •&gt; 2 John Krnat/. livery, :i months, museiana 12 ."&gt;() John Ki-nat/. livery 12 50 u m isci.ins 2 (i. A. [former Co., 'Jo. gallons floor wax 10 00 2 G. A. Harmer Co., 'Jo. ealloi ir wax 2 Wesi Disenfecting Co., Cholo •"&gt; 7.") .) 1.1 2 Shindler and Kline. 1 gallons rye :'. &lt;&gt;(i ."&gt; I.. C Hepperly, 10 bushels carrots 7 ."))i 7 .)() 7 Hoffm m an. I Vielle, dishes 2n fin 2d tio 7 -I. P. Ilayis. postage 1"&gt; 00 15 (Ml 7 u &lt;i. Brian, State Treasurer, deposit 288 7ti li. (i. Brian, State Tr&lt; H It sit l!i ( '. W. Landers, freighi on cement sacks 1 4"&gt; 1 4.') 111 ( '. W. Laixlers. freighi on c 21 .1. R. Hayes, postage 1"&gt; 00 15 (in 2ti Freight on sewer pipe :{4 -il 54 31 28 lv II. Oury, express ch 8 29 s 2fl Ir. Stranskv, ."i tons hay 28 Mr. Stransky. :&gt; tons liay 2.") (Mi Mar. 4 &lt; '. \\ . Landers, freight on soap tanks :{ 30 Mar 4 ('. W. Landers, freight on ip tanl !t .1. 1". Peeival. I,'. I.', fare adv. for Van Horn 7 35 9 J. 1'. Peeival, \l. R. fare ad\ tOr Van Horn Id A. K. Leonard for drugs 12 '.)'&lt; Id A. K. Leonard for dru 12 !»."» 11 ( '. W. Landers, freight on cement sacks ( '. W. Landers, freight 11 15 -I. I'. Peeival. lor Miss Weston to Sioux City 4 57 in to Sioux City 4 r&gt;7 17 Loren !&gt;rn&lt;_:ji-enia!i. 1 lampshade (i.~&gt; • i 17 Haarman 1'ickle Co.. 1 barrel sauerkraut 1 sauerkraut needles ii Singer Sewing .Machine Co •&gt;■) </seg>
            <seg id="p029">u IT !..&lt;;. Doup, 1 bale of I 17 Beeler Bros., dry goods 18 S. F. Dimn to iraiisiim a ish for new store bldg. 1 8 S. V. Dimn to transom in -I. I\. Hayes, postage 15 imi ■_'■_' ('. N. \V. H. K. Co., freight on coffee urn 24 Nebraska Telephone Co.. 8 dry batteries '.! 00 25 -I. ]'. Pecival, patient of Omaha J 75 I. P. Pecival, patient 26 Agent ('. &amp; N. \V. U. H L'ti Agent ('. &amp; N. \V. R. R. Co.. freight on boiler Conn. 11 49 Conn •SI L. O. Brian, ? I reasurer., deposit 1 freight to Union Pacific 1 E. II. Oury, express charges '2 ■). R. Hayes, postage 15 txi 4 L U. Brian, state Treasurer, deposit 7&lt;&gt; 00 4 Pacific H\[ irges on picture mach. i 70 il L. (i. Brian, 8 deposit Apr. 1 freight to Union I* •&gt; ■). R. Hayes, posi Til nn ii rges on picture mach. 4 To 8 Freight and express Freight and ex 13 T. C. Cantwell, sta 13 T. C. Cantwell, stall rent for Jan., Feb., .Mar. -- Dickey Clay Manufacturing Co., dent, diai _ on brick 4 00 Dickey Cla 22 .1. R. Hayes, postage 15 00 -- -I. If. (laves, 23 Albert Jochens, l6\-&gt; bu. of potatoes fl 2"&gt; •&gt; All 2!) Freight on wire gates and ropi 2!) Freight on v 2!) Freight on hay carrier 2 1:&gt; 2!) Freight on hay cai :!(&gt; E. II. Oury. express chai ~ 50 E. II. Our Mms 1 E. J. Schoreg 2 E. J. Sehorefi ries 1 20 :! L. *i. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit 7"&gt; 60 L. &lt;i. Brian, St :{ Es. South. 5 His. block tin 2 25 m &gt; A Weekly Press. 1,000 blanks 7 no ■i Omaha Printing Co., office suppli 4 45 :{ Hoffman and Vielle, dishes and fixtures :{ Iloffinan and V 7 ielle \ 1 1 1 ri :} .Majestic Manufacturing Co.. stove repairs 4 Western Union Telegraph Co., Feb., Mar., and Mar., and 7 Herman Gerecke, r from Omaha, sliip - nient of hogs 4 nii I )i ii a h ;i . nIi ] m i !' J. If. Hayes, postage 1"&gt; ihi 21 Freight on pipe 1 58 I'i 27 ("has. P. Huls. returned patient Chas. P. Ilnls. returned ■ il -I. P. Peeival, railro.id fare advanced for John 31 J. I'. Peeival, railroid fai Hart (.n 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">434 1 B. II. Oury. express charges for May 5 99 :n Iv II. Oury. express eharges for May C. W. Landers, freight OB stationery Ad. in Daily News 1 ( '. \V. Landers, freight on stationery 2 00 .June 1 I A.I. in Daily News 75 9 10 (I Freight paid on motors 54 33 Freight paid on motors •John H. Hayes, postage 54 33 1 John H. Hayes, postage 15 0(1 11 15 00 14 4 Freight pai.l on window screens 28 84 Freight paid on window screens L (i. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit ('lias. I'. IIuls. returned patient (Sherman Freight on motor 28 84 14 4 L (i. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit 1,450 9:5 1,450 9H 17 7 ('lias. I'. IIuls. returned patient (Sherman) 9 14 9 14 25 !.") Freight on motor 10 93 10 93 27 !7 I). Lutz. 20 ll.s. oleo. 3 60 I). Llltz, 20 His. oleo. 3 60 2s 18 K. I). Hammond, rhubarb 5 00 1 Western Union Telegraph Co., messages, May 4 24 E. I). Hammond, rhubarb 5 00 Julv 1 Western Union Telegraph Co., messages, May Western Union Telegraph Co., messages. June Kxpress charges for Jane 4 24 4 Western Union Telegraph Co., messages. June 6 64 4 6 64 4 Kxpress charges for .June 2 49 2 4!t 5 K. II. Oury. express and postage. 6 2:} K. II. Oury. express and postage E. A. Hulloek. cutting pipe 6 2i{ • i »i E. A. Bullock, cutting pipe 1 85 1 85 s Herman Qereeke, trip to Omaha with hogs 4 09 4 09 !) Frank S. Beta Co.. for drugs 5 00 5 00 it; 6 .1. H. Hayes, postage 15 00 J. H. Hayes, postage 15 00 8 L (J. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit 28 25 L. (i. Brian, State Treasurer, deposit •I. I'. Pecival. return patient (Davis) 18 28 2f&gt; Ill !) .1. 1'. Pecival. return patient (Davis; 8 00 8 00 !!) Paul Luebke, groceries 1 20 Paul Luebke, groceries 1 20 29 :{ii ill !■]. II. Oury. express charges for .July (i 48 K. II. Oury. express ehargea for .July (i 4S SO W. Lise for chickens 2 10 W. Lise for chickens 2 10 10 Omaha Printing Co ... 1 84 Omaha Printing Co. _ 1 84 to J. I'. I'eeival trip to Lincoln and Humphrey 15 &lt;&gt;2 J. I'. PeeivaJ trip to Lincoln and Humphrey 15 (i2 :{() Aug. :{ Norfolk Weekly Press 7 50 •{ Herman Qereeke, K. K. fare and exp. to Humphrey 1 50 4 L (i. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit 1.426 10 13 •I. H. Hayes, postage I.i 0(1 13 I. P. Pecival trip to Lincoln, exp. 11 82 ]:: Herman Krtzner. cutting 30 acres oats 25 00 13 Freight on electrical goods 2 04 13 Freight on electrical goods . 6 'SI 15 .M. ( '. lla/.en. tickets for patients to chautauqua 16 74 15 P. M. Barrett, 2 gallons whiskey 8 00 17 Freight on paint from Omaha 95 18 Express charges on bull from Lincoln 6 19 1!! :S&lt;| :{&lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p031">435 l!l I. owe Brothers, garden seed l!l Western Stone Ware Co., jar rubbers Freight oil bed screens 24 •&gt;7 L. Watzel. cutting steam pi] Express charges for August _'l Sepi Western Union Telegraph Co.. messages for •&gt; 1 no August I,. C. Hepperly, !&gt; dozen peppers Freight on window shades i ■&gt;: Smith Premier Typewriter Co., supplies -I. K. Haves, postage stamps 4 4.", •). I', l'ecival. money adv. for maps. etc. Freight on engine repairs :» 4«' 2 05 15 17 ('has. P. llnls. exp.. patient Hayes Freight on sewer and gas pipe 3 67 27 oo •Jo Thompson Bros.. 30 bu. apples J. 1'. I'eeival for directory I., (i. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit Albert Marquart, threshing oats Freight on asbestos and sheet iron Hxpress charges for September •I. \i. Hayes, postage ,0 :,o 13 .",»; 28 29 29 :{() 15 oo :«&gt; Money advaned for H. K. fare for Hachett S. II. Leyhaman. tuning piano :&lt;0 Oct. .) Herman Qereeke, H. H. fare to .Madison E. S. South, plumbing goods 4 lo .&gt; 5 2.". (i C. A. McKiinm. veterinary services Vaughns seed store, bulbs t; 1 26 12 Western Union Telegraph Co., messages .1. H. Hayes, postage L. 0. Brian. State Treasurer, deposit 90 70 24 28 Freight paid on goods 2H 31 ■ s 1!i H. E. Theim, good* lit L. Buckendorf, flowen •) 4(i 1 Express charge* for August 1 ('. A. McKimra, veterinary service .&gt; .1. k. I laves, postage si amps 12 Kreighi on disinfectant and Paint 12 -I. I*. lVcival. money adv. for mar •&gt;•&gt; ■&gt;•) »i Vaughns seed store, bums (i World Publishing Co.. 1 ad (&gt; liort-n Bruggeman, 1 electric tap* :: Exprt'ss chargei for Oetober </seg>
            <seg id="p032">436 i Singer Sewing Maehine Co 2 27 o Freight on goods 2 Western Union Telei 4 I'. M. Barrett, o' ban 5 Chan. Kiec. 4 barreL :» R. E. Theira for olt 11 36 jiiiat'UMrin 5 40 15 1). E. Lutz for oleomargarin 4 00 15 Louden .Machinery Co., barn door latches. 22 Freight cm laundry baskets 2.") Freight on 2o grate bars 2ti .1. I*. Pecival, hospital record 28 Andrew Nord, 2'^ tuns of hay I'll L G. Brian, State Treasurer, deposil 2 lo 1 2.", Total paid out + 14.22., 2., FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF THE HOSPITAL FOR THE IN - SANE, NORFOLK, NEBRASKA. lor the Biennial Period Ending November 30th, 1910. 1909 Exp. Halaiu Officers' salaries &gt; Id. mi $ 13,243 81 $ 2.7.")ti 19 Employes' wag Maintenance General repairs Barn Heating, plumbing and completing Engine, boiler and cold 10,300 oo 5J&gt;37 62 4.7' in Freight on eyebesma for cellar rraph Co., message* ■Is 1 00 15 00 3 92 1 92 i"&gt; -I. K. Hayes, postage 19 Preighi on repairs 10,000 00 :{&lt;&gt;.&gt; 17 L'-J 9,182 78 80,000 00 57,834 65 22,1( 5,000 00 4.7H4 78 295 22 4,000 00 3,667 87 :«2 13 Furnishing new buildings :{.ii(K) (Mi 2."&gt; l."),000 (hi 11,590 24 :{.4' 1 &lt;:{.:{(M&gt; mi $129,912 4:{ * 4:i.:^7 57 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK 437 RECEIPTS AND DISBURSEMENTS FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 10, 1910. Steward's Cash Receipts. 1908 Dec. 1 Balance on hand I E. Netheway, 4!io ll.s. hides 2!) 40 B. Netheway, old iron 17 2u i) P. Haas, house rent 5 &lt;H&gt; 17 B. Netheway, old ii 6 90 17 E. Nethewiy, old ii 6 90 17 &lt;;. II. Grimes, house rent ."&gt; imi 17 &lt;;. II. Grimes, house rent ."&gt; oo 18 B. N'etheway. :!•")(» ll)s. hides 21 00 2:! EL Netheway, 154 ll&gt;s. hid.s !i 24 30 P. Haas. 21 loaves bread 1 IN) 1 A. F. Bauer, horse feed .") (HI 2 L. Wolff Manufacturing Co., over pay 147 12 I'. Haas. 21 loaves bread 1 oo 11109 Jan. 1 A. F. Bauer, horse feed "&gt; oo ■&gt; L. Wolff Manufacturing Co., over pay 147 12 4 P. E. Hilt green, hoard 20 imi 4 F. E. Hiltgreen, hoard 20 00 1.") &lt;i. II. (Jriines. house rent ."&gt; (Ml l."&gt; (;. II. Grimes, house rent ."&gt; (Mi 28 (I. \V. Staleop 22 50 28 Q. W. Stalcop 22 50 28 Wilson Byerly, :!!Mi ll.s. lard :!1 68 •&gt; Wilson lSyerly. 396 ll.s. lard HI 68 Feb. 1 W. &lt;;. Mertem. board 1,025 titi 1 W. &lt;;. Mertem. hoard 1.02: 1 K. Netheway, 4&lt;K&gt; Iba. hides 2ti 00 E. Netheway, 400 ll&gt;s. hides 2ti (Ki 1 A. F. Bauer, hone feed ."&gt; h 1 A. F. Bauer, horse feed ."&gt; OO 4 V. E. HoltgTeen, hoard 15 im&gt; 4 F. E. Hultgreen, hoard 15 (Mi 5 Andrew Nord, home rent ."&gt; imi Andrew Xord. house rent ."&gt; oo .) 2d Fair Store. 98 bushels spuds 44 ]n 20 Fair Store, its bushels spuds 44 ]n 22 E. Luikart. !&gt;7 50-60 bushels spuds 44 on 1 E. Netheway, :57() lbs. tallow. 12 95 Mar. 1 K. Netheway. :{70 lbs. tallow. 12 95 1 K. E. Thiein. 424 lbs. lard :!:{ 92 K. E. Thiein. 424 lbs. lard :!:{ 92 1 B. E. Thiein. :!!)() lbs. hides 2:5 4(&gt; 1 |{. E. Thiein. 390 ll.s. hidei 23 40 1 Leopold 1'lisek 10 &lt;M) 1 I pold Plisek 10 00 l:{ A. F. Bauer, horse feed 10 (Ml 13 A. F. Bauer, horse feed 10 00 l:{ Wilson Byerly. 41(1 lbs. lard 13 Wilson Byerly. 41o lbs. lard 15 Andrew Nord, house rent 5 tHi 15 Andrew Xord. house rent 5 imi 1.") (1. Qrimes, house rent •"• imi 1.") &lt;;. Grimes, house rent "&gt; (Hi 18 Salter Coal &amp; (Jrain Co.. 13,680 lbs. hogl B34 18 IS gaiter Coal &amp; Grain Co.. 13,680 lbs. hogs &gt;:!4 48 23 F. E. Hnltgrecn, board P. E. Hultgrecn, board 35 00 &gt;■ 2ti Standard Oil &lt; !o., 4 bbls. 26 E Netheway 2!is lbs hides 17 &gt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p034">438 2*1 K. Netheway, 4!t.") lbs. tallow 16 0!) Apr. 1 (i. Grimes, house rent f&gt; (Mi 15 Andrew .\&lt;&gt;nl. house rent 5 00 IT T. Tiirnbull. 14.") trees 14 50 22 Matt Sehaffer. 4*»1 lbs. lard 32 08 26 C Sallada. hoard and lodging 175 mi .May 1 Clarence Gerecke, :S1 ll&gt;s. lard 2 4S 1 E. Netheway, 431 lbs. hides 28 01 1 E. Netheway. 4&lt;»n II.s. tallow 13 00 ■i Salter Coal ft Grain Co.. 13,050 lbs ho^rs 86] 85 3 Salter Coal t Grain Co.. 13.050 lbs hogs 861 25 S Harrison Nursery ('o., 75 olive trees 2 85 Harrison Nursery Co.. 75 olive trees 2 25 » 24 T. Whiteford, board 4 30 24 T. Whiteford, board 4 30 24 Salter Coal &amp; Grain Co.. 8,60(1 lbs. kogi 2:14 00 7 A. F. Bauer, horse feed 13 00 24 Salter Coal &amp; Grain Co.. 3.60(1 lbs. hon 234 00 June 7 A. F. Bauer, horse feed 13 00 10 Frank Dowlinir. board and lodging 22 00 10 Frank Dowling, board and lodging 22 on 12 E. Xetheway. 60 His. hides :{ 90 12 E. Netheway, tin His. hides :{ !)n 22 II. Pribnow, :i hogs 10 00 II. Pribnow, :i hon In 00 22 Mada Tannahill, board :{ 00 22 .Mad. i Tannahill. lioanl :{ on July 111 Louis Hehrens. board 40 00 1!) Louis Hehreiis. board 40 00 2 II. Kaufman, 12 Imshels a|»ple&gt;&gt; t» 00 :{ Robert Klents. board 13 •")•'. kng. 2 II. Kaufman. 12 hushels applen t» on Robert Klents. Imard 13 55 •) ■i E Wilson Byerly, S bushels appli i 1 50 :{ Wilson Byerly, S Kushels apple* 1 50 II. Kaufman. 12 bushels applt^i li 00 4 II. Kaufman. 12 hushels appleo ti 00 Salter Coal &amp; Grain C-o., 5,010 lbs. hoga 350 7.". 14 Salter Coal i: Grain Co.. 1,633 lbs. ton lid 4&gt; 14 \V. P. Peterseii. :{ shoats 1 50 2:5 Dick Hill, hay ■i i.) 2:5 Dew Jones, board 41 41 88 H. C. Walter, old ragH 1 4."&gt; Dew .Jones, hoard and lodging ;{&lt;j tjo Sept. 1 Krnest Siefert. 1 bushel plums 1 .")ll 3 C F. Bilger, 2 bus. apples 1 i\o 4 Dew -limes, board and lodging :{4 (Mi ti .Mrs, -1. II. Allen. 15 gallon* eider 2 2.~&gt; K. .1. Kix. 1 bushel tomatoes 50 i .Mrs. Desmond. 1 bushel tomatoes i .Mrs. Desmond. 1 bushel tomatoes 80 II. Kaufman, tomatoes 111 4n - !) \V. G. Metern. use of team ti on 11 Dew Jones, board and lodging ».■ II U'.iif, ..I 11 lull. I t -t ■&gt;■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p035">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORKOI.h Met N D. lti I. T. Cook. 'A bushels tomati 18 Mrs. McClary, 4 baahek tomati 18 Dew Jones, board and lodging :n «m rinjj 22 A. F. Bauer, horse feed Q ni •&gt; in 2."&gt; A. II. Kaufman. 4 bushels tomato :. (Mi 2."i A. II. Kaufman, waterm !cili&gt; :i.-. 2« i Dew Jones, board and lodging 27 Mrs. Leonard, tomato ::&gt; 27 I). Hammond, 1hli bushels apples It: 1 , ltd 22! I 50 27 I). Hammond, 510 bushels apples 27 I). Hammond. S4l&gt; bushels apples 1 .1. V. Vaughn, board and lodirinir :, tin 2 Dew Jones, board and lodging !) Dew Jones, board and lodgin 39 In :.2 in 12 IN. I Dew Jones, electric light 14 J. V. Vaugh, board and lodging 1 2.-, l(i Dew Jones, board and lodging M M 41 40 2'A Dew Jones, board and lodging U 78 2.") P. I). Haas, house rent, milk and bread ill Dew Jones, board and lodging 37 55 J. II. Vanaukeii. special case Dew Jones, board and lodging 40 (HI :{2 40 12 Salter Coal and Grain Co.. 4.7."&gt;o lbs., hojr 13 Dew Jones, board .:.!•' .mi :{t; 4(1 13 Wilson Byerly. kith till 2(1 Dew Jones, board :n 10 S IMI :;n imi 4!) 7(1 1.1 LSI :{ti !) \V. ('. Merten, board from State B.. 1 1 Dew Jones, board lu 7:i 15 \V. A. Thomas. l(i."&gt; lbs. bides 18 Dew Jones, board 2f) Dew Jones, board i\ A. F. Bauer, hone f&lt; SI 1'. 1). Hats, house rent &gt;&gt;-| I ) |v Tf *1L» ■ 1 00 44 4d 27 Dew Jones, board 29 1'. 1). Haas, hmisf rent 29 1'. 1). Haas, milk 1 \V. .1. Gow, board Edom. ■4 Dew Jones, board 2() .1. 1'. PecivaL </seg>
            <seg id="p036">440 31 W. J. 0&lt;&gt;\v. board 1910 19M •Ian. 1 Dew Jones, hoard 8 Dew Jones, board 1-") John Shields. 1 range 15 Dew Jones, board 1"&gt; Dew Jones. 30,775 lbs. eoal 25 P. I). Haas, milk 1 Dew Jones, board Dew .Tones, board John Shields. 1 range Dew -Jones, board 8 15 15 15 Dew Jones, 30,775 lbs. eoal P. D. Haas, milk ■ir, Fell. 7 Supt. to steward 7 Supt. to Steward W. Bard, deceased W. A. Thomas, hides 26 .Mrs. J. K. Wilson, time lost 2(i llermrtii Gereeke, hauling frenerator Supt. to steward &lt; Supt. to Steward W. Hard, deceased W. A. Thomas, hides i Til 26 ID 26 .Mrs. J. K. Wilson, time lost 1 61 26 Herman Gereeke, hauling generator \V. J. (iow. board ( Esmond I 20 00 Mar. 3 \V. J. (iow. board (Esmond !» J. C Vanaaken, board Mrs. Vanaaken HI Dallard, deceased. 1 pair |&gt;ants 30 J. Robinson, junk Mar :: 9 25 00 •I. C Vanauken, board Mrs. Vanauken Dallard, deceased. 1 pair panto 15 00 1(1 2 25 :«i •J. Robinson, junk John Robinson, raga A. P. Bauer 27 75 Apr. 1 John Robinson, rags Apr. 1 ! ;j lo rl A. P. Bauer 1 W. J. Gow. board (Edmond ■i(t W. J. (low. board | Kdniond 30 Simon, sale of lime 15 (Mi W. J. (iow. board (Edmond W. J. Qow, board i Bdmond Simon, sale of lime 25 (Ml 25 00 7 50 May .") W. F. Denny Co.. 15,000 lbs. hogs ■") Sunderland Bros. Co.. :{!»2 empty bags K' A. F. Bauer, horse feed l-'5 J. Robinson, 17."&gt; lbs. hides 13 J. Robinson, :{.{7 lbs. bides 13 J. Robinson, 22:&gt; lbs. tallow 13 A. Robinson, 413 lbs. tallow May 1 ,:{(i:{ 5»; .5!) 2o 9 oo 13 •J. Robinson, 175 lbs. hides 11 97 13 J. Robinson, :{:*7 lbs. hides •J. Robinson, 225 lbs. tallow •F. Robinson, 413 lbs. tallow lti 85 la 9 12 1 2:5 te ■{ W. A. (iow. board (Edmond :}&lt;i Thennometen :{.") oo 3 25 luly 2 W. J. Gow, board (Edmund 7 \V. F. Denny Co.. 14,830 lbs. ln.^ 11 J. Bambbeny, patient board 1-i Kster Ruhlow, dress 13 J. A. Wiles, board 13 Patient board ltJ Otto Zelow. bull 18 Otto ZeloW, calves 25 0&lt;i 1.215 97 25 00 3 oo ].-{ •(. A. Wiles, board 33 (Mi 13 Patient board 21 63 16 Otto Zelow, bull ti2 .""&gt;&lt;) 4(1 OH A 1 1 if W i * t \\~ 1 i I U* 1 ] </seg>
            <seg id="p037">441 II. Oerecke, hoard •I. A. Wiles. 2 piga mm Sales of hides to Johnson 11 • I. R. Baniherry. hoard 2.~&gt; no 12 &lt; ' irl Garnette, patient 12 Kujrdale. patieni 97 Hauling marble 4 ihi dla Gleason, board 4 no •"&gt; Vowtka Foeliteh ;m&lt;l Sidlo i.ii (&gt;;&gt; 1 Miss Jones, dress gooda 1 fi.~&gt; Miss Jones, dress roods 1 6"» :i«! W. J. &lt;Jow. hoard (Edmond) s W. -I. Gow, hoard ( Kdmond 11 Joseph Pappmek. Joseph Pappusek 1"&gt; Mary Clause, dreaa gooda Mary Clause, dress &lt;roods in Frank II. Wheeler, board 27 75 Frank II. Wheeler, hoard 27 ~~&lt; -1 J. R. Bamberry, board •27&gt; Albert F. Bauer, hone feed (J. A. s. O. \. D 24 00 2s Rlnora Petemon, drem gooda 1 70 Hlnora Peterson, dress goodfi 1 70 2H Cora Jones, drem jroods 1 00 &gt;s Cora Jones, dress vooiIn 1 00 :il W. .1. (l..w. board (Edmood ■_&gt;:» 00 7 R. I,. fN.Ik ('.... in in) 11 W. .1. (low. hoard ( Kdmond 2.~&gt; imi \o\ K. L. Polk Co., in ini 1") &lt;i. &lt; &gt;. ftfengahall, l)oard patieni 40 00 17 John Robinson, iron. etc. 24 In l."&gt; Mrs. Georgia Warn, dreasea :i 25 21 .John I). Hasck. 2 calves 20 &lt;&gt;&lt;&gt; •&gt;s </seg>
        
            <seg id="p038">( Apportionments to School Districts 14 N Apportionments and Bxj&gt;enditures Board of Educational Lands and Funds TJ Educational l^and* a ti&lt; I funds l:» Permanent School Kiind l-'i Temporary School Kund 13 Apportionments and Kxpenditur I' Educational Land mil Knmls 5 Educational Lands and Kim Appropriations, Estimated, for 1911-1912 H s Boards and Dates of Meeting* Commissioners of I'ublie Lands and Buildings Department of Surveying Depart inent of Surveying Dates of MeetingH of Boards 3 Dates of Meetings of Boards 3 Estimate of Expenses, Bicnnium April 1, Hill. March 31, 1913 Estimate of Expense*, Biennium April 1. 1911, March il. 1i)l s Expenses of Maintenance, and Salaries State Institution^ Expenses of Maintenance, ami Salaries State Institution* Livestock. Value of in all Institutions •'{•"» Value of in all Institutions •'{•"» Xanies and Location of State Institutions Names and Location of State Institutions Names of Superintendents of Institutions Names of Superintendent*) of Institutions Official Roster. Commissioner's Office 7 Official Roster. Commissioner's Otii i Roster St ite Officer*, 1909-191U 4 Roster St ite Officers, 1909-1910 4 Hoster State Officers, 1911-1912 Hoster State Officer* 1!I1M!»12 Work of the liicnnium. Tables IT Work of the Biennium, Tallies 17 Reports from State Institutions: Penitentiary. Lincoln 4'.t Soldiers and Sailors' Home. Grand Island Soldiers and Sailors' Home. Milford 131-140 Industrial School for Girls, Geneva 141-150 Industrial School for Boy*, Kearney 151-180 Institute for Feeble .Minded Youth. Beatrice 181-200 Institute for the Blind. Nebraska City 201-234 Nebraska Industrial Home. .Milford L':{.-&gt;-24* Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 249-28« School for the Deaf. Omaha 2*!I-:{OS Hospital for Insane. Hastings 309-376 Hospital for Insane. Lincoln 377-404 Reports from State Institution Penitentiary, Lincoln 4'« Sailors' Home. Grand Island ira' Home. .Milford ]:&lt;l-14(i Industrial School for Girls. Geneva 141-150 Industrial School for Boys, Kearney 1"&gt;1 tute for Ke.l.le .Miiid.-d Youth. Beatrice 181-200 te for the Blind. Nebraska City 201-234 ndustrial Home. .Milfonl l':{.")-24^ Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 249-28S Deaf. Omaha 2HU-WH </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>