<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Seventh Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the Orthopedic Hospital</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Seventh Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Orthopedic Hospital LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">410 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL LINCOLN. NEBRASKA OFFIC ERS Superintendent .Chief Surgeon Bbvebty A. Finkle, M. D A. I. MrKlNNOX, M. D... . Cahii M. Benbkook .... Syiaia E. Miller, R. N.. Mayme Stkate, R. N May mk Duwnky Anna Wilson Ci.ar* NURSES' TRAINING SCHOOL Subjects and Instructors Junior Year Anatomy and physiology Dr. B. A. Finkle Practical nursing Sylvia E. Miller, R. N. Dr. R. B. Adams Materiu medica Bacteriology Dr. E. G. Zimmerer Ethics of nursing Sylvia E. Miller, R. N. History of nursing and obstetrics Mayme L. Strate. R. N. Intermediate Anatomy and physiology Dr. B. A. Finkle Dietetics Dept. of Domestic Science, Uni. of Neb. Surgical nursing Mayme L. Strate, R. N. Materia medica Dr. R. B. Adams Bacteriology and pathology Dr. E. G. Zimmerer Massage and hydrotherapy Helena Warner Ethics of nursing Sylvia E. Miller, R. N. Surgical methods Dr. A. I. McKinnon History of nursing and obstetrics Mayme L. Strate, R. N. Pediatrics Dr. W. O. Colburn Nervous and mental diseases Dr. J. D. Case Senior Year The training of the senior year is taken at the University Hospital in Omaha. The affiliation is mentioned elsewhere in this report. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 411 ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To his Excellency, Honorable Keith Neville, Governor, and to the Honorable Members of the Board of Cotn- misgionera of State Institutions, Henry Oerdes, Silas A. Holcomb. ami Eugene 0. Mayfield. (1&lt; ntlciiien : The seventh biennial report of the operation of the Orthopedic Hospital, for the period ending November 30, 1918, is herewith submitted. My appointment as superintendent dates from Sep - tember 18, 1918, consequently this report deals largely with the administration of my predecessor, Dr. W. Hall Crutcher. The Orthopedic Hospital was created by an enactment of the legislature of 1905 and on October 1st of the same year was opened for the reception of patients. The pur - pose of the hospital is the prevention and treatment of deformities arising in children who are financially unable to procure proper medical or surgical care. Tables em - bodied in this report will readily illustrate the scope of the work and the nature of the cases which are treated. Appli - cation for admission is made directly to the superintendent and consists of two blank forms which are supplied by the institution: One of these forms, which is to be filled in by the parent, consists of statistics relative to the applicant and an affidavit as to the financial status of the applicant and his parents. The other form to be made out by a physician, covers statements regarding mental and physical condition. No charge is imposed for hospital service nor for medical or surgical treatment but parents are required to furnish such clothing as is needed and in case mechanical appliances are found necessary it is the duty of the parent to reimburse the hospital for such expenditure. The children of this institution are given the benefit of continuing their school work and classes are conducted for all grades of the common school. The work followed </seg>
            <seg id="p004">412 THIRI) BIENNIAL REPORT OF is outlined by the county superintendent of public instruc - tion and, upon completion of the eighth grade, pupils are permitted to take the examination for high school entrance. This school work is supplemented by an excellent library which is maintained by the State Library Commission and is the source of much pleasure to the employees as well as the patients. The hospital maintains a training school for nurses which is under the supervision of the superintendent and the nurses In charge, who, together with physicians from the city and instructors from the university, form the teaching staff. It is fully recognized by the State Board of Exam - iners for Nurses and is affiliated with the University of Nebraska Hospital where our pupils take their last year of training. The entrance requirements are the same as those of any recognized hospital and the course given offers an excellent opportunity for those wishing to acquire an educa - tion enabling them to follow this profession. Dr. H. Winnett Orr, superintendent at the beginning of the biennium, resigned May 1, 1917, and a few months later entered the army. Dr. W. H. Crutcher, first assistant at the Ingleside Hospital for the Insane, was appointed to fill the vacancy and remained until September 18, 1918, when he too joined the colors. At that time the present incumbent, who was first assistant at the Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk, was appointed to the superin - tendency of this hospital. Dr. J. P. Lord, for many years chief surgeon, began his services for the Government Oc - tober 1, 1917, and Dr. E. C. Henry filled this position for a few months. In May. 191 S, when Dr. Henry answered the call of his country, Dr. A. I. McKinnon was offered the position and has since been doing valuable work for the inmates of the institution. For a short time Dr. E. H. Flansburg acted as consulting surgeon but this position was later abolished. Due to the shortage of labor, we have had numerous changes among our nurses, office force and employees as a whole, but we have been exceptionally fortunate in secur - ing very competent people for the more important positions. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 413 I feel constrained to mention that our matron, Carrie M. Benbrook, is the only officer regaining who was here at the beginning of the period and that her knowledge of the institution and her kindly assistance have been of inestim - able value to the many newcomers. In the future we shall endeavor not only to keep the Orthopedic Hospital up to its present, standard but to in - crease its usefulness and, if possible, impress upon the people and especially the physicians of Nebraska the benefits which can be derived from early treatment in certain cases. I would urge that every effort be put forth seeking to have the law changed so that all worthy orthopedic cases might be admitted to this hospital. At the present time only in certain instances and then by special permission can adult cases be admitted. Does it not seem plausible that these persons should enter the hospital on the same basis as the other cases or that the county of residence be permitted to enter the individual and pay a maintenance fee such as is charged by state institutions which care for the insane? There are any number of counties within the state which do not have and cannot well afford to maintain county hospitals and I feel confident that such legislation would be gratefully received by these people. There are also individuals through - out ¥he state who are in moderate circumstances yet cannot meet the expenses of prolonged hospital treatment and if these people could enter the hospital and themselves pay a nominal maintenance fee it would undoubtedly be a relief to many sufferers. RECOMMENDATIONS In formulating the following recommendations I have ever kept in mind the strenuous times and the call of the Government for financial aid, both of which make it im - perative that state institutions be as economical as possible and that in asking the people of Nebraska for appropria - tions we must be conservative; but also I see in the future, numbers of our soldier boys returning to this state in a crippled condition, seeking relief from certain deformities, and without question the most we can do for these men </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 414 will be small compared with what they have done for us. These cases, together with the increasing number of appli - cants from over the state, will find our present buildings inadequate and as there is no other hospital in the state devoting its entire time and energy to the prevention and correction of deformities, either congenital or acquired, I feel that these recommendations will receive just consider - ation. NEW BUILDINGS 1. Hospital Building There is much need for a new hospital building, the site to be. directly west of the Administration Building. This should be constructed so as to accommodate most of the patients who are now in what is known as the "Old Hospital", as this building is not fire-proof, is unsanitary and is in no way in keeping with the present clay needs of an Orthopedic Hospital. It should also include the kitchen as the present kitchen is located in the basement where light and ventilation are extremely poor and the ceiling is traversed by many pipes which convey steam and water to the building. These pipes, together with the lack of sunlight and fresh air, give rise to an atmosphere which is indeed unsanitary as well as making it unpleasant for those employed therein. A new building, such as would meet our requirements in this line, could be put up at a cost of $100,000. Vegetable Cellar. Cold Storage and Refrigerating Plant We find ourselves greatly handicapped by having no place suitable in which to store vegetables, keep meats, canned fruits, milk, etc. Under the present conditions we are compelled to purchase potatoes, carrots and other vegetables a few bushels at a time and with no choice of market price; but with the vegetable cellar we could pur - chase greater quantities and at a time when prices are at a minimum. The cold storage would answer practically the samp purpose as far as meats are concerned and would </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 415 be of great value to us in caring for milk, which should be kept in the most possible sanitary way, as it composes the greater part of the diet for our babies as well as for a number of our bed patients. The refrigerating plant would be a great saving relative to the consumption of ice and without a doubt is the most economical way of running a cold storage. This building, which would be neither elabo - rate nor large, could be constructed at a cost of $5,200.00 and I feel confident that from the view point of either the financier or the health officer, it would be money well spent. IMPROVEMENTS TO BUILDINGS The "Old Hospital," which was mentioned in a pre - ceding paragraph, should be remodeled and the building put in such shape that a portion of it could still be used as a hospital tor ambulatory cases and the remainder used for quarters for nurses and others employed at the institution. The living quarters now occupied by some of our people are quite undesirable and not of sufficient magnitude and in one instance we had five nurses sleeping in one room which should accommodate at most but two or three persons. The fitting up of this building for quarters for employees will also permit us to use the present power plant building, with slight remodeling, exclusively for shops to be used by car - penter, painter, plumber, electrician, etc. The changes needed in the power plant building can be done by our own force of workers and will call for no extra expenditure of money but the remodeling of the "Old Hospital" building to suit our needs will require an appropriation of $1,500.00. There should be some provision made for exit from the basement of the Administration Building. In the base - ment of this building are located the class rooms for both patients and nurses, the cafeteria or dining room and the bacteriology laboratory. In case of fire there is absolutely no means of escape e: cept to ascend the inclines to the building proper or to go through the tunnel which leads to the old building which is not fireproof. Therefore I would suggest that cement steps leading to the outside be placed at either end of the basement. An expenditure of $175.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 416 will complete this work which might be the means of saving manv lives. EQUIPMENT I wish to urge strongly the installation of machinery and equipment whereby braces and orthopedic appliances may be made at our own institution. During the past year much difficulty has been encountered in procuring these ap - pliances and prices charged for them seem, in some cases, to be entirely out of reason. I feel confident that with the proper equipment a great financial saving could be made, in addition to the fact that appliances made where they can actually be fitted and adjusted to the individual whom they are to serve, are infinitely more satisfactory. It is not un - likely that a number of our older patients could be trained in this line of work thereby giving them mental and physi - cal activity in conjunction with the fact that this vocation might be followed upon their discharge from the hospital making them self-supporting citizens rather than a burden upon the state. The equipment needed for this enterprise can be installed for $5,000.00. SUMMARY New Buildings Hospital building, including general lichen $100,000 Vegetable cellar, cold storage and refrig- rating plant .200 $105,20' Permanent Improvements to Buildings Remodeling of the old Hospital Building..! 1,500 Kxits from basement of Administration lluilding 175 1,67 Equipment .Machinery for the manufacturing of or thopedic appliances $ 5,000.00 5,000.011 Total 1111,875.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 417 ESTIMATE FOR ORDINARY EXPENDITURES Salary and Wages During the biennium it has been extremely difficult to employ such help as is needed. Several changes have al - ready been made in our salary schedule and should the pres - ent condition continue other and more extensive changes will be necessary. Should affairs become more normal and our new building be erected extra help will, of necessity, be put on at that time. General Repairs Our older buildings will need much in the way of re - pairs such as plastering, re-wiring, partial removal of plumb - ing, etc. This re-wiring will be necessary because many of the wires are exposed, making the danger from fire much greater. The plumbing, especially the lead connections, is beyond repair and the leakage causes destruction of walls, plastering, etc. These parts should be replaced with better materials. Other Maintenance The increase in price of foods and all other articles un - der this heading will call for a raising of this estimate over the one for the previous biennium. SUMMARY Salaries and wages General repairs . . . $ 45.6OO.UU ,500.00 Other maintenance 94,500.00 1147,600.00 At the beginning of the biennium the Orthopedic Hos - pital and the Nebraska Home for Dependent Children were under the same management but in the spring of 1918 this close relationship was severed and Miss Amy V. Stephens was appointed superintendent of the last named institution. The hospital now supplies heat, laundry and food for the Nebraska Home for Dependent Children for which we re- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OK 418 ceive remuneration based upon the cost per capita. In most ways this is proving very satisfactory and the co - operation between the two institutions is, indeed, pleasant. Considering the close proximity of the two institutions it is quite reasonable and just that one power plant and one laundry serve for both but I fully believe that it would be more economical as well as more satisfactory to all con - cerned if separate kitchens were maintained. More eco - nomical in that after cooked food has been transported over ground it is not so palatable and more or less of it is re - jected. In separate kitchens much of this could be utilized in preparing other dishes. More satisfactory to the Ne - braska Home for Dependent Children because they could choose their own rations and prepare the same to suit them - selves. More satisfactory to the Orthopedic hospital in that a certain overhead expense is incurred for which we cannot be recompensed. Also in the fact that in buying the extra food, employing the help, etc., that our statement of expendi - tures does not and cannot take this into consideration and for this reason appears quite out of proportion to our actual population. During; the two-year period no new buildings have been constructed nor have any radical changes been made In the buildings now occupied. The old hospital building has been painted both exterior and interior and presents a much different appearance than at the beginning of the period. The elevator has been remodeled and repairs made which make it a safe means for transporting patients from one floor to another. The drug room and store room, which are located in the basement of this building, have under - gone changes which make them more sanitary as well as more convenient. Awnings and window shades have been placed on the sun porches and fire escapes are now under construction which make freer exits, not only from the sun porches, but from the buildings in general. A large cement court has been constructed between the several buildings, thereby doing away with a source of annoyance to the housekeepers as well as making safer the travel from one </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 419 building to another of those patients who mobilize by the aid of crutches and wheelchairs. The superintendent's cottage has been repaired and re - decorated. New furniture has been supplied, most of which was manufactured at the State Penitentiary and is very at - tractive in design. The old pavilion, which stood near the hospital building, has been moved to a more suitable loca - tion, undergone certain changes and is now used as a garage. On account of the increased amount of laundry work it has become necessary to install certain new ma - chinery which greatly facilitates the work of this department, and large ventilating fans have been placed in the build - ing, making it more comfortable during working hours, which is conducive to better service. An exhaust fan and steam cookers have been added to the kitchen equipment and a new gas range has taken the place of an old one which was beyond repair. The operating room has been supplied with a few new instruments and a Halley table makes our plaster room equipment more complete. We are indeed grateful to the many theatres, moving picture shows, florists and automobile owners who have so kindly and generously remembered our children. The Vic - trola which was presented to the hospital by Miss Billie Burke, and for which she has made an allowance for the purchase of records, seems almost indispensable, for music is the one amusement of which bed-ridden patients do not tire. To the many persons who contribute in any manner to the pleasure and happiness of our population we wish to express our sincere thanks. It is often true, and especially so with our class of patients, that a word of friendship or an act of kindness is the source of many pleasant memories. Our Christmas times are full of happiness and the real Christmas spirit prevails. This is largely due to the efforts of the Woman's Club, the several Sunday school classes and other organiza - tions and individuals who, if they could see the fruits of their labors, would read in the expression of each face the words of the Christmas Carol, "and so, as tiny Tim ob - served. 'God bless us everyone'." </seg>
            <seg id="p012">420 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF We have lately made arrangements with Dean Davis of the dental department of The University of Nebraska whereby our dental work is done and in partial reciprocity for this we are conducting a two-hour surgical clinic weekly at which the students receive valuable instructions but we feel that our acknowledgments would not be complete with - out thanks from everyone of us, not only for dental work done, but for the real interest shown by every instructor and student and for the gentlemanly way in which the boys conduct themselves at the surgical clinic. Such success as has been attained is largely due to the staunch support of the official staff. It is indeed a pleasure to state that since the writer's connection with this hospital there has been unity of action between the heads of depart - ments and the employees in general, making for efficiency and loyalty to the interests of the patients, the institutions, and the State of Nebraska. I wish to thank you, gentlemen of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, for your hearty co-opera - tion, wise counsel and courteous treatment and assure you that the keen and thoughtful interest you have shown in the general direction of this hospital has been greatly ap - preciated and has instilled into each of us an inspiration to serve more faithfully. Respectfully submitted, Beverly A. Fixkle. Superintendent. Lincoln. Nebraska, November 30, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 421 STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS AND CREDITS AND BALANCE OF THE PATIENTS' FUND December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918 Notb — These are the personal funds of the patients held in trust by the Institution for these patients and received and expended for their individual benefit. Approximate average number of accounts December 1. 1916 to December 1, 1918, was 10. PERIOD Debits ' Credits Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1916, $256.39. December, 1916 January, 1917 . February, 1917 March. 1917. . ( 24.85 : S 27.15 104.66 44.50 27.87 22.46 22.13 13.50 April. 1917. May. 1917 June, 1917. July. 1917.. August, 1917 ttJt 16.00 107.92 9.20 13.87 U.95 27.73 64.09 19.91 32 .30 16.75 September, 1917 October, 1917 November, 1917 28.11 1655 36.00 47.00 49.48 Total for year t 476.87 1 $ 339.71 Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 191 , $118.23 Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1917, 1118.23. December, 1917 % 75.64 | 59.42 January, 1918 25.69 43.72 22.71 12.00 February, 1918 March. 1918 47.85 29.50 April, 1918 50.75 26.(10 10.00 May, 1918 11.50 June, 1918 16.95 10.00 12.45 15.50 July, 1918 August. 1918 33.40 23 .SO September, 1918 6.25 19.40 .25 October, 1918 7.70 November, 1918 Total for year 13.05 106.45 355.54 * 32S.94 I t Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1918, Grand total for two yean 1149.83 $ 800.81 : t 69525 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF RECEIPTS CREDITED TO INSTITUTION CASH FUND December 1, 1816, to December 1, 1918 AMWIW13 lULblVLU GENERAL SOURCES Total Dee. 1. 1916 Dec. 1. 1917 Dec. 1. 1D16 to to to Dec. I, 1917 Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1. 1918 Food, laundry, supplied and labor furnished Nebraska Home for Dependent Children Maintenance of patients , . . . Radiation Material for employees' uniforms. Safe and drayag? to depot Thermometers | Garbage t Meals ; Patients' fund transferred i Rags Engineer supplies Cinders Radiators Hospital supplies Bath tub Junk Articles made in school ... Braces Yarn Wages carpenter work at another institution) Paper Vouchers Gunny sacks Medicine Crutches Train fare, patient, refund " Train fare, employee, refund Stamps j Lodging j $ 1589.72 $ 14646.78 If 162.16.50 ; 451.61 451.61 127.50 127.50 51.68 40.67 92.35 60.00 S0.00 31. 90 10.2C 42.16 28.92 14.40 41.32 88.45 7.75 :I6.2O 33.00 33.00 10.00 7.58 17.5X S2.04 .12.04 30.00 .25 30.25 29.IMI 29.00 15.18 15.18 15.00 15.00 1.15 ltS7 14.12 Ml 4.25 13.05 10.00 10.00 9.49 9.49 9.00 9.00 5J0 5.30 .38 4.88 5.26 Ml Ml 4.88 1.50 1.50 1.00 1.00 M .80 .»0 JO M .02 1.75 j 1.75 Tot»i« : . . . . S 1909.65 $ 15427.01 t 17336.66 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 423 INVENTORY OF LANDS, BUILDINGS. FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT AND IMPROVE - MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE for observation, renewal of ca?ts, or such other treatment as may be necessary November 30, 191S Ill, 91« ) i i Acre* Acres Cultivated Inrultivated Total E«ti- ' Acre- mated Garden Farm Orchard Campux Waste ; age Value Land owned hy institution , 2.3 .6 2.9 t 1:1435.00 Land rented by institution &lt;eash i Land rented hy institution i shares' Total 2.:i .,; 2.9 \ $13436.00 ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF BUILDING . . AND IMPROVEMENT Building Furniture Equipment Improvement Total Administration * 60000.00 » 1520.00 $ 5454.00 $ 69974.00 Old hospital 30000.00 1:100.00 :iu;5.ciii $ 34765.00 Laundry 3000.00 67.00 1200.00 7267.00 Power plant 1500.00 130.00 2:110.00 3940.00 Superintendent's cottage S00.00 650.00 156.00 1606.00 Garage 150.00 2.00 152.00 ('■round improvements 20.1(0 280.00 1500.00 1800.00 Total $ 95450.00 $ 6687.00 $ 15867.00 1500.00 * 119504.00 TABLE 1 MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Year For Year ' endinf ending Total MOVEMENT Nov. 30. Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 ; Hienmum I M. F. T. M. F. T. ! M. F. T. Present at beginning of period 70 54 124J 40 38 78 70 54 124 Admitted: For first time 90 75 1S5! 37 59 96 127 134 261 Readmitted 71 77 148 59 63 122| 130 140 270 Transferred from other institution* 41 27 68 35 37 72 76 64 140 Total under treatment 272 233 505 j 171 197 368 403 392 795 Discharged: Cured 97 94 191 91 100 1911 188 194 382 Impro%ed 116 90 206 35 40 75 151130 281 Unimproved 9 4 13 5 6 11 14 10 24 Died 10 7 17 7 3 10 17 10 27 Total discharged . 232 195 427 138 149 287 370 S44 714 Remaining at end of period Ill :I8 781 33 48 81 33 48 81 Average under treatment 60 42 102 34 34 69 47 38 85 ltemaining at end of period: Patients in the hospital 40 38 78: 22 32 54 22 32 54 'Patients on parole 11 16 27 11 16 27 Total 40 38 78 S3 48 81 33 48 81 i i i These patients do not require daily hospital care but return to the institution at intervals </seg>
            <seg id="p016">424 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE II -AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE III CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year CIVIL STATl M arrieii . Widowed Divorced 1 :] I'nknown TABLE IV -EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED ending rnding Total Nov. 30, Nov. 80, (or 191" 15)18 Bicnnium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T AGE For Year For Year ending endinc Total Nov. 30. Nov. 30, for 1917 lain Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. j M. F. T. I'nder 1 month 1 and under .1 months 3 And under ti month* 6 and under 12 month* 1 and under 2 yeant . 2 and under 5 years . 5 and under 10 years. 10 and under 15 years . 15 and under 20 years . 20 and under 25 years. . . 25 and under 30 years. . :tl) and under 40 years. . . 40 and under 50 years . . Over 50 years 1 l! ... 1 1 . 2 2 I S 1 4 t 3 6 i; 4 10 j 3 1 4 1 3 1 4 li 2 8 2 5 7 3 4 7 5 9 14 15 7 22 3 12 15 18 19 37 27 20 47 15 13 28 42 33 7i 49 27 76 49 36 85 98 63 161 54 56 110 30 49 79 84 105 189 23 32 55 14 26 40 37 58 95 7 11 18 6 9 15 13 20 33 5 12 17 2 3 5 7 15 22 5 3 8 2 2 5 5 10 5 16 2 2 7 18 4 2 &lt;i I 15 2 7 Totals 202 179 381: 131 IH XM S33 333 &lt;I71 For Year For Year EDUCATION ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30. for 1917 !S)18 Biennium M. F. T. ( M. F. T. M. F. T. Mone Primary 1st to 4th grade Ith to 8th (rade Sth to 12th grade College or University Unknown 58 33 91 29 46 75 87 79 166 13 4 17 I 5 10 18 9 27 54 58 112 44 25 69 98 83 181 58 58 116 30 50 80 X* 108 196 18 22 III 10 16 26 28 38 66 1 4 5 1 4 5 13 17 30 13 17 30 Totals . . . a 202 179 381 131 159 290 333 338 671 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE V NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE VI COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM NATIVITY For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 3 I, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. : M. F. T. Sebriska United States, other than Nebraska 151 127 2H0 117 143 260 270 270 540 | 46 48 94| 9 12 21 55 60 115 Total satire born 199 175 374 126 155 281 32.'&gt; ,(33 655 Canada Denmark- Germany Greece Netherlands Poland Mexico 1 1 1 1 1 . ll 1 ... 1 I 12 1 1 ! 2 3 11112 2 1 1, 1 1 II 1 2 :l 2 2 4 ! I... 4 4... 4 Total foreign born . .... 3 4 t| S 4 9 8 8 16 Total *)&gt; 17!) Ml 131 159 290 330 338 671 if. COUNTY For Year ! '■nding Nov. 30, i 1917 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1918 ir V. Total lor Biennium Ml Hemaininif Nov. 30, 1918 M I ■ T M 1. K. T. M. P. T. M. F. T. Adams Antelope . Brown Boone Box Butte Boyd . Buffalo Burt Butler . . Cu Cedar Cherry Chaae Colfax rustir Dakota Dawes Dawson Deuel Dixon Dodge Dundy Douglas Fillmor..- Franklin Frontier Furnaa Ga«e GoRper Greeley Hall Hamilton Hayes. Hitchcock Holt Hooker Jefferson . . Johnson 2 '.'.'." 'i\ 2 2 1 1 I 1 6 6 1 1 11 1 1 1 1 1 1 112 2 2 2 2 . 2 2 6 4 io 2 2 i '. '. '. '. i 3 2 5 1 1 1 1 12 3 1 1 i. '.'. '. " i 1 . . 1 1 2 3 1 2 3| 1 1 1 2 2 1 1 1 2 1 1 . . 2 ' 1 1 '* 2 . :. 4 1 1 1 . " i " 2 1 1 1 1 ! 2 2 1 1 1 2 ' 2 2 1 -• 3 2 1 1 1 2 * ■ :l J !' 2 I 1 :i 1 2 2 :l 2 2 I . . . . 1 1 2 2 1 1 2 2 11 3 31 7 2'. :::: \ I ::: \ \\ i i 2 2: 1 ! 1 II 1 '. 2 1 1 2 2 2 I .... 2 2: 2 2 1 4 •&gt; 2 J ll 8 19 ! 1 3 1 } \ !| 5 I ii .... 2 a . 1 2 :i 2 1 :i, .... :t :i 2 1 :) 2 1 3 1.... 1 3 I 3 4 7' 2 . : 1 1 . .1 1 ', 2 " ' : l 5 1 1 ::: V :: 2 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 6 1 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">426 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VI— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIF.NNIUM— Continued COUNTY For Year For Year I ending ending Total Nov. SO, Nov. 30, i (or 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. II. P. T. All Remaining Nov. 30, 1918 M. F. T. Knox Lancaster. . Lincoln. . Morrill Loup Madison.. MePherson Merriek Nance .. Nemaha Nuekolls fltoe Pawnee. . . Phelps Pierce Polk Red Willow Richardson Saline . Seotts Bluff Seward Sherman . . . Thayer .... Thomas Thurston .... Valley Webster ..... Wheeler Washington ■ York Other states. . 2 2 1 1 2 S 1 4 . 131 121 252; 94 114 208 225 235 160 2 1 3 1 1 2j 3 2 6 1 1 1 1 1 1 .... 1 1 . 1. 1 1.... 1 . 3 3 3 3 1... 1 1.... 1 . 2 2 2 2 3... 3 1 1 2 4 1 5 1. . 1 1... 1 . 1 1 2 1 ... 1 2 1 3 I.... 1 1 .... 1 2 . . 2 2.... 2 2... 2. 4 2 6 1 1 2 5 3 8j 1 2 8 1 2 3 ! 1 4 6 1 4 5 4.... 4 4.... 4 . 2 2 4 2 2 4 1. ... 1 1.... 1. 3 1 4 3 1 4 1 1 t 1 . 4... 4 2 1 S 6 1 7. 3 t .... 1 1 .... 4 4. 1 1 1 .... 1 1 1 2 S 1 7 6 1 7. » 1 4 3 1 4 1 J 1 1 1 1 2 1.... 1 1.... 1 . 1 3 4 1 1 2 2 4 6. 1 1 .... 1 1 . 1 1 6 18 24 ........ i .. . i i i 2 i ' 3 ! j • j '.'.'.'. i "l i l Total : . I 202 179 381 131 159 290 333 338 671 22 32 54 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 427 TABLE VII— FORM OF DISEASE OF THOSE REMAINING IN HOSPITAL NOVEMBER 30, 191S, AND OF THOSE ADMITTED DURING BIENNIUM i For Year I For Year ] ending ending Total DISEASE Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 I Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Abdominal abeess 2 2 2 2 Adenoids 8 4 12 1 1 8 5 13 Adenoids and tonsils, removal 16 9 25 23 18 41 39 27 66 AnkyloeiR, knee : 2 2 2 2 Ankylosig, shoulder 3.... 8 3.... 3 Anemia 1 . . . . 1 1. . . . 1 Appendicitis 1 5 6 1 1 2 2 6 8 Arthritis, knee 1 1 2 1 1 2 Arthritis 2 1 3 2 1 3 Auto-toxemia 1 1 2 1 1 2 Bronchitis 2 1 t 3 3 2 4 6 Bum 2 2 ... 1 1.... 3 3 Cervical eariea 112 112 Chicken pox 3... 3 2 2 4 5 2 7 Chorea 2 13 112 3 2 5 Club foot 7 4 11 2 9 11 9 13 22 Contracture, from burns 1 1 1 1 Conjunctivitis 1 1 1 1 Contracture tendon Achilles 1 1 1 1 Claw toes 1 1 ... 1 1 Deformities, multiple 4 4 4 4 Diptberia 9 14 23 ... 1 1 9 15 24 Disloeated shoulder 1... 1 1... 1 Dislocation, knee 1.... 1 1... 1 Dislocation, elbow 1 1 1 1 Dislocation, hip congenital 4 6 10 1 5 6 5 11 IS Dermatitis I.... 1 1 I Dysmenorrhea 2 2 1 1 3 3 Empyema 1 . . . . 1 1.... 1 Epistaxis I 1 1 1 Examination 2 I 2 2 Eye, injury 1 . . . . 1 1.... 1 Fecal impaetion 1 1 2 1 1 2 Feebleminded 1... 1 1... 1 Foot, weak 2 2 2 2 Fracture, clavicle 1.... 1 1.... 1 Fracture at base of skull 1 1 1 1 Fracture, tibia congenital S 4 7 » 4 7 Fracture, depressed and partial paralysis 1 . . . . 1 1 1 Fracture, cofles 1... 1 1 1 Fracture, compound 1-... 1 1 . . . . 1 Fracture, humerus 1... 1... 1 1 1 1 2 Fracture, leg 3 1 4 3 1 4 Furuncle 1 1 1 1 Gastritis * 4 • 1 2 3 3 6 9 Grippe 2 6 7... 1 1 2 6 8 Genu-recurvatum 1 1 1 1 Genu-valgus 1 . . . . 1 1.... 1 Glands, enlarged 1 1... 2 ».... 3 S Gonorrhea 1 1... 1 1... 2 2 Goitre 1 1 1 1 Hare lip and deft palate S 1 4 ( 1 7 9 2 H Hernia, ingunal 5 1 « I.... 2 7 18 Hernia, umbilical 1 1 1 1 Hypospadiaa 2.... 2 I.,.. 2 Influenza 23 27 50 23 27 50 Infection, knee 1 1... 1 1 Infection, arm 1 1 . . . . 1 1 Infection, scalp 1 1 .1 1 Injury, knee 1 1 1 1 Ileocolitis 1 1 1 1 Little's disease 1 1 1.... 1 Lacerated hip 1 1 1 1 Laek of development of 3d and 4th cervical vertebrae 1 1 1 1 Luetic Pharyngitis 1 1 1 1 Lues 1.... 1 1.... 1 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">428 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VII— FORM OF DISEASE OF THOSE REMAINING IN HOSPITAL NOVEMBER 30, 1916. AND OF THOSE ADMITTED DURING B1ENNIUM Continued DISEASE Lordosis. cervical . . Mastoiditis Meningocele Measles Marasmus Muscle, strain Myxedema Nails in hip from previous operation Neuritis Osteo arthritis, spine Ophthalmia neonatorum Osteomyelitis Otitis media Panophthalmitia Paralysis, pes cavus Paralysis, infantile, acute Paralysis, infantile Paralysis, spastic, Paralysis, ps«udo hypertrophic muscular Paralysis, traumatic Pneumonia Phimosi? Pleural abscefls Popiteal abscess Pott's disease Pelvic p« ritonitis Pericarditis Rheumatism Rachitis Retention of urine Septum, deviated Scarlet fever Sclerosis, amptrophic lateral Scoliotfis Spondylitis Spina binda Sprain, ankle Sterilization Stomatitis Small pox Syphilis Strabismus Talipes calcaneous Talipes planus Tonsils, hypertrophied Tumor of femur Tuberculosis, miliary Tuberculosis, epidid vmis Tuberculosis, spine Tuberculosis, axillary glands Tuberculosis, cervical elands Tuberculosis, hip Tuberculosis, knee Teeth, extraction of Tonsilitia Torticollis Ulcer, duodenal Ulcer , stomach Uterus, fibroid of Urticaria Vaccina Varicose veins Vaxinitis Totals For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. P. T. M. F. 1 1 1.... ll 1 1 2 i.... l I l.... i 2.... 2 ! 2 ... 2 15 5 20 . ... 2 2 15 7 22 1 1 2 1 1 2 1... 1 1... 1 1.... 1 1... 1 1 1 .... 1 1 1 1 1 1 i... i i.... l i i i i 5 3 8 5 5 10 10 8 18 1 1 2 1 1 2 1 .... 1 1 . . 1 1 1 1 1 1.... 1 1 1 17 19 36 4 4 8' 21 23 44 3 2 5 2 3 5 5 5 10 1 1 2 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 I... 1 I.... 1 2... 2 I.... 1 1 ... 1 1... 1 1... 1 2... 2 1... 1 I... 1 2 I 3 2 1 S 1 1 .... 1 1 I.... 1 1 ... 1 1 ... 1 1 ... 1 5... t .... 4 4 5 4 9 1... 1 I. ... 1 1.... 1 I.... 1 5 11 16 6 3 91 11 14 25 1 1 .... 1 1 7 8 15 2 6 8 9 14 23 1.... 1 I.... 1 2 2 2 2 1... 1 I.... 1 1 1 2 1 1 2 2 2 4 1 1 2 1 1 2 6 5.... 5 5 1 t 3 1 2 3 I.... 1 1.... 1 I 1 .... 1 1 1 1 2 1 .... 1 2 1 3 13 13 26 10 19 29 23 32 55 1 I .... 1 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 1... 1 I.... 1 7 7 14 7 7 14 1 1 1 1 1 1 .... 1 1 9 5 14 5 2 7 14 7 21 1 2 I .... 1 1 1 3 4 1 1 .... 1 1 .... 2 2 4 5 9 4 5 9 3 3 3 3 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 I.... 2 2 ....1 2..-. 2 2.... 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 .... 1 1 202 179 381 131 159 290 333 333 671 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 429 TABLE VIII -OPERATIONS DURINC BIENNIUM TABLE IX— DURATION OF HOSPITAL RESIDENCE OF THOSE DISCHARGED DURINC BIENNIUM TABLE X SUMMARY OF RESULT OF THOSE DISCHARGED RESULT Number Per Cent Cured 382 53.50 281 34.36 24 3.36 27 3.78 Improved Tnimproved Died Totals 714 100.00 OPERATIONS Surgical operations Plaster dressings Surgical dressings Roentgen-ray pictures Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 M. F. T. I 89 67 15« 232 12.997 165 Year ending Total Nov. 30. for 1918 Biennium M. P. T. M. F. T. : 58 73 131 147 140 287 £40 472 12.997 25,967 165 330 KS vermge Resident 32 days 270 d»ys 14 d*y» 177 d»y. 123 days Cured Improved I'nimproved Died Average residence of mil dischmr] M </seg>
            <seg id="p022">430 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF ;t .1 n 2 1 TABLE XI CAUSE OF DEATH For Ye»r For Yemr ending ending Total For Ye»r For Yemr ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, (or 1917 1918 Biennium CAUSE OF DEATH CAUSE OF DEATH Nov. 30, Nov. 30, (or 1917 1918 Biennium M. P. T. M. F. T. j M. F. T. I.... 1 i I.. . 2 1 3 1... l! 3 1 M. F. T. M. F. T. i M. F. T. Accident Accident i.... i i i Broncho pneumonia Broncho pneumonia Cholera infantum . . . 1 3 1 . l! 3 1 Cholera infantum 1 1 1 1 1 ... 1 Convulsions due to spastic paralysis Convulsions due to spastic paralysis Colitis 1 1 1 1 1 .... 1 Colitis 1 1 ... . 1 1 1.... 1 Diptheria, laryangeal Diptheria, laryanceal Enteritis 1 ... 1 1 . . .. 1 1 2 1 1 1... 1 1 1 Enteritis 1 1 2; 1 1 Empyema Empyema 1.... 1 1. . 1... 1 1 Fracture at base of skull 1.... 1 1 ... Fracture at base of skull Meningitis, simple l.... l ! l Meningitis, simple :::::::::::: i:::: ! ! ::: •■i... 1 :::: ::::|-i 1... 11 1 1.... 1 1 Meningitis, tbc Meningitis, tbc Nephritis, acute Nephritis, acute 1 1 1 Paralysis, paeudo muscular Paralysis, paeudo muscular Pneumonia i...._ i • i:::... 1 ... 1 :::: r , ! i.... i i.. . i.... i : l... l... i l... i i : .... i i.... ij i .... i.... i i... .11... i 10 7 17 7 3 Id 17 10 2 Pneumonia i i .... i Sclerosis, amyotrophic, lat Sclerosis, amyotrophic, lat 1 1 ... 1 Scarlet fever Scarlet fever 1 1 I.... 1 ; ■ i" i 1 1 1 Septic embolism Septic embolism Septicaemia . . Septicaemia 1 Syphilis, laryngeal Syphilis, lar&gt;'ngeal Surgica) shock . i Surgical shock 1 ... 1 1 Syphilis, gastroenteritis Syphilis, gastroenteritis TuDerculosis, general . . . Uterus, fibroid of 1... J 1... 1 1 1 1 1 Tuberculosis, general l T t*rus, fibroid of Totals 1 Totals 10 7 17 7 3 Id 17 10 TABLE XII -AGE AT DEATH For Year ' For Year ending ending Total Nov. SO, ! Nov. 30, for AGE 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. I M. F. T. 1 and under 3 months. 3 and under 6 months. 6 and under 12 months 1 and under 2 yean I and under 5 yean. . . . 5 and under 10 years. . 10 and under 5 years 25 and under 30 years . . 40 and under 50 yean. . 1 1 2, 1 1 11112 1 1 1 I.... 1 1 1 2 1 3 2 1 1 1 2 1 1 3 2 6 2 . 2 S 2 3.... 3 1.... 1 1 2.... 2 2 1 1.... 1 .... 1 1 1 1 Totals 10 7 17 7 3 101 17 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OP COMMISSIONERS 431 TABLE XIII-RAT1O OF EMPLOYEES TO PATIENTS If. F. T. Number of physicians, including superintendent Ratio of same to patients 1:21 1:19 I .-41 Number of day nurses* .... Ratio of same to patients 12 12 1:7.1 4 1:4 1:3.1 Number of night nurses Ratio of same to patients 4 1:12 1:9.5 1:21.5 Total officers and employees** Ratio of same to patients 11 :!7 48 1:1.8 1.1 LI •Does not include graduate nurses. **In considering this ratio one must bear in mind that the Orthopedic Hospital furnishes to the Nebraska Home for Dependent Childred food, laundry and heat. The hospital receives pay for this but in so far as such work requires extra employees this ratio is not correct. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>