<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family</title>
               <date value="1930-08">1930-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 248 August. 1930 The Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family J. O. RANKIN Department of Rural Economics • I I 1 . F" ~J~ ~~i SO [=j TENANTS gg Jj,'g^ D ! J GO AU. EXDENOITUBE UNDER *UOO" tieOO- P VEn CROUPS *1200 179&lt;3 1399 *i399 COST PER I'IiHSON The cost of rluthinu a piT«on over one' year old Kvergßud $40 per year in U2H Nebraska farm h«»me&lt;. - The nverajre" total cost of family jiving was Sl.fiSO. This includes both money spent ami the value of the fowl, fuel, and shelter furnished by thv furni. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. IiURK. Director j </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY BY LINES S Tr" ZZT* M "'* '-*'*« *•" «■•&lt;■—' '»» »r, one-tenth over $2,399. Pa ges ;{ a nd -I. ' '""■ h ° me ' " r §4!1 " er '~ -- ' j - Clothing c-osts per person varied greatly with locality. Pa K e &lt;i Flarn, clothing costs per person were about equal to those of the citv wage-enrninK and low-salaried c-lasses. Pa K es (! &lt;• • Among me n and boys ciothi, Ifir &#132;st, u,,,. .owest in the &#132;,,„„,„,„, l.te and highest anjohg single men 22 to-25 vear, old Pages ,•■ n Among women and girls practically the same was true. I^ ( , 15-2^ Homemade garments were almost entir.lv f,,, ,\ —mainly for the children Th !• " me " Hnd thildren </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family 1 .T. O. RANKIN Clothing is an important item of the cost pf- living. It must protect against heat and cold in such a; way as to maintain health. It must be appropriate and attractive and reasonably pleasing to the wearer and those with whom he is associated. Farm people feel the pressure of keeping up appearances less than city people, but this difference has gradually lessened as communication has brought more' frequent contact with other people. Studies were made recently to learn how much Nebraska farm people spend for clothing and what they buy. Very detailed information was obtained as to the number and cost of the garments of each kind purchased per year for each member, of the family. No unpaid labor was included in the costs of either made-over garments ori new ones made at home. Gift clothing was omitted. Table I. — Homes by tenure and expenditure groups "■I. '. li- TT^"— Part- ; Hired Expenditure group All . Owners owners Tenants ; ' men Number 328 107 I 58 156 7 Under $1200 ....: 81 29 ! 8 38 6 $1200—1799 130 43 16 70 1 $1800— 2399 ....;. I 83 23 21 39 0 Over $2399. . ......... 34 12 13 9 0 Percentages. &#132;. 100.0 100.0 i 1100.0 100.0 100.0 Under $1200 24.7 27.1 i 13.8 24.3 85.7 $1200— 1799. .......... 39.6 40.2 27.6 44.9 14.3 $1800— 2399 ......... 25.3 21.5 36.2 25.0 ; 0.0 Over $2399 .j 10.4 11.2 122.4 5.8 ! 0.0 • ■ 2. •* * J r Table 1 shows the tenure and expenditure grouping of 328 farm families whose clothing expenditures were reported fully enough to be made the basis of this study. More than half were families of owners and part-owners and all the rest were of tenants, except seven hired men. The part-owner is a farmer who owns part of the land heifarms and rents part from someone else. A mortgage on an owner's farm does not make him a part-owner. Thruout this bulletin owner means owner-operator and never refers to the landlord. About one-fourth of the families spent less than $1,200 per home per year for all items of family living. Two-fifths spent 1 Except as otherwise noted, hased upon the survey described on pases 3-fi of Cost nf Feeding the Nebraska Farm Family. Nebr. AKr. Kxp. Sta. Bui. 219. June, 1927. Especial credit is due Miss Eleanor H. Hinmnn for aid in the analysis of all wpmen's clothing data and in graphic presentation, anil to Mrs. E. L. Dane for the preparation of the tables. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 248 PEn CENT O 10 ZO 30 40 50 60 -TO SO . 90 100 " EN6m5^^T i i i i i i I wiped i^HH^BHH^HH^hHlHHI^I^^HHriil^HH^I^H^^^^^^^^^ " i i PEQ CtNT O &gt;0 iO -50 -ft) SO 60 70 80 90 100 ■ UNDER ggl *U00- [=] *1SOO- r^q OVER | PIC. I.— rERCENTAGK DISTRIIIUTION OK Uo.MKS STUI1IKD I'lirt-nwiMTs fell very largely in the hiKhor expenditure 1 irruiip.H ami hireil men in the lower, but owner* and tunantx both- conformed very L-l.iscly t.. th. uem-ral nwirnitf: between $1,200 and $1,799; one-fourth, between SI. 800 and $2,399: and one-tenth, over $2,399. Owners and tenants showed about the same distribution among expenditure groups, but part-owners fell much more largely in the two groups above $1,800. This is because they have larger -house - holds than owners and not because they spend more per person. Owners and part-owners both spent §428 per person for all living costs, but tenants spent only $367 -per person. TOTAL CLOTHING COSTS PER HOME Table 2 shows a cost of $197 per home to clothe about four persons per home. This is $49 per person including men. women, and children, whose varying expenditures are shown in later tables. The number clothed per family was a little less than the number fed per household, because of the omis - sion from the clothing data of hired help and visitors who lived in the same household and ate at the same table, but were not clothed from the family purse. There were even some resident members of the family who possessed an inde - pendent income and bought their clothing from that ; these too were omitted. A few children away at school or for other reasons not fed at home, but clothed from the family pocket book, formed a partial counterpoise to the above-mentioned omissions. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family . -500 j ■! -j tenant:, EIS MEN 0 ■ B i0 ° AV\- EXPSNDITUHE UNOEO *l*00- *1SOO- OVER -.COUDS *U00 1799 &lt;tS99 | **399 FIG. 2.— COST PER HOME Thi» *-tr-t &lt;if cluthinu per homo ur per family increased much more from low to hich expenditure levels than co&amp;t per person, because the homes mnUitur the creater ex - "'■iri&lt;liturfs ■ were -mainly thotte containing the larser families. Table 2. — Clothing costs per home and per person ''■■'• ~~~] 1 ! ■ ' : Part- Hired Expenditure groups All J Owners j owners Tenants men AH • ' ' ' . Cost per houw: ' $197 $188 $236 $197 $73 Cost per person ....... 49 52 54 48 17 ■'■'■■,.■ - ■ ■' ■ '■ f I- ■■ • " Curler $1200 . Cost per home ...... 94 89 114 100 58 Cost per person 32 34 . 40 33 13 $1200^1799 Cost per home 174 173 162 177 161 Cost per person ...,.,. i 48 51 48 46 40 •• f • ; i -I ■ 51800-^2399 ; Cost per home ........ 262 : 230 270 278 Cost per person ....... 55 51 ; 56 56 ... Over $2399 Cost per home 369 ■ i • 401 i 349 354 Cost per person ....... 63 78 60 51 The expenditure by groups shown in Table 2 increased with the size of the family but not in proportion to the size of the family, for the larger families spent more per person as well as more per home on clothing. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 248 Area variations. — The cost of clothing per household was $271 in the Kimball county area in western Nebraska, $200 in the Washington and Lancaster areas, and $140 in the Clay county area, where there were many economical elderly couples. The cost per person varied in about the same way, from $62 in Kimball to $40 in Clay county. The presence of many relatively young farmers in the west may help to ac - count for the higher clothing expenditures in that area. Table 3. — Farm and city clothing costs per home and per person ' .. _ . , ■_ . ■Under $1200- $1800- I Over All i $1200 1799 2399 I $23!l!&lt; Cost per home . ■ . Farm •. $197 $ 94 $174 $262 , $36!i 92 cities .238 151 227 332 : 50:J Omaha...... 231 139 204 ' 316 I 468 . Grand Island ....-■ 245 131 235 326 j 539 Cost per person • . Farm . . '. .49 32 48 55 , »i:{ 92 cities ■ 48 34 47 63 Tit Omaha . ' 48 , 35 44 60 rt&lt;&gt; Grand Island .... 54. 34 51 71 83 Homes, percentage distribution Farm. . . 100.0 24.7 39.6 25.3 \ 10.4 92 cities . . . ... 100.0 22.8 55.3 19.0 2,9 Omaha 100.0 7.S 68.6 19.6' .i.it Grand Island 100.0 24.7' 48.1 22.1: 5.2 lUrban data from Cost of Living in the United States. IT. S. Dept. I.al&gt;.. Bur. I.al). Stat . Bui. 357. 1924, paRes 5. '.12 and 49. This survey . covered 12,096 families of wa^e-turners and »»w-salaried wnrkers in 02 cities r 102 in Omaha and 77 in Grand Island. FARM AND CITY COMPARED ■ ■ . The cost of clothing per person was practically the same in the farm homes studied as in the 92 cities studied by the United States Bureau of Labor Statistics in 1918 and 1919. The cost per family was greater in the cities because of greater numbers in these working-men's homes than in the farm homes studied. While city families in general were slightly larger than farm families, they varied more from expenditure class to expenditure class than those on farms. The 328 Nebraska farm homes studied averaged 3.99 persons for whom clothing was purchased as compared with 4.3 for Omaha in 1920, 4.8 among the Omaha working-men's homes studied in 1918, and 4.4 in all Nebraska farm house - holds in 1925. The 1925 figure was obtained by dividing the number of farm people by the number of farms. It there - fore includes hired help, which was excluded from the city </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family ■ NEBOASKA B58 3 2 ' Is = voo_ ■farms p= ;,oo OMAHA @ ISLAND Kg 1 AU. EXPENDmjDE UNDER *\Z0O- *|600- OVER G.0OUP5 I 9 U0O I *ir&lt;=&gt;9 | *Z399 | *Z399 | FIG. ».— FARM AND CITY COSTS PER FAMILY in all expenditure Kroups. the Nebraska farm families spent less for clothinit than ih.- f.imilies of cither Omaha or Grand Island earners of wages and low salaries. These Nebraska cities averaged alxmt the same ai; '.12 cities scattered thru th? 4H states. figures and from the farm survey figures used as the basis of clothing computations.- In both city and country the amounts spent for clothing varied roughly, at least, with the income (city) or total expenditure (farm). It is unfortunate that strictly comparable statistics of the clothing expenditures for farm and city families are not available. In 1918 and the years immediately preceding and following, city labor was fully employed. Because of full - time employment at high money wages, city workers as a whole felt prosperous in 1918, and doubtless spent money more freely for clothing than they have done during many other periods. The price of farm products fell very sharply in the fall of 1920, and from that year until 1924, when our records were taken, the purchasing power of farm products was relatively low, varying from 75 to. 92 per cent of the five pre-war years. As a result of this long-continued agricultural depression most farmers did not feel prosperous in 1923 and 1924, and as a result the farm expenditures for clothing in J The Northern States. U. S. Census of Aur.. Part I. 0. 5G. .1925. Population: Composition and Characteristics of the Population by Stages. Four - teenth Census of the U. S.. Part III, GOB. 608, and G00. 1920. Coat of Uvinir in the United States. U. S. Dept. Lab. Bui. 3Bi. pp. H. 32. and 49. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 248 *eo h ' ' I ? I 1 "Ti^o ■ 6 ~\ —NEBRASKA ng 9Z Rgg = ■FA0M5 tsa CITIES kI_ = _-_ TO SO _ S OMAHA m -J|W 1 - -W | 1 6 ° all EXPErtDmme under | *imo- *ieoo- ovep GROUPS *UOO IT99 £'309 H^^9 PIG. I.--KAKM AND CITY COSTS I'KIi I'KRSON Cii-Uh per person were about the same in f:u-m 'in\\ city homed. They wvrc ;i little lower in Omaha and distinctly hinher in Grand Island than In the Nebraska farm homes. There is u difference between cost per farm home and per city home which i - in contrast to thi&lt; practical e&lt;|iiulity of the cObt per person. Such 11 contrast can result only from difference in number of persons per home — 1 in Nebraska farm homes, 4.9 in Omaha homes, 4.5 in Grand Isfand home-, nnd -l.'J in those of the '. ( "J cities. the year of the .survey were undoubtedly abnormally, low, It is, therefore, not surprising that the farm clothing cost per home stood below the city cost in every expenditure group. Another reason for a discrepancy is that clothing costs wen. 1 somewhat higher in 1918 than in 1924.-. The expenditure groupings are quite comparable except that: (1) the city figures divide the two upper groups at $2,500 instead of $2,400 as in the case of the farm data, and (2) the city groups are based .on income instead of expenditure. The latter discrepancy is less serious than might appear at first glance, and doubtless neither one seriously affects the com - parability of the farm group as a whole with the city group as a whole. . Table 3 shows that in total clothing expenditure per person the classes are practically equal. They may differ, however, in the items entering into the totals. The farm clothing cost per home stood below the city cost in every expenditure group. 'Prices and Cost of Livinc. Mo. Lab. Uev. U. S. Deiit. Lab., Ilur. I.ab. Stat., i&gt;p. 73 and 7G. Aucust, 192,1. A clothing conversion factor of 1.01 1 was computed by the method outlined in foot - notes 1 and 2. Table 5, Ncbr. Ajrr. Kxp. Sta. Ilul. 219. This was recarded n« indi - cating too sliisht a chance in the purchnsinn power of the clothing dollar to justify index-number treatment of the 1!&gt;1R data. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family In the 92 cities it went from $151 in the group under $1,200 to $503 in the group over $2,499, as compared with a rise from $94 to $369 for farm families of the group over $2,399. Omaha families spent slightly less on clothing than the aver - age for the 92 cities, and Grand Island families somewhat more. The farmers spent less per person than the town dwellers in all of the expenditure groups except the $1,200 - to-$l,799 group. In general, the farmers showed a smaller rise in clothing expenditures than the city families relative to the general rise in cost of living between the lower and the higher expenditure groups. But the two upper expenditure groups included a larger proportion of the farm than of the city families: TOTAL CLOTHING COST PER PERSON About $49 was the clothing cost found per person in Ne - braska farm homes. Outer garments cost $28, footwear $13, underwear $5, and accessories $3. Children's footwear re - quired a higher percentage of their clothing cost, but the percentage spent for outer garments and underwear increased with age. Cost per person ranged from $13 for children one or two-years of age to about $100 for the unmarried between 22 and 25 years of age ; the married in this age group spent $62 each. Doubtless for some time after marriage clothing on hand was worn- and little new clothing purchased, that early home-making expenses might be met. The cost of the clothing of the married increased very gradually until about 35, but then decreased until it averaged $39 for all over 50 years of age. This paragraph includes figures not found in tables in this or any other publication. Farm men and boys under 21 spent about 15 per cent less, each, than the city men and boys of the same age. Above the age of 21 the city men spent distinctly more for clothing than men in the country. The cost of clothing farm girls was much, less than for city girls up to 21, but the farm wives spent a little more than the wives of city wage-earners and low-salaried men. The farm figures for the married include also the single over 59. who were not numerous enough or sufficiently different in clothing expenditure to justify a separate grouping. At the higher expenditure levels shown in Table 4 there was a much more marked tendency for the city to outspend the country for clothing, except in the case of the wives. The city wives spent rather less than those in the counti'y, perhaps because the other members in the family must com - pete so keenly in shop, office, and school that there is less left for the stay-at-home wife and mother. Perhaps the city </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 248 Table 4.~Far,n and city clothing costs per person by sex. age Sex and age AI , EPA" *}%°°- j $1800- j Over ■ A " . 51200 1799 ! 2399 | $2399 „ ■ ■ • "_ 38 0 3 73 90 Husbands F arm . Citv 2° 35 oo 64 73 ' . ol '- 90 9G Uomen and girls Farm , v &gt; ... . Clt&gt; ol 34 49 . 67 86 - 1 ?*?™ 24 13 22 29 u Clt&gt; ;f l 23 3l 39 . 41 I2 " 21 ■ %?:■■■ s ; 8: if g ; jjV: i. ■Ja^te^^j-ajjijB^j; &gt;»„ ,»„., „„, .„ ,„„„„„, ■ especially true amonj faSn giffs The 55"IS . T ? iS WaS MEN'S AND BOYS' CLOTHING The amounts spenl SSSfSSSS SSft %t%S£ </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family *ioo , | *ioo ■a«5 H YQ^.. S YDS. e BANDS &amp;O I .= ' E . 60 £=0 = = = -^; = bO ■ &amp; |y ao 100 _J 100 AVI. EXPENDITURES .UNOEq »U00- *^60O- OVEQ | CQOUPS. I *IZOO | 1799 I X399 I *Z599 | FKi. r&gt;.— FAKM AND CITY COSTS FOR MEN AND HOYS Nebraska farm men anil bbys in Kencral spent distinctly less than those of the !&gt;2 ■itifs' for clothini.'. (specially above the nuc of 12 years. Until that aise, the boys' •luihinjr costs were about the same in farm and city. I I ■ ' i T i I 1 ■ AGES KS\R3IS3 YO5. B"WR&gt; so I I [ pi eo ao : — Sfe- [Ste = — - = 60 &gt;» "^ m * *^" Jj J^^ W» HM tfh h- &amp;0 |J_ : b 3 _^E__ _^S 6O eo S; = -§ = so . —^-B-|3 . 100 100 ijo izo ALL EXPENDITURE UNDER »UOO- *ISOO- OVER I CjDOUPS I *IZOO. 1 1T99 I A599 I *;ra99 | FIG. rt. — FARM AND CITY COSTS FOR WOMEN AND GIRLS The Nebraska farm women spent more than the women in the wane-earners' homes in it'2 cities. Under 12 years of aKe the costs were about the name in the city and country. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 248 Table 5. — Men's and boys' main clothing costs . _ . . . . . . . Outer Under- Foot- Access- Age All garments garments wear ories . All $47 $2S S3 $13 $3 1-11....:. ......... 25 13 2 '■&gt; 1 • . ■ ' - . ■ . 1-2 14 fi 2 5 \ 3- 5 . ;. : 1 it !) 2 7 ' 1 6- « . 28 ■ 15 2 .10 1 9-11.: .. :!7 20 2 lo ' -2 12-21 ■...;...,•' 55 35 . .3 14 3 12-14 ........ 12 23 3 .14 2 15-17. 5d 40 ' 3 13 3 I 18-21 "!•'■■ 16 ■! ;T ' Single men 22-59 (17 14 ". Vi 5 22-25 ........ S5. 56 li ! k V 26-5!). .': lil 40 5 •'&gt; Husbands 22-5S :.- 55 33 t :! I 22-25 ..... fid 37 . ■■; U&gt; \ 26-29 , Gl 38 1 15 . 1 30-34 53 32 3 14 1 35-39. . ■ Go 11 1 11 ii • . 40-49 ...I: 4!i : 27 5 13 i 50-59 . 50 2'j -1 II All men over 59 40 23 ' 1 - and less regularly than expenditures for the other main items. Footwear was always an important item hut never a very costly one among farm men and boys, as indicated by Table 5. Undergarments and miscellaneous accessories were much less expensive than footwear in the clothing budget of farm men and boys. For boys 1 to 11 years old. the principal garments in the order of amount spent for them were shoes, overalls, suits. * shirts, hose, union-suits, hats and caps, and overcoats. About 85 per cent of the total went for these items. Among boys and young men 12 to 21 years old, the order changed to suits, shoes, overalls, shirts, overcoats, union-suits, hats and caps, hose, rubbers and overshoes, and sweaters and raincoats. After marriage the order remained the same except that jumpers and rubbers and overshoes went further up in the list. Hardly any jumpers were bought for the boys and </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family *&gt; F"' ' ' 1 1 I 1 I I I 1 1 I 1 1 l $i °° err, OUTED . _| IZd GA0MENT5 ■ 9° 80 _ ggj FOOTWEAR y /M/ ao 70 _ rm UNDEQ- 7777 '/M 70 e,o_ GA0MENTS Wwfr W 60 I-Z 5-b &lt;b-a 9-11 IZ-1* 15-17 18*1 2Z-^S Ur59 ZZVS K19 303*p39|yH9 50-59 AU 1 1 1 1 1 , OVECJ bOYS SINGLE HUSbANOS 59 FIG. 7.— COST OK MAIN GROUPS OF CLOTHING OF MEN AND BOYS Outer Knrmcnts accounted for most of the clothinc costs of men and boys above five yearn c»f ajce. llelow that aire, footwear was almost as expensive as outer Rarments. The peak camr in the early twenties, doubtless because of courtship and marrinpe, after which coats quickly fell to about those of the middle teens and then gradually declined. young men under 22 years. Each man or boy bought during the year about 4 shirts, 4 pairs of overalls, 2 1 /J&gt; pairs of shoes, and I 1 /-; hats, on the average. City wage-earners and their boys bought more suits, trousers, caps, and overcoats, and fewer pairs of overalls than the farm men and boys. By age and expenditure groups. — About $47 per year was the average annual cost of clothing for men and boys, but of course this~ varied greatly with the age and somewhat with the expenditure level and many other factors. The cost was under $20 per year for the boys 1 to 5 years old. It then rose continuously to over $70. At about 30 a decrease set in. After the age. of 59 the annual expenditure for cloth - ing averaged about $40 per man. The men's clothing expenditure per person was greatest in those homes which made the greatest total expenditures for all items in the cost of living. Those in the $l,200-to-$l,799 group spent about 40 per cent more per man than those in the group under $1,200, and those in the $l,800-to-$2,399 group about 60 per cent more. The "Over $2,399" group showed the same tendency but much less markedly and less consistently. In this connection three points should be noted. (1) In the higher income and expenditure groups lower per - centages of the money were spent for clothing and other necessities for which the demand is inelastic. (2) Doubtless </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 248 Table 6. — Total clothing costs of men and boys by age and . expenditure groups I Under $1200- j $1800- I Over Age All I $1200 1799 2399 | $2399 . All '_.-.' $47 $33 $46 $52 $55 1-11.-.. 25 " 17 23 30 27 1-2 !■ 14 8 16 17 12 3-5 .19 18 21 19 18 6- 8. . . 28 18 24 33 26 9-11 .37 28 35 39 43 12-21 ' .55 40 52 5!) 59 12-14 :..... 42 21 39 41 47 15-17 • 59 34 58 66 63 18-21 71 49 60 84 . 69 Single men . ... 22-59... :- .67 ■ KB 48 . 75 85 22-25 '.'•.'. :•.•' «5 .... 103 64 93 26-59.... 61 6&lt;i .37 82 72 j Husbands . 22-59 55 35 55 64 7;! 22-25... • 60 36 68 26-29 61 35 70 104 121 30-34 '.' . 53 32 62 66 68 35-39 ...: U5 34 61 73 124 40-49 ... 49 :!7 44 58 61 50-59 i 50 39 41 52 70. All men over 59 . 10 29 4(&gt; 49 58 fewer farm families were spending over $2,399 in 1924 than a few years earlier and more families were living on much less than this amount, so the averages in this group were based on smaller numbers of cases. They may therefore be expected to be less consistent and regular and more subject to chance variations. (3) The main cause of the irregular showing in the "Over $2,399" group is the great range it covers — $2,400 to the very highest found. The following paragraphs include data not published in tabular form. Outer garments. — The cost of men's and boys' outer garments was $28 per person, beginning with $6 at one to two years old and reaching $46 between 18 and 21. Above that age the amount showed a general decrease among mar - ried men. The single men continued to increase their cloth - ing expenditures a little longer, reaching their peak of $56 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family in the 22-to-25-year age group. The "Over $2,399" group spent about twice as much per man or boy for outer garments as the "Under $1,200" group. Undergarments. — The cost of underwear for men and boys was very low because (1) it is worn less continuously, (2) it is less exposed to severe wear, and (3) only utility need be considered; color, style, and other similar considerations can be almost completely ignored. The cost was about $2 per year during years one to eleven. Then came a steady but gradual increase which almost doubled the annual cost of men's underclothing by the age of 21. Men's underwear costs were like all other men's clothing costs in reaching their highest peak among the single men of the 22-to-25-year age group. Footwear. — The next main class of clothing was footwear. It included shoes, rubbers, overshoes, stockings, socks, slippers, and similar articles. It varied a little more, proportionately, with expenditure groups and much less with age than any of the other main classes of clothing. It was twice as great in the group over $2,399 as in the "Under $1,200" group. As in the case of most other clothing, its peak came at about age 22 to 25. It was almost one-third of all boys' clothing costs at the one-to-eight-year period, but was nearer one-fourth of the total during the rest of life. Accessories. — Handkerchiefs and all other articles of clothing not included under the three classes just discussed were included in accessories. They are not very important cost items in any age or expenditure group. WOMEN'S AND GIRLS' CLOTHING Main clothing costs. — Women and girls averaged $52 a year, for clothing expense, of which $29, or nearly three - fifths, was for outer garments, $14, or two-sevenths, for foot - wear, $7, or one-eighth, for undergarments, and the remain - ing $2 for accesssories and miscellaneous costs. Hose were included as footwear. Accessories included gloves, mittens, neckwear, belts, pins, handkerchiefs, umbrellas, handbags, and miscellaneous items. Girls began with a total clothing cost of $13 for ages one and two years, or slightly less than that for their brothers of the same age. In the three-to-five-year group, however, more was spent for girls than for their brothers, and the amount rose steadily to a peak of $132 among unmarried women 22 to 25 years old. There were, however, only six of the latter reported and half of these were in the highest expenditure group. Sixty-eight dollars was the average clothing cost of </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 248 Table 7.— Women's and girls' main clothing costs . I Outer Under- Foot- JAcwss- IZ._ garments , garments wear ories A1K '•.• ■■■' $52 $2lT~ ""$" ~~^ $ , i-n...;;. 24 . ii . 3 9 i 1 12-21.:.:., fi 8 38 ' - 8 ,., ! 3 12-14.... '....■ . . 43 ■ 29 . • ,.■!'■., I 15-17.- 82 -47 o 11 7 18-21 85 so io :&gt;i :! Single women 22 " 59 - 74 "48 7 15 ., |2-25. 132 90 -12 2:! Wives 22-59... ;.. M - 88 ■..-■.. -,,. ;•. ,, iiiii: : f R y "S::::: ;::::: ] '« -» : ■ °°-o» 52 30 (y All women over 59 :irs l.s " i; girls 12 to 21 years old. Single women ovei- 25 years old had a clothing eost of $48, about one-third, that of the younger un - married women and three-fourths that of the wives WfSV?^ 22 tO 5 .°i yeai ' S ° ld avera e ed §64 for' clothes. Wives 30 to 34 years old spent the most. The wives' clothing costs increased slightly up to this age and decreased markedly nn e t» ° me + n °u fer 59 , y u ars old s P ent on{ y $ 38 °» clothes. Uutei garments showed the greatest range, varying in cost from one-half the total clothing cost of girls one to two -ears old to two-thirds that of unmarried women 22 to 25 Under - wear formed about one-ninth or one-tenth of the clothing tttW 3 K wom ?" u ? to the age of 40 y ears « but abovt No a ~ I° n t °"e-eighth and finally one-sixth of the total. than fhP^?9 P ,' h0 rr ei '' Spent - mOre money for underwear than the $12 spent by unmarried women 22 to 25 years old Footwear formed about one-third of the clothing expeliSe of </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Cost of Clothing the Nebraska: Farm Family •*&gt; 1 1 ' ' ' ' 1 1 i y i i i i i i i k. m OUTER ii 120 _ M GAQMENTS |%; : uo no _ E5 footwear no 100 _. -m, UNDER- 100 90 _ &lt;» lD accessories __ %?/ -r^ 70 I I 1 i ill— il " : _____|||_ppppp^ =:: &gt; 1 5- 5 |g-8 |9-ll|lM4|l3-l7|ia-ZI lualttWlK^lteOTlso-Mls-S^wlso^l All, j FIG. s.— COST OK MAIN GROUPS OK CLOTHING OF WOMEN AND GIRLS Outer garments wen- the main items in the cost of; clothing women and girls in must uko Kroups above two years. The costs were about the same as for boys up to i.l years, and after 35 years of aKe. After 14 young women's clothing costs rose much more rapidly than younK men's, but fell more rapidly immediately after the age of marrK'.ir**. As amonvr men antl boys, footwear was second; to outer garments in cost, and accessories were rather unimportant. Underwear was more expensive for women and irirl* of most art" groups than for men and boy*. little girls and elderly women and from one-fourth to one - fifth of the expense of young women, including young wives. It varied less with the age than any of the other main groups of clothing items. The cost of accessories and miscellaneous items was not more than $7 for any age group. The main garments bought by the Nebraska farm women and girls in the order of the amount spent for them were dresses, shoes, hose, coats, and hats. This order remained unchanged from girlhood to old age, tho the amounts spent and the garments purchased varied. Girls over 12 years old bought more dresses than those under that age. Most of them were cotton but during the year a third of the younger girls had received one wool dress each, and a fifth, one silk dress each. Between 12 and 21 nearly every girl had a new wool dress and a silk dress during the year! studied. After mar - riage a little less was spent for each of [the clothing items ex - cept aprons, suits, furs, hats, chemises, brassieres, and corsets. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 248 By age and expenditure groups. — The average clothinir cost for all women and girls varied from $31 in families spending less than $1,200 a year for all living costs to $7* in families spending more than $2,399. It ran very closelv «? ™o in the two mid(11 e expenditure groups, $1 200-to - $1/799 and $l,800-to-$2,399, being $50 and $57 respective!? • Yi , One t 0 two years old were clothed at a cost of $10 each in the lowest expenditure group and $16 in the highest. Bv age three to five the expenditure groups began to diverge %g e 'H e low *?t spending only $14 per girl and the highest §42. The clothing cost continued to rise, slowly in the lowest expenditure groups and relatively faster in the higher ones, until girls ; 18 to 21 . m the former spent $41 and in the 6 tW ° gr ° UPS Spent * 85 - a " d *" Tarle 8.— Total clothing costs of ivomen and girls by age and expenditure groups ■ Under i $1200- i $1800- Over e _j_ All $1200 1799 239&lt;- j $2399 A " : $52 $31 . ~$50 $5T : " $72 1-11- • ... 24 13 22 2'. ■ :u .;■■ »?::::::::::;:; 3? !i I . | '; | 12 " 21 68 36 66 ::; M) ' ■ ™{::EB:: : « ' - S si :S 18 ' 21 * 5 41 85 S4 in; Single women ■ 22 - 59 - : :.-...:.;.....' 74-- 19 fi7 6 o ; r , 4 H5I::::::::::::::; '!f » ■, 'U ■;. S.1 'S Wives 22 - 5S •■•■■• 64 42 63 74 S7 afCl? 76- 37 74 151 162 2^ 8o 57 68 104 ' 14S »EE:e:B "i.-a I j: g. AH women over 59 .. , 38 30 :}0 46 ' &lt;»o </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Cost of Clothing the Nebraska ; Farm Family The clothing cost of single women" over 21 years presents some anomalies because, of 20 such women, there were only three in the lowest expenditure group and these were all middle-aged dependents averaging only $19 for clothing ex - pense. The daughters of the less prosperous farmers married early or left home to work. This circumstance together with the small number of unmarried women found in even the well-to-do homes accounts for the irregularities of the group. The figures illustrate the importance of dress during the period preceding marriage, from 15 years at the earliest to 25 at the latest, the marked falling-off in clothing costs after marriage, and the s.till more marked fall if the young woman remains at home unmarried. This "display age" began earlier in the poorer homes and ended sooner. In the group, spending under $1,200 a year it affected expenditure for girls between 15 and 17 years old; in the group spending over $2,399 there was no marked display period indicated by costs before 18 years of age. Young wives showed lower clothing costs than those of unmarried women their own age or just younger. This was due partly to the need for economy while starting a family and a business, but perhaps partly to the trousseau. After marriage the wives' clothing expenses increased more or less constantly in all expenditure groups up to the age of 34 years, after which they decreased abruptly. In the two upper ex - penditure groups the wives 26 to 34 years old spent as much as or more than the girls and single women of the "display age", but in the two lower expenditure: groups, constituting the majority of the homes studied, the wives spent less than girls of the "display age". Outer garments. — Outer garments constituted about one - third of the total clothing cost .per woman or girl in the lowest expenditure group and over one-half in the uppermost, altho this varied considerably from one age group to another. In general the more money spent for clothing, the higher the proportion of it spent for outer garments. Single women 22 to 25 years of age in the "Over $2,399" group had the highest clothing costs ; here outer garments constituted two-thirds of the total. Single women 26 to 59 years iof age in the "Under $1,200" group had the lowest clothing; costs of all over 11 years old ; here the outer garments constituted only one-third of the total. Undergarments. — Undergarments were a relatively small item in the clothing cost. They were less than one-eighth of the total clothing cost of women under |40 in all expenditure groups. Above this age undergarments sometimes rose as high as one-sixth of the total cost. The average cost of </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 248 undergarments per girl or woman was $5 for the group spending under $1,200, $6 for the $1.200-to-$l,799 and $1,800 - to-$2,399 groups, and $9 for the group spending over $2,399. Nightwear is included with undergarments, but hosiery is not. Footwear. — Footwear proved the most stable item of the women's as of the men's clothing costs. It constituted about one-fourth of the clothing cost per woman and girl in all expenditure groups. In the group under $1,200 among young children and elderly women footwear constituted from one-third to one-half the total clothing expense, because much of their other clothing can be made at home. Accessories. — Accessories and miscellaneous clothing costs were a minor item in these farm homes, being about one-twelfth the total clothing cost in the homes spending under $1,200 and about one-fifteenth in homes spending over $2,399. In general, of the sum specified for accessories and miscellaneous items, about one-half went for accessories, about one-eighth for cleaning and sewing expenses, and the rest for unitemized clothing. HOMEMADE GARMENTS Homemade garments were apparently almost exclusively tor women and girls and for babies under two ' years old. Practically no material was bought for garments for men or tor boys over two years of age. Only $6 out of; every $1,000 spent for farm men's and boy's clothing went into materials tor homemade clothing. Above 12. years of age it was only $2 or $3 out of every $1,000, but in the one-to-two-year irroun $87 out of every $1,000. . ' Money cost of materials does not show at all clearly the comparative value of homemade clothing worn by. the various age groups. The expenditures for materials for homemade, garments for children one to eleven years of age were $6 -is compared with $11 for their mothers. Girls 12 to 21 years old apparently demanded better ma - terial in their homemade dresses, for their expenditures were higher on the average than for any other age group In general, the higher expenditure groups spent lower -percent - ages of their totals for materials for homemade clothing The proportion of the money spent for homemade clothing was largest in babyhood, being 32.8 per cent for girls one to two years old. There was a gradual decrease to 14 2 per cent for wives 22 to 34 years of age. From this point it increased to 21.9 per cent for women 60 years old and over. This in - crease with age may have been due to the difficultv some </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family i ■ ' '"'■■'■' ' • I ! Tablk 9. — ( nst of. women's and girls' homemade garments ' Under : $1200- ! $1800- ' Over Age AH $1200 1799 2399 I $2399 ■ '--.;— -. . — ; - — 1 — . , ~ All ages '... S 9 $ 7 $10 $ 9 $11 1-11. 6 4 7 6 4 1-2 4 4 5 4 0 \ 3-5 5 3 6 5,2 6-11.. ;:..:. ..:. 6 4 7 8 5 '■■ ■ " • ; ■ ■ - : ■ " '■ ; . I - i '. 12-21 . ... .". . 13 6 15 11 17 Single women 22-o!» 11 r 3 10 17 14 Wives ■•"'!••■ 22-59. ..... ,. 11 10 11 11 10 J2-.i4 ..,.....! 11 10 11 15 6 35-59 11 10 12 9 11 All women' over oil 8.6 8 5 32 elderly women experience in buying ready-made garments that tit and are suitable for a reasonable price. OTHER STATES SPEND MORE V Per family. — Data are at hand from fourteen other . states in which similar clothing studies have been made. Among these, only Vermont spent less per family — $178, or 11.5 per cent of the total cost of family living. The states V included are, in order of amounts spent for clothing: Ver - mont. S178. or 11.5 per cent; Nebraska, $197, or 11.8 per cent: Tennessee, $199, or 17.7 per cent; Kansas, $201, or 13.5 per cent; Kentucky, $223, or 14.9 per cent; Connecticut, $228. or 11. 6 per cent; South Carolina, $233, or 15.7 per cent; Ohio. $238. or 15.4 per cent; Iowa, $242, or 14.5 per cent; New Hampshire, $244, or 13.3 per cent ; [Massachusetts, $246, or 12.6 per cent; Alabama, $257, or 15.9 per cent; Missouri, $268, or 14.1 per cent; New York, $273, or 13.8 per cent; and Texas, S298, or 20.5 per cent. Nebraska owners' and tenants' clothing costs did not differ markedly, but in most other states tenants spent distinctly or even markedly less for clothing than did owner-operators. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska experiment StatIon Bulletin 2-18 families. 4 B owners and $164 among tenants' for^rYoTk^enSef ISa'S^SW!- not states these costs ave,a|ed $53 o? ahn.^L 1 " the Other eleve " braska. Husbands and wives ha 1 pS $ , 4 ™. ore th ™ in Ne - e even states; but theKSawivi clothing costs in the Nebraska husbands $4 less than thf Spent ?5 more and states. Women and girls in all a J &lt;^ avera^ for the eleven under 15 averaged about the 8 !mp^° U i&amp;\ Und f r 26 and bovs gjven states, but the M^M^^JiJ i ■' . '.■'•''■■ ■ ■ ■ ■■..-■ - * Kirkpatrick, F I tk l - rs'iM.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024">OTHER NEBRASKA SURVEY BULLETINS Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes. Univ. Nybr A«r. Exp. Sta. Bui. IKO. 1i)22. 2S pp., 8 figs. Lincoln. Out of print but available as a mimeographed digest. The Nebraska Farm Family: Some Land Tenure Phases. Univ. Nebr. Ajrr. Exp. Sta: Bui. 1 S."S. 1023. :M pp.; - tiirs. Lincoln. Nebraska Farm Homes: A Comparison of Some Living Conditions of Owners, Part-owners, and Tenants. Univ. Nebr Aki\ Exp. Sta. Bui. 191. 1923. IS pp., 1!) fijr.a. .-Lincoln.' Out of print. Nebraska Farm Tenancy: Some Community Phases. ■ Uiiiv." Nebr. Airr. Exp. Sta. Bui. I '.Hi. 1923. 50 pp.. ■• ! ti"s Lincoln. Out of print. Landlords of Nebraska Farms. Univ. Xebr \gv KNU.Sia Bui. 202. 1921. :;s PP -. . -| nfrs . Lincoln, Tenure and. Farm Investment in Nebraska. I'll ' Nchr Apr. Exp. Sta.'Bul. 205. 1925. 30 pp., | t\ K &lt;. Lincoln." Out of print, but available as a 17-pairi- mimcographfij •ligeV't. Steps to Nebraska Farm Ownership. Univ. Xcl.r l'-.'i Si i Bui. 210. 1!)23. :!2 pp.. 4 figs. Cost of Feeding the Nebraska Farm Family. Ilv N'flir Exp. Sta. Bui. 21!t. 1!I27. 36 pp., t tivs. - The Use of Time in Farm Homes. I'niv N'.l.r I'y-, St'-i Bui. 2-30. 1!)2S. 50 pp.. 18' figs; For copies addlt'ss " . College of Agriculture ' . Lincoln, Xehr. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>