<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00052.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00052.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Eighteenth Biennial Report Labor and Compensation</title>
               <date value="1922-07-01">1922-07-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">1 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT Labor and December 31, 1920 to July 1, 1922 NEBRASKA SAMUEL R. McKELVIE, Gov FRANK A. KENNEDY, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">STAFF Secretary of Labor ,. Prank A . Kennedy Chief of Division of Compensation Lester L. Dunn Investigator Jonn Larsen Record Clerk Orpna L Doling Stenographer _ Marguerite L. George Clerk in Omaha Branch Office Arthur F. Clark Manager Free Employment Office, Lincoln Clarence C. Becker </seg>
            <seg id="p004">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Lincoln, Nebraska, July 1, 1922. To Hi* Excellency Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor of Nebraska: In compliance with the laws of the State of Nebraska I have the honor of submitting herewith the Eighteenth Biennial Report of the De - partment of Labor of this state; covering the period from December 31, 1920, to July 1, 1922, and in addition thereto the report of the Commis - sioner of the Workmen's Compensation Law as amended by the Legisla - ture of 1917-1919-1921, effective July 28, 1921. Respectfully, PRANK A. KENNEDY, Secretary of Labor and Compensation Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">PART I DIVISION OF COMPENSATION Lincoln, Nebraska, July 1, 1922. Hon. Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Governor: The Department of Labor respectfully submits its report of activities covering the period from December 31, 1920, to July 1, 1922, Following is the statistical report of the activities of the Division of Compensation for the year 1921: First reports of accidents 11,356 Final reports of accidents 8,673 Casea pending 2,683 Complaints received 637 Personal investigations 637 Lump sum settlements : 17 Amount involved $24,047.96 Total compensation paid $481,596.18 Total medical and hospital expense 138,736.99 Total $620,333.17 Following is the report for the six months period from December 31, 1921, to July 1, 1922 First reports of accidents 5,850 Final reports of accidents 3,964 Cases pending 1,896 Complaints received 81 Personal investigations 81 Lump sum settlements 14 Amount involved $ 28,238.11 Total compensation paid $282,975.61 Total medical and hospital expense paid - 86,877.42 Total $369,853.03 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 6 Total compensation, medical and hospital expense paid during 1921 $620,333.17 Total compensation, medical and hospital expense paid during six months, 1922 ....$369,853.03 Grand total for one and one-half years $990,186.20 The amount of compensation, medical and hospital expense adminis- tered by the department during the last three and one-half years as compared with the four previous years is as follows: No. of Compensation Accidents and Medical 1915 to 1918 (inclusive) 33,263 $ 470,413.08 1919 to July 1, 1922 (inclusive) 42,155 1,875,875.52 The amount of compensation, medical and hospital expense paid to the injured workers of the state during the last three and one-half years, in excess of the four previous years, was $1,405,462.44. The reasons for the difference in the amount of compensation, medi - cal and hospital expense paid to the injured workers of the state during the last three and one-half years, over the four previous years, are briefly, as follows : The amendments to the law by the 1919-1921 sessions of the legislature; the increased wages during the peak years; an in - sistence on strict compliance with the law by all employers and insurance companies; a careful review and investigation of permanent disability settlements; a follow-up of the department's press clipping service covering accidents in all parts of the state; by constantly demanding prompt and regular payment of compensation as required by law; by securing important interpretations of the law by following certain cases through the district and supreme courts; by securing the greatest possible amount of free advertising for the law through the newspapers* by talking on the compensation law to every organization in the state that extends us an invitation; by inducing the Lincoln public school authorities to give instruction in fundamentals of the compensation law to the children; by keeping an accurate record of compensation payments being made on all serious accidents which result in an extended period of disability; by keeping a card system of all employers in the state who carry compensation insurance, thus enabling the department to get immediate and direct action following complaints of injured workers. All of these activities were inaugurated under the present administration. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 7 DEVELOPMENT OF THE LAW IN FIGURES The following table shows the expenses paid each year since the amount of compensation and medical law was adopted: 1915 $ 50,346.51 1916 „ _ ■-_ _ 125,262.37 1917 153,031.73 1918 _ _ _ 141,772.47 1919 345,476.24 1920 --- 540,213.08 1921 620,333.17 1922 (to July 1) 369,853.03 Total $2,346,288.60 COMPARATIVE STATEMENT Below is a comparative statement compiled from the records of the Department since the compensation law became effective in Nebraska No. Cases Compen- Medical Year Acc'ds. Closed sation Expense Total 1915 4,082 2,222 $ 24,923.62 $ 25,422.89 % 50,346 51 1916 10,822 5,411 76,143.50 49,118.87 125,262.37 1917 13,293 13,298 101,204.51 51,827.22 153,031.73 1918 7,066 6,463 102,540.48 39,231.99 141,772.47 1919 11,273 8,791 255,313.36 90,162.88 345,476.24 1920 13,676 9,729 402,780.94 137,432.14 540,213.08 1921 11,356 8,673 481,596.18 138,736.99 620,333.17 •1922 5,850 3,964 282,975.61 86,877.42 369,853.03 ACCIDENTS IN PACKING INDUSTRY It might be of interest to give the following accident reports covering the packing industry of the state: 1915 1916 1917 1918 1919 1920 1921 »1922 Armour &amp; Co 69 138 21 350 207 410 210 1«6 Cudahy Packing Co 33 55 106 224 120 126 121 71 Morton-Gregson 38 42 147 192 138 177 128 81 Swift &amp; Co 54 215 307 191 339 454 442 168 Morris &amp; Co 38 6 7 11 59 157 499 158 Dold Packing Co — — — — — 279 65 31 •January 1 to July 1, 1922 There Is a marked improvement in the service of the insurance com- panies and self-Insured employers toward the injured workers. This improvement has been gradual from the middle of the year 1919 and the service is now somewhere near 100 per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT Early in the year one large corporation was denied a license to carry its own insurance because of its persistent violation of the law. The legal department of this corporation sent a man to Lincoln to hear the complaints of the Commissioner. Following this hearing a license was granted this corporation to carry its own insurance on the promises made by its attorney that it would comply with the provisions of the law in the future. Since then this corporation has given the Department no trouble. Late in 1921 a complaint was filed with the insurance commissioner against a reciprocal company and a stock company for making bargain settlements with injured workers contrary to law. The reciprocal com - pany came in at once and agreed to re-open the case complained of on condition that the Commissioner withdraw the complaint filed with the insurance commissioner. The Commissioner agreed, provided the ad - juster who made the fraudulent settlement be discharged. The adjuster was discharged and the case involved is now proceeding in a regular and lawful manner. The case against the stock company before the insurance com - missioner is a different story. The company contested the case before the insurance commissioner and the latter decided he had no authority to set aside a court order and dismissed the complaint. The compensa - tion Department then had the case brought before the district judge who approved the bargain settlement. The judge set aside the settlement order and the case is now pending before the district court to be heard on its merits. It is hoped by the Department that the practice of a few adjusters making unlawful settlements in compensation cases has been broken up. The companies who do a legitimate compensation business complain of the unfair competition on the part of a few companies who attempt tc make a profit at the expense of the injured workers. There were five of these unlawful "bargain" settlements made during 1921. They involved an amount totaling approximately $5,000 that the Injured workers had practically agreed to cheat themselves out of. How - ever, the full amount due them under the law will be paid. During the last year and a half, compensation, when due, and medical and hospital expenses were paid without a dispute in approximately 17,000 cases. Where the first payment of compensation is delayed beyond the time provided by law, it is, in most instances, the fault of the employer who failed to report the accident to the Insurance company; or to the injured person who, through ignorance as to the provisions of the law, neglected to report the accident to his employer. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 9 There was a large increase in the number of contested cases during the last year and one-half. During this period 367 cases were heard. During 1919-1920 286 cases were heard; or a total of 653 cases. During the two years previous to the present administration 74 cases were heard by the Commissioner. Before the 1921 session of the legislature it waa very evident to the Department that something must be done to take care of the increase in the number of contested cases coming before the Commissioner for hearing. An amendment to the law was presented to the legislature giving the Commissioner authority to deputize other em - ployes of the Department to hear cases. This amendment prevented the Commissioner being overwhelmed with hearings. It is not uncommon now for the Commissioner and the investigator to hear four cases a day in Omaha, while on the same day the Chief of the Division of Com - pensation in Lincoln will be hearing a case. In April, 1921, the Com - missioner was 51 cases behind. The new amendment went into effect July 28, 1921. Since then the Department has been able to keep up with the cases that pressed for hearings. Each one of these cases consumes a half day; occasionally they run into several half days. This, with seemingly inevitable postponements, would consume nearly every work - ing day of the Commissioner's time, had it not been for the new amendment to the law. Industry was responsible for thirty deaths during 1921, and 15 during the period from January 1, 1922, to July 1, 1922. There were 28 deaths from accidents during 1919 and 50 in 1920. This would make a total of 123 during the three and one-half years of the present administration. The supreme court decision in the Ulaski vs. Morris Packing Com - pany case settled for all time the dispute between the adjusters of the various insurance companies and self-insured corporations, and tho Department, as to the interpretation of paragraph 3 of article 3662, section 112 of the compensation law. This question was in dispute from July, 1920, until the Ulaski decision was handed down. The commis - sioner held that an injured worker was entitled to compensation for temporary total disability from the date of injury up to the time it was determined that the injured person had a permanent injury; after com - pensation had been paid for temporary total disability, then the injured worker was entitled to additional compensation for permanent disability. The Department's interpretation as the rule made in the Ulaski casa was written into the compensation law by the 1921 legislature. This Is very important to the injured workers of the state; its importance being fully understood by the insurance adjusters and the Department of Labor, if not by the workers. The decision in full is printed in another part of this report. After floundering around from pillaf to post for more than two years, the Department, early in the summer of 1921, finally secured </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT permanent headquarters for its branch office in Omaha. The quarters are located on the ground floor of the Douglas County Court House The equipment in the office is the property of the Department of Labor of the state. Contested compensation cases are heard in this office, and whenever more than two cases a day are heard, an idle court room in some other part of the building is secured for the hearing. To this office come all the workers with compensation complaints, wage com- plaints and labor law violation complaints. Fridays and Saturdays are particularly busy days, as the Commissioner is in town. There is no Saturday half holiday for the employes of this Department so long as there is any person in the office in search of information or assistance. When it is understood that half the accidents in the state, or 500 a month, occur in Omaha, the importance of this branch office can be appreciated. UNLIMITED MEDICAL AMENDMENT At the 1921 session of the legislature this Department fathered an amendment to the compensation law, providing for unlimited medical attention to injured workers who might require such attention on account of unusually severe injuries. Some of the employers of the state did not favor this amendment because of a fear that the medical expenso would run so high that insurance companies would increase the rates. Up to July 1, 1922, the new amendment was in effect eleven months; during that time the medical expense exceeded $200 (the limit under the old law) in twenty-four cases. The following table shows the name of the injured person, the class of industry in which the accident occurred, and the amount of medical and hospital expense in each case: W. D. Golike, river construction % 222.00 Alex Brown, building construction 203.50 Edward Self, county road grading 209.05 Neal Brown, harness factory 351.00 August Schade, bakery _... 257.75 J. H. Kaufman, Ford Motor Company 215.50 J. B. Breedlove, furniture store 232.00 Simon Bruce, plumbing industry 365.14 W. R. Nelson, telephone industry 232.75 Herman Warmbier, creamery industry 225.25 Harry Porter, railroad construction work 201.75 R. B. Plummer, Drug Co. truck driver 607.30 Frank Shelton, carpenter work 908.88 J. Nrgkoli, meat packing industry 286.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 11 Before this new amendment went into effect, the insurance com - panies paid the {200 limit and then the injured man paid the remainder if he had it. Otherwise the surgeons and hospitals failed to receive their pay. Sometimes the injured man would be compelled to go without treatment. Other times he would go to the county hospital or to a free medical clinic. There were times, however, when the insurance companies would spend much more than the $200 limit for surgical treatment in an effort to reduce the per cent of loss of use of a member and thus save the cost to them in compensation for loss of such member. The Commissioner is of the opinion that this amendment to the law is just and humane; that the industry should pay compensation for disa - bilities suffered by the workers, but that a few dollars should not stand in the way of restoring the victims of industrial accidents to former normal physical condition. Nebraska surgeons are doing wonderful work in repairing arms, legs and backs. In only two instances have we had injured men who unreasonably refused to submit to surgical treatment. In one of these instances tho injured man, 32 years old with a wife and three children, refused to submit to an operation to repair both legs at the ankles. He preferred to stay on the compensation pay roll for life rather than be repaired and go back to work. In this case the Commissioner made an order directing him to submit to surgical treatment. He refused, and appealed the case to the district court. The district court reversed the order of the Com - missioner and the insurance company appealed the case to the supreme court, where it is now pending. If the supreme court decides the man does not have to submit to reasonable surgical treatment to restore him to somewhere near normal physical condition, it will not be very dis - couraging to the Department, for the reason that we have so few out of so many thousand who refuse treatment. The many who gladly and willingly accept surgical treatment so that they may be repaired and go back to work offsets many, many times the few who balk, so that they may stay on the compensation pay roll indefinitely. J. G. Merriman, coal wagon driver 275.00 Wm. Ruser, street railway employe 249.00 Howard Hopkins, excavation work 465.60 J. L. Lyckholm, newspaper mailer 413.88 Albert Gordon, meat packing industry 271.90 Robert C. Peterson, electrical contract work 220.57 John Davis, building industry 422.40 George Jenkins, truck driver 254.90 Amos Merriman, telephone industry 211.75 H. E. Thompson, automobile painting 318.50 Total $7,621.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT SUPREME COURT DECISIONS It may be of interest to the public to read a statement of the com - pensation cases which have been appealed to the supreme court and the disposition made of them by that body. In the following cases the award of the Commissioner was sustained: 1-3 Mary Rooney vs. City of Omaha. 1-8 William D. Anderson vs. George Kiene and Wm. Busch. 1-34 Addle E. Crowley vs. Lincoln Gas &amp; Electric Light Company. 1-49 John E. Perry vs. W. L. Huffman Automobile Company. 2-55 Jennie M. Blanchard vs. Farmers Grain &amp; Supply Company. 2-26 Western Newspaper Union vs. Arthur Dee. 3-129 Walter Pelecki vs. Morris Packing Company. 3-176 Melvin B. Chadwick vs. Intermountain Railway, Light &amp; Power Co. 4-9 Arthur M. Shivers vs. T. M. Cohagan. 4-32 Frank Ulaski vs. Morris Packing Co. 4-47 Henry Duhrkopf vs. George Bennett. 5-81 Earl E. Sharp vs. Great Western Sugar Company, 2-48 Julia Socha vs. Cudahy Packing Co. 3-34 George Troxcil vs. Morris Packing Co. 1-50 Abel Construction Company vs. William Goodman, sustained and modified. 3-82 F. S. Prince vs. Swift Packing Company. 1-6 Updike Grain Co. vs. Albert Swanson, award increased 3-73 E. W. Poast vs. Merchants Express, award increased. 3-148 Edward L: Simon vs. H. J. Cathroe Co. 4-65 Adolph G. Majowich vs. Morris Packing Company. In the following cases the decisions of the commissioner were re - versed by the supreme court: 1-27 Catherine Cassil vs. Omaha Smelting Company. 3-4 Myrtle E. Christianson vs. Protector Sales Company. 3-36 John P. Ray vs. School District of Lincoln. 3-48 Nettie Mecomber vs. City of North Platte. 3-49 Mary Rogers vs. City of North Platte. 3-53 Jonathan A. Bridger vs. Lincoln Fuel Company. 4-86 William J. Shewan vs. Petrow &amp; Giano. 4-125 William M. Gaskill vs. Jake Kaplan. 3-61 Elizabeth Urak vs. Morris Packing Company. In the cases of John P. Ray, Nettie Mecomber and Mary Rogers, the same principle was involved, the supreme court holding that the state and every governmental agency created by it did not come within the provisions of the act, for the reason that they were not run "for gain or profit." However, these cases are now compensable under the law. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 13 The following compensation cases are pending in the Supreme Court: 3-179 Joseph C. Copeland vs. Max Orkin. 6-12 Carl J. Nosky vs. Farmers Union Co-operative Association. THE ULASKI CASE In April, 1919, the principle involved in the I'laski case first came to the attention of the compensation Department. The paragraph in the law covering the issue in the case is as follows: "For all disability resulting from permanent injury of the following classes, the compensation shall be exclusively as follows:" 3662 sub - div. (3.). Then follows the schedule of compensation allowed for loss of fingers, hands, legs, etc. On April 11, 1919, the Commissioner wrote the following letter to the attorney general's office for an opinion: April 11, 1919. "George W. Ayres, Deputy Attorney General, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Sir: Will you kindly give the Compensation Commissioner an opinion on the following question: Accident occurs on 14th day of November, 1918. Fourth or little finger is injured. Physician for employer endeavors to avoid amputa - tion if possible, and does not remove injured member until February 3, 1919, approximately twelve weeks from the date of the accident. Under the law, this would only leave three week's time for the injured party to recover from the operation and resume his vocation — admittedly too short a time for such a recovery. The question now arises as to whether the specified period of fifteen weeks for the loss of the fourth finger should run from-the date of the injury or from the date of the dismemberment. An early opinion on this question would be greatly appreciated. Yours respectfully, F. A. KENNEDY, Compensation Commissioner." </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT Following is the Attorney General's reply: April 13, 1919. Mr. P. A. Kennedy, Deputy Compensation Commissioner, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Sir: You say: Accident occurs on 14th day of November, 1918. Fourth or little finger is injured. Physician for employer endeavors to avoid am - putation if possible, and does not remove injured member until Febru - ary 3, 1919, approximately twelve weeks from the date of accident. Under the law, this would only leave three weeks' time for the injured party to recover from the operation and resume his vocation — admittedly too Bhort a period of time for such a recovery." You inquire whether the specified period during which under the compensation law an injured employe is entitled to recover compensa - tion for the loss of a finger should begin to run from the date of the injury or from the date of the dismemberment. The question which you propound is not entirely free from doubt. I am of the opinion, however, that the proper course for your office to pursue, unless and until the courts hold otherwise, is to allow compen - sation for such an injury for a period of fifteen weeks, beginning with the date of the dismemberment. To hold otherwise in such a case might lead to consequences not only unexpected but absurd. To illustrate: Suppose for the purpose of the argument that in a case of serious injury to the little finger of an employe, an attempt to save the finger should be prolonged until payment for more than fifteen weeks of temporary total disability had been made and finally the attempt would fail and the finger be amputated. In such case, the party injured would owe the employer something because of overpayment If it should be held that the fifteen weeks for which compensation is al - lowed for the loss of a little finger should begin to run at the time the injury occurred, and not at the time of the actual dismemberment. In other words, the party injured would, so far as the "Workmen's Com - pensation law" is concerned, receive less compensation because of the loss of his finger than he would receive if it were saved. This, I take it, cannot have been the legislative intent. Yours very truly. CLARENCE A. DAVIS, Attorney General. By GEO. W. AYRES, Deputy Attorney General. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 15 From this period until the decision of the supreme court was handed down, on October 14, 1921, the interpretation of the above mentioned paragraph was continually in dispute between the adjusters of insurance companies and self insured employers and the compensation Department. Sometimes the insurance companies paid according to the interpretation of the law placed on it by the Attorney General's office but always under protest. They never seemed anxious to go to the supreme court for a decision. Finally the Ulaski vs. Morris Packing Company case was appealed from the Commissioner's award to the district court and then to the supreme court. When the case reached the supreme court, Kennedy, Holland, DeLacy &amp; McLaughlin of Omaha appeared as friends of the court to plead for the insurance companies interpretation of the law. On the other hand Lester L. Dunn of the Department of Labor, and Jackson C. Chase, of the Attorney General's office, appeared as friends of the court on behalf of the Compensation Commissioner. Following is the decision of the supreme court in full: ULASAKI V. MORRIS &amp; COMPANY (No. 22191) (Supreme Court of Nebraska. October 14, 1921). (Syllabus by the Court) 1. Master and servant 418(6) — District court's finding on conflicting evidence in compensation case conclusive. "Where the district court in workmen's compensation case finds on substantially conflicting evidence, that the employe was injured in a particular manner, such finding of fact will not be reversed on appeal unless clearly wrong." Swift and Company vs. Prince, 106 Neb.— 183 N. W. 55 2. Master and servant 387 — Compensation allowable for loss of finger stated. Where the injured employe suffered 25 per cent partial permanent loss of the normal use of his second or middle finger of his right hand, the extent of the injury not being ascertainable until 10 weeks after the accident, then he is entitled, under Rev. St. 1913, 3662, as amended by Laws 1917, c. 85, to compensation for the period of 7 1-2 weeks, at $15 a week, commencing, not with the day of the accident, but with the day when the extent of the injury is ascertainable, and in addition is entitled to $15 a week for 10 weeks. 3. Witnesses 28(1)— Expert only entitled to statutory fee. "One testifying as an expert on a subject requiring special knowl - edge and skill, in the absence of a special contract, is entitled only to the statutory fee." Main vs. Sherman County, 74 Nebraska. 155, 103 N. W. 1038. (Additional Syllabus by Editorial Staff) 4. Master and servant 420 — Attorney's fee allowed compensation claimant held reasonable. Seventy-five dollars, allowed compensation claimant by district </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT court on appeal, held a reasonable attorney's fee provided for under Rev. St. 1913, 3666, as amended by laws 1917, c. 85, and Laws 1919, c. 91. Appeal from District Court, Douglas County; Wakeley, Judge. Application by Frank Ulaski to the Compensation Commissioner for an award under the Workmen's Compensation Act, opposed by Morris &amp; Company, employers, in which an award was made and upheld and increased on appeal to the District Court, and the defendant appeals. Modified and affirmed. James C. Kinsler of Omaha, for appellant. A. H. Bigelow of Omaha, for appellee. Heard before Morrissey, C. J. and Aldrich, Day, Dean, Flansburg, and Rose, J. J. Aldrich, J. On September 11, 1920, Frank Ulaski, an employe of de - fendant, was injured while in the course of his employment. He was what is called a "beef lugger." On that day he says that a beef fell from an overhead rail, and in catching it a bone sliver was forced into the first joint of the middle finger of the right hand. The defendant's physician administered some iodine and bandaged the finger and he hart dally dressings at the doctor's office. In the meantime an infection developed and it became necessary to open the wound. Finally, he was sent home, where he stayed during the succeeding week and two days. He was treated daily by the company physician and his finger was re - peatedly lanced. He returned on September 29, under direction of tha company's physician, and was assigned a lighter task in which he did not have to use the injured finger. On October 1, he was called to the office and given a check for 95 to cover his compensation for two days, the 27th and 28th of Sep - tember, the first week being exempted by law. He signed a release; and then returned to work and was required to do work that necessitated the use of his finger. He told the foreman he could not do that work because of his sore finger. An altercation ensued and he was perman - ently discharged. This discharge occurred about two hours after he had signed the release, and, notwithstanding his discharge, he was treated by the company physician for several days afterwards. Later while his finger was still swollen and open, the company physician refused him further treatment. It was on October 7, that he was refused further com - pensation, and then he went to the compensation commissioner, who informed the companys claim agent and told him that Ulaski was at that time entitled to a week's compensation. Ulaski then went to the com - pany's office and was paid the sum of $15 and was required to sign two releases. His finger was at that time still sore and swollen. He returned to the defendant company on November 16, seeking work. The de - fendant company had not at that time begun to lay off men, although they refused him employment. It is claimed that plaintiff was not yet in condition to work and was not able to use the knife. Even at thia time his finger was in such condition that he was unable to work and was forced to quit after shoveling coal for a few hours. January fol - lowing he applied for compensation, was awarded a hearing and was allowed additional compensation. Upon a hearing in the district court being had, the trial court among other things held that — "The plaintiff have and recover from the defendant company, in addition to the sum already paid, compensation at the rate of $15 per week for a period of 17 1-2 weeks, all of which is now due and payablo forthwith ; that the defendant company be and it is hereby ordered to pay - to plaintiff the sum of $75 for attorney's fee in this court, and to pay </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 17 to the plaintiff for expert witness fees charged as costs the sum of $50, and to pay into court the costs of this suit; that, unless said payments are made forthwith, the defendants shall also pay 50 per cent of the said compensation for 17 1-2 weeks as the statutory waiting time." From the judgment so rendered the defendant appealed. (1) In Swift &amp; Co. vs. Prince, 106 Neb.— 183 N. W. 557, the court said: "The trial court saw the witnesses and heard their testimony, and its findings, upon conflicting evidence, should not be disturbed. It is the rule in cases of this kind that finding of fact, supported by sufficient evi - dence, or findings of fact on substantial conflicting evidence, will not be reversed unless clearly wrong." The rule announced in the Prince Case is applicable to the fact* before us and we adhere thereto. The finding of fact is amply supported by the record. The court was justified in allowing Ulaski 10 weeks for total disability in addition to the week and two days formerly allowed by the court under the finding of fj^3t. (2) The record shows conclusively that plaintiff was allowed 10 week's compensation for time lost dating from October 7, 1920. After he had rested and had had time to make improvement it was further found that he had lost 25 per cent of the normal use of his injured finger. His loss altogether, then, was 10 weeks for total disability and 7 1-2 weeks for permanent partial loss of the finger, making a total loss of time of 17 1-2 weeks at $15.00 a week, as provided by statute. The defendant refused to pay the award as made by the Compensation Commissioner. Then the case was tried in he district court and the decision of the Compensation Commissioner affirmed. As appears of record there was total disability of 10 weeks, and ac - cording to the spirit and intent of the statute the plaintiff was entitled to a recovery of $15 a week pending that time, and to a permanent partial disability for a period of 7 1-2 weeks. This in the aggregate con - stitutes the total loss of the plaintiff for the entire time of the injury ( and we concur in the finding of the court in this regard as it is simply sustained by the record. This case is not unlike the principle found In Addison vs. Wood Co. 207 Mich. 319, 174 N. W. 149. The principles of the statute as applied to this case are fully discussed and the application of the law which we follow is made. We adhere to the principle of law therein involved. It is in point in the instant case. We believe the court was right in allowing a total disability for a period of 10 weeks and was correct in allowing permanent partial disability at the rate of $15 a week. The requirements of the statute have been amply complied with and the court has met the situation as shown in plaintiff's case. We are not unmindful of the fact that in the discussion and con - clusion of the instant case there are cases holding a different principle and conclusion from what we have arrived at, but at the same time we believe that our conclusion has the support of law and does ample justice to the parties under these facts. (4) On the question of attorney's fees, section 3666, Rev. St. 1913, as amended by chapter 85, Laws 1917, and chapter 91, Laws 1919, provides as follows: "Whenever the employer refuses payment, or when the employer neglects to pay compensation for thirty days after injury, and proceedings are had before the Compensation Commissioner, a reasonable attorney's </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT fee shall be allowed the employe by the court in the event the employer appeals from the award of the commissioner and fails to obtain any re - duction in the amount of such award, the appellate court shall in like manner allow the plaintiff a reasonabe sum as attorney's fees for the appellate proceedings." The $75 so allowed by the trial judge is correct and just and we affirm it. It follows that defendant must pay the costs of this suit. (3) There is, however, no provision in the law for the payment of expert witness fees. The expert witnesses are therefore allowed the usual and lawful witness fee, and no more. Main vs. Sherman County, 74 Neb. 155, 103 N. W. 1038. The judgment of the district court is affirmed except as modified herein. It is ordered that the court disallow the expert witness fees in the amount of $50, and that the expert witness recover only the usual and lawful witness fees; and that defendant receive credit for one and one-third week's compensation which defendant has already paid on plaintiff's claim. It is further ordered that defendant pay an attorney fee for plaintiff, as costs, in this court, in the sum of $100. Affirmed as modified. A QUESTIONNAIRE ON THE COMPENSATION LAW A group of Ohio manufacturers and employers called the "Impartial Committee on Workmen's Compensation" sent this Department a ques - tionnaire on the administration of the Compensation Law. The questions asked and answered may be of interest to the employes p*" 1 — orkers of Nebraska. For that reason the questionnaire is printed in full as follows: REGULATION OF INSURANCE CARRIERS 1. What reserves are required? Workmen's Compensation Insur - ance which is generally written for a period of one year, carries a reserve of 50 per cent of the net amount of premiums in force. If by chance a policy is written for a period of more than one year, the amount set aside as a reserve would be the pro rata amount unearned. In addition to the said reserve as explained, a special reserve is required to be main - tained by the Workmen's Compensation Companies for unpaid compen - sation losses, which is arrived at by using Schedule) "P," which is found in the Annual Statement blanks adopted by the National Convention ot Insurance Commissioners. This latter reserve is a computation based upon the company's own experience. 2. What provisions do you have regarding the solvency of a carrier? The solvency of a Compensation Insurance Company is recognized when the said company has over and above all liabilities, a workable surplus which is determined by the Insurance Department of this State, from which information is transferred to our department. 3. Do you use the standard reserve law? The reserves required to be maintained by the State of Nebraska are those which are usually termed standard, with the addition of Schedule "P" as explained above, which is a ruling of the Insurance Department of this State. 4. If not, what is in practice? Need not be answered. 5. How do you regulate the operation of private insurance carriers? The same careful attention that is given to the stock or other companies. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 19 CLAIM ADJUSTMENT. 1. How do you regulate claim adjustment? We see that they are made in conformity with the law. 2. What safeguards are provided which protect the employe against undue delay in the payment of claims by Insurance carriers? Fifty per cent penalty may be added by the Commissioner or the Court. 3. What per cen( of claims for compensation were paid when due for the years 1919, 1920 and 1921, divided among stock, mutual, self - insurer, State Fund, reciprocals? Percentage cannot be given. During 1919 there were a large number of claims where payments were delayed among all companies and self-insured. During 1920-21 one self-insurer had a number of delayed claims. During 1920-1921 the employers were responsible for delayed payments by insurance companies due to their failure to report accidents. 4. Likewise, what per cent of compensation claims were contro - verted according to the different types of carriers or claimant for the above period? Total number of accidents 36,305. Contested Cases: Stock companies, 329; self-insured, 286; Mutual, 34; Reciprocal, 4. Total controverted cases, 653. 5. Likewise, what per cent of those controverted were appealed ta the courts during the same period? One hundred and fifty-eight cases were appealed. 6. Can the license to practice workmen's compensation insurance be revoked by the Industrial Commission or Insurance Commission for failure to pay compensation claims promptly? Insurance Commissioner or Compensation Commissioner. 7. Do you provide a penalty for unnecessarily delaying compensa - tion payments? Yes; 50 per cent added. 8. What percentage of claims are heard before a referee or a board? All cases heard by the Commissioner, or an assistant deputized by the Commissioner. 9. What percentage of claims are appealed from the referee or board to the lower court? See question five. 10. What per cent to the higher court? Approximately 5 per cent. 11. What percentage of cases are won by (a). Employe? (b). Compromise? (c). Carrier? A. 72 per cent; B. 8 per cent; C. 20 per cent. 12. What type carrier controverts the most claims (a). Stock? (b.) Reciprocal? (c.) Mutual? (d.) Self-insurer? (e). State Fund? See question number 4. 13. What are the principle reasons for controversies? The question of liability. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT COMPENSATION 1. What is the maximum and minimum amount of compensation payable under your Act? $15.00 maximum, $4.50 minimum. 2. What is the maximum and minimum fatal award? |5,400; in - cluding $150.00 burial benefit; minimum, depending on the degree of dependency. 3. What is the percentage of wages? 66 2-3 per cent of the wages. 4. What is the waiting period? Seven days, where disability is for a period of less than six weeks. Six weeks or more no waiting period. 5. When is compensation payable? Compensation is payable on the eighth calendar day. 6. Do you require the carrier to notify you when compensation pay - ment was started? Yes, by periodical reports. 7. What police power is the commission clothed with to enforce this? Power to revoke license for failure to comply with rules ol commission. 8. Do you require the carrier to notify the commission when com - pensation has been terminated? We do. 9. How can you enforce this requirement? See No. 7. 10. Do you check over each case to determine that the proper amount of compensation has been paid? We do. 11. How long after the date of injury can the claim be re-opened after closed? One year after last payment of compensation. 12. Upon what evidence is the adjudication of claims made? On the evidence of doctors. 13. Can the employer be sued at common law if (a) He fails to abide by the order of the commission? (b) Willfully negligent? (c) If he violates the safety laws? (d) If he fails to insure his risk? (a) Sue on the commissioner's award and execute on judgment, (b) No. (c) Never tested by the supreme court, (d) Yes. 14. What defenses remain for the employer under such circum - stances? (a) None, (b) Cannot be sued, (c) Defenses not allowed: "That the employe was negligent, unless and except it shall also appear that such negligence was willful, or that the employe was in the state of intoxication; (b) that the injury was caused by the negligence of a fellow employe; (c) that the employe had assumed the risk inherent in, or incidental to, or arising from the failure of the employer to pro - vide and maintain safe premises and suitable applicancies." (d) never been tested by the supreme court. 15. Do you require every employer to show that he has secured the payment of compensation for his injured employes? No: we require the Self-insured or the insurance company to make the showing. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 21 EXPENSES 1. If you have a State Fund, how are the expenses borne? No State Fund. 2. Does the State Fund pay taxes? If so, how much? No. 3. What is the expense ratio to the amount of premiums collected? See No. 1. 4. How are the administrative expenses borne? General funds of state. 5. Does the State Fund regulate the acquisition expense of the in - surance carriers? No state fund. 6. Are the carriers required to spend the minimum amount for accident prevention work? No requirement. 7. If a medical examination is authorized by the Industrial Com - mission to determine the merits of the claim which has been contro - verted, who ultimately pays the cost of such an examination and how much is usually paid? Self-insurer or insurance company pays for exam - inations. Usual charge $5.00. 8. What provision do you have relating to or providing for a catas - trophe fund? No provisions. 9. What provision do you have for the payment of a subsequent injury resulting in a permanent total disability? Compensation paid only for subsequent injury. 10. Does the insurance carrier or employer pay for the second injury and a special fund to care for the pension? Self-insurer and insurance company pay for subsequent injury. RATING SYSTEM 1. Are the Workmen's Compensation rates regulated by the State? No. 2. Are your rates regulated as to adequacy and reasonableness or adequacy alone? See regulated. 3. Does your rating system provide for merit rating including schedule and experience? No rating, system. 4. What disadvantages do you believe result from a merit rating system? None. 5. What is your opinion on the advantages of a merit rating system? Should be encouraged. 6. If you do not have a merit rating system, what system of rating is practiced? Insurance companies have merit rating system. 7. If a State Fund is operated, is its basis of rating the same as the insurance carriers? No State Fund. 8. If not, what is the advantage to the State Fund? No State Fund. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT ADMINISTRATION 1. How many Commisioners do you have? One. (a) What is the salary of the Chairman? $5,000 per year. (b)f What is the salary of the members? No members. 2. For how long are the members appointed? Commissioner ap - pointed for two years. 3. Of what does the membership of the commission consist? The Commissioner. 4. Who appoints the Commissioner? The Governor. 5. Do you have a state fund manager? No. 6. How is the state fund manager appointed? No manager. 7. How can this amount be exceeded? No limit. 8. What is the salary paid to him? No manager. 9. Is the state fund operated independently from the commission? No State Fund? 10. What jurisdiction does the Industrial Commission have over the fund? No fund. 11. Has your state department undergone any re-organization within the last four years ? Complete re-organization of the Department in 1919. 12. How is the Workmen's Compensation Act administered since the re-organization? System of keeping records and respsonsibility centralized. 13. How was the Workmen's Compensation Act administered before the re-organization? We would rather not answer that question. 14. What advantages have accrued from the re-organization? The office has been systematized and a closer supervision of the cases maintained. ACCIDENT PREVENTION 1. Do the carriers do any accident prevention work for their policy holders? Yes. 2. Which of the stock, mutual, self-insurer, reciprocal or state fund do the most effective work? Stock companies. 3. Do the carriers make inspections of plants? Yes. 4. How often are these inspections made? Depends upon the hazard. 5. Are the recomendations generally filed by these inspectors intel - ligent ones? Yes. 6. Are the inspectors mechanical engineers? Mostly. 7. If not, what type of men usually are employed? Practical men. 8. What are the powers of the Commission or the Insurance Com - missioner with regard to enforcing accident prevent work? Covered by statute. 9. What is the effect of this work? Redaction of hazard and main - tainence of safer premises. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 23 10. Does the Industrial Commission, directly, do any accident pre - vention work? Yes. 11. Do you require every accident to be recorded to you? Every accident requiring medical aid. MEDICAL 1. Does your law provide for the establishment of first aid room where there are one hundred or more employes? No. 2. What is the type medical attention given by the insurance car - riers? Usually first class. 3. Is the employe compelled to accept medical treatment provided for by the employer or carrier? Yes, except cases of dismemberment and major surgical operations. 4. Can the employe choose his own physician? If he pays the expense himself. 5. Do the carriers employ reputable and competent men? Yes. 6. Is there a limitation to the amount that can be expended for medical treatment? No. 7. How can this amount ze exceeded? No limit. 8. Do the insurance carriers exceed this amount when necessary or does the commission have to place an order against them to furnish additional treatment? No limit. 9. Do the insurance carriers provide any unusual medical service? When the medical was limited, they did. 10. What type clinics and hospitals do the carriers conduct? None. 11. What police power is given the commission to enforce proper and equitable medical attention? None necessary. 12. To what extent do the insurance carriers rehabilitate the indus - trial cripple? No rehabilitation on the part of the insurance company or Self-insurer. Rehabilitation inaugurated in 1921 by government and State Fund in connection with the State University, under the direction of the State Board of Vocatonal education and the State Department of Labor. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT HEARINGS BY THE COMMISSIONER Following is a brief story of each of the 653 cases heard by the Commissioner during the years 1921 and up to July 1, 1922: DOCKET TWO 2-7: David Blumenthal vs. Thomas Z. Waite, Omaha (Insurance Carrier: Raw Amsterdam Casualty Co.) On October 3rd, 1918, while in the employ of plaintiff, as a butcher, defendant strained the ligaments of his right side while lifting a case of meat. Compensation was paid until January 25, 1919. A petition was filed to have the Commissioner determine what, if any, further com - pensation was coming to the defendant. On November 12, 1920, plain - tiff asked that case be dismissed. DOCKET THREE 3-107: J. P. Burnette vs. Nebraska Cement Company, Superior. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corp.) On October 8, 1919, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintifi while stepping over to look at a clutch foot, slipped and fell on a moving cog wheel and drive shaft of stoker. His left leg and abdomen and left ankle were injured. A hearing was had on January 25, 1921, and on reports of two doctors it was held that plaintiff had suffered 50% of the loss of use of left leg. He was allowed 107 Vt weeks compensation at the rate of $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expenses. 3-108: Irene Murphy vs. City of Omaha. On July 23, 1919, Frank Murphy, husband of plaintiff, died as the result of a gunshot wound received while attempting to arrest Jud Tobias, July 16, 1919. A petition was filed praying for compensation under the Nebraska Workmen's compensation law. On November 30, 1921, the case was dismissed at the request of plaintiff, because of the Supreme Court decision in the case of J. Rooney vs. City of Omaha. 3-127: Jack Branaugh vs. Ensign Omnibus A Transfer Company, Lin - coln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corp.) On August 2, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company a truck upset and plaintiff cut his foot and shin and bruised his arm. A petition was filed September S, 1920. Subsequent thereto and previous to a hearing, compensation was paid and the case dismissed. 3-129: Walter Peleckl vs. Morris Packing Company, Omaha, On July 29, 1920, -while in the employ of the defendant company, plaintiff cut the nerves and ligaments in thumb of left hand. A final settlement receipt was taken from plaintiff on September 3, 1920 and |60 paid in compensation. September 10, 1920, a petition was filed. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 25 The company doctor testified that he treated the injured man 55 times at the plant first aid station after he signed the final receipt on September 3. A hearing was had on December 7, 1920. and compensation was al - lowed from date of accident, July 29, 1920, until disability shall have ended, with the 50% penalty for delayed payments of compensation. Appealed. District and supreme court affirmed the decision of the com - missioner. 3-133: U. S. F. &amp; G. vs. Ocean Accident and Guarantee Cora, and Mrs. Mary E. South, Lincoln. (Insurance Currier: C. S. F. &amp; G. and Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Co) On April 10, 1920, while in the employ of N. R. Soucie, sub-con - tractor, as a laborer, William South was smothered to death in a ditch. The U. S. F. &amp; G. paid compensation, but in September fhis company filed a petition praying that the commissioner hold the Ocean Acci - dent and Guarantee Company liable for compensation. A hearing was had March 8, 1921, and it was then stipulated that the U. S. F. &amp; G. pay the compensation and later have the district court determine which company was liable. 3-138: Alonzo D. Baitey vs. Ft. A. Heacock Company, Falls City Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Ca smalt 7 Co.) On April 28, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a bricklayer, plaintiff stumbled over a loose board in attempting to step over a belt and sprained his knee. A petition was filed and a hearing had on March 23, 1921. Compensation was allowed for three weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense. 3-1-'O: Louis O. Medley vs. Condon A Bolen, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: New Amsterdam Casualty Co.) On October 15, 1919, while in the employ of defendant company as a steam shovel man, plaintiff alleged he injured his back and spine. After the petition and answer were filed the case was set for hearing five different times between February 18, 1921, and July 8. 1921. The plaintiff did not show up at any of the hearings. On September 12, 1921, the attorney for plaintiff notified the department that he could not locate the plaintiff, and the case was dismissed. 3-147: Brandeis Investment Co. vs. Hazel Hoden, Omaha. i Insurance carrier: London Guarantee and Accident C&gt; On July 7, 1919, while in the employ of plaintiff company as an elevator operator, defendant's right foot was caught between elevator and floor and crushed, causing a compound fracture of the leg above the ankle. Compensation was paid for thirty-nine weeks, when plain - tiff filed a petition to have a hearing to determine the disability result - ing from the accident. A hearing was had on February 10, 1921, and compensation for 30 per cent of the loss of use of the foot was allowed being 37J weeks at $8.40 each week, in addition to what had been paid, together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case appealed. Later case dismissed and compensation paid. 3-149: Laura Still mock vs. Skinner Packing Company, Omaha. On May 17, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plain - tiff suffered an injury to her left foot, caused by a door falling on it. Compensation of $69.96 and medical expense of $12.00 was paid. In </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT October a petition was filed asking for further compensation. A hear - ing was had November 19, 1920, when two physicians stated that there was no disability. Attorney for plaintiff requested that further ex - aminations be made 30 days hence. On January 5, 1921 one doctor made a further examination and again reported no disability. Case dismissed. 3-157: Paul H. Cole vs. Nebraska Printing Company, Lincoln. On October 10, 1918, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff broke his left ankle, dislocated his shoulder, and in - jured his spine. Compensation was paid from October 10, 1918, until March 9, 191,9. A petition was filed October 28. 1920, praying for addi - tional compensation. After the petition was filed and before the case was heard a settlement for $350.00 was agreed upon between the injured man and the insurance adjuster, with the approval of the Commissioner, and the case was dismissed. 3-158: Madge L. Feder vs. W. I. Assenmacher Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Currier: Ocean Accident and (iunrantee Corp.) On March 1, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, as foreman, Frank L. Feder, deceased, was struck on the head by a quarter of a brick. He worked until April 1, 1920, but suffered head - aches from day of accident. Quit work on April 1; was operated on, September 21, at Mayo hospital, Rochester, Minnesota, and died Sep - tember 22. A hearing was had March 2, 1921, and compensation al - lowed his widow for 350 weeks at $15.00 each week together with $150 funeral benefit, and medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. The case was appealed June 2, 1921; a lump sum setlement for $2,800 was agreed to by the parties at interest and the same was approved by the Commissioner. 3-160: Roy McGinnis vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. On June 12, 1920, while employed by defendant company, plaintiff strained his back while lifting a box of meat. From date of injury to date of hearing November 17, 1920. plaintiff showed loss of six weeks time from work. Compensation was allowed for six weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical expenses of $4.00 and doctor bill of $2.50. 3-161: William C. Fritz vs. Vaughn Construction Company, Omaha (Iiisurnnce Carrier: Maryland Casualty Co.) On August 14, 1919, while in the employ of defendant company as a carpenter, plaintiff fell from a ladder and broke his left wrist. Com - pensation was paid for eight weeks at $15.00 each week. On No - vember 3, 1920, plaintiff filed a petition praying for additional com - pensation for per cent of loss of use of hand. Before a hearing was had, the insurance company paid $266.25 for per cent of loss of use of the hand, and the case was dismissed. 3-162: Charles Cathery vs. Swift S. Company, Omaha. On August 19, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff suffered a rupture while lifting heavy timber. Company doctor treated plaintiff for nine weeks more or less and then plaintiff was examined by another physician who told him he had a hernia. Com- ilnsunince Carrier: Travelers Inmirnnrp Company. ) </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 27 pany doctor said he offered to operate but plaintiff was not inclined to accept it or did not understand. A petition was filed November 1, 1920, and a hearing was had February 10, 1921. Compensation was al - lowed for nine weeks from date of accident at {15.00 each week together with 50% penalty for delayed payments of compensation for that period; plaintiff was also ordered to submit himself for an operation within thirty days from the date of the award, the same to be paid for by defendant, together with $15.00 compensation each week, during dis - ability caused by such operation. 3-166: Willis E. Phillips vs. George Gorges, sub-contractor, and Hugh Murphy Construction Company, Fremont. On May 3, 1920, while in the employ of defendants as a laborer, plaintiff received a blow from the handle of a scraper across the left abdomen, which disabled him for three weeks and four days. When the hearing was had, on March 17, 1921, plaintiff was in Creston, Iowa, without means to pay his expenses to the hearing, submitting an affi - davit to that effect. The hearing proceeded and compensation was al - lowed for two weeks and four days at $12.00 per week, together with the 50% penalty for waiting time also medical expense as provided by law. 3-167: S. W. Brown vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Somewhere between the 2nd and 23rd day of September, 1920, while employed as a sheep butcher, plaintiff alleged that he injured the first finger of his right hand. A petition was filed November 13, 1920, at the Omaha branch office and on July 14, 1921, another petition was filed from Sioux City, Iowa. The case was set for hearing three times but plaintiff did not show up. On May 27, 1922, the case was dismissed. 3-169: A. L. McCandless vs. Sample Hart Motor Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident ( On October 7, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a Ford mechanic, plaintiff strained himself while lifting Ford truck bodies. Compensation was paid for one week and then stopped. A hearing was had on February 16, 1921, and compensation allowed at $15.00 each week from October 12, 1920, until November 29, 1920, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 3-170: George Johnson vs. Beddeo Clothing Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On April 22, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a collector, plaintiff fractured his left ankle. A petition was filed No - vember 29, 1920, praying for compensation and medical and hospital treatment. After the petition and answer were filed it was agreed that compensation for $245.00 and medical and hospital expenses of $136.25 be paid. This was approved by the Commissioner and case dis - missed. 3-171: William Perkins vs. John Cleveland, Holt County. Plaintiff alleged that he was injured November 25, 1919, while work - ing with a haybaler. A petition was filed for compensation and re - peated requests were made to the plaintiff as to when he would prefer to have the case heard. No reply was ever received from him and the case was dismissed. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 3-172: John Lawlor v*. Union Stock Yards Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On October 8, 1920, while employed as a laborer by defendant, plain - till injured two fingers of his left hand by having them caught between a wagon and a gate. Compensation was paid for two weeks and one day when a final receipt was taken. On December 1, 1920, a petition was filed asking for further compensation. A hearing was had February 8, 1921, and compensation was allowed for two additional weeks at $15.00 each week. 3-173: Alfred O. Johnson vs. James Stewart Construction Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co. On September 9, 1920, while employed by defendant company, plain - tiff was struck near the left eye with a red hot rivet, knocking his head Taack against a post. Compensation was paid for a period and then stopped. A petition was filed and a hearing had on April 15, 1921. Further compensation was allowed and plaintiff ordered to submit him - self for treatment to restore him to former condition. The case was appealed. District court allowed compensation for 54^ weeks, at $15.00 each week, and $200 medical expenses. 3-174: John Smith vs. American Smelting &amp; Refining Company, Omaha. On November 5, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff alleged that he sprained his ankle, foot and leg when he slip - ped from the bottom of a metal pot. Petition was filed December 3, 1920, and a hearing day set for February 16, 1921. Plaintiff did not show up at the hearing and the case was continued. Another hearing: day was set for May 3, 1921, and again plaintiff did not make an ap - pearance. Case was dismissed without prejudice. 3-175: Herbert Giles vs. Martin &amp; Day, Lincoln. On May 14, 1920, while in the employ of defendant firm as a lab - orer, plaintiff injured his back, broke three ribs and suffered a fracture - dislocation of the right ankle. Compensation in the sum of $450.00 was paid and then stopped. A hearing was had on January 13, 1921, and com - pensation was allowed for 30 additional weeks from October 21, 1920, at $15.00 each week. 3-176: Melvin B. Chadwick vs. Intermountain Railway Light and Power Company, Holdrege. IIiiHiirance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Cuinpany On June 28, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company. Orin S. Eidson, grandson of plaintiff, was electrocuted. Compensation was denied. A petition was filed and on July 15, 1921, a hearing was held at Omaha. Depositions were read from witnesses and it was shown the deceased was raised by the grandfather from the time he was a year and one-half old until he grew to manhood; that the boy had con - tributed to the support of the grandfather, before and after entering the service during the war; that he had made his war insurance payable to the grandfather; that the grandfather actually received the insurance at the time of the hearing; that the grandfather was depending on the boy for his future support. The Commissioner allowed the grandfather the full amount of compensation, namely $15.00 each week for 350 ( InsuraiM v GftfYtsf : Lund on (■uurnntre &amp; Are: dent Co ) </seg>
            <seg id="p029">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 29 weeks, $150.00 burial benefit and medical expense as provided by law. Case appealed. Sustained by the district and supreme courts. 3-177: Margaret Anderson vs. Armour &amp; Company, Omaha. On July 23, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plain - tiff while employed as a packer in the shipping department in the ham house, ruptured her left side. A petition was filed December 6, 1920. A hearing was had February 9, 1921. and compensation was allowed for 11% weeks at $13.44 each week; $75 doctor bill for operation, medi - cine and hospital expense, as provided by law. Case appealed. Sus - tained by district court, penalty added. 3-178: Charley Balderston vs. Haigler Equity Exchange, Haigler, Neb. On July 27. 1920, while in the employ of defendant as manager of elevator at Haigler, plaintiff bruised his right hand in a back fire of an automobile while cranking it. Infection set in and as a result plain - tiff lost his ring finger, 85 per cent of his second finger and 25 per cent of the little finger. A hearing was had at Haigler and compensa - tion allowed^ in the amount of $738.75 together with medical and hos - pital expense as provided by law. Case appealed. District court al - lowed 62%weeks at $15.00 each week and $200 medical expense. 3-179: Joseph C. Copeland vs. Max Orkin, Omaha In April, 1920, while in the employ of defendant, Joseph C. Cope - land, plaintiff, now deceased, received an injury, resulting in hernia. He was operated on for hernia August 4, 1920, and died December 17, 1920. A petition was filed December 8, 1920, to recover compensation. A hearing was had May 20, and June 20. 1921, and compensation was al - lowed his widow for 350 weeks at $15.00 each week, $150.00 burial bene - fit and medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case ap - pealed. District court sustained the commissioner. Appealed to su - preme court. 3-180: Sam Way vs. Swift &amp; Company, Lincoln. On August 12, 1920, while employed by defendant, plaintiff alleged that he was injured by slipping on a step ladder while working on a boiler. He did not lose a day's work after the accident. In November he was discharged from his job. (Plaintiff stated that he would not have filed a petition if he had not been discharged.) Doctor's bill was $6.00. Compensation was denied and case dismissed. 3-181 : Roberts &amp; Schaefer Construction Company vs. Arthur T. Hull, Omaha. On April 11, 1918, while in the employ of plaintiff company as a carpenter, defendant fell 21 feet striking his right leg on the railroad track, crushing ankle and foot, resulting in amputation below the knee, July 29, 1918. After a hearing, Former Commissioner Norman allowed compensation for a total of 175 weeks, less 37 weeks paid up to De - cember 26, 1918. This left 138 weeks compensation, at $12.00 each week, to be paid from December 26, 1918. The insurance company arbitrarily discontinued paying compensation in the latter part of the year 1920, and on December 10, 1920, filed a petition asking for modi - fication of the award of Commissioner Norman. After a hearing the Iuioranre Carrier: London (iuaranttv anil AwiiltMit Co.) I Insurance Carrier: Lonclun Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL, REPORT Commissioner declined to disturb the previous award, and, further, al - lowed the 50% penalty for delayed compensation from the last pay - ment made up to the date of this award. Case appealed. Later set - tled for $1,503.00. 3-182: Irene McFiilen vs. National Biscuit Company, Kansas City, Mo, A petition was filed in this case for compensation for the death of plaintiff's husband, killed while employed as a salesman for defendant company. Before the date of hearing, plaintiff requested that case be dismissed. 3-183: Mary and Samuel Ream vs. William Dudley, Grand Island, (Insurance Carrier: Employers Liability Assurance Corp.) On June 22, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as clothes cleaner, Vern Ream, 19 year old son of plaintiff, was asphyxiated by the fumes of gases used in his work. A petition was filed claiming partial dependency of said Vern Ream, deceased. A hearing was had on March 29. 1921, at Grand Island, and compensation allowed for 350 weeks at $6.66 each week, $150 burial expense and hospital and medi - cal expense as provided by law. Case appealed. Later settled for $1,350.00. 3-184: Alfred Caniglia vs. John S. Harrington, Omaha On May 28, 1919, while in the employ of defendant, plaintiff broke his right leg above the ankle in a sewer ditch while employed as a laborer. Compensation was paid up to December 7, 1920. A petition was filed and a hearing had on February 16, 1921. Compensation was allowed for 40% loss of use of the foot, being 50 weeks at $12.00 each week, in addition to what had already been paid and medical and hospital expenses provided by law. 3-185: Harold Conn vs. Nebraska Cement Company, Superior. I Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) On July 28, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a mix tender, plaintiff ran into a bed of hot cinders with his bare feet after a swim in a cooling pool on company's premises during working hours. It was shown that it was the practice of the night men to go into this pool for a dip at spare moments during working hours. A petition was filed and a hearing had on March 24, 1921. Compensation was allowed for eight weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 3-186: Wm. Kirkpatrick vs. Charles Derr, Lincoln I Insurance Carrier: Maryland Casualty Co.) On April 10, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as a clerk and repair man, plaintiff strained his hands and arms in lifting a stove. Compensation was paid by the insurance company for 32 weeks, and then discontinued. A petition was filed December 14, 1920, and a hear - ing had on January 12, 1921. Treatments were ordered given plaintiff for five weeks in an effort to restore him to his former normal physical condition. A further hearing was had on March 9, 1921, and compen - sation was allowed until disability ends at $15.00 each week. Case was appealed. Commissioner sustained by the district and supreme courts. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 3-187: William H. Wicman vt. Patriot Motors Company, Lincoln. I Insurance Carrier: Continental Casualty Co.) On October 12, 1920, while in the employ of the Patriot Motors Company running a gander, plaintiff caught the index finger of his left hand between board and sander, lacerating first two joints, and fracturing the bone in the distal phalange. A hearing was had on January 11, 1921, and the Commissioner allowed compensation at the rate of $15.00 a week for 10% weeks for 30% loss of use of finger, plus hospital and medical expense; together with 50% penalty for delayed payments of compensation. 3-188: Willoughby C. Howard vs. General Supply Company, Lincoln. On August 8, 1920, while in tne employ of defendant company, plain - tiff was injured by stepping on a nail. Petition was filed for a hearing, but before an answer was filed the parties agreed upon a settlement in accordance with the compensation law. The case was dismissed. 3-189: Mrs. Stella Peterson vs. Delavan Hotel, Lincoln. On October 6, 1920, while in the employ of the Delavan Hotel as a maid, plaintiff fell down stairs, injuring her back. A hearing was had on January 12, 1921, and it was shown by canceled wage check that plaintiff had been paid for five weeks and four days labor up to and in - cluding October 21. Compensation was allowed for period from October 21, 1920, until December 1, 1920, at $9.33 per week, plus $12.00 medical bill. 3-190: Axel W. Peterson vs. Omaha Gas Company. On December 30, 1919, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer putting in gas pipes plaintiff fell off the side of stairs, a distance of about six feet, striking on his head and right shoulder. Compensation was paid to October 7, 1920. A hearing was had February 7, 1921. The Commissioner decided he should receive further treatment. On September 2, 1921, a further hearing was had and testimony taken as to the treatment given during preceding months. Compensation was allowed at the rate of (15.00 each week up to September 2, 1921, together with medical and hospital ex - pense as provided by law. Case appealed. 3-191: Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company vt. Horace L. Wood, Minden. Insurance Carrier: Hartford Aoeident and Indemnity Co.) On March 26, 1920, while in the employ of the Minneapolis Thresh - ing Machine Company of Hopkins, Minn., as a salesman, defendant fractured his wrist while cranking a Ford car. He was paid his full wages from date of accident to June 8, 1920. No compensation was paid or tendered defendant by the insurance company carrying the risk, but considerable correspondence was had to get "a settlement." In December the insurance company filed a petition for a hearing. On March 25, 1921, a hearing was had and compensation was allowed tor 25% loss of use of the hand, or 43% weeks, at $15.00 each week; 50% penalty for delayed payments of compensation from June 8, 1920; plus medical and hospital expenses provided by law. Case appealed. Commissioner's award sustained in district court. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 3-192: Truman O. Smith vs. Square Turn Tractor Company, Norfolk. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.) On August 20, 1920, while in. the employ of defendant company, plaintiff was injured, resulting in the loss of end of third finger on right hand. Blood poisoning set in, leaving stiff fingers. A petition was filed for a hearing. Before the date of hearing the parties agreed upon a settlment in accordance with the compensation law. DOCKET FOUR 4-1: George W. Beardsley vt. General Fire Extinguisher Company, Omaha. i Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) On October 29, 1920, while in the employ of defendant Company as a pipe fitter's helper at the Burgess-Nash building, plaintiff fell with a scaffold a distance of 30 feet, injuring his feet and side of head. Compensation was paid for four weeks, when doctor said he was ablo to go to work. A petition was filed December 23, 1920, and the case set for hearing three different times, but plaintiff went to Illinois and did not respond to the notice of hearing. On August 12, 1921, a hearing was had. Compensation was allowed for the amount claimed by plain - tiff, being two weeks at $15.00 each week. 4-2: Anthony Dambra vs. Morris &amp; Company, Omaha. On October 16, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff suffered an accident from strain, which resulted in a hernia on both sides. He accepted a truss furnished by employer but did not want an operation. Later he was laid off and then he filed a petition claiming compensation. Hearing was had on February 11, 1921, and compensation was allowed for five weeks at $15.00 each week, also plaintiff was ordered to submit himself for an operation with compen - sation and medical and hospital expenses to be paid for by defendant company. Case appealed. Sustained in district court. 4-3: Gordon W. Holler vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha On July 30, 1920, while employed by defendant company, plaintiff injured three fingers of his left hand when the cotton glove on the hand was caught in an unguarded gear. Fingers were bruised, crushed and lacerated and one-third of the first phalange of second finger was cut off. A hearing was had on February 11, 1921, and compensation was allowed for seven weeks disability, ten weeks for loss of fingers, 50% penalty for waiting time and medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case appealed. Later Commissioner's award paid. 4—4: E. A. Bramon vs. Omaha-Auburn Motor Company, Don H. H ink- ley A Fred A. Fay, Omaha. On April 20, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as an automobile mechanic, plaintiff injured his thumb at the nail. Later in - fection set in, but plaintiff was kept on the pay roll all the time. Was in hospital four days. A hearing was had February 19, 1921, and com - pensation was allowed for one and one-half weeks at $15.00 each week together with medical and hospital expenses of $47.00. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 33 4-5: James Kelley vs. Hugh Murphy Construction Company, Fremont. In November, 1919, while in the employ of defendant company, as a laborer on Lincoln highway, plaintiff slipped off a truck and his right foot was caught under the wheel and injured. He was disabled seven - teen weeks. Petition was filed with the Department on December 27, 1920 — more than a year after the accident. At the hearing on March. 17, 1921, defendant's attorney raised the statute of limitation against the plaintiff and case was dismissed. Plaintiff claimed that he retained an attorney at Fremont to look alter his case in March, 1920, but ihe petition was not filed until date mentioned above. 4-6: Earl Leonard Whitaker, et al vs. Clark J. Gibson, Fremont. On September 22, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as truck, driver, plaintiff was injured when the truck turned over in the road. Later his right leg was amputated above the knee. A hearing was held March 8, 1921, and compensation was allowed for 215 weeks at $12.00 each week for the loss of a leg, and medical and hospital expenses as pro - vided by law. Case appealed. Later settled for $2,000.00 without ap - proval of Commissioner. 4-7: Jennie Rose, by Fred Stephens, her legally appointed Guardian, vs. Peter Mehrens, Omaha. Insurance Carrier: Georgia Casualty Co On November 30, 1918, while in the employ of Peter Mehrens as a waitress, plaintiff fell through a trap door in the floor and was in - jured in the head and back, affecting mind and mental faculties. A petition was filed December 29, 1920, and a hearing was had March 4, 1921. Compensation was allowed from November 30, 1918, less 14 weeks, at $7.32 each week until disability shall have ended, 50% penalty for delayed payments; together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case appealed. Settled for $150.00 without the ap - proval of the Commissioner. 4-8: Grover C. Carter vs. The Morris Transfer Company, Lincoln. On or about September 13, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff alleged that he injured his hand and wrist in lifting a piano from a truck aided by three other men. A hearing was had on January 18, 1921, and a large number of witnesses were heard. Compensation was allowed for 12% weeks from September 22, 1920 at $15.00 each week, and $15.00 doctor bill. 4:9: Arthur M. Shivers vs. T. M. Cohagan, North Platte. On November 14, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as a lab - orer and truck driver, lacerated and injured two fingers of his left hand on a buzz saw. Treatment was given injured members and $107.50 in compensation and medical treatment was paid and receipted lor "in full." On May 14, 1921, it became necessary to amputate the second finger between the first and second joints. A hearing was had in North Platte October 11, 1921, and compensation for 30 weeks at $15.00 each week was allowed, and medical and hospital expenses as provided, by law, less $57.50 medical expense already paid. On appeal to the dis - trict and supreme courts the Commissioner was sustained. 4-10: Earl Otto vs. William Seivers, Omaha Express Company, Omaha. On October 20, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as a laborer, plaintiff injured his hand by having it pinched between a truck and the </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT steps he was ascending. Three days later the hand became infected. Employer carried no insurance at the time of the accident, but took out a policy after the accident. The injured man returned to work, after a period of idleness and injured the hand again. A hearing was had on February 23, 1921. He was given compensation in the amount of $14.33 and $14.00 medical expense in addition to the amount already paid. 4-11: James Sprout v». George Parks &amp; Company, Omaha. (Insurance Currier: General Accident Fire anil Life Assurance Corporation.) On November 3, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff was injured by a pile of brick falling on him; and his hip and three ribs on right side were severely injured or fractured. Compensation was paid for six weeks at $15.00 each week and then discontinued. Petition was filed for a hearing by plaintiff. On Feb - ruary 23, 1921, a hearing was had and compensation allowed since date it was discontinued and the same to be continued until disability of plaintiff shall have ended. It was further ordered that plaintiff should submit himself for treatments in an effort to restore him to his former normal condition, the same to be paid for by the insurance Company. Case appealed. District court allowed 20 weeks compensation at $15.00 each week. 4-12: David William Gobin vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. On January 14, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a door opener, a door fell on plaintiff injuring his left wrist; com - pensation was paid for a week and one-half. Then plaintiff was put back to work again. In November he was dismissed. January 8, 1921, a petition was filed. May 24, a hearing was held. At the end of the hearing company attorney agreed to pay compensation from date of dis - charge of plaintiff up to and during period of treatment to be given plaintiff in an effort to restore his hand to normal. After treatments it was found plaintiff had lost the use of his left hand. Compensation was allowed for 175 weeks at $12.40 each week, to date from October 2, 1920, and medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 4-13: Elmer T. King vs. Nebraska State Highway Commission, Lin - coln. Petition was filed January 8, 1921 in which plaintiff alleged to have injured his back in lifting, while in the employ of the defendant. Case was set for hearing a number of times, but each time plaintiff failed to make an appearance. Case was dismissed. 4-14: William Shea vs. Hoffland Potash Company, Hoffland. (.Insurance Carrier: New Amsterdam Casualty Company.) On December 21, 1919, while in the employ of defendant company as a steam fitter, plaintiff was injured by the explosion of a steam heater. Compensation was paid for 49% weeks for disability, per cent of loss of vision in one eye and per cent of loss of hearing in one ear. Later a petition was filed and a hearing had in Omaha, June 11, 1921. It developed at the hearing that plaintiff had a hernia as result of the accident and that he had a per cent of loss of vision in both eyes. Commissioner ordered compensation at the rate of $15.00 each week during disability following operation for hernia, and also compensation for eight and one-fourth per cent loss of vision in both eyes being $1.23% per week for 300 weeks, and, in addition thereto, eight and one- </seg>
            <seg id="p035">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 35 fourth per cent of $12.00 per week, or $ .99 for the remainder of his life. Case appealed. Later settled for $300 without approval of Com - missioner. Plaintiff failed to answer letters from Department after settlement was made. 4-15: Harry Hawkins vs. George Kiene &amp; Company, Omaha (Insurance Carrier: D. S. Fidelity &amp; Guarantee Co.) On October 22, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, as a laborer to wreck a building, plaintiff slipped while lifting a timber, spraining his back. A hearing was had on February 24, 1921, and com - pensation was allowed at the rate of $15.00 each week from October 30, 1920, to January 31, 1921, together with medical and hospital expenses, as provided by law. 4-16: Fred Emanuel vs. Burgess-Nash Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On January 21, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a janitor, plaintiff ran a rusty nail into the heel of his thumb. In - fection set in and plaintiff spent several weeks in the hospital. Com - pensation was paid to July 28, 1920, final receipt signed and plaintiff returned to work on January 11, 1921. A hearing was had September 6, 1921, and compensation was allowed for 15% loss of use of right hand, or 26*4 weeks at $12.00 each week. 4-17: Joseph Shultz vs. Partridge-Thompson Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Corp.) On March 26, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff, as a laborer, had the muscles of his right arm lacerated above the elbow by the dipper of a steam shovel. H3 was paid compensation for 22&gt;4 weeks. On January 11, 1921, plaintiff filed a petition for further compensation. A hearing was had February 10, 1921, and compensation was allowed for ten weeks, in addition to what had been paid, at $15.00 each week. 4-18: E. B. Echtermeyer vs. J. A. Hultgren, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire and Life Assurance Corp.) On October 8, 1920, while in the employ of defendant, plaintiff in - jured right foot when a piece of plaster board fell on it while making alterations as a carpenter at the Empress Theatre building. Compen - sation was paid for nine weeks at $15.00 each week, when a final re - ceipt was signed by plaintiff. Later he filed a petition for a hearing to determine whether or not he had a permanent injury. A hearing was had on February 7, 1921, and, from the reports of the various sur - geons, the case was dismissed. 4-19: Steve Krager vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. On September 24, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a catch basin man, plaintiff was caught between a backing wagon and the loading dock, causing "hernia. Hearing was had on February 25, 1921, and compensation allowed from date of injury until disability ended, together with the 50% penalty for delayed payments, and medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. 4-20: J. C. Sheridan vs. American Railway Express Company, Omaha. On August 29, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a freight piler, plaintiff fell from truck and pulled a box down on top </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT of himself, injuring his right shoulder. A hearing was had on February 25, 1921 and compensation allowed for four weeks at $15.00 each week from August 30, 1920. 4-21: W. J. Weaver vs. Beatrice Creamery Company, Lincoln I Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On October 13, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff was struck on the leg by a cake of ice jumping out of chute and striking him between knee and ankle. Compensation was paid at $15.00 a week from date of injury until latter part of December, 1920. A hearing was had on March 2, 1921. Compensation was allowed at $15.00 each week until disability ended together with medical and hospital expenses. Case appealed and Commissioner's award sustained by district court. 4-22: David T. Hall vs. Schleuter Bros., Fremont, (Insurance Carrier: Louden Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) Some time in April, 1920, while employed as a teamster on a dump wagon for defendant, plaintiff strained his knee because of the pressure he used in holding the brake of a dump wagon on a hill near Beemer. He knew nothing about the compensation law and drifted aimlessly from place to place in the state. In January 1921, he filed a petition and a hearing was had March 3, 1921 at Fremont. Because no claim was made for compensation within six months as provided by the compensation law, this case was dismissed. Case appealed. Dismissed in district court. 4-23: Nebraska Fuel Company vs. Porter Camp, Omaha. (Insurance Currier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On August 27, 1919, while in the employ of plaintiff company, de - fendant while carrying a coal chute slipped on the grass, fell and broke his left leg at the thigh. Compensation was paid from date of accident to January 4, 1921. A petition was filed by plaintiff January 18, 1921, to have the commissioner determine the extent of permanent disability. Before a hearing was had the parties agreed to a lump sum settlement for $500.00. Compensation previously paid was $1,065.00; medical and hospital expenses $1,429.58. 4-24: H. B. Sweetwood vs. Imperial Sash &amp; Door Factory, Omaha, (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) Plaintiff was injured September 25, 1920, by having the index and middle fingers of his left hand caught in a circular saw. Compensation was paid at the rate of $15 per week for a period of 32% weeks, being 50% of the loss of the use of the two fingers. The insurance company refused to pay compensation for the period of temporary total disability in addition to the permanent disability. A petition was filed January 18, 1921, and the case heard at Omaha, September 1, 1921, when an award was made allowing compensation for a period of eleven weeks in addition to the amount already paid. 4-25: Edward H. Walters vs. Investors Syndicate, Chance, South Dakota. On November 1, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as a bond salesman, plaintiff suffered an injury resulting in a sprained ankle and broken bone in ankle. Plaintiffs home is in Chance, South Dakota. The contract of hire was made in Minneapolis, Minnesota, and he was Injured in Plainview, Nebraska. For the reason that plantiff was employed in </seg>
            <seg id="p037">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 37 Minnesota, the Commissioner found that he had no jurisdiction. Case was dismissed. 4-26: P. G. James vs. Able Construction Company, Wayne. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corporation.) On November 19, 1920, plaintiff was employed by defendant company as a laborer on a paving contract. After the noon whistle blew plaintiff went to meat market for meat for dinner. After coming out of the market, Roy King, superintendent of construction work, asked him If he wanted a ride home in his (King's) personal automobile. Plaintiff rode on the running board and when the car turned a corner he was thrown to the pavement, striking his head and fracturing his skull. Con - tention of plaintiff's lawyer was that he was on his employer's premises while he was on the paved streets and therefore should receive com - pensation. Commissioner denied compensation and dismissed the case. 4-27: Western Paint and Glass Company vs. J. H. McKelvie, Lincoln. i Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp On July 20, 1920, while in the employ of the Western Paint and Glass company, paint boxes fell on defendant and broke his right leg. Compensation and medical and hospital expenses were paid until De - cember 30, 1920. A hearing was had March 15, 1921, and further com - pensation of 15 weeks at 815.00 each week was allowed. 4-28: H. E. McGrath vs. Liberty Machine &amp; Auto Works, Lincoln, On May 26, 1920, while working at the Liberty Machine and Auto works, plaintiff injured his eyes by molten metal flying into them. The employer denied that plaintiff was employed at the time because no agreement to hire had been entered into. The doctor testified that when the employer brought the injured workman to him he said, "This man is working for us, take care of him and the insurance company will take care of the account." Compensation was allowed for 55 weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense. The case was appealed, but later settled out of court with the approval of the commissioner. 4-29: Jay Burns Baking Company vs. Fred O. Morley, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Casualty Reciprocal Exchange. ) On August 13, 1920, while in the employ of plaintiff as a laborer at night, defendant's arm was caught between an endless belt and a pulley and his forearm was fractured, bones in hand broken and upper arm muscles injured. Compensation and medical expense in excess of $200 was paid, and a petition was filed by the insurance company to determine the permanent disability. A hearing was had on March 4 and 5, 1921. Defendant was ordered to submit himself for an operation to restore his hand to its former normal physical condition. Compensation to be paid during disability resulting from such operation. A further hearing to be had later to determine what disability, if any existed. Appealed. Commissioner's award sustained. 4-30: Mike Karas vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. In the spring of 1919, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff injured his right leg and face in an elevator accident. On April 8, 1920, plaintiff's right leg was amputated between the knee and i Insurance Carrier: Iinyal Indemnity Co.) </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT the hip. A hearing was had May 6 and 23 and compensation was allowed for 175 weeks at $12 each week, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. Appealed. 4-31: Thomas Gorup vs. Armour &amp; Company, Omaha. Some time in November, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as a steam fitter, plaintiff strained himself while lifting a steam trap. Three weeks later reported his condition to the office. Later he went to a hospital and was operated on for a hernia. A hearing was had February 21, 1921, and compensation was allowed for six weeks at $15.00 each week, together with $75.00 doctor bil land $49.50 hospital ex - pense. 4-32: Frank Ulaski vs. Morris &amp; Company, Omaha. On September 11, 1920, while employed by defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff ran a bone sliver into the end of the middle finger of his right hand. He worked four days following the injury and then had to quit because his finger had become infected. Compensation was paid for one week and final release taken. Complaint was made to the Com - pensation Department and the employer was told plaintiff should get more compensation as well as medical treatment. Five dollars was paid plaintiff on that day and another final release secured from the injured man. He was treated three times and given medicine after last final release was signed. A hearing was had February 21, 1921, and compen - sation was allowed for an additional ten weeks at $15.00 together with the 50 per cent penalty for delinquent payments. Case appealed. The District and Supreme courts sustained' the Commissioner. 4-33: Edward Ebert vs. E. F. Hanson, Omaha. On December 31, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as a truck driver, plaintiff broke his wrist cranking the car. He was paid wages for three weeks and then was discharged. A petition was filed and a hearing was had on March 5. 1921. Compensation was allowed for seven weeks after January 31, 1921, at $15.00 each week together with medical and hospital expenses, as provided by law. 4-34: H. C. Larson vs. American Smelting &amp; Refining Company, Omaha. Plaintiff alleged that on the 21st day of December, 1920, he was Injured by arsenic smoke in his department. Petition was filed and a hearing date set. On the day of the hearing plaintiff requested that the case be dismissed. 4-35: Roscoe H. Deahl vs. Lincoln Traction Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On or about September 22, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a one-man motor car operator, plaintiff in running to a switch tripped over a wire and fell, rupturing himself. Petition was filed and a hearing was had on March 30, 1921. Commissioner ordered plaintiff to submit himself for an operation at the expense of the in - surance company and that he be paid compensation during disability resulting from such operation. 4-36: J. C. Wood vs. Public Service Company, Aurora, (Insurance Carrier: Globe Indemnity Co.) On October 22, 1920, while employed by defendant company as a </seg>
            <seg id="p039">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 39 fireman, plaintiff got a hot cinder in his right eye. A few days later erysipelas set in immediately around the injured eye. Ulcer developed and then plaintiff had the flu. As a result plaintiff lost his right eye. A hearing was had on March 29, 1921, and compensation was allowed for 62 1-2 weeks at the rate of $15.00 each week, together with $144.60 doctor bill, and $12.00 hospital bill. 4-37: Charles A. Chandler vs. Western Brick &amp; Supply Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp On August 7, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a foreman directing the unloading of a car of sand, the clam bucket was swung around with such force as to strike plaintiff, breaking his arm. He was paid full wages and furnished medical treatment until October 30, 1920, when he was laid off. A hearing was had on March 14, 1921. Ordered to submit to surgical treatment. On appeal awarded $180.00 compensation; $5.00 a week till disability ends, not to exceed 177 weeks. 4-38: Charles Sluyter vs. Lyman-Richey Sand Company, Louisville On December 15, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff was injured by being kicked by a fellow employe. There was no "horse-play." A petition was filed and an informal hear - ing had on March 31, 1921. Compensation was allowed for eleven weeks and five days at $15.00 each week and hospital bill of $44.75 paid by plaintiff. Also doctor bill of $50. 4-39: P. A. McCrary, father of Loren McCrary, deceased, minor, vs. John F. Wolff, Plattsmouth. Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Company On September 30, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as helper in garage, Loren McCrary, deceased, while on an errand, attempted to get on a moving truck, fell under the rear wheel and was injured so badly that he died the next day. A petition was filed and on April 4, 1921, a hearing was had. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $9.75 each week plus $150 burial benefit and medical and hospital expense. Case appealed. Sustained in the district court. Appealed to the Supreme court. 4—40: John A. Carlson vs. Ideal Cement Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.&gt; On March 12, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff's left ankle was caught in a transfer car and broken. Thirty-two weeks' compensation and medical expenses were paid. A petition was filed February 8, 1921. On March 10, 1921, &amp; hearing was had and fifteen weeks' additional compensation was allowed for a per cent loss of the use of the foot. Case appealed. District court allowed $175 and costs. 4-41 : Anna Newman vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha On January 19, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff stepped through a hole in the floor of the dock one morning, on her way to work, injuring her right leg below the knee. Compen - sation was allowed for 3 1-2 weeks at $12.40 each week and a final </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT receipt was signed February 28, 1920. Later the leg gave her trouble and in August the company doctor told her to go to another physician for treatment. January 29, 1921, she quit work on account of her dis - ability. A hearing was had July 22, 1921, and compensation was allowed to July 22, 1921, at $12.40 each week together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Appealed. District court allowed $150 and costs. 4-42: Jerry Brown vs. City of Omaha. On January 15, 1921, while in the employ of the defendant, plaintiff slipped on the pavement, resulting in a fractured knee cap. A petition was filed, but before the hearing a settlement for $60 and doctor bill was agreed upon and the case was dismissed. 4-43: Everett Price vs. F. E. Potter A. Son, Omaha (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) On or about May 1, 1920, while in the employ of defendants as a laborer, installing fire escapes, plaintiff fell a distance of 18 feet, striking on back and leg. Plaintiff was given medical attention four days. He then went to Tekamah. A hearing was had May 9, 1921, and compensation was allowed for 21 weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case ap - pealed. District court allowed $270. 4-44: Pauline Flowers vs. Conant Hotel, Omaha (Insurance Carrier: London (iuarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On September 1, 1920, while in the employ of the defendant as a waitress, plaintiff fell down an elevator shaft, fracturing her collar bone, cut head, and hip badly bruised. Nineteen weeks compensa - tion was paid and then stopped, because insurance company contended that the amount allowed for board in addition to wages was too high. A hearing was had February 24, 1921, and amount of compensation allowed was $14.23 each week until the disability ended. Medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case appealed. Commis - sioner's award sustained. Compensation paid to July 1, 1922. Later lump sum settlement for $800.44 was made, with the approval of the Commissioner. 4-45: R. P. Edwards vs. O'Brien-DavisCoad Auto Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Asurance Co.) On January 24, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as an automobile mechanic apprentice, plaintiff strained himself and lost ten days time. A hearing was had and compensation was al - lowed at $2.40 per day for four days, together with medical expenses as provided by law. 4-46: Walter Fox vs. John Latenser A Sons, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Asurance Co.) On September 17, 1920, while in the employ of the defendants, plaintiff was struck in the palm of the right hand with a brick. Several days later right little finger swelled up. It was opened and dressed and healed in about twelve weeks, but left the finger stiff. Petition -was filed, but before a hearing was had the parties agreed to a settlement of 28 weeks' compensation at the rate of $15.00 each week, plus hospital and medical expense as provided by law. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 41 4—47: Henry Duhrkopf vs. George Bennett and Lincoln Gat A. Electric Light Company, Lincoln. On January 3, 1918, while in the employ of George Bennett as a house mover, plaintiff sustained an electric shock, which resulted in the loss of one foot and one hand. In December, 1918, a com - mon law settlement was made for $2,000. On February 16, 1921, a petition was filed praying for compensation under the compensa - tion law. On March 9, and June 21, 1921, hearings were had. For the reason that plaintiff disregarded the benefits of the compen - sation law and elected to proceed under the common law, and for the further reason that the statute of limitation applied, the case w.as dismissed. Case appealed to district and supreme court and order of Commissioner was sustained. 4-48: Irene Foutch vt. Iten Biscuit Company, Omaha. On August 8, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company in the icing department, plaintiff alleged that she scratched the in - dex finger of her right hand; that it healed in a day or two and then became swollen, painful and inflamed. A week later her left knee became swollen and she could not stand or walk. Tlw medi - cal testimony was that plaintiff's trouble, both in the finzer and the knee, was arthritis and was not caused from an injury. No evidence of an injury while at work was presented. The Ameri - can Smelting and Refining Company furnished medical and hos - pital care in this case, because the father of plaintiff was em - ployed by the latter company. Compensation was denied and the case dismissed. 4-49: George Toman vs. Gordon-Rainalter Company, Omaha. ilrsurunee Currier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On October 21, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as a candy cutter, plaintiff injured the index and middle fingers of his right hand. He lost seven weeks work. A hearing was had April 5, 1921, and further compensation for seven addi - tional weeks at $14.40 was allowed. 4-50: Herman McCurley vs. Mart Gerton, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Maryland Casualty ( On July 10, 1920, while employed by defendant as a plasterer, plaintiff fell from scaffold and put his arm through a window, severely cutting it at the elbow. Compensation was paid for 31 weeks and then stopped. Petition was filed. Hearings were had on March 21, 1921, April 13, 1921, and April 25, 1921. Compensa - tion was allowed from last payment at $15.00 each week, and plain - tiff was ordered to submit himself within thirty days for an opera - tion in an effort to restore his arm to its former normal condi - tion. After the operation a further hearing would be had to deter - mine the disability. Case appealed. Settled for $300. 4-51: American Potash Company vs. R. R. IS'cFall, Antioch. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident and QnafaDtM Corp.) On July 8, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff was hit by a piece of iron in the left eye. A hearing ilnsurnnce Carrier: Traveler* Insuranre Co.) </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 EIGHTEENTH BIEXNIAL REPORT was had in Omaha on April 1. 1921, and on report of eye spec - ialists submitted, Commissioner allowed compensation for 62% weeks at $15.00 each week. 4-52: Wm. Kemp vs. J. I. Case Plow Company, Omaha On December 29, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as a janitor, plaintiff fell from a ladder from Tvhich he was cleaning windows and sprained his ankle. On February 21, 1921, petition was filed and a hearing was had on March 19, 1921. Com - pensation was allowed for seven weeks at $13.33 each week, to - gether with 50 per cent penalty for delayed payments, and medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. 4-53: Joseph Bomber vs. Sanitary Bakery, Omaha On December 27, 1920. while in the employ of defendant, plain - tiff scratched the index finger cf his right hand on a nail in a board he was throwing into the oven fire box. Infection set in and plaintiff was disabled from work. He was given medical treat - ment until January 20, 1921, when he was taken to Leavenworth prison, where he was treated by the prison doctor. Compensation was allowed for one-fourth of the loss of the use of index finger, amounting to 8% weeks at $15.00 each week, 50 per cent penalty for delayed payments, together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. 5-54: Ben S. Robertson vs. Western Sugar Company, Mitchell I Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee *V Accident Co. i On November 5, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany, Ernest Robertson, son of plaintiff, was killed by falling from a scaffolding 14 feet high, striking his head on the cement floor, fracturing his skull; death following almost immediately. A peti - tion was filed by plaintiff, his father, as a dependent. A hearing was had April 1, 1921, and compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $7.50 each week and $150 burial benefit. 4-55: Mrs. A. M. Lesac vs. Jubilee Manufacturing Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Now Amsterdam Casualty Co On the 22d day of November, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff injured little finger of her right hand. It became infected resulting in a 100 per cent loss. Petition was filed but before the hearing the parties agreed upon a settlement of $212.10 paid in weekly payments of $14.14, plus $76.50 hospital and medical expense. The case was dismissed. 4-56: William Strof v*. Omaha Structural Steel Company, Omaha linwn Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty &lt; On October 11. 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany, plaintiff ruptured himself while straining to bend a three - inch pipe. A petition was filed and on April 22, 1921, a hearing held. Compensation was allowed for nine weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. dr. sura nor Carrier : London («nam litre nntl Accident Co. ) </seg>
            <seg id="p043">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 43 4—57: George Bodeker vs. Overland Tire &amp; Rubber Company, Omaha. On June 1, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff's shoulder was fractured. Compensation was paid until January 25, 1921, and then discontinued. A petition was filed and on March 26, 1921. a hearing was had. Compensation was allowed for 40 per cent loss of use of the arm, or 80 weeks compensation at $15.00 each week. Case appealed. District court affirmed the Commissioner's award. 4—58: Mrs. Mary Knuckles vs. Armour &amp; Company, Omaha. On December 10, 1920, while George Knuckles, deceased, hus - band of plaintiff, was employed by defendant company as a laborer, a fellow employe threw scalding soda water on his foot, causing severe burn, which became infected and resulted in his death. Compensation was paid during disability. A petition vaB filed by plaintiff, but before a hearing was had, plaintiff died, thus leaving the burial expense of $150 and compensation for the weeks between the death of George Knuckles and the death of his widow to be adjusted in the interest of the only heir, a daughter. The burial expense of $150 and 6 weeks and two days compensa - tion at the rate of $15.00 each week was allowed, and the case dismissed. 4-59: Henry C. Sternberg vs. Cushman Motor Works, Lincoln I Insurance Carrier: Ocean Guarantee ami Accident Corp.) On or about July 15, 1919, while in the employ of defendant works as a moulder, plaintiff strained himself and broke a blood vessel in his right leg. On March 7, 1921, he filed a petition for a hearing. On March 30, 1921, a hearing was had and case was dis - missed because the statute of limitation had run against plaintiff. 4-60: Wilber L. Rickett vs. L. R. Des Voignes, Ogallala. On October 9. 1920, while in the employ of defendant as a car - penter, plaintiff suffered the loss of his little finger on the left hand at the second joint. A petition was filed March 8, 1922. Defendant left the state and the Department could not get service. Several requests were made to the plaintiff for disposition of claim. On his failing to reply the case was dismissed. 4-61: Ben B. Loiler vs. Paxton &amp; Vierling Iron Works, Omaha Inauranre Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty f On June 18, 1920. while in the employ of defendant as a painter, but while helping a derrick man. plaintiff mashed second, third and fourth fingers of right hand. Compensation and medical expense was paid for thirteen weeks. A petition was filed and hearing had to determine what further compensation plaintiff had coming. Plaintiff was allowed further compensation of ten and two-thirds weeks at $15.00 each week for permanent per cent of loss of use of fingers. Case appealed. District court affirmed the Commissioner's award and added the penalty. 4-62: Delia Morris vs. H. Herpolsheimer Company, Lincoln. i Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp;l Accident Co, On November 12, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as a saleslady, plaintiff injured her thumb while demonstrat- llnanranee farrier: (leorttiii I'lisunlty Co.) </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT ing a wringer. Compensation was paid for fifteen weeks and then stopped. A petition was filed and a hearing had April 6, 1921. Further compensation was allowed for six weeks at 110.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense. 4-63: Marshall Bros. Company, a corporation, vs. Tony Bullock, Ar- lington. (Insurance Carrier: Employers Liability Assurance Corp.) On September 11, 1919, while in the employ of plaintiff com - pany's nursery as a laborer, a double tree broke and struck de - fendant on the left leg between the knee and hip, fracturing same. Compensation, medical and hospital expenses were paid up to March 11, 1920. when defendant refused to accept further com - pensation and began suit under common law. The insu/arce com - pany then filed a petition before the Commissioner to determine the disability under the compensation law. A hearing was had in Fremont. The injured man was taken to a doctor for examination. The doctor found him to have suffered a 50 per cent lo.«s of use of his left leg. An award was made allowing him \liy? we(&gt;k&amp; compensation at $13.33 each week to date from March it. 1D20, together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. The case was tried in the district court at Blair. Plaintiff claimed that it was not a compensation case. His claim was dismissed for the reason that it was held to be a compensation case, as plaintiff's accep - tance of compensation bound him to the provisions of the law 4-64: Peter Defasi vs. Union Stock Yards, Oma a. On June 23, 1920. while employed as a laborer for defendant, plaintiff scratched his shin with a shovel, resulting in five weeks disability. A hearing was had on April 20, 1921, and compensa - tion was allowed for the weeks claimed. The insurance company maintained that the disability was caused by varicose veins and that claim was not made for compensation. The injured man proved he had an accident to his shin and that he had made claim for compensation within six months. He was allowed compensa - tion for a period of five weeks at $15.00 each week, plus hospital and medical* expense. 4-65: Adolph G. Majowich vs. Morris Packing Company, Omaha. On August 21, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff fell down a flight of stairs, injuring his back. He kept on working until October 22, 1920, when he had hemorrhages and has not worked since. It was claimed that the fall brought on the hemorrhages. A hearing was had July 21, 1921. At the conclusion of the testimony the defendant asked the privilege of having an examination made of plaintiff by an expert diagnostician. Thife was granted, but the next morning plaintiff's physician forbid the X-raying of plaintiff in a written note to his attorney. It was plain to the Commissioner that an appeal would be taken, no mat - ter which side won. In the interest of plaintiff the Commissioner decided to prevent delay, therefore dismissed the case without pre - judice. Case appealed. Commissioner's dismissal sustained. Ap - pealed to supreme court. i Insurance Carrier : London (tunrantte &amp; Aci-hlent Co.) </seg>
            <seg id="p045">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 45 4-66: Archie M. Crone vc. Western Brick &amp; Supply Company, Lincoln. 1 1 Msuriim »• Carrier: Ocean Accident A: Guarantee Corp ) On November 18, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany, plaintiff sustained injuries to his right shoulder and elbow. Compensation was paid for some time, then insurance company filed a petition to determine the permanent disability sustained. A hearing was held on April 7, 1921, and plaintiff was awarded compensation at the rate of $15.00 per week for a period of 56% weeks, together with hospital and medical expenses, as provided by law. 4-67: Roscoe Marino vs. M. E. Smith &amp; Company and James Stew- art Construction Company, Omaha. On October 3, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany, plaintiff fell off a cement pile and sprained his ankle. Com - pensation was paid for eleven weeks and release taken. A petition was filed March 21, 1921, and a hearing held on July 1, 1921. Two doctors, after examination reported no permanent disability and one doctor testified that disability existed from the date of his examination to a period in the future cf six to eight weeks. The Commissioner then sent plaintiff to another surgeon for examination. In May, 1922, re - port of doctor's examination was made and the Commissioner allowed plaintiff compensation for 10 per cent of the loss of use of his right foot, being 15 weeks at $15.00 each week. 4—68: Ed Schoenheitcr vs. The Geer Company; Grand Island, Neb. IiiHiirnnee Carrier: Integrity Mulu.il Casualty Ci&gt;i On March 18, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff suffered three hernias while unloading lumber. Petition was filed but before a hearing was had. plaintiff filed a request before the Commissioner that the case be dismissed as satisfac - tory settlement had been made. 4-69: Clarence Frye vs. Gooch Milling and Elevator Company, Lin - coln. Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) On October 23, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany, plaintiff alleged that he injured his ankle and on January 29, 1921, had it operated on to remove a growth. It was shown in the evidence of a surgeon that he had the growth in August, 1920. Compensation was denied and the case dismissed. 4-70: Earnest Pierson vs. Norfolk Bridge &amp; Construction Company, Boyd. On June 4, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company at Boyd, plaintiff fractured a finger while driving pile on a bridge. Petition was filed, but before a hearing was had, parties agreed upon a settlement of compensation for 18 weeks and 2 days at 115.00 each week, plus $123.50 hospital and medical expense. Case dis - missed. i Iiimiimih'i- Carrier: I.omlon Guarantee &amp; Accident C&lt; cIiiHiirai.ci' Carrier: Employer* Liability AxHiirunce Corp. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 4-71: Clarence Jump vs. Omaha Wrecking Company, Omaha (Insurance Carrier: Georgia Casualty Co.) On December 23, 1919, while in the employ of the Omaha Wreck - ing company, plaintiff slipped on the floor of the second story and fell through a man hole, striking his neck and shoulders. He was given treatment and compensation and in July, 1920, was arrested charged with receiving a stolen automobile and taken to Tekamah, where he remained in jail until November, 1920, when he was taken to the penitentiary at Lincoln. Compensation was paid to August 18, 1920, at $15.00 each week. A great deal of conversation and con - siderable correspondence was had over this case, and finally a peti - tion was filed March 22, 1921, and a hearing held in Omaha, June 18, 1921. Compensation was allowed until disability ends at $15.00 each week. The penalty of 50 per cent was applied on compensa - tion due since last payment, medical and hospital expenses as pro - vided by law. Later, case settled for $3,000 with the Commissioner's approval. 4-72: Omar T. Barnum vs. J. W. Velte Grain Company, Brandon On August 20, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as grain buyer and laborer, plaintiff broke his right leg below the hip when a pile of grain doors fell on him. Plaintiff and his family and five children were supported by the county commissioners of Perkins county for five months following the accident. A petition was filed March 24, 1921, and a hearing had June 22, 1921. Com - pensation was allowed from August 25, 1920, to March 31, 1921, at $15.00 each week, and 5 per cent of the loss of the use of the right leg, or 10% weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 4-73: Edgar V. Shawhan vs. Table Rock Brick and Material Company, Table Rock. ( I nsu r:i ikc Currier: London Qoarantce &amp; Accident Co.) On June 28, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a tender of the dry pan used in the manufacture of brick, the dirt rolled from chute knocking him onto a belt and fly wheel. His right shoulder was broken, ribs broken and fractured and otherwise bruised. Compensation was paid for 35 weeks and then stopped. A petition was filed and a hearing had April 26, 1921. Compensation was al - lowed for 30 per cent loss of the use of the right arm, being 67% weeks, at $15.00 each week, to date from December 17, 1920. It was further ordered that plaintiff within thirty days, should submit him - self for treatment for his teeth at the expense of defendants. Ap - pealed. District court allowed 35 per cent loss of use of the arm, or 78% weeks, at $15.00 each week. 4-74: Charles F. Wilkinson vs. Chambers-O'Neill Wrecking Company, Omaha. On March 11, 1921, while in the employ of defendants as a laborer, plaintiff fell from a second story window to the ground in a building that was being wrecked, bruising his neck and shoulder. A hearing was had May 20, 1921, and compensation for one week and one half day at $15.00 per week, with the 50 per cent penalty for delayed payments together with medical and hospital expense. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 47 4-75: Swift A. Company vs. Joseph G. McNichols, Omaha. On April 14, 1919, wh'le employed by plaintiff, defendant was coming down stairs, when railing gave way, and he fell 10 feet to cement floor, fracturing both wrists. Compensation was paid for 96 weeks, or up to March 15, 1921, when a petition was filed to have the Commissioner determine the permanent disability. On April 21, 1921, a hearing was had and compensation was allowed for total disability, or 300 weeks at $15.00 each week, and then $12.00 each week fcr the balance of his life. 4-76: Anton Stefanek vs. A. Bakke Bakery Company, Omaha. On December 11, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as the driver of truck, plaintiff stepped from the running board of the truck to the street and jarred his body in such a manner as to cause a supuration inguinal adenitis. A hearing was had April 30, 1921. Compensation was allowed for 11% weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. Case appealed. Commissioner's award affirmed and penalty added. 4-77: Frank X. McCaffery vs. W. C. Ferrin Van and Storage Com- pany, Omaha. 1 1 iisiiiuiice Currier: (leiiernl Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Co On June 6. 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff was squeezed between two wagons, fracturing a rib and breaking an arm. Was paid six weeks compensation. Re - turned to work July 18. Layed off because he could not do the work. Petition was filed April 8, 1921. Hearings May 2 and 24. Compen - sation was allowed at $15.00 each week until disability ends, or for total disability in case no recovery is obtained. Case appealed. 4-78: John Gavin vs. Yale &amp; Hopewell Company, Lincoln. On August 23, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff injured his left thumb on a rip-saw. Compensation was paid for 29 weeks. A petition was filed and a hearing had April 26, 1921. Compensation was allowed for nine weeks at $15.00 each week for a specific loss of the use of the thumb, in addition to the amount al - ready paid. 4-79: Fred J. Nemitz vs. Gooch Milling A Elevator Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Currier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co) On January 21, 1921, while employed as a laborer for defendant company, plaintiff was lifting a sack of wheat off an elevator and twisted his neck in such a manner as to cause his head to lean over to one side. He was taken to hospital at once, but in a few days wanted to go home to Kansas. The Commissioner visited him in the hospital and urged him to remain. In a day or two he left the hospital and in a week went home to Kansas. On April 8, 1921. he filed a petition for a hearing. At the hearing he admitted he had had two previous attacks of the same character during 1920. Doctors testified that there was no injury to his neck. Case dismissed. (Inauranee Canter: London Guarantee &amp; Aciileut Co (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident At (Suaninttv Co. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 4-80: Nina Smith vs. Hayden Brothers, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Maryland Casualty Co.) On January 27, 1921, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as a cashier, plaintiff fell down stairs, spraining her ankle and injuring her back. The accident was not reported to the depart - ment until March 19, 1921, though it was reported by the employer on January 28, 1921. A petition was filed and a hearing had on June 10, 1921.~ Compensation was allowed from January 27, to Feb - ruary 24 and from May 25 to June 18, at $9.33 each week, 50 per cent penalty for delayed payments of compensation, medical and hospital expense as provided by law, a total of $104.80 and medical expense. 4-81: Archie Parker vs. City of David City. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On July 3, 1920, while in the employ of defendant city as a line - man, plaintiff was riding on a motorcycle from one part of the city to another, when the top of his left low shoe caught in the spoke of the wheel and pulled it into the wheel in such a manner as to severely injure the heel. Compensation was paid for 10 weeks total disability and five weeks partial disability. A hearing was had in David City on May 18, 1921, and further compensation was allowed *or 10 per cent of the loss of the use of his foot, or 15 weeks, at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense as pro - vided by law. Case appealed. 4-82: H. C. Avery vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. On April 24, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a janitor, plaintiff got lime, sand and mortar in left eye, resulting in loss of sight of the eye. A hearing was had May 2, 1921, and evidence taken. The case was left open for defendant company to make fur - ther investigation. On July 25, nothing having been heard from the company, the Commissioner wrote an award allowing plaintiff com - pensation for 125 weeks at $15.00 each week for the loss of an eye. 4-84: Gust and Alma Lundquist vs. Nebraska Gas &amp; Electric Com pany, St. Edwards. (Insurance Carrier: Globe Indemnity Co.) On August 28, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a lineman and electrician, Nells Lundquist, son of plaintiff, was electrocuted, dying almost instantly. The insurance company inspector made an investigation and found no dependency. The press clipping service of the department picked up the case. The department wrote the employer and received a letter describing the accident. Then the attention of the insurance carrier was called to the fact that no re - port of the accident was made to the department. On February 3, 1921, the first report of the accident was received. A petition was filed April 14, 1921, and a hearing had June 9, 1921. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $6.52 each week, $150 burial benefit and medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 4-85: Earl V. Dunkin vs. Oakdale Milling Company, Oakdale. (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Minimi Casualty Co.) On November 29, 1920, plaintiff's right hand was crushed between the rolls of a feed grinder, while demonstrating an elevator, at River - ton, Wyoming. A petition was filed on April 18, 1921, and the case </seg>
            <seg id="p049">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 49 was heard before the Commissioner July 16, 1921. Proof was shown at the hearing that the defendant had assumed the liability and paid the plaintiff compensation and medical expense as provided by law, up to the date of the hearing. The plaintiff having lost a hand, the liability of the defendant was definite, therefore, the case was dis - missed. 4-86: Wm. J. Shewan vs. Petrow &amp; Giano, Omaha (Insurance Carrier: Globe Indemnity Co.) On February 1, 1921, while in the employ of defendant partner - ship, plaintiff was struck in the left eye with a nail, resulting in the loss of the vision of the eye. A hearing was had May 17, 1921, and compensation was allowed for 125 weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case ap - pealed. District court sustained the Commissioner. Supreme court reversed the district court and Commissioner. 4-87: Nancy Thomas vs. The City of Seward. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On July 25, 1917, while in the employ of the City of Seward as Street Commissioner, Henry F. Thomas, son of plaintiff, was instantly killed while attempting to remove a live wire off the street. Com - pensation was paid to December 22, 1920, when it was discontinued on account of a" decision of the supreme court in another case. A petition was filed April 22, 1921, and a hearing had June 8, 1921. The Commissioner found for the plaintiff and ordered compensation paid to the mother of deceased, aged 78, until the 350 weeks are paid. 4-88: Solomon D. Gordon vs. Vaughn Construction Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Maryland Casualty Co.) On August 11, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff alleged that he strained himself lifting planks, causing infection of the auxiliary glands of the arm pit in the right side., A hearing was had May 10, 1921. Doctor testified that condi - tion complained of by plaintiff could not be caused by a strain. The Commissioner called at Creighton Free Dispensary and the surgeon in charge informed him that plaintiff had a boil under his arm when he came to dispensary; that it could not be caused from a strain; that plaintiff refused an operation and left the hospital. Case dismissed. 4-89: Blair Telephone Company vs. William Markham. Blair. I Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corp.) On February 21, 1920, while in the employ of plaintiff company, defendant fell from the roof of a building while it was being moved, injuring both feet at the ankles. Compensation was paid for a period and then stopped, . because defendant was alleged to have refused medical treatment. A hearing was held on July 1, 1921. Compensa - tion was allowed until disability ended at $15.00 each week to date from the last payment, April 23, 1921. Case appealed. Compensa - tion patU to March 28, 1922, then settled for $3,012.63. 4-90: Louis Graja vs. Hasklns Bros., Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Maryland Casualty Co.) On September 16, 1919, while in the employ of defendant as a laborer, plaintiff fell down an elevator shaft forty feet, breaking his </seg>
            <seg id="p050">EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 50 left arm, left leg near the thigh and injuring his back, near hip. Compensation was paid for 42 weeks. A petition was filed April 26, 1921, and a hearing had May 25, 1921. Compensation was allowed from date of last payment at $15.00 each week until disability ends. Case appealed. Commissioner's award sustained. 4-91: M. E. Smith &amp; Company vs. Ollie Peck, Omaha On September 9, 1920, while in the employ of plaintiff company, defendant slipped on a wet floor and broke her leg at the ankle. Com - pensation was paid for nine weeks. A hearing was had June 3, 1951, and compensation allowed for 30 weeks and four days at $11.53 each week, together with medical and hospital expenses. 4-92: Polly A. Croft vs. Omaha Cooperage Company, Omaha. On July 20, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a stationary fireman, Henry Croft received a heat stroke and col - lapsed as soon as he reached home after quiting work in the even - ing and died July 26, 1920. A hearing was had May 28, 1921, and compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $15.00 each week, $150 burial benefit, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 4—93: Joe Alexander vs. Hicks Retinning Company, Omaha. ) Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Co.) On June 4, 1920, while employed as a tinner for defendant com - pany, plaintiff was helping to carry a machine upstairs. The stairs were narrow and only two men could do the lifting. Plaintiff strained and ruptured himself. A hearing was had on June 4, 1921, and com - pensation was allowed for five weeks and one day at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 4-94: Jennings Johnson vs. David Cole Creamery Company, Omaha. Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Co.) On September 15, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as an automobile mechanic, plaintiff received severe burns on his arms and back. Compensation was paid for about five months. A petition was filed to have the Commissioner determine the disability of plaintiff. A hearing was had July 8, 1921. Compensation was allowed for 60 per cent of total disability to be $9.00 each week for 300 weeks, and thereafter during life $7.20 each week, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. Case appealed. Court allowed $6.93 per week for 271 weeks; thereafter $5.55 for remainder of life. 4-95: George Gingles vs. Armour &amp; Company, Omaha. On March 2, 1921. plaintiff slipped and strained himself while placing hogs on a table. Petition was filed, but before the date of hearing, parties agreed upon a settlement and the case was dis - missed. 4-96: Terrence Shields vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. On January 20, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as * Itisiirui.rc Carrier: I.onilmi Guarantee ft Accident Co I Insurant 1 ? Curri?r: London Guarantee &amp; A&lt;fl&lt;l?nt C&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p051">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 51 millwright, plaintiff broke hia arm at the elbow. Compensation was paid for 15 weeks and five days up to May 8, 1920. On May 6, 1921, a petition was filed praying for further compensation. On the same day the petition was filed, an informal hearing was had and compensation was allowed for 131% weeks at $15.00 each week, and medical and hospital expense as provided by law. Case appealed. District court allowed 115% weeks at $15.00 each week. 4-97: William Nehaus vs. Dietz Club, Omaha. Plaintiff was employed by the defendant as a caretaker for the club grounds. On March 8, 1921, while engaged in cleaning up and burning weeds, one of the buildings caught fire and in getting water to put out the fire plaintiff stepped on the cover of an old well that gave away, causing him to fall, dislocating his right shoulder and fracturing the humurus. The employer paid some of the medical ex - pense, but contended they did not come under the provisions of the compensation act, as they were not operating for pecuniary profit. A petition was filed May 12, 1921, and a hearing had at Omaha August 25, 1921. Plaintiff was awarded compensation for a period of 123 weeks at $13.30 per week, together with hospital and medi - cal expense, as provided by law. Case appealed. 4-98: Frank W. Dart vs. Grand Island Horse &amp; Mule Company, Grand Island. Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident Ac (Guarantee Cori On April 26, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a horse cuffer, plaintiff's right arm was broken just above the wrist. Compensation was paid for twelve weeks. A hearing was had July 13, 1921, and compensation allowed for 21 weeks for 12 per cent loss of use of the hand, in addition to what had already been paid, at $15.00 each week. 4-99: Mrs. Julia Fuss vs. American Beet Sugar Company, Grand Island. Insurance Carrier: Globe Indemnity Co On the first day of January, 1921, plaintiff's son, Edward Blaise, while employed by defendant as sugar washer, was injured by a spray pipe striking his left side. The injury resulted in 'his death. A petition was filed for compensation, but before a hearing date was set, parties agreed upon a settlement in accordance with the law. Case dismissed. 4-100: Mrs. Anna Petrick vs. Armour Packing Company, Omaha. On February 18, 1921, Mike Petrick, employe of defendant company, died. Petition was filed alleging that death was caused by unhealthful conditions existing in department where deceased worked. The case was set for hearing several times, but each time plaintiff failed to make an appearance. Case was dismissed. 4-101: Frank Police vs. Morris Packing Company, Omaha. On March 2, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a meat stamper, plaintiff alleged that he had "sustained a broken knee in the discharge of his duties and was sent to St. Joseph's hos - pital." At the hearing July 23, 1921, it developed that plaintiff had been to the hospital to undergo operation a second time for varicose vein ulcers. Compensation was denied and case dismissed. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 4-102: Alexander L. Lyon vs. State Journal Company, Lincoln. On December 4, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as a janitor and watchman, plaintiff injured the instep of his right foot, from the falling of a lever of a baling machine. No re - port of an accident was made. Defendant company paid plaintiff rOO and medical and hospital expenses. Later plaintiff employed attorney and the latter made a common law settlement of the case for $150.00 and submitted it to the department for approval. The Commissioner declined to approve settlement because no acci - dent had been reported and because he had no jurisdiction over claims outside the compensation law. A petition was then filed and hearing had on June 1, 1921. Compensation for eight weeks and one day at $13.33 was allowed, less $84.00 already paid, together with medical and hospital expense. 4-103: John M. Strmic, administrator estate of Nick Kevo, deceased, vs. William Adams Company, Pending. 4-104: James Mclntyre vs. L. V. Nicholas Oil Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Standard Accident Insurance ( On April 25, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff strained himself, resulting in hernia. A petition was filed May 20, 1921, and a hearing had July 16. 1921. Compensation was allowed for eight weeks from May 20 1921, at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expenses. 4-105: Pearl Denman Wright vs. William J. Poppe, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Employers Liability Assurance Corp.) This is a case where a petition was filed on May 24, 1921, pray - ing for the Commissioner to review a doctor bill which had previously been adjusted. The petition should not have been received, as other procedure is followed to determine the reasonableness of a doctor'3 bill. Case was dismissed. Case appealed. 4-106: Mary Jackson vs. Railsbach Grain Company, Ashland. On July 24, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, Frank Jackson, husband of plaintiff, fell down stairs and was so severely injured that he died in two days. Defendant com - pany offered to pay compensation, but the advisors of the widow prevailed on her to refuse the compensation. Common law action was begun, but after a day's hearing in district court at Wahoo, the case was withdrawn. Then the widow filed a petition praying for compensation. A hearing was had at Ashland and the Com - missioner allowed her 350 weeks and $150 burial benefit, as pro - vided by law. Case apealed. District court reversed the Commis - sioner. Case is again in the district court on a common law action. 4-107: Robert Franklin vs. Lincoln Traction Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On April 9, 1921, while employed by defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff was struck on the head with a shovel by a fellow workman; knocked unconscious and lost three weeks work on ac - count of disability. The attack was unprovoked. A hearing /as had June 1, 1921, and compensation was allowed for two weeks at $12.00 each week, together with medical expense. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 53 4-108: Angu* R. Beaton vs. Square Turn Tractor Company, Norfolk. On February 19, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a blacksmith's helper, plaintiff sustained an injury to his left foot. A petition was filed June 4, 1921. A hearing was had in Norfolk July 28, 1921. The defendant confessed liability and re - quested that an award be made in accordance with the law. Com - pensation was allowed tor three weeks at $15.00 each week, to - gether with hospital and medical expenses as provided by law. 4-109: J. H. Vanvelkenburg vs. Yale &amp; Hopewell, Lincoln. I Insurance Carrier: Ocean Guarantee &amp; Accident Corp.) In May, 1920, while in the employ of defendant, plaintiff strained himself lifting a machine on a wooden track, resulting in hernia. He was operated on May 18, 1920, and on the following day his wife and mother left a written claim for compensation on account of the accident and disability resulting. A petition was filed June 7, 1921, and a hearing had July 6, 1921. Compensation was allowed at $15.00 each week from May 18, 1920, to July 12, 1920, together with $100 doctor bill, $12.50 hospital bill; $5.00 ambulance bill and 50 per cent penalty for delayed payments of compensation. 4-110: Stanley Kirmiel vs. Armour A Company. Plaintiff received an injury April 15, 1920, while employed by defendant company, that resulted in a double hernia and he was disabled from June 23, 1920, to the time of hearing. A petition was filed June 7, 1921, asking for an award of compensation and surgical treatment to restore plaintiff to his former physical condi - tion, if possible. A hearing was had at Omaha September 8, 1921. It was shown that defendant had offered and was still willing to operate on the plaintiff and pay compensation during temporary dis - ability, but up to this time he had refused the operation. An award was made ordering plaintiff to submit to an operation paid for by the defendant, also compensation at the rate of $15.00 per week during disability caused by operation. Case appealed. Commissioner'a award affirmed. . 4-111: William Ransom vs. Northwestern Iron &amp; Metal Company, Lincoln. I Insurance farrier: Georgia Casualty Co.) On October 29, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany, plaintiff fell from the top of a bale of rags and injured his right knee. Compensation was paid to January 29, 1921, and final release taken. Later a petition was filed and a hearing had July 7, 1921. Compensation was allowed from date of accident until dis - ability ends, less the amount already paid, and medical and hos - pital expense as provided by law. 4—112: Shibley Cathrey vs. Armour &amp; Company, Omaha. Plaintiff claimed he sustained an injury on or about the first day of July, 1920, while employed by the defendant company. A petition was filed June 9, 1921, contending that an operation was necessary to restore plaintiff to his former physical condition, he having sustained a severe rupture of the right side. This case was set for hearing at Omaha several times, both sides being duly noti - fied, and in each instance the plaintiff failed to appear. Case waa dismissed without prejudice. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 4-113: American Railway Express Company vs. Lou O. Booker, Vir- ginia Gordon and James D. Patteson, Chicago. On February 7, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff company, James D. Patteson was on his way from Chicago to Osceola, Neb. to attend court. While in Omaha, on his way to the superintendent's office of plaintiff company, Mr. Patteson slipped and fell on the icy sidewalk, cutting a gash in his head which required several stitches. Infection set in and on February 14, 1921, Mr. Patteson died. Petition was filed by Mrs. Lou O. Booker, dependent sister, A hearing was had and compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at 85c each week, $150 burial benefit and medical and hospital ex - pense as provided by law. 4-114: Henry C. Cook vs. Omaha School Supply Company, Omaha, (llnsurance Carrirr: Emplimrs Liability Assurance Corf On June 11, 1921, a petition was filed by the plaintiff, who claimed he sustained an injury while in the employ of the defendant company some time during the month of September or October, 1919, exact date unknown. Several dates were fixed for a hearing in this case. In each instance the plaintiff failed to appear. Case was dis - missed without prejudice. 4-115: Fred Brooks vs. Morris &amp; Company, Omaha. Plaintiff sustained an injury that resulted in the loss of vision of his left eye. A grain of coal dust got into his eye, causing same to become infected. Compensation was denied on the ground that plain - tiff was employed by a contractor doing work by contract for de - fendant. A petition was filed June 4, 1921, and a hearing had at Omaha August 24, 1921. Evidence disclosed that the defendant com - pany paid plaintiff's wages by check. An award for compensation for 125 weeks at $15.00 per week was made in addition to hospital and medical expenses as prived by law. Case appealed. Affirmed by district court. 4-116: Pete Zoroya vs. Armour &amp; Company, Omaha. On January 27, 1921, plaintiff, while employed by defendant com - pany as laborer in the loading department, strained himself resulting in hemorrhage of the stomach. Petition was filed, but before a hear - ing date was set parties agreed upon a settlement in accordance with the compensation law. Case dismissed. 4-117: Arthur Bomar vs. I ten Biscuit Company, Omaha. (Insnrance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) Plaintiff alleged he received an injury to his eyes by an explosion of flour that he was throwing into the furnace while performing his usual work for the defendant company. A petition was filed June 15, and the case set for hearing August 22, 1921. Evidence showed that plaintiff's eyes were not injured when treated by the doctor, but that he was suffering with pink eye. Compensation denied and case dismissed. 4-118: George A. Curtis vs. Morris &amp; Company, Omaha. On January 27, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as chief electrician, plaintiff alleged that the packing blew out of </seg>
            <seg id="p055">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 55 an ammonia compresser and that he inhaled ammonia causing aggra - vation of heart leisons. A hearing was had October 6, 1921, and the evidence submitted did not substantiate the claim. The refrigerator engineer and chief engineer denied flatly that there had been a blow - out. Compensation was denied and case dismissed. 4-119: Mike Kusak vs. Swift &amp;. Company, Omaha. Pending. 4—120: Chas. E. Harrington vs. Fairmont Creamery Company, Geneva. On April 22, 1921, while employed by defendant company to wash the windows and clean up the place, plaintiff fell from a scaffold striking his side on the top of a barrel, breaking three ribs. A peti - tion was filed and a hearing had July 26, 1921. Commissioner found the employment was casual as the man was employed washing win - dows and had only worked three hours. There was no agreement as to wages, but plaintiff presumed he was to get 25c an hour. Caso dismissed. 4—121 : W. H. Gross vs. Hardy Furniture Company, Lincoln. i Insurance Carrier: Employers Liability Assurance Corp On April 15, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff alleged that he. as a stove repair man, was required to do painting in a close room for about three weeks, contracting lead poisoning resulting in disability of about three months. A hearing was had July 11, 1921. The Commissioner was unable to finci this plaintiff had anything other than an occupational disease an i there - fore dismissed the case. 4-122: William T. Gillam vs. Peoples Coal Company, a corporation, Lincoln. On July 1, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a coal teamster, plaintiff alleged that he jumped from a coal car to the bed of his wagon and strained his back. He was off from work one week and had a doctor call on him once. On the seventh work - ing day after the accident he returned to work and continued at work shoveling coal in and out of his wagon for a year, earning more money than before the accident. The doctor would not say he had a disability at the hearing, July 14, 1921. Compensation denied and case dismissed. 4-123: Tom Harmon vs. Rivett Lumber Company, Omaha. I Insurance Carrier: (Jeneral Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Co.) On May 3, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff was injured when a pile of sacks of cement fell on him, striking on the right side of the head, face and body. The insurance company declined to pay compensation. A petition was filed and a hearing had, September 7, 1921. Plaintiff was given num - erous physical examinations and X-ray sittings, but not much treat - ment. Compensation was allowed from May 3, 1921, to September 7, 1921. In addition he was ordered to submit himself for treatment to restore him to his former physical condition at the expense of the insurance company. Case appealed. District court affirmed the Com - missioner's award. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 4-124: Jessie W. Webster vs. Omaha Structural Steel Works, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) Plaintiff alleged he received an injury to his back while in the employ of the defendant company. A petition was filed June 25, 1921, asking that compensation and medical expense be paid during period of disability. Case was heard at Omaha August 26, 1921. Plaintiff failed to show his condition was due to the injury com - plained of, but evidence of physician who treated the case was to the effect that his condition was due to disease. Compensation denied, and case dismissed. 4-125: William M. Gaskell vs. Jake Kaplan, Omaha. On or about May 6, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a carpenter, plaintiff ran a sliver into the top of his right thumb. It became infected and resulted in the total loss of use of thumb, also caused stiffness to the four fingers, the extent of which could not be determined for a period of six months. Compensation was allowed for loss of use of thumb or 60 weeks at $15.00 each week, medical and hospital expense as provided by law, also that a further hearing be had at the end of six months to determine the loss of use of fingers if there be any by that time. On appeal to the district court the Commissioner was sustained. The supreme court reversed the district court and the Commissioner. 4-126: Jacob A. and Matilda L. Schmitz vs. John F. Reader, Hastings. (Insurance Carrier: Standard Accident Insurance Co.) On July 2, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as a truck driver, Morton R. Schmitz, deceased, was killed when a railroad train ran into his truck. A hearing was had October 10, 1921. No tirst report of this accident was made by the insurance company. The burial benefit was not paid. Medical and hospital expenses were not paid, as required by law. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $15.00 each week, burial benefit of $150, medical expenses of $120, hospital expense of $31.30, and 50 per cent penalty for de layed payments of compensation. Case appealed. 4-127: Charles Churchill vs. Pacific Fruit Express Company, North Platte. On or about February 1, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a storekeeper, plaintiff slipped and fell on his back. He •worked two and a half days after the accident and then had to quit. Called a doctor who treated him 55 times. Plaintiff knew nothing of the compensation law and never had been informed by his em - ployer that he was covered by the law. A petition was filed in June, 1921, and a hearing had October 11, 1921. Compensation was allowed from February 1, 1921, at $15.00 each week until disability ends; medi - cal and hospital expenses as provided by law. Plaintiff was ordered to submit himself for further medical treatment to be paid for by defendant. 4-128: S. D. Rengler vs. F. H. Gllchrlst Lumber Company, Kearney. (Inaurance Carrier: New Amsterdam Casualty Co.) On July 24, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company 8 manager, a bundle of flooring dislodged and struck plaintiff on the loft leg below the knee. Soon after the accident plaintiff was advised </seg>
            <seg id="p057">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 57 to go to California for his health. This resulted in delayed payments of compensation, as only one check for $150 reached him. Compen - sation was allowed until disability ends, 50 per cent penalty for de - layed payments, together with medical and hospital expenses as pro - vided by law. Case appealed. Commissioner's award sustained with the exception of the penalty. 4-129: Western Glass &amp; Paint Company vs. E. E. Dunmire, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident 4 Guarantee Corp.) On August 9, 1910, while in the employ of plaintiff company, defendant fell from a ladder on his head and shoulders, injuring his back and abdomen. Compensation was paid to June 20, 1921, when a petition was filed to have a hearing to determine the disability. Compensation was ordered paid until disability ends. 4-130: Oscar Lundberg vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Plaintiff sustained an injury to his hand March 14, 1921, which resulted in a 75 per cent loss of use of middle finger on left hand, while unloading ice for defendant company at Ralston. Compensa - tion was denied by the defendant for the reason that employment was casual. A petition was filed July 1, 1921, and a hearing had at Omaha August 23, 1921. An award was made of compensation for nine weeks temporary disability and 75 per cent of the loss of the use of the finger which was permanent, making a total of 31% weeks compensation at $15.00 per week, together with hospital and medical expense as provided by law. 4-131: W. P. Deverill vs. Mrs. Gottlieb Goodman, mother of Frank Goodman, Omaha. I Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On May 28, 1918, while in the employ of W. P. Deverill, as foreman of laborers, Frank Goodman was killed. The insurance com - pany began paying $12.00 per week for 350 weeks to Mrs. Gottlieb Goodman, mother of Frank Goodman. On July 2, 1921, the insurance company filed a petition to have compensation discontinued on the grounds that at the time of Frank Goodman's death there was another unmarried grown son, named William Goodman. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $12.00 each week, less the number of weeks already paid. 4-132: Burt Gordon vs. Cottage Grocery, J. Asbyll, proprietor, Lincoln. On February 17, 1921, while in the employ of defendant, as a butcher, plaintiff cut the back of his thumb with a knife. He made an alleged settlement with his employer for $51.60, without reporting the accident to the department. Later plaintiff filed a petition. A hearing was had on August 11, 1921, and compensation allowed for eight weeks at $13.32 each week, less $51.60 already paid, together with medical and hospital expense of $66.00, as provided by law. 4-133: Alfred E. Barto vs. Ak Sar Ben Exposition Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On March 15, 1921, plaintiff was in the employ of defendant com - pany as a laborer, driving a team. Team ran away, throwing him from wagon. Fractured right hand. Compensation was paid for eight weeks. A petition was filed and a hearing had July 21, 1921. Com - pensation was allowed from June 30, 1921, until disability ends, to - gether with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">56 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 4-124: Jessie W. Webster vs. Omaha Structural Steel Works, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) Plaintiff alleged he received an injury to his back while in the employ of the defendant company. A petition was filed June 25, 1921, asking that compensation and medical expense be paid during period of disability. Case was heard at Omaha August 26, 1921. Plaintiff failed to show his condition was due to the injury com - plained of, but evidence of physician who treated the case was to the effect that his condition was due to disease. Compensation denied, and case dismissed. 4-125: William M. Gaskell vs. Jake Kaplan, Omaha. On or about May 6, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a carpenter, plaintiff ran a sliver into the top of his right thumb. It became infected and resulted in the total loss of use of thumb, also caused stiffness to the four fingers, the extent of which could not be determined for a period of six months. Compensation was allowed for loss of use of thumb or 60 weeks at $15.00 each week, medical and hospital expense as provided by law, also that a further hearing be had at the end of six months to determine the loss of use of fingers if there be any by that time. On appeal to the district court the Commissioner was sustained. The supreme court reversed the district court and the Commissioner. 4-126: Jacob A. and Matilda L. Schmitz vs. John F. Reader, Hastings. (Insurance Carrier: Standard Accident Insurance Co.) On July 2, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as a truck driver, Morton R. Schmitz, deceased, was killed when a railroad train ran Into his truck. A hearing was had October 10, 1921. No first report of this accident was made by the insurance company. The burial benefit was not paid. Medical and hospital expenses were not paid, as required by law. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $15.00 each week, burial benefit of $150, medical expenses of $120, hospital expense of $31.30, and 50 per cent penalty for de layed payments of compensation. Case appealed. 4-127: Charles Churchill vs. Pacific Fruit Express Company, North Platte. On or about February 1, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a storekeeper, plaintiff slipped and fell on his back. He worked two and a half days after the accident and then had to quit. Called a doctor who treated him 55 times. Plaintiff knew nothing of the compensation law and never had been informed by his em - ployer that he was covered by the law. A petition was filed in June, 1921, and a hearing had October 11, 1921. Compensation was allowed from February 1, 1921, at $15.00 each week until disability ends; medi - cal and hospital expenses as provided by law. Plaintiff was ordered to submit himself for further medical treatment to be paid for by defendant. 4-128: S. D. Rengler vs. F. H. Gilchrist Lumber Company, Kearney. (Insurance Carrier: New Amsterdam Casualty Co.) On July 24, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company s manager, a bundle of flooring dislodged and struck plaintiff on the left leg below the knee. Soon after the accident plaintiff was advised </seg>
            <seg id="p059">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 57 to go to California for his health. This resulted in delayed payments of compensation, as only one check for $150 reached him. Compen - sation was allowed until disability ends, 50 per cent penalty for de - layed payments, together with medical and hospital expenses as pro - vided by law. Case appealed. Commissioner's award sustained with the exception of the penalty. 4-129: Western Glass &amp; Paint Company vs. E. E. Dunmire, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On August 9, 1910, while in the employ of plaintiff company, defendant fell from a ladder on his head and shoulders, injuring his back and abdomen. Compensation was paid to June 20, 1921, when a petition was filed to have a hearing to determine the disability. Compensation was ordered paid until disability ends. 4-130: Oscar Lundberg vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Plaintiff sustained an injury to his hand March 14, 1921, which resulted in a 75 per cent loss of use of middle finger on left hand, while unloading ice for defendant company at Ralston. Compensa - tion was denied by the defendant for the reason that employment was casual. A petition was filed July 1, 1921, and a hearing had at Omaha August 23, 1921. An award was made of compensation for nine weeks temporary disability and 75 per cent of the loss of the use of the finger which was permanent, making a total of 31% weeks compensation at $15.00 per week, together with hospital and medical expense as provided by law. 4-131: W. P. Deverill vs. Mrs. Gottlieb Goodman, mother of Frank Goodman, Omaha. (Insurance Currier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On May 28, 1918, while in the employ of W. P. Deverill, as foreman of laborers, Frank Goodman was killed. The insurance com - pany began paying $12.00 per week for 350 weeks to Mrs. Gottlieb Goodman, mother of Frank Goodman. On July 2, 1921, the insurance company filed a petition to have compensation discontinued on the grounds that at the time of Frank Goodman's death there was another unmarried grown son, named William Goodman. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $12.00 each week, less the number of weeks already paid. 4-132: Burt Gordon vs. Cottage Grocery, J. Asbyll, proprietor, Lincoln. On February 17, 1921, while in the employ of defendant, as a butcher, plaintiff cut the back of his thumb with a knife. He made an alleged settlement with his employer for $51.60, without reporting the accident to the department. Later plaintiff filed a petition. A hearing was had on August 11, 1921, and compensation allowed for eight weeks at $13.32 each week, less $51.60 already paid, together with medical and hospital expense of $66.00, as provided by law. 4-133: Alfred E. Barto vs. Ak-Sar-Ben Exposition Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On March 15, 1921, plaintiff was in the employ of defendant com - pany as a laborer, driving a team. Team ran away, throwing him from wagon. Fractured right hand. Compensation was paid for eight weeks. A petition was filed and a hearing had July 21, 1921. Com - pensation was allowed from June 30, 1921, until disability ends, to - gether with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">58 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 4-134: Leonard Rouse v*. Ferry Screen Company, Omaha IiiHiiruure Currier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) On December 24, 1921, while In the employ of defendant, plain - tiff dislocated his index finger at joint, and lost majority of distal phalanx of the same finger and injured second finger, left hand. A petition was filed but before a hearing date was set, parties agreed upon a settlement according to law. Case dismissed. 4-1 34! - 2 : Milan Martinow, Boris Visty. administrator, vs. Armour &amp; Company, Omaha. On January 10, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, Milan Martinow, deceased, fell down an elevator shaft and was killed. A petition was filed and a hearing had on August 22, 1921. Plaintiff claimed compensation for dependent child 19 years old in Serbia. Compensation was denied because the Nebraska law does not allow compensation for dependent children over 16 years of age. Case appealed. 4-135: Earl Stiner vs. Gilinsky Fruit Company, Omaha. ( Insurance Carrier: Globe Indemnity Co On January 15, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a truck driver, plaintiff broke his right arm at the elbow while cranking a car. A hearing was had August 27, 1921, and compensa - tion at $15.00 each week for 112% weeks was allowed for 50 per cent loss of use of arm. Case appealed. District court allowed 225 weeks at $4.05 each week. Later a lump sum settlement was for $821.33. 4-136: Albert Anderson vs. Commercial Supply Company, Omaha. IllMMM Carrier: Integrity Mutual ('usually Co. I On April 10, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a roofer, plaintiff fell three stories from the roof of a building. He was paid compensation for nine weeks at $15.00 each week and later paid $100 for six weeks and four days and settlement receipt taken, being compensation to July 29, 1920. A petition was filed July 14, 1921. Hearings were had September 15 and 29. The Commissioner allowed compensation from July 31, 1921, until disability ends at $15.00 each week, subject to the provisions of the law, 50 per cent penalty for unpaid compensation from July 31, 1921, to date, medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 4-137: Simon Brothers vs. Bert Summit, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: New Amsterdam Casualty Co.) On February 14, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff injured his right hand. A hearing was held September 6, 1921. Compensation was allowed for 50 per cent of the loss of use of his right hand, being 87% weeks at $15.00 each week, medical and hospital expense as provided by law. Later a settlement was made with Summit for one-half the Commissioner's award. The Commis - sioner protested the settlement before the insurance commissioner and later the judge who approved the settlement set it aside. The case is now in the district court awaiting to be heard on its merits. 4-138: Gerald H. Way vs. C. F. Way 4. Son, Lincoln. i Insiiranci. Carrier: Georgia Casualty Company.) On March 3, 1921, while in the employ of C. F. Way &amp; Son, </seg>
            <seg id="p061">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 59 Lincoln, plaintiff caught the wheel of his motorcycle in the street car track and threw him from his wheel against a telephone pole, breaking right arm and leg and injuring his head. At the time of the accident he was on his way home to supper and had intended to go back to the store after supper. Compensation was denied on the ground that his injuries did not occur while he was at work. Case dismissed. Case appealed. On appeal the testimony was that plain - tiff was injured while at work and was awarded compensation In amount of $750. 4-139: Lincoln Traction Company vs. L. Dillard, Lincoln. i Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On January 14, 1920, while in the employ of plaintiff company as a laborer, defendant was struck on the right leg at the ankle by a stoker, fracturing the same. Compensation was paid until June 15, 1921, when the company filed a petition for a hearing to determine the disability. Hearing was had August 10, 1921, and compensation was allowed for 30 per cent of loss of use of right foot, being 45 weeks compensation at $15.00 each week, in addition to the amount al - ready paid, and medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 4-140: Jack Reynolds vs. Fontenelle Hotel, Omaha. On September 20, 1920, while in the employ of defendant as cook apprentice, plaintiff slipped while standing on a box and skinned his leg about six inches from ankle up, causing ulcer. He went to Creighton free dispensary for treatment a few days. Was sent to St. Joseph's hospital as a charity patient. Was operated on for varicose veins on right leg at and above the knee. Injury to ankle was open sore. Up to time of hearing he had been charity patient In Milwaukee and Cincinnati hospitals. Then he came back to Omaha. Charity patient at University hospital and then sent to county hos - pital. All these hospitals had treated him for sore on the ankle. He was given Wasserman tests thirteen times, once the spinal test. In one instance 2-plus was found. In all other tests negative was reported. Was paid $60.00 and signed final receipt November 29, 1920. Petition was filed July 20, 1921, and hearings had August 22 and 26, 19-21. After hearing case plaintiff could not be found. In March 1922, insurance company paid eleven weeks compensation and final receipt was taken. 4-141: R. F. Samson vs. Cook and O'Brien, Omaha, I Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.) The plaintiff received an injury to his knee while engaged in doing some grading work for the defendant company. A claim was made for compensation, the insurance company contesting the case, contending that the plaintiff was an independent contractor; also that he had permitted the statute of limitation to run against him, he not filing his claim within one year from date of accident. The case was heard at Omaha December 8, 1921. The plaintiff admitted he was doing the work by contract, and employed his own help, also paid his employes out of the estimates paid him on his contract Case dismissed. 4-142: Edward L. Simon vs. H. J. Cathroe, Lincoln. (In^irance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.) On January 15, 1915, while in the employ of defendant as a (iBiaranee Carrk-r: London Gaarutcc ami Accident Co.) </seg>
            <seg id="p062">60 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT bricklayer, plaintiff was injured by being struck on the upper left side of the head by a basket, or container of bricks. Compensation was paid for total and partial disability for a period of 300 weeks. A petiticit was filed before the Commissioner for a hearing to deter - mine whether or not plaintiff was suffering further disability. After the hearing the Commissioner made further investigation in the case by consulting the surgeon who operated on plaintiff's head in the early period of his disability and also consulted a brain and nerve specialist in Omaha. The Commissioner then allowed compensation for total disability at 18.00 each week, during the balance -of his life. On appeal, the district court reversed the Commissioner. 4-143: David Naylor vs. C. H. Frey, Lincoln. tli.surniicp Carrier: Employers Liability Assurance Corp.) On the 6th day of November, 1920, plaintiff alleged that septic poisoning affected him while employed as a laborer putting putty on seams of glass roof of green house and that he had to quit January 21, 1921. A hearing was had August 31, 1921. No evidence of an accident was presented and doctors testified and made written state - ments that plaintiff was suffering from sciatic rheumatism. Com - pensation was denied and case dismissed because disability was from natural causes. Case appealed. 4-144: James M. Farlee vs. Swift &amp; Company, Columbus. On or about December 29, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff was spraying chicken batteries with a whitewash and dip solution. A spray of the solution shot out of the side of the nozzle into his left eye. A hearing was had in Colum - bus November 9, 1921. Plaintiff was ordered to submit himself with - in sixty days for an operation at the expense of the employer in an effort to restore his vision to normal. Was operated on December 24, 1921. Another hearing was had at Columbus April 20, 1922. Com - pensation was allowed for loss of use of left eye, being 125 weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case appealed. 4-145: George Freeney vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha On December 18, 1920, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as a laborer cutting beef for luggers under a sheep drop, plain - tiff was struck on the right side of the head and shoulder by a Eep that fell some 75 feet. Compensation was paid to July 9, 1921, $15.00 per week. On this date compensation payments were dis - tinued. A petition was filed and a hearing was had August 25, I. Further compensation was denied and case dismissed. DOCKET FIVE 5-1: Agnes Baroch vs. Hosburgh Cannon Sales Company, Lincoln. On July 4, 1921, Will J. Baroch of Geneva, Nebraska, employed by defendant company to make contracts for sales in various parts of the country, was injured in an automobile accident between Roscoe and Absarokee, Montana, where the party in the automobile was go- </seg>
            <seg id="p063">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 61 ing to a Fourth of July celebration, and died July 7, 1921. His widow sued for compensation. The Commissioner denied compensation for the reason that deceased was not working at the time of the accident. Case dismissed. 5-2: Tracy Tolsby vs. Ford Motor Company, Omaha Insurance Carrier: V. S. Fidelity &amp; Guarantee f On May 27, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff fell betwen a car and loading dock injuring his side. A hearing was had September 1, 1921, and compensation was allowed for three weeks at $15.00 each week and medical and hos - pital expense. 5-3: John Carter vs. Morris Transfer Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) — Pending. 5-4: John Moran vs. Great Western Sugar Company, Scottsbluff. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.) On or about January 14, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a sweeper, plaintiff injured himself in attempting to lift a barrel of caustic weighing 700 pounds. Compensation was paid for 11 weeks and plaintiff was operated on for hernia. A petition was filed and a hearing had October 13, 1921, at Scottsbluff. Compensa - tion was allowed from date of accident to August 15, 1921, at $15.00 each week, less amount of compensation already paid, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 5-5: John Breth vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. John Breth, employed by the Cudahy Packing Company, was in - jured December 20, 1017, while standing on a ladder lifting bacon. He re - ceived a rupture which disabled him for two weeks. He was fitted with a truss and returned to work, working steadily until some time in March, 1921, when he was unable to continue doing the kind of work he had been doing. He was then transferred to a job tending door, but the rupture kept on coming down on him and he was dis - charged on or about April 15, 1921. He then filed a petition asking for compensation from the culmination of the injury sustained. Case came on for hearing September 22, 1921, and he was awarded com - pensation from April 1st, 1920, until disability shall have ended, ac - cording to law, at $13.60 per week. Case appealed. Later settled for $1,000. 5-6: Mike Ryan vs. Morris &amp; Company, Omaha. Plaintiff alleged he received an injury to his leg and knee on or about the 26th day of November, 1920. Employer denied liability on the grounds that disability was not the result of an injury but due to disease. A peti - tion was filed August 9, 1921, and a hearing had September 21, 1921. The evidence disclosed that plaintiff was injured and treated by the company physician. Later he was sent out to the county hospital, where the defendant's physician called on him several times. Compensation was awarded at $15.30 per week from date of injury, except six weeks that plaintiff worked, until disability shall have ended, also 50 per cent penalty, hospital and medical expense as provided by law. Case appealed. Sustained by district court. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">62 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 5-7: W. T. Mahoney vs. Peter Crawshuck, Omaha. On July 20, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a paper hanger, defendant fell from a ladder and broke his left wrist. A hearing was had September 2, 1921. Compensation was allowed from July 20, 1921, to September 2, 1921, as temporary total and 5 per cent loss of use of hand, or 8 3-4 weeks at $15.00 each week for permanent disability, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. Appealed. District court reversed Commissioner. 5-8: Nick Goss vs. Peoples Ice and Cold Storage Company, Omaha. I Insurance Carrier: Employers Liability Assurance Corp.) Nick Goss, employed by the defendant company, was injured August 15, 1920, by falling off a platform on to the tender of an engine, injuring his arm and hip. He later returned to work and worked a short time, but was unable to continue on account of the injury to his hip. The in - surance company denied liability, contending that the plaintiff's condition was not due to injury but caused by an old conditon. The case was heard and the Commssioner found that plaintiffs condition was due to the in - jury sustained while in the employ of the defendant and ordered com - pensation paid at the rate of $15.00 per week from August 2, 1921, until disability shall have ended. 5-9: Mary Nichols, widow of J. J. Nichols vs. M. L. Rawlings, Wymore. I Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.") On January 16, 1918, while in the employ of defendant, J. J. Nichols, deceased, clutch man in ice plant, had his right arm almost torn from his body and it was amputated shortly after accident. Compensation was paid for 170 weeks, when he died. A petition was filed and a hearing was had October 28, 1921, and again on January 13, 1922. After the evi - dence was in the Commissioner made further investigation by consulting state medical men. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $15.00 eaoh week, less the amount already paid, $100 funeral benefit and medi - cal and hospital expense as provided by law. Case appealed. 5-10: Carl Harden vs. F. L. Jacobs, Omaha Plaintiff was injured August 17, 1921. Case was heard at Omaha September 16, 1921. Defendant having been duly notified, failed to appear anu award was entered in favor of the plaintiff at $15.00 each week for 4% weeks, also the 50 per cent penalty, hospital and medical expense as provided by law. 5-11: Lincoln Brinkley vs. Russell L. Rouse, Hastings. On March 14, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a roofer, plaintiff slipped off the edge of the roof to the pavement, striking both heels, fracturing them. A hearing was had October 10, 1921, and com - pensation was allowed at $15.00 each week from March 14, 1921, to August 22, 1921, and $34.00 doctor bill. Case appealed. Commissioner's award was affirmed. 5-12: Carl J. Nosky vs. Farmers Union Co-operative Association, Paul. On June 2, 1921, while in the employ of defendant association, plain - tiff fell down a man-lift elevator, a distance of 35 or 40 feet, injuring his ankle, arm and back. The accident was not reported. The employer carried no insurance. A hearing was had at Nebraska City, October 26, </seg>
            <seg id="p065">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 63 1921. It was ordered that plaintiff submit himself for medical treatment within thirty days at the expense of the defendant, subject to the pro - vsions of the law, and that he be paid compensation from June 2, 1921, at $15 each week, until disability ends. Case appealed. District court affirmed the commissioner. Appealed to supreme court. 5-13: Dale Forsberg vs. The Battery Parts Company, Omaha. i I MKiir;i net- Carrier: (leneral Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Corp.) On May 16, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, as an automobile parts mechanic, plaintiff injured his eyes by the explosion of a battery. A petition was filed and a hearing had September 15, 1921, after which plaintiff was sent to a doctor for an examination. Before the hearing was concluded the parties agreed upon a settlement of $225 which was approved by the commissioner. Case dismissed. 5-14: W. M. Earls vs. Omaha Merchants Express Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee ami AttUent Co.) On August 5, 1921, plaintiff bruised right hand which became in - fected. A petition for compensation was filed, but before the hearing, parties agreed upon a settlement in accordance with the compensation law. Cas dismissed. 5-15: Carl Placek vs. Morris Packing Company, Omaha. June 17, 1921, while in the employ of the defendant company, plaintiff received an injury. A petition was filed for compensation, but before the case was heard a settlement was agreed upon in accordance with the compensation law. Case dismissed. 5-16: James A. McCarthy vs. Kritenbrink &amp; Sons, Omaha James A. McCarthy reecived a severe burn on the index and middle fingers of his left hand, March 12, 1921, while employed as a janitor at the Carlo-Vista Apartments for Kritenbrink &amp; Sons, owners, who denied compensation, claiming no loss of time. Petition was filed claiming a permanent loss of function his index finger. Case came on for hearing September 16, 1921. A further hearing was asked in order to get the testimony of the doctor who treated the burn. The case was again heard October 8, 1921, and the plaintiff was awarded medical treatment ac - cording to law and ordered to submit to further examination six months from date to determine functional loss to finger. Later examination showed a loss of 40 per cent and he was awarded compensation at the rate of $7.70 per week for a period of 14 weeks. 5-17: William B. Booth vs. R. O. Stake and Omaha Steel Works, Schuyler. On May 2, 1921, while in the employ of defendant, plaintiff was in - jured by a heavy piece of steel falling on his right foot. Petition was filed for compensation, but before the case was heard a settlement was agreed upon in accordance with the compensation law. Case dismissed. 5-18: Petra Lindblad vs. Alex K. Zakem, Fremont. On July 22, 1921, while in the employ of deefndant as a cook, de - fendant burned her arm from flying particles off a stove. Infection set in and she was disabled for four weeks. A hearing was had October 10, 1921, and compensation was allowed for three weeks at $11.33 each week and $21.00 medical expense as provided by law. Case appealed. I Insurance Currier: Travelers Insurance Cn.) i insuiMiK't' Carrier: Employers Liability Assurance Corp.) </seg>
            <seg id="p066">64 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 5-19: Walter Brown vs. Roberts Sanitary Dairy, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Company.) On July 12, 1921, while in the employ of Roberts Sanitary Dairy, plaintiff was thrown out of a wagon when the horse that he was driving became frightened and ran away. Brown sustained a serious injury to his knee. Compensation was paid for nearly 7 months. Insurance com - pany then stopped payments, denying further liability, whereupon plain - tiff filed a petition for a hearing. The hearing was had and he was awarded compensation until disability ends, plus hospital and medical ex - penses. Case appealed. Settled for $400. 6-20: Harold L. Bridges vs. M. T. Cumings Coal &amp; Grain Company, Lincoln. iliisuruuic Currier: United States Fidelity &amp; Guarantee Company.) On August 25, 1921, while unloading coal for defendant company, Harold L. Bridges received an injury by having a lump of coal weighing 60 pounds roll on his foot. Petition was filed. A hearng was held on September 26, 1921. Bridges was awarded $28. SO compensation, together with medical expenses. 5-21: Wesley Sutton vs Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Plaintiff filed a petition September 5, 1921, asking for compensation for a disability alleged to be caused by tuberculosis, contracted in the course of his employment with the defendant company. The case was heard at Omaha September 23, 1921, and it was determined that the dis - ability complained of was not compensabla under the law. Case dismissed. 5-22: Sam Lei vs. Western Heating A Plumbing Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: United States Fidelity &amp; Guarantee Company.) Plaintiff received injuries by a ditch caving in and some dirt striking him while employed by the defendant. No agreement could be reached as to the period of disability as the plaintiff has not worked since injury and refused to go back to work for the defendant after the doctors re - ported him able to work. A petition was filed and the case heard at Omaha, December 19, 1921. The defendant showed by reports of several doctors and J^-ray plates that the plaintiffs disability should not have extended over a period of two weeks. Four weeks' disability having been allowed by the defendant. Case dismissed. 5-23: W. O. Evans vs. Omaha &amp; Council Bluffs Street Railway Company, Omaha. Plaintiff was injured while employed as a motorman for defendant company while coupling on to a "dead" car. The draw bar slipped, striking him on the shin. Defendant denied liability on the grounds that plantiff was sufferng from a varicose condition and not due to an injury. A petition was filed and a hearing had at Omaha. Plaintiff was awarded compensation at $15 per w'eek for a period of 6 weeks and four days together with hospital and medical expenses as provided by law. Case appealed. Reversed by the district court. 5-24: Peter Fries vs. Nebraska Hotel Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Employers Liability Assurance Corp.) Peter Pries, while in the employ of the Lincoln Hotel, received an Injury to his index finger when a 300 pound cake of ice slipped which he was handling. Upon filing a petition the insurance company assumed liability and Fries was paid $75.75 compensation and hosiptal and medi - cal- expenses. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 65 2-25: John Alvin McCord vs. Pacific Fruit Express, North Platte Pending. 6-26: John R. Slingerland vs. Western Union Telegraph Company, Omaha On February 4, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a messenger boy, plaintiff was run into by a Ford car, injuring his back and foot. Medical and hospital bill of 1105.00 was paid in July and $52.72 was pad in compensation to the boy's mother in two payments. A petition was tiled to recover additional compensation. A hearing was had September 26. 1921, when it was shown plaintiff had been paid for one week's compensation more than he had coming and that the doctor and hospital bill had been paid. Case dismissed. 5-27: Jacob W. Mclntosh vs. Condon &amp; Bollen, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Co.) Plaintiff sustained an injury while in the employ of defendant com - pany, being struck several times on the head with a pair of iron knuckles by the foreman. A dispute arose as to the per cent of loss of hearing in one ear. Case* was tried by stipulation, doctors' reports were submitted and the assistant commissioner recommended that plaintiff be awarded compensation for two weeks' temporary total and 40 per cent loss of hearing in one ear, or a total of 22 weeks at $14.00 per week, together with hospital and medical expense, as provided by law. 5-28: Patrick Conlin vs. C. H. Buffington, Omaha. Plaintiff alleged that he had been injured by having his finger cut in a lawn mower and that a spider had bitten his heel while he slept in a room provided by his employer. He asked that compensation be awarded him during the period of disability from September 9, 1921, to October 1, 1921. The case was heard September 14, 1921. The evidence failed to show that he had been injured in the course of his employment, but a spider that bit him during the night caused his disability. Com - pensation denied. 5-29: Arthur Taylor vs. Central Bridge &amp; Construction Company, Wa - hoo. Pending. 5-30: Raymond N. Buck vs. Armour &amp; Company, Crookston. Plaintiff received severe injuries in an automobile accident while engaged as a traveling representative of the defendant company. They disagreed as to the amount of compensation due. A petition was filed and the case was heard at Omaha by agreement of both sides. (Acci - dent happened near Crookston, Neb.) An award was made allowing the plaintiff compensation for a period of 27 1-2 weeks from September 29, 1920. at $15 a week until plaintiff was able to resume his work as a salesman; also $200 hospital and medical expense was allowed according to law. 5-31: Jacob Mattox vs. Union Stock Yards Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London (lunrantee and Accident Co.) On or about May 5, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a water man, plaintiff was knocked down when a wild steer plunged through a gate of one of the pens at the stock yards. Plaintiff struck the back of his head on the hard pavement, causing concussion. Compen- </seg>
            <seg id="p068">66 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT sation was paid for thirteen weeks. A hearing was had November 14, 1921. Compensation was allowed at $15 each week until disability ends as provided by law. 5-32: Gustave Claussen vs. McCaffey Brothers Company, Omaha. The plaintiff was injured in the course of bis employment by falling over a barrel of lime. A dispute arose as to the period of disability and the plaintiff's ability to do the kind of work he did before the injury. A hearing was had at Omaha January 3, 1922, and plaintiff was awarded compensation at $15 per week from date of injury, June 9, 1921, less amount already paid, and surgical and medical expense as provided by law. Case appealed. 5-33: Nebraska Power Company vs. Mrs. Harry Lighthall, Omaha. On August 6, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff company, Alfred L. Hewitt, deceased, came to his death while sliding down a rope into a coal bunker. A hearing was had October 7, 1921, to determine the dependency of his mother. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $10 each week, being the amount he contributed to his mother in proportion to his wages, also $150 burial benefit, and medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case appealed. Settled for $2,386.60 and medical and 'hospital expenses. 5-34: Minnie D. Weaver vs. Beatrice Creamery Company, Lincoln. On June 30, 1921, W. J. Weaver died from injuries received on Oc - tober 13, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company. Compensa - tion was paid during disability following the injury. This petition was filed by his widow as dependent. A hearing was held May 31. 1922, and compensation was allowed for 350 weeks, less the amount already paid, at $15 each week and $150 burial benefit. 5-35: Fred Colton vs. Terminal Warehouse Company, Omaha. I Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co. On July 27, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintil. was struck on head with a pile of tractor plow beams. Petition was filed for compensation, but before a hearing was held, parties came to an agreement and a settlement was made in accordance with the compen - sation law. Case dismissed. 5-35J: James Nellis vs. A. H. Rait, Lincoln James Nellis, a carpenter, while in the employ of A. H. Rait, sus - tained an injury by falling from a scaffold. Liability was denied and Mr. Nellis filed a petition. A hearing was held and he was awarded compensation at the rate of $15 per week for a period of 3 days, plus medical expense. 5-36: E. F. Moore vs. Wood Brothers Construction Company, Bellevue. I Insurance Carrier: New Amsterdam Casualty Co.) September 8, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a deck hand on the Missouri river near Bellevue, plaintiff drank river water on two days when the ice ran out. It had been the custom to use con - densed water when they had ice, but on those two days when there was no ice, plaintiff drank river water and contracted typhoid fever. He 1 1 nsu raiKc Carrier: Tltnkti Insurance Co.) IIiiHurnnrp Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; &lt; .imruntee Corp.) </seg>
            <seg id="p069">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 67 went to a hospital and was disabled from September 10 to October 4, 1921. A hearing was had October 21, 1921. Compensation was denied and case was dismissed. 5-37: H. L. Tribner vs. Nebraska Cement Company, Superior. — Pending. 5-38: Table Rock Brick and Material Company vs. L. P. Jones, Table Rock. I Insurance farrier: Travelers Insurance Company.) On May 11, 1921, while in the employ of the Table Rock Brick and Material company as a laborer, defendant injured his right knee by tearing the ligaments loose. Compensation was paid from May 12 to June 29. A hearing was had October 27. It was ordered that plaintiff submit to an operation within thirty days and the compensation be paid at $15.00 each week from June 29 until disability ends. 5-39: Fairbury Ice Company vs. A. C. Wagner, Fairbury. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) On July 22, 1920, while in the employ of the Fairbury Ice Company as an elevator man, defendant fell with loaded elevator, two stories, in - juring his hips, knees, feet and head. Compensation was paid for total and partial disability to July 7, 1921. A hearing was had to determine extent of disability. Compensation was allowed for 35 weeks, in addition to what had already been paid, at $15.00 each week, together with med - ical and hospital expense as provided by law. 5—40: Eugene W. Woods vs. Monarch Engineering Company, Auburn. On September 1, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff was injured by a bridge cap falling on his left knee causing serious bruises above the knee cap. Petition was filed for a hearing on October 3, 1921, but before a hearing date was set the par - ties agreed upon a settlement in accordance with the compensation law. Case dismissed. 5-41: Harold Buehler vs. Alamito Dairy Company, Omaha. (Insurance Currier: Kinployers Liability Assurance Corporation On the 3rd and 18th of January, 1921, while in the employ of de - fendant company, plaintiff _ slipped on ice and dislocated cartilage of left knee. Compensation was paid for one week and plaintiff returned to work. In August plaintiff made a settlement with the insurance adjusters. The Commissioner declined to approve the settlement for the reason that he knew nothing about the case. A petition was filed and a hearing had October 22, 1921. It was agreed that the Com - missioner should decide the case on the reports of the doctors. Com - pensation was allowed for 25 per cent of the loss of the use cf the leg, being 37J weeks at $15.00 each week. 5-42: Rudge &amp; Guenzel vs. Helen Richards Carlson, Lincoln. I Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On or about April 26, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff company as an office clerk, defendant fell down a flight of stairs injuring her right wrist and left elbow. Compensation was paid to September 27, 1921. A hearing was had November 15. 1921, and compensation was allowed fcr 300 weeks, less amount already paid, at $2.10 each week, and $1.42 i Insiii ;iih ■!■ Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) </seg>
            <seg id="p070">68 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT each week for the balance of defendant's life. This was for 10% per - manent loss of use of right wrist and 25\Cr permanent loss of left arm. Case appealed. Lump sum settlement for $1,000. 5-43: Hilda Lundberg vs. Marie Tiernan, Lincoln. Hilda Lundberg claimed that while in the employ of Marie Tiernan. she fell and sustained a severe sprain and several bruises on her arm. A hearing was held and the Commissioner found that the injured was not an employe of the defendant. Compensation denied. 6-44: Jesse Vermillian vs. Kiewit &amp; Sons, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London (iuarautee &amp; Accident Co.) Plaintiff and insurance company could not agree as to the per cent of the permanent loss to plaintiff's finger. The case came on for hearing August 22, 1921; both sides appearing without counsel and after an informal hearing it was decided that the disability was such as to entitle him to 22J weeks compensation at $13.20 each week, less amount already paid. 5-45: John Lennon vs. Stewart Construction Company, Omaha. I Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Company, i John Lennon, an employe of the defendant, sustained a rupture. December 27, 1920. A dispute arose as to whether or not he should submit to treatment furnished by the employer or be paid compensa - tion during his disability. The insurance company paid him 10 weeks compensaton and on the advise of the attending physician insisted on an operation to reduce the hernia. A hearing was had November 10, 1921, when he was ordered to submit to treatment furnished and paid for by the employer, also compensation at the rate of $15 per week during the period of disability caused by such treatment. 5-46: Cudahy Packing Company vs. Birdie Lollis, Omaha. The defendant claimed she sustained an injury to her back by fall - ing while in the employe of the plaintiff. A petition was filed by the employer for the purpose of having the Commissioner decide if there was any lability on his part for the alleged injury. A hearing was had December 7, 1921 and defendant was ordered to submit to an examination by a competent surgeon selected by the. Commissioner. A report was later submitted showing no disability due to injury. Case dismissed. 5-47: Mabel F. King vs. Pullman Company, Omaha. Plaintiff received an injury to her head while employed by defen - dant company as a car cleaner on or about the 15th day of July, 1921, and was confined to her home and bed for a period of about 25 days, Eshe developed a case of mastoiditis, a recurring condition or ag - ition of an existing dorment condition. A dispute arose as to the ty of the employer and a pettion filed. The case was heard at la, December 20, 1921, when it was determined that her disability was a result of the injury. She was given an award of $15 per week compensation from date of injury until disability shall have ended, in addition to hospital and medical expense as provided by law. Settled for $2,872 lump sum with the approval of Commissioner. 6-48: Minnie Smith vs. Swift * Company, Omaha. Mrs. Minnie Smith, an employe of the defendant company, was injured by slipping on the icy dock, February 28, 1920, sustaining an injury to her sciatic nerve and also a fracture of the coccyx. The de- </seg>
            <seg id="p071">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 69 fendant company paid compensation at the rate of $13.73 for a period of SI weeks. A dispute arose as to her ability to resume work. A petition was filed and the case was heard at Omaha, December 29, 1921, and it was found that she was still disabled and recommendation was made for the continuation of compensation payments until disability shall have ended. 5-49: Elmer Fetters vs. John Ford, Omaha (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Company.) On May 19, 1921, while in the employ of defendant, painting a sheep shed, plaintiff fell fifteen feet when the scaffold broke and injured the ligaments of his left leg from the knee to the ankle. Compensation was paid to June 25, 1D21. A hearing was had November 10, 1921. Doctors testified there was nc permanent injury; that plaintiff was suf - fering from wearing a brace tightly laced on the leg and ankle; that ex-ray showed no bone injury; that if plaintiff would gradually loosen the brace and in a short time discard it his leg would become normal. Order of Commissioner was that plaintiff follow instructions of doctor and if at the end of sixty days the leg had not become normal he was to return to have his disability determined. Plaintiff claimed that he could not stand on his foot after removing the leather brace and con - tinued to work with it on his ankle. Later another hearing was had when three doctors testified that there was no injury to the bones of the foot and the disability the plaintiff suffered from was due to the tight leather brace worn on his loot and lower leg. After the hearing the Commissioner ordered plaintiff tc submit himself for treatment in a hospital by a surgeon selected by himself, with the approval of the Commissioner, at the expense of the insurance company, and that com - pensation at $15 each week be paid while receiving such treatment. 5-50: Carl Johnson vs. J. L. Brandeis &amp; Sons, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Company.) Carl Johnson, an employe of the defendant, suffered an injury which resulted in a double inguinal hernia. There wag a dispute as to the period of the plaintiff's disability. A petition was filed "and case come on for hearng. It was shown that owing to a stitch abcess and weak abdominal wall that made recovery slow, he should be entitled to com - pensation at the rate of $15.00 per week for a period of 23 and eight - tenths weeks, less 5 weeks paid since the date of hearing. 5-51: Malvin S. Sells vs. Omaha Taxi Company. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident. Fire and Life Assurance Co.) The plaintiff was injured while lifting a heavy taxi body for the defendant company. A dispute arose as to the liability of the de - fendant, inasmuch as the employe continued to do his regular work for sometime after the injury. The case was heard and an award for 7 weeks and 1 days compensation at $15.00 per week was given, to - gether with hospital and medical expense as provided by law. 5-52: Pat Hays vs. The Standard Oil Company, Auburn. Plaintiff was employed to paint a new service station for the de - fendant at Auburn, where he fell from a step ladder and broke the ankle and two metatarsal bones. Defendant refused payment of compensation on the grounds that employment was casual. A petition was filed Oc - tober 22, 1921, and a hearing was had at Auburn, February 24, 1922, when </seg>
            <seg id="p072">70 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT plaintiff was awarded compensation at the rate of $15 per week for 19 and one-sixth weeks temporary total disability and in addition com - pensation for 50 weeks. The same being for 33 and one-third per cent permanent loss of use of the foot, making a total of 69 and one-sixth weeks, together with hospital and medical expense, as provided by law. Case appealed. 5-53: Wm. H. Griggs vs. Charles G. Ruenker, Grand Island. On February 17, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as an auto mechanic, plaintiff's second finger of left hand was caught under car and crushed. Infection of bone followed and hand did not heal until August. A petition was filed October 25, 1921, and a hearing had on January 31, 1922. Compensation was allowed for a period of disability while hand was healing and 75 per cent of the loss of use of second finger of left hand at $15 each week, together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case appealed. Commissioner's award reversed. 5-54: Fred Tolles vc. J. H. Yost Lumber Company, McCool Junction. (Insurance Carrier: Employers Liahllity Assurance Corp.i On July 13th while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff ruptured himself. He visited one doctor once, bought a truss, wore it three weeks and then went to Omaha for "bloodless treatment for hernia." Insurance company refused to pay for treatments and traveling expenses for plaintiff. A hearing was had in Lincoln, November 30, 1921. Commissioner ordered plaintiff submit hmself for an operation in an effort to restore him to former normal physical condition. Also that he be paid $5.00 expended for a truss. 5-55: H. C. Smith et al vs. John White, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Standard Accident Insurance Co.) Clarence Smith, an employe of the defendant, received injuries that resulted in his death, while in the course of his employment. The action was brought to determine the dependency of the plaintiff. Case was heard on November 25, 1921, evidence introduced and case continued to December 3, 1921, when further evidence was taken. The commis - sioner found that plaintiff was entitled to compensation at the rate of $14.66 per week for 350 weeks, hospital and medical expense amounting to $61.75 as well as $150 burial benefit. Case appealed. 5-56: George F. Parrish vs. H. Pelton, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: New Amsterdam Casualty Company. George F. Parrish, an employe of defendant, received injuries that resulted in the total loss of his right eye and partial loss of the left eye, while demonstrating a car to a prospective customer. The Insurance Company contested the case, claiming that it was not a demonstration but that the parties were joy riding and also that plaintiff was intoxi - cated at the time of the accident. A hearing was had at Omaha. An award was made for compensation at the rate of $15 per week from date of accident until the loss of vision could be determined when a further hearing would be held to determine the permanent loss of vision. Case appealed. 5-57: Will Wattley vs. Armour A. Company. Will Wattley sustained an injury to his ankle May 10, 1921, while in </seg>
            <seg id="p073">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 71 the employ of the defendant company. A dispute arose as to the period of disability. A hearing was had on November 23, 1921. The evidence showd that there was no disability after September 9, when the pay - ments of compensation were stopped. Case dismissed. 5-58: American Railway Express Company vs. Anton B. Rumery, Omaha. The defendant received an injury to his right knee while in the employ of the plaintiff on or about May 2, 1921, by a truck breaking through the pavement, throwing him out on the pavement. A petition was filed by the employer to determine the per cent of loss of use of defendant's leg. A hearing was had at Omaha January 19, 1922, and defendant was awarded compensation for 60 per cent of the loss of his leg, amounting to 129 weeks at $15 per week, in addition to amount paid for temporary total disability, hospital and medical expenses, as provided by law. 5-59: Paxton Mitchell Company vs. Don G. Higbee, Omaha, Insurance Currier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee I'o.) On January 31, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff company, as a molder, defendant suffered an injury to his left eye. Compensation was paid. On November 8, 1921, a petition was filed praying for a hearing to determine the per cent of loss of vision to his eye. Compensation was allowed for a total of 53 weeks at $15 each week, together with medical and hospital expenses, as provided by law. 5-60: Swift &amp; Company vs. Joseph G. McNichols, Omaha. This case came on for re-hearing on February 3, 1922. At previous hearing compensation was allowed for total disability for loss of use of both hands. At the second hearing the commissioner allowed compen - sation for 158 weeks at $6.80 each week, and $4.69 each week for the remainder of his life, beginning on the termination of the 158 weeks. Case appealed. 5-61: Roy Merritt vs. Ringle Drug Company, Omaha &lt; Insurance Carrier: General Accident. Fire. &amp; Life AnBiirnnce Co.) Roy Merritt, while employed by defendant company, was thrown from his bicycle, injuring his head and neck. The employer refused to pay compensation. Plaintiff filed a petition, but when the case was brought to the insurance company's attention, the compensation was paid. Case dismissed. 5-62: Harry L. Harmon vs. Lincoln Gas &amp; Electric Light Company, Lincoln. (Insurance farrier: T\ S. F. &amp; O. Co.1 On May 15, 1918, while in the employ of the Lincoln Gas &amp; Electric Light Company as a meter reader, plaintiff slipped on a broken step and tell down a flight of stairs, injuring both feet. Compensation was paid to February 7, 1919, when plaintiff signed final receipts and returned to work. On August 1, 1921, he was compelled to quit work because tlie original injury culminated in total disability. A petition was filed for a hearing. Plaintiff submitted to operation and extent of disability was reduced. Compensation was allowed at the hearing for $251.56 for tem - porary total disability; $1.61 per week for 233 1-6 weeks, and $1.09 per week fcr the remainder of his life, medical and hospital expense as pro - vided by law. Later settled for $1,100, with the approval of Commis - sioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">72 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 5-63: Paul Laubsch v«. C. C. Bickel, Norfolk. (Insurance Carier: General Accident Fire and Life Assurance Corp.) Plaintiff sustained an injury to his knee by falling June 7, 1921, while in the employ of defendant at Norfolk. Owing to the employer's delay in making a report on this case the insurance company denied liability. A petition was filed November 8, 1921. and a hearing was had at Norfolk, March 6, 1922. Plaintiff was awarded compensntion at the rate of $15 per week from June 10, 1922, until disability ended. Also penalty of 5ft% from August 5, 1921, to date of the award, for failure to pay promptly the compensation. Plaintiff was further ordered to submit to surgical treatment to restore the use of the leg. Case appealed. 5-64: V. P. Chiodo vt. A. Commarata, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Aetna Insurance Co.) The plaintiff through his insurance company filed a petition to de - termine the disibility of Cammarata, who severely injured his foot while employed as a brick mason. On the 4th day of February, 1922, the case was heard and defendant was awarded compensation -at the rate of $15.00 per week for a period of 22i weeks, in addition to com - pensation amounting to $1,545 which had already been paid, together with medical expense as provided by law. 5-65: Adolph Wallert vs. Omaha &amp; Council Bluffs Street Railway Com- pany, Omaha. The plaintiff suffered an injury November 20, 1920, by being struck In the right eye with a piece of steel from the face of a hammer. A dispute arose as to the percent of vision lost. The doctors reports varied from 11% loss to industrial blindness. The case was heard at Omaha, December 27, 1921, and the plaintiff was awarded two weeks total temporary disability and 125 weeks at $15.00 per week for the loss of the right eye. 5-66: Herman E. Allender vs. Evans Laundry Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corp.) On December 20, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a driver, plaintiff had his left leg crushed below the knee when a fellow employe caused a car to jump forward and pin him against the wall of garage. His employer paid him full wages during his disability — $39 each week. November 12, 1921, plaintiff filed a petition askng for a hearing to determine whether or not he had a permanent per cent of loss of use of leg. Compensation was allowed for 7 1-2 per cent loss of leg, or 16 weeks at $15.00 each week. 5-67: C. R. Dudley vs. Goldsberry &amp; Soklyn, Lincoln. Employer carried no insurance and both parties appeared without counsel. On September 26, 1921, while in the employ of the defendants, plaintiff broke the thumb bone of his right hand at the base. A hearing was had November 29, 1921, and compensation was allowed for nine weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expense, and 50 per cent penalty for delayed payments. 5-68: Byrdee M. Needham vs. Nash Sales Company, Omaha (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Corp.) The plaintiff received a sprained wrist that resulted in a bursitis of the shoulder. The insurance company contested the claim, contending </seg>
            <seg id="p075">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 73 that a bursitis was not the result of strain, but is caused by trauma di - rectly on the bursa or some facial infection. The case came on for hearing December 5, 1921, and doctors' reports submitted showed that her condition could be due to this sprain received on or about July 17, 1921. She was awarded compensation for $15 each week until disability shall have ended. She was ordered to submit to treatment .uniished and paid for by the defendant. Case appealed. 5-69: James Oliver vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. The plaintiff alleged he was injured while in the employ of the de - fendant company by getting rust in his eyes from an iron i.ar he was using. A petition was filed and a hearing had at Omaha, January 23, 1921. The commissioner found for the defendant and the case was dismissed. 5-70: Louise Muldoon vs. Hayden Brothers, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Maryland Casualty Co.) The plaintiff was injured on or about June 30, 1921, while lifting a pail of candy, the pail catching on a protruding shelf or board back of counter. She was taken to a hospital and operated on, being disabled for a period of twelve weeks and one day. The insurance company con - tested the claim, contending that her condition was due to female trouble rather than the result of an injury. The case was heard December 5, 1921. Evidence showed that she was hurt by lifting, receiving a severe strain, causing immediate symptoms of an injury. She was awarded compensation at the rate of $12 per week for 12 weeks and 1 day, together with hospital and medical expense as provided by law. 5-71: W. J. Assenmacher vs. Alexander Brown, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Company.) On September 24, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff as a laborer, defendant slipped and bruised his right breast on the corner of a wheel - barrow, causing an absces. A petition was filed by the insurance com - pany. On the day of hearing the insurance company admitted liability and agreed to pay compensation in full from September 29, 1921, to De - cember 3, 1921, at $15 each week, together with medical and hospital expense. 5-72: Central Power Company vs. Roy Martin, Kearney. On December 6, 1920, while in the employ of plaintiff company, as a gas maker, defendant was injured in a gas explosion. Company paid compensation and filed a petition November 21, 1921, to have the Com - missioner determine the per cent of loss of use of right arm. On January 19, 1922, the case was heard informally and examining doctor found he had 60 per cent loss of use of arm. This would be 135 weeks at $15.00 each week, or a total of $2,025. Case appealed. District court allowed 60 per cent loss of use of hand, or 105 weeks at $15.00 each week. 5-73: Edward Madelaine vs. Nebraska Tire &amp; Rubber Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Corp.) This case was set down for hearing December 12, 1921, both sides being duly notified, plaintiff failed to appear. Case was again set for hearing December 23, 1921. Defendant appeared by attorney. Plaintiff failed to appear. Case dismissed. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">74 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 5-74: A. L. Scott vs. M. M. Bree, Culbertson. On October 23, 1921, plaintiff was burned by gasoline about the left hand and wrist. Petition was filed but before a hearing was had par - ties agreed upon a settlement in accordance with the compensation law. A final receipt was executed and case dismissed. 5-75: William Playford vs. Wyuka Cemetery Association, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Maryland Casualty Co.) William Playford, while digging a grave at the Wyuka Cemetery, sustained an injury to his foot on September 3, 1921. Defendant de - nied liability. A petiton was filed and a hearing was held. Plaintiff was awarded compensation at the rate of $15.00 per week until disability ends, together with hospital and medical expenses. 5-76: George H. Baker vs. McGee, Incorporated, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Company.) On November 20, 1918, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff was delivering goods on a motor cycle. An automobile ran into him, throwing him against the claxon of another car, injuring him. The injury did not culminate until May, 1921, when he was operated on. Salary was paid during disability. A hearing was had February 15, 1922. An award was allowed for the payment of medical and hospital ex - pense as provided by law. 5-77: Dora and Church Wright vs. The Home Builders, Inc., and Union Insulating and Construction Company, Columbus. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Company.) This case was filed for the purpose of determining the per cent of dependency. James Paul Wright, son of the plaintiff, was killed by electrocution while in the employ of the defendants. The evidence showed that he was making regular contributions for the support of his parents and they were awarded compensation at the rate of $6.38 per week for 350 weeks, also burial benefits of $150 as provided by law. Case appealed. Settled for $2,162.69. 5-78: Julius Broderson vs. Stewart Construction Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.) This case was set for hearing December 22, 1921, at which time de - fendant showed the Commissioner that an agreement had been made whereby plaintiff was paid compensation according to law, 30% loss of use of left hand. Both parties requested that case be dismissed. 5-79: C. Z. McFarland vs. Olson Construction Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: I*. S. F. &amp; G. Co.) Some time during August, 1920, while working for Olson Construc- t company, plaintiff sustained a broken bone in his foot. At the time ie injury it was not considered serious, but it later developed into •ious condition. A petition was filed and a hearing held. Plaintiff awarded compensation at the rate of $15.00 each week until dis ty ends, together with hospital and medical expense as provided iWi 5-80: John Stoner vs. Walter Thatcher and J. C. Griswold, Omaha. John Stoner a plumber was injured by falling, striking his back on a corner of a box while in the employ of Walter Thatcher, contractor, doing some work for J. C. Griswold. The contractor wanted to pay com- </seg>
            <seg id="p077">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 75 pensation as provided by law, but was unable to do so at the time. He gave the plaintiff $10 and an order on a third party for whom he had done some work. This order the party refused to honor. A petition was filed and a hearing had February 16, 1922. An award was made giving plaintiff compensation at the rate of $15.00 per week for 61 weeks; also doctor and medical expense, as provided by law. Case ap - pealed. District Court allowed compensation for five weeks and four days. 5-81 : Earl E. Sharp v*. Great Western Sugar Company, Scottsbluff. (Insurance Currier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.) On November 7, 1919, while in the employ of defendant as a beet washer, plaintiff slipped on stairs and strained his back and side. He was given treatment for two weeks and continued working until early in January, 1921. Between February 10, and 15, 1921, he submitted to au operation on a tubercular abscess of his back. He did not work from that time to date of hearing. On January 18. 1922, a hearing was had at the plaintiff's home aud testimony of plaintiff and two surgeons was taken. The Commissioner found that the man had a tubercular spine which was caused by the injury in 1919, and allowed compen - sation from February 15, 1921, until disability ends, at $15.00 each week. Plaintiff was ordered to submit himself for medical treatment to be paid for by defendant in an effort to restore him to his former normal condition. Case appealed. Commissioner was sustained in District and Supreme Court. 5-82: Mrs. Stella Hensley vs. Westminster Women's Society of Lincoln and Mrs. L. J. Dunn, president, and Mrs. E. A. Pegler et al. On the 7th day of September, 1921, while in the employ of defendant at their restaurant on the Nebraska State Fair grounds, plaintiff cut the index finger of her right hand with a potato knife. Infection set in and on October 12, 1921, the finger was amputated. A hearing was had a.id the Commissioner allowed plaintiff two weeks temporary total disability and thirty-five weeks on account of the loss of the finger, being 37 weeks at $15.00 each week or a total of $555.00. Case ap - pealed. 5-83: Jewel Tea Company vs. W. D. Campbell, Nebraska City. Defendant received an injury while in the employ of the plaintiff as a salesman at Nebraska City. While cranking the car furnished by the employer it back-fired, breaking the wrist of defendan't right arm. Compensation was paid for a period of 6 weeks for temporary disability. A petition was then filed by the employer November 9, 1921, asking for a hearing before the Commissioner for the purpose of determining if there was any further liability. A hearing was had at Nebraska City March 20, 1922. The defendant was awerded compensation at $15.00 per week for 35 weeks same being for 20% loss of use of right hand. Case appealed. 5-84: Walter Ernst vs. A. J. Benson, on behalf of Earl Long, Deceased, Grand Island. (Insurance Carrier: Aetna Insurance Company.) On November 18, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff as a baker, Earl Long, deceased, was instantly killed by accident. A petition was filed by the insurance company to establish dependency on the part of the boy's grandfather, A. J. Benson, with whom he had been living for </seg>
            <seg id="p078">76 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT two years prior to his death. A hearing was had ou January 31, 1922, and compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $5.33 each week, $150.00 burial benefit and medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 5 85: F. C. Crossley vs. Charles C. Rork, Kearney. (Insurance Carrier: Employers Liability Assurance Corp.) On March 20, 1920, while in the employ of plaintiff as a carpenter, defendant fell a distance, fracturing his left hip. The fracture was not discovered until January 19, 1921. He signed a final settlement receipt on the advice of his doctor May 21, 1920. The case was reopened in September, 1921, and compensation was paid from the date of last payment and continued. Upon further examination it was determined that defendant had lost the use of his left leg. Compensation was al - lowed for 215 weeks, dating from January 27, 1921. at $15.00 each week together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 5-86: William J. Brenton vs. North Platte Light and Power Company, North Platte. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co. and London Guarantee &amp; Ac- The plaintiff, an employe of the North Platte Light &amp; Power Com - pany at North Platte, Nebraska, received an injury August 16, 1919, that did not disable him until December 14, 1921. A petition was filed to determine whether or not the disability was due to the original injury or an aggravation of a condition existing produced by a subsequent strain. The case was heard at Omaha by agreement January 19, 1922, and it was decided that the condition was a culmination of the first injury and an award made holding the London Guarantee &amp; Acident Company liable for compensation and treatment ordered. Compensation has allowed at the rate of $15.00 per week from December 14, 1921, until disability ended, hospital and medical expense as provided by law. 5-87: Nebraska Material Company vs. Jack Frost, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: U. S. F. &amp; G. Co.) On December 26, 1919, while in the employ of the Nebraska Ma - terial Company as a laborer, defendant was walking backwards pulling a car of cement out of a kiln. The car ran off of transfer and caught defendant between car and partition wall, breaking both legs, below the knees. Compensation was paid at $15.00 each week from date of acci - dent until December 8, 1921, when a petition was filed by the insurance company asking for a hearing to determine the permanent disability. A hearing was had on December 28, 1921, and January 11, 1922. The Commissioner ordered defendant to submit himself within thirty days for surgical treatment at the expense of plaintiff, to the end that he be restored as far as possible to his former normal physical condition. Case appealel. 5-88: George Schlacter vs. Fontenelle Hotel, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.) Plaintiff alleged that on the 23rd day of October, 1921, he had his throat and neck slashed by an employe of the above named defendant. Petition was filed for a hearing December 8th, 1921. The case was set for hearing reveral times but each time plaintiff failed to make an appearance. Case dismissed. cident Co. ) </seg>
            <seg id="p079">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 77 5-89: Edward Garnsey vs. Edward S. Flor, Omaha Plaintiff alleged that he received an injury while employed by the defendant. His back was sprained, resulting in partial paralysis of the left side of body and the right side of the face. ' A hearing was had at Omaha by agreement of both parties January 20, 1922, and the Commissioner found the plaintiff's disability due to cerebral hemorrhage and not the result of injury. Case dismissed. 5-90: Ed Warren vs. E. E. Calwell, Dawes County. January 28, 1921, while in the employ of the defendant as a car - penter, plaintiff fell from the roof of a building he was working on, injuring one of his legs. A petition was filed and a hearing held in Hay Springs, March 7, 1922. Compensation was allowed at $9.23 each week for nine weeks for temporary total disability. It was further ordered that plaintiff sumbit himself for an examination to determine the permanent disability he had sustained. Case appealed. Commis - sioner's award reversed. 5-91: John E. Finnegan vs. Condon &amp; Bolen, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident, Fire and Life Assurance Corp.) On October 14, 1921, while in the employ of defendants as a laborer, plaintiff injured his arm and back when horses jerked scraper that plaintiff was handling. Compensation was paid. A hearing was had on May 4, 1922, to determine per cent of loss of use of the left arm. Compen - sation was allowed for 60 per cent of loss of use of left arm, being 13b weeks at $15.00 each week, together with medical and hospital expenses, as provided by law. Also $G.0O for expenses to Omaha and $3.60 ex - pended by plaintiff. Case appealed. 5-92: Emit Levitus vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha On February 8, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a ham skinner, plaintiff scratched his left hand on a ham bone, later becoming infected. On June 10. a final settlement receipt was signed for $430.00. On December 9, 1921, plaintiff filed a petition for further compensation. On January 7, 1922, a hearing was had and compensation was allowed for 50 per cent loss of use of his hand, being $1,537.50, less amount already paid. Case appealed. District Court affirmed Commis - sioner's award. 5-93: Anton James vs. Dold Packing Company, Omaha. On August 11, 1921, while in the employment of defendant company, plaintiff fractured the metatarsal bone of left foot when a truck turned over and a piece of iron fell on it. Compensation was paid and medical treatment furnished. Friends of the injured man gave him advice ana he refused the medical treatment furnished by the employer and re - quested another doctor to treat him in a hospital. The insurance com pany refused to pay further compensation or the second doctor and hos - pital bills. A petition was filed and an informal hearing had on De - cember 24, 1921. After hearing both sides of the story the Commis - sioner sent the injured man to an independent doctor to have it de - termined whether or not the operation was necessary. The Commis - sioner allowed the injured man compensation from the date of the acci - dent up to the date of the informal hearing, but declined to order the employer to pay the second doctor and hospital bills. Case appealed. District Court affirmed Commissioner's order and award. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">78 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 5-94: The County of Boone vs. J. E. Tracy, Albion. tOn October 5, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff, as a laborer, de - ant was trying to remove a space block in the track, hit it with a mer and a piece of steel flew into his left eye, resulting in loss of &gt;n of eye. Compensation was paid and a hearing was had to de - line amount of compensation to be paid. Commissioner allowed com - iation for 125 weks at $15.00 each week; also $61.08 hospital, railroad and medicine to be paid by defendant. 5-95: E. E. Trimble vs. Consumers Tea and Coffee Company, Lincoln. On November 12, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff fractured his right wrist while cranking a car. A hearing was had January 25, 1922, and compensation was allowed for 10 per cent of loss of use of his right hand, this being 17J weeks at $9.91 each week, to - gether with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. 5-97: Fred C. Clemonc vs. Elmer Cary, Omaha. On November 3, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a sheet metal worker, plaintiff fell from a ladder, breaking his left leg. The undisputed evidence was that the employer instructed plaintiff to erect a scaffold upon which to do the work. This he neglected to do, and the accident resulted. Compensation denied and case dismissed. 5-98: Julius Borsen vs. Union Fuel Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident, Fire and Life Assurance Corp.) Plaintiff received an injury by falling off plank with a wheel barrow full of coal, while in the employ of defendant company. The insurance company denied compensation alleging disability not due to injury. A petition was filed and a hearing had at Omaha, January 18, 1922. The commissioner found for the plaintiff and awarded compensation from October 19, 1921 to January 13, 1922. 5-99 Thomas J. Adams vs. Pacific Fruit Express, North Platte. tOn January 23, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, ntiff was caught in a shaft while repairing an elevator and injured leg, side and back. He was treated until April 1, 1921. A hearing had January 16, 1922, at North Platte. Compensation at $15 each k was allowed until disability shall have ended and the 50 per cent Uty allowed for delinquent compensation payments from date of in - until April 1, 1921. 5-100: Logan Yule vs. Pittsburgh Glass and Paint Company, Omaha. I Insurance Currier: American -Mutual Liability Insurance Co.) On February 2, 1921, while in the employ of defendant com - pany, as a box maker, plaintiff alleged that he injured his back, arm, chest and jaw. On January 31, 1922, a hearing was had. Plaintiff was awarded full wages during the time he was disabled and he did not substantiate the claim that he was entitled to further compensation. Case dismissed. 5-101: W. A. Larson vs. H. S. Potter and Charles Hart, Lincoln. About the middle of January, 1921 while in the employ of defen - dants as a dairy laborer, plaintiff fell over a can, striking his right side, resulting in a perinephritic abscess. This developed in July, 1921. The </seg>
            <seg id="p081">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 79 plaintiff lost no time from work between January and July, 1921. A pe - tition was filed and a hearing was had February 14, 1922. The com - missioner on being advised found that the disability suffered by the plaintiff was due to natural causes and not from an injury. Case dis - missed. 5-102: Anton Fuxa vs. John F. White, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) This action was by the insurance carrier for the purpose of ter - minating the payments of compensation, defendant having received com - pensation at the rate of |15 tor a disability of 4 weeks and 1 day. A hearing was had at Omaha. January 14, 1922. Defendant claimed 12 weeks disability. His own doctor estimated the disability of not more than 3 weeks. An examination by a disinterested surgeon showed him to be suffering with a broken transverse arch which is a fairly com - mon occurrance and not a result of an injury such as this defendant com - plaied of. Further compensation denied. 5-103: John Tragas vc. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Plaintiff lost the middle, ring and little finger oi his right hand while grinding a cold chisel on a grindstone in the beef killing de - poriment ot me defendant. A dispute arose as to the liability of the employer, Inasmuch as he contended that the chisel was the property of the employe and he was doing the grinding during the noon hour. The case was heard at Omaha January 30, 1922. The evidence showed that it was customary for the employes to grind tools during the noon hour and also that he used the chisel in performing his work for the de - fendant company. An award was made for 65 weeks compensation at #14.40 per week, hospital and medical, as provided by law. Case ap - pealed. 5-104: M. Pearl Hines vs. City of Kenesaw i Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On May 27, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a mechanic, Ed Hines, deceased, was electrocuted on the roof of a small building he was working on for the village of Kenesaw. A hearing was had in Hastings. March 9, 1922, and compensation was allowed widow for 350 weeks at $15 each week, $150 burial benefit, medical and hospital ex - penses as provided by law. Case appealed. 5-105: Ralph P. Stone vs. City of Omaha. Plaintiff was injured wliile working for the city as a painter and decorator by falling from a defective ladder striking his back on a box and injuring his spine. A dispute arose as to whether or not his em - ployment was casual and not compensable under the provisions of the Nebraska laws. A hearing was bad at Omaha, January 27, 1922, and plaintiff was awarded compensation at $15 per week from October 21, 1921, date of injury, until disabbility shall have ended; hospital and medical expenses, as provided by law. 5-106: Louis D. Greusel vs. Board of Regents, University of Nebraska, Lincoln. On September 23, 1921, while in the employ of defendant, plaintiff strained himself, causing a hernia. A petition was filed and a hearing had February 8, 1922. Compensation was denied and case dismissed be - cause plaintiff was employed as a farm laborer, which is excluded from the provisions of the Compensation law. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 80 6-107: Uriah Bastrum Peek vs. Jerpe Commission Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident, Fire and Life Assurance Corp.) Plaintiff was overcome by gas from a heater in a railroad car that he was ordered to line with paper. A dispute arose as to whether or not his disability was due to this accident or disease. A petition was filed and a hearing had at Omaha, January 27, 1922. The Commissioner awarded compensation at the rate of $15 per week from December 21, 1921, date of injury, until disability shall have ended. 5-108: T. M. Hindel vs. Albert Frederick, Lincoln. On December 30, 1921, while in the employ of defendant, plaintiff had upper front tooth knocked out by 6-penny nail. A hearing was had February 16, 1922, and plaintiff was ordered to submit to dental treatment at expense of employer. There was no lost time or medical expense at time of accident. 5-109: Harold Standley vs. Mrs. E. H. Jenkins, Eagle, On November 14, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a car - penter, plaintiff fell against a brace holding a stall post in a barn be - ing erected, fracturing one rib and loosening another one. He worked three days, then went to see a doctor. Was off from work for a total of thirteen days. A hearing was had March 5, 1922. Compensation was allowed for one week at $11.20 and $5.00 doctor bill. Appealed. District. Court reversed the Commissioner's award. 6-110: Fred W. Brueningsen vs. Van Gilder &amp; Bottenfield, Hastings. (Insurance Carrier: Aetna Life Insurance Co.) — Pending. 5-111: Robert E. McAllister vs. Wells-Abbott-Neiman, Schuyler. (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Company) — Pending. 6-112: M. B. Travis vs. County Commissioners of Hall County. (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) On September 30, 1920, while in the employ of defendant, County of Hall, plaintiff, as a teamster, was thrown off a dump wagon be - tween the wagon and horses and injured his stomach and chest. Com - pensation was paid for ten weeks at $15 per week. On December 31, 1921 (seventeen days after the statute of limitation had run) plaintiff filed a petition for a hearing. The commissioner investigated the case at Grand Island January 31, 1922, and found that plaintiff had paid doctor, hospital and ex-ray bills of $41.35 during the time when the case was alive. The insurance company was requested to pay these bills. 6-113: W. R. Graham vs. Swift &amp; Company, Omaha. The plaintiff received an injury to his hand while employed by the defendant company and compensation was paid for 2} weeks at $14.88 per week. A dispute arose as to the payment of further compensa - tion, plaintiff claiming additional disability amounting to four weeks. A petition was filed and the case was heard at Omaha, February 14, 1922, and plaintiff was awarded compensation for two weeks at $14.88 per week from November 29, 1921, the date of the last payment of com- 5-114: Carl Muntz vs. G. A. Crancer, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) On February 19, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff, 16 years old, fell down elevator shaft injuring his head and </seg>
            <seg id="p083">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 81 hip and resulting in partial loss of hearing. Compensation was paid from February 19, 1921, to April 23, 1921, inclusive. A hearing was had February 15, 1922, to determine disability, and compensation was allowed for 75 per cent loss of hearing in both ears, or 75 weeks compensation at $6.00 per week, and medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. 5-115: Mary Warcek vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. On the 24 of September, 1921, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as a sausage packer, plaintiff was hit on the head by piece of pipe. A petition was filed for compensation, but before a hearing was held plain - tiff requested that the case be dismissed on the gorunds that she had been fully compensated. 5-116: B. F. McDougal vs. Wm. Schmidt, Lincoln On December 2, 1921, while employed by defendant to dig a well, a horse fell into the hole on top of plaintiff, dislocating his shoulder. A hearing was had February 7, 1922, and compensation was allowed for $50 and medical expenses as provided by law. 5-117: Leonard Long vs. Maust Brothers Oil Company, Falls City. I Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) Plaintiff in this case alleged that on December 16, 1921, he injured his side while employed lor defendant company; that he worked until January 2, 1922, when he layed oft and went to see a doctor, that Uoc tor told him he was slightly ruptured. A hearing was had in Falls City March 7, 1922, and medical testimony taken. Two doctors testified that they had examined plaintiff and found no hernia. Later the in - jured man's doctor wrote the Commissioner that plaintiff had tender - ness over abdomen and that such pain may have been caused by lift - ing. There was no evidence of a hernia. Compensation denied and case dismissed. 5-118: Carl M. Jordan vs. Morton-Gregson Company, Nebraska City Plaintiff sustained injury while employed by defendant which re - sulted in the amputation of his left thumb below the first joint. A dis - pute arose as to the liability of the employer, inasmuch as proper no - tice of injury had not been given. Also the contention of the doctor that injury was. an old one and probably there when plaintiff was hired. A hearing was had February 24, at Nebraska City, and an award was made in favor of the plaintiff for one week temporary disability and 60 weeks for the loss of thumb at $14.00 per week, also hospital and med - ical treatment, as provided by law. The first defense was a technical one furthermore defendant failed to show a previous injury. 5-119: Bert Lawson vs. Jess Kimberley and Daniel Frantz, Blue Springs. On November 22, 1921, while in the employ cf defendant, plaintiff got lime in his eye. The disability caused by the lime resulted in a total loss of vision in the left eye. Petition was filed against Kimberley, the contractor and Daniel Frantz., the owner. On March 7. 1922, a hear - ing was had and plaintiff was awarded compensation at the rate of $11.73 each week for a period of 125 weeks, together with hospital and medical expenses as provided by law. The case was appealed. 5-120: Bertha Wright vs. Dold Packing Company, Omaha. {Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) On May 17, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, Dave Wright, husband of defendant, in attempting to remove incandescent </seg>
            <seg id="p084">82 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT Iric light globe from socket, received an electric shock, which ed his immediate death. Wright had a wife and two children in Bay Texas. Burial benefit or $150 was paid by the insurance company, the relatives had difficulty in getting wife of deceased to come to ha and prosecute the case. A petition was filed January 20, 1922, a hearing was had. After the hearing and before an award was ten parties agreed to a lump settlement for $2,250 net to plaintiff, the approval of the compensation commissioner. 5-121 : Edward L. Green vs. Omaha Steel Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Southern Surety Co. &gt; Plaintiff claims he sustained an injury to his back while lifting boxes of sand as a moulder's helper. The insurance company denied liability for the reason that his condition was not due to a strain, but the result of a severe cold followed by the griup. A petition was filed and the case heard at Omaha February 10, 1922. The Commissioner found fcr the defendant, and case was dismissed. 5-122: William Brown vs. Crown Tire and Rubber Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Georgia Casualty Company.) On July 5, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plain - tiff lost his right eye by having it accidently cut with a knife. Compen- Em was paid until December 20, 1921, then discontinued. A peti - was filed, but before a hearing was had defendant admitted his lity and an award was made giving the plaintiff $11 each week for weeks, in addition to what had already been paid, 50 per cent pen - for delayed payments, and hospital and medical expenses as pro - by law. 5-123: Dora M. Duffield vs. Western Furniture Company, Lincoln ((Insurance Carrier: Aetna Life Insurance Co.) — Pending. 5-124: Ethel Morris vs. Woodmen of the World, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Employers Liability Company.) On November 11, 1921, while in the employ of defendant order, planitiff sprained her ankle, while participating in Armistice day parade. A hearing was had February 21, 1922, and compensation was allowed from November 11, 1921, to January 9, 1922, at $12 each week less two weeks already paid, and 20 per cent loss of use of fcot, being 30 weeks at $15 each week, in addition to total temporary disability; also medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. 5-125: Zeta M. Christensen vs. York Auto Company, York (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident and Guarantee Co.) On October 6, 1921, while in the employ of the York Auto Company as auto mechanic, Leonard Christensen, deceased, husband of plaintiff, strained himself in some manner while working under a car, result - ing in a knotting of a bowel. Three days later an operation was per - formed and he died October 9. A petition was filed Jenuary 27, 1922, and a hearing was had March 10, 1922. After the evidence was heard and before the award was written the commissioner approved a lump sum settlement for $2,500 net to the widow. 5-126: B. E. Smith vs. Albert Frederick, Lincoln. On December 22, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a car - penter, planitiff fell from a ladder and broke his left wrist. A hear- </seg>
            <seg id="p085">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 83 ing was had February 16, 1922, and compensation was allowed at $14.40 each week from December 16, 1921, to February 15, 1922, less two weeks already paid; together with medical expense of $45 as provided by law. 5-127: George Hite vs. Morris &amp; Company, Omaha. October 28, 1921, while in employ of defendant, plaintiff was in - jured by having the lid of a manhole slip and fall on the great toe of his left foot. Compensation was paid for 9 weeks at $15 per week. A petition was filed for further compensation but before the date of hearing, plaintiff executed a final settlement receipt in accordance with the compensation law. 5-128: Joseph Hudecek vs. Gordon-Lawless Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.) Plaintiff was injured July 2, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company by getting his fingers crushed in a punch press, necessitating the amputation of the distal phalanges of the index and ring fingers and the middle finger at the second joint of his left hand. The in - surance company paid the plaintiff 85 weeks compensation for the loss of the 3 fingers. A dispute arose as to whether or not plaintiff was entitled to a per cent of the loss of the use of the hand. A petition was filed and a hearing had at Omaha February 21, 1922. The defendant made a showing to the effect that they had paid plaintiff in full as pro - vided by law. Case dismissed. 5-129: Hutchins &amp; Hyatt Company vs. J. G. Merriman, Lincoln. (Insurance farrier: Ocean Accident and Guarantee Co.) On October 27, 1921, while employed by Hutchins &amp; Hyatt Company, as a teamster, defendant was seriously injured when the ambulance of Castle, Roper &amp; Mathews, ran into his team, overturning the wagon. On February 28, 1922, a hearing was had to determine per cent of perma - none disability. Compensation was allowed for 25 per cent loss of use of left arm, being 56J weks, at $15 each week, in addition to what has already been paid, together with medical and hospital expenses, as pro - vided by law. 5-130: Joseph Will vs. Charles Tillotson, Madison. — Pending. 5-131: Heady Eggers vs. C. M. Gay, North Platte. i Insurance Carrier: Maryland Casualty Co.) On April 5, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff was injured by a heavy piece of iron falling on his leg. Com - pensation was paid until September 16, 1921, then discontinued. Peti - tion was filed for further compensation, but before the date of hear ing the insurance company agreed to pay. 5-132: Steve Watrasy vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. On December 1, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, as casing inspector, plaintiff ruptured himself lifting a barrel of cas - ings. He worked two days, then stayed home during the strike. On February 4, 1922, he filed a petition, praying for compensation. A hearing was had March 28, 1922. Plaintiff was ordered to submit himself for an operation within ten days from date of award at the ex - pense of defendant company and that he be allowed compensation from February 4, 1922, until disability ends, at $13.16 each week. Case ap - pealed. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">84 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 5-133: L. McCandless vt. C. C. Bickel, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Kire aud Life Assurance Corp.) On May 19. 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a laborer plain - tiff fell a distance of five feet with a wheelbarrow load of mortar, sus - taining fracture below the knee and at the knee. Compensation was paid from date of injury to December 1, 1921. A hearing was had March 5. 1922, and compensation was allowed for 85 per cent of the loss of use of right leg, at $14.40 each week, in addition to compensation already paid, to date from December 15, 1921. Case appealed. 5-134: Milo M. Mitchell vs. Parsons Construction Company, Omaha {Insurance Carriers: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co. and General Accident Fire and Life Assurance Corp. I On October 8, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a bricklayer, plaintiff sustained an injury to bis left foot when a fellow employe dumped a wheelbarrow loaded with brick onto his foot. From this date until the latter part of December. 1921. he only worked about three days. In the latter part of December the left leg was ampu - tated a few inches below the knee. A petition was filed February S, 1922. Two insurance companies became involved in a dispute as to which one might be liable for the loss. The dispute being as to whether or not it was an Iowa compensation case. The Commissioner had hearings March 22, 1922; March 29, 1922, July 17, 1922, and July 19, 1922. At the March 29 hearing the Commissioner verbally dismissed the case. All this time the injured man was without legal advise. Later he retained counsel and his attorneys desired a hearing before the Nebraska commissioner. Inasmuch as the injured man was an - chored in the middle of the Missouri river, with one insurance com - pany saying it was an Iowa case and the other claiming it was a Ne - braska case, the Commissioner determined to give the man a hearing, so that the case could be appealed to the district court and the injury and jurisdiction could be tried out on their merits. Commissioner al - lowed compensation from October 8 1921 until December 24, 1921, for temporary total disability at $15 each week, and 150 weeks for loss of left foot, together with hospital and medical expense. Appealed. 5-135: Tony Ynkysh vs. Morris &amp; Company, Omaha. On November 5, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plaintiff ran a bone sliver in back of his left hand which become in - fected. A petition was filed for compensation, but before the date of hearing, the parties at interest agreed upon a settlement in ac - cordance with the compensation law. Case dismossed. 5-136: Alfred L. Calvert vs. Omaha and Council Bluffs Street Railway Company. Plaintiff alleged he was disabled from the effect of an injury sus - tained October 10th, 1920, after having worked at his usual work up to December 14, 1921. The defendant company denied liability for the reason, he made no demand on them within the statutory time of one year and that he suffered no disability as a result of an injury. A petition was filed February 9th and a hearing had al Omaha March 21. 1922, which was continued to September 5, 1922, to get the evidence of one of the doctors. The evidence did not disclose that there was any disabiblity as a result of the injury beyond the period paid for by the defendant com - pany and the case was dismissed. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 85 5-137: Harold L. Bridges vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Plaintiff claimed he suffered a permanent disability due to an in - jury sustained while employed by the defendant. A petition was filed and a hearing was held at Omaha, March 3, 1922. Plaintiff failed to show a permanent disability and case was dismissed. 5-137i: Odis Hayes vs. Lindell Hotel, Lincoln. (Insurance Currier: T"nlted Stales Fidelity &amp; Guaranty Company.) On or about the 25th of January, 1922, plaintiff sustained an in - jury by having a heavy piece of ice fall on his foot. He lost only one week's time and reported back tor work. Later a petition was filed and a hearing was held. He was awarded hospital and medical expense, hut no compensation, for the reason that he was only off from work 7 days. His wages were $65 per month. On appeal he was awarded compensation at the rate of $15 per week for a period of eight weeks. 5-138: Mrs. Eva Pugh vs. Thomas Cusack Company, Omaha. On January 9, 1922, while in the employ of defendant company as a fireman, James H. Pugh, husband of plaintiff, was obliged to stand in water to drain a boiler; get his feet wet, caught cold, developed into flu, then into bronchial pneumonia, causing his death on January 15, 1922. Hearing held March 27, 1922. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $15 each week, $150 burial benefit and medical and hos - pital expenses as provided by law. Appealed. District court reversed the Commissioner's award. 5-139: Bernard B. Regier vs. Hamilton County Commissioners, Henderson. On September 22, 1921, while in the employ of the defendant as a laborer, defendant injured his ankle above the heel, resulting in dis - ability until November 15, 1921. A hearing was had in Aurora, March 9, 1922, and compensation was allowed at $15.00 each week for the period of disability and 50 per cent penalty for delayed payments, also $10 doctor bill. The county commissioners formerly carried insurance on district road workers but on renewal of policy excluded these workers from coverage to save money. The commissioner declined to make any distinction between road workers employed by the county commis - sioners and road workers employed by road overseers. Case appealed. Settled without commissioner's approval. 5-140: Willet Harold Starns vs. Wright Electrical Construction Com- pany, Fremont. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corp.) On March 1, 1921, while in the employ of Wright Electrical Con - struction Company as a lineman, plaintiff was badly burned about the head and righi leg. The insurance company paid plaintiff compensation at the rate of $15 per week from March 1, 1921 to June 18, 1921, when plaintiff signed a final release and returned to work. When plaintiff re - turned to work he learned that he hart not fully recovered from the in - jury and worked only 20 days between June 19, 1921 and November 9,1921. The insurance company denied further compensation. A petition was filed and a hearing was held. Paintiff was awarded additional compensa - tion at $15 per week from June 20, 1921 to November 19, 1921, less the 20 days he had worked. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">86 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT £-141: Leo. J. Luther vs. Orleans Electric Light Company, Orleans. Plaintiff was injured July 5, 1921, by falling while removing wires from a pole, breaking his leg above the knee. Doctor bills were paid by the employer. A dispute arose as to the liability of the employer. A petition was filed February 23, 1922, and a hearing had at Orleans June IS, 1922. An award was made allowing compensation from date of Injury at $15 per week temporary disability until the extent of the permanent disability can be determined. Plaintiff was also ordered to submit to surgical treatment for the purpose of restoring the use of the leg to as near normal as possible, when another hear - ing will be had to ascertain the per cent of permanent loss. 5-142: Mason B. Buck, and Mason B. Buck, as administrator of the estate of Grover C. Buck, deceased, vs. The County of Lancaster, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: IT. S. F. Ic G. Company.) On November 14, 1921, while in the employ oi defendant as a trac - tor operator on the highway, Grover C. Buck, deceased, was injured when the tractor went through a bridge at Oak Creek, falling about o'O feet. Compensation was paid for a period. Later physical conditions culminated and he was operated on on January 13, and 17, 1922, but died January 17, 1922. A petition was filed by the young man's father and a hearing was had March 30, 1922. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks less, amount of compensation already paid, $150 burial bene - fit, and medical and hospital expense as provided by law. Appealed. 6-143: Julia Agnes Scott vs. City of Omaha. On February 9, 1922, James E. Scott, a probation police officer of the City of Omaha, was shot and killed while in the performance of his duties. Mrs. Julia Agnes Scott, his mother, aged 65 years, filed a petition praying for compensation under the compensation law as his sole dependent. A hearing was had on March 28, 1922, and compensa - tion was allowed for 350 weeks at $15 each "week, $150 funeral benefit and medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. 5-144: Frank Garcia vs. Swift &amp; Company, Omaha. Plaintiff alleged he had sustained an injury to his back by falling, while in the employ of defendant Company. A hearing was had at Omaha, April 4, 1922 It was found that there was not sufficient evi - dence to show that plaintiffs condition was caused by an injury and case was dismissed. 5-145: Mike McCarthy vs. Morton-Gregson Company, Nebraska City. Plaintiff received injuries to the index finger of the leu hand, while in the employ of defendant company, January 30, 1922. Claim was made for compensation but the employer ignored the claim and a petition was filed February 14, 1922. Before the case was set for hearing the defendant admitted liability and compensation was paid. 5-146: Donald Gaughenbaugh vs. George Bressler, O'Neil. On January 28, 1922, plaintiff fell through an open cellarway wrenching his ankle, causing disability for 5 weeks. A petition was filed for compensation, but before the date of hearing parties agreed upon a settlement in accordance with the law. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">87 STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 5-147: Arthur J. Hyland vs. City of Omaha. Plaintiff was injured September 21, 1920, by being thrown fro* a fire truck that was responding to an alarm on the south side. He struck his head on the pavement receiving severe injuies that disabled him fo a period of 14 months. A petition was filed March 3, 1922, and a hearing was had at Omaha March 2S, 1922. Defendant was willing to admit the injury but conteb-le4 that the city firemen Jid not come under the law when this injury occurred. Further, that more than one year had elapsed from the date of injury until demand was made for compensation and therefor could not recover. Defenses were sustained and compensation denied. 5-148: Charles J. Lodge vs. Lancaster County. (Insurance Carrier: U. S. F. &amp; G. Co.) — Pendhi 5-149: American Smelting &amp; Refining Company vs. C. F. Ward, Omaha. Defendant received an injury August 28, 1921. while in the em - ploy of plaintiff by having some molten metal splashed on him. Plain - tiff paid compensation to the amount of $495.00, then denied liability for further payments of compensation on the ground that defendant was blind in the right eye due to an injury received prior to the time de - fendant started working for plaintiff. A petition was filed March 7, 1922, by the employer. A hearing was had at Omaha, May, 3, 1922, evi - dence showed that the defendant had suffered a previous injury and had lost the vision of the eye before he was employed by the plaintiff. Further compensation was denied. 5-150: John Marcell vs. Union Stock Yards Company, South Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee and Accident Co.* — Pending. 5-151: Mrs. Jeanette Dubuque vs. Donley-Stahl Company, Lincoln. On March 16, 1921, while in the employ of defendant, Roy Clyde Dubuque, son of plaintiff, delivering goods on bicycle, was run over by truck and killed. Defendant paid the boy's mother $100 and paid the funeral expenses amounting in total $576.00. A petition was filed by plaintiff claiming compensation as partial dependant. A hearing was had April 5, 1922. Compensation was allowed for 350 weeks at $6,074 each week and $150.00 burial benefit. 5-152: Frank Goodro vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Plaintiff, while employed by defendant company gradually lost the use of his right hand and arm. A petition was filed asking for com - pensation, plaintiff contending that in working on a double seaming machine in the tin shop his arm became weak and partly paralyzed. Case was heard at Omaha, June 8, 1922. The evidence showed that plaintiff's condition was due to a slow growing brain tumor or en - cephalitis, and not caused by injury. Case dismissed. 5-153: Isaac Pharaoh vs. Morton-Gregson Company, Nebraska City. On September 8, 1921, while in the employ cf defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff fell and injured his ankle, arm and shoulder. A petition was filed March 11, 1922, and a hearing had in Nebraska City. April 19, 1922. Compensation was allowed for seven weeks and one day at $14.40 each week, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by law. Case appealed. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">88 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 5-154: Albert G. Frank* vs. Jetters Beverage Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident, Fire &amp; Life Assurance Corp.) — Pending. 5-155: Tom Thomas vs. Hippodrome Cafe, Louis Petros and George Ligias, proprietors. Plaintiff received an injury to his right hand by having his fingers caught in an exhaust fan while attempting to shut off the power. A dispute arose as to the liability of the employers, as they contended that plaintiff was injured on his own time before his day's work be - gan. A hearing was had at Omaha, April 5, 1922, and it was found that the injury did arise out of and in the course of the employment and plaintiff was awarded compensation at $8.00 per week from De - cember 14, 1921, together with hospital and medical expense as pro - vided by law. Plaintiff was further ordered to submit to surgical treat - ment paid for by the defendant to restore the impaired function of his little finger and receive compensation at $8.00 per week during dis - ability caused by said treatment. 5-156: Queenie Smith vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Plaintiff sustained an injury December 29, 1921, by being struck with, a conveyor falling from a rail. Defendant paid compensation at $10.24 per week from date of injury to March 28, 1922, when her doc - tor reported her able to return to work. A petition was filed claim - ing that on account of weakness in her shoulder she could not resume her duties. A hearing was had at Omaha, April 6, 1922 and she was awarded compensation and treatment until her disability shall have ended. Case appealed. Settled for $200. 5-157: Arvel C. Swearingen vs. Chamber &amp; O'Neil Wrecking Company, Omaha. Plaintiff received an injury May 26, 1921, which resulted in the loss of the index finger and some disability to the middle finger of his right hand, while in the employ of the defendants. A petition was filed for the purpose of determining the loss of use of the second finger, defendant having paid plaintiff 35 weeks compensation at $15 per week for the loss of the index finger. A hearing was had at Oma - ha, April 5, 1922, and plaintiff was awarded compensation at $15 per week for 71 weeks, being 25 per cent of loss of use of middle finger. 5-158: C. A. Bone vs. Joseph B. Tridle, Nebraska City. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Company.) Defendant received an injury to his arm while in the employ of C. A. Bone that resulted in some permanent disability. A petition was filed by the insurance carrier for the purpose of determining the permanent loss. A hearing was bad at Nebraska City .April 19, 1922, and an award was made giving the defendant compensation for 70 per cent loss of use of hand, being 11 2J weeks at $15 per week, dating from February 1, 1922. 5—159: John Monita vs. Omaha Tanning Company, Omaha (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) Plaintiff alleged he received a severe burn by getting his foot into a vat containing a solution of Tanic acid and water used for tanning hides, and was disabled for a period of 16 days. A petition was filed and a hearing was held at Omaha, April 10, 1922. There was not. sufficient evi - dence to show that plaintiff's disability was caused by an accident arising out of and in the course of his employment. Case dismissed. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 89 6-160: Earl Levell vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Plaintiff fell while employed by the defendant company, on Decem - ber 31, 1921, and injured his knee. A petition was filed March 25, 1922, claiming compensation at $15 per week during the period of dis - ability, also hospital and medical expense as provided by law. The case was heard at Omaha, April 14, 1922. Evidence showed that there was no disability immediately following the alleged injury. The surgeon who treated plaintiff testified that if condition was caused by fall there would have been at least one week disability following injury. His opinion was that the condition was of long standing and not a result of an accident. Case dismissed. 5-161: J. Russel Salsbury vs. Redpath Homer Chautauquas, Friend. (Insurance Carrier: U. S. V. &amp; G. Co.) Plaintiff suffered an injury in the course of his employment July 29, 1921, while double staking a tent just before a severe storm, which de - veloped later into empyemia requiring surgical treatment over a long period of time. The insurance carrier denied liability, contending that the condition was not due to an injury, but to disease. A petition was filed and a hearing had at Lyons by agreement. Plaintiff wa awarded compensation at $6.00 per week from September 11, 1921, until disability shall have ended. Also hospital and medical as provided by law. Appealed. 5-162: James R. McDonald vs. City of Omaha. Plaintiff received injury in the course of his employment that re - sulted in the amputation of plaintiff's left leg just above the knee. A petition was filed to determine the liability of the defendant. A hearing was had at Omaha, April 17, 1922, and the commissioner found that the plaintiff was entitled to compensation for 7 weeks temporary total dis - ability at $15 per week and 215 weeks at $15 per week for loss of the leg, also doctor and medical expense as provided by law. 5-163: Frank Schultz vs. Lincoln Inn Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) Plaintiff was employed by defendant company and received an in - jury that resulted in a badly infected hand. Plaintiff was paid compen - sation at the rate of $10.00 per week for a period of 10 6-7 weeks. A dispute arose as to the plaintiff's ability to resume work. A petition was filed and a hearing was held April 14, 1922. The Commissioner found that plaintiff had been fully compensated. Case dismissed. 5-164: Frank Bokla vs. Morris A Company, Omaha. Plaintiff was injured while employed by defendant company, shak - ing hides. On or about the 22nd day of February, 1922, he suffered an injury to his back. Defendant claimed they had no notice of injury or record of employment, and denied compensation. A hearing was had at Omaha, April 17, 1922. Some evidence was introduced and the hear - ing was continued to give the defendant an opportunity to investigate further. Later defendant admitted liability and an award was made granting plaintiff compensation at $10.40 per week until disability shall have ended, also hospital and medical expenses as provided by law. 5-165: J. H. Scoutt vs. Western Publishing and Engraving Company, Kearney. On October 21, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, as a traveling salesman, plaintiff broke his right wrist while cranking </seg>
            <seg id="p092">90 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT a car, also injuring the right shoulder. He continued to work at reg - ular wage until January, 1922. A petition was filed and a hearing had April 26, 1922. Plaintiff was ordered to submit himself for medical treatment to be paid for by defendant company; $15.00 a week com - pensation, from date of accepting treatment until discharged by doc - tor. A further hearing to be had to determine permanent disability, if there be any. 5-166: Ernest Beckett vs. Swift Packing Company, Omaha On December 20, 1921, plaintiff was injured by a piece of steel fly - %g off from a flue into his second finger. Infection set in, resultain. in the loss of the use of the finger. A petition was filed, but before the date of the hearing, defendant assumed liability and agreed to pay com - pensation in accordance with the law. Case dismissed. 5-167: J. W. Winter vs. Gooch Milling Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) On February 8, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, as a laborer, handling 100 pound sacks of flour, plaintiff bruised the left side of his abdomen, causing an abscess. A hearing was had on May 2, 1922. After the evidence was taken and before an award was written the parties at interest agreed to a compromise settlement, with the approval of the commissioner, for $88.00 and the case was closed. 5-168: Henry A. Voss vs. J. L. Brandies &amp; Son, Omaha. i Insurance Currier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On March 18, 1922, while in the employ of defendant as a furniture finisher, plaintiff suffered a double hernia as a result of a strain while lifting a box off a truck. A petition was filed but at the hearing it was shown the insurance company offered an operation immediately follow - ing surgeon's examination. Plaintiff seemed to be opposed to take op - eration. Commissioner ordered plaintiff to submit within ten days for operation and treatment for hernia to be paid for by defendant, and compensation at $15.00 each week during disability following operation. Insurance company volunteered to pay two weeks before and two weeks following day of operation in advance. Plaintiff failed to sub - mit to operation. 5-169: R. McCathern vs. Martain Schmidt and Holmquist Grain &amp;■ Lumber Company, Bancroft. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Co.) Plaintiff suffered a sun stroke August 27, 1921, while in the em - ploy of the defendant company at Bancroft, cutting weeds and doing other work about the yard. A petition was filed for compensation and a hearing was had at Bancroft, April 28, 1922. It was shown that the injury arose out of, and in the course of the employment and com - pensation was awarded at $13.09 per week from date of injury until disability shall have ended; not, however, to exceed 300 weeks, as provided by law. Case appealed. 5-170: Standard Bridge Company vs. Jack Corlett, Maywood. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) On November 1, 1921, while in the employ of the plaintiff company, defendant broke the knee cap of his left leg, while hauling steel beams for the bridge company. Compensation was paid from date of accident until April 1, 1922. Defendant paid the doctor bill of $63.00. He </seg>
            <seg id="p093">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 91 went to Omaha for examination in March. April 10, 1922, the London Guarantee and Accident Company filed a petition for the employer to have the commissioner determine the disability. After a hearing the Commissioner advised that defendant be sent to an orthopedic spe - cialist in Lincoln for examination and operation if necessary to restore defendant's leg to former normal condition. After an examination by an orthopedic surgeon in Lincoln, defendant (and his son) called at office and informed the Commissioner that he was afraid of an op - eration and expressed a willingness to take whatever the insurance com - pany saw fit to pay. The defendant impressed the Commissioner as being an honest man and one not attempting to get money in lieu of an operation. The commissioner suggested a compromise settlement, but the insurance company only wanted to pay for 15 per cent loss of leg and $150 additional in lieu of an operation. The Commissioner allowed 75 per cent loss of use of leg being 161} weeks at $15.00 each week and medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 5-171: D. J. Sheehy vs. J. L. Brandeis 4. Sons, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co. On May 30, 1921. while in the employ of defendant company as a stationary fireman, plaintiff suffered an injury to his right eye when hot oil squirted from an engine into it, resulting in loss of vision. A&gt; hearing was had May 4, 1922. Compensation was allowed for loss oi vision in right eye, being 125 weeks at $15 each week less amount al - ready paid, together with medical and hospital expense. Case ap - pealed. 5-172: J. C. Creegan vs. American Radiator Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Aetna Life Insurance Co.) Plaintiff claimed an attack of appendicitis was caused by seveiv. strain. Insurance company denied liability. A petition was filed and the case was heard at Omaha April 27, 1922. The Commissioner found that the condition complained of was not due to strain, but was caused by disease. Case dismissed. 5-173: Morris P. Warden vs. Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On December 12, 1921, while in the employ of defendant com - pany as a laborer, plaintiff stepped into a hole and injured his leg. Compensation was paid to February 14, 1922, and a final release taken. On April 8, 1922, a petition was filed by plaintiff asking for further com - pensation. A hearing was had May 24, 1922. Compensation was allowed for eight weeks from February 14, 1922, at $15.00 each week. 5-174: P. H. Gammel vs. W. J. Assenmacher &amp; Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Travelers Insurance Co.) On November 29, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff injured himself. Compensation was paid for 16 weeks. A petition was filed and a hearing wah had May 2, 1922. Com - pensation was allowed from November 29, 1921, to April 28, 1922, at $12.60 each week, less the number of weeks already paid, together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. 5-175: Ed Lewi* vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. On January 19, 1922, while In the employ of the defendant company as a laborer, plaintiff got rust in his right eye. Treatment was given </seg>
            <seg id="p094">92 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT and compensation was paid for one week and one day at $12.00 per week. Later plaintiff was sent to hospital for operation to cure eye. Plaintiff is blind in left eye. A bearing was had and compensation was Allowed for 12 weeks and 3 days at $12.00 each week, and medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 5-176: Mrs. Peder Johnson vs. Omaha &amp; Council Bluffs Street Railway Company, Omaha. On December 6, 1918, while Peder Johnson, husband of plaintiff, was in the employ of defendant as a watchman at 25th and Cuming streets, Omaha, he was found unconscious on the sidewalk or street sometime during the night. He was injured on the back of the head, right side and right arm. Compensation was paid from date of accident to February 3, 1922, when he died. At times during the period he was insane. His wife filed a petition praying for compensation as dependant under the law. A hearing was had May 12, 1922, and compensation allowed for 350 weeks at $12.00 each week, less the number of weeks already paid, $100.00 burial benefit and medical and hospital expense as pro - vided by law. Case appealed. 5-177: William Patterson vs. Armour Packing Company, Omaha. On March 16, 1922, while employed by defendant company, plain - tiff was injured by a piece of lumber falling on his head. A petition was filed before the Commissioner for compensation. Before the date or hearing, the plaintiff executed a final settlement release showing full satisfaction. Case dismissed. 5-178: Peter Domm vs. Alfred Bloom Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Amirance CorD.) On March 3, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a cabinet maker, plaintiff ran a splinter in palm of left hand at base of the middle finger. It became infected and spread to right leg below the knee. The middle finger was amputated. Compensation was allowed for loss of finger and temporary total disability. May 26, 1922, a hearing was had to determine permanent disability. Compensation was allowed for 20 per cent loss of use of foot (30 weeks) and 20 per cent loss of use of hand (35 weeks) making 65 weeks at $15.00 per week, in addition to what had already beed paid, together with medical and hospital ex - pense as provied by law. Case appealed. 5-179: John von Schooten vs. Farmers Grain &amp; Lumber Company, Sprague. On May 9, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company, plain - tiff sustained an injury to his left eye. An informal hearing was had, doctors {examinations submitted, and the commissioner found that $560.78 should be allowed for per cent of loss of vision, and medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 5-180: Clara Atkinson vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Pending. 5-181: Thomas J. Thompson vs. Morris A Company, Omaha. Plaintiff while in the employ of defendant company received an in - jury by cutting the muscles of his left arm causing a temporary dis - ability of three weeks and one day. Compensation was paid for two weeks and one day. May 1, 1922, plaintiff filed a petition asking for fur - ther payments of compensation, contending that he was and would be </seg>
            <seg id="p095">STATE DEPARTMENT OP LABOR 93 for a long time to come unable to do the kind of work he did before the injury. A hearing was had at Omaha, May 26, 1922, where it was shown there was no permanent disability and that plaintiff had fully recovered. Case dismissed. 5-182: James J. Hughey vs. Hibberd Brick Company, Kearney — Pending. 5-183: Emmet Allen vs. Motor Mesenger Service, Lincoln. On December 24, 1921, plaintiff's bicycle was run into by a car, throwing him off, injuring his head and thumb. A petition was filed for a hearing and he was awarded compensation for three weeks at $6.00 each week, and medical and hospital expense. 5-184: Niels Lilliethorup vs. Louis Minkin, Omaha. — Pending, 5-185: Pat Cunningham vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. On November 26, 1921, plaintiff received an injury to his head and spine by falling while in the employ of defendant company. Com - pensation was paid for a period of eleven weeks and one-half at $14.66 per week. A final release was then secured on the promise of giving plaintiff a job at light work. May 8, 1922, a petition was filed and a hear - ing had at Omaha, May 29, 1922. Compensation was awarded from tho last payment until disability shall have ended. Also hospital and medical expense as needed. Case appealed. 5-186: Paul Trullinger vs. C. Herbert Coy Seed Company, Clarks. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corporation.) Plaintiff claimed he received an injury resulting in an acute attack of appendicitis while employed by defendant company. A petition was filed May 4, 1922, and case was heard at Valley, May 25, 1922. Evidence disclosed condition not due to injury, but caused by disease and not compensable under the provisions of the law. Case dismissed. 5-187: Harold Van Velkinburgh vs. Sanitary Towel &amp; Laundry Com- pany, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corporation.) On July 19, 1921, while in the employ of defendant as a truck driver, plaintiff was stung on the left wrist by a spider which resulted in an infected hand and arm. Compensation was paid for seven weeks and one day. A petition was filed May 10, 1922, claiming permanent per cent of loss of use of arm. The Commissioner allowed compensa - tion for four weeks, immediately following the signing of the final receipt, because he did not work and was treated twice for the open sores on als wrist. 5-188: Berne K. Stickels va. Omaha Flat Work Laundry, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Globe Indemnity Co.) Plaintiff received an injury while in the employ of defendant August 31, 1921. No report of accident was made by the employer to the insurance company. A petition was filed May 11, 1922, but before the case was set for hearing the insurance company admitted liability. Compensation was paid. Case dismissed. 5-189: Eliza Pankratz v«. M. F. Shafer Company, Omaha. Pending. 6-190: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corporation v«. Henry E. Thomp- son, Lincoln. Pending. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">94 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 6-191: John F. Moody vs. U. 8. Fidelity &amp; Guaranty Company, Lewanna. Pending. 5-192: August H. Mueller vs. Farmers Union Co-operative Association, Palmer. On October 22, 1920, while in the employ of defendant association as a clerk, plaintiff fell into an elevator shaft, fracturing his left hip. Compensation was paid for 17 months at $50.00 each month. A petition was filed May 16, 1922, and a hearing held at Central City, June 12, 1922. Compensation was allowed for loss of use of left leg, being 215 weeks at $11.54 each week, to begin to run from April 1, 1922, less amount al - ready paid, together with medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. 6-193: John Cole vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha. Plaintiff injured his back February 22, 1922, while trucking out of a car for the defendant company. He was paid compensation for a period of one and one-half weeks, then went back to do light work after signing final releases. The work was too heavy and he was forced to quit. Defendant denied libility on the grounds that condition of plain - tiff was due to rheumatism and not caused by Injury. A petition was filed and a hearng held, when plaintiff was awarded compensation for 61 weeks at $11!. 40 each week. Doctor and medicine bills to be paid for by plaintiff as he refused to accept treatment tendered by employer. 6-194: Marion Greenlee vs. John Loric and James Jones, Omaha. Pending. 5-195: George Macklin vs. Cudahy Packing Company, Omaha, On March 17, 1922, while in the employ of defendant company as a cattle gamboler, plaintiff was struck on the right leg at the shin with a gambol, causing an injury to a previous condition. A bearing was had June 9, 1922, and compensation was allowed at $10 each week from March 20, 1922, until disability ended. Case appealed. 5-196: Central Granaries Company vs. Frank Sutter, Aurora. On March 5, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff company, de - fendant broke his right leg. Compensation, medical and hospital ex - penses were paid. A petition to determine the permanent disability was filed. An informal hearing was had May 17, 1922. Compensation was allowed for 20% loss of use of leg, amounting to $631.90. in addition to what had already been paid. 6-197: Herman Sell, by Fanny Sell, his mother and next friends, vs. Columbus Beverage Company, Columbus. (Insurance Carrier: Casualty Reciprocal Exchange of Kansas City, Missouri.) On September 10, 1920, while in the employ of defendant company as a laborer, Herman Sell, son of plaintiff, aged 18 years, was burned on the face, chest, back, abdomen, both arms and left leg. Compensation and medical and hospital expenses were paid from date of injury up to October 4, 1921, when the adjuster for the insurance company pre - vailed upon the plaintiff and her son to sign common law releases and final settlement receipt for $450. The Compensation Department made an investigation of the case and found that plaintiff and her son had been defrauded in a sum exceeding $2,700. Complaint was filed with the state insurance commissioner and the next week a representative </seg>
            <seg id="p097">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 95 of the insurance company came to Omaha and reopened the compensa - tion case. The complaint filed with the insurance commissioner was dismissed. In April 1922, an examination of plaintff's arm was made by two Omaha doctors &amp;nd their opinion submitted to the Commissioner. The insurance company waived a formal hearing before the Commis - sioner, and the latter made an award allowing plaintiff for 90% loss of use of her son's arm, amounting to 202J weeks at $15.00 each week, a total of $3,137.50. Case appealed. 5-198: Frank Vach vs. Frank Svoboda Monument Company, Omaha. Pending. 5-199: Mrs. Julia Payne vs. Orchard 4. Wilhelm Company, Omaha, Insurance Carrier: V. S. Fidelity &amp; Guaranty C On April 11, 1921, while in the employ of the defendant company as a furniture duster, plaintiff fell from some steps, headfirst, into some furniture and onto the floor, injuring her right hip, right knee and - rib. She lost but a few days work following the accident until July 4, 1921, since which time she was paid compensation up to May 16, 1922. A petition was filed and a hearing had June 9, 1922. Compensation was allowed from last payment of compensation until disability shall have ended, as provided by law. Also medical and hospital expenses as provided by law. Case appealed. 5-200: Yale-Hopewell vs. Fred Herrick, Lincoln I Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corp.) On June 20, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff company as a molder, molten metal spilled onto foot of defendant, causing third degree burn of three smaller toes of right fcot. Compensation was paid from date of accident to May 1, 1922. A petition was filed May 23, 1922, to determine permanent disability. A hearing was had June 27, 1922. Compensation was allowed for 12% loss of use of right foot at $15.00 each week, in addition to what had already been paid; end medical and hospital expense as provided by law. 5-201: F. F. Brightenberg vs. Orchard &amp; Wilhelm Company, Omaha. &lt; Insurance Carrier: U. S. F. &amp; G. Co.) On May 15, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a furniture repair man, plaintiff was instructed to mix furniture polish in a container or machine. While mixing the polish the lid of the ma - chine came off and the fluid splashed into plaintiff's face and eyes and the fumes were inhaled into his nostrils, resulting in almost immedate interference with vision. Compensation, medical and hospital expense were paid to March 9, 1922, when a final settlement receipt was signed. May 26 a petition was filed and a hearing had June 23, 1922, when com - pensation was allowed for loss of vision in left eye, being 125 weeks at $15.00 each week, less amount already paid. 5-202: Norman Crawshaw vs. Florence Lumber Company, Florence. (Insurances Carrier: Georgia Casualty Co.) Plaintiff on October 20, 1920, lost the sight of his right eye by be - ing struck with a nail while in the employ of the Florence Lumber Company. Compensation was paid for a period of 62 weeks when plaintiff was induced to sign final releases. An investigation by the De - partment disclosed the fact that plaintiff had a greater loss than paid for by the insurance company. A petition was filed and a hearing held when plaintiff was awarded compensation for a period of 125 weeks </seg>
            <seg id="p098">96 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT at $15.00 per week, less amount already paid, together with hospital and medical expense, as provided by law. 5-203: O. L. Prater vs. M. T. dimming* Grain' Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: U. S. Fidelity &amp; Guaranty Co.) — Pending. 5-204: Geo. Joshenbec vs. Dold Packing Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: Integrity Mutual Casualty Co.) — Pending. 5-205: C. Z. McFarland vs. Olson Construction Company, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: U. S. Fidelity &amp; Guaranty Co.) — Pending. 5-206: Orlie V. Rausch vs. Singer Sewing Machine Co., Hastings. On August 27, 1921, while in the employ of defendant company as a salesman and general employe, plaintiff sustained an injury when a crated sewing machine slipped and fell, striking him on the outside of the left leg just above the knee. A growth developed on the leg and it was treated and later operated on in Dcember, 1921. On March 4, 1922, his leg was amputated above the knee. On June 7, 1922, a peti - tion was filed and a hearing held at Hastings. Compensation was al - lowed for temporary total disability from October 18, 1921, to March 4, 1922, at $15.00 each week; 215 weeks at $15.00 each week for loss of left leg and medical and hospital expense in the amount of $750.00. 5-207: James A. Edgerton vs. Robert Parks Heating Company, Platts - mouth. (Insurance Carrier: Georgia Casualty Company.) — Pending. 5-208: Donald Lee vs. Night A Day Messenger Service, Omaha. Pending. 5-209: Joseph Palmaffy vs. Swift A Company, Omaha. Pending. 5-210: Joseph P. Wentz vs. Gordon Van &amp; Storage Company, Omaha. (Insurance Carrier: General Accident Fire &amp; Life Assurance Corp.) — Pending 5-211: Earl E. Thompson vs. Great Western Sugar Company, Bayard. (Insurance Carrier: London Guarantee &amp; Accident Co.) — Pending. 5-212: Lincoln Telephone &amp; Telegraph Company vs. A. V. Loy, Beatrice. Pending. 5-213: George Smith vs. A. C. Butke, Contractor, Omaha. (Insurance .Carrier: Aetna Life Insurance Co.) — Pending. 5-214: Beulah Van Vleet vs. Public Service Company, York. (Insurance Carrier: Utilities Indemnity Exchange.) — Pending, 5-215: Walter Garrett vs. C. O. Faulk and James Morton &amp; Son, Omaha. Pending. 5-216: Yankee Hill Brick Company vs. Geo. B. Doyle, Lincoln. (Insurance Carrier: Ocean Accident &amp; Guarantee Corporation.) On September 21, 1921, while in the employ of plaintiff company as a machine tender, defendant had his right arm caught between belt and pulley bruising and crushing soft tissues between the hand and the shoulder. Compensation was paid in the amount of $226.00. A petition was filed by the plaintiff to have the permanent disability determined. Compensation was allowed for 10 per cent loss of use of right arm, being 22 1 weeks at $15.00 each week, in addition to what had already been paid, together with medical and hospital expense as provided by </seg>
            <seg id="p099">PART II DEPARTMENT OF LABOR FACTORY INSPECTIONS. The Department has little or no complaint to make regarding those subject to the various labor laws. Employers of labor have learned that it is to their advantage to protect their workmen. In complying -with the labor laws by guarding carefully all machinery they can reduce the premiums on their compensation insurance. The Department has been aided in its factory inspections by the insurance companies. They find that the employer who complies with the health and safety regulations has less accidents. During 1921 session of the legislature, this Department sponsored an amendment to Art. 12 Title V, Chapter 190, of the laws for 1919, re - quiring insurance companies to file inspection reports with the Depart - ment of Labor. We quote here the amendment Section 1. Amendment.— That Article 13, Title V, Chapter 190 ol the laws of Nebraska for 1919, be amended by the addition thereto of a new section to be numbered Section 24, to read as follows: Section 24. Insurance inspectors report — failure — penalty. — When - ever any employer shall insure liability to employes as provided by law in any liability insurance company or companies, or in any mutual in - surance association, and such insurance company or associations shall, by agent, representative or otherwise, inspect the premises covered by agent, representative or otherwise, inspect the premises covered by the insurance policy, such company or association shall furnish to the Department of Labor a full and complete copy of the report of the physi - cal defects together with recommendations made by such agent, represent - ative or other inspector making the report. Wilful failure to comply promptly with the provisions of this section, shall be sufficient cause for the revocation of the charter of such insurance company or asso - ciation. By this amendment the department is able to keep a check on the various inspections made by the inspectors of the insurance com - panies thereby enabling it to get a better compliance with the health and safety regulations and further it enables the Department to know just where the defective machinery is. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">98 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT FEMALE LABOR There has been a general compliance with the Female Labor law. There were 15 complaints filed with the department, but when the em - ployers' attention was brought to the provisions of the law they agreed to comply. No arrests were made, the violators agreed to promptly abide by the law. CHILD LABOR There were 756 age and school certificates filed during the last year and one-half. Outside of a few complaints there has been a general com - pliance with the child labor law. No arrests were necessary. All em - ployers agreed to abide by the law. FREE EMPLOYMENT During the last year and one-half the Division of Free Employ - ment which maintains an office at Lincoln has done very good work. The Employment Division co-operates with the federal and municipal employment agencies. Following is the report of the Division for the last year and one- half: 1921 Registra- Help Referred Reported COLLECTION OF WAGES Although this Department has no power under the law to enforce the payment of wages due working people, we did, however, succeed in collecting $839 59. INDUSTRIAL DISTURBANCES. There were but two strikes in the state covering the period from January 1921, to July 1, 1922, the most serious being the packing house workers in Omaha and Nebraska City. The other being the job printers strike in Omaha. tions. Wanted. Placed. Hale 10,223 6,030 6,074 3 v 460 Female 771 544 473 267 Total 10,994 6,574 6,547 3,727 From January 1, 1922, to July 1, 1922. fale 1,932 2,025 1,222 967 i'emale _ 736 719 461 335 Total 2,668 2,744 1,683 1.302 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 99 On December 5, 1921, the Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen's Union ordered all its members on strike on that day to resist a reduction in wages. The total membership of the organization on that date was 3,000. The strike had international union sanction, and it affected 4,625 employes. The wage scale on date of strike was, men 45c to 82Jc per hour and women 33c to 40c per hour. Strike break - ers were imported to till the places of the strikers, but the number im - ported is unknown. The strike was lost. The wage scale at the end ol the strike was, men 37Jc to 79 Jc per hour; women 26c to 37 Jc per hoar. The cost of the strike to the union was $11,452. Loss in wages esti - mated at $662,343.30. Financial assistance was received from various un - ions and individuals. The money so received was accounted for by publication. This strike affected seven local unions chartered by the international union in the packing centers of the country. Following were the number affected in the different plants in Omaha and Nebraska City on the date of the strike: No. of Remained On Strike. The printers strike in Omaha to secure the 44-hour week occurred May 1, 1921. Eighty members of the union were called out. The wage scale at the time of the strike was $42 per week for 48 hours. The scale demanded under the 44-hour week was $41 per week. Omaha Typographical Union No. 190 was organized in 1883 and it had 340 members when the strike occurred. It is an international strike, the contest being as stubbornly resisted in Canada as in this country. Ap - proximately 8,000 members walked out in the jurisdiction on May 1, 1921. The outstanding feature of this strike is the assessment voted by the members to maintain the strike. For many months there was a 10 per cent, assessment on the earnings of the 60,000 working members. From May, 1921, to July 1, 1922, $10,021,917.05 was collected by this assess - ment. All of this sum except $400,000 was paid out to the strikers, they being paid $23 and $27 each week. The assessmen was reduced to seven per cent' in December and then to five per cent, in April of this year. The strike is still on. Omaha is the only city in Nebraska affected by this strike. Armour &amp; Company ... Employes. 1,330 at work 390 k. 940 Swift &amp; Company 1,385 830 550 Morris &amp; Company 800 200 600 Cudahy Packing Co. ... Dold Packing Co 1,900 620 250 120 1,655 500 Morton-Gregson 450 65 385 Total ..6,485 1.855 4,630 4,63 </seg>
            <seg id="p102">100 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT WAGE SCALE FOR OMAHA 1922. The wage scale of the skilled workers in Omaha follows : for 1922, is as INDUSTRIAL STATISTICS. While agriculture is the basis of Nebraska's material wealth, the fact Is that Nebraska is becoming a great manufacturing state. The chief difficulty of the Department is to get reports from the manufacturing establishments. The law requires every manufacturer to send in a report. When the manufacturer fails to report, he is wilfully missing an opportunity to boost himself as well as his state. Fourteen hundred questionnaires were sent out for each of the years 1920 and 1921, and 525 reported for 1920, and 363 for 1921. It is hoped that this co-operation will be improved upon during the years to come. The following tables show the importance of Nebraska as a manu - facturing and Industrial state: Per Hour. Carpenters _ _ _ $ .90 Cement finishers 90 Electricians - 1.12 J Hod carriers 55 to .60 Common laborers 35 to .45 Lathers : 1.00 Painters 90 Plasterers v 1.25 Plaster helpers ..._ _ 35 to .45 Brick layers ..._ _ 1.00 Elevator constructors „ _ 1.00 Gas fitters .... _ 1.121 Hoisting engineers 1.00 Marble cutters .871 Marble setters _ 1.00 Masons _ 1.00 Ornamental Iron workers _ 1.00 Pipe coverers 1.00 Plumbers _ _ 1.00 Roofers 1.00 Sheet metal workers 1.00 Steam fitters _ 1.00 Steam fitter helpers _ _ 75 Stone cutters 1.00 Structural iron workers _ 1.00 Tile setters _.._ _ 1.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">■&amp; c: s ! s i X X c ? X u = »&lt; &lt; x e P ili*sii^LK S^&lt; *2 fH *♦ »O fh N W »-t §ri __ b to xxxxxxxxae«« «xxxxxx&gt;-go*xxxxxiC£xx xx « &amp; % 3 3 _ _ x s;:5;is.-.::isjsuM:i:::5;;;t.-.5::.:5:;;^5S P4 Ft Ft Ft Ft 1*^ T** T*"! o « B S es jc ri ti ?i w f-&lt; ci « ci w »-i c4 ?i t^ ?i r: ci ri *-&lt; k c-i ri ?i ci ?i « « *h ,h w ?h 5 " " y — -■ — — ► i fci A $ I- «CS-f.^FHCS**»-'CI=C^'&lt;'»^«?ISl-?lS — « — 5*Q0?i«««rt«-*?liMrt?lKS •Oq. t- r-t^&lt;»^ •*« F-.t Ft «T F-tfi't ga- Ul i Ml! IS! Jj5lii*M jNj | if i I 1 s M- ill M i !h ill! I ill U j is«^ </seg>
            <seg id="p104">3 5 *H S V a is • « -dt-e » N ri « l&lt; rc_ « N ! OC CO 00 00 00 IS 00 00 [00X00 CXOCXXCXt-i.-XXXXXKZXI'-KSKeoo I- I 3 s I 1 B B SS2Sys a SS32S« :s SyS^S2 = = 2SS = SJS2S2*2S e =2 D i) 2 SggSggSS |S8S S88SSSS^SSSS8SS88!gS3S88 &gt;-■ ■■ _ ; — r _ I 1 *;§te;Sg^9tt 8888S888S8SS888!:S88@S88 »^ t-t rt r-t — — ——_" = i I M " _ . "3 8Iil»lillKms«(!gS8 S 8&amp;i!8f9|iKS8e S « 3 5 O i 1 u 23» t -«i5- l S"S' S| -' H *5!;S?;ri ;s ' r^*S' 11 "2 t -g2 t -iS t -S«J5 I I liiliiili I I III it I ill [hi Mi hi ■ f \\\i\ ! | i 1 1 if j if I ! ■ 1 1 i i I \l i i i iJi i ||i|i| |i 'i\k\u c lil: Niii'iii 1 S : S •• St. I 1* I j o &gt;&gt; -O : : a «b;- {l. g : ,h&lt;h S W ;a&lt;S '_ ■ \if3s% I : ; ••§ ««f "i-M S. »sg — c a i^ s v — — = *" &amp; — a C E- P*s 1 n-Sj&lt; :: ' : S= 1 5c^ </seg>
            <seg id="p105">i 5 noxi-:iOr-'f-)i');yOK5i-':^nO'*'(;oi:-,©t-c:5o^cr-5-f 'fosi - ■ri'I»»i-5ii-Hrto- ii'Ii:p.ii-eJ«MZKS-«i-l-i*i-?Sc : 3 2* fja.SV;gSi3?!§j5S?5SSK§.55i2?.5S£SSg?i.3gi'S$. a i I a II III.! Ur X 2 IJC MIHI PI i»I 1 ill K i 1 1 Hfi 1 1 1 Mi$$i I » z Illllllllllllllllllilllllllllcl^llli X r- S?aSSagS?iS§3SSSS33358gSSSS§!?igSSi2SS!S£ -? »•■■• ~ "" " "•"•a • I ! j i I i : i I i i ; ■ ; i • i i l« 1 s I i I M I i i i I I hi ill Is lli« II II' 1 1 1 1 1! NIL a a g = a s a c t s s s a g b s s 3 s s * 2 ? s ffl s Jsj? s 2 sl £l 8 s fe **"i-T » © i-I so -i- « r: ? J ci i4 ?i i- r^ i-* iH -| — I si S8SS.i8 ? 8$383S2£S8SS3*&amp;i:8tSaSt;88t$S8i S !i S 5 2 S i 2 , r J i! 2 -i 2 !2 S « f S 2 5 i ■= 2 ?-' * 5; 2 S 3 5 3 S r; 5 2 £ ?. *fr — SO &gt;5 o Ill 9 V KM ©^ = i-o2ri£M = i-:i-.-.« r -rt»;q? 1 :s-i.£is!r--»'=;rn-j2ei-Kt-acKm </seg>
            <seg id="p106">1 *.*!* © * h ft go a o h o « qc « p- ct-cetrcct-^Kh-ctvcevf 104 •» «98&amp;8.9888^88.8«8SS898.^8^$8Sfai8i:R&amp;9M a- 38 [^ 5 ig « : K i- X e •*« «■*■ - « ~f f! 3 iH 3 ■ S S 3 3^ 5 =n i- JHi c S 5 c;-»j. fc ?i 5t t-* n«movi* w Jo 5ct «■* t-5-* rf cc«f- fi »- S at I I «« i 2? S c. 71 «1 us S L' !) fe !» ZK i X 1 IMS;; 8S£!$:28s&amp;S!8SggSSgggggS8S!8S£8SM '• 'A K5 ss -f os w ~ -. i a ci f i- « S r - N ? e ct c * * ?i ec oc « ec « ■* ei ci - ci i: hi MM Mil 1 Hi il ■I g 1 mIjM ! l £ ' i! I Ml I i Hi 11 J UN y] rfji *i '« hi i y|illlsli!5aliil|b!l!lii|?||il||8| </seg>
            <seg id="p107">STATE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR 105 LABOR DEPARTMENT APPROPRIATIONS Following are the appropriations made by the legislature for the Labor Department from 1887 to 1923 : Salary Maintenance Years nn&gt;«.i- Number n fl Deputy J?.£" of Officers Office ff' Lleres ft clerks ciency Total 1*87-89...- _ i $3,000.00 | '...._ [ $1,200.00 f $4,200.00 8.000.00 8,000.00 6,000.00 6,100.00 7,130.42 8,000.00 9,380.00 9,480.00 9,880.00 8,562.38 10.403.94 9,964.90 10,680.00 13,680.00 20,860.00 35,420.00 50.35&amp; 00 1888-91 1 3,000.00 j $2,000.00 2 3,000.00 J 1S81-93 3,000.00 i 2,000.00 2 3,000.00 1893-05 ! 3,000.00 2,000.00 2 1.000.00 o 1896-97 J 3,000.00 2,000.00 ' 2 1,100.00 I 1897-99 | 3,000.00 2,000.00 | 2 650.00 $1,430.42 1899-01 ! 3,000.00 | 3,000.00 [ 3 2,000.00 1901-03. _...| 3,000.00 t 3,680.00 I 3 2,700.00 l '.* i:; -i&gt;.-, 1903-05 ', 3.000.00 3.C80 .00 3 2^00.00 1905-07 ! 3.000.00 4,080.00 | 3 2,800.00 2.800.00 W07-00 3.000.00 ' 1.680.00 2 3.600.00 282.38 1 1909-11 _ I 3.000.00 | 1,680 00 I 2 5,000.00 723.64 1911-13... 3,000.00 ! 1,680.00 2 5,000.00 284.90 1913-15..._ | 3.000.00 1,680.00 | 2 6,000.00 1915-17 3,000.00 I 1,680 00 2 9.000.00 _ 1915-17 3,000.00 I 1,080.00 1917-19. I 10,000.00 4,680.00 4 13.130.00 1919-21 1 10.000.00 ! 8.520.00 I 7 16,900.00 _. 1921 23* - I 10,000.00 I 26,208.00 | 7 14,150.00 1921 23* - I 10,000.00 I 26,208.00 •For the biennium beginning July 1, 1921 and ending June 30, 1923. </seg>
            <seg id="p108">106 EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT DEPARTMENT ORGANIZED IN 1887 The Labor Department of the State was organized in 1887 as the Bureau of Labor. A Deputy Commissioner of Labor, appointed by the Governor, conducted the affairs of the office until 1919, when the De- partment of Labor was established under the Civil Administrative Code Law, with the title of Secretary of Labor. The names of the Deputy Labor Commissioners and the years of their service, are as follows: John Jenkins ..„ 1887-1888 John Jenkins 1889-1890 Philip Andres 1 1891-1892 J. B. Erion 1893-1894 J. H. Powers _ 1895-1896 Sidney J. Kent .... 1897-1898 Sidney J. Kent „ 1899-1900 C. E. Watson ....1901-1902 Burrett Bush * 1903-1 904 Burrett Bush _.'. 1905-1906 John J. Ryder .1907-1908 W. M. Maupin 1909-1910 L. V. Guye ........ 1911-1912 C. W. Pool 1913-1914 F. M. Coffey _ 1915-1916 G. E. Norman 1917-1918 Prank A. Kennedy _.. _. _ 1919-1920 Frank A. Kennedy _ — 1921-1922 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>