<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00057.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00057.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the State Reformatory for Men Lincoln, Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1923">1923</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> 
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE State Reformatory for Men LINCOLN. NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions / For the Period Ending June 30, 1923 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">FOREWORD Tgjlis Excellency, the Governor : The Board of Control herewith transmits the Fifth Biennial Report of the State Institutions of Nebraska for the period ending June 30, 1923. The biennium formerly ended on November 30 of each even-numbered year, but this date was changed by an act of the legislature, so that this report really covers a period of thirty-one months from December 1, 1920, to June 30, 1923. During the period, no change has occurred in the personnel of the Board, but several changes have been made in the chief officers of institutions. Dr. Beverly A. Finkle, superintendent of the Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska, resigned to enter private practice, and was succeeded on August 23, 1921, by Dr. J. H. Matthai. Miss Amy V. Stevens, who had been superintendent of the Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Nebraska, for a number of years, resigned on July 5, 1922, being succeeded by her sister, Miss Nellie Stevens. The latter served until February 19, 1923, when her resignation was received, and Miss Lena Driever was appointed to the position. We call attention with pride and pleasure to the fact that the report shows the institutions to have gone through the bien - nium without incurring any deficiencies ; although the cost of living, and consequently the cost of supporting the state's depen - dents, has certainly not decreased since the appropriations were made for the biennium. Some improvements of a permament character have been made at the various institutions during the period covered by this report. A hospital building, bakery and scullery have been erected at the Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded, Beatrice, Nebraska ; a cottage for girls at the Girls' Training School, Geneva, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska ; a gymnasium building at the State Industrial School, Kearney, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney, Nebraska ; a farm house and a barn at the Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a warehouse at the State Penitentiary, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska; a kitchen building at the Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk, Nebraska ; a main building at the State Reformatory for Women, York, Nebraska. These buildings were badly needed, and they will have to be followed by others in the very near future if our wards are to be properly, efficiently and economically cared for. The legislature just past made provision for two or three buildings, but failed to see the necessity for several others that were urgently requested. Brief mention was made in the last report of the establishment of the Reformatory for Men at Lincoln, but the importance of the institution calls, we believe, for rather more extended notice. This institution was established as a result, primarily, of a wide recognition of the need of segregating young first-term offenders from more mature criminals. The legislature of 1921 authorized the establishment, therefore, of such an institution, making an initial approproation of $300,000. Of this sum the Board ex - pended $37,500 for 10 acres and a brick building known as the Hayward Military Academy, later buying about 152 acres of contiguous land for the sum of $49,531.25. This land is used for farming, stock raising, dairying, and intensive gardening. Various trades are taught such as tailoring, shoe repairing, carpentry and joinery, brick laying, electricity, automobile repairing, launder - ing, engineering, firing, and barbering. The manual labor about the institution is, of course, performed by the inmates, of which there are at this date 189. Mr. A. W. Miller, the superintendent, is doing much constructive work with the young men committed to his charge, and we believe the institution is amply justifying itself. The difficulty of employing the penitentiary inmates at suitable labor that does not conflict too much with the prerogatives of the free workers of our state, has been pretty well overcome. The state still operates the fibre furniture factory which has been at the prison for some years, and has also established relations with the Oberman Company by which shirts are made and disposed of with a minimum of competition with free labor. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 INMATE POPULATION There are seventeen institutions under the control of the Board, and at this time (July 1, 1923) the inmate population is 5917, as compared with an average of 4980 for the biennium ending in 1921, and 4907 for the biennium just prior to that. The following table will be found of interest as showing the population of the different institutions during the past two biennia : Av. pop. Av. pop. Largest biennium biennium number Institutions ending ending at any one (With "Key" Letters) j une 39, j une 30, time past 1921 1923 two years A— Institution for Feeble-Mindcd 607 725 756 B— Girls' Training School 106 173 189 C— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 409 353 412 D— Hastings State Hospital 1152 1193 1219 E— State Industrial School 217 214 241 F— Hospital for Tuberculous 78 102 106 G— Lincoln State Hospital 837 971 995 H— Orthopedic Hospital 64 88 102 J — State Penitentiary 363 586 596 K— Nebraska Industrial Home 73 86 99 L— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 148 162 195 M— School for the Blind (a) 47 53 57 N— Norfolk State Hospital 646 733 768 P— School for the Deaf (a) 171 178 187 R— State Reformatory for Women 9 18 28 S— Home for Dependent Children 53 91 107 53 91 107 T— State Reformatory for Men (b) Not open 150 192 Total 4980 5876 6249 (a) 19 months (1921, 9 months school; 1922, 10 months school.) (b) Open only 21 months; started October 1, 1921. EXPENDITURES The following table reveals the expenditures at the various institutions for the past biennium, the item of salaries and wages being included under Maintenance in all instances excepting the first. Capital outlay represents permanent improvements to the realty and equipment. Board of Control, Lincoln — Maintenance $ 5,151.87 Salaries and Wages 42,529.53 $ 47,681.40 Institution for Feeble-Minded, Beatrice — Maintenance 253,843.43 Cash 27,524.49 Capital Outlay 93,899.95 375,267.87 Girls' Training School, Geneva — Maintenance 111,808.47 Cash 4,964.20 Capital Outlay 42,000.00 158,772.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett— Maintenance ...„ 176,14828 Cash _ _ 67 846.61 67,846.61 Capital Outlay _ 115,000.00 358,994.89 Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside — Maintenance 501,184.46 Cash 99.853.78 99,853.78 Capital Outlay 38,85025 639,888.49 State Industrial School, Kearney — Maintenance „ 161,200.06 Cash 26,345.72 26,345.72 Capital Outlay 43,440.24 230,986.02 Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney — Maintenance „ 106,076.45 Cash 30,794.13 Capital Outlay : 117,826.18 254,696.76 Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance _ 375,095,50 Cash 89,072.43 89,072.43 Capital Outlay 74,803.84 538,971.77 Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 122,286.28 Cash _ _ _ 25,627.53 25,627.53 Capital Outlay 4,490.17 152,403.98 State Penitentiary, Lincoln — Maintenance „ 229,205 92 Cash 161,633.02 Capital Outlay 390,838,94 Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford — Maintenance _ 61 306.38 Cash 2,578.26 Capital Outlay 63,884.64 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford — Maintenance 94,40699 Cash _ 29.700.29 29,700.29 Capital Outlay Z 15,934.10 140,041.38 School for the Blind, Nebraska City- Maintenance 57 82522 Cash 3.989.06 3,989.06 Capital Outlay..... .„. 3,952.01 65.766.29 Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk- Maintenance _ 321.060 71 Cash 50.535.76 50,535.76 Capital Outlay 59,999.01 431,595.48 School for the Deaf, Omaha — Maintenance _ 137,695.55 Cash ZZ 16,819.16 Capital Outlay. — Z 4,'500.00 159,014.71 State Reformatory for Women, York — Maintenance „ 28,489.38 Cash _ 2713 3Q Capital Outlay 46,996.15 78218.92 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln — Grand Total 4,538,783.65 At its various institutions the state owns something over 4000 acres of land, of which in excess of 3500 are in farm and garden. About 800 acres are rented in addition. Details of operation are given in the reports from the several superintendents which are appended hereto. The health of the inmate population has been generally good during the past biennium. We are pleased to be able to report that no epidemic has broken out at any of the institutions, and our medical men have been able to cope with such sporadic cases of contagious disease as have appeared. In conclusion we wish to express our appreciation of the efforts of the officers and employees of the various institutions in striving to bring about a betterment of the living conditions of the wards under their care. We wish also to thank the Governor for his manifestations of interest and for his assistance in the work of this department, and we trust that he will continue his efforts to help us provide better means of caring for the wards of the state. Board of Control, KATHERINE F. WORLEY, Chairman, A. E. ALLYN, L. C. OBERLIES. Attest : E. B. FAIRFIELD, Secretary. Maintenance Cash Capital Outlay 65,026.59 7,584.94 72,611.53 Itate Reformatory for Men, Lincoln — Maintenance Cash Capital Outlay „ 72,188.46 6,959.45 300,000.00 379,147.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 AVERAGE DAILY POPULATION STATE INSTITUTIONS OF 5,876 TOTAL POPULATION </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 4 EXPENDITURES FOR 1921-1922 SALARIES and WAGES OPERATION and MAINTENANCE FURNITURE and EQUIPMENT NEW BUILDINGS LAND 48.7H8.O8 FIXED CHARGES and STATE AID 1^2.276.94 II 72,46 5.46 I96,O93.9M 6O3.6H9.60 6,848.53 PERMANENT IMP. TO BUILDINGS and GROUNDS 1 1 1 ,02570 TOTAL H,M 91, 102.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 INCOME FOR 1021-1922 3,841,318.13 598,304.90 66,960.00 48,100.56 4,554,713.59 STATE FUNDS CASH FUNDS FEDERAL FUNDS TRUST FUNDS TOTAL • UNEXPENDEO BALANCE OF CASH , FEDERAL HMD TRUST FUND (clothing funo.institute for feebleminded) rerppropriateo </seg> 
            <seg id="p011">11 (a) Opened October 1, 1921. 21 months. tun: July 1, 1 11 to June 30, 1' Salaries and Wages Operation and Maintenance Furniture and Equipment Permanent Improvements to Bldgs. and Grounds New Buildings Land Fixed and State Aid Charges Total for Biennium Per Cent Institution for Feeble-Minded... Girls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital . State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital School for the Deaf. _ State Reformatory for Women.... Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men (a).... I 89,73778 31,660.01 77,410,19 226,534.52 60,739.65 45,281.20 178107.10 56464.88 93,393.20 19,294.61 35,009.08 32,444.05 137 84L88 77,242.53 9,137.15 19,53925 52,439.86 $ 186,411.64 82,797.68 155,19827 351,30624 120,474.65 87,490.63 269,172.04 89,805.58 288,86020 42,879,03 88144.78 28,007.41 229,413.66 74,549.12 19,058.85 49,977.47 108,91821 $ 25232.79 9,782.66 8,110.35 15,447.16 10,56822 16,452.47 16,898.41 4.786.04 4,309.18 520.59 5,468.85 676.87 38,443.00 7,223.06 3,470.00 1,003.35 27,700.94 $236.00 16.08 150.50 8,557.31 10.72 2,124.19 28,624.45 1,347.48 3,776.36 1,165.66 10,552.41 685.95 3,634.66 $72,778.39 34,51234 118.115.58 37,87247 39,192.78 103,34827 45,077.86 _ $871,27 3.40 10.00 171.19 i;o9i"9i "■ $ 375267,87 158,77*67 358,994.89 639,888.49 230,986.02 254,69676 538,971.77 152,403.98 390,838,94 63384.64 140,041.38 65,76629 431,595.48 139,01471 78218.92 72611.53 379,147.91 8.3 3.5 8.0 142 5.1 5.7 12.0 3.4 8.7 1.4 3.1 1.4 10.0 3.5 1.7 1.6 8.4 ;... ... "■84726" 500.00 24,75 19.00 3,952.01 200.00 2A66228" 7,500.00 2,091.46 50,552.47 wjxasa" 90789JS" 48,747"08 "■ _ Total $1,242,276.94 $2,272,465.46 $196,093.94 $121,025.70 $603,649.60 $48,747.08 $6,843.53 $4,491,10225 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">16 POPULATION AND PER CAPITA REPORT OF STATE INSTITUTIONS July 1, 1921, to June 30, 1923 (s) Average during school year. &lt;H) Opened October 1, 1021-21 month*, Number of Inmates June 30, 1923 Average number Inmates during Biennium Number of employees June 30, 1921. Average number employees during Biennium Average number Inm.ites to each employee Average per Capita Cost for Biennium Average per Capita Cost per month Average amount Pay Roll per month Institution for Feeble-Minded Girls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett _ Hutting* State Hospital State Industrial School...... ........... Hospital for Tuberculous __..-.... Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital itatc Penitentiary..... Nebraska Industrial Home ............. loldiers' Home, Mllford lebraska School for the Blind (a).... Norfolk State Hospital febraaka School for the Deaf (a) laU Reformatory for Women... lonw for Dependent Children...... .. State ReforfiMtory for Men (b).......,.. 747 183 301 1,200 207 103 981 93 579 63 154 53 767 187 25 87 187 725 173 353 1,193 214 102 971 88 586 86 162 53 7^ 178 18 91 130 66 20 72 160 40 36 132 49 55 11 32 24 90 49 14 26 61 19 62 158 38 35 131 48 S 11 31 24 9 i 1.1 8 12 9 6 7 5 3 7 2 11 8 ! 2 8 \ 6 $ 380.89 661.60 G5y.ou 484.27 846.80 1,301.68 460.63 1,662.10 652.31 722.95 760.20 1,140.59 501.03 R5276 1,566.44 763.92 1,075.72 $ 15.87 27.57 27.46 20.18 .15.28 54.23 19.19 69.25 27.18 30.12 31.67 47.52 20.87 35.5.1 65.27 .11,83 51.22 $ 3,562.47 1,319.17 3,225.42 9,438.94 2,530.82 1,886.72 7,421.13 2,352.70 3,891.47 803.94 1,458.71 1,351.84 5,743.41 3.J18.44 380.01 814.14 2,497,13 Total ... 5,917 5,876 m ' ssi ' 7 $ fM.ll ~$24&gt;2 *.M,«)6,46 1 . .; | .^ ___ ; _ </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 ~! AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME •eri ling une Under 5 years 5 to 9 yrs; inc 10 to 14 yrs. inc. 15 to 17 yrs, inc, 18 to 24 yrs. inc, 25 to 34 yrs, inc. 35 to 44 yrs. inc. 45 to 49 yrs. inc. 50 to 59 yrs. inc. 60 to 69 yrs, inc. 70 to 79 yrs. inc. 80 to 90 yrs. inc. Over 90 years Unascer- tained Total nstitution for Feeble-Minded - rirls' Training School ioldiers' Home, Burkett lastings State Hospital — itate industrial School lospital for Tuberculous — ,incoln State Hospital _ )rthopedic Hospital _.. ttate Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home ioldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital _ Nebraska School for the Deaf _ itate Reformatory for Women iome for Dependent Children itate Reformatory for Men « ./67 70 28 38 134 33 11 6 6 246 162 135 472 333 229 586 384 369 92 125 21 344 35 62 238 241 !■«■»— -M ■ ■■■■■■ ....1.11 — 13 204 18 17 57 13 59 33 41 60 54 41 37 31 112 80 1 36 "" 9 59 16 58 79 61 30 15 2 3 6 V '\i 9 65 ■ 14 63 ' 185 17 223 28 135 10 61 ... 16 SO 3 18 12 70 8 43 1 1 ... 67 160 89 31 2 14 3 I 7 7 1 4 3 12 2 8 6 15 3 6 is 66 "4 2 26 ... 4 27 1 39 80 74 ... 36 38 '34 i 121 6 5 3 i 67 " """44 180 46 ... ...I Total.. 211 293 324 599 581 743 399 172 212 181 271 76 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 FIRST TIME Biei inium Endini June 30, 19; t. lor Feeble Minded Giri»' alntng School aadStOom' Home Burkctt Halting* Hospital State Industrial School H T5r* 1 Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Ottho»*dic Hospital State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers »ud Sailors' Home Mllford Nebmaka School (or the Blind Norfolk State Hospital Nebraska School (or the Deaf Befomatory (or Women Home (or Dependent Children Rriormjttiry tor Men Total Australia _ Austria 2 5 6 7 i ............... ..... 14 ... 7 20 12 3 28 1 18 24 28 3 6 95 7 1 4 21 4 6 1 22 1 1929 1 4 14 30 1 8 1 2 1 2 44 6 1 1564 124 30 -ri " "" ._ tsonemia Bulgaria Canada China Czecho-Slovakia Denmark ._. England Finland France Germany Greece ___ „ Holland JHL_ Hungary _ Ireland Italy Japan Macedonia Mexico Moravia _ Nebraska _ Netherlands Norway Poland Russia . Saxony Scotland Seria Seryja _ Sicijia Spain Sweden Switzerland Turkey „ U. S. other than Nebraska. Unknown Other Countries 2 2 „ —f-4 "~ 7 .. 12 3 ... 1 I I „ 1 1 7 6 17 8 6 2 l»mn ■— ............... " _ "i 3 1 1 4 1 _ 2 i 4 S 1 2 73 | "2 _„_. ._ 1 19 1 _ " 2~ 2 T - 1 3 2 1 1 i 2 _ ...... i 2 ~ l"~ "~5 _ I "" i n i 3 1 i i 3 ... — n - 1 - .... '"" 4 2 ..._ i n " 1 l l 119 1 3 ~ 2 i 1 209 " 98 __ -..-.. ... iS7~'~ m 201 339" 74 66 i 12 103 26 30 ; 232 72 """ i 2 3 8 1 2 1 ni 2 i 2 1 2 5 i ... _ _ i 1 4 i 2 ! ... 2 1 i j _ ) i I ... H ...„ 2 ' """ 2 13 2 4 2 9 i I r r 13 1 i "" 32 56™ 4 119 205 26 W" ' 209 42 4 " 42 i i 256 5 20 1 116 8 129" 9 29"" 5 1 .... I _ 116 45 ... 26 . Total.. 246 162 135 472 333 586 384 369 125 35 4074 92 21 344 238 241 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 CLASSIFICATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Biennium Ending J'me 30, 1923, County TmHtut Inn for Feeble Minded Qirls' Training School Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Milford Nebraska School for the Blind I Norfolk State Hospital Nebraska School for the Deaf Reformatory for ; Women Home for Dependent Children Reformatory for Men Total AntMMto 8 1 2 6 10 43 5 1 8 3 1 9 3 2 2 2 1 5 97 35 1 2 2 26 20 27 19 85 31 38 46 38 14 1&lt;&gt; 51 32 I') 2( 7-, 23 26 46 8 13 58 810 9 36 27 14 27 110 7 9 5 ! 12 112 39 22 4 1 is 31 5 22 29 11 30 14 8 12 29 726 46 3 37 7 19 1 29 21 43 33 49 20 16 22 20 40 12 39 68 8 38 11 39 44 53 28 27 7 \7 32 16 25 1 43 19 16 19 1 1 55^ 4074 Arthur Banner BUine 1 1 1 1 1 20 ~ i ... 3 2 4 1 5 3 7 4 2 1 | I : 1 Boom Box Bntte Boyd Brown Buffalo Burt Butler Caw Cedar Chaae .._. Cherry CheycMte &lt;U» „_ ' « olfax &lt; umiuM Cu**er ' US' Dakota . „. _. Uawc. llaWMMI .-._.._.. lleuel Z Di«ou ..____ Ijodicc Mttdy ..... L____1__.J_' Killmore. Franklin Frontier Fumas .............. ___ ___ &lt;»»fe GaraeJd TZ ZZZ tioaper Grant ...._.. Greeley ' Hall ... Hamilton _ Harlan . Hayes .„ _._ . Hitchcock Hoh _ Hooker Howard Jefferson Johnson Kearney _ . Keith Keya Paha KkHhalt __."_" Lancaster , Lincoln _... MJkmm —-IT ,. , MePherson ... Uerrick _ ___ Nebraska Industrial Home Merrill _..... Wuekolls ome zzzzzzz. p&gt; i "**" — ... ... re nuns _..™.._...._...._..™._.. Phelps Pierce Plane ZIZZZZZ PoHr _ ; Red Willow _ _ Ricfisrdfton Rock Z Saline ZZZZZZZ. Sarpy „.. srottt RitdiZZZZZZZZ Seward Wierifrn _ Sherman Sioux _.. StaafcMi 7 i 1 4 3 4 1 3 5 6 1 4 I 6 9 2 1 2 1 (, 2 6 1 2 13 125 i i 1 8 1 7 12 3 9 3 4 1 _ 2 9 "3 2 6 "25" 1 12 1 1 9 3 2 1 1 ... 1 3 1 S 2 1 1 2 3 1 2 1 3 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 5 2 5 10 " 7 2 &gt; I 1 2 1 6 1 To i' 3 « 2 4 ip 2 4 2 2 1 16 2 4 2 4 "4 ...... 1 2 i 16 1 6 1 1 1 " 9 16 4 3 2 i' 2 » "2 1 1 6 4 19 4 2 2 4 ....... 7 14 3 ' ... 6 6 1 1 2 i 1 H _ I 12 3 1 7 10 4 3 3 i 4 i 2 2 4 1 2 1 1 2 ! 5 _ 10 1 2 32 2 44 2 1 2 6 7 109 1 2 4" 68 is 211 2 2 6 1 3 5 2 1 8 i '. I S" 76 1 i "Is" G8 ~ 3 1 4 5 4 17 13 5 9 1 1 2 2 » i 1 3 « i * ! 1 3 1 1 ! * 9 1 -I 2 12 3 1 1 2 7 1 2 I i I \ I 1 1 2 2 56 1 1 4 1 1 1 2 8 i 2 2 4 I I ' " i ■ ■ ■ ■ ii ■ i' 3 1 4 1 i ... 3 I i ; I I 1 1 -~i i r ""'\ i I" '" 1 I i _... 1 3 1 2 2 _ 5 25 12 10 2 5 1 1 i I i i i 1 1 32 5 6 3 3 5 2 2 3 .3 11 5 1 1 3 5 8 ! 3 ... 2 1 I 3 i. 6 2 2 4 1 2 2 i ' _ i h- 3 1 1 3 2 8 11 3 1 1 3 1 4 1 2 18 1 ................. ...... "" i 2 1 i 12 4 2 1 2 1 1 1 1 62 3 1 I 3 2 2 2 I 2 4 1 1 3 6 '2 1 i I i ! i 6 2 ... '7 "■ i I 1 1 4 24 S ... f l 1 1 1 2 3 25 3 1 1 214 1 3 1 12 14 1 1 16 2 1 -&gt; .- - 49""" 3 2 1 3 4 1 i'45 1 38 1 16 2 ..... 1 " 2 ' j 15 102 14 9 4' 1 3 1 1 2 3 4 3 4 2 .... „ " 2 4 3 1 2 i 1 I 1 3 21 ~i ' 2 "1 ... .............. ...... .^^ 6 1 4 1 7 3 1 2 8 o '. 2 8 2 3 "1 1 20 1 i 2 1 5 1 4 3 1 1 15 l"8 9 4 3 2 7 1 2 1 6 1 _ 1 1 i 1 2 i 3 4 8 1 1 1 i 1 I T~ 1 2 i 2 1 1 1 2 2 i 2 2 i' "i 5 7 1 1 lo 10 3 12 i 9 14 1 1 2 5 1 5 " 3 6 i" j 3 7 i 18 4 3 2 . 5 2 i 2 i 4 S IS 1 1 1 { """ 1 17 6 19 ri 2 "i 3 3 1 7 3 2 4 i 1 1 1 3 3 1 4 1 7 1 4 6 5 i' 2 1 2 6 3 5 11 9 2 1 2 3 . 1 8 S 1 6 6 11 7 . 2 " 10 2 2" 8 . _ 2 2 .... 2 "" ~ I 2 1 1 4 I l 2 2 ' i 1 3 2 1 2 1 5 6 I!wyer 17 2 6 "i i 4 • i Thomas — t...-~. I*...... 7 '"" 2 Thurston Unknown Valley Washington i Wavne Webster _.„ j ? "i 16 - 13 _ ii i 7 - - 2 2 2 " : 2 1 1 1 2 _ 7~ _ T 2 - ... I 2 ~r ~- — , ~"i ' '. r "i" 10 1 Other States".. ..." York _.._ .._ 1 _ ..._ _ 1 1 1 11 ■ 1 J' ■■-••• 1 i ~18 8 - 7 1 r 4 Total 246 162 135 472 333 229 586 3«4 369 92 I 125 21 344 35 62 238 241 </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">17 STATE REFORMATORY FOR MEN LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OFFICERS A. W. MILLER Superintendent H. P. SCHEIDELER C. C. BOSLAW Assistant Superintendent Steward DR. B. A FINKLE CAL. R. PHILLIPI Physician Educational Supervisor Miscellaneous Statement Established 1921 Number of employees 26 Number of inmates June 30, 1923 189 Highest number of inmates 192 Per capita cost per month $51.22 Number of acres 162 Number of acres rented 17.5 Number of acres under cultivation 132 Value of lands and buildings $217,790.00 Principal industries : Farming, gardening, stock raising, and in - dustrial trades. Visiting days : Every day excepting Sundays and holidays Hours 9 :30 a. m. to 1 1 :00 a. m. and 2 :00 p. m. to 4 :00 p. m. Any person not less than sixteen nor more than thirty years of age at the time of conviction of a felony for the first time may be sentenced to the reformatory instead of the penitentiary when in the judgment of the court the person is capable of reformation and the sentence is compatible with the general welfare. </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019">19 To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln. Nebraska. I herewith submit the first report of this institution, covering the period beginning October 1, 1921, and ending June 30, 1923. On the date first named, the institution was opened with a population of eighty persons , seventy-seven of whom were transferred from the penitentiary. Many discomforts were experienced during the winter of 1921 in housing the inmates and officers from the fact that the building and remodeling had to virtually be carried on over our heads. But despite these in - conveniences and discomforts, the construction has gone steadily forward until we now have at the close of the bicnnium, a structure complete in detail of plumbing, heating and lighting. During the year that has elapsed since the first occupation, the following work in construction has been completed : A substantial brick boiler house and engine room have been built to meet the needs of the institution, and will suffice for some years to come; a concrete smoke-stack one hundred and five feet high ; a steel water-tower and reservoir, with a capacity of fifty thousand gallons ; an emergency reservoir with a capacity of nearly sixty thousand gallons ; a new well and pump-house with a substantial guardhouse above ; a three hundred foot tunnel connect - ing the main building with the heating plant ; a woven steel wire fence enclosing the seven acres — this fence is emplanted in a base of concrete. Outside the fence we have erected a good hog-house from lumber salvaged from old buildings ; a brick garage with a capacity for eight cars which was built entirely by the inmates ; a large vegetable cellar of concrete with a capacity for a carload of potatoes, cabbage and other vegetables; a storehouse for lumber, building material and tools ; a septic tank ; a transformer house ; six manholes. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 There are occasions in all institutional work when stricter discipline must obtain for such as refuse to abide by the rules; and for these cases there has been erected within the enclosure, a concrete structure or so-called jail, where the more serious offenders may be punished by complete isolation. We are happy to state that while this building has not been brought into requi - sition to any appreciable extent; it nevertheless has added to the morale of the place. All material entering into new construction and remodeling, which material consisted of tons of cement, sand, lime, brick and stone, had to be hauled to the institution over roads that at times were almost impassible. Our school system was inaugurated in October, 1922, and is a wonderful asset to our institution, one in which the general public and all welfare workers should take a hearty interest. Instruction is given in all the grades up to the eighth ; and the school is in operation six hours a day for five days of the week. To get as far away as possible from the stigma of prison life and the handicap incurring from prison servitude the reformatory was established ; and in this school work we seek to give the greatest possible aid in the up-building of character and to restore to citizenship a finished product, an upright human being. In addition to our school, we have established several useful activities : A manual training school, where many useful articles of furniture are made and furniture for the insitution is made and repaired ; a tailor shop in which much of the clothing worn by the inmates is made, and where worn garments are repaired ; a shoe shop which is busy all the time repairing inmates' shoes and the shoes for other state institutions ; an automobile repair shop where our truck and automobiles are kept in repair; a barber shop where a number of inmates are learning a trade, and where a number who have served their time have learned a useful trade that enables them to support their families ; a modern and well - equipped steam laundry that gives employment to inmates who are thus learning a useful trade ; an ice plant that furnishes ice for the institution, and gives perfect refrigeration for our perishable supplies; paint, plumbing, and electrical shops complete the list of activities; and each department is under the supervision of a competent and skilled foreman. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 We also have a music department, in which the inmates are receiving instruction. This department is a valued adjunct to our institution in consequence of which there is always a big waiting list of those who desire instruction in orchestra and band music. It is the constant aim and effort of the officers, both by precept and example, to influence the inmates to lead upright and honest lives. Their spiritual welfare is subserved by chapel exercises which are held each Sunday and consist of song services, lectures and sermons by ministers residing in Lincoln and neighboring towns. The religious beliefs of our inmates are respected and all denominations are alike invited to minister to our spiritual needs. The legislature of 1923 appropriated fifty thousand dollars for the erection of suitable buildings in so far as the sum would suffice and fifteen thousand dollars for a building for industrial activities. Plans are being worked out for both buildings. Respectfully submitted, A. W. MILLER, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 TABLE III— NATIVITY OF THOSE COMMITTED FOR FIRST TIME For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Admitted : For first time Returned parole or furlough Returned escape Returned for safe keeping Returned for investigation Transferred from Penitentiary 241 11 12 1 1 135 Total received 401 Released : Escaped - Discharged Transferred to Penitentiary and other institutions Paroled Released to Parole Board 19 31 33 127 2 Total released 212 Remaining at end of period _ 18&lt;) TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE COMMITTE For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Total Fifteen and under seventeen .-. Eighteen and under twenty-four Twenty-five and under thirty-four IS 180 46 Total 241 For Period Ending June 30, 192: Total China France Germany England - Italy _ Mexico Nebraska Sweden United States other than Nebraska „ Other countries _ _ 2 72 1 116 45 Total 241 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Divorced | 8 Total I 241 For Period Ending June 30, 1923 White M 215 21 2 2 1 Negro Indian Mexican Zhinese Total 241 TABLE V— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMIT ED FOR FIRST TIME Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 None Primary Common school High school College or university 4 13 161 5V 4 Total 241 TABLE VI— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE COMMITTED FOR FIRST TIME I Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 Single .... Married . \\r: j i 180 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 TABLE VII— COUNTY FROM WHICH COMMITTED For Period Ending . June 30, 1923 Adams 5 Boone 3 Box Butte 4 Buffalo 7 Butler : Burt _ 2 2 Cass 3 Cedar 1 Chase 2 Cheyenne ! Cherry 6 1 Custer 8 Clay 1 Dawson 10 Douglas 68 Dodge 6 Furnas 2 Gage 4 Greeley Hall .Zl 2 8 Hamilton Harlan Z '"""" 2 4 Hayes 1 Holt 2 Hitchcock -— -_-ZZII__Z!!____Z!__I Jefferson _ 2 2 Keya Paha Lancaster 1 14 Lincoln 9 Morrill 2 Nance 3 Otoe 5 Perkins Phelps _!__L____ 2 -&gt; Red Willow ZIZ__ Richardson 5 15 Rock 1 Saline 1 Scotts Bluff 3! Seward 8 5 Sarpy 1 Sheridan 1 Thayer 1 Thurston _ Valley /7~~ 1 2 York 4 Total 241 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 TABLE VIII— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE COMMITTED Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 Acetylene welder Acetylene welder Apple picker 1 Apple picker 1 Baker Baker Ball player Ball player Bejl hop Bell hop Brick mason Brick mason Bridge worker Bridge worker Blacksmith Blacksmith 2 Boiler maker Boiler maker 2 Bralceman Bralceman 1 Butcher Butcher 3 Carpenter Carpenter S Car repairer. Car repairer 2 Caser in oil wells Caser in oil wells 1 Cement worker Cement worker 2 Chauffeur Chauffeur 2 Clerk Clerk 11 1 Construction engineer Construction engineer Cook Cook 11 1 Engineer Engineer Electrician Farmer Electrician 3 3 Farmer 51 3 51 Fireman Fireman 3 Hydraulic well man Hydraulic well man Ice man 1 1 Ice man 2 2 Iron moulder _ Janitor Iron moulder _ 1 1 Janitor 1 1 Jockey Jockey 1 1 Laborer Laborer 36 36 1 Lineman Lineman 1 Machinist Machinist 2 2 Manager, hotel Manager, hotel. 1 1 Manager, advertising agency Manager, advertising agency 1 1 Mechanic Mechanic 16 16 1 Moving picture man Miner .'. Moving picture man 1 Miner .'. 1 1 Optician office Optician office Painter 1 1 Painter 6 6 Plumber Plumber 1 1 Photographer Printer Photographer 1 1 Printer ' "' 2 2 Press feeder Press feeder 1 1 Pipe maker Pipe maker 1 1 Porter -.ZZZZZZZZZI Porter 2 7 Rancher Rancher 1 1 Salesman Salesman 8 8 Shoemaker Shoemaker 3 Shipping clerk ™._ j Shipping clerk 1 1 Sheet metal worker Sheet metal worker ZZZZ^ 3 3 Student, high school Steam engineer Student, high school 5 5 Steam engineer 1 1 Steel worker Steel worker 1 1 Steam fitter ._.._.._!._™~'...."..." Steam fitter. 1 1 Stone mason Stone mason 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 TABLE VIII— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE COMMITTED (Continued) Tailor Teacher Teamster Time keeper Tile maker ... Tree trimmer Truck driver Typesetter Waiter Wood worker .. No occupation Total TABLE IX— RELIGIOUS PREFERENCE OF THOSE COMMITTED Period Ending June 30, 1923 Altering and defacing auto Arson Auto stealing Assault to rape ... Assault to rob ... Assault to wound Breaking and entering Bench parole violation Burglary Burglary and larceny Cattle stealing Causing death while exceeding speed limit Carrying concealed weapons r* IT _*-l t_. 1 1 Concealing stolen property .. Disposing of stolen property Drawing "No Fund" check .. Forgery 1 1 2 26 Forging and counterfeiting bank check Grand larceny 1 23 Highway robbery 5 Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 3 1 2 1 1 1 9 1 6 1 2 241 Total 'rotestant Catholic Ihinese ewish to preference 18.3 36 1 2 19 Total 241 TABLE X— CRIME FOR WHICH COMMITT '""~\ Total for </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 TABLE X— CRIME FOR WHICH COMMITTED (Continued) Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 Horse stealing 2 Hog stealing 5 Intent to defraud by forgery [ Larcenv Larcenv of an auto , 2 Larceny as bailee ' 2 Manslaughter ■ I 2 Perjury Rape 3 Receiving and selling stolen property | Robbery ' 17 Seduction : 1 Shooting with intent to wound j 2 Shooting with intent to kill | 1 Statutory race 2 2 Statutory rape Stealing auto and receiving stolen auto 7 Stealing wheat 2 / Protecting auto thief Unlawfully abandoning wife and children I 1 Wife desertion 2 Writing forged checks I 2 Chicken stealing 5 Chicken stealing 241 TABLE XI— CHARACTER OF PARENTAGE OF THOSE COMMITTED I FOR FIRST TIME Total Father dead 41 Mother dead 42 Both parents dead \ 21 Both parents living 126 Unknown 11 Total I 241 TABLE XII— PHYSICAL AND MENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE COMMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 General Health : Sound : I 132 Diseased j 109 Mental State : Sane ! 190 Sub-normal I 50 Feeble-minded 1 Defect, amputations : 2 Arm amputations - Leg, defects ' Blind, nnp eve ... 1 Blind, one eye </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 §88 8 8 JO \n~* | no 2; : i-5 ! : •8-dS I i i ! • ©o&gt;vo ' u •2 n b h V I Si II (-1 U « «J3 §"8 S3 » CS s 5a § 55 S Q. CO* M 1 U o S U ?S8 S -3 Si E NO&lt;-iOOt^gg ■v I i i n ! : j ; ! L i II j j i I i I • i i . ||l Mil •gftj a rt rt « a, Sou M tfifrf 8 ig.sp « O u o -a v 5 5 c. ho c c en Ml '5. 1 1 1 i i ! ! : : : : I ! i ! I 1 I i Ik : : : :"" Mi; : : : I I ! ilh i i i ! j ! ioo : : *— &lt; u M O m ; : ; : »-h (A •■o vc-ioo •s 1 : i I I I </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCTS For Period ending June 30, 1923 Total produced Prqduct Measure Value Beans, string Beans, dried Beets 2,200 lbs. 0 70 bu. 70 00 3,540 lbs. 53.10 70 bu. 0 Cabbage Carrots 3,540 lbs. 1,000 lbs. 0 1,000 lbs. 15.00 0 Corn, sweet Corn, pop ... Cucumbers Lettuce 266 bu. 571.90 2,520 lbs. 75.60 266 bu. 0 2,520 lbs. 750 lbs. 700 lbs. 3,000 lbs. 625 lbs. 500 lbs. 450 lbs. 0 750 lbs. 22.50 0 700 lbs. 14.00 0 0 Melons, musk Onions, green Parsnips 0 500 lbs. 10.00 0 Peas 450 lbs. 36.00 0 Potatoes, sweet Potatoes 20 bu. .30.00 20 bu 580 bu. 0 580 bu. 580.00 2,480 lbs. 37.20 0 Radishes Spinach Tomatoes Turnips Squash ... 2,480 lbs. 0 500 lbs. 0 10,800 lbs. 4,620 lbs. 0 0 72 lbs. 720 72 lbs. 800 bu. 0 Corn, field Alfalfa 1,000 bu. 600.00 5 tons 60.00 200 bu. 5 tons 0 $3,102.05 Total Bal ? nc^ on Consumed T h £ n&lt; L,, June 30, 1923 900 lbs. 0 900 lbs. $ 90.00 2,200 lbs. 132.00 3,000 lbs". 150.00 625 lbs. 3125 500 lbs. 15.00 10,800 lbs. 432.00 4,620 lbs. 69.30 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>