<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00029">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00029</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Strawberries in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1920-02">1920-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Circular 11 February, 1920 NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION Strawberries in Nebraska C. C. WI( ANS The strawberry is probably the most important small fruit grown in Nebraska. It thrives well in all sections of the State where the moisture supply is not too limited, being found almost universally in home plant - ings. It is also produced commercially in certain favored localities but this acreage is limited. Strawberries are very easily grown and little difficulty should be experi - enced in producing them for home use. Harvesting and marketing them com - mercially, however, requires more care and ability. Since berries are pro - duced the second season after setting the plants, they may be used profitably by the tenant as well as by a land - owner. The plant is very cosmopolitan in its soil and climatic requirements and can be grown over a wide range of conditions. Widespread use of the fruit in both the fresh and preserved states makes for extended plantings. Also it should be included in every home fruit garden because of the fact that it ripens earlier than any other fruit. Strawberries for home use are gen - erally considered as a part of the vegetable garden planting. Because of their temporary nature — one plant - ing rarely being continued for more than three or four years — they fit in very well as a part of the garden rotation. They are also frequently set in young home orchards, a very good location, since the cultivation essential to strawberries is also very beneficial for the young trees. Both berries and trees thrive under such conditions. A small planting is usually sufficient to supply the needs of an average family. Frequently a large neglected bed will not yield as much fruit as a Tho Senator Dunlap. the best variety for Nebraska smaller one receiving proper care. Strawberry variety tests conducted by the University of Nebraska Department of Horticulture at Lincoln in 1913 and 1914 showed that the average yield of the 15 highest producing varieties was 25.68 quarts per 60-foot row (40 plants), or approximately 225 crates per acre. Several varieties gave considerably greater yieMs. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 Nfbhaska Experiment Station Ctrcttt-Ar 11 SOILS Strawberries thrive best on a well drained fairly light soil. Ordinary garden loam or land well suited for corn or other farm crops will gen - erally be suitab'e for the berry plantings. A soil should be well supplied with humus and be fairly fertile but excessive fert'litv is to be avoided or too much vine growth will result. Sandy or gravelly soils are slightly "earlier" than loamy soils. The bed is more easily cared for if the ground upon which it is planted is free from weed sped. This condition may be brought about by preced'ng ♦■he berry crop with potatoes or some other hoed crop. Where it is avai'able newly cleared land makes an ideal location for strawberries. Sod land is to be avoided, for the first year at least, on account of the presence of white grubs. Ground for strawberries should be preDared by a deep fall plowing. The soil may be left ridged until spring, however, so as to srather and hold more moisture from the snows and winter rains. Fall plowed land may be easily prepared for early spring planting by disking and harrow - ing or dragging. SITE The question of a suitable site for the strawberry bed is of some importance because the first blossoms on early varieties especially are sometimes killed by late spring frosts. A slope insures better soil drain - age and somewhat better protection from frost damage but level ground is easier to cultivate and many successful growers use only comparatively level around. BeTies ripen a few days earlier on a south or southeast s'one. Gen - erally, however, a north or northeast slone is to be nrpferred because the plants blossom somewhat later and hence are less liable to be im'ured by cold. Also the northern exposures tend to hold moisture better and occasionally moisture is a very important factor near the end of the fruiting season. PLANTING Plants. Only one year plants should be used. These can be dis - tinguished from older crowns by their lighter colored roots. Plants may be taken from an older bed or secured from any reliable nurseryman. In either case they should be on hand in plenty of time for early planting. If they cannot be used at once upon their receipt they should be healed-in. This is accomplished by opening the bundles and spreading the roots out in a shallow trench. Soil is then packed firmly against the roots. In this condition plants may be held for several weeks until the field is ready for planting. If plants are taken from an adjoining bed they usually are not dug until they are needed. In digging strawberry plants, a portion of the root system is un - avoidably left behind. Hence, all plants should be pruned at time of setting. Pruning consists of removing all the leaves except perhaps the two inner ones and shortening the roots back somewhat. Unpruned plants are likely to wilt because of the evaporation from the extensive leaf surface, and often a poor stand will result. Time of planting. Spring setting of strawberry plants is preferable to fall planting under most circumstances. Spring set plants, except some of the ever-bearing sort, do not bear the first year but a great many runners are formed and new crowns set so that a good row is secured for the following season's crop. On the other hand, fall set plants, if afforded </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Stkawukuicik* i.n Nebraska 3 protection thru the winter, will bear a fair crop the next season Spring planting is done just as soon as the ground will do to work while late August or early September is used for fall planting. Distance to plant. Strawberry rows are usuahy 3V4 feet apart, but with strong growing varieties 4 feet is close enough. The plants in the row are from 1 to 2 feet apart, 18 inches probably being the average distance. Method of planting. Planting strawberries is a simple proposition except that some care must be used in getting the crown of the plant just at the soil level. Plants set too high will dry out while the bud is often killed in those set too deep. Also the roots should be spread ojt to some extent instead of being pressed into one compact bunch. The soil should be pressed firmly about the roots. A spade, dibble or hoe may be used in the planting operation. CULTURE The strawberry plant should receive intensive culture thruout its first season in the field. Hoeing soon after they are set establishes a dust mulch which should then be maintained by frequent cultivations. In some sections the beds are given weekly plowings with a horse cultivator and hoed perhaps a half dozen times during the growing period. Some hand hoeing is necessary in order to keep down weeds and secure cultivation in the row. All blossom stems should be kept pinched off during the first year. A good matted row System of training. Under Nebraska conditions the "matted row" system of training is probably to be preferred. This system, which is least expensive to maintain, consists essentially of allowing the runners to set crowns promiscuously within a row 18 to 24 inches wide. Some- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 \ki:i:a&gt;ka Kxri- Station Cimculas 11 \ times the new plants are spaced somewhat during the hoeing but this is not essential. The cultivator drags the runners lengthwise of the row and tnus prevents a sond mass oi plants between rows, it the runner is weignted Oown ligntly with soil near the node ttie new plant will become mote quickly estaonsned on its own roots. i ne - niii" sysiem is sometimes used to produce fancy berries. Indi - vidual iruits usually are much larger but the total yield is less man with the matted row system. Here tne runners are kept cut off so that trie plant torms a single very large crown. Many fruit stems are then pro - duced and one plant produces a considerable quantity of berries. \Vith certain of our everbearing sorts the hill system may be advisable. Mulching. Strawberries should be mulched for several reasons. Unmulched beds are likely to suffer from the drying effect of winter winds and may even be winterkilled by heaving. A mulch also tends to keep down weeds during the fruiting season at a time when cultivation is undesirable. Berries taken from mulched fields are uniformly cleaner than those not protected by a mulch. Mulches also help hold moisture during the spring and early summer. Wheat straw is as near the ideal mulch as can be obtained but even here grain remaining in the straw may give trouble by germinating. Oal straw may be used but tends to pack somewhat too tigntly. Prairie hay and cornstalks are not suitable because of their coarseness or tendency to tangle. The mulch should be applied just after the first hard freeze. From 4 to 6 tons per acre will give a coating 4 to 6 inches thick. It should be spread uniformly over the rows and middles, where it remains until spring. Removal of the mulch consists in merely raking it off of the row and piling it up in the middles. Occasionally some may even need to be hauled from the field. By permitting the mulch to remain on the row somewhat late in the spring, the early blossoms may sometimes be protected from late frosts. The ripening period is delayed somewhat by such procedure. FERTILIZERS The average Nebraska soil in the region suited for strawberry grow - ing will not require the addition of commercial fertilizers to make it produce satisfactory crops of strawberries. Soils deficient in nitrogen may be improved by turning under a crop of red clover or adding manure. Such operations should precede the setting of the plants by at least one season, or too much leaf growth on the berry plants will result. Weeds too are often troublesome and so they should be subdued by the cultiva - tion of the previous crop. Acid phosphate or steamed bone may be bene - ficial in certain instances where the soil is low in phosphorus. An appli - cation of 300 pounds per acre is sufficient. HARVESTING Strawberries should always be picked early in the day but should never be taken from vines wet with dew or rain. The fruit should be pinched, not pulled, from the plant. If the calyx and a short length of the stem remain on the berry it will keep considerably longer in the fresh state. For home use the berries may remain on the vine until thoroly ripened. A berry just colored is not ripe. Another day or two of growth will add materially to its size and sweetness. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SlliAWllKKKlts l.N NkUKAUKA 5 The bed should be picked regularly at least once in every two days. Daily picking is preferable for then a much more uniform product is secured and over ripe berries eliminated. Where berries are handled in commercial quantities they must be picked while still underripe so that they will reach market in prime con - dition. They must be well-colored, however. Overripe berries even when shipped under refrigeration often are unsalable by the time the market is reached. Frequently the quantity of fruit on a home planting of strawberries is more than sufficient for a family's needs. In such a case the surplus usually finds ready sale on the local market. In packing fruit for such purposes only the standard quart boxes should be used. RENEWAL By renewal is meant the preparation of a strawberry bed for the second or later crop. A bed prepared as outlined above bears very few berries the first season and a large crop the second. Later crops dwindle very rapidly in size and the size of the individual berries is also greatly reduced. This is due largely to overcrowding and lack of care, for with very little attention the second and even the third crop is quite profitable. Generally speaking, however, where the rainfall is no greater than in Nebraska, it will not pay to renew more than twice, and if the very best berries are to be produced a new bed should be started every second year. When it is recalled that a matted row develops in one season from plants set 1V4 by 3% feet it can readily be seen that the main aim in renewal is thinning out the row and giving the remaining plants good growing conditions. The one year old crowns are more fruitful than older ones and hence another object is to get rid of the older plants. The first step in the process is the removal of the mulch from the field. Ordinarily the bed is mowed and then mulch and foliage raked off together and burned. In some cases they may be burned in the field but burning the bed over is a questionable operation because of the danger of killing the plants. If burning is resorted to it should be on a dry windy day when the ground is moist. Under such conditions the fire travels rapidly and does little damage to the crowns. Destruction of the mulch and foliage is of great benefit in controlling diseases and insect pests. The thinning out process may be accomplished either with a hoe or a plow. If a hoe is used the surplus plants are cut away leaving a well established plant every 9 to 12 inches. Plants should be left closer than they were originally set for they will not make as good runner growth the second season as they did the first. The plants should then be hoed and the rows kept cultivated as during the previous season. A sufficient number of new crowns should set so that a good "matted row" develops for the following season. When the planting is large enough to warrant the use of team labor, renewing is done by plowing out one side of the original matted row together with the middle with a cultivator or turning plow. The ridges are then leveled down and the field is often harrowed crosswise. This tends to cultivate the plants still left in the row. Subsequent cultivation is similar to that of the preceding year. Where the soil is thin, the rainfall low or the variety a poor plant maker, judgment must be used in determining how much of the row to plow out. If too much is taken, a poor stand for the following year </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 -NtllllASKA ExrEKI.MK.Vl STATION ClULULAH 11 results. In such cases it may be advisable simply to plow thru the middle of the row with a narrow shovel and then cultivate as before. The mulching of the second season is similar to tnat of tne first. Later renewals may be made in the way described above. Each suc - ceeding season, however, the remaining plants make a poorer growth than before because the fertility of the soil is less and aiso cultivation becomes less efficient. It is far better to set a new bed every two or thiee years than to attempt to hold an old planting for four or hve crops. Some growers make a practice of starting a small new bed each year and such a plan has many things to commend it. DISEASES AND INSECTS Fortunately few diseases or insects damage the strawberry sufficiently to warrant measures for their control. The leaf spot is the only disease of importance while insect damage comes largely from leaf rollers and white grubs. The crown borer may also occasionally do some injury. Strawberry Leaf Spot is identified by the small round spots or noles found in leaves soon alter the blooming period. Many leaves drop off and hence lessen the vigor of the plant, it may be controlled by using Bordeaux Mixture (4-6-yO) when growth is just beginning and later just before blooming time. Some varieties are much more resistant than others. White Grubs or larvae of the June bug are injurious only when strawberries are set on sod land. They may be avoided by growing some cultivated crop before the berries are set. Strawberry Leaf Rollers are small, greenish larvae which cause the leaflets to curl up. Spraying must be done early before rhe rolling begins. Arsenate of Lead applied two or three times at intervals of a week will tend to hold it in check. This material is used at the rate of one pound of the powder or two of the paste to fifty gallons of water. It may be combined with the leaf spot spray mentioned above and both troubles controlled by one application. For small areas White Hellebore (1 lb. to 3 gal.) may be substituted for Lead Arsenate in the control of leaf rollers. Hellebore may be used with perfect safety even on f ru»t of considerable size. EVERBEARING STRAWBERRIES The so-called "everbearing" or, to be more exact, "fall-bearing' strawberries have attracted considerable attention during the past few years. The yield, while not totalling as much as that of the standard varieties, comes usually during the late summer and early fall months and hence is quite a novelty. Everbearing strawberries are handled very much as outlined above but there are some differences. In the first place, some varieties, such as Progressive, will bear a considerable crop of fruit during the first season, that is, plants set in the spring bear the following autumn. An - other difference which might be noted is that under few circumstances will it pay to renew these varieties. A new bed should be planted every year. Certain varieties such as Superb are not good plant makers and hence some difficulty may be experienced in securing a good row. Of the dozen or more varieties on the market the Progressive is by far the most widely used. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Strawhkkkikk i\ Nkrkakk.\ 7 VARIETIES It is said that up to the present time more than 1,800 varieties of strawberries have been listed in America. Consequently, it is possible to find one or more varieties suited to almost every possible condition of soil and market requirement. Certain varieties are grown only in very restricted sections — indeed they seem to be adapted only to the conditions pecu'iar to that locality. Other varieties do we'l almost universally. Out of the whole list of varieties that have been developed the aver - age cower should limit himself to a very few. It is doubtful if there should be more than two or three varieties in the ordinary olanting. An extra earlv variety furnishing a few early fruits — a mid-season sort, usually giving the best yie'ds and used as the main crop — and an ever - bearing variety to give fresh fruit for table use over the late summer months, make a good combination of varieties. If only one variety is to be us»*d H should be one of the dependable mid-season sorts, the Senator Dunlap being the choice for Nebraska conditions. Certain varieties produce little fruit if planted alone. These are known as pistillate varieties: in other words the flowers are largely impprfpct in that they lack the pollen necessary for fertilization. Such a d'fficultv may be avowed by usine some staminate variety as a pol - lenizer. evei-y fourth or fifth row being of this sort. In t^e following list are given the names of several standard varieties and also thpir approximate season of ripening. The Ii3t is by no means complete and all varieties may not be expected to do well under all condi - tions. Some of them, however, may be expected to succeed almost anvwhe^p in the State. The letter (S) indicates a staminate variety and i P&gt; a pistillate sort. (10.M Early Early Ozark (S) St. Louis (S) Excelsior (S) Bederwood (3) Medium Early Crescent (P) Clyde (S) Warfield (P) Mid-season Haverland (P) Senator Dunlap (S) Wm. Belt (S) Glenmary (Semi-S) Parsons (S) Bubach (P) Medium Late Chesapeake (S) Joe Johnson (S) Sample (P) Klondike (S) Aroma IS) Jessie (Semi-S) Buster (P) Brandy wine (S) [.ate Gandy (S) Everbearing Progressive (P) Superb (P) </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>