<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THIRTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Commissioner OF Public Lands and Buildings TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA DECEMBER 1, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
		       <change>
		          <date>2007-09-06</date>
		          <respStmt>
		             <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
		          </respStmt>
		          <item>Enrichment</item>
		       </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OV THK Commissioner OF Public Lands and Buildings TO THB Governor of tiie State of Nebraska DECEMBKIt 1, 11M12 GEO. D. FOLLMKK COMMISSIONER OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS 1901 Thb Fremont Tribune Fremont, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">OFFICIAL ROSTER. Geo. D. Follmer, Oak Commissioner H. M. Eaton, Fremont Deputy Brad P. Cook, Lincoln Chief Clerk ♦Alex Schlegel, Lincoln Draughtsman Frank J. Fitle, So. Omaha Bookkeeper Frank W. Hollingworth, Oak Bookkeeper Maggie Kroese, Hickman Lease Contract Clerk Jeanette Rehlaender, Lincoln Delinquent Clerk Cora A. Garber, Red Cloud Assignment Clerk Mary J. Holland, Friend Assignment Clerk Annette Galbraith, Hebron Stenographer f Robert Harvey, St. Paul Draughtsman •Resigned Nov. 30, 1902. tAppointed to fill vacancy. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, Lincoln, Neb., December i, 1902. tHis Excellency, Ezra P. Savage, Governor of Nebraska: r: I have the honor to submit herewith the thirteenth biennial report of the Office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings for the two years ending November 30, 1902, together with the reports of the several State Institutions under the general control and management of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, in compliance with the requirements of the Constitution of the State of Nebraska as stated in Section 22, Article 5. Yours respectfully, Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">MEETS FIRST MONDAY IN EACH MONTH. Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings President Geo. W. Marsh, Secretary of State Secretary Wm. Steufer State Treasurer Frank N. Prout Attorney General HOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS. MEETS SECOND TUESDAY OF EACH MONTH. Ezra P. Savage, Governor Chairman Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner Secretary Wm. Steufer State Treasurer Geo. W. Marsh Secretary of State Frank N. Prout Attorney General BOARD OF PURCHASE AND SUPPLIES. MEETS FIRST WORKING DAY IN JANUARY, APRIL, JULY AND OCTOBER. Ezra P. Savage, Governor Chairman Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner Secretary Geo. W. Marsh Secretary of State Wm. Steufer State Treasurer Frank N. Prout Attorney Genera^ </seg>
            <seg id="p006">• rS SECOND WEDNESDAY IN FEBRUARY, MAY, AUGUST AND NOVEMBER. Charles Weston, Auditor Chairman Geo. W. Marsh, Secretary of Slate Secretary Frank N. Prout ". . Attorney General Wm. Steufer State Treasurer Geo. D. Follmer. . Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. rS THIRD TUESDAYS IN JANUARY, APRIL, JULY AND OCTOBER EACH YEAR. E. P. Savage, Governor Chairman Wm. K. Fowler, State Superintendent Secretary Geo. D. Follmer Commissioner BOARD OF IRRIGATION MEETS FIRST WEDNESDAY IN APRIL AND SEPTEMBER E. P. Savage, Governor Chairman Geo. D. Follmer. . . .Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings Frank N. Prout Attorney General </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Appropriations 10 Assignments 1&gt; Asylum for Incurable Insane 183 Board of Purchase and Supplies 12 Boyd County Case. Board of Public Lands and Buildings 61 Board of Educational Lands and Funds 12 Collections 12 Cheyenne County Warrants 12 Certified Copies of Records 12 Custodian of Field Notes and Plants 13 Conversion of Lease into Sale Contract 17 Expenditures 10 Extension of Sale Contracts 18 Escheats 45 Educational Lands Forfeiture Fees 13 Forfeitures 51 Home for the Friendless 233 Indemnity School Lands — Sioux Reservation 18 In Closing 73 Insane Asylum, Norfolk 1*&gt;3 Industrial School, Girls, Geneva 333 Institute for the Deaf and Dumb, Omaha 393 Institute for the Blind 3."&gt;9 Lost Contracts li&gt; Lease Contracts 16 Miscellaneous 13 Name and Location of State Institutions with Supt. in charge 8 Nebraska Hospital for the Insane 75 Nebraska Soldiers and Sailors Home Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford 261 Nebraska Institute for the Feeble-minded Youth 209 Penitentiary Land 14 Permanent School Fund 54 Recommendations 15 Recommendations Relating to Laws of Educational Lands 49 Soldiers and Sailors Home, Milford 349 Some Facts 52 State Industrial School, Kearney 311 Some Figures 63 State Penitentiary 129 This Biennium 55 Table of State Educational Lands 56 Table Showing Work Done this Biennium 61 Total Interest on Sale Contracts and Comments 64 Temporary School Fund 54 Total Rental Lease Contracts and Comments 66 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">SUPERINTENDENTS IN CHARGE. Nebraska Hospital foe the Insane — Lincoln. Dr. J. L. Greene. Asylum for the Incurable Insane. — Hastings. Dr. W. B. Kern. Insaxk Asylum at Nokfolk. (Burned September 23, 1901.) Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home — Grand Island. Colonel A. V. Cole. Soldiers' and Sailobs' Home — Milfobd. Colonel Charles Penn. Home for the Friendless — Lincoln. Sarah B. Sonus. State Industrial School— Kearney. Dr. J. V. Beghtol. Girls' Industrial School — Geneva. Horace M. Clark. Nebraska Institution fob Feeble-minded Youth — Beatrice. Dr. A. Johnson. Institute for the Deaf and Dumb — Omaha. R. E. Stewart. Institute for the Blind —Nebraska City. J. F. Morey. Dr. F. F. Teal. Nebraska Industrial Home — Milford. Margaret Kealy. State Penitentiary — Lincoln. E. D. Davis. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">ESTIMATED EXPENDITURES FOR THE NEXT BIENNIUM BEGINNING APRIL 1ST, 1903 AND ENDING MARCH 3ist, 1905. COMMISSIONER'S OFFICE. Salary of Commissioner $ 4000.00 Salary of Deputy 3600.00 Salary of Chief Clerk 2600.00 Salary of Draughtsman 2600.00 Salary of two bookkeepers 4800.00 Salary of lease contract clerk 2000.00 Salary of delinquent clerk 2000.00 Salary of stenographer 1680.00 Salary of two assignment clerks 4000.00 Furniture and repairs 250.00 Telephone and telegraph 250.00 Postage 1000.00 Stationery and other expenses 600.00 $29,380.00 BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. Fuel, light and engine house expenses $ 6000.00 Improvements, repairs and care of Capitol buildings and grounds 7000.00 Employees' wages 15000.00 Incidentals 2000.00 Total $30,000.00 BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS Expenses for serving school land notices, school land supplies to county treasurers, etc $ 5000.00 BOARD OF PURCHASE AND SUPPLIES. Expenses for publishing notices, printing, postage, etc. $400.00 a </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 APPROPRIATIONS. Ii the matter of appropriations I have carefully looked forward tie needs of the state for the next two years and have only id what in my judgment will be absolutely necessary to meet expenses for the next biennium, for the use of the office of nmissioner of Public Lands and Buildings and the different rds of which I am a member. I believe it to be poor economy ut down appropriations to such an extent that a deficiency to be created in order to meet the expenses necessary to perly carry on the work of the state. It is a well known fact an individual cannot purchase supplies on credit as cheaply le can for cash and what applies to the individual will apply. 1 greater force to the state. If the appropriation is too large ill revert to the state treasury. I have asked for $5,000 for the expenses of the Board of Edu - onal Lands and Funds as this board must furnish school land plies to county treasurers to enable them to properly carry on work which relates to school land transactions; and to meet expenses of the Commissioner's office incident to forfeitures auctions as well as to pay appraisers for reappraising ;racts as they become due, I deem it necessary that this mnt be allowed. I "he Board of Public Linds and Buildings has used the strict - economy during this biennium but find that the amount al - ed them is not sufficient to pay the running expenses and make necessary repairs without improvements which should be made rder that the Capitol building and grounds may be kept in &gt;ndition in keeping with the great State of Nebraska. I have efore asked that this Board be allowed the full sum of $30,000 e used for expenses, improvements and repair and care of &gt;itol building and grounds. EXPENDITURES. E taking charge of the office of Commissioner of Public and Buildings on January 3rd, 1901, I found the appropriation made by the Legislature of 1899 expended, </seg>
            <seg id="p011">APPROPRIATED BY THR l^RGISLATL'RR IQOI, KTC. 11 except that which belonged to the salary and the postage fund, hence expenses had to be paid by deficiency until April ist, when the new appropriation became available. In the matter of ex- pending the public money I have, in every instance, handled it as carefully as I would my own and submit statement of the expense of conducting the business of this department during the past two years. APPROPRIATED BY THE LEGISLATURE 1901 FOR USE OF COMMISSIONER'S OFFICE. Books, stationery and office supplies $ 600.00 Amount expended 263.68 Amount on hand Dec. ist, 1902 $336.32 Postage and postal expenses $1000.00 Amount expended 600.00 Balance on hand Dec. ist, 1902 $ 400.00 Furniture and repairs $ 200.00 Amount expended 70.30 Balance on hand Dec. ist, 1902 $ 129.70 Telephone and telegraph $ 250.00 Amount expended 182.36 Balance on hand Dec. ist, 1902 $ 67.64 Traveling expenses $ 250.00 Amount expended 000.00 Amount on hand Dec. ist, 1902 $ 250.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 APPROPRIATED FOR USE OF BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS. Books, stationery, county treasurers' supplies, etc ... $ 5000.00 Amount expended Nov. 30th 1866.18 Balance on hand Dec. 1st, 1902 $3133.82 BOARD OF PURCHASE AND SUPPLIES Appropriated by the legislature of 1901 for their use. . $ 400.00 Amount expended I 9 I -55 Amount on hand Dec. 1st, 1902 $ 208.45 This statement is taken from the books of the Land Com- missioner's office which show that vouchers have been signed and when warrants are drawn it will leave no outstanding debts whatever. COLLECTIONS. Cheyenne county warrants and interest on same. . . . $ 19.90 Certified copies of records ity'.oo Field notes, plats and topographical maps 454.14 Miscellaneous 608.76 Forfeiture fees 980.89 Rental Penitentiary Land 1470.00 Total receipts to Dec. 1st, 1902 $3547-69 CHEYENNE COUNTY WARRANTS. I received from my predecessor, two Cheyenne county war- rants, which had been issued in payment of field notes, one for $6.90 the other for $10.00. These I collected with interest amounting to $3.00 and paid same to State Treasurer, taking his receipt therefor. CERTIFIED COPIES OF RECORDS. Numerous requests have been made by individuals for certi- fied copies of different records in the office, many for the most trivial matters, thus making a large amount of unnecessary </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 work. J deemed it for the best interests of the state to make a small charge for each copy issued, and have by such action abated the abuse to a great extent, although this charge is con - trary to custom and there is no specific law in reference to a fee for this kind of work. CUSTODIAN OF FIELD NO^PES AND PLATS. By statute, the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings is made custodian of the government plats and field notes which belong to the state. 1 have made a small charge for copies in order to prevent imposition and at the same time to cover cost of time and material in preparing them. All of the work of making maps, preparing the field notes and plats has been done by the draughtsman and the fees turned into the state treasury, this will account for the increased receipts for this biennium as we find that while it has been customary to make charges in the past, many field notes have been prepared by parties in the state house and proof read Q in the commissioner's office and the fees received turned over to the individual instead of into the state treasury. MTsrFTJ.ANF.ons. On May 5th, 1901, the Superintendent of the Home for the Friendless turned over to me a check for $506.88 from the cash fund of that institution, and on May 23rd, 1901, I turned this over to Mrs. Sarah Sohus, the new Superintendent of the home, taking her receipt for same. The balance of the miscellaneous funds was received from various sources and turned into the state treasury. FORFEITURE FEES. Section 17, Chapter 80, Compiled Statutes, states "that the owner of any contract of sale or lease that is forfeited may be redeemed by paying all delinquencies and costs of serving no - tices and advertising at any time before such land is sold or leased." Pursuant to this, the Board of Educational Lands and Funds decided that a fee of fifty cents be charged each contract holder for every delinquent notice sent. This is very nearly the </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Ed cost of sending same, considering material, time and post- The money received for this has been collected by the ity Treasurers and noted upon the school land receipts but funds so received have been placed in the State General ■ PENITENTIARY LAND. The United States government granted to the State of Nebraska fifty sections of land for the purpose of the erection of penitentiary buildings. Nearly all of this was sold and the pro - ceeds applied as designated, but there still remains the South - east one-fourth (S. E. %) of the South-west one-fourth (S. W. % ) and the South-east one-fourth ( S. E. % ) of section twenty - six (26), township eight (8), range five (5), East; the North - west one-fourth (N. W. J^) of section thirty (30), township nine (9), range five (5); the East half (E. )&amp;) of the South - east one-fourth (S. E. %), section thirty-four (34), township nine (9), range four (4), and the North-west one-fourth (N. W. %) of section twenty-eight (28), township eleven (11), range four (4). Six-hundred seventy six and 71-100 acres situated in Lancaster and Seward counties. As all the public lands are placed under the control of the Board of Public Lands and Build - ings, when not otherwise specifically stated, I have leased this land from year to year to the highest bidder and have collected and turned over to the State Treasurer the sum of $1470.00 as rental during this biennium. I have in hand two notes for $100.00 each, payable December ist, 1903. I found among the papers of the last administration an old note of $50.00 which I collected and turned the proceeds into the State Treasury. We note that the Hon. John Steen, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, in his Seventh Biennial Report recom - mended to the Legislature that something be done with this land in order that same might be rented and the proceeds ditected to some use, this recommendation has been made in every report since then but no action has been taken. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 I would also call your attention to the fact that there is now in the hands of the State Treasurer the amount of $4,088.00 in the Penitentiary Land Fund and I would respectfully recom - mend that the coming legislature pass some measure authoriz- Ithe State Treasurer to credit the money received as rental this land to either the temporary school fund or to the State leral Fund. I would also recommend that the legislature direct this land Ite made a part of the educational lands of the state or that it sold and the proceeds turned into the general fund for use in uilding and repairing the penitentiary. LOST CONTRACTS. During the past two years, I have issued several hundred K:s of contracts supposed to be lost or destroyed, upon suit - proof being made, and have made no charge for this work, d that this is becoming a nuisance for many contracts are found after the copies have been issued. I believe many con - tracts are lost or mislaid through carelessness because a certi - fied copy can be obtained without charge and with less trouble than to search for the mislaid one. ASSIGNMENTS. I have recorded during my term of office 5,626 assignments, s, probate records, court records, etc., aggregating several usand pages of written matter. The time of two clerks is taken 3 this line of work ; as this record is for the protection of the vidual, I see no reason why a small fee should not be charged entering them of record. RECOMMENDATIONS. K would therefore recommend to the coming legislature that ■ enact a suitable law definitely fixing the amount of fees to </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 |:harged for field notes, certified copies of records, certified ies of lost contracts and for entering of record of the various gnments, etc., and designating that the fees so collected be :ed in the temporary school fund to be distributed twice a rfor the benefit of the school children of the state, or that r be turned in the State General Fund to help defray the gen - expenses of the state. By charging such fees it will nearly if fully defray the expenses of the Board of Educational Lands Funds which has to do directly with carrying on the busi - i which pertains to the school lands of the state. LEASE CONTRACTS. During the last biennium I have held auction in fifty-eight counties, leasing 164,711.60 acres of land; 53,390.15 of this was left unleased by my predecessor and 111,321.45 acres were for - feited by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. Owing to the better condition of the people of the state all lands have been leased at a higher valuation than formerly and the tendency is for it to go still higher, thus increasing the amount of rental to turn into the temporary school fund. This office has received many letters from different persons throughout the state, requesting reappraisement of many old school land leases, offer - ing more than double the price which is now received ; especially is this true in the entire eastern portion of the state. When we consider that nearly all the land in this section of the state was leased from fifteen to twenty-five years ago at a valuation preva - lent at that time, it can be readily seen that the valuation is indeed insufficient at the present time. I would respectfully recommend to the legislature that an appropriation be made to the Board of Educational Lands and Funds sufficient to meet the expense incurred incident to reap - praisement in accordance with the five-year clause in the lease contract and with the laws existing at the time the lease contract was entered into. A fact that sustains me in the above recom - mendation is that d urine the present biennium a number of or </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Lease Contracts. 17 E contracts have expired and new contracts entered into, the d of Educational Lands and Funds in each case has ordered ppraisement and the valuation has been raised from three enty dollars an acre on each and every contract. CONVERSION OF LEASE INTO SALE CONTRACTS. In the early part of my term of office, I received many uiries relative to the purchase of school lands by parties hold - lease contracts. The legislature of 1897 passed a measure ing the educational lands from the market, thus permitting them to be leased only. After personal investigation and enforced by an opinion from the Attorney General, I decided that any person holding a lease contract subsequent to July 1st, 1879 and prior to July 1st, 1897 could, upon proper procedure convert his lease into a sale contract or pay out immediately and receive a deed from the state. Psing my decision upon the fact that the law at the time of ig contained a clause stating that any person leasing the educational lands could surrender his lease contract at any during the life of the lease (twenty-five years) and receive instead a sale contract. This led many persons to build sub- Ritial houses thereon, to fence and place many other perma - t improvements upon the leased land, having full faith that at any time before the expiration of the lease contract, that it could be surrendered as stated by the law and a sale contract received upon which a deed could be obtained, thus enabling them to secure the full benefit of their time, labor and money which had been expended upon it. In consequence of the above decision I have issued eleven sale contracts for 1205.18 acres of land, amounting to a valuation of $17,389.75, which will increase the permanent school fund that amount when the con - tracts are fully paid. ' The Board of Educational Lands and Funds have at all times used their discretion in reference to the sufficiency of the appraisement, personally investigating each case to ascertain whether the amount designated would be fair both to the individual and the state; they have in many cases ordered a reappraisement in accordance with law by three resi- / ; </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 § free-holders, and in every instance where this has been the appraisement has been raised from one-third to one - of the original appraisement. EXTENSION OF SALE CONTRACTS. Iy order of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds, I : extended 186 sale contracts, aggregating 18,915 acres of for a period of ten years, in accordance with the law. A ;r number of contracts should have been extended and no &gt;t would have been, had it not been that the holders of sale racts were able to borrow money from loan companies for than six per cent, the rate specified by law on sale contracts; led many to borrow money at a cheaper rate, pay out on - sale contracts and obtain deeds. IDEMNITY SCHOOL LANDS IN THE BIG SIOUX RESERVATION, BOYD COUNTY, NEBRASKA. By Clear Uat No. 1, dated May 22, 1897, the honorable Secretary of the Interior, C. N. Bliss, on behalf of the United States, certified to the State of Nebraska certain Indemnity school land selections amounting to 2228.09 acres, made by the State in Boyd county, August 11, 1891, in conformity with a decision of former Secretary of the Interior Hon. Hoke Smith, dated February 12, 1894. These lands were entered upon the books in this office, appraised, and disposed of in accordance with the laws of this State. In May, 1889, the U. S. Land Office at O'Neill, Nebraska, in a letter addressed to J. V. Wolfe, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, inclosed a decis - ion of the honorable Secretary of the Interior (Hon. E. A. Hitchcock) dated May 5, 1899, overruling decision of February 12, 1894, and holding that the approval and certification to the state of the lands embraced in List No. 1, of May 22, 1897, (2228.09 acres) was null and void and ineffectual to convey to the state any right or title * * but directed that early </seg>
            <seg id="p019">X ™ 1 1 I OvfiUvLi X^Ai^lUo* 19 legislative relief be obtained by the state to secure the lands in question. Nothing whatever seems to have been done or attempted by this office looking towards the recovery of the lands, although two congressional sessions had been held, and the first notice to me of the status of these lands was the following letter from the honorable Commissioner of the General Land Department of the Interior, General Land Office. Washington, D. C, May 18, 1901. Hon. Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, Lincoln, Nebraska. Sir: May 5, 1899, the honorable Secretary of the Interior held that the selections embraced in List No. 1 of indemnity school land, O'Neill district, within the former Great Sioux Res - ervation, were invalid, and the approval and certification thereof to the state was null and void and ineffectual to convey to the state any right or title, but directed, in view of the fact that the state may have disposed of some of the tracts since certification, that an opportunity be afforded the state or its grantees to obtain relief by legislation, authorizing the purchase of the lands, and to that end, said lands have been withheld from entry. Since the promulgation of said decision, it does not appear that the state authorities have taken any action toward securing legislative relief. I hat this office may make proper report and recommenda - to the department with a view to the restoration of these s to settlement and entry, without jeopardizing rights ired by third parties in good faith from the state, I have to iest that this office be advised as to whether the state has [inhered, sold, leased or disposed of or agreed to sell, lease ispose of any of the following described lands or whether part thereof is in possession of any third party under any or commission of the state, and if any of said lands have sold, leased or encumbered, that you give the date of the </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 conveyance, lease or other instrument, and the date of the expir - ation of any lease, etc. * * * * * * Your earliest attention will be greatly appreciated. Very respectfully, Bingbr Herman, Commissioner. To which the following reply was sent: Office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. Lincoln, Nebraska, June 3, 1901. Hon. Binger Herman, Commissioner of the General Land Office, Washington, D. C. Sir: I have the honor to acknowledge receipt of your letter "G" of May 18th, 1901, and as requested therein, I herewith enclose a statement showing, first, list of the indemnity lands certified to the State of Nebraska by Clear List No. I, O'Neill Land District, May 22, 1897. Second, disposition of said lands by the state to individuals, giving name, post-office address, date, character and terms of contract. In the lease contracts issued by the state, the lease holder has the option during the term of the lease, to change same to a sale contract; in this con - nection I have the honor to state that some of the lands embraced in said Clear List No. 1, were selected at the instance and request of the present holders of leases who had exhausted their homestead rights upon government lands in Holt and other counties in this state, which they were compelled to abandon, because they were found, after a few years' residence thereon, to be totally worthless for the purpose of agriculture, upon which they depended for a living, and were therefore com - pelled to find state lands to establish a home and farm. Upon these tracts, homes are now established, houses and outbuildings of considerable value have been placed and the land is under cultivation. It is stated in your letter, above referred to, that the decision of the Secretary of the Interior of March 5, 1899, holding "that the selection embraced in List No. "1 of indemnity school lands, O'Neill District, within the former "Great Sioux Reservation were invalid and the approval and "certification thereof to the state was null and void, etc., etc., "etc.." but directed "in view of the fact that the state mav have </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 "tunity be afforded the state or its grantees to obtain relief by "legislation authorizing the purchase of the lands, and to that "end said lands have been withheld from entry," and it is also stated "that since the promulgation of said decision it does not "appear that the state authorities have taken any action toward I am unable to understand why my predecessor failed to urge upon our members of congress and our senators to protect, in some manner, the state and innocent holders of state con - tracts, by congressional legislation. Your letter to me is the first notice of the status of the lands in question and I would respectfully ask that in view of the facts above set forth that time be extended for the state to secure such legislation in the next congress as will protect the state and the holders of its contracts, and to this end I shall inform and urge upon our senators and members of congress to obtain the earliest possible action. Very truly yours, Gko. D. Follmkr, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings. Immediately after sending the foregoing letter, Senators Diet - rich and Millard and Representatives Burkett and Neville were severally given a full history of the case and urged to pass a bill at the earliest possible moment with the object of obtaining from congress the title to the lands. Senator Dietrich with the kind assistance of the Hon. Wm. A. Richards, Assistant Commis - sioner of the General Land Office, formulated the following "Bill" which under the able direction of the Senator and Con - gressman Burkett was passed in both houses of congress and be - came a law. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">.Land Commissioner s IvRport. 22 A BILL CONFIRMING TITLE TO THE STATE OF NEBRASKA OF CERTAIN SELECTED INDEMNITY SCHOOL LANDS. fe it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of United States of America in Congress assembled. I hat title be and is hereby confirmed to the State of Nebras - o all those certain tracts of land in the O'Neill, Nebraska, district, aggregating two thousand two hundred and twen - ght acres and nine-hundredths of an acre, heretofore selected tie state as indemnity for granted school lands which selec - i were approved by the Secretary of the Interior, May 22, ', in list numbered one, and duly certified to the State of Ne - ka by the Commissioner of the General Land office, but :h certification was, on May 5, 1899, declared by the Sec - •y of the Interior to be null and void and ineffectual to con - to the state any right or title : Biovided, That the State of Nebraska shall not hereafter be ed to further indemnity for the specific losses accruing to state in lieu of which said selections were made. Act approved April 15th 1902. Kius 2228.09 acres, valued at $33,421.35 were irrevocably rmed to the state. rEMNITY SCHOOL LAND SELECTIONS IN THE 3ANDONED FORT RANDALL MILITARY RES - ERVATION IN BOYD COUNTY, NEBRASKA. On March 3, 1893, congress passed the following: I In Act to provide for the survey and transfer of that part of Fort Randall Military reservation in the State of Nebraska lid state for school and other purposes. (27 U. S. Stat. Be it Enacted by the Senate and House of Represen - tatives of the United States of America in Congress Assembled: That the odd numbered sections in the portion of the Fort Randall Military Reservation situated in the State of Ne- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Indemnity School Land Selections. 23 braska, after the same shall have been surveyed as herein pro - vided, may be selected by the State of Nebraska at any time within one year after the filing of the official plats of survey in the District Land office as a part of the lands granted to said state as school indemnity for school lands lost in place under the provisions of "An act to provide for the admission of the State of Nebraska into the Union", approved February 9th, 1867, provided: that no existing lawful rights under any of the land laws of the United States providing for the disposition of the public lands, shall be accepted by the State of Nebraska in full satisfaction of lawful claims now existing or that may hereafter arise for school indemnity for a corresponding number of acres upon assignment of the bases of the claims by description and selection in accordance with the regulations of the Interior De - partment within the period of limitation aforesaid, such selection to be equally distributed so far as practicable among the several townships. Section 2. — That the even numbered sections and all of the odd numbered sections in said Reservation not selected under the pro - visions of section one of the act, shall be open to settlement under the homestead law only, provided, that before said lands shall be opened to settlement under this section, the Secretary of the In - terior shall appoint a Commission of three disinterested citizens of the United States who shall appraise said land and fix the value of each quarter section, and persons who take such lands under the homestead laws shall pay for such lands in three equal installments at times to be fixed by the Secretary of the Interior and they shall also comply with all provisions of home - stead laws of the United States. Sec. 3. — That the Secretary of the Interior be and hereby is authorized and directed to cause the lands embraced in that part of that said Military Reservation of Fort Randall in the State of Nebraska to be regularly surveyed by an extension of the public surveys over the unsurveyed portions of the same. Approved March 3, 1893. Bnder authority of an act of the Legislature of the State of raska (Chap. 122, Session Laws 1897 — 459) conferring </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Land Commissioner's Report. 24 upon the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings full power and authority to select from the lands embraced within the said Fort Randall Military Reservation, as provided by the said act of con- gress, and to receipt for the same, my predecessor computed the losses of school lands sustained by the state, by reason of Indian allotments, homestead entries and other appropriations of school sections, etc., and found them to amount to 6,554.51 acres, and he selected November El, 1897, from the odd numbered sections in the Fort Randall Military Reservation 6,434.48 acres and from lands formerly in the Big Sioux Indian Reservation added to the state (now Boyd county) 120 acres making a total of selections of 6,554.48 acres, as shown by his list of selections No. 2, dated November II, 1897, filed in the U. S. Land Office at O'Neill, Nebraska. The status of the list of selections No. 2, O'Neill Land Dis- trict is at present as follows, to-wit: Number of acres due the state 6,554.51 Number of acres selected in Fort Randall Reser- vation in odd numbered sections 6,434.48- Number of acres selected in vacant lands, Big Sioux Reservation, Boyd county 120.00 Total 6,554 4&amp; Eber of acres certified and confirmed to the te in the Fort Randall Reservation by the :retary of the Interior bv Clear List No. 2, Nov. 9, 1898 3.4 22 - 11 r by .Clear List No. 3, March 9, 1901 1,599.06 by Clear List No. 4, February 18, 1902 787.68 Total amount confirmed 5,808.85 Selections relinquished on account of prior selec - tion of bases in Valentine District July 24, 1883, List No. 7 320.00* Disapproval of excess of base of loss Tp. 32, R. 8 W 5.9c Disapproval of selection in the Great Sioux Reser- vation 1 20.00 445.90- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Indemnity School Land Selections. 25 Balance of selections allowed, but not yet con- As shown above, all the selections on the Fort Randall Reser - vation with the exeption of 299.47 acres has been confirmed and the title is now in the state, and the latter, 299 47 acres, has been allowed, and it is expected that they will be confirmed before this report is printed. Of the 5,800 acres of land confirmed to the state in the Ft. Randall Military Reservation about 3,000 acres, or about three-fifths of the total amount was for losses sustained in school sections 16 and 36 in Boyd county by reason of home - stead entries, Townsite appropriation and Indian allotments, the balance bf the losses werepruTcipally in the counties of Knox, Washington and Richardson, on account of Indian allotments and pre-emption of school sections. All but 1,560 acres of the land above referred to have been appraised according to law. I 'he records of this office show that when my predecessor, •. Wolfe) made the selections of indemnity lands in the Fort idall reservation, November 11, 1897, the following persons applied to the Register of the U. S. Land Office at leill to enter lands on the odd numbered sections granted to state, claiming settlement, to-wit: George Blair, N. E., Sec. J5-ir W.; John J. Blair, S. E. Sec. 33-35-1 1 W.; Etta D. rett, S. W. Sec. 17-34-10 W.; Rufus M. Everett, S. E. . 17-34-10 W.; Henry Blair, N. W. Sec. 3-35-11 W.; John 1, S. E. Sec. 5-34-1 1 W.; Joe Bowers, N. W. Sec. 9-34-1 1 W. All of the foregoing applications were rejected by the land office for the reason, that all odd numbered sections were granted to the state and were not subject to homestead entry. Appeals were taken by the applicants to the General Land Office and notices of appeal filed in this office. My predecessor finding that enough land of equal value could be selected from other odd sections or tracts to cover all deficiency, did not select the said tracts, and also, in the case of Henry Blair, 3 irmed 2 99-47 Total 745.37 Amount confirmed 5.808.85 Total .6,554.22 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Land Commissioner's Report. 26 Iie description of land was evidently erroneous, he omitted the list of selections the N. W. y K 33-35-11, presuming for of better or definite information that the said Henry Blair in all probability located on the same section with his rela - , George and John J. Blair, a most reasonable conclusion, was done not because of any rights of these parties, use they must be regarded as "Sooners" and "Trespassers" g to obtain school lands granted to the state, in violation of but because of the generosity of the state and its represen - e, the Commissioner. All of the odd numbered sections not selected by the state were opened to settlement by the homestead entrymen. After the filing of the list of selections November IX, 1897, Henry Blair and some eighteen other parties attemped to file homestead applications upon indemnity school land selections made by the state on odd numbered sections, all of which were rejected by the officers of the United States land office at O'Neill, for the reason that the land belonged to the State of Nebraska under its grant and by reason of its selection. They appealed from this decision to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, who approved the decisions of the local land office, and finally, they appealed from the decision of the General Land Office to the Secretary of the Interior, with the result that the decisions of the local land office and the General Land Office were sustained, and approved by the Secretary of the Interior. The case of H. A. Blair being the strongest case presented, the decision of the Hon. Secretary of the Interior of June 27, 1899, is important and is in part as follows: DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR. Washington, D. C, June 27, 1899. Henry A. Blair, ) v. \ State of Nebraska. ) , To the Commissioner of the General Land Office • * </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Department of the Interior. 27 "The triplicate plat of the survey of the land embraced in the portion of the Fort Randall Reservation situated in the State of Nebraska was filed in the local land office at O'Neill, Novem - ber 27, 1896. In a letter of instructions sent by your office to the register and receiver at O'Neill, Nebraska, August 18, 1897, (25 L. D. 141) it was said: Inder the terms of said act of March 3, 1893, the even num - :d sections on this portion of said reservation, and such of odd numbered sections as may not be selected by the state tin the time prescribed, were opened to settlement under the lestead law only. As said lands have been surveyed and raised, and the appraisal approved, you are hereby directed How homestead entries to go to record for lands in the said 1 numbered sections, but you will under no circumstances, n entries to go to record for any of the lands in the odd ibered sections on this reservation until further orders. The land in controversy is an odd numbered section covered by said survey, was selected by the state within one year after the filing of the plat of survey, and, if the selection is otherwise regular, must be sustained, unless such action will be prejudicial to an existing lawful right under some land law of the United States providing for the disposition of the public lands. Blair does not claim to have had any right whatever to the land at the time of the passage of the act of March 3, 1893, and by the terms of that act the lands in the odd numbered sections, to which there was no existing lawful right when the act was passed, were to be withheld from other disposition until one year after the filing of the official plats of survey in the district land office in order that the state might at any time during said year se - lect .the same as indemnity school lands. These lands if not so selected by the state within the time named, were to be appraised as provided in section 2, and then and not before were to be open to settlement under the homestead law. I rights to any of the lands in odd numbered sections could be ired by homestead settlement made after the passage of the ad before the expiration of the time accorded to the state for the :ise of its preference right of selection^ rights to all the lands </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Ki sections could be acquired in this manner, and thus the state eated in its right of selection. Nothing ot/this sort was in - i. ('he state was plainly given a preferred right to be exercised ny time within one year after the filing of the plats in the -ict land office. Blair's settlement on March 9, 1893, and his lication to enter on October 4, 1897, were both subsequent to date of the act and prior to the time given to the state for exercise of its preferred right of selection. If the state's selection of the land here in question was in ac - cordance with the regulations of this department governing the selection of school indemnity lands, the decision of your office is correct. Although the conclusion reached in that decision of necessity presupposes the regularity of the selection, no affirma - tive declaration seems to have been made upon this subject. Subject to the conditions named, the decision of your office is affirmed." The papers are herewith returned. Very respectfully, E. A. Hitchcock, Secretary. And then on appeal for review from this decision the follow - ing decision was rendered : DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR. K Washington, D. C, October 4, 1900. andbr H. Blair, ) , v. State of Nebraska. The Commissioner of the General Land Office. E: — "This is a duly entertained and matured motion for of Department decision of June 27, 1899 (28 L. D. which affirmed the decision of your office denying the ition of Alexander H. Blair to make homestead entry of </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Department of the Interior. 29 the N. W. %, Sec. 3, T. 34 N., R. 11 W., O'Neill land district, I 'his land is within the abandoned Fort Randall Military ervation, and Blair's application, which alleged settlement eon March 9, 1893, was rejected because of a selection of tract, November 11, 1897, by the State of Nebraska, on Hint of its school grant, under an act of congress of March B93, (27 Stat., 555), entitled "An act to provide for the sur - and transfer of that part of the Fort Randall Military Reser- Dn in the State of Nebraska to said state for school and x purposes", section 1 of which act is as follows: Be it eiacted by the Senate and Mouse of Representatives of the United States of America, in Congress Assembled: That the odd numbered sections in the portion of the Fort Randall Military Reservation situated in the State of Nebraska, after the same shall have been surveyed as herein provided, may be selected by the State of Nebraska at any time within one year after the filing of the official plats of survey in the district land office as a part of the lands granted to said state as school indemnity for school lands lost in place under the pro - visions of "An act to provide for the admission of the State of Nebraska into the Union" approved February 9, 1867 : -provided, That no existing lawful rights under any of the land laws of the United States providing for the disposition of the public lands shall be prejudiced by this act. And provided further, That said lands shall be accepted by said State of Nebraska in full satisfaction of lawful claims now existing or that may here - after arise, for school land indemnity for a corresponding num - ber of acres, upon assignment of the bases of the claims by description and selection in accordance with the regulations of the Interior Department within the period of limitation, afore - said; such selections to be equally distributed as far as practi - cable, among several townships. Kie settlement as alleged by Blair in his said application hav - been made subsequent to the passage of said act, it was by the decision under review that a settlement on an odd </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 iibered section within said reservation after the passage of act of March 3, 1893, supra, and an application to enter the t thus settled upon, filed prior to the expiration of the period &gt;rded to the state by said act within which to exercise a erence right of school indemnity selection, cannot defeat assertion of such right on the part of the state. The motion for review proper, presents no question which was not fully and carefully considered when the decision under review was rendered, and nothing which casts doubt upon the correctness of that decision upon the facts as then presented. But a reconsideration and modification of said decision is asked because of alleged newly discovered evidence, and in an affidavit in support of said motion, Blair spates : That at the date of his application for the tract of land involved herein, affiant was misled in the showing made as to the exact date of his settlement and residence upon said tract, in that affiant was laboring under the belief that his settlement right began to run from the date he moved his family upon the said tract, to-wit: March 3, 1893, whereas the true date of affiant's settlement upon said tract was on the 19th of February, 1893. That on the 22nd day of February, 1893, affiant com - menced the construction of a dwelling house and stable upon the said tract of land, and resided upon and occupied the said land the greater portion of the time from February 22, 1893, to March 9, 1893, at which time affiant moved his family, consist - ing of a wife and two children, upon the said tract, and have continued to reside thereon to the present time and cultivate and utilize said premises under the homestead laws of the United States. i'hese statements are corroborated by an affidavit signed by persons, who aver personal knowledge of the facts therein ed, and, inasmuch as they are not controverted by the state, be taken as true. The question, therefore, arises as to the ct of a settlement on an odd numbered section of land within abandoned Fort Randall Military Reservation, made prior to passage of the act of March 3, 1893, and existing at the date le passage of said act. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 If Blair's settlement upon said land was an existing lawful right under any land law of the United States providing for the disposition of the public lands, it is protected by the first pro - viso to section one of said act; otherwise such settlement was no bar to the state's right of selection. At the date of said settle - ment the land in controversy was in the military reservation. October 20, 1893, the reservation was turned over to this department by the Secretary of War for disposition under the act of July 5, 1894, or as otherwise provided by law. It is not necessary to inquire whether the military reservation ceased at the date of the passage of the act of March 3, 1893, or whether that reservation continued until October 20, 1893, when the War department formally relinquished its control thereof. If the military reservation ceased March 3, 1893, this land being an odd numbered section therein, was withheld from other dis - position by said act for one year after the filing of the official plat of survey thereof in the district land office, in order that the state might by indemnity selection thereof satisfy losses in place in its school grant. At the date of Blair's settlement, and at all times since then to the time of the state's selection, no law - ful right could have been initiated upon said land under any public land law of the Untied States, and hence at the date of the act of March 3, 1893, Blair did not have an existing lawful right. His act of settlement was not authorized by any law, was a mere trespass, and he took nothing thereby. The debates of congress upon the bill which afterwards became the law above quoted seem to indicate that the "existing lawful rights" intended to be protected by said proviso were such as it was contemplated might exist by reason of the provisions of an act of July 5, 1884, (23 Stat. 103) entitled "an act to provide for the disposal of abandoned and useless military reservations," under which this land would have been disposed of, upon being turned over by the War Department, but for this special legislation contained in the act of March 3, 1893. Kud act of July 5, 1884, provides that any settler who was in al occupation of any portion of an abandoned military reser - )n prior to the location of such reservation, or who had set- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 tied thereon, prior to January i, 1884, in good faith and for the purpose of securing a home and entering the same under the general land laws and had continued in such occupation to the date of the *£t, should be entitled to enter the land so occupied according to the government surveys and sub-divisions, if qualified to make entry under the homestead laws, provided that the land was subject to entry at the date of the withdrawal. A question very similar to the one herein involved was con - sidered and passed upon by the Department in the case of John W. Imes (12 L. D. 288). That case arose under the act of February 13, 1891, (26 Stat., 749), which was an act provid - ing for the disposition of the abandoned Fort Ellis Military Reservation in Montana. The act provided for an extension of the public surveys over the unsurveyed portion of the reserva - tion, and gave the state the right to select at any time within one year after the approval of the survey, any portion of said lands in satisfaction of its school grant, with the proviso, "That 00 existing lawful rights to any of said lands initiated under any of the laws of the United States shall be invalidated by this act." At page 289, the Department said: I 'he only lawful rights to these lands (that) could exist at date of this grant to the state were those acquired under act of July 5, 1884, that is by seitlers prior to the reserve, o January 1, 1884, who continued occupancy for the pur - ; of securing a home. KUair is not within the provisions of the act of 1884. He was in actmil occupation of the land in controversy prior to the lion of the reservation and had not settled thereon prior to \uary 1, 1884. The motion for review is denied. The papers are herewith returned. Very respectfully, Thos. Ryan, Acting Secretary. In the same manner all of the contests of the trespassers upon the school lands in the Ft. Randall Reservation were finally closed as far as the general government was concerned and the </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 I of the lands confirmed to the state. All this was done with - the state making any defense whatsoever or putting to proof several allegations of the contestants, relying entirely upon sufficiency of the act of congress, approved March 3rd, 3, granting the lands to the state for schools. These alleged squatters and trtspassers failing in their attempts before the Interior Department of the United States to defraud the state of its indemnity school lands, then sought to obtain leg - islative relief, and so, the legislature of 1901 passed Chapters 109, in and 115, in the last days of the session, directing the Governor to execute a deed of relinquishment to the United States to the land in question, assuming that the lands had not been confirmed to the state by the United States government. The same Legislature also passed House Roll No. 23, for the relief of Russell L. Loomis of Red Willow county who claimed certain land (school land) under the same, in fact, under a better condition of affairs, so far as he was concerned, and the Gover - nor was directed to execute a deed to the land to Loomis, and when the four bills were presented to Governor Dietrich he vetoed House Roll No. 23, for the following reasons: "In exer - cising the veto power in this case, I do it on constitutional grounds, this act in my opinion is clearly in conflict with section 18, Art. 3 of the Constitution which provides: that lands under control of the state shall never be donated to railroad com- I" ;s, private corporations or individuals. Being also in conflict section 8, article 8 which says, university, agricultural col - common school or other lands which are now held or may ifter be acquired by the state for educational purposes shall )e sold for less than $7.00 an acre, nor less than the lised value. Since the Constitution permits neither the leg - ire nor the chief executive to specialize, it is evident there - that though the contemplated beneficiary may by rules of y be entitled to relief, such relief cannot come in the manner ided for in this act." Kotwithstanding this veto for the relief of Loomis, the Gov - &gt;r did approve Chapters 109, 111 and 115, for the relief of ers on Ft. Randall Reservation, upon the written opinion of </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 the Attorney General of the state, which opinion was as follows : State of Nebraska, Officb of Attorney General. Lincoln, April ist, xooi. Hon. Charles H. Dietrich, Governor of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Sir: — After an examination of Senate File No. 215 in connection with the record in the office of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, I submit the following in response to an inquiry from the executive office : Alexander H. Blair's homestead is part of the indemnity school land selected by the state, but the selection has not beeo approved by the government, and the state may select an equal amount of other land in the Fort Randall Military Reservation. The record of the United States Land Office, a copy of which is on file in the office of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, shows that Blair's claim is a just one made in good faith. The department of the Interior at Washington decided that if Blair will procure the state's relinquishment to the tract in question, his application will be given equitable consideration and the state will be allowed to select other lands of equal area from any of the undisposed of odd numbered sections in said res - ervation. Since the selection made by the state has not been finally approved, and since the state may select other land in lieu of Blair's homestead, the state may relinquish its right to the land described in Senate File No. 215, without violating any provision of the Constitution. I have made hasty examination of some of the records of t*ie claims of persons for whose benefit Senate Files 300 and 301 were passed, and find them in the same situation as the claim of Alexander H. Blair. Very respectfully yours, F. N. Prout, Attorney General. Tnis opinion of the Attorney General was clearly erroneous, inasmuch as the records of this office did show at that time that the lands had been confirmed to the state March 9, igo /, and fur - ther, that there were no other lands in the Fort Randall Military </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 Reservation subject to selection by the state in lieu of the lands sought to be relinquished, and therefore, the offer to permit the state to select other lands in the Fort Randall Reservation could not be entertained. All cases stood upon equal footing, and if Loomis was not entitled to relief, settlers in Fort Randall Reservation were not entitled to anything whatever, a peculiar state of facts to say the least. There is no question but that all the acts passed by the legislature of 1901, for these lands or affecting them, were and are unconstitutional; nevertheless, on February nth, 1902, the Board of Educational Lands and Funds passed a resolution granting relief to the settlers in Fort Randall Reservation instructing the Attorney General to prepare a deed for the Gov - ernor to sign, relinquishing the lands in Boyd county to the United States. I strongly and earnestly protested against the action of the Board for that the same was unconstitutional, and for that the General Land Office and the Secretary of the Interior of the U. S. had denied the right of the settlers to either homestead or pre-empt any of the land selected by the state as school indemnity land. In this matter I had consulted Hon. M. B. Reese, ex-Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of this state, and before final action on the resolution I presented and had read the following opinion : WRITTEN OPINION. JUDGE REESE RELATIVE TO RIGHTS OF BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND FUNDS TO TAKE ACTION IN RELATION TO PETI- TION OF MR. BLAIR AND OTHERS IN BOYD COUNTY LAND CASE. First: It seems to me that the title to the land has become fully vested in the state for the benefit of the school funds of the state and is within the provisions of the Constitution relating to the school lands. the title having thus vested, I am unable to see how the state be divested of its title except in the method prescribed by </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 the Constitution. Section i, of article 8, places all such lands in the custody and control of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. Section 2 prohibits the disposition of the lands in any other way than "in accordance with the terms of the grant," the only method given by the Constitution for the disposition of such lands are sale or lease and by section 8, article 8, of the Constitution, it specifically states "university, agricultural, com - mon school or other lands which are no.w held or may hereafter be acquired by the state for educational purposes, shall not be sold for less than $7.00 per acre," and the Constitution further states (See section 18, Art. 3) that lands under control of the state shall never be donated to railroad companies, private cor - porations or individuals. The only theory upon which the acts of April, 1901, (Session Laws 1901, page 516 Id.) can be held to he constitutional is that the title has never vested in the state, but that the selection by the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings is void or voidable. Neither of these positions can be maintained. The land did belong to the United States, the United States trans - ferred it to the state and the state accepted the title — if the lands belong to the state, the Constitution places it in the care and management of the Board. It can go nowhere else. If the acts of the legislature of 1901 are upheld, they have deprived the Board of any authority over the land, and that body can have nothing to do with it; the law directs the Gov - ernor to give the lands back to the United States, and that unconditionally ; the Board is not to i&gt;e consulted. Under the provisions of these acts there is nothing to be done but the simple act of the Governor, in making the deed. The Board, the custodian of the state land, who is the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, and has direct charge of said lands, according to all laws and customs of this state and other states, is not to be consulted. The Constitution says "shall constitute a Board of Commissioners for the sale, leasing and general management of all lands and funds set apart for educational purposes, etc." The provisions of both the acts of 1901 are the same, "that the Governor of the State of Nebraska be and he is </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Written Opinion. 37 hereby authorized and directed to execute a deed of reltnqnish - tnent to the United States of America, conveying any and all interests of the State of Nebraska in and to the said particular tracts of school land." There is nothing for the Board to do — there is no action for it to take; it is my opinion that both acts are in clear violation of the Constitution and are void, and that they confer no authority on any person or board to take any action in the matter, and that any conveyance of said land by the Governor — or by any other person, either with or with - out the sanction of the Board — would be wholly without author- It seems to me proper to show the history of the proceedings leading up to the passage of the resolution of February It, 1902. The record shows, that when the resolution was pre - sented to the Board for passage, one member voted in the affirmative, one in the affirmative, wilh the proviso that the matter should be settled in the courts, another in the affirmative, stating that his reason for so doing that the state could appeal it if it so desired and the settlers could not. I voted No on constitu - tional objections to the legality of the proceedings. My object in calling attention to this, is that in view of the vote and expres - sion of the members of the Board it was not then decided that the Governor should execute and issue a deed as prayed for, except in a certain contingency, and one member's vote was clear that he was not in favor of the passage of the resolution, unless the question was settled by the courts; it then seemed to me that the Governor had no authority vested in him by this resolution as passed by the Board unless other and further proceedings were had and done and the resolution was not passed by a legal majority vote; that the record of the proceedings shows that the legality and constitutionality of the resolution was specifically challenged by the vote of the members of the Board, as the President of the Board did not vote, hence the resolution does not seem to have been legally carried. This may seem somewhat technical on my part, nevertheless it is a circumstance to be taken into consideration, and I still adhere to the opinion, that the grant was not legally authorized and that before the Governor </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Land Commissioner's Report. should deliver a deed, the legality thereof should have been adjudicated by a court of competent jurisdiction of this state before the same could be made binding upon this state. A deed to the land was subsequently prepared by the Attorney General and presented to me for my signature, which deed I refused to sign for reasons stated. Yet the deed was executed and delivered by the Governor to the attorneys for the appli - cants, and by them sent to the Secretary of the Interior, where it is now pending, without my signature, as required by Sec. 7, Chap. 69, Laws of 1899, which provides: "When the Board of Educational Lands and Funds become satisfied that full payment has been made on any tract of land heretofore sold, the Gov - ernor shall under the Great Seal of the State, make a deed therefor to the purchaser or his assignee, and all deeds so issued shall be attested by the Commissioner of Public Lands and Build - ings, and record thereof kept in his office." This is the only gen - eral law in the statutes of this state that I hare discovered for the making and delivery of a deed. It cannot be seriously urged that the Law of 188 1, Sec. 3979, Chap. 69, Compiled S atutes 1902, was applicable to the case, or could authorize the action of the Board. That act simply pro - vides * * * "That whenever any person has been allowed a homestead or -preemption filing on land in any United States Land Office in the State of Nebraska supposing the land to belong to the United States • • ♦ supposing the same to be open to homestead or preemption settlement because of being settled and improved upon before the survey thereof, and having made valuable improvements thereon." Neither Mr. Blair nor any of his co-petitioners came within the provisions of this act because they had never been allowed a homestead or -preemption filing in any United States Land Office in Nebraska for these lands. Again in circular from the United States General Land Office, issued July 11, 1890, page 11, it is said, "Applicants to make homestead entries were restricted by Sec. 2289, Rev. Stat. U. S. to "unappropriated public lands upon which such person may have filed a preemption claim or which may at the </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Written Opinion. 39 * • ■■ ■ Lite tt y) L-J 1 1^. a I i \j\ I Jo 1X1 41%,! \T % c/C &amp;UvfG%*w £ t/ Z'TvcTflZ'* #C/7p« U LA L I 1 1C act of March 3, 1891, which repealed the preemption laws so amended said section 2289 as to describe the class of lands sub - ject to homestead entry simply as "unappropriated public lands." A homestead settler on unsurveyed public land not yet open to entry must make entry within three months after the filing of the township plat of survey in the District Land Office. Id. P. 13. (Act May 14, 1880, 2; Stat. L. 140.) I also call attention to an extract from an opinion rendered this office by Attorney General Prout under date of April 15, 1902. The state leased to one Hill a quarter section of school land in Stanton county, and that by mesne assignment, one Layton holds the lease, claims the right to surrender it and demands from the state a sale contract or deed for the land demised. Extract from opinion. * * * Cites Sec. 1, Art. 3 of the Constitution defining powers and duties of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds * * * "The * Constitution charged the Board of Educational Lands and Funds with the duty of selling educational lands, and it is fair to assume that the members thereof were to have some discretion in regard to the purchase price. If they have such discretion, then it is not within the power of the legislature to transfer that dis - cretion to another tribunal over which the Board has no control. If the Board has power under the Constitution to reject an offer which , is wholly inadequate the legislature cannot make appraisers appointed by county officers final arbiters to fix the value of the state's lands, that power committed by the Consti - tution to the Board of Educational Lands and Funds cannot be transferred by legislative enactment to another tribunal. See State vs. Bartley. 40 Neb. 298. A number of decisions support the theory that the State Board may exercise discretion in regard to rental values or purchase price of educational lands. The supreme court has held that the Board in managing school lands is charged with the administration of a trust and that the courts will not interfere with the Board's management unless there is an abuse of trust or discretion ♦ * * * In * * State vs. Scott, 18 Neb. 600, the court said: The Board of </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Land Commissioner's Report. 40 educational Lands and Funds is a trustee for the sale and leas - ing of the land set apart for the support of educational institu - tions, and to justify the interference of a court there must be an abuse of the trust. ♦ ♦ * // is the duty of the Bourd to sell or lease the educational lands of the state for the highest price possible to be obtained attd increase and protect by all hon - orable means thejunds for the support of the educational institu - tions; and so long as ihe Board is faithfully performing its duly in that regard this court will refuse to interfere. * * * If the rule stated is applicable to the present case, the holder of the lease cannot compel the officers of the state to execute a sale contract or deed for the demised premises for a consideration less than the full value of the lands. For the reasons stated I am of the opinion that the stale should not execute a sale contract for the land in question for the price fixed by the appraisers unless ordered to do so by a court of competent jurisdiction." Now if the reasoning of the Attorney General is sound (and I believe it is) and applicable to the case then presented, it cer - tainly seems that it must of necessity be applicable to a case where an effort is made to donate school lands without even the slightest remuneration. This same question had been previously decided by ex-Attor - ney General Smythe in an opinion rendered to my predecessor pertaining to Senate File No. 312, which particularly appertains to school lands and is as follows: In June, 1897, a question arose as to the powers granted by Senate File No. 312, passed by the legislature of 1897. The Board of Educational Lands and Funds had set aside certain lands for the use of the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane. In an opinion rendered by Attorney General Smythe to the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings relative thereto, he says: "Senate File No. 312 cannot be sustained, at least as far as it affected that portion of land which was school land." The act in question purported to set the land aside for the use of the hospital. "That if the intention of the legislature was to give the land to that institu - tion the act was in conflict with the Constitution and amounted to a diversion of the public school fund, and it was not within the </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Written Opinion. 41 power of the legislature to transfer the land to the hospital for the insane, and if that was the purpose of the act, it was clearly When the United States granted the land to the State of Nebraska (Chap. 200 U. S. Stat. at large, Vol. 27, p. 555) the act among other things provided: "That -said lands shall be accepted by the State of Nebraska in full satisfaction of lawful claims now (then) existing or that may hereafter arise from school land indemnity for a corresponding number of acres." The State of Nebraska accepted the land on these conditions and so receipted for same to the United States. And I believe the rule of law is well settled, that the state may control and regulate the use of state land under the grant, but it has no right to dispose of the property and to devote it to private use, thereby destroying the trust created for the benefit of the school fund of the state. I hen the settlers made settlement upon the land and made able improvements thereon, as they claim, they had ample •rtunity of knowing that government surveys had been rided and been marked by stone monuments up to and sur - ding the Fort Randall Military Reservation in August, 1, and the plats filed in the United States Land Office at eill on November 27, 1896, and preliminary lines had been tided across the reservation from these government surveys &gt;cal*8urveyors as evidenced by the fact that wagon roads fenites surrounding the sections in the military reserve were d in the United States' survey of 1895 to be within a few of a perfect alignment of the sections as surveyed by the ed States surveyor in 1895. The lands sought to be deeded to the United States are school lands, and cannot be deeded except as provided by the Constitu - tion and laws of Nebraska. Sec. 3, Art. 8 of the Constitution provides: "The following are hereby declared to be perpetual funds for common school purposes of which the annual interest or income can only be appropriated, to-wit : Such per-centum as has been or may hereinafter be granted by congress on the sale of lands in this state. 2. All moneys arising from sale or 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 leasing of sections 16 and 36 in each township in this state and the lands selected or that may be selected in lieu thereof. 3. The proceeds of all lands that have been granted or may hereafter be granted to the state where by the terms and con - ditions of such grant, the same are not to be otherwise appro - priated. 5. All money, stocks, bonds, land and other property now belonging to the common school fund. Again, section 9, article 8, of the Constitution provides, all funds belonging to the state for educational purposes, the income and interest thereof are only to be used, shall be deemed to be trust funds held by the state, and the state shall supply all losses thereof, that may in any manner accrue so that same shall remain forever inviolate and undiminished. The Constitution of the state is higher in authority than any law direction or order made by anybody or any officer assuming to act under it. Since such body or officer must necessarily be subservient to the instrument by which the delegation is made, this is a fundamental principle of law and cannot be questioned. Under section 1, article 8, of Constitution, the Governor, Sec - retary of State, Treasurer, Attorney General and Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings are created a Board of Commis - sioners for the sale, leasing and general management of all lands and funds set apart for educational purposes and for the invest - ment of school funds in such a manner as may be prescribed by law. There is really no merit in the contention of the settlers; none of them claim to have made settlement until the year 1893, the survey was made in 1895, and the plats in the United States Land office filed in November, 1896. By the act, chapter 300, providing for the grant of the land to the state, it is provided in section 2 of the act as follows: E'hat even numbered sections and all the odd numbered see - in said reservation not selected under the provisions of &gt;n 1 of the act shall be open to settlement under the home - 1 law only. Provided, that before such lands shall be ed to settlement under this section, the Secretary of the </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Wkittbn Opinion. 43 Interior shall appoint a commission of three disinterested citizens of the United States, who shall appraise said lands and fix the value of each quarter section, and persons who may take such land under the homestead laws shall pay for such lands in three equal installments at times fixed by the Secretary of the Interior, and they shall also comply with the provisions of the homestead laws of the United States." It will be seen, therefore, that they never came under the pro - visions of the terms of the grant to the state and their attempt to secure the land cannot be termed other than that of an attempt at an unlawful appropriation of the state school lands, intended and created exclusively for school purposes by the United States in making the grant. It should be noted that in the preamble of the acts of the slature of 1901, chapters 109, 111, 115, the legislature arded the title to these indemnity school lands as unconfirmed, ' had been selected by mistake, which was false and untrue; they e confirmed to the state, and had been selected according to law. s evident the legislature acted upon this information upon e premises. And it is asserted that the legislature before passage of these bills, never consulted this office or inquired examined the records of this office; otherwise it would e been informed of the facts that the records of this office show that these lands had been confirmed to the state. I 'articular attention is called to the fact that the public lands his state that remain as public lands subject to entry or ction are practically worthless as evidenced by the i introduced and now pending in congress to reserve all lie lands remaining in the state for grazing purposes to be ed at two cents per acre, suppose we figure the value of the Is upon a basis of six per cent per acre, there being 26S0 ■s of land sought to be alienated from the state and other Is to be selected in lieu thereof, at six per cent, the value of land to be selected per acre would be 2&gt;Z% cents. Lands selected and confirmed to the state in 1891 were the best lands remaining in the public domain subject to selection at that time; the value of these lands, as made by the county com- </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 missioners of the various counties according to law, ranges from twenty-five cents to $1.50 per acre, the average being about 50 cents per acre, all of which is evidenced by the records of this office. It is asserted as a fact that the fair market value of the land in controversy without improvements was $7.00 per acre at the time of selection, and that the land is now reasonably worth at least $20 per acre. Taking this land at $20 an acre it will be seen that if this land grabbing scheme goes through, the State of Nebraska would lose from the school fund of this state at least $53,600.00 and in addition would involve all indemnity selection in the Ft. Randall Reservation, amounting to about 6,100 acres, of the value of $122,000.00. To exchange this valuable land for other lands, even at an appraised value of $1.25 per acre, would depreciate the value of school lands acquired and held by this state, and thereby the school fund would not remain inviolate — the same would be depreciated and diminished, the state would be going into the business of speculating with school property and it would be a most serious and dangerous precedent to establish. Itie people of the State of Nebraska view any encroachment 1 the school lands and funds of this state with apprehension alarm. Any attempt to diminish or lessen either the lands le funds of the state which have been dedicated for school oses are deemed a sacred trust, entrusted to the care and ting of our state officers for a specific and definite purpose — ;rmit them under any circumstances to divert the lands or s, from the purpose for which they were intended would ssented by the people of this state as misconduct in office. The experience of the State of Nebraska in the past, is a warning to anyone, who seeks to interfere with, or destroy, the stability of the school funds or the value of the school lands of the state. This office has been harassed by the attorneys of these squatters in every way possible in the discharge of its duty under the law as evidenced by injunction proceedings had at the instance of some of the beneficiaries in this pretended deed, not only during this, but the previous administration, to- wit : </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 John Brimmer, Frank J. Bednar, Stephen Tanner, Art McCright filed a petition in the county court in Boyd county (the records of this office fail to show upon what ground the suit was brought) against the officers of the Board of Educa - tional Lands and Funds and the county treasurer to enjoin them from interfering in any manner with their possession and settle - ment of land which is supposed to cover the land allotted to them in the deed; they secured a temporary injunction on May 5, 1899, from the County Judge in the absence of the District Judge from the county, default entered of all the defendants on October 6, 1899, and temporary injunction made perpetual on October 6, 1899. I here are certain injunction proceedings now pending and :termined in the district court in B )yd county relative to e lands, which are being properly attended to by the irney General. In all my proceedings had and done it has 1 my earnest effort to prevent, while I am an officer of this :, thfe unlawful sequestration of a penny of the school fund foot of school land unless as by the Constitution directed, I thus seek to impress these views upon and urge them to attention of the legislature. ESCHEATS. Under act of legislature of 1899, chapter 73, section 71, Compiled Statutes, the state secured 640 acres of land in Chey - enne county now known as the Fawcus land or escheat, paying for t^e same a sum of $6,630.00. This land had been lying idle for several years, or used by parties without the consent of the state and without any payment or income to the state for such use, while the few improvements that were upon the land at the time of the appraisement were rapidly disappearing. As custodian of the lands of the state I concluded that it was my duty to protect the state's interests in reference to this es - cheat as well as to, in some manner, place this land on a basis that a partial payment would be made to the state, for money in - vested therein. At the meeting of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds in June, 1901, I presented the matter fully to them with the request that they ask a written opinion from the </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Isrney General relative to what officer or State Board should trol the above mentioned escheat under the provisions of sec - 70-73, chapter 73, Compiled Statutes, which restricted non - dent aliens in their right to acquire and hpld real estate, what disposition should be made of the funds arising from sale or leasing of such land and as to whether this land could lisposed of as stated in section 71, chapter 73, as the other s belonging to the state. On June nth, I received the fol - ng opinion adressed to the Board of Educational Lands and Section 1, article 8 of the Constitution provides: "The Gov - ernor, Secretary of State, Treasurer, Attorney General and Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings shall, under the direction of the legislature, constitute a board of "commissioners for the sale, leasing and general management of all lands and funds set apart for educational purposes, and for the investment of school funds in such manner as may be prescribed by law." Section 3, of the same article provides : iThe following are hereby declared to be perpetual funds for mon school purposes of which the annual interest or income r can be appropriated, to-wit: * •- • ♦ The net pro- Is of lands and other property and effects that may come to state, by escheat or forfeiture." Section 4 of said article contains this provision: Ehe interest arising from all the funds mentioned in the pre - g action, together with all the rents of the unsold school , and such other means as the legislature may provide, be exclusively applied to the support and maintenance of ion schools in each school district in the state." From the above quoted provisions of the constitution 1 con - clude (1), that lands which the state acquires by escheat must be managed and controlled by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds; (2), that in case the lands thus escheated are sold by the direction of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds, the net proceeds of such sale will belong to the permanent school </seg>
            <seg id="p047">W R1TTRN V-/PINION. 47 leased, the funds arising from such lease will belong to the itm - porary school fund of the state. K'he constitutional requirements to which I have adverted are paramount law of this state and cannot be defeated by legis- In adhearing to the directions of the constitution, it will be necessary for the board to disregard contradictory provisions in section 29, chapter 80, Compiled Statutes, that such escheated lands shall be managed by the governor, and superintendent of public instruction, and that the proceeds thereof shall be placed in the temporary school fund. iection I, article 9, chapter 83, Compiled Statutes, authoriz - the State Treasurer to sell such lands, is also to be disre - jed in so far as it may be construed to take from the .Board Educational Lands and Funds the constitutional power under ch they are directed to control school lands. Yours very respectfully, F. N. Prout, Attorney General." Acting upon the aforesaid opinion of the Attorney General, the Board of Educational Lands and Funds on June mh, directed the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings to have this escheated land appraised in accordance to law, this was done at once, and on July 10th, the County Commissioners of Cheyenne county reported that they had appraised the land at its just and true value together with the improvements thereon, as follows: S.W N. E. of 24-20- 32 containing 40 acres at $5. 00 per am', imp. #5.50 M . W. N . \V. of 24-20-52 containing 40 acres at $ 2. 50 per acre, imp. 1 K.M S.W. K.W. of 24-20-52 containing 40 acres at |I3.OO per acre, imp. 8.80 S. K. X. \V of L'4-20-52containing40acre8at$6.00peracTe 1 imp. IS. W.of 24-20-52containing40acresat#2.50peracre, imp. 6.60 S.W. of 24-20-52 containing 40 acres at $2. 50 per acre, imp. 8.80 S.W. of 24-.'0-52containing40acrenat$2.50peracre, imp. 8.80 S. W. of 24-20-.VJcontaining40acre8att2.50peracre, imp. 110.60 . S. E. of 24-20 -52containiug40acresat$2.00peracre, imp. 3.30 S. K. of 24-20-52containing40acresat$2.00peracre, imp. S. E. S. E. of 24-20-52 containing 40 acres at $2. 00 per acre, imp. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 N.E. N.W. of 25-20-52containing40acre8att2.00peracre, imp. N.W.N.W. of 25-20-52 containing 40acresat $3. OOperacre, imp. 11.80 S.W.N.W. of 25-20-52containing40acre8at$1.25peracre, imp. 17.60 N.W.S. W.of 25-20-52containing40acresat$1.25peracre, imp. 16.60 S.W. S. W. of 25-20-52containing40acresat$1.25peracre, imp. 8.80 Total acreage acquired 640 Value of Imp'm'ts . $221.80 This appraisement was accepted by the Board of Educational Lands and Funds and same was ordered placed upon the abstract books in the office of Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings to be leased in like manner as other educational lands of the state. After proper notice had been given by advertisement in a paper published in Cheyenne county, a special auction was held at Sidney in Cheyenne county, on the 15th day of August, 1901, and these lands were leased to the highest and best bidder at the appraised value together with a cash bonus of $250.00, in addi - tion to the payment of $221.80, the appraised value of the improvements. Is the laws relating to escheats seem to be somewhat at vari - with the constitutional powers and duties of the Board of rational Lands and Funds, I would respectfully recommend section 29, chapter 80, be repealed, or amended to read,"all ■erty, real or personal, which may now belong to this state scheat, or that may hereafter escheat to the state for want wers, shall be managed by the Board of Educational Lands Funds and such property be made part and parcel of the ol lands of the state to be leased in the manner prescribed iw for other school land." t would recommend further that chapter 73, section 71-73, lpiled Statutes, be amended in such manner as to repeal the se whereby the state pays the costs incurred in the proceed - , and that the costs of suit be deducted from the total raised value of the escheat. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">» 49 RECOMMENDATIONS RELATING TO LAWS OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS. I would recommend that chapter 69, article 1, steetion 5, Compiled Statutes, be repealed or amended. All questions of right to homestead or preemption has been, and necessarily must be, settled and determined by the United States Land Depart - ment. The law of 1881, chapter 58, section 1, provides for "persons who have been allowed filing on land in any United States Land Office, supposing same to belong to the United States and open to homestead or preemption settlement because of being settled upon and improved before the survey thereof and having made valuable improvements * * * Afterwards ascertaining that lands belong to the state ♦ * *." This law as it now stands creates confusion and permits of unlawful action to be taken against the best interests of the state, the par - ties having ample rights and facilities to demonstrate their rights to the lands before the United States Land Office. If this law be not repealed it should be amended so as to provide that when - ever such parties have fully adjudicated their rights before the United States Land Office and have obtained a decree of adjudi - cation there, in their favor, that then, and then only, should they be entitled to any relief from the state under the provision of this act. Section 6, chapter 69, should also be repealed, or amended so as to conform to the above recommendation. I would respectfully recommend that section 17, chapter 80, ipiled Statutes, be amended to read, "Provided, The owner ny contract of sale or lease so forfeited, may redeem the e by paying all delinquencies and costs at any time before the :e of publication of auction, or before such land is leased; rided, further, That the Commissioner of Public Lands and dings is hereby required to serve notice of delinquency and :eed with forfeiture, as stated in such notice, at least once in 1 year. Persons owning movable improvements on lands rting to the state may remove the same within ninety days r such land is released, and all improvements not so removed, I inure to the benefit of the state." </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 I would also recommend that a measure be passed giving the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, at his discretion, a right to lease lands forfeited for non-payment of interest or rental to other parties upon payment of all back interest and ren - tal; this could work no harm to the state, or to the individual holding the contract; at the same time it would keep much of the land under lease without the loss of time or rental. The law as it now stands in reference to redeeming the land at any time before same is leased, works against the best interests of the state, as it gives the contract holders an oppor - tunity to make payment at the last moment before auction. At the time of holding auction all delinquent lands have been adver - tised to be leased, at a definite time and place; parties come from a distance at considerable cost of time and money expect - ing to be able to secure a lease or to bid, at least, on lands adver - tised; the holder of a forfeited contract, if he sees that there will be competition, will pay up the delinquent interest and take the land from the auction list. In this way parties who had a right to believe that the land would be auctioned, as published, have no chance of securing the same or to come into competition with the holder of delinquent contract to secure same. This has become generally known throughout the slate, and many parties who desire to secure leases do not attend the auctions of school lands, knowing that a large quantity of the land advertised may be, or is apt to be, paid upon and withdrawn without being offered, if competition is at hand. If the law be amended to read as recommended, it will save costs to the state of holding a great many auctions, by forcing payment before costs are made, and, at the same time when the land has been once advertised it will increase the number of bidders by insuring them that all lands so advertised, will be offered at auction. Time is also an essential element in leasing land, and ninety days is sufficient for the removal of temporary improvements, and, as the law now stands, these improvements, if not removed within six months, inure to the benefit of the lessee. I cannot see as the new lessee has - any right to the improvements of a </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 fner lessee, but that the state has a right, in consequence of loss of rental and costs made incidental to forfeiture. FORFEITURES. I have endeavored to enforce the law in reference to collec - tion of delinquent interest and rentals by declaring all sale con - tracts forfeited that were one year in arrears, and all lease con - tracts that were behind for six months, as provided by law. In making up the delinquent list in 1901, preparatory to forfeiture, I found many contracts that were delinquent for periods ranging from three to ten years. Some of these I extended, deeming that it would be unjust to collect the entire amount at one time, sincf so much leniency had before been shown, and it would be almost impossible for many of the contract holders to have raised the amount of their delinquency in one year; at the same time I demanded, before making an extension, that sufficient pay - ment be made to show good faith, and at this time the most of these extended contracts are paid in full, and there are but few of them that are now behind farther than the legal require - ments. iam of the opinion that the law in reference to forfeitures uld be strictly enforced in order that the interests of the state 1 be protected and that the delinquent rentals and interest t not amount to more than the value of the contract to the ler. It is much easier for contract holders to keep up their ments as they become due than to meet an accumulation of rest and rental for several years at any one time. Upon the delinquent list of 1901 the back interest amounted to $115,293.49. Upon the delinquent list of 1902 we find but $7,965.77; this is due principally to two causes: — first, The edu - cation of the lease holder to meet the requirements as prescribed by law, and strictly upheld by this office; and second, To the general prosperity of the state and the increased value of a lease or sale contract upon the school lands of the state. Bevious to this it was quite common to find contracts delin - t for such a length of time that the amount of delinquency d be greater than the value of the contract itself. This led </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 many to let the law of forfeiture take its course, permitting their contracts to be cancelled for non-payment, then by agreement have other parties bid in the land at auction, and after the lease contract had been issued by the state they would receive the contract from the new lessee on assignment ; thus the first con - tract holder would secure the land under a new lease for a period of twenty-five years with no delinquent rental against it; the state being the loser of the delinquent interest or rental. The Board of Educational Lands and Funds forfeited during the year 1901, 216,936.92 acres; of this amount 105,615.47 was redeemed and re-instated; this year they forfeited less than 75, - 000 acres and the greater part of this will be redeemed and re - instated before publication of auction. I firmly believe that if collections are kept to where they should be under the law, that in a few years forfeitures will be rare instead of the rule. School lands are valuable, lease contracts under their liberal provisions are worth more to the individual than sale contracts, and wheth - er the land is for farming or grazing purposes, lease contracts can be secured for a period of twenty-five years with but little cost beyond the payment of the six per cent upon the appraised valuation, there being no tax upon the land itself to be met yearly. SOME FACTS. The following table showing facts relative to the educational lands of the state and their condition at the present time, has been carefully prepared and I believe it to be accurate. I have gone over the books of the office, compared and checked the general abstract book with the sale and lease ledgers, and these with the records of abstracts of sales and leases and, after num - erous corrections, the footings agree. I presumed when the auction work for the year was over that I had leased all of the lands in the state with the exception of 765.06 acres, but after going thoroughly through the books the amount of unleased land increased to 1,339.50 acres; 564.44 acres were found under closed accounts both upon the abstract books and face of ledgers and from which the state received no income. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Educational Lands. 53 Under the ruling of this office that parties holding lease con - tracts dated subsequent to July ist, 1879 and prior to July 1st, 1897, I find 489,195.80 acres standing under 6,000 different con - tracts that are capable of being converted into salt- contracts and ultimately into deeds. Counting this at the least possible price, ($7.00 per acre), as stated by the constitution, the permanent school fund will be increased $3,424,470.60. There is now under contract of purchase 414,977.04 acres of educational land; the amount still due upon these contracts is $2,257,275.11 which in the course of a very few years will be received into the perma - nent school fund. The interest upon this unpaid value amounts to $164,128.23 yearly. Under lease contract there is 1,939,258. - 40 acres of school land, the appraised value of which is $2,029, - 948.39 upon which rental is paid at 6 per cent per annum and this brings into the temporary school fund $124,930.16 per year. The money received as interest on sale contracts, and rental on lease contracts is credited to the temporary school fund and dis - tributed twice a year, the total amount that should be turned into the temporary school fund for distribution as shown by the above figures is $289,058.39. The amount given as interest upon sale contracts will decrease probably in the next two years because many of the contracts now held under sale and drawing 6 per cent interest, are being rapidly paid in full and deeds given in place, while there is, and will be, comparatively few con - tracts converted from lease into sale. The amount given as income from lease contracts will not vary a great deal for several years, still as the land is converted from lease into sale con - tracts the income from this source will decrease. If the 1,339.50 acres of land now vacant can be leased, there will he a slight increase in the income of rented lands. If the recommendation that I have made to the legislature, in reference to reappraise - ment be acted upon favorably, there will be a material increase in the valuation of lease contracts and a corresponding increase in the income received, from the fact that the appraised valua - tion of a large amount of leased land is entirely too low. The only way that the income upon leased land can be materially decreased would be failure to collect the rentals due the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 PERMANENT SCHOOL FUND. Permanent common school securities $5,072,223.79 Cash on hand 131.30 Total • 5,O72,355'O9 Permanent University Securities 101,050.97 Cash on hand 643.05 Total 101,694.02 Agricultural College Securities 224,692.14 Cash Balance 674.51 Total 225,366.65 Normal Endowment Securities 59,000.00 Cash Balance 812.49 Total 59,812.49 Total Securities in Permanent School Fund 5,459,228.25 Value of Sale Contracts 2,257,275.11 Value of Lease Contracts 2,029,948.39 Total Interest Bearing Values 9,746,451.75 Ei all lease contracts that are capable of being iverted into sale are so transferred and fully d it will increase the total interest bearing ue of the permanent school fund of the state to more than 1 2,000,000.00 The Permanent School Fund is composed of interest bear- ing United States and State securities, registered county bonds and state general fund warrants and was obtained from the fol- lowing sources: (1) Sale of Educational Lands. (2) Five Per Cent Sale of Government Lands of the State. (3) Escheated Estates. The Temporary School Fund is obtained from the follow- ing sources : ( 1 ) Interest on Permanent School Securities. (2) Rental on Educational Lands under Lease. (3) Interest on Valuation of Lands Held under Sale Contracts. (4) S:ate School Tax of Not Less than One-half Per Cent, </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Educational, Lands. 55 nor More than One and a Half Per Cent, on the Assessed Valuation. (5) Bonus Received as a Premium to Secure Lease Contracts. (6) Interest on Delinquent Rental. (7) Money Received for State Licenses, Fines, Fees, etc. This temporary school fund is apportioned twice a year by the State Superintendent to the different counties in the state for the support of the public schools, and is generally known as the semi-annual apportionment. This with the local license fees and fines, together with the direct district tax which cannot exceed twenty-five mills, compose the ways and means by which the schools of the state are supported. EDUCATIONAL LANDS. Total Number of Acres Acquired 2 »973&gt;4 o2 -53 Total Number of Acres Deeded 614,773.31 Amount Remaining • 2,358,629.22 Total Number of Acres under Sale Contract .... 414,947.04 Total Number Acres under Lease Contract 1,939,258.41 Number Acres Vacant in Entire State J »339 5° In Various Conditions but Unavailable 3,084.27 Total in State 2,358,629.22 THIS BIENNIUM. Number Assignments Recorded 5,626.00 Number Acres Deeded 130,224.09 Number Acres Placed Under Sale Contract 1,167.68 Number Acres Leased 164,722.60 Total Amount Collected as Interest on Sale Con tracts $390,070.31 Total Amount Collected as Rental upon Lease Contracts 250,854.83 Interest on Rental and Bonus Received 12,352 05 Penalty for Serving Notice of Delinquency 967.06 Total Principal Collected on Sale Contracts 910,722.88 Total Collected During Biennium 1,564,967.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">ABLE SHOWTN( Facts Relativi ! TO STi te Educational. Lands, Decembe S 1, 1902, COUNTY h It m t 3-8 P e a C — aa ■8 si — .2- l|2 1 •r. 1 I &gt; Antelope Box Butte ..... Buffalo Douglas Franklin ....... Garfield .'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Hamilton Harlan Hayes Hitchcock Jefferson 20480.00 31400.00 26880 00 25530.45 23675.28 40960.00 22353.25 4oyyo . aO 30813.29 17487.88 21687.10 19733.98 26804.36 33280*00 243864.09 106253.02 21240.00 14459.69 19044.70 92017.98 7163.19 49280.00 36105.15 82567 31 15931.20 18507.07 9170.23 33257.01 20648 51 20471 85 34560 00 25602.80 24637.31 20480.00 16640.00 29000.00 20475.30 19612 40 20487.56 20400.69 25600.00 25494.87 87376.60 26158.59 23041.44 20484.08 12160.00 5002.23 7104.76 722.00 85.70 11 00 8148.26 12504.21 16746.80 17754.40 12831.00 903 48 93.92 450 00 12944.62 10761.81 11990.99 2246.00 1708.45 452 43 3474.60 12.06 6639.61 16478.09 8130.19 1 00 17104.32 4090 39 1202 00 2042.00 19222.81 481.33 1282 00 6080.00 7477.77 "6879;54 I "37!8O 83.00 10444.90 4083.67 4065.10 1759.58 8840.00 682.00 383.06 1200.00 7635.38 2398 75 6878.71 8566 00 3804.49 40.00 11421 00 595.60 8063.93 1672 93 828 45 680.00 3344.19 4026.10 2080.00 5810.80 5020.00 198.67 5520 00 2240.00 18920.00 26880 00 25630.4,5 ....... 9674.97 39968.00 280 19710.86 40904.90 12207.86 660.00 885.20 220.00 5133.36 31694.52 242904.09 480 104603.02 660 00 1274 13 165.00 81205.98 1646.32 3.93 48747.57 40 21209.55 81959 65 1208.40 356.06 181.54 32576 01 200.00 12355.36 31278.00 17750.00i 391.50 3 19760.00 40 9838.00 1 29000.00 15748.67 3151.25 487.56 8576.83 24652.20 200 23732.85 84661.18 26038 59 11257.15 3876.90 oVieioi (*)25K.S» "(V'tt.ti (*) 240.00 '"mi'.ia ' («)'25;66 (7) 10.00 "m&amp;'M "mi mm 1248.10 10099.30 15916.59 3826.70 193.31 668.62 1645.42 3478.53 6261.85 4077.41 7997.16 554.49 1093.40 1080.00 120 00 7701.91 7312.86 oo) h.biy " 4082.38 9294.32 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">lj 13 LJC A riO^ AL« l^AN US- 57 Table Showing Facts Relative to State Educational Lands- 5 lONTINUED CX)UNTY h I? a a Q ** I t JSZ |1! 00 ■ 1 a &gt; Johnson Kearney Ifeya Paha '.'.'.'.'. Kimball Lancaster Lincoln McFberson Madison Merrick Nuckolls ....... Red Wiiiow ".'.'. Richardson 13440.00 18581.40 45662.40 26222.46 36578.88 42893.81 31236.84 97890.93 20480 00 20393.28 56320.00 24639.43 14996.99 11792.34 21049 10 21992.44 20034.85 31523.75 JOOBM 20480.00 23655.48 16787.68 25485.30 10400.00 40232.40 20480 00 MM 27 26390.99 25467.65 20560.00 94627.74 20477 20 80972.22 15360 00 20472.35 25600.00 20474.88 13851.86 15360.00 20480.00 20480.00 20474.00 10631.67 5442.28 45.00 231.30 6202.78 22497.87 500.80 "32o!66 11807.92 6766.86 10293.49 9001.76 16925.69 15006.53 3761.82 5244.74 13852.21 9535.58 1488.06 8110.00 80.00 17587.00 6995.69 20790.91 177.46 16399.21 367.87 496.51 80.00 6986.09 10793.45 2405 00 7782.16 1079.40 202 70 13989 34 7485.00 7270.08 "48o!66 9711.51 4520.32 1160.00 10947.64 4526.75 4868 32 10432. 2H 7995.26 7994 17 5450.80 4155.75 1360.00 403.33 5366.96 44536 33 25188.46 3«578 88 22695.79 1244.45 90104.06 20480 00 19593.28 5«320.00 3120 00 3709.81 225 65 1099.70 520.00 160.00 31283.75 6034.50 7240.00 1809.10 1801.30 19841.50 930.00 40152.40 600.00 284.88 400.00 24772.54 603.64 93969.88 15253.12 mu.n 2280.00 3035.23 25600.00 11913.51 1814.90 "'tin "5.96 '246!66 1 (») 16.00 oV)ii3;26 h")'26;66 Saunders Scotts Bluff... Sheridan Stanton 2293.00 1707.70 5191.76 517.65 3557.15 284 99 4727.57 "imkM "'5'. 66 "6093!9i 6643.67 "■*6!66 ... Thomas Washington .... Wheeler 3928.28 10295.80 8920.00 4401.00 3.00 13728.24 4633.09 1720.86 6440.00 7398.00 40.00 5192.37 irn'mUm 8675.00 20437.00 1553 39 541460.06 340527.23 1909138.02 1339.50 2795532.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 Land Commissioner's Report. Table Showing Facts Relative to State Educational Lands- Continued Lancaster 12804. so «7:S2.2:5 :m2.:u 80. ON COUNTY 1*8 ¥ 00 Si .I 1 lit i 58 I — ■o a !§§ &gt; ! Antelope 1600.00 1920 00 320.00 640.00 8322.10 4480.00 2240.00 4916.68 3197.67 17789.63 289 00 1280.00 360.00 920.00 1280.00 680.00 1205.66 1922.85 5222.11 &lt;W0 02 240. (X) 320.00 280 00 1240.00 1760.00 800.00 3558.92 1274.82 6620.04 320.98 400.00 6162.10 1440.00 760.00 152.10 ...... .... .--.- "5947!48 Total 45426.08 13159.621 17tW.HU 15182.66 iricultu: :al col ayue . ...... 640.00 25405.47 960.00 640.00 2240.00 33500.19 10113.96 15648.98 480.00 10270.98 680.00 603.92 1313.90 4769.17 2704 03 9340.27 160.00 11434.23 280.00 "3706!26 796.00 22097.62 6131.25 6302.38 36.08 120.00 6633.40 1278.68 (") io.io ;;;;;; eM Total 89148.60 30162.27 47201.48 11768 421 18.* SA :ne .ncaster + 24 212')9.13 6141.96 I 3089.31 (19)15103. NORMAL </seg>
            <seg id="p059">dL)\J\^ ATIO^ A L \-s Art DS. 59 ■i). 16.01 acres, supposed right of way, Omaha, Niobrara Hack Hills Ry. K). 2518.89 acres confirmed to the state but awaiting result ntest. (3). 12.27 acres U. P. right of way. (4). 240 acres in river. (5). 3.02 held by F. E. &amp; M. V. as right of way. (6). 25 acres final payment made but no deed issued. (7). 10 acres final payment but no deed. (8). 10 acres payment but no deed issued. (8). 9.26 acres right of way, Chicago, St. P. &amp; Minn. Ry. (9). 20.05 acres U. P. right of way. (9). 10 acres homesteaded by state relinquishing through legislature. (10). 6 acres B. &amp; M. right of way. In). 7.50 acres final payment made but no deed issued. 11). 2.02 acres U. P. right of way. {12). 16 acres U. P. right of way. 13). 113.20 acres in river. (14). 20 acres final payment made but no deed issued. (15). 8.32 acres final payment made but no deed issued. (16). 20.30 acres in court in Iowa. (17). 10.10 acres Chicago, St Paul &amp; Minn, right of way. (18). 6.33 acres Chicago, St. Paul &amp; Minn, right of way. (19). 15,103.84 acres of Saline land was set aside by the legislature as follows: State University and city lots 320 acres, Lincoln Hospital for Insane 699.04, Model Farm 1,280 acres, Normal school 12,804.80. I 'he railroad companies holding the above mentioned right of '8 have not fully complied with the laws . relative to the pro - an for procuring same, therefore have secured no deed or il right or title thereto. The constitution states "that lands er the control of the state shall never be donated to railroad ipanies, private corporations or individuals." I believe that railroad companies should be compelled to obtain legal title proper procedure and compensate the state for loss of land aken. This would enable the abstract books in my office to </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Land Commissioner's Report. correspond with the other records as regards to the sale and dis - posal of the educational lands. t number of railroads at the request of different Commis - rs, have condemned and procured title in the proper man- </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 Table Showing Work of the Biennium. County I i I ■a g I I t &lt; I I i §1 1 s| 3-D I ii Pu u if Total Adams .... Antelope.. Banner Blaine .... Boone Box Butte. Boyd Brown Cheyenne . oSftmk '.'.'.'. Cuming ... Custer .... Dakota . . . Dawes Dawson . . Deuel Ulxon Dodge Douglas ... Dundy Fillmore . . Franklin . . Frontier . Furnas... Oi|e QarHeld ... Gosper .... Grant Greeley ... Ball Hamilton Harlan . . . Hayes .... Hitchoock. Holt Hooker Howard.. . Jefferson .. Johnson . . . Kearney... Keith Keya Pahs Klmball... Knox Lancaster. Lincoln . . Madison'.'." McPhers'n Merrlck ... Nemaha .. Nuckolls .. Otoe Pawneee . . Perkins... Phelps.... 2200.00 2087. 90 80.00 40 00 I2O!(W 25W.0OJ •917 20 7888 30 1434 82 1366.04 1448.68 4647.44 4496 98 3348.64 4689.85 586 00 737.04 221.80 1709.72 2044 69 18451.10 7489.81 168.85 686 42 164 65 10857 60 640.86 4364.64 2040.72 5104.00 1151.26 418 92 64.10 2087 18 74.40 4386.27 5916.70 4177 63 175.98 1336 01 2482.91 983 93 3017.82 2096.12 170.98 3387.21 2816.86 2422.79 18232.26 1611.36 4430.61 1507.17 392.86 1770.46 5294 98 3549 95 1456.27 6632 OS 1082 81 8235 66 1199.53 1892.92 860.56 156S 35 2889.40 282. 68 471.15 547.10 80 80 1461.86 ua so 18239.62 8814 63 •31.73 272 50 43.30 83.45 46.28 184 76 403.61 116 32 886.61 8.M 5 36 3.98 86 50 86 47 657.83 584 38 2.16 9.13 3.97 1111 03 17.58 160.63 82.78 214 49 43.86 15.75 1.18 76.59 1.71 426.16 322.74 186.90 4.46 37.43 87.86 27.26 90.81 84.52 7.40 230.80 86.98 115.64 946.97 67.66 279.12 34.06 10.80 367.94 263.31 135.90 31.89 174.18 42.87 266.46 62.74 72.43 30.41 177.36 63.38 7 89 11.88 3 96 tte\ 113416. Jffl 14300.77 H 13 6. 10 u. 28 •20829 06 28989 70 1484 « 1458 79 20107 39 4742.20 4989 a 3567 28 26888.81 26438 M S8B47.C 16072 80 372SB.M 3887 48 19890 63 11208 00 28706 23 27141. 28 29317 83 2O2H.08 8908.74 4626.01 18829 97 5684 01 27811 75 18842 98 5109 42 2864 13 17641 83 15799.08 7851 81 9690 16 20981.97 2909 92 10466 29 1013.19 7486.31 17894 25 36043 47 18088 00 3271.08 3603.88 19682.48 1747.34 18289 48 24473 91 9050.94 22488.10 6267 10 MOB 26 1489 18 36188.91 47445.46 13476.86 1265 it 36897.70 1761 20 14291.28 5781.31 34982 49 23081 88 30024 96 1506 46 16808 61 1900.50 722.00 85.70 "ak'.ib 8687.88 "iras'im "idol 7040 00 2296.62 7040.00 Ml .00 80.00 37.89 73.92 9980 53 4631 63 565421 MB6.6t 9067.32 624 92 sw.eo 696.87 7061.73 3628 35 7241.13 8804 90 3236.81 s * 19111.49 363.02 7»72 97 2424.43 1591.76 483. 16 3280.20 8393 61 1589 37 4466.73 4791.73 254 98 4320.52 M.00 144.00 10723.92 21268.86 30650 22 12152.00 26391 60 1008.00 237.51 2404.80 21478.00 22940.88 21BU7.58 76.00 3111.00 1615.95 2458.40 5197.33 1520 00 4719 00 160.00 93.92 3*0 00 3040 0U 3807.32 3379.70 'a&gt;!66 1278.87 32289.86 9381 75 10.501 6.50 63 50 32.14 '"zioioo M17.4M 668.17 9040.00 .50 48.M) 1.50 17 50 13 00 12.50 6.50 4.00 KA 5.00 BH.M 1980 00 478.84 "eewioJ 86.SS "'ssoiioo 18687.37 13779.88 3461.88 "moo 3800.00 .50 7.00 2 00 11.00 3.00 27.00 1.00 3.60 11.00 2 00 5.50 5.50 3 50 19.50 10.00 17 50 36 00 10.00 18 00 3 50 1 50 13 00 36 50 8.00 1.80 14. nO 10.50 23.00 3.00 8.50 11 00 10.50 7.50 1.00 16.00 3 00 2.60 4 00 II no 2010.00 MO 00 1202 00 250.00 3216 00 160.00 480 00 I i ' 160.00 2440.00 1380.00 84 60 380.00 240.00 40 00 180.00 "i436s'52 7583.00 733.00 22008 80 1278.00 3674.00 240.00 1521 OOl 4640.001 1864.7? 10 00 h:d 2708.18 5664.11 4843.64 6193.48 296.23 530. 75 1286.20 68.82 6166.56 8973.18 2661.89 8472.61 682.31 286 OR 1864.66 10064.00 30018 00 8318.23 63.00 417.00 4032.00 " 6JO.O0 874 07 1881 50 988 00 1651.87 [io'.id 102.26 5619.50 10101.07 6M0.0U 240.00 820.00 180.00 3.33 640.00 5826 86 1288.88 8800 00 510.00 435.00 3810.73 180 0C 2000 00 6397.18 15966.00 6083.90 11962.10 '"wiiffl "'i486'. 32 ' MOO.OO 4238 97 120.00 11470 20 9922.47 4258.02 18898.00 36406.81 703.72 ' '3B72.'«S " "sn.wi 9285.03 "ieoeo^i 1636 79 399.08 3862 50 1800 00 2199 00 2580 00 293.80 50.65' 80.001 4802.75 1431.74 9894.86 5427.581 5763.311 7528 20 40*8.50 2468B 80 17100.28 14207.541 240.00 80.00 "«ffi'S 80.00 380 00 480.00 ' mi jr. 40.61 32.44 ' "»i6'.66 14284 Ool </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Land Commissioner's Report. Table Showing Work of the Biennium— Continued. AGRICULTURAL COLLEGE County i ! I ! I 1 § 1 1 I] Is = •» c gSE a s ll Si £3 S° I* If I* Total »olk KM Willow Richards'n Rook Saline S«rpy sunders.. ootts Bl'ff eward ... Sherman . . Wash'gfn. Webster... SM2.6I 1800.00 "e66!66 40 00 ""iirlin 1100.00 21U.80 6.00 160.00] •77-.J 40.00 40.00 1080.00 30.00 3490.00 80 00 'u6!66 "8066.08 11098.44 1781 78 4030.87 618.13 3*96.91 639.00 187.5* 330 20 1887 *2 704.24 8687.80 3017.05 6468.86 1136 R5 1061 76 1049.81 1096.36 1919.58 67*0 30 1888.38 3182 43 786.03 •7684.01 4612.96 330940 2*66.06 21.00 3888.51 8161.20 6847.14 311.42 3048.81 188.78 3707.33 136.01 78.00 836 00 11.00 283 31 7.88 2.72 10 40 175. 05 68.27 3(2.80 148.10 205 SO 52.88 40.79 38.11 87.77 102.10 123622.20 11804.20 900 00 5626.00 260.00 1 SOB. 58 3815.50 24030.24 1076.20 15648.80 28 00 1008 00 13.50! 12.50 81.60 1S.60 4.00 .60 5.00 28.00 .60 22.50 10.60 16.00 4.00 3.00 9.60 700 4.60 3.60 11.00 7.86 4.50 0086 12 8522.08 #63.72 16341 07 6567.64 32122.08 4472.80 20360.62 0060.77 8881.07 8680.16 19334.56 15604 47 1096.45 9182.50 11869.38 36706 89 14033 30 32X8.76 24124 64 "«7J14 'iBoo.ob 0MO 38 iio'.bbl ° 320.00 5040.00 ■5407.00 5191.06 "12734 '.on 9807.87 840.00 841.96 4620 00 1080.00 "06 90 "iiu'is 2706 48 (918*2 8447 7* 88982.00 7198 60 "iio'bb 1040.00 4886.08 30.24 5600 61 ii.m 88.84 18 50 "iMolto 107576.44 801.86 "irereloo 164381 SO 237066.30 318768.07 11772.04 757827.35 0O:O30 1327231 15 Table S ro Wi IRK Ol JNIV F THE BlENNI ERSITY. onti COUNTY. &lt; ■a 1 t s I 1 I 2 Jl lii 5 is I 8 ■C • c "Z § .50 1 S2?T:::::::::::::: tskota r— twiii'.'.'.'*!.'".'.'"" leroe 110*4 800.00 280.00 440.00 330.00 440.00 40.00 266.66 149.66 108.00 258*. 76 441.00 43 70 68.80 848.66 708.76 151.0* *TO 06 046.13 1469.66 869.86 2726 77 1208.74 4710.08 8.29 8.50 106.12 18.37 .16 3.58 1548.68 4660.00 100.00 1664.00 1060.00 1000 00 S942.00 400.00 5976.00 609* 80 ■■ j ;d 8547.88 5447 2« KIM 2034.06 4098.51 2889 42 4846.71 3180.69 7183.7* MO.OO S38.60 -i:. "oi.'oo ' 1548 '» "m.°66 ,00 4107.84 341.00; 5017 80 18987.51 102 60 283*4 48 10.00 »=.= 160 00 H51.79 160.00 '.'.'.'... 1184.28 '.'.'.'.'.'. '""io.'m ltO.lt 1926 76 4S1.74 80.48 10286.32 218.00 "ttl 'SMM.'SJ io!6b 47988.18 218 00 ii. a 4072. 06 40S1S. 18 1373803 (mm n uming 38 SO* 74 M 14.17 »kot» »Uoo y»3n&gt;e 388.96 3086.80 1161. 91 3718.08 14504 63 M8.7K 17811. 36 4977 12 7641. M 30?!. 06 80392 .52 8111.00 28808 46 ii'66 1.00 4.60 ital... 3671. 751 419H 39| 115. 481 04015. »l * sol 1307M 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 NORMAL. SALINE. Lunster llSO.IgSM.OS 4139.78 11908. Vt ZSS.OS! 19581. Ill S3 00 32717 « CITY LOTS. Lucuttr Lots 7 and 8. Block 228. Lots 4 and 10, Block 229. SOME FIGURES. I give below some figures that will be of interest to the pub - lic in general, and at the same time they will show the tendency of decrease of income from interest on unpaid portions of sale contracts, and increase of income from rental upon lands held under lease contract. The collection of this interest and rental is done through the various county treasurers of the state, but it is greatly influenced by the policy of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Build - ings and the Board of Educational Lands and Funds. BIENNUM 1897-8. Rental collected on leases: Interest collected on sales: Dec., 1898 104,534.65 Dec., 1898 45,131.24 Total collected $612,675.97 Total collected $208, 723.46 BIENNIUM 1899-00. May, 1899 $128,877.10 May, 1899 $ 42,726.45 Dec., 1899 69,482.08 Dec., 1899 54,874.31 M»y, 1900 165,409.06 May, 1900 60,1. Dec., 1900 89,927.26 Dec., 1900 62,379.47 Total collected . ...$453,695.50 Total collected $220,085.75 B1897 1153,622.77 May, 1897 t 44,2tii\4&lt;i 1897 146,239.20 Dec., 1897 71,887.89 1898 208,279.35 May, 1898 47,441.93 COUNTY i 3 ! •&lt; ■ ■ I V is ij I 1 m c Hi 1 i it n 1m .ancMter... ON 07.20 3782.40 .17 I5NM 7.00, 19TS1.*- I </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 BIENNIUM 1901-2. May, 1901 $10fi,203.85 May, 1901 t 55,988.31 Dec., 1901 72,081.71 Dec., 1901 •••• 61,356.27 May, 1902 122,281.78 May, 1902 78,332.88 Dec., 1902 36,001.06 Dec., 1902 46,751.10 Total collected $336,568.40 Total collected $242,428.56 TOTAL INTEREST COLLECTED ON SALE CONTRACTS. Biennium 1897-8 $612,675.97 Biennium 1899-00 $453,695.50 Biennium 1899-00 453,695.50 Biennium 1901-2 336,568.40 Decrease 1898 to 1900. .$158,980.47 Decrease 1900 to 1902. .$117,127.10 TOTAL COLLECTIONS ON SALE CONTRACTS AND COMMENTS. 1897-8 $612,675.97 1899-00. .. .$453,695.50 1901-2 $336,568.40 I It will be noticed from the above footings that the interest col - ed on sale contracts is decreasing very rapidly. This is due tie fact that when the purchase price is paid and deeds ed, or when partial payments are made upon the principal of contracts, the money so received is turned into the state sury by the county treasurers and is placed in the permanent &gt;ol fund. The state has issued but few sale contracts during past four years, hence the interest that could be collected by direction of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Build - i must decrease to the extent of six per cent upon the amount lived as principal during this time. In the Land Commissioner's report of 1898, page 9, the amount given that was due the state at that time as unpaid bal - ance upon sale contracts, amounted to $4,652,123.00, while in the report of 1900, on page n, we find that there was $3,946, - 083.07 due upon these contracts, a decrease during the biennium of $706,039.93, hence a decrease in interest amounting to six per cent of the amount paid ($706,039.93), or $42,362,39. While according to these figures there should have been a decrease of only $42,362.39 during this period of time, there was an actual decrease in interest collected, as shown above, amounting to $158,980 47. This difference can be accounted for in three ways. (1). By turning to Commissioner's report of 1898, page 1 -i, where it is stated that 1,330,000 acres of land was found to </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 Ilelinquent at the beginning of his term of office, for an aver - of six years, and that upon notice being given, a large num - of contract holders paid their back interest, and that the rd of Educational Lands and Funds were compelled to for - 720,000 acres of this land, mostly lease contracts, hence, the iquent interest on sale contracts was, in the main, paid, tn this it can be readily seen that as this back interest was scted it went to swell the temporary school fund of the years j and 1898. k(2). About this time, 1897-8, better times, good crops and r prices enabled the state contract holders not only to pay delinquent interest, but to pay in advance as the law peo - i they should. t(3) At this time a number of sale contracts were forfeited, as they were then turned into lease contracts, this would rease the interest-bearing valuation for the next biennium, by so doing would decrease the income, therefore the inter - received during the next two years would decrease six per t of the valuation of the forfeited contracts. 1 During the past two years this office lias received as princi - on unpaid portions of sale contracts $774,508.48, decreasing interest-bearing value six per cent of this amount, or $46, - .00. I The total decrease in interest-bearing value, with but little ease from new sale contracts issued, for the four years inclusive) would amount to the sum of $706,039.93 icted during the years 1899-1900, and $774,508.48 collected ng the years 1901-1902, or a grand total of $1,480,548.41. per cent of this amount would be $88,832.90, which is the -ease in the amount that could be collected and turned the temporary school fund through the office of Commis - er of Public Lands and Buildings, or the collection of which Commissioner could in any way be held responsible. I This will not only affect the interest as collected through this at, and the collection of which the Commissioner of Public ids and Buildings is held responsible by the public, but it will 1 reduce the amount of the entire semi-annual apportionment </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 In amount equal to the difference of three or three and one - per cent, as loaned by the State Treasurer by direction of Board of Educational Lands and Funds, and six per cent, rate of interest charged upon the value of principal, of sale racts. Ilt will also be noted that there was a decrease of $i 1 7, 1 2 1 . 10 ig the past biennium when there should have been but a ction of $88,832.80. This is principally due to three causes: ■ (1). To a large amount of interest paid in advance on contracts. (2). To forfeiture of sale contracts. 1(3). The first Monday in December, which is the day that State Treasurer certifies the amount in the temporary school i to the State Superintendent, fell upon the second day of the ith, hence it was impossible for the November collection for year 1902 to be received and credited thereto. rAL RENTAL. COLLECTED ON LEASE CONTRACTS AND COMMENTS. 1897-8.... 1208, 723. 46 1899-00 ... .$220,085.75 1901-2. ...$242,428.56 The rental on lease contracts has increased each succeeding biennium, as shown in the above, the increase for the biennium of 1900 over that of 1898 being $ 1 1,362.39 and the increase for the present biennium over theone just preceding it is $22,342.81. This - rental cannot be increased to any great extent, from the fact that all but 1,339 50 a cres of the school lands in the entire state are now under lease, unless reappraisement takes place. AGAIN. Yearly rental collected from 1897 to 1902: Rental on lease contracts is payable on the first day of Jan - uary and July of each year in advance. When the July payment became due in the year 1901, I received many letters from lease holders in different parts of the state, stating that it would be impossible, or a sacrifice, at least, to make payment at that time. LOW I «11U,1UU.6O 18»8 8 92,573.17 1899 9 97,600.78 l900 $122,484.99 1901 $117,344.58 1902 $125,083.98 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 The reasons given were that the lease holders were busy with their farms and herds and had nothing ready for the market, and requested that an extension be granted them until the fall of the year, when their produce could be turned into money. In granting the extensions asked for I suggested that it would be better for them to make payment in the fall of the year for the back interest or rental and then pay for a full year in advance. At the same time I wrote to many of the county treasurers sug - gesting to them that they call the attention of all the lease hold - ers in their county to this matter when making payment. This has in general been done, and thousands of lease holders, that before had been making their payments twice a year, now pay them for a full year at the time of making the January payment. I By this method of payment it decreases the work of both lty treasurer and this office, and saves the lease holder the syance of notice and worry of delinquency at the particular : of year when funds are low and hard to obtain, and time i the field is money to him; at the same time it cannot make difference to the schools of the state. True, it will increase May apportionment and decrease the one made in December, but the sum total for the year will not be affected. ""\ \ BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. Ils Chairman of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, I re to report to you, and through you to the legislature of disposition of the several amounts made by appropriation by legislature of 1901 for the various state institutions and pub - mildings under control of this board. I'he legislature of 1901 made an appropriation of $500.00 for :w well with pumping machinery at the- Asylum for Incur- Insane at Hastings, Nebraska. After duly advertising for , the board, on January 22, 1901, met and after considering he bids submitted, accepted the bid of Joseph Burns, in the of $767.65, his being the lowest and best bid, and awarded contract to him. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 The legislature of 1901 made an appropriation of $5,000 for building and equipping a new kitchen at the Asylum for Chronic Insane at Hastings, but this amount being inadequate for the purpose, and other provision having been made for the time being, so that the institution has got along without this new building and equipment, the amount appropriated remains intact in the hands of the state treasurer. The legislature of 1901 made an appropriation of $50,000.00 for the purpose of building and equipping a new fire proof wing at the Asylum for Chronic Insane at Hastings. After adver - tising for bids for the construction of same, the board on May 22, 1901, met, and after considering all the bids submitted, awarded the contract to R. Butke, his bid being $41,400.00, the lowest bid submitted. On the same day, at the same meeting, the board awarded the contract for plumbing and heating of the building to F. W. Barclay, in the sum of $4,975 00. On June 17, 1901, after advertising for bids" for the electrical wiring of the new building, the board met and awarded the contract to the Western Electrical Co. at the contract price of $1,152 00, this being the lowest bid submitted for the work. On August 9, 1901, a change in the plans of the building having become necessary as it was deemed advisable to increase the height of the basement story, a supplemental contract was made with Mr. Butke in the sum of $3,565.00, with the understanding that this amount would be a deficiency and the contractor agreed to await the action of the legislature of 1903 for payment. Messrs. Berlinghof and Grant, of Beatrice, drew up the plans and specifications, and these gentlemen were selected by the board to superintend the construction of the building. On November 12, 1902, the board met and accepted the building, after having made a personal and careful inspection of the The sum of $15,000 00 was appropriated by the legislature of 1 90 1 for the purchase of additional land for the Institute for Feeble Minded Youth, at Beatrice. After some time spent in looking up suitable tracts of land and it being for the best inter- </seg>
            <seg id="p069">Board of Public Lands and Buildings. 69 the state on which the buildings are located, a piece of land adjoining the state's land on the west and a piece lying and adjoining on the south containing 182.82 acres was selected and after considering propositions from parties who had land to dis - pose of, on May 6th, 1901, the board met and purchased said tracts at the price of $13,711.50. March 1, 1901, a disastrous fire occurred at the state peniten - tiary whereby the administration building and west cell house were practically destroyed. The legislature of 1901 appro - priated the sum of $7,500 00 for the rebuilding of the same and for the putting in of new cells in the east cell house. After advertising for bids for new cells, the board on March 22, 1901, met and after considering all the bids submitted, awarded the contract for the construction of the same to the Pauly Jail Building and manufacturing Company at the contract price of $18,720. The board also advertised for bids for material to rebuild and for construction of the destroyed portions of the institution and on June 25, 1901, after considering all bids sub - mitted, awarded the contract for cut stone work to the Johnson Stone Co. in the sum of $11,250.00, the contractors agreeing to use all the convict labor that could be furnished. At the same meeting the contract for all. stone footings was awarded to C. J. Johnson for 16 cents per foot. After having advertised for bids, the board at the same meeting on June 25, 1901, awarded the contract for metal work to Paxton and Vierling for the sum of $9,540.00, the contractors agreeing to use all the convict labor that could be furnished, at the rate of 1 2 % cents per hour. The same day, at the same meeting, the contract for fire proof - ing was awarded to the Pioneer Fire Proofing Co. for the sum of $6,950 00, the contractor agreeing to use such convict labor as could be provided. On August II, 1901, the contract for furnishing window and outside door frames was awarded to Thistlewait Brothers in the sum of $1,448.56. |&gt;n September II, 1901, after having advertised for bids for al work needed in the connection of the west cell house, a mtract was entered into with H. T. Ward &amp; Co. to furnish same in the sum of $4,800.00. These several items, together </seg>
            <seg id="p070">Land Commissioner's Report. 70 with the moneys paid out of the appropriation for labor and material necessary to place the buildings in a condition to with - stand the weather until such time as a further appropriation could be made by the legislature, having exhausted the appro - priation, work on the buildings has ceased. The buildings, while under cover, are not yet completed as to all inside work, and are not ready for occupancy, and a further appropriation of $30,000 or more is needed to complete them. The legislature of 1901 appropriated $35,000.00 for the pur - chase of grounds and support of the State Fair, placing the same in charge of this Board. After having negotiated with numer - ous parties and investigated the merits of several tracts of land adjacent to the City of Lincoln and advertised for parties to sub - mit propositions, the Board on June 8, 1901, purchased the land of the Nebraska Exposition Association, 123.75 acres, for $18,000, and on July 15, 1901, after advertising for bids, awarded contracts for the erection and completion of neces - sary buildings and the establishment of water systems in the aggregate amount of $6,458.75. Contracts were awarded on the same day for all lumber, brick, cement, sand, lime and other material, and the amount of these items added to sums paid for labor and other expense has practically exhausted the appro - priation. The legislature of 1901 appropriated the sum of $2,000.00 for the completion of four vaults in the basement of State house; one for the use of the Secretary of State, one for the use of the Auditor, one for the use of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings and one for the State Library. After having advertised for bids for the completion of the work, the Board on October 25, 1901, met and awarded contract for four vault doors to G. Andreen for $388.00, and November 8, 1901, contract was awarded to Reimers &amp; Fried for cement floors in the sum of $424 80. On December 16, 1001, a contract was awarded to Reimers &amp; Fried for plastering vaults and storerooms in the basement of the Capitol building in the amount of $300.00. Other labor and material was furnished to </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Board of Public Lands and Buildings. 71 complete said vaults and storerooms, which were needed very much by the state officers named. The condition of the basement of the Capitol building, while greatly improved over two years ago, is in bad shape as con - cerns liability to fire. A great portion of the floors and the stairs leading to the basement are of wood which should be removed and replaced with brick and iron. The ceilings in the storerooms should be lathed with metal lath and fire proofing materials be used wherever practicable. The board would recommend that an appropriation be made, by the legislature about to convene, in order that the improve - ments spoken of may be made and the basement rendered fire proof as near as possible. |7he legislature at the session of 1901 appropriated the sum $4,500 for the establishment of a water system for the jitol building and grounds. The board advertised for bids the work and material and on April 28, 1901, after consid - ig all bids submitted, awarded the contract to Joseph Burns he contract price of $4,387.00. I would say that the estab - ment of this water plant has caused a saving to the state he matter of expense for water, besides affording better protection than the building has ever had. The Hospital for Insane at Norfolk had been for some time badly in need of better fire protectioa, and the legislature of 1901, realizing this fact, made an appropriation of $3,500 for a new standpipe at that institution. The Board advertised for bids as soon as the appropriation became available, and on June 24, 1901, after having considered all proposals submitted, awarded the contract for the erection of a standpipe to Drake, Wilson &amp; Williams in the amount of $3,440.00. The contractors lost no time in getting to work, and used every effort as far as this Board could determine to push the work to completion, but on September 23, 1901, before the standpipe was finished, there occurred a fire which rendered the institution useless for further occupancy. The Board, however, recommended that the work on the standpipe proceed to com- </seg>
            <seg id="p072">Land Commissioner^ Report 72 pletion according to contract, which was done and the work completed. The Board of Public Lands and Buildings have had a large amount of work to perform during this biennium and have inves - tigated as far as possible the condition of the various State Insti - tutions from time to time and inquired into the methods of those in charge in keeping the books and records of the institution. From investigation it seems to me that there is a lack of uni - formity in the methods of keeping the books and accounts of these institutions, each being kept in a way peculiar to the per - son in charge. It is the duty of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings to examine into the accounts and records, which they have done to the best of their ability and time, that could be taken from their other many and varied duties. Had this Board the expert knowledge necessary to a thorough examination, it would be impossible to do so with all the other duties imposed upon them by the laws of the state. It would therefore recommend to the coming legislature that able measure be passed whereby a state accountant could rmanently employed whose first duty would be to unify the ods of keeping the accounts and records of the different institutions, and then to examine thoroughly the different s and records at least once a month and to perform such duties as the Board of Public Lands and Buildings may t, and to report his findings to the chairman of the Board of c Lands and Buildings at least once a month. This would create one more officer to be supported by the state, yet I feel satisfied in my own mind that it would produce a saving to the state that would amount to many times the cost of salary and expenses attendant thereto, as well as prevent much of the trouble and scandal that has arisen from time to time through the negligence or carelessness of those who have this </seg>
            <seg id="p073">73 IN CLOSING. In closing I wish to express my appreciation to your excel - lency and the rest of the state officers for their many acts of kindness and for the many courtesies extended to me during the past two years. I especially desire to commend the members of my office force for their efficient service, and to express my thanks to them for the prompt, careful and willing manner in which they have performed the work of the state entrusted to them. George D. Follmer, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. </seg>
            <seg id="p074"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>