<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report OF THE WARDEN OF THE Nebraska State Penitenitary AT LANCASTER, NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Biennial Report —OF THE- WARDEN -OF THE - Nebraska State Penitentiary AT LANCASTER, NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902 — by — EDWARD D. DAVIS, WARDEN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">( FFICERS AND EMPLOYEES, WITH DATE OF APPOINTMENT. Edward D. Davis, Warden, Feb. 15, 1901. James D. Jones, Deputy Warden, Sept. 1, 1901. Frank L. Wilmeth, Physician, Feb. 15, 1901. George W. Martin, D. D., Chaplain, Jan. 1, 1902. Ernest B. Fairfield, Clerk, June 1, 1901. IN. Aills, Engineer, Oct. 1, 1902. es Delahunty, Steward, Feb. 15, 1901. Ham B. Baird, Storekeeper, Sept. 4, 1901. i P. Pickel, Farmer, May 3, 1902. mas Cokeley, Mechanic, May 16, 1889. list Bartle, Cell House Keeper, March, 15, 1901. rles A. Albright, Shop Guard, Aug. 22, 1901. ert H. McManis, Shop Guard, Feb. 22, 1902. i Schmitt, Shop Guard, March 20, 1902. IF. Green, Shop Guard, Dec. 8, 1901. ■ick Desmond, Shop Guard, Aug. 6, 1902. a McNeil, Night Cell Keeper, March 16, 1901, mas Doody, Cage Guard, Nov. 26, 1901. mel M. Craig, Cage Guard, Mar. 4, 1901. 1 Tatman, Cell Keeper, Dec. 8, 1901. Jack Jenkins, Gate Keeper, Mar. 4, 1901. '. Townsend, Laundryman, Sept. 8, 1897. I Hockenbary, Turnkey, Aug. 26, 1901. rles Lewis, Kitchen Guard, July 22, 1902. c J. Kirkman, Usher, June 24, 1902. iWettlaufer, Yard Man, Mar. 21, 1901. irles A. Eckley, Wall Guard, May 28, 1896. lliam Vandenburg, Wall Guard, Nov. 14, 1901. in L. Grimes, Wall Guard, Apr. 1, 1902. in Hudson, Wall Guard, Feb. 10, 1902. &gt;mas H. Benton, Wall Guard, July 11, 1902. Fred Moore, Wall Guard, July 28, 1902. nes Spencer, Wall Guard, Sept. 18, 1902. O. Dietie, Wall Guard, Oct. 31, 1902. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">131 Hon. Ezra P. Savage, Governor, and the Honorable Board of Public Lands and Buildings: I have the honor to submit herewith a report of this institu - tion for the biennial period ending November 30, 1901. The omission herefrom of many statistical tables, generally embodied in documents of this kind, will not, it is hoped, be unacceptable. The past two years have proven in many ways to be the most eventful in the history of the penitentiary. The disastrous fire of 1 90 1, following the less calamitous one of 1S99, a narrowly averted attempt at still a third conflagration, a well-planned effort toward a wholesale delivery of convicts, an unprecedented num - ber of deaths among inmates, the housing of the administration offices and guards' quarters in a temporarily converted hen - house — these, coupled with other more prosaical episodes, have managed to make the administration one long to be remembered. The primary cause of all these tribulations was the fire of mys - terious origin that occurred on the morning of March 1, 1901, just fifteen days after the undersigned had been installed as warden and before the deputy and other officers of the previous administration had been relieved. The flames quickly trans - formed the penitentiary into a corral — with neither cells for the convicts nor means of preparing food for anyone. Sine perceived the true situation more quickly than the tes, who straightway laid plans for a delivery. The plan •eded to the extent that a dozen men reached the outer air, but they were detected and returned to the cell house, so called because it had space for cells. Individual escapes occurred from time to time, but it was the surprise of experienced prison men who visited the institution that under the circumstances any of the convicts should consent to stay. "They must like the place," was a common remark of such callers. The sanitary condition of the prison at this time was most wretched, all of the convicts being herded in one unpartitioned </seg>
            <seg id="p004">132 have found a more favored spot and death was but to be expected. Nor did illness and its grim attendant spare the employees; they were as poorly housed as the convicts and with the latter shared most of the privations. On June 23, 1901, a deliberate attempt was made to burn down the broom factory, but the fire was discovered and quenched in its incipiency. The incendiaries, who were in all probability con- victs, could not be definitely located, although a rigid investiga- tion was made. The destructive conflagration of the first of March devoured the contents and roof of the west cell house and the central building, the warden's quarters, administration offices, guards' apartments, kitchen, chapel, bakery and the other departments in that section of the institution. The calam- ity not only entailed a great direct pecuniary loss, but made it necessary to employ on the repair and reconstruction work many convicts who might have otherwise been engaged in earning money under contractors in the shops. This income would of course have accrued to the maintenance fund of the institution and greatly lessened (if not, indeed, entirely obliterated) the unpaid claims at the close of the biennium. By this labor, how- ever, the rebuilding fund was saved to a great extent, the value of the convicts' work being deducted from the contractor's claims. Such labor, and that first mentioned, and the value thereof may be conservatively estimated as follows, the total being $9,904.71 : Roofing, lathing and plastering west cell house $266.05 Reconstruction of administration building 7 1 79 83 Fire-proofing administration building 632 49 Cutting stone for administration building 353-83 Setting iron work, administration building 482.52 Putting steam pipes into east cell house 24.90 Erecting eight temporary steel cells 121.50 Erecting sixty permanent steel cells 824.29 Roofing administration building I 4-75 Putting in electric wires, new building 4.55 Convict labor was also used in the construction of works cal- culated to add to the facilities for heating, lighting, sanitation and fire protection; likewise in efforts to permanently beautify the </seg>
            <seg id="p005">133 prison enclosure. The value of such work is as follows, the total being $3272.17: Excavating for reservoir $69.75 Sinking new well 188 55 Connection between reservoir and pump 76 50 Connection between pump and water main 104 62 Putting sod and railing about hospital building 67 50 Laying new walk in east gateway 1125 Ditches and tunnel for steam pipe.- 491.50 Constructing sanitary sewer 443.25 Laying stone and brick walks 484.75 Carpenter work 226.00 Blacksmithing 278.54 Tinsmithing 87.40 Painting 41.10 Shoemaking and harness repairing 701.46 PRISON CONTRACTS. At various times in the past the convicts have been employed in the manufacture of many different articles of commerce. Cooper shops, implement factories, iron foundries, harness fact- ories, and other establishments have been operated by contract- ors with prison labor, but at present only two industries are represented in this institution — broom making and button cutting. Under the terms of their respective contracts, the Lee Broom and Duster Company pays 50 cents per day for its labor, while the Western Button Manufacturing Company is charged 55 The money received for this labor constitutes the "Special Labor Fund" and goes to assist in the payment of the running expenses of the institution. During the past two years the con- siderable sum of $44,268.38 has been paid into the warden': hands by the two contractors and by him turned over to the state treasurer. TWe present is, I believe, the only administration of recent years that has succeeded in collecting all of the money due from </seg>
            <seg id="p006">134 tractors during its tenure of office. When I assumed charge e penitentiary the Western Button Manufacturing Company greatly in arrears in its accounts with former wardens, being 3ted to the state in the sum of $4,476.50. Since that time ompany has paid its current bills for labor and has wiped out ►•53 of the old balance, leaving still due on the latter During the twenty months just past, the contractors were will - ing to employ more convicts than had been assigned to them, but as already stated the rebuilding and repair work required an unusually large "yard gang." However at the present time, over 150 men are booked in the broom shops, while 34 are em - ployed in the button factory. The female prisoners are engaged principally in carding the finished buttons. Of the income from this work the state re - ceives a large share, while the women themselves are allowed a per cent. Provision ought to be made for a matron, as the dif - ficulties now encountered in ministering to the wants of these inmates, and keeping good order in that ward, are numerous and burdensome. THE PRISON AT PRESENT. I he new central building has reached the stage at which it is merely the finishing and furnishing touches. The walls roof are complete; the floors of tile and concrete are laid; ire-proofing has been accomplished; the windows and out - doors are in place. The interior wood-work, the stairways the furniture remain to be introduced. I he west cell house has been capped with a fire-proof roof has also been replastered and provided with new windows doors. Unless, possibly, the steel roof beams were put in e without the removal of sufficient of the burned and crum - stone from the old walls, this building is better than ever will last many years. The sinking of additional wells within the enclosure, the in - stallation of a pump and the purchase of a few thousand feet of </seg>
            <seg id="p007">135 serviceable hose hare combined to create a stronger feeling of security against fire. The erection of sixty steel cells of latest pattern has afforded safe quarters for as many inmates as can be crowded into them. The beauty and utility of these cells have created an appetite for more — for enough more to give all of the convicts accom - modation. LThe Bertillon system of identification of criminals has been tablished in the penitentiary during the past year and is now in operation. To give this part of the work the greatest value, the institution should become a member of the National Bureau at Washington. This central office collects measurements of criminals over the country and keeps its clients advised of the previous records of the men whose signalments are received. The agricultural department of the penitentiary has under - gone the two extremes of famine and plenty during the biennium. The first year witnessed an unusual dearth of everything in the hay, grain and vegetable line, while during the past season the earth has worked overtime in the production of all that goes to make the farmer and the gardener glad. From 170 acres have been raised 15 tons of hay, 4,000 bushels of corn, 98 bushels of rye, 4,000 bushels of potatoes, 1,000 bushels of turnips, 500 bush - els of onions, 300 bushels of parsnips, 150 bushels of carrots, 5 tons of corn fodder, 15 tons of cane fodder, 100 bushels of sweet corn, besides radishes, lettuce, beets, string beans and other vegetables — the whole to an extent that warranted the sale of several hundred dollars' worth of the crops. SOME JUMBLED FIGURES. SJune 1, 1901, the clerical force in my office underwent a e, the bookkeeper who was holding over from the fusion tration being superseded by order of the Governor. The were found to be in such a chaotic condition that I had them submitted to the Honorable -Board of Public Lands and Buildings, who authorized expert accountants to examine into them. The gentlemen were unable to unravel the mysteries of the wonderful aggregation of meaningless figures, partly by </seg>
            <seg id="p008">136 reason of the fact that the original vouchers and books of initial entry had been destroyed by fire. One of the accountants ex - pressed a firm belief that an omniscientist would have been un - able to untangle the accounts as they stood. The books failed of E lance by something like $19,000. The manner of keeping :ash book was unique indeed. The debits were placed on xedit side and vice versa. This is but an illustration of the ner in which the other books were kept, in accordance with culiar and modern system of accounts. Ehen the books were finally returned to this office, there was ing left to do but secure from the books of the Auditor of : the figures herein used as bases of computation and do not le estimating. A new set of books were duly opened and accounts are now kept in an excellent manner, showing y detail of each transaction. CONDITION OF CONVICTS. !he institution has upheld a fair degree of discipline, and this out resorting to inhuman methods of punishment. The idea been to instill into each inmate's mind the fact that implicit lience to rules is the '-royal way" to the best the prison af - s. Brutality has been allowed to take no part in the main - nce of good order. The principal mode of chastisement has 1 reduction in food supplies, it having been demonstrated the shortest route to some people's brains is via their The officials have made determined efforts to stop the im - portation of gum opium (by convicts denominated as "dope" or "hop") into the prison, but with only partial success. On the advice of the Governor, one man who was averred to have brought in some of the drug was arrested, but the ex-convicts needed as witnesses were spirited away and the case fell through. "Dope" is harmful to even its old-time slaves, but the greatest horror of its presence in the penitentiary lies in the fact that young convicts are led into the use of it. The only vicious assaults made upon guards in the past two years have been the work of convicts whose temporary strength, recklessness and </seg>
            <seg id="p009">State Penitentiary. 137 disregard of consequences were born in a ball of "hop." The fight against the drug should be continued in the courts, and the importers, if caught, severely dealt with. The food given prisoners has been of better quality and of greater variety than that furnished in most prisons of the coun - try. Of course there is a sameness to the menu week by week, but this is hardly to be unexpected, especially when it is remem - bered that felons are not sent hither like citizens recommended to a certain hotel. The following is the bill of fare for the aver - age week. Monday — Breakfast: Hash, coffee, bread. Dinner: Baked pork and beans, soup, bread. B upper: Prunes (or stewed apples), tea, syrup, bread, sday- Bieakfast: Hash, coffee, bread. Dinner: Irish stew, bread, kraut. t upper: Brown gravy, bread, tea, syrup inesday — Breakfast: Hash, coffee, bread. Dinner: Boiled pork and beans, soup, bread. Supper: Oatmeal and sugar, tea, bread, syrup. Thursday — Breakfast: Hash, coffee, bread. firmer: Roast beef, potatoes, bread, kraut (or turnips.) upper: Stewed apples, tea, bread, syrup. Friday- Breakfast: Hash, coffee, bread. Dinner: Codfish and potatoes, corn bread. K upper: Brown Gravy (or mush), bread, tea, syrup, lrdav — Breakfast: Hash, bread, coffee. r inner: Boiled beef and gravy, boiled potatoes, cabbage, lpper: Stewed rice with sauce, bread, syrup, tea. Sunday- Breakfast: Hash (or bacon and potatoes), coffee, bread. Dinner: Roast beef and gravy, potatoes, coffee. 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">138 Supper: Pie, syrup, bread, tea. Broughout the year, the inmates are treated to the vegetables son, adding not a little to the variety and healthfulness of diet. Once each month the convicts are permitted to order, through the steward, such articles as are not contraband, paying therefor with money given them by friends or earned by overtime in the shops. In this way the men get many delicacies and, too often, ailments arising from over-feeding. The ills are cheerfully un - dergone, however, for the sake of getting the goods. The law relative to the transfer of insane convicts to asylums has proved a decided success. Eight unfortunates have been dealt with in accordance with the provisions of this statute and two of these have already been returned to the prison to com - plete their terms. NEEDS OF THE PRISON. The condition in which the prison now finds itself presents a most favorable opportunity for making those material improve - ments which will have to be made sooner or later. At present the improvements could be made while the new building was being completed and would entail no tearing down. I would respectfully request that two tiers of steel cells be placed in the west cell house, so as to afford room for all of the convicts, of whom over a hundred are quartered outside of cells. This would not only be a move toward better sanitary conditions, but it would of course add to the security of the prison. With all the inmates in cells, the night guard could be divided, requir - ing no additional employees. Pbe prison should have its own lighting plant. For the past ral years it has cost the state considerably more than $100 month to light the institution; for this sum, paid in like installments, a lighting plant could be put in that would furnish more lights and better; a year's rental at present rates would do L After the first twelve-month, the only expense would be a hours' extra steam in the evening to operate the dynamo. The stone building near the west wall which was disembow- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">139 I by the fire of December, 1899, can be repaired with »tone on hand, but it will require some money for a roof and for king material. A permanent and fire-proof carpenter shop blacksmith shop can and should also be erected. This can one from the same pile of stone. For these purposes, and of pointing up the walls of the prison, which are in sad need lmediate care, 1 have asked a small appropriation. This appropriation is also intended to cover the placing of two death cells and a permanent gallows in the building mentioned, These grim appurtenances seem to be required under the provi - sions of the law requiring executions to take place in the prison enclosure. Above the death cells and the gallows-room should be placed the convicts' bath house, which is at present in another place and in a condition absolutely demanding attention. I he east cell house most wofully needs a new roof. There roof on it now, but it does not perform that function peculiar 1 good roofs, viz, shed water. The present roof keeps the from entering in sheets, but it does not prevent it from com - in as rivulets, booklets, etc. Many attempts have been e to repair the roof, but they have simply changed the jraphy of the water courses. E.side from these material changes, I believe it would be for best interests of the institution to have the convicts graded three classes. Into the second of these the new inmate is ed and he is either promoted into the first grade, reduced to third, or kept in the second, according to his behavior. This hod has been tried for years in many prisons and is found to nost conducive to good order. I would recommend the establishment of some fixed rules as e admission of the public to the institution. At present vis - are allowed access excepting on Sunday, and even this free - causes complaint among some who declare that on Sunday is it possible for them to leave their work and visit the tution. Personally I am in favor of a charge for admis - —a rule that prevails in most penitentiaries — but it would some time for the public to become accustomed to practice. Appended hereto will be seen a financial report </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Land Commissioner's Report. 140 and some statistics that may be of interest. It is noticeable that an insignificant minority of the convicts sent hither during the biennium are illiterates; also that the great majority aver to have had some religious training, while the part that liquor has played can be observed only too plainly in the table relating to the habits of those received. The political beliefs of convicts are not given for the reason that they vary with the complexion of the state at large; if an administration is republican, most of the newcomers claim affiliation with that party, while if the fusion - ists are in control of the capitol, that element gets the greatest nominal support. Why this should be the case is not entirely Ptiat Nebraska has always borne a good reputation for law order is a well recognized fact; perhaps the exact figures are not so commonly known. This state has one convict for every 3,816 of its inhabitants, and it is confidently believed that no other commonwealth in the Union can make so good a show - ing. Certainly Nebraska sets her immediate next-door neigh - bors too fast a moral pace. Iowa has a convict to every 1,937 inhabitants; South Dakota, one to every 2,769; Kansas, one to every 1,556, while Colorado has one man in stripes to every 1,050 of its population. Efore closing this portion of this report, I wish to extend my re thanks to his excellency, the governor, and to the honor - members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, for the many manifestations of their courtesy towards me, and to publicly acknowledge my gratitude to Mr. Jones, the deputy war - den, and the various officers and employees who have stayed faithfully by during the grievous trials of my administration. E. D. Davis, Warden. Lancaster, Nebr., December 1, 1902. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">141 THE FINANCES. rintenance Appropriation, 1899-1900 — Balance Dec. 1, 1900 t 22.54 Maintenance Appropriation, 1901-1902 35,000.00 Special Labor Fund — Balance Dec. 1, 1900 19.57 Special Labor Fund— Received in Biennium $44,268.38 Total $79,310.49 Expended in Biennium 77,368.68 Balance, Nov. 30. 1902 t 1,941.81 STATE CA8H FUND. Balance, Dec. 1, 1900 $ 585.46 Received in Biennium 5,848.99 Total $6,434.45 Expended in Biennium $4,299.09 Balance, Nov. 30, 1902 $2,135.36 Total expenditures of all monies during the Biennium . . $81,6* LIBRARY FUND. Of the State Cash Fund balance given above, $610.01 belongs to Library Account. CONVICT8' PRIVATE FUNDS — RECEIVED AND DISBURSED. On hand November 30, 1900 $1,403.20 Received during the Biennium 7,651.29 Total $9,054.49 Expended on orders of convicts 7,725.88 Balance, November 30, 1902. $1,328.61 FARM PRODUCTS. Value of farm products raised during Biennium $6,500.00 Value of livestock on hand 2,215.00 PER CAPITA COST. Including unpaid claims, it has cost for all purposes $0,390 to </seg>
            <seg id="p014">142 CENSUS OF PRISON. N amber of inmates in prison, December 1, 1800 284 Received on commitments during the Biennium 338 Returned from parole for various reasons 20 Returned after having escaped l Returned from a conditional commutation * Returned from a four days' furlough l Returned from the Insane Asylum Total 651 Discharged by expiration of time 209 Commuted by the Governor 37 Conditionally commuted by the Governor 1 Remanded to sheriffs by order of Supreme Court Died in prison 10 Escaped from the prison 14 Released on parole by the Governor ? 8 Released on four days' furlough * Transferred to Insane Asylums 8 ~ 365 Count, December 1. 1 902 286 PAROLED CONVICTS. Number on parole, December 1, 1900 23 Paroled during the Biennium J^ Total • 101 Discharged 32 Returned to prison 20 Escaped while on parole 10 Commuted by Governor 4 B6 On parole, Nov. 30, 1902 35 FEMALE DEPARTMENT. Number in prison, December 1, 1902 4 Received on commitments in Biennium ' Returned from parole * Returned from Insane Hospital l </seg>
            <seg id="p015">143 Discharged 3 Transferred to Asylum 1 Died in prison 1 5 On hand, Nov. 30, 1902 8 AVERAGES FOR THE BIENNICM. Average number of officers and employees Average number of inmates 28tt. 86 Average number of members of families of officers Graud average 327. 1 1 EX AND COLOR OF PRESENT INMATES Males 278 Females 8 White males, 252; Negro males, 26; White females, 2; Negro females, 6. AS TO THOSE RECEIVED. SOCIAL RELATIONS. Single Married 101 Having father only 34 Having mother only 82 Having both parents 1S1 Having neither parent 95 HABITS. Temperate 12 7 Moderate 64 Intemperate 141 t'KIMKS. Larcenous Assaults on person 88 Blackmail 8 Arson 2 Bigamy 3 Perjury 3 Child stealing 9 Under 20 years 63 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">144 Between 21 and 30 159 Between 31 and 50 97 Over 50 years 13 RELIGIOUS BELIEF. Professing religious beliefs 817 Not professing any religions beliefs 115 EDUCATION. Those able to read and write 302 Those unable to read and write 30 SENTENCES IMPOSED. 8 to 5 years 164 6 to SsO years 37 Life 8 To be hanged 2 PREVIOUS RECORDS. Number who have served 1 previous term 35 Number who have served 2 previous terms 8 Number who have served 3 previous terms 1 Number who have been in Reform School 20 No criminal record known 268 GUILT OR INNOCENCE. Those who admit they were guilty 205 Those who deny their guilt 187 NATIVITY. As to the place of birth of those received during the biennium, a plurality were born in Nebraska, the exact number being 51. Iowa comes second, with 46; Illinois third, with 45; Missouri fourth, with 32, while 37 were foreign born. A FEW NOTES There are now 24 life men in prison. The "oldest termer" of these has been here for fourteen years. The first pardon issued to a Nebraska convict was signed by Governor Furnas in favor of Hurlbut Pfeiffer, No. 15. Pfeiffer was doing one year for larceny in Douglas county. The first life m&amp;n to do His full time was I nmes W hitebrc&lt;i st </seg>
            <seg id="p017">145 Et death was also the first in the prison. He was sent up Dixon county for murder, and served a little over three Iie first man to be regularly discharged was John Wallace, 73, who did one year for larceny from Douglas county. He discharged on March 12, 1873. In May 26, 1875, occurred the first case in which a guard compelled to kill a convict. The victim was William Mc - ers, who was doing 21 years for murder from Otoe county. The shortest term ever served by a convict was in December, I 873. when Harry Sage was sent up from Cass county to serve one day for manslaughter. He was pardoned the same day he came. Another short timer was Patrick Melier of Sarpy, who was sentenced to do one day for manslaughter. He was received September 7, 187 1, and discharged the following morning. In both of these case the officials had to hurry to get the man dressed, shaved and photographed. B! first woman convict received was Kate McNamara, ed November 28, 1871, for five years, Douglas county, aughter. PHYSICIAN'S REPORT. HON. E. D. Davis, Warden, Lancaster, Nebraska: My Dear Sir : — I submit herewith a report of my department for the biennial period ending November 30, 1902. The institution was in quarantine for smallpox and all of the inmates recently vaccinated when I took charge as physician. Many of those vaccinated developed symptoms of blood poison, were unable to work and required daily attention until recovery. The damage by fire rendered kitchen and cell house unhealthy and added to the already morbid condition by crowding the men closer together. The ventilation was entirely insufficient and the drainage deplorable. The institution was quickly put in as good shape as was possible under the circumstances, but many cases of fever were directly traceable to the congested condition of the prison. That the loss of life was no greater than it was occasioned surprise as a lartre Dercentacre of the convicts are </seg>
            <seg id="p018">146 afflicted with diseases which leave them peculiarly susceptible to other ailments and extend less hope of recovery when taken down. I would urge that the cell houses and kitchen be hurried to completion; that single cells of modern design be furnished for all of the prisoners; that lights be furnished for each cell so the candle system may be abolished, and that the bathing facilities be enlarged. The prevalence of syphilis makes the latter recommendation almost mandatory. I would urge that the hospital facilities be extended, that contagious or infectious diseases may be isolated; that the surg - ical cases may receive proper attention without being subject to infection by other disease. There are many prisoners who are incapable of performing manual labor, and if suitable apparatus could be supplied they might be discharged in such condition that at least physical disability could not stand as an excuse for crime. tThe subjoined table sets forth the movements o£ patients who ive applied to this department for relief; it will be found com - ete in every detail. Syphilitic rheumatism is probably the most prevalent disease at all times of the year, and this needs great attention, as the pain therefrom frequently leads to the formation of the opium habit in an attempt to get relief from the suffering. This habit is almost always formed before coming into this institution, yet there are some instances I think in which the initial dose has been received from some convict friend who has had it smuggled into the peni- tentiary. It is a very easy matter for a person afflicted with syphilitic rheumatism to form the opium habit, as this remedy, or similar ones, are sometimes given by physicians to afford immediate relief, but this only more strongly impresses the importance of properly treating these cases, which must sooner or later be again turned out on the public, probably to repeat offenses against the society that took away their liberty but did not improve their physical condition. The females are afflicted in the same manner with such habits </seg>
            <seg id="p019">147 Kiseases, and they are more difficult of treatment under the nt conditions than the males from the fact that no attendant sent to give attention to detail of treatment. I would recom - the appointment of a matron for this department. S conclusion I wish to urge the authorities to agree that any avement of the physical condition of these people placed in harge of the state is a wonderful advantage in redeeming from vice and crime and the influences of heredity. ■'hile I do not mean that the institution shall be transformed a sanitarium in any sense, I would urge that modern appli- *Deaths (Indicated by number of stars). nces and facilities usu; lly to be found in a physician and sur- for this place and the surgeon in charge [eon's office be supplie »e held responsible for heir care. I 4 s . % h I si S| a 1 i $ r s I s i= i= I DATE g| . isr- 339 0 71 236J 4 5 4 5 r . October November December January February September November 495 1323 1328 993 454 446 472 619 583 465 312 m 430 536 544 541 779 579 642 677 668 531 483 0 152 34 4 1 4 0 168 114.' 4! 6 5 0 90 1221 5 17 13 0 95 885 13 13 »16 10 0 41 398 lit 15 14 11 0 37 401 11 8 11 8 0 28 438 8 6 6 0 139 462 6 18 **10i 14 0 138 431 14 14 "14 14 0 98 3fiO 14 7 *10 11 0 36 269 11 7 10 8 0 39 334 8 9 2 0 26 395 9 8 3 0 55 473 3 8 « 5 1 97 441 5 5 » 4 5 47 482 4 7 3 22 95 641 3 21 4 30 64 478 4 7 7 4 38 65 530 4 9 12 1 4 63 598 1 12 11 2 2 74 583 2 9 " 5 6 0 97 430 6 4 6 4 23 55 401 4 4 6 2 Totals I 14621 125 1870 12406 220 L'22 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">148 K closing my report I wish to thank you and the deputy en, as well as the other officers and employees of the prison, leir kindnesses to me. Respectfully submitted, F. L. Wilmbth, M. D., Physician N. S. P. REPORT OF THE CHAPLAIN. In submitting the appended report of the Chaplain of the Prison, the Warden would suggest that the religious work at the prison be placed entirely in the hands of the head of that depart - ment, he being privileged to call in such assistance from time to time as he may deem proper. The report follows: Hon. E. D. Davis, Warden Nebraska State Penitentiary. Respected Sir: — I have the honor to lay before you my first report as Chaplain of the institution over which you preside. The fire which occurred in the first month of this biennium, when the chapel and library building were destroyed, leaving the institution without room in which to hold religious services, greatly demoralized the work pertaining to the Chaplain's depart - ment and added to this the sad disability which came upon the greatly beloved and honored chaplain, Rev. P. W. Howe, who for fifteen years ministered to the spiritual needs of the institu - tion, brought a sadness which was felt in every part of our state ; yes, more, for Elder Howe's name was national among penolog - ists and the hallowed influence which he exerted while connected with the institution will be felt to the farthest cycle of eternity, and now while seated in his easy chair in his present home he frequently inquires for the "boys" in prison, and often the inmates of the institution make kindly inquiries in relation to their former chaplain. In July, 1901, Governor Savage requested me to take charge of the work as acting chaplain of the institution which I did, and on January 1, 1902, he appointed me chaplain. For several months our only service was in personal talks at the cell door. Later arrangements were made by which we could hold our </seg>
            <seg id="p021">149 in the space allotted for the dining room, the other half remaining in their cells, which of course has made it very unpleasant in many ways and yet we have endeavored to make the services as interesting and profitable as possible under the circumstances. We have had individual talks in our office with some who have personally desired to counsel with us in relation to their spiritual interests. We feel assured these services have been helpful to the individual and beneficial to the institution. 5 'he library is now supplied with 411 books donated by friends e the fire. We also have received many magazines and ers that have been contributed by friends in different parts of state, and for these gifts we are truly thankful. We now e in the library fund a balance of $610.01 which will be used oon as the building is completed and ready to receive books. Eere is an urgent demand for a school in the institution. We a number who ought to be given an opportunity to secure st a knowledge of the primary branches of an English ed - &gt;n, and while our state has neglected this in the past in the 1, we trust that it will be provided for in the future. I conclusion I wish to extend my sincere gratitude to you for niform courtesy shown me in my work and return my is to the deputy warden, |. D. Jones, Dr. F. L. Wilmeth, the employees of the institution for universal friendship n me in the discharge of my duties. Courteously, George W. Martin, Chaplain. UNPAID CLAIMS. Swift &lt;fc Co 91 121.90 C. M. SeiU 52.34 Hargreaves Bros 709. 29 CM. Seitz 16.63 Fleischmann A Co 4. 50 Lincoln Mill Co 130.07 Hargreaves Bros 545. 59 Cudahy Packing Co 396. 36 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">150 Fleischmann A Co • 5 - 2&amp; Swift A Co 294.43 Cudahy Packing Co 523.87 Hargreaves Bros * 2 '- 22 CM. Seita 15- 15 Beatrice Creamery Co 42.48 Hargreaves Bros *** 34 Fleischmann A Co 6.00 Lincoln Mill Co 2 ?3.68 A. Booth A Co 9.50 CM. Seitz 36.45 Cudahy PackingCo 685.35 Beatrice Creamery Co 45.64 Fleischmann A Co 6. 75 Hargreaves Bros 311.24 Cudahy Packing Co 255.21 Raymond Bros. -Clarke Co 77.77 C. M. Seitz 13.65 Ed. Cerf A Co 63.54 Ed.CerfACo 2 l-42 Mayer Bros 6. 7 1 Ed.CerfACo 79.10 Ed. Cerf A Co.... 77.03 Miller A Paine 178 Miller A Paine ■ 2 8.25 Miller A Paine 77.45 Ed.CerfACo 40.68 Ed. Cerf &amp; Co 18.07 R. S. Young Bldg. Supply Co 43. 15 Joseph Burns 575.00 Cooper A Cole Bros 58. 51 Rudge A Guenzel Co 43. 81 Pauly Jail Bldg. Co 17.90 C. A. Adams 13.85 Western Supply Co 75.23 Hall Bros. Co 26.05 Sprajrue Drujr Co 44. 73 Sprague Drug Co 50.70 Kostka Glass and Paint Co 63.94 Lincoln Gas and Electric Co 105.56 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">151 Union Fuel Co $ 734. 76 Lincoln Gag and Electric Co 103. 74 Lincoln Gas and Electric Co Ill.M Union Fuel Co 1055.16 Whitebreast C. and L. Co 600 07 Lincoln Gas and Electric Co 154.44 Capital City Iron Works 6. 50 Soderburg A Landgren t&gt;. m&gt; Dunn &lt;fc Perrin Co 44. 88 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co 9. 86 Western Boiler Comp. Co 31.25 Humphrey Hardware Co 18.65 Rudge &lt;fc Guenzel Co 10. 1 0 State Journal Co 28. 75 Carl Funke 15. 18 Lincoln Hardware Co 84. 8a Cooper &lt;fc Cole Bros 17.t&gt;8 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co 7.05 Dr. W. T. Johnson 60. 00 Burlington Railway 61.52 Dierks Lumber Co 28. 7tt Lincoln Pottery 2.46 Marshall Oil Co 69.4a H. J. Smith 85.00 Griswold Seed Co 7.55 Fleischmann &lt;fc Co 6.00 Ed. Cerf &amp; Co 63.16 Kostka Glass and Paint Co 36. 83 Beatrice Creamery Co 817.51 Orleans Milling Co 371.67 Humphrey Hardware Co 45.31 Raymond Bros.-Clarke Co . 834. 30 Whitebreast C. &lt;fc L. Co 978. 59 Cudahy Packing Co 342.84 C. M. Seitz 29. 90 Lincoln Gas and Electric Co 147. 16 C. A. Adams 8. 90 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">The total unpaid claims of the biennium just previous to the one now closed amounted to $17,88767, a difference in favor of this administration (despite the emergency disbursements caused by the fire) of $3,65642. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>