<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00054.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00054.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Public Documents of Nebraska 1923-1924 Volume I</title>
               <date value="1923-1924">1923-1924</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1923-1924 VOLUME 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY 51; &gt;• hm 4ST0B. LBNOX U &gt; 1! 1!! L </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS VOLUME 1 Governor's Messages Charles W. Bryan, Retiring Message, 1925. Adam McMullen, Inaugural Message, 1925. Secretary of State, Biennial Report, 1923-1924 Auditor of Public Accounts, Biennial Report, 1923-1924. a. Appropriations, etc., 43d Legislative Session, 1925. Treasurer, Biennial Report, 1922-1924. Department of Public Instruction, Biennial Report, 1923 - 1924. Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, Biennial Report, 1923-1924. Railway Commission, Annual Reports, 1923, 1924 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Message of Governor Charles W. Bryan Delivered to the Forty -third Session of the Legislature of Nebraska January 8, 1925 </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">GOVERNOR BRYAN'S FAREWELL MESSAGE To the Members of the Forty-third Session of the State Legislature of N TI.EMEN f an outgoing governor is expected to embody during the preceding two years bers of the legislature and to the people of mendations that the departing ch.ef t eta c of his study and experience in the dis- ring the time that he has held the position as gov- ( :e des that the governor shall take executed, that the affairs of the ie sta' hat the business of the state is ef- tered and ally conducted c to execute the dcties and carry out the obligations I have had a varied and interesting ■eiiu.icii o£ the chiel ex« ind of the people, at the time I was elected, was : affairs and a reduction in taxes. This could be a reduction in the cost of government. Although plan of reorganizing the state government into a economical business method were not entirely very satisfactory progress. We have been ie lack o-f legislature cooperation through failure to repeal •equire a continuation of unnecessary and expensive certain statutes that require a contin ■plications in educational effort, overlapping and triplications in admin- c impractical and complex system of government in rat which results in an imposition upon U the time the present retiring Chief Executive came into office two l years ago the Code Law administration had been in operation under the former governor almost four years. During the biennium of Go\ error Neville's administration the cost of government was $9,000,000. The unprecedented cost of the state government for the first two years of Governor McKelvie's administration, under the Code, was approxi - mately $20,000,000 and during the succeeding two years of the same «'imini. j tr:ition the appropriations for conducting the state's affairs ad - vanced to the a.-tounding amount of 530,000,000. This tremendous cost </seg>
            <seg id="p007">2 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR BRYAN cf government proved to be such a hardship on the taxpayers and so unnecessary from a business standpoint and the protest from the public became so pronounced that a special session of the legislature w=as called during the second term of the preceding administration and the appro - priations for the conduct of the state's affairs were reduced to about $27,000,000. Reriews State's Financial History I am reviewing in a general way the financial history of the state during the six years preceding my administration for the purpose of aying a foundation for a comparison of the cost of government, etc., during the two years of my administration with the preceding two years so that your honorable body and the people of the state may have the &gt;enent of such information as is brought out to enable you to plan more understanding^ your legislative program for this session, ar.d also to give the incoming administration the information and facts baseil upon on the experience ar.d observation of the retiring governor as intended the Constitution. In my inaugural address two year? ago, later in my budget message and in a special message I recommended the repeal of the Code Law, and in its place I submitted to the legislature a practical simplified form of government in which the responsibility for deternrning the major policies of a state administration was vested in the elective constitutional state officers. The constitutional executive duties of the governor and the administrative work of the state were fixed directly in the governor. The appointive power of administrative employee? was fixed in the governor to enable him to maintain an efficient and responsive staff; and the responsibility for the planning and the conduct of the state's affairs was fixed inevasibly in the hands of the elected ?tate officers, who ai* held responsible by the voters for their conduct of the state's affr.ir*. The recommendation? sr.d copies of bills, through which the recommenda - tions of this simplified ar.d inexpensive form of government could be carried into effect, may be found by your honorable body in the rtcords of the last session of the legislature. Legislature Retains Code Law The legislature of two year.s ago declined to enact into law the busi - ness reorganisation of the state's affairs by repealing the Code but in the closing hours of the session passed a bill which diffused responsibility, created six governors in place of one, destroyed the possibility of any c« ordination between the six separate executive heads, and violated and made impossible the chief executive's duty as provided in the Constitution. its only apparent result would have been a dividing of the large number of state employees among the various state officials and neither the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">LINCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 8. 1925. 3 governor nor ■nj'ww else would have had the authority to remove the unnecessary employees or to eliminate unnecessary duplications, over- lappings, extravagar.ee and waste in the multitudinous number of de - partments, bureaus, commissioners, deputies, inspectors, etc. I felt it bill ar.d I do not recall having seen or heard any de- my i,u fense of the bin since that time by those who drafted it or supported it. ie outeoing governor two years ago recommended in his budget his estimate of the state's needs during the messaee present biermium. 1 recommended a budget fifteen days later providing for a cost of $21,987,554.41 as the operating expense of the state's appropriated $24,652,532.44. Of this amount act $23,191,532.44 corresponded with the items covered in my budget of ■'1 other words the legislature appropriated $1,203,- le Chief Executive recommended, although in ippropriation= the state auditor omitted $1,368,- 8.02 which w&gt; reappropriated of the capitol building fund, which was udget recommendations, and by from the appropriations by the legislature port was widely circulated through re had appropriated $1,083,234.05 less than when as a fact it was $l,203,97S.0S in e\ce: ov, in the Chief Executive's opinion, duct the state's affairs conditioned on the repeal of the w ugh notice was given by the Governor that he would veto 1 and unworkable Code revision bill that was passed by the legislature, the legislature* failed to make any appropriation for salaries of Code secretaries, tix of whom were drawing salaries of $5 000 per year. Thus the Governor was left with a Code Law in effect but with no provision to pay the salaries of Code secretaries. By re- ducing the number of slate employees, by abolishing unnecessary de- partments that were not required by law, by transferring activities from one department to another, by dispensing with the services of some de- partmental hrads, some bureau heads, some division head?, and by con- *olidating and coordinating work between various departments, a great reduction in the cost of administering the state government has been brought abo Number of State Employees Reduced During the first six months of the present administration as compared with the first six months of the preceding administration the number of state employees in the departments directly under the governor were reduced from six hundred ten to two hundred seventy-two. The administrative expenditures of the departments under the governor were </seg>
            <seg id="p009">4 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR BRYAN reduced for the first six months of the present administration as com - pared with the first six months of the preceding biennium $917,742.47. The number of employees in the departments directly under the governor, who are employed by the year a.-= shown on a list prepared for the incoming governor as of January 1st, 1925, is two hundred twenty-one. In an effort to establi.-h and maintain efficiency in the departments directly under the Governor's control the Governor has, during the past two year*, voluntarily established something on the order of civil service among certain classes or p-rades of work such as erjriner - ing, mechanical, accounting, bookkeeping, stenographic, clerical and other skilled labor where it was not nece=?nry to secure executive and adminis - trative heads who were in sympathy with and were needed to carry into effect the policies of the chief executive. Of the two hundred twenty-one taxpayers of Lancaster County of $29&gt;",.309.00 during this I compared with the taxe; for state purposes during the prece er.nium. The saving to Douglas County amounts to $620. all other counties in proportion. Cost of Road Building Reduced. During the past two years the cost of building roads has been greatly reduced. This has been brought about by a rule adopted by the Chief Executive which was enacted into law by the last legislature on the recommendation of the Governor. This law requires that for all regular employees referred to above, one hundred eleven, or more than ore-half, mm a part of &gt;.h? I in the employ of the fon ernor. State Taxes Reduced The saving in taxes l&lt;llnf the past two years as compared with the two preceding yet^rs has amounted to f.6,160,107. This represents a saving of that many dollar- in the cost of operating the state /. ■vern- ment during the past two year- ;. compared with the two preceding years. It means that there has been $6,160,107 less collected from th« people in the form of taxes for state purpose- during the past two n than was levied in the two preceding years. This represents a reduction in the taxes levied for state i.urp he ye^rs 1923-24 of 2:: r ' pius, a l compared with the years 1921-1:2. These tax sta from the state tax eommissoner's records and represent trr ta made by the state hoard of equalization ar.d apportioned by it to th&lt; ious counties of the state. Ai Bhistrative of what this tax reduction during this benrium MUl to the various courties, it will be ob that each county in the state is now sendinc: an average of about $1 le.~s to the state trearurcr this bier.niui.i lhar. they were required to do during the preceding biennium. For instance, this means a saviiig to the H </seg>
            <seg id="p010">LINCOLN, NEIIR., JANUARY S, 1925. 5 public work to be done, the state or counties must advertise for bids and that these bids must be received and opened at the hour Mt for the bidding to be closed and that the bids must be opened in the presence of the bidders. This rule prevents what is known as "teakettling" of bids and also encourapes competition in bidding, as it assures the lowest idder [retting the eontrr.ct. County commissioners have been encouraged to bid on state aid work in their respective counties as assurance against collusion in bidding by private contractors. A threat to open a state gravel pit secured an immediate reduction of about 33% in the price of gravel. Through the.=e various means the cost of road building in Ne- braska has been reduced between 259c and 309c, representing a saving ring the present biennitua in road construction alone of about $600,000 ; compared with what the road work was costing in Nebraska prior to e past two years. Price of Coal Reduced. i ecutive of the state, acting in his individual capacity an official of the state, has done what he could last winter ter to protect the people of the state from profiteers in necessaries of life, comfort and convenience such as fuel, In response to a demar.d of the people of the state r protection against the high price of coal I undertook to furnish coal price to the officials of any o r.ny puMic corvmittee or officials of any who would a ssist in the distribution of coal at a reasonable real competition has been established rice v- a r r ale of eotl, and the retail price of coal ■een reduced from $3.00 to $5.00 a ton and has resulted in a saving c bout $10,000,000 a year on their fuel bills t&gt; ! The state has had no connection with and has paid no part of the expense tate Reduced Price of Gasoline e by the state, through the Chief ;n price at which gasoline should" be sold, has resulted in a saving to the people of Nebraska during the past year and a half of a sum conservatively estimated at $9,000,000 a year. During the summer of 1923 it was observed that there was a margin between the wholesale and retail price of gasoline in Nebraska of about eleven cents :i gallon and, as Governor, I wired the Attorney General of the United States asking that immediate legal action be taken against the gasoline combination. I also wired the Federal Trade Commission and at the same time I wired the general office of the Standard Oil Company demanding an immediate reduction in the price of gasoline and notified them that I had called on the Federal authorities to prosecute them for coal </seg>
            <seg id="p011">6 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR BRYAN conspiracy in restraint of trade. I also stated that unless the Standard Oil Company immediately reduced the price of gasoline to a reasonable figure that the state would feel it its duty to its citizens to establish •ales agencies throughout the state. The following day the Standard Oil Company reduced the price of gasoline in Nebraska six cents a gallon. However, during the year of 1924 the price of gasoline was gradually advanced until it became intolerable. A demand was again made that the price be reduced or the state would undertake to establish competi - tion in the retailing of gasoline. This threat not meeting a ready re- sponse, a public filling station for gasoline was established at the ma - terial yards of the public works department in the city of Lincoln. Th« retail price of gasoline was from nineteen to twenty-one cent? a gallon, and upon opening the state filling station the retail price was fixed the state at fifteen cents. After opening the one statior nounced that unless there wa? a reduction in the price of g.i.-olir.e throughout the state to a reasonable figure the =tate would undert establish local filling stations throughout Nebraska. Immed tion by the private dealers of one cent a gallon followed later another two cents reduction was made and other r« ing the Governor of Nebraska, for engaging in the gasolir establishing a retail market for gasoline by the state. The st filling station has been self-supportinp and in addition to bringing at a saving to the people of Nebraska of abcut $9,000,000 a year, k produced a net profit, during the short time it has been in ope of about $2,5C0 to the state. I recommend that the Mate continue th* filling station, and that the legislature enact a statute that will give the state specific authority when necessary' to buy and sell gasoline and coal or any other fuel used for warmth or for generating heat or power. The fact that the state possessed such authority would, in itself, prevent excessive prices being charged by private producers or dealers iu these necessities to life, health, comfort and business development Budget for 1925 The budget I have just submitted contains suggested amounts neces - sary to cover the cost of the state's activities for the biennium of 1925-27 which, if the legislature embody into the appropriation bills of this ses - sion, will make another large reduction in the cost of the state govern - ment without, in my judgment, handicapping, injuring or crippling an&gt; necessary state activity or lowering the high state of efficiency by which „...».] *:i 4.1 : *i .1 i. vt_i 1 i i .1 : r i lowed until the price throughout Nebraska vas based or. the price fined by the state. As the wholesale price of gasoline was further reduce! Lhe state price \va? fixed at thirteen cents and this became the basic piice throughout the state and it was not ehamred until the morning of November 5, 1924. The National Petroleum Association at a convention held recently in Ohio pMMd a resolution, &gt; hch was broadcast through- out the presr- associations and published in he daily new ;.ur- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">LINCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 8, 1925. 7 the state's work has been carried on during the past two years. The total amount of appropriations as suggested in my budget for the coming biennium is $17,223,101.( nounts in the budget for the various spending and I beiieve that my assumption is correct, c that all department? of the state government, executive, judicial, legis- lministrative, have had ample funds during lue he past two years to conduct their respective departments successfully, md to bring the service of the state to as high, if not a higher state of biennium. I have, therefore, in making \ budget, used in a great many instances, the amounts that were for the same activities. In other instances, I \.:.- in excess of the \ resent Governor's tions two years ago, his recommendations at that time have rated, and in some instances, I have arrived at the amount guested appiopriation by taking the appropriation made for ty two ywn ago, ascertaining the amount of the appropria- r id been consumed in the first seventeen months of the present id after allowing a like amount for each of the seven re- of the biennium, have deducted from the budget item seemed to be in excess of the needs for that activity sent biennium. lie's activities directly under the governor, and grouped largely t was known as the "Code System," have been reorganized v hn ttle of the former code organization remains. This was partly le last legislature failing to appropriate money for salaries of the code departments, but was largely brought about by icutive, of the past two years, who has endeavored to dis- r.ecessary or duplicated activities that the code 3 remove from the pay roll all unnecessary em- the budpet for the activities directly under the gov - med that the people, acting through the legislature, i :tion was necessary to eliminate any and administrative and educational activities of the ierefore made up a budget covering certain ac- he thought in mind that these duplications and overlappings would be abolished, a? both the major political parties in the state, through thoir =tr:tp nlutfnrms. hnvp nrnmkpfl tliA nonnla t^av «f a i,u ■*« \\ tforms, have promised the people they would do. Duplications in Departments provision for the finance department has been made because the code code law should be immediately repealed and the finance department handled by the state auditor, or the state auditor's work should be ployee </seg>
            <seg id="p013">MESSAGE OF GO\ ERNOR BRi A.N 8 handled by the finance department. They are a duplication of each other and serve no good purpose. This consolidation would make a saving to the taxpayers of $25,000. The agricultural department should be abolished. An inspection de - partment including all necessary state inspections should be established. These inspections should then be arranged for at their source, or at the place the shipments enter the state, and in this manner save hundreds of thousands of dollars a biennium, and a more efficient department could be conducted with less than half of the present force employed in the agricultural department, although that department is operating now with a greatly reduced force from that of two years ago. In my judgment the seed analysis department should be transferred to the State Agricultural College. We have-, during the past two yean, abolished from the agricultural department the market news and pub - licity department, the radio outfit — all of which were duplications of service paid for by the people through other agencies, and was money worse than wasted. The state bureau of markets is of no value as it is being duplicated by the Agricultural College and the Federal author - ities. The retiring Governor recommends that the public welfare depart - ment, as it originally existed under the code, be abolished, which can only be done by statute; and that the child welfare and child hygiene departments be transferred to the state superintendent, where this work is being handled largely in other states, and where such work will not be duplicated, as now, by the welfare department of the state, by the university extension work, and also in the state superintendent's office. By concentrating this work in one department, and then properly financ - ing it, the service to the state would be greatly enhanced and the an - noyance and expense to the public would be greatly reduced. A recommedation is made that the athletic department should be consolidated with the game and fish department under the game warden where it has been handled under the present administration, the same as in gome other states. It appears that the Sheppard-Towner Aet, which is known as the Maternity Measure, could better be operated under the extension de - partment of the university rather than be more or less duplicated as at present. The inspection department of the fire prevention department should, in my judgment, be transferred to the suggested department of inspee- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">LINCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 8, 1925. 9 tion. The investigation department of the division of fire prevention is lerwriters supply experts, on demand, to r unnecessary vestigate questionable fire Abolish Blue Sky Department of the division of the Bureau of Securities during the The Governor's responsibility firmly convinces me I' id bolished, and that legislation be substituted which would hold the officers of a company or corporation financially ami criminally responsible for any misrepresentations by their agents of corporation stock or bond.-- sold within the confines of Nebraska. Independent State Banking Department 1'he state banking department is of such size and importance that, in es :n experienced superintendent who would de vote his entire time to the work, to be appointed by the governor and directly responsible only to him. The guarantee of bank deposits has been of inestimable value to the people of Nebraska, and care should be .te tee of deposits law is not modified or *-eaker;ed. The operation and administration of that law, which was intended exclusively for the benefit and protection of the depositors m state banks, &gt;hould bo kept directly in the hands and under the super- bility of the governor i The insurance business has grown to such large proportions that it ould also be a separate department with a supervisory head appointed by. and responsible to, the governor, ard not be a subdivision of some other department with scattered and diffused authority that prevents it from having the immediate care and attention of a supervisory head who b capable of giving it the attention that its importance deserve: The division of hail insurance should be strengthened ro as to give more ample protection to those whose crops are destroyed by hail. Eliminate Duplication of Library Work. No provision has been made in the budget for the legislative refer - ence bureau or the library commission. These activities are duplications of similar work and therefore prevent efficient service and at the same time add unnecessary expense and burden the pay roll with unnecessary - employees. The state university library extension department can en of the banking law .-crutinized, reate Department of Insurance </seg>
            <seg id="p015">10 MESSAGE OP GOVERNOR BRYAN supply all reference books that are now supplied by both the university and the legislative reference bureau, and the attorney general's office can draft the bills for the legislature by adding an assistant or two to his staff during the time the legislature is in session. The state library, the university library, the legislative reference bureau, the library com - mission, and the state historical society are all building up libraiies that are more or less duplicated. These five state libraries that the tax - payers are now maintaining in the city of Lincoln could be consolidated and handled by the state university library and the state library at the State House. Normal Work Triplicated The training for teachers for public school* is carried on in thr different departments of our educational system of the state, viz., the university, normal &gt;chools and high school?, which is a triplication of effort, causes an increase in taxes and probably lessens the effeetiveres of the effort of each of these schools. I suggest th consider the possibility of centralizing the state's effort In trair men and women as teachers for the schools of the state and that .sufficit funds then be provided to properly conduct the trair Test Farmers Wheat Free I recommend that the Staid Agricultural College e.--tabli tain the necessity machinery or equipment to test the far and ascertain free of cost the amount of gluten in each mitted by the faimer. This would add very little to the c&lt; given by the State .Agricultural Collepe but it would be woi of dollars a year to the farmers. Repeal Intangible Tax Law The so-called intangible tax law that was enacted four years ajro which provides that the intangible property such a.= stocks, bonds, notes, mort - gages, etc., shall be assessed at one-fourth their face value while tangible property such as farms, homes, merchandise, etc., should be assessed at their full val.ie Is unfair, unjust and un-American in that it enables those best able to pay taxes for the support of the frovernme.it, to trans- fer three-fourth? of their taxes onto those who are already overburdened. This law should, in my judgment, be repealed and all classes of property and all classes of people should pay according to what property they have, and abolish the system of transferring the taxes from the rich tu the poor which has developed through the so-called intangible tax law. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">11 c LINCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 8, 1925. Government Development of Water Power. measure be enacted so that the water power ch b owned by the people can be retained as their heri- under government control by municipal, county b ■overnment t in Public Works Department attention of your honorable body to conditions that sied in the department of public works during the prior and up to the time that I came into office. n There was found to be a deficit in the road department two years ago. i Thi? deficit had been accumulating for three years prior to that tinw ici of the legislature at its session two years ppointed a joint committee of the senate and tu hou.-e to investigate the deficit which was officially reported by the int committee reported that there was no deficit in G j and that there would be a cash balance in the road administration after all claims against it were paid. &gt;'■ report was adopted by both branches of the legis - ma it has been determined by the Supreme Court that c in the road department, in the case taken to the t Supreme Court wherein the contractors attempted to mandamus the for road work done on contracts let by the state for &gt;: 9-20 and of 1921-22. The Supreme Court upheld the &gt;vs;nor that there was a deficit in the road fund, and ■ road work in a prior biennium could not be paid in the following biennium and that the only way that lese unpaid claims of road contractors could be liquid - jh a deficiency appropriation at the next session of the C( et t- While the exact amount of the deficit in the road depart- &gt;f two yean ago ci:n not be definitely determined at this time, the has fixed the amount a* definitely as they could on December 31st, 1924, at $340,048.05. I recommend that a de- ftciency appropriation be made to pay the claims against the state road i 1 department that were contracted for prior to January 4, 1923. w Deficit in Bridge Fund There is found to be a deficit in the state aid bridge fund for the biennium preceding- my administration. It appears that after the bridge appropriation for the former biennium was exhausted the heads of the public works department authorized the officials of thirteen different ccui'.ties to build and repair bridges on promise that the state would pay its share of the cost. The total amount due these various counties is </seg>
            <seg id="p017">12 MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR BRYAN $128,567.47. This represents a deficit that can only be paid by a de - ficiency appropriation of the legislature and I recommend that such an appropriation be made and that said deficit in the bridge fund for the former biennium be liquidated. The total deficit in the road and bridge fund of the former administration is found to be about $474,615.52. Irregularities in Road Department. The unecrtainty as to the exact amount of the deficieny in the road department under the former administration is on account of irregular - ities found to exist in that department through an investigation made hy the Federal authorities a.iil the present retiring Go% - ernor during the past year. These irregularities consist of a falsification of the record* in the public works department to .-how a large increase in the yardage of dirt moved over the yardage of dirt actually moved. This has resulted in the payment, by the state, of large sums of money to road con - tractors in excess of the amount due them for the service rendered. The records were also falsified so that the federal government was r« - &lt;iuired to pay the state, which in turn went to the contractor, sums of money for work in excess of what had been rendered by the contractor. The federal government has made a demand upon the state for the re - turn of the money pcil to the state on two road projectr which was secured by a falsification of the n the public works department of Nebraska, by increasing the number of yards of earth moved in excess of the amount of dirt actually handled by the contractor. The federal jrovernment also discovered additional falsifications on varicus road pro - jects but did so in ti; .\e to refuse payment. The records in the public works department show that these mount* in exce.-s of the actual service rendered were paid out to road contractors on orders and approval of those in charge of the public works department prior to January 1923. This investigation also has shown that classification of material moved were changed by the former -tate enp-irieer's department without con - sent or advance approval of the federal r-overnment, and in violation of lav r.nd that large sura ; of money were paid out by the state prior to January 4, 192:\ nnd that the re.ult of this change in classification on one or more projects has resulted in the payment to contractors of up - wards of $100,000.00 by the state ir, excess of the contract agreement entered into by the federal and itate government with the contractors at the time the contract was let. I have laid before the Attorney General of this state the result of the investigation made by the federal government and the present re - tiring Governor, together with copies of the records in the public works department covering the various projects where falsification of the records has been found, and also supplied copies of affidavits showing when and how said falsifications were made, and have supplied the At- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">LINCOLN. NEHR., JANUARY 8, 1925. 13 torney Genera) with copies of results of investigations by county officials of Nebraska covering re-classification of materials by the former heads of the public works department of Nebraska which has resulted in the loss of laree sums of money to the taxpayers of the state. I have recom - mended to the Attorney Geneiai that he take appropriate action to punish the guilty and to recover the large sums of money wrongfully paid out by the state. I recommend a deficiency appropriation by the legislature to reimburse the federal government for the sums paid to the state in excess of the amounts actually due, whenever, in the judgment of the Attorney General, the ends of justice will not be impaired by supplying the legislature with the necessary data on which the federal govern - ment ask? for the return of money paid to the state through misrepre - sentation. Progress in Road Development. Great progress has been made in road development in Nebraska during the past two years and especially during 1924. A delay in letting 1 road contracts occurred in the summer of 1923 because of the mandamus proceedings in the Supreme Court by the road contractors in an effort to have the appropriation of this biennium for road purposes u?ed to pay the amounts clnimed by road contractors for contracts let during the preceding bicnnium. However, more federal aid roadwork has been done Nebraska daring 1!»24 than for any preceding year and almost three nv miles of road were graveled in 1924 than for all of the preceding rears eombin wo cents a gallon on gasoline for road building purposes &gt;L l .-iitn?ested by vaiiou.- organizations. There is no question in 1 l 1jt that the people of Nebraska at this time are opposed to ieir t?N burdens, whether it be through a tax on gaso- c line or through any other plan. If a tax is to be levied on gasoline, it must be paid by the consumer and if the consumer is to have an in - creased burden of two cents a. galled on gasoline, the same consumer should receive B reduction of an equal amount en the other taxes that he is now paying. In my judp-menl there is no need, necessity or defense of any increa.-e in the armunt of taxes that arc being collected at the pres - ent time for conducting the state's busir.o: s for the coming two years. The Child Labor Constitutional Amendment I submit herewith the proposed amendment to the federal constitu - tion relating to child labor. This amendment was sent to the Chief Exe - cutive of Nebraska by the federal Secretary of State in the manner ( Ipposes Increase In Taxes, Gasoline or Otherwise </seg>
            <seg id="p019">ip •l i t be e i c 14 MESSAGE OP GOVEKMUK BRYAN prescribed for the submission to the various state legislatures for jroval or rejection. 1 sugirest i'iat your honorable body give this pro posed amendment the careful consideration which its importance me If the proposed amendment is intended to enable Federal authorities to protect children of tender ape from working in factor:? du: trial plants, I believe that this amendment has merit r.r:d if aci would serve a worthy purpose. If, however, it is the intention of the amendment to take from the parents the control of their own chi until after they are eighteen years of age, so that a child would permitted to have the benefit of outdoor life on the farm, and be give constitutional development and educational training that th of the farmers are now receiving in assisting their parents in &lt;l chores and the lighi farm work, it would t h human to the parents ami wuuki destrc i child. It might be well to submit the cr endum vote of the peop Deposit Fees In General Fund I would recommend that all funds of whatsoever ch they be from federal aid, intere/t op monies invented, f service by the stata in the form of inspect i l and all spending agencies receiving state aiu taroagh appr str.te money or state funds from any other :;ourcs : hould, b &lt;;uired to deposit all such receipts in the genera! fund wi treasurer, and that no money should be paid out by any spending of the state, or to which the state contributes, without specif appropriated by the legislature for each activity, a the regular voucher system of the state \vh? U:l state and the state treasurer approve same. H' spending agencies receiving state aid in any form or m examined under the authority of the state auditor or stat ment. There has been some suggestion through the i dutions by different organizations fcr a tax a building fund for vtaiou? spending c L from a taxpayer's standpoint I do r.ot be v. certain mill levy is authorized, then the supporters of the sper agency would be interested in ir.cr er crease the total receipts from the fixed mill levy, and this might r. not only a hardship on the taxpayers but it enables the spending agi to collect p.n increasing amount of funds which, in turn, er.courag cessive expenditures without the knowledge or consent of those who are taxed to provide the funds. Opposes Special Mi!! Ltvi </seg>
            <seg id="p020">LINCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY 8, 1925. 15 Board Of Mediation The statute providing for a Board of Mediation and Concilliation, to serve in di-putes l&gt;et\veen capital and labor before the strike or lockout stage has been reached, was inadvertently repealed a few years ago. However, the appropriation of $1,000 made to defray the expenses of led by the legislature four years ago and also two such a board w ear:- ago. A bill of this kind was recommended by the Governor two ed in the legislature but did not become a law yeai&gt; ;:jro ar although the legislature indicated its intention to enact the law as an ap- lor the expense of such a board, i recommend t i -wa.: inadvertently repealed, be reenacted so that .-tijjatiou und arbitration can be utilized not only ;al and labor but for the protection of the generaJ 1 labor but for the protection of the genera) orVmen's Compensation Fund he state of Nebraska who are injured in line oj titled to workmen's compensation under th» em- f ru unable to draw any com- of no spech'ic appropriation having on aecou ie by the legislature for that purpose. I recommend that ip making appropriations lor salaries and wajres of the various employee? appropriations to the state who would come under the workmen's compensation law that ppropriation be added for this specific purpose, and that the spending agency be authorized to make payments to injured employees by the state labor commissioner or by the courts whose awar Attorney General Should Be Appointed horizing the chief executive of ihere is no provision bv statute the state to provide himself with a counselor and no money has been appropriated for thr.t purpose. I believe that the legal department of the state should be operated directly under the authority of the gover- nor and that the attorney general or legal advisor of the governor should be appointed by the frovernor. I therefore recommend that the legisla- ture submit an amendment to the constitution to be voted on by the peo- ple at the next freneral election, providing for the appointment by the governor of the attorney general instead of electing him as a constitu- tional officer. Arbor Lodge During the past two years a magnificent contribution has been mad* to the state. Mr. Joy Morton has presented to the state of Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p021">16 home place at Nebraska City, together with Morton Park comprising- about seventy acres. This property, valued at $200,000.00, was the home of Joy Morton's father, J. Sterling Morton, founder of Arbor Day and former Secretary of the United States Department of Agriculture. The state has formally accepted the mansion and grounds known as "Arbor Lodge," and has agreed to maintain the property as a state park. The State Park Board has taken charge of the beautiful home and ground? and "Arbor Lodge" is being visited by thousands of people yearly whr testify to the state's appreciation of the generous gift of Joy Morton and the opportunity it has given the state to perpetuate "Arbor Lodge' in memory of the late J. Sterling Morton. Law Enforcement The passage of the law, by the legislature two years ap-o, giving tit aturo two year governor authority to remove couv.ty and city law enf&lt; for failure to enforce the prohibition law of local law enforcement officers and given the chief state deputv law enforcement ot'ficer, who i- directl IXO that he needed to make law enforcement effective. The ]■-.- merit department ha- operated so satisfactorily to the enforcement of liquo: lawi and the law against aut enforcement of liquor lawi and the law against automobile thef the complaints apainst the violation of these laws ha the complaints against the violation of these laws have been gr&lt; du-'ed and ther' Itta been practically no complaint a: du-'ed and there- h prac coinpl.--.int which the state law enforcemerit department ha- vpt which the plate law er to enforcing the liquor law and the law agninst thi the state law enforce the various comtv c public m f prosecuting variou-- crimes such hi ouantities of merchandise from various stores in differc of th» M:/e. tA summary of the results of the efforts of the state Mit department, together with federal prohibition officer thorities for the yenrs 1923 and 1924, is as follows: Total case? pending 444 Total jail sentences ' 786 Total UMSjat of fines paid $350,20^.17 Total numbei of cars confiscated 135 Estimated value of cars 20.250.00 Total amount of lir.c.i paid for liquor violations for the years 1923-24 $370,458.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">UNCOLN, NEBR., JANUARY &amp;, 1925. 17 * ummarv of the number of cars, stolen in the state for the year* .1 J23-24, and the number of car? recovered as reported by the chief i b iave been apprehended by the hirh include the state, county n the state. This v were fficiencv of the state law en- forcement department for this be - ith ?75,OOO for the pMnding bi - nmer.dation for this department of mum. wiuiri' Triil Judcc To Fix Reasonable Miniiiium Sentence lr i 1 believe that the jury should have the bene- arrivuig fit of th« trial juke's opinion as to the evidence. I therefore surest an amendment to ;he statutes, which will enable trial judges in Nebraska v to discuss the evidence for the enlightenment of the jury as the federal judges are permitted to do under federal rules in jury cases. leputv law enforcement officer i= as follow ief Executive of the state 1 desire to call the attention of the he increase of crime, especially crime? of violence or in passing sentence upon criminals MB me to twenty year- and immriH tely :: pi rat ion of the one year, including jrood behaviour which re- sentence to ten months, the prisoner, his friends or attorneys B Bo-.ird of Panloni and Pawie* for a hearine on the ciue-tion i.;.. under tlie law, coulci fix a defii i:e sentence the custom of fixi.-.c the minimum at one M of what a reasonable niir.!mum sentence for certain r to iho PanUm Board which is compo-ed of ititutioaal officers. I therefore recommend a statute rc&lt;iUir- to fix a reasonable minimum as well as maximum sen- believe, will lessen the nun.ber of crime? committed in ml t'n ■&gt;f Nebraska and will therefore reduce the number of prisoners e-ed for Increasing penitentiary room and will lessen the work f the c officers who ronpo.-e the Pardon Board. Tri:ii Judro To Discuss Evidence .. n jur ■y ca.es, ia ci\ler to clarify the testimony and assist the jury In :a u </seg>
            <seg id="p023">IS MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR BRYAN Supreme Court Commission The Supreme Court, owing to the congestion of the docket, should lave relief for at least two years and as the state bar association haz recommended that aid be given the Supreme Court in the form of a commission as was done by statute in 1915. I suggest that yoar honorable &gt;ody favorably consider this recommendation. Pardons and Paroles The statutes provide that the ure a report of the activities of roles, including a list of all pudoti he names of the prisoners, the r&lt; ncy and copy of dissenting opiniol he publication of a report cf this age a typewritten report 1 ■; &lt;oard of Pardons :.::&lt;! PmlM, wh ion that the law reqxdm except reasons for each separate art of c opinions are on file, to^etlw error -hall submit to the lee: Board of Pard commutations, paroles and respite o:. why the Board extended cler ipropriation w d I am submitt'ng wi te Chief Probation O hi includes al (- Boar towards the prisoner plete record- a: ■r office of the Board of P: I' roles. The action of the Board of ■ each case. Therefore there ar« Pardons and Parole ; v.as unti. no minority opinion.- submitted The first construction or the part of e will house all the constitutional officers and all the active admini-trative departments of the state government is piactically completed. Pan i :' the constitutional officers of the state and practically all of the adminis - trative officers and employees of the state are now housed in their per - manent quarters in the new capitol. Nebraska's new state capitol, as designed by the architect, Mr. Goodhue, f.nd being built or. plar.s laid down by him, is producing a substantial snd magnificent building- The contract for the foundation and the first section was entered into by the former Governor and capitol commission, and the excavation for tha basement and the basement walls and the foundation were laid before the present retiring Governor took up his official duties as chairman of: the capitol commission. During the past two years the first con - struction or first section of the building has been completed, and the greater portion of the building has been accepted from the eapitol com - mission by the Governor on behalf of the state, and is now occupied by the Governor and all the departments directly under the governor's eon- The New Capiio. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">LINCOLN. Ntl?R., JANUARY 8, 1925. 19 The architect, Mr. Goodhue, passed away during the past two years but the general plans and specifications were so near completion that the capitol commission was able to enter into very satisfactory arrange - ments with the Goodhue business organization to complete the detailed specifications of the Goodhue architectural and building plans, and to superintend the construction and equipment of the building. The total amount of moneys paid out by the capitol commission from the time the first work on the plans commenced, to December 16, 1924, including payments to the general contractors and stone contractors authorized on that date, aggregate $2,732,160.84. There is still due on anding contracts for material and labor $284,655.93. The total nt which the commission has expended or which it is under obli- gation to spend is, therefore, $3,016,816.77. The capitol commission es - timates that four years will be required to complete the building in ac - cordance with the original plans and that the work still to be done — in addition to the existing uncompleted contracts, will cost approximately $4,923,000 00. This would bring the total cost of the new capitol to I4O,O(M).(K). I am advised by the capitol commission that the increase in the cost ie capitol over the original sum estimated and provided for by the gislature, viz., $5,000,000.00, was due to the fact that after the original ze of the building had been agreed upon the capitol commission found g other capitol buildings, constructed in recent years, that the buildings had been underestimated to meet the growth of the me i that the Nebraska capitol commission increased the t Nebraska's capitol from seven and one half million cubic f i one hundred thousand cubic feet. My service as jitol commission, during the past two years, has led he size M now planned could not be reduced without c proper anticipated growth and development, of the e need for housing space. I believe that the tax- •aver- of Nebraska are getting the worth of their money for each dollar pent in the construction of the new capitol, and that when it is finished, if the plans are carried out and the building completed along the strict business lines and care with which it has been constructed thus far, Nebraska will have the be&gt;t capitol building in the United States and it will have been built for the lowest cost per cubic foot of any public building of its character erected in the nation. The tax levy now being collected will complete the six year levy made for the new capitol building purposes, and will create a fund of about $5,300,000.00. About $3,000,000.00 of this money has already been expended and the other twa million and a third is in the hands of the state treasurer, or the bulk of it is and the remainder is being col - lected with the 1924 taxes. The capitol commission, for the purpose of 5123281) </seg>
            <seg id="p025">20 MESSAGE OP GOVERNOR BRYAN completing the building on the broad, substantial and economically beau- tiful plans as prepared by Mr Goodhue, recommends that the special tax levy for the new capitol building purposes be extended to raise the es- timated cost of $7,040,000.00. The proceeds from this levy will, ui the present plans, complete the building a originally intended eluding a heating plant at an estimated cc-t of 5300,000.00, p.ru] ?r.(v 000.00 for furnishing and decorating the building, and landscaping grounds, and all other expense in connection with the construction, equip- ment and completion of the new capitol and prounds. The proe from the six year tax levy for the new capitol building purpose r a- already been appropriated and will be contracted against for the ond section or second construction by the end of the biennium therefore will not need to be reapproprated by this session of the legislature. Howaver, the additional contracts which will have to be entered into by the capitol commission before another session o legislature, will probably require an additional appropriation out of the funds to be provided from the extension tax levy of three or four hundred thousand dollar.;. In ord ontinue the construe ruction, which will ho the new capitol and have the seco House of Representatives, re ice up ture meets in January 1927, it will be necessary for contrac c for the second section or second construction in the verv imme&lt; i ture, and the old building will have to be *orn away imn:« the adjournment of the present therefore, that the reeo:nmendatio mission be given the earliest possible consideration by your honor body, and I recommend that the nh-.n of the c «bove, receive your early and favorable cc In Conclusion I could not lay aside my official dutie.- as governor mending those officials and employees who have so hor and efficiently labored during the past two years as public servar to give to the state the high character of government and service the people of Nebraska have enjoyed. It is with pride that I point to the fact that no person appointed by me or serving under me. as g ernor, during my term has been criticized by the press or privately criticized, as far as I know, either as to their qualifications for the posi- tion they hold or for the manner in which they have discharged their respective public duties. I am deeply indebted to them for the coopera- tion they have given me and thank them for the State for the splendid service they have given Nebraska. The very cordial relations which have existed between the elective constitutional officials of the state during this administration and the non-partisan and business-like manner in which they have cooperated in </seg>
            <seg id="p026">LINCOLN. NEBR., JANUARY 8, 1925. 21 ir official duties, is gratefully appreciated by the retiring governor is a member of the following state boards and Ch G , Board of Pardons and Paroles, State Board of Equali - f Educational Lands and Funds, also the Capitol Com- ective state executive officers constitute these boards 1 is not all of one poliv'cal party every official boards and commission during this tin atisfactorily to each member, and re - question by every member of each mined eac: rd.= and commission Nebraska daring the past crops, ar.d a profitable return from e must, however, bear in mind the unprofitable years many demands which suirh in c V T our honorable body, I feel sure, ppoi lously c I n bringing to a close my work as the Chief ore vou. o of the Nebraska Legislature and to thmi bessio: Governor my mo ; -t sincere good wishes for comu :h of you and ;i successful completion c: 1 u CHARLES W. BRYAN, Governor. Tmine the many and important permit me to exfnpa to the </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>