<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00001">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00001</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>MESSAGE OF GOVERNOR WILLIAM A. POYNTER TO THE TWENTY-SEVENTH SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA, JANUARY 3, 1901</title>
               <date value="1901">1901</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-29</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
I 



<seg id="p002">
l/Q/ 1 / 

s 


GOVERNOR WILLIAM A. POYNXEK </seg>









            <seg id="p003">
To the Senators and Representative* of the Twenty-seventh Session of the 

Legislature of Nebraska: 

Gextleme.x — Complying with the provisions of the Constitution of the 
state of Nebraska, I place before you a summary of the operations of 
the Tarious departments of state during the past biennium, and offer for 
your consideration some suggestions as to what I deem the needs of the 
state. 

I desire to congratulate you as the chosen representatives of a moat 
progressive and intelligent constituency. It is a notable honor to be 
chosen the representative in any capacity of a people such as comprise 
the citizenship of our state. Doubtless many difficult problems will present 
themselves for your solution. Upon the wisdom with which yon 
deal with them will depend. In a large measure, the continued advancement 
and welfare of Nebraska. 

Too much of our legislation is built upon the give and take plan — a 
system "of you help me and I'll help you" between legislators. Logrolling 
is notorious in almost every legislative hall, and all the way up to the 
national halls of Congress. The lobby exerts undue influence. As a 
result of these things we have a mass of ill-considered laws, the meaning 
of which is obscure, many contradictory, and, when submitted to the test 
of constitutional interpretation, utterly fail and become null and void. 
We need fever rather than more laws. The legislators who will repeal * 
large number of laws now upon our law books, which are and have been 
S </seg>


            <seg id="p004">
overnor William A. Poynter 
TO THK 

Tweaty-sereitk Sesskw of the Legislature of Nebraska. 

"* 

JANUARY 3, 19O1. 





tor ream dead letters, and will strip others of useless verbiage which tends 
to obscure their meaning, and clothe them in language so plain that the 
"wayfaring man, though a simpleton, need not err therein," and in the 
enactment of the few needed laws frame them so plain and direct that 
there can he no room for any quibbling as to their meaning, would earn 
for themselves memorial tablets from their grateful fellow citizens. 

Many laws passed by the legislature would fail of enactment if the 
voters and taxpayers of the state had the opportunity of expressing themselves 
upon their desirability before they went into effect. If every law 
had to pass the test of popular approval the number of statutes would 
be much smaller than it is now, and the enforcement of those approved 
would be an easy task. Purely partisan measures would be unknown, and 
the occupation of the lobbyist would be at an end. I believe it would be 
to the great benefit of the state if all acts of the legislature, except 
emergency legislation for the maintenance of public business and institutions, 
were submitted to the ratification of the people. The material 
growth and advancement of the state depends in no small degree upon 
the character of its laws. If the people themselves had a more direct 
interest in the framing of laws for their government, the laws would 
more generally be in accord with their needs. 

FINANCIAL. 

The State Treasurer reports a balance on hand at close of business 
November 30, 1900, of $615,018.34. The bonded indebtedness of the state 
has been entirely paid and a balance in the sinking fund of $56,165.23. 
This yon should transfer to the general fund and authorize the Treasurer 
to credit any further moneys coming into that fund to the general fund. 
No further levy for the sinking fund has been made, but some back taxes 
upon that fund will be collected from year to year. Our floating indebtedness 
represented by state warrants is $1,727,509.72. The school fund has 
Invested in $1,165,762.12 of this amount, -which has practically put the 
state upon a cash basis so far as the purchase of .supplies and the maintenance 
of our state institutions are concerned. The interest arising from 
these warrants goes into the temporary school fund, and is distributed 
again to the taxpayers through the school fund apportionment. The 
Treasurer very justly remarks that a thorough revision of the revenue 
laws should be made, or an amendment authorizing a levy of seven (7) 
mills for the general fund Instead of five (5), since the present levy does 
not keep up with the appropriations, thereby increasing, rather than reducing, 
our floating indebtedness. To my mind a just assessment is 
much more preferable than an increased levy. Our present levy of five 
(6) mills would be all sufficient if our assessment was what it should 
be. The state's educational funds are Invested in the securities designated 
by the Constitution to the amount of $4,365,544.63. Each year 
finds it more difficult to secure Investment for these funds in the securities 
required by the Constitution. The Constitution thould be amended 
allowing a larger Mope for investment of the state's educational funds.</seg> 








            <seg id="p005">
« 

s 


I eoacur In the recommendation of the Treasurer, reducing the Interest 
upon state warrants to three (3) per cent. This will enable the Treasurer 
to secure practically all of these warrants for the school fund 
Investment. The present condition of the state's finances, as compared 
with even so recent a date as four years ago, must be a source of congratulation 
to the citizens of Nebraska. Should this condition continue, 
your best euorts must be used and your wisdom devise ways and means 



to keep the appropriates within the limit of the levy permitted by law. 


ELECTION OF UNITED STATES SENATORS. 

One of the most important duties which you have to perforn- is the 
election of two senators to represent Nebraska in the Senate of the 
United States. The experience of our own state, as well as that of other 
states, in times past, recalls to us the difficulty attending this duty. Sectionalism, 
individual preferences, business Interests, and many other 
factors enter into this problem. The selection of senators would be much 
simplified, and those chosen to that high office more representative, if the 
people themselves chose them by direct vote. The time of the legislature, 
which is really too short for the careful consideration of legislation, is 
taken up and the minds of the members distracted with the too often long 
drawn out struggles in the election of United States senators. Grave 
suspicions are aroused in the minds of the people that money exercises 
undue influence in these elections. Illy considered legislation is placed 
upon the statute books. All these grave evils would be eliminated by 
direct election by popular vote. 




I would recommend that you memorialize Congress to submit a constitutional 
amendment providing for the election of senators by direct 
vote of the people. The scandals which have occurred In other stales 
wherein bribery has been openly charged, and in some instances proven, 
while in many cases fully established In the public mind, have fortunately 
in times past been avoided In our state. Older states have very keenly 
felt the necessity of a change in the manner of election of United States 
senators. A number of states have passed resolutions upon this subject 
by their legislatures. The legislature of the state of Pennsylvania, at its 
last session, passed the following resolution without a dissenting vote: 

"Whereas, A large number of state legislatures have at various times 
adopted memorials and resolutions in favor of election of United States 
senators by popular vote; and 

"Whereas, The National House of Representatives has on four separate 
occasions, within recent years, adopted resolutions In favor of this proposed 
change in the method of electing United States senators, which 
were not adopted by the Senate; and 

"Whereas, Article V of the Constitution of the United States provides 
that Congress, on the application of the legislatures of two-thirds of the 
several states, shall call a convention for proposing amendments, and 
bells-ring there Is a general desire upon the part of the cltixens of the </seg>







            <seg id="p006">
4 




state of Pennsylvania that the United States senators should be elected by 
a direct vote of the people; therefore be It 

"Resolved (if the Senate concur), that the legislature of the state of 
Pennsylvania favors the adoption of an amendment to the Constitution 
which snail provide for the election of United States senators by popular 
vote, and joins with other states of the Union in respectfully requesting 
that a convention be called for the purpose of proposing an amendment to 
the Constitution of the United States, as provided for in Article V of the 
said Constitution, which amendment shall provide for a change in the 
present method of electing United States senators, so that they can be 
chosen in each state by a direct vote of the people. 

"Resolved, that a copy of thLs Joint Resolution and application to Congress 
for the calling of a convention be sent to the secretary of state 
of each of the United States, and that a similar copy be sent to the 
President of the United States Senate and the Speaker of the House of 
Representatives." 

I would earnestly recommend the passage of like resolutions by your 
honorable ~ody. 

STATE OFFICERS AXD INSTITUTIONS. 

The state officers and the heads of the various public institutions have 
presented full and exhaustive reports of the business management of the 
state and the needs of the departments for the next biennium. These 
reports show the great care and business ability with which the affairs 
of the state have been managed, and their recommendations should receive 
a careful consideration from you. 

For your guidance in making appropriations for the next biennium 
for the several Institutions of the state, I have had prepared and herewith 
submit a table showing the exact cost of maintenance of each institution 
in the state for the past nine years. A careful scrutiny of this table 
would be a correct guide in making future appropriations. I do not 
deem it necessary to burden you with a review of the work done at each of 
these public institutions, but take pleasure in saying that their reports, 
to which I refer you, show conscientious regard for duty. A reference 
to the table, which I submit, will show you the commendable economy 
with which they have been managed. In showing this economical business 
management I desire to call your attention to the fact that, notwithstanding 
the increase in prices of almost all needed supplies for the 
maintenance of these institutions, brought about by trusts and combinations, 
the per capita cost has largely decreased. In 1892 the per capita 
cost in all of our state institutions was $242.61, while in 1899 it was but 
$160.27. Such a showing is certainly the best evidence of the careful 
business methods applied by those having in charge our state institutions. 

I commend this table to your careful scrutiny: </seg>



            <seg id="p007">6 







I 
o « *r 
a • 2 2 
M 3 « &lt; 
= z - _: 
m 
to 

2 

_¦ 
&lt; 

• — ixtiJ-r^t-cScc 

• 00 sC ™ sO C~ QD •*" 

* z 
ho 

u 

• x ¦«&lt; is -&gt;n » x r: 

:S222S8a5 

as 
Is 

is I 
R a 
w 

. . . t- ¦* as ¦*! a 
• * • IO 0? O3 C-l -^ d 
: : ig 1 ""®'* 

;8 :SS3SSS 
• X t*~ c~ 3 
¦ —. . **5 « CO 
:• : o 

¦ 
\ 
p 
E 
&lt; 

Si 

• * • f-l 1-H T-) 

is 
&gt; w 
S z 
5 
?; « 

q 
M 
Q 
g 
i 

is 
£ h 
S 

H 

i- t- ¦_ c i-~ — — — 36 

t™ w O iC O O O O 

u 

£• 35 ¦* O -* »-*#-&lt; 

saxvresi 

SCO 55 OS O *-^ *3 'fl 
2 ¦?! *c c^ ** i5 ?J to 
t^ iO \zt *.• *r* 

it © QC O »"^ ""^ O »fl 
™ ™ C3 -^ n w C3 C3 CQ 

M 
s 
M 

¦ H C p? C t» a ot 

:SSSSS3SS 

SSAOMK3 

S33I4JO 

¦ i* i: in o i* li l 1 ; o 

C 
tf Z 

ci t. Si o- oE ci 3; 5s s 
CC CO QC 3D 00 3D 00 X ji 
OjuupOOOCO 

UVi&gt;uOOOOO 
QQCQZZZZZ 

O </seg>
            <seg id="p008">
I 

o 

•OHM 'SONUSVH 

;aHN 'sioasn 

KflTASV 

asvsxi noa 

bkvsni navxaDKi 

ivxidSOH vasvMsa.s: 





o 





g 

1 « 9 o 
Pi O a 
w c a &lt; 
fi 55 B. 3 
« W PC 
I 

;S3SSSSJ:S 

: &gt;&gt; 
- -^ 

| 
a 
H 
2« 
is 
z z 
m H 
18 
to z 
&gt; « 
11 
s « 
5§S 

¦&lt; 

si 

jjg2Se5RS?SS 

Ha 
¦ 

: : igggggS 
• • • g g i-H ¦« » O5 

* • * S ¦* i-t pi S m 

I 
X 
0 
X 
- 
- 

-5 

I 
B 
Q 
I 
C 
B 
s 

a 
* w 
2 " 
3 &lt; 
55 5 
x 2 
o 

&lt;s 

IE 
O 

§!2 2 98 S S! Zi ° £? 
¥*^q QD p^» 

ss 
0 
a. 
H 
&gt; 

SSAOldKH 

:8838S?S!S5 

•rt^HrtrtHHH 

H ¦&lt; 
O 03 
|° 
9 
1 
I 

saaudo I 

II 

GC 00 55 30 30 30 00 30 5^ 
vvuSooooo 
QQQQZ2ZZZ 

cc cc oo ro ft ft rt cc cc 
o d u (j &gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;' 
OOUUOOOOO 

••«•¦*¦••«&lt;•»¦»•«&lt;*&lt; 

o 

I 

I 

-aaN 'sioiHos 

•shn 'aNvnsi aKviio 

HKVSNI 

anv ,s«Hiaios 

HHi HOi 1V1MSOB </seg>






            <seg id="p009">7 




t"* o o 3! ?5 
m r * 4 QQ 2 V 
g» &lt;— c?5« to 

: j : tSSSSae:? 
• • • . g^ Qp t? CO 
: : : :gS«s3 

• • • jjj«o»aoo» 

• • • . 1-4 (JO 
• • • . *¦* T^ 
: ! i I* 

:83e28S=538 
• JS33 S.-ic5i3 

: : : :g28 
CO 

1^5 QO Q5 C^ ffi CO 
co t"~ Ji cjj 

t^4^ OD r^* 

*^ CD Cl A Cl CD 
Soft PQ Tn CO 09 
CC CO CO 74 CO CO 

3SSS5S 

gjssgggagg 

as •• io is •-&lt; m 

jssssssss 

««««n« 

'¦cveicimmmmm 

m .S3S88 
rzzzzz. 

ifOUVOOOOO 
::aazzzzz 

•a&amp;n 'AiiD vxsvtishk 

SItOH 

OMTIS 
8HX HOJ HXQXUSKl 

,t»nm any .snaiaios </seg>





            <seg id="p010">
8 



\ 

o 
M 

ass 
&gt; &lt; s * 
2 5 § 2 
« a a 5 
- / - - 
p « &lt; 
1 

i 

:S5$328SS 
* SS ® 9 S3 55 

:85^SSS :l 
§100900000 • 
£2£S3 : 
• S * 

j 

go 
2 « 
gS 
S E 
si 
&gt;« 
«"* 
*g 
o § 
22 
P 
3 

B 
o 
i- 
&lt; 
I 
c 

Q 
K 
c 
z 
a 
a 

a m 

s 
Is 
I 

g B. 
•¦3 

p. «: 
u 

8 u 

5S52228Sg 
O^ O^ 00 GO t^ Cp 

¦g O fHlHIO 

j : :SS :S8S 
• • ¦ Ti tD ¦ &lt;g&gt; lp i— I 
: : :• : •* </seg>
            <seg id="p011">
: : :g :-$S 
: : : m : * 

8S j :ti ;8S ; 

SS j :S ;SS j 
gg : :S i-'S : 
t» : : : - 1 : 

S-* t- n » •* oo tr • 

* CO 85 06 CO w r^ ¦ ¦ 
'0&gt;9OB«O • ¦ 
i*^" : ! 

QD »2 00 00 w^ 

S38Sg8SSi2 : 
Cj M »-t rH rH i-H i-t iH • 

SSXVKKI §§S§2rtrtrt§ 

CO t** O CO 00 O • 

d 
I 

saAoiina 

:§SSSSS5SS 

;«?3S858S | 

S33HJ0 | 

•COCOCOCOCOCO^'^' 

¦co co co co co oo oo * 

|l 
*8 </seg>

            <seg id="p012">cococ3C5coc'5c'5S5fl5 
iiiiiiiii 
Daaazzzzz 

CQCOZZZZZ 

w 
as 

s 

§ 

¦aaK 'yhvko 

arena auv avna 

aa.M 'aorsxvas 
HXflOA 
aaatnH hihhhj «oa 
XXOXU6NI YISYIBlii 

BHi HOi HinjJXSKJ 






: : :S?8 : :££ 
: : :Sf : :Bg 
: : :|s : I-" 0 * 

' H c?9B56 rt fi9Q 
¦aoaS^c^Oi-"©*-* 

; : |M i jss 
: : i*^ : : rt 

:ggSS353S 

:3 :2 : : :KS 
¦ CO * • 9 

* * 00 CD 05 9 08 CC 

¦ So ] aB • j -SS 
• t- •« : • 'ass 
• . • • • co co 

c ?i ti r w t- 1' » 

-HiHo5oi-*o5t-t-?o 
W rH 

rt rt rt 

nr IHH-i 

SSSSS^SSS 

-asaaa -ecs 

• IO 50 5O 5= iO ¦• ¦* -W 

• CO CO CO CO *COCO 

;nW-**««MN 

COCOCOCO^'COO^COO? 
uvaiCooooo 
QQQQZZ2Z2 

CO CC CO CO v3 vi CO A A 
J«|Siooooo 
caaszzzzz 

•«XM 'iTIODNn 

•hhn 'a-a.oj.im 

ssaia.-caiaH 

BKOH 

XHX HOd HKOH 

iTPusaatn YxsvsaaM 











i 

is \nnn 
:• : 

m 
pi 
0) 

| 

:83SS!SS35S 

CO 2 
•&lt; 2 
&gt; « 
fa 0? 

E 
j 
¦&lt; 
g 
| 

1,1 
II 
a a 

18 
5 j 
i 
I 8 

•&lt; 
g 5 

II 

8 j ;S2SSS j 

9 i is25S88 j 

jg :888822 
• •-I 'oisnoar- 

:S8S8 ;88 : 
¦ cot&lt;tQ • t-o ¦ 
¦ *O tO P* w • '"" t m • 
¦ t*35n« ¦ oo fH ¦ 
«¦" j I 

:SS2« :° CT : 
:1 : : 

jssssssss 

2 u 

S«C t- &lt;N 1O O d -H U5 
rH CO CN CO CO &gt;* O QD "^ 
o5 S5 55 

¦¦""Ji §S§§§I§S§ 

:PSgS8S?8S 

o 
I 

SSAOIdKH 

isassssss 

¦ c-icoaoaoaoaoeo 

SHDMdO | 

¦CiOOlOt-OCt- 

•lC5Dt0 0 40lO&gt;OlO 

U W 

ll 

QQQQZZZZZ 

SSSS8SS88 

M 
3 

o 

i 

i 

aaN 'AHNTivax 
snaaNHdio aiLKHAnl 
noa ioohos 
avmxsaoni Bxvxs 

¦SHN 'VABNBO 
alUZBAOl HOJ 1OOH3S 
TyraxsQam ,rmo </seg>






            <seg id="p013">11 



















1 
w4 

















i . ¦« Is 


_:* «S "ja 5a-g 
Iliff 11 a -sS § f 
g| as Sa5 SS|-o . 
S|f:SgsS--§sa 















3 ill * 
It 11 ill § -i ! 
2 O O o "H e&gt;5 oo t- &lt;m" » ¦ 
] 

• | ¦ 
¦ • ¦ i-c 2J «o t- e* it 

: : :„ rt 

:8S :258gg 
¦Hg • Q tQ op yi 
• ODCQ ¦ t™ N QD 

• io 3S ¦ 25 S *-* ¦* S 
:$ rt : 

• 00 QO W ffi t^ C*5 *^ 

' ; jg'-''- 1 '-' •-• 

§^*^ US Cq 00 
flafiaast 
v3 Vw v3 vT v* V s ! 

: : :'=SSs§SSS 

• • ¦ IM « C» « H 7i 

coccccccc'5c'5c' l 5s'5c'5 
QQQQZZZZZ 

HHK 'K1ODKH 

AVTIXMaXLtUM </seg>






            <seg id="p014">12 













THK LABOB BUSEAU. 

The work done by the Labor Bureau for the past biennium as shown 
by the report of that department, is of great value to the labor interests 
of the state. The compilation of labor and industrial statistics, the unique 
way of showing by a map of the counties the surplus product shipment 
and the incomes to the state therefrom certainly afforu one of the very 
best means of placing Nebraska and her resources before home seekers. 
The money expended in the work of the Labor Bureau has certainly been 
a very profitable investment for the state. 

I commend to your attention the recommendations of the Deputy Labor 
Commissioner as embodying ideas which it would be wise for you to 
incorporate, witn the duties of the department. There seems to have 
been a disposition upon the part of former legislatures to, give this department 
meager support. His Excellency, Governor Crounse, at the close 
of his term, called attention to the needs of this department with recommendations 
of either more liberal appropriation or the abolishment of the 
bureau. I would certainly deem it unwise to abolish this department. 
The enlargement of its scope with commensurate means to conduct it, 
it seems to me, would display much more wisdom upon the part of your 
honorable body. 

RELIEF FOB THE SUPREME COURT. 

There are now pending in the Supreme Court of our state seventeen 
hundred and nine cases, and notwithstanding the best efforts of the 
Court, the number constantly increases rather than decreases. If no new 
cases should be filed and the Court should make the same progress in 
adjudication they have been able to make in the past, it would require 
more than three years to clear the court docket. A3 a matter of fact, 
under these conditions, the Supreme Court is regarded as the tomb in 
which lie buried the hopes of litigants, awaiting a very indefinite resurrection. 
An increase in the number of judges at once suggests itself as 
the most rational way with which to meet this difficulty. No one can 
dispute that an early determination of honest litigation is desirable. 
If the number of judges were increased the work of the court could be 
brought forward and litigants could have their suits disposed of promptly. 
The condition which now exists is not new. As far back as 1893 there 
were 1,285 cases pending. 

The legislature of 1893 created a Supreme Court Commission, permitting 
the supreme judges to select three commissioners, taking effect March, 
1893. This was intended as a temporary relief to the Court, and was to 
continue for the term of three years. The legislature of 1895 extended 
the term an additional three years, so that it would cease by limitation 
March, 1899. At that time it ceased to exist, and after its six years work 
there were pending before the court, 1,434 cases, or an increase of 49 
oases, showing that with the assistance of the commission the court had </seg>






            <seg id="p015">13 


kept almost even In its work, adjudicating nearly as many eases as wera 
filed. 


The Constitution of the state determines the number of Supreme 
Judges, so that that number must remain as at present until the Constitution 
shall be amended increasing the number. To my mind it seems 
desirable that a constitutional amendment should be submitted to the 
electors increasing the number of supreme Judges to at least five. Pending 
the time, however, when such amendment shall have been adopted and be 

effective, I would suggest that your honorable body empower the Supreme 
Court 10 call to its aid any number of district judges in the state, not less 
than ten. With this assistance the court would be enabled to clear the 
docket in a reasonable time, and, having it once clear, and with an Increase 
in the number of judges, it would be enabled to keep it so. At present 


many of the district judges in the state are not occupied to exceed onehalf 
of their time. Their entire time belongs to the state. I can see 


nothing unreasonable in asking that their unoccupied time be used by 
the state In relief of the Supreme Court. 


NEBRASKA NATIONAL Ot'ARD. 


The Nebraska National Guard was wholly disorganized by the Spanish- 
American war. When I came into office the Second Nebraska Volunteer 
Regiment, which was largely made up of the Second Nebraska National 
Guard, had recently been mustered out of the service of the United 
States and was being reorganized. The reorganization was continued 
under my administration as rapidly as possible. When the First Nebraska 
Volunteers, most of the members of which had formerly belonged 
to the National Guard, returned from the Philippines and were mustered 
out of the service of the United States, immediately the work of reorganization 
of the First Regiment, N. N. G., was taken up. In the reorganization 
of this regiment preference was given, urst. to members of 
the First Nebraska Volunteers; second, to members of Second and Third 
Nebraska Volunteers, and then to former members of the Nebraska 
National Guard. In this way quite a large percentage of the members 
of the present Nebraska National Guard is composed of men who saw 
service in the Spanish-American war. The Guard as now constituted 
consists of two regiments of infantry, a troop of cavalry, and a battery 
of artillery. It is a body of men of which the state may justly feel 
proud. It has been my endeavor to make the Guard as efficient as possible, 
and I am sure there never was a time when the Nebraska National 
Guard was as well prepared for emergency as now. If every state was as 
well provided in proportion to its population, with a national guard as 
efficient as Nebraska, the general government could be furnished on short 
notice with a splendid army should occasion require. The state dm 
not afford to treat her Nebraska Guard niggardly. I approve of the 
estimate made by the Adjutant General for the next biennium, and recommend 
appropriations accordingly. . </seg>





            <seg id="p016">
14 



i 


The legislature at Its last session passed a resolution authorizing th« 

Governor to procure medals for the volunteer soldiers of our state who 
gave their services in the Spanish-American war. No appropriation was 
provided to carry out the provisions of the resolution. However, I authorized 
the Adjutant General to make investigation as to cost of such 


badges, and he has embodied in his report to me the results of his in- 


vestigation, the recommendations of which I fully approve. Such a testi- 

monial would be a fitting tribute from the state as showing, in a small 


degree, the esteem in which our boys are held by the state. I would recom- 

mend an appropriation in accord with the estimate of the Adjutant 
General. 

RETURN Or FIRST NEBRASKA VOLUNTEERS. 

When our gallant First Nebraska Regiment returned from the Philippines 
and arrived in San Francisco, I determined, if possible, that its 
members should be returned to their homes without cost to them. I 
thought this would be a fitting tribute to them, as showing the appreciation 
of our state for their bravery and devotion to solaier duty. I first 
endeavored to get special rates from the railway lines. This I was utterly 
unable to do. I then endeavored to get the railway companies to bring 
the regiment home and file their bill with the Auditor ls a claim against 
the state, to be paid by your honorable body. They refused to do this. 
I then endeavored to secure a loan from the banking interests of the state. 
Falling in this, I appealed to the generous patriotic people of Nebraska 
to advance sufficient funds. The appeal met with loyal response. More 
than enough was sent in, and the regiment received a welcome befitting 
the esteem in which it was held by our people. 

The amounts contributed are a loan to the state of Nebraska, and provisions 
for its payment should be made by you in an early appropriation. 
The amount contributed was $40,342.75. Of this $36,315.45 was required 
to pay the expenses of the return of the regiment. Of the excess $3,971.00 
was returned to individual donors. The list of those who subscribed to 
this fund is a part of the files of the executive office. 

REVENUE AXD TAXATION. 

The inequalities in our revenue system must be apparent to any one 
who has examined it. A general revision of the entire law upon the subject 
is necessary. Numerous attempts have been made in the past to accomplish 
such revision, but the short time occupied in a legislative session, the vast 
amount of work to be accomplished, and the magnitude and difficulty 
of the task have prevented its consummation. It seems to me that a 
competent commission authorized to procure the revenue laws of the 
different states in the Union, and from them formulate for our state a 
new revenue law to be submitted for the ratification of the next session 
of the legislature would procure for us a revenue law which would be 
just and equitable. This seems a long Una to await a revision of our rev- </seg>





            <seg id="p017">
15 








enue system, but past experience has shown us the great difficulty attending 
the task, and it seems to me a more careful and satisfactory revision 
- - ¦ * ¦ U.— ¦ ¦ A.W _ . il J _» *_ _al *.__» .1 •_ _»«___ 

could be secured by the method above Indicated than in any other way. 

RAXLWAT REGULATIONS. 

The question of railway regulation is one that has occupied the attention 
of the legislators in our state probably more than any other. As 


early as 1876 this was a prominent issue upon which members of the 
legislature were elected. The people demanded relief from what they 
thought oppressive rates of freight and passenger tariff. Each succeeding 
legislature adjourned without any measure being passed until 1885 whan 
the members elected almost entirely, upon this issue, made the most determined 
effort to redeem pre-election pledges. The first maximum rat* 
bill was prepared and strenuous efforts made to incorporate It into the 
la ire of our state. This measure met with defeat, but a compromise measure 
was at last agreed upon by which Nebraska had her first railway 
commission established. It was a makeshift to avoid the provisions of the 
Constitution, and a sop thrown out to quiet the demands of the people. 
As a member of the legislature of 1885 I voted against the measure, giving 
th« following as my reason: 

'This olll does not accomplish what the people of Neuraska have demande 
— a rate of transportation. If this commission was clothed with 
moie power man to merely draw a salary, if it could even sit as an advisory 
board in the matter of rates upon the railway company's own 
schedules, and, as the representatives' of the people, have a voice in determining 
what would be Just rates of charges for transportation, I could 
support the measure; but I do not think the state at this time demands 
the creation of a new office, nor do I think the treasury so over crowded 
with funds that we need an ornamental board of officials whose only duty 
would be to relieve the railway corporations of this state of some of the 
responsibility which now rests upon them, and the state treasury of cash. 
Believing the bill to be detrimental to the best interests of the people, 
I vote NO." 

Two years' trial of the law proved the correctness of my reasoning, 
since tl e next legislature passed, or supposed it passed, the commission 
law, which has been upon our statute books until very recently, when onr 
Supreme Court decided the law null and void. It passed away without a 
regret, as I think, from any one. It was never satisfactory either to the 
railway companies or the people. The endeavor to enforce its provisions 
resulted in no appreciable advantage to the people of the state, while the 
constant opposition upon the part of the railway companies showed their 
lack of appreciation of any advantage it might be to them. The maximum 
rate law is entirely inoperative, being tied np In the courts, with it* 
final determination very questionable, and, besides, should it be declared 
valid, Its enforcement is made the duty of the Board of Transportation. 
The law creating this Board has just been declared unconstitutional, se </seg>



            <seg id="p018">
16 


that we are really to-day without any railway regulation In this state. 
The ultimate and, aa I believe, the only correct solution of the transportation 
problem, will be found in government ownership. When the general 
government owns and operates the means of public transportation and 
communication, neither unjust tariff rates, destructive discriminations 
between individuals or localities, nor any other form of injustice which 
now prevails in the matter of transportation, will continue. The railways 
will be public highways for the benefit of Bll the people. But under 
present conditions our state Constitution provides that it is your duty 
to provide adequate laws for the regulation of freight and passenger 
charges. I would favor an elective commission with plenary powers. 




A commission chosen by direct vote of the people would feel its responsibility 
to the people, and would more likely mete out justice between 
the corporations and the people. But the election of such commission 
would require an amendment to our state Constitution. 

I would recommend the submission to the electors an amendment to 
our Constitution providing for the election of a railway commission. 
Pending the time when such amendment could be ratified by the voters of 
the state, I would recommend the enactment by your honorable boay of a 
maximum rate upon the commodities in car load lots, such as salt, 
coal, grain, live stock, and lumber. It seems to me at this time that these 
two measures are all that can be done in the matter of regulation of 
transportation charges. 

run food law. 

The legislature at its last session enacted a law known as the pure food 
law, designating the Governor of the State, Food Commissioner, with 
authority to appoint a deputy food commissioner. Acting under this law 
I appointed Mr. F. B. Hibbard, of Irvington, Deputy Food Commissioner, 
who proceeded to organize the department and enforce the provisions of 
the act. The law provided for the collection of fees and licenses from 
certain lines' of business, and the expenses of the department to be paid 
out of such collection. When the salary vouchers of the deputy and 
clerk of the department were presented, they were refused by the Auditor 
upon the ground that no appropriation, as provided by the Constitution, 
had been made by the legislature. The case having been submitted to the 
Supreme Court, that tribunal decided that the legislature had failed to 
make specific appropriation, consequently the salaries could not be paid. 
As a result the work of the department has been much hampered. The 
law is one which met with general favor with the people and was especially 
appreciated and desired by the dairy interests of the state. Any one 
well informed fully appreciates the necessity of a Judicious pure food law 
for the state. Many of our sister states have excellent food laws which 
are well enforced. If we would prevent Nebraska from becoming the 
dumping ground of many fraudulent compounds as food for man and </seg>









            <seg id="p019">
17 




beast, proper legislation, similar in kind to oar sister states, must be 
provided which will protect our people from adulterated foods of all kinds. 


I would recommend an Increase in the scope of the present law, extending 
to the suppression of the manufacture and sale of all kinds of adulterated 
food products within the state. There has been collected in fees 
and licenses by the department the sum of $3,286, which has all been 
turned into the state treasury. I herewith submit you an itemized statement 
of the expenses of the department. I recommend that an appropriation 
be made to meet these expenses, as contemplated by the law Itself, 
drawn upon the fund, which fees and licenses have produced, now in the 
state treasury. 




LTVI STOCK REGULATIONS. 


During my term of office there have been numerous calis upon this 
department relative to the suppression and control of contagious diseases 
among live stock. That the live stock Industry is of paramount Importance 
in the state all will admit, and it seems to me but good business judgment 


that adequate laws should be made for the protection of this industry 




from the ravages of contagious animal diseases. The laws we now have 
are cumbersome, and if enforced, with sufficient appropriation to make 
them effective, would prove a great burden upon the tax-payers of the 
state. For this reason no appropriation for live stock protection was made 
by the last session of the legislature. 

I trust to your wisdom to frame an adequate law upon this subject. 


It seems to me one providing for a competent veterinarian, whose duty 


it should be to determine the nature of disease and whether quarantine 
regulations were necessary, would be ample. This being determined, the 
law should place the enforcement of the regulations prescribed by the 
veterinarian in the hands of the sheriff of the county wherein the disease 
is prevalent, or some other peace officer. A law so framed would give 
ample protection against the spread of contagious diseases among live 
stock, would afford the owners whose animals might be affected medical 
advice free of cost, and be of little or no burden to the general public 

The law as now constituted provides that animals with contagious diseases 
may be killed by the agent of the state, and the value of animals 
so killed paid to the owners of such animals. This would many times be 
the source of imposition upon the state, and even though honestly administered 
would entail a larger expense than the state could afford to pay. 
I would recommend, therefore, the repeal of the present law and the enactment 
of a law providing for a state veterinarian, with power to recom- 


mend quarantine regulations when in his judgment occasion demanded, 
and directing the proper officer to enforce his recommendations. 

STATE BOAKD OF AGRICULTURE. 

The State Board 6t Agriculture is deserving of most liberal treatment 
at your hands. No one power has done more for the advancement of the </seg>









            <seg id="p020">

18 




Interests of the state. The work the Board has done in ad- 

the state and thereby Inducing Immigration has been of great 

The only aid the Board has received from the state has been a 

appropriation of $4,000, conditioned that the entire amount should 
to pay premiums at a state fair held by the Board. The Board 

has been considered a state institution under the direction of law, and 
yet has been compelled to improvise whatever funds were necessary to 
carry on its work. For twelve years past the state has given the State 
Board of Agriculture warrants to the amount of $24,000, the entire amount 
to be used only as premiums upon exhibits at State Pairs. During that 
same time the State Board has paid for the same purpose $156,000, and 
for the benefit of the state altogether, over and above state aid, tfie 
total turn of $396,275.17. It has published statistics and reports of great 
value. It has maintained each year an exposition of the products and 
industries of the state. The last session of the legislature established a 
permanent home for the Board at the capital city. 

I would therefore recommend that the state provide suitable grounds and 
buildings for state fair purposes and annual appropriation sufficient to at 
least pay the expenses for the maintenance of the State Board, thereby 
allowing the revenue arising from the annual state fairs to be used for 
the collection of statistics and Information, and the distribution of the 
same, and the increase in payment of premiums. Such an appropriation 
should be made as would leave the board unhampered in its work, and 
enable it to accomplish still better results for the interests of the agriculture 
of the state than it has in the past 

CONVICT LABOR. 

The problem of employment for convicts in our state penitentiary Is 
one which should receive your careful consideration. Humanity demands 
that those who are incarcerated in state prisons should be kept busj. 
Justice to honest labor forbids that the work of convicts should be 
brought into competition with its effort. The contract system employed in 
so many states, whereby prison-made goods are thrown upon the market 
in direct competition with the goods of free labor, is manifestly unjust 
and unfair to the honest workman. He is not only taxed to support the 
criminal In the penitentiary, but must sell his labor for unremunerative 
prices to enable him to compete with the criminal labor. 

It seems to me it should be the policy of our state, so far as we may be 
able, to prevent this competition by furnishing employment to convicts 
which in no way Interferes with honest labor. The manufacture of goods 
needed by the state for the wards of the state In our various eleemosynary 
institutions would be legitimate work for convicts. A few persons have 
been employed in the manufacture of shoes for the prison and also for 
the asylums for the insane. The work done was satisfactory and paid a 
larger return than any received upon contract The employment of a 
put of the prisoners during the past season In the growing of sugar beets </seg>









            <seg id="p021">
19 

has proven a financial success. There were grown thirty 

beets during the last season. Counting convict labor at fifty 
day, the same as received on contract and all other expenses, a 
was had of $363.71. This ia certainly a good showing for first ei 
and demonstrates the practicability of employing convict labor e: 

honorable body 
abandonment of 

in the growing of sugar beets. I certainly think your 


should pass such laws as would look toward the final 

prison contracts, and the employment of state prisoners upon such work 
as will most nearly render the prison self-supporting and at the same 
time interfere in the least degree with free labor. 

STATE NORMAL SCHOOL. 


The largely increased attendance at the State Normal School makes 
it imperative that some increase in the facilities should be provided by 
you. The assembly room there has a capacity for seating 500. The atr 
tendance during the term last passed was far in excess of that number, 
with the probability of yet further increase during the present term. 
There has been constantly recurring before each legislature for a number 
of years past, the question of building additional normal schools In the 
state. I neeu not point out to you that the creation of an additional 
school or schools would create additional expense for the management 
of the same. Each school would require officers and conveniences for the 
conduct of the business of the school. These are practically the same for 
either a large or small school. To create new schools would require a 
duplication of these necessities, and a corresponding increase in outlay. 
An increase in library facilities, laboratory facilities, and other necessities 
of a school already equipped would be trivial as compared with the building 
and equipment of an entire new school. The location of our present 
normal school may not be as central as would be most convenient, but 
having already made the great outlay which has been made in the building 
and equipment of the State Normal School, it is better business judgment 
to afford ample facilities there than to attempt to build up schools in 
other localities. One great normal school, like one great university. Is 
better for the educational interests of the state than two or more smaller 
institutions. An appropriation for the building of a new assembly room 
and a library building to adequately and properly care for the library of 
fifteen thousand volumes now owned by the state would afford ample 
normal school facilities for a number of years to come, and would be the 
means of building up a normal-school which would be a source of pardonable 
pride to our state. The expenditure necessary to afford these needed 
facilities ac the present school would be small indeed compared with th« 
cost of building and equipping an entirely new normal school. 


BOARD OF HEALTH. 


At the last session of the legislature a special bill was passed giving 
Bie State Board of Health sanitary powers to act in the presence ot </seg>






            <seg id="p022">
20 




epidemic, and made an appropriation of $1,500 to meet the 
The constant presence of smallpox In the state and the numer- 

i calls for an expert Inspector to order proper measures of quarantine 
lausted the appropriation some months ago. This appropriation was 

used only In the cases of smallpox. Provisions should be made to extend 
the work of a sanitary inspection to other contagious diseases, such as 
diphtheria, scarlet fever, etc., by increased appropriation, to be at the 

disposal of the State Board of Health. The law empowering the State 

Board of Health to act is sufficient, but should nave an appropriation 
such as would enable the board to do effective work. 

POWER TO COMPROMISE CLAIMS. 


I called the attention of the last legislature in a special message to the 
advisability of some legislation which would authorize the settlement of 
claims which the state might have against individuals wherein disputes 
had arisen. I suggested that it would be a good business proposition 
should pow^r be conferred by the legislature to compromise proper cases. 

In the conduct of the state's business, disputes have not infrequently 
arisen with regard to claims asserted by the state against indiriduals 
entering into contractural relations with it. In some cases the financial 
inability of the individual to meet the whole demand, and, in others, 
doubts existing as to the legality of the state's demand have delayed the 
state in obtaining satisfaction, and have resulted in protracted and expensive 
litigation. While ample provision has been made by the. law 

for civil suits between the state* and individuals, there Is no provision 
whereby any of the state officers are authorized to make compromises 
of doubtful claims. The result is that the state must in all instances 
resort to litigation and continue such litigation to a determination without 
regard to the prudence of such procedure, and while encouraging the 
avoidance of litigation between citizens is obliged itself to pursue a contrary 
policy. 

I would recommend to your careful consideration the propriety of the 
adoption of a measure whereby, in proper cases, compromises of disputed 
demands may be effected, and the state thus permitted to exercise in its 
financial transactions with the same prudence and business judgment which 
U permitted and encouraged in individuals. 

THE PAX-AMERICAN EXPOSITION. 

At the request of the organizers of this exposition I appointed two vicepresidents 
to represent Nebraska's intertest. Since their appointment 
the exposition has grown In magnitude and Importance until at this time 
there is little doubt but that it will be the largest ever held in America, 
with the single exception of the World's Columbian Exposition, at Chicago. 
Its location at Buffalo, New York, seems to me advantageous for the presentation 
of Nebraska products and Industries. The Trans-Mississippi 
Exposition, at Omaha, was really the first opportunity the people of the </seg>








            <seg id="p023">
21 


East had of becoming acquainted with Nebraska. More people from 
East will probably attend the Pan-American than were at the Trans-1 
sissippi, and so will afford Nebraska an opportunity to make known 
resources and possibilities to a large number of people who may be indu 
to become citizens. A reasonable appropriation for the proper prese: 
tion of Nebraska's resources at the Pan-American Exposition would 
money well invested. 


CONSTITUTIONAL CONVENTION. 


As Indicated in what has gone before in this message, there are In 
opinion a number of amendments needed to our state Constitution. ' 
experience we have had in times past with constitutional amendmi 
has not been satisfactory. It seems to me you should make provlsl 
for the calling of a constitutional convention to formulate for our si 
a constitution fitted to our present development, and making provii 
for our future growth. Should this oe done, many of the problems wl 
now present themselves would be solved. 


EXECUTIVE MANSION. 


The legislature at its last session made appropriation for the purchase of 
an executive mansion, and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, is 
accord with that provision, secured a very desirable property for that 
purpose. No provision was made, however, for the renewal of furnishing 
and the care and maintenance of such residence. The care of a public 
residence entails a heavy expense upon the Governor. It seems to me no 
good reason can be given for requiring the Governor to maintain a mansion 
which is very largely for public benefit at his own expense. The state 
should take care of the state's property. For this reason I would recommend 
that you make adequate provision for the care and maintenance of 
the Governor's mansion and grounds. Having been the first occupant 
of the mansion, and knowing the burden the care and maintenance of the 
property places upon the Governor, as I go out of office I feel competent 
to make recommendation upon this matter without being subject to criti- 


cism of personal interest. 

Retiring from the highest office in the gift of the people of our state, 
I congratulate you as the chosen representatives of the most progressive 
and best educated constituency In our country. I congratulate you upon 
the splendid financial condition of our state. The past biennium has 
witnessed the payment of our entire bonded indebtedness. It has witnessed 
the reduction of the rate of interest upon our floating indebtedness to four 
per cent, and our state warrants at that low rate of Interest selling at a 
premium of one per cent, showing the confidence of our own people, as well 
as capitalists of other states, in the ability of our state to pay its obligations 
and the integrity of the management of our financial affairs. 

I congratulate you upon the economy and business ability with i 
th« public Institutions of our lUU hav« b«en managed during the 
</seg>




            <seg id="p024">
• 







n 

m, m shown in the reports herewith submitted, not less upon the 
it ewe given the unfortunate wards of the state. Our eleemosynary 

tltutlons are the equal of any sister state In the Union. They reflect 
progress and advanced civilization of the state. The demands of civill- 

require the most scrupulous care of those whom misfortune makes 

the wards of the state. Justice to the taxpayers requires this care to be 
given in a way creating as little burden as may be. The requirements 
of both have been fully met during the past blennium. 

I trust that your duties in making new laws and amending old ones, 
and in the repeal of those you deem detrimental or unnecessary, may be 

pleasant and all your work for the good of the people and the advancement 
of the welfare of our state. 

I wish to return my sincere shanks to the people of Nebraska for the 
confidence they reposed In me, and the uniform courtesy always shows 
me and the many kind and complimentary words and letters commendatory 
of my administration received from so many citizens of the state. In all 
my acts I have had beyond all other considerations the welfare and best 
interests of the state. For whatever mistakes I may have made I ask charitable 
leniency. The administration as a whole I submit to the honest 
judgment of an intelligent people. 

(Signed) W. A. POYNTER, 

Governor. 

Executive Chailbir, Lincoln, N«b., January 3, 1901. 
</seg>




. 



<seg id="p025">23 










COMMUTATIONS OP PENITENTIARY SENTENCES GRANTED 

WILLIAM A. POYNTER, GOVERNOR OP NEBRASKA, FROM 

JANUARY 6, 1899, TO JANUARY 3, ltOL 


9-1021. 


George S. Williams, Jefferson county; twelve yean for murder; commuted 
to fire years, on ground of new evidence not obtainable at 
time of trial and would have had strong influence with the Jury, f"4 
failing health of prisoner; recommended by both trial judges, prosecuting 
attorney, ex-sheriff, warden, and prison physician. January 

31, 1899. 


12-3353. 

George Kennedy, Gage county; one year and six months, horse steal- 


ing; commuted to seven months; owing to extreme youth of the 
prisoner (15 years) he had been led into crime by others. It is my 

opinion that he ought to have been sent to the reform school Instead 


of the penitentiary. Responsible relatives having agreed to take 
charge of the boy, the sentence was commuted as above. February 

24, 1899. 
19-3118. 

Leonard A. Collins, Cherry county; seven years for burglary; commuted 
to five years; excessive sentence and doubt as to his guilt. 

destitute mother requiring his support; recommended by the trial 
judge. February 28, 1899. 

10-3264. 

Bert White, Kimball county; five years for burglary; commuted to 

one year and four months; recommended by the trial Judge and prosecuting 
attorney. March 2, 1899. 

14-3342. 

Thomas Morris, Douglas county; five years for burglary; commuted 

to one year; recommended by the trial Judge, prosecuting attorney 
and large number of citizens. March 22, 1899. 

6-3215. 

Herman F. Schwaberow, Cherry county; five years for cattle stealing; 
commuted to one year and nine months; new testimony not brought 
out at trial, and supported by affidavit showing a conspiracy which 
resulted in the conviction of the prisoner; recommended by the trial 

Judge, nine members of the jury and a large number of citizens. 
March 22, 1899. 

28-2869. 

Abraham Lauder, Douglas county; fifteen years for assault to rape; 

commuted to tour yean and seven months; recommended by the </seg>



            <seg id="p026">24 







trial judge, prosecuting attorney and large number ol citizens. April 
30, 1899. 

47-3234. 

George B. Henry, York county; two years for forgery; commuted to 
one year, nine months and ten days; on recommendation of the 
warden and certificate of the prison physician that prisoner was 
suffering from cistitis and rheumaloid arthritis, producing con- 

traction of the knee; the sentence was commuted as above. May 17, 
1899. . 

31-2425. 

John B. Kearnes, CaaB county; life sentence for murder; commuted 
to seven years and six months; upon the prison physician's certificate 
that the prisoner was in a dying condition, and that his disease was 

incurable, humanity usually exercised in such cases dictated that the 
prisoner should be sent home to die. May 20, 1899. 

S3- Not delivered at Penitentiary. 

James Phiiamalee, Cedar county; one year in the penitentiary and 
costs of prosecution; alleged crime was committed over a horse trade 
while aa parties concerned were intoxicated. It appeared extremely 
doubtful that crime was intended. Prison sentence is remitted on 
condition that his conduct for one year be exemplary and that cost 
of prosecution are paid. May 20, 1899. Unconditional pardon and 

ulscharge from penitentiary granted and restored to all his civil 
rights, December 18, 1900. 

41-3056. 

Charles Wilson, Douglas county; nine years for burglary; commuted 
to three years and two months; on petition and recommendation 
of the trial Judge and prosecuting attorney, both holding that injustice 
was done the prisoner in view of the facts ueveloped after the 

trial and sentence, and that the sentence was excessive, I commuted 
the sentence as above. May 24, 1899. 

•4-1504. 

Ole Anderson, Brown county; life sentence for murder; commuted to 
fifteen years, one month and eight days; acting under authority of 
Section 569c of the Statutes, and upon petition of a large number of 
citizens and it being represented to me by the warden that the prisoner 
was a fit subject for executive clemency, I commuted his sen- 

tence as above, granting him his freedom July 4, 1899; done July 
S, 1899. 

(6-1653. 

Andrew Jackson, right name Andrew White, Lancaster county; thirty 
years for murder; commuted to seventeen years, five months and 
eleven days; acting under authority of Section 569c of the Statutes, 
and upon the petition of citizens, and it being represented to me by 

U»« warden that the prisoner tw a fit subject (or executive clemency, </seg>


            <seg id="p027">25 








* 



4, 1899; done July 3, 1899. 
77-3394. 


Andrew Harpster, Douglas county, one year for cattle stealing; 
commuted to ten months and three days; on certificate of the prison 
physician that prisoner is badly afflicted with dropsy, and unable 


to outlive his sentence, and on recommendation of the warden the 
sentence was shortened as above. August 29, 1899. 


83-2654. 


Patrick Donovan, Douglas county; fifteen years, assault to commit 
rape; commuted to seven years; doubt as to guilt; recommended by 

the trial judge, ten of the jurors, ex-warden Leidigh and many citizens, 
moved me to shorten the sentence. September 25, 1899. 


106-3447. 


i 

John Cox, Douglas county; four years for burglary; commuted to 
one year, two months and ten days; excessive sentence in light of 


new testimony discovered since trial. Recommended by the trial 
judge, prosecuting witness, and citizens. January 13, 1900. 


1-3251. 


Benjamin D. Mills, Harlan county; five years for embezzlement; 
commuted to two years, seven months and two days; on the petition 
of a large number of G. A. R. Posts of the state, and upon the personal 
solicitation of Ex-Governor J. M. Thayer, and petition of C. H. 
Gere, G. M. Lambertson, M. B. Reese, C. J. Dilworth. T. J. Majors, 
C. M. Morrlll. E. J. Burket, J. B. Strode, J. W. Deweese, G. W. 
Holdrege, W. T. Morian (prosecuting attorney of the case.i. S. H. 


Bunham, Rev. W. M. Hlndman, Rev. L. P. Ludden. Tobias Castor, 
and many other reputable citizens. February 28, 1900. 

114-S5E1. 

H. D. Mitchell, Hall county; one year for burglary; commuted to 
two months and eight days; on the certificate of the prison physician 
that the prisoner was suffering from a severe attack of diabetes 
and not able to live, the sentence was shortened so as to give him 

his liberty March 21, 1900. On the following night death overtook 
him. Done March 21, 1900. 

72-9367. 

Charles D. Tate, Cherry county; two years for selling liquor to 
Indians; commuted to one year, seven months and five days; new 
evidence noi obtainable at time of trial which wou.d have had strong 

bearing in favor of prisoner; recommended by the trial judge, and 
large number of citizens. March 31, 1900. 


68-2849. 

John Gallagher, Sarpy county; fifteen years for shooting to kill; commuted 
to five years; on recommendation of the trial judge, and upon 
Um certificate Of prison physician showing the prisoner'* health tedly </seg>









            <seg id="p028">
26 




impurod, tho sentence waa commuted bo u to rcle&amp;sc him Novcm- 

ber 11, 1900; later, on the 18th day of July, 1900, the prisoner died, 
before his commuted sentence expired. Done July 14, 1900. 


127-3596. 


Charles Barnett, Douglas county; one year for assault to wound; 
conditioned commutation of sentence based on good conduct condi- 


tioned on file; recommended by the trial Judge, prosecuting attorney, 
county officials and reliable citizens. July 18, 1900. 



136-3607. 

Elmer Woodcock, Douglas county; one year for daylight burglary; 
commuted to three months and eighteen days; upon the personal 
request of the trial judge, the petition of eight of the Jurors, sheriff. 


mayor and chief of police of the city of Omaha, and numerous citizens. 
July 28, 1900. 


REMISSION OF FINES AND JAIL SENTENCES GRANTED BY 
WILLIAM A. POYNTER, GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA, FROM 



JANUARY 6, 1899, TO JANUARY 3, 1901. 


38. 

Samuel Lore, Burt county; fined $400.00 and costs of prosecution 
taxed at $67.15 for having intoxicating liquor in his possession, with 
intent to sell without a license; he paid $366.00 of said fine by confinement 
in the county Jan; the unpaid balance of the fine was remitted 
on recommendation of prominent citizens and officials of the 
county. April 18, 1899. 





102. 


J. B. Haines, Knox county; fined to forty days in county jail for assauit 
and battery; twenty days of the fine was remitted on recommendation 
of the trial judge and large number of citizens. November 
29, 1899. 


129. 

Joseph and Worthy Goodman, Johnson county; balance of unpaid 
fine as remitted by my predecessor for selling liquor without a license, 
is remitted as it is shown that the punishment would fall on the 
father who is the surety, and is represented as unable to bear the bur- 



den; recommended by many responsible citizens of the county. June 
19, 1900. 

Maud A. Allen, Jefferson county; committed to Girl's Industrial 


School; exemplary conduct; good home secured for her; recommended 
by Superintendent B. R. B. Weber. December 20, 1900. 


'- 9-3077. 

Frank Webber, Lancaster county; six years for burglary; commuted 
to five years and nine months; upon the recommendation of the trial 



]udf« who held that hi* M&amp;tenc* waa excessive, the prisoner it 
</seg>








            <seg id="p029">
» 

given credit for the three months he was confined In Jail prior to 
his sentence, and sentence shortened accordingly. Novembw 19 
1900. 


ACCOUNT OF VOLUNTARY CONTRIBUTIONS FQR THE PURPOSE OF 
RETURNING THE FIRST REGIMENT NEBRASKA VOLUNTEERS 
FROM SAN FRANCISCO TO THEIR HOMES 
IN NEBRASKA. 


DEBIT. 


Aug. 21, 1899. Total contributions as per list on file ln'execu- 


tive office | 40,342 75 


CREDIT. 


Aug. 24, 1899. Paid B. ft M. R. R. Co. fares for 868 officers 
and men $32,550 00 
Paid B. ft M. R. R. Co. 564 tourist berths at $5. . 2,820 00 
Paid B. ft M. R. R. Co. 2 Pullman berths at $11.50 23 00 


Paid B. ft M. R. R. Co. for returning 19 men at 



$37.50 712 50 


Paid B. ft M. R. R. Co. Col. Mulford one-half 

officer's fare 30 00 

Aug. 26, 1899. Returned duplicate contribution to John Steen.. 20 00 

Returned duplicate contribution to F. Salsbury. 20 00 

Sept. 1, 1899. Returned J. E. Baum, chairman Omaha Com- 

mittee 1,500 00 

Sept. 13, 1899. Paid Western Union Tel. Co. for services 23 30 

Oct. 3, 1899. Refunded railroad fare to Private James D. 

Wolfe 37 50 

Oct 12, 1839. Refunded railroad fare to Private George H 

Chase 3" 50 

Paid exchange on checks 3 65 

Nov. 16, 1899. Paid for 100 stamped bank checks 1:0% 

Nov. 25, 1899. Paid for 50 stamped bank checks 1 00 

Nov. 29, 1899. Refunded railroad fare to Private E. S. Pearsall. 37 50 

Dec. 31, 1899. Refunded to contributors to date 2,411 00 

Feb. 1, 1900. Refunded to David Cole, Omaha, contritution. . . 20 00 

Apr. 23, 1900. Paid B. ft M. R. R. Co. fare for Lieut Wadsworth 37 50 
Unexpended balance in First National Bank 

Lincoln 56 30 

Total $40,342 75 

¦ </seg>






            <seg id="p030">28 







» 

ACCOUNT OF CONTRIBUTORS TO GALVBSTON, TEXAS, 
FLOOD SUFFERERS. 


DEBIT. 

Sept. 12, 1900. Received John N. Standt, Holdrege $20 00 
Sept. 13, 1900. Received F. S. Gable, Lincoln 1 5 00 

Sept. 13, 1900. Receivad A. V. Johnson, Lincoln 10 00 

oept. 13, 1900. Received A. B. McCoskey, Lincoln 5 00 

Sept. 13, 1900. Received S. M. Benedict, Lincoln 5 00 

Sept. 13, 1900. Received J. N. Campbell, Kearney 1 00 ' 

Sept. 15, 1900. Received Knights of Maccabees, Syracuse . 5 00 &amp; 

Sept. 15, 1900. Received J. B. Kitchen, Omaha 20 00 

Sept. 15, 1900. Received A. Poska M. D., Upland 1 00 

Sept. 15, 1900. Received Miss M. P. Wooster 73 

Sept. 17, 1900. Received J. W. Vosberg, Kearney 2 00 

Sept. 17, 1900. Received Martin I. Bower, Fullerton 5 00 

Sept. 18, 1900. Received Jas. V. Wood, David City 5 00 

Sept. 18, 1900. Received Congregational Sunday School, Indianola 15 77 
Sept. 19, 1900. Received St. Joseph's Catholic Church, Agnew 5 00 

Sept. 19, 1900. Received John A. Ruff, Grand Island 5 00 

Sept. 19, 1900. Received Chas. Shafer and Wife, Mowells 5 00 

Sept. 20, 1900. Received Citizens of Dannebrog 75 75 

Sept. 24, 1900. Received A. E. Day, Cortland 1 00 

Sept. 24, 1900. Received Citizens of Grand Island per Independent 

Publishing Co 92 00 

Sept 25, 1900. Received Catholic Church of Cortland 5 00 

Oct. 1,1900. Received H. J. Davenport 2 00 

Total $291 27 

CREDIT. 

Sept. 15, 1900. Paid Mayor Brashear, Houston, Texas $72 50 

Sept. 19, 1900. Paid Mayor Brashear, Houston, Texas 28 00 - 

Sept 24, 1900. Paid Mayor Brashear, Houston, Texas 183 77 

Oct. 11, 1900. Paid Mayor Brashear, Houston, Texas 7 00 

Total $291 27 </seg>








            <seg id="p031">
• 


» 


ACCOUNT OF DISBURSEMENTS TO RAILROADS, ETC., OF MONEYS 
RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT ON 
SECOND SETTLEMENT FOR REIMBURSEMENT OF NEBRASKA 
FOR EXPENSES INCURRED IN MOBILIZING AND MAINTAINING 
THE FIRST, SECOND, AND THIRD REGIMENTS, NEBRASKA 
VOLUNTEERS, INFANTRY, IN THE SPANISH-AMERICAN WAR. 
1898. 


Not. 4, 1900. United States treasury warrant $14,996 85 

CREDIT. 

Nov. 10, 1899. Paid B. 4 M. R. R. Co 4,650 86 

Paid U. P. R. R. Co 1,830 78 

r&gt;*&gt;;,4 tt r» r&gt; r&gt; r» rt 1 S7ft 7fl 

Paid O. * R. V. Ry. Co 252 83 

Paid K. C. &amp; O. Ry. Co 6 58 

Paid M. P. Ry. Co 47 88 

Paid F. E. &amp; M. V. Ry. Co 2,515 87 

Paid C, St. P.. M. * O. Ry. 464 16 

Paid C, R. I. * P. Ry. Co 395 70 

Paid Patrick Barry 25 37 

(receipt No. 13858) dis- 

Balance turned into state treasury 

tributed as follows: 

Pay of rejected men $4,685 60 

Transportation of baggage 92 22 

St. Elizabeth Hospital ' 29 00 4,806 82 

Total $14,996 85 


OFFICE FEES AND CASH ACCOLNT. 

governor's office. 

1899 

DEBIT. 

Fees for issuing extradation warrants $1,047 00 

Fees for issuing Commissioner of Deeds 60 00 

From Federal Government, five per cent on sales of public lands 

819 00 

in Nebraska, Credit 

From Federal Government in aid to Soldier's and Sailor's Home 
treasury on date received 23,806 21 

Total * 2 *. 732 21 </seg>










            <seg id="p032">
30 


CREDIT. 

Paid Into state treasury on date received $24,732 21 



Fees for issuing extradition warrants $24 00 

Fees for issuing Commissioner of Deeds 20 00 


From Federal Government, five per cent on public lands in 
Nebraska 1,278 32 

From Federal Government in aid to Soldier's and Sailor's Home. 29,742 66 

Total $31,064 98 

CREDIT. 

Paid into state treasury on date received $31,064 98 

ACCOUNT OF RELIEF APPROPRIATION FOR FIRST AND THIRD 
REGIMENTS NEBRASKA INFANTRY VOLUNTEERS. 

(HOUSE ROLL NO. 623-1899). 

DEBIT. 

Apr. 14, 1899. Received cash for warrant No. B29159 $1,000 00 

July 31, 1899. Received cash for warrant No. B33200 1,000 00 

Nov. 14, 1899. Received from Angle F. Newman unexpended 

balance 150 00 

Total $2,150 00 

CREDIT. 

Apr. 14, 1899. Paid to Angie F. Newman for White Cross Society $1,000 00 

July 31, 1899. Paid Redington ft Co., San Francisco 600 lung 

protectors at 40c 240 00 

July 31, 1899. Reimbursed Co. "G" for lung protectors, Captain 

Ough 30 40 

July 31, 1899. Reimbursed Co. "M" for lung protectors Captain 

Stockham 38 00 

July 31, 1899. Reimbursed Co. "B" for lung protectors Captain 

Sandrock 30 40 

Dec. 2, 1899. Paid state treasurer, Receipt No. 14036 661 20 

Nov. 14, 1900. Paid state treasurer, Receipt No. 17645 150 00 

Total $2,150 00 </seg>

         </p>

		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>