<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00043.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00043.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-Sixth Annual Report of the Secretary of the State Banking Board Showing the Condition of the Building and Loan Associations of Nebraska for the year ending June 30, 1918</title>
               <date value="1918-06-30">1918-06-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE SECRETARY OK THE STATE BANKING BOARD Showing the condition of the Building and Loan Associations OF NEBRASKA FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 SUBMITTED TO THE (JOVERXOR AND THE STATE BANKING BOARD NOVEMBER 1. 1918 J. J. TOOLEY, Secretary 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 DKl'AKTMKXT OF BANKING OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA BOARD HON. KEITH NEVILLE Governor, President HON. W. H. SMITH Auditor Public Accounts HON. WILLIS E. REED Attorney General J. J. TOOLEY Secretary RUTH STRE1TZ Clerk MAUDE HOGE Assistant Clerk EMMA HAHLBECK Assistant Clerk FAY FORBES Stenographer EXAMINERS S. M. PATTERSON M. R. SULLIVAN CHAS. R. WHITE J. H. WEHN S. A. LAPP A. D. TOUZALIN T. P. SMITH J. H. DONNELLY F. T. HOPKA N. B. GIPSON </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 3 Lincoln, January 1, 1919. To His Excellency. Keith. Neville, Governor, Hon. Wm. B. Smith, Auditor of Public Accounts Hon. Willis E. Reed, Attorney General. Members of the State Banking Board. Sirs: I have the honor of submitting herewith the 26th annual report of the State Banking Department, showing the condition of each of the seventy-three building and loan associations oper - ating under state authority at the close of the fiscal year June 30. 1918. During the year one new association was chart ?red, one voluntarily liquidated and one other is in process of liquidation. Due to the war there has been less activity in building and loan operations during the period covered by this report than in either of the two years immediately preceding. But, a careful analysis of the individual reports and comparison with those submitted in former years will distlose abundant evidence of a substantial and healthful growth. As will be noted in the com - bined statement the total assets have increased during the year $2,605,915.92. Loans in process of foreclosure show a marked decrease, emphasizing forcefully the increasing care given by managing officials to the quality of loans accepted and the col - lection of periodical payments. Government securities aggre - gating more than $$900,000.00 are held by the associations. Their war activities, however, should not be measured by this in - vestment alone as every facility possible has been provided to aid their membership in the purchase of bonds, and contribution to all war funds. These institutions are rendering a distinctive service in their particular field of operation. While providing a reasonably safe agency for the investment of idle funds, their chief purpose or aim is to encourage and develop the building of modest homes. Tt is a field capable of almost unlimited development. In build - ing and loan activities Nebraska, compared with nthe* 1 states, ranks very high. In fact, the largest association in the United States is a Nebraska concern. This high plane of usefulness and safety has been attained through wise legislation, equally protecting the investor and the homebuilder. The law a-s it now stands appears to be satisfactory as a whole and there is no de - mand for material change in the Act at this time. Interest rates seem to be adjusting themselves and premium charges to bor - rowers have been almost entirely eliminated, only seven associa - tions including such charges as a part of their fixed fees. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE The larger associations as well as many of the smaller ones are to he especially commended for their most complete and com - prehensive systems of accounting and auditing. Special effort has been made by the examiner to have all adopt a system as nearly uniform as the varied conditions will permit. In this he has met with reasonable success. The value of State supervision is to be very largely measured by the efficiency of the examiner and the thoroughness with which he performs his exacting duties. During the present ad - ministration this work has been assigned to Examiner A. D. Touziilin and he is entitled to the commendation of the Depart - ment for the very satisfactory results obtained. In conclusion, permit me to thank the individual members of the Board for their splendid co-operation and helpful counsel in all matters pertaining to the Department. The members of tlie office force, composed of young women of more than ordinary attainments, have discharged their duties in a manner forcefully emphasizing a keen perception of the courteous and efficient service to which those having business with the Ranking Depart - ment are entitled. Respectfully submitted J. .1. TOOLEY. Secretary. State Hanking Department. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 SUMMARY of the condition of the SEVENTY-THREE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS of the STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 30th Day ot June, 1918. ASSETS First mortgage loans M 951,258,011.20 Loans in process of foreclosure 185,282.84 Loans on stock or pass book security 543.034 86 Real estate, office 330,272.40 Other real estate 370,970.31 Real estate sold on contract 371,672.23 State and municipal securities 283.010.S8 Cash 2,325,744.63 Delinquent interest, fines, etc 111,883.68 Furniture and fixtures 44.914.80 Taxes paid 16,712.18 Other assets .... 204.283.81 Liberty Bonds and War Savings Stamps 908,735.61 Tax sale certificates 3,501.17 Certificates of deposit 193,507.50 Total $57,151,545.70 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $38,715,890.72 Paid-up stock and dividends 15.556.073.32 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 595,312.74 Reserve fund 1,539,432.03 Individed profits 541,439.90 Other liabilities _ _.. 105,374.04 Matured stock 31,302.95 Bills payable 67.7JM* Total $57,151,645.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report * 2,885,984.85 Dues (running stock) 13,088,199.15 Paid-up stock 5,873,693.04 Mortgage payments .... 8.849,656.32 Stock loan payments 826,868.12 Real estate sales 216,919.11 Interest 3,341,840.48 Premium _ 121,368.78 Fines 12,808.11 Rents 22,700.48 Membership and transfer fees : 39.404.56 Rents and office building receipts 29,121.65 Other receipts in detail 630,546.55 Liberty Bonds 1,358,971.67 Tax certificates 1,862.91 Certificates of deposit 317,797.32 Incomplete loans 1,333,135.13 Bills payable 774,175.00 Real estate contract 116,008.26 Bills receivable 21,983.75 Total $39,863,045.24 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans J12.162.860.96 Stock loans 909,351.07 Witbdraals running stock and dividends 12,578,552.53 Withdrawals nafd up stock 4.715 ?88 50 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock 674,577.64 Salaries 282,866.10 Commissions 60,170.96 Other expense 124,109.26 Real estate account 262,207.69 Cash on hand 2,323,157.47 Other disbursements in detail 679,534.29 Tax certificates 7,012.63 Liberty Bonds 2.029,974.42 Real estate contract 59,423.45 Certificates of deposit 177,447.40 Incomplete loans 1,974.599.25 Bills payable 746,416.48 Matured stock 95,495.14 Total ?39,863,045.24 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 7 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association, permanent 56, combination 5, serial 12 73 Number of shares issued since organization ' 692 Number of shares issued since organization 2,928,666.27 Number of shares outstanding last report 1,144,204.22 Shares issued since last report 260,327.63 Total 1,404.531.86 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report.... 240,026.98 Number of shares in force this date 1,190,784.02 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 8,618.50 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 1,626.50 Average running time of stock matured during the year — (47 reporting) 109 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders 32,076 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 72,287 Number of loans made for building purposes during jour..-. 2,116 109 Mo. Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead mortgages during year 3,520 Par value of each share of stock 52 at $100, 18 at 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 40,382.94 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 38,568.56 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid.... 133,729.06 Number and amount of mortgages subject to fore - closure No. 387 545,277.19 Number and amount of mortgages in process of fore - closure No. 188 2,788,491.19 Amount of loang on improved real estate 51,088,493.43 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 101.847.562.80 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 172,542.95 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made 533,585.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the as - sociation as collateral security 789,101.25 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 36,494,538.00 Amount of money loaned on improved farms 3,372,400.00 Appraised value of land not including improvements 6,057,618.80 Value of improvements 1,208,695.00 Amount of fire insurance thereon 368,700.00 Amount of tornado insurance thereon : 224.000.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 277.739.36 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 46,569.83 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1,955.165.05 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 838,408.63 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock dur - ing year (70 reporting) 7.043% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year (54 reporting) 6.14% Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year (72 reporting) 7.96% Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year (7 reporting) 1.70% </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT Of the total number of associations, numbers of shares in force, and total assets, from 1892, the first year that authentic reports were made. the present time. down to Number of Number of Year Association Shares in Total Assets 1892 71 45,012.5 $ 2,902,557.67 1893 84 61,964.1 3,653,096.83 1894 86 71,231.5 3,888,001.31 1895 81 70.615 3,929,778.27 1896 73 64,891.75 3,771,833.53 1897 68 67.597.5 3,554,788.08 1898 64 79,973 3,428,728.11 1899 CO 89,492 3,332,781.67 l»00 60 105,625 3,697,356.06 1901 69 119,985 4,314,744.86 1902 58 130,083 4,758,293.97 1903 59 159,424 5,343,429.38 1904 6(i 174,022 6,217,350.40 1906 59 196,030 7,269,297.48 1906 61 220,648 8,961,788.11 1907 66 315,372 11,422,890.86 1908 68 372,826.77 13,415,822.89 1909 70 438,054.19 17.094,771.5" l»10 70 512,344.71 21,327,766.83 1911 69 602,159.94 24,885,285.15 1»1J 68 668,122.85 28,946.108.63 1»13 70 740,925.29 32,746,726.24 1»14 72 816,571.25 37,138,413.21 1915 71 891,333.79 41,660,870.53 1916 72 1,007,346.63 47,917,847.08 1117 73 1,122,518.01 54,545,629.78 1*18 73 1,190,784.02 57,151,546.70 additional associations not included in last report, reported this Two time and two associations liquidated. Two associations were organized and chartered: Holdrege Savings and Loan Association, Holdrege; Security Savings and Loan Association, Newman Grove. Two associations were liquidated: Humphrey Building, Loan and Savings Association, Humphrey; Pawnee City Savings and Building Asso- ciation, Pawnee City. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 9 STATEMENTS Showing the condition of each of the seventy-three Build - ing and Loan Associations in the State of Nebraska at the close of business June 30, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 STATEMENT of the condition of the ALBION BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALBION, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President P. A. Krause T. F. Martin -F. A. Doten Vice President Secretary DIRECTORS P. A. Krause F. A. Doten H. P. Bull C. A. Bull T. F. Martin F. S. Thompson R. T. Flotree W. B. Martin ASSETS First mortgage loans Loans on stock or pass book security Other real estate Delinquent Interest, tinea, etc Furniture and fixtures insuranoe n(lvam-«Ml Tax Kale i-ertlfloates Total LIABILITIES Running Mock and dividends % jn.WS.1 Treasnry overdrawn ........! ,, :«ii. o Beterre for delinquent intereat _________________ («!.': Total ........—............._..... _„ „_ Jf 120,136,: Rcaerve fund .""wa'inoi Tndlvided profits ' moir Bills payable _ _ , 7&gt;nn 0' </seg>
            <seg id="p011">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 11 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RKCEIPTS 4 'ash od hand last report I &gt;uis irtinntnK slock i f .VtT.iT •u.XiiJri Mortgage payments stock loun payment* Heal estate lilt's _ U.10O.U0 l.'.NNMIO aoo.oo Interest Kines 7.H*t.!)l £&gt;2.20 Rents 120.01) Mi'iuii&gt;T&gt;liip and i riiu.-fiT tee* Insurance returned 241 .30 !).:» Bills iwivMlile _ _ 2O.4.TO.OO •JO.4oO.00 Tax salt- MTtilleatwi _ _ :Hl.s7 Trensury ovprilrawn 32B.O* 329.04 Total * 73.«X!ll IlISIURSEMKNTS Mortgnge lum- Stock loans $ 41.10t&gt;.00 1. 700.00 WltMrawala running stock a»d dividend* Kalarlca n.fWi.r- 1 1 .25B.tr, other ex pen«* 1M.0O Heal estate account RtllR payable .VUll n.a».ot&gt; i 'i i * — i'&lt;i.».i..i&gt; Interest on Itiiililiut; Permits Tax sale certificates l«7.4.-i Insurance advanced 51.00 Total t 7.-..K-JS.IU STTPI.KMENTAI, RKPOKT Plan of association INTllillliellt Number of shares kaiiti since oricanlzation 14.70ft Number of shares outstanding last report t.'.tai Shares issued sintt hist report _ 717 Total - - ■:&lt;*- Shares wil lid ruwu. matured or cancelled since last report ■«!' Xiimlwr of shares in force this date 4.7TK Numl&gt;er of horrowinK stoclthohlers 131 Number of non-l»orrowinK stockholders :&amp;ni Number of loans made for huildlnit purposex ilurlnx rear Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of nomestead-mortKaues 1 ilurln^ year 1M Par vMhn- of each share of stock $ 100.00 Amount of interest, premiums anil Bins iluc and unpaid tlHl.£&gt; NumlK-r and amount of morteaires subject to foreclosure. No. 1(( '.i.COO.IN) Amount of loans mi improved r*-:i I estate 1"_'(..*&lt;xuio Aiipratseil valtu* of Improved rent estati- n|x&gt;ii which loans have Ween made XTflMuM Amount of fin" Insuraiii-e in fore- and ussiiriiol to the usmMiatloii as collateral security 121.N0ft.0l) Auiount of tornailo insumui-e in fon-e and assigned to the tnmxia tion as collateral security 12Ti.2OTi.0O Amount credited to reserve fund during ye«r iiiiO.Oi) Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year rt.77R..TT :«».0» Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year .WII'MIIII III III* HII-ii'in iininiin «i* i&lt;iiiiii"t. r&lt;iui M K "I" ■min.-M Rate per &lt;-ent of dividends declared on running stock during rear 7&lt;?v- Itatc per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year. .078 to Aug. since then - - — .0flft'"c </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 STATEMENT of the condition of the ALLIANCE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALLIANCE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President R. M. Hampton Vice President , Jerry Rowan Secretary M. S. Hargraves Treasurer F. W. Harris Attorney Burton &amp; Reddisu DIRECTORS rm McDonald W. Irish W. C. Mounts E. D. Henry George Davis ASSETS Firm mortgage lonns f 224..T0O.00 [-...ins on stock or pass ho*k necurtty 2.5)00.00 other real .-state _ 71R.77 rash ■■ 4.420.4:'. Dellniiuent Interest, aim, etc. 1.417.7B Furniture and fixtures 7H0.00 Taxes paid _ 317.81 Other assets, insurance 123.90 Total * 2SR. l«8.it&gt; LIABILITIES Running utock and dividends f 110,»15.:KI Paid-up Htock and dividend* 120.731.dK Reserve fund 2.733.A3 Other liabilities "". _ - _ - 1.417.7« ToUl 9 235.198.7* </seg>
            <seg id="p013">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 13 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES TOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 1918 •, Id -i is K II i'.i-h on hand last n i"Ti * Z.M1.TT Hues i rn rilling stock Paid-up stock ."fct.-.teij.'i 53JMH.4o -•«;.7nn.nt Mortmain- payments stock En njmli ltcill , -sliil,. sales _ Ltt. 7)10.04 iCiti.nn r.Mi.im - 1IM..11 later**) Fines L-4.iem.ix St. 'M !£&gt;.&lt;■ IJK lit T "4 77 sm'.'M Kellts rj.-..i« Insuram Taxes ix. to 7J4.77 11. fir, lonrt io«t« Attorney fii \\.K, :-.-...m :•.-..«■ Total $ IXt.~i2..*» * WH l&gt;!SI:i "liSKMKXTK Mortgage loans Stuck li.nns *4&lt;l.7!ll.K): in. -.1111. 1'-l.- loaBB, *ti.ll!«.7." f 4Jl.NMB.7Ti Inii.iiiplcic h«U*. 9H.0MK.Ti * «UHI.r i,vii.i« Withdrawals runniui: sio. k ;iml dividend Withdrawals paid up stiM-k I divi.l.ii.ls MI.3U.47 WilliilmnnU iliviilinil on imiil-up stixk SiilHrics up stixk K.UI7..1* 1 'IIOIKI 100.M CoiiiiniHsions on r«-:il rstutt Other exnenxe , 4J2.S1 ■■■I istnti' :i . &lt; oil 111 I'ush on h.'iinl 4.-O.V. t.42».4.1 Court roan iiml Mttoruey tn Tmxra ■jxh.::: 2«.7:i lllsur;llli-i- rani \[i'i i-il;llniMi- S1.TO TotHl * l.tsi.r SII'I'I.KMKNTAI, RKPOBT Plan of ii-isi'i'ititimi IVrmanent NumlMT of shares isKlleil sim-e or^;)l&gt;iz;llinii li.'J'JS. tft Nninh4&gt;r of shnres oiit.stiiiitliuj; Inrtt report 2.C7#.7b Sluing issut'il sin!-,. Iji^i rt'ixirt W1T.40 Total _ . ::..".7vlii Shares withdrawn, tnatureo or raiirelleil nliicr In^t r*&gt;|&gt;ort ..(O.it \iiiiilnr i.r nlMH ill fon-.' tlii&gt; ilate :;.."7s.7: Niuulier of shares on whirli tines me ileliiniueiit Nuiniiir of iihaim aabjcrl to t-ancrllatina for iioii|iaynient ,&gt;r Mm si.."i(&gt; Aeraee runniim time of sio.k inalilreil ilnrnif tile y&lt; :i r lUino. NuiiiIht of liorrtiwiui: stoi-kholHers un Number of non-borruw in^ ;i." N'mulier of loans inaile for balkllu |mr|&gt;osi&gt;s ilurinK year Number of loans nunle for rim iinxlin: lioinesleHils or imyment of lioinestead-niortjraees iluriuu year 20 Par value of eiti-h s!i:ire of st,M-k $ _■»■! im Totiil amount of ilues- ileliuciiient m this il.iti j. H.: (4 Amount of ilues owinir liv liorrowinc stiH-kholilers 2.1BG.U A u ii I of interest, premiums ami tines ilue mill uupaiil 1.417.7)! .iilliniiil in ininrmi in inn ii iu&gt; .iiiii wi ii one 111111 iiii|i:i.'i i tii ,&lt;■ Number ami amount of inortjraffi'" subJiM't to foreelosure. No. 4 i;.l1kmio Amount of loans on linproveil ml istati J24J&lt;U\00 Appraisi'il vulue of improseil real estate upon uhi.h loaus hare kaaa inaile 4.V...-|«0.n&lt;i Amount of tin- Inmirimee in force anil .issiirn.-.i to the »smM*iatioii as collateral security Js4.ii."iO.I»l Amount of toruatlo lnsiimiiii^ in force ami assi^ni^l to rh t - a*xoi iatlon as collateral seinrlty 14."i.J00.(10 Aiiioiiiitcreilited to reserve funil tin rinir year I.^C.Bl Amount of 1oms*»m clinrifeil to reserve fniul ilurintr yt^ir . _ l."2fifi.2O Amount of illvidenils ilei lareil on runniTn.' stock iluriue year 17" Amount of iliviilemls naiil on matureil .mil paiil-up stock ilurlnr .rear H.197..T0 Itatc imt i-cnt of iliviilenils ili^-lareil on running stock iluriii£ vcar .170'! Kate iht cent nf iliviili-mls paiil on m.iturei'. ami full paid stock during year »% Rate i&gt;er cent of interest charired borrowers dutine year '.\.'j r ; </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 STATEMENT of the condition of the SOITHEASTERX NEBRASKA WILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AUBURN. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Wm. B. Smith Vice President R. E. Harmon Secretary J. M. Gillan Treasurer B. C. Howe Attorney Edgar Fernaeu DIRECTORS E. M. Kerns B. C. Howe R. E. Harmon J. M. Gillan R. M. Gillan Wm. B. Smith ASSKTS Klr»t mortgage loans 4 211.170.00 Loans in prm-ess- of foreHiwure ~ 2JKBM I.«.iins mi stuck or pass Imok seiiirlly M8&amp;M othiT rcni estate "Z!ZllLZ..!lV/..™..!!Z.'.!..r/.!!..V..!!...V..! i4,stii.ih&gt; Iteal I'siini- sold on rontrmi '. 4.1U.QC ca«ii ;...................'.'.!...jz...."...."...™;..v.v/.;.i..^.".v..;..'.v." ii,m.o)i I M-l ■ ■■&lt; i mil t Interest, lines, i-li- 2.4-Vi.SM I'uriiilurc und fixture** '_•*."». (Kt Tsxpk pal&lt;l :KU.(iK I.llxrty Kouils ..! _ . txhi ini Total $ 256,963.89 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ fil.3ttt.87 Paid-up stock and dividends ._.......__....'. .'. 182.100.00 Reserve fund _ - i;.*40.00 Individed profit* _ 6.58T&gt;.47 Advance interest and premiums _ &lt;w..v. ToUl . — _ * 256*6i» </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 RECEIPTS AXD EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RKt KIPTS Cash on band last ivport $ 11.71IUB Dues (running stock! lj£iiS.4B Paid-up stock .'."".'. "'.'."."."".".".'."."".'.". .'."" 44.WMJ Mortgage pay men ts - — M£4tLti Stock loan payments _ &lt;•».(»&gt; Real estate sales JJL VT'.'.-U! Interest (premiums and linen) _ _ 10,1 4U.M Real estate contracts ■ ... 1 ::il O&gt; Rents ■ — ___ HMt Meml&gt;ership and transfer fees 1.10.00 I.ilHTty Bonds - I M Total _ S 13H.M2.2* nisnrnsEMKXTs Mortgage loans $ 44i.47."V.(W Stock loans \ __ _ 7iK&lt;m Withdrawals running stock and dividends "". .!......'..'...".-.... 1H.2MK0O Withdrawals paiil up stock .'...y.Z.Zl.Z-'.'..."".. »4.f«M» Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stork _ _ 10. 421.38 Salaries ""' 2.71 1 A.' Commissions Ji'Ji ~*&gt; Other expense •~».TT.75 Real estate account _ J.44.1.2"&gt; Cash (in hand 11.17M8 Foreclosure account Mi Reserve fund - T* '.'7 Liberty Bonds WJtMLtk Insurance and taxes MM Total $ i:»i!M2.i« SriTI.KMK.NT A I REPORT Plan of association Pcrniuncnt NuihImt of shares Issued since nr^iiiiiuitinn I£!.:Hl.flO Nunilier of shares natataJHllBl last re|»&gt;rt "i.41!t Shares issued since last report _ 006 Total |M Shares withdrawn, matured or can&lt;rlled since l.H". Number of shares in force this date -V1K: Averaee runnlnK time of stock matured during year "B" 144 m« Numher of liorrnwlne stockholders M Numher of non-ln»rro»inK stix-kholders Number of loans made for ituiUliiiK purposes during year Number of loano made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year -W Plan of premium „ Monthly Par value of each share of stock — $ ikhhi Amountof Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 2.435.SH Plan of premium tmm Number ami amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. Xo. 10 IIJMlM Number and amount of mortgages in proc*«»s of foreclosure. No. 2 _'•'■."!» M Amount of loans on improcd real estate 2flO.9llkM Appraised value of Improved rciil estate upon which loans have b*«&gt;» made 4."W..T4(l.i» Amount of loans on iinimproveil real estate 1."JI10.0» Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans havr l&gt;een made _ &amp;MMB Amount &lt;&gt;f Ore inernrance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security '"BiOW Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral seenrity as collateral security 2ft2,3nliiO Amount credited to reserve fund during ye«r MJ1 Amount of losses charged to reserve fnnd durilng year R4IO? Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 2.934.C7 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock daring year 10.421 .Vi 2.9S*.f7 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year... 6% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and fall paid stock dur - ing year «* Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers daring ye«r *«v Bate par cent of premiums charged borrowers daring ye»r IS-Wt </seg>
            <seg id="p016">TWKNT V-S1XTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 16 STATEMENT of the condition of the Al'RORA IUILD1N0 AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AURORA. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President B. A. Munson .W. E. Reber Vice President Secretary James Schoonover ...W. E. Lounsbury J. S. Grosvenor Treasurer Attorney DIRECTORS B. A. Munson WE Reber N. J. Ronin J. A. Isaman Joseph Johnson H. E. Newton Jas. Schoonover E. C. Rhinehart W. B. Lounsbury First mortgage loans Prnitiirc hihI fixture S. f Mil I II lloml- Total llilliniliK Hlock ami iliviilemls I'aiil mi siix-k btme fund UndiTided proflts Lotins &lt;iii stock or ,»:is- Innk wrurtt.v otluT r«*nl imtM tn </seg>
            <seg id="p017">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 17 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, , 1918 Plan of association PermanMlt I lilll Ul HNM.rilllll'll N'uiiiiicr of M-ries- issu,.. 1 slmv orvanlutlon — All utock (inverted 1-11* Niimtxr of shares issued since oreaniratlon O.C18 Numher of shares ..utstiindinic last report 1.8HB N'uiiiImt of shares issued since orKanirntion Shares issuer since last report -48H Total 1.91«i, shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since laat report _ S80^* Number of shares In force this date 1.SWJ Average running time of stock matured during toe re«r 127 mo. Number of borrowing stockholders — 40 Number of non-borrowing stockholders Par value of each share of stock • 100.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 55,900.00 Total Amount of loans on Improved real efttate Appraised valne of Improved real estate upon which loans have been ■ made 123.130.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association made as collateral security flB.400 Auiountof tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security .b».+i«i Amount credited to reserve fund during year 2T.1 :•; Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 222.65 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year i.JfUM .\UI"lllll 1.1 Illlllirillin '!&gt;■&gt; i. Ill 11 "li I •■■■•■■lib. P.IV. * KU.'Hft .»'■•■ Amounts of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per cent of dividends paid on full paid stock during year SO Rate imt cent of interest charged borrower* during year. first half S.4-WJ last half 7.2-10% KKCKIITK Catch mi hand last report Hues i running stork I _ Paid up KtiK'k Mortgage payments Stork limn payments Interest I 'inc* Itents _ M.inUrslili. ami transfer fws ProBt on stock withdrawals liitf.i-*i on conn dt&gt;&lt; rt-f Settlement foreclosure run** Advance costs repaid Insurance premiums repaid Bill* recelvahle ti-30-17 Bills receival.le 12-S1-17 . Total $ -U'.i-.i-i 10..V.NI.40 :i.».oo 1M.X»)0.(IO Kon.on .'•.1TB.4.1 ■.-J4.:i«i 17:1.3.". MM lil.'.r.' 47.40 771. 7r, "•2.00 $ 43.«0.T.' niSIllHSEMFXTS Wltbdrawala runuiim sto.k and ilivldends Withdruwiils paid-up stoc-k WlthitrawnlK diridend cm paid-up «tix-k Salaries Other MMM Kcal estate account Cash on hand Insurance Attorney fees in foreclosure &lt;hm* „ „ Hent refunded from IT to RE Matured stock I'nited States I.llierty Roads Total » 24^5A6» &gt;U»'i»( KUlKt 7SS.00 l.V)..V. 4.VW r&gt;.«7.sl 4.00 222.05 124.T) aoo.on .-..ooo.no .. $ 43.650.7-.' ur*ni&gt;t rwrvTlT IfrtvibT s &gt;&lt;( </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL, REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the THK STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS Preaident '. A. H. Kidd Vice President T. J. Chidester Secretary L. Hevelone Treasurer Louie Graf Attorney Rinaker &amp; Kidd DIRECTORS A. H. Kidd T. J. Chidester W. C. Black, Jr. D. C. McGaffey E. L. Hevelone ASSETS Firm mortgaite loans t 1.T57.4O0.00 Loi,ns in process nf forci-lnsure 8,500.00 I^ians on Kt'x-k &lt;»r paHfl book security 2.!&gt;7ri.00 t:il esticte. ..fflc-e. $6,000: other re«l esUte. -fl2.28T.7S 18,2X7.7.1 Real esticte. nfflc-e. 16.000: other re«l estate. $12.287.T» 18.287.Tn keal estate Hold on contract 6.073.!i7 ill extnte Hold on contract fl.0T3.ii7 ("ash lftft.iSTi" in 1OB.1S717 IteliiKiucnt Interest, lines, etc _.. 3. ¥3.81 liiiniii'iit interest, fine*, etc „ _ 3 3KI.S1 Furniture anil fixtures 1 7.10.0 i Furniture and fixtures 1 730.0 i Tam jiiil.l 2.4OTi.w&lt; i Ither assets „ _ — „ 374.fc7 I.ll.«rty Ilr.uils •JK.7NO..'&lt;I P. S. (Vrtifli-atm &lt;if Inilelitedneiix ."i.00l).n&lt;i Mfllii- supplies ,. M-,.00 Total „ $ l,S84.!t73.!l LIABILITIES Kunninic stock and dividends ,.....» 1,258,286.91 Paid-up stock and dividends 44B.000.on Due shareholders on incomplete loans : S8.&lt;M7.R'' S8.fM7.R&lt;' Reserve fund „__ ZT/™7.7!I!r^r.V.\™V.Vi™.'."™."."'."!' is'.22B!O7 r mil rlded ■—* Si , , ™ „ "" " 7o!83o!l^ Toui „ ....,....,■.■....,... $ i.snm.w </seg>
            <seg id="p019">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 19 * RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS *'ash on hand last report $ 290.411.10 Hues irunniiiL- stork) 38S.B79.»2 Paid-up stock 195i»7."j.00 KKUM..M Mortgage payments Stork loan payment* 50.00 UeHl HtatC sales _ 11.. TM2.3U Interest _.7.____™1___________________. lS2.91d.25 Liberty Honilii anil War Savings Stamp* 41.303.1.-. Fines ____ _ _ l«_.3tt Rents ..\\...7.™7.™7™..JZ7.\~_________________ _____ SS1.15 Membership and transfer fees Kents and office luiitilimr receipts 4.239.S0 2UT.SO Other receipts 921.18 Abstract fees ______________ , _ 2. 418.95 Real estate sold on contract _ BJOB.OT Tax sale certificates _______ 1.308. ■-&gt; ToUl _ f UUU KISKinSKMI-.NTS Mortgage loans * r&gt;74.440_t Stock lonns 3.92."i.00 Withdrawals running stock ; and dl-ide_ds '"\7!7.7.7!T.7.~.7.7.7.7.77.7.7'!17.7.*!...7.7.7 2O4.:t!&lt;!i.M« Withdrawals paid-up stock ___L"ZZ.__ZZZ._Z...Z 138.400.00 Withdrawals dlvlldend on paid-np stock ' ........L 17.4Kt.Ht Salaries _________________ 10.761.92 Commissions 2..'M«.."&gt;S Other expense „ _ ._ 2.173.10 Keal estate account _ _' .tjx.O'p Cash on hand _ 1M0.197.17 Other disbursements _ 438.67 Other disbursements _ _ 4,TS.fi7 Traveling exitenses _ l.flft*2.1M Traveling exiienses _ „ l.l_r_.lM Collecting and exchange _ 4,rt»n v " Collecting and exchange ' .".. 4.fRt * Furniture and fixture* " 68.06 Furniture and flxturen _______ 68.06 OtHce building account .... B34.00 Office iMilldine account _ .... __ .......7 K14.00 Keceived fees . .. 337 tt" HecelTed fees 7. 7.7.7. ___ __ ________ M7!f-" Tax sale certificate* ' 2.470.83 Tax salt. eettt-K— ta I "77.7.7.77/.7.7_7.7"7.7.._ _. " 2.470.83 Korecliisiire expense _ 901.33 Foreclosure expense _ .... . 901.33 Liberty li.ni. Is ami War Savings Stamp* 70.OK1 &lt;;"■ Total $1_3B7K1J: M I'l'I-KMKNTAI. REPORT I.ll&gt;erty Ilonds and War llil-|l tf-jnt HMD Total $ ii»i7t:i i; HlTl'I-HMKNTAI. REPORT Plan of Mss. .iai i. hi _ Permanent Plan of aancciatlon . _ Permanent Number of shares Issued since organization _____ l+4.r_»i&lt;i-. Number of shares issued since organization _________ I44.."_*it&gt;-. Xumlper of shares outstanding last report _ 5&amp;8BO% Shares Issued since last report 2&amp;8MM4 Total 78.748 Xunilier of shares outstanding laiit report _ 5MB0% Shares Issued since last report 2O.0MH4 Total . 76.748 Shnres withdrawn, matured or cancelled «t_ce la-l re|&gt;ort llJiS Shares withdrawn, matured or i ili-l liiin'l 1 1 '"■l-ii"l' -iiil iii't'-li 1l!2».T Xumlier of shares In force this date i '»".... I; 1 . Xumlier of shares In force this date &gt;■.""...--&gt;;•. Average running time of stock inatunni during the -ear 112 mo. Number of l&gt;orrnwing stockholders 1.083 Aferage rn n tiii.tr time of sto&lt;k matured diirini: the year 112 mo. Number of lxirro\viu_ iio.-khold.r- 1.0R3 Numlter of non-borrowlnjr stockholders.... ::.tCR&gt; Niimlier «»f ii.in l.orrowin^ stockholders XtOtt Number of loans made for building purposes during year 103 Number of loans made for ImlldinK purposes Muring year 168 Number of loans made for purchasing of lioni* steads or iwiyment of homestead -mortgages 'luring year 21."&gt; Numlier of loans made fur purchasing of Ikmik steads or pajment of homestead- mortgages during year 21.T Par value of each share of stock f 100,l*i Par value of encli share at st IM -k . .$ 100.0i&gt; Amount of dues owing l&gt;y borrowing stockholder* H.MUI Amount of dues nwinir l&gt;v borrowing stockholders HMnUM Amount of interest, iiremlillliis nnd flues due and unpaid . ...... Amount of interest, iiremiiums and flues due and unpaid 3,38SJtl Number and amount ol mortgages siil.Jert to foreiiosun-. So. Z l.'.ifiO.OO Number and amount ol mortgages siilject to foreclosure. No. I l.'.nTO.nit Number anil anioiuu of mortgages it, proc«*ss of fortvlosure. No. n H..V)0.0i» N'umher mid iimouiu of mortgages it, process of forei-losnn-. No. 3 S..V)O.0o Amount of loans on improved real estate l..~_Et.ini&gt;.no Appraiscil vuluv of ini|&gt;n&gt;vcil rial estate upon which loans hire bee - made _ i Amount of loans on Miiinprovcd r«*jil estate •-■.7:'-"..70aoo 2.S00.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made T.800.00 Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1JW7.1.TO.0O Amount of tornado insuramv in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1.7SS.S00.0O Amount credited to reserve fund during year as collateral security from B% net profits. IB.SW.11 : miscellaneous. J88.SK _!_.7.7.7__!i.~7 .\47O._M Amonnt of losses chargeil to reserve fund during year 4,17*~3l Amount of dividends declared on running stock during rear 82.A71.4i&gt; Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-np stock during rear n; •-*&lt;■ *r. Rate per cent of dividends &lt;leclared on runninc stock during year.... R I Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dur - ing year, first half. 5&lt;7r : second half 6% Rate ikt cent of Interest charged borrowers during jear 7_! and »% </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 STATEMENT of the condition of the BEATRICE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President C. P. Fall, M. D. Vice President Ernst Schaekel Secretary F. B. Sheldon Treasurer .-. Ernst Schaekel Attorney F. B. Sheldon DIRECTORS C. P. Fall, M. D. H. E. Sackett C. A. Janssen Kirsi iiioriKiip' limns * 42S.'i-J-J.-_".t \\4fOA2 l.n.-ms iii pMM of fom-lnsiiri- Loan* nn stink or paw iHMik BMBrity otlHT real estate atum 17.128.61 Ken] cstnti- sold mi •■&gt;nl r;i . I st.-n.' and munii tpnl securities '.i.'.i:ir..ii:i Ut.31T.2a 4T»J«.-»..V. Hiiruilure anil liMur.-* tttl.2T T»t«l t . r i:i.~&gt;.7W.io I-IAItlMTIKS Uunniiii; slock anil ili\ idpnilx . $ 2:t7,.*&gt;47.0" I'Niil lilt stoik :iml ■liviili'iul* ; 2Sl!7()0.no itmrvp fund — i]379."i7 Other llatillltim ....._ ~" 12s;-(» Total _ f 535.7tl8.lO ASKRTK ln.llvi.le.1 profit* ™.™/Z~..."!V™7^_Z71_.~~/Z~Z~Z~"™ZI"."..I 14&gt;H&lt;U6 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 21 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES TOR THE YEAR ENDING Plan of association „ Permiinent Nunilier of shares issiu-il aterr &lt;ireanixnti.ui ...Z 40.n.i&gt;-i Number of ihtltf fiutHtiin.lin^ last report l(i.;t.V&gt;.2." Shares issued since last report 2.~iH'&gt;. Total ....__.!._. 1SJW5JR Shares witlidrnnn. tnntunil or rtMHM since last report T .»1B N'unilier of shares in force this date 1S.«B* Avcr.iite running time of stock matured during the ve»r 114 m« Numlter of horrowlnfr sto«-kholders Number of non- borrowing stockholders 1.0CU Number of loans made for building purposes .luring rnr 1* Nunilier of loans made for purchasing of houiestead* or purulent of homestead -mortgages (luring ymir Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 Number ami amount of mortgages suhjei-t to foreclosure. No. W 17.000.00 NmnlH-r and amount of mortgages in pro&lt;&gt;e*s of foreclosure. No. s 1.1.4HO.42 Amount of Ioanx on Improved real estate 41N.lr.rJ i' Appraised value of Improved real estate u|M»n which loans have been made , . 8r&gt;2.rt2T&gt;.0O Amount of flre insnraii.i- in fon-e and as-signed to the association as collateral sec-urity 4!W.S.T0.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in turn and assigned to the association as collateral security 42S.iOO.OO Amount credited to reserve fund during vear l.rtTrv.OO Amount of loRHew charged to reserve fund during year 4.r&gt;2n..~tft Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1S.W2.47 Amount of dividends oald on matured nnd paid-up stock dtlritng year 1"l 4:».&lt;1k Rate per rent of dividends declared on running stock during rear "'■ Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year I** Kate per cent of Interest charged borrower* .luring year _ 8.4% J L .1£j Oil, XJ1O RKl'KII'TS Cash on band last report Dues tit'iiniiic sto&lt;-k i I'.-lliI ill. stork MortKiicc payment* Stock loan payment* Heal extate sales Interest „ Membership and traimfer Item _ _ Contracts Foreclosure account - - _ I. s Unmix, stamnx Other reoelpttt Total t 17.H1J.:!-- 72.!&gt;V.(.71 132.300.00 WT...V.1 .«■.■ l n&gt;.-.n.. "' 12*4 '"0 17.0B7.24 1+..VW..-.7 1.141.42 f 424^7«.» IMSIUKKKMKNTS Mortgage loans Stuck ln;nis _ Withdrawals running stock and divideml. Withdrawals paid-up stock Withdrawals dividend on paid up stock Salaries Commissions Other t-xpelise -. Real estate account _ &lt;'hs1i on hand .; KoreHomirp account _. I". S. Konds, Stamps _ Contracts IU-serve fund KnrnUiire and «itnr«i other disbursements _ - Total $ M (..-»V...T&lt;( l..-4.-).fl0 M2.1SO.14 lofi.vjr. on l.V4.1&gt;l.&lt;M 4.200.00 1.2K.C4 1. !I21. 31 12.1O7..V. 4.-&gt;.HH5..-« 14..1M..T7 S0.SHKX! 4.5S3JW am 1.134.T* $ KtjgnM ■I I I IBM— III RKPORT </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 TWENTY SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Philip Graff Vice President J. E. Lang Secretary M. F. Eickmann Treasurer Carl Sonderegger Attorney .... Rinaker &amp; Kidd DIRECTORS Philip Graff J. E. Lang Carl Sonderegger Henry Jurgens John Huttenmaier ASSETS First uiorteuKc loons 4 KH.K70.0i&gt; State and miiuicliml stvnritleti 21.770.00 rjhh _ .v..7ii:.'.i7 I &gt;.-l iii- 111. -in lauriii't. Him. tic. .._........_.._...._.....________ J.2S."&gt;.W I nrnitiirv ;iinl fixtures .' 4!'7.7O I iirnitiirv and flxturcK ! J'.iT.TO Til hiiI,. cT-rtifliHtei. 2.047.3H Tax siil,. cTrttfli-HteK '.'.........".""".."......_ ...."1.1 .......J.'."..".......... 2.O47..V. v.urt i*osts atlvxiKHil STJBi ( "oiirt i*os!k nilviin&lt;i'&lt;l ..™ — — 3TJiC&gt; &lt;Vrt!fl&lt;-ateH of dvpoMit _ ."i2.()00.00 ToUl ( 4O7.175.4X I.IARIMTIKS Running atoek and diriilpndn _ 4 lia.M&gt;7.i:i Paid-up stork and dividends „ 272.22T..0O ]»ue shareholders on in&lt;-ouoplete loanji _ „ XS07.(?.» tUmrrt fund 2.235.00 2.235.00 1'ndividiMl proBts " " " ' 11.&amp;M.K1 Itond uayments 484.SO Total . _ I 407.175.48 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■2Z RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 riau of association Permanent XumlKT of shares issued siinee organisation l:t.rtO«T Number of shares outstanding last report fl.34Hi Shares issued since last report 3.515% Total i mn&lt; ShareR withdrawn, matured or cancelled since l«*t report 2.214", Number of shares in force this date 7.ft*.% 1 4 Average running time of stock matured during the year — 12S mo. Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders 541 Number of loans made for building purposes during year Number of loans made /or purchasing homesteads or payment of a homestead -mortgages during year 54 Par value of each sbare of stock » 100.60 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stoekhold* rs 1.0M130 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 1.70H.4O Number nud amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. No. 10 14.350.no Nunil&gt;er and amount of mortgages in process of coreclosure. No. 1 "i.000.0i&gt; Amount of loans on improved real estate 2&lt;Ki.t&gt;iO.OO Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loam hare been made S20.'V43.O0 Amount of Joans on unimproved real estate 1.200.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hare been made 3.430.00 Amount of fire insnrnnce in force and assigned to the association „ „ „ us collateral security 287.SjO.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned tn the association as collateral security M -I?5-55 as collateral security as collateral security ■^'AvX'aH Amount credlited to reserve fund during year 212S2 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 7.300.37 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 1O.«1«14 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during ye«r Kate per cent of diividends paid on matured and full paid nock Ml nnif ppr win vi uutiuniun pom uu uiKiiiiru ami »«j« isaiu -.i~. •■ dnrtnc ye«r tT«r««e W»* Bate per cent of Interest charged borrower! dnriing year M% Mtiirn Cash on hand lant report Dues (running stock i - - I*aid-np stock - Mortgage payments - Interest - - - Fines Membership and transfer fee» _ Accrued interest Certiorates of deposit Tax sale certificates Liberty and municipal bonds Loan fees Incomplete loans r.inid payments — Total _ M n ... t 4O.tex.fi7 H2.S30.0N 174.173.00 2+.r&gt;3O.flO 23.877.HX 4.VJ0 .._ 778."'0 l.l.TT.Ofi 101,000.00 .12. or. 14..VX&gt;.&lt;&gt;0 470 oo :...'..'....~ 2B.3S7..M 9K4..TO f 4n.73«.»4 niSBIUSEMKXTS Mortgage loans Withdrawals running ntwk and dividends Withdrawals paid-np stock Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock Salaries ( »ther expense Cash on hand Incomplete loans Certificates of deposit Tax sale certificates Accrued Interest Court costs advanced Libert; and Municipal Boik'.h Dividends credited Bond payments' Total t KI.2UO.0t&gt; 4O.42O.00 _ 27.ir_ &gt; Ml&lt;&gt; lO.RUUl il.TS.du 1..128.7.-) .Vi.71fi.!»" 23.372.B2 73.000.00 &gt;.'-r,.rA 223!5 4« ."rr.m 44.J70.WI 500.00 f 471,7r«.»4 KVI'I'LKMKNTAL UPMK </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the BLAIR BriLl)IN&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BLAIR. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President E. R. Stewart Vice President F. W. Arndt Secretary John Schmaling Treasurer C. A. Schmidt Attorney Clark O'Hanlon DIRECTORS J. E. Carver J. Mueller ASSETS I'ii-Kt inortmKf loan* 4 lOfl.rti'.OII la»h 1.174.17 Total $ 1O7.7UU.17 LIARIMT1KS ItiiniiiliE HtOvk and . I n i.i.u.l- f K1.XIH.44 I'nlil u |i Kt&lt;K-k and dividend* _IL'.'."..___ .TZZZ™Z!.™iIIirZr_'."Z*J.".V~.Z. ll!~&lt;M.&lt;l» Kewrvc fund .... [_ IJMiH ■"""" imiiu .MIU..HI I'ndivided nroflu _ _ _ :t.tW..17 Bills payable _. 7.0W.OO 7.000.00 Total 1 4 W7.7W47 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 •Vkf7.1l lti.0tB.7O •.SUtlK.00 7.740.11* Cash mi band last report Imii-s (running stock i .... Mortitnge payments Interest Fin* s 1IXV.1K Membership nml transfer fw* Itllls parable T.iwaoo Total .Vi..sm.:up MorleiiKi' loans V.i l.TO.nn 7.«7H.!'T io.7ni.il)) Withdrawals running stock nnil dividend* Withdrawals paid up stock Interest paid up »to.-k 7r««i * MJK17H Total SIIM'I.KMKNTAI KKI'oItT I ■rinnnent rian of uHMH-itition •. Numlier of shares &lt;iutstaiulinar last report MB Shares issued since last ri'port •!•• Total tm Shares withdrawn, matured or i-aiicr!le&lt;t siiue last rei»&gt;rt ::m; Numher of share* in force tills date .•.:■..:! Number of share* on which dues are dcliniiueiit SI Numlier of shares sul,j..,i to cancellation for non-pajmrat of dm- AveniKi- ruiinlnc time of stock matured during the year 110 Mo. Number of borrowing atorkholdrrn I. (WE! Nnmlwr of non.l»orrowinii st«»ckin»l»ters 1.30 Nuuit'cr of loans made for building puriMises .liirini: jrrtr Hki 100.00 Par value of each share «&gt;t stin-k * Total amount of dues deliuc|uent at this date moo Amount of due-- owini; by liorrnwiiiK stockholders *«.oo Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 4H.H0 Amount of imtrtcjiu'cs subject tn fore&lt;-losure .-..300.00 kxi .fti-i.on Amount of loanR on improved real pntate Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans harp l&gt;een made lrt.HOO (« Amount of fire insurance in force an&lt;l assixned to the association as collateral security 1 ai.-T00.no nioono.on Amount of tornado insurance in force ajid amiiineil to the a»so«-latlon as collateral security Amount credited to reserve fund diirlnK year liT.On Amount of dividends declared on running sto«k ilurinc year P.1S1.J0 Hate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during T&lt;«r K« ltiite per cent of interest charged iMirroners during year -•4.-,.llU 1.174.17 N.Lliirics- inh'-r cxiM'iiHf tush oil hand </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the •mssr-sua&amp;'S.'rtf-M'x *;.. sx. -." .;z*. ENTERPRISE LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION CAMBRIDGE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President W. H. Faling Vice President R. H. Rankin Secretary D. L. Tallmadge Treasurer ....James Kelly Attorney B. F. Butler DIRECTORS W. H. Faling R. H. Rankin C. M. Brown J. M. Hollingsworth H. H. Moose! H. E. Day H. E. Thorndike D. F. Neiswanger J. M. Hammond ASSETS I'lmt muriicHKi' loans S Sl..T0nm&gt; Loan* nu stfM'k or pins booii miiitkll... 330.00 Liberty I«&gt;«n _ 1.000.00 r.«h :::: _. :. 1.4:17..;.-, U-iimniHiit latgrek; ■»««. He. Z'.'.'. I _■ 1S.4O Tnw paid ' ___________________ i:m:. Total * 34.414.JO LIABILITIES Runninr Rtook and dividend* _ _ J ttMMn Ihip sharebolder* on incomplete lo«nn _ 2TjC.T." K&gt;-Kerve fund ._ S&gt;-42 Iii.iivliled protu ""."".".'.""""J.."...™....™ '.'. !'_..!ZI ~r~'~ZV""~T 4.«is:47 Kill* payable __-._.. _ 2.1JO 00 Taxes received _ 88.70 88. TO Tot«l , t 34.414.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 27 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS I'as'i on band last report - 3 4^M1-")O Dues (running stock) l6..1nft.bo Mortgage payments 17.100.00 Interest .._.___ ____...!!"V™"."...._J"'"."~...... 2.43(182 Klnes _________ _____ _ 22.00 Membership and transfer feee _ _____________ ......._ '.'.."■&lt;i Total „ S J4.R10.7i PISBI RSKMKXT8 Mortgage loans stork loans . . t is.noo.oo 330.00 withdrawal* running stock and dWidends Withdrawals paid-up stock tKJU.UlF 8.XUL00 4.000.00 Withdrawals dividend nn paid-up stock Salaries 1. 402.77 301.00 Otlier expense • 'ash on hand 22« 1.4S7.SB Total t 34.819.7- SIPI'I.EMENTAI, KEPOItT Plan of association Permanent Numlter of shares Issued since organization 1.733 Number of shares nt last reimrt 801 By Error at last re|M&gt;rt ..„ 1 Shares issued since last report .3t2 Total l.lltt Shares withdrawn, matured or ioiiiceiiitd "iiiacc ; iii» npwt 202 Number of sli.ir--s in force this date TO Nnmlier of shares on which due« are delinquent ■2» Average running time of stmk matured during the rear SI Mn. Numl&gt;er of horri)wlni; stockholders n»; nXmher of non-borrowine stockholders .71 Number of loans made for building purposes during icar 1* Par value of each share of stock 9 loom Total amount of dues delinquent at this d.ite 24.00 Amount of dues- owing by borrowing stockholders 24.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 18.40 Amount of loans nn improved real estate :tl..'i00.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare h#*a made M ,a»i.Ni Amount of fire insurance in force aud assigneil to the association as collateral security 4O.0TiO.0O Amount of tornado insurance in force anil assigned to the association an collateral security 4O.IITiO.fl0 44.:iT0.UO Value of improvements Amount credited to re-erve fund dining year 107.28 Amount of dividends paid :ind matured stix-k timing year -..4!f.'.T7 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during rear «-, Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year... W% </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 T\\ LNT^ -SIXTH ANNUAL* REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CENTRAL CITY Bl'ILDINU AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CENTRAL CITY. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President E. E. Roes Vice President R. Tooley Secretary F. K. Sprague Treasurer J. W. Vieregg Attorney E. E. Ross DIRECTORS E. E. Ross R. Tooley J. W. Vieregg P. A. Duffy F. K. Sprague ASSETS Kintt u.orltap- InmiK f 2O.!MO.no Limns nn stork or paws Ixxik wrurity ' " -j.mhi I'hxIi ________ _ 4MMW Iteliiniurnt imprest, flnw. rtr. 4!t7!oo Ulx-rty Loan BondR _______ 2.nbo!(IO Total S 24.«7«.«i I.IAIIII.ITIKS Kunninc Mork anil illvlilrnilx $ lS.!lT"i.T» UcstTVc fund ..........._.'......."..Z.____1.__— l.^W.rv; Ucservc fund l.LW.STi Ilnlivid.il i&gt;rofltK ... VM.m riinniil inti-ri-st ;iii&lt;1 Bin- 4!&gt;7.0() Mills liuvill.il- _______________ 3.H0O.0O Totml _ « 24.«7«.«&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p029">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 i;ki El I' is (ash &lt;&gt;n lianil last report I mi's i running stuck &gt; * 2.7VO.OO 1JMB.TT&gt; Mnrtirace payments Interest Ktnes :C1.7O Membership and tran*cfer (&gt; •— Hills puvatde ."►4 .INI 4.200.01) Ti.tal * MAn I1ISH! KSK Mi: NTS .-.imn.no Mortgage loans StOck lOillls * &gt;««I.(N) Withdrawals running otix-k and ■livi.i. n . I ~ Salaries ii.oii.Tr, 112.30 Other iaimki - «'ash on hand ltllls parable ».» 43».R!&gt; 400.00 .000.00 I.IImtiv Loan Il.in.l~ Interest paid 2.00 Total * ABI8v.1l SITPI.KMK NT A I. It K PORT I'lan of association 1 'ermnne't 2 M Number "f shares outHtandini; la»t re|M)rt Shares issued since last report M Total 1.1» Slnin-s willulra^n. matured or '-ami'lleil sin&lt;-e !;i~r report XiiiiiImt of shares in force rhls tlut" n« HE! NmnlM'r of shares on which i]n»s ;,rc ilellnipit ul ViiiiiImt «»f shares- s-.ibjecl ro canc%'llatii &gt; Ullll»er of l.orrnw inu' stockholders "viiuilier of unn l.orrow inir stockholders .s'limher of loans iimde for nurcltitsinif II for i:.iii |»a\ in. in ..f diif 8 of lii.ln. -lia.U ..r I inmeiit of 4 honiestead-iiiortaratres during &gt;c:ir l';ir value of m&lt; h share of stock Iota' amount of dues delinquent nt thi- Alnounl of dues ouiujr liy liorrowint; st Amount of interest, premiums ami lines * 1IHI ■■•■ S24.OO ■-■O4.00 407.M ilat" (.-kholdcrs due . . fill 1 1 1 1 1 . . 1 1 . 1 Nnnilier anil anniunt of morteases sulijeit to foreclosure. N. Amount of loans on improved real estate 1.400.00 47.100.00 L'4.K"&gt;0.0l&gt; Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare liewi made Amount of Ore insurance in forer and amidied to the association as collateral Amount of tornado iusiinince in force ami :i-sign«l to the amoriation us collateral L&gt;4.&gt;C«.()l&gt; \iii"iiut credited to reserve fund during year ItM Amount of dividends drrlarrd on runnine stock: durlnir year Kate per cent of dividends declared on miiiiiiiiL' stock .InriiiL' year Rate per i-ent of interest charged liorroners dnrilnc year 1. .104 90 M Mt Number of ihtrM Ivwd siprt* organization </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CLAY CENTER Bl'ILDINc; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CLAY CENTER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President E. W. Orr Vice President C. D. Ellis Secretary J. L. Campbell Treasurer J. L. Campbell DIRECTORS J. W. Whitlam L. B. Sluyter N. W. Johnson J. L. Campbell H. B. Campbell Geo. S. Ward ASSETS Firm inorttfaitc loans ~ J 39.04O.0O Limits in MMMM of foreclosure 2.fiO0.(l0 (•tiler ri-»l ewtatc .TOO.OO rush 1.WL22 Ih-limiiicnt intiTcHt. lines, tit !K?7.14 Thxcs and liisiir.-nii'i' nniil 32.STi LilH-rty boada - ■ _ 2.noo.(»i Total t 4«.s31.21 LIABILITIES ltuiiniuir «to&lt;-k and divltlpnds I'aid-uu stock and dlrldcndu $ :il.2Si.H7 11,900.00 lteiwrvi" fund _ _ _ ..." 2.100.00 Indlvtded Droflts paid _ $574.20 I'Ddlrlded Drofltg naid Indlvlded oroHM unpaid 9«1.14 1.541.34 joUl _ _ t 46,831.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 31 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 Snares withdrawn, matured or cancelled sim-e last report 441 Number of shares in force thin date _______ 7»i Numher of shares on which dues arc il ■Ilixillf ut Number &lt;if shares subject to cancellation for non payment of dues 111 IS Averajce runninir time of stock matured during the year 7." Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders 47 Numt&gt;er of non-horrowins: stockholders :a» Number of loans made for purcbastng of homesteads or payment of homeotead-mortei'EPK durinE year i I'lan of premium M.mtlih Par yalue of each share of stock _ _ 4 1U0.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at thin date _ l.m.im I']:m of premium l.SHtX) Amount of dues owing by borrowiug stockholders 1-fOnu Amount of interest, premiums and flues due mil unpaid D7U.14 NuiulH»r and amount of mortgages (nibJtK-t to fi^rwlosure. So. «S .'i.ilOO.oii uNmber and amount of mortgages in pr&lt;»oess of foreclosure. . No. :l •J.OOO im Amount of loans on improved rcnl i.st.:t». 41.iS4O.rt!t Appraised yalue of improved real estate upon which lonns have been made MX.!M).0o Amount of loans on unimproved real estate flOO.OO Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - '....- IB0.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the aaaoctation as collateral security M.4«0.0o as collateral fteenrity Amount of tornado insurance in force and as.-igned to the association as collateral security " &gt;0 ™I!It Amount credited to reserve fund during year S2?? Amount of dividends declared on running stock during jemr 4.:Urfi.74 Rate per nut of dividends declared on running stock during year. Rate per cent of interest charged borrower* during year 8% KM 'Kir*lH rash on ham! last retort Ones i running stuck) _ Paid-up stock MurtffHet- payment* Interest ~ „ Premium - Kincs m Kent* .-._ Mfiiii».T&gt;liln and transfer fees Taxes and insurance repaid Sundries Tot«l * .-i.we.4u ft.«n.2ft 11.:i«m»i 15^00.00 .1.200.H fMK.!r.&gt; 1.7t 17.50 2T&gt;.0O - M.tiO lT.--iil I 44.."137.0!l DISBrKSEMEXTS Mortirniro loans Withdrawal* running »t&lt;x-k and dlTldrnd* 'ominiMston. m other i-xiniisi- | rush on hxmi &gt;»ct.n.l r. S. I.llxrtT b«»dii ;. Total ... _ S MM .■M.0T2.JO «2 »•■ 81.01 1 &lt;*•&gt; •"' 2.0KI.IKI * 44..-K17.0. srPIM.EMENTAL HEI'OUT I'lan of Bxaociatlon Nuiiilicr of »hur&gt;&gt;s outstiiniliiiK last report Slmr«&lt; IkhuciI since last reuurt Total &lt; I... ... . j &gt;»(tk.l&gt;..... ■ « _ . ■■""■"» "~m "IV" '. " " IVrniiiiii'ii. il« 1.14." </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the I'ondition of the COLl'MHI'S LAND LOAN AND lil'lLDINii ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1918 OFFICERS President J. H. Galley rieaiutjui «»• «• uantj Vice President G. W. Viereutz Secretary Henrv Hockenberepr Treasurer H. Chambers H. Chambers DIRECTORS E. P. Dussell Theo. Moersen L. F. Gottschalk C. C. Hardy J. W. Herrod ASSKTS First BMMi loans $ 4."S8.1&lt;KMM) I-oniis nn stock or pass Imok WuWllQ (I.OOO.flll Other real estate 480.WI It. ii I estate aolil on contract 1.1SB.IBI Cash .__..____ ._.„................ IK-Iliniiiciit iuten-st. flnes. efcV"l"iZIIZIIZl__" »4«.W I'. S. I.ilMTty Honils _ _____ 20.110.00 Total ■ $ 475.327.W LIABILITIES Running Mock and iliviilcmls 4 'M\ .400.iL' Paid-up stock anil citviilciuls HU..VXU10 Btnerrr fund - »,3TS.U0 Individwl profits _ ."iO.'.i; Total _..$ 475.327.1!) RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 KKCKII'TS Cash on band last report .. Due" (running stock) t 40.1CM.M 120.012.10 Paid-up stock ___________ 9.900.0U </seg>
            <seg id="p033">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ Plan of asRoclatlOB Perm.m.nl Number of series Issued since ortrnniiation. up to time of .-hani-. - to Permanent plan 2T&gt; Nnmher of sharen Issued since orKaniution JS3.47S Niimlter of shares outstanding lust report . 1O.H77» Shnrps Issued since last report 1 WC Total 12.B37 Shares withdrawn, matured or can&lt;-«lle&lt;l since last liijiiwl 2.230 Number of shares in force this date 10.407 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent IWt Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dnen .102 Average runnine time of stock matured dnrine the year, old plan HRMi months, new plan IIS to 120 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders _ 274 Number of non-borm wing- stockholders 387 Number of loans made for huildinc mirnose* during year Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of home-stead mortgages during year 32 Par value of earn share of rtork _ 4 10000 home-stead mortgnges during* year 100 00 Total amount of dnen delinquent at this date 4.421.2* Amount of dues owtnjr by borrowing stockholder* _ 4.421.2(1 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid X1«i.ft* Number nnd amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. Ni&gt;. IS 30.20000 Amount of loans on improved real estate 427.300.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate anon which loans have been made !M!&gt;.200.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 10.80O.M Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made 1R..T00.00 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 3nft.4A0.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned t« the association as collateral security _ MUJMtiM Amount of money loaned on Improved farms 2..T00.00 Appraised value of lor.d not Including improvement* 2.^80.00 Value of improvements 2.000.0n Amount of fire insurance thereon 1.400.** Amount of tornado Insurance thereon 1.400.00 Amonnt credited to reserve fund during vear 1.420.30 Amount of losses* chaiged to reserve fund during vear 100.00 Amonnt of dividends declared on running stock during year 22.2*14. !&gt;3 Amount of dividends paid on matured and nald-up stock during year .1.314. .10 Rate per cent of dividends declared on mnnlng stock during year ft 1 -,, r / Rut* ner cent &gt;,f dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dur ing year Ml Rate per cent of interest charged borrower* during Tear — • €-W% Mnrteaec payments Stock loan payments Keal estate sales Interest .... ... Interest from bank _ - Fines Interest from Liberty Hnnds _ _ Membership and transfer fMMi _. Installments on Liberty Bonds _ _ Insurnnfv premiums ..' Mortenee foreclosures Totnl I....: 'a.im.00 .'...'.'.'.' K.43S.26 MUI 1.2SO.1S .isn..-ii( mar, 40.00 4.m».~. lMKIHItSKMKXTS Mnrtgiice loans _; Stork loans Withdrawal* running stork and dividend*.! Withdrawals mild -up stork Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock .... Salaries Other expense Renl estate account Cash on hand „ Interest refunded I S. I.llierty Bonds . __. _._ Insurance premiums Mortgage foreclosures _____ Reserve fund f 11S.000.00 -.noo.on 133.1S7.41 24.ono.oo XSMM 3.RM.W1 ..: 41R.fB» J4S.2« \vn» 13..17 1.-&gt;.1.V).00 so.3&lt;; mt.m loo.on Total _ • * 3is.am.n SrPTT.KMFNTAL KKPl •OR! </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 TWENTY SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President ..Henry Ragatz W. A. Boettcner Vice President Secretary ..J. C. Echols G. B. Speice Treasurer Attorney Louis Lightner DIRECTORS Henry Ragaiz W. A. Boetlcher J. C. Echols G. B. Speice Louis Lightner Loiiu* on Mark or aaaa liook wiurity iiilur nil! patatr Total LIABILITIES Uunniiik' stuck nnil dividends PaM-ap atack and dlrldendH Hi'st-rvr fund $ 231.025.Hi 2."7.(«O.OO 11. 837. IS I'lidiriilitl profits «58.24 Total _ $ 501,420.01 EQHTABLK I*riLI)IN&lt;J. LOAN AND 8AVING8 ASSOCIATION ASSETS First MMpgl Ion us • •nxti 1 &gt;i-liu&lt;i*i!'in inlvri'Mt, flue* etc. I S. I.il.irtv lt.»n&lt;l» </seg>
            <seg id="p035">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE KE&lt; Cash nu hand last, report Inn— i r u ii ti i i iir stockl 30,402.10 77..V.i7.7'.i tN.ooa.oo l'ntd -up stm k Mortgage payments ■lack loan payment* Interest im.4tw.uo 1. XUO.OII 1.87ilO Hues Knits ■111'. 7" 372.30 Mvnbervhlp ami transfer I . s. Liberty llomls .v&lt;i k .-..n.'i.on Interest on deposit .VJI.sk Interest mi I I Lliierty Mnn.l Taxes paid MB.38 llO.trr Total ■J!il.:xo..&gt;* 1I1SIU1 Mortgage l"an stin-k loans K7.4TiO.0O l.-JNI.KP ■STi.l'.H.T.'. 52.73040 l.-p£SS.:M) J.'.ll!M!l Withilrawals nniiiini; stock anil dlvlden Withdrawal!) pald-ap stock Withdrawals iliviili'inl mi imu.I up stock Salaries Commissions UtlliT e.Xpell l.-rfi.fl»! nn.oii Keal i-statf ari-iiuut Casu on hanil BN8.12 14.457..% Intrri-Nt ri-turneil ... I S. I.iliert.v llomls 81.20 11 IKMII Total SIl'I'l.KMK.S l'lan •&gt;( association ■rtnati' .Nntulirr of shares issued shin- nriranizatii XUIK Number of shares ciitstainlin^ last report 11.X7S Shares issueil sine" last report _'._'|:l Total H.ll'l Shares witiiiirann. maliireil ,.r .-anrplled -iiM last report NuiiiIkt of shares in force this &lt;latc 4411 1 , ll.CiBS, Xumlier nf shares ,m whii-h dww .ire ili'lin&lt;|iieiit : jt;l Xumlter of shares snljeet to i-aneellation for noil-payment of il Averaire rninini.' time of stock inatureil ilurinK the vear Niiinlier of liorroniui.' stockholders IIS 113 Mo. ::tl XiiuiIht of mom horn. wint stockholders m Nunilier of loans maiie for Imildinir purpiif durtnic &gt;.-ar U Nunilier of loans iiiaile for |.ur&lt; lia-tinir of home steads or pavnmit i»f homesteail-inortjrayes during year : . t. 1 Par value of eacli share of stock * Km 111 Total anionnt of dues' delliniiieut at this ,|-,tr Ainoiint of dues owtag hy liorrowintr stockholders Amount of interest, premiums anil tines due anil unpaid 4.733.13 I.7S3.1.1 .1104.4.-. NumlitT and amount of mortmain** sulijeet to forei-losure. No. Is Amount" of loans on improved real estate in.7os.oo it::.:a«).fNi Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have Iwen made DIUMMN Amount of loans on unimproved real eKiatt* T.JOd.m) Appraised value of unimproved real estate ii|tou which loan* have tiwn made _ lX.fSTiO.Ot&gt; Amount of fire iiisurani-e in fonv anil assigned to the a»MN-iatton as i-ollateral Ml mil j H.-.l.-iO.iW Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the a— •■•• iatimi as eollateral &lt;ii iiritv ::Tr..2.V}.llll Aiuount credited to reserve fund durum yiiir 1.44HK1M-. I2.T63.TC i.-..j.v&gt;.-j; .1 ill • • 1 1 ill vi»imi&gt;i i« ■ ■ m ■ v v- iii.ni 'mi ins ,iiiu . . Amount of dividends diilared on runnim: stock durini; year Alwiuut of dividends paid on matured and paid up stoi-k durinir year Kate per .em of dividends' declared on riinuiut; stock during year Hate per cent of dividends iMtil on matured and full paid stock during «' «', year Rate per cent of interest charted borrowers during year 7 i-5'; $ a»i.»n..-iK </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL. REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION CRETE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Geo. H. Hastings Vice President P. J. Rademacher Secretary W. S. Collett Treasurer W. S. Collett Attorney Geo. H. Hastings DIRECTORS B. G. Miller E. M. Parker E. J. Steidl Geo. H. Hastings W. S. Collett R. R. Hastings (One Vacancy) V. J. Shebl F. J. Rademacher ASSKTS First mortgage loan* _ _ $ 111.500.00 l.onns on «i.M-k &lt;&gt;r imihk lM&gt;ok security 2J60.0U Canl. 274.98 IMIii&lt;ir&lt;ut inu-rcKt. fine*, etc _.'.' 1S8.97 Ih'liiniiK-iil illleH 112..T0 112..10 Till snlc i-trtifleatrs 4SI1.I7 Insuri nit- imlil ii&lt;- it 302.12 Total $ 115.214.84 MAIUMTIRS Runninc Mock and dividends $ 107.274.6!) Dvc&gt; sliurf!M)lders I *»n incomplete loans 510.S1 Keaerve fun.l .__ 2.M&amp;.30 I n. I ivl, :.-,! profit* _: _ _ ;:. 17.04 Ortllicat.- of iDdebtednesi (Mat itock).... ....'. 4,747.00 Total % 115,214*4 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 37 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RKf EIPTS Cash on hand last report Dues (running stock) 4 MM 21.2S2.0O Mortgage payments ... ____________ 1R.010.00 Stock loan payments Interest 4.10.00 7.144.02 Finos _ 71.SR Membership and transfer fees 14.00 Tar sales and Insurance , ' ' ,' 1.001.S* In-omplotc loans _ 1.3A1.90 l.sm.no Crrtiflcntes- of tadebt*dii»~"(ltat"»t«iS)_..~V~J~"JlV™l!I!3™L^™™ 4.747.00 Total $ 54.302.18 PISIIIKSK mi:nts Mortgage loans $ S.1S».2O Stuck loans mo.oo Withdrawals running stock and dividends 37.912.7T. Salaried _. Other expense 4S0.00 «49.«4 Cash on hand 274.9« Insn ranee and tax gales 972.00 Incomplete loans 1.813.41 rertlfloates of Indebtedness (Mat. stock R.700.00 Total » M.S02.1* SIPPI.EMKNTAL REPORT Plan of association Serial Nuinlier of aerie* Issued si»ce T""l'l" 111 ■ _ '« Number of shares issneil sine organization fl.007 Number of shares ..ntstin.llrit' last report _ S.tMO Shares issued since l«st report Total "' '" ,, s.!&gt;77 Shares withdrawn, m.-itnr.il or ivmci'llcfi winct- lust n*|»ort ■- . -^R" Number of sh.ircs in foriv this ilntc 3 SSB Number of shares on wliich (lues nrc ilclln&lt;iii*-nt 117 Averaire rminlnc- time of sto&lt;|t mntureil ilnrinir the year 1+0 Mo. Viimhtr of t&gt;orrowinji stockholders .* „ I7(s Number of mm -borrowing stockholders VJS 191 Number of loans made for Imildlne imrposi-. ilurlnK yc:ir 1 Number of loans made for iHirdcislng homi-stends or ii.iyincnt of homestead-mortjraffes during yo:ir 1 t*i»r v:ilue of t'jich «hnre of stock $ lOOOn 'IVr.il amount of dues tlcliunuent »t this dnte li2..*i0 Amount of dues nwi«i" »»v borrowing sto*^*!©!!!*'!^* 11**..V&gt; Amount of interest unil fnes due and unpulil ia«."7 Amount of lonns on iiiturnvwl real estate lll..Vp0.0n Apprmlwd \-.\hw &lt;1 Inniroved real estate upon which lo.m« harr been made 2W.4OO.()n Amount of tire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1.TO.T70.00 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security lin.IWOno Amount credited to reserve fund durllna- year 40B.41 Amount of dividends declared on running- stcck during- vear r&gt;.«7R.0O Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year S.7« Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year . «l% </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the DAVID CITY BUILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION DAVID CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President W. F. Delaney Vice President S. J. Hyatt Secretary G. A. Bryant Treasurer John F. Eberly Attorney R. C. Roper DIRECTORS John F. Eberly W. F. Delaney G. A. Bryant C. F. Clark S. J. Hyatt H. F. Anderson B. J. Sheldon C. D. Ammon J. B. Hookstra ASSKTS Kirxt innrtitaKr loan* » 07.100.1I0 Loans on xto&lt;-k or pass book xwiirlty ('null 142.00 .-...•KH.OH Total $ 102JMJM I.IAHII.ITIKS Kiiniih.e stock aod ilirhlroiU _ % 27.1M..V. Paiil m, »l««k uiKl ilivldciiils 1A:Xt2.TC, Dm- slinn-lMililiT* on incomplete loans ..._ 210.00 HeiuTTi- funil . "iSO.l" llem-m- fund .___..____ __ 180.17 in.llvi.i,-.! profliM .... 30H.lt; Snri-iv Inv. t'd. i-oiuiuiKKlona not paid 53.70 Total * 102,636.09 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 39 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING Plan of association Permanent NiiiiiImt of sharex ontstamlini; last report 2.10n.7T» Shares issued siiwe lust ir|M&gt;rt . ... 1 SIS 4:t Total ."1922.1ts Kharea withdrawn, mature. I or caneelled since last report 7»BI.£1 Nniulier of shares in force thin date I1MM Niinil.er of shares on whi.h dues are delinquent ji&gt; Nunil.er of shares subject to eauiellatlon for imhi payiuent of dam. ... Jo Number of borrowing MackboMcn . &gt;&lt;i Xumlier of non borrow Iiik stockholders . 1«7 Number of loans made for building purpokex Ibis year 42 Nunibetr of loans made for purchasing "f homei«te»d« »r payment of homet*te«d-bortgaKes during year IK Plan of premium, per share rtD Par value of each share of stock $ Mtfi Total amount of dues delin(|iient at this date _Vd im Plan of premium. Amount of duett owintf by borrowing stockholders !m1Ai Amount of interest, premium* and dues due and unpaid MLM Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreolomire, So. I Amount of loans on improved real estate _____ !.... 97.100.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loan* nave l&gt;een made 1 (M.I 30.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ _ 120.flm.00 Amount of tornado Insurance in force and axrlnned to the aaaactatton as collateral security _. .Vt.UOO.OO Amount credited to reserTe fund during year _ 2SS.17 Amount of dividend-* declared on running stock during year 1.874.11 Amount of dividends paid on matured and pi:ld up stock during year 2.428.14 Rate per cent of divinens ecdlared on running stock during year "W Rate per cent of dividends paid ou matured and full paid stock during .-.war «&lt;- Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during ye«r 9% .-year j » -&gt; r. ■&gt;■'. i7io RECEIPTS Tash on hand lnat rpport _ 1 Hit's i rtimiinir stork i „._ ['Mill Up stark M'Ttliilllr 1 1; I &gt; Ilii 'II I H st«M*k lomi payment* Interest _ Fines Meiul&gt;erslitp nnd transfer fee» _ Notes jiuynlilf _ _ Protest fevs returned Over mill wliiirt Toui seooo i-.il&gt; ___ '' J6,rc 44S.15 10.000.0l&gt; 2.04 1.80 $ 121.MW.27 DISHrllSKMKNTS Mortt-aBo loans Stuek loans _ Withdrawals running st&lt;M*k and divldpnds _ „ NN'ii lulrawalH paid up stin-k ... _ _. Withdrawals dividend on paid up stock Sniiiries _ &lt; 'iiiiiuiissious „ (Illiie posture llilviineeil, (tc _ .".""'. """." ' ish mi hand .. ._ Interest paid on notps _ ~ Collection fw» Hills payable repaid _ Total t .'.1.9W.80 210 00 .1.1.-V4.0TI MM4.SK 1.028.SC im.M 277.80 JM.--I .■...■BH.OU Bas.rtx 273.IK 23.500.00 f 121.358.27 8UPPLKMKNTAL REPORT </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL, REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of tbe Hl'ILDINC! &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRF1ELD, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President C. L. Lewis Vice President Wm. Ashby Secretary P. Anawalt Treasurer F. Anawalt DIRECTORS J. E. Spatz Walter Hogue Wm. Ashby Wm. Hoevet C. L. Lewis F. Anawalt ASSETS First mortgage loans . .. $ 43.5TiO.00 iH&gt;2.3f&gt; Other real estate Real estate sold on contract ~ _ _ _ 500.00 ra»h "~~ 1,058.86 Taxes paid _______________________________ 106.2V* Liberty — «^4» 1.000.00 Total „ t 47.208.") LIABILITIES llunninc stock and dividends I 29.822.10 l'ald up stock and dividends .._ _ 13^00.00 kaaw-t fund _ _ 2.000.00 2.000.00 I'lKl'vlded profltB .._. . 2,032. W Other liabilities _______ ._ _ _. H.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 41 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS Cash on hand lait report - f 3. 732-00 Pues ( running stock) ___..._._..V.~"Z'.......I!.1"~. 4.864.00 Mortgage payments _ - '.'".'.'....... «.36o!o» Heal eslatf -airs „ flfi..V&gt; I lite rest ~ .. 4..*V7!t.7'_' Fines „ „ _ „ 3It.io Kcnts 37.00 Ml-Kll»-rslli|, _ 28.75 Taxes, insurance, abstracts and recorders fees 238.40 Total t 19.974.41 DISBIRSEMEXTS Mortgage loans _.. _ $ 4,000.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividends... _ ."."...".'.'....".".".!.'. 11.392.10 Withdrawals paid-up stock _ '400!w» Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock 846.80 Salaries „ .T11.00 other expense .T7.21 Real estate account - — - 631.22 rash on hand _ 1.0SK.M Taxes. Insurance, abstract and recorders' fees 197 K Liberty Bonds ....' ' S 8 Tr.till * 19.974.41 SfPPI.KMKNTAI. HKI'IIHT I'lan of iissocintion Permanent Number of share* issued since organization 2.071 Number of shares outstanding last report dj» shares issued since last report Total _ shares issued since last report .. *n Total _ ; ; :...:.:".:. .. w. Shnres withdrawn, matured or cancelled since l«st report 12n 1» Xumlier of shares in force this datp ________ 77« Number of shares on which due) 1 are delinquent 32 NuinlxT of ohari-s subject to cancellation for nonpayment of does 28 Average running time of stock matured during the year 93 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders " 61 Number of non-borrowing stockholders ..._...... 46 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 4 Number of loans made for purchasing of homestead's or payment of homestead-mortgages during year T Par value of each shi re of stock Par value of each shire of stock _ f loniii Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 373.85 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders _ 375.39 375 JO Amount of interest, premiums and fines doe and unpaid 26B.0R Ajiiiujui vi luicitvi. iiiruiiiuu&gt; nun uitr* uiii- ami uu|ibiu iw.un Kumber and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 5 2.400.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 43.580.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made 98.6W.00 Amount of fire Insurance in force and asvlgned to the association as collateral security S2.100.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security M.000.00 Amonnt credited to re?.erve fund during year BUI Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 3.STO.S4 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year PMkSI Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during ye«r n% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dur- ing year Rnte per' cent of interest charged borrower., dnrllng rear K} </seg>
            <seg id="p042">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OP THE 42 STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME BUILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION' FALLS CITY. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President J. H. Hutchings Vice President R. R. Rule Secretary W. L. Redwood Treasurer W. A .Greenwald Attorney R- C. James DIRECTORS J. H. Hutchings R. R. Rule W. L. Redwood W. A. Greenwald P. B. Weaver ASSETS First wort gam- loans $ 4s..".l.-,.((: i I.nnns on stork or p»ss book security "....!...!!'. .... iso!on Other real estate 2.747^72 Cash _ - - 3.11R.02 Delinquent Interest, line*, etc ________ 22s!20 Taxes paid and insurance 237^74 r. 8. War Stamps - 412!of) I'. R. I.llM&gt;rt.v Bond* iwcoimI lssm-i _ 4.(Mo!nn Total * al.438.0K LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends % r&gt;1.244.24 aPld-up stock and dividends ...................!....!! s!l25!6t) Reserve fund l!ftOR fM&gt; S.12S.0O I'ndlvlrted profit* Z__I____________.'. 232!_S t uulTiiieu pruuiB T2 iin Delinquent Interest ________ 228.20 Total _ _ | 61.438.SS </seg>
            <seg id="p043">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 43 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1918 Plan of assoi'iation Permanent XumlKT of shares issm-d winre i.rKauixation :'&gt;.7T.7V 4 Xuinlier i.f shares KiitstandiuK last report .... 1 91KU, Shares issued sliu-e last report 1W% Total 2.03S% Shares withdrawn, matured or lanifllid sllii&lt; v last report 3M Xnml.er of shares in fonv this date 1.R4H4 XumlM»r nf shares on which dnew are delinquent 277 Xuinl.i'r of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dam 55 Xuiiit.er of tmrrowiujc stockholders 114 Xuinber of non-borrowing stockholders 90 XumlH*r of loans nuidi* for purduisiim of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortjcages during year 9 l'nr value of each share of stock $ inniii Total amount of dues delinquent at this datt 2.000.00 Amount of dues owing l.y l.orrowiujr stockholdcm Amount of interest, i.rcmiiiius miiiI ilius due anil unpaid l.liw.mi ■-"JS.2O Xumber ami amount of inort*::i»res sul»Jei-t to foreclosure No. 2 2.000.011 Amount of loans on improved real estate 4S.000.I10 A|.j&gt; raised value of improved real eslate U|K&gt;n which loasn kilTr Ihvii made • 100.000 00 Amount of loans &lt;&gt;n unimproved real estate 31S.M Appraiseil value of unimproved real estate upon which loam* have l&gt;een made l..Vi0.0» \moiint of lire insuram-e in fori-e and assigned to the anxorlatlon as collateral security ni..VW.0n Amount of tornado insiiram-e in force and assigned to the asnooiation as collateral security tR.000.OD ate per cent of dividends' declared on running stock during year - Hate per c«'iit of dividends paid ou matured and full paid stork dur - ing year rt'.' Kate iier 'int of Interest charged l.orn.wers during year nil-; TITS'E a&lt;»-&lt; aujjnp thhb .Iuiuimu no poj»|.wp spa^p|A|p ;o lanoinv IMITT-1 credited to ri serve hind during year 26 amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during rear v«; .to ii r a rjn^ rash on hand last report — IMieK i running stock* . 1'uiil-iip stock Mortnar paratrata Stork loan payments „ Iteal i-state sales 1 in i&gt;r*&gt;st Kcnts M^liilMTwhip anil transfer ft?e« l'rnflts on withdrawals Taxes ami Insurance _ .. Lojm f&lt;t*s Total t B..W2..V1 10..SW..V. 275.00 7.4."iO.OO .-&gt;03.0r) 2S0.00 4.083.7R r&gt;7.00 17.00 249.82 403.57 38.2S t 3L399.07 DISBIItSKMEXTS Mortgage loan* stock loans Withdrawal* running stock anil dividend* _ Withdrawal* paid-ap st«M'k Withdrawals dividenil on paid-up stork _ Salaries ( &gt;ther ex penHe Flea lesijite account _ .'ash on hanil V. S. Ubertjr Hi. nils __ I'. S. War Stamps _ 1 iiliiKj Mint taxes and insurance Total $ S.S33.30 1&gt;«.00 14.0».(U )«0.00 4ML40 470.00 108. 2T, 141. 15 .■U18.02 4.000.00 412.00 311.11 ..$ Sl.390.07 SI I'l'I.KMKNTAI. KKI'OItT </seg>
            <seg id="p044">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 44 STATEMENT of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT, NEBRASKA on the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Frank Hammond Vice President Frank Fowler Secretary Arthur Truesdell Treasurer Chas. B. Vsazie Attorney Geo. L. Loomis DIRECTORS Fred Bader Fred H. Richards James A. Donahue Frank Hanlon ASSKTS First imirtKuei- loans I...iins on sunk or puss book security fash t ""u -.„ IMlnnuent Interest, liner, etc Eirnlture and fixtures lKTt.v Itnll.ls it of balance Total LIABILITIES Running mock and dirtdend. _ t 244J07.M l'uiil up stork and dividends 28.9B6.74 t 244J07.M Reatrve fund "■"■I..l'.7//.'-""'.'."'.'-".'-'-"IIII-J 5.800.00 I ndlvided tTHJ** 754^63 Total — f J80.018.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS Cash on haml last report IMies (running mock) t o.w-.oi iu.TM.nn I'nlil -mi stock fl.2BO.0o Mortgage payments Stock loan payments Interest 31.flOO.00 435.00 1H.SW.3S Fines 14!UO Mi-iiiti.T-hii. Mini transfeer fees Other receipts In detail 1H0.00 3.91O1 Total t 134.&lt;W1 43 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans „ _ $ S3.fi00.0fl Withdrawals running stock and dividends" _. 48.029.71 Withdrawals paid-up stock ~~7_!VZ1Z~'.""!.""I!.".""™I.".I!!...". 11.0H0.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stork l.CMJB Salaries 1.200.00 other exiK-nse ._........ _ U5.3B Cash on hand \ 10.123.41 other ilisliursementii in detail . V ...Z.Z..Z.""~"—- 4.906.71 Liberty Konds ZlZ^'^l^^ZL7~~ZZ~Z~Z"S/~—'.S....-'"~~. 3.000.00 Total f 134. mi. 4:i SfPPLKMENTAL REPORT Plan of association {serial or permanent) Both Number of series issued since organization Number of shares outstanding last report 2JW*4 4rt shares issued since last report 738% Total MM ShareR withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report **S Number of shures Inforce thin date MSO 1^ Average ninniiiL- time of stock matured during the year 11!&gt; Mo Number of borrowing stockholders 20ft Number of non-borrowing stockholders 24S Number of loans made for building purposes during year — . • Nuinlier of loans made for purchasing of homesteads nr payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ 43 Par value of each share of stock _ 9 200.00 Amount of interest, premiums and fines doe and unpaid l.;V45..V» Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure, No. 14 2.441. &gt;c. Amount of loans on improved real estate _ 283.700.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hare been made _ 41.000.000 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 272.500.00 Amount of tornado insurant— In force and assljrned to the ■aanctatinn as collateral security 201.000.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year £00.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1.~i.2MI..~&gt;2 l.-i.2WI..-i2 .tllli'uui vi in&gt; iiit-iki ~ tinmii'i ■&gt;■■ iuuniiik ww» illirillK J»"«r l.l.^*ni.«i_ Amount of dividends paid on matured and pald-1111 stock daring year 1.A1A.2A Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year f9 Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - 'i^r Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers dnrilng ye«r ______ 7 2-10% </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 TWENTY SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NKMRASKA STATE IHILDINd AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President T. L. Mathews Vice President Secretary Ross L. Hammond D. D. Rowe Treasurer Attorney . J. T. May W. J. Courtright DIRECTORS T. L. Mathews J. T. May Chas. H. Hawley Dan V. Stephens E. R. Gurney Ross L. Hammond W. J. Courtright D. D. Rowe Paul Colson Paul Colson First ntorteajrc loans * 2.11S.0O.-..OO 1 -• ■ : 1 1 1 ~- iii nr&lt;MfHH of foreclosure 7.0R2 it I.oiins on slock nr |M l&gt;ook security ihIht n i nl estnte 1,. -ino.no 11JH6JV4 i«.rw.K 5.&lt;M4.4n 51.000.00 t 2.S14.7ffi.2-.' Tolnl LIAI' Kunninfr Rto&lt;-k and divi«l«'iMls Paid-un Kto&lt;&gt;k Htiil dividends 7di.400.0O Dm sliiirtliolilcrs cm Inromnlete loans !i.r.lo.(Ni liesfnc fund ..V..........»___;.....^:....!!. 44.'riO0.(iO I"ndivl«!&lt;Ml profit!' iM.-V.'rt.iMi Hills nayalilp 40.000.00 Tntrrest to cover dellniiaenry .-i,944.4ti Total $ 2.214.765.22 ASSKTS -'.'.&gt;77&gt;s (■■■ta !&gt;• liii.iih in Intrtvxt. flue*, etc r. S. Ubnty Honda ILITIF.S * 1.279.88S.SIS </seg>
            <seg id="p047">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 47 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 KKC KII Cash on han, I last report Duen i rim ti in lt stock) ... nn.7SK!M W0.3WCW JHS.MM.00 :b«t.,ti«2.ii 10,014.21 14'.i.:a-j.ti; i'aid-ui* stock Morteairc payments Keal estate sales, nuts. .i&lt; Interest Profit on real estate sale Fines anil forfeitures Metiiliersliin and loan fee: Hills payable .'.Tysc, :!.43O..-« llll««l.«. 7.2iS7.ss 41.985.41 FnreelOslire :|. . ..II lit Incomplete loanH Total n»:..r&gt;4 :i DISMRSK ■■Hill loans Slock loans ■ ;«:■. i-Hi '«i .'UO.Otl Withdrawals rininiiiir stock anil dividend* Withdrawals paid up atacfc :Ui;..&gt;k.»t Hi.4oi.im .•ai.iV7n.2-l Withdrawals dividend on patd-np st'N-k Salaries '.(■.iii.no ."■.747.4:1 Commissions Posture, lent, etc. U -:il estate aeronnt Cash un hand .l.-'Wt.m 8.927.7Ti 41.7»i.M .-•l.tNM.on IMvideiids on runnhiL' sunk IniiMiiplete loans r. s. Liberty Itonds Korei-losure aei-onut 7.M3JM Examination and traveliini; «i»n 2.S.-1.-1.41 Total n»;..r.t ::t sri'i'i.KMKvr I'lau of association •erniani'iit I'nknnwn NnuilMT of sharps issiunl mare "reantxallon XiimlxT of shares otitstandine last report 4».141 Shares issued since last re|&gt;ort 12.."»&lt;iK Total in. Tin 0..-.7K S2.1.T1 Shares withdrawn, matured or canceihnl since last rv|x»rt Nuniher of sliares in for&lt;-«' tliis date Average rnnnine time of stock matured iluiing tb«' re«r N'umlKT of horrowing stiwkholderM Of. Mo. IJStP 2.142 Number of non-borrowine stockholdirs Number nf loans made for buildinc purposes durti's yi^ar Xumher of loans made for purchasing of homesteails or payment of M hitiiesti'i.d -mortcairi's durine yar Par value of each share of stoek m * inn on Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid Number and amount of lnortuajfes subject to foreclosure Number and amount of m^rtsraues 1 in process of forecloruse Amount of loans on improved rfwl "state .-&gt;.!H4.4H 21.2SO9O 7.0N2.47 :.jm.rA"..nn Apprais*'d vilue of improved real estate upon which loans have been made 4.104..1flO..-iO Amount of fire Insurance in for&lt;v and ■aatajawa' to the association an collateral security 2.424..V«.-i.on Amount of tornado insurant in force anil nsslcned to the association as collateral se* .iritj* 2.414.420.00 Amount credited to reserv-- 1 fund during year tJSMJW 2.144 ..V&gt; !»2.244.4R Amount of losses chnreed to reserve fund dnrlnir ve.ir Amount of dividends declared on runninar stock during rear Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock dnrtnr Tear Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock I'nrintr year Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock durine m.na.24 «-; IK- year Kate per cent of Interest chanted borrowers daring- rear </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 STATEMENT "TO of the condition of the EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION GRAND ISLAND, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Chas. Q. Ryan Vice President _ Richard Goehring Secretary C. W. Brininger Assistant Secretary John A. Ferguson Treasurer S. N. Wolbach Attorney Jas. H. Wodley DIRECTORS R. J. Ban- R. R. Horth August Kruse Guy L. Harrison August J. Baumann L. T. Geer ASSETS First mortgage loani $ 882.200.00 Loans on stock or pass book security 11,100.00 t 882.200.00 Real estate, ofllce __.....ZZZZZZZZZZ 12.'o0o!oO Cash _ 11,597.08 11.507.08 Delinquent interest, linen, etc _ __ _ (BOOR ii-iiii. I m- ii i luirimi, uiim, rw., thPFli.) Taxes paid 823.33 Liberty ItnmlK i.ii'trtv unmix ie.ono.no r. S. War S-ivlncs Stamp* 533.00 5.13.00 Mtg. loans settlement balances ,,, " 4.151.3n Total f 089.054.82 LIABILITIES Running stork and dividends $ T25.926.90 Paid in. stork anil dividends ZZZZZZ.ZZZZZ.Z.Z 170.800.00 Due slmreholderN on incomplete loans ...'"!]"1!"!!!Z.". 40o!oo Keserve fund _ ZZZl'ZZZZZZZZZV 3»J55O;0O Undivided proflts ZZZZZZZZZZZ l3t7'.57 Interest paid in advance , ~ 430.8S To** 1 - * 869.064.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 49 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 REf EIPTS Cash on hand lam report t 14.2M.4« Due* i miming stock) 224.048.80 Paid-up stock ..„ 28.500.00 MorteftKe payment* S2.706JS(i Stock loan payments ......7". _ 4.!t*tft.9i Inter* st _ .. ."»7.406.ln Fines * S0B.7S Membership and transfer teem 10.20 Fines lb:2O RentB and nDIrr lnill.line receipts _ 420.00 npniH iillil nm&lt;v iiuikudk re«*eiins _ __ _ 1&gt;:i viiii-iits on settlement balance accounts 4.371.50 Tnt. on Liberty Bond" and W. S. 8. w&gt;\a _. 708.4* Tax sales redeemed .'*3.2O Total » 418.5W.82 DIsnrHSEMENTS MortiriiBi- loan* * 21.1.100.00 .norTeajfc loans • ;riw.w Stock loiins .. 3.700.00 MOcK loans .... .... .... a,iw.iiu Withdrawals run nine stock and dividend* 87.178.98 Withdrawals pnld-up stock I""IZ'Z-'1*...*".".".'...._Z 29.400.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock .... SSS PlvliUnds paid on paid-up stock — B.MfcflB iMvnu-nns paia on paiti-up siock — *».*■»■■■».»■ Salaries 6.473.30 Other expense ''3192 Real estate account - .%37.15 Real estate account kchi enaip account - .nx.i.&gt; Cash on hand _.. _ - ll.39T.0g tiisn on rianu _^ _. „ }}-'rl±!£ Liberty Bonds and W. 8. Stamps ll.djB.T7 Liineny hoihis nna v* . n. ittanpn u.wk-ii Matured shares paid -.. 43J5O0.0O Tax Rales purchased ,. 430.01 Total ...,, • 418.88T.82 SI PPLEMENTAL UKPORt 1'lan of association _ Permatteht Number of shares issued *inee orMnixatlon All matured Number of shares issued since orsanliatinn 108.JSB Numl&gt;er of shares outstandlnE last report 2S.TSS l'lilll of association .^uiiiricr ui snares issiiiM] since orKUiiixaiion Nuinber of shares ontstandlnE last report .Milliner in snares ouismmiiUK lasi rei»&gt;n i.». i^r» Shares Issued alnce last report *M&amp; Total 2H.pi Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report — 5.»44 Number of shares in force this date 23.412 Total .*iiiiiiit-i vi nuairn 111 iviir mis unir — — «.^»— Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Ill Average rnnnlnsr time of stock matured during the yeinr..... ."....Serial 80 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing- stockholders LOOT Number of loans made for building purposes during; year It Number of loans made for purchasing- of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortg'ng'eH during* year Par value of each share of stock _ Z} 100.00 Amount of interest, premiums and tines dne and unpaid flMMH Amount of loans on improved real estate S79.609.0i ffiO.OK Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loan* haw beca made 1.3WI.3no.nn mane i^n»ri..vi».f^i Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 2.000 00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - 8.4»0.at Amount of ire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security M2.4M.St Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 7JHUM.J5 Amount of money loi.ned on improved farms •,080.00 Appraised value "f land not inclu line Improvements 9.000.00 9.000.00 Value of improvements . 1.000.00 \ mue or improvements i.wjw.wj Amount of lire insurance thereon „ flOOOO Amount credited to reserve fund during* vear 2. 700.00 Amount of dividends declared on running* stock during* year 3A.50R47 2.700.00 AIIMiillll oi lllVMieilil** un inrni wu ruuuiui wi'wn nuriiiK .*"r«i w**vrt.-r i Amount of dividends palil on matured and paid-up stock durlnr year 1O,075.1» Rate per cent of dividends declared on running* stock daring* year. •* Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock daring* Rate per cent of Interest charred borrowers dorliaa* year «■«% </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL, REPORT OF THE STATEMENT On the 30th day of June, 1918 HARTIXUTOX WILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HARTINGTON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS OFFICERS President President M. E. Eby Vice President Vice President H. D. Spork Secretary Secretary F. O. Robinson Treasurer W. S. Weston Treasurer DIRECTORS DIRECTORS M. E. Eby W. S. Weston J- G. W. S. Weston G. S. Scoville J. G. Beste M. E. Eby H. D. Spork H. D. Spork G. S. Scoville ASSETS ASSETS First mortgage loans 4 106,2."iO.0&lt;&gt; First iiiort^ujr** loans Loans on Mock or pass book security 230.00 I. "jtiis on stork or paKR bonk mM'iirlty stHti- junl inunipiral securities Slate anil niunlpl.n] securities ."jOO.OO State mill niunici|ial securities - - 3.077.3T State «n&lt;l municipal sfcurlties - - C ahn — ~- fiD.70 Itellniiiient intereHt. flnex. etc riOO.OO fifl.70 I&gt;i'liti.|i:&lt;'ii&gt; intiTHXt. fine*, etc lHliii.|i]ent iuterpBt. flnw. etc Knrultnrc hihI fixtures }''n fuil n re it ml fixtures ill ."0 lx-limine'it &lt;1upr _. Total _ $ 112.50R.nT LIABILITIES HiinniiiK stock and dividend* - t 96.741.211 Due shareholder* on nnromplete loam _ _ _ 12..Vi0.00 Reserve fond _ .....~ I.!.'!.!!..!! '.... 2,180.00 Undivided profits 875.81 Pan In advance 381.50 Total 1 U2.S06.57 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 51 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 BBCKIPTS lash on baud Itisi report _ $ 1AURM I&gt;ues i running stock i£Mll.."iO I'ai't ii|&gt; stock * 4,ti*tO.OO Mortgage payments 'A£IQM Interest .". _ - -.- 9.3N8.6X Fines 53.U0 Membership and transfer fees 23.1.00 Money borrowed 5,223.00 Total .* 07,«86.08 IHSnritSKMKXTK Mortgage loans _...* 25.080.00 Withdrawal* rnuing Mark anVl dividends __ Z_L_I1__1_! _...._ 8.TK.1S Withdrawals paid-up stock - K.:»0.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock :£&gt;«.7K Salaries ___^______ 600.00 &lt; (tiler expense _ „ _ _ 62.80 1'ash on hand -■- 3,077.37 .-,.:•.«;. n Bllla nayalile and iutirent _ r...14«.4H Mat ll led stock _ 14.300.00 Matured' stork .MllllJItil sflH ft _ , | ___ .„___._.....„,.„._„_ ■*._*■„_ ._..*_-. 11,tluV.Wr Kruiture and flitures _ _ _ :W)0.00 Liberty Bonds _ rmo.w i Mil of balance - ■•"»*' Total - $ 67.MWi.08 SUPPLEMENTAL UKI'OKT Plan of Assoei.-itiim -. Both NnmlM-r of series issued siniv orKaniiation - 21 Number of shares Issued sim-e (irtfiiiilzation 5.481 Number of shares outstanding last report 2.30f» Shnrt's Issued since lust report SI* Total .I.Offl Total Slmres withdrawn, matured nr eam-elle«l since last re|M&gt;rt — NuuiIkt of shares in fore*' this date UH Number of shares ou which dues are delimiueiit 22 Average riiiiiinii; time of stock umtiireil liuriiiir the yetr -. SO Mo. Niiinbcr of bormwini; stockholder* 97 Number of nou-borrowinir stockholder.^ 176 Number «&gt;f loniis made for buildiim |Mir|M&gt;scs durinic year - Par value of each share of stock - t limiKi far value or eacii snare or siock - 9 im— Total amount of dues delimiueiit at this dati ftl.&amp;u Amount of dues owing by borrowing stiM-klntltters ttl.30 Amount of interest, iiremiuius ami nues due and unpaid H0.70 Amount of loans on improved real estate 10M.250.00 Appralard value of iinpnned rt'al estate hih.ii which loans h»re been made "JOO.IHIO.OO Amount of tire insurance in force ami assigned to the association as collateral seiurity 147.«OO.0O as collateral security Amount of tornado insurance in fon-e and asslgneil to the association lU.7f».0i» as collateral security lU.7t».0l&gt; Amount credited to reserve fund during year 4."O.0O Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 8.410I2* .\ll|i'lln&gt; &gt;&gt;l «ll»n»«-u«l" unwini "ii imiiiiihk niuin nuiiiiK .» ra i --• Amount of dividend* paid on matured and paid-up stock during rear aB * L 7 Kate per cent of dividends ilcrlaretl oa running slock during year 11'' Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year N year Rate per cent of Interest charged iMirrowers during year !•* </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HASTINGS BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HASTINGS, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President H. B. Cornelius Vice President W. M. Lowman Secretary J. O. Rohrer Treasurer J. O. Rohrer Attorney - John Snider DIRECTORS W. M. Lowman H. B. Cornelius Henry Siekmann G. H. Pratt H. C. Haverly Herman Stein E. Langevin ASSETS KirKt mortRORe losns S 231,510.00 l^oaus on stock or pass book security 24,700.00 cub _ zzzzz 4;3ot;7» Furniture and fixture* „ _ ■ 'm!ob Liberty Bon&lt;ln _ 9.750.00 0.730.00 Total _ _ „ „ f 270.442.7i* LIABILITIES RuDDlnar stock and dividends ..._ - 4 2S6.979.2fl Reserre fond _._._. _.___"" 7,'675.00 Indlvlded profits ""'"'"...'.... S;732!» Matured stock unpaid _.™'.'.~".".Z~.".ZZZ~_.".'. 3,066.fl5 Total __._.» 270.442.79 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 53 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 RECEIPTS C«»h on band last report $ 16.13S.77i Dues l running stock) _ _ 47,302.30 Mortgage payments* 35,461.00 :15.461.00 Stock luan payments _ _ 11.345.00 Interest _ 18,74*. 71 Fines ...._.... .'.'.'....'.'..'.'.'....'.1...' 93.47 Membership and transfer fmt _ „ 63.7S »H" 1 1 1 1 kt&gt; i) i p and iraiisier ktm m.is Taxes paid _ 42.06 Total - _ _ M 127,434.23 DISBURSEMENTS Mortgage loans 63,900.00 .»ii»r i &amp;&amp;Kr luaus iK&gt;,auv.uu Stock loanH - 14,135.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividends 12,087.94 Withdrawals matured stock - - - 21,387.53 Salaries „ 1,233.00 other expense, including real - 541.87 Cash on band - - - - 4.3U7.TH Salaries 541.87 4.307.7H Directors fees _ 61.00 Liberty Bonds - - - - — 0,750.00 Total - - - -S 127.4S4.23 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 20.308 Number of shares outstanding last report _ 7.988 7.088 Shares Issued since last report 1,219 Total - 84(07 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report .- - - 821 Number of shares in force this date 8.086 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 14* Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues. 61 61 Amerage running time of stock matured during the year 135 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders _ ?"&gt; Number of non-borrowing stockholders _ ttB Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year _ value of eacb share of stock 9 100.00 •V. Par value of each share of stock l*ar value or eacn suare or miock # luv.uv Total amount of dnes delinquent at this date 410 Amount of dues owing liy borrowing stockholders _ 240 Amount of interest, premiums anil fines dues and unpaid — 266 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 2 1,200.00 .MlllintT iinii iiiii'Miiii oi iimriKUKes ivuujtti ui [BnTiimurr .^o. £ i.jm.w Amount of loans on improved real estate 231.310.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 307.100.00 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association a* collateral security 234.800.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral sei urlty 227.400.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 743.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 14,100.30 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during Tear 6.1% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers duriing Tear «••* </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HAVELOCK BI'ILDINUS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HAVELOCK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Sam'l Hinkle Vice President Arch Adams Secretary V. F. Hofmann Treasurer F. B. Young Attorney _ P. B. Sidles DIRECTORS W. F. Ackerman F. Kroehler F. B. Young F. B. Sidles Sam'l Hinkle E. E. Anderson Geo. W. Anderson Arch Adams C. F. Ballard V. F. Hofma V. F. Hofmann ASSKTS First liinrtirriKf loans % 2tt.m.*0 l.o:ms on stock or pass I. ..ok security _____________ 3.822.00 utlier real nutate . .'. :i ooo.Oo Cast iri.axt.7T :i.00O.0i&gt; &lt;asu IMiimiicm interest, lines, etc _ 1.322. .V&gt; Furniture and fixture* 340.7." other assets fl!i:t.20 Furniture and fixture* M.V20 Lll&gt;ert.v Bonds _ „ 12.000.00 Total $ 281.N80.22 LIAIUL1TIKS Uunnine mock and dlvlili-nils 4 214.."JW.!h; I'ai'1-up stork and dividends 81.200.00 01 .200.00 Rraprre fund 4.74L4U rndlvided profits __J!."_.".""™"Z™."Z!.~ZI! 1^328!77 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 55 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR JUNE 30, 1918 ENDING RECEIPTS Cash on band lost report $ 12.ft17.38 Dues ( running stock ) 42.63."&gt;."iO Paid-up stock _ 20.^)0.00 Mortgage payment** - - 68,27.".ito Stock loan payments 3,450. 00 Real estate sales 1 _ _ _ _... 3.000.00 Interest 24.1H.1.nr&gt; Fines _ _ 146.40 Membership and transfer fw Other receipts In detail 478.00 2.«12.43 Total _ I 177.83B.88 DISBfRSEMENTS Mortgage loans t 89.800.00 Stock loans 3.270.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividends - _ - - 2ft.381.31 Withdrawals paid-up stock _ 25.300.00 Withdrawals Interest on paid-up stock - 3.772.00 Salaries _ _ _ 1.750.00 Commissions - - lftO.OO Other expense _ _ 755.6B Real estate account - - 3.000.00 Cash on hand _ _ - l."i.2O«.77 Other disbursements In detail - 521.70 Liberty Bonds 12.000.00 Dividends credit """"~IZII".-IZZ— 1 "'.' r_I~ZII— .LZJiZI l.\4!)r:n Total * 177.S38.fiN SfPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association Permanent p urn Number of shares outstanding last report Shares issued since last report - _. - - 880 Total £&gt;,18S Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report _ _... 1.M0 Number of shares In force this date - 3.813 Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 1R3 Average running time of stock matured during the year 120 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders _ 181 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 319 Number of loans made for building purposes during year 23 Par value of each share of stock $ 200.00 200.00 rar value 01 r»&lt; u siiorr in *i*»» ™ — * _tkmh&gt; Total amount of does delinquent at this date - 967.00 Amount of interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid 1.322.50 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 1 1.000.00 1.000.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 243.175.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made - 291.850.00 Amount of fire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _ 2«K.ViO.no Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 28R.3M.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1.0KI.SH Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 130. if.) 2fiR.Vio.no Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 15.491.21 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 3.77200 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year %&amp; Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - - •&lt;*■ Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 9.M1 «&lt;* </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THH STATEMENT of the condition of the HOLDREGE SAVING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HOLDRBGE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President John A. Slater Vice President L. T. Johnson Secretary Adolph H. Held Treasurer. - - G. M. Titus Attorney Prank A. Anderson DIRECTORS G. H. Titus L. B. Titus I* T. Johnson R. H. Perry Frank A. Anderson E. A. Roth W. H. Kronguest John A. Slater Frank Johnson ASSETS Cash - - -$ KVi.tVi Other a«sete _ - - 40.35 Total - - - • 1.005 00 LIABILITIES Running «oek and dividends 4 90B.0O PaM-ap ctock and dividends 100.00 100.00 Total . | LM6.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 57 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS Dues ( running stockj - - $ 905.00 Paid-up stock - 100.00 100.00 Mi'tiitifrshlp and transfer ifee« - — 84.00 Total _ _ f 1 .080.00 DISMRSEMFXTS Other expense „ 4 13S.3T* (.'skIi on fin nil OflHjfl MMB T(»mi 4 i.«m» SrPPLEMENTAI, REPORT Plan of association Permanent Xumlier of shares Issued since orKiinixation - — I-'** Totul - - _ M Shares issued alnce last report ~ JW Number of shurew in forc« i tills date - 3-T# Numl»er of non-i»orrowing stcu klmldt-rs 27 Rate per cent inteniit tliHrged borrowers dining year 9V </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 STATEMENT of the condition of the HOOPER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HOOPER. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President John F. Heine Vice President B. Monnich Secretary Geo. W. Heine Treasurer Jacob Sanders DIRECTORS »M. Tlllman J Vlasak .Toe Stipsky Jacob Kirsch R. L. Schwab ASSKTS Firnt mortgage loans _ * 20,000.00 Cash _ _ '.'...'.'.'. !..„!!. 3,217.01 Furniturr and fixtures _ _ 40.00 Total _ .$ 23.257.01 LIABILITIES Running stock sod dividends .$ 22.3«».3« Reaerre faad — _____ HTJI Total - 4 23, 287 .01 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 RECEIPTS Ca-h on band last report t l-"&gt;2 Dues i running stock) - 4,3flN.OO Mortgage payment* — 4,400.00 .Murieatci' payments _ ~ *,-w-f.w Interest - — - I.ft4."«.!)!&gt; Pined . 1 — — 4.80 Membership and tranKfer fee« 17.00 Total _ _ _ - I 10, 437.31 I.ISWKSKMKNTK Mort cage loan* * 2 -°9!&gt;S? Withdrawals running stock and dividends — - — 4.18.8." Salaries _________ _ 100.00 r^ii in nes iw.tiu Other expense - - - - ~ &lt;*-4o Cash on hand ' 3.217.01 Bills payable ...I »6-00 Total $ 10.437.31 SITPI.E.MEXTAI, RKI'OKT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares Issued ifince orfrnnlxatton __ _ 1.170 Xumher of shares outstanding last report —86 Shares issued since last report - .' 35 Total -. «H Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 10 Xnmlier of frtiares in font" tliis -lute - "l Average runninir time of stock matured during the year - 133 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders .' - 20 Number of non-borrowing- stockholders 35 Number of loans made for building purposes rfnriBff year — 1 XumlHT of loans made for purcnasinif of homesteads, or pa.rment of homestead mortgages during year 1 Par value of each share of stock 1 200.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 20.000.00 Appraised value of Improved real e-tate ripon which loan* have hren made 38.300.00 Amount of lire Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 21.230 00 Amount of tornado insurnnce in force and assigned to the association ax collateral security 21.230 00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year ."" l! Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1..^2ft.27 Rate per cent of dividends declared on runninir stock during year S14"^ Kate per cent of Interest charged IXMTowers during year 7»'; </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 STATEMENT of the condition of the Ill'MKOLDT BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HUMBOLDT, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President L. S. Hackett Vice President Otto Kotouc Secretary H. E. Boyd Treasurer I. Shirley DIRECTORS Butterfield, F. R. Boyd. H. E. Campbell. N. C DaviB, J. S. Hackett, L. S. Shirley, I. Cope. E. S. Kotouc, Otto Stramsr, B ASSKTS Flr«t uiortlcaKf loims $ W.OSU.U-'i I.oiius on xtovk or unns Wool: «-&lt;iirlt.v .l.TM I" Other real est»te 1.QU0.00 (•»«!, L».421.3."&gt; Total 4 -w.NH0.4ri I.IAHII.ITIKS KuudIdk utOfk «nd tllvklends _ 4 4.V.t87.!tl Hratrve fund _ 8BK.38 4 4r.,!t87.!tl Indivlded proflU - _ 2.16 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 61 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 RECEIPTS Cash on band last report - - * 29G.2D Dues I running stock) _ 1 _ 1.VWJ0 Mortgage payments _ .I.SOO.no Stock loan payments "........... _ 2.420.00 Interest - _ - - .T-WLKn Membership and transfer fee* - 7.00 Total _ 4 25.281.00 DISBVRSEMKNTB Mortgage loans _ f 400 00 Stock loans _ _ S.72f&gt;.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividends _ _ 13.sn.V15 Salaries _ mono Salaries Other expense - - - 270.34 Cash on hand - — - 2.421..V. Interest paid on mortgaged stock - - - TM.."0 iniHi-Hsr paid un monKngen stock - _ _ iw.. w Dividends 1.714.75 Total - 4 25.281.01) SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association _ Serial Number of series' issued sfnee organization 27 Number of share* Issued since nrganlntion 4,513 Serial 4^13 Nnmber of shares outstanding last report _ 1,218 Shares loaned since last report ~ 75 Total 1.M© Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 247% Number of shares in force this date _ - 1.042"4 Average running time of stock matured during the year SO Mo Avtrnjt^ ruuuiuK imir m »i'h-r luniureti uuriiig me ,»«ir iw &gt;i" Number of borrowing stockholders M Number of non-borrowlne stockholders 84 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages' during year Par Talue of each share of stock Par Talue of each share of stock ' _ $ 100.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 38.078.65 38.078.6S Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare been made 81 .330.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 380.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have hee» made -... 8*0.00 Amount of Ore insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 51.190.10 Amount of tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the association 4Sjmo.no an collateral neourity 4S£0O.flO Amount or«Mt1t*Mi to iwrvp fund during year 1*0.1* Amount of rttvidpndH declared on running Btwk riurtnjr .rear _ 1.T14.TO 1.714.7S \ii)imiiii hi iiiviiiHiHiK u»*&lt;"inr*'ii nu riiiiiiuiK «km*k uurniK jpir _ i.u^.m Rate per cent of intermt char(re&lt;1 borrpwen* rtnrinic yetr . , — «— — . 10% </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the KEARNEY SAVING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION KEARNEY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President S. A. D. Henline Vice President John W. Patterson Secretary Treasurer Arthur Barney Attorney John N. Dryden DIRECTORS S. A. D. Henline John N. Dryden N. P. McDonald John W. Patterson Frank Kollingswortn Gilbert Haase Willard F. Bailey ASSETS First mortKHKc loans $ MJM.6S .-..M0.20 Total _ _ $ ft"»,470.hu I.IAIIII.ITIKS KiiniiiiiL' xtock :iml iliriili'iuls $ Kl.O2».2!i I'iiiil-mi stock and ilivMendii ...___.___ZL_."~. 4(»!ooo!oo I!.~»TV.. flin.I ; ________ '72o!flli 1 ii'ti\ iil»-«l profits 1.7:K»&gt;r» Total _ f 9G.479.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 I. 1918 W KIl'TS Cash on Land last rt'|&gt;ort I "lies iriniiiini; stork i ... Paid up -"" k Mortgage payment Interest 1'ines ntliir rceeipts In detail Total iMsitru SKMKNTS Mortgage ln:Mis Withdrawals ruimiiitr Block anil divideuds Withdrawal! paid-up stock Wit bdraw ;ils &lt;livi&lt;l&lt;-n&lt;l on p;iiil up -ii&gt;«&lt; t *. Ot her ex iM'iisc Caaa on hand Paid from It II it fmi.l ti&gt; iiniliviilcil i&gt;n&gt;Bts. !:ist 1; inonth 17X.W Total * 7O.910. 1« SIIM'I.KMKNT AL KKI'liKT IM1111 of associatiOD IVrmanent NiiiiiIht of shares — tmtm widimg last n-|H»rt 982.75 Slians witliilrawu. mutureil or nnflM sIikt lust report 13B.71 NmmiIht of horriiw i 11 stot-klmlilrrs «S Nuiiiiiir ..f null liorniwlntr sto.kholilirs l."iO Nuiiihcr of ltmus ma&lt;lt&gt; for ImlNliiie i»tir|&gt;os&lt;&gt;H iImi-Ihk year 1 Suniliir of loans uiailr fc.r pin 1 ■»■!■&gt; of hmiiistvails or imvmviit of lionii'sti'tiil-iuortuMt'i's iluriiiK raai lit Amount of interest, pn-iuiuins anil nu*'s ilu«&gt; anil unpaiil .1141.03 NuiuImt aiul amount at iiiorlKuccs sul»J*-«t tu forirlosuiv Xt: Amount of loans on improved real i&gt;sl:it«' _ ft4 Appraiscil value of improved real estate upon « hlrh loans Imve Ikh&gt;ii la 1^4.(IH0.0O Amount of fire iiisiiraut-e in fori-e and assigned to the asKin-iation as .ollateral semrity 142.1)00.00 Amount of tornado in»niralii-e in for«-v and as*ij;uttl to xliv «sso«-iatioii i&gt; I'olliiteriil seiurity 14L'.. 1 «0.00 Appraised value of land not iiieliidini.' iiiiprovemeiits :iK.7."i0.0O \'alue of iinprovements „ „ „ ll.'.rglO.OO Amount of flre Ilisuraiire thereon _ _ 142.00O.0* Amount of tornailo Insurame thereon _ 14L'. li O0.(lo Amount crpilltwl to reserve fund durlni; yi'ar 177.71 Amount of dividends dei lared on runninc stiuk ilurini; year 3.7Q&amp;31 Amount 0/ dividend-- paid on matured anil paid-up stoek during year IM4JM Kate per c-.^at of dividends dei lared oa ruiiniiii: st. H -k duriue year...'. s..".'. Hate per rent of dividends paid on matured ami full paid stoek during year '!'. Itate p*'r eent of interest eharjred Imrrowers during year _ Ts'' r Hate per cent of premiums charged liorrowera during ye«r 1'. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 STATEMENT of the condition of the LAUREL BUILDINCi AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LAUREL. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President J. B. Felber Vice President C. F. Furley Secretary Guy Wilson Treasurer Guy Wilson Attorney F. P. Voter DIRECTORS J. B. Felber C. E. Nevin W. T. Graham Guy Wilson C. F. Furley F. P. Voter O. A. Johnson ASSETS First mortgage loans 4 40,300.00 Cash _ _ _ __ " "980.12 Stocks and bonds _ .'.7.*.'..'... 1,000.00 Total .$ 42.2H0.12 LIABILITIES Runnln* stock and dividends _...» 39,496.51 Reserve fund - 1,186.42 Undivided profits - ........1!!!!!!!Z!Z"!" l JHaV.ll Total _———_— $ 42,280.12 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 KEIKII TS Cash on band last report - ♦ O..'!7(MH&gt; t'.tsh on band last report l&gt;ues I running stork I 1 iun ( riiDiiiuK stock l _ - ll.liT'l.T-i MnrtKiiict* puynifUlK „ _ 14.Kitl.0ii Interest anil iirciiiiiini 4.tl*.".:Si 1 , Fines - 4l.no \lt*iu Im'Ts lii|&gt; it nil t rtmsfpr f*H^t — T.'.OO UmbMraUp and transfer feei Bills payable J.:i7r..ii«i Total * 3U.SU. 01 IUSB1 I SK MEXTS Mortgage loans * 12.HKi.40 Withdrawals running stock anil dividends Salaries lianm Other expense I'usli oil halKl Hiils payable Liberty Hond 1.10.411 '.W1I.1J 20*75.00 l.UMMJD Total * ai.»i.oi ■ill'PI.KMKNT A I. UEPOBT l'liiii of association Serial Nllllllier of series Issued slniv uruanluitioii H Number of shares issued since nrKanlzatiou ■2.r*a NuinUer sf slmres oiitstiiiHliiii: bM n-port 1.14^ Shares issued since last re|Mirt 331 Total - 1.474 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled siin-v last re|»ort MS Nunilter of shares in force this date 1.1T2 Average runniuK time nf stuck inatureil during i tit- rear 92 Mo. Nuinl'cr of horrowine stockholders ::-J Number of lion liorn.w ink' stockholders 113 Number nf loans made fur Uuilillnir purpose* during year 4 Number of Inans ininb* for piirchashm of homesteads t»r pnymen of homestead -nmrtjrajres during year Ill rian of premium Serial l'ar value of each share of stock * 1110.00 Amount nf loans on improved real extnte HI..1H1.KI Appraised value of improved real estate in which loans have l&gt;een made - MM Amount of fire Insurance In force and assigned to the association an collateral security :io.ion.nn Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 4!l..!00 (XI Amount credited to reserve fund dtirinc year 1ST.!* Amount of dividends declared on ru lining stock during year :!.4&gt;*;.sn Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year, semi-annual M Rate per &lt;-ent of interest .liarucl borrowers Kate i&gt;er cent of premiums charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA CENTRAL BUILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1918 OFFICERS President Homer K. Burket Vice President J. Gibson Secretary M. W. Folsom Treasurer T. N. Burket Auditor J. A. Piper Mgr. of Agencies E. P .Leonard DIRECTORS Homer K. Burket J. Gibson M. W. Folsom T. N. Burket J. A. Piper E. P. Leonard ASSETS First mortgage loans _ _ I 3.908,7sfc.fl2 Loans in prows* of foreclosure __ liO.iSJO.OO Loam od stock or p«&gt;s lH&gt;ok security - „ - 15,314. ~H othe rreal eHtut«&gt; _ 76,7*JO.HO Heal &lt; Ktiite ho1«] on contract - 43.113.1H V. S. Liberty Bonds 73,704..'IH CaHb 1H1.087.54 2M.791.no Ofllce ImlldinR and furniture and fixtures Total - _ _ 4 4.374,1 15.C.I LIABILITIES Kunnins stock anil dividends * 2.211.H1-"...}! I'aid-up stock and dirideadg ""..'.I.-I "-I-II— I II „ lJSA.TT&amp;SO Eeierre fund Illl IIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII...IIIIIIIIIIIIIIIII.IIIIIIIIIII..IIIIIIL.IIII.IIIIIIIII 144.21O.M 1'ndivided pronts to pay July. 1!UK dlvtilends _ 1«3.3.'».:17 ToUl ': 4 4,374,115.0*1 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 67 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS Cash on hand lam ri port - 4 2©7.446.."&gt;!&gt; Hues (running stock) • H24.0S7.fi2 Dues (running stock! - - S24.0S7.62 Paid-up stock __________________-____.—..- T11.323.4O- Paid-u p stork - TH.32S.4O Mortgage payment* _ - - - 8B3.7r&gt;O.xfl Mortgage p-rr™ *^tt -■'■ - 8BH."r&gt;o.»fl Stock loan payments - - — 13.8B9.Ht Stock loan payments _ - — 13.6B9.H* Real estate sales . _ _ 18.787.53 Real estate sales ____________.Z._._.-...~.._— .. 18.787.53 Inte.rent - 3Or&gt;,14&lt;l.&amp;4 Inte.rest flVi.14ii.tK Keal estate - 24,1132.17 Real estate '. ...'..'. '.. " - 24,632.17 Pines _ — - . 1,681.47 Pines _ ~ 1,861.47 Kent* _ 4,380.."iO Rents .__-___.____^_ _ 4.38O..1O Bills payable • • - 2S.flU0.0o Bills payable ~ 25.0U0.0O Reserve fund 2O.214.."&gt;7 Total _ -I 3*6O.0M.l!&gt; Reserve fund 2O.214.."i" Total - * M80.0Sl.lii DISItritSEMENTS nisitrnsEMKNTs Mortgage loans f 1.32H.020.W Mortgage loans f 1.32«.02n.!&gt;6 Stock loans 12.6MU2 Stock loans 12.flBft.12 Indivlded profits dividends credited on ruiiiiinir st&lt;x-k 1S2..*O«.23 Individed nroflts dividends credited on running stock 152.."0fl.23 WlthilrawalH running «tock and dividend" 771.4B2.SN Withdrawals running stock and dividends 771.4&lt;&gt;2.&gt;»&lt; Withdrawals pald-uV stock - 277.7M.ir&gt; Withdrawals pald-uV stock ____ Z 2T7.TO3.15 Withdrawals dividend oa pald-a* st.nk - MJMT Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock - KO.22K.O7 Salaries 2R.:UR.O2 Salaries 2S,:tlR.rK Commissions „ „ 11.4."tfi.'.*!&gt; Com missions _ „ „ 11.4."tfi.'.*!&gt; Other expi^nse - - 10,17!».2« Other expense - 10.179.2fi Real estate nceount „ „ . 52.80rt.!&gt;'_ &gt; Real estate account - - 52.80S.fK,' Cnited States Liberty Ilonds ..'. _ _ 7S.7O4..Tii Tntted States Liberty Konds - - - 7n.7O4.Wi rash on hand - 1K1.0K7.M 2S4.Wl.no rash on hand .'. _ ...1K1.0R7.54 2S4.TOl.flo Undivided profits, reserve fund - - 20.000.00 f'ndivlded profits, reserve fund - - 20.000.00 Rills payable 23 000 01) nil Is payable 25,000.00 Reserve fund 1.112.S1 Taxes' of office building - , 5«t.23 Taxew of office building - 54W.23 Ki ill estilte sold _ 12.323.5A Office building and furniture I.TS5.M Total * S.«no.O«l.l!i SfPPLKMKXTAI. KKPOKT IMmi of association Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report .14.". 445 Number of xhnres outstanding last report 1IIO.'.NI7 Shares issuwl since ll;st report 28.108 Total 1J!&gt;.O7:'. Shares withdrawn, maturetl or cam-elled since last report 20.Tt'2 Number of shares In force this- date _ 10N.:t41 Average running time of &lt;to.-k matured iluring the ye«r - 117 Mo. Number of borrowing- stockholders 2.S42 Nnmlier of nonborrowlne stockh&lt;dders 4.WO Numtier of loans made for bnildiing purpr»scs during year 3.10 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages luring year '. 303 Par value of each stare of stock ~ -$ 100.00 Amount of interest, and fines due and unpaid 11.531 Tl Number and amount of mortgages' subject to foreclosure No. 31 4K.000.00 :e« .^UllimT :1HU HIIIUIIIIl Itl III"! I Ki'Kl '&gt; i"llnjt-i-( |if lumiWlirr »»». ,m W,immhp Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. 4.1 SO.^OOn Amount of loans on Improved real estate n.!)0J&gt;.7S*l.it. &gt; Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made !&gt;.T74.O4f..0o Amount of fire and tornado insurance in force and assigned to iissuciation as collateral 5.922.402.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during yeat 20.214.57 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during ye«r 1.112.81 "i.!)22.4O2.On Amount of dividends declared on running stock during ye«r 152.5WJ.23 Amonnt of dividends paid on mjLtnred and paid-up stock during year 80.22A.O7 Sit.22ft.07 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during vear 7C£ Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during vpfip ,_ _ _ „ rt^-f Rate per cent oif interest charged borrower* during yiar HI </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the AMERICAN SAVING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 191S OFFICERS President W. A. Selleck Vice President E. W. Brown Secretary-Treasurer E. F. Snavely Attorney E. W. Brown DIRECTORS W. A. Selleck E. F. Snavely fW. Brown H. McClay C. J. Olson E. C. Hurd H. H. Wilson Frank Parks L. C. Oberlies John T. Dorgan ASSETS Kirxt mortgage loan* _ __ 4 400.475.00 I. nun* in procfis of forcclosre - 2.200.00 Loaaa on stock or pnsx liook security - - - - 3.500.00 &lt; M her rt'iil t*Htate - 3,871.85 Cash 15.ft44.24 lh-]&lt;ni|ii&lt;'iit l»Hr««t. Hni-s, .'t&lt;- _ _ _ IMJi Taxes paid _ _ - 1.880.98 Total 4 437,362.92 LIABILITIES KnnnlnK stock and dividends _ _ 4 108,639.27 I'ni.1 -mi stock and dlvidendti ___ '1 '.". 319.42S.0O Due HlmrehoMen* on incomplete loans 4.724.00 Rwrw fund "... ..i..! LI 4.S20.24 I'ndlvlilpil pronis 244.81 ToUl 4 437.3«2.92 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 69 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS Cash »n hand last report - - - 4 2,!IO3.-- Dues I running stock) _ 133.551..16 133.S61.36 Paid-up stock ___________________________ _ „ 206,800.00 Illltl'Up SI OCK .... ..... . ... ..... JWI,wWJ.W Mortgage payments -. _ _ - 76,000.00 Stock loan payment* - - 1.300.00 Real estate sale* _ _ _ _ 33.80 Interest _ 27,800.11 JT.s.O.11 Liberty Bonds ____________ _ .... _ „... 15,67T&gt;.7^ Membership ami transfer fees _ 2.430.S-.' Stock loans ___ _____ 4.4O0.Ot) Withdrawals paid-up stock l:t0.4i»0.00 Withdrawals running stock — _. - - -. f&gt;,"V40.-l and dividends „ _ lUMKUn Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock 16.437.53 Salaries 3.2-O.On Other expense -. _ .VKR.«&gt; Real estate account .- . ~ . — . 3 705 4.% Cash on bund _ 15,844. -4 iri.S44.lM other disbursements in detail ~ ~ 2 £47. -TO T., * . ... ■» in ii Taxes 2.413.44 Libert J Honds _ l*iJ»~r,.Tr, Total &gt; 470.279.12 SII'PI.KMKXTAL REPORT I'lan of association Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report .8.388.75 Shares issued since last report 4.837.00 Total - - - 13.0O."&gt;.7T&gt; Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 3.131. SO Number of shares in force this date !»,874._T&gt; Number of borrowing stockholders ytl Number of non-l&gt;orrowing stockholder* 502 Number of loans made for bulding purposes during year 3"t Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteams or payment of homestead-innortgajres during year 20 Par value of each share of stock .$ 100.0 1 100.01 Xuml&gt;er and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. 1 ..JOOno .^iliin— r .inn aiiiuuiii ui i i li.i^t 1^ in prutT^n vi i»in"iiwuir. .Ml. 1 ■— ■— Amount of loans on improved rt-n I estate 403.4-5.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loan- haTe bwn made S31 •» o» Amount, of loans on unimprove&lt;l real i-state 8.2TiO.U0 Appraisetl value of unlinpnved real estate upon which loans have been made _ 17.000.0c Amount of flre inMimince In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 4«-.!&gt;00.00 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral srcrrlty 333 !«&gt;0&lt;&gt; Amount credited to leserve fund during year l.l &gt; 30.4.'&gt; Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year ."..'»40.21 .\lliuiiiu in ii it iiii-iiii^ iii'i-hi i ,-u on iiiiiiiiiik sii« R iiiiiiiik &gt;enr u,.r— /..i Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 16.437.53 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8r» Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock duriing year &lt;V. year Rate i&gt;er cent of interest churgi'd borrowers during year '-''■ Other receipt!* in detail _ - —_.. Taxes - 3.001.M 1.914.2-1 3.001.02 1.914.24 Total - — ......I 470.2TO.12 DISBURSEMENTS Mort gaffe loan* _ $ 14R. 632.72 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 STATEMENT of the condition of the LINCOLN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION- LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President E. W. Brown Vice President H. H. Wilson Secretary E. F. Snavely Treasurer Frank Parks DIRECTORS E. W. Brown H. H. Wilon Frank Parks E. F. Snavely Charles Olson E. C. Hurd J. H. McClay John T. Dorgan W. A. Selleck L. C. Oberlies ASSKTS Firxt niurtKOK'- loanK $ 3U.83&amp;.M Loans In imiccMM nf furi'iloHiiri' _ _ lS.7t0.00 Loan* on stock or (&gt;iiwh lMMtk s**&lt;-urity tiTrfMJO otliiT n'ttl pslntc 32.028.rKj other n'Hl pslntc .'. 32.028.~kj Iteal estate sold on contract _ 28.:!lfl.iW Iteal csiatf moIi) on contract _ 28.:!lfl.iW Can.li 3K.111.4O Iieliiiiiuciit lntfrv»i. flnex. etc _ „ &amp;jaaiM Kurnlture ami fixtures : _ l.OTiit.si Taxpti paid 3,fiR4.xi' 1 »fliiniu«-iit Interest, tines, etc S.fiW.Mt (VrtlflcHtcs nf de|K)slt _ 1M.nmi.(H&gt; Kmnis I4.7~J War KaTlne» Slam|w „ tWUXI Total f 717,i:&gt;5.3x i.iAHii.rriKs Kunnlng Kt&lt;Hk and dividends 4 ~4O.818.0G Paid-up stock and dividends 364,110.00 Due nhareholders on incomplete loans 2. ..477.85 Reserve fund ~ - 9,7nw.21 Undivided p-**'* 180.27 Xot»l _ , $ 717.156.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 71 RKCE1PTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 REC EIPTS Cash on band last report I Hies I running stock! S2.464.52 13H..-i31.1* 1O4.9R0.0O l«0.979.10 Paid-up stock Mortgage payment* stock loan payment* Konl estate Bales .... Ueal estate contract!! interest 1 .71S.M 17.458.01 I1.23&amp;30 MJCM0 Miscellaneous receipts Kil.es 2.640.04 135.70 Taxes 3.712.77 UemlHTKhip anil abstract feei Bonds and C. I&gt;. 1.815.28 .-.,325.7r&gt; Total _ | xw.rv*.*'. SEMEXTS nisnrF Mortgage loans * 142.775.00 Stock loans 44K.OO Withdrawals running stock and dividend 17.Y2S7.S2 6B.ew.oo 18.ftW.4n Withdrawals paid-up stock Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock Salaries 6.43A.MI 2.201.17 Commissions Other expense 5.6SL92 31.3S2.12 14.1233+4 3«.l 11.40 43.808.00 Real estate account Real estate contracts rush on hand Honds. War Savings stumps nud (Vrtlfli ate* of deposit Fiirniturf and fixtures 3kk.oi Keserve 2.782.23 3.256.87 Ta\es * .V.3.350.83 Total SIPPI.F.MENT AI. ItKPOHT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares issued since organization 54,3fl8.4!&gt; XumlMT of shares outstanding last report 1S.07Ti.10 Shares issued since last report 4.900.5 Total _ 22.975.6 res withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report 4,616.3 22.975.6 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report Number of shares in force this date 18.380.1 Average running time of stock matured during the year US Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders _ 46ft Number of non-borrowing stockholders 1J5RX NuihImt of loan-* made for Ituilding purposes during venr 66 Nnmlier of loans made for purchasing of homesteads nr payment of homestead-mortgages during year 21 Par value of each share of stock .' f 100.0) Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid .Vi9B.st» Numlier and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 21 27.40000 Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. 12 13 700.01) Amount of loans on Improved real estate ."V4.Vi2ft.O0 Appraised value of improved rcai estate ui&gt;on which loans have l»een made D0B.200.nn Amount of lire insurant in force and assigned to the asaooUtion as collateral security 600.210.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association a» collateral security 421.070.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 2.225.00 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year 2.702.23 421.070.00 Amount of losses churned to reserve fund during year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year - 18.710.11 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 18.93n.4:&gt; 18.93S.4O Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year. 6% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year , •* year Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year 7Jt% </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 STATEMENT of the condition of tbe SECURITY SAVIGNS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN. NEBRASKA on the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President L. C. Oberlies Vice President J. T. Dorgan Secretary E. F. Snavely Treasurer E. F. Snavely Attorney E. W. Brown DIRECTORS L. C. Oberlies John T. Dorgan J. H. McClay W A. Selleck E. W. Brown E. F. Snavely E. C. Hurd H. H. Wilson C. J. Olson Frank Parks ASSETS First mortgage loans - X lW.l-Vi.00 Loans In process of foreciomire 5-5 32'!S Loans on Ml nr pass book security 'rS'IS other real estate _ ..'..'"..I """".".. SB-g-I'r 2S Real estate sold on contract - 2 ? - 2D} ?- Cash "' 4.8!ilX&gt; r&gt;elinn.uent interest, fines, etc 4,"t4.^- Furniture and fixtures .....' - - - 552-98 Taxes paid — -I— 2 -«J»X War Saints Stamps ~'.J~~ - ,1^-15 CertlApates of deposit ~.~ - - 5.000.00 ToUl ■* 288.647.81 LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends - * lSB.WO.ra Paid-up stock and divldendd ' " 97.985.00 Reserve fund - — _______.___„__.... 4.24!t.ft3 T'nilivldHti itrofltM 552.06 Tot,) _ _ 4 28S.647.8l </seg>
            <seg id="p073">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 73 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 KBTEIPTS Cash on hand last report * 12.570.7S Dues &lt; running stock) 51.37ft.R^ Mort gage payments 54.375.00 Stock loan payments _ _ ft«2.0O Real estate - - 22.54S.V) 22..MA.R» Interest ._ Real estate sold on contract 4.433.04 llomls and certificates of deposit _ _ 18.02fl.8T Membership and transfer fees O. K - 798-ftft Other receipts in detail .'. - 1W7.34 Taxes - MM Total - * 180.06S.ai IMSRrUKKMEXTS Mortgage lonns .'. f 43.7TB.00 Withdrawals running stock R2.2R3.3n and dividends ■■■■■■ - 10.12fi.6H and invmenus - uMj&gt;.on Withdrawals paid-up stock - — 16.300.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock 6.270.2» Salaries - 625.00 Commission*, real estate sold on contract _ 4*4.32 8.33S.34 Other expense 1.M2.44 1 M utT t*X Of^n^P • *-•-- - § ..«1™. "f-T Real estate on account • 7.2«3.j!l Cash on hand - - - — *.&amp;n .KB t asn on nann - - - — -t.wn.'-.i Other disbursements in detail ...- - s -25- ao Taxes 1.22R.S3 War Hattmm »— ■» ■ IK. 10 Total - - * l&amp;MtM SrPPLEMKXTAL REPORT Plan of association - Permanent Number of shares outstanding last report 7.0HS.8S Shares issued since last report _ 480 Totel - - TJHS.W Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since la*t report 2.032.00 Number of shares in force this date _ 5.311.JK Number of borrowing stockholders - _ Number of Bon-borrowlne stockholdeis 41° Number of loans madr for building purposes during year » Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-morteaces during year - 10 Par value of each share of stock $ 1O00O Amount of interest, premiums nnd fines due ind unpaid 4.TS4.O* in Amount of interest, premiums nnd fines due and unpaid NnmW and amount of mortgages snhiect to foreelosnre No. B 12.100.00 Mimwr Hun amouni "I morigHKe* »ui»iei-i u&gt; uinri'mnn- .-«o. « i~. '™'.«- Number and amount of mortgages In process of foreclosure No. 5 R.WO.0O Amount of loans on improved renl estate WD.70B.Wi \pprnlse* 1 value of improved real * state upon which loans have been made 3S2.SI0.00 \monnt of fln- insurnnc" in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 230..10O0 t Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security lfln.mooo Amount credited to ieserve fund during year 913.2S Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year -V0IW.2O Amount of losses charged to reserve ninn miring year n.wwv^w Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 10.12ft.flR Amount of dividends paid on matured ami naid-up stock during year 8.270.2!) Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during veur «"7r Hate per rent of dividends paid on matured anil full paid slock .luring year - ■ — — - «2r «~, Rate per cent of interent cbarRed Imrrowers during yp»r _ H </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the UNION LOAN AND SAVING SASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President A. W. Miller Vice President W. B. Ryons Secretary Loyd A. Winship Treasurer L. J. Dunn DIRECTORS A. W. Miller W. B. Ryons Loyd A. Winship L. J. Dunn John M. Stewart ASSETS First mortgage loans $ 849,162.40 Interest on certificates of deposit 1,771.33 Loans on stock or pass book security ~ -. 1.700.00 Other real estate - - 22,379.96 Real estate sold on contract 7,003.4.** Ortifloates of deposit - _ 00^07.r&gt;0 Cash _ 15,.Vi5.t)i Delinquent interest. fineK, etc 2,347.^4 Furniture and fixtures _ _ _ 1.7W.47 Taxes paid - 2,304.3!&gt; liberty Bopds _ 17.0nit.l0 Insurance advanced 113.6* War Savings Stamps 276.17 Overdrawn mortgage loans - 142.S1 Total $ l.&lt;n:!.02K.2O LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ SQSTHKR Paid-up stock and dividends &lt;*;•_■. 7"0.im Doe shareholders on incomplete lounc no.377.4'.' Reserve fund 12.414.17 Undivided profits _. 3.74'i.SKi Total s 1.01-MO.J) </seg>
            <seg id="p075">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 75 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING Cash on hand last report Kiifs (running slock) ... 1S.IW.52 17!».Sfifi.ir, ruj.HOO.no »n..&gt;".(io Paid-up stork .Mortgage payments Slock loan payments Keiil estate sales 10.000.0n 11..M.Y22 I Merest Fines TT.-.U'.-IT Items Keul estate all under i-ontrad Certificates of deposit '..i.Tm.t.-, 3.5M.46 Taxed untt insurance Total 1.10O.X12.04 Mortgage loans Stock loans .... 427.C3B.2fi lO.MB.Mu Certificates of de|M&gt;sit S.1.447.40 JOP.170.7X SB.H&amp;M Withdrawals run nine stock nml dividends Withdrawals paid-up stock fUjmi l« withdrawals ma Withdrawal* dividend on paid-up stock Salaried ::vtz&gt;7. a ii.:.iL-.oi» I'liininissions Other expense H42.3H Furniture ami fixture Heal estate aivount ... Cash on hand l.Mi.in »,T».(« l.-...V&gt;.-,.(r7 li'.onB.io I.ilM&gt;rty Honds N\'jtr Suvinps Stamp: 278.17 Tax i-tTtiflcnteff and insurance advanced Kent - 2.2«*.!&gt;.1 1.118. Tx Heal estate contracts 4.7OB.97 S Total 1.10O.X-i2.04 SITPI.EMKXT AI, KKl'ltliT I'liiii of association Permanent Xiiiiilx-r of shares issueil sln&lt;v orKimlxntion _ ra.l24.4"i XuihImt of shares outstnniiin^ last report - 2r».70*i.."0 Shares issued since last report a\73al90 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled sinn last re|M»rt .*i.424.2."i Numlier of liorrcnvinit stockhoMers 494 Nanhrr of imn-liorroninK stockholders lilt; NuniUcr of loans made for balMing |iurpos*'s tlurinir year 00 Par value of each share ot stock S 'on •■« Amount of Interest, premiuins aiul tines due and unpaid ( 11s. *&gt;7 \'unil&gt;er and aniouiit of mnTtfgrm mhjpri to foreilosure V«. ." 1*).!MHi&lt;m Xiiinlni aad amount of mortmains in process of foreclosun&gt; No. 2 ?*0ii0"&gt; Amount of loans on improved ml estate M!&gt;.lrt2.4O Appralsvd value of improved rell estate ll|H&gt;li which loans have lu-*-n made l.«jO.7«"..«n Amount of loans on unimproved real estate S.4'JTi.uo Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have tieen made M Toll.Otl Amount of flre insurance in force and assigned to the association ii- collateral security S.VUW..0t) Amount of tornado Insurance in fon-e and ;i- -iu'iicl to the association :i- ...llateral security 7irr..TK».OO Amount credited to reserve fund duriine vea' SOiniNi Amount of !os-s.s chart'ed t» reserve fund ilurine rear (CT.-V! Amount of dividends &lt;!.■. I i r.&lt;l on runniuK stock during vear 1.~i.!&gt;l.*&gt;! '.":■, Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during- year :W.I«I7 4' Rat* I'er cent of dividends declared on running stock during vear S' ; Hate per ppat of dividends paid on matured ami full paid stock during year — ft Tr Rate per cent of interest charged l&gt;orrower» during ye«r !)~, 2UR.3!) 94M.75 918.70 1.70S.1S T.taM.77 Total :ri,4:2.ft(i Nnmher of shuivs in forre fliis date m.inr.T.' </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 STATEMENT of the condition of the I 3 FIDELITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION -.1 On the 30th day of June, 1918 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OFFICERS President W. D. Forsyth Vice President Fred D. Mason Secretary ...C. E. Bardwell DIRECTORS W. A. Forsyth Fred D. Mason J. G. Horning C. E. Bardwell ASSETS First mortgage loans _ „.$ l.Vt.oj.'.OO I. ohms In procesK of fororlonurt* ~ +42.IW Other real cHtatc _ S,4sTi!4:l Iteal t-Ktiiti- ho1&lt;1 on contract ,,, .iis8S.nl «'a*h '."...!!..".ll..l... 4]r»7n!: Furniture and flxtnre* _ _______ 3TO.1S Taxm paid 2!*O 10 2!i0.10 Expenses piiiil _ _ _______ KHLKt Lilw*rty Honds „ „ '\ yriOiio \-r&lt;n.m War Savings Stamp* _ ..*".............. SXSL40 Rllln i-eoeivalile 437..V) iXTM Total _ n VK,iK&gt;.-2:, LIABILITIES Hiiuniiie Ktork and dividend* .$ 73.47.1.1S l'aiil-up stock anil dlvldendn .Z.!"!."™.... ftriiOdioio Hui shureliolder* on incomplete loan* _ '" s'o4 ltenerve fund _ _ 2,26." *17 5.04 liewrve fund I'ndiviiled proflt« __!!__" s!518.S«i Total » si Td **&gt; fi </seg>
            <seg id="p077">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 77 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAH ENDING I'lan of association - Permanent \uinl»er of shares issued slni-e orfranlxatiim 10.ii4 I _. .5,345 Number of slum's outstanding last rv|nn*t Shares hMri sincr last rejwtrt W» Total m rt.:»14 Shares withdrawn, maturea or cnni-elled sin&lt;*e last re|M»rt Xilinlier of shares in force this date ."i.4:!7 Number of borrowing sto&lt;-khold«'rs 74 Nunilier nf iiiin-lforrowlnK MorklmMm 44."i Nil in I ht of loans made fur pun-hasum of lintui'steads or payment of liomeHtend-niortKi'Fes durtnt; year _ !» I*ar value of each share of stock $ ltlO.Oo N'uinlier and amount of mortirages in protvss of foreclomin" No 1 (."UM« Amount of loans on improved real estate ;.... l.~»:t.O*_'.~.4lo Appraised value of impro|H'd real estate u|&gt;on which loans h»pe ti«&gt;n made •JS2.*7r..oo Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 17S..K10.I1O Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association :is ,-ollateral security _ 161.300.0;) Amount credited to reserve fund duriin; year 61!&gt;.17 Amount of dividends deelanil on runnlntr stink during rear 4.. 'At. 71 Amount of dividends paid on matured and pnid-np stock during year 7.02X.7S hate per i-ent of dividends' declared on runninc stock duriing year. I lEate iht rent of dividends luiid on matured and full paid sto&lt;*k during year «'. Kate i&gt;er ivnt of Interest charged borrower* during year H JUINtt 3U, 15«1» irara &lt;'ash on hand la~t report I&gt;ues i running st(M-ki - I'll ill -up stork Mortgage payments lifiil estate salen _ Interest Itents (real extatel - Mrinlierxhip and transfer fees Rents untl office l»iii Nl i iiu receipt* - Kxpclise rrwlit Inoiinplctf loan« Fiirnimrc anil flxturm TaxpB — rwelpts Total ..» T.r.T'.i.-.t: HH.H0OX) 44.IMO.tWI i:i.!N«i.ou tcs.xi U.:«CJ.s&gt;. IKi.00 INII.OII MM 2..-ML2JS itue Mm ...» l.TO.rwm.TK HISIUKSKMKNTS MortgaiCf loans Withdrawals runiiiiiir &lt;to«k ami iliviilcmls Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock Salaries 4 '0111 mission* Other exi»enKe - Keal cstatt' ac&lt;"iiunt Casli mi li.'ind — -- - — - Furniture and fixture* Incomplete loans Liberty Bonds and War Savings Slumps Total 7.0-JX.Ts i..-«m.oci ::■...■&gt; • i.at7..-,i 1.373.2! •Ml 1.*&gt;.OT3.OC1 4.0m.+() » MMJHLM sri-IM.KMKNTAI. KF.rOIt tT </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 STATEMENT of the condition of the LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JUNE 30, 1918 OFFICERS President Wm. Seelenfreund Vice President Secretary F. E. Gillen F. B. Sidles Treasurer Attorney . Fred Whittemore F. B. Sidles DIRECTORS Wm. Seelenfreund P. B. Sidles F. E. Gillen Fred Whitt&lt; H. E. Sidles Fred Whittemore ASSKTS ifftt lllortjruKr Iniiii" l.oiin- ill prcx-fKx ..f fiiriM-lnsiiri' l.Oiiiis mii sto&lt;k or imiss Wook avraritT otln-r n*nl «-stjit*- Ural i-siiitr hoIiI on raalrad Stuii- anil iiiiinii'i|i:il siMiirilii-s Cash Kurniniiv :uii] lt\tun*s T»xi-» imlil I'Miilup Kt(Mk and diriiienils 1!t«.'.K10.(l&lt;i 1:. -^t-r\ i- fuuil . -- •"► S!*N 71* ■ n a a^ I * ■ ui*n *^" !■■■■» *■■•• i !■■■■■■ - •*—-»' I'ndlvUlpil profit r ToUl « * 587,005.7:2 l'KOYIDKNT SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION I'.niik lertifiiuli s nf ili|&gt;O"ir I.llKTt.v Ifcilllls Total I.IAItlMTIKS KiinniiiK «to&lt;k nnil MiMwdn * .lW.i"j0.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 79 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE Y JUNE 30. 1918 EAR ENDING RKCKIl'TS »a-h on hand last report liu.-s i run ii in ir siiH-k) .... L'anh on hand lant rr|»ort * 14.IBll.3a * 14.IH1 .!•_' lni.s i ruuiiiim sunk i MJIM l.-,T.l'.i:t.'.«7 [■aid up stock _ 11.NTiO.oi&gt; I'aid-up stock Mortgage payments Stm k loan |i;i&gt; linnr- Keal estate sale!* .Morten Jfe I*" vinents — __ - 8tt^W-"V.0O Ml^M.OO Stock lojiii pgjBIStl - 1.100.(10 Ki'ii I estate sale* - "J.till.J'.l 2.K11.2!&gt; Interest ttjMMi Interest c.'.mu.m TjlX^.S ;|&lt; '("&lt; &gt;|| H I 12T.«1 Taxes account Fin* 1 !* 12T.J1 Kint&gt;M ii.~ In liTUO Muni, lpal wcarllkn ________ _»_• Municipal nearttin :mi.{» MiTiil.iTshlii anil tninsfer tii-* T— •.80 7-1UIO Membership anil transfer fi Furniture nml fixtures ]'*u rn i 1 11 rt* and fixturt'w — — 'JO.OIJ ».oo Ural estate sold nil contract Bank certificates of deitosit Liberty Bonds itiiii I'sintf sold mi iwmu imi.oo D»lll Bank certifliatis of deiHisit (iT.OOO.On lii.ooo.on Uberty Bonds n mo.nu Total % 3St -j.flno.nu * Total IMSmitSKMKNTS iHsitrii SK MKNTS MortKSKP loans * 88.O7Ti.0il Mortgage loans * SN.&lt;I7.\OI( Slock loans stock loans _ :)00.no .KXIIIII Withdrawals runninK mwk and divid.-ml* - 140.Mtl.2K Withdrawals runninK utix-k and dividends- 14O.9t!l.a&lt; :f,.lt)0.(IO I'.'JB«.13 WlthilrawalH paid-up stink .ti.loO.OO Withdrawals paid-up stock Withdrawals diridend on paid il|« BliH'k Withdraw all dividend on paM-np Hto«-k li^BftlS Salaries 7.1 lu.ou Snlarlrs T.11O.0O Com missions „ „ _ 7'JJ*.00 T-.-.llXI t'ommission Other expei Be _ l.:!74&gt;8 Other ex|»"l s«. l.:i74&gt;S Keal estate iii'eoiint 1 "~- s Heal t-state account 1.072. m Cub ..n hiind il.207.2!) &lt;'ash on hand Ken! fst;ile solil un eoiltr^i*t - 11.4."» 11.4.". Taxes .iriiiiiiit W3.NK Hank cvrtleatex of ilrpoxit jiiimtMHi 3O.0M.0O ■Lv.'.'Kl.TII I.ilierty Bonds Municipal se&lt;urltii Total I im.-iK.to SII'PI.KMKXT AT. REPORT I'lau of aKModatloii 1 'erlliailellt Xiimlicr of shares issued stnev orKani/.ati"n r.i.MH NunilMT of shari-s outstaudine last it-port Sharev issiieil since last report Total 2.277'.] 1S.HK2 Sliares wittiilrawu. iiiaturnl or cancelled since last report I'M lT.rw Numlier of shares in fori-c thic ilatc Nuinlter of shares on which dues are deliiniueiit .-,m Average running: time of stock matured during tile year. 110 Mo. Number of horrowini; stockholders nit Number of non-lM&gt;rrowinK stockliolders l.Wt Xnmher of loans made for Imildinir pnrpoaea dnrlns year s Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or homestead tnorteaires durlnit year Xi Tar value of each share of stock l(X).0O Total amount of dues delinquent at this- date tl.WJ.0K Amount of dues oiviiiK by borrowing tttookholders d.-iffJ.Ofi ii.3s»..«n 14.2tlO.()0 Amount of interest, premiums and nes due and unpaid Number and amount of mortiraees subject to f oreclonu re. Numl&gt;er anil nmount of mortgages in proivss of foni-losure. i.rooo-&gt; Amount of loans on Improved real estate ■Wt.-JTi.OO Appraiseil value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made Kll.)!nO.0it Amount of loans fin unimproved real ewtate S.MS.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loan* hare been made !&gt;.2.V)0t) been made Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security .Vc'..TCO.0O Amount of tornado in»nrani-e in tortv and assigned to the axoortation as collateral security _ .II.I.'.M-'I.O'* as collateral security _ i.i.!M«.o'&gt; Ainount credited to reserve fund during year 1.T3M0 Amount t&gt;f losses cliareed to reserve fund during year 14-"».-~- 1.730.00 Amount of lossvs cliareed to reserve fund during year Anionnt &lt;if dlviiiemls diilnred on running sto«l; iluring year '.'irrai 17 Vinount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during rear 1'J.sRii.iri Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock iluring year 7% Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured anil full paid stock during ft', year - •% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year 7.2 and 9% </seg>
            <seg id="p080">10 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Rj E. Harrington Vice President J. Y. M. Swigart Secretary Prank Mili» Treasurer E. M. Bair Attorney J. A. Brown DIRECTORS H. T. Wilson R. E. Harrington George Hager Frank Mills E. M. Bair J. Y. M. Swigart J. A. Brown E. M. Bair ASSETS First mortgage lotm $ 124.500.00 Loans on ntc&gt;&lt;-k or pass haak wiurity I..V1O.OO t'iish fl.541.0H Ifc*lln«|iifi.t inter.'st. fiiHK, etr „ 272.40 Furniture mid fixtures 240.35 Taxes paid :u;/.*:\ IlKlirunre p.ltll _ HOC) Total | 133.14H.7H I.IAIIIMTIKS Kl iMK slo,k illld .Mvj.lellils $ 5.1.71S.41 l'aiil-un slo&lt;k him) cliviili'iuls _ 7IL21W.00 Uewnrr fund _ BBS.72 1'ndiTided proflM 2,882.63 Tottl , f «M*W </seg>
            <seg id="p081">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 51 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 UKl'KII is Cjish on liiiiiil last report $ n.OSd.+o Dues i running stock) 41.1 1.Y (IT. I'tiiii -ii|&gt; stock ... "' no!ooo!oo Mortgage payment* „ „_ 6.0110.00 Stork limn payment* 2.CKI.M [Merest .....Z.....ZZZZZZZZZZ.ZZZZ. 7.2!*."».ft'l Pines ' ' 2.4O MeuilxTshlu and transfer fecx M.Ktt.OO Total I 1 l.x.:EM.0fi IMSHIKSKMKXTS Mortgage loans _ * 67.100.00 Stock loans ~ 3^585.00 Withdrawal! running stock ami dividends LZZZZZ.Z.ZZZ..Z.ZZZZZ.. HJZLM Withdrawals paid-up stock Withdrawals paid-up stock - 21,000.66 Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock „ _ .1.380..1:! X3an.x\ Salaries ______________ liMB.70 Communion* __ _ 5i310.4S Other ex|K»nw» HA8.00 Cash on hand ___________ B.J41.0R Other disbursements In detiiil W0.1B Cash on h.in.l lOO.lfl Total f lli.ra4.0ti Rl I'I'I.KMKXTAL kKfOHT l'lan of assofiatlon „. „ Permanent Number of shares is-uc.l since oreanlxation 12.01." Xumlier of shares outstandiui; last report _ 3,04.1 -Minuter ui snares fMiisiaiHuiii; i«sr report „. .i.iFt-1 Shares issued sinc&lt;&gt; last report - JMKU Total _ 11.70* shares withdrawn, matured or canrrlled since last report 1.370 Number of shares in force this date 10.32S Number of borrowing wtockholders - „ _ 107 1.370 Number of non-borrowing -tockliolileni 1.040 Number of loan* made for building nurpooes mirinir rear. Number of loans made for purchasing of homeoteads or payment of bomentead mortgage* during year !._ S3 Par value of each snare of stock $ lOOOn .VI Amount of interest, premiums ami lines due and unpaid - 272^40 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure So. 1 1,200 00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 123,200.00 Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare been made 312.860.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate _. 1,300.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - 4.S00.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 170.000.00 Amount of tornado insurance in fori-e and assigned to the association as collateral security 144.noO.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year J9S.."i7 Amount of dividends declareil on running stock during year 2.521.20 Amount of diviidends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year fl.350.33 Kate per cent of dividend" declared on runningxtockdnrlncyear. %% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock ilnr- In jp yp&gt;r 6*% Itatt* |K»r &lt;*ent &lt;»f intcrvst. ffc nrjj**il Imrrowrr* durlne T«*ar — — — (14% (f-. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">52 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL. REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the MIDWEST SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA on the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Julius Reusch Vice President Dr. H. P. Wekesser Secretary E. C. Boehmer Treasurer Nicholas Resi&gt; Attorney F. A. Boehmer DIRECTORS Julius Reusch Nicholas Ress Adolph Lebsack, Jr. M. Wagner Dr. H. P. Wekesser T. H. Berg ASSKTB Firm inortirain- loans * 13«.:SOO.O(&gt; l.onns on Ktmk or mis* l.c.k &lt;.-,iiriiv 1.(100 01) Cann .' S.AZA..Vi Kurnitnre and fixture** 172.00 Ta-en paid ________________________________ l!t!iO Second Liberty Bonds _ ".'. _______________ mm Third Liberty Bondi* i".v&gt;.."ii War Sn vines' Stamps ' liifticn 2 ii -n r: &lt; paid fU.ii. T»tal % 14..4SR.T- LIAIULITIKS KnnniliK »to&lt;k ;in,l dividends _ $ 1!».ri7«.41 I'Kiil -up stock and dividends 1W.IWV00 Imic sliarclHildcrs on incomplete liunii _ L'.-iK"..*^ X 19..-i7«.41 _jK_m Kescrvc fund *4&lt;M).()0 i inlivided profits _ " 3.47^-^ J'renaid *tock 114'rt? Total — _ % 1I..W8.7H </seg>
            <seg id="p083">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD ■ RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE Y EAR ENDING Cash mi liuuil last MM Dues I running stock I Paid-up stock .*. Mortgage payments Stock loan payments Interest Memltership and transfer fi Taxes Insurance City National Hank. note Second Liberty Loan Third Liberty Loan Total Mortgage loan Stork loans . Withdrawals running stock and dividends Withdrawals paid-up stock l'l..SOO.O0 4-_'.&gt;O0 0n Withdrawals dividend on paid-up Mack Salaries 3.1K.IM 175.00 Commissions . other expense (ash on band Tales :»M.fio «•■ v,. rt.tBB.Sfi ioo.mi Insurance paid mjs Furniture ami fixtures . Ctty National Bank, not Seconil Lilierty Loan 172.00 ti.OOOOO UO.U Third Liberty Loan War Savings Stamps 1.452.2H l«r&gt;.(5li Total $ HMMU3 sn-rr.KMKXT AI. BKPORT Plan of association Permanent Nuinlier of shares outstandilii; last report - _ 2.235 shares iMsut d since last report 1.6HG Total _ :;.&lt;io ■■ Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled sincv last report ~!H . Xnnilier of shares in forif this date SJSLw Xninber of shares 011 which dues are cielini|iicnt HM Xunilicr of shares subject to cnini nation for 11011- payment of duen 2M Number of borrowing stockholders 82 Number of non-borron ini; stockholders 18S Number of loans- made for hallrilnc pyfpf cinrlnir year R I'iir value, of each share of stock % 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 3..TJ7.70 Amount of lines nwuiir by borrowing stockholders 1.21.'&gt;.0O Amount of interest, iiri'iiiiinus and lies due :iud unpaid (&gt;71.0r» Nninber and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. ft KJAIO.an Amount of loans on improved real estate l.'M.TOOOO AppraUe&lt;1 value of improved real estate u|N&gt;n which loans hare lieeu made 241.H0O.0O Amount of loans on uniluprcivcd real estate - 1. 100.00 Appraised value of unimproved rc:il "stati- ut&gt;on which loans- have been made a.SOO.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and -cssitned to tbe association as collateral security ! I-WAVkOO Amount of tornado iusurainv in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 130.KW.fl0 Amount credited to reserve fund during year ."W0.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year .*LVi.O!) Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year :MWl.fto Rate per pent of dividends declared on running stock during year ft r ; Hate* i&gt;er cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dur - ing year •*£ Itate per cent of interest charged borrowen. during jr«r 7.2% </seg>
            <seg id="p084">54 STATEMENT of the condition of the THE McCOOK CO-OPERATIVE Bl'ILDIXG AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION McCOOK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President John E. Kelley Vice President J. A. Wilcox DIRECTORS John E. Kelley J. A. Wilcox H. P. Waite L. W. McConnell W. B. Mills •". 1-. Kahnen ck M. Lawritson F. M. Kimuiol! C. J. O'Brien ASSETS Fimi innrtKiiKi- loans X 20B.88Ti.OI) Loans ou xtix-k or puss lionk ■pcnrttr '•iWOO Oanh ......' ' 2.004.17 Tax**** pa iil -. - - til. 7— KxpenHn. i»«id :...:....: ___._ ,22-i£ illlVrty BiMliU '" ~ 1.000.00 Total - - $ 214,071.31 LIABILITIES Uunnine «to&lt;-k and dividends 4 m.l!XV44 RiwrTF fund _ 8.743.61I I'ndlTided profits _ ____________ 8&gt;no'.lK Adranoe dues „ 241.0U •Total - 4 214.071.S1 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 55 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 itKC 'EH' TS Cm* on hand last report - - - _| HM Dues i running stork &gt; - 4SJ84.O0 Mortgage payments _ _ . . 82 i.iOOO Real estate sales _ 97950 Interest _ _ _ _ lft.UI-.or&gt; Kini's _________________ _ 60.18 Meml&gt;crship ami transfer fe&gt;"» - - - 74.70 Tax sale redemptions 5-7.G0 Total $ i:».!IOl..TI. DISBURSEMKXTS Mortgage loan* - % 72,975.00 Stock loans „ - 150.00 Wlttdr-wala r---_ir tort a-d iUtHi-— - -M.4Ki.7n Withdrawals matured st.sk ________ '- — 14.MO.00 ,uuu.uu 540.00 Salaries other e-'pi-M - ..I ..- 20.94K.O0 KxpfnMi's \n\ ill ~ — - • ►.00 Cash on hand — ............ __ ............... 2,004,17 Tax sale &lt;^Ttitir^eZZ''yZZ~'ZZIZZZZyZr''''Z~ZZ..I.'. ___ :B4.!« Liberty Ilonds 1.000.00 Total - - - — ■♦ 136.901..16 SrPPI.EMEXTAI. RKPORT Plan of association Scprial Number of series issued since organization - ftl Xuinlier of shares outstiindliiK since organization 12.S14V4 A72B Numlier of shares (uitstuniliiiK iHst rvimrt Shares issued since last report 747 Tnt«l . 447B 1 1 I ( ;| | . 1.1(11 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report tEW'« Number of shares in force this dnte - - 3JBW I £ Average running time of stock m:itur»'d during the year 123 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders M| Number of non-borrowing stockhnlderx •&gt;— ' Number of loans made for building purposes during year 10 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year «_. « Par value of each share of stock - - ■• . 200.00 Par value of each share of stock Amount of loan* on improved real estate 200.&gt;"X&gt;.00 Appraised vi:lnc of Improved real estate npoi&gt; which loans hare be«-n made 3B7.B7S.OO Amount oir lire nnd tornado Insurance In force and assigned to the .TO7.S0O.00 association as collateral security .WI—MLjJ Amount credited to renerve fund during year Amount credited to lesvrve runn during year ■-*▼» -i~ I Mil lint of dividends declared on running stock during year 1(&gt;.471..&gt;O hate l&gt;er cent o' dividends declared op running stock during year. s~. Rate iht cent of Interest charged l«&gt;rrowers during year !&gt; r 'r </seg>
            <seg id="p086">56 STATEMENT of the condition of the MADISON COl'NTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION E?~ MADISON. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June 1918 OFFICERS President C. S. Snyder Vice President W. H. Field Secretary A. E. Ward Treasurer _ - J- L- Grant Attorney M. B. Foster DIRECTORS C. S. Snyder Jas. L. Grant P. M. Yeaiel R Snyder H. Davi. Ja8. L. Grant W. H. Field FYed H. Davi.- W. H. Field I M. Dawsoi ASSKTS ASSKTS Kin«t MltMl Linns $ 1S4.1M.00 Kir»t Mltp«l limns * lrW.lM.OO KM* i« process &gt;tf fnrerloxiire 1X10.00 Uw iii pro* i-ss nf fnrtfloKiirp 1.MIO.0O I. onus on stock or MM iHink w&lt;iirit&gt; '... 4.V).o«i i-HHh S^M.12 faun :t.^.i^ I &gt;•- 1 i ■■• | ii&lt; - 1 1 1 inlcrfst. Iih, ftc - .Tjei.sa Kiimit ii r* 1 mi'l fixtures rtTl.rm Knrnit ii r* 1 mi'l Hxtiircs rtTl.rm Eimid &lt; mortKHKml nrrailMwi - 17!l.0."i I IIi.ikIh l.OOIMNI i ai-.-'iint 8.18 Tuxes imiil I morlKHKml prvnilKexl - IT.t.O.', I.IImtiv Bond* 1.000.00 KriHbtA irmlll aiS 8.1S Total _ * MMBJI mi _ f 1«1.821.17 I.IAnil.lTlKS ltunniiifr stock mil iliviilmiU % 7.i..V.to.4'.' PaM-up sto.k ami ilivldi-mU 7B.00O.UI Mil I II fund 2.089.00 1 "mltviilwl profits -.KIO.T^t Itills payable — J!! — JZ. 2.000.00 Xotal - H 161,821.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 57 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 MM T&gt; K II Cash m hand last n port 4 4.7(Mi.n iMit-s truiiiijii^ siocki n;.«K*4.i:'. Paid-up stock .* .* ." ...'""".. 24.mio.Of&gt; Mort^n^r** puymt'iitM 3».rtK&gt;.7r» St.M k hum payment* „ .'iOO.OO StlM k llllltl Ilil.VIIICIII- - _ .'lOO.OO interest 1 :;.(H5.4t; Fines _ _ 'J3R.33 Liberty Bonds „ 10,420.11 l.iliert.v Bonds _ ln.42tl.ll Taxes redeemed .* _... JiNJ.17 Taxes ' redeemed .*. *....." ... *:ML17 Hills payable ti.iioo (Ml Itills payable u.ooo.oo &lt; '&lt;»ll**&lt;iions refunded „ _ 4.HO ( »ther receipts £{.0i&gt; Out of Imlaiic** ~ „ 4.27 * Mit of linlaii»t* — „ 4.27 Total 4 10ft..*WC*T&gt; Total 4 lM.39ft.25 maitrnsKMKXTs AfortKaire loaiiK $ Stwk loauM TflO.O(» stock loauH 700.00 Withtlrawala runniiiK ■toek ;iihI (Ifvlileml.-* -t.TLVE! Withdrawala running mtark aad dividends 4,71.1.1:1 \VithilmwrtlM uuld-un nunk lt;.riTiO.0iv \yith(lriiw«lH uuid-un stock Hi.ilVl.no WitlnlniwHls (lividends on ptihl up vnn-k 4, 7-1. He Salaries _ l,33fi.0l Salaries _ l.H3S.in &lt; &gt;t her t'Xpcusc .„ _ H ■ (ientTUl expen»t* _ „_ ■.".&gt;7.J.~&gt; t'iu*h oil hand „ .'&gt;.^lTt. vj Cash on hand „ .* ■'•.JttTi.l'j Taxes '2'S"&gt;.'H\ Taxes JJ."».'.Ni Bills pavalile nnleemeO - _ 4.(100. IJO Bill* pa va hit' rwievmed - _ 4,()00.()l&gt; Litwrty BondH 11.420.11 Lil&gt;ert.v Bonds 11.41*1 Ml Total - 4 10««&gt;8.^ Total _ 4 lOtsrsiR.:^ Stl'l'I.KMKNTAI. KKPOKT Kri'L'LKMKVr.W, KKIMUtT I'luu &lt;»f association „ Perinanm; I'luu of usHOclsdon „ PtTinanm; NuiuUt nf akana issued sliio- orKaaiutiou UK% NuiuUt of shares issued slno- orKaniution MtB% XumliiT of shares outstaudiiiK hint report _ 1,701 Xunihtr &lt;if shart-H outstandiiiK laxt repon _ 1,701 Shares issued since last report ShartH isKiii'il sincv last rtport 474% Total reB i«sueil since last report 474 \ Total Sharra withdrawn, maturtil or . anci Ili-U xlui-v la»t report Jfi« - 4 Shares withdrawn, matured or cauct lied since last report MB* t Number of shares in force this ilate 1.M0SI Number »f shares In force this date 1.M0SI Nuuilter of shares on whirh dues are delinquent 127 Number of shares on wbieh dues ar*» dellniiuetit 127 Nuniher of shares suhjevt to i-.ui&lt;-ellatiou for uon-payment of dues. . 1 XumlHT of shares subject to i-.ux-ellatlitu for non-payment of due*.... I Averace runnlnK time of stn&lt;k matured during the year 117 Mo. Averace runuiiiK time of stnek matured during the year 117 Mo. Number of luirrowiujr stockholders _ 108 Xumlier of non-lM»rrowinir stockholders (B NumlxT of loan* made for building t&gt;ur[Mises during year 10 Numl&gt;er (if loan* made for iniri'hasini; of homesteads or payment of homestead -mortgage* during yenr ■ Par value of each share of stock 4 JOO.OO Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 374.00 Amount of dues owing l»y borrowing stockholders 274.6.&gt; Amount of interest, premiuins and flues due and unpaid _ 5H3.:t*J NnmlM»r and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure Xo. 1 JOO.OO Xumlier and amount of morttraces in pro.rKx of foreclosure Xo. 1 1.H000O Amount of loans on improved real estate l.V&gt;.!t!t4.(IO Appraisal value of improved real estate uiniii which loans have been made 24.-i.d0O.0O Amount of Ore insurance 111 force and assigned to the association as collateral security 182.700 110 Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security as collateral security 14«.jno.0o Amount credited to leserve fund during year 471.HO Amount of dividend* declared 011 rminiiit: stock during year _ ll.:t&lt;8&gt;.lo Amount of dividends paid oa inatund and paid-up stock during year l.ms.Hli Kate |ier cent of dividends declared on nubfl sttH-k during year '-&gt; r ; Kate tier cent of iliviilends paid on matured ami full paid stock 11 &lt; I r Ing year - «" , Rate per cent of Interest . barged liorrowers during year »', </seg>
            <seg id="p088">58 STATEMENT of the condition of the NEBRASKA CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Henry Fastenau Vice President J. W. Butt Secretary W. H. Pitzer Treasurer H. F. Meyer Attorney W. H. Pitzer DIRECTORS F. M. Cook George Bader W. M. Metz H. D. Thiele W. H. Pitzer E. H. Buhlman H. F. Meyer E. J. Von Gil!ern J. C. Miller ASSETS Klr*t inortjr&amp;ffe loans f 153,506.85 I.nans on Htock or pass book Ktvurtty (W52.18 Other real estate „ 2,732.14 K**nl pstatp wild on &lt;-*&gt;ntract ft.4tVt.37 State and municipal HpruritieK ."&gt;.050.&lt;*&gt; j \t'a | ( "I nlr W I1U UIi C"' "II rail - * .............._............„_.•.„....„..„....„„__.„....._„.._*...... »••,•&gt; 4 State and municipal HeinritieK 5.0SO.00 Casli lB,fjn.ii:i Cash l(Ct2»'i-l Dflinciucnt interpKt. fines, etc- 2.16SJA Dflinciucnt interext. nnex. pt&lt;- 2.URM Knrniturp and Bxtnrex „ 100.0(1 Kiirnlturf and fixtures „ 100.01) Taxes paid lSUW Tuxes paid lJW.fiN InsiiraiK-c paid 40."* Total - * l«5.0M).!l!i 1-rABIMTIKS lillUllilli: «to&lt;k ;in«l ilivi.lMlldK » WH.922.WI I'nld-uii «t&lt;Mk and dlridendu _ *i.000.0(» Itewrre fund - 5.611.4^ Indlvided proflU 2JM.TI Total I VKiMOM </seg>
            <seg id="p089">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 59 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report $ 17.tWt.44 I Mies i mailing stork t rn.9O6.:27 I'aid-up stork _ ".TTiO.tX) Mortgage payments- Xt.'MJ.Xi Stock loan payment* _ 13.H15.2S Rial .-state sales - 2J87..1B 1 llterest 12.XO1 ,4H Kents ' "i&amp;tlu Membership anil transfer fees „ ttt4J6 I'ounty warrants _ _ 4.706. 7&lt;t Insimiiire. $X!M: Taxes. JlClM _______ lKT.tH I'rotlts. |__: font-losim- it— X. *llt:.7K _ J-JH..TI J-JH..TI Correction entries _ _ Sl.Ofi Total » 130^00.07 DlSItlRSEMEXTS Mortgage loans * • B&gt; Tf)9? &gt; stiwk inans ___I_JI...JIII________________."!~!~!!~ !i.«sn.w \VlthUr«w«l» raB-r»ir"nf. : ii i»d iHrldfdii ..ZZ'ZZZ. :tl.0i!.x: Withdrawals- paid-up stock - - - VHSS-9S Withdrawals dividend on paid up itiKk — - T'TiHi!) Salaries _________________ l --*_2"9ii other expense - - - ■- 4'.O.4i Real estate a.-cotint - - - 4! 5*I ('a»h on hand KUSUa Insuranev 194.i_i Insurance insuraucv BTSS Kor«M-Iosiire expense, $10: taxi's, $3&lt;!U»."&gt; _ - ISft'^i School ' Iton.ls ! ! - ■■■ •"'■ ffl !S-S5 I.ilMTty Honds ~ -TO.JO I.iiN-rty lionus SJ-iS Keal .state .ontra.ts 1.100.00 Total - I l»;Wi.07 SIPPI.EMEXTAI, RKPOKT I'lafl of as«.latlon Per ""S£ n ,' Nuinl'er of whares issne&lt;l sln.-e orjcanlxntlon !*^8&amp;V» NiiiiiImt of shares .nitstanilin b last rep&lt;irt •'•i_?v5 l .MIIIUHT or simres oiusiiiii.iiiiK ias» re|H.ri iiii r Shares issued since last report &lt;■»% Total - - :i.«2Vi Shares withdrawn, matured or ran.-elled since last report 4»T&gt; 1 ~ Nnniber at shares in fore* this date - 1^ Avenitie runiiint' time .if stock matured diirlnc the year - 1: *i n^'A!" i'ar value of eath share of *«X'k __ - ■* 2WJ.00 Amount of Interest, premiums and anew dues I'lid unpaid .rJS^S Amount of loans on iinuroeri nnl estate - 1X5,306.85 Appraised value of improved real eslat. uimjii n hl&lt; h loans hare hwn made - 23a.:«0.00 Amount of lire insurance in fnn-e and assured to the ass&lt;H-iation as collateral security 224.tXiO.00 Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the a*s&lt;x-iatii&gt;n _» _, as collateral security - — ■ 141.000.00 Amount credited to n serve fund during year - .TH3.W4 Amount of dividends declared on runtime stock during year ft.OO&amp;ftl Amount of dividends paiil on matured and paid up stack during year •-'.tS».."iO Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year Rate per &lt; i-iit of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dur- e Per ITUI HI UlTl.iril.l" l*«m "11 .mm-....,.. ...... ..... ».-... -.".» ..■-. Ing year . H ins year _ ■ ' Kate per cent of Interest chanted UornnverK ilurllnr year . &gt;'■ I </seg>
            <seg id="p090">9n STATEMENT of the condition of the NTCKOLLS ("OrXTY Ml IM)]N(i AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NELSON, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President . .Geo. Lyon, Jr. W. C. McHenry Vice President Secretary Treasurer Attorney DIRECTORS W. W. Hawley F. E. Bottenfield J. B Goodrich ASSKTS lut'-n-Ht pulrt Kipenw Total I.IAHII.ITIKS HunnlnK MiHk nn&lt;l rliviilcnfls Knll paid st&lt;x-k Bnrnrp fund l.«83.7:i Inilivided pruBtn ■■—■ ' — •' 3.010.38 T»t«l - - 4 92.74U.S2 Geo. Lyon. Jr. E. D. Brown H. E. Goodrich Kirst mortjmjri' loan* Ummm on sinrk or $LM honk wvuriiy IMiii«|iit&gt;nt iat«n1, flues rtr Tjixi'k p:ii.] Itondx </seg>
            <seg id="p091">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 91 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE Y EAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RKC K IPTS • 'asl: on hnnd lust report lMit'S i running stock I .... 4 3,VH."4 14.:!7r&gt;.!t!&gt; I 'aii I -up stock 'J.'.mo.Ou Mortgage payments I"- k lOHn payment? Real estate sales . Interest 22.304.74 2D5.00 l.siro* i).!WK.4!i Membership and trunsfer fees Tax sale redemption" M.75 150.13 Total — .» n.w»M diskii si- MKXTS Mortgage loanft Stock loans * 30.811.ri 210.00 Withdiawals running stink ami dividen Withdrawals paid up Mark N mill matured 1S.O»:1.44 7.100.00 Salaries joaoo Other exiH'iisr H4.HK Rt'al &lt;t*tate mm I l.iis.-. Id 4.!«3.71 &lt;*:i-1l on llHIKl Tax sale c-ertlncati' [MtiTi'st paiil S07.41 MtHL.IO Itiimls ri.OOO.Oo Total * r&gt;2,2!&gt;2.*4 sri'pr.KMK NTAL ltKl'OUT l'liin of association IVnnaiient N'umlier of shares oiitstamliiiK la&lt;t rep&lt; Shares Issued slmv I: st n'ix&gt;rt rt MM :M1 Total J.4L-.I..-, Shares withdrawn, iiiiitunil or ram-ellei Number of shares in fnn-e this ilat4- ll iiin-e last report -■i-.T Itt!.." Number of shares on whlt-h tines are delinquent sia Numher of shares siilijeit !i&gt; raaepllatlM for iiou-|i:i.wueut of ilue*. 71 Average running time of .&lt;ti&gt;&lt;-k matured ilurlni; the year 111 Mn Numlter of Iwnwriag stoekhohlers HKt Number nf non borrow inp stoi-kholilers km; Numbi r of loans inadi- for tmlliling puri&gt;oses during year J&gt; l'ar value of each share of stock * 1I»M»| Total aiiii-uiil of lines tlelilli|ueut at this ilati STi&amp;SO Amount of dues owinir bv borrowinir stm klmlilers .■h:i.V) Amouut of Interest, premiums and flues ilue anil unpaid 354. IN Nuuiher and amount of mortgn^es stibjcet to foreclosure.-- No. 4 Amount of loans on Improved real estate s.-i.4:tn.75 Appraised value of improved r«-al esrate upon whii-h loans have tieen made 177..&gt;e.-..0(» Amount of lire Insurance in force and assigned to. the association as collateral security 117..-i(K&gt;.©i&gt; Amouut of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the aumx-iation as .'O I lateral security 1 17..-s».0l&gt; Aiiiounr '-redited to reserve fund during &gt;iar 281 111 Amount of losses ehar^ed to reserve fund dnrinc \ear -■:.w Amount of dividends pnld on uunire,l ami paid up stock ilurinir year ."..J!r,.&gt;e Kate per cent of dividends dei-lared on running stock during year - Kate |mt i-eut of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock dur ing year l&gt; and Kate per eent of interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NEWMAN GROVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY * NEWMAN GROVE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1918 OFFICERS President Chas. Letheby Vice President C. J. Peterson Secretary-Treasurer E. H. Gerhart DIRECTORS Chas. Letheby C. J. Peterson E. H. Gerhart C. E. Barrett A. L. Doty Rob't Chauned ASSKTS First mortgage loans J$ 4O.-HI0.0i&gt; L&gt;elln&lt;iuent interest, tint**. *»tc - - 1TK5.2O Expenses 'J05.00 Total _ 4 40.8W.0U Total 4 -IO.80H.00 LIAHILITIKS LFABILITIKS Running stork and dividends 4 2O.o7:i.S Running stork and dividends .$ 2O.o7:t.i". Paid-up stock and dividendK „ 5,730.30 Paid-up stork and dividends „ 5,730,30 Due »harehol(lers nn Incomplete Innns ."&gt;,400.&lt;NI 1WS(^T^ IllBQ .-- SfiR.ftt Rt'iMi ie fund .. MfiR.O;» ToUl 4 40,808.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 KEl KIPTS Cash on hand last report f '.tt.40 Hues (running stock! .. K.i*B3.8O Paid-up stock __________________ ___ .!. 400.00 Mortgage payment)* - 4.200.00 interest ~ „ -.-40,X"i I'rt'nilum - - - - ."79.95 Ivni.te, Kines 28.ft" Sundries _ 77.00 I'roflt account - !•*.!• Total - -t l!)JCt7.ftT&gt; DISBI'RSK MKXTS Mortgage loans * 8,1110.00 Withdrawals running stock and dividend* 10.820.6r. Salaries 1.10.00 Other expense W.00 Cawh on hand - ''7.^0 Sundries _ 136.30 Total _ $ 1!IX17.(E1 SrPPI.KMKXTAI. REPORT Plan of ussociution Serial Number of scries issued since organization 26 Number of shares issued sin&lt;v orKanlzation 1.(102 Number of shares oiitstandilnir last report - — 473 Shares issued since last report - M6 Total HTl* Shares withdrawn. -naUired or cancelled since tout wport 97 Nunilier "f shares in force this date 57S Number of shares on whuch dues are d* llnmient _ 12 Avcrnee running time of stock matured during the year 117 Mo. a Numl»er of borrowing stockholders .• 24 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 44 Xumlier of loans made for building pur|Hises during ve«r •"&gt; Plan of premium Monthly Par value of each share of stock $ 200.00 200.00 Total amount of dues delimiuent nt this date „ 01. 2A Amount of dues owing by borrow lag stockholders SI. 20 Amount of interest, premiums .-mil fines due and unpaid - 44.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 40.400.00 Appraised value of improved real estate u|x&gt;n which loans have lieen made Hfi.dfiO.OO Amount of lire insurance in force r_l nssigned to the association as collateral se«*lirlty S0..'iO0.0O Amount of tornado lnsiir:ince in fon-e und assigned to the association as collateral security 41.00000 Amount credited to reserve fund during year _... 132.15 Vipnunt of illvidends declared on running stock during ye»r 2.511 20 Ttate per cent of dividend * declnred on running stock during rear 10 r S 2.511 20 Rsite per cent of Interest charged borrowers 'hiring rear .'. Hrr, Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year 1.6f£ </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 STATEMENT of the condition of the SECURITY SAVINGS AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION NEWMAN GROVE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Geo. H. Gutru E. W. Johnson Vice President Secretary O. H. Olson .O. H. Olson Treasurer Attorney H. H. Halderson DIRECTORS R. I. Gutru O. H. Olson Phoebe Gutru R. I. Gturu E. W. Johnson ASSKTS lirsi inorlKM).'!' loiiiis $ 2x.«w.eo s.7'.'7.:bi 1 from Norfolk Nartaul Bask. Norfolk lullicl Sliin- Treasury ciTliliciiti-s of iiiil&lt;'liii'&lt;lin'&gt; 4.VIIO NU100.00 .« 47.ti42.W Ti.Ul UAItll.lTIKS * :!..V.1.3I&gt; ltiiunliiK Ktoi-k .'intl iMvlilt'iiils 1'nlil ii i&gt; Ktock unit iliviiti'iiiU Hill &gt;e fund 4:i..soa.(M&gt; tm.at mixw I Bdlrided profits ToUl 4 47,642.39 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BAN-RING BOARD 95 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 KKlKIl is * 2JKH.XI 4.1.S00.M Total * 4T.H.".T.'.'l insist i:sk MKXTS Mortgagee loam other riMMr Cash on haml * .•s.xm.in a»jsa HuM I niteil States Trea-*ury iiTtifleates nf iml«*l»t»Mlmi ln.iMi.im Tot .il * 4T.H.-,-!&gt;1 SI I'IM.KMKNT AI. RKPOKT 1'l.iii nf turn I'iiiiion r. riiiiiil.nt Nillnlit'r nf shart's t&gt;sui-il ttmrr ur^antxuti* NtimluT nf shiirps in fon-i- tliis datr Niiml.«'r nf I't.rrnxvitiy sto&lt; kliolilrrs XiiiiiImt nf non-horrou iim stnrklioMMrs .. NiimiImt of loans uiadi- for imiltlhiK inir|'«'j Nuinlicr nf Inans maili for nun Iiii ttag of ii 1.07B 1.071! II ;i; ITinif yc:ir s linmefleails or p.i&gt; tuiiit nf l»oi!icstr:iil-i!iortir.ii:«'s tliiriiij \ '.ir Plan nf pniniiini in Monthly 1IKI.0' l'ar vahif of pa&lt;-li shar»* nf stoi'k * Amount of limns on iiuprovtMl r»*al ffti 1 A |i|»r:i isril valiu* of iiiiprnvi&gt;il r«*al i-stut JS.H0OO&lt;» i'ih.ii wttrft Inans hav Ittfn inadc Ki.onn.nn Amount of fir- insumiicc in font' niul us i-ollaternl twM'iirity ssit'Ilr.l to tin assiM'iatioii 2&gt;.100.IMI Amount nf torniulo inHurnn&lt;i&gt; in fnrit&gt; anil as collateral security a»Hl&gt;rii(Hl la tlH- sisiwlatioii •JO.IOO.IKI Amount &gt; rfililnl to reserve fuml iluring yv Amount of iliviilelHls ileclarcil nil running ;ir Ml. no Mork iluriiiK year nnn.riK Kali- nvr .mi of ilivi.icn.u palil on niiitiircit ami full piiiil Mark &lt;liir int' year Kale per cent of interest c liaru'.'.l Imrrnwcra illlliHc year I &gt;tii-&lt; {running stuck i I'rtiil-U|i stook lutrtvst &lt;(.T!&gt;7.3!i Norfolk Natioiinl is.-uik. Norfolk. NVI&gt;r. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 STATEMENT of the condition of the NORFOLK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President H. A. Pasewalk Vice President J. C. Stitt Secretary C. B. Durland Treasurer C. J. Hulac Attorney Mapes and McFarland DIRECTORS H. A. Pasewalk J. C. Stitt E. F. Huse I. M. Macy A. Bucholz S. G. Dean John Welsh Burt Mapes G. B. Christoph ASSKTS First mortgage loans S flOft.tViO.nn Loans in proeefi* at fnre&lt;lo»ure 1.:BH.23 Loans on Rturk or diixk liiMik woiirtty ."&gt;,OWi.!K&gt; Real estate, offltv. $16 JU0.-J*; ..th.-r real estate. W.RWJ-SO 21.30R.fB Real estate, office. *li!.:H!i.JB: other retltMuiiiT, |S^iMJ»" 1'1'.'.'!.'Z.'"..1.Z! 21.30R.fl Real isiiii. »old on .onini.t 4.fii'O.S2 Liberty Bondo .. . S.S2B.Bfi Ct«h .' lX.lTSJSd Liberty Bonds 5.520.!V&gt; Delinquent intermit, flnex. et&lt;- - _ 1.71!l.S0 Furniture and fixturex 570.2Ti Taies paid 8O.i:t Total * 8U2.8R7.4!. MABIT.ITIES KnnninK iitook and dividends 4 .T77.IH8.5:'. Paid-up stork R«««rve fund 2rc.xu.00 10.fl0T.24 T'ndivided profits ______________ l.M&amp;SB Net parningH fi months 17]»74!l" Total .._____________.-_. 4 B82.SS7.4n </seg>
            <seg id="p097">SECRKTARY OF THE STATK HANKING BOARD 97 RKCEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RKt'KlPTr ('ii*h on hand last ri'|Kiri $ ."■.r.i'U.xSi Hues &lt; ruin. ing stock I - - lUtMKll.Kl Paid-up »to&lt; k .._.____ '...'. .iiii.bkmiii Mortgage payments _ 1 tli.lHin.no Stock luilll payments ."i.ifJ.OI* I lea 1 fit ate sales T..V*T.TH Interval 4T.."ist.T4 1'roflt and hiss «^. 1 .11+4.7- Fines _ 41H.:St Kfiiis .i~ta.it&gt; Membership and transfer f«-rs -_\Ki4.iri rash iii 7..*»11.:;i Itills iKiyiii.ir r.i.wii).im Taxes, fill III . pxpvsar. xl,l««. 1.402.1!) i: 11 11 ni iiu- stm-k _ _ 1.202.."*) i: ii ii ni iiu- stock _ _ \:M!.:n Liberty Homlw :i.K7'.i.ft-&gt; Liberty Roads :t.N7!i.ft-i Furniture anil taftna, ilivi.len.ls. f.l »l 151.81 Furniture and tlMnn — . *1JO: dividend". £tl.M - 1M.S1 Total _ * 711.tCi3.li; Total * Til— W DISHIItSKMKNTS I&gt;im:I i:si .MKXTS Mortgage 1""" Stock lllHIIN . Mc.rtBiiKi- Inn us $ 2tt.081.WI * L'l.~&gt;.0M.0U Stix-k limns «.&gt;T&gt;1 R.287.81 TI.HH3S Withdrawal)! runiiiim "fork and ■livi.lcin Wir hrlran iitw paM-vp &gt;to»-k Withilrnniils ruiiiiinir "!"• k and diviU.-nds 71.MM.2S Wlthdrawala i&gt;.ii.l mi. &gt;to,k 2in.O22.0n n'lthdravalii ditidrnil cm pald-mi si.Kk 12.4M.2« SiilnrlpH -M~v4 O.i I.l.M.O.i "lii.iiniuio siixim^ii^-. jii.ikmi: Btiix iiiiviii.il'. xis.i»«j rm.neo.im imIht fX|M'iiw 4.7'_1».."7 Real I'sl.'ilr ;I,TOIIIII mid llffiri t'asli nil lijiinl lifiil csi.iic anoniit iincl iitflif _ 1'J.lil.i.j" • 'ash uii iiitml i::.iT.". r^; Uhertjr Iii.i.ils !&gt;.«».&lt;»&gt; Uherty liu; .Is IT.. Hi nil. I \nmm. fl.:u;i.^s: furnltiirp .in. I &lt; iish. $7.)!f..41 : tux.-s. auiJU I'n.tii :ni.l I. is*. »l.:uil.2S: furnlturp ami flxtntv*. »:ei«».j."i „ 1.7T.1..V. &lt;iish V7.tun.41: i«\.-s. jctti..-«i _ 7.&lt;:7.nii WitlHlriiwnls imi&lt;l ll&gt;, sto.k - 2IH.022.0O Surplus _ l.tr_Vi.."l l.«K.V..."l Interest on loan mill dues U'4.."it) VU'*) Tatal 711.iKl.li; - SI ri'l.KMKXTAI. KKPORT l'hin ..f iisstM-hition I'.-riiuin. in Nniiil»«*r of j*h»n-s i.ntHtiinitiniz l-i'*! n*|M»rt l!t.'.»10 siiarr&gt; is-n.-tl siiici' last report _ S.flHTU* T..I ill 28.Si5.lt .-..N47!&gt; ■.'J.74H.0 Shar.-s wttllilriiwn inatlirt'.l or t-an.-cllftl sili.t- last r**|M»rt -NnmtM-r of shares in for.--- this data NiiiiiImt of sliiir.'s nu whi.-li .In--, an- .h'lin.iii. nt I. '.'70 NnnilHT of s)iar.-s BRbJvti l&lt;&gt; &gt; an.t'llation for nou pa\ in. m ' ..f daeM. AfffBB. rnnninB tiim&gt; nf stock niatnn-&lt;l ilnriiiK tli* 1 year M7 m mo. NiiiiiImt of borrowing sto.-kholilcrs Nunilicr of nnn-lmrr &gt;»iinr atorkboldrra t.i; mr, Jl NiiiiiImt of loans iikii'.i' for I. nil. link' purposes i nrlliL' year N'unilier of loans iua..e for pur.-hasiim of lioni.'stea.ls- or payment of hoinesteail-tnort^a»-es .liirint: year ■&lt;s I'ar value of eaeh share of stoek * 100.00 T..tal aluniint of ilues ileliii.iueiit at this ,lal. Amount of lines owin^ by borrowing -i ix-khol.lers A in. t of interest, premiums I tines Mile ami un|&gt;ai.l Nuinlier ami amouiit of mortk'aues suliji-it to forceloxure. No. :'. Nuuibei anil atiionni of inortgattTes In process of foreclosure No. H Amount of loans on improved real estate WM5.2B :ilN.i' I.TW.W J.300.00 i4.MW.no «M.!«0.(X&gt; Apprnise.l value of improved real estate upon \\ lii.li loans hare. Imh&gt;d made 1.1O1 ..'Ml.lll Aiiioinit of loans on iinimprove.t ri'al estate 1.7O0.0. Appraisett value of unimproved ri'al estate u|m»u which loans have Im'cii made n. -jou.no Amount of (Ire iiiMtiiinie in force and uKslitneil to the aiuwx-iatimi us eollaieral se&lt;urity c,~ .400.(10 Ami. nun of tornado insurance in force anil assigned to the »-mk i.nion as collateral s«M-itrlt.v uift.flao.aft Amount cnillteil to reserve fund during year Amount ..f losses chared to reserve fund during year Amount of dividends •leclared on running stock .luring v-ar Amount of ivi. lends paid on nrit'm.l and patd-ap sto. k during year Rate i»t cent of ilivldends d.clari'd on rnniniiL- stock during venr Kate per cent of dividends paid on mitliin-d anil full pal. I stock dur Ing year - -S and Kate i«er cent of lntemrt chargnl lw)rro\ver» .luring year » and j.'.nr.o.-. 1.U1.43 :tn..am. v. 1Z41SJ1 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 STATEMENT of the condition of the ELKIIORN BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Dr. H. J. Cole Vice President F. E. Davenport Secretary T. E. Odiorne Treasurer H. J. Cole DIRECTORS Dr. H. J. Cole F. P. Davenport T. E. Odiorne A. Degner C. E. Doughty H. T. Donner ASSKTS Firm mortgHKr lonns * ."i7.000.O1) &lt; 'nslj 1.030.""- I &gt;&lt;-lii&gt;&gt;|iii-iit Interest, fines, etc J!tL &gt; .!&gt;7 Taxes iiu Id - ~ .'tT».7(l lMin&lt;|iirnt inferest, fines, etc. :f..7O Ubertj ltonils and Stamps t.UBM Tiital - t til.117.fK! LIABILITIES Kunning «to&lt;k and divid-uns t 21,4117.74 KiiriniliL' KtOik Mid (Ilvi(i"ua8 $ 21.4!t".T4 Paiil-ii|i stock and dividend* V&gt; -2S!MK htilH fun.l , . _— _ '-'■ i.VK).OO Indlvirted proitW'''.'.".'."..'..'.'.'."'.............. 1.211P.JK &gt;j' otll l 4 61,117.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 Cash on hand last report Dues i running stock ) Paid-up *t&lt;K-k 'i.nTiO.ito MfirtRHKi' |&gt;«.vni"iits - KV..ViO.(»O I iitrrrst 4, WtO.!&gt;H iMVMCf - HB&gt;.~2 Total ni8I»rR«EMKXTS Mm i«.,hi« t 2i.:ioo.o&lt;&gt; Wiithilraniils ruimliiu slink ami iii\ iili-mls JB7M.II0 nncl 4.01'J.SS Wnthdrawals rminltiK stock ami dh idcnd Withdrawals paid-up stock Withdrawals pai&lt;l-ii|i »t&lt;i.-k - 10.4.-i0.0(i KU.TO.On Wltliilrnwals (liviileiul on |iiiiil-ii|i st&lt;Hk 2.2VVSi •-•.24O.i'i Withdrawals dividend an paid li|&gt; -nick Salaries SalaricK -JUVOII &lt;'omuilsHhiDK -»JM&gt; Commissions I'iish on han ("a?fh on hniul i l.(iT!O..V- Insurant'e paid Jti.KT Insurance paid Kent, telephoiif. printine. adrertixinp Liberty BondH and Stamps Kent, tflrnhoiif. printing. ailvi-rti»ini; tt&gt;r£i J.l.Vl.00 Total * 4:l.«4"..^O sri'PI.KMKXTAI, liKI'llKT I'lan of axsoriatlon Permanent N'limlier of shares issued sllmv orennixiition 4.."i.'Wii &lt; XnmlM»r of shares outstanding last report - 7H4 1 Shares issmd &lt;in.-c li.st report 310 Total - - HM| Shares ntthdrann. matured »r i-anielleil shin Insi rv|"&gt;rt Vlf* Xumlier of ?harea in force this date SS4 Xiimber nf tHtrrowtiiK stockholders _ 4M Numlier of non-liorrowinir atnrkkaMm -T* NuihImt of loans made for liuiMi'iir unrposi-s duriut; Xilinli«*r of loans made for itun-liiwini; of hoinesti-nds or cnvincnt of homestead -niortirajres durinir year tl Par value of earh share of stock $ ■.'(NMIo Amount of interest, premiums and ttnes ilue and unpaid 2&gt;g.ft7 Number and amount of mortir.iires subject la foreclosure No. ."&gt; imnim Amount of loans on improved real estate ."&gt;T.0OO.)M&gt; Appraised vnlue of improved real estate upon which loans have l«een made !K).000.0(» Amount of lire insurance in force and assigntM to th" association an collateral security ~&gt;.U00.0ii Amount of tornado insurance in for«v and assigned to the :•* tociation a» collateral security - 70.01)000 Amount credited to reserve fuud dnrine year :U*0 00 Amount of dividends declared on runnliif stock during *■••*- IW.HI Amount of dividenils paltl on matured and n-ild-mi rtar% &lt;lur *"ir vear "-•.24O.2T&gt; Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock ilurinir v&gt;ar rt^ Rate fier rent of dividends paid on matured ami full pi id stock ■ liiriiii.' year _ •&lt;« Kate |K&gt;r ceiit of interent . h.irz.-.I lK&gt;rroners ilnrinc r«ir S'J </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the NORTH LOl'F BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH LOUP, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of Jun*, 11,18 OFFICERS mrt~-* President Geo. E. Johnson Vice President Secretary E. A. Hutchins -E. J. Babcock E. J. Babcock E. J. Babeock Treasurer Attorney DIRECTORS H. C. Sample Geo. S. Mayo S. L. Clement E. J. Babcock I'irM imnii I. .ill. l.ojiii- on sitH-k or paM book *»i-urilv Uw» - lNiin.|iMiii unirint. late i'ii Total I.IAISM.1TIKS Kiinniim atork :m&lt;l iliviiliinl l':iiil mi sIih k tin ililiviiliinl I 'it.- *hnri'h"iiliT-c nil ii iA|&gt;Mc lunu IfrsiTVf rillial I iiiliviil.il |.n.ht&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p101">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 101 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 Cash on baiul last report iHii'M {running stuck) ... I'ald-up stock 1.M7.KI J..-iflK..-,7 l.'.WO.IIO 1.710.0tJ i .irio.trr Mortgage payments Interest ■.M.Tr. Kines Membership and transfer fee* «S.4T. Total 9.77S.XI Mortgage loans Stork loans i;..a«&gt;ini 100.00 Withdrawal running stock and dividends Withdrawals paid-un sttx*k l!«.0O J.OOO.Ol) Interest on paid-up stock Salaries „ V.C..4K '.-48.011 Other expense Cash on hand Matured stock :e».mi •J8.i". ■-'4.-..U Interest on matured stock 428.44 Total * 9.TTS.3 SIPPLK.MF VI- AL REPORT l'lan of association „ Pernunent Number of shares issued since orKiinixation 1.71BS) Number of shares outstanding last report 807V shares issued since last re|&gt;ort W Total 70IH-. Sliares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report S3 Xumher of shares in force this date ** 3 ty Xuiul&gt;er of shares- on which dues are delinquent !"?* Average ruuning time of atari matured (luring th eyear US Mo NhuiImt of horrowing stockholders 51 Nuinlier of loans made for Imildlng purposes durinK year 1 Number of loans made for nurchasing of homesteads or paymeut of houiefttead-mortgage* during year I value of each share of stock 4 KIO.OH Par value of each share of stock Total amount of dues delinquent at this date .'.7-'.i»&gt; Amount of dues owing bj borrowing stockholders- JIE.llO Amount of interest, premiums ami fines due and unpaid M3J14 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 7 tSBRM Amount of loans on improved real estate - -Jl ,!»N."i.0O No. 7 4 nun oo Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate iiimui which loans hare lieen made :t!i.7no.(»i Amount of loans on unimproved real estate JIO.OO Appraised value of unimproved mi estate upon w hii-h loans have been made :HI0.0i&gt; been made Amount of fire insurance in force ami as-signed to the association as collateral security J7.0."«1.lll) Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - J7.OTiO.IKl as collateral secuniy - .t.»w.i«' Amount credited to reserve fund during year t!4.10 Amount of dividend* declared on running stock during year 1.IM.VU 1.01.1.01 Amount of interest paid on matured and paid-up stock during year. . tEfiJM Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year '*' &gt; Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid slock during year T ■ Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year »•» I NumlHT of non- borrow! njr stockholders 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 STATEMENT of the condition of the MUTUAL BlILDIXd AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH PLATTE, NEBRASKA on the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Thos. C. Patterson Vice President Victor von Goetz Secretary Samuel Goozee Treasurer W. H. Munger Attorneys .. Wilcox and Halligan DIRECTORS Ira L. Bare M. J. Forbes F. T. Richmond Victor vor. Goetz W. W. summing W. R. Maloney Geo. W. Finn Thos. C. Patterson C. O. Weingand ASSKTS Kirxt UMirlKuc- louns * WEi.UIIU.INi I.OHIls til pPOc*'SH of foPerlOKUFH ~ _ rtO4t.lMl) I^piiiiw M Ktiwk or pans Ixxik iwiuritj - _ 5.400.01, KeHl * j «tat« J . oflli-v "Jit.:i23.14 liitleil Stat«*« (io%*('rnnn'iit ImiimIk _ . 10,4O0.(N&gt; (■a«h l!t.74O..'il (■a«h l!».74O.."il I ii'liiiiiiii'iit lntereMt. finite (OH.'M Furniture ami f xtnres 1.01 7Ji7 Furniture ami *xtures 1,01 7.37 Kiiri'il&lt;iKiin&gt; ;•■■&lt; ount tVi.TU Total 4 !M1.-«I.(M Knri'ildsiirc ;•.&lt; ount tVi.TU Total * !M1.7O:U!4 I.IAIUI.ITIKS LIAHII.ITIES ltunnlnK took nuil iliri&lt;leiiilx * 432.:«V..O1 Itunnlns took nuil iliriilfiulx * 432.3ft'.01 I'niil tin Htoik unil illviili-nils 45O.TOO.(M) I'aiil u|i Ktoik uml illviilciulx ,.'", ' " '..,, 450.700.00 KeK«-rve fund .. . 22.500.00 Kexrrvv fund 22.300.00 ruiliviili-il iirofltH 38.10R.ns AdvaiKf Interest 30.00 Total * Wl.703.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 103 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 KKCEIPT8 Cash on band last report - - $ li2,(H0.b&amp; Cash on band last report - - $ lS2,(HO.b&amp; l»ues i running stinkl 1^3,^41.00 lMies i running stitck) 1^3,^41.00 PBid-np «to.k _ -. 8a,a».oo Paid-up stock ______________ ..ZL1.Z1.Z.™..... -. 8a.200.O0 Mortgage p:i v mcnts '.►7,7^tt.-4 Stock loan payments _ _ - 1.TTKJ2 MortiraK 1 ' payment* '.►7,7^tt.-4 Stock limn pa v men! » _ _ - 1 .TTIM^ Office huililini; _ ."4JU.00 Office building JX&gt;.00 Interest SL8T2.M [nltn-sl . . . U1.H7'.:.IH Fines _ iiU.lt&gt; Fines _ BS1.1O Membership and transfer b«a _ - _ MSJB MiMnlHTHhip Hnd ti-aU8frr (i«&lt; - - - M5.3i Rents, office building _ 1,020.87 KfUtn. office hiiililiiiK - 1,020.87 Sale lultecl Stuten Itonds _ 000.00 Sale Inlted Stuten llonds _ 000.00 Foifil— life account 80.2C Foreclosure :lccount 80.2C Total _ _ 4 3Hn.7O7.6«&gt; Total _ _ 4 3N«.7O7.6«&gt; UISBIKSEMEXTS IMSIUKSEMENTS Mortgage loans _ 4 J08.000.00 Mortgage loans _ 4 J08.000.00 Stock loans _ -uu.wi Witbdraw-ils running stock and divi&lt;Ieu«li* _ ,Vf,H55.H.*&gt; Witbdrawala palil-ii|&gt; stink 53,300.00 Withdrawals i]l\ i.l.n.i on paid-up mock a,in"L74 Salaries — _ _ '456000 Other expense _ ri.Vl.ls Keal estate account, olflce building - - 101.34 Cash on hand 19,740.,'il I'nited States government Bonds _ JO.OOO.Oo foreclosure accouut — — K1.04 Total * :wo,7O7.uu 8UPPLEMKXT AL KEI'OKT I'lan of association Permanent Number of series issued since organization All matured 17 Nuuil'cr of shares issueil since urbanization - I XumlMT of shares nutstaiidiiiK last report -. 10.&amp;SIS Shares issued sln&lt;-»* last report 2,313V* Total li lJ.mT Shares issued sin&lt;-c last report Total h Shares withdrawn, matured «r cancelled since l»*t report J.056S! N'mnlier of shares iu force this date : 10..VO C Xumlier of shares on which dues are delinquent 342',a Averaife running time of stock matured during toe ye«r 127 Mo. 10.580 "~ Xumlier of borrowing stockholders _ _ 475 .\umt&gt;er of non-lforrowina stockholders ti*; Xiinilx-r of loans made for building- purposes durinlg year 11 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads' or payment of homestead-mortgages during year 60 Tiir value of each share of stock $ Total amount tt dues deliuiiuetit at this ilatt - !Ca).IIO Amount of dues owing bw borrowing stockholders .".jO.OU Amount of interest and tines due and unpaid N.'M.'.IO Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. t; 7.100.00 Number and amount of mort gages in process of foreclosure No. 1 .100.00 .Milliner .iiui iiuiouiii l-i uiuriKii.iccK in iiroccsn wi mm iiwun 1 .^o. x .mmf.imi Amount of loans on improved real estate )*H, 700.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which Joans hare been made 1.."&gt;7l'..'!!i."i.uO Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 600.no Appraise! value of unimproved real estate upon which loahs have been made .... w l.riOO.OO Amount of fire insurance in force and Hffslgned to the association as collateral security 98S.O1IO.OD Amount of tornado insurance in force anil assigned to the association as collateral security !»20.335.0O Amount credited to reserve fund during year 3,000.00 3.000.00 Amount of dividends declared M running stock during ye«r 31.31J.lt&gt; Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid up stock during year •jr&gt;.rtl." &gt; .74 Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 9% Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year 8^ Rate per cent of iiit.-rest charged borrowers during rear 7.1% </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 STATEMENT of the condition of the NKHRASKA SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President Thomas A. Frj Vice President _ R. S. Wilcox Secretary J. R. Brandt C. E. Brinkman Treasurer Attorney Edgar M. Morsman, Jr. DIRECTORS Thcs. J. Fitzmorris Thos. F. Godfrey C. E. Brinkman B. R. Hastings O. D. Kiplinger Wm. G. Ure B. R. Hastings Thos. A. Fry B. Julien R. S. Wilcox ASSKTS I'lrsl iwirtKHK"' louus _ „ _ 4 1,14*. 773.011 Uaaaa in pct't— at torrclaMN - lOJMJC Loans on »to&lt;k nr pass 1 k Wf Hty 2S.8SS.SX &lt; &gt;ther r**ti I «*f*tatt* -.(&gt;7T».7* Heal estate sojil &lt;&gt;n rontrui't ~ - 4.iKI7.'Ht St»tt* and nuiniripii! scrnritlt^* 2f&gt;,72!t.^ rush 50,8.t7.44 Cnsh ."jO.SS7.44 1 ►&lt; 1 i 1 1 . 1 1 1 . ■ 1 1 1 Interest. faM «&gt;W taxii» _ 4:f&gt;.T2 r. X. UWrty KuniU, W. S. S. ami Thrift StiiDin|M 'Jl.4Ti6.wi IX'liU'iui'in Interest. (i»is and taxii» _ _ MB.TS 4SB.73 r. X. UWrty KiiniU, W. s. s. un.1 Thrift StiiDiniM 21.-ti6.Wi Total - » 1.286.573.4^ Total - $ 1.286.573.4:: T/IABIIJTIK8 T-IAIUIJTIKS ltiinniiik' »to&lt;k unil .Ilvi.l.-nils $ 1.00().24«.tis nuiiik' MHfe unil .Ilvi.l.-nils $ 1.00O.24H.BK l'aiil ii|&gt; stiM k anil .livi.l.rnlx _ IMTp.OTO 11 ill up stoik anil ilivlilenilH _ li4.-p.O7O 11 jiut* mIiu rt'linhlcrs on i ik-oiii |i Ift i- liMins _ _ 2..~41.2O Idle xhari'linliliTs on incomplete* Iimidm _ 2^&gt;41.30 Kwrvr fiiod _ - ZT.i'iO.OO Kwerve fund _ - 27.2Ti0.0l I radlTtdfd pr«&gt;flt» 11.4&lt;i-».4S Total * 1,280,573.42 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 KK&lt; KII'TS Cash mi baud last report :»,0L-».iT 70.02.\HK Hues (running stock! Paid-up stork Mortgage payments JOK.lT-'.UO t.V533.IKI Stock loan payment Real Mtat* &lt;:iies Keal tatate MM !&gt;l5.:ts Interest .... 77. 1137.81' Interest Fees :«W.7(I I H*H il« i iifin interest ... 1.2-flilH Cash over ."i2.:&gt; Cash over 1. s. Liberty liomli j::.4.'iO.O&lt;l V. S. Liberty Koud ft.4aa.aa War Savings' and Thrift Stamp* _ _ _ '.W7.2I War Savings and Thrift Stamp. ■AK.JM Ciiy Warrants ( it y Warrants _ I"-i.Oip I '.ills payable _ ."iO.IIOO.OO I'.ilU payable Received from inemlHTN on accounts due and lunw refund* BUi ToUl 4 83i7tH.2i anil i 11 i.-r. — r refund- Total UI8HIUSKMKNTS DISH1KSK MKXTS M&lt;&gt;rtKUK&lt;- loans 9 H6,TaK.."&gt;S llMlais loans s aftj-tuc! Stock loans 51.«Ki.7^ .-.t.wc.7.-. Stock loans Withdrawals ruiiiilnic st.M-k and dividends - 37D.:iO--'.'Hi Withdrawals runnlnic Mark and dividend 37U.:W-'.!i« Withdrawn Is patd-ap stock - 12lljHrtK.u"» Withdrawals |iaid-iip stock i-jK^ntim lS.7W.il Withdrawal* dividend on iiaiil up stock 1S.T1&amp;21 Wlthdrawabi dividend ou paid up st&lt;H-k Salaries 4.322.U2 Sularit-s 4.:tr.MfJ P. S. I.ilx?rty BodiIk - - 44.017.&lt;»&gt; P. S. I.ilwrty BodiIk 44.017.(» other expense &lt; H her exp«*us4' „ _ .'i,O'JS.."i!t :i.«JW..V.&gt; Kenl estate ;M niniii Tft.7 1 -* Keal estate ai-riMint 7».?&gt; t'ash on hau&lt;l — - - r.O3r&gt;7 44 dish on hand .-.0.3.17 U Hills payable _____ '.'.'. ."i0.00O.flO Hills payahle •W.000.01) l)cllli.|lli-'in interest 1 )eliut|llent interest IMI'.t. 1 7 (ttci.17 Kore*-losnre aceonnt Korec Insure Hceonnt - 10..V0.HL' 10.:fO.Hj War Savinics and Thrift Stampx - 0!t7.1H War Savin*.'* ami Tlirlft Stamps 907.18 Interest on Idlls payable and refunds _-k41 Interest on Idlls paynlde and refund: i»it..4-j TaaM paid for borrower: I'jvis paid for borrowers _ -. _ - M_M M-.1K1 rity warrant t 'ity warrants 'JflO.iK) ■.•oo.i w A t las (Jreater Omaha - 30.25 At Ins (Jreater Omaha :*&gt;.\2i ( ash *hort _».4« Total - 4 83J.TS4.2i ■lM Casii s-hort Total SUPPI.KMKX TAI. KKl'OKT Plan of assiM-iattnn _ Perinaiien a*.!!^ Number of shares outstanding; last report .Numlier of shares outstanding last report 38,113% Shares issued since last report 4.fl80*4 Total - 4O.7»«V. Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled sin&lt;-e last report UMM Number of sbarex In force tbU ilate SiSlI** Nuint&gt;er of borrowing stockholders „ 738 Shares issued since last rt'imrt Total MBS sutfi NuinlH"r of horrowing stockholders Number of non-borrowing stockholders 1.200 Number of loans made for buildiuir purposes during year ?i Nuuilter of loans' made for purchasing &lt;&gt;f homesteads nr payment of homestead -mortgages during year _ 28 Par value of each share jt stock f l(»l.i») Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid *■'..". 7''. Nunilwr and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure. Xo. ."» tl.or.O.H Number and aiuouni of mortguk'es in proi-ess of foreclosure.! "... No. r&gt; IC.'HO.sJ Amount of loans on improved real estate ~ 1.14a,77&amp;.00 Appraiseil value of improved mil estate upon which loans hare been made 'J..*R:l^0r&gt;.0U Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security _... 1 .■~iT7.onu.im Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1.4.11.7AU.OU Amount credlttMl to n serve fuml during year _ ~CaW.4» Aiiiount of divldemlH decljreil on running stock during year 4W.0OO.4:! njBOM 4!&gt; Amount of dividends declared on running slock during year Amount of dividends paid on matured an. I tu.ii'.up stock during year i::.71H.'jT Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 5 * -"&gt; '-■ r ; Rate per cent of Interest charted borrowers during year - H 1 ", Hale per cirui ui iiiitrtcDi. iuni|ni uu»»wwci» uuiiuk jmi n r Kate per cent of dividend paid ou matured and fall paid stock during year - 5 and 8V4% </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the OCCIDENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President John F. Flack Vice President R. A. McEachron Secretary E. N. Bovell Assistant Secretary John T. Brownlee Treasurer George C. Flack Attorney T. F. Wiles DIRECTORS John F. Flack R. A. Mcachron George C. Flack E. N. Bovell Robert Dempster ASSETS First mortgage loans 4 «,O73,170.8T&gt; Loans In process of foreclosure ' ' 2fM)3K.44 Loans on stock or pass hook security __.._.___._._..__!._] 2n!3KU~&gt; Real estate sold on contract '.'. Z~....1ZZ!"ZZ"Z~!!1....*" R4]302.2fi State and municipal securities lo!772.S3 rash .__1ZZZ! 57l'.*&gt;7.7fi Delinquent Interest, fines, etc _ 35.73.YS7 I-ilH-rtv Bonds _ IZZZZIH___ 12o] 400.00 ut*m I., iwuut; _ l.a*,-f^N,.1&gt;*l War Saving" Stamps _ _ «S«.41 Total _ _ ; $ 6,952.^7.;- LIABILITIES Running stock and dividends $ 2.70'.'.14.".S2 Paid-up stock and dividends _ _.J...!Z!!~_JZ_...Z!Z!. 5!fls£«».&lt;l7 Due shareholders on incomplete loans _ „ „ ' ii0.'r&gt;70. Reserve faod - 20o!ooo!oi&gt; fndiTlded profits _____________ ~ 6,'fM1.01 Total _ _...._ _ _ ! $ 6,952,357.27 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 107 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RKCEIPTH Cash on hiiml last rr|xirt t 757157 72 Hues (Running stock I _ _ 914 318! 13 914,318.13 I'll ill -lip stock 1,4751210.94 .. — •- — - A,iio,.^v.tM Mortgage payments _ _ ___ 1,414,491.071 Stock loan payments _ _ ' 72,0Oit.K«i ICi-nl estate sales _ _ 17.571.07 IlltlTl'Mt :ia&gt;.C17ii;; Premium „ !!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! 116!72l!i"» win _J!Z!~!™".._mim!__!!™"!~~" i'sikmI:: Kciil etate contract* „ _ !!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! 15*,734.81 MemUrship and transfer fee« _ 7. ~.\Z..........-.J...~. 9.3WA0 Foreclosures „ !!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! !!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! 30*818! K6 Profit and loss -^ mmmm ' 111.00 I&lt;oan fee and expense _ _ _ ' 25,!»979:i State antl municipal securities 34,86*l.7!t iu'sBH.r'' War Savings Stamps 1904*62 Liberty Loan Bonds 298 2TO.00 I-llH-rty lAtun Bonds Total 2S6,S"iO.0O | 5^30.045 0-J DI8IUUSEMKNTS Mortgage loans _$ 2.419,206..'.7 Mi&gt;rtK:iKc loans _$ 2 419 a» :i7 stock loans 73^8*4 01 Stock loan; Stock loans 75,884 01 Withdrawals runntug stock and dividends ..... 733,8K3'41 Withdrawals rininliiir stock anil dividends .. 75388341 733.8S3.41 Withdrawals patd-ap stix-k WittadrawMl* paid ap stock 1.0H.1W.1.1 W thdrawals paid tin stork _ 1,068,189.13 \\ ithdrawals dlvidciMl on paid-up stork 208,492.^1 » ltnnrawals ilividciiil mi paid-up stock 200 49° "'l 209. 492.1'! Salarlw ™~ " 48!724«l salaries !Z''Z!!Z'!ZZZ''"!!Z'ZZZ'!Z 48'724'oct i'oinmUMionH _ _ „ _ 21 °*B 77 Commissions ■&gt;! oJJa'77 &lt; ithiT expense _ "I!!.!..."""""..! 14377 07 Heal estate account _ _ 4,91S.7i» Cash on hanil _ „ „ „ _ _ 571^*7. 7H Heal estate coutractit „ 3138 44) FortelOHureH „ _ _ _ 19* 782 3j&gt; Profit and Iokh ..* „ _ _ l]SKM Ml lea Be and Expense _ " 7170 85 .Mileage and Kxpense _ _ 717085 State and municipal gwiirltir* _ _ _ _ _ 8.AOO.00 State and municipal gwiirltir* _ _ _ _ _ 8.500.00 H..VXXO0 War ShvIujts Stamps m 2 ."VW 44 War Sitvinjrs Stamps m 2*.'»4fl'44 Liberty Loan Bonds — _ !..!"..'.'.. .T07'iro!oo I.ihert y Loan Romls — _ !..!".."!.. .107!l."&lt;) 00 * 'out indent fund o 44^ ."Vi Total « 5^S0.045.02 srPPI.KMKXTAr. RKPl »RT Plan of association Permanent NumlNT of shares outstanding last report ~~/"~.ZZZjeiiOtoi~v£/iHii Shares issued since last report jr.. if* 252/tlOO 2T..0W 252/flOO , Total _ loii.:** 3B2 (»» Shures withdrawn, nirtured or cancelled sim-e lust report '. 20,907 174 (MO Total .Nuuilier of shares in force thin date sr.'iltil 188/flOO Average running time of stock matured during the year _ _. 110 Mo. 110 M«'. Number of Itorrowing stockholders 4.170 Nunilier of non -borrowing stockholders H.8R4 Xumlier of loans made for liuilding purposes during year 42« Nunilier of loans made for purchasing nf homesteads or payment of «.Stt4 hiiinestead-mortgages during year '. .Yrti Plan of premium Plan of premium with interest Monthlv Par value of each share of stock a JOOOO 4 JOO.flO Amount of interest, premiums and linen due and unpaid 35,7X&gt;'."i7 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure Xo. ."# N3.N00.IM&gt; Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure! Xo! tW Jit'Ota! 4 1 Amount of loans uu improved real estate ...........! H.073.170 MT. Appralse&lt;l value of improved real estate upon which loans hare lieen made 10.412.330.00 Amount of lire insurance in fonv and assigned to the aceosiation as collateral security _ _ 11.608. 115.00 Amount of money loaned on improved farms 7. _ 267.35001) Appraised value of land not including improvements !!!!!!!!.!!.!! 50o!70o!oo Amount credited to reserve fund during year 72!l4.t!74 Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during year !! !! 12 143 74 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year ia8,eO2.!¥&lt; l«8,eO2.!¥&lt; Amount of dividends paid mi matured and paid-up stock during year 21rt.l."i7!iVi Kate |mt cent of dividends declared on running stock during year. ' 7'', Kate per 'i-nt of dividends paid on matured and full paid stork during year %r/ r Kate per cent of Intel est charged borrowers during year 6% Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year 1 *■ , U« </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 STATEMENT of the condition of the OMAHA LOAN AND M'lUMN*; ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of Juno, 1518 OFFICERS President G. W. Loomis Vice President W. S. Wright Secretary Wm. R. Adair Treasurer Wm. R. Adair Attorney F. H. Galne» Assistant Secretary .....J. T. Helgren Assistant Secretary A. A. A!lwine DIRECTORS Chas. E. Black John H. Butler Millard M. Robertson Joseph Barker E. A. Parmelee R. J. Dinning ASSETS First mortgage loans J$ 9,781.470.00 I.-iiin- In pnx'wiK of foreclOKiire S.244.04 I. ...-in* on Ktoek or !&gt;«»» Ixmk ■'frily l."il .780.7:'. it. Hi .-stiiir. ..tn.-H $is.-,.ooo.on i .lih.r ri*r&lt;»iiiVr&lt;mjinJML".~lZSZ[Z'Z:.:. ■jm;'.rui:M&lt; Kr»l eHtute sold on .ontrart 7ft.iKB.71 State anil nMiuiii|ia&lt; swuritl™ 3O.SR - i.!)l i ,,&gt;|, _ 141 .!HT7.n7 lN'lliii|iii-nt intt-ri'st. nni-s. ttr 7.901.07 Kurnitiiri- ami flxtnrex 2.822.: l.ilKTty It.. nils 10r&gt;,S.T0.ni) Total $10.Mti.:B« MABIL.ITIK8 RunnlnK "took and &lt;11vidrndB $ S,3S8.7RR.flO l'ili'1-iMi sto.k and dlvidendu 6B1.181.1T Due sharcholderK on incomplete loiinn 97.S47.41 Keserve f 11 11 ■ 1 _ „ „ _ 2S7..".2»;. j:'. indivlilMl profltn ...! Z..Z'.'.Z..'...'.'.ZZ'....Z nMlMl l.ilKTty Loan payment-. 67.4OTi.or&gt; ToUl J10,516.3(».^; </seg>
            <seg id="p109">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 109 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KOR THr YEAR ENDING JUNE Gaat on Ii.-iimI l.-ist report hues i running atorkl !.e£!XM.10 l'aid up stock r£i..ViO.eii I.11-J..M11.00 Morl^M^f |i;i.\ nit nl~ Stock loan payment* Rml estate MM -in.s.\-,M- ai.vin.tm lllllTfSl ."iMI.12i.Kl 1 IH'.i.l3i..VJ Il|cil|liplc|c lOilllS Bond* and warrants Miscellaneous earning UKM-li." i.'.KIK.lli Keiits and iittin- iiniiftiiiu' r. ■ . ipi Foreclosure* W..JS 7.W1.2". l.il»erty Loan rvevlptii LMmtiv HoihIs receipt Btlln pajablr T.-O-'.M £M.10IMI» ritw.oiio.uo Tot;il * T.J-'iti.Mlt'.N!! HISIU'1 Mortsafr Utt Shirk lo.-ins f »IK'MM&gt; M(.n»*.7ii •-•.7»4.7«».-.'!t Wit lHlr:iwnls runniiiir nail (Mvt«i&lt;&gt;iHl Willnlrnw ;il^ pjntl ii|&gt; &lt;uu k ■Mt.xm.M Withdrawal* iltrlilciif) mi nriiil-up »i*li Salnrii^. J4.B73..'* M .541.17 lllc-'iln|il|.ti. hi:lllH utli.T nprmmr i.i;t.-..irj.-..iit \tjaa.M IA.174.3H 141.!l«7..'i1 :t."T.»no.on Total KI'PI'LRMi VI Al. RKPOBT l'lan "f association Pmaaam: NnnilitT c»f Shan's laanrd ■!■** or^niii/.ation NihiiUt &lt; .f akana wH«aadl»g laxt n-|&gt;&lt;&gt;rt Share:* issued sin«^- last report 2fO51.".'(, 1J7.*«' 1N.4.-1K ■i Total i mjm : . 10.1»i Shares witlHlrimn. matured or eane*'lled sin VhiiiImt of share* in fore- this late Nuiulter of liorrowm^ stoeklxdders N'ninlier of non-liorrowin^' sioekholders . Niimlier of ioiins niiide for Imildinu ttiirpn- NuinlM-r of loans made for pur&lt;-h:*:siim of last n-port I2T.1.W 4.7OB 1J.3M iliiriliir vear W holnesK^lils or pavnient if Ii&lt;iiueslead-mortc;i:ees durinc yt.xr I'ar v»ilue of each share of stock Amount of interest, premiums an.- &lt;1 flu .ill l * -110.1)0 lue and unpaid 7.'.lOl.fi7 XumlKT and amount of mortgagr* siii.ject i.i fnrrrlnaTf, N 4 nn..-iOfi.no Nunil«r ami amount of inortcaev's in hmw of fnritln— 1». V \ S.241.04 Amount of loans n« improved nil .state n.&lt;»c.s.-.2.a." Appraised value of improved real estate Bpaa » hieh loans hare been lS.72fi.KSO.Oii iii.nl, Airount of loans en unimproved r,nl estate !!K.li17.!&gt;.-, AppraUed value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hare I.een made SM.2K.0TV Amount of lire insnranee in fate* and assigns! to the axMH-lation 12.177.HBB.3 hs oollateral aemillj \im'iunt of lorundo insiiran, c in for&lt; e and assigned to the assooiation as collateral se, urity - - _... 8.0BS.2OO.OO S7.r.2«.43 Amount of dividends ,1. -dared nn ruiuiiiii: sloek during year aw.aoo.M Amount of divldind' paid oa inaliircd and aaM-ap atorft ilurinK Tear .17.201*1 Bate per ml of dividends declared on ruunlne "took during yrar Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured anil full paid stork dur - ing year . r &gt;-6 r ', Kate per' cent of interest charted borrower* during year 9-* 6-10% * :HO..T?.».a&lt; ■■•I rsi.Llr ;h.OMII! &lt; Iisll nil Itllllll Kon i r|i&gt;snri'- Offlrc Mll»l I »i| i Ii t i II u' t-\p&lt; I. Itflls payable l.llMTtV Itilllils Liberty I^mns I'm nit ii r&gt;- mill ri\in ri~ .. i«;ix4.ki .'■mi.tiiiii.n.1 lttt.tEM.7t! •.'.2B7.4X $ T.:»r&gt;.*rJ.*i m&lt; .-oll;in-ral wiaritj Amount &lt;Te*llt*tl In wwrti fund #lnrliii; ivar </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 STATEMENT of the condition of the CONSKRVAT1VK SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, Ibl8 On the 30th day of June, 1S18 OFFICERS OFFICERS President ....Paul W. Kuhns -esident ....Paul W. Kuhns Vice President Edgar A. Baird ce President Edgar A. Baird Secretary James A. Lyons scretary James A. Lyons Treasurer J. Herbert McMiillan •easurer J. Herbert McMiillan Attorney William Baird :torney William Baird DIRECTORS DIRECTORS Paul W. Kuhns William Baird E. A. Benson A. W. Bowman lul W. Kuhns Robert Dempster J. A. Sunderland Robert Dempster J. A. Sundexland illiam Baird John F. Flack H. A. Thompson A. Benson Charles C. George A. P. Tukey John F. Flack H. A. Thompson Charles C. George A. P. Tukey Byron R. Hastings C. M. Wilhelm , W. Bowman Byron R. Hastings C. M. Wilhelm Randall K. Brown J. C. Robinson andall K. Brown J. C. Robinson ASSETS ASSETS Kir»t niorteaKi" loan* _ !r»t niorteaKi" loan* - 9tU8n.4ti.9t I.oans in iiriHWH of foreolofnire 7.700.0** oaii« In |ir«c«« of fnrwlinnire 7.700.0** l.onns on sick &gt;&gt;r |m»s boi&gt;k wrnrlty 180,917.1 Heal fHtntf. ofB«f. tm.000.00: oIIkt rral HKtntf. W»T7i74.:tl • 12TJS74.3 rmns on sim-k or pa«s book mailljr 15O.ill7.7r&gt; 1S0.S17.73 &lt;-al .•suit.'. 011,1'. fM .000.00: oiIkt rral H«tnti\ *4K..~&gt;74.:n • 127.S74.31 l-'T..-.74.:u Iteal .-stnlH sold on iiwtrart 24,708.02 pal i-Ktnte nH on iiintrart 24.7M.62 ■tr anil niniiicipiil nwiiritlp* 121,654.10 Si.it.- lad niniiicipHl swiirltlos 121.854.lrt C as |l 64X.WV&gt;.."7 i h h 64X.Sfi5.ri7 i-liii&lt;iii&lt;-iit inl^r.-st lo!."i!H).Ol [ifllmim-nt inttrest 10.."i!H).01 Initeil Stiltes It.MHls 2M.S00 00 nili-.l SMtes ItolHlK 2OR.S00 00 ••Miivi.lB.- Itloi-k" i&gt;uri-liiiK«l for tmtmtr offli-e uw- _.. lfloinOO.OM Diivi.lB.- Hack" pun-liMMwl for fiitnn. office iw inO.OOO.OH Total 414.368,270.44 Total UiBttim UnnniiiE »to&lt;k nnil diviilenda - $11.2$lfi,0-V;..-|l I'ald-np Ktook nud dtrtdeads 2.MR.a33.ft» I'aid-up stock mm* &lt;livl&lt;li-nil.&lt; 2.30R.!W3.f&gt;4 Hue sliiirohcililcrs on IWMlpMr loan* 271.032.0." il**s*Tve fund 450,000.00 Indlvided iiroflts - - 4O.371.OIP Itavldge Block rentals 1,878.1.-| ToUl 4H.3«8.270.44 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 111 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. 1918 REl K IPTS Cash ou hand last report $ fiSl.20ft.ll Dues i running stock) - _ 4.0BO.1S1.63 Paid-up stock 6SO..V&gt;2.:tti Mortgage payments _ 2.047. 0l!&gt;.3.~&gt; ,»|'*ll^Lilt* 1 Ml \ I I I'll I r* ■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■ ■■! !■■ »»»...-..f«...»..p... --.-■■■■ *,V^ I ,1J1"',"^P Stock loan payments _ - -. 274.2!&gt;7.-&gt;4 Real estate sales „ il.702.Hrt Interest 72.V1SO I State and municipal wtrmtOm _ 20O7&gt;2n.2O Inited States Bonds - _ -1S8. 400.00 Rents, Davidge Block _ 1S.444.3O Loan fees _ _ 13.V.1.44 RentR and omce )&gt;u i Idtn tr receipt* - 4.140.00 Foreclosure account .TSXfiS.SL' Heal estate account ...... 4«"i.*^72..t7 Profit from insurance 4,^»OO.o6 Profit and logs account - - - W4.S8 Total * '.U30.035.8ti IUSnVRSEMENTS Mortgage loans f 2.400.!&gt;70.L &gt; 1 stock loans '.'. S24JW5.1JI Withdrawals running stock and dividends _ 4.130.*a».32 *» uimraw ni» ruiimuK siock iiiiu iii\iiii » - i.i.Mf.;»_i..&gt;_ Withdrawals paid-up stock &gt; dividend-* i _ TWJML-V Reserve fund - 0.2.V»..Vt liPMvrvp TiJiKi *-- +• ---- -- ------- „,. ---.« *f,»«»p.*p*' Salaries S7.0R7.3S Davidjre Block - 1O.*K1.*U Davidge Block - 10.flRl.64 General expense _ _ _ - 19.M5.S0 General expense _ __ - lfl.M5.S0 Real estate account ro.flOR.SS Cash 4in hand - - MKMB ."7 Pash on hand - - WM.ftflB ."7 Foreclosure account - ~ ~ 21.WH.."W&gt; '•■n' estate sold on contract - 12.M0.tU "-a 1 estate sold on contract - 12"1!&gt;.»4 State and municipal securities ISSSMhM State nnd municipal securities 1MS1»^0 I - nite&lt;l States Bonds Stlim l&gt;0 Interest on Bonds, etc - .".V*"_'..T''. Interest on Bonds, etc - R.1*2.J0 Taxes ami exi&gt;ensc of i&gt;AW Imildiiir 4.sT&lt; Tii I.onn fees !t. MUM Total * *.\MM&amp;J* nxm $ !(.1M.IIXi.si; Total SITPLEMEXTAI. RKI'ORT SfPPI.EMEXTAI. REPORT Plan of association Perirnnef Plan of association Perirmi&gt;—- Numlier of shares Issued sinc-e nrKanlxation l.flfil.!WW Numlier of shares issued slm-e oriranixatinn l..*tl.!WW N'umher of shares outstandinn last repoK _ W7.7W N'nmher of shares outstanding last repoi* W7.7W Shares issued since lust report M.700 Shares issued slme last report Total - 401.411 Total - -Wt.411 Shares cancelled siin-c last rcnort - — 4ft.."iWt Number of shares in force this date — .V&gt;i&gt;*^ Number of borrowing stockholders ."»,4O2 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 17.W? NumlxT of !o«ns Bade for biiildiiii: niir|Mis.-s durine year - 40 .^IIIIIIMT 111 Plinil" lUIHir 1«1 mk |*UB |(iii yii •iin&gt;&gt;.-. .. . .t i wv \ni"tuT of loans mjtde for pnrchiisini; of homesteads or payment of homestend-mortarajres durinir year 271 Par value of each share of stock - $ iflO.on Amount of interest, due and unpaid 10.."ifl0.ni Number and amount "f 'nortifaKes subject to foreclosure Vo. -Jii 7« ."iOO.O" Nuinlier and iiniount of morti'aires in nroiess of foreclosure No. !&gt; 7.700.0* Amount of loans on improved real estate 12.87!M«C0l&gt; Vnprnised value of improved rettl estate u|m&gt;m which loans have been made 27.!ra.(m.W \mount of fire instirance in force nnd assigned to the association as collateral security - 13.!WO.475 0 &gt; \mount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security !&gt;.07oOSf&gt;00 Amount of money binned o"! Improved farms n.OBL.VO.OO Appraised value of land not including improvements ..._ .Yfnn.im so Appraised value or lanu hot inrmtuug imiiniwiufiii" ..._ Ulw « Value of improvements - - 837.318.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during veur *4 r« j"&gt; Amount of louses chnrsed to reserve fnnil during year n 23S.'n \raount of dividends declared on running stock during year Jl" "V4».4O Mnount of dividend- paid on m.itnred nnd nald-nn stock during v*»r HO.SW^O Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during rear H% Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and fall paid stock uuriiiK jtt«i -■-■-•• -...-.-- ,"'V'"llll'' "I"" "»"_. »fw Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during ye«r _ %% </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 TWENTY SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the COUMKKUAL SAV1NCS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NEBRASKA On the bOth day of June. 1918 OFFIC ERS President Patrick J. Sheeny Vice President Secretary W. P. Adkins Jas. J. Fitzgerald Treasurer Attorney Alvin Johnson A. H. Murdock DIREt TORS Patrick J. Sheehy W. P. Adkins A. H. Murdock #\ F. Quinlan Jas. J. Fitzgerald W. J. Coad E. ('. Kohansky L. F. Etler Frank Koutsky Lbum on stoik or nass baak ■wrlty other rc;il r«tiiri&gt; Tom] LIABIL KunniiiK »to&lt;'k and illvlili-niN I'jiid up xtiH-k :iii&lt;) &lt;llvi&lt;lt*nils IMit* slmri'lioltli-rs nil tiifi id f » It-T &lt; - loans Itt-xerve f u ml I ntlividtnl iintflis Total rf:ceipts and expenditures for the year ending JUNE 30. 1918 $ :ci. J07.1W Z94,4Sr&gt;.«l Vi.flou.no 20.-1.02.1.00 ASSh Klrsl moNk'tid 1 loan* Real i-si.-h.. ioM iw contract r«Kii I K' 1 i 1 1 « 1 1 1 » • i ■ r int&lt;*r«'Kt Liberty Bt»"l* KKCRIPTH </seg>
            <seg id="p113">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 113 Stock loan payments lienl entail- sales- 2,2»..-,7 70.382. 4J 1 ..'iffl.UK Interest Loan .\pclis. I H*Unt|iient interest 835.41 Heal estate sulil mi contract Ural Mrtate sold on iintrari liltwrt and Mnrafu Tin.--? Interest anil earnings 4.OK7.II4 •At. MUM Incomplete loans K\pense Incomplete loans K\|»elise : „ 135.«7 Cash cxchangi' &lt; 'ash plrkMB no.jof..?:! Si:.44;i vi ii.tiNN.oo 4&lt;l.l«»0.IKI H.l£!.!« l.Iliirt.v lloliils, So. -2 l.ilierty lion. Is. No. :: t'ertlflciites of de|&gt;oslt l.tlierty lloiiils, Nn. -1 l.il«rtv Itonds, No. :: t'erllficatcs of ilel&gt;O»lt VlnuU ntiil Investment s.iM'k Tntnl Warrant* ami hnWHI -.'■&lt; k Total t lrj».«."i.Tn lHSIttliSK lHSIUUSKUK \IK N is Mi»rtgaa&gt; lonns Mi»rtgs.a&gt; loan * 1KT..S11I.0O StlXli IiiiIIIH Stork loan* 1M.1'.I.",.00 Withdrawal* riinnini; stoik &gt;inil iliviilemls Withdrawal* raanteg Mark a»d illTWrwb :tic,.mL'.in Withdrawal* iutM-ni&gt; Mto&lt;-k * Withdrawak i&gt;al&lt;l-ni&gt; stork !IM..-|5r&gt;.03 Warrants ami investnient stock Warrants anil invi'stiui'iit stock n.403.11 Delin&lt;|iient interest _ - n&lt;Mn&gt;|Ui'nt interest 1.3W.2O Siihirics Salnrii's J. 100 .00 I'jl^ti cM'llallKe i 'ash I'xi'lianv't' nO.iOfi.L'n ( ttllcr eX|M'n(M» (itlii-r I'XiM-nsi- (1.1O1..V. Re;i I estnte :lci*iitmt Hi-al rstat«- ariimnt 4.4ST.24 *'jisli on Iiiiim] t'ash (mi hai:i] CM •"- Inteivst itml t'tiriiinjTM lntiT&gt;&gt;st anil ijirninir- Interest _ Interest 112.57 t'niliviileil profits t'ntliviiletl jirnflts v.e Loan expense T.i&gt;:i ii ex |ielis«» „ _ l..'iItt.0« Ineoniplete loans Incnniplete lonns 1O4.2*V:» 2.TTC.00 Kenl i-sinte sold nn contmt - Keal i-«tiite sold on contnlrt I.il.ertv Ilnnils. N&lt;p. •_• I.il.erty Itonds. N&lt;p 21.23fl.2T. T.il.ertv Ronils. No. :! Tntal l.ll.erty Ilonils. No. flLOW.mt Total $ !*2».41"&gt;.7s sri'I'I.KMKNTAI, KlHlItT &lt;II'ri.K.\IKN I AI. I Clan of ass*n-iatiitn I'liiii of awni latlw I'erniau^Mi NiiiiiImt of slutres issueil since oruanlxation .. Number uf shares issiH'il sinee organization _. K.292'i Vntulier of slmres ontstamlini; last report liMTfi^i Vntulier of slinres ontstanilin); last report Vniulier of shares oiitstiiiiilini; last repiirt _.._ 22.rt7i Shares issneil since last report Tntal Sliares issneil since last report Total ■Glares wltliilrann. matured or cain-elled sini^ of nharva in force tlii&gt; date lane report 3..W« 19.07T. Nunil»er of borrowing stiH-kliolders W Vuniher of non-liorrowhiu stoekholdern 1.321 v nnil»er of loans nuule for lmlldlnfr pnrpo»M*s during year 22 Numlier of loans mnde for imrehiisInK of homestead* or payment of hnnie»tead-nmrt(ra(te» ilurlnB year *» Par value of each nhoro of Mook Par value of each share of Mock ■$ 200.00 Vnwiint of Interest, due and unpaid — 1.021.54 1.011.54 Nnml&gt;er and amount of mortgages subject to forwlonure No. 3 3 300.00 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 1.0IR.31.V00 Appraised yalue of Improved real estate upon which loans bare heen made 2.3WUW0.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate 4.fl0fi.00 Appraised value of unimproved real elate u|x&gt;u which loan* hare lie. le 11. .ViO.nO Amount of tin- insur'tiice in force and assigned tn the asso*'iation as collateral security 1.5fi9.8W&gt;.0n Amount of tornado insurance In force and assigned to the association as col lateral security 1.210.120.00 Amount of money lo.ined on improved farms "i.OOO.OO Appraised value of land not in. ludlni: lniprovcu.entii 10.000.00 Value of liniirov.- it _ 1.5O0.0O Amoiiul of flre insurain-e Hienoii 1.300.00 Vlnouut of tornado insurance ttiereoll 1.300.00 Amount creilited to ies»'rve fund during year ri.000.00 Antouul of dividends declared on running stock during year 43.r»!¥).90 \lMOunt of ilividcnds paid on matured and nalil -up stixk during year 1 3.1 40. 4.1 Kale pn ivnt of divlilends declared on running stock during year H% r /&lt; Kale |ht cent of divlilends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - W&gt;'' Rate per cent of inteiext charged borrower* during year . «.•% </seg>
            <seg id="p114">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 114 STATEMENT of the condition of the PRUDENTIAL SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President W. C. Bullard Vice President C. R. Sherman Secretary D. H. Christie Treasurer D. D. Miller Attorney Smith-Schall &amp; Howard DIRECTORS Ed P. Smith W. C. Bullard C. R. Sherman D. D. Miller E. A. Blum T. E. Wood D. H. Christie ASSETS First mortgage loans S 4i7.14.\01( Loans nn stork or pass book security -ll.ViOOn other real estate - n.OOO.&lt;K) lleal pvtat* MM on lontrait D.7O0 0O Cash H,'iM:t.r»T Furniture and fixture* _ &amp;4 -&gt; CO I.ll«Ttv Itonils 4.4M 00 I&gt;ue from various i&gt;enu&gt;ns 12.00 12.00 Total _ _ „ $ 438,:ei7.77 LIABILITIES ltniininc «wk iind lUrlilendu _ f 4-IO.~2ii.On Due shart- holders on Incomplete loans L*_JZ!!!!L..~!!!!". 12!oin." Henerve fund - S!72o!on I'ndlTlded profits _______________ l,8BS.2n Loan fee« —.—_—__________ ' 6T97 ToUl __ _ __| 458,S»7.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p115">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 115 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING Eir is HKi Cash on huml last report Ouch (running stock) 4 lU.H41.Mi l'.U..1t4.H4 Martgue pa.vn ts Sim k li'iin payments Interest .M..I50.00 l.cKXI.IHl i"..:U4..",l Mcniliersliip and transfer fees Liberty Honds _ _ ... :CiO.."iO 11V.KW.OI&gt; .Misceli; us .'ll.Mtfi.Hl $ ssi.wu..-.; Total DISBIKXEMEXTS .Mortgage loans Stock loans* .... * i:(o.tC4.jri &amp;230.M Withdrawals runninic -tin-k anil dividend Salaries 13!I.H&amp;4.41 J.IWO.On Other hmm Gin tin hand Kent, fees 4.-j&gt;.:Mi S.dM.-iT '.liW.iNI Liberty Boudx MiscellHlleous . 1K.S40.00 ■J»,M-M .» 3SI.8.M.SJ Total BUPPLKJIKNTAL KKI-OKT Plan of MssiM-ini i.m - Permanent Xumlier of shares issued siiu-e nricanixation l'.tfH Nuuiher of slians iiutstulidiuic last report Shares issued siu&lt;-e last report l^tM Total 12.KW Shares withdrawn, inatunil or cancelled sim-e last report l.iw. Nuinlier of shares ill force this date 11.823 NudiIht of horrowinj: stttckholders ~ NumlMT of non-liorrowiiiit stockholders -... 673 Nmulier of loans made for ImildiiiK purpose* durlnx ye«r • -&gt;lllUI»*"r "1 ll*illl« III. Hit- 1V1 1&gt;K iiui|^,ori. 'iiniu* .'»Mi Nuiulicr of Iniiiis made for inirchasine nf homesteads or payment of ■ homestead uiortK.:Kex iluiinic year -TO value of each share of Ktock $ lflO.flO P:ir value of each share of Mock 1'ar value or eacn snare oi rum-k « n»i/.iiw Aniount of iuterest. premiuuiK ami fines due and unpaid - - _1XTi Nnmber and amount of morticaices suliject to foreclosure No. .1 lO.TOU.OO Amount of loans on iniprnved real estate 421.W3.0O Appraised value of improved real estate upou whU-b loans bare lieen made H4.'t.N(iO.0O Amount of loaiiK on unimproved real esmte - .VadO.Ot* Appraised value of ■■Improved re.il estate upon which loans have __«„ lieen made lfl.i00.00 Vmount of tire insurance In force and assluued to the association as collateral security 42-.'.OO0.t» Amount, of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 4W.000.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1.111.00 .ViiMiunt of dividends declared on riiniiinK sti«k during year 1U,«47.7O Hate per cent of dividends declareil on running stock during year rt r ; Hate per &lt;-ent of iuterest charged borrowers during year — IN JLNE 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NEBRASKA On '.he 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President H. M. Beall Vice President Secretary E. O. Ames Irving G. Barighi Irving G. Baright Treasurer Attorney E. C. Hodder DIRECTORS E. O. Ameg H. M. Beall E. C. Hodder Irving G. Barighi H. C. Getscher ASSKTS Flint mnrtKHKP lo.-ms * 215.55S.0a Loans mi stock &lt;ir miss- hook security ('a«h S.6K.W -0.&lt;il9.:i:t I &gt;clihi|iiciit ihtrrext. flupK, etr. Furniture anil flxtures ..101.54 IIIMP.Oii uihiT assets 2K7.2Ti Mlierty Kou&lt;ls Misccllnn* «iiis . r,..:io.4!t m.m Total $ 2f».tCV&gt;.2: I.IAnlMTIKS Running stock and aivldendR $ UMST.M Paid-up stock and dividends Hue sharpholdern on Incomplete luaus .VI.418.-JO S.H4O.O4 i'ii&gt; nuni ru&lt;'iuri »• i&gt;ii | in u ill J&gt;H | (■ Klnlln — . ... ~i,~rtv.'rt Reserve fund 1.H77.7X I'ndlvlded oroflt _______________________ l]02S.«7 Other Ualiilltietf 3° 40 Total — $ 2M.trfVi.J2 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 117 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE JUNE 30, 1918 EAR ENDING Y RECEIPTS Cash on hand last leport S 13,4)31.941 I&gt;ut*s ( rmmiiiLT stock I 1111,306.02 Paid-up stork _______ ..... T.'.ifiO.OO Mortgage payments lK.JiiiK.1.' St. i.k Inn ii payments _ _ 8..J7M.J) Real estate saies 572.8° Interest _ - 14.-M0.tM Delinquent tiitwut 7flB.l« Delinquent intpnit 1 IS.- 1 * Incomplete I onus -- — — 775.42 I.ilterty Bonds 3,311. ft7 Total » 1XS.0W.41 I.ilierty Bonds 3,311.07 $ lN8.0»-.'.4t Total ItlRM'KSKMKNTS D1SIU ItSK MKNTS Mortemre loan - % S8.flfl2.22 stork loans " 2.2B2.00 stock loans " 2.292.00 Withdrawals raaalas stock and rtlvidenrtu - ti2.n74.!&gt;l Withdrawal- ri_»_W utork and dW-MMli - 4e.im.91 Wltliilrawnls paid up sto.k 2S.700.OO Withdrawnls paid up stock i.".700.0y Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock 3..TT8JIS Withdrawals dividend mi paid-up slock 3.STOJB S:il:irics 2.457.«&gt; I 'i mi missions - - 5.00 Cninniissions - - 5.00 ( &gt;tli**r expense 1.514.7S t '^si! on hand _6.4il!UW Miscellaneous - l_!t.01 Furniture and fixtures 80.40 Liberty Bonds - 8.(i_2.4«i Attorney fees ; 100.00 I !'■! iin i n fin inten'Ht 1.2flft.38 Total - I 18«.0!&lt;2.44 SiriT.EMEXTAI. ltEI'Or ,T nan of association Permanent Xumlier of shares outstanding la« report 5.703 Shares issued since lust report - _!,5a©Vi Total MH ' I Total "•zS f Shares withdrawn, matured or e»n&lt;elled since last report '-fSi Miares \\ u niirit" n. iiijimren ur i .iiii iiieu since in"i n-piiii •■ XuinlMT of shares in force this date - ' !■ Nunilier of ttorrowiim st«nkiiolders - - 173 Xumlier of uonliorrowinu stockholders '&lt;■''} Number of loans maile for Imildinc purposes iluriiiK year S Nmiiliir of loans- ■»lU fur purchaxlnc of homesteads or payment of ■ homestead-mortjriitfes dnrinir y.'ar _ 52 Par value of each share of stock $ 100.410 Amount nf interest, nreinlums and fines due anil unpaid 2,.)O1..&gt;4 Amount of loans on Improved real estate 215.386.00 Appniised value of improved real .-slate upon which loans have l&gt;een ._„_-,_, made — 47SJi«.0» .Vinouni of fire insuniuc.' in force ami assigned to the assiH'iatinn ms col lateral security _H».t&gt;40.0(&gt; as &lt;-nllater»l sectrity Amount of tornado insurance in fonv snd a^slirned to the association as collateral s.vurity 2411.140.4)0 as collateral s.vurity - -" l LV!,J Amount credited to reserve fund ilnriiiltf year »^_t2 Amount of dividenils declared on runnini: stw k ■lurlnn year 7.224.SO Amount of dividends uald on matured :ind paid up stock dnrinc year 3.4XI.T4K Rate per cent of dividends declared on riinninir stock durinic year Wt- Rate per rent of dividends paid on matured .ind full paid stock e per i-ciii "i immriiii.- |..ii.t ...i .,,_,,...,. «■■.. ..,,. ■ -■- ■■• — — ilurinsr year ■ during year __ Itat.' per i-ent nf intetest i-liareed borrowers during year 4Bc prt *14» </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the PROTECTIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ORD, NEBRASKA ORD, NEBRASKA On ;he 30th day of June, 1918 On :he 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS OFFICERS President _ M. B. Goodenow President _ M. B. Goodenow Vice President Geo. R. Gard Vice President Geo. R. Gard Secretary Joseph P. Barta Secretary Joseph P. Barta Treasurer Joseph P. Barta Treasurer Joseph P. Barta Attorney C. A. Davis Attorney C. A. Davis DIRECTORS DIRECTORS M. B. Goodenow Jos. P Barta L. D. Milliken M. B. Goodenow Geo. R. Gard Jos. P Barta C. A. Hager L. D. Milliken C. A. Davis Geo. R. Gard C. A. Hager C. A. Davis ASSETS ASSETS Klr»t inort|.'::ir&lt;' loans .$ ik4.IKiO.fln 4 rn.iao.ao 1 .mi n- on Ktoik &lt;ir ni.ss h.K.k f««rll) -JO0.0O LI 10.00 C«Kb 4.S10.OJ Kurniturr anil flxturm I.ilMTty Koiids Furniture anil fixtures JO8.41 Liberty 1 funds 1/flO.OH \Vjir Savings Si :t nips :i47.JO Wjtr Savings Stamps Total * 101.&lt;WtU:t LIABILITIES Running stock anil .livid. -nils _ .| 01.4M.11 l'aiil-np mnok anil ilivlilrnilK .....Z Kesi'rvi' fund 10.773.10 W..4S I'mliviiliHl profits _ ■ l.4!i Total - % 101,006.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 119 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 REf EIPTS rush mi hand hist report $ UMLM Dues ) running stock t „ .. „ 41.42.~i.l-''. Paid-up stork 2fi!l0o]o0 Mortgage payments _ 10.i~O.O0 Interest „ ti.:tr»2.2S Membership and transfer fee* -. - K¥).7O l.i ■:) n ft-*--- _ _ ruifi.oo Taxes paid _ _____ 1.92 Total _ t !».84«.!&gt;2 KISHIKSE MKNTS Mortgage loans * .~i3.3m.00 Stock loans ______________________________ 20o!flO Withilrawals runnlnir stock unit dhrMmda ....-.- * -. K.8«&gt;.47 Withdrawals pnid-up stork - l.i,Aflb.O© Withdrawals dividend mi p.;id upstock 1.005.48 Salaried ______ _________ 730.00 &lt; 'om missions _ 231.!&gt;tf Other expense 797.88 Cash on hand _ _ ____ ____™™..7™1VZZLV™LZ3ZV1T.™.'."." 4.kio!.-&gt;2 War Savings Stamp* 247.20 Liberty Bonds _ ." 1.0.10. Oil Furniture and flxtnrew - 2OR.41 Paid on incomplete loans _ _. r&gt;..~]AO.0O Total f 1W.H46.92 SrPPI.KMKNTAI. HKPORT Plan of association __ Permanent NunitHT of shares issued siliice orfranixntfon 9,21S% Number of shares nutstandinsr last report 6^17^4 Number of shares issued siluce orK»&gt;iixntion Shares issui ri since last report 4.Z&gt;3 Total lojmv, l.«12'v Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report Number of shares in force thiff dale ft.21S&gt;i Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 728 Numtwr of borrowing stockholders 7« Number of non-borrowina: stockholders 820 Number of loans made for building purposes during rear 11 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year - SB Par value of each share of stock _ 4 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent nt this date _ 1.32A.45 •-•n Total amount of dues delinquent itt this date Amount of dueff owing by borrowing stockholders 184.65 Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 210.7% Amount of loans on Improved re_) estate iH.SSO.OO 210. 7* Amount of loans on improved re_! estate Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare been made 17r&gt;.000.flO Amount of lire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security !*t..1«)0.00 Amount of tornado insurant In force and assigned to the association an collateral security 102.MO.Ui Amount credited to reserve fund during year .•s.v ■« Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1.478.2S Amount of dividends paid on matured and nald-up stock during year 2.0OB.S8 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 8«4"r Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year •* e per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year %fr H&lt;-r Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 STATEMENT of the condition of the PLATTSMOITH LOAN AND WILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President E. P. Lutz Vice President I! A. Bates Secretary T. M. Patterson Treasurer F. T. Ramge Attorney J. M. Leyda DIRECTORS E. P. LuU R. A. Bates F. T. Ramge J. M. Leyda H. F. Goos C. A. Johnson T. J. Yanda S. H. Schulhof T. M. Patterson ASSETS Klrxt mortitHire loanx .J 247.177 .IK) Iximds on stock or pass hook xvcurlty 7.6.TO.OO Real estate sold on contract _______________ IJW7.S0 Ciish Ift7.^1 IVIiuiiucnt intcivnt. nuc«, etc ."7O.S7 Tax«*« ml vnm-«'il 4r».llTt I.ilierty ItoniU .._.. n.«&gt;o!o(l Total * 2HB.7T*.S I.l.\nH.!TIKS Itiiniilni: xtiM-k and illvtdenilM .» 2-J&lt;l.Ha"..:U Patd-np xtock iiml ilivldcixls :u. 700.00 llwrvr fun. I 4..vm.oi liiillvliied profit* 91.752.0!) Total .____ . f a68.7Ti«.:!.i &lt; &gt;ther real rotate .'. ti.iMs.on </seg>
            <seg id="p121">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 121 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR 1'HK YEAR ENDING JUNE ■Mt 1918 i;i:i !•; II Is M*rtca(* |ni.\ munis :w.747.'l t'«-k liiini payments 4,782.11 I merest I!i.:t!l7x: ntm - 97.K8 Items credited to n'ul flail ;i..niiiil _ 152.00 Mcinliership Hllil inmMtn fee* - 21.2T. Other rei-cipts Id detail 16.20 Total 4 HJKfl nisiti usf MKXTS Mortgage loaaa $ 4T.Kt2.ilo Stock Inn us _ :i,H00.0O IWthdrawalt raaaiac Mark ami dividends S8.000.21 Willidrawals paid-un stock lft.000.00 Withdrawals dividend on paid up stock 2.O7.".47 Salaries l.:MVJOIl Other expense -. 241.."»7 Heal estate account ."&gt;38Jfci t 'ash i til hand — — ltS7.— 1 fiixcs advanced 4-Vii" l.llMTI.v IWuid* .1.000 0' Totiil S 1K1.1SI2.RI KI'PPLRlll XTAI. ItKI'tlKT Phi n of association Seniit Nuinlier of series ilssueil sin.f iirKiinlziitlon 87 NuniliiT of shares issued since organization IMWH stiares withdrawn, matured t»r cancelled sini-e last n*tM»rt ' l..t2ft..*iO NuhiImt of shares in fonv this dale :i.iV4:1'-j Number of shares on which dues are delinquent 01 NimituT of shares subject to cancellation for nou-iMi.vinent of duet*. Average running time of stock matured durini; the year IM Xuiulivr of borrowing stockholilers 21H Number of uon-lM&gt;rrow intr stockholders SI© Number of loans made for buildinic purpowii during year 1 NumliiT of loans made for purchasUm of homesteads or payment of honiestead-mortKHKcs during year 1.1 l"ar rater of each share of stock — - 4 20000 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 'JS3.no l'ar value of eacti share of stock JTklOO Amount of dues owiuir I'.v borrowing stiKkholderx 22*1.00 tiiioiiiii ui Hue-* uitiuu H» UHiiiii simnMiunnn Aiuoiint of interest. |&gt;reiuiutiis and titu- ,1m. and unpaid .'V44.K7 Nuinbcr ami amount .if ■ortovm subject to fore&lt;lo»nre No. .t .'.0IIO0O Amuuni of loans ou improved real estate 247.217.00 Apiiraiscd rater of improved real estate upon which limns have been made .1k-i.tW0.00 Ainount of tire ilisuraui'e in fonv and assiened to the association as collateral security - _ '2SV4 .!**.%. 00 Amount of turibino MuHuranc&lt;- in force and assigned to the association as collateral security Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year .".N33.34 Kate i&gt;er ivnt of dividends declared on niunitii; stock during .rear %Vi*fr Kate per ivnt of dividends pan! on matured and full paid stock during year _ M K.-itc per cent of interest charged borrower** durini; year 8% &lt; ;isli "Hi hand lusi rc|M»rt _ - J$ 2.LSW.M) 1 Mies i running stork I 42,047.00 l';iM Up miM-k l.T00.4M» Nimilur of slum's iiutstuniliiift last re|M&gt;rt 7.2W Slmn-H Issncil siini' lam n'lx'rt - 1.248 Tm al _ 8.«7 ns «-olint«Tiil s«Hiirity II&amp;ONTkOO Aim m nt credited to uacrvL fund ihirintr year 000.00 Aiuoiint of .iivi.l.THls dc&lt; lured on running Rtorlj dnriDK ve*ir 8.21.1.44. </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the e ~:m&amp; SEWARD EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION SEWARD. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1&amp;18 OFFICERS President John Zimmerer Vice President J. F. Geesen Secretary _...H. A. Graff Treasurer W. E. Langworthy Attorney J. J. Thomas DIRECTORS M. C. Miller H. D. Landis L. E. Ost Win. Leuhman Roy R. Schick J. M. Calder S. D. Atkins ASSETS First mortRaire loans „ % WkJKKkJm Loan* on stock or puss hook security 10.. r pOTi.OO 1 ,i»;tii^ on Kto&lt;*k or imss l»o&lt;&gt;k *«'»urit v 10,r»Or&gt;.00 Cash ! .'. «M.4O I tell lit | ut' lit illt*'re»*t, fliifs Mini tint-- _ TfiO.iVt Flirnitnn* h ml flxtlirt's _ 235.00 Fnrnitun* mid fixtiirt'« _ 23T&gt;.00 &lt;;«"vcrnineiit HoikIk _... 1.2fi0.00 In sum lift* unpaid 34.3M IiisnrHtn-t* unpaid &lt;&gt;ffl&lt;*e siippllPK 1S9.S5 Tu Kale certificate* BBJi Total ( lW.!»00.2n MABILITIRS Running stock and dividends _ t l.TB.iriO.42 Paid-up stock and dividend** 2^)00.00 Due sbarebnlders on incomplete loans _ 2.S30.7.". Reserve fund ............ ft.8tR.W&gt; Individed profits _________ 32.50 Advance due* 406. 7T&gt; Advance interest 38.70 Treasurer overdrawn _. 2.00K.24 Total - „ $ 168.000.2Ti </seg>
            <seg id="p123">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 123 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDINu JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS Duet* (running stock) _ - — .$ 52.i?r2..T2 Paid-up stoek 2.000.00 Mortgage payments 16.!M4.r&gt;!i Interest - l-.088.8ft I-"im — 12O.B0 Membership anil transfer fees _ l.~i);..tfl Insurance repaid — ~ fi.00 Tax »alc redeemed - .. -"V43.17 Treasurer overdrawn 1.173.M Total - _ t 85.30(5.71 IUSRIKKEMEXTS Mortgage loans anil stock loans _ J$ W.0MH.JS Withdrawal* running ■fork ami dividends 2S.3O9.7r. Salaries 1.005.00 Other expeUHe H6.:14 Omcrnment Ilomls _ 1.290.00 Tax sale i-ertlflcateH _ 487. 4!&gt; I nsu ranee „ tn s;'. Interest on overdraft ~ 44.92 Treasurer overdrawn 7-1-17 ."i.087.1.1 Total $ WJ0T..71 SfPPI.EMBXTAI. KEPOKT Plan of association Serial auil IVriniuieut Xumlier of series issued since organization SI Number of shares issuetl since organization 10,086% Xumber of series issued since organization 10.onr.s-4 Xnmlier of shares outstanding last report Z.TRH Shares issueil since Inst report M4.1 Total _ :1.717V. -'.TTl'i... Total Shares ■ilMim, matured or cnni-elled sinire last report 732 Xumher of shares' in force this date - 2.983V. Xuinlwr of shares oi: «iiich dues are delinquent ««■ * : _- Averaue luiiniiig time of stock manned during the .ve«r B Mo. Xumher of iwirrowing stockholders 166 X'nmlier of nun borrowing stockh&lt;dders 20K Xuinber of loans- minle for building purposes during vear W Number of loans n:nde for purchasing of hoimsteails or payment of homestead-mortgages iluring year 31 homestead-mortgiiges iluring year I'nr value of .a.h ikun. of stoik Serial $200.00 PeriiKineiit $ 100.00 Total amount of dues delini|iient »t this date 4.10.00 Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockliolib rs „ 422..T0 Amount of interest, premiuins and flues dues anil unpaid rO0..~&gt;.1 Xuinber anil amount «? mi.rtgages subject to foreclosure No. 4 2..'tV).00 Amount of loans- on improved real i state 14M..T25.00 Appraiseil value of improved real estute nnun which loans h»Te Ix^n made _ 217.27^.00 Amount of loans on unimproved real estate fi..*i&lt;10.00 Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have Imm'U made - 14.000.00 Amount of fire insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 1B.1.B45.00 Amount of tornado insura'i'-e in force and assigned to the association a» wllateral security X2.tV4O.0n Amount credited to reserve fund during year ,"»m.12 an ii.llateral security ,".77.12 Amount of dividends .leclarcii on running st.M-k during vear 10.!NiO.M» Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid up stock during year i carried as undivided nmfltsi Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during vear 7 77 li«v . Rate per rent of dividends paid ..n iiumnil anil full paid stoek during year •*% e per cent of interest charged borrower* during year 7.8% Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during Tear </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SIDNEY LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION SIDNEY, NEBRASKA on the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President ....H. G. Doran J. R. Williams Vice President Secretary Rob't. A. Barlow Treasurer DIRECTORS A. Granneman Lorenz Jessen C. P. Chambers Lena Jessen J. R. Williams Myrtle Lancaster Rob't A. Barlow H. G. Doran L. Neubauer L. Neubauer rtrxl iiinrticiKf loaus I &gt;&lt;]in.|ii.ni intercut, Hnex. etc l'lirnltiirc anil flxtureft Other a8(«*ts Total LIAIIIUTIKH llunniiik' stixk ami lilviilt-llils * Xt.lW.tNI lflMlhT, lti~.rv.- fmiil I uilivl.l.Ml y— *»^' UK.H ToUl f Si.441.81 L. Neubauer </seg>
            <seg id="p125">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 125 I'liili of usso&lt;iiill&lt;iu lvrinniifiit NuiiiIkt of ihin oiitstiinilinit: laxt report 4UK Slmrt-^ isMiu-d nince hist r«»[Mirt 41 Total _ _ ."fctU sliiiiis withdrawn, matured i&gt;r cancelled since last report 51 Numlier of sharex in force tht» date 4SK Average running time i&gt;f stock uintured during the year - - la* Mo. Masker of liorronins stockholders _ .'I Nninlier of non-liomnintc stockholders 48 Number of lounir nia&lt;)«&gt; for ImildiiiK purposes during year Amount of interest, premiums anil fines due anil unpaid 9 4W1.0O Amount of louns on improved real estate 32,900.00 A iiidii ti I of fin* iiisumnci' in tmrr* nnil ussluned to the association as ■-• 1 1 lateral security *33.."iOO.OO Amount credited to reserve fund dtirine year _ 12R.3* Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year J..V&lt;&gt;.."7 Kate iM-r cent of dividends decliircd on running stiK-k during year BHD Kati' per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year gU Kate INT cent of Interest charged borrower* during year RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR TH KA LNDINQ JUNE 30, 1918 ItKt'EIPTS &lt;'a-&lt;h on hand last report I&gt;ue« (running stock i ■ Mortgage pn&gt; merit* - - - Interest . „ Fines _ _ Total 4 |M| 4.«88.(W ■.•.:iio..7* n^SB t 1H.8U.77 DISH! ItSKMKNTS Mortgage loaux Withdrawal! running Moek and diviilenils - Withdrawal ilivldend «.n putd-up sti M -k Siilarlen * &gt;ther exlH'lUH 1 ( 'affh on hand _ f iaxi.oo 1AM ■i.:*&lt;o."i lou.m 117.47 i.4m:4.T« Total * man Sri'I'I.KMKXTAI. H*MR </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the CIT1ZKNS BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION SUPERIOR, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President W. S. Young Vice President John E. Eyre Secretary J. T. Robbins DIRECTORS W. S. Young rin E. Syre M. Silver W. J. Elliott F. S. Southard H. C. Duwe John A. Jones .T. H. Laird J. T. Robbins Harold T. Sullivan .1* . ASSETS First iiiortiriiBi. loans &lt; 53.400.00 Loans on xtovk or pa»» Jmm&gt;|[ wcurlty (500.00 Otter real estate 5,335.32 Real estate solil on iKMitraet 1.000.00 &lt; ' H Kh _ -.307. TO Furuitnre und fixture* _ .V).OO Xotal $ &lt;£!,ti03.0"_' I.IARIUTIKS .* 23.7S2.36 RunnliiK dt&lt;K'k anil ilfri&lt;li'inls rai&lt;l-up Mwk and iltYlilrnrtx _ _ ,, , 3S,1&lt;».«I Hwwrve fund J.riOO.00 1 n.ilvi.l.-.l profits _ l.IWO.HO Matured slock L'.OOO.OO Total * e2.8B3.O-.: </seg>
            <seg id="p127">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 127 RECEIPT8 AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE TZAH ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RECEIPTS Cash on hand hist report - * 2.925.3S' 1 luw i miming stock p ll.S6O.44 I lues ( running »to&lt;k I (l.SOO.44 r;tt«l-up mm. k '.t,lK)O.W&gt; Mort £agc puy incuts - - --. — — 9,000.00 &gt;|lin LTIttt' [Hi* Illl HIS . .- •- .. ..... ..... • -J,VUV.w Stock Iohu payments _ H00.00 Keal put ate sales TTiO.OO IntereM ZZ.Z;i.'_ — _ 4.721.S1 Bmta 3H2.:.i&gt; Other receipts — . 301.78 Total * M.121.*.' nismitSEMKNTS Mortgage loans * «.*2S-?0 Sto&lt;-k louns 100.00 stock loans „ 'SS WithdrawaU rniiuiiii! stock anil iliviilciiilN _... 14.312.1 1 Withdrawals paldan stock 4 - 2 9?-9 n . Withdrawals dividend on paid-up «lixk li.ol.'.HO Salaries .".„ ______________________ IE.U0II ( &gt;ther ex IM'llse — jBG.ll &lt;"asli mi liHtni -.IMYi.'iO To reserve fund ~ - 5U0.0O To undivided proflN - - -T1.04 Total ♦ 30.121. «2 SUPPLEMENTAL KKPUKT l'lan of association — Permanent Number of shares outstandling last report 1.111 Shares Issued since l.ist report -■*" Total IX* Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled shut* lawt report - Xumlier of shares in fnrce this dale - KV Average ninninir time of stuck matured ilurluir tlH' y«ir ■ Mn. Numlier of liorrowinir stotkholders 41 Number of non-borrowing sto&lt;-khnlders - 81 Numlicr of loans made for parrbaxinK of nonieHtead* or payment of 1 lioiiiestea.I-niortsiigeH during the year - 8 value of each share of stock • lOn.Oi Par value of each share of stock I'ar value or eacn snare oi stock ♦ . SS" Amount of loans on improved real estate .i3.400.0O Appnuied value of improveil real fstate upon which loin* have Iiimmi niiiile i.i.OtKKOO Amount of lire insurance in force anil assiicned to the asMx'iation as collateral security 4 .TO.OWi.OO Amount of tornado insurance in fori-e and assigned to thq association .S .~iO.000.00 as c&lt;illateral secertty - * " l0 -S5J-S Amount crediteil to reser\-e fund ilnrimr year aOO.OO Aniimnt of illvldenils declared on runnlnc «to&lt;k tlurine year 1.41354 Amount of ilivlileiids paid on matured and paid-up stock durinir rear •_'.iil~..iii Kate per cent of dividends declared on ruiininir stock dnrlnir year Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stork Ml during year - 6 and M I Uate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year W, r </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the TE(TMSKH BniiDIXU AND LOAN ASSOCIATION TECUMSEH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of Jum 1918 OFFICERS P. A. Brundage President Vice President .E. C. Hedrick Secretary J. B. Douglas Treasurer Harry Phelps Attorney J. c. Moor* DIRECTORS P. A. Brundage J. B. Douglas G. W. Ha»sett E. C. Hedrick Adolph Kovarik R. F. Reynolds C. M. Shaw William Sherman Harold T. Sullivan ASSETS First iimrtKiiKi- lotinx i:as. :!:».( hi First mortftaKc imam lW.230.au I.01111S on Bto&lt;-k or mukk l»&lt;»ok s**&lt;-iirltv 4.770.t»o I^oauH on stork or musk book s*H-nrtty 4.770.00 &lt;-«h1i ■ 4O7.H4 &lt;-ih1i 407 ..VI Delinquent intereiit. Buck mul ilum i'U.lN lVlimiuent inttrrat. fines i,ml ilun ' i'U.lN Furniture And fixturei* xtx.'.t."i I'niteU States BondK MMM Total f 14S.:tlO.!i7 Total f 14S.:CIO.!i7 LIABILITIES I.IABII-ITIES Running ntcx-k and (livi.lendw Jt 104.100.51 Paid-up xtook and dividend* :tl,K)O.Oil Keferve fund - 3 42.". s-j I'ndivided proflu .I.nfln.2!' Ail vinrc rtu^i* and lnt**rf^it - - - ~ 3S.3T* Total $ 14^.3.*W.l&gt;7 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 129 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1'llS itKiKir Ts Cash on hand last report * 1,173.73 Hues irunnlnc *tm\) _ ' 3MM.M Paid-up stock _ _ „ 17.lO0.oo Mortgage payments, stock loan payments _ 41.17S.OO Keal estate nates ....'. .. Interest _ .■'..Mom 11.324. 13 Fines ___________________________________ •-•4.V.M Rent* mmaam „„ . .. S^ l,"i MenilierstiiD and transfer fee* _______ 444.30 82.13 Vnlte-d suites Bonds sold ......'_.'. S.flBO.uO Interest accrued thereon .T0.1M Total $ 114..T01 JB I&gt;ISI1IKSKMEXTS Mortgage and stock loans $ 53.9MJO Withdrawals running stock and dividends 27JM».» Wit hdrawa Is paid u n stock - laMJ* Withdrawals dividend on paid up stock „._ _ 1 ,742.81 Salaries ________ i.'l7«!no t'omniisslMii-* „ ._ „ MEi.OO Other 1» , . ,, Z". !.; Z~. 1ML4H R*«l estate aeoount _ _ _ .-im.4!&gt; Taah on hand - - - WT M Matured »tock - - 11,900.00 Inited States Bonds Innieht T.OMlW Accrued Interest thereon 28.1." Total - f 114.^01.^1 Sri'PI.KMKN T AI. ltKI'OUT I'lan of association Serial .Numtwr of series issued since orfraiiixatlon M Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares issued since organization l&gt;.«30 Number of shares outstanding* lust report _ .3,&lt;M7 Mliares issued fiimr last iviMirt _ M5 Total - MH Sharps withdrawn, matured or cancelled since last report Numlier nf shares in force this dnte S.a» Numlter of shares on which dues are dellmiuent — _ 127 Average running time of stock matured during the year 7t» M«. Numlier (if Itornuvtne stockholders .'. _ 161 Number of non-borrowing stockholder** ir»*fl Number of loans tmide for building purposes during yetir •i XllllllHT Of loans mnde for pur.hasinE of houiesteads' or payment of homestead -mortgages during yenr - - Par value of each slinre of stock .$ ifKt.C 1 Total amount of dues delinquent a | this date 14B.-IO Amount of dues owine bj borrowing r-tockholders _ 14A.40 Amount of Interest, premiums amf flues due and unpaid R7.7R Amount of loan* on improved real estate - i:«;.i-M).oo Appraised valilt* of Improved real c&gt;tate upon which Iondk hare been made - - a)4.3IIO.Oi&gt; Amount of Ore insurance in force :ind ,*i«siiri:cd to the association as collateral security - ira.400 0i Amount of tornado insurance in force and assign,*, I to the association as collateral security 138.TO.ao Amount credited to reserve fund during year .TUK.20 Amount of dividends declared on running sto-ck during year 7.716.4- Auount of dividend* paid on matured and paid up stock durintr year 1.742.31 Rate per rent of dividends declared on running stock during year S.1.M Rate per cent of dividends paid on mature,! and full paid stock daring year ••?$. Rate per cent of interest charred borrowers during year - 8.4% </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the LOAN AND miU)IN&lt;; ASSOCIATION TRENTON. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President O. E. Reynolds Vice President J. c. Hurst Secretary j. p. Allen Treasurer C. H. Thomas DIRECTORS J. F. Ratchoff R. H. Pember O. W. DeWald C. U Allen A. T. McCoy ASSKTS First mortgage loans $ T.OTiO.flO &lt;'«»h ___-_________________.._.„_____. 62W.H Total 4 13.3.10.74 I.IAI1II.IT1KS KuuniuK stock and dividends f 10.S06.00 t'ndivided protlts ...______ ___________ . 2,524.74 Total ~ . I 13.330 74 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 131 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RKCETPTS &lt; a*h on hand lust r. port Dues i running stock * •-\8»0 0i&gt; 2..100.00 Mortgage payment Interest -•.1 H Fillet! t.Tn Total * mm.* nism i SEMKXTS Withdrawals r minim; stock and dividend Withdrawals paid-up stork „ * 1 -.'ll .",1 u.jio.no Salaries 1.13.00 other expense rash on hand --•..00 C-xiTi m.sbb.t:-. Total * RVPPI.KMKXT AI. UKPORT Plan of association Serial Numlier of scries issueil sIiht oriraiiixati 12 'ii NuiiiImt of shares outstaiidinc la-t ren&lt;irt :-T, &lt; Total SH Sliares withdrawn, nintiirfd or &lt;-:iiu-&lt;&gt;lh-d winif last report Nmnl&gt;er of shares in force rhis date \K Average runniiiLr thin- of Maek matured ilurini: tin- year Xnmlier of borrowing storkbolderK SO Mo' m N'limlier of noii-liorruwiiii; sIcm kliolilers Par value of eaeh share of sto&lt;-k Amount of loans on irnprovinl tvnl estat ill * lnn.oo «.z&gt;o.no Appraised value of improved real aatoate upon whidi li&gt;ans haTe l»een made _ Appraised value of unimproved Mai estate upon ivhirh loans havr l&gt;een made 12.--I.no 10.100.00 Amount of fire insurance in fon-r iniii as^itned to tlie association an collateral seeurity _ Amount of tornado insurance In foree and assigned to tin- association as collateral security .-. '.".Too.no Amount of dividends p-iid on matured and paid up stock dtirintr year Rate per rent of dividends paid on matured anil full paid stork - during: year s-; Hate per cent of interest ■■harmed ixirroners ilurlnc year ii.riOO.iM&gt; Moo.no Ainnunt of lonns &lt;&gt;n unimproved real estate </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the FIRST BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOC1ATIC.N UNIVERSITY PLACE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President A. L. Johnson Vice President E. D. Currier Secretary B. H. Schaberg Treasurer Attorney DIRECTORS A. L Johnson E. D. Currier M. B. Myers W. R. Gaylord W. G. Bishop S. H. Chism ASSKTS I irM HHirtK.i^f iiiillls I...:mi- in pnrmr of fani-limun' 1-mnIi Tot»l _ f 88.512.K3 MABII.1TIKS ItillllllllK SllK'k Hlld ilivill IS .» 22.C."0.«7 I'xl.l up stork unil illviili ml« ' I14.H0OIP0 ]:.--. tvi. fund l ,o«i .'.m T»l«l _ | 88J12J« </seg>
            <seg id="p133">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 133 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 KKl KIPTK Qmk nn hanil last rrport _ _ 4 ITJMUI iMies { running stock I _ „ 32.K44i.'.*i Paid-up stuck :M.fc».fli&gt; Mortgage payments - - - 2S.400.00 ■uitikiiki' pa * meuis — . — u,-t^wf.if»f Real estate sales 2.500.00 Interest _ _ - _ 5.M4.H! Fines _ _ 111.40 Membership and transfer fee* .W7.00 Abstract and mine fees - 3W.no Total - f lMjnji Dism KSKMKXTS Mortgage loans 9 4W.00 Withdrawals running stock ami dividend* _ ajRUT Withdrawals paid -tin stock _ S2.noo.oo Withdrawal dividend paid up stock '. :t.44T&gt;.23 Salaries .1-.S&gt;.00 Commissions „ _ A4.uo f)ther expense ,^__ 114.31 Heal estate account _ _ _. 2.00 Cash on band _^___ :t»a.R: Reserve fnnd .'._ _ flrifi.IH Al.strnct an.l fllling fepK HM Collection charjcew „ _ 2Tl&gt;8 Advertising „ RTV.Vi Office supplle* fl.no. I*r«*paid stock - S4.21 iotal f US.ff7S.2B SIPPI.KMEXTAL RKPORT Plan of association Permanent XuiiiImt of shares issued since nreuniiation ____^__ S.744W, Number of shares outstanding? last report 2.000 Shares issued since l:.st report 902 Total 2.1W8 Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled since lsat report — __ 'km Xumher of shares In force this date - 2.07'J Nimilu'r of shares on which dues are delinquent XT!) 1 *- *»••. Nuinlwr of borrowing stockholders 44 Number of non- borrowing stockholders 1«" Number of loans made for buldlne puri&gt;o*es during; year 10 Numlier of loans made for purchnsine of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgage* during year 8 Par value of each share of stock 9 100.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date _ - 1.WW.0O Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders' 1.AR8.00 Par value of each share of stock I r,w mi Amount of interest, premiums and lines due and unpaid !V&gt;S.OO Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 3 .-.iiooon fKW.OO Number ami amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 2 2.000.00 miiim"t anfi amoimi ui inoriuiiK* *s in iir*»ci'ss 01 lorecivsurv .^o. j j.ihrmpi Amount of loans on unimproved real estate SO0.no Amount of loans on Improved real estate 'iT.XiO.on Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made 1.H0O.OO Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made been made _ lliL'.iaffl.OI) Amount of lire Insurance In force and, assigned to the association as collateral security - lO.tiuono Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security !H».rtOO0O Amount credited to reserve fund during vear tTU"V!tl flBfi.91 .Minium (-r^-«iiii-u I" rt-m-r*e mini uuriuic &gt;ear nwt.Hi Amount of losses charged to reserve fnnd dnriing year lOfi.fl.T Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 1.2fln.7 -&gt; Amount of dividend* paid on matured anil naid-up stock dnrinir year .1..~&gt;4.'.2:! Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year ff~. Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year «&lt;; Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during rear AS and Ufl </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 TWENTY SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the VALENTINE IUIU)1N&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION VALENTINE, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 President H. W. Hoenig W. T. Kincaid Vice President Secretary F. A. Curabow Treasurer Chas. Lewis Attorney Walcott &amp; Walcott DIRECTORS E. C. Davenport L. L. Bivens ('. A. Ruby E. B. Foster John M. Tucker ASSKTS Kirn inortcajtc loiin $ l.-ci.sTitp.K.i I.c&gt;:iii» in proii'xs i if fun'i'lusiiri' C«k1i l.tWO.Wi 3fiO.~i IliliiKiuinl iiitcnsl, flm*, &lt;'li. IllHiirtilKi' |.n iiiiilins piilil I'nltiHl Stales I.ilMTty IIipikIs 7N7.WI l."Uill 1. 1*10.(10 Total * 133.810.W l.lAIill.lTIKS HuuuiiiK stoik and diridrnilx $ lici.Ofiii.il.; 300.30 I ni«- shMtvliuliliTs od iuioinplett' law Krserro fund 2.961.71 Matured stock. Certlflciitpfi oiitstnnuiiisr — • 21.500.0ti Total _ _- _ - * 133316.1H OFFICERS </seg>
            <seg id="p135">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 135 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 RKt KI1 Ts I'asli on hand last report l&gt;ni"i i running stock i * sjn.Tt i7.uRn.riO s..hut.ri Mortgage 1 payment Keal estate sales 7B0.IW llltiTfSI rtmm hitrrrsi - H.ltUi.ftt |.'jn,.s „ _ 80.20 slljo M.iiilxrsliip ami transfer fees - 35.2B Total i 43.S02.frJ Xi.Z, Membership and inuisfi-r fti (tal S 4:«.NO2.»J nisniitSRMEXTs nism USRMRXTH Mortgage loans f 1RJSB4.27 Mortgage loans f 1RJSB4.27 Withdrawals running stock and dividends I.2S2.*! Mortgage loans Withdrawals running stork and •livi&lt;l&lt;-iifl« 1.2S2.B41 1.2S2.fl«; Salaries ffTo.OO Salarleii tI7!Viio Other expense ... _ „ 142.00 Other expense _ _ „ 142.00 rash nn hand .I,ft3.7* Tasth nn hand S/KK1.7* Matured stock redeemed _ 1«.VO.no Miitnrcd stock rpdwmed _ 1«.Vfl.nn Interest paid on matured stork - 1.M4.47 Interest paid on matured stock - 1.M4.47 IMsrount on adTjtn«v pitymeiits _ 44O.7R discount on advane- payment* _ 440.78 Kxnensc rharKed imill fund - _ SO.OO Kxpense charged limit fiind _ _ .V).0O Y. S. Liberty Bonds purchased l.OOO.OO Total $ 43.802.fK; V. S. Liberty Bonds purchased 1.000.00 Total I 43.8O2.tK: SIPI'I.KMBXTAI- RKPORT SI iM'I.KMKNTAL RKPORT Plan of association Serial Plan of association Serial Numt&gt;er of series issued sinre oreaniziition - 3&gt;" Number of series issued sinrr •irgauiziition ~ 30 \nmlM»r of shares issued since itrirnnlzation 4,164 Numher of shares outstanding In &lt;t ri'ixirt 1.45»i&gt;'. shares issued since lnst report 1S1 Total 1.S8T'" Shares withdrawn, uintured or inncelled since last report 217 Number of shares in force this (late l.STO^ Number of shares on which dues :ire delir&gt;t|Ufiir 1W Number of shares subject tn raneejlalion for iton-payment of dues 41 Average running time of stock matured during the year 122 Mo. Number of borrowing stockhi»lders „ „ 92 Number of non-borrowing stockholders „ _ 118 Number of loans made for building nnrpnoes during rear Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during year * Par value of each share of stock $ 200.00 Total amount of dues delinquent at this date «2S.0O Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholder* W7.0O Amount of Interest, premiums nnil tines due ami unpaid 787.flO Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. .". x.fino.00 Number and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 1 l.flOO.OO Amount of loans on improved real (-state 12fl.W&gt;O.no Apprnised value of Improved real esta'e upon which loans hare been made 288.000.ft0 Amount of fire insurance in force ami assigned to the association as collateral security 18«.200 nn Amount of tornado insurance in fori-c and assigned to the association as collateral security 172.1V).OI&gt; Amount credited to reserve fund during vear .*WI!U Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during vear 2^2.00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock •luring year J*.01ft..1.^ Amount of dividends pnid on inntured and naidnp stock during rear 1X44.47 Rate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during vear f)R32&lt;T Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year TT Rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during year MM </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 TWKNTY -SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WAHOO MITIAL LOAN AND HriLIHNCi ASSOCIATION WAHOO. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1918 OFFICERS B. E. Hendricks President J. L. Winter ..H. M. Stralton ...J. J. Johnson G. N. Simpson Vice President Secretary Treasurer Attorney DIRECTORS G. H. Simpson Jas. O'Donnell R. F. McCreery M. A. Phelps F. J. Kirrhman L. J. Kudrna First niort(taife loans $ 127,!«J0.OO Ixianx on stock nr puss hook mt-urlty NTiO.OO Cash _______ .'.'.'.'..'....'.'...'.'.'.'. tt.«n.2!&gt; Kuriiiturc and fixtures „ l~»0.0&lt;) T«vmh nai.l ___ Si.:iO r. m™»« -- - _ Total _ - - - J$ 1X»,44«S.17 Total „ _ _ 4 13U.446.17 AKSKTS IN'TSuiml a &lt;*'*&lt;&gt; II l| t rt lft2.**H I.IImtij Bon&lt;l« MM MAHII.ITIKK Kiinninit Hick uml ilivlilendN _ * Iffi.&lt;ft2.92 Km-rrr fund r&gt;,t£!T&gt;.00 I'lldiviiJed profits - - 188.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 137 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 i:i-:&gt; KIPTS CMH on hand I:im n-|H&gt;rl Hues i running stock I .:... $ '.101.4:: i-'.m.W Mortgage payments Stock loan p;i&gt; nu-iit - Interest 7.'.»«UT -•..wo.oo R.4OA.N.1 rrt'tniuiii Fines .. 2 4X0 21 •.«». to Membership anil transfer It TaiM _ f* 10K 7"&gt; 10H.7.". ___ ."&gt;7.0f&gt; .-,7 0;-. IVrsonul accounts I-ilierty Bonds _ g3 fOl R3.NK 1.. 150.1)0 Total I 4tt.M8.4-.' S 4rt.IMS.4- IMSTURSKMEXTS msm ii SKMENTS Mortgage loiins _ $ lB'.iuono t 16.lljO.Oo Withdrawals riinniuir stock and dividend* Salaries „ ; and &lt;livl&lt;lnnl* _ 16.HTT.40 16.1577.40 I«M&gt;I 000 &lt;M&gt; '. ___ IRS 71 other expense Cash on haml Mlirrty Bonds Taxes 1SS.71 6.B21.3* «.«21.2ft -&gt;.noo.o» r, ooo oo " ■ ■ 4.47 .tfi.V. Interest 4.47 Total * 4*048.42 $ 4*048.42 HITPI.K.MKXTAI. KKI'OKT A I. UKI'OHT IMan of association Serial NiiiiiIht of series issued since organisation - _ 49 NuiiiImt of shares outstniidfiiir lust report ~ J,7WI Shares issued since li.st report ** Total 4.1(tt Sluires wlttidrmx ti. luntured or c-illlcclled since last report - VW Number of shares in fonv this ilate _ 3.R23 NuinU-r of shares on which lines ;ir» delinquent 12tV Xumher of shares siliject to cnncellatlon for inn puvment of due: Amerave niniiintr time of stock matured durlni; the year 1.10 Mo. NuiiiInt of horrowinp stockholders _ _ 90 Nmnlier of non borrow Ine stoikhohlerK 1*5 Number of loani* made for luiildiiiL' purpo«e« .luring year • Number of loans made for liorlaa antomoliile 1 Number of loans made for iiurcliasinir of homesteads or payment of homeRtend-mortffPfres during year _ 5 Plan of premium -_ 13c per mo. Par value of each share of stork 4 100.00 Total 'imoiint of dues delimiuent :it this date - 3VT0O Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders _ 2310.00 Amount of interest, premiums and flues due and unpaid .102.00 Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. "2 .TOO.OO .102.00 Amount of loans on Unproved real estate 127.flO0.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have lieen made 221.009.00 A MM of fire tnsiiruni— in forrr and nssigi.eil to the association as collateral security 148.JMI0.0O Amount of tornado Insurani-e in for. .■ and assigned to the association an collateral security 117.07.'&gt;.(P0 Amount credited to reserve fund during year .TOO.OO Amount of dividend* declared on running stock during year S.SM0.!k- Rate per cent of dividends .1.-. hired on running stock during year... 7'-.'. Rate per •■ent of interest charged borrower* during year «"". Rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during year, monthly l.V per share </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL. REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the SALINE COUNTY BUILDING ASSOCIATION WILBER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. 1918 OFFICERS President Jos. Cerny Vice President V. J. Kohout Secretary W. J. Borecky Treasurer J. J. Novok Attorney Stanley Bartos DIRECTORS - H. Bihger J. A. Sasek E. H. Houser H. A. Greer Wm. Skopec Anton Shimoney Chas. Pospisil Wm. Bohacek E. J. prucha ASSETS P|r«t mortraarp loan* - * n. &lt;W».no r ir"i mun iriiirp itMn* _ * i i.imu.iki T.nHna on stork or pas* honk wenrltr 0 !!. Cnxh '....'. JHJI Arrpftr dui*s ■ 2.^*0 Total ..'. $ 73.1*4 07 T,IABII.TTIKS Running stock and dtYidenda : $ 71.SR3.flA Reaero fnnd '.'. 2.1M.0n TndjTided orofltn ..__-_ _________________________ 4O.!H&gt; AdTtneed dne« 47.00 T»t«l - - _ — _...» 7S^*M.O7 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 139 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 ISWKFPTS I'ash on hauil lust lepurt l&gt;ue» iruuninK stocki * 1,173.00 -".U27..1O i«. avo.no 1 XSS.OO 4.7SS.IH MortKajie payments Si.., k loan payments Interest Premium ftrnm O.7.". :a.m M ImtsIiip and transfer f.-&gt; 110.20 Total * .-«3.2so.*&lt; DISM RSKMKNTS Montane loan Stork loans * U. 100.000 :i.300.00 Withdrawal runnine stork mi&lt;i dividend Salaries mt&gt;.:*&gt; Other ...vin.ns rash on han 117!'O Ml .57 Total * wumm SIPPI.KMKNT AI. IIKI1IRT 1'ijii of aHso&lt;iatinn Serial Number Of series issueil siure nrflill— _':\ Number of shares onlslandiiiK last report 1.1H Shares issued ate^s Inst rejn'rt Total .1«. :«l'i Shares withdrawn, matured or ranit-lled sin&lt;T last rvnort Nlllliln r of shares In foree this date 1.010 '-. Number nf shares on \\ llieh dues' are dellluiuellt .-&gt; Average riiniiiiiL r time of stoek matured during year 7« Mo. Number "f borrowini- stoikhidders (IT Number of nun horrmvini.' HtwkhaMm Number of law unxie for building purposes durinir year 1 I'rtr vitlue of each share of stu.-k * _1«M«I Total amount of dues delinquent at this dati J.."i0 Ai t i.f fire ilisuranee In furee and assiirued to tit.- a«ao&lt; ;is .-ollateral &lt;WH-iirity ■I; ation at ion 7.i.7jr&gt;.no Amount of tornado Insurance in T..r, ,■ and nssiKiied to ill. ■I, asso. an collateral seeurity tr7.7TiO.IK) Amiiunt ireiliteil to reserye fund during year 2«.«B Ainoimt of diylileuds .leetared on rtiiiulni; stm-k during year :ism..-,7 Kale per cent of diyidends declared on running stock ilurinjr yt 1 ;ir .ors,': Rate i»t (*nt of interest charged hanmmn* duriiie year «'. </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WOOD RIVER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION WOOD RIVER, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of Jun 1(18 I.IAnil.ITIKS Running srork and dividends Kpm»rve fund 4 72..-&gt;77.!«i :.«s.4a Other linMlltles 2.966.74 President Vice President Secretary Treasurer S. M. Nelson J. E. Hoge W. D. Sprague M. C. Wingert IHREC'TORS S. M. Nelson J. E. Ayer J. E. Hoge J. P. Mullen C. E. Towne J. W. Cunningham D. V. McKee W. S. Warren MM! Klnn mortgage Iobiik Limns In profess of foreclosure I^uins on sto«k or |»hhh hook aecuritv Cash «- IH-limiuent Interest. flneK, etc Total | 7«.H0O.&lt;X) 179.ST. 1100.00 340.41' 'J37.80 -..4 78,158.07 </seg>
            <seg id="p141">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 141 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 UK( KI1 TS Cash on liuncl last report _ - .$ !«.00 Dues i running stock I 14,tt!1.7O Mortgage payment* M.O'JO.i.'** Interest - - _ _ _ •\O73]90 Premium '.tin. To [in,— _ 57.65 MemlMTHblp and transfer fecit &gt;4.5o Taxes and insurance refunded - KB Total ♦ *.»M.74 I1ISBI USKMKXTS Mortgage loans .* lOJKW.IIO Stock loans _ J00.0O Withdrawals running stock and dividend* 10.+41i.n»! Withdrawals paid-up stink _ B.HO00O Withdrawal* dividend on paid-up atact ........_ _ 'll"u«? Salaries 470.0(1 Other expense 13.00 CaHh on hand :H0.42 Taxes and insurance advanced _ (W14 Interest on advance payment* MMI Total - 4 28,920.74 sippi.emkn r AI. RKPORT Plan of association Serial and Permanent for ."&gt; years Number nf series issued since organisation 12 Number of shares outstanding last report l.lkM Number of serif* laaMd sln«-e organisation 1.9M Shares issued since lt*t report _ 218 Total _ __ 2,1*4 Shares' withdrawn, miitured or cancelled slni-e last report -""-&gt; Number of shares In fore* this date 1.0CA NuiiiImt of shares on which (lues are delinquent 30 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of due* .10 Average running time of stock matured during the year - 114 Mo. Nnmlter of borrowing stockholders '. 56 XhiiiInt of non borrowing stockholder* 100 Numlier of loans made for building purposes during yeMr Number of loan made for purchasing of homestead* 1 or payment of homestead -mortgages during yeur 6 Plan of premium .'. Fixed Par value of each share of stock % 100.00 Total amount of dues delimiuent at thin date _ lC.'.OO Amount of (lues owing by borrowing stockholder* 102.00 Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid - l.Vi.SO Nambrr and amount of mortgage-. subjiKt to forecloxare No. ."&gt; :i.000.0l&gt; XiiiiiIht and amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. 1 lTO.STi Amount of loans on improved real estate 7tJ..soo.u(l Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loan* have lieen made - - 12r&gt;.!100.(10 Amount nf lire insurance in kM and assigned to the anxoclation a* collateral necurity !M.lO0.0O Amount of tornado insurance in force and aswigned to the a**ociation as collateral security - - ftft.Vi." On Amount credited to reserve fund 14.1. 43 ■MJi Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 4.A47.03 Amount of dividends paid mm matured and paid-up stock during year 11.1.00 Kate per cent of dividend* declared on running stock during year H'X- Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year •% Rate per cent of interest charged borrower* during year tifr Rate per cent of premiums] charged iMirrower* during year - X.t% a* </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 TWKNTY SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the WY.MOUK Hlll.l)IN(i AND LOAN ASSOCIATION WYMORE. NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1M OFFICERS President J. A. Reuliing D. A. Lasher M. J. Moran Vice President Secretary Treasurer Attorney J. A. Reuling A. T. Sherman M. J Moran First niortiruKt* losins Cask Insurant-*- . I.iUirt.v Ilonils Total I.IABII-ITIKS Kuiinine sloi-k anil iliviilt-mls $ 36,847.51 Pai&lt;l-ll|. stock mill (llvidillils flfi.900.0O I&gt;u«- shart'liolders on iMMpMt ImitiK 833.60 ici'scrvc fund 1,468.70 1"ndivlde&lt;I profits - 4.34&amp;6C jotal - - - $ 108,396.47 I &gt;« • 1 i 1 1 • i &lt; I l»t&gt;wt. flm*. i'H Furniture iinit fixtures </seg>
            <seg id="p143">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 143 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 MCKIFTI 'ash on luiii.t last report ~ _ $ Dups &lt; running stork \ Paid-up itvcS Mortgay** piyilU I lit 'TCSt . Mi'inhonrhlp and transfer fmi Taxes IiH'oinpiHt* 1 loans I ii&lt; u r.iin i I ►♦•linquont intervM .". vs.".-! 19.157.7s •J7.ino.no Ift.OKi.im &gt; 7Ki -:i .TJ-JOO S.(T, 5SLT3 41.-..1N Total $ 72.M0.fi0 DISItlRSKMKNTS MorreaKe loans 9 \Vithdra wills running stork ami dividends \V it luirji w ji Is |i;i i&lt;l ii p *&lt;to&lt;'k Withdrawal dividend aaM-ap stock - Salaries i 'oni missions &lt; Hher expense I ncomplete loan** — — &lt; 'ash on hithil Taxes' _ _ Liberty Bonds Insurance - Surplus Miscellaneous -.n.^no.nn l!».O74.1!i XTSt.V. aw* ■H-II.IN, 11.IJII Xt&gt;.M&gt; 1 •&gt;;. ttt T3." rvjt.iup ."►4.4!i Total * xu SIIM'I.KMENTAI. KKI'oRT riiin or association 1 Xunilirr iif shjin-s issni'H siti.-r ort; iiii/iitiun XunilMT of rtiarwi oiiistniitlinir hist n l |M&gt;rt 2.VM\ shart-s Issued sin«t' l:«st report *n2 Total Sh;ir.'&lt; willKlmwii. nuit n r. -.1 or i-nm-i -lli-il sin.,, last iv|M&gt;rt NuiiiImt of shares in force this date Xuinlter of shares on \vhi&lt;h dues are tleliu«iuent NuiiiImt of borrowing stoekiiolders _ N'limber of non-horrowinu stoeklioldert* Xunilier of lonns niaile fi.r I'liildmir i&gt;ur|&gt;os«.s .lurinir year XuniWer of loans made for purfliasiim of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortKaKe*' durinir yt:ir Par value of each s-hare of stoek S Total amount of dues dcliixiuent tit this dnte _ \innunf of dues owinir liv liorrowlnir stoekhnlilera Amount of Interest, premiums ;md fines due ami unpaid Number and amount of BKtrtaaam sulijeet to fore&lt;]osure No. 3 Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans haTe been made Amount of loans on unimproved real estate - Appraised value of unimproved real estate npon which loan* hare lieen made - Amount of flre insurance in force and assigned to the association aa collateral wcurlty - Amount of tornado Insurance in force nnd assigned to the assortatloin aa collateral security Amount credited to reserve fund durinc year - Amount of dividends declared on running stork during year Amount of dividends paid on matured and pnid-up stock during year Rate per cent of dividends declared on rrmiinp stock during year . . Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock during year - Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during year Naii t SJM •-'..SOk Hi 1 302 "'i*", 1?7 170 12 ■ ; loo.on (rrr,.no sm.oo lKi.fiS 1. srio.no io4.v&gt;n.no 180.400.00 225.00 %50.00 121.00000 ittvooo.no 3«2.3n •MM rt7».T3 »'; n </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 TWENTY SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the YORK MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK, NEBRASKA JUNE 30, 1918 OFFICERS President .Geo. W. Shreck ...C. A. McCloud Hattie S. Reed Vice President Secretary Treasurer Attorney W. L. White W. W. Wyckoff DIRECTORS Dr. E. B. Hanna Wade H. Read N. A. Dean Maj. Geo. H. Holdeman ASSKTS ihIht rt-nl e*tnte ' :i'.02K.4:; l.ilM-rty Road* _ .-..0OO.0M I'auli 2JS&amp;31 I'uriiiiiiri' ami Bxlnivf ...".... 2KJS Tmxtv paid 7.SH Tumi * 135^33.H4 I.IAHII.niKS m m mt • 13S^63.H4 I'irM mnrtiMk'i' limns $ 1M.400.0iI I.nans hi pro&lt;t*ss of fort^-loKure if.iit.O? Loans on Btmk »r paa l&gt;ook security n.imo.oii IMlaqocal liMM, (Iim-h. rt&lt;- _____ 136.!t4 ItumiiiiK Ktoi-k ami ilirlilpniU * 13I.228.!*! Ut-wrrr fllllil U.MKI.M rndlrtdMl i&gt;rofltK 27.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p145">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 145 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1918 KE( 'Ell •Ts Cash on hand last rrport 4 _'.i.710..h1 Dues ( running stock i - .~&gt;7.!&lt;.'tt.t)0 Mortgage unil stock loan payments - 2n.a50.OO Morticam* uml stork loan paym-ats - 2O.30O.0O Interest and premium - 10.17fl.HK Interest and premium - 10.lTfi.HIV Fines ... _ - 111.74 lines _ _ 111.74 KentK ________ _____ _ . JS.00 Items JS.0O Membership mill transfer fee* *— 4.7r» Memliership Mini transfer fees 424.7."i Koreclomiren !i0B..V&gt; Total * 10K,7»», Foreclowure* '.WO..V1 » 10K,7*t..&gt;. Total KI8III ItSEMKXTS l'l.-l I I. SEMKXTS Mortgage loans _ .$ S1.TOO.00 Mi&gt;n ts.-itti- loans 4 31,700.00 Stuck loans _ 1.300.00 Stock loans !.___"_________ - 1.S00.00 mock loans _ i..wv.w Withdrawal* running- stock, di.idpnds ami interest 71.804.«3 Withdrawals running stock, illviilenils antl interest 71.S04.«3 Salaries S40.0H Salaries !_ '. - S40.00 Other expene XW.17 Real pMtatt* _w*iiiiDt _ — - — — ■ _"*j -*" Real estate aiconnt - _ - — -••■ J£"£ Cash on tuiiiil — U,Dii5..&gt;l Total $ 1OS.7WJ1 SIPPI.KMK NT AI. KKPORT 1'lan of association Combination Nuinln-r of site's issiieil sinif organisation •*■$ NmnluT of sharps Issuttl *ln&lt;t* uriranlxation - .Tl.flni .V&gt; Number nf shares ImsiipiI "inif iirinmlxation Nmnlier of shares iiutstnniiiing last ri*|K&gt;rt Ji.427 Shan-s issiit-il slnrr last ivport - 1.172 Total M_| Shares withdrawn, utiit 11 n&gt;il or i-auri-Itril sinit' lust re|Mirt l,4."il Nuinber of sharps in force thN tlate — S.148 Xuml&gt;er of shares on which duet* are delinquent - &amp; Number of shares sill Jpit to cancellation for non-payment of ilur" ■ Avrnire numiue time of tock niatiirnl during the year s."Mo. Xuiulier of liorrowiue stockholders JO Numl»**r of non-l&gt;orro«iiiK stockholders 410 Number of Iiniiis niuilc for ItuildiiiK pur|K&gt;Hps during year Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead- mortgages during year . 1' Plan of premium - — - — - Wt X k Ji 1 lan 01 premium ~ — ~ — - V™v™\ Par value of each share of stock - f 100.00 Total amount of dues deltni|ueiit ;it this date - 14A.0O Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders 137. flO Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid 13G.1H 13ftm Number anil amount of mortgages subjpct to foreclosure No. 1 1. .100.00 Number and amount of mortgages in prm-ess of foreclosure ao. 1 !»»&gt;_ Amount of loan* on Improve!? real p«tate 120.100.00 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loann have l&gt;een made 236..'»0.0«i Amount of loans nn unimproved real estate 300.00 Appraised value of unimproved rpul estate upon which loans hare l&lt;een made H0O.O" Amount of lire iriMmni. e in force aud 3««tgned to the aMoctatlon Ms collateral security - 12i.000.01&gt; Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the annotation an i-ollateral security 115.000.00 Amount of dividends declared on running Mock during year 8J5OS.21 Kate per cent of dividends declnrnl on running stock during .rear *H'* Rate per cent of Interest chargi-d borrowers during year iMVt Rate per cent of Interest rhargi-d borrowers during Tear </seg>
            <seg id="p146">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 146 STATEMENT of the condition of the WORKIXOMEX'S SAVIXOS AND LOAX ASSOCTATTOX YORK, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of Juno, 191S OFFICERS President Secretary Treasurer Attorney N. A. Dean W. W. Wyckoff G. H. Holdeman W. W. Wyckoff DIRECTORS W. E. McCloud G. H. Holdeman N. A. Dean W W. Wyckoff AS8KTS First luortBOKt' |iiiili» » R.40IJ.OO r««h ———*• — — ;;;; ' 407.IK Tot.l * 8.MT.1M I.IAHI1-ITIKS Running stock and dlrldend* -f 8 'SS"ii Rwerre fund - 860.67 UndlTlded y«t« ,,., ' 2S.CH Total ~- — - - . ■♦ 8.807.1S </seg>
            <seg id="p147">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 147 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1918 KK&lt; EIPTH &lt;ash i. u him. I last report 1 Mies i running st&lt;M-k&gt; . * 3.48B.0O 2.311.00 MnriK:i&gt;ri' payment Interest .-...■.cKi.ni MBl1« Total * ii.'.»r..lii DISHIKSKMKNTS Withdrawals r _- in, k and dividend: Salaries » 11.176.72 JOO.OU Other expense Cash on band 6.00 407.1s Interest on withdraw 11S.W Total I 11.9O5.1K SII'I'I.KMKNTAI. REPORT Plan of association Permanent Number of shares »«liHaadi»| last Nfjati - 41 shiins withdrawn, mnturiil or eaBcrtlrd atscc lust report 251 Number of shares in fore* this date lKi Number of shares ea whiili ilnt-s arc ilt'Mn'iueii! Ml Number of shares siibjeet tn eaueellution taw M"ii | • r 1 1 m of -In,-* 10 Number of borrowing stoekholilers 12 NunilHT of non liorrowiiiK stoekholilers A 1'ar value of each share of stock — $ 100.UO Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 120.00 Amount of dues owinc by borriwn irostoekholders _ 120.00 Amount of interest, premiums anil Hues due uud unpaid .70 Number and MBMM of mmrtgamn subjeet i., farccloMre Xo. 1 1. 1100.00 Amount of loans on iin|&gt;roreil real estate n. 400.00 AppralWd value &lt;&gt;f imprnnil real estate iii&gt;ou whieh loans have been made 14.000.00 Amount of fire insur.in.r in foree and assigned to the association as &lt;-ollateral security li.000.0o Amount of tornado insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security !).000.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year Mi Amount nf dividend* declared on riinniiiir sti«k during year MUI Kate per cent nf diviil Is declared on rnnniiii- stock durin&gt;- year M Hate i»-r ecM of int&lt; n&gt;st rharawl borrowers during year 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the LIVINGSTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA On the 30th day M June. 191£ OFFICERS President D. B. Smith Vice President F. G. En.?enberger Secretary C. G. Fricke Treasurer Dr. C. A. Marshall Attorney A. L. Tidd DIRECTORS H. M. Soennisehsen D. B. Smith Dr. C. A. Marshall Wm. Holly Wm. Hassler F. E. Schlater H. S. Barthold F. G. Egenberger C. G. Fricke ASSKTS KtrKt mortgage loanx $ 210,.tSI.4N Loanx on xtm-k or pasx book mn-urity 16,010.00 Real extate Hold on contract _ _ 4.395.13 &lt;"aah _ ___.__JZ 3.644.5:! Furniture and fixture* *** :wh.4.~&gt; I.llKTty Loan _ 3,000.00 .1 .006.00 Total _ _ 4 237.883. .TiP I.IA1III.ITIKS RuniiiiiB Btook and dividend* _ 4 lflR.O4O.fi7 Vlijl-up M«M k tuiil dtvitlendx 5S.880.14 gStit t*|d 11.419.11 11,418.11 T ndlviied proflts 4JXM.0R Total t 2S7.fl83.au </seg>
            <seg id="p149">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 149 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 l:K' 'KCPTH I*ues i running stock ► 3 43,144.8(5 Paid-up stork SS.4a.14 MnrtirniTf pH vinents .18,310,28 Stock loan payment* 1.390.00 l'.soo'oo Heal estate sales Interest 17.8S9.S1 Rents _ _ Mft.fi uenis ~ — ........ _»*vn«&gt; Membership and transfer fees 179.00 Total - - I 138.TJH132 DISBl ItSKMENTS Mortgage loans 4 44.82.~i.no stork loans - 3*320.00 Withdrawal* riinninic stock and dividend* - .'Ht.313.0B Withdrawals paid-up stock '.'. — 1Z. 1 33.840.00 Withdrawals divi&lt;lend on paid up stock - - - 8.432.3B Salaries 1.800.00 J.SOO.OO Real estate contracts Cart on hand, overdrawn SB8.M Cash \644.52 .1.000.00 Liberty Loan 1,11 MTiy t&gt;oun fi.uuv.uv Furniture and fixtures 304.46 Total - 4 138.798JCi SUPPLEMENTAL KKPuKT Plan of association — Serial XuiuImt of series issued since irgnnliation — ""I 1 Numlier of shares lamwd since organization 4,18* Xumlter of. shares outstanding last rt?port - - Shares lssiieil since last report -. 827 Total - 3.8B4 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cancelled sluct last report \uml»er of shares in force this date .1.048 m AveraK&lt;- runnlnt.' time of stock matured during the year _... 131 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholder* Number of non- borrowing stockholders 504 Number of loan.-; iikmIc for building purposes during .rear Par value of each shure of stock ■$ 200.00 300.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate 210.321t.48 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans hare l&gt;een made 380.000.00 been [llltlle Amount of lire Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security 223.400.00 an i ■ • i iii i &lt; 1 4i i rt*i u»»»..i ■■ '• .«-».—— Amount of tornado insuranc" in force and assigned to the association as collateral seci.rlty 78.500.00 Appraised value of land not including; improvements _ lSO.flOO.00 Value of improvements _ - J07.000.00 Amount of lire ln»nmnce thereon - — '223,400.00 Amount of tornado insurance thereon 78.~flO.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year - _ 724.37 Amount of dividend* declared on running stock during year - 5.614.01 Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stork during year 14.1.V1 ."is Kate per cent of dividends declared on running stock during year 4 and tTr Kate per cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stock m __ during year 1°' &lt;■ au ring year »t Kate |K&gt;r cent of interest charged liorrowers during year S r i </seg>
            <seg id="p150">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE 150 STATEMENT of the condition of the On the 30th day ol June U'lS OFFICERS President J. C. Michelsen Wm. E. Davis Vice President Secretary H. Earl Cox Treasurer Attorney Perry M. Wheeler A. C. Pancoast niltECTORS O. F. Beavers F. A. Cressey Richard De Young ASSETS Flrxt mortgage loans * 97,237.11 Loans on stock or pass hook security Cash S07.7* 3.728.21 Furnimri' anil tixtnn Liberty IlninI* MS.M i.2&lt;io.nii Total S 10S.S10.0l LIABILITIES Runninic stork and &lt;iirl&lt;londg - 4 67.462.82 Paid-up stork and dividends 26.100.00 26.100.00 i c- fond - '.. .....™...L.~.....ZZ1.ZIL_JZ________.__ liKl^Ol I'ndlvlded proflts _ ___ _________^ _____ 2.Vi29.71 Lilxrty Bond* „____________________.________ ~'90Ti!oo B11U payable _ LZ.7...ZZZZZZZZZ.Z JfiUO.iMi Toui f 10S.M9.04 IIO.MK SAVINGS AND LOAN' ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NEBRASKA Claude R. Orchard A. F. Stryker W. S. Shafer C. L. Talbot </seg>
            <seg id="p151">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 151 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30 1918 KE&lt; 1 II TS rash on Ii.-iihI list report Inn's i running stork) t "..tl'.i UP nn.«ii..-,i Paid-up sto.-k 13.00S.Kt Mnrtsajre pnvmcnts Stock loan iMiymi in Interest 14.204.35 i,07«.«s «.«'3.."i4 Liberty Bonds !KK.0l&gt; !W77 im.iwo.oo fniirinln on bMaraat Bill? payable Total $ 92.f«2.28 nisBrF SKMF.NTS Mortgage loans Stork loans $ rtl.014.SK rt.2Wl.-vj Withdrawals riitinin- -link ;inil iliviilcn.l Withiirawals paid-np sto&lt;k 2Ti.37rt.nl *.K».sn 1.22X0H Withdrawals diyideml on paid-up -i&gt;.. k Salaries l.OlR.fTi Other expense &lt;"ash on ha nil Liberty Bonds !)18.ftl rt.72S.21 i.'aoo.*n Furniture and flxrnrei mils payable .-•.no l.t.oon.nn Interest credited rt.27».Jtt Total * 92.ns2.2s SrPPI.EMEXTAI. KEPORT Plan of association Pprmanent Number of series issued since organization 1 Xiiinbcr of shares* issued since organisation 7.04.*ii._. Number of ihim outstanding last report 2.7O1S, Shares issued since last report STO Total - rt..771i.. Shares withdrawn, mntnreri or oancollrd since last report 42S Number of shares in force this date _ 3.148V.. Number of shares 1 on which dues are delinquent - 42* Number of borrowing stockholders 100 Number of non-borrowing stockholders 1CT Number of loans made for building purposes during year 2 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of homestead-mortgages during yar IS Par value of each share of stock $ 100.00 U Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 700.00 Amount of loans on improved real estate - 9S.O+4. SO Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which leans hire been made 237.2.W0O Amount of lire insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security 146 MO.OO Amount of tornado Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security - 122.47S.00 Amount credited to reserve fund during year ttt a Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year 3,279.83 Amount of dividends paid in matured and paid-up stock during year... 1.22S.0K Rate per cent of dividends declared on runninc stock during year .... !H4f&amp; Rate per cent of dividends paid on matun-il nnd full paid stock during year — 5U* Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers duriiiK y:ir t* </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATEMENT of the condition of the BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRBURY, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFICERS President A. V. Pease Vice President E. L. Simpkins Secretary ...F. A. Houston Treasurer H. H. Todt Attorney F. L. Rain DIRECTORS J. A. Aztel! r. L. Rain J. C. Lien H. H. Todt J. H. Bond E. L. Simpkins S. H. Di'ler F. A. Houston A. V. Pease ASSETS First mortgage limns f 5H.2^~i.Oo Loan* in prm-es» of foreclosure 1. '."00.00 Loans on xtixk or ii:ihk book security tSOO.OO Ee and municipal seouritiet. _ ■ » l..T.i-j.4&lt;&gt; 2 '.171 ."7 ' : — — T«t«l $ tti.(IKH.!l7 Total $ H5.0Wt.ll7 LIABILITIES Running stork and &lt;ll»ieU*n&lt;lir -$ 54,985.80 Paid-up mock and dividend* _ 7.700.00 Baaenre 1.750.00 I ndlvideii profits 8KU7 Total - — - - — 4 «6.088.!i7 </seg>
            <seg id="p153">SECRETARY OP THE STATE BANKING BOARD 153 YEAR ENDING RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE JUNE "0 1918 MM KI1 1 T&gt; l'ash on hand lasi report _ - -.$ 6,019.14 Dues I running stork i 10.826.3l&gt; I "nil! lip stock - _ 600.00 Mortgage payments _ _ „ _ 12,450.00 Stock loan payment!* _ tiTi.uo Interest - ______ _ _ -.. 4,9ni.3» Fini's _______________________________________________ ti.'.i; Meml.ership and transfer fee* - - 270,1. Total f 35.1811.00 IlISBl KSKMENTS Mortgage loans .f 17.1— &gt;.OO Withdrawal- running stock and dividends 12.6M.flK Withdrawal* paid-up &gt;iwk ______________________ :W..0O Withdrawal* dividend M KlM-tr *ttrll IMM Salaries _________________ 300.00 Commissions 131.00 &lt; 'tht-r expense 74.0Ci Cush on hand ...._ — — 4.J65.JT Total * M.l».«- Hl'PPLEMENT AI. RKPoKT Plan of association - Permanent Number of share* outstanding hint report 1.879 Shares issued since last report - 261 Total 2,140 Total Shares withdrawn, matured or cam-elled since last report — 1^5 Numl»er of shares In force this date 1,97.% Avtraire running time of stock matured ilnriln. year — 77 Mo. Number of borrowing stockholders «S Number of non-borrowing stockholders — 147 Number of loans made for building purposes duriug year 1 Number of Joans nuide for inirchHsing homestead* or payment of homestead-mortfciiges during year - S Par value of each share of stock 4 10tt00 Amount of interest. | rcmiums and flues due and unpaid TlUi Number and amount of mortgages subject to foreclosure No. 4 n.100.60 ■ Number und amount of mortgages in pnwess of foreclosure No. 1 i.!iuh&gt;o Amount of I mi us &lt;m improved real estate -- 6&gt;,12T».O© Appraised value at improved real estate upon which loans have been made lOB/iilO.OU lieen made Amount of fire insuriiuce in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ....000.01) Amount of tornado Insurance in tan* and assigned to the association as ,'ollatcral security B4."pOOOO Amount credited to reserve fund during year *i«».00 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during year .VCLTO IW.N Amount of dividends paid on nuiturcd n ml imtd-up stock during year 444.00 Kate |ier cent of dividends declared on running stock during year _. 1% Kate pm cent of dividends paid on matured and full paid stork during year "' • Kate I&gt;er leilt of interest charged borrowers during year "4" </seg>
            <seg id="p154">154 STATEMENT of the condition of the HANKERS SAVINGS AND LOAN' ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1918 OFFIC ERS W. D. Lincoln P resident Vice President N. A. Speisberger Secretary A. D. Tongalin Assistant Secretary A. A. Tenoper Treasurer L. D. Spalding Attorney Thomas D. Crane DIRECTORS W. D. Lincoln T. D. Crane G. Turner Haines C. D. Hutchinson C. F. Kuncl N. A. apeisberger A. D. Touzalin L. I) Spalding John C. Wharton .T. P. Leary A: I8E •is First mortgage loans I'OatiK fn pro«t*ss nf foreclosure % Hflfi.TTKJ.CIO n.xno.oo Tamils mi stork or puss hook j«M-iirit.v 1_. 198.111 other mil rvtatr ~........~.. ....................... 7.47."i..'i-j Kfal eKtatc »ohl on .H.ntrint 3.700.00 ruh _______ _________ 14.717.11" I •»- 1 i 1 1 • | ■ i • - it iutrlvHt. fln«t». .■!■• 1.K12.UO Kn nil t ii re ;i in I tl x t u rc^ — 1 ,fl00."&gt; 'I'jiXfs puitl ."i.'Ct.K:! I.ilM-rly Honiis (I.000.0O War rtavin|?H stamps 4.fil Tut » I _ '. f _N,13IM MABfI.ITI?:S Running utock a n&lt;l .h\ i.l,-n.ls $ 458.793.L'O 1'aid -up Btork anil dividends 1S8.583.:«&gt; l&gt;ue nhareh«»lder« on iin-otuplei.- loanx _ 4,"».10.(H Pald-np Btork and dividends 4.53O.B4 Rt^ervp fund - - 't.fil-.ff* i'ndlvlded profltn - _ 130.45 Insurance commission „ 86."t8 Xotal -, $ 8MJ86.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p155">SECRETARY OF THE STATE BANKING BOARD 155 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918 KEf EIPTS Cash on band last report Dues (running stock i t 18.8J7.80 .X&gt;fi.W.-.2-J Paid-up stock W.KW.00 Mortgage payments Stork loan payments ... Real estate foreolnsur* 1 373000,, »•?»••! imfa Real estate sold on contract Interest 2.7M.00 «.K20.41 Commission Finos M&gt;.nn 4.20 Warrants 224.40 Insurance commission 186.50 Liberty Bond!) anil Wnr Savings Stamp* Expense ll.2n7.3S .T70.4R Delinquent Interest Taxes paid l.O7«.i)o 113.43 11O.9M..17 Incomplete loans Total _ 4 «29.t«S.l'.i IUSI I li .SKMKXT8 Mortgage loans Stock lonns * 110.KW.nn 17.2OSA3 27»&gt;.!M2.72 M.nwi.on 10.00!) 71 Withdrawals rumiirii: stock nn&lt;l dividend Withdrawals paid-up stock Withdrawals dividend on paid-up stock Salaries 4.21«.&lt;V. 1S21O .*,.47S.«2 41vm.no ._ 1*1.11. . 1S21O Insurance commissions Other expense Sold on contract 312.07 Renl estate foreclosure rash on hand 14.717 03 Ueservp fund 3*1.41 Incomplete loans 131.0R2 78 1S.101 m Liberty Bonds and War Baring* Stamp: Taxes pnld 17.1* Delinquent Interest 1.42AH4 Total « •sn.nai.in STPPI.EMKN TAI. REPORT 1'ljin of association Permiii Number of shares Intend sincp organization XumlttT of shnres outMtjiniliui; last report Shares issued since lnst report suns 1 12S 1 .4*4 1 Total 1(I.M2 »-10 2.013 1-2 14..-r!&gt;0 2 -. Shares withilrawn. matured or cancelled since last report Number of shares in force this date Nnmber of borrowing stockholders N'unibpr :&gt;f nonborrowinc sto&lt;kholders 311 v- Number of loans made for building purposes dnring rear 12 Number of loans made for purchasing of homesteads or payment of Iiiiint'steiHl-inortfirages during year 20 I'iir viilu.' of .■nil] «hiir.' of stock ' ♦ MO.0O Amount of interest, premiums and Hues due iind unpaid 1.S12.0O Xnniber and amount of mortgages snbieet to feroclosnre No. 1 1. 4r-O.no Numl»er and nmount of mortgages in process of foreclosure No. R 11.STi0.0n Amount of loans on Improved real estate 577.JW5.O0 Apprnised value of improvpil renl estate upon which loans have been made _... l.MO.OCn.Gn Amount of are insurance in force and assigned to the association a* collateral security — KB2.000.00 an collateral security Amount of tornado insurance in force ami assigned to the association as collateral security S2n.ion.no Amount credited to reserve fund during year 1.407. IS Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during vear SflO.41 Amount of dividends declared on running stock during vear 1R.S43.4O Amount of dividends paid on matured and paid-up stock during year 10.0W 71 Rate per cent of dividends declarpd on running stock during vear .Ofit Rate per cent of dividends paid on matured and fnll paid stock during year .(XI^ e per cent of interest charged borrowers darling ye»r . 02'r Mfr Rate per cent of interest charged borrowers darling year </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>