<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fourteenth Biennial Report OF THE Nebraska Institute for the Blind TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE YEARS 1901 AND 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
 	       <change>
 	          <date>2007-09-06</date>
 	          <respStmt>
 	             <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
 	          </respStmt>
 	          <item>Enrichment</item>
 	       </change>
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Fourteenth Biennial Report —OF THE— Nebraska Institute for the Blind —TO THE— GOVERNOR FOR THE YEARS 1901 AND 190a 1902 The Frimort Tmthtm Frbmobt, Nbb. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL. Nebraska Institute for the Blind, Nebraska City, Neb., Dec. i, 1902. Hon. Ezra P. Savage, Governor. Sir: — In compliance with section 12, chapter 26, of the ses - sion laws of 1896, the Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Blind have the honor to transmit herewith the fourteenth biennial report for that institution upon the work accomplished during the period ending November 30, 1902. Respectfully, Clinton Orcutt, Chas. Nownks, C. G. Ellw anger. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">GENERAL INFORMATION. The Nebraska Institute for the Blind, located at Nebraska City, is organized as a school, and is conducted solely for the purpose of educating the blind children of the state who are normal except as to sight. It is in no sense an asylum or a hospi - tal, but a school. f "he law provides that only those of suitable age and capacity 11 be admitted, and the rule has been established that pupils between the ages of eight and twenty-one are eligible for admis- f Tuition, board, and medical attendance are furnished free for who are admitted, but parents or guardians are expected to Kvide suitable clothing, pay all traveling expenses to and from Institute, and take charge of the pupil during the summer ation. The school year begins on the second Wednesday in Septem - ber and closes on the second Wednesday in June, unless other - wise indicated. It is expected that all pupils will be present at the opening of the term, and except in case of sickness or una - voidable necessity, remain to the close of the term. Each pupil shall come provided with an adequate supply of comfortable clothing, which must be replenished from time to time as becomes necessary. Each article should be distinctly marked with the owner's name, and must be sent in good con - dition. The supply should embrace the following: Boys — Two hats, two suits of clothes, two extra pairs of trousers, four pairs of socks or six pairs of stockings, four shirts, two suits of under - wear for mild weather, and two suits of heavier material for cold weather; two pairs of shoes, six handkerchiefs, two pairs of suspenders, tooth brush, comb, and hair brush. Girls — Two woolen and two cotton dresses, four aprons, re night dresses, two suits of summer, and two suits of win - underwear; two dark and two light skirts, six pairs of </seg>
            <seg id="p004">362 stockings, six handkerchiefs, a wrap, hat, rubbers, two pairs of shoes, tooth brush, hair brush, clothes brush and comb. A small sum of money should be provided each pupil, to be deposited at the office, to pay for postage, repair of shoes, etc. Eupils are expected to attend church on each Sunday morn - in suitable weather, at such places as they or their parents gnate. Persons not residents of this state may be admitted to the benefits of this institute during the school year upon payment of $100.00 quarterly, in advance; provided, that no such person shall be received to the exclusion of any resident of the state. Those of suitable age and capacity and possessing good moral character will be admitted, but in case after a fair trial one proves incompetent or manifests repeated disregard of the school regulations, he will be discharged. Profanity, obscenity, the use of intoxicants and tobacco in all their forms are strictly prohibited. No person should be brought to the institute until a letter of admission has been received from the principal. Persons who may know of blind children are requested to inform them of the character of this school, and send their address to the principal. All inquiries regarding the admission of pupils will be promptly answered. E"o insure prompt delivery, all letters and express packages the pupils should be addressed in care of the "Nebraska titute for the Blind." HOME INSTRUCTION FOR THE BLIND. tt is manifestly impracticable under ordinary circumstances to i children from home to school under the age of eight years, if no effort be put forth before this time for the intellectual elopment of the child, valuable time is lost. Parents, brothers, sisters, and friends may accomplish much with a little painstaking, and the child thus becomes interested in acquiring knowledge, and when the time comes to attend the institute they will go forth with a feeling of pleasant anticipa - tion, rather than aversion, and will be able to enter classes fully </seg>
            <seg id="p005">institute por the dlind. 363 one or two years in advance of those whose early training has been neglected. The following is given by way of suggestion as some of the things upon which blind children should be instructed before entering the institute : First of all they should not only be allowed, but required as much as possible to help themselves, to dress and feed them - ives, to walk, erect and independently, to care properly for :ir clothing and their person. Induce habits of observation, :ourage them to explore the house, the barn, the premises nerally, to examine the cat, the dog, and other domestic ani - ls, and teach him their habits. Let them handle the tools i learn to use them. At the same time they should learn to count, add, and sub - tract small numbers, and the multiplication table; learn to spell the common words and their meaning and use, the geography of the farm, town, county and state, and other facts which every child should know. Reading with the fingers should also begin early. If neg - lected the loss can never be made good. A delicacy and nice frimination of the sense of touch is seldom acquired after age of fifteen or sixteen years. Alphabet sheets and other matter in embossed type will be gladly furnished, upon the following: i. Give full name of applicant. 2. Where born ; year, month, day of month 3. Parents names. 4. Are parents related in any way by birth; if so, in what degree ? 5. Are parents living? 6. Address of parent or guardian. 7. Where was applicant born? 8. Was applicant born blind? If not, at what age was sight lost? 9. What was the cause? 10. Is blindness total or partial? </seg>
            <seg id="p006">364 Is applicant of sound mind and susceptible of mental cul - ture? II 12 Has applicant any contagious or eruptive disease? Has applicant any bodily deformity? J 3 If so, what is its nature? : 4 Has applicant been successfully vaccinated? If so, when was vaccination performed? '5 i6 Does applicant use tobacco or spirituous liquor in any form? •7 18. As all pupils are expected to attend church at least once every Sunday, what church is it desired that applicant attend? Who will provide clothing, keep same in proper repair, pay necessary traveling expenses, and take charge of applicant during vacations? '9 Does applicant promise to abstain from the use of tobacco and spirituous liquors, in all forms, while a pupil of this school? 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR BLIND. Ezra P. Savage Governor BOARD OF TRUSTEES Clinton Orcutt President Chas. Nownes Secretary C. G. Ellwanger OFFICERS. J. T. Morey, A. M. (Union) Superintendent and Steward Annabel R. Morey Matron Table showing superintendents and teachers of the Nebraska Institute for the Blind, from its organization to the present time. SUPERINTENDENTS. Samuel Bacon ..March 1, 1875 Nov. 22, 1877. Board Pub. Lands .2-8-21 J. B. Parmelee.Nov. 22, 1877 May 4, 1891... Gov. S. Garber. 13-5-12 ♦C. D. Rakestra w, April 21, 1891 May 5, 1891. . . .Gov. Boyd. J. B. Parmelee.May 5, 1891 Feb. 15, 1892. Act. Gov. Thayer. . .9-10 C. D. Rakestra w . Feb. 15, 1892 April 10, 1893. Gov. Boyd 1-1-25 Win. Ebright April 10, 1893 Oct. 5, 1895 Gov. Crounse 2-5-25 D. Neil Johnson.. Oct. 5, 1895 March 1, 1896. .Gov. Holcomb 4-26 Wm. A. Jones . . .March 1, 1890 June 9, 1899 . . .Gov. Holcomb 3-3-8 J. E. Harris ; June 9, 1899 March 1, 1901. .Gov. Poynter 1-8-23 J. T. Morey .... March—, 1901 Gov. Dietrich *Did not take charge until May 4. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">TEACHERS. Mary E. Bishop, L. . . Pi Niermeyer, M . . tia Hotchkiss, M la Langford, M . McGinnis, M... Chadsey, M .1875-1877 .1875-1880 .1877-1887 .1877 Carl D. Beghtol, L 1894-1896 E. C. Cook, L ( 1894-1896) 1899 H. E. Dawes. M 1895-1897 .1880-1886 .1880-1884 .1884-1892 .1884-1886 .1886-1889 .1887-1891 (1887-1891) 1893 M. E. Dawes, M 1895-1897 Annie Sidwell, L 1895 M. O. Parmelee, M. C. M. Scott, I W. H. Wright, L 1895-1895 Gertrude Sousley, M 1895 Blanche Bedell, M. M. L. Nichol, L M. L. S. Connor, M 1896-1898 Almeda Adams, M 1896-1898 Clark Bruce, I. N. C. Abbott, L 1896-1898 C. K. Mansfield, Ka Delong, M. ie Sinclair, L L Collins, L . .1887-1891 .1889-1891 .1889-1891 .1891-1893 .1891-1893 .1891-1893 .1891-1893 .1891-1893 .1891-1893 .1891-1893 . 1891-1893 .1891-1893 .1893-1895 .1893-1895 .1893-1895 .1893-1895 .1893-1895 . 1894-1896 W. B. Woods, L 1897-1899 Mrs. W. B. Woods, L. .1897-1899 Frances Tibbets, L 1897-1898 Walter Alexander, L. Mary F. Morton, L . . . Cara M. Noble, L . . . . Mrs H. Brinkmeyer, L W. W. Campbell, L. . ■■•Campbell, M Jennie Holland, M 1898-1899 Alice Baker. M 1898-1900 R. M. Volk, May 1898 A. McTaggart, L 1898-1899 Mrs. C. McTaggart, L. . 1898-1899 Allie Truesdale, M 1898-1902 Julia Noble, M R. A. Lyman, L 1899-1900 J. M. C. Manager, M F. O. Taylor, I Mrs. R. A. Lyman, L ... 1899-1900 A. Loeb, M 1899 Olive Grant, L... Minnie Trask, L. Flora Bullock, L 1899-1902 Mrs. F. H. Marnell, I. . . .1899-1901 Carrie McClurken, M. Blanch Smith, M Jennie Johnson, L. 1900 Lois Burruss, M 1902 Ivy Hoffhine, L. H. N. Blake, L. H. W. Newton, T 1902 t Denotes teacher in literary department, in music. I industrial, typewriting. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF TRUSTEES. Nebraska Institute for the Blind, Nebraska City, Neb., Dec. i, 1902. To the Governor: The Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Blind have the honor to submit the following report : CHANGE IN OFFICERS. By appointment of Governor Dietrich, J. T. Morey became superintendent of the institution and took charge thereof March 1, 1901. Clinton Orcutt was appointed by Governor Savage as mem - ber of the board of trustees in place of B. F. Allen, whose term expired May 15, 1901. On resignation of J. J. Card well as member of the board, the Governor appointed C. G. Ellwanger, of Nebraska City, to fill the office, taking his place April 15, 1902. S There were in the institute November 30, 1902, fifty-five lie and female pupils. The whole number of pupils enrolled during the biennial term was eighty-six. The highest number of pupils in the institute at any one time was fifty-eight; the lowest number, fifty; and the average fifty-fivt-. The number of pupils graduated in class 1901 was seven, class 1902, two. The capacity of the institute is ninety, viz., forty-eight males, forty-two females. The industries of the institute taught are, broom-making, carpet- weaving, hammock and net making, piano tuning, plain sewing and bead work. The girls are taught all save broom - making. TEACHERS. LITERARY DEPARTMENT. Annie Sid well (Rock ford College) History and Literary E. C. Cook (Neb. Inst. for Blind) . . . Mathematics and English Jennie Johnson (Neb. In«t. for Blind) Primary H. W. Newton Typewriting </seg>
            <seg id="p010">368 MUSICAL DEPARTMENT. rrtrude Sousley (New England Conservatory, Boston, 1894) Pianoforte, Theory, History of Music, Cecilian Chorus Lois Burruss (Neb. University, School of Music, 1902) Vocal Culture, Pianoforte, Junior Chorus) A. Loeb (Heidelberg, Germany) Violin, Orchestra, Band, Mixed Chorus INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENT. Clark Bruce (Ohio Inst. for Blind) Boys Industrial Work Jennie C. Walker Girls Industrial Work Effie Campbell Nurse PHYSICIAN. J. A. Haggard M. D. COMPENSATION OF OFFICERS Board of Trustees Traveling and personal expense J. T. Morey, superintendent and steward . $1,800.00 per annum Annabel R. Morey, matron 400.00 per annum J. A. Haggard, M. D., physician 180.00 per annum TEACHERS SALARIES PER MONTH. Annie Sidwell $ 50 00 E. C. Cook 60.00 Jennie Johnson 25.00 H. W. Newton 40 00 Gertrude Sousley 50.00 Lois Burruss 40&lt;00 A. Loeb 65.00 Clark Bruce 50.00 Jennie C. Walker 45 .oo Effie Campbell 40 00 EMPLOYES WAGES. J. J. Hill, engineer $ 70.00 Elias Smith, teamster, etc 30.00 H. W. Meyer, night watch 30 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">369 Cynthia Pugh, laundress $25.00 Susan Wiison, laundress 25.00 Miry Rehse, cook 25.00 Jessie Dilley, second cook I5- 00 Anna Sullivan, domestic i5°° Miry Wehrs, domestic i5-°° Elizabeth Harrow, domestic I5'°° Ray Adams, domestic i5-°° Lizzie Scholl, domestic i5-°° Jennie Lemon, domestic 15 00 Chas. Spevak, bellringer 5-°° ENROLLMENT FOR THE BIENNIUM Name. A«e. P. O. Address. Nativity. Date of Adm'n Ackerson, Anna . . . 24 . . Colon, Neb . . . Nebraska.Nov. 20, 1899 21.. Palmyra, Neb. Illinois. . .Jan. 1,1897 Arnold, Don . Baker, Alice . Beery, Sarah 33. . Belle vue, Neb. Missouri .Sept. 26, 1893 i7..Holdrege, Neb.Iowa ....Oct. 16, 1901 Boche, William . . .11. .Winside, Neb. Nebraska .Oct. 25, 1898 Carter, James . . . .20. .So.Omaha.Neb.Nebraska.Sept. 11, 1901 Conley, Letha . . . . 20. .Stromsb'rg.Neb.Missouri .Feb. 21, 1808 Conlev, Laila 12 . .Stromsb'rg.Neb.Missouri .Sept. 7, 1889 Condon, Eugene.. 25. . Columbus. Neb. Nebraska.Sept. 27, 1900 Cave, Herbert 11 . .Neb. City, Neb. Nebraska .Oct. 2,1899 Childers, Chas. .. .12. .Lincoln, Neb .. Nebraska .Oct. 1, 1901 Chambers, Myrtle. 14. .Omaha, Neb . .Iowa Sept. 10,1901 Conn, Merton 22 .. Sutton, Neb . . . Nebraska . Oct. 3, 1902 Cozad, George. . . 10. .Lincoln, Neb. .Nebraska .Sept. 10,1902 5. .Lincoln, Neb. .Nebraska .Sept. 10,1902 Cozad, Albert Currie, Willie 9 . . Lincoln, Neb . . Nebraska . Sept. 11, 1902 Duncan, Sylvia. . .26. . Auburn, Neb. .Illinois. .. .Jan. 12, 1888 Dean, Martha 8. .Minden, Neb .. Nebraska .Nov. 2, 1901 Eastman, Edith. . .30. .Campbell, Neb. Wisconsin Sept. 11,1899 Fedalar, Frank . . . 14 . . Lincoln, Neb . . Nebraska . Sept. 2, 1896 Finney, Myrtle. ... 9. .Pawnee Cty " .Nebraska .Sept. 11,1901 Gordon, Bessie . . . .22. .Kenesaw, Neb. Wyoming. Feb. 14, 1890 GUh, Clarence 17- .Angus, Neb.. .Illinois Oct. 2, 1895 36 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">370 Grensemann, Lizzie. 20 Hexthausen, Hans . 20 Harter, Maud 21 Hallam, Neb . . Illinois . . . .Jan. 2, 1900 Omaha, Neb .. Nebraska .Apr. 4, 1893 Kenesaw, Neb. Nebraska .Sept. 2, 1896 21 Husa, Rosa 17 Hultstedt, Oscar ... 29 Hollabaugh, W. E.29 Hughson, Laura. . . 19 Haynes, Frank . . . . 31 Horton, Roy 16. Holderman, Clara. 15. Huit, Nola 7 . Johnson, Sarah . . .17 Journey, Wallace ..12. Jennings, Leona ... n . Johnson, Mildred .. 6. Koontz, Edna . . . . 13 . Knapp, Anna 25 . Lawler, Mamie... 21. Lindstrom,Chris'ne. 16 Lindstrom, Anna ..12. Long, Delia 31 Laird, Clyde 13. Lewis, Glen 13. Rockville, Neb.Nebraska.Sept. 12,1894 Mead, Neb. . .Illinois. . . .Sept. 7, 1898 Neb. City, Neb.Nebraska . Nov. 29, 1898 Omaha, Neb. .Nebraska Jan. 13, 1892 Wahoo, Neb. .Iowa Sept. 10,1902 Table Rock " So. Dak . . .Sept. 10,1901 Omaha, Neb. .New York.Jan. 3, 1902 Callaway, Neb.Nebraska .Sept. 9, 1902 Plattsmouth, " Nebraska .Sept. 20,1902 Omaha, Neb. .Nebraska .Nov. 1, 1901 Neb. City, Neb.Iowa Jan. 1, 1900 Lincoln, Neb. .Nebraska. Sept. 10,1901 Omaha, Neb. .Nebraska .Sept. 10,1901 Neb. City, Neb.Nebraska .Jan. 4, 1897 Wilber, Neb . . Nebraska . Oct. 23,1895 Exeter, Neb . . . Nebraska . Sept. 23, 1890 .Stromsburg, " Nebraska .Nov. 10,1897 Stromsburg, " Nebraska .Nov. 10,1897 Douglas, Neb. Missouri . .Sept. 7, 1898 Hayes Center," Nebraska. Sept. 6, 1899 Beatrice, Neb. .Nebraska. Sept. 13,1899 13 Leonard, Elizabeth. 5. LaNoue, Elma .... 18 . Murry, Minnie. ... 12 . McCandless,Harper22 McKinney, Frank. 14 Monford, Henry ... 8 Moulton, Esther.. 14. Morey, Myrtle ....11. Morsch, Joseph. . .40. Nelson, Danella . . .13. Neumann, Carl . . . 53 . Olmstead, Jennie. .14, Severson, Anna ... 23. Plattsmouth, " Missouri . . Mar. 3, 1902 Upton, Wyo. . Kansas . . .Sept. 11,1901 Bee, Neb Nebraska . Nov. 10,1897 .Broken Bow," Nebraska Oct. 2, 1895 Mead, Neb. . .Florida . . .Jan. 2, 1902 Ashland, Neb.Nebraska .Sept. 10,1901 Lincoln, Neb.Nebraska .Sept. 20,1901 Neb. City, " Nebraska .Jan. 5, 1902 North Platte " Nebraska . Apr. 10, 1901 Blair, Neb Nebraska. . Sept. 8, 1897 Omaha, Neb . . Germany . .Sept. 10,1902 Wayne, Neb. .Nebraska. .Sept. 7, 1898 Wolbach, Neb.Iowa Mar. 10,1897 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Institute for the Blind. 371 Stuart, Mon.i 22. . Rock Bl'ff, Neb Nebraska Sept.25,1890 Stuckert, John .... 25 .. Omaha, Neb . . Iowa Mar. 27,1899 Spreen, Fred. 27 .. Pender, Neb. . . Germany . . Feb. 5, 1900 24 . . Omaha, Neb . . Nebraska . .Sept. 5, 1900 Schmitz, Sylvester 12. .Freeport, Neb. Kansas. .. .Nov. 7, 1899 Schmitz, Delia... . 17 . .Freeport, Neb. Nebraska.. Nov. 7, 1899 Scott, Minnie Seuma, Alma 24 .. Omaha, Neb . . Iowa Sept. 5, 1900 15 .. Omaha, Neb . . Nebraska .Sept. 6, 1899 Schlegel, Mathew .60. .Omaha, Neb. .Switzerl'nd Sept. 10,1902 Smith, A. J... Thrapp, Otto Tichy, Sophie 45 . .Omaha, Neb. .Russia .... Sept. 14,1901 22 .. Neb. City, Neb.Nebraska . .Sept. 18,1899 14 . . Niobrara, Neb. " Dec. 3, 1898 Wright, Eva 17. .Brock, Neb.. .. ■ Dec. 1, 1897 West, Nona 18. .Omaha, Neb. .Iowa Sept. 13,1893 Whitehill, Vere . . . II . . Neb. City, Neb.Nebraska. . Sept. 6, 1899 Zadina, Charles.. .16.. Omaha, Neb. .Bohemia. . .Sept.14,1892 ESTIMATES of the amount of appropriations that will be necessary for the proper maintenance of all departments of the institution for the years i9O3-'O4: Salary of superintendent $3,600.00 Matron 1,000.00 Salaries of teachers 9,000.00 Employes' wages ■ 7,500.00 Fuel and light 6,000.00 Water rent 800.00 Musical instruments and music books 3,000.00 Stationery and printing 300.00 Furniture, clothing and bedding 500.00 Telephone 150.00 Drugs 3C0.C0 Stock feed 1,000.00 General repairs 800.00 Medical attendance 600.00 Contingent fund 500.00 Spevak, Chas </seg>
            <seg id="p014">372 Land Commissioner's Rkport. Paints and oils $ 600.00 Shop and laundry supplies and repairs 500.00 Living expenses 9,000.00 Library fund 1 50 00 Developing industrial department 250.00 Painting main building 1,000.00 EXTRAORDINARY. Enlarging ice house and cave 300.00 For driveways, and improving grounds 500.00 COMPARATIVE STATEMENT. showing amount of appropriations for all departments of the Institution for the biennial period ending November 30, 1902, and amount of estimates submitted by the Board of Trustees for the years 1903- 1904: APPr °lKi attOn8 ""lS."** Increas*. Dccreue Superintendent's salary .$ 3,600.00 $3,600.00 Matron's salary 800.00 1,000.00$ 200.00 Steward and bookkeep'r 1,600.00 $1,600.00 Salaries of teachers. . . 10,000.00 9,000.00 1,000.00 Employes' wages 7,500.00 7,500.00 Living expenses 10,000.00 9,000.00 1,000.00 Fuel and light 5,000.00 6,000.00 1,000.00 Water rent 600,00 800.00 200.00 Stationery and printing 500.00 300.00 200.00 Telephone 1 50.00 1 50 00 Express and telegraph 75-OO 75-OO Drugs 250.00 300.00 50.00 Stock feed 800.00 1,000.00 200 00 Furniture, bedding, etc. 800.00 500 00 300.00 Medical attendance . . . 600.00 600.00 Contingent fund 300.00 500.00 200.00 Musical instruments and music 800.00 3,000.00 2,200.00 General repairs 300.00 included with laundry, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">/ 373 Shop, laundry repairs and supplies $ $ 500.00 $ $ 150.00 Paints and oils 600 00 600.00 Library fund 200.00 150.00 50.00 Developing industrial department 500.00, 250.00 250.00 Driveway and Improv- ing grounds 300.00 500.00 200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">374 &lt; &gt; i tobi ie : : o o o o : : : : : : o : o o &lt;n : : : : =&gt;' &lt;=&gt; '■ '• «&lt;■ •jBj^30u«[Bg • -2g2g * 'fte™ • • • -SS -53 psiBmnsa : :^ rt - rf . : : : : : : : : : :^ rt : : ■ «B ■ ■ 9&gt; co/ie J«w ::::::::::.::::::::::::: : A'ouapgdQ ::::::::::::::::::::::::: ; p^Bmnsg : ; : :::::::::::::::::;:; ; §-h — 90 • &lt;8 &gt;S «~ •*■"»■ -a:S5©t-o -as — m -cq »- ar-8 -usooeibr-- ■xusoso -r-r-s&gt; • JS r- 6681 pasdBq : : ;-*-§ : -"js- 1 :™ «~« ;« "*:Sg : : : &lt;n* : : : : ■♦* • - •«» ■ ■ • «» 6061 '1 »3a 8KgqSI3552SSSgEqS8SSS5ESS : SI «5i-tcti«S"'"i5'"'O?'? tc*i-rtSu; ell Tf t~ ac c — re M-Hrt^i *m 1— 1 — 1 —55 ; I : « • :«• 88SS88P8RSSgSa?888S8S888 .IS njnnail vm ctcCSHi-r-ooaciifi + M'j'i'ce-t-^joi' 2 5**55r-fHCiftHKSClrt M ■*?* — ■* Ol— 1 MM M ' i8S55s38sssssegsse8ssspa8i~r5 O O 5C r~ C^ t"™ *^ O M CO f^ l~~ 00 0C 'fT nC OS O S3 O f~* O • C^ I ITtii 1 T w » v T^ C'l T'l r^ C^ O ' "7 O 3C JC 3C » t"~ *1 » » 'X. QC O ■ *?i I ~ 8SSSSSSSSS8SS88S88888888 j|8 «* i-TcTr^o irT • Up" r^ • » 55 0D 8881 •ddy 0061 'I TA1*T ••• • • ........... ..... p^ 1 . J9 61 ■* *»■ p.B.doaddv :::::::::::::::::: :» ::::: x! jCanapBaq :•::::::::::: : : : . : :g • : : : :ls S-ocf-^qoMr-^i o woos sc as © ©ep«o -as — © • • M • « rt as 36 os © ; »-t 36 m r- in h ao r 1 - © SB 06 'hNI • ■ ao . *M •** -h iC IO l5 i-h -* • • Cir+'+r* ■ ■ ■ dS ; 1 : : .« m ■ • ■ - tr. B ill: Ml Mil: Hill;!; iilis ; . . . . g fliiiji!i:ii|iii!iisii]!li iiiiiii 3*2 S E.i Si g-l S£ 5 £ x =2 *°-3 3T£ Xs </seg>
            <seg id="p017">375 ' S ~ *" c ™ during the biennial term ending November 30, 1902 RECEIPTS. Balance on hand December 1, 1900 $ 39 1 -&lt;?i Brooms sold 1 73.64 Twine and rings 62.30 Beads and bead work 62.60 Receipts from scales 7.50 Point slates 24.55 Carpet weaving 39-85 Calves sold 32.00 Pigs sold 1 75.80 Miscellaneous articles 1572 Potatoes sold 17.58 Cash transferred from superintendent's account 23.75 Hammock and twine sold - 62.20 Point paper 5.45 Uncanceled revenue stamps 2.32 Milk sold 1.90 Stock feed 28.14 Horse (crippled) 45.00 Cows 98.00 Tuition for pupil from Wyoming 200.00 Car fare for indigent pupil 7 47 $1,477.68 EXPENDITURES. For postage stamps $ 85.00 Revenue stamps 5.00 General repairs 82.15 Fruit trees 50.27 Stock feed 89.82 Drugs 38.20 Freight and express 4°-34 Miscellaneous articles 57.32 "State Journal" 7.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">376 Land Commissioner's Report. "News" $ i.So Superintendent's expense to Lincoln and return (two trips) 8.00 Railroad fare for indigent pupils 21.07 Labor on grounds, etc 45-4O Point slates 1485 Rubber stamps 4.91 Beads and bead wire 7 2 45 Rental for lots 6 00 P1;ints 500 Lawn swings, for blind children 17 00 Herding cows 2.00 Oats 28.00 Cows 1 25.OO Digging potatoes 2.25 Fire extinguishers 14 00 ♦'Daily Press" 6.75 Twine for hammock." 4 2 -49 Broom corn 52.12 Returning two boys to institute 4.74 Harrow 1O 00 Service of veterinary surgeon 2.00 Mower knife 3.99 Plastering 7.65 Lawn mower 6.50 Cane and millet seed 8.05 One-horse mower 40.00 "Milwaukee Review" 4 00 Apple barrels, for storing apples 10 00 Carpet warp 2.20 S ationery loo $1,024.82 Balance on hand November 30, 192 $ 452.68 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Institution for the olind. 377 GRADUATES OF THE NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND. Name. Graduated year. P. O-AddreM. S*» .emr. . kj. -iu™.. S u»tainln«. Aaberg, Albert L '86. . Bazille, Neb Yes Adams, Nellie L '90. Neb. City, Neb.. . V Bail, James B. C '98. .Tecumseh, Neb. Yes Baker, Alice V. P. T. . . '98 . . Battle Creek, Mich Yes Bebout, Isabella L '94. .Neb. City, Neb. . .Yes Bell, Bertram V '97 . Jacksonville, 111 ... Yes Beuter, Harry B '97. Omaha, Neb No Botsford, Anna L '98 . . Emporia, Kans . . . Yes Bruce, Clark L '86 . . Neb. City, Neb. . . Yes Bush, S.J T. B '00. .Marquette, Neb. Yes Burns, James T '98 . . Kenesaw, Neb deceas'd Brown, Gertrude L '90 . . Madrid, Neb No Campbell, Lucy L '86 .. Graf, Neb Yes Clark, Roy L. P '99. . Lincoln, Neb Yes Cozad, Harry L. T '94. .Neb. City, Neb. . .Yes Cozad, Sarah L '94 . . Long Island, Kans Yes Crowder, William B '98. .Peru, Neb Yes Coryell, Levi L '88. .Brock, Neb Yes Crim, Emma L '86 .. Nemaha City, Neb. Yes Curtis, Frederick L '94. .Lincoln, Neb Yes Delong Clara L '86 .. Alexandria, Neb . . Yes Deranleau, Remi P. T '99. . Rapid City, S. D . . Yes » Duncan, Sylvia L '99 . . Stella, Neb No Dueholm, Christian . . . . L '88 .. Lewisville, Neb . . . Yes Gregg, William L '86. Lincoln, Neb Yes Kmon, Mary L ........ '86 . . Buffalo Gap, S. D . . No el, Paul T '99 Yes Hexthausen, Hans L. T.P.B . . '01 . . Omaha, Neb Yes Hollabaugh, William .. . T. B '02 .. Neb. City, Neb . . . Yes Hollingsworth, Ferd . . . L. B '98 .. North Platte, Neb . Yes Hollingsworth, Nora. . L '99. .Diller, Neb Yes ? Johnson, Ing wald B '96 . . Genoa, Neb ? Johnson, Jennie L. P '99. .Fremont, Neb. . . .Yes ) Jones, Clarence T. L '98. .Neb. City, Neb. . .Yes </seg>
            <seg id="p020">' 378 Jones, Frances L '96 .Neb. City, Neb.. .Yes Jones, Josephine L '94 Neb. City, Neb. . .Yes Knapp, Anna L. P '01 Wilber, Neb Yes L inham, Alma L '96 . Cozad, Neb Yes Lewis, Clarence B '97 Red Cloud, Neb.. Yes Mathews, Golda L '96 So. Omaha, Neb. .-Yes McAuley, Mary L. P '98 Neb. City, Neb.. Yes Miller, E. J L Madison, Neb. ... ? 94 Miller, Stella L '96 Neb. City, Neb.. V Martin, Nora (x) L. P. V.. .'01 Rogers, Neb Moore, E. C L. P '99 Guide Rock, Neb. ? Mullins, Julia L '86 Salem, Neb No Noble, Bell L '94 ' Oleson, Ida L '01 Stromsberg, Neb. . Yes Page, Adelbert L. T. B Omaha, Neb Yes 99 Parrish, Mer L. T '96 Beatrice, Neb Yes Q aandt, Gustave L '86 Grand Island, Neb V Regelin, Minnie L '96 No Rowejohn L. T. R.V.'o2 Los Angeles, CaL.Yes Simpson, Arthur B Peru, Neb Yes OJ Shike, Ray L. V. T Yes 00 Stinger, May L Gering, Neb Yes 99 Tarwater, Kay L Neb. City, Neb. . . V 94 Warrick, Maud L '90. Blair, Neb Yes White, Owen L. B Albion, Neb Yes 94 Wilson, Austin L Battle Creek, Mich Yes 94 L. — Literary department. B. — Broom-making. V.— Violin. P.— Piano. T. — Piano tuning. (x) — Pupil in Fremont Normal. f r e submit appended hereto as part of this report the physi - 's report, giving the hygienic conditions of the school, also the report of the superintendent, giving full and detailed </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Institution for the Ijlind. 379 information as to the present condition and needs of the school, and ask a careful perusal of the statements and suggestions therein narrated. Clinton Orcutt, Chas. Nownks, C. G. Ellwanger, Board of Trustees. PHYSICIAN'S REPORT. To the honorable Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Blind: fBNTLKMBN: — According to law I hereby submit my bien - report, for the term ending November 30, 1902 : Tnere has not been during the past term much sickness. The health of the pupils and teachers generally speaking has been very good. One case of hemorrhage of the lungs seemed quite serious for a time, but was soon under control, and there has been no return of hemorrhage. October 1, 1902, I discovered a well marked case of small - pox, it having been carried into the institute by one of two little girls; one from Omaha and the other from Lincoln. This first case was at once sent out of the Institute to her home in the city, and kept until all danger was over from her, but following this case, was six others, well marked, and a few cases that were so light as not to make any disturbance. The above named six cases were isolated at once, by being placed in the hospital rooms. By constant vigilance on the part of the superintendent, the nurse and myself, we succeeded in stamping the smallpox out in about six weeks, and the rooms and halls of the building have been thoroughly fumigated. The health of the inmates sirce has been exceedingly good. The pupils have been thoroughly vaccinated. (consider the sanitary conditions of the institute excellent superintendent, teachers, and pupils have cooperated in ging around the best hygienic conditions possible. The </seg>
            <seg id="p022">1 380 Land Commissioner's Report. Eren have plenty of fresh air and systematic exercise in the nasium, and I consider the institute in a healthy and pros - us condition. Respectfully submitted, J. A. Haggard, Physician. REPORT OF SUPERINTENDENT. To the Board of Trustees, Nebraska Institute for the Blind, Nebraska City, Neb. : ti accordance with statute provisions, I herewith submit for r consideration the fourteenth biennial report of the affairs of institution. As shown by the course of study printed elsewhere, this school undertakes the usual work of the common schools of the state, except in such branches as drawing, and fine penmanship, where sight is essential. In addition to the work of the common schools, we give thorough instruction in music, as well as in several industrial occupations, or trades. LIBRARY DEPARTMENT. fi the literary department of our school the usual studies from primary grades through the High school are pursued. It is no longer necessary to undertake to show that children deprived of sight are capable of education, nor do we now have to argue the advantage of an education for the blind. The time has gone by when the only place offered by society to the blind man is a secluded corner, and the only occupation that of beg - ging. Blind men and women today occupy positions of honor and trust in various industries and professions. They are found, too, in places where the unthinking would least expect to find them. One of the leading boat designers and builders of the country, John Herreshoff, of Bristol, R. I., is a blind man, while Professor E. V. Campbell, of the University of Michigan, having charge of the chemical engineering department of that institution , and supervision of the largest chemical laboratory in this country, has been totally blind for years. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">} 381 Education can not make a successful man or woman out of every blind child, but when we compare the status of the blind today with that of fifty years ago no further argument for the support of schools for the blind should be needed. K Notwithstanding what has been accomplished, and what is ng accomplished, without sight, it is folly to contend that a given person can do as much without sight as with it, or that a given number of children without sight can be as readily edu - cated as though they were possessed of all their senses. It takes more teachers, and more time. Consequently, the expense of educating a given number of blind children must be greater than for an equal number of chil - dren with the normal number of senses. MUSK AL DEIWKTMKXT Ever since the organization of schools for the blind, music has held an important place in their curricula. Blindness in no way gives an aptitude for music, but for such as have this aptitude it is of the greatest value. Many make a living by teaching or Iacticing in one or more of its branches, while for many others affords a means of agreeably entertaining their friends or lacing themselves in hours otherwise drear and lonely. Eiree choral classes give opportunity to all in vocal work, junior class takes in beginners, while two or more advanced es give further work to those found capable of taking it. E dividual training in voice culture is also given, though ously it is not worth while to attempt to make accomplished ers of all. A graded course of instruction on the pianoforte is provided, as well as on the violin, horn and other instruments. A brass band, as also an orchestra, is supported by the pupils. While well-equipped in many respects, our musical department is lacking in one essential respect. Our school stands alone, or nearly so, in the sisterhood of schools for the blind, in being without the king of musical instruments — a pipe organ. One of the leading organists of the country is a blind man, while many others support themselves wholly or in part by the </seg>
            <seg id="p024">382 re means. A good organ would be of inestimable value to school as a whole, while to a few it might furnish directly means of an honorable livelihood. (During the past biennium 40 have received instruction on the uioforte, 21 on the violin, 20 in individual voice training, 38 in orus work, 18 in band and orchestral work. Only selections of recognized merit are made use of in our school work, as is shown by the few typical examples following, mastered during the past two years : tFor the pianoforte — Studies by Duvernoy, Loeschhorn, Hel - , Czerny, Bach, Chopin, or their equivalent; sonatas by Hay - n, Mozart, Beethoven; selections from Mendelssohn, Chopin, humann, Liszt, or their equivalent. ■On the violin — 7th Aire, by DeBeriot; Legende, by Wieni - rsky; 5th Aire, with Variations, Scene de Ballet, 6th Concerto, by DeBeriot; Souvenirs de Bellini, by J. Artot; Intermezzo Sin - »iico, by Mascagni; II Trovatore Fantasie, by Atlar; Souvenir the Alps, by A. Herman. For the band — On the Rhine Waltzes, by Keler Bela; Living Pictures, by Dalbey; Svveet Briar Overture, by Laurendeau; Gems of Steven Foster, by Theo. M. Tobani; El Capitan, High School Cadets, King Cotton, Stars and Stripes, by Sousa; Prince Charming, by Innes; Veni, Vedi, Vici, by R. B. Ball. Orchestral — America, by Theo. Moses; Caprice, Blue Vio - lets, by R. Eilenberg; The Dawn of Love, by Theo. Bendix; Overture, Mirtha, by Flotow; La Pompadour, by Boettger; Cocoanut Dance, by Andrew Hermin; The Serenade — Selec - tions, by Victor Herbert. Ehoruses — Oh, Italia, by Donizetta; Farmer's Mass, in Bflat; ning Hymn, C. Reinecke; Jubilate Deo in F, by Schnecker; idiantina, by P. Lacome; Till We Meet Again, by Eben H. ey, etc. I Occasional recitals aregiyen by our pupils, which are valuable tending to give confidence, while at the same time they afford index of the advancement made. During the present year a cert for the entertainment of the school was given by the sic faculty, which, from its value in showing what good music </seg>
            <seg id="p025">f 383 is, it is hoped is but the forerunner of others to follow. Especial - ly are such recitals valuable to us on account of our isolated position. INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENT Here is undertaken the work of teaching certain manual trades or occupations, whereby the blind man, so desiring, may secure a livelihood by the combined exertions of hand and brain. Bead work as the training for the hand as well as a means of profitably employing a portion of the child's time is taught beginners. Some of the older girls, howtver, find it a source of pecuniary profit as well. Netting hammocks and fly-nets is taught both girls and boys from ten years of age and upward, and is a simple occupation from which incidentally at least, some revenue may be derived. rof our boys, Fred Spreen, unusually industrious in turning spare minutes to account, has derived several hundred dol - lars from this source during the past three years. Piano-tuning is commonly given first place as a remunerative occupation for the blind man, providing he has the requisite aptitude for such work. But few, comparatively, have the "ear" and mechanical skill necessary to success, while the bungler not only makes a failure for himself, but by his failure throws discredit upon other blind tuners, thereby making their path more difficult, even though they be thoroughly competent. It gives me pleasure to state that good reports have come to me of the work done by tuners sent out from this school, indi- Kg alike that good methods of instruction are used, and that sr discrimination has been used in granting diplomas. Broom-making is also taught, and several graduates are work - ing with success at this trade. Carpet-weaving, seems to me, to offer as practical and profit - able a field for the efforts of the average blind person as any - thing that has come to my attention. There is nothing difficult to learn in the operation of the flying shuttle loom, and with a little aid from seeing members of the family in arranging colors </seg>
            <seg id="p026">T 384 ri necessary, the blind man, or woman, is nearly on an lity with the seeing person. Ei addition to his loom the blind man, with a simple equip - it for cane-seating chairs, harness mending, hammock work, fly-net weaving, need not lack for employment in any com - lity, provided he be possessed of other attributes necessary uccess in any person, seeing or sightless. In this connection I would say that it seems desirable, as a rule, for our graduates to enter upon their work in the neigh - borhood from which they came to us. At home they are known, and can more readily obtain favors necessary to make a start. I)ur girls are taught the fundamentals of housekeeping, being uired to look after their rooms and, as they acquire the skill, ir clothing. Nor is lack of sight a bar on the part of an ■lligent girl to cooking. A young woman of my acquain - :e, totally blind from early childhood, has for years kept ise, including the cooking, for several brothers. In this con - nection I am sorry to report that the plans partly formulated last season for equipping a kitchen where regular instruction under a competent teacher, might be given in the scientific preparation I food, have not yet been completed, but hope that this want 1 soon be supplied, for as must be recognized, the greater nber of our girls will spend their time at home, and it would m that should we fail to equip them, so far as possible, to e an intelligent part in the domestic affairs of the home, our ching of literature, history, mathematics, and music would be e else than a sham and pretense. Following is a list of cles made in the work rooms as a part of the regular instruc- Seventy-six dozen brooms, 320 yards rag carpet, two dozen sheets, nine laundry bags, two comforts, two biscuit sofa cush - ions, one silk sofa cushion, one dress skirt, one quilt — pieced, two crocheted mats, two pair knit mittens, six yards crocheted wool lace, twenty-four silver polishers (hemmed), twenty-four dishtowels (hemmed), one fancy knit mat, thirteen hanging baskets, four lambrequins, fourteen bead handkerchief boxes, </seg>
            <seg id="p027">1 385 225 bead napkin rings, fifty small articles, six wall pockets, three aprons, one gymnasium suit, six star mats (beads), one corset cover, two handkerchiefs — sofa pillows, five small bead baskets, three pairs crocheted slippers. Darning and mending is also done in this department. IN GENERAL, While it is the intent to admit to this school only those of from 8 to 21 years of age, there are individual cases in which an exception is made. I agree with Prof. Samuel Bacon, him - self a blind man, and as elsewhere noted the first superintendent ot this institution, that the long continuance of a blind person, as pupil, in schools for the blind is undesirable from the standpoint of the best interest of the blind person. A child enterirg at the age of five and remaining till past twenty is likely to come to look upon the school too much as a permanent abiding place; he fails to acquire that sense of independence, which it is the province of the school to inculcate. It is preferable that the blind child go to school for a time with his seeing brothers and sisters. He can learn much by listening to their work, and with a little extra effort on the part of teacher can make good progress. By constant association, too, for so great a time with others having the same defect as himself, his own defect is likely to more deeply color his after life. I agree, too, that it is gener - ally undesirable to include in our school persons of mature years. Their influence is not likely to be for the best upon the younger ones, though here too, exceptions are made. During the past two years five men of middle life who had recently lost their sight, desiring to learn how others similarly afflicted live and occupy their time, have been admitted, and in only one case have I been led to feel that an injury to the school had been worked by making the exception. In the last named exception, however, it is understood that the connection with the school is to be for a short time only — six or nine months. The effort is made to impress on the minds of all connected with this institution the fact that it is conducted solely for the benefit of the pupils and in no sense for the benefit of officers. 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">1 386 I&gt;ANI&gt; C^OMMISSIONKR S K.RPOKT. teachers, or employes, though it sometimes seems difficult to lead people to see that the same requirements should be expected of those in the employ of the state as of those in the employ of a private individual. It is not a place for the social entertainment of friends by either teachers or employes. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS. |)n all property such as this a certain percentage must be wed for deterioration. Roofs must be repaired, paint :wed, furniture, instruments and apparatus replaced. A low re for expenditures does not always betoken economy. The e of the adage, "A stitch in time," is nowhere more appar - than here. The outside wall? of our buildings are showing effect of lime and the weather, and it would seem that a coat - of good paint would prove economical in the end. The er and porches will need some outlay soon to make them • I would call attention to the fact that there is no safe or vault lected with this institution for the preservation of the records, he time our fire-escapes were erected, they were undoubt - the best to be had, but I believe it desirable that one of the er tubular forms be erected for the use of the girls at least, ur test shows that while the boys get out in a remarkably t time, several minutes elapse before the little girls are safely 1e ground. In safeguarding these sightless children, no one rs a policy of parsimony. Iur appropriation for water, and for fuel and light, has been fficient during the past few years. In order to keep within appropriation in these particulars it has been necessary to down the supply of light to the limit of safety, and far beyond limit of comfort, or convenience. The argument that meets 1 this respect is, that the blind have no need of light. It t be remembered that in a building the size of this there are y halls and rooms to be lighted in order that teachers and loyes may perform their duties. Further, we should not lider that because these boys and girls have lost the power ght they are therefore not susceptible to the influence of </seg>
            <seg id="p029">387 light. The lack of power to perceive objects is not always accompanied by inability to distinguish betv\etn light and dark, and I have failed to find one who does not prefer during the evening, a lighted room to a dungeon. In this connection I would suggest ownership by the state of a plant for supplying light and water, as well as for refriger - ating purposes. A gasoline engine of moderate power would be sufficient to run the required dynamo, pump and compressor. It would be well however in any event, to retain the present con - nections for fire protection. In conclusion I would express my appreciation of the aid ren - dered me by the Governor, the Board of Trustees, and the various teachers and officers of the school. I would also remember the clergymen of the city for kindly services rendered, especially the Rev. H. L. House, and Mr. G. E. Bone, for many neighborly acts of accommodation. To my »decessor, Hon.J. E. Harris, and Mr. F. H. Marnell, steward, the many courtesies extended, my heartfelt thanks are due. Respectfully submitted, J. T. Mokey, December i, 1902. Supt. COURSE OF STUDY PRIMARY GRADES, FIRST YEAR. Reading. — Alphabet, primer and first reader Writing.— N. Y. Point. Spelling. — Words from reading lessons. Numbers.— Combinations to ten; count to 100. Make use of Speer blocks and method for form and proportion. Language. — Correct a few common errors in speech; drills on correct forms, to impress on memory. E s neral. — Talks on people and animals of our own and other :ries; on care of body; manners and morals, using concrete pies; Thanksgiving Day; Christmas. Blusic. — Chorus work, and such instrumental work as is ed to capacity of individual. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">y 388 Industrial. — Bead work and such other suitahle work as may be selected by teachers. B ymnastics. — Systematic work daily under direction of her. Baths weekly. SECOND YKAK Reading. — Second readers. Writing.— N. Y. Point. Spelling. — Words from reading lessons ■umbers. — Combinations to twenty; Speer blocks; number es. Language. — As in first year. General. — As in first year, memory gems. Music. — As in first year. rdustrial. — As in first year, ymnastics. — As in first year. THIRD YKAR. Reading. — Third readers; tables for children. Writing. — N. Y. Point. Spelling. — From reading lessons. Numbers. — Hall's arithmetic. Book I, parts i and 2. Geography. — Long's home geography as basis. Language. — Hyde's first book to page 50. Follow spirit of author. Memorize selections. Music. — As before. rdustrial. — Bead and hammock work, ymnastics. — As before. (GRAMMAR GRADKS— FOURTH YEAR Beading. — Fifth reader and equivalent matter from other LS. Writing. — As before. Spelling. — As before. Numbers. — Hall's arithmetic. Book II, part 1. Eeography. — Redway's natural geography. Book I, to page and review; become familiar with dissected map of the ed States. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">9 INSTITUTE FOR. v HE DL^D. 389 Kinguage. — Hyde's first book, to page 150, and review; as re. Music. — As before. Industrial. — As in third year. Girls take up plain sewing Gymnastics. — As before. FIFTH YEAR. Reading. — Seventh reader, and other equivalent matter Give attention to expression. Writing.— N. Y. Point. Spelling. — Words from various lessons. Make word list. Arithmetic. — Hall's arithmetic. Book II, part I. Geography. — Redway's natural geography. Book I. Com- pleted review. Language. — Hyde's first book. Completed review, as before. Music. — As before. Industrial. — As in fourth year. Gymnastics, etc. — As before. SIXTH YKAK. Reading. — Eighth reader, and supplemental work. Writing. — N. Y. Point and script with pencil. Spelling. — As in fifth year. Arithmetic. — Hall's arithmetic. Book II, part 1. Drills in rapid combinations. Geography. — Redway's natural geography, to second book to page 100. Carpenter's North America; as before. firammar. — Hyde's second book to page 109. Follow spirit author. Music. — As before. Industrial. — As before. Gymnastics. — As before. SKVENTH YEAR. Reading. — From various suitable sources. Writing. — N. Y. Point and pencil script. Arithmetic. — Hall's arithmetic. Book III, part 1, as before. Geography. — Redway's natural geography. Second book complete. Review Carpenter's Europe and Asia. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">T 390 Grammar. — Hyde's second book, part V. Drills on principal parts of irregular verbs. Apply principles of grammar to everyday speech. Music, etc. — As before. EKJKTH YEAR Arithmetic. — Hall's arithmetic. Book III, part 2. Grammar. — Hyde's second book, reviewed; memorizing; composition. History. — McMaster's history of the United States. Music, etc. — As before. HIGH SCHOOL NIN'TH YEAR Algebra 5 Composition and rhetoric 5 Physiology 5 Music, industrial, etc TENTH YEAR. Algebra 5 Latin, lessons and grammar 5 English literature 1 Ancient history 3 - Music, industrial, etc KI-KVENTH YEAR. Geometry, plant- 5 hours weekly Latin, from Caesar and Cicero 5 hours weekly English and American literature 2 hours weekly Chemistry 3 hours weekly- Modern history 5 hours weekly Music, industrial, etc TWKLKTH YEAR. Geometry, and arithmetic reviewed 5 hours weekly Physics 3 hours weekly English grammar 2 hours weekly Civics 5 hrs wkly J^yr U. S. history, Johnston's 2 hrs wkly J^yr Political economy 3 hrs wkly }£yr Music, industrial, etc </seg>
            <seg id="p033">I 1?JS 1 1 1 L»TE FOR THE xiLIN D. 391 INSTITUTE FOR BLIND SCHEDUL.I 11KVJ-I 6:30 Rising bell. 6:50 Warning bell. 7:00 Breakfast. 2 130 Chorus — boys' gymnas- tics. 3:00 Orchestra — Monday, 7:45 Chapel. 8:00 Choir. 8:15 Classes. 9:00 Classes. 9:45 Classes. 5:50 Warning bell 6:00 Supper. 6:20 Office. 10:30 Classes. 7:00 Reading. 7:45 Reading. 11:15 Classes. 11:50 Warning bell 8:00 Younger retire. 12:00 Dinner. 1 xx) Classes. 1:45 Recess. 8:30 Reading close — Inter. 2:00 Band — girls gymnastics. PROGRAM. Thursday, June 6, 1901, at 2:30 r. M Overture — Poet and Peasant F. v Suppe Orchestra. Two Queens Anna Knapp. Two Pianofortes — Eriksgang and Kroungs — march Kretschmer The Beautiful is as Useful as the Useful Nora Martin. Light The Owl and the Pussy Cat Ingraham Choral Class. Wednesday, Friday. 3:50 Recess. 4:00 Industrial. retire. y:&lt;&gt;o All retire. 9:15 Silence bell. GKA Ul •ATI N( ; KX Kl MJIS KS Misses Johnson and Sousley. Ida Oleson. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">392 Physical Environment as a Factor in Civilization Hans Hexthausen. Legende, op 17 Wieniawski Nora Martin. ■ Invasion of Armies may be Resisted: An Invasion of Ideas, Never Mona Stuart. Presentation of Diplomas by J. J. Cardwell. Fatinitza March F. v Suppe Orchestra. GRADUATING EXERCISES. Friday, June 6, 1902, 2 o'clock. Institution Orchestra — Wilhelmina Waltzes Hall Two Pianofortes — Gondoliera op 86b, No. 1 Reinecke Sketch — "A Visit to the Cave of Aeolus" Maud Harter Essay— "Our Flag" Wallace Journey "A Letter" Clyde Laird. Ladies' Trio— "Murmur Soft, Ye Breezes" Wekerlin By the Cecilians. Exhibit from the Geometry Class By Delia Long. Exhibit from the Algebra Class By John Rowe Exhibit from the Physics Class By Charles Zadina. Violin— Fantaisie, Rigoletto Singelee John Rowe. Essay— "Historical Sketch of the Piano" W. E. Hollabaugh. Presentation of Diplomas by Mr. C. Orcutt Mazurka Caprice — "Blue Violets" Eilenberg </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>