<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Routine and Seasonal Work of Nebraska Farm Women</title>
               <date value="1930-01">1930-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bu,etin 238 January, 1930 The Routine and Seasonal Work of Nebraska Farm Women M. RUTH CLARK and GRETA GRAY Home Economics THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR. DIKECTOK </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY Data used in this bulletin were secured during 1927 and 1928 from 179 Nebraska farm women. INSIDE ROUTINE TASKS The most important routine work of the farm woman is care of her home and family. The size of the household changed somewhat during the year from 4.2 persons in October to 4.7 persons in June. Only in October were the average family and the average household the same size. The number of rooms used changed slightly during the year. During spring and summer months a larger number of rooms were used per household than during the fall and winter. Laundering was a part of the routine work of the group included in this study. Ninety-eight per cent of the women did all the launder - ing, while the remaining 2 per cent did a portion of it. Some sewing was done at all seasons of the year. More garments were made for women than for children. In April and November the largest number of children's garments were made, while the largest number of women's dresses were made in May. Sewing for the house itself was heaviest in the winter months. Baking bread, cake, and cookies was a routine task for a portion of the women, per cent baked all, 50 per cent a portion of the bread used. ■ Only 8 per cent baked no bread. Ninety-four per cent baked all the cake used, while the remaining 6 per cent baked a portion of it. All cookies used were baked by 63 per cent, a portion by 34 per cent of the women. Only 3 per cent baked no cookies. Care of milk and cream and making of butter continued with some fluctuations thruout the year. More women made butter during the winter and spring than during the summer and fall. The average amount of butter made per month was largest in May and smallest in October. The average number of gallons of milk cared for daily was also greatest in May. INSIDE SEASONAL TASKS Canning of fruits and vegetables is a strictly seasonal task. The canning of fruits spreads over a slightly longer time than the canning of vegetables. June, July, August, and September were the busiest fruit-canning months. Canning of vegetables started later and reached its peak in August and September. It was during the busy canning season that the largest number of extra persons to whom meals were served was reported. Such extra meals were served to guests, and hired help who were members of the household for less than one month. MODERN CONVENIENCES Modern conveniences are an important factor in a consideration of the labor of the farm woman. Forty-one per cent of the homes rep- </seg>
            <seg id="p003">resented had no system of running water, 24 per cent had a pump in the kitchen, and 35 per cent had running cold water in the kitchen, rTt y frZ er u C T hEd b ° th hot and cold runnin e wa ter, 36 per litht, * 5 a £ tUbS ' 23 F 6 J Cen * inBide flush toilets ' 21 P« &lt;*nt electric lights, and 37 per cent furnaces. Only 40 per cent used ice for re - frigeration, while 60 per cent used a cave, cellar, basement, well or running water. Thirty-eight per cent of the group occupied homes having no modern conveniences; only 6.7 per cent possessed all four of the modern conveniences of water, heating, and lighting systems, and a system of refrigeration other than cave, cellar, or water. When the farm homemakers were asked for their opinions in regard to those features the possession of which was considered the greatest convenience, and the lack of which the greatest inconvenience, running water was listed first in both cases. OUTSIDE ROUTINE TASKS Eighty-two per cent of the group took all or a major portion of the care of the poultry. During April, May, and June, when baby chicks are hatched or purchased, the average number of chickens more than trebled the number at the beginning of the year. During July, August and September the largest sales of chickens took place. OUTSIDE SEASONAL TASKS Gardening is one of the most purely seasonal occupations of the farm homemaker. Sixteen per cent of the women took entire care of the garden 64 per cent received help, and 20 per icent did no gardening. In April, May, June, and July the largest number of women reported work in the garden. Thirty-five per cent of the total number helped with the outside work of the farm. The tasks ranged from frequent trips to town for repair parts to the heaviest type of field work. A few women reported these tasks as a part of their routine work, but in most cases such work was only occasional. Forty-four per cent of the women helped with the milking. This was a task performed by most women only in emergencies. HELP WHICH HOMEMAKER RECEIVED The largest part of the help which this group of women received came from children. A few women had hired help and in various tasks husbands gave assistance. CONTRIBUTION TO CASH INCOME Seventy per cent of the group reported a money addition to the family income thru the sale of eggs, poultry, cream, milk, butter, fruit vegetables, etc. ILLNESS . Illness of any member of the household means increased work for the homemaker. The women themselves reported the largest number of days of illness in March. In the same month children spent the greatest number of days of illness. The largest amount of illness for other members of the household was reported in June. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">CLUBS AND SOCIAL ORGANIZATIONS Sixty-nine per cent of the group belonged to clubs and social or church organizations. PROPOSED REMEDIES In her work the farm woman is greatly influenced by the seasonal nature of farming. There are certain seasons of the year in which no amount of careful planning can eliminate rush work. She might, how - ever, lighten her work at all seasons by more careful planning over a long period, by the use of modern equipment and labor-saving devices, by ceasing to do in the home many of the tasks which can be done outside, by using more hired labor, or by working in cooperation with one or more neighbors on various tasks. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Routine and Seasonal Work of Nebraska Farm Women M. RUTH CLARK AND GRETA GRAY 1 iQ97 e d l t i O 3?o e l ented in this bulleti n were secured during 1927 and 1928 from a group of 179 Nebraska farm home - makers. Records were kept during a period of one year In addition a questionnaire giving general information as to the conditions under which the work of the housewife was done was filled out by each record-keeper. The aims with which the study was undertaken were to learn the nature and extent of the various tasks undertaken by the Nebraska rural housewife, how such tasks are dis - tributed thruout the year, what leisure time she has what assistance she receives in her work, from whom such assist - ance comes, and to propose possible remedies for her labor problems. The records were kept by farm homemakers living in various districts of the state. The major portion came from the central and eastern parts, with the eastern sections more fully represented. The western part was represented by only one county, Perkins. The counties from which records came were: Cedar, Wayne, Madison, Boone, Garfield, Coif ax, baunders, Douglas, Cass, Seward, Gage, Clay, Hall, Dawson, Custer, Logan, Perkins, Saline. A local woman was secured as superintendent in each section and the record-keeping was carried on under her direction and supervision. The superintendents were visited by the project leader, who was in constant touch with the work both thru the super - intendents and thru correspondence with many of the home - makers co-operating. The records were not complete in every case. The number of records from which this study is made i3 small, but they present a representative sample of Nebraska farm women and the kinds of work they do. It is of interest to know something about the group of farm homemakers from whom the records came. They were un - selected except on the basis of their willingness to co-operate in this study. They differed in many respects, as Table 1 indicates. The size of the farm in acres, the size of the house, and the number of persons in the family have been used as criteria of the status of the farm families included in this study. 1 Greta Gray is now an associate professor in the University of California at .03 Angeles. * </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 238 household consisted of 4.2 persons. In every other month there were additional people in the households. The house cannot, of course, change in size with the chang - ing number of persons, but the number of rooms used did change from month to month. The average number of bedrooms used each month had a very close relation to the average number of persons in the household, as is evident from Figure 1. In June, the month when the average household was largest (4.7 persons), each household used 2.6 bedrooms, the largest number used at any time thrueut the year. From March to September a larger number of sleeping rooms were used than during the months from October to February. This suggests that heating the house, as well as the number of persons, has a direct effect up - on the number of sleeping rooms used. This is true also of other rooms used, as is shown by Figure 1. From November to March the average number of other rooms used per house - hold was less than during the months from April to October. 4- . s^ — ~^L IS — z : ; — Av. Number op Deq&amp;o/I&amp; - - AV. /lUM&amp;tQ OF Bt-DIJOOMS ,: . Av. /IumBE^ofOtheij Qooms * I I -I 1 — _l 1 ol I I I I I I L — I 1 1 Jam. fee.. Ma$. Ap&amp;. May Jute Jwy Auc. Sw&gt;. Oct. Hck Dol FlQ, 1. — Average number of persons per household, of bedrooms used, and of other rooms used per household </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Seasonal Work of Nebraska Farm Women The work of the farm homemaker is both routine and seasonal. Her activities, while not so decidedly affected by the changing seasons of the year as are those of the farmer himself, are still influenced to a considerable extent by the seasonal nature of the business of farming. Much of the routine work of the farm homemaker was not entered in the records from which this study was made. Such work as the preparation of meals (except extra meals served) and the care of the house and the children are tasks which, it is taken for granted, go on from day to day. Laundering, sew - ing, and baking may or may not be a portion of the routine work of the farm homemaker. In the homes included in this study, however, laundering might well be considered a por - tion of the regular routine work of the homemaker, as 98 per cent of the entire group did all of the family and house - hold laundry, while the remaining 2 per cent did a portion of it. Laundering of course changes somewhat with the number of persons in the household and the season of the year, but is, on the whole, subject to slight fluctuation. The ease or the difficulty with which it is done is, however, very depend - ent upon the type of equipment used. Gasoline-driven machines were found in the largest number of homes — 50 per cent having this type of equipment — while 25 per cent used hand power and 19 per cent electric washers. Six per cent had no machines. The sewing for the family was not so generally a portion of the routine work as was the laundry. Only 38 per cent did all of the family sewing, 58 per cent did a portion of it, and 4 per cent did none at all. Sewing (which included mend - ing) , like laundering, must be done to some extent during all seasons of the year. Certain seasons niake much heavier demands than others, but a certain amount is necessary thru - out the entire year when a homemaker does all or any con - siderable portion of the sewing and. the mending for herself or her family. The number and types of sewing machines used by the homemakers have a close relationship to the time and energy expended in sewing. Only 2 per cent reported no machine of any kind, while another 2 per cent had electric machines. The remaining 96 per cent had machines driven by foot - power. Figures 2 and 3 show the distribution of sewing done by the farm women over the period during which records were kept. The women's garments included those which the farm homemakers made for themselves and those which they made for other women in the household, as mother, sister, </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 238 anfl^nfmSfl, 8 Fi «™ e * that Jt ™* during the summer t^f v *? tha A fc the s™ 8 " 6 !* Percentage of farm homemakers made butter A number of explanations for this fact might be offered During this time the farm homemaker is very busy with hired help and more of her time is demanded for preparation of meals. There are more persons in the farm pX f°i TV? g a po 5*!2. n °f these months ' in addition to the extra farm labor, and the demand for milk and cream for table purposes is increased. Another reason is probably the lack of satisfactory methods in many farm homes for keeping foods cool m summer Churning, if done at all, must be done much more frequently than in winter. Butter can be pur - ahfv^niTS 1 a ™°H nt8 «&gt;d the storage problem consider - 3«L» P %. Du " n « the summer and autumn, also, the 1o^*Vi? P ° f th V a ?ture probably has some effect in cutting down the amount of butter made. Jam. Feb. Mas Ap* May JoHe July Aik&lt;. 5&gt;er Oct Nov. Dec. Fig. 4.— Percentage by months of farm homemakers who make butter for sale or for home use </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 238 TAB J£ 8 "Trt*°* e l Y es the - Vossesion of which was con - sidered the greatest convenience and the lack of which the greatest inconvenience, by the farm homemakers Greatest Greatest convenience inconvenience Running water and drain or pump and drain in kitchen.... 77 , Q Bathing facilities , " 11 2d Heating system ; g % Lighting system on A Size of house... Z..ZZ 6 \a General arrangement of house 12 35 Closet and drawer space. 3 11 Arrangement of kitchen 8 ji Sufficient cupboard space 23 % Back porch or screened porch 13 0 Store room and wash room 3 o Miscellaneous ; .. # - - g % convenience, while 39 homemakers felt lack of water in the 9?m*S £ 6 the ,5reatest handicap under which they worked; 24 others thought lack of bathing facilities their greatest in - convenience. Lighting and heating systems were more highly valued by those who had them than by those who did no? as in 29 instances a lighting system was considered the great - est convenience, while only 10 considered it the greatest in - convenience to be without such systems; in the matter of heating systems also, 8 believed them a great convenience while only 3 thought the. lack of such systems a grSHn?on - venience. The general arrangement of the house and its size y,ere high in the list of inconvenient features as were also the arrangement of the kitchen and the lack of adequate storage space. In "arrangement of kitchen" were included such items as unsatisfactory arrangement of kitchen furni - ture, insufficient lighting of work places, a room of such size and shape as to require many unnecessary steps and motions, and relation of the kitchen to the rest of the house. Sufficient cupboard space and « back. porch or a screened porch both stood high in the list of convenient features, but neither of these items received much attention in the list of desired con - veniences. The miscellaneous items included labor-saving devices, such as power washing machine, refrigerator elec - tric iron, and pressure cooker. It is of interest to note that labor-saving devices received very little attention, however, as compared to the "modern" conveniences of water, lighting and heating systems. While it is true that modern conven- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Seasonal Work op Nebraska Farm Women iences are being installed in many farm homes, it is evident from replies to these questions that they are not yet at the command of many farm homemakers who are conscious of the disadvantages and inconveniences under which they labor in their homes because they lack such conveniences. So far this study has dealt primarily with those activities of the farm homemaker which have to do directly with the farm family and the farm home. The work of the farm home - makers is not, however, in most cases confined to tasks which can be carried on within the home. On every farm poultry is kept and in most instances the homemaker, either wholly or in part, is responsible for the care of such poultry. Of the women who kept records for the present study, 147, or 82 per cent, of the entire group took either all or a major por - tion of the care of the poultry. While the raising of chickens may well, be considered a part of the routine work of the women on the farm, the great fluctuation in the number of chickens cared for in different seasons of the year lends this activity much of the nature of seasonal work. Figure 8 shows the change in num-- - ber of chickens cared for during the various months of the year. Beginning in March the average number increased very rapidly until June, almost doubling in that time. This in - crease was greatest during April, the principal hatching 1 month. In May a smaller increase occurred. Figure 8 represents all chickens cared for. During March, April, May, and part of June, care of baby chicks might be considered a seasonal activity. In June the average number of chickens cared for began to decrease. This decrease was quite rapid during June, July, and August and considerably slower during September, November, and December. The greatest sale of chickens, then, came during July, August, and September, when young chickens were placed upon the market. The chickens sold were probably three or four months old. By September or early October the flock was usually fairly well reduced, with only laying hens and pullets retained for the winter season. Figure 8 shows that during the months of April, May, and June the average number of chickens cared for by the women keeping records was three times the number cared for at the beginning of the year. It does not, however, show the great increase in the amount of time and attention the farm women must devote to chickens. The time during the hatching or baby-chick season would be in - creased more than proportionately to the increase in number, as baby chicks require special attention. Care of chickens during this season cannot be confined to certain times of the </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028"/>
            <seg id="p029"/>
            <seg id="p030"/>
            <seg id="p031"/>
            <seg id="p032">Seasonal Work of Nebraska Farm Women . Of 125 farm homemakers who added to the family income by the sale of farm products produced in part by their direct efforts, 72 per cent reported sale of cream with a total income of $20,457.77, or an average income from such cream sales of .$229.85. This was the largest total amount made by the sale of any one product, but not the highest average income. The sale of milk, reported by 7.2 per cent of the group of 125, resulted in a total income of $2,506.60, with an average income for the number making such sales of $278.51. Income from the sale of cream and milk is not altogether a result of the iiomemaker's efforts. There may therefore be some question as to the validity of including income derived from the sale of dairy products under those items of the family income due wholly or in part to her labor. ' Such income is included here, however, on the assumption that the farm woman devoted a considerable portion of her time to work connected with dairy products. The milk and cream in most farm homes are cared for by the homemaker. It is she who washes the separator and other milk utensils; very often it is she who markets the dairy products. Dairy pro - ducts also should include the butter sold. Only 12.8 per cent of the group reported sales of butter, with a total income of $2,608.52, or an average of $163.03. A larger percentage of this group reported income from poultry than from dairy products, altho the total as well as the average income in every case was smaller than from dairy products. Of the 125 women represented in Table 17, 85.8 per cent sold eggs with a total income of $14,734.07 and an average income of $137.70; an even larger number, 93.6 per cent, marketed poultry, with a total income of $13,134.47 and an average income of $120.81. Fruit, vegetables, and lard were sold by a few homemakers. The 6.4 per cent of the women who reported income from miscellaneous sources did various kinds of work other than selling farm products. The income came from such work as sewing, teaching school, acting as postmistress, helping neigh - bors, etc. In a number of instances the teacher of the neigh - borhood school was boarded, but the amount of income was not given. Such cases are not included in the figures given. In addition to all of her other work, caring for her home and family, sewing, washing and baking, 70 per cent of the entire group of 179 women represented by these records were partially responsible for an average gross addition of $447.06 to the family income. In this figure no value is placed upon the food provided for the farm household by the homemaker. In addition to the poultry, eggs, milk, butter, and vegetables, </seg>
            <seg id="p033"/>
            <seg id="p034">Seasonal Work op Nebraska Farm Women Table 19. — Number of farm homemakers reporting member~ ship in various organizations Number Type of organization I belonging Church work, aid society, or missionary work 52 Women's clubs : 41 University extension study clubs 32 Civic work 19 Social club 16 Lodge 15 Agricultural club 7 Leader of boys' and girls' clubs... 4 W. C. T. U 2 County fair superintendent : 2 Parent-teacher association : 1 P. E. O 1 Red Cross 1 Y. W. C. A .j 1 . I Table 18. The majority of the women in this group are with - in the child-bearing period and child-birth may account for a large part of the illness reported by the homemakers. With all the activities, both outside and inside the home, which this group of farm women reported, they still spent time in club work and reading. The clubs and organizations to which the farm homemakers belonged are shown in Table 19. The total of 123 women who belonged to clubs and social and church organizations represented 195 affiliations. Of these, 75 women belonged to one group or club, 31 belonged to 2 groups each, 12 had membership in 3 groups each, while 3 belonged to 4 organizations and 2 to 5 organizations each. Table 20. — Number and percentages of homemakers belong - ing to clubs and organizations Number Number of clubs or organizations belonging Per cent : i __ 0 :. '......I 56 i 31 1 | 75 T 42 2 1 31 I 17 3 _ [ 12 j 7 4 ! 3 2 5 2 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p035"/>
            <seg id="p036">Seasonal Work op Nebraska Farm Women were most numerous in May and September, altho the aver - age number of mornings away from home was greatest in November. In May also the largest number of homemakers reported afternoons away from home, while the women re - porting evenings away were most numerous in April. In June, however, the average number of evenings away from home was greater than during any other month. The figures in Table 21 show that the farm homemakers in this group, despite the great number of household and other tasks which they performed, still found time for recrea - tion and for a part in the social life of the community. The figures shown in Table 21 represent, however, time spent away from home in shopping, business, visits to doctors, dentists, etc., as well as time spent in recreation. The evenings re - ported away from home were spent largely in recreation, but this of course is not true of the mornings away, nor of all of the afternoons. These figures show, however, that the farm homemaker is no longer isolated and forced to spend long periods of time without leaving the farm, as she was a few years ago when it was still very difficult to travel from place to place. Automobiles and good roads have brought about this change in her life. In her work the farm homemaker is inevitably influenced by the seasonal character of farming. There are certain seasons in which no amount of careful planning can eliminate rush work. She might, however, lighten her labor at such seasons, and indeed thruout the entire year, by more careful planning of her work over a long period, by the use of modern equip - ment and labor-saving devices, by ceasing to do in the home many of the tasks which can be done outside the home, by using more hired labor, by working in co-operation with one or more neighbors on various tasks. Of these possible ways by which the farm homemaker might lighten her work, the first is the most available one, as it requires no expenditure of money and depends very largely upon the homemaker herself. All the tasks which can be done during the winter months, when the homemaker has more leisure than at any other time of the year, should be left until those months. Certain months are by the nature of the farm business very busy ones. By looking far enough ahead and planning intelligently and carefully, the home - maker can leave those months clear of everything except that work which simply must be done.. Such work as house - cleaning can with foresight usually be taken care of in the less rushed periods except that small portion of such tasks which must be done thruout the year. It is for example possible that much of the sewing for the family as well as for </seg>
            <seg id="p037"/>
            <seg id="p038">Seasonal Work of Nebraska Farm Women the home could be distributed somewhat differently and con - centrated in the winter months when the farm homemaker has more free time. If she could foresee the sewing needs for some time ahead and leave the spring, summer, and fall months for various kinds of work which cannot be done at any other season of the year, she might lighten considerably the demands of the busy seasons upon her time and energy. That she has already done this to some extent is evident from Table 2. She might, however, go further and confine her sew - ing activities largely to the late fall, winter, and early spring months. There would always be a certain amount of emer - gency sewing to be done at other times, but careful planning could cut such demands to a minimum. By careful planning, the help available can be used to best advantage to lighten the work during the busiest months. The ease with which the work of the farm home is carried on might be many times increased if the farm home were modern, convenient, easily kept clean, and equipped with labor-saving devices. This is, perhaps, the most obvious way for the farm homemaker to lighten her labor and increase her efficiency. It is necessary that the farm homemaker realize the tremendous handicaps, under which she works in a home without running, water, without a lighting system, without a furnace, and without an adequate supply of small labor-sav - ing devices. In a modern home, with careful planning, the farm homemaker can carry on the many tasks shown by this study and still manage to have leisure time to devote to re - creation and to the improvement of herself, her family, and the living conditions on the farm. The cost of such labor - saving equipment and modern conveniences has been the obstacle in the way of this method. Such equipment does not add directly to the family income, and for this reason it is difficult to convince farm homemakers that it is necessary and forms a legitimate type of expenditure. The farm woman in a very large percentage of the cases continues to perform many of the tasks which have in the past been taken care of in the home, but which are now per - formed outside the home for urban homemakers. Many farm women at the present time make very limited use of outside agencies for the performance of household tasks. The chief arguments for continuing to do various tasks in the home are that the products secured are superior to those which can be purchased, and that in such ways women add considerably to the income of the family. Both of these arguments are undoubtedly valid-, but against them must be weighed the benefits which might accrue to the farm family if the home - maker were free to devote her time and energies to im- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 238 proving living conditions in other ways than by supplying better and cheaper produce than could be purchased. It is a question of relative values which every farm homemaker must decide very largely for herself. As specialization in - creases and manufactured products become cheaper, it may be better economy for the farm woman to purchase more of her food and clothing and devote more of her time to other phases of the care of her home and her family. If, however, the farm homemaker continues to produce at home a large part of the household supplies, she might find it possible to do this more easily if she entered into co-opera - tion with her neighbors in various phases of the work. In this way it would be possible to have better equipment with which to work, and there are numerous tasks among those listed in this study which should lend themselves to such co-opera - tion. The farm homemaker has worked in isolation and her work has therefore lacked the interest which companionship can give. If it were possible to have hired help in the farm home, the problems of the homemaker might be solved in that way! Very few farm homes, however, can afford hired help for more than a few days or weeks during the busiest season of the year. Even if it were economically possible- for the majority of farm homemakers to employ hired help, they would find themselves forced to solve an almost equally difficult problem of where to find that help. While hired help does, in a very limited number of farm homes, free the home - maker from overwork, this is a solution of the problem open to very few. [3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>