<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00017.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00017.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Tenth Biennial Report OF THE BUREAU OF LABOR AND INDUSTRIAL STATISTICS FOR THE State of Nebraska 1905-1906</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE BUREAU OF LABOR AND INDUSTRIAL STATISTICS FOR THE State of Nebraska 19054906 BURRETT BUSH DEPUTY COMMISSIONER DON C DESPAIN CHIEF CLERK LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, 1907. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Vy/5 F.xcellemv, Homvable (ieorge Lmcsom SbeUon, Qrverno- Nebraska: ISik In compliance with the provisions of Section 10, pter 3!*b, of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 19c ■ the honor to present for your consideration the Tenth nial Report of the Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statis' Very respectfully, BUKRKTT Kl'SH, Deputy Commit </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">5 INTRODUCTORY I A government, whether state or national, is a complicated admin itive machine. Precisely as a large corporation has its various irtments and officer* for the management of its many fields and inels of business, so the state h»s its executive, its secretary, its surer, attorney general, auditor, public lands department, ednca - al department and the various boards, bureaus and commissions for administration of laws relating to subjects not covered in the work le above named constitutional departments. Among the subordi departments are the board of irrigation, department of banking, tau of labor and statistics, pure food commissioner, fish and game mission, and department of insurance. The question frequently asked, and by very intelligent people, ' *O# what good is a Bureau of Labor and Statistics? Does the average citi - zen or workingman receive any direct benefits from its existence'' These questions cannot be answered very specifically, any more than could one asking for the direct benefits of the public school. It would be a difficult process to show how a dollar more is made to enter the pockets of the working people, or any citizen, through the existence of the public schools, or any other educational institution, and yet all men will admit that the sum of material benefits is immensely increased by the operation of schools. Primarily, the Bureau of Statistics, wherever it exists, is simply a part of the educational machinery established by the state through which it is enabled to know more of itself. "Know thyself" is an injunction which should be applied to communities as well as to individuals, and it is only through the medium of statistical data secured by rigid, impartial and fearless investigations that any community can know itself in all the various fields of its activities. From another view the Bureau might be properly termed the "advertis - ing department" of the state. It seeks, by the dissemination of official bulletins, to portray to the world the commercial, social, and labor con - ditions of the commonwealth and the resources we have, not only to support, but to further increase the- industrial enterprises within our borders. Its reports "and various publications are for the purpose of conveying to the people ot our Eastern states the information that Nebraska compares well with the leading states of this republican union of ours and to dissipate the many laughable and ridiculous impressions which exist in the minds of the people of the Eastern states, concerning the state's primitiveness. It aims to enlighten Eastern capital to the fact that the buying of Nebraska real estate is a safe and extraordinary paying investment. It wishes to inform the farmer not entirely satisfied </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 with his lot in the congested farming communities ot the KaM that here in Nebraska we have land which may be purchased at a much cheaper price than that which he now ixmM~i.se&gt;.. lint which can lie excelled nowhere in fertility and productive capacity. The various re|,. the Bureau find their way to every corner of the civilized world. The Amercian consuls. immigration agencies and Hfanrtai the world over, and certain departments of all foreign government- in on the perma nent mailing lists of the Bureau anil receive all publications issued Through them channels information raadsM the lietter daat of foreign immigrants that the land of freedom and plenty, in search of which they bade farewell to Um land of inonurchial institutions and pe can be found upon the bioad valleys and rolling uplands ot a iw tf) of which a noted traveler once said The sun and mi.hii) conceived and the iasoe wan Nebraska. Nebraska ranks third in the union in the production of com and has retained that rank for several years, yet only three or four years ago a high official of the I'nited Stati-s Department of Agriculture refused to include Nebraska within the rum lielt ami it necessitated the proof of statixtics and a trip of personal oliservation to ooavinoa him of his error and compel his withdrawal of the embargo placed apoa the - agricultural standing. If such an opinion coaM exist in the mind of an official whose duties should necessarily acquaint him thoroughly with agricultural conditions throughout the nation, it is fail to gut-sun the average Eastern citizen poaaMasl limited knowledge of our great wealth and advantages Such conditions create a held lot educa tioual work, and therein lies one of the greatest duties uf the Bureau of I The statistical work of the Bureau has bsaa greatly increased, lin - ed and placed upon a more accurate and systematic basis during last four yearn Prior to four years ago the publications of the de - ment consisted of a biennial report ot one thousand copies. During last four years the Bureau has issued quarterly bulletins every thre« iths, an annual bulletin each year and a biennial report covering the k of the bieiinium The quarterly bulletins vary m size from thirty ne hundred pages and are generally lamed in lots of t.MQ capias, •e deal with acreages ami yields of all craaa, shipments of products 1 various counties, tit. \ great demand exists for these etins. as the information they give is fresh and pre|iaivd in such M as to be interesting and convincing. The annual bulletin is a larger volume, generally issued in i lota, and gives exhaustive information on practically evwry conceivable subject relative to the agricultural, industrial and economic conditions in the state biennial report summarize* the work of the hienniuui. especially ing with labor conditions and recommendations tor legislation. Very few people have any knowledge of the extent of the work of the Bureau or of the methods used in securing the various t.nn- af statistics. For example, probably the most thorough and coasplai </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 if m &lt;&gt;f enumeration ami compilation in use by the Bureau in that used in connection with agricutural data. The methods of the oftice in this field of work are an complete and perfect ax will he found in any state, and in many ways excel the methods of the national department. Many i&gt;eople think the figures on crop acreage*, etc.. are arrived at by guana work on the part of those in the Bureau. Such is not the case. The figures or. acreages of crop* are (fathered by the seventeen hundred iMamHor* in the state at the time of the assessment of property. The auncimoi- are comjielled by law to list the number of acres planted to various ctufm Hv *adl |&gt;erson they visit. Blank books are furnished especially for that ■MTfjaaa. When the assessor has completed his work bookl are returned to the county clerks, who make a summary ot ea'h townsliip or precinct and return the totals to the Bureau. Kroiu •worn returns the acreages of all crojis in the state are secured. untie-, and become the liasis of the year's figures on crops fat the pajrpoaa at MCttriasj data on crop yields the Bureau has an or - ganized corps of crop correspondents numliering nine hundred in the state anil ten in each county. The organization of this body of corre - s|Kindents was Ihe work of nearly two years The difficulty of doing this is not apparent to one not familiar with the work. Firat.it is necoK - -•■ntative persons of good judgment and intelligence. It is MMMr; to have those wbcaa judgment can be relied upon to give accurate re))orts and estiumtes Second, it is hard to secure those who will take an interest in the work and who will continue to act from ■ year It is further of prime importance to secure correspondents who do not have a selfish or pecuniary interest in the character of the re)xirt All these difficulties have been overcome as far as |H»&lt;sible and during the jiast bicnnium the Bureau has had a very efficient organiza - tion in this line. The prestige which the agricultural rejMirts of the bureau have gained throughout the nation has proven this. The ten rmp correspondents in each county are located in ten different sections of the county and instead of being authorized to estimate crop yields for the entire county 1 which has not proven practicable ithey are author - ized to reixirt on yields within a ten mile radius of their resident*. I Within this distance they should lie fairly familiar with the condi - i of the crops The ten rejxirts are received by the Bureau and an age of the ten computed, which should he a reliable figure for the age yield of the county. This is the system used in arriving at the nction of each of the fifteen principal crops in the state, and the • has been commended by the United States Department of Agri ire and the statistics of the Bureau during the past two years have used to a large extent by that department In case questionable e&gt; are returned or there ap)iea!-s a discrepancy in comparison with ions years the matter is taken up with the county assessor or the his del "ties, who verify or correct the reporter's figures During the years IM to UMiti inclusive, the Bureau has issued twenty reports ami bulletins aggregating SM.000 volumes, which have </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Eid their way to all parts and corners of the globe. An idea of the ecte covered in these reports and the extent of statistical work ac - plished by the Bureau can be obtained from the following list of the inels in which investigations have been made : Manufacturers and Wages. Meat Packing Industry Railroad Statistics. The Dairy Industry Flouring and Grist Mills. Labor Organizations. Reports of Strikes and Lockouts. Municipal Stat i Ecclesiastical, School and Professional Condition) Criminal Statistics. Lodges and Fraternal Societies. Charity and Charitable Institutions. Nebraska's Surplus Products Crop Production and Crop Conditions Quarterly. General Agricultural Conditions Land Values and Conditions Mortgage Indebtedness. Railroad Freight Rates. The statistical work of the Bureau, however. dom not constitute all the work of the office. Several important laws have their enforcement and administration performed by the Commissioner of Labor. The most important of these probably is the child labor law. A new child labor law was enacted by the recent legislature which ia mm of the moat comprehensive and stringent child labor statutes to be found in the United States. The general administration of this law rests with th,. Commissioner of Labor. An idea of the magnitude of the tank to thor - oughly enforce this law can be gained when it is considered that there are 2,645 manufacturing establishments in the state, of which, at least SO per cent employ child labor to some extent. There are 7ti.a-t."i male children in Nebraska between 10 and 15 years of age, of which nujiber. 17.5 per cent, or 13,342,are engaged in bread-winning occupations. The fesail* children in the state between HI and 15 years of age number 74,465, of which it. 8 per cent, or 2,820, are working at various occupa - tions. In other words. 1,800 manufacturing establishments, together with 2,000 or more mercantile establishments, stores, laundries, I offices, etc., must be inspected frequently to regulate, in conformity to this law, the employment of these 18,000 children below the age of 16 The fire-escape law demands much attention and is administered solely by the Commissioner of Labor. The legislature of 1905 made this law more stringent and necessitates more work and scrutiny to properly enforce it for the protection of people working or living in buildings throughout the state. Buildings are constantly being erected in city and town in the state. Old buildings are being remodeled and </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 E larger and higher. All these must receive tbe Commissioner's tion and investigation. The female labor law necessitates the application of much time in ferreting out violations of the same in wholesale houses, mercantile establishments, millinery houses, laundries, etc. This law prohibit* the employment of females longer than ten hours each day and this employ- ment must be between the hours of &gt;; o'clock A.M. and 10 o'clock P. M the principal work of the Bureau. a heavy correspondence to be an - rinable relative to the state roaches tThe foregoing duties constitute not all of it. There is always red. Every sort of inquiry inmj Commissioner from everywhere. oral papers, commercial review: other periodicals an constantly er in the nature of statistics or resources, values, economic con Newspapers, trade journals, agri year book publishers, magazines requesting information and data. of a descriptive character regarding ditions, etc. , etc. It will be seen, therefore, that the work of the Bureau of Statistic* is not of an ostentatious character. The most of the good accomplished is ofet of the state and tt; benefited in a thousand way* for which the Bureau receives no credit and few know of the good Thirty-four states have created and now maintain Bureaus of Statistics. The majority are equipped with every possible facility for -ive work, and the longer they continue to operate and the better itiipi&gt;ed. the more appreciative becomes the general public and the greater are the results to their respective states. The rapid ad - is made in the past ten years has astonished the coun- I'he great majority of the credit for the same is due to Secretary Cuban of the Hoard of Agriculture, who, by years of methodical effort, \ eloped one of the most efficient agricultural statistical depart lnent in the fnited States His bulletins, reports and publication go he world telling all the people what Kansas is doing. By races sant and ]&gt;ersistent effort he has succeeded in getting the eyes of the irned on Kansas, and events of the past few years in that state show the result Such are the aims of the Bureau in Nebraska. Its publication ning known ; real estate men and commercial clubs who coiiu- in contact with the work being done are the most apprecia - tive of the Bureau and its work. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 CHILD LABOR LEGISLATION, A REQUISITE FOR INDUSTRIAL EFFICIENCY Ur continually atmert that we are living in an industrial age and un many occasions we openly Buaal of our industrial achievements ; it is, fur instanif almost iiuputsihle to make an Booapcabte Fourth at July m without iniprt— i»i\^ mention of the railroads and telegraph lines which bind together a mighty continent " Although in our moments of expun siveoens we nu fully admit tin- il industrialism, at other tm. aem to be aatu.med of it and continually insist that mm must rind our cul - ture, uur religion and our education ijuite outside of it. as if the inner »orld developed in complete independence of the outer This may be ooe reason that our culture, our religion and our education so often seem weak ami feeble compared to our industrialism. We fail to realize that because we are living in un industrial age we must find our culture through that industry, and that to seek culture in MM other age that is not our amu is .ir a borrowed and ill-titting garment ; that if we fail to aDply our religion to the industrial situation aim refuse to lie guided by it through the problem* which current industrialism develop. that it |ierforce hecoMW meaningless and remote, and that even more is this true in regard to edu -.1 which fails to give outlet and direction, to the growing intelligence of the child ' to widen and organize his exjiei ience with : •NOB to the world in which lie lives merely dresse&gt; his mind in antiquated precept- and gives him no clue to the life which he inuM lead II -d that a child went to school unwillingly and that ha there entered into an unending struggle with his teacher, who wa.s often justified in the use of coercion The new ]&gt;edugogy, which is so ably n •anted in New York, holds that it is a child's instinct and pleasure to ex - erciite all his faculties and to make discoveries in the world around him. ! is the chief husines* of the teacher merely to direct his activitv .u id to feed his insatiable curiosity In order to accomplish this he is forced to relate the child to the surroundings in which he lives, and the ■Mat advanced schools are using modern industry for this pin: Kducators have ceased to mourn the changed industrial condit. ii children were taught agricultural and industrial arts by natural cu operation with their parents, and they ale endeavoring to supply thi - adrantage hv manual arts in the school, bjr ionises in industrial hi - and by miniature reproductions of industrial | ,mtl&gt; coming into lietter relations with the pre-*nt factory system. E advocates for child labor legislation, as all the sessions of th: - lia\e testified are most heartily m sympathy with this new stand nd in several notable instances the advanced educator is he wbu in </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 II conspicuously striving for adequate legal protection for the child, members of this conference are in n&gt;&gt; MM* those who advocate a life of leas or of meaningless activity for the growing child, nor do they be - • in u spurious or "leisure dasa" culture On the contrary I hope tu ble to show that because we recognize the significance and power of temporary industrialism that we hold it an obligation to protect chil from premature participation in its rpighty operations, not only that may Mean the training and fibre which will later make that partici in effective, hut that their minds may finally take possession of the I which they will guide and feed. There has l&gt;een for many years an increasing criticism of the modern factory system, both from the point of view of the worker and from the point of view ol the product itself It has been said many times that we cannot secure good workmanship nor turn out a satisfactory product unless men and women have MM sort of interest in their work, and some way of expressing that interest in relation to it The system which makes do demand upon originality, upon invention, upon self-direction, works auto - maticallv, as it were, towards an unintelligent producer and towards au uninteresting product This was at first said only by such artists and so - cial reformers as .Morris and Kuskin, hut it is being gradually admitted by men of affairs and may at last i ■corporate' itself into actual factory man - agement, in which case the factory itself will favor child laW«r legislation or any other measure which increases the free and full development of the individual, because he thereby beooaMS a more valuable producer. We may gradually discover that in the iatamts of this industrial society of uurs it becomes a distinct loss to put large numbers of producers prema turelv at work, not only becaaae the community inevitably lose* their mature working power, but also beaasjas their ' free labor quality," which valuable., is permanently destroyed. Exercise of the instinct of work manship not only affords great satisfaction to the producer, but also to the consumer who i- i of any critical faculty We are told that the German products hold a foremost place in the markets of the world because of Germain s tine educational system, which includes training in trade schools for so many young men. and that thai* is at the present moment a strong party in Germany opposing militarism, not from the ' peace society point of view, but because it withdraws all of the young men from industrial life for the best part of three yean, dur - ing which time their activity is merely disciplinary, with no relation to the industrial life of the nation. This unti military party insists that the kiss of the three years is serious, and the nation cannot successfully hold its advanced place if it must compete with those nations who do not thus withdraw their youth from continuous training at the period of their greatest docility and aptitude. It is said that among the workingmen of England, many of whan are engaged in supply ing those cheap markets composed of semi-savage people :i it is the pride of Great Britain to open to her manufactures, there is growing up a protest against the cheap and inferior articles which they are constantly obliged to make Tfca workers m the factories producing </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 these unworthy goods are lieginning to feel roblied of the skill which would be demanded if they were supplying Um markets of civilized people and were ministering to the demands of increasing taste "Cheap and nasty goods hare an evil effect upon the prodooar h will as ■pan the consumer. " It would lie a curious result it f mark&lt;'ts which the British em - pire hat so eagerly sought would finally remit in w dcUising the English workmguicn that they would at hist lie shut out from their legitimate share of the civilized markets of the world It would tx- easy to produce other illustration* to demonstrate that in the leading industrial countries a belief is slowly developing that the workman himself is the chief asset, and that the intelligent interest of skilled men, that power of --elf direction and co - operation which is only i&gt;«ssihle among the free horn and educated, k the only thing which will hold out in the markets of the world. As the foremen of aguin and again, factory discipline is valuable c nly up to a certain point, after which they must depend upon something else if they would achieve Um Its. The smallest child I .t work « ithern mill,- a little girl of five walked up and down her product the mill was turning out wtt which was said to lie designed for a* ally a child of five, holding her snuff *hort lane in a spindle room The cotton sheeting of the coarsest sort, in the Chinese army. Quite natur - &lt;tick against her first "milk teeth" and tying threads with her clumsy baby hands, could not contribute to a product demanding care and skill, ami a mill which used up the labor power of its community in such reckless fashion could never hope to com - pete with the product turned out in another community in which a large •hare of the niechanii-s had bean carefully educated in the public school and in which the maaicipality itself aoatained a textile school Eonopoly of the raw material and newly-opened mai &gt; rtainly lie factors in a nation's industrial prosperity, tint while we spend and bM otect the one and to sisure the other, we wantonly y the niofit valuable factor of all. which is intelligent labor. We have made public education in. ncern in America and per - haps the i -tetn is our Moat distinctive achievement. but there is a certain lack of ■ in the relation of I the child after he leaves the public school. At a gnat expsasa the state has provided school buildings and equipment, and yet other buildings in which to pre - pare professional teachers It ha- spared no jiains to make the system complete, and yet as rapidly a- the children leave the school room the state seems to lose all interest and responsibility in their welfare, and has, until recently, turned them over to the employer, with no restrictions as to the number of hours he shall ] emit them to work, nor as to the sort of employment which he shall give them The Webbs long ago us«-d in illus - n of this contradictory attitude of tin- state the story of an em| who might ask the - ii]p his factory with machinery of recant in - vention that he might use it for his own profit and with but the incidental benefit to the community , at the end of a few years finding it worn be would agan a new e«, mi value, throwing the old back upon the state which had | I it to him </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 KiVehlw insist that this is Maalogoai to the em])loyer asking the state liMlwi who have been edmoftted in the public schools, demanding that -pecially drilled in habits of obedieaoi and promptness and in practical studies which make them the most useful to him; ho putt to work, and if they an worn out at the termination of a few yean by lalxir beyond their strength, the stai hospitals, and poorbooeea, but it list the employer w I I ith his requirements, which he ronce (ran the state ,\l no |k&gt; -1 you to profit by the labor of tr it, and we demand that th&gt; .ill lie exhausted, nor shall they labor which is beyond their strength. will have to me of them t take* them back without a word of amis ■ fresh lot. educated in accord - ing again overwork without any ml (1 iv we have ltlren whom we have educated work so many hours that be allowed to undertake that sort of lor shall they spend their time at work which is absolutely devoid of a wlucation which they have received ii of making them valuable and normal i lurational value. The preliminary 'I is but one step in the process itizens.and we cannot afford to have t intention thwarted, even though the community as well as yourself profit by the bo ivity which your factory affords. Such a perfectly IiwiWii ■ml yet the same citizens who willingly axes to support an alaborata public school system strenuously oppose lost moderate attempts to guunl the children from needless and useless itation after they have left school and have entered industry. Mr. Edgar Gardner Murphy, a member of the National Child Labor Committee, has said that child labor is a national problem, even as public education is a national duty. The children of Alabama, of Rhode Island and Pennsylvania, belong to the nation quite as much as they belong to each state, and the nation has an interest in the children at least in relation - industrial efficiency, quite as it has an interest in enacting protective tariffs for the preservation of American industries. In a democratic coun - try children in one station of life are quite as valuable as those in another, not only from a human point of view, which is true the world over, but from a strictly national point of view, and in studying industrial condi - tions in the light of their effect upon the children we may discover that the children cannot be adequately protected by too much deference to state lines, quite as it was found that a railroad commission must repre - sent interstate authority in order to deal with railroads which were inde - pendent of state boundaries. There is a distinct manufacturing region composed of Western Pennsylvania. West Virginia and Ohio in which similar labor conditions prevail, and yet Ohio has a law which forbids a child under sixteen to work all night. In Pennsylvania any child over thirteen may work all night, and in West Virginia any child over twelve. The manufacturing establishments in these three nates enjoy the same protective tariff and railroad rates, concerning which the federal govern - ment ia most alert that no discrimination shall be made, and yet the nation is quite unmoved if the children in West Virginia are crushed and brutal - ized by being allowed to do night work four years earlier than the children of Ohio. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 I'niform compulsory education laws in connection with uniform child labor legislation are the important factors in securing educated producer* for the nation, bat there is another tide to the benefits of child labor legis - lation represented by the time element, the leisure which is secured to the child for the pursuit of his own affairs, quite aside from the opportunity afforded him to attend Bchool Helplessness in childhood, the scientists tell as. is the guarantee of adult intellect &gt;&gt;ut they also assert that play in youth is the guarantee of adult culture. It ia the most valuable instru - ment the race possesses to keep life from becoming mechanical. The child who cannot lire life is prone to dramatize it. and the very process is a constant compromise between imitation and imagination as the overmas - tering impulse itself which drives him to incessant play is both reminiscent and anticipatory In proportion as the child in later life is to he subjected to a mechanical and one sided activity and aa a hlglilj auMlihWi labor is to he demanded from him. it is therefore most im]&gt;ortant that he should have his full period of childhood and youth for this play expression, that he may cultivate within himself the root of that culture which can alone give his later activity a meaning, and this is true whether or not we ac - cept the theory that the aesthetic feelings originate from the play impulse with its corollary that the constant experimentation found in the com - moneftt plays are to tie looked upon as "the principal source of all kinds of art " In this moment when individual forces are concentrated and unified aa sever before, unusual care must he taken to secure to the children their normal play period that the art instinct may have Mime chance and that the producer himself may have enough coherence of character to avoid becom - ing a mere cog in the vast industrial machine Iuite aside also from the individual development and from the fact ilay in which the power of choice is constantly presented and "— ive imagination required is the best corrective of the future din ary life of the factory, there is another reason why the children who become producers under the present system should he given their jild life period The entire population of the factory town and of those enormous di« ■ in every large city in which the children live who most need the protection of child labor legislation consists of people who have come to - gether in response to the demands of modern industry and who are held together by the purely impersonal tie of working in one large factory, in which they not only do not know each other, but in which no one person. nor even group of people, knows all of them. They are utterly without the natural and minute acquaintance and inter family relationships which rural and village life affords, and are therefore much more dependent upon the social sympathy and power of effect- ,tion which is becoming it* urban substitute This substitute can be most easily experienced among groups of children Eiy is the great social stimulus, and it is the prime motive which children and draws them into comradeship. A true democratic re - uid ease of acquaintance is found only among the children in a factory community because they readily overcome differences of </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 language .tradition and religion, which form insuperable harriers to adults "It ia in play that nature reveals her anxious care to discover men to each other and this happy and important task children unconsciously forward day by day with all the excitement and .joy of coordinate activity They accomplish that which their elders could not possibly do. and they tnpnrtant service to the community. Social observer* com - ment upon the influence of this group and gang spirit aa it ia carried into politics, but no valuable observations have as yet been recorded m to the present system of production, which is so pre eminently one of large numliers of men working together for hours at a time, prohahly Mi the factory offers so little opportunity for its exercise compared to the operations of self government even in its most unsatisfactory manifea - in a crowded city quarter. It would bring a new power into modern industry if the factors ivail itself of that afttii i/&lt; eurjm, that triumphant buoyancy which the hild e.\|&gt;erienc&lt;-s when he faata his complete identification with a Ki that sense of security which comes ni&lt;on him sitting in a th&gt; party" when he issues forth from himself and is lowt in a fairyland which has lieen evoked not only by his own imagination, but by that of MfMMicM as well. This power of association of assimilation, which children jiossess in such a high degree, is aaailj carried over into the affair* nth if it but lie given opjiortunity and freedom for action as it i* in the college life of more favored young |»-ople The cmfirit il&gt; ntrpt of an athletic team that ;u*tonishir.g force of co operation, is. however, i consciously carried over into industry, and is persistently disregarded. It is indeed lost before it is discovered, it 1 may be permitted an Irish hull, in the case of children who are put to work before they have had timetode - velop the |K)wer bejroad &gt; ts 'nost childish and haphazard manifest;!" ■ actorv life de|iends upon groups of people working together and yet ■ontent with the morphology of the gToup. M it were, paying a in to its |&gt;sychology. to the interaction of itsmemliers By leg. riling producer its a solitary unit a tremendous jxiwer is totally unutilized. but in the MM of children who are conditions an unwarranted nervou - effort to stand up to the individual group and family dependence We when we were not allowed to go ' &lt; were overcome with rage and helpli it the playing group which an ments of even more bitter isolation owing to some eccentricity of dram trolling adult, we still felt quite out prematurely put to work under socta strain i- added as they make their duties of life while still in the stage of can all recall moments in our childhood &gt;ut to play with other children and ■ss despair a&gt; we looked from the win- could not j)in. We can recall mo when we were "with the other - ir some other stupid mistake of a con - .lde of the group which we so fervently 1 our own Some such remembrance may perhapw aid our imagina - tion in behalf of the Military child working in a cmnded factory. E? naturally associate a factor with orderly productive action, but rity of action without identical thought and cooperative intelligence eion and not order, and the present factory discipline needs to he led as the old school discipline has been redeemed. In the latter the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 BIENNIAL REPORT system of priies and punishments has been given uj. 11 were difficult to administer, but because they utterly failed to trm power of the child. "The fear of starvation. " of which the old Made bo much, is. after all. hut a poor incentive to work, and the appeal to cupidity by which a man is induce.1 to "apaed up" in all the va devices of piecework is very little batter. The natural these in the determined effort-, of workmen ' to limit tin- output ' has ar raigned the entire system. It is the old revolt ajjain^t incessant muscular tabor divorced from any exercise of the Instinct of workmanship and ik of the creative touch of the artist Let us realize before it is too late that m this age of iron, of tending, and of sub-divided lalxir. that ■ lie—iMilml and inspired activity of youth To cut it out from our nat life, as we constantly do in regard to thousands of working children, is most perilous undertaking and endangers the. very industry to which hare been sacrificed We may in time learn to lie discontented with the pleas which « tinually put forth on behalf of more adequate child lalior legislatio! standing, as we continually do. that the child ba —cared his normal : of growth and his full ok prin such education as the state is able to provide; we may in time add to that, that we are imperilling our ilization because at the moment of its most mark.il materialism we waa tonly sacrifice to it that eternal spirit of youth, that power of var: which alone prevents it from degenerating into a saera mechanism , that in the interests of industrial efficiency we will be obliged to extend legis - lation for the protection of working children —.lane Addams. Mull 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 r SCHOOL AS A FORCE ARRAYED AGAINST CHILD LABOR The list (if the mW forces that MM arrayed against child lal ■tad on the program of the annual meeting of the .National Chil.l I Committee seems ao overwhelming as to lead us to mppoaa that the duration of this evil must ha hut brief Yrt. when we rememlier the uni - versality of greed, the pwilHww of poverty, and the 1 - of chil.l li.xxl we realize that this right will not be so sjieedilv won and tha' have need of every force that can be utilized for the conflict. If ever we. as Americans, lose enthusiasm with regard to the form of our government and its administration, it is when we see the slown. Ieps by which educational and mi n the way of securing legislation )f thought and when we further i ■ of such laws as have 1). of government, to secure by one ( lary for the protection of our t ng has indicated, it is not our he iral reforms arc seined, the difticul - that has the universal approval of ■onsider the unsatisfactory aili; acted. It is impossible, under our enactment such legislatioi •hildren. As the chairman of our pe to secure federal legislation on I matter, we reallize that we must plead our cause not Vfore one tri - 1. but before half a hundred. In Germany it was poMibk k to bring together the distracted units of (Jerman ) possible a united Italy : hut in America we must rally a mtiltitu rs before we can bring about a reform of any kind. We thei&gt; il to public opinion. We are organized to influence public opinion: lesire to present our claims to the thoughtful men and women of this Iry.and through them we hop* to Mcnre. in 01 nch legislation ) believe necessary. Within past years we have traveled far in our ideas of the state. We no longer believe that government to lie l&gt;est that governs least. M longer believe in the state, wl t authority is the badge of |hj temples are its jails and penitentiaries whose sole dih.s I protect life and property, and secure the enforcement of the com Iinents. ■Thou shalt not kill" an-1 government has no higher duty, i f its n\vn existence by whatever f&lt; hat existence; but we believe it h r life us well as its lower life, and M things better than armie: lurches and books are no less nece- Thou shalt not steal." We realize .it certain times. than the preserva &gt;rce may 1 -y to mak i the duty of the state to guard its that, in guarding is higher life, I and navies, and that school hi instrumentalities for national than gunpowder and dynamite Representing the school, we represent our nation and the ooontr :■ the </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 t&gt; i ;ill in its parental capacity. We believe in popular edacatiun. in universal education. We do not claim that this i- u pai for all ills or a remedy fur all We do nol expect I made wine, or ju- that with the bast w . mad&gt; d We : .; wit) will lie Mime failures in lilt- On • rimi tlmt m opportunity must !»■ given to e»i will l&gt;e Mime failures in lilt- Oi -itiun tlmt an opportunity v and tli mM max! have the privi irking out bin on -r that is in him ami therefore we believe that I vv'irkiiii! mil his ow ! is iii him ami therefore we believe iliat ev( \ child must have the chance ot an education. \\ «■ are c&gt;pi»«ed to rliili child must have the chance of an education. We are opi becaiiM- it shuts nrl that opportunity, ami makes education impooail out thai opportunity, and m ition impuxsibU Therefore no legislation on thi&gt; Kuliject can torv if it ianor itinii on tin- subject tory it it i I requirement* of tl nal requirement* »l the child The ill an age ic law-, lint a deeper philoaopl ! iii.n t ~ Our problem is nut m.Ti'ly tn I .:. , at of tlie factun or mine. Ijnt to keeii the child at wtn t uf the factory ur mine, but to keep the child at m wtory l- 1 letter than the slmii^ it ma} lie that tin- factory i tor} is Ix-ttrr than the shuns it ma\ Ik- that the fac i place than the home, tint it is n&lt; • jilace than the DOOM, Imt it is never better than tbi taJ obligation has faileil. .just « here tlni hoi i parental obligation has fail* disappeared from the life of the child, that the kbooI must atep ia &lt;liKap|M'ar&lt;d from the life of the child, that . must step in t other home and the teacher must I lace of the parent w] other home and tin- teacher must tak deaurted hiscbai. that child i I t to have an enactment .11 enai n _' the child must lie alile to read and write 1 iiild must l&gt;e able to read and writ) ''inn allowed It is not unnatural for such a child .ill that I and to drift nd writing is a very smal _• and writing is nt, when it sta childhood that merit, when ir lucational test between childhoo i ami manhood that should look alter itaelf; and j muKt to- ] nd manhood thai -In mid look after itself: and vi every state in the Union, I amppoaa, there are children at work mid i neither read nor write The I'nii and Labor lasi ■ .ii neithei writ md Labor last i ial study of 1,881 children nt work in thirteen a bulletin making a - lildren ut work in th ■ dren at work who were unal and write. Mind you, taking only •■ unable to read and write. Mind you. takin il they were not x» ially t' ill theV Ml illiteracy, in ten of them there were found ii KxamininK the stat ■ I wort md that t t of th teen atatev who hail . terin« upon work, \vl there were also a number ul children who had attended for only one or tw&lt; yean. 1 must acknowledge with regret that of the states whi waa shown up in that examination four of the thirti to tin nth Carolina. Ueorcia. and Alaljama chiklren that fell to tin- Of that numtier 14ti were wholly illiterate. "i7 had never attended school, while Hit ithers had an. r,d.-.l I .r less than three \.-.u&gt; That mean- only about rif </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 is only about halt mi ordinary school year. It is an to retuin ly about h It is unnecessary to remind yoa that a child can Irani but little at school in one yea« of five hi 1 u of five months. It takt-s a good many of thus,- tents to give enough infcirmutiun to t • It tal noujfh inforinatiuii to be. a permanent met, a permanent part of the child's character. The litt 1KT inent a permanent part n that short time character. The little f kllu " Bed in that short tia avay in a few year iV iway in a after the child baa left the school, and meh children a t the sell tirelv illiterate alter spending a feu year.-, at work m the factory. But the Southerners are not linnei ,. remind V iterate alt lms a lew a work in the I nil. Let me remind t one of oar pamphlet*, containing information obtained "by tl one of our pamphlet* containing n ii'dliv the Pennsylvania Child Labor Committee, which (hows that in the city of Philadelphia ( Committee, which shows n the city of Philadelphia alone there are 18,000 children under the age Of thirteen who are not ill -;h the law say* they shall be tiiei if thirteen who are not in iw l'hese children home waiting until they an- old enough t&lt; i k. or at work with home waiting until they are old enough to oecure work, or at work with certificates! that are falsified, or perhaps. Mven. without certifies From the standpoint ot the scliool we urge thre lertificates that are falsified, or perhapH. even, without certificate mi the stand consideration of this subj I We contend that th. finite educational re definite educational re quiremenl in every child labor law. The n lisbmenl .if u nrement in every child labor law. The re establishment of an Agt limit i&gt; insufficient, and the requirement that the child shall be al it is insufficient, and the requirement that the child shall be able to read and write is pitifully small. A law requiring that the child shall at write is pitifully small. A that the child shall at '''"'I '1 while at work is some improvement, but is o] -erious objection, and in practical operatioi m found - ry. A child cannot work in a factory i\ or eight boars a da\ meat, but is o]n-ii also to in found - rv. A child cannot work in a factory sii or .-i^ht hours a day and lo intellectual work at night : and a law permitting children to work during j intellectual work at night ; and a law permitting children to work during the vacation period puts a premium II The second principle for which we contend is that those who an I short school terms nd is that those wb interested in the education of the child shall have BOOM ation of the chili t guards that edn cation of the law that guards that education The Baking out .id not lie placed in the hands of iiouri - wi for this operation, nor should such certificates Ik- made out on tt. w 1 supported affidavit of parents, who- may be unscrupulous in thei i»ir parents, who- ilia scrupulous in their di secure gain from the child's lalior : but the responsibility should •cure gain from the child's lalior : but the responsibility should W placed in the hands of the men and women who are interested in the child he child and its education. III. The third point I would make is a plea for better pchook an. third |Miint I would make is a plea for Utter pchooll l more of them I speak on that point a- a Southern man Of all our prob them man Of all our prob Imm that is the problem that is nu&gt;st far reaching We have another problem called peculiarly the Southern problem, bu Southern problem, but in my opinion • n i&gt; nut so nni venial a problem i «1 a problem nor ■ inns a menace to our general prosperity a- is the distressing fact of illiter acy ami our insufficient educational opportunities There are many living ilucatioiial are many living in the South who know little of an blem through |ier-onal t There are many communities where peace and good will ri th who ki There h nd good will and the two races are living side by side working out their t;isks with MM the two races are living side by side working out their tasks with mutual sympathy, forbearance, and friendship. But there is no State in mutual sympathy, forbearance, and friendship But there is do Sta Is 1 the South, no community that is not struggling with the problem nf pro the South, no community that is not struggling with the problem of pro n ii and sympathy that </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 i \ A 9^&lt;t r^ I 1~j *r Pj r^^^ Xv haa been extended to us hy otl us in working out this problem. ■h a task men MW brought doM together The bitterness of fonMf - will !«■ iu&lt;»t qniekljr (orgottea liy ikoM working together in a (Treat and holy The founder (if the institution with which I himself a citizen of this city in writing alnmt its in: un«l thet* si^niticant woi If Vandertiilt rniveisjty shall, through its influence, contribute, evm rtraBCtheolag the ties which slioiild exist hutwimi all KOHRraphical sittions ,if our coinmon country, I shall feel that it km the objects that led me to take an interest in it In that feeling of common interest and in that spirit of Mend &gt;ur country must unite to promote the work of educa - md to repress the evils of child lalnir. This is a task neither f&lt; of childhood is the cause of humanity. We lay. I tliti liurden of American childhood.- i^nor at of infli ilitie- for tomorrow. —James M K banotUor of Vanderbilt L'nivermity, N.isln illc. lenncwee. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 NEBRASKA CHILD LABOR LAW An act to regulate the employment and use of child labor, to provide for the enforcement of its provisions, and a penalty for its violation. Be it enacted by the legislature of the State of Nebraska Kftiun 1. No child aadar fourteen yearn of age shall ho em] iffered to wurk in. or in ooanectioa with, any theatr - all. or place of amusement, or any pi intoxicating Uqaon Id. or in any SSUU ■IllUll institution, store. office, hotel, laundr 1 . itabiiahmflot, bowling-alley, passenger or freight eleva- ir driver therefor, within this state. in or corporation to employ any child vice whatever during the town, township, village or city in Kr workshop, or as a messenger n 1 lie .unlawful for any |ierson tin fourteen years of age in any hu when the puhli. t the the child i tttion i. No child l)etwpen fourteen ami sixteen years of agi ployed, jieriiiitted or siirleiel to work in any theatre, concert hall or if amusement, or in any mercantile institutioi y. manufacturing establishment bowling alia] i&gt;r, factory or workshop, or as a meanengnr or driver therefor within ate. unless the piiiKi or oorporatiun employing him procures and on file and accessihle to the truant officer! of the town or city, the Commissioner of Labor and his deputies, and the members .if the i Board of Inspection, an emph rxl.and keejw two complet n rile and one i -ly an ing in which such children are mplovment of a child so i certificate shall In- forthwith tr unty suix-rintendent of schools lyment certificate as hereinafter pre - of all such children employed therein. ■M near the principal entrance of the employed. I'pon the terminat red. and whose certih ansmitted liv the employer to tl unity in which the child re aides, and shall he turned over to the child named therein iijk.ii den truant officer, the State Commissioner of Labor, or his deputi mem 1 xr of the State Board of Inspection, naj make demand on any em| in whose plaie of business a child apparently under the age ■ is employed or permitted &lt;n suffered to work, and whose ssaploymeoi titicate is not then filed as required by this section, thatsuch employer shall either turnish him within ten days, evidence satisfactory to him that child is in fact over six* to employ or permit or suffer such child to work in such place of business. The same evidence of tin ■ J h child may U' required from such employer a-s is required on the issuance of an employment certificate provided uployei furnishing such evidence shall not lie raqalrad to furnish any </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 forth the child In case such employer shall fail ..luce ami deliver to the truant oflcer, thi ■mission •■r of Labor or inemlier of the. State •ion. within ten days aft -r demand 1 lion, within ten days aft "r demand lor the same, such evi my child h 'ired of him under the pro- ich evi mi under the pro ifter continue t • lii&gt; act. and shall thereafter continue to employ Mich child or . child to work in Mich place of business, proof of the in pi proof of ih i.l file such evidence lilara t . i I til" mcfc evidence Kbf prima I &gt;ii any p; ion, that such child is ui tie prima facie evidence, in any prosecution brought for a violation ■ion, that such child is under sixteen &gt;• and is unlaw- ught for a v lind is fully - \n employment certificate shall lie approved only by the H An employment certificate aha] approved only by got corporation in which the child re whlcl or by a person authorized by him in writing, or where there i&gt; no A n&lt; ntendent rBOB authorized by the school district ovided that no school district officer or other person authorized ithority to approve such certificate for any child .1 distri mtendenl authorized by tl in or about to enter, his own employment, or the employment of a in or about to enter, his own empli the employment of or imputation of which he is a member, ofleer or employee, or ill . or li i The ofticer or jiersoii approving such cer hi api ,11 liave authority to administer the oath provided for therein or lamination necessary for the approval thi .11 have authority to administer tl. ivided for therein {ration or examination necessary f the approval thereof inn for adininis ill tie charged for approving any such certificate nor for adminis- -hall tie charged for approving ai _; any oatli or rendering any service therein in respect thereto. The any oath or rendering any service therei : of director^ ot end i|Hjration shall establish and maintain h and maintair ; all such certificates and all documents OOB- ill such certified! and all documents hall provide the l of this act • I therewith shall lie riled ami preserved and shall provide the . aary deck tor carrying out the provisions of this act » clerical service for carrying out lh&lt; person authorized t sou authorized to issue all employment certificate until hi has : examined, approved mplovment certificat ihiill li &lt;h certificate until h t filed the following papers dnl child, property filled out and prov Bowing papers duly ex&lt; ichool record of such child. pro]&gt;erty filled out anil provided in this act. showing •he child has completed the work of the Kighth Grade of the public impleted the work of the Eigl schools, or its equivalent or is regularly attending night school in compli- ance with Section Kight i«; of tin- A Passport, or duly ail - ript of ll birth or baptism or other religious or official wing the date anil place of birth ol (ocb child A duly at' - ript of the birth certificate filed according to l.iw with a registrar of or other officer charged with the duty of recording births. script of the birth certificate filed according t ,ch child :i The affidavit • parent. or guardian, or custodian of a child, which shall be required, only in case none of the documents mentioned in clause t\\ lion can i 'I and Bled, showing the place and date of parent. or guardian child, which ~hall be reijui the docamentx mentioned in clause t ion can I 1 and Hied, »howing the place and date of With of such child: which affidavit must betaken bef ore tin- officer issuing birth of such child: which affidavit must In- taken before the otto 9och employment (•■rtificate shall not lie is- sued fore, aid been examined child </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 - in the English language and II write simj that in his opinion the child is f mil developm health and is i in tin' work which it intends to do * shall lie determined by a mi ficer of the hoard or di liartment of ie State Board of Inspection. \V1 bout ti i child, he may in d for the certificate to appear ■t f Mid the judgment of the court upon t some one of tl. tl i med Two ajtl ertificatea. Every em ploy n f the ofticer iwming tl ue by t name it is issued weight and f such child and that the ion have been duly examined, ap- proved ami riled and that the child before the officer signing said c. iti n such certificate has appeared 1 been examined. mi Four shall lie - &gt;n ii The scl hool which such child has atti a child entitleil thereto. It shall by the teacher and principal of tin and shall tie furnished on demand contain a statement certifying that public schooK or schools eqaivaler :ian three fourths of the sch.x,] I fourteen years, or daring th ie child has regularly attended the thereto, or parochial schools for not ear pi his arriving at the v ear previous to applying for mple sentences in the English rd.und is able to v language. It shall also state the an measured by the grade of the public Such school record shall also give I it of work completed by such child. .Is in the city or county nee of the child as the name of its parent, or guardian. shown on the records of tl or custodian. is. or the school directors uf niit between the first and tenth day Commissioner of Labor a li any village, town oi county, shall tr ■h month to the office of the St I lie name- of the children to whom c it itiricates have lieen i Section - Kegular attenuan maintained in any city or Till twenty weeks each year ami ti. evening, shall authorize the issnano the icbooling certificate fails to instruction is given not BM each week and two houi t employment where lat the child has comploted the work w of the eighth giade required by ts titicate and all other'certiticati provided, the schooling cer- rintendent ipalof liar attendant-' child or up wards, and has il of it^ uj{f. ami is in sound il Htnem -.hall be determined liy a — iUcml lent ill health. &lt;n by a physician provided by \\ 'lifiicvi-r the lxM-Min antliorizfil t mty .) mix*"- wlit'n 1 the ijoi ■tificiite. Notice lemuml inspection of employment ligned in the pn nd phut' of liirth of and eyes, the height and papers required by tli iperintendi n 01 county, shall tran faild at any pafalic evening - itherwiae in Uue form and the appti- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 h evening school . and provided further, every child employed under such certificate shall furnish to his employer a weekly certificate showing regular attendance each week while the evening school is in session. Who- K employs a child in violation of the provisions oi this section shall lie not more than fifty dollars (fW.MJ for each offence A j&gt;arent. guar - or custodian who permits a child under his control to be employed in violation of the provisions of this section shall l»e fined not more than twenty dollars - Section I. The age and schooling certificate provided for herein shall be made out uix&gt;n blank forms furnished by the State Commissioner of Labor and shall be in the following four SCHOOL ATTENDANCE CEKTIFICATE Nebraska (dmte Thi- certif • hild (name ■mpleted the work of the th grade, can read and write legibly simple sentences in the English This also certifies that according tti ords of this school and in my belief, tl I name of chila) born at xy or town on the month. and hat. attended said school within the past twelve month: |»-ri.Ki the following Signature Teacher Signature Principal a&lt;;e and school ING CEKTIFICATE IWI Tliis certifies thai I am the jibfi mother, icuardmn or custodian and that liorn at on the and is now moiit: language. in Nebraska in </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 read at sight and E simple sentences in the English language, that said child 1; before me and betm personally examined by me: that all certificates per required by law have, in due form, been presented to. and ap - by me. and the same have been placed on file. tin case the child is attendin further certify that 1 X&gt;1 insert here the following .. -.ihirly &gt;r attending the lame • &gt;rce only so long a&gt; the regular at certified weekly by a teacher tli This certificate shall continue in tendance of said child at said school t l This certificate belongs to (name of child) uperintendent i vvheneTer I the service of the person, firm (he or she r|x&gt;ration holding the same as m plover t ; (Signature and in authorized to approve and ainn EVENING SCHOOL AT TENDANCE CERTIFICATE This certifies that i .me of child registered in and regularly attends evening school. This also certifies ■ I and in my lielief tilt that according to the records oi my i name of chili) &gt; ami is to be surrendered to tlit Nebraska (name ot city or town) (dale) There jiersoiKilly appeared l&gt;efore me the aliove liameil and being sworn uiame of iierxm siifnimt) testified that the foregoing certificate hv signe.1 is true to the best I knowledge or I • 'i her i I hereby approve the foregoing certificate of height i mime of child) inches, weight i" y&gt;: ■•!- •■ complexion hair (fair ordarkl having no Mitticient reason to iloubt &lt; color* t h ut i- of the age herein certified. ( he o. I hereby certify that ■ r she &lt;-sin or cam. (-.•■ul at. *iieht. iinil write </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 E-mh certiflcatM sluill be retained in all cases by the or officer issuing the BMM anil kept on rile by the sugir rintendent • &gt;f nr school district director* &lt; if the enmity in which the same are Section 10. No peraua under the age of si\t- -hall be employe* rtered or permitted to work in any theatre, noncerl hall, or pal amusement or in any mercantile institution, store, office, hotel. laundry ifacturing establishment, packing house, bowling alley, pad workshop, bast Said, or as ■ messenger or drive therefor, more than forty-eight hours in any one week, nor more than eigh ' '" any M I before the boar of -i\ o'clock in the morning iftet the hour of eight o'clock in the evening. Every employer slut! !&gt;■ room where such children an ■1 a printed notice stating the hoan required of them each day of the week, the ] inmencing and or times allowed for dinner or ■ill of such notice shall lie bar. stopping work and the hours when the for other meals liegin and end. The furnished by tbe state Commis nil Whoever em: whoever, having under his control to lie employed in violation of child undei pa and a child under such age, permits such ten i 10) or lie fined not more than tift\ d "" ;i ' I whoever continues to employ any child in violation o itter lieing notified by a truant officer B I Vputy Commissioner of Lalior oi a auwlm of the State Board o ■ction, shall for every day thereafter that such employment continue* led not less than Hm .r more than twenty dollars ($80.00 lailure of an employer of child lab; Q authorized to demand the -ame .red by this act. shall l»e puma f uiy child whose employment i name is not listed An tkm ( - in violation of Haction 1 of authun/.ed or stateimiit prewritied by Section I &gt;r to produce, upon the request of a inployment certificate or list m ie evidence of the illegal employ- ertiricate is not produced or wlm». r eiujiloyer retaining eui])loyment this act sluill l&gt;e fined ten dollars required to sign any certificate or t tlii- act. or who K"'nes or I ii to any material false statement therein shall be fined not to exceed fifty ■I'l" nation, agent or manager. ■nn or corporation \\h. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 refuse admittance to any officer &lt;&gt;r person authorized to visit ur i premises or place of bosinem under the provisions of this act ait all certificates and lists he may have, when demanded, after ii shall have announced his name and the office he holds and (J instruct such officers in tl iis act. shall lie guilty ■■! i their dnl scrihed t 1 in any sum no) &gt;f( fifty .1 thirty days dollai- or be ini| I i The ]iresence of a child D any of the places of busint shall Ik.' prima I duty of the Deputy Commission v the provisions of this ac by any officer or person authoriz - where child labor &gt;- ■d t have been violated, shall file jiloyed, that any if tt IV 1 st the jienson or persons guilty i 9cntion of the same. Provided, that or cause to lie filed information offense and cause the arrest and nothing in this act shall prevent ment of the provisions of this a&lt; business enumerated in Section any children are employed then and tin y shall report ans sioner of Lalior and to tl;&gt; 1 other person from causing the enforce Truant officers shall visit the pi .ii t e 1 .if this act to ascertain whether 'ontrary to the provisions of this act Oi tion 12. It is hereby mi the duty of the governor, immediately oint five persons, two, at le;ist of whom ' the Boarn of Inspectors and who shall t M shall I* 1 women, who shall const! serve without compensation. T tut m for which such i— factors shall foar and five yeat t th is hereby made one, tw( The appointment shall d. ti-iin for which each i—psctor ir appoint one person to serve for a l V a I rill any vacancy on the board. The .if the beard and shall reside in the head in bet ■d of county employing the largest r of children under th Inspectors shall have |x&gt;wer to demand Any member of the Boa ixamination, by sum the Board, of any child under ically unable to perform the lal and no child under sixteen shal 1 of fitness from such ] ection 18 No child u v work which bj i all I*" em: nature of the work, or pi if tl n which its health may be injured innance is dmigerous to life or lim I) parent, guardian, or other i hi 1&lt;1. causes or permits said child to •■tion shall l&gt;e guilty of a mis Is may be depravi-d A who. having under his control ai work or lie employed in violation of lhan fifty dollars 1« imprisoi of his \i&gt;it. cir shall otherwi meanor and mum convictioi not to exce*u thirty days ip|i irenth at • mneuiteil in Section One (t) of thi it employment therein. It sluill 1 i&gt;t Labor ami the several truant ofti. i iv county attorney, when int' if Mich illegal employment totlM Com mi* itv Attorn- lpon the pas ]H)inte&lt;l. The - hall. period of five yean and -hal chairman shall !«■ the axecutiv Lurly licensed physician, to be selected hy -ixl*-cn jtmn otf ;ik&gt;' who may &gt;efin ]&gt;hys- n at which such child mav l&gt;e fini □ ployed wlm cannot obtain a </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 reliv and in conflict herewith are he Section 15. Wh&lt; ■■Wf LJ exists, this a&lt;-t shall take effect after its [ussage anil approval. lane trum and 1) ML XETTLETON i of flnnm erf RapraMatativ Attest CLYDE BAKXARD Chief Clerk (if House of ke|ires.-ntativ M K. HOPEWELL. President of Senat B. H. OOULDING. Secrotary of Senat Api&gt;roved March *»th. VMK ( EC)K(iK LAW8ON SHELDOX Govern IE OF NKBRASKA I. Clyde Banianl. Chief Clerk that the within Bill originated in tht hirtieth Spwiion on the Twenty ixth day at March, KHiT House of Representatives, hereby certify the House and passed the Legislature of CLYDE BARNARD, duct Clerk R"ntp of BeprfwentativeH </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 i 1 . SUMMARY OF THE NEBRASKA CHILD LABOR LAW - Where Employment is Prohibited No chikl under H yean of age shall !)&lt;• permitted to work in any theatre' concert hull, or place of amusement. or any place where mtox icating Ik) 111. or in any meicantile institution, store, office. hotel, laundry, manufacturing establishment, (lacking house, bowling alley. passenger or freight elevat senger or driver therefor r, factory or workshop, or as a mes Employment During School Hour It is unlawful to employ any child under 14 years of age during i are in session. the hours when the public school Certificate Must Ik- Kept on File: Children between 14 and lti y .irs of age may 1* employed in the I named alxive in No. 1. providing the employer keeps on file and -ible to the Commissioner of Lalxir. or his deputies, the truant ■tan and members of the State Board of Ins|&gt;ection, a certiticat. the superintendent of schools giving the ago of the child and ib that he or slie has finisheil the eighth grade of the public schools equivalent, or is a regular attendant of a night school Employment Dangerous to Health or Morals: No child under l»i years of age shall be employed in am which is dangerous to life or limb, or in which its health may lie in jured or its morals depi \i\ed. 1'enalty of #50 or imprisonment n feeding 10 days for i guardians wlio permit children under their care to engage, in any employment in violation of this secti of Children Employed: Every employer of child lai&gt;or must keep two complete lists such children employ n tile and one conspicuously } the principal entrance of the building wherein the children an Certificate Must lie Surrendered U|H)ii the termination of the employment of a child so regi-- inch certificate shall be forthwith city or county supeiintendent of to the child named I therein upon and whose certificate is so tiled, transmitted by the employer to th schools who shall surrender same demand. Limitation of Hours to l*&lt; Employed and Notice I No child under Hi years of age shall he employed or compelled to Wrh 4 H hours a week, nor more than H hours a day ■ I 1 . M. Employers must post </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 BIENNIAL KKPOKT 1 IV A A nent ( Form M I ling a Form M-N mplov ndan. ploy id f t of a child t in authorized by Labor, t mav dema 1 Failur ing employed lie iir VIII of tl My j ition where cliildi ting the hours reqai red of tin-in each day of time allowed fur eacl red by 1 iw Three certilicati in .\J So. 1 E\ 1 (Vrtihi M No intl " Age and S&lt; I M So 2, otherwise u child is permitting him or her work, ami has ri n i?-littl the eighth grade of the puhlii should fill nut ai 1: ndent nt mI uwever, that tr iililie schools, but V I - lriol.1 :&gt;1 till nut and r t with the superinten win i will 1 instruction is giv inent i-'itifiiate. providt kly Cert I : H.I he or she must furnish t week wliil- - Penultv : Wboev child in violation uf tin action shall 1h- rineil nut n nch i.ffense A parent or rostodian who permit* employn ln~ control in viol lit By Whom Employment ( rtihc.ites Mu-t 1m- Approved l*-rint indent i by ;i i« ; officer ■ t Child » Age Must Ik' 1 j km1ii Whin- ■ child apparently m .is .&gt;t i child is on file the Cotninissioi truant -rt iiiemln if the Hoard uf InspectiiN that the employer furnish ithin in days, evidence that ha to employ hild so do will l»e prima facie evidence that said child is ht in violation of the child labor law and the employer shall there 1 a] Whoever employs a child in violation ol ml -••«]ian permitting a child to !»• eaployad in riofa 1 lie fined il t&lt; • in the law a» the "Empfc u applicant for an employ a So I, with Ihe superint MX. plover a u /lar at ition nf tin-, section ■&gt;)w An employment certificate shall !*• approved only by th«' -iujiern ti-mlent ••( rtowli or by a i ■ itically authorized by him. i each </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 14 ■r such atfe. permits such child to II. X or X 11 of the act shall for having under his control ;i child ur !»■ employed in violation of section fined not more than late the provisions of the foregoing truant officer, a Deputy Conn Board of [oapaetioa shall be fined f i; and whoever continues t tions after beisg notified ■r of Laln)r. or a member tor each day at t Any employer retaining •ction II of the act shall !»• tin Every person authorized rei|iiireil to sijjn any certit or V i if the Act. who km inent therein, or who &gt;e fined no! itemeut prescribed l&gt;v Secti rtities Of makes oath to any matei ulates either of saici Kctioi 1 is authorized by the act to produce all certificates or li^ts nied not to Any person obstructing oft it. or who shall fail or refu when called for. shall lx* fined not t .11 XIII of the Act shall lie fin- f Any person violati to exceed fOOor imprisoned not en To Whom Violations Must 1h- Ke| All violations of the Act must Lalior and the County Attorney. Superintendents of Schools Must 5 ported to the ( 'mini! lend Lists &gt;r the school directors of any vi itween the first and tenth of town, or county, shall transmit bt month to the office of the State Commissioner of Lalioi a list of the names of the children to whom certificates Inn Certificates. Blank Forms, etc , Furnished by; All certificates, hlank forms, copMn of the law. etc will nefamiahed h » \\ hiH*Vf r t*iii ploys u &lt;*iiil(t m mployment certificates in viol hI 110. •eding in day rted : The superintendent of icho </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 rION OF ATTORNEY GENERAL ON NEBRASKA CHILD LABOR LAW Replying to ;i request from County Attorney .lames P. Knglish of Itougla- County, for an opinion oa the new law gmilliag the employment • if rhilil Wnr, the Attorney (leneral (if Nebraska prepared tho followin Lincoln, Xelir.. Jnlv 6. IW Jamet. P. fogiiah. Eeq County Attorney of Doaglaa County Omaha. Nebr. Bhave the honor to aeknowlc ]it of your lettt-r t&gt;f .In ittinjf the follow il reqaestinK an opinion thereon: KOm a ihihl nmlt-r the wge &lt;if fourte.i lawfully einjili work in Imsiui-ss institutions or to awful ■ the kiniK -i&gt;»natcd in BMtitMl 1. House K jll '.I. Chapter iWi. Session Laws is follow year of age shall lie employed, pe rk in. or in connection with, an -i-ment. &lt;ir any place wke tutioi ililishment, lx&gt;w ir freight elevator, factory or worksho] .i mnrnici r or driver therefor, within this state, shall l&gt;e unlawful for n.firui or corporation to einpli pf age in any Imsn -er (luring the hours when the public schools of th -hip village or city in which the child A maximum i&gt;enalty of |M.M is provided for in the act for violation Moll. This law is [irohiliitive and restrictive. Direful examination of the entire act, consisting of fourteen us. it la in&gt; opinion that a child under the age of fourteen years may not be lawfully employed, iierinitted or suffered to work in, or in connec with "any theater, concer, hall, or place of amusement, or any place ling liqnon are sold. or in any mercantile institution, store, office, hotel, laundry, manufacturing establishment, bowling-allay, pas (■eager or freight elevator, factory or workshop. or at a messenger or driver r. within this state K-iuh employment ot a child undei fourteen years of .,. liaa placed an alisolute prohibition, either during hourvur at a, me. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 The second sentence of the section above set oat should be read and construed in connection with section 13 of the act. Section 13 provides as follows : "No child under the age of sixteen years shall be employed in any work which by reason of the nature of the work, or place of performance, is dangerous to life or limb or in which its health may be injured or its morals may be depraved. Any parent, guardian, or other person, who. having under his run trol any child, causes or permits said child to work or be employed in violation of this section shall be guilty of a mis demeanor and upon conviction shall be lined not more than Fifty Dollars ($50. 00). or be imprisoned not exceeding ten days When so read and construed it is my judgment that the law further prohibits the employment of any child under fourteen years of age n business or service whatever during the hours when public schools of the town, township, village. or cities in which the child resides are in session A child under the age of fourteen years, however, may be lawfully em - ployed to perform services other than those denned in the first sentence of section 1, when the nature of the work, or the place of performance, i - dangerous to life or limb, or in which his health may not be injured or his morals depraved, provided the time of employment does not conflict with school hours when school is in session. To summarize: 1. A child under the age of fourteen years may not be employed or suffered to work in, or in connection with any theater. concert hall, or place of amusement, or any place where intoxicating liquors are sold, or in any mercantile institution, store, office, hotel, laundry, manufacturing estab - lishment, bowling-alley. iiassenger or freight elevator, factory or work - or as a messenger or driver therefor, or in any other business or s. whatever during the hours when the public schools of its residence are in session, or employed in any work which by reason of the nature of the work, or place of performance, is dangerous to life or limb, or in which, his health may be injured or his morals depraved. 2. Any child under the age of fourteen years may be lawfully em ployed to perform services not especially prohibited as above set forth when the time of such employment does not conflict with school hours. Very respectfully. WILLIAM T. THOMPSON, Attorney General. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 rECTORY OF MANUFACTURING ESTABLISHMENTS IN NEBRASKA ARRANGED BY SPECIFIED INDUSTRIES AGRICULTURAL IMPLEMENTS Barker Manuf.i David City. Brown Bm- a I Fremont ■ ntir Maimfai turn | Clay &lt; 'enter Emcmii Manufacturing Co iha (121 Omaha (1213 Leavenworth Street ARTIFICIAL STONE. CONCRETE BLOCKS, ETC Norfolk. Bethany Beaver &lt; Sty University Placx Byron Qraad Uaad Papillion. Omaha fit-It Line Central &lt; 'itv S (1 uthOmal McCook. r Fairbury Hooper. Danm DeWitt Lincoln Hasii Kim ( Norfolk. Beatrice Util Clouil Lincoln (Corner l'.tth Fremont Vine and Fremont Pawn H.-.1 Cl.m.l. Fairbury. Norfolk. HambokU aul. &lt; 'ambridK 1 Amerine h Bateman, Kch ! Beaver City Cement Brick 0 Hollow \\;.l! I GflBMnt Hl&lt;M*k RmMir \ Cement MaeMaery \ Bapply O ■;il City Cnii-nt Warki I) M A H.i-li M Works sr. Williani trical Concrete I Hydraulic B tinhind' m, Walter F tnnt Artificial Stm ■ Fuller &amp; Fr.inkentield n. K (iohler. William ■V .1 (irutwr. Andrew H.ath Stone Co </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 ) St Eiron Hydraulic Stone ( tier Bros Hebron Lincoln Helling ft Son (&lt; Hollingsworth (iranil Island. Beat! Klow Wall ft Concrete Brick ( il Stone ( So Bloomington. David City. Johnson. tnson Stone Co es &amp; Crawmer Hartley Kearney Artificial Stone ( Kirt.y, T. .1 Kearney. ( Ireaaan. Lincoln. Lincoln Artificial Stone ft Til &lt; Lincoln Stone &amp; Supply O Ladwift Al Lincoln (Corner lHth and Y Arlington Lynch ( Vmcnt Block O Mathi'wson Stone ( 'i&gt; Lynch David City ( 'arletoo Bier. J. W ler, K. B Harwell Stanton Milligan Ord Miller A- Robinnon Milligan Cement Block A: Bricl &lt; W. H era.ska HolUnv WiUKVC.m raska Stone ( o ( Kearney Omaha. (5th and Jones Went 1'oint Neligh, W. T. S North Bend Cement Work- Oakland Cement Stone Mfg. Co Old Reliable Cement Stone Co Omaha Cement. Stone* BricK Iff Omaha Concrete Stone Co North Bend &lt; Ink I and Fremont i Omaha (17th ft Cuining) Omaha ('.'Sth Av. and Boyd I Ircliatil ( Orci Cement Works Owens Concrete Host I Perrv &amp; Bee Co Omaha Fairburj Erson Broj t. E. .1 1. Ezra K Omaha ( IBIS Burt) Red cloud Hardy Alliance Norfolk Hurwell Rengler &amp; Kaymond Ke&gt; nolds &amp; King Ele ft ( 'ottin ft Mill, lerford ft Let Lexington Beatrice Evving ( 'oliimhus York &gt;.ick. .1. K Smith. K. B Lexington Ker Mira.le. Block ( ban it Konev Spencer (irand Nland Stn.h. Alfretl Hooper ■ ior Cement ( '&lt;■ Tapp Construction C Superior Omaha ville Blk 1 ) </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Thompson, D ... Cairo Western Stone Works. Western \\ liber Stone Works Wilber Wymore Concrete Co Wymore York Hydraulic Stone Co York AWNINGS, TENTS, ETC Crawford, R. T York Lincoln Tent &amp; Awning Co Lincoln (1024 P) Little. Adelbert D Lincoln (824 P) Nebraska Tent and Awning Co Omaha (803 No. 20th St. ) Omaha Tent and Awning Co Rogers Tent and Awning Co Wolf Brother-, A On Omaha (1023 Harney) Fremont Omaha (70S So. 16th) SAGS AND BAGGING Bern is Omaha Bag Co Lincoln Paper &lt; Omaha Lincoln (1315 P St. ) Lincoln (109 N. !tth St Omaha &lt; 1212 Douglas) Nebraska Paper and Bag Co Omaha Pai&gt;er Bag .Mfg. Co BAKING POWDkR YEAST, EXTRACTS, ETC Omaha (10th and Farnam Omaha (Ml fuming) Omaha 1 102\! Douglas) r Brothers Company r. G H Chase &amp; Co (E. M Nt-lira&gt;ka City tcoln CuSw &amp; Spice Mills Time Yaaal Oto Lincoln (20H So. 9th) Omaha (4301 No. 38th) Omaha (10th and Jones) Omaha (802 So. 10th) i'axtoii A Gallagher Smith Kxtract &amp; Hy. BALE TIES AND BALING WIRE Oman* Bale Tj Kumbel &amp; Son (R) Omaha (132 Nicholas) Omaha (1124 N. 14th) BARBER SUPPLIES Melchoir. Hugo Omaha (1113 Farnam) Omaha (1406 Howard) Omaha (151C Dodge) Phillips Medical Co land. A. L BARRELS-SEE "COOPERAGE" BELTS Hahn- Butler Co Lincoln (1115 O) </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 BOILER COMPOUND Mallory &amp; Co Omaha («SU No. 17th) Omaha (MM No Mtkj Omaha (2.V&gt;2 ('timing ) Nebraska Boiler Compound ('&lt; Sterling Boiler Compound Co BIRD AND FISH FOOD Oeisler, Max Omaha (308 Xo. ltith BOOTS AND SHOES Kirk.-n.lull &amp; ( Lincoln leather OB Lutz &amp; Co. (C. A. ) Recent Shot- Mfg. ( Omaha (411 So 10th Lincoln (1024 F) ( 'oluinhiis Lincoln (Hth and P BOTTLED GOODS SEE MINERAL WATER, POP, ETC. BOXES Eggera-O'Flyng Co Omaha 1 142;! Leavenwortb (irand Island Grand Island Cigar Box Factory Lincoln Pa]«r Box Co Lincoln [ISM Oi Omaha Box Co Omaha (21 and Av. H. K. Om Omaha (cor I^avrnworth and Omaha (1W3 St. Mary's Av.' | Omaha (HM No, 91 Eia Paper Box ( Box Factory t. tL A ... BREAD AND OTHER BAKERY PRODUCTS AbleidinK^r. .1. B Ahlrep, George Albion Steam Bakery Altschuler, Charles Armstrong. Mrs Jennie Baehr. Henry M ail i s&lt; &gt;n Plattsmouth Albion Tekamah North Platte Wisner Kberd. Herman Rs. N Talmage Fullerton Wahoo Bmhde, John O Bahr, L. F David City Bakke, A Omaha (HIT So. 6th) Omaha ( 1520 Farnam ) Omah., J4th) Burwvll Bald u IT. \V S Bantin, Frederic H Barker &amp; Co. (A) Bease. William Red Cloud Hampton O Neill Eett, Mrs. (i \\ ley, Mrs. C. H eron. Mrs. L. J rs, William Fai rbury Blair Blanchard. George H Lincoln (1531 O) </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 II Bradehoft, John Breeden, I Omaha (1606 X. 24th j Fairmont Breitling &amp; Co (E. S . ) Fremont Ashland Bockmaster, C. A Bustard. Frank J Butts. E. L Lincoln (3049 O Cambridge Campbell, Charles Capel &amp; Etling Capte. A Omaha (716 N. 16th) Alma Omaha Carlson, C. R Omaha (2406 Cuming Beatr Chamberlain &amp; Co. (D A. ) Chappell, A. O Hartington Christensen. Christian Christensen, .1 I Omaha (HOB ('tuning Omaha Clark, 0 I Fairbury Lvnch Claaeman Brothers . Clement*. £. S Coberly &amp; Alfurdi Coffland, Harley College View Bakery Connecticut Pi' Conner V. E (iiiioa Fairbury Colle^ i Omaha (*»•» !S. 20th PUh City Cook Brothers Corder, J f Coverdale. F H M(H Lexington Nebraska City (•rand Island ( 'hadron Culbertson, Edward Danley, W A Douglaw, Mrs I. B Bmmw, W. 1- Omaha (1WW Howard) Omaha (UN Vinton St Fullerton Erickson, A Erikson. P« i Ewing, Mrs. Addie Ewing, J Omaha (1988 Clark) Omaha (1204 N. 24th Niolirara Falkenbnrg, H. S Fead. Estella York Omaha (2202 Farnam Pawnee City Fredericks. J. A Ferry, Mrs. D W Fleck, Joseph Talmage South Omaha (156 &amp; Lincoln (1307 O) York ( olumlius Oavid City Kails City Lincoln (912 P Broken Bow Geistlinger Gillings, William Gray. Mrs. George, Sr Greater America Bakery Greenberg &amp; Wiseman Bloom Held Omaha (KOH No l«th Omaha (1310 Dodge) Folaom Bak.-r &gt; &gt; '&lt; &gt; Funnan, W. R Uaaeman. E. W Gates. O W Oebling, J. P </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 Greisel Bakery Co Haith A. F. I'nivernity Place Tecum-sen Hale &amp; Co. (J. H Harrison. Q. I' Omaha (2421 Grant) Ashland Etwell, J. « l«er &amp; Tt-lK) ptman. (ii-ors en. W L Haatinga Nebraska City South Omaha (41K X. 26th) Omaha ! 4HO-J fuming) Plamview Omaha (3418 B. IWth load Herlierger. Joseph Herger, C. L Eman. Mtn Ant man (' Erege Bakery •tt. Mrs W K ey's Bakery Homer, W M Hummel A I Hyatt. (J W i; Imlay. .1. M Omaha (8180 An. Stanton Eder, .1. H William ek. V (Jrand Island Spen. • .lohnson, .1. N ■luhnsun \- Ott&gt; Jones. Charles ( Omaha (Ml So lHth) ( &gt;aklaml Pawnee City Plainview JJ£ ColuinliiiK Havelm-k Ensen, J. P vy. V. A It Bros South Omaha (2411 X) South Omaha (2tt &amp; Z) Omaha ( 11M So. 17th) Norfolk Kaufman. E. B Kearns, Mary Ellen Keefe, C. A Spiildin^ York Keller Bros South Omaha («H N. 24th) St. Paul Omaha \ Uti Williams) Scribner -ka City Hamholdt West Point Omaha (4016 Hamilton) Omaha (3811 Spaulding) Omaha (2301 Leaven worth) Fremont tkins &amp; Jewell ton, K. C IMattMnouth Omaha 14IW S. lHth Hoojkt HoldrvR* Flort'iH't" Kean Beatrice Omaha (1406 Dougla-s) Randolph Killian. Mrs .1 A Kirchner, R J Kiteerow. H Krasny. Frank Krepela, Charles Kretsachmar, F. H Kruse, John Kuenne, U I </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Kurtz &amp; Karnum Lakey. W Randolph O .Will L*nderman .1 P St. Mwii Sterling Langford. S \ Larkin- K A |y.il«.UI. William Lenhart K A ft KiiKli&gt;h Loesrh. John Milford Concord Nebraska City Omaha I M24 X 16th) Omaha (MOt No. 24th Norfolk Omal. 18th McCook burg, John Cedar Bluffs &lt; 'entral ( 'ity Kails City I X lough. T. H Beat ritf Blair Burtie. Mr* ste&lt;lt .1. A Bloomfield KN I) . T 8 South Omaha (4H N -Mth Kullerton South Omaha | MM N North Platte Martin. A B Kavcnna nowics, William MauUr. .lnM&gt;ph South Omaha (61o N Anslev Smith Beaver City W a hoi i Beatrice Omali. -&gt;ttth Auburn Miles. William I) Beatriiv Kigali. Thomaa F ■r. On Omaha | 1H« N. 24th B.irwtll iidh Bakery Ord Sanitarium Pood Oo Nelson. Hn C K Lincoln Belden Nelson. 1'iilir N.«.-ll. N .1 Omaha i Illli N. 24th North Bend X. « Nork Bakery NielHon. Anton Nielsen. Nicholas Nurnlier K . E Hildreth I'lattMiiouth ( hnaha ( 1»OT Cuming Omaha (1711 Vinton) Plainview Crete riner F B Alliance (ienua O Daniel- &amp; Kilton Ota.. A E.i ntr. Rohan 0f, .l«hn .1 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 11 Omaha 24th and Hamiltc Seward Alliaiu Bine Hill Schoyler V W I ■il, .luhn I'urdie it Pone way - W. B W^st F'.iint Harvard fern Raanmaao, Henry \iina Raven Omaha 8124 LeaTenworth Tilden Omaha i l.'iiNi N. 18th Craig Rhoadn Hanson Woman \ i; Omaha 1916 No. 24th Lincoln ISO s... l«th) Omaha 'J«2i) Karnam I Omaha .'Ti'l Coning I'lattsmonth Omaha l*H Schayler teder i!k Arnold Schnier. Charlt-s Behrqn*, Mrs H A S&lt;humacher. Frank Schunk. Nicholas Wak.htld Humphrey Kenesaw Krienil Omaha 118 No. 11th Howell Soil William I" C Spiri. Joseph South Omaha (*W N 2tith Hold 1 1 ulienz. H Strong Brothers SundKren A (i Mitti-rle. .laeoli n, A. E Tocanueh (leneva ' Omaha llil'.t No. 24th Omaha 720 S. 28th i Wisner Burwell SwoUxla. Adolph Thomas. E F Omaha Hith A Dod^e Hebron Newman i \\ illiam I'anl.-y. H. P. ft K H Puck * s,,,, r H. ) I'rank .1 E.I. K f't Bakery liiu-r. M. .1 i-h. W BloomiiiKtoM Lincoln -.'84 Su 11th WihxI Kiver &lt; I &gt;1 11I11 1 111 Olll;lli;i ( hrerton Wilher Koliv. O. E Bra. &amp; Lut* nMMM A /.. H M W Hooper Bak. Knli;irtl&gt;. I S K.ikusfk. y », Mrs. M Srhiappaiussf, John Hchoafaoe, Hans Seifaert. F K Wall </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Thompson. -Mrs. Eliz ■ ft Baldric Omaha (2»H Farnair Grand Island tWf A Baird w s Albion Crmwford Trans Mississiji] ii Bakery I'nion Bakery Omaha 1404 X. &gt;40 IfoCook Lam Baking Co ide. EaiAl .1 Omaha MM X. 30th Dakota City t Patten. C I k, Anton Hasting Omaha | 12 Bo. 18th Wil&gt;«er Vaaek, B. .1 Vodrie (W. D. ) and VodrU Anton Stella Oiuuha r,M&gt;th and Farnam ('olnmlius H. I) Nelson Pierce Wagner, Martin Wagner. Otto C Omaha (1701 L«'a\ en worth Hickman tvoord.B ren. V E Wymore Et. Mr&gt; Emniartlla tiern. .lohn Omal bennaa Av Omaha (2908 N 24th) Enhold &amp; CalbertBoa rtman Clrand Island Omaha :\2 N. ltith Sutton Wieden Wiwler, (ins Lincoln (401 So. 11th -ihek Brii I ruff. Roliert H Omaha (17SS I^ea\ en worth Fremont Blue Spring Hastings Yelinek, Joweph Omai - 13th Omaha I 150B S. WHk Omaha 24.iL' S. tith t merman. All&gt;ert ;. A BRICK Alliance Prewaed Brick U Anderson. Andrew Alliance Oakland Aurora Brick Works Bayer. Carl Aurora Hooper Beagle. A. F Falls City Beatrice Hydraulic Cement &amp; Brick Works Beat rice Benzien. Charles F Berglund A StromsliuiK Bickel. .1. K -ka City Bloomtield fclllHeld Brick and Tile C. Ireaa, C. C Emerson Stroll] &amp; Pel lhall &amp; Son Stromsliurg Tekamah </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 Broghamer &amp; Pitman Brenton. T. H Chadron N'aligh Brinkman. Fred Arlington Brodhun it Maineday Brukner. .1. (' Buhk, Henry Kt* Brick Manufacturing O II. W. H Darid City Deshler Cannon, E. .1 Corneer Bros Omaha. M and B. &lt;&amp;- M. K. K Table K.K-k Cotton Brick ( IVKiM-k. Benjamin WvilKllf Crete Uh.KiKf. August Dhooge, Henry D.Witt Aliniiia WollKUh (ierinj? Qnide Kwk Fairbory Atlianct' Fremont Funk i{O\v &amp; Dye .i a s.m. r. p am. William H ier &amp; Sroboda mond it' Mathenv ion Brick Yards Randolph Shubert Freun &gt;nt Fremont Hastings Kearney Milkman Hart man &amp; Sloggett led Brick ('( Hibliard Brick Oo Mink ft Morrison HiKlkinson. William Hollister. Allen H Horrum. W. H Heaver City Waterloo Auburn Humlxjldt Brick C( Hunziker, S Humboldt Sutton .John York Jackson iSt Meenson Johnson. Morten Ky. William Nichols Co BCarl F er Co.. A Dodge Ravenna Bmbmt Hooper Iiver. (iiliiion K irhid.' ft Uo, .lolni K y. Ckariai Co.. .Inhn Eury Brick C Uecirgf M '. August Lbrant Bms Brick mnd Improrement Co Genoa (Jen-eke. Herman Norfolk Ft. Culhoun Peru Oimiha. K12 Paxton Blk Ed#ar Old Ostvolu Phelps ArapahiH' ( oiumhuH Madison * i«-n«'\ ,i </seg>
            <seg id="p044">* 44 \ K.m.I (&gt; ) X h Ave Aurora Ii tinlirink. .1. H ich. Frank M iimIii Brick Wurha i'&lt;«ik Brick MTorha DunaM ft McGintie i \Y Doniphan Beatrice South Omaha. ■■&gt;* and Humphrey Lincoln. 1 mil.- \\ McCVmk NVIiKh Ni'liffli t\'un(l«'i|MHi] ill. .1. E Kairliiiiv Millilrll Minden Krick RTotfa Piaturaoath N.hi:isku t ' i 1 \ Poaca m. John P. and I) .1 Neville .lame.* I. 11. ■In.., K Brick and Till- ('&lt; m-n Br Niobium l,&lt;iu]i Cily Omaha i Brick ( V Omaha Hynlaulir Pmbu Brick O ms Brick Yanl- Omaha MR S liitli Parker .1 M Superior Hasting Lynch Polenske Hi Polenske. S.-hellak * ('. Kaffertv A Kaffertv Kh&lt;xin&gt; Jan Kichter .Inhn irl Schmidt. Lavia Schmidt Mantis Blair Blair Blair Millard (irand Island. K. K 1 WahiMi tiliii. r Brick Manufacturing C rUihn. .l.ihn K Scribner Wayne Kith Brick &lt; . ith. .1 Kre.1 Omaha, tl and W.miIw -! and Lake Brick Manufacturing O N-ls,,n Stan tun Hart instill Ord Talile Kink Superior r'ullertmi Bpaldian Waaau Krick Manufacturing ('&lt; k Vardii Shubeii William II Street ft l.aun • ht &amp; (irulier K.H-k da] ! () </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 Northman. William Yankee Hill Brick Co Voting Building Snpph ( York Brick and Til. Bmnham Lincoln. I York BRISTLES Suuili Omal BROOMS Urand Islai Pl'lldlT Bloomin|rto Beat i \tt Bnioni Kactorv &lt;iallaher it Canninghan (iiKHlman Broooa Sh«i]i no'l Broom Factory Hamilton. L. M Lincoln, &lt;2» N Ti-ciiiiisih 12th Kranklin. R. I Pawnee City HaHtinga &gt;. \. Muukii Hill. \V. B Haiti iij; OBf Ideal Manufaiturinff &lt; ( it-ori't' W Urand Island B*- BrcMjm and D«atar ( w. B. t Lincoln. Penitei Pair bury tiai y KeVial. .lam Flattsmonth Seward K-i. David iid. A -Malm BUGGY TOP EYELETS Norfolk tern Brick C.» Hart] ern Brick Mitiiiifai-tiiriiiK C5o Omaha. S W. Had and I". I' K. K Western Gompoiito Brick Omaha. i:v.m Phumi Wmrt Point Milling Oo West I'ninl Winsiile Brick Yard \\ iii^i.le W.khI Bros Aurora Worthman. William Sewanl A (i:il E' BlCM' ?r. H. A O«otga K er &amp; Seifert Iiderwind. Jhm Omaha. I'M* So. -.'Nth. », 0. II Adams T. 1-.. ami M.tz .1 V S.-wanl K)ii. Fr«l S Omaha. ISth and FaciH r &amp; Son.C K N'ebrwka City sen Bms Omaha. ]:(17 Chka«o 1. Henry Fremont BUTTER </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 1 1 Arlington &lt; reamery Beatn&lt; •&lt;- ( 'reame ry O ■ r. William tmry &lt; Biiulilt-r ("ream- Arlington Lincoln. 7th anil I' Blue Hill Minden Kontanelle Carleton Colombo* Ht-ml- Xeligh Kairti.ld h .11 1 mi Hit Creamery (\ Omaha. Ini ; How Kiemont v Oermmntuwn Frenioiit Ooliunboa Arclier Ha^'l &amp; Co Paol TompUa iig Cruan Hartwell. A. F Hold 1 nery KirMlihrann &amp; Omaha, 808 Harney Inavale Holdnge Omaha. IM Howard Dniiian LiMp l'latte \';dl LyonH ( reainery ( lo Lyons niery Amelia Ealiolm Cooiierative ( 'ream artinslmrg &lt; reamer) idhind Creamery Co ii. Mulcolm Martinsbarg (irand Island Memphis r\ A Ponca Beatric Kavenna m. K F. D. N"&lt; St. Paul Omaha. li«17 Howard BUTTONS K Thf Omaha, l.'ll So. 18tl CABINET MAKERS ry O boa Klkhom Valley Creamery ('&lt; Kairrield Creamery Oo mtown &lt; '•ooperativ* &lt; Inm (tolden K&lt;h1 Creamery (&gt;o e Spring &lt;'ieam&lt;;r\ City i ma ClWM umI Pmaiiiwij Association Ked Cloud \\ i Ilium Miailow limv Kivert uncrv Kiverton .rl Craton, K. F &gt;t 1'anl Cn Schuyler f'nwiiwji On lyler C. W «d P SiruiiDiburir </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 BY CANNED FRUITS, VEGETABLES AND PRESERVES Eitie Canning t i irn Canning Co la Canning Co r Canning ( 'o Fremont Auburn Barada Edgar Grand Island Causing Co aiming Factory Grand Ealaad Hasting! Langs Canning and Preserving O Martin &amp; Nurse Beatrici Blair Nebraska City Benson, K. F. D. St. Paul CAR AND GENERAL SHOP CONSTRUCTION AND REPAIRS STEAM RAILROAD COMPANIES IM R. R. Co M. K. R Co M. K. K. Co M. K. K. Co M. K. K. Co M. K. R. Co M. R. R Co M. R. R. Co M. R. R. Oo M. R. R Co M. R. R. Oo M. R. R. Co M. R. R Co M. R. R. Oo Alliance Aurora (iilison Hastings Havelock tioldrege Lincoln McCook Nebraska City Oxford Plattsinonth kavenna Seneca Wyni' Chadron Fremont Hastings Lincoln Long Pine Norfolk igo &amp; Northwestern R. R igo &amp; Northwestem R. R ( hii-ago It Northwestern R. R tgo &amp; Northwestern R. R igo ft Northwestern R. R Igo &amp; Northwestern R. R igo &amp;• Northwestern R. R ago A Northwestern R. R Missouri Pacific R. R. Co ( )akilali South Omaha Lincoln Union Pacific R. R. O I'nion Pacific R. R. ('&lt; Union Pacific R. R. Ct I'nion Pacific R. R. Co Union Pacific R. R. C&lt; Union Pacific R. R. Oo Union Pacific R. R. C&lt;i Beatrice ( 'olumbu (Iranil Island Kearney North Platte Omaha Sidney Otoe Preserving Oo Solomon. E. (•., Si. F'aul running O </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 CARPETS AND RUGS Bi'.'t .mil Koa Factory it Kqx ami Ten- All iii in Beatric i hi- ting t &lt; iiluinl'ii i Air House &lt; 'leaning Nu. 1 Wayne eik ci I r\\\ n Kocln : ( huaha Lincoln Kuk Facti Miller. \ii ' Lincoln. % Lincoln. Nebraska &lt; ir\ ■ ity U\i^' Winks ( hnaha Kuk ( '" Omaha. 1321 l.ravoiu Omaha. 1443 So. Hi I'ol.-ai Hasting Richards A. l&gt; CARRIAGE TOPS AND CUSHIONS Omuhii CARRIAGES AND WAGONS Lincoln, lii-.'u M Wakel.eld A mil r- in Mi Haul ( AnaatruOK. N \\ William Omaha. 1115 \ Kniinint ( 'amp Daniel \\ &lt; 'ainp. Jan Kreiuoi Omaha, Til Si, 1 4th Bancroft Sterling Mk .1 l» - Matthew I - Omaha OarriaKf Top i'&lt; .1 c Omaha. MM Karnaii Omaha. SIM Cumini KreinuJlt • . ler I'feiffi r. William Knmaii. Chartaa .1 Omaha. -'?th ami Leaven wortt Lincoln. :il!i So. I lth Omaha 14d'.i Dodgi Omaha. Hth &amp; Nichola fop O a &lt; 'hriwl iiiiiwii ~&gt;m. I. &lt;) &lt; linalia. 1 I |l Lincoln, •"&gt;:(-' So. xt Lincoln, 842 8a 10 Oliialin i ill Dnunmuml &lt; 'an Dnni.hv. R. K Krwmont ( \i Hanv .i a w South Omaha 7K N&lt; Bethany s, Matthew K Lincoln, Jin No l.'th h Aiitiiinnliilr 4 &gt;inuliu It* 80. Mth (ferfy, Fn Omaliii. I21S Lcavcnwurth .!. \\ trice Murphy. Andre* A - Onuihu. 1410 .l;u-K- Vntun K Havelook </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 Omaha Casket ( iimii Furniture &amp; Com'ii Co Lincoln. IHM L r'aultl&lt; ffenm-tt Dip &lt; prise Cattle Dij .1. L. ami W. H Harlnne ChMM &lt; to Jenny Bra CHEMICALS SEE PATENT MEDICINES, CHEMICALS FOOD." STOCK CIDER • lit Cider ( Fremont Nehaw k; CIGARS \ustin 1 Blue Spring] Scribner BbriHtM iini'k. John St. Haul York Frank B.( kinan. Joaepfa Bennett. .1 Omaha. lWt Kaiinan McCook Earn. Frwl in, Barman ■i up. William .lanu's H Omaha, 183H X 22nd Omaha, MM Patrick Avenue Omaha 1832 St. Marys Avuuut! South Omaha. 230U S Nebraska &lt; 'ity Flattsniouth (iiaiul Island Fremoat H .1 Kmeyer. .1. \V It A U Bn-it.-nd.-lil. H.nry (1 Kroki-n How Cinar ( '. Boaehenstein, Louis Urand [aland Tililrn. Numum F York Up- To- Data Wagoa A GMiiage Mfe. KalN Citj Ml &amp; Sun. I.suiu Broken Bow Allian Kis, Rich ha, II. •my ion. ('. B </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 J» Avi-nn Fullerton Dodge Central City Linwood WilU-r Omaha rg. N H I&lt; Lincoln. AX&gt; No. '.'tl llnnili.iMt pp \- Mel. u*. William C Cullen A- L/xk Sterling Fairbury Beatrice Wayne Dammeyer. William r Cigar F Dellecker. OK Minden Omaha. l:«M Karnan Central Citv IJeKD. l\ . It ..in Un Doenges, Conrad Omaha, 1104 So. UNd Papillion Dohn «. fffnl Henry FJcatric Omaha. VM&gt;. 80. littl Omaha, 1!I4(I Vinton Howella Leijfh Strrlinj; Briatow AaUand Fremont Wvmorc Ashhuul Fullerton ■tad, William William :. Phillip W Forman, A. .1 Fox. Luther Fuller. W H Fullerton Cigar ( o Eith. .1 1. William ham. C H ■ Superior Pooca Omaha. 1819 St. Mar Omaha (ireen. T L (iregg. i&gt;. K Qraad Harvard Haml&gt;aiher. Frederick Hammon. .Tameh .1 Omaha. 3"i24 Ameo Randolph Hardy CiK Harm. A Har.lv Omaha. ■-'■-Ml O Omaha Harm. Nellie Harrow. R. W Bart, John H Hart, W K Nebraska City Hastings MeCook Schnyler HastingK Omaha. I2U4 So. tl Aulmrn Waho. Cannon. H. K Car]" Orny. Joseph Charvat. Frank Harak Bajtfagi ( i^ui ( Hayduk. John K. Kdwanl </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 jrth Avenue Fremont Omalia. 1304 Douglas Lincoln. 139 So. 10 (ieileVU Herminghaus &amp; Hellwi Hem. George A Heyu. Mm, S Hobbs Bros Omaha. 1S3M Leavenwi Pawnee City Hornyak. Qoatav A • ttler. John B Hatching- Johnsoii. Alfred Johnson, (ieor^ Johnenn, H. E Nebraska City Uloomfield Butte Oakland Omaha »11 N VVausa E-&lt;uren ensky. Charles ely. Rol»ert Omaha. I-'. Clark- Halls City Kanka &amp; I'lich Kaxseliaujn Fn-d KawieKiuiii. William Kaufman. Kie&lt;l I'lattsmouth Stan ton Kninonl Lanrel Kearney Kcarnrv KeUey, Loui: K.-nt H. A Lincoln, I Humphrey h A- ( 'o. Henry er &amp; Co Hastings Columliii' Tekamah Seward King, Howard Kleiu-k. Phillip. .Ir K.xh. Clans Nebraska City Koop, Charles C .Omalia. 1710 Vinton South Omaha. 1711 P Scribnar Knunshsvh Kurs)*'. Frit/ Kuwitzky. Horace Kuwitzky. Jonph l^iiina. Joseph l«iitner Barbx&gt;ra O Uiurson. Louis C Jacob Nebraska City Omaha. Id: Falls City KiVhetston- - ', Oliver HuiulKildt Liljerty Eirren, Ulysses nnell. H. L ussun, H. F er, Louis Hiimlxildt Wilber Chad ran Arlington David City Paul Miller &amp; Konnovsky Miratsky. Thomas Mitchell. J. W Omaha, Iit44 So. 12 Hebron Xloeller, P. (4 Hein ft Co., Mwwd H Hene ft I to Omaha. B150 Ames Avenue Sihuylfi South Omaha. 122 No IMk Weeping Water Omaha, li </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 u\ - Avinii ■i«al. Lou iHrtner nan. 1&gt;iui- Patterson Cigar Fuctc Millard Lincoln. I Faiilmi v iry (leneva Omaha. 1818 II I'lattMiioinli K-'ph rliertf. .lull us . John )( XebraMka &lt; it\ Ejn. Hlllil If. K il Bros Omaba. taw Pierce ,-ka City Wilier ■I Pt«k I 1'ulee, Th' l'\intan C'iK«r &lt; S Keka Conrad C Kenc. John I'lattMiiouth Milligan (irand Island '.&gt;int () NeiU Oman., UiM Point Keuichek. Anna a h Horn Cigar Rtm, Wali' Blair (Irand 1-land Teoun K. Samuel 1) « HiMinan A South Omaha Sujierior Fremont BaauBons &amp; Packard •ton, Frank Lincoln IS8 No. 1 .' Omaha. 1711 8t Ma Broken Bow Ker. William B Stanton Columhu 8chuatag. E - SchnialzrieB, J. F s.huit/. a o Omaha. MIS Cumin North Ptstte Sekomacher. J ,,,,,, J. B flunlwifir in 1 William iir. .lame*, I Oinaha. lilt 1) (Jranil bfawd I'lattMiiouth l'a« nee City lladii Havelock York Blair Omaha. 122&lt;&gt; Arclur Lincoln. 9i4 S IVllUl'l Sharka .John Sink »V Bl(«mi Cigar O - mi. Him \ 8pi»*.. Han Speer. &lt; 'lau&lt;l • • .l;UUi» M H. W Bi;i\it City H-i-t ings </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 EX Kldard. .Joseph II tych. John F Tamme. F Teske. (iustav Trim]*-. Fred Triska, Anton tier, I. 8 Towns. William Omaha. tt*4 So Hi • &gt;maha 4.' -It! Fariium Columlms Underwood Bros, cigar &lt; Irlian. Anna I'rhan. Aiitnne Mrs Louise Voight, .1. B H .1 Wagner, (ieorgf WiU-r. William I. (Jodfred Wei rick ('igar O Omaha, MM I^eaven worth I'luttsmouth Hooper Grand Island Omaha. 2123 Seward Norfolk Wilde, Albert Eenberg. Peter .1 ■ina«ler. Hennan ruff, W. I) Wright. C Wurl Bros Wvatt &amp; Gray Zieeche K. M Norfolk Pierce Zimrnan Bros CIGAR BOXES SEE "BOXES.' CLOTHING SEE "OVERALLS, SHIRTS, SKIRTS, ETC COFFEE, SPICES, ETC. SEE 'BAKING POWDER, YEAST TRACTS, ETC COLLARS AND CUFFS Capital City Collar* Cuff Factory Lincoln, ,&gt;:r&gt;l O CONCRETE BLOCKS SEE "ARTIFICIAL STONE CONFECTIONERY Omaha. 1114 Farnain Omaha. ;H14 (;• Fullerton St. 1'anl Madison I'olnmliu.* Aurora Btuitric Prague Oinalut. I«li3 No. &gt;4 (iraml Island Grand Islam) Bridgeix&gt;rt Lincoli Lincoln. Wi'.i () Lincoln Hi.") ,) AshlunU llUIIllKlldt Plattsmouth Beatrice Omaha. 203 So. II </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Avenu&lt; Brenker Bros Beatrice Colombo. Emanuel Debarbieri. Louis DlUbm Candv Co Omaha. JM So. It Omaha. 504 So. IS Omaha. 508 So. H Omaha, 151N Douglas Hastings D&gt;ball Catherine &amp; H. W Fisber A- Smith Co (iillan &amp; Boney Lincoln. 2OH No. n Ormnd Island Candy Kitchen Grand lslund Haag. A. L York Lincoln Candv Kitchen Maxwell Co Lincoln. 14th and (&gt; Lincoln. 1426 O Ben Company. D. J a Candy Co Omaha. 1202 Howard Omaha, 218 So. IS Pmm&gt;. \\ .1 Beatrice Petereen Christian P Voegele &amp; Dinning Whalen. H Lincoln IWI Wood Omaha. ISM tamm Wayne COOPERAGE Crete Batter Tul&gt; Co ( 'uininiiiK- .l.inieH O'Brien &amp; Vaughn Omaha Cooperage Co VogeliiiiiiK A' Schiirinaii F H Crete Omuhu. 2101 Boulevard Nelmukit City South Omaha 'M\ and I Fremont Omuhu. MM Di.ukI.is \\ih«1.ii Package Mfg. &lt;'.. Omaha. Mth and Walnut COPPER CABLE Shinn W. C Lincoln. 322 So. 11 COPPERSMITH GOODS Kacwuier Reinold Omah;. CORNICES mice WOrks B.iornfton &amp; Hiiiis Beatrice Omaha. 214 No. U Omaha. 1722 St. Mary Fremont CMn. R. L Durkee Charles T Epeneter O. F Omaha. 61-1 Lincoln. H15 V OsiMr Bros Lincoln Cornice and Metal Works Lincoln. 335 So. H Krauae. William Lincoln HBO Lincoln. H Smith F M Fremont CORN HUSKERS AND HARVESTERS Beatrice Manufacturing Co Km.. .1 (i Beatric* 1 Nebraska City International HoakerCo Wftltcr PftQi JttflkDQr iicturiiif ( n Bocitrict^ </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 Block Block CRACKERS, BISCUITS, ETC. National Biscuit Co Omuhii CREAMERY-SEE "BUTTER" CREAMERY SUPPLIES .•■ry Paohaga Mfg. Co Omaha. l'-JUl Jones CURBING AND GUTTERING McWillium Bn Omaha. 4:« Paxton DENTAL SUPPLIES Hilling* A Sum, A. S Omaha. 412 Paxton DOOR DEVICES Hall, ttoorge N Omaha ELECTRICITY ILLUMINATING Adams Electric Light Co Adams Ansley Electric Light &amp; Power Co Ansley Arlington Electric Light ('■&gt; Arling Arlington Ashland Light. Mill &amp; Power Co Ashland Atkinson Heat &amp; Light Oo Atkinso Atkinson Ern Mutual Light &amp; Power Co Auburn ra Klectric Light and Power CoAurora ice Electric Oo Beatrio Beatric&lt; Bell &amp; Son David City Benedict Elec'tric Light ( Benedict Blair Electric Light Oo Blair Bradshaw Electric Light Co Bradshaw I bridge Electric Light Iron Electric Light &amp; Electric Light I Electric Light I Klectric Light Oo ks Electric Light On kson Electric Plant minis Electric Light ( i Orchard Electric Co Ob „ ( 'ambridge Power Co Chad ron FalN City Grand Inland Humboldt Clarks Clarkson Columbus o ( 'rab Orchard Ir Electric Light &amp; Power Co Edgar &gt;ury Electric Light &amp; Power Co Fairbury rton Electric Light &amp; Power CoFullerton ir. P. .1 Sutton jn Light. Power &amp; Heating Co Hebron erson Electric Light Co Henderson ler &amp;• Craven Pi - rege Electric Co Holdrege </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 ■ trie Plant How el K - trie Light &amp; I wur Butt.' Jonw S H W,l)|.H K Electric Light O Hli mi Electric &lt; adu/.a Mill- Miiirien Valentim • ( 'larc nee ()m-.-..1.. BLiKht. Power * Heating &lt; trie Light A Power ( Matt. 1 Electric Light &gt; NorfoH &gt;wer North Platta in Elertric Heat &amp; I Kearmy Oakdale Oakdal. H. . ( i &amp; Lisht ( Omaha Electric Light ft Power ( H Omaha &lt;\ N Albion rk 1 \\ ,if« S»-hiiyler Electric Plant Electric Litfht ( '■ Schuvlir Shelby Snperi' a" Br Electric Li^ht Co Electric LiKht 1'lant i&gt; Eltn-tric Light On ■ trir ( d Sutton VerdiKrin Wymore ■ .V I HUT I'oint SiuinKvif" \\ 'inner L A ■ Electric Li^ht I'lant Electric Lij:ht I Wayne ELECTRICAL SUPPLIES tmlen &lt; Onniha :(!:( So. IS Omaha. MM DMghM Omaha ISM lih&gt;l Omaha W* No 11 .1.1. William and .1. W Omaha Electrical Woi ENVELOPES \ Enveloi&gt;e ( Omaha 120 No |.j itr&lt;- Ticki Omaha Mil EXTRACTS SEE "BAKING POWDER, YEAST, EXTRACTS KENCE IRON, WIRE AND SLAT \\ .-I' II! .OmrK Bectrir Li^Iit H Oiiuihu MS No li </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 Bui Id in, Healy * OOM K .Streitwietter, Herman Tnlley Fenc. Grand htaai Beatrice -teen. .1 H FERTILIZER Kearnev FLOUR BLEACHER Xaylor &amp; Oerrard Columbus FLOUR AND GRIST MILLS Abie Milling Co Acme Milling O Adams. H Abie Blair Holdrege Alber, W. D Rising City Albion Albion Milling Co Alfalaf Meal &amp; Milling C Alfalfa Meal Oo Alma Lincoln, Hi and Omaha. 5 X. V Superior Y Alfalfa Meal Co Alfalfa Meal 00 Alma Milling ('&lt; 1 if. Alma Red Cloud Irvington Minden Anderson &amp; Son. A B Andrews A- Wansworth Indianola Anselmo Anslev Kmo Roller Mill * Elevator ( y Milling Oo Mill O Ponca Arlington Mill O Arlington Atkinson Aurora Kison Milling (irain tt Stock ( ra Milling Oo Barta Joseph Bazille Mill C Bom H Sohuvler Bazille Mill Kear; Beatrice Corn Mill Bedford. Henry Beatric- Hhuk Bro.s Biddock, F. .1 Blue Springs Roller Mills Blackburn A At— im Ik Blair A: I'.illev Blev. A. A Stockvillt- Bl&lt;Hjintield A ins worth So ward Bliss, Johnson W Bloomfield Roller Mill Q reek Mills Hulshizer * ('( Fremont ( )maha. !«&gt;1 Douglas 1'lattsmouth A in buy Milling &amp; Elevat&lt; Anderson Bros Bent i Di'cutur Blue Spring: St. Edwards Wauneta Madison </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 I, Bridge, C S.and W.II..&amp; Beck.K W Norfolk Broken Bow Milling Co Brown Milling O Broken Bow Fremont Bryson &amp; Miller Biitte Milling Co Callaway Milling &amp; Mfg Carlson. A ii &lt; 'allaway enbai? Hartington Doris Carlson Bros KIT &amp; Pointer rter Bros U.xxl Rivei Rapid ung Cedar Rapid* Improvement C«dar Valley Mill Co Chadron Holler Mill Clark, (ieorge E Clarkson Milling Oo t hadron Arapahoe Clarkson Waverly Bold] Homer Clay &amp; Co . F. M Colcleeser. Henry Combs. S. A. and P. E Comb &amp; Son, S. y HuMard Coons. A T 8teele City Humboldt Tildt'ii Cooper &amp; Linn tkle Bros. &amp; Dauphin ndall. \\. .1 Firth tighton Milling Co te Mills _'hton Cummins, Addison L Curtis, W L DuBois Bracken -. W. L Uaggeti &amp; Sun Brownville Salem Dakota City Milling Co Darner, J. H Dakota City Co/.ad Davw, A. O Unadilla Homer Davis &amp; Co.. J. W Davis &amp; Son, J H Deardorf &amp; Duke DeSann &amp; Son. W H Deshler Roller Mills Co Diels Brothers G i bbon.- Mason City Juniata lVsliler Scrilmer Dixon Kxon Roller Mills line. D M Valparais. Dodge Dodge Milling &amp; (train O Doescher I Douglas. William Duff, R. H Beemer Falls City Bertrand Dun &amp; Owens Bloomington 'xfonl Mi.ldl. East Oxford Roller Ebery. John H </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 Eat or Holler Mills Co ... wood Mill &lt;t Elevator ninger, George L Columbus Elm wood Osceola Minden Eiire Milling ng, OeurjB A Ub nil's H ■field Mills David City Hardy Johnstown Farmers' Elevat WilUSU Farmers' Milling Jfc Elevat Newman Grove &gt;r Felix &amp; I^ewis Finney. .1. B Meadow Grove A ins worth Fonda &amp; Bro. . H. E Fox Creek Milling C Frederick &amp; Smith Fremont Milling Oo ( Jenoa Curtis Cirafton Fremont Papillion Friend I Milling O Fullerton Mill Cc Fullerton Gallaway flour Mill &amp; Elevator Oo Oakdale Gately Bros Stromsburg Brainard Gel wick &amp; getown Holler Mills &amp; Power Georgetown (iering Franklin Neligh Val'-ntine Tekamah Omaha. tOB Izard Gordon Nebraska City Nebraska City lev (treat Western ( ■ Greeley Milling I Campbell Superior Arapaho* Curtis Hagadom &amp; Son. A. O Hagemeistti F. and W Hall, Leroy Henderson tord Petersburg Hampton til. 1^-wis K Hampton Mill &amp; Grain O Harvard Milling &amp; ".Power Oo Harvard Hastings Milling * Hasting Haatinga Heinzelman. C. M. and J. A Verdon Hibner, (• Benneti Bennett Plattsmouth H.-isW C KG, ing Roller Mill Je, Thoma- Olasson. Joseph (ilencoe Mills . ■ Mill Co Seth r (iuthrie A: Oo (iuthrie A I Haas &amp; Oearhart Pleasant.Hill (it'ii'va </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Hooiwr Roller Milling Co Howell Milling On Hooper Bewail Hopkins X. A St 1'aul Kick ins. (ii-orge E hMl « - r City I ii-ueese Hnui]ilirey Roller Mills hiding Charles F Humphrey North Plutte ttfcaca t Milling Jackson Roller Mills Jagg, JacfcMM Blue Hill NMp Dannrhrog Dunnolirog Nelson L. K Jermen &amp; Hatt Jennen &amp; Hanwn Janaen Milling Co Jam &amp; Zop]&gt; Emerson SterliiiK .li'ssuji Milfonl .St. James Champion I'rajjue Kendall-Smith Co Kleitsi-h ft Halme: Kummer. R. B iitien H Laurel Milling Co Long Pine Laurel Lawrence Milling A Lester Milling Oo Lawivbo) Lexington Mill ft KlevatorCo Lincoln Mill (V A Mill Lincoln Mill Co Lexington Hastings Lincoln N Looergan. M I' Steele City Broken Bow Lcxiii Em .V Milling C&lt; City Mill ft Light Co rn Product* Co Loup ( lty Omaha-. :«M 1st Nat'l Bank Buildir Lushton ton Milling Co Lynch Milling «\ ■ Bros Lynch ure. E K Broken Bow MoCook k Milling Co ■kle Bros ft Dauphin McDowell Br.,s Tilden Alexandria r'airburv M&lt; Uowell ft Mendenhall hind &amp; Co Tobias Benson re, Joseph McBean Plainview JesHup Roller Mills Johnson &amp; Jones. Thomas X Lincoln. ?:l"i K WVfjiing Wilier Red Cloud </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 I&gt; an Avenue Angus Beaver Crossing Spencer Munini &amp; Rosendahl May mini Bros Staplehurst, K. K. Brock Milling Co ■r, c. R . May wood Silver Creole Oak Ernst Eer, George H er &amp; Thorp igan. J. O Surpn.se Thayer WakerieM York ttgomery &amp; Cotton ton, IV. C Brainar'l Kushville M. P Nebraska Flour &amp; Meal Mills Stella Elm Creek Xehawka St. Paul IE Bros. Company tavvka Milling i man &lt;V Jenkins s-bauer. Hugo Hon. Dennis E brara Milling &lt; lkamper. William 1h Bend Milling Co them Milling Co wood. Nathaniel T ander. Jacob Hildreth Wayne Niobrara Turner North Bend Arcadia Edgar Bancroft Omaha. IUI Ord Sherni; Kaha Milling O Roller Mills Orleans Flour and Oatmeal Milling Orlean: Co Orr Bros Clay Center Oxford (ford Roller Mills pillion Roller Mill vlick Brus IVttet Tecumseh Phillips, .hiMin L Pien-e. Milling Ct (iothenhurg Ainsworth inn Platte Valley Milling Cc. Plum River Mill- Prestim Mills Ravenna Flouring MilK Renard, Fred Ravenna Oakland Richardson A: Co., W F Rigner, JJ Roberts Bros .Johnson A Bruning Robertson Bros Cook Cook Hoby. Frank F Koarney Roca Flour Mill Roea Kickolls, John in, J. P &amp; Berens .... Papillion Verdigris Peru Sweetwiitt'i- Davenport </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 rman Rodwell &amp; Brown Roe, W. H Cambridge Kearnev Koyston Milling Co Sanders. J. E Fremont Battle Creek Ewing Sanders. Martin T Sanders. F. 1. Schafer &amp; Carter Schempton &amp; Swain Schleip. ('. Charles Schmitt. Peter Stan ton Fairmont Holmesvill' Kenningtoi ( olumbus Snyder Schneider. Conrad «der. O. A Schnminker &amp; Co Seward Cereal Mi IK Sharrett. F. M trymcmm Columhu -ku City ird Crab Orchard Shelton Sbelton Milling Co Sbeperdson &amp; Son Sloan. Thomas L Smith, J. R Kiverton Pender Falls City Ashland Steinauer David City Snell. James H Steinauer Milling Co Steiner Medinger Co Stone &amp; Son. F. E Struthers &amp; Son, A Taylor, James Omaha. 1 1M Sin Craig South Auburn Dawson Taylor. John J Toenmseh Milling Co TeciiHiM-h Tekamah Roller Mill &amp; Electric Light Paint Thacker. L Tbeohold &amp; A they Thom»en M. L Thorndike &amp; K-.-1 Tucker, L. B Tekamah Falls City Bartlev Platte Onter Randolph Julian K Lumber Co.. J. L . James Kavenna Central City St-otia Vmecore. Dee Wahoo HUk Warner. Jowph Weber Bros Wall..,, Arapahoe Wavne Weber A Son Florence Suttoii Weber Si Son, (ieorge Weeth. C. S (iretna Bitein &amp; Co.. X P Abbott &amp; Xeiman f. W MartinsburK Schuyler (irand Island Hebron </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 :. Loll Fairtield Wilsonville Roller Mill: Wilt &amp; Pollev Wilsonville Naponee Bl Mill &amp; Elevator ( te, Charles H Tecumseh Wisner rirs, Harry Co Bros I'lvsses Seribner Kiore Implement A uf, .1. M Wymore Stamford DeWitt tachek Jk Askmit achek &amp; A. skin it Wilher FLUMES Mitimnis Flume Mfg. . Co Kimball FOLDING COOPS Solomon Manufacturing Co Omaha, 610 Bee Building FOUNDRY AND MACHINE SHOPS Andreen. (i Ery Manufacturing Oo iter &amp; Son, Ch;i I &amp; Kuhn Bros Blaha, Vaclav Omaha. MS So II Hastings Brueningsen, Fred Ktol City Iron Works ad. Otis H Lincoln, HI 2 So. Broken Bow Killing* &amp; Beltner mings &amp; Borden ;ett. Daniel Fremont Burchard Kearney Plymouth Bi &amp; Krentzt s Bros Omaha, 14(»5 Jackson Beatr EM ill Mfg ■ n ie-W right Mfg Co e, Wilson &amp; Williams ev. V H York Omaha. 19 and Pierce Lincoln Kir on Works . A V Lincoln. H25 M Omaha, 2416 Grant Nebraska Citv ■..n. F B Elsaaser. Herman Essinger. Dan Fahrenbruck Omaha Holstein lioOook Fairburv Iron Works and Wind Mill Fairbury Fremont Co Eiont Foundry iV Machine ( d Island Iron Works ings Sheet Metal Works ■s Puniji and Planter Co (irand Island Hastings Osaka. N K Ooram Omaha, K10 So. 14 Omaha, HIT Farnam I'tica Kearnev </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 Building rth Block k Lincoln. 7 and M (tut hen burn Hedge* Lincoln Iron Works Hedman Bros Holdrege Found ry Holloway. J. F Hulquist Bros H.ildrege Bridgeport Holdrege International Mfg. Co Johnson. Peter J Omaha. -MKi .1. ■ Newman (trove Omaha, 414 Met ague Nebraska City Kenny, Vincent King Drill Mfg. I Kregel. George F Kucera Wind Mill Co Lamb Manufacturing Co Langdon. Horace Nebraska City Grand Inland South Sioux City Beat! Omaha, 14116 Howard Omaha. HOX Jackson Axtell Laraen Ice Machine ( Liddell. John Lilienborg A Lnedtke. R. A Maekie. D. T i.oirs, P *irry, C. A el, Charles Lincoln. Ut West (t Oaceola Omaha. 421 So. B Alliance Hebron Norfolk Norfolk Foundry &amp; Machine Olson Bros Omaha, 2.*&gt;7O Leavenw Omaha, U and Izanl Omaha, MM So. 19 Omaha, 7U7 Dim^M Hastings Omaha Boiler Works Omaha Structural Steel Work- Omaha Tank Manutacturing &lt; FWtora Bros Iig &amp; Mcwsholder Roller Foundry ■ner, Williair Lincoln, Mi So, Omaha, 111 No. U Red Cloud Sharp Machine Works. L (' Smith Machine Works. K L Strong &amp; Farley r. Thomas Wales Machine Sh..,, Wall. John Jr Wearne Bros Omaha, 14&lt;l!» Jackson Lincoln. BM N Wortover &amp; Co. . X Wilson Steam Boiler Co Wingert &amp; Taylor Omaha, 19 and Pierce ( i rand Island «. A l J oint HumlKildt York York Foundry &amp; Engine W&lt; irks FUR GOODS Omaha. oOB Karbach Omaha. Karbach Bloc! Omaha. 813 S.. lfi Hubermann. H. E. and E Shnkert, (i I Omaha. 606 So. 10 Lincoln, 247 So. W Omaha, 12*0 Dodgt Falls I Nebraska Citv Nebraska Citv </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 Steele. Ollis Lincoln. Brownell Blk Omaha. 141? Farnam Lincoln. 14« So. lii Tbomaen. Henry K Voelker. F. E GAS MACHINES AND LAMPS Barnum. F. P Omaha Monarch Acetylene &lt; Olds Gm Engine Work.s Wilhelmy. W. H Omaha. 1012 Farnam Omaha. 10!H Farnam Nebraska City Automatic Gas Lamp ( Omaha. 20 and Pierce GAS ILLUMINATING AND HEATING AmtylMM ' Diller Klene i .ition Utica Albion Bloomiield Gas. C'&lt; Bloomfield Burwell Heat and Light ( &gt; City Gas Oo Burwell Beatrice City Gas( Kearney Derby (las Plant Bellwood Kont Gas and Electric Lin d Island Gas Co lit ( o Fremont Grand Island Oreeley Heat and Light &lt; 'o Hastings Light and Heat C&lt; Greeley Hastings Havelock &gt; Eock Uas Co ?s. Charles F In (ias Co CVntralCity Lincoln (ias Co Lyons Nebraska City Light and G Co Nebraska City ;is Elk Light and Pm Bend City Qm Works . J. E Norfolk North Bend Elmwotid Omaha Gas Co Omaha. 1224 Farnam Ord Light and Fuel Co Ord sburg Acetylene Ga- Plattsmouth Gas and Electric Petersburg Light Co Plattsmouth Rising City Spelling Sttnborn. .1. E Spalding Heat and Light Co Syracuse Heating and Lighting Co Byraewc Thorns. John A Tilden Tilden Western Light and Fuel C\ Broken Bow Winter Bancroft York Gas and Electric Co York GASKET CUTTING MACHINE Hastings </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 unk Bid GASOLINE ENGINES Cash man Motor Co Lincoln. 2 GATES Gibbet. E. B Omaha. 3009 Bo. SO GLOVtS AND MITTENS Craig. Henry M Plattsinnuth Hanly Glove Mai.ufactur; Hardy Omaha Mitten and Manufacturing Omaha. 1807 Howar i Nebraska Cotton Gloi &lt; hnahu. l."H»i) Jacks n 8t St. .lohnB Manufacturing O Wilson Vfymore GREASES AND TALLOWS Hoebener &amp; Co.. J. H Fremont Union Rendering and Kenning Oo South Omaha HARDWARE Kees. F. D HARNESS AND SADDLERY Adam- Alberts V Baker Harness Co Bat«man. J. R Berry. Edward .1 B Bertrand Harness SI Blair Horw Collar I Blankenburg. Edward Bloodheart &amp; Lundstn&gt;in Blum. H.. Estate; Bertram BUir North l J latt Hloomtield Palisade Bockelmann. Ht-niy Bradehoft. Latch Pien ka Citv Buckstaff Bros. M an uf actarin Co LiocoL Budler Hardware and Implement Co Hampton Burnett. L. C Burnham I Butler. James A Chi Ids. George Cloco.. Emil -ka ( 'ity i J a« nee City Waketield Fremont Collins &amp; Morrison Cornish &amp; Co . Alfred Cuber. Frank Omaha. :t!4 S&lt; Omaha. 1110 Farnam M Cum ing Dewitz. Amos Dick &amp; Sod. R Dixon. Brice W Beatrice I .i-l &gt;uji&lt; &gt;n O'Neill First Nail </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 Nebraska City (ionli. Qwtajfeon, John Alfred Hammeratrom, .1 Oakland Minden Hasting! Kearney Omaha. 811 Lincoln. 8M P Hasting David C'ity va Herzog. Harry Paul Omaha, in* ( 'uhiiiik Falls Citv Hfwcii A ( lo u. c: Hewitt, P. .T Hasting Lexington Hibbler A I Boldan, Milo A Hulm. Henrv Omaha. ! I DnBois Harm, L. R ich, Henrv Hiililmrd Co.. F. \V Hulier. Fretl • ier. F A Strinauer Ke|ilinger. A. ( ' South Auburn Klnsaner. John HumlKildt F. J Schuvler Emil HumUildt Wayne John S. . Jr ,.irle&gt; Faruell Lun«l. Ole P Haitington iren &amp; McKanzie Fairburv M&lt;. Milieu. \V. W McCook John. Sr O'Neill .Mark^ Bree. Saddlerv Co Omaha. 1BOB Harney Matoush. Frank I Iranian] Millisan, N B»-aver Cit\' Frunk Ord Mitchell, David DeWitt Moffett, Cfaai Hlu jinin«ton IV t A Bcott'i Bluff ninx Saddlery t'o, \V A Kearney linger, CharK- F Firth st&lt;-r, A. B Hartin»»ton efelt. William . Tnfiniwnh mat Saddlery Od Fremont ley. Owen P Nebraska Cil .J. H .1. H .1. H Hurpham Bi Haokina, K. W K&lt;'s A: Nitschts lac Br. Lincoln. 118 0 Adams Omaha, 1090 Douglas Alexandria i iatonia Newcastle </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Mary aven worth i II Moore, Egnatz Morris, J F Nahrgang. .1. .' Nash. Andrew .1 Necken. E W N«pory. J. C Nicholas. W. S Olson, John L Dannebrog McCool Junction Steele City Osmund Crete Geneva AxU-11 Omaha Omaha Harness Supply Co Parker. F. W Table Rock Beau i rr. J. B R. 8 Blue Hill Trenton Maywood Wayne Pember. R H Peterson. Ralph &amp; Co Piepenatock, William Purtier, John Lindsay Diller Raymond, L. P Rockhill, Cyrenens Rom, Charles Harvard Omaha, 17 18 St Cofambus Blair Mind, -ii Schuyler Harness Go Scger, J. F .Omaha. M ...Omaha. WA Ni Erger. John ;r, John C , T. R Ainsworth Beatrice Burr, C. C Pawnee City Wilber atf neck's Harness Shop Sundin, FA Gothenburg Superior Superior Harness Co Tecka, Frank Tripp, Charles E Voight, W E Wachtel. O Walthers. Louis A Walther. L. A Whitten. F. M Wilding, W. K Williams, D. L Columlm&gt; Tekamah Lexington Omaha. Hin S, Omaha Ord Williams, Frank E Winter, W. H . Cambridge Norfolk Woodworth, John L Lincoln, rji- o Scbeffler, Gun ischlageter. &lt; ' K Schmid. George S Plymouth Kenesaw Schuyler Crete Kp|ir-uw Onjaha, MM Ctapitol Anm Kails City Lincoln, 148 So. M Wtjmtmm </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 HATS Deputy Spongier Hat Co Kaplan, Samuel Lincoln, 222 N Omaha, 114 So. IS Omaha. 107 No. 17 Omaha. 220 So. 14 Omaha. (*i:&gt; Na lti Kerr &amp; Mcllroy Kamser. W A Schmarse, Henry HAIR GOODS Bell, Mrs. .1 C Monheit, Morit/ Lincoln. 1414 O Omaha, 1411 Farnain HAY BALER Leul)lit*n Balt-r Co Lincoln. :H:&lt; No H HEMP TOW i.K-k Cordage 0 Havelock HEN'S NESTS Bennington Manufacturing Co Bennington ICE Eln Ice and Cold Storage Do Lincoln, 72&lt;&gt; L i\ |M I'lant Kearney ■ Ice and OoJd Storage Co Omaha. 42:. ICE MAKING MACHINES Lanen- Baker Ice Machine ( Omaha, 1!H)1 Nicholas ICE CREAM Lincoln. 7 and L Oinahii. Ill N,. II Lincoln, I8M N Collins Ice Cream C Dalsell Confectioner \ Franklin Ice Civam &lt; nn Factorv Leming. C. A., and M K Stuckey, John H Geneva Lincoln. 401 Lincoln, 1837 O Omaha, -Mil No If. Zees. John INCUBATORS Burr Incubator Co Omaha, 28 and Davenport Hastings Hastings Manufacturing Co Hebron Incubator Co Hebron Lincoln Fairfield Stan ton Nelson Eln Incubator Co ay Inculiator Co e, Robert Kbator Factory . son Co. . M. M Clay Center Fairfield Nebraska Incubator Co Pinkerton Manufacturing Co Reliable Incubator Co Lincoln. Corner 14 anil Y Batten </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 Standard Incubator Hatch Inculiator C Fremont INSECTICIDE Hansun A. Net ha way Waho. JEWELRY f 'arxm &amp; Bank Omaha, tl Barker Block ( imalia. ISM Capitol Avriiu i 20 1 DoukIum tdman Jk Oo., I'. K bermunn. A B .. \. .1 Omaha. 1511 l)i«l^ r &gt; Omaha. I Arlington Block Omaha. MM W. O \V I'.uildin Omalia. IJKH Dongtaa 11. L, ( Her. Onristopo Stilling. N 1' Omaha 581 Pmxton Bl(H-k Omaha. 543 Kamge Bl«K-k JOB PRINTING, BOOK BINDING, ETC. SEE "NEWSPAPERS ETC." Auburn Printing ft I'ubli n. &lt;i I hint; ( Auburn Omalia 701 Brummond, W. K Brnnncr. W K Burkley Printing Oo il J'ul)lisliiiiK&lt; 'i 111 No 15 Uaootn. IS York Bint- Spring - Printing and Specialty Oulnmboa Hast ings York t.al Printini an. Thonia.- Currier. A. B Carter. Harrv P Kullerton Kalis City Douglas Print n Festner Printii - Fink Printing Omaha, l'.'th and Haniey .Oau Howard OHMl 14th Omaha. IM So. U 11. 1520 O iklin Press Iner Print, Ke Bn« Omaha, 111 So. 14 i.iiii-..iii. na Omaha. BU So. 12 Lincoln, ID K Printing Oo ■ A: PkilUpi Printing ( d Omaha EMaU, Charlei B onmlui. 10 and Paeite kwurtl ()mah;i, 1 1 IT Pattfixm HliM-k Liiuuln. 184 N.i 14 KaMMj Krh. .1 A University lMa&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 N Hald, Fred (irand Island Holdrege tilton, Theodore J mond. A H &lt; amhridge Kremont Hammond It Stephens ( '&lt; - hi Printing Oo Omaha. ISOB Howard South Omaha 091 I York Printing ( Huffman. - Iw Pnm Liaooln, 139 No. 12 Omaha. iMH Cuinings Oraalia, loth and Douglas Omaha, llilo Howard Omaha, 11(1* Douglas Kp ft Bartlett O ra * Co Kramer ft Chandler Kri.-hn. U C Omaha. Mi Omaha. Ill So. II I. Edward Beatrice, 107 No. 4 W \ moiv Ifardock, C. M EA Co . Jacob Ik Printing Co on, H. E Lincoln. 11 18 M Norfolk Omaha, 7t« So 2 Ea Directory C. Publishing Co a Printing Co , E. L Omaha. Ramge Blo&lt;'k Lincoln, S. W. Corner 18 and Omaha. !U* Karnain yuinby &amp; Lynn. L \\ Omaha. 180M Hartley Omaha. N Y Lite Building K.dtield &amp; Co.. .1. B., -Ir Omaha .lob Printing C Omaba. 2023 Karnam Kees Printing ( Keliner. P. K Omaha, 40^! Hastings ids &amp; Co., V. D Omaha. 131« Dodge K George E ts. E Omaha Roberts Printing Co., J. H &gt;n Brt» L.mon Publishing Oo Lincoln. SU3 Kunke Building Lincoln Press Printery Lincoln. 211 So. 10 Ly—fd. J. H \ Omaha. II!) No 1»&gt; ft Oo V Omaha, Itlfl Dodge McVcy Printing o Limoln. IM Sa 12 lty Prinpnf{&amp; Pab Co Suuth Omaha. 511 No. \li MuiiKuin A Coiflpany Omaha, ltm s H. (' C Nefaraaka City Midland Publisl^tnp i Omaha Milburn &amp; Scott Bcatrict'. 107 No. 4 ■nul Printing &lt;&lt;&gt; Omaha, ."m&gt;9 S. PnbliaUag Ob Owhi .»."&gt;l(i B -K;i WllWlflWll Tiiiun Vurk wka I'rinting ('.. Liiuuln. 3S» 80. 12 Century Priilwi Laaoula, ,'li &gt; N.Hinyer, S. B Unida Rock Omaha, :il? No. IS </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 &lt; Buildin Omaha, 414 So. 12 Omaha. 1314 Williams Omaha, 315 So. 11 Beatrice York Omaha, 32 Barker Block Lincoln, F. Jk M. Insurance South Omaha tical Bilile PabUabing Co 11 F Book and Credit Oo Waters Printing Co Omaha. MM Farnam Omaha, 1 307 Howard Lincoln, 14 and O Omaha. 15 and Howard Kearney Etern Newsjiaper L'nion tern Xewsjiajier l'nion bert. H A E Ilium*. Manley .1 HianiMin. V K od Printiiif: Omaha, 112 So. 14 Havelock Lincoln, 11 and M Lincoln, Itt No. 11 WixxlrufT-ColliiiN Printing Oo KNIT GOODS if, Christian Omaha, 1722 Vinton Omaha National Knitting Factory Omaha. M So. 10 LEATHER GOODS Western Fur Ko)*e and Tanning Co Oniaha. 1424 So. 13 LEGGINGS Omaha. 1114 Jackson Omaha LIGHTNING RODS Omaha Lightning Hod and Electric Omaha. 1512 Wel»ter LINSEED OIL Woodman Linseed Oil Works Omaha. 1023 No. 17 LIQUORS, MALTS, ETC Koerster. Anna Niobrara Fremont Freincnt Brewing Co I ity Malt (iehling. Mn Omaha. 2nd and Pin Fulls City UuKgPnmoM". Caroline Brewing Co Koraenbrock. J H Omaha. 1415 Canton South Omaha Columbus Crete Kobee Estate Krug Brewing Co.. Fred Mlison I M Sherwood. ('. A Springer, Paul Stilson. William E Swiirtz Jk McKelvv Omaha. 10!) So. 15 Omaha, IIS No. IS Ta^er. H . K HuntiiiKton A Son. L &lt; Corker LeKKinK I </seg>
            <seg id="p073">73 jrth Avenue v rtli Avenue Brewing G Rainbour, I Omaha. (! and Leaven w Schuvler Brewing ( Omaha. 1K19 Sherman ion West Point '■ &gt;int Brew. Wilber Brew Wilier Willow Springs Brewing ( Omaha, 3rd and Hickor St.Helent MANTELS TILE, FLOORING, ETC. ( Lincoln, :!24 N llaiiilinjf. F. M Omaha. 308 MARBLE AND GRANITE MONUMENTS Auringer &amp; Coleman Xeligh Burwick. .1 »ln, 223 No. '.» B^oermeiator M numentiU \V Omaha. 1142 No. 18 Colnmbai ks «'. A nan. I ■huvler &amp; Co., .1 F Omaha. I81S Kiirnam Lexington &amp; Xisley Clam, Fred \\ Omaha, 1 K I7 LeaTenwo Kean lord. .Tami Currie, J Blair &amp; Co., William Central City Wayne Dun-in, Kotiort Farrell &amp; Omaha. &gt;\~. - rlastii MA M. .1 Omaha. 2212 Poppleton Nsbraaka Citv W. A Broken Bow HmI.1i -lern ( Omali Kean Harmon, R. I Auburn Fremont $ &amp; Baldw Nebraska ( Works ranite and M rl Omaha 14M N'o. 17th York Kiklow, .1. M Kimball &gt; icoln. l."i(»6 O K.irth &amp; Alltel Norfolk Hebrun Blair I) Mrl-aughlin &lt;!t n .1. A. ison York Blair Mann. Hat Humlioldt Hast . Miller. Carl .1 i Monumen </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 19th Neidhart, Charles Neittel. A Tecumseh Falls City Olsen L Newman Grove Red Cloud Orating Bros. &amp; Co Paine &amp; Co. Ira T Pecht &amp; Harm Grand Island Falls City Pettit &amp; Son Fairbury Red Cloud Marble and Granite Co Red Cloud Ritner, William O Schmidt, W North Platte Pone* Shane, Frank aheey, James F Smith.C. G Pawnee City Lincoln, 2021 O David City Sommers. L Randolph SpeideU. Charles E Stannard. D Lincoln, 233 No. 11 O'Neill tW— mini &amp; Son Norfolk Superior Superior Marble Works Sweeny. J. V Omaha, 212 No. 15 Seward Vnnders. James S Woatonpal, Joseph . West Point MATTRESSES PILLOWS, LOUNGES, ETC. Analyn. Maxwell Doop, L. G Omaha, 1721 Cuming Omaha. 1307 Nicholas Lincoln, 2018 O Lincoln Upholstering Co Omaha Bedding Co Omaha, 1113 Harney Omaha. 1721 Cuming Omaha Pillow Co Parlor Furniture &amp; Mattress Co .. Fremont Payne* Leek Lincoln, 2020 O Lincoln, 335 S. Omaha Western Furniture Co Wykert. H. R MINERAL WATER, POP, ETC Alliance Bottling Works AsBwii mi Bottling Co _ Baer, Henry Alliance Fremont York Blatt. Ph McCook Norfolk Auburn BUtt, Rudolph Bomfield, W. L Kibus BoUling Works Mineral Springs Co sr, A. P Columbus Omaha. N. Bet. 18th and Fairbury Edinger, J. A West Point Plattsmouth Ejjenberger, Fred G Elwick Bottling Works. C. L Geneva Pop Works Lincoln, 1841 O Geneva Hey« William North Platte </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 Hornberg, P Wymore Humphrey Bottling Works Janorich, Prokop Humphrey Wilber Kay, William Keenan, J. E Wakefield Kearney Tecumseh Schuyler Falls City Korarik, Adolph Krivohlavek, Wesley Lacher, John E-Kola Bottling Works .In Bottling Works , C. August Oakland Fremont Marr &amp; Son Nebraksa City Bottling Works Novacek, F. D Nebraska City Brainard Odell &amp; Son, E. B Ohmatede &amp; Son ... McCook Wahoo Omaha Bottling Works Porter, C. C Omaha. 10 &amp; Pierce Holdrege K Bottling Works &amp; Sons, W. H , George Pawnee City Falls City Beatrice St. Paul Crete Eidt, Paul ke, August ke, Charles Columbus Seward El Bottling Works Lithia Springs Co M Milford Nebraska City Hastings Stier, William. Jr Stochl. H Creighton Prague Suchy, Thoe Superior Bottling Works Tetzman, F Superior Alma Eer &amp; Kriesmann ng, Louis Q i Bottling Works York Hooper Superior Grand Island O'Neill Valentine Valentine Broken Bow West Point Bottling Works Western Bottling Works .... Wolff. Victor ..West Point Hastings Blair Wood, M. R Omaha, 1513 Hurt MIRRORS Koatka Glass &amp; Pan Lincoln, 1210 O Omaha Mirror Manufacturing Co Omaha, 1108 Farnam Omaha, 1310 Howard Lincoln, 1524 N </seg>
            <seg id="p076">■e 76 ETC MOULDINGS SEE PLANING MILLS JOBBcn Bros Central City MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS Albre&lt;ht • Sloan, .1 .1 Omaha. 404 W. O. \V Bldg Grant) Island NEWSPAPERS, ETC. SEE JOB PRINTING BOOKBINDING Adams Globe A Ainsworth' Star-Journal Ainsworth Ainsworth Rai Brand Recorder Ainsworth Albion Ar^u* Albion Albion Weekly Kewg Albion Alexandria Argus Alexandria Allen News Allen Alliance Baptist Herald All Alliance Semi-Weeklv Tinx Alliance Alliance Herald Alliano Alliance Pioneer Grip Alliano Alma— Harlan County Journal Alma Alma Record Alma Anoka Herald Ansley Argosy Andey Chronicle-Citizen Ansley raskan Arapahoe Pioneer Ara]iali( Arapahoe Public Mr Arapah Aic-adia Champion Arcadia Arlington Review H. raid Arlingtoi Ashland Gazette Ashland Ashland Living Witness Ashland Journal Ashland Atkinson (iraphii- Atkinaot Auburn Crozier. Episcoj&gt;al Monthly Autium Auburn Granger Auburn Auburn— Nemaha County Herald Auburn Auburn— Xemaha Co. Republican Auburn Auburn Westliche Beobachtei man Aubui'j rurn Scarlet and • tional Auburn Aurora Aurora Aurora Axtel Aurora— Hamilton County Registt Aurora Republican T Aurora Sun Aitel Times Blade roft N </seg>
            <seg id="p077">77 Barnestoi Bartlett— Wheeler Cuunu n tlett 1 iartley Rock Count) l;i&gt;M'It Battle Creek Eni lattle I attle i Battle Creek Republic 1 rd Beatrice Daily &amp; Semi -U E I itri Beau ( 'ounty Di t tri Beat! i ( i unit v Herald ■atri ■atri latri. ■atrn Beatrice, Weekly Times I iv.r City Independent Ex in] i ivit Croa ing Beaver Crossing Rev !iver C ing B mi ldei B»-lgrade Hera llevne- ( )a» B B. Bellu. HwixhI ■lvidert Bt;videre tndependent Benediol News Herald linan Chronicle B B IHilict nkeliiKin nkelman Benkelman News Bennet Union Benniogton Herald Benson Tim li. B, li. B. llllet nnington I1MII1 Bertrand Independent- Herald ... Bethany Christian News, Keligio Bladen Enterprise B B. ■rtrand thany aden 1 Bh r Bl Bl Bl; Sohn, German HI. mi field Bl.K.minKt Blue Hill 1 Bl. Bloom Bin.- Hill t'llt Bartley Inter ( toeai Bayard Traoacri] Beuuiiv Nebraska I Beatrice- Saturday Summary r City Times- Tribune 2 Pride ot Beemer Tir Bflden Pro, Blu.l. Blair Blair Couri Blair Danskeren, Danish Blair Democrat Blair Newa Blair Pilot Blair Republican Blair title! (iermania, (ierman Bloomrield fii'ld Journal Blumntield BliM.mtield Monitor Bloomfield braska HermaaBi </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Blue Springs Sentinel Boot* Enteipriae Blue Springs Boooe Bradshaw Republican Brudshaw Brainard Clipper Brewster &gt; Bridgeport Blade Brainard Brewster Bridgeport Bridgeport— Platte Valley News Bridgeport t Enterprise Bristow Brock Bulletin Brock Broken Bow — Ouster Co. Beacon . ..Broken Bow Broken Bow- -Canter County Chief Broken Bow Broken Bow— Custer County Repub- Broken Bow Brownville Brnning Brownville Letter Braning Courier Barcbard Tinie&gt; Burchard Burwell Butte Burwell Tribune Butte— Boyd County Register Butte Gazette Butte Byron Cairo Byron Blade Cairo Record Callaway Courier-Tribune Callaway ( allaway ( 'ambridge Campliell ( 'arleton Callaway Loup Valley Queen Cambridge Clarion CampU-ll Citizen Carleton Leader Carroll Index Carroll Cedar Bluffs Standard Cedar Bluffs Cedar Rapids Center Cedar Rapids Outlook Center Register Central City Democrat Central City rtral City- Nebraska Friend, He ligious Central City Central City Central City ( 'hadron Central City Nonpareil Central City Record Central City Republican Chadron Journal Chadruii Times Chadron Chambers Chappell Chester Chambers Bugle Chappell Register Charter Herald Clarks Enterprise Clarks Clarkaon Herald Clark-«,n Clay Center Patriot Clay Center Clay Center Clay Center Clay Center Poultry Gazette ' enter Sun Clearwater Keo.r.l </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 Coleridge Blade t 'oleridge College View Evangelist Sendehucl 'ollege View ( College View— Sions Vaktara.Swed ish 'ollege View 'olumbus ( Columbus Journal ( Columbus — Nebraska Bien- Columbus — Platte County Argus 'olumbus ( ( ilunilms ( 'ulumbus Telegraph ( ilumbus ird — Dixon County World ( ineord «&gt;k Cook Courier ( ( Cortland Sun irtland &gt;zad Cozad Local ( Cozad Tribune Ooznd Crab Orchard Herald Crab Orchard Craig Advertiser and Bnrt County News Craig Crawford Bulletin Crawford ( 'rawford Creighton Crawford Tribune Creighton Courier Creighton News Creighton Creston Creston Statesman Crete Democrat Crete Crete Crete Crete Doane Owl Crete Vidette Herald Culbertson Banner Culbertson Curtis Curtis Courier Curtis Enterprise Curti Dakota County Herald Dakota City Dakota City Danbury Dakota City— North Nebraska Eagle Danbury Lebanon Leader Danbury News Danbury Dannebrog News Dannebrog Davenport David City David City David City David City Duwson Davenport — People's Journal David City— Butler County Press David City Journal David City Public School David City People's Banner Dawson News Boy Daykin Journal Daykin Decatur Deshler Deweese DeWitt DeWitt DeWitt Diller Decatur Herald Deshler Chronicle Deweese Hustler DeWitt Eagle DeWitt— Saline Co. Independent De\V itt Times- News Diller Record Dixon Herald Dizon Dodge Dodge Criterion </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 r Dunbar H. Dorcl Dona Don bar Beacon Elgin ■ E Herald 'reck Bi ikmJ Ueader-Ecfa ,1 Built tin Klk &lt; Elm ' Ehnw Elwood - .11 Eoterpri Eustig .I Canl Eoati Kwin Ewing 1 Enterprise ■unty N Fairln; Fairbu w , iy Journal Faiilmry S Fai tinny Fairhary Kairtiilil Kairlield Fairmont Fall&gt; City Falls City Falls City t Eiont C'hronicli City Journal City V City Triliunt - mi Echo Farnatn Franklin Franklin Fremont EMn 1 din St-ntinel unt Herald unt National ( ,ii n (ii \\ •r .lournal Fri'inoiit Runt Ptatta I n'nnan /.I'itui Friend nt Trilimu itinel Fri&lt;-nd Fullerton News Journal Fullerton Fo~t FnUerton Fullerton son Arfiu iikIv Garriaon Genoa Leader </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 i Tiim ( ig Courier ( t ( ( ring Ciiblnin Reporter ibbon iltner iltner Giltner Clarioi Oiltner Gazette (Jlenville li ( ilenvillt- Jordon in Journal ( Gothenburg Independent burg ihurg i.in S ( rat'ton Island Democrat ( rand Island rand Island rand Island 1 Island F ( 1 Island Independent ( (iranil Island --Nebraska Anaeigi Herald &lt; rand Island rant Perkins i k&gt;unt\ s ( • Perkins County Sentin ( rant . &lt; 'itizi ( reeley (irit'ley LeAdar- Independent ( I Statesmar ( wood Iresham :;iin (lazet ( ( rt'tna &gt; il County ( tour ( Hardv Herald Hardv - iiiri; Banner Count Harrisburg Harrison Hartington Cedar County News HartinKton Hartington Cedar County \Va&lt;-ht OaraMa ■r Hartington Hartington Harvard Hartington Herald Harvard Courier \dams ( 'o. Den Hastings Hastings Hastings Hastings Hastings ngs Journa Hastingx News Hasting! Otaerrer Hasting! Kepnblicai gs Tribune Hast in lock Time: HavnliH-k County Times Republican Hayes Center Hay Springs Hebron Spring! Knterpris. n Champioi m Journal Hebron Hebron Hiekman Enterjiri Hiekman Hildreth Holhrook Holbrook Hildreth T&lt; Hdbrook Herald Holhrook Observe Holdrege ( ltizeii Holdrege </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 Holdrege Progress Holdrefce Homer Echo Homer Hooper Sentinel Hoopei Hoskins Headlight Hoakin Howells Journal Howell Habbell Standard Hubbell Humboidt Enterprise Humboldt Humboldt Leader lluinlxililt Humboldt Standard Humholdt Humphrey Leader Humphrey Humphrey— Platte County Leader Humphrey Hyannis -Grant County Tribune Hyannis Imperial — Chase County Tribune Imperial Imperial Republican Imperial Indianola Alfalfa Bel' Indianola Indianola Independent Reporter Indianola Inmmn News Imnan Ithaca Index Ithaca Jaekaon Criterion Jackson Hubbard Times Johnson News _ lohnaon Juniata Herald .luniata Kearney Democrat Kearney Kearney Hub Kearney Kearney Journal Kearney Kearney New Era Standard Kearney Kearney— Western Poultry &amp; Dairy Joarnal Kearney Keneaaw Citizen Kenesaw Kennanl Enterprise Kennard Kim ball— Western Nebr. Observer Kimball Laurel Advocate Laurel Lawrence Locomotive Lawren&lt;e Lebanon Leader Lebanun Leigh World Leigh Lexington Clipper Citizen Lexington Lexington— Da wson Co Pioneer Lexington Liberty Journal Liberty Lincoln -Acacia Masonic Journal Lincoln •i Central Farmer Lincoln Lincoln — Commoner I Lincoln County Merchant Lincoln b Ainerikanisc.her Farmer Lincoln Lincoln Evening News Lincoln In —Farm Patriot 1 Lincoln -Farm &amp; Town Lincoln Lincoln — Freie Preaae, German Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 Lincoln Daily Star Lincoln Trade Review Lincoln — Western Medic Lincoln- Western Newsj: Lindsay Opinion Lincoln Lincoln al Review Lincoln aper Union Lincoln Lindsay Lindsay Post Lindsay K3eld Monitor pole Express Pine Journal rille Courier Litchneld Lixlgepole Long Pine Louisville Loop City North \* Loup City Loup City— Sherman County Time Independent Loup City Lynch ■ Lynch- Boyd County News Lynch Journal Lynch Lyons Lyons Lyons Mirror Sun McCook Republican McCook Tribune McCook McCook McCool Junction— Blue Valley Jour nal McCool Junction Madison Em Chrouicle m Star- Mail t Mail Madison Magnet Mason City Maywood Mead Mason City Star Maywood Eagle- Reporter Mead Advocate Kw Grove Press Postal Card .. Meadow Grove Merna Lincoln Herald Lincoln Lincoln Interstat i«r Co Lincoln Lincoln -Midwest Lincoln Lincoln — Nebraska Congregational I News Lincoln •uln — Nebraska Farn Lincoln ■iiln— Nebraska Farm Journal Lincoln Lincoln — Nebraska Independent Lincoln Lincoln— Nebraska Legal Ne\\&gt; Lincoln Lincoln Nehraskan Lincoln Lincoln — Nebraska State Capital Lincoln Lincoln — Nebraska State Democrat Lincoln Lincoln- Nebraska Teacher Lincoln Lincoln — Nebraska State Journal Lincoln Lincoln New Patriot Lincoln Kin— Pilger . Lincoln In Ponltry Toyfoi Lincoln In — Pythian Sunt&gt;eum Lincoln Lincoln — Royal Neighbors Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 it it v NackoUa County HeraM N NiK-kolls County Sun Nelson Nemaha— Nebraska Advertiser N Milford Xebraskan Milligan Tin.. - Minatare Sentinel Minilen Courier Minden M Mitchell Index Mill Milligan Minal;ii&gt;- Miiuli'ii Mindeii Mitchell Monowi N' Monuxvi &gt;uking (ilaaa Mi'i Monroe Etapablicu Mullen- -Hooker (uunty Trihune MimiiM- Mullen Xaper &gt; Xaper Xeli. - Xebraska ( Nebi ■ ar Messeii- Xebi i-ka City Tribune Nabraaka &lt; &gt;\ ka Htgi- N.hawka Xeligh Leailer IMi«h Xeligb KeKister Xeligh Voeman n Gazette li«b Seh New. Newman Grove Herald Newman •' Vwinaii (Stove Madison Coaaty Reporter Neunmii (i 'ewport Republican Newport "iobrara Tribune Niubrara 'urtolk Anzei^er. German Norfolk 'orfolk Daily New- Norfolk "orfolk I'i Norfolk Norfolk TimesTritj&gt;. Norfolk North Bend Bagta North Ben.l rrth Loup Loyalist North I»up rth Plitte Lim-oln County .lour nal North Plan orth Flatte Telegraph North Plat orth Platte Tribune North Hat Oak News Oak akilale Sentinel Oakdale akland Independont Oakland Oakland Republican &gt; inkland oonto Re^i-ter Oeoato Odell M Odell Ogalalla | Ohmwan </seg>
            <seg id="p085">85 Omaha— American Homestead Omaha Omaha Bunkers Union Herald Omaha Omaha Omaha. Church and Home, ReligioasOmaha Omaha Commercial Omaha Omaha- Danske Pioneer, Danish Omah Omaha- Dansk Folketidende. DanishOmal Oniuha Druggist Omal Omaha Kntir]ii isi Omaha Examiner Omaha Omaha Excelsior ( &gt;mah; Omaha- Farm Magazine Omah; Omaha Fraternal Journal Omaha Omaha- Good Will Tiding! Omah; Homeless Children's Advocate Omah; Omaha Hospedar, Bohemian Omah; Omaha Mercury Omaha Omaha Milling and Grain Mews Omaha Omaha Nebraska Farmer Omaha Omaha— Nebraska Tribune Omah; Omaha Daily News Omah; Omaha— Monthly Tidings Omaha Omahan Omah Omaha- Oaveta Amerika, BohemianOmaha i Pokruk Zapadu, Bohemian Omaha Omaha Posten, Swedish Omaha Omaha Omaha l^nill Omaha ia Daily Record Omaha Omaha Hotel Reporter Omaha Omaha Retail Merchants Journal Omaha Omaha Royal Woodman Omah; Om»hn— Sovereign Visitor Omaha Omali. ,;i Farm .lourr wedish Omaha • imaha ■le Fxhilir Omah - ver Omal Omaha True &gt;ii e Omah ! « utieth Century FarinerOm Omaha Vlust, Bohemian Omah Omaha Western Laborer Omaha Omaha Western Scot Omaha Omaha — West lie-he Presse, German Omaha Omaha — Workers Tri-Citj Omahi Omaha World Herald Omah O'Neill Frontier ( I'Neill . Unit ( &lt;junt\ i Neill </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 Pawnee City Pawnee City Pawnee City Pender iee Republican Pander Repubh Pender Time* Peru Pointer Penilrr Peru Petersburg Inde\ Pierce County Call nty Leader Pilger Herald Petersburg Pierce Pierce Pilger Plainview News Plainview Plainview Plainview Republican PUtt- Ugaal Plattsmouth Journal Plattsmouth News- Herald Plymouth News lMatte I Plattsmouth Plattsmouth Plymouth Ei— Dixon County Leader Ponca them Nebraska Journal Ponca rose Record Primr^ Primrose Randolph Reporter Randolph Randolph Tim— Randolph Ravenna N Kavenna Red Cloud Red Cloud Rod Cloud Commercial Advertiser Red Cloud Red Cloud Nation Red Cloud loud— Nebraska &amp; Kansas Farmer and Breeder Red Cloud Red Cloud Signal Red Cloud Rad Cloud I '.lunty Argus Red Cloud Republican City— Harlan County Ranger Republican C Rising City Riverton Kiting City Independent Kiverton Review Kand Gazette ville Recorder Rowland Rushville Orchard K«Wl Orchard Ord Journal OrU OTd Quiz Ord Orleans Courier (Ml Oaoeola Polk Count&gt; DMMOM Osreola Oaceola Rwunl CKct-ola Osmond Keputilir.ui (Kmomt ri Herald Overtoil Oxford Standard Oxford Page Reporter Page Palmyra Item* Palmyra Papillion— San&gt;y County RepuhlicanPapillion Papilliun Time?. Papillion Pawnee Chief Pawnee ( Pawnee Press Pawnee C </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 Rushville Standard Rushville Kuskin Leader Ku-kin St. Edwards- Boone County AdvanceSt. Edwards St. Edwards Sun ... St. Edwards St. Paul Phonograph -Press St. Paul r'aul Present Truth St. Paul St Paul Republican St. Paul - Index Santee Agency- lapi I Same*' Agency Sargent Leader Sargent Schuyler ('•■sky Otaaor, Bohemian Scbuyl* Schuyler Free Lance .... Shuyler Schuyler Vnill Schnyk Schuyler Sun Schuvlt Scotia b Bluff Herald Scott's Bluff - Bluff Republican . Scott'l Bluff Scribner Nowi Scribner Scribner Rustler Scnhner Seward-Blue Valley Bla&lt;i&gt; sewanl Seward Dem(x-rat Sewanl I Nebraska Deutsche Farmer Zeitun^ Sewanl Shelby Sun Shelby Shelton Clipper Shelton Shickley Herald Shikley Sholes Signal Sholea Shubert Citizen Shubert Sidney Republican Sidney • ■&gt;• Telegraph Sidney- Silver Creek Sand Silver South Omaha Daily Drovers Journal Stockman South Omaha South Omaha Independent South Omaha ■i Omaha Labor Gazette South Omaha i Omaha Mid West Eagle South Omaha So. Omaha Nebraska Daily DemocratSouth Omaha South Omaha Plow Share South Omaha South Omaha Republican Soutl. Omaha i Omaha Stockman s Brand South Omaha South Sioux City— Dakota County Record South Sioux ( itv Spalding Enterprise .dding Spalding Sentinel SjialdinK S[&gt;encer Advot^ate Spencer Spencer Reporter Spencer Springfield Monitor Springfield Springview Herald Sprii </seg>
            <seg id="p088">T u 1 ■ha ( 11 Pick Storkvillt l{i'|iuli. Straus Rei&gt;orter Stminslmr Stl'olllhlmi', Stromsbar Stuart Stromnhnnt •'nun \i«- Stuart Sa peri&lt; Su|M-rii Suptri&lt; ior .limrmil tjiericir Philatelic \\&lt; t ,V&lt; nit-r Lai - hi New mix-rat Svracu» . ribane Tainiira Ki i Table U. Talma^' Tamora raylor ( 'larion Taylor ■ hii-fti feiMimi* unlit v .1 lTeruniM'h 11 riinmoh Juhntioi tiiinc C'oantv Tri maeh Tekamali Ttkainali tonl riUen uah Burt Com \ Herald iiiirna ui Mill Ki'puhli man Tildin ■ Tildfii Sewn Tilci.n Tohian Tobiaa Trenton Tryoo lint- &lt; 'uiinty Trvmi llranhii - Dispatch L'lVHI L'nadilla I'mon 1'iuulilla fniv. .ii </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 Kversity Weaiayaa nid Eagle University Plare I'pland Ctica Eitine Democrat itine Republican y Enterpri - iraiso Visitor Valentine Valentine Valley Valparaiso Yerdel Verdel Outlook . Verdigris Citizen Verdigria Progres Verdon Vedette Wahoo Dcanocral Verdi rgis Verdigris Yerdon WahiHi Sumidfrs County New Era Wanoo Wasp Berield Republican ninKton Post Waketield Washington Waterbury Waterloo Wauneta Bi (iaz»-tte UeiiKK-rat Wayne Herald Wayne Republican \\ w w iMineta MM nyne ay ne nyne W W Eing Water Herald ing Water Republican •rn Wave eeping Water eeping Water ■stern W West Point— (.'timing County -Demo .rat W •st Point ■t Point— Nebraska Volksblatt (term an I'oint W.st Point Wilber i'oint Republican Wilber Listy, Bohemian Wilber Republican Wilber Wilber W ilcox Wileox Wilbar— Saline County Democrat ■ v Banner Wilcoz Herald Wilsonville Review Wilsonville Winside Winttide Tribune Wisner Chronicle Wisner Wisner Wolbach Wolbach Advertiser Wood River Interests Wood River Wood River Wymore River Sunbeam Wymore Arl&gt;or State Wyniorean Wymore York York Democrat York Republican York Utica Sun Wahoo \Vuh&lt;Hi Wahoo i bury Criterion . Iim) (iasette i Free i're' </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 York Teller York Times York York Yutan Conaomers' Commercial Cy clone Yutan NEWSPAPER SUPPLIES American Prei#&gt; Asso Omaha, II Hi Karnam NOVtLTIES RUBBER STAMPS, ETC Cooke &amp; Co Omaha, 1121 Farnaa Newell Novelty Oo Lincoln. 12-1 No 1J I Manufacturing ( 'o FtaberMcUill Manufacturm Newton, C M Omaha. WI Bo II &gt;maha. 2420 N North Platte Omaha Paraphernalia House Th'irp.' * Ool, Thomas .? Omaha. 411 So. 19 Unooli OPTICAL GOODS Agnew. D. G . and A. I be Optical i Omaha. Ill Omaha, 21H So. 1H Oraaha. 214 H meson ft Co. .1. ( OVERALLS SHIRTS, SKIRTS, ETC Bomow 8hin Co Omaha. 8024 Karnam Bryne &amp; Hammer Dr&gt; Cahn. Albert Omaha. 1113 Howard Omaha. 1322 Farnam College View Tailorir . Harris Custom Shirt 1 Harrison. \V H College View Lincoln, IM So. 11 Omaha. 1524 Dodj?e Herman Brothtrs Manufacturing CoLincoln. 301 So. 10 Inter Ocean Shirt Factory Kellev, Thomas - Lincoln. 24 and O Omaha. Ml No. 1H K( tr.ih. mi Manufacturing In Overall and Shirt Co . Martin 'maha 61 : Lincoln. 14(M) I Omaha. 1.1 Hi Harnev lie Skirt Factory Miner. B Lincoln. 123ti N Humlxildt Princess Manufacturing ( Omaha M. E Omaha, 1 101 Dougla* PAINT AND GLASS n Paint and Color Co Lincoln, mi M Midland Olawt and Paint Co Omaha, 1610 Harney Omaha Paint and Glass Co ■ al Oil and Paint Co Omaha. UII Dodge Omaha, 1015 Jones Nebraska Paint and Load ■ Lincoln. 308 O Western Glass and Paint Co Lincoln. 301 So Lincoln. 301 8a 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 PAPER BAGS SEE BAGS PAPER BOXES- SEE BOXES PAPER -WRAPPING Carpenter i'afx Omaha, N.E. Corner 12 and PASTE Kin Strain Fiitttu Co a Steam Pa- Lincoln. H(m \V Oniaha, 2210 Coming PATENT MEDICINE, STOCK FOOD, ETC. Acneine Pharmacal Co Omaha. .VHi So. 16 Australian Eucalyptus Chem Co Omaha. U02 Jackson Omaha, 1301 Farnain Wilber Omaha. 3 Krug Blk. Omaha. 1418 Harney Omaha. 120fi No. 24 Omaha. 202 Brown Blk Fairbury rin Drug Co J. H Chimney Rock Medical Co Crescent Chemical Co Bdwanls. C. M Bka Chemical &gt;urv Stock Food Co (ierman Stock and Poultry Remedy Co Goodrich Drug Co Haller Proprietary Co Huffman Manufacturing Co. . W.L Omaha, 609 So. 13 Hunt and Wright. Z. and H. Mfg. Co Wymore Imperial Stock Food Co Omaha, UU2 .lurks.. n Iowa Hog. Cattle and Powder South Omaha. 608 L Ki Ho-Ma Medicine Co Lee Co. , George H Falls City Omaha, llir&gt; Harney Omaha. «0» So. H (•a Stock Food Co cal Chemical Co ■s- Dillon Drug Co Era Stock Food Co Eoru Chemical ('&lt; ital Remedy 0B less Stock Powder Co sr Ryerson Hoobler Co Stock Food Co South Omaha. 407 No. 2 t Omaha. 1523 Farnam Omaha. 1441 No. M Omaha. 902 Jackson li rand Island Falls City Omaha. 1112 Howard Omaha. 80U So. 16 Lincoln. MM O Riggs Pharmacal Co Rightmeyer, August Robbins. F. B Gretna North Loup Stalnaker Co. J. L Omaha, SitU No. M Omaha. 1507 Howard Omaha, 10 Creigbton Blk Lincoln, 1525 P Standard Stock Food Co Thompson Co . . I'ngles Hoggette Co South Omaha. 817 No. M Omaha. 2702 Cuming Blair </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 I'nitad Mutual Pharmaeal Co Fairbury Vulcan Chemical Oe Omaha Omaha Dnplexopbone Manufacturing Co Lincoln. 129 So. 11 PICTURE FRAMES AND MOULDINGS Omaha. 1~&gt;19 Douglas Omaha. 1614 Izard H,*,.,. A PICKLES Thieasfn, Hennan Omaha, 3101 So. 24 PLATING Adler &amp; Welna Omaha, 14t»6 Howard PLANING MILL PRODUCTS Adams &amp; Kell. Anchor Planing Mill Automatic Threshold O&gt; Balback &amp; Hagedorn (n Beatrice Planing Mill Co Bfctes Planing Mill Omaha. 1529 .Sherman Are South Omaha. 2? and 7. Elgin Omaha, II and Cuming Beati I South Omaha Bloom Co , Alfred Omaha, 1.502 California Lincoln, 601 M Curtis and Bart Ditbrow &amp; Co M A Omaha, 1002 No. 12 Lincoln. 241H N Enterprise Planing Mill Co Erwin, E Nebraska City York -ler &amp; Chesman Kandolph Seward Wilaon, David J Omaha, 3«4O No. 4« Zeller* Stock Food Co Hooper PATTERNS AND MODELS (Vhrl.v I Omaha, HOB Jackson I. William A Omaha. MM Jackson PAVING Barter Abjitaalt Pavii ... Omaha. M McCague Bl \il City C.niHiit Oo Lincoln Hatnel. (&lt; Umaha, Mil Dm Bitulithic • Omaha, f.rxi Bee Buildin. MmhI Kn-id ('&lt;&lt; Lincoln, 1127 y Scheffel. Milliain (iran&lt;l Island Trirnwnnh Paving Co Tt-cumseh </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 Clark Johnson &amp; McLean Co \ Omaha, 6th and Jones .Omaha, MIS Vinton Raster, H. .1 Neligh Lincoln Sash and Door Co Lincoln, '21 &amp; Y Kwig, A. ( a, c. l Arlington Columbus Norfolk Norfolk Planing Mill Omaha Wood Working Co Parks, Johnson &amp; Parks Rouen bery, A Omaha, 1029 So. 18 South Omaha, K and 12 Omaha. 1501 Marcy Seebeck, John Snyder Standard Planing Mill O Thompson. W. M Lincoln. HiH No. 11 Fremont Thistlewait Bros Traub W. I Beatrice Gordon r.iiiiiaK. Chi. H rpstill. R. A Long Pine PLASTER ) psum Plaster Co Uyniort 1 PLEATING (t.iKlman Pleating Co Omaha, 200 Douglas Blk POP SEE "MINERAL WATER, POP, ETC. 1 PRESERVES SEE "CANNED FRUITS AND VEGETABLES PRESERVES' PRINTERS' ROLLERS Famous Roller Cc Omaha. 924 Farnam RAILROAD SUPPLIES Paxton Mitchell Co Omaha, 509 Ware Blk REED AND RATTAN GOODS Omaha Reed and Rattan Works Omaha, 1512 Howard Pearson Bros Omaha, BUT Leaven worth ROOFING, ETC. Barrick, Edward Hinman, H. L Omaha, 1616 ( 'liming Lincoln, 335 So. 9 Omaha. 151T Burt Omaha, 512 So. 12 Jones Rooting Co. . J. H Mica Roofing Co National Roofing Co Omaha, 11 Be. Nicholas and Omaha Cornice &amp; Building Material Omaha, 1911 Cuining Sunderland Roofing &amp; Supply Co Omaha, 1006 Douglas </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 RUBBER STAMPS SEE NOVELTIES. RUBBER STAMPS RUGS SEE "CARPETS AND RUGS" RUSTIC CHAIRS AND OTHER ARTICLES HoiK-hin M. K South Sioux City SADDLERY SEE "HARNESS AND SADDLERY SADDLE TREES AND NECK YOKES Allison Neligh Omaha Saddle Tree ( Omaha, tl and Ixx-UNt SAD IRONS SARATOGA CHIPS Perwd* &amp; Day Omaha. 2911 No. 24 SAW MILL PRODUCTS Forest Lumber Co Hamilton, Me loom, William C Noyes, C. H Alliance Florence St. Helena Decatur Tienken. Henry Xaper SCALES Schuster Scale* &amp; Machine \Y ork* Columbu SHADES Lincoln Shade Co Lincoln, 833 O SHEET MUSIC AND BOOKS OF MUSIC Park* Co.. .1 A York SHOE LACES AND MACHINERY Alhrecht. O. A. Co Omaha. :l* Barker Block SHOES SEE "BOOTS AND SHOES - SIGNS, LODGE SUPPLIES, ETC. Carleton R Omaha. 218 So. 14 Lincoln Lincoln Sign Works Omaha Gunning System Waller Display Co Omaha, 1409 Harney Omahu. Ittl Farnam Omaha. 1510 Howard Zaran, John W Jubilee Iron ('■&gt; Omaha, 150T&gt; JadWM </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 STEEL SHOT, BAR LEAD, ETC Lawrence Shot &amp; Lead Co South Omaha. 2fl and A Omaha Shot and Lead Works Omaha SLAUGHTERING AND DRESSING MEAT Armour &amp; Company Cudahy Packing Co Duehreen Co. , Fred South Omaha South Omaha Omaha e Packing Co. , Henry iman Kosher Meat Co lnnger, B. M South Omaha South Omaha Beat i . Morton -Gregson Co Naegele, H -ka Citv Omaha. 4261 So. 16 South Omaha Omaha Packing ( Swift &amp; Company Smith Omaha SMELTING AND REFINING Omaha 1518 Dodge Omaha Plant American Smeltiu .V Refining C Omaha SOAP Eins Bros. &amp; C .rd Brady Co ing Companie Omaha. US Hickory Omaha. 719 So. II South Omaha STARCH Bince Starch Co onal Starch d Omaha. 2022 Farnam Nebraska City STONE QUARRY - A: Mayne Blue Springs STRUCTURAL AND ORNAMENTAL IRON AND WORKS Canon, Cleeve &amp; Son Oonnela &amp; Bros. O Omaha 218 So. 18 Omaha 2025 Farnam Pazton &amp; Vierling Iron Works Omaha U. P. R. R. &amp; 17 SUGAR AND MOLASSES American Beet Sugar C( Fairchild Bros Grand Island Endicott A Syrup &amp; Preserving Co .. South Sioux City SUSPENDERS AND DUCK LEGGINGS Nebraska Suspender F Kearnev </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 tl TAGS INDEX Smith Charles C Exeter TILES SEE 'MANTELS, TILES, FLOORS TINWARE, TIN ROOFING, ETC. Baker. Leon Brennan, Neil -unut-1 Unwell Bros Blair Lincoln. 140 No. 10 O Xeill Sutton Fairbnry Fairlnirv tvenaugh. DM Her. John Lincoln. 14*8 () Beat r i Lock. Ira NMt, Albert Omaha. 717 No M raven t.man &amp; Pet'hner nby, R. B Naketield Ravage. Edward Spear &amp; Co . \\ . L ii. William Simonson &amp; Norby Sinhold, Theod' Western Tinw.. Omaha, 8H83 Karnan va Omaha. Mil Hamilton Omaha. MM Capitol Av Omaha. MIS Leavenwor Omaha. Mil Ma Lincoln, ttll O Stanton Wegener &amp; Bro TOOLS 1&gt; .match. Oswald Peterson T. W Omaha, 417 .Ion. Omaha. 7d."i Ijeavcnwortl TRUNK FACTORY Eay Trunk Factory i ha Trunk Factory irence A Omaha. Hi* Uougla.- Omaha. ISM Famam Lincoln, 1036 O TUBS-SEE "COOPERAGE- UMBRELLAS VINEGAR Haarman Bros ...Omaha. 1014 So. *&gt; Lincoln Lincoln Vinegar Work&gt; Voght, William In HI Pine Hickcri ng. t*. h Toihb. David Omah. Omaha, (!*&gt; So. it </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 WAGONS SEE 'CARRIAGES AND WAGONS* WELL CASING Dimmoek Manufacturing Co Newman Grove WHIPS i.lated Whip and Leather Co Omaha. MM So. It Smith Lockwood Manufacturing Go Omaha, iMO A me* At* WIGS, ETC (iriftith. D. S Omaha, 12 Frenzer Blk Laifaaa &amp; Boa, Thao Monheit. Mont/. Omaha, 1410 Howanl Omaha. 141! Karnam WIRE WORKS Hiroch. L. Omaha. BM So. It Omaha, till So. IK Omaha. 2127 Karnam Omaha. 1216 Harney Kpion Iron &amp; Wire Works 1a Wire &amp; Iron Works hie Iron &amp; Wire Works .YEAST-SEE "BAKING POWDER, YEASTS, EXTRACTS </seg>
            <seg id="p098">M </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 rCTORY OF MANUFACTURING ESTABLISHMENTS IN NEBRASKA ARRANGED BY COUNTIES ADAMS COUNTY Hastings Name or Establishment Kind of Bus^MvtA Adams County Democrat Bruecingsen, Fred Newspaper and job printing Machinery Burlington Car Shops Locomotive and car repairs Chicago &amp; Northwestern Shops Commercial Printing Co Locomotive and car repairs Job printing Electrical Concrete Fence Post Concrete fence post M A Marble, granite and stone woik Confection- er &amp; Smith Co. Haney ft Co. (J. H.) Hart, John H Saddles, harness and collars Cigars Bakery products Brooms Harnes Brick Hastings Brick Cc Kngs Canning Co ngs Cigar Co. . Canned vegetable Cigars Engs Light and Heat Co iik* Manufacuring Co. ngs Milling Co Illuminating gas and gas stoves Incubators and brooders Flour, feed and meal Brick Hastings Pressed Brick Co. . . . Hastings Sheet Metal Works Hewett ft Co Metal work Harness Hill, W. B Brooms Bakery products Johnson, W. F Journal Newspaper and job printing Cigars Kessler ft Co Lincoln Mill Co. "A" Mill. . Miller, Carl J Flour, meal and feed Monuments and grave stones Newspaper and job printing Newspaper and job printing Brick Kl Publishing Co rver Foundry and repair shop Job printing Reuner, P. R Republican . . Newspaper and job printing Carpets and rugs Richards. A. D Rom ft Son, (J. A. Gasket cutting machine Cigars Sinx &amp; Bloom Cigar Co. Ewell, J. G .ins, S. R ins, R. W PoJenske, Shellak &amp; Co. Feter Bros </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 I Name of Euablishmr ni K.nd..f Bnm^v Suyder A Brewer Cigars W. A Cigars ■ . William. Jr Bottled good Tribune Newspaper and job printing Van Patten . Bakery product Eestt-rn Bottling Works estern Brick Co .Soda and mineral waters, bottle Yager. P. W Bakery products Holstein r, Dan .Foundry and machine shop Juniata &amp; Son. (W. Hi and feed and .loli printing Kenesaw Citizen i|&gt;tr and joli printing Soiiulti, S ...Harnes: runk Nicholas Bakery produc HarneM Roseland i|&gt;n and job printing ANTELOPE COUNTY Clear-water Newspaper and job printing Elgin Automatic Threshold Co Lumber, sash, doors and blinds * N&lt; wi ,|&gt;er and job printing Jessup Jessup Roller Mills Flour and feed Neligh Allison, C. J Neck yokes Auringer &amp; Coleman Marble and stone work Brenton. T. H Brick Elkhorn Valley Creamery Co Butter Oilman. S. F. . Flour, meal, feed and offal Ke«ter, H. J ..Planing mill wor leader Newspaper and job printing McDonald &amp; McGintie Brick </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 Kof Establishment enna, W YcK'man .News] Job printing Oakdale tgo &amp; Northwestern R. R... wav Flour Mill and Eleva Railroad repair shops Flour, meal and feed Light anil heat lor C Oakdale Heat and Light Co Shively, Fred \V Printing and publishing Newspaper and job printing Sentinel Orchard Newspaper ami Job printing Cemenl blocks Orrhard Cement Work Tilden Kirkle Bros .v Dauphin v. 0. K Thorns. John A BANNER COUNTY Harnsburg and job printing BLAINE COUNTY Brewster ...Newspaper and job printing BOONE COUNTY Albion Albion Carpet and Rim ( Albion Km Milling Co s taper and job printin Albion Steam Bakery and other bakery product iaper and job printing Ker, I H. . H Brick and tile Electric light Torrey &amp; Baird Brepd an I other bakery products Cedar Cedar Rapids Improvement Co Outlook Flour, feed and meal Newspaper and job printing Kind of Busim Brick Plow, read, etr Baker) product ' &gt; and rim Flour uncl Rapids </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 ;::;; Kind of Busin Peter»burg Hallstead. Liewis K Flour, and grist mill products paper and job printing sburR Acetyli-i St Edwards HUi-klnirii * Ainsworlh Borwie County Advance. l.anrterman Bakery. . Flour and gri Nrwspaper and Job printing Bakery products BOX BUTTE COUNTY Alliance Eian&lt;f Bottling WorHs lance Pressed Brick Oa • irink Hiic-k and tile .Printing and publishing Bii'Thenstein. l»uis Land M. Re|&gt;air S l^oooniotivi- and car repairs l.uni Brick Crip Publishing Co .Newspaper and job printing .Printing and publishing Herald Krtx-rry. C. A onnar. F. B Steel tanks Bread and otht r bakery proc Bread and otlu r bakery prof Cement bricks and blocks -paper and job printing Panle.N. H. F. and F. H Rengier k Raymond . . BOYD COUNTY Anoka ns K S .Printint: -tud publishing Bnstow Entei | .Printing and iiublishing .Cigars Ensiling. William Butte td County Register te Milling Co -paper and job printing Flour and grist mill product Inter-State Electric Light * P &gt;w er Co Eletric lights and flour mill Newspai»er and job printing Cigars Gaiette Hutching- Grots Boyd County Courier Printing and publishing i]m i atul joli printing </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 Nam** of KMahliNhnient Kind of Burin* Lynch .Printing and publishing Boyd Count&gt; News Bakery products Cement blocks Clascniiin Bros Lynch Cement Block Co Lvnch Journal Newspaper and job printing Lynch Milling and Power Co Flour an i product! Raffertv &amp; Rafferly Brick Monowi Newspaper Mid Job printing Naper Newspaper and job printing Lumber Tienken, Henry Spencer Newspaper and job printing Bakery products Advocate Jerusek. V Flour and feed Artificial stone Mara &amp; Berens ■ r Miracle Block Co COUNTY BROWN Ainsworth Bone (reek Mills Finney, J. B Flour and feed Flour and feed ind lumber Harness Plum River Mills Spencer, John C. Star-Journal Newspaper and job printing Western Rancher and Brand Re corde Newspaper and job printing Johnstown Fairfield Mills ml lumber Long Pine Chicago &amp; Northwestern R. R Railroad repair shops Journal ■ per and job printing Flour and feed Kyner, Stephen H Upstill, R. A Saw mill products BUFFALO COUNTY Elm Creek Beacon Newspaper and job printing Elm Hydraulic Stone Co Artificial stone Journal Newspaper and job printing Neff Bros. Co Flour and feed </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 HllllllCllT in ii Nane of KklahHsbment Kind of Busine* Gibbon Davis * Son U. Hi Reporter Flour an.l Printing and publishin Kearney Flo.ir and Machine shop products . Publishing and priminj .Cigars and tobacco Cannon cii.\ i; Illuminatini &gt;rd. .lames Dm* 1 Marble an&lt;l granite 1111 Hardware novelties Priming and publishii Harness, saddi. Downing Saddlery Co., w trimmings Marble works Hani' t''o.. i.l 11 I rdie c K"ertiliier and Hlbbaid Brick liool. Hub Pub! ii, tl Brick Printing and publishin Printing and publishin Aitificial luiililii trnejr Artiflclal BUh« ii. .1 . E works Umi&gt; Ewa&gt; Bonling Works lei Monument Work Carltonated beve Monunients E)iaska Hollow Wall and Con - Cement blocks ■ I i Factory New Bra Standard Siispendei-s and duck l&lt; Printing and uublishin Rirth western Electric. Heat and Pow el Co nectric light Flour and gri rink F . W. H . . Johns Manufacturii.i ('■love manufacturing LottWOtlw and car re] Job printing, etc. ton PaciHc R. R. Co. Shops btert. HA n Poultry and Dairy Jour - nal Printing and publishing Ravenna Martin, A. B. Bakery products 8) Ivewer. . . Blirfc &amp; Kuhn Bros Bowker £ Eaton... y |iio&lt;1iici </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 d Nmme of feiublishmeni News Kind of Business Newspaper and job printing Locomotive and car repairs B. * M R. R Shops Rasmtissen. Henry.. . Bakery products . Brick Enna Brick Yarl - nna Creamery Co. . . . nna Flouring Mills. . . er Lumber Co. (J. L.) Butter Flour and feed Lumber and flour Shelton Clipper Newspaper and job printing Flour and grist Shelton Milling Co Sweetwater Richardson &amp; Co., \V. F Flour and feed BURT COUNTY Craig riser Priming and publishing Bakery products M. VV Decatur k, F. J Heral,] Flour, feed, etc Newspaper and job printing Sawed lumber Lyons ClMMSta, K S ■ Bros Bread and other bakery products Flour and feed H|&gt;er and job printing iper and job printing Oakland Anderson, Andrew Brick (iustafson, John Alfred Independent .Harvest, halters ami bridles Newspaper and job printing .Cignrs Johnson, Alfred. Johnson. M. W Lund. C. August Bakery products Soda ani mineral waters, bottle Oakland Cement Btona Manufac turlng Co Artiticia! stone Flour and feed Renard. Fred Republican Newspaper and job printing Struthers &amp; Son, (A.) Flour and feed Ks Creamery Co s Cas Co.... Butter </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 Kind of Bmhw Tekamah N»n)e 1 .tEsi»l.li»hnient Eichuler, Cha« mhall * Son t County Herald won. Joseph .... Bakery product Newspaper and job printing: i and electric lights Journal ■ r and Job printing BUTLER COUNTY Abie Flmir and feed Be 1 1 wood *p&gt;per and job priming Plain ylen&lt; HeHit - Artificial stou Brainard Clipper EwJck *. ■ton, W . Flourmlll product ir and feed Matoush, Frank rid saddles ..Mottled goods k, F I) David City Bahr. U P. Bakery products Barker Manufacturing Co U icultural imi-lements Bell ft Son ights Bushell. W. H tier County Press. . ng * Co. (George I ■ r and" job printing . Flour and feed &lt;; w Bakery product? Hawes £ Hrushka, Joseph C Ideal Ston. Oo ..Printing and publishing ..Artificial stone Newspaper and job printing Journal E.thewson Stone Co. . ind Kouii' ople's Banner . Artificial stone . . Newspaper and job printing Imperial Mills Mill products ble monuments Smith Garrison Argug Newspaper and Job printing Linwood Cerny, Joseph Clgara Rg, Howard i|M&gt;l&gt; J D. . Newspaper Mid i &gt;*&gt; printing </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 N&gt;ae of EKUMishment Kind of Buaiaes* Rising City rs, W. D. . Feed mill products Independent Newspaper and job printing San born. J. E Acetylene gas Surprise Citizen NewsiKiper and job printing Miller, George H Flour and feed Ulysses Dispatch Newspaper and Job printing Withers, Harry C Flour and feed CA8S COUNTY Eagle Newspaper and job priming Elm wood Elm wood Mill and K Leader-Echo 1. v utor Flour and leeil Newspa|&gt;er and job printing s, J. E Gas Greenwood Newspaper -nun Newspaper and job printing Louisville Courier Newspaper and job printing Nehawka Nehawka Milling Co Flour mill products Pollard &amp; Son (Isaac) ....Cider and vinegar Register Newspaper and job priming Plattsmouth Ahlrep, Georg&gt; Bie.xl an prod •ep, George. . . Bre.nl .m, I o v producl Bookmeyer, J. \V. . Cig.i Bookmeyer, J. \V .Cigars B. £ M. R. R. Shops Loc.miotive and car repairs B. &amp; M. R. R. Shops Loc.miotive and car repairs Craig, Henry M Ulo* Craig, Henry M .Glow Egenfoerger, Fred G Soda and ginger ale 0 Flour and feed ■nnberger, Fred G Soda and ginger ale C Flour and feed Merger, C. 1 Bakery products r, C. L Bakery products Journal .Wwspuper and job printing Kanka ft t'lich Cigars Kanka &amp; I'lich Mockenhaupt, C Brick Mockenhaupt. C Brick \o»-s Newspaper and Job printing I ork Baker Bakery products Pepperberg, Julius Cigars and clippings </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 Nanc or buNiument Kind of Busme- Plattsmouth Gas and Electric Light Co Lights tiK * Bajeck hal. James. Brooms, whisk and to] ITOllUCtS Schlappasse. John Herman . . . »ieser, Herman Weber. Willian Ornamental iron fencing Wiirl Bros Cigars Union I'JW Weeping Water Herald Newspaper and joh priming Flour and feed E Pitch * Halmes ursan, Louis C . publican CEDAR COUNTY m Belden . Bakery produc Newspaper and job printing Coleridge Blade Newspaper and joh printing Hartington / Carlson Broi Ear County News. . ar County Wachter ppell. A. C, il&gt;er and job printing i per and job printing Bread and other bakery pr Harness, etc. Foivater, A. B Herald -paper and job printing Harness, i Lydlck. M D Street A Laumert. .Brick Laurel Ail voca it- rapaper and job printing .Cigars Kaufman, Fred Laurel Milling Co Flour mill products Randolph Cigars Bricks Hammon. James J. ... Hammond A Matheny Hill. Jesse A Planing mill products Bakery products G. W aper anrt joh printir Cigars tpaper ami joh printing N&gt;l8on. Mi&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 Ntroe of Establishment Kurtz ft Farnum. . Reporter Kind of Buiine* .Bakery products .Newspaper and Job printing .Marble monuments Sommerg, L Thorndike &amp; Reed .Flour and feed Newspaper and Job printing St. Helena William C Joseph . . . .Sawed lumber and custom sawing .Lager beer St James /•lie] Mills . Flour ami CHASE COUNTY Champion Flour and feed Imperial KB County Tribune Is, J. F. . . . Newspaper and job printing Harness, etc Republican Newspaper and job printing Wauneta Blair &amp; Pi Flour ami feed Newspaper and H job printing CHERRY COUNTY Cody Cow Bo\ Newspaper and job printing Valentine job printing -paper and .Flour and feed .Electric lights Newspaper and .Pop • Clinton, S. F Minnechaduza Mills Republican job printing Webb, A. F Webb A Co .Bottled goods CHEYENNE COUNTY Bayard .Newspaper and job printing Bridgeport paper and Tanks </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 S»me of bubluhmem Kind of Iluain«» Placte Valley News Newspaper and job printing • r, Georgie Cigars Lodgepole Newt-paper and jol) ]&gt;rinting Sidney Republican Newspaper and job printing Telegraph Newspaper and job printing Inion P'cifio R. R. Shops LoeOMOtire and Car repairs CLAY COUNTY. Clay Center i "enter Mfg. Co Agricultural implements Johnson Co. i.M. Mi Incubators and brooders Orr Bros Floiir and feed Patriot Newspaper and job printing Poultry Gazette Sun Newspaper and job priming Newspaper and job printing Deweese Hubl&gt;ell £ Son- Flour and feed Hustler News]ia|&gt;er and job printing Edgar Cook Bros Bread and other bakery product! Edgar Canning Co Canned corn and tomatoes Edgar Electric Light and Power •Co Electric light Graham, William H Brick Norwood, Nathaniel T Flour and feed Post Newspaper and job printing Sun-News Newspaper and job printing Fair-field Fairfleld Creamery Co Butter Herald * Newspaper and job printing Independent Newspaper and job printing Lindsay Incubator Co Incubators and brooders Nebraska Incubator Co Incubators and brooders Wilson, Lou Flour and feed Glcnville Warner, L. H Newspaper and job printing Harvard Courier Newspaper and job printing </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 Maine of EstablisAment Kind of Business Gregg, P. K Cigars Harvard Milling and Power Co, . . Flour and feed Purdie A. Beneway Rockhill, Cyrenens .Bakery products .Harm Ong MfK. Co Br(X)nis Sutton ■ y, Samuel Stmv pipes, copper, brass and ware (Jemar, P. .1 Hunxiker. S .Electric lights .Brick .Newspaper and job printing .Newspaper and job printing ReRiste Kble Incubator Co. . . n Electric Light an Incubators and brooders 1 Pow &amp; Son (George) Wieden. W. \V Floor and feed Bakery COLFAX COUNTY. Clarkson Anton Odvarka Printing and publishing Electric light E;son Electric I'lani Lson Milling Co. . ensky, Charle*. . . Id Flour ami Cigar Newspaper and job printing Howells Bagels, Henry Cigar Howells Electric Plant. Howells Milling Co Electricky Flour ami Journal Newspaper ami job printing Soil. Wm. P. C . . Bakery products Leigh Jenny Bros Cheese World Newspaper and job printing Schuyler Harm. Joseph Flour and feed Bergman, E Granite and marble monuments v Obzor Newspaper and job printing Ensles, J Cigars Lance Newspaper and job printing Harxke, George Cigars </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 Name of BuaMiihmeot Kind of Bnshw Kovar, P. J , Saddles, harness and repairing Krivohlavek. Wesle&gt; Pop, ginger a '■ I mm Joseph Cigars Pesek, Prank J Bread and other bakery products Quill . Newspaper and job printing Schraeder £ Arnold Bread and other bakery product* Sohuyler Brew*-- Beer and mall Schuyler Creamery Co Butter Schuyler Electric Plant. . Electric Ugh Schuyler Harness Co Harness Sharka, John Cigars Sun .Newspaper and joli priming Abbott * Xieman Flour and feed CUMING COUNTY Bancroft Harvet R l| \. »- Newspaper and job printing Ockander, Jaco!&gt; Hour and feed Wininr. C \V \. tylene eas Beemer Buhk, Henry Brick and tile Doeecher. C. ( Times Flour and feed ipei and job printing West Point Cuming County Democrat. fuming County Democrat Newspaper and job printing Newspaper and job printing Pop Edinger. J. A. . .1. Charies- Edinger. J. A Po|. la, Charies Bakery products Bak«*ry product Nebraska Volksblati ska Volksblatt ind job printing Artificial stone Newspaper and job printing i. W T. 8 Artificial stone Premossil, John Premossil, John » products Bakery prodnrt:- Radler. H S Radlei. H S Republican Newspaper and job printing Cigirs Newspaper and job printing Reznk-hek, Anna '"oint Bottling Works i'oint Brewery Association. Point Electric Light and Power Co oi»t Milling Co Oigirs Reinichek, Anna l*oint Botiling Works Bottle beer Bottli l^gei West Point Brewery Association. I-ager leer Point Electric Light and Power Co Electric light Electric light r'oiBt Milling Co Brick and floi.r Brick and floi.; Wobte. A Foundrj' products Foundry products Wostonpal. Joseph Wostonital. Marble and granite monuments Marble and granite monuments Newspa|&gt;fr anil job printing </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 Name of Establishment Witner. Baehr, Henry Bakery product Benxern, Charles F Chronicle . Brick Newspaper and job printing Free Press Newspaper and job printing i le, Jacob Bakery product Electric Light Plant , Roller Mills. Ek-ctric lights Flour and feed CU8TER COUNTY Anselmo no Rollei Mills ami Eleva tor (■&lt;■ Flour .mil feed Analey Ansley Electric Light &amp; Power Electric light Ansley Electric Light ft Power Flour and feed Chronicle-Citizen Newspaper and job printing Bakery products Mauler, Joseph Newspaper and job printing Nebraska n Broken Bow Broken Bow Cigar I Broken Bow Milling Co Conrad, Otis H Cigars .Flour and feed .Water tanks, windmills, towers, • r County Beacon Newspaper and job printing r County Chief Newspaper and job printing Custer County Republican Newspapti and job printing Uillings. William Bakery products Glaze ft Co Marble works Longeran. M. P Flour and feed McClure, E. F Flour and feed Schaefer. William B • .Cigars Wateameder. W Mineral water and pop ern Light and Fuel Co Callaway Callaway Milling and Mfg. Co Flour and feed Courier-Tribune Newspaper and job printing I»iip Valley Queen Newspaper and job printing </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 Nsaoe of JDMMtahment Kind of BuatMMi Georgetown Oorgetown Roller Mills and Power Co ...Flour and sxisl Mason City Deardorf £ Dnk' Flo.ir and feed S-.i Newspa|&gt;er and Job printing Oconto Register Newspaper and job printing Sargent Harris, C. I Artificial stone 1^-aili-i . \fWs|iH|M-r and job printing DAKOTA COUNTY Dakota City Dakota City Milling Co Flour and feed Herald Newspa|&gt;er and job printing North Nebraska Eagle Newspaper and job printing Vand.-, Zedde J Bakery product Homer Combs, 8. A. and F. E Flour and feed Davis ft Co Flour and feed Echo ... Newspaper and job printing Hubbard 8. Q Comb ft Son Flour and feed Jackson Criterion Newspaper and job priming Jackson Roller Mills Flour and feed Times .. Newspaper and job printing South Sioux City Houchtn, M. E Rustic chairs and other articles Lamb Manufacturing Co Iron, etc National Syrup and Preserving Co Beet syrup and preserves Record Newspaper and job printing DAWE8 COUNTY Chadron Broghamer ft Pitman Brick and tile </seg>
            <seg id="p115">115 Nasae of Establishment Chadron Electric Light and Power Co. Electric light Chadron Roller Mills. Flour and feed Chicago, Northwestern R. R Railroad repair shops Danley, W. A Bakery products Newspaper and Job printing Metzler, l-oiiis. Cigars NVwspaiKT and joh printing Crawford Rulk-tin Newspaper and job printing Hall, I^eroy Flour and feed Townsend. W. S Bakery products Tribune Newspaper and job printing DAWSON COUNTY Cozad Cozad Roller Mill Co Flour and grist Local Newspaper and job printing Tribune Newspaper and job printing Farnam Echo Newspaper and job printing Gothenburg Electric Roller Mill Co Flour and grist mill product* Hedman Bros Machine shop Independent Newspaper and job printing Platte Valley Milling Co Flour and feed Sun Newspaper and job printing Sundin. F. A Harness Lexington Bruse &amp; Nisley Marble and granite monuments Clipper Citizen Newspaper and job printing Corder, J. F Bakery products Hewitt, P. J Harness and repairs Islington Mill and Elevator Co. . Flour and feed Pioneer Newspaper and job printing Roe &amp; Milter. Smith, R. B.. Wnitten. F. M Artificial stone Artificial stone Harness, etc. Overton y^ v v w r • * ■ m m y 1 t </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 Kind of Burine*. DEUEL COUNTY Chappell Newspaper anil job printing DIXON COUNTY Allen News|&gt;aner and jol printing Concord printin Dixon tx.jn Koll.-i Mills •raid .Flour ana r and mm Emerson tier-son Brick Works terprisr ■ i&gt; &amp; Zopi Martinsburg .Butter ■ nstein &amp; ■ ( V Flour and feed I Newcastle Lund. Ole P. . Harness Newspaper and joh rintine Ponca Flour and feed . Hani Aowa Mill Co.. . Berry, Edward J Dixon County Leader torn ;&gt;aper and job p irintiim Brick Nelson. John P and D. J... Northern Nebraska Journal Ponca Creamery Co Newspaper and job printing Butler Sohoer, Charles Bread and other bakery products Schmidt, W Marble and granite works Standard Incubator Co Incubator! Wakefield Anderson, L. O Wagons Chi Ids. George. Harness William Pop, soda wai. Cxon County World rkins. R A .Newspaper and j»»i .Bakery prodnc i l&gt;er and job printing Brick |i &gt;r and job priming Plo'ir mill product! </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 Rl of KMaMishment gan. J. O Kind of Business Flour and feed Quimby, R. B Republican . Tin work, tin and bicycle repairs Newspaper and job printing Sch^ogge, Mrs. H. A I'iikery products DODGE COUNTY Ames ard BeeJ Sugar Co .Granulated and raw sugar, molasses Dodge Hroiihmi &amp; Mamedaj Brick Cigar iper and Job pi inline Milling and Grain Co Flour and fe&lt; Fremont Krican Bottling Oo strong. W. W Atlanta Canning Breitenfeld, Henry G. (E. £ Bro*n Bros. &amp; Koyen Brown Milling I : frull anil vegetables Bakery products Inipl.- nients Flour ami Job printing Kl Bel t nt an. A. .1 Ront Artificial Stone (So ont Brewing Co Arfifi.-i, n« Kont Carriage M . (.nt Cider I Ront Concrete Stone Oo ont Cieaniery Co Artificial stout Hu nt Foundry and Machine nt Gas &amp; Electric Light 1 1 1 ii : ii in hi; ( ■ int Milliiu ■ ui j Saddl' irnic* Wor Floii! strap work, elc Galv. cornice and metallic sky - liul Bmond &amp; Stephens Co W Job printing Brick (F M.) &amp; Cloos, I Fencing Carpenter. Ueors Criterion BoHled gon Kner, \V R Job printing IK&lt;&gt; &amp; Northwestern R. R Railroad repair hso| : Emil. ... ... .Hani. Machine Bbop prodiu an an:l gasolini </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 Kind of n— &lt;ni« Cigars Name of ttuMtrtment Hetn * Co. (Bdw. Hi Herald Newspaper and job printing Marble and granite monuments Hides, tallow and grease Hodges and Baldwin... Hoebener * Co. (J. H&gt; Kassebaum. William... Kuntzman. Margaret... Marr ft Son Cigars Bakery products Soda water, etc. National Grain Growers' Journal Old Reliable Cement Stone Co.. Parlor Furniture * Mattress Co. Peterson, Peter Printing and publishing Artificial stone Lounges, couches, mattresses, etc Light farm wagons and repairing News|&gt;a|&gt;er and job printing PUtte Rlrer Zeitung Pratt. M K. I Golden Rod Cream- BiMter ery i tens Tent and Awning Co ston Milling Co Tents and awnings Flour and feed Cigars and smoking tobacco Sheet metal works and cornice Incubators and brooders Sash, doors, mouldings, etc. paper and job printing Butter tubs Saeger ft Sons Eith. iF M.i * Son. . e Hatch Incubator Co mpaon. F M Tribune Voceinng &amp; So h ii r ma n Weikel. Henry Brooms Bakery product Wolr., George F Hooper Bayer. Carl Brick Brick tl&lt;W Brick Manufacturing Co crete Stone Co Artificial stone Bakery product Flour and feed Bakery product Hoffman. C Hooper Roller Milling Co. Reed. Thomas A Sentinel Newspaper and job printing Artificial stone Stroh. Alfred Pop, mineral. so&lt;U water, etc Cigars Kling. Lou. gle. Godfrel S«o?k food Kellers Stock Food Co North Bend K , j Newspaiwr and job print ing Newell. N. J Bakery product North Bend Cement Works Artificial stone and brick North Bend City Gas Works Gas North Bend Milling Co Flour and feed Scribncr Armbi.ster, C. M Cigars </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 Establishment Brothers Kind of Businew Flour and feed Bakery products Cigars Eron, g.. pe, Frits. News-paper and job printing Bbrer Brick Manufacturing Ifr ( i.. Brick Newspaper and job printing Flour and feed Witt Bio Snyder Senneiik r. Conrad Sesbeck, John Flour and feed Planing mill products Brick Snyder Brick Manufacturing C DOUGLAS COUNTY Ntnrmpttfmt and job printing Flour and feed Srhleip. Chart Benson ■fcGoire, JoM^k Meal, feed, etc NewsiHiiter and job printing Florence Hamilton. M. C .Saw mill products Hollett, Mrs. M K Items Bakery products Newspaper and job printing r * Son Flour and feed Irvington Anderson Bros .Flour and feed Millard Cisrn Brick Omaha Acneine Pharmacal Co Medicin Adams &amp; Kellv Co Planing mill products Agnew, D. G., and A. I Optical goods and repairing Arbrecht, °- A - Co Shoe laces and machinery Albrecht &amp; Son (Ad) Musical instruments KBennington nKt&lt;m MannfacliirinK Co Hens' nests [t . . \V«&gt;ili9iit)r K Gibson ngtou &amp; Missouri R. R Railroad repair shops N'aehtigal, Umis Svhutte, Carl... Adler &amp; Welna Placing Alamito Sanitary Dairy Co Butttr </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 ■in- in and escapes rv priwin nit- roofing n 11 t in tt of Buablishinem Ifa Meal Co... Kind of BuaiMM Alfalfa meal Baking powder Allen Bros Co American Homestead Newspaper and job i Newspaper supplies Fence trican Press Association hor Fence Mfg. 0 Cenoo-Mlllard Co. iven. (i .Carriages and wagons .Fire doors, shutters a . Pillow* tilyn. Maxwell tbM«l Furs lisa Eucalyptus Che mical Medieii Gasoline lamps Extracts, etc Process engraving Lumber, harness, etc Pinups and windmill Bakery products H Baker Brother K-nnfacniri: Kback * Hagedorn Co .luff. • S Planing mill products Confectionery and WaV Bakery products Banlin. Frcirick H KixT Asphalt Paviim Co num. f I Asphalt pavins unps Baroch. I-ej Iron and wire work Gravel, asphalt and Job printing k, Edward Barton. G. I t Monumental ton Drug Co Works Marble monuments Etiic. htold. Ch. kman. .lost ph Job printing v Printing &lt; D Book and job printing Dally newspaper and Bags ami bagging Carriages and v&gt; t.ha Bag Co . William Erani. Kred. . . •lin. Merman CUai&gt; Engs &amp; Sons I A. S.) . t. r Denial supplif: Knit §o Eerup. William ison ft Haas Clean :i e works Machine shope HI oni Co. ( Alfred I . . Bloom ft Co. iJ F.I Planing mill products Uranite works tionery Knuleboft. John Baker&gt; products ic light fixtures Burgfss-Gramlen Co. Burgee atlirtCo.... </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 t Name of ICnlahlishnie Kind uf HiiMnrss Envelopes Burkley Envelope C&lt; BurUey Printing Ct Job printing, book bindin Incubators Overalls ('air Bread and other bakery i&gt;rodu&lt; Hid other bakery products Breul and other bakery pi Carina, C. K ton. R. . . -son &amp; Rant &lt; interior In in is hi up cornice works K Home . Keli - . Couc Kred \V. . . . ColomlK), Kmaiine Confectionery Pie ( Wl Ku I imps and ( ings C Corneer B .Brict Harnes Creamery supplit Patent medicines Hani' mi ins. Jam* i per ;ind job printing Printing an.l publishing Debarbie ■ction* Defiance Starch ( ■&lt; Dellecker, O. K ( Sash, doors, blin- B.ikerv products telas, 'Mrs I. B. las Printing Co : inting Burr Incuhator Co Bjrrae &amp; Hammer Dry (ioods C Cahn. Albeit . . Caple. A M«n printing Wrapping paper Carpenter F Cemeal Wacbii Champion Iron &amp; Wire Works Ba'ik ind offlc« railing!, '" Extracts, baklm Chimney Rock Medical Co Medicine Christensen, Christian Brwri and oth"r bakery pro Chrisieiisfn. J. S Breac 1 and ot: Christopher, Ceorge R. .Chan Whip and Learh Cornish &amp; Co. (Alfred) Creamery Package Mamifaotur ing Co en I Chemical O r, Frank i nmmtns, Ja | II Confectionery Co Ire Cream, candy an 1 liakery pr Dansk Folketidend Danske Pioneer. . . Dlckraan, Mrs K Dlsbrow &amp; Co. I M A I </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 at te of BstkblisAineni p, U G mini if niMtnni furniture and mi i re 88es Drake-Williams-Mount Co Drtebus Candy Co and sheet iron products Confectionery Drummond Carriage Co Drusstgo. V Carriages, wagons and repair: Cigars .Sausages t?hrsen Co. (Fred) an, U. F Job printing Dyball, R. W. A Catherine Edwards, C. M 1 candy and ice cream mes Bggers-OFhng Co Elsaaser. Herman Paper and cigar hox€ Cigars Eisele. H .Cold and silver refined an num rtsold Kierson Manufacturing Co. terprise .Agricultural implements .Newspaper and job printing .Cornice works K meter, G. F . kson, Peter M Bakery product Eureka Chemical Co. Ewing, Mrs. Addie. . Examiner Chemical preparation .Bread and othtr bakery produc .Printing and publishing Excelsior Fairmont Create Famous Roller Co.... Fanners' Magazine.... Printers' roller Printing and publishing trell *. Co d. Eilellu . Molasses, syrup and preserves .Marble monun;' Feenan ft Son (M. ••• Festner Printing Co . . Fink Printing O Fin:a&gt;~son. Samuel Flodman A Co. (P. E ) Forby Trunk Factor&gt; Fraternal Journal (f Bread and other bakery product* . . . Books and job printing Job printing Job printing Jewelry Trunks .Newspaper ainl job printing and repairing ..Jolj |irinting Frost, Harry Erdner Printing Co te City Mai rman Printing Co isler, Max ljq'ior Job printing ..Bird and fish food ( 'mars Getxschmann, C. H Gibbs, E. B ' i ii I *"S Eliam Printing Co ncoe Mills i printing ..Flour, feed, i . .Optical goods Globe Optical Co Godfrey Tobacco Machine shop procluc Bakery products q&gt;er and job printing Butter </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 Name of KMalihshment Goldman Pleating Co Goo Irich Drug I Kind or Butines-. Pleating Good Will Tidin Printing and publishing (ionncll.i &amp; Bra Gould &amp; Son (F. Pi Greater American Baker lireat Western Granite Works Western Type Foundry Cre.it Western Printing Co... Greenburg &amp; Wiseman . Br. ad and other baker; product .Monuments Broad and other bakery products Wigs, etc. Griffith, D. S Hale &amp; Co. (J. H HaJl, George N Bread and other bakery products Door devices Hambacher, Frederick Hatnel, Gust Cigars Ctnient sidewalks Hamling, F. M Art glass, tile, flooring, etc. Harness, saddles and collars Butter Picture frames Cigars Harm. Xellit Harrison, W H Haskins Bros. &amp; Co Haven, W. L .Bread and other bakery product .Cigars Hayduk, John Heaston, R. C Hene &amp; Co . . . Herzog. Harry Heyn, Mrs. S. Bread and other bakery products Cigars Harnes Cigars Harnes: Hibbler &amp; Co. (D.) Henry. Hofmann. Mrs. Antonia Hopson, W. B mil other bakery products Book an I job printing Horwich, Hem Ha me Picture frames and mouldin Newspaper an,! J3i&gt; printing ipfr and jab printing Fur and seal skin garments Iry Hubermann. H E. and E mann, A. B Hueck, Theodo Buttons Medicine Hfg Co I W ■inducts iicint's Ornamental moshic and marl&gt;le work liriok Electrotype plates ■lob printing Guggenmose, Caroline Haarmann Bros Weiss beer Pickies. vinesar, mustard sauces Haney &amp; Co. (J. H.I Harding Cream Co . . Hardy Co. (H.) Shirts Electric and nitohanical i work H(«s|«&gt;d.i Repo </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 y product Hill neks ami and hand etc iing, etc N »rnc of Establiuroenl KirKi..f Busine n gs Euntington ft Son &lt;l. Optical good Imlay, J. M Bread and other baker Stock food Imperial Stock Food Co International Manufacturing Oo. .ranite and Mar- Washing machine Monuments Iry ble Works tubson. Jai nson Bros Job printing Cigars Knson, George I. nson. .! N Bakery proiluc Johnson &amp; McLean Planing mill product Roofing tnes Roofing Co (J Hi risen sen. .1 P.. ry prodiif - C A Jubilee Iron Co Kiu, L. |. Sash and screen wo in' sad irons Iry Kaewener, Reinhold . Kapek Bros s smith Bread and other bak Kaplan, Samuel Karbach Automobile and Vehicle Co Carriages, wagons, til pairs and autom Bottled goods Kola Bottling Works Kelley, Thomas S.. Shirts Kennedy, J. R. Kenny. Vincent Kerr ft Mcllroy Elevators ihydrauli :s and engines Hats Shirts, pants, overall Bakery products Cat -Graham Manufacturing Co.. rchner, R J Men's boots and sho* Butter Erktndall ft Co. IF Pi rschbraun ft Son opp ft Bartlett &lt; Job printing, book bin Carpets and r«| Kocher. Fred Koops. Charle^ Kotera &amp; Co Kramer ft Chandler /schmar. F H. Kriehn, W. C Cigars Printing and embossing Job printing produc Book and job printing Book and job printing Krisel, Edward Krug Brewing Co. (Fredi Kruse. John. . Bakery product Kuenne. G. C Kuwitzky. Joseph Larsen-Baker Ice Machine Co. Machinery </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 tot Establishment C. R Kind or Bualne .Lumber, slat and wire fencing .Poultry and stock food and insec- Co. (Oeorge H.) ticide; E&gt;en &amp; Son (Theo. ) hart, R. A Wigs, Hakt iv produce Kis &amp; English is, Jacob... I and other bakery products Cigars Uddell, John Foundry products Knit goods Christian John. i anil other bakery products Tools, etc. Lomateh, Oswald l-oomis Theatre Ticket and E n vtlape 0 ukets and envelopes Fee.lniill products I.ucern Produce Co Lynstad. J. H Book and job printing Chip and bar laundry soap Job printing McCord-Brady Co McCoy ft Co McDonald. William and I \V E,afferty, Fred S Villiams Bros. . lory ft Co Carriages and wagons Curbing and gutterin Boiler compound Mangum ft Company .Job i rinting Marks Bros. Saddlery C .Harness, s iddleiy an 1 collars .Stock food . Barber supplies . Machinery Melchiorg, P Mercury . Newspaper, job printing, etc. Beer E; Bros. Brewing Co Martin. . . . Shirts Mica Roofing Co. Michalek, Joseph Roofing Bread and other bakery products Paints, oils and glass Eland Glass and Paint C land Publishing Co.... ing and Grain News. . itsky, Thomas 'o Job printing Printing and publishing Cigars Moller. P. G Ciga tarch Acetylene Gas C heit. Moritz Gas Machine: Hair goods 'o Printing and publishing Bakery products Monthly Tiding Mulligan, Thomas F Ephy ft Son (Andrew) rs-Dillon Drug Co. . . ?ele, H Carriages and wagons Hospital supplies, drugs, paints, Sausages Klonal Biscuit Co. ional Printing Oo .Crackers, biscuits, etc • r. job printing, etc ; ictil supplies, t&gt;rass and bronze work ta Stock Food Co hior, Hugo </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 etc products et products n wort orage Co Hirer &gt;nts . Albert Kind ut ' Tinware, and hardwa National Oil and Paini Co colon in oil and white lead National Roofing ( CIravel and slate roofing, tag par Publishing and printing F. I . . Nebraska Hi! uliihi. I D Nebraska Boiler Compound Co -ka Farmer Nebraska and Iowa Steel Tank Tanks ■ ska Stone Co rraska Tent and Awnr Awnings and tent Newspaper, job printing ind other bakery Stock food ivdar New Era Slock Food Co aper, job printing md other bakery products Klson, Anton. . [son. Nicholas ■ nufacturing Co OBri. ajr (D. J.) (&gt;ehrl. - and check i candv Patterns and mod lgines, etc. Bakery products Bake iv ;&gt;roducis Engine » I n. Chris J. Olson Bros and galvanized i Omaha Ice and Cold St&lt; Mattresses and pillows i engines . soda water Wood' Omaha Bale Tie Co. . . I Bedding Vorks •ling Work Kaha Brick Co »ha Candy Co Biuk 111 Carriage To; On all. Caskets Mat, Stone and Brick MfK. Co I«I siiinf ;ind bri I riming and publishin Artifiiial stone immercial e Stone Co tna Cornice and Ruilding Ma ■ R cornice manufac tha A Council Bluffs Street quipnie Omaha In On.ai.a Elect nc Light * Puwer Paving Boil&lt; r ("impound i mittens iltural news]ia|i ! candy tc.tmi </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 Kind of Business Kha Electrical Wort . Elevators, dynamos, etc. .Illuminating gag . etc Harness Kh.i Hvdraulic Pma B:-lck Co ha Ice and Cold Storage Co. ha l.iKlitninp Rod tic Electric B uk Distilled water Ice &lt; Milliue Co Omaha Muten Manufacturing Co Mirror Manufacturing Co. n Mittens Mirrors Printing and publishing Bags, etc. Paper boxes Omaha Paint and Glass Co. Oman;' PanjfcOTMlta Hoiis Omaha Pillow Co Oils and paints Novelties Mattresse Omaha Plant. American Smelt K| and Refining C'c ha Plating Co. . . ra Printing Co. Sm It ing and refining Electroplating Book and job printing, etc Kl and Rattan Works ha Rug Co iid rattan goods Rugs Omaha Saddle Tree C Saddle tre Omaha Shot and !&gt;&gt;acl Works Omaha Steam Paste Co 1-eal manufacture Paste Ea Structural Steel Works. . a Tank Manufacturing Co. . a Tent and Awning I Foundry supplies Tanks, etc. Awnings, tents, leggings, wagon covers, flags, rubber goods Omaha Trunk Factory Trunks Omaha Wire and Iron Work Omaha Wood Working Co. Wire goods', etc. Casings, sashes, doors, counters, and finishing lumber On Time Yeast Co Yeast, baking powders, starch, etc. Ka-Americka (Bohemian) s Concrete Post Co Newspaper and job printing Concrete posts Omozoru Chemical Cc Paxton &amp; Gallagher . Paxton-Mitchell Co. .. Chemical Extracts Railroad supplies n &amp; Vierling Iron Works Structural and ornamental ir»« and steel work m, Andrew Baskets MB ft Co., (J. C.) Pellican, Joseph Wagons and carriages KIs &amp; son Bros Saratoga chips ■ building machinery Omaha Gm Omaha Harness Supi irning rods ii, feed, etc. i Paier H Omaha Paper Box Co. ..... </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 Eie of KaiiHMmni prson, Edward, erson, H. E. ereon, I-. C Kind of Cigars Book and job printing Jewel rv E erson. T. \V iffer, William... kering. E . F. Tools, etc t I ward ar, J. W... Cigars Erak Publish i ter, A. W. Publishing Bakery produc Porter. K 1 book and job printing Chemii ttei-Ryerson-Hoobler Co. i&lt; 11 and job printing and job printing Skirts Job printin, rW. A Anna . . Bakery product \i wspaper, job printing, etc Job printing r field &amp; Co. (J. B., Jr. I 1 Printing 00 lob printing 7. H Bakery products Printing Co . Itook and job printing, binding, etc Eiable Iron and Wire V ail Merchants' Journal... Roller Found i &gt; .lion, wire and brass goods . Semi-monthly journal Foundry products Rex Stock Food Co . Stock foods .Job printing trs Reynolds &amp; Co. iV. D.I Rerac, John Eiades, Haii hard son Drug Co g, George E Bakery product Toilet preparations Job printing Roberts Printing Co. (J Rokusek, Q Job printing Bakery product Root, Alason I RoBenbery, A. Book and job printing, etc Sashes, doors and other planing mill products r stock &amp; Co. (Hi Charles . Smoking toDacc Horse collars Eucels. J. M i-al Woodman . . mbel &amp; Son iR &gt; Des, Mrs. M Book and job printing Newspaper, etc. ies and baling wire Bakery products Carri&amp;f Barbel supplies [Tmluellaa nby &amp; Lynn^qiiesi . Job printin . Hats </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 Kind of Business Cigars El of Establishment pson, Frank . . &gt;ge, Edward . . Tin, galvanized iron, zinc and cop- per work Schall &amp; Co. (A.) Schindler, Christoph . Schraarse, Henry . . . . Schneiderwind, James Schouboe, Hans Brooms Piead and other bakery products Cigars Schroeder, Peter C Schupp. J. B Cigars Segar, J. F Harness Sharp Machine Works (I. C.) Sherwood, C. A Machinery Book and job printing Shukert, C. ■. : Wolff .. Simon, William Men's and women's fur garments Bakery products Milk cans Tinware Simonson &amp; Norby Bpson &amp; Son (A. J.) old, Theodore . . . . Carriages and wagons Tinning and metal roofing Electroplating and polishing Brick Slavin, Louis Smith Brick Co Smith Extract and Spice Co. (D. Ki Baking powder and extracts Smith Lockwood Manufacturing Whips Brick ( i. J. Fred El &amp; Co. (M. El ovsky, Charles . ■■rger. John Overalls, jumpers, shirts, etc. Cigars Harness Solomon Manufacturing Co. Sovereign Visitor Folding coops F raternal newspaper Stock food Stalnaker Co. (J. L.) Standard Stock Food Co Star Box Factory Horse and cattle condimental food Boxes Kling Boiler Compound Co in K . N. P Boiler compound Jewelry Ee &amp; Son, (F. E.) i Brew.inK Co. . 1, William Pancake flour Beer Patterns and models Machinery Kng &amp; Farley ns. U I ml, T. F... Bread and other bakery product* Dump wagons Sunderland Roofing and Supply Roofing, belting and hose, etc. Bakery product* Sllllil. Dressed stone Jtwelry Hats </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 b printin b printing, etr. ranite monumen nntin ron inting, f ntin ntin car repa etc r bakery produc y product Ear . .f Ksiabluthmeoi anson. Fr« arti ft McKelvv Kind .. Brooi inting t American Publishii edish Publishing - papers, jol Newspapers, jol Marble and gr Bakery product Book and job i ninding. et Traveh rs' Tinn True Voice Ek and Vn enticth Century Farmer tleland, A. 1 ipplies uolive and &gt; product y product Bakery product i candy I'nion Pacific Sho| • Vodrie Bakery Co ■ ft Dinning Louis. Voight. W. E Harnes Vulcan Cht-mical d Chemicals Bakery produc Barrels, tanks. Walker. P. B Waller Display Co Walters, W. G. .. . . &gt;o Creamery Co Waters Printing I Watt, Mrs. Emmarella We line Bros .lob printing anil otlie General foundr; Bakery product ■erg, John West, J. B... Western Brick Manufactu n Composite Brick I n Fur Robe and Tanning Brick Brick Co Tanned Goods Sweeny, J. V. Swobo,1;i. \dolph H K "app I ntent blocks. Herman PleklM etc. hon: ery product homi homstn. E. II .ml wl honisen, Henr&gt; H »it&gt;l). David. 'r«de Exhibit Co. Newspapers, jo ran;- Bal ery prodncti riska. Anton ■ler. I. S paper, jol r, jol loli i rintin !ia|H&gt;r </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 Name of Establishment Western Laborer . Kind of Busines Newspaper Ktern -Newspaper I'nion tern Tinware Oo Tinware and stove i paper and job printing ■aper and job printing Bread and other bakery pro Kliche Pr ern Scot ■te &amp; Ortman hen, J. F. .. . Harn Box Ker, R. A ing. \V. K Bnsky &amp; Co. (H ams, Manley. . Kw Siirings Brewing Cc n, David J Medicine Boilers Wilson Steam Boiler C Wiiaschek Bros Bakery products K Brothers £ , M B Awnings, tents and canvas covers Bottled goods Elen Package Mft; Iman Linseed Oil Wort By, William Butter tubs »'(1 oil Cabinet maker ri-Cily Caz&lt; Id-Herald .tper and job printinK. etr Newspaper Ken, Joseph lck, Joseph bakery protect! cam Zees, John Zer'.an, John W Zimman Bros. . Zimmerman, Al and other bakery products Bakery products South Omaha Anchor Planing Mill Armour &amp; Company Sash, door- Meat packing, etc Bates Planing Mill, (C. Si Bliss, James H Doors, windows, blin^ Cigars Chicago &amp; Northwestern Shops Click, D. M Railroad repairs Artificial stone ihy Packing Cc Soap powder, soap, glycerine, meat packing, etc Curo Mineral Sprin. Daily Drovers Journal-Stockman Duve Packing Co, ( Henry ) Slaughtering and packing Rubber stamps Fisher McGill Mfg. Co Fleck, Joseph Bakery products Slaughtering ■nan Kosher Meat Co (Jerniiin Stock and Poultry Rem- edy Co Joli i riming, etc Box manufactu Harness lry Job i Tinting ■ lated beverages 11M.TS, etc. StocK </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 EC of &amp;t»blu»hment rne ft Son, (Fred) m, A Kind of Business Deliver; wagons, drays and repair Bakery product Hauptman. I Howe, C. C Joli iirinting, books, etc N«wapM*C, job printing. Stock powder Independent Cattle ft Powder r Brewing Co ( &gt; nsen, J. P Kadavy, V. A.. Keller Bros... Bakery product Bakery product ry product j.iokin Brick Knmslisch. Joseph Kritinbrink. I. H La bo Printing and publishir Cigars L»itner &amp; Co Shot, bar lea Kwrt-nce Shot and Lead C iglc City Printing and j I ■ul lisbi: Mann ft Sons. iN D.) Markey. John J i and othei ! product Inary renu Printing Martinowics. Wm Medical Chemical ( Midwest Eagle . .. NV»- ih printing ska Dail&gt; Den Omaha Cooperage ■ Omaha Packing Co Krk. Johnson ft Park iw Share Planing mill products Republican Rover. Samuel D Spin. Joseph. . . . tckmans Brand Ift A Co Printing and publishing laid. etc. .Bristles Trainor ft Gabrio Trumble Co, (H F.I .Job printing Valley Enterprise i per and job printing Waterloo Gasette apei ami job printing Brio 1 ; Hollister, Allen H DUNDY COUNTY Benkelman .Newspaper, job printing .Printing and publish .H.ikin prods ib ] riming, etc - job printir prod u&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p133">133 as fl Kind of Hu&gt;inc! Name of KstaWwhmenl FILLMORE COUNTY Exeter Flour, fed' !, Job printing, etc. r, job printing, etc Index tags. etc. Fillmore Count » Smith. Charles C Fairmont KIOHI Creamery C loot Chronicle. ■ '"inMng etr Geneva Ne w Job printing, etc I Ice Cream Factory i Pop Works Pop, soft drill U- Flour, teed, etc. Krie &amp; ( ac I! ro .Haine: ler Co.. (A) olas. W. S. Uriel Han Kerson Cigar F;h ne Bros Bakery product i per anil job printing Tinsmithine. plumbing and e ska Signa (W. L in Graf ton Flouring mill products Fredrick &amp; Smith i per, job printing, etc Milligan Artificial stone and ujick Cigars Pulee. Thoma Ohiowan Shickley . . Newspaper, job printing, etc Strang Kord. Henry rprise . . . . Bakery products Bu'ter Million Cement BliK'k am Brick Co N. wspaper, job printini: Ohiowa . . X. wspaptr and job printing </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 c Kuk of KMvhfchmeDi Kind of Busin FRANKLIN COUNTY Bloomington anil job j&gt; i in Fl.iiii I and Conor Brick Artificial stone anil brie Harniss and repairing Bakery products t Moffeli, Charlts K km. j. r. .. Campbell rintiu &lt;■ 'uinia y if Brooms Sentinel niiii Hildreth iy produc! Flour, feed, etc Newspaper, job &amp; Son intin Naponee v Polle Flour, feei Riverton rea Butter and skimm ti milk •b print paper an.r i Flour, feed, etc Upland c FRONTIER COUNTY Curtis job ]&gt; job |- Flour, feed, etc. Flour, feed. etc. •intiiiK c l-riiiii' Milling I ., a.) Eust.s (paper, jol Flour fodd, et" Franklin Newspaper, job printing Flour, fe=d. etc. F. job | r, job [Hinting </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 tc etc etc ete etc etc etc Name uf Establishment 1\ ntti of HuMn&lt; Maywood NewKpaper, job printing Flour, feed, etc. Stockville lohnson VV Republican Pfcbcr Flour, fejd, et i printing. FURNAS COUNTY Arapahoe Flour Flour Brick -paper, job printing, iiper, job printing, Flour mill products Beaver City Kit City Cement Brick inaon, William Co Artificial stone and brick Brick and tile Hotchkin, George E Meadows, T. L .Flour, feed, etc. .Bakery products Shafter, Miller &amp; Co Times-Tribune paper, job printing. Cambridge Butts, E. I Bakery products Cambridge Concrete Co. ... Cambridge Electric Light C Clarion Artificial - 3 Electric light Hammond, A. H Ro.lwell &amp; Brown. Williams, Frank E Job printing Fiour. feed, etc 38 and repair Holbrook sst r, job printing, . job printing. Oxford B. £ M. R. R. Shops Darner, J. H Locomotive and car repair printing, « Standard tie-Reporter wood Milling Co rson. Ralph &amp; ( ,.,.,,.1 /'„„,-., C A (Jearhart Kailey. William. . Pioneer KG Mirror., er, Joseph .HanKM and repairing .Cigars r, job prli </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 a« printing printir printing, e in irintin printin printin. and fruit Kind uf Busin Wilsonville . Newspaper, job . Flour, feed, etc Smith, I. H GAGE COUNTY Adam* Adams Electric Light Co Bryson &amp; Miller. . .Electric lights .Flour, feed, etc r, jot Horrnm. I-. R Shore* 0 M BroomH Barneston Newspaper, jo Beatrice Mills Cornice Beatrice Cornice Works Beatrice Electric Co Electricit Beatrice Hydraulic Cement and Brick Works Artificial stone and brick ce Manufacturing Co Corn huskers Ice Planing Mill Co Planing mill pr Beatrice Rug &amp; Tent Co and tent.s Black Bros Flour, feed Breaker Bros Confectionery Chamberlain * Co (D A I Bakery product las Co Illuminating ga Cramer, P. C Broonis Cullen and Lock Cigirs Dempster Mill Manufacturing Co. .Windmills, towt Dohner. J. A paper, job I. B Artificial stone Gage County Democrat jiaptr, job Gage County Herald Newspaper, job Heffelfinger. B. M hidt Hollingsworth, A. C stone Horner, W M Bakery produc Ke«a, F I) Hardwar KkMe. «i ■ £ Co Brick Langdon, Horace Foundry product Lass* Canning A Preserving Co..' getable Lock Ira ,»nd furnace? ough, T H oducts </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 Name of Kotabli&gt;hniem • r, I. w Kind uf HusineSh Wagons Meyers &amp; Smith Mil'mrn &amp; Scott MUe«, William D Nebraska Post.. NYidhart, Charle Parker. .). H Bakery products Boak binders and job printers Bakery products Newspaper, job printing;, etc Monuments, etc. &gt;■ and repairing Confectionery \V. .1 i City Creamery Cc is. B Butter and eggs Printer and publisher Rutherford &amp; 1 .Artificial stone, etc agelke, George Bottling, etc ilaj Suniniarv Springer, Paul ThistU'wait B Newspaper, job printing, etc 1'nderwood Bros. Cigar C Inio.i Pacific R. R. Shoi Locomotive and car repairs, etc Fencing Von Steen, J. H Corn huske Cigars Blue Spring* Austin R Church, J A I &amp; Maym Inel Cigar me quarry Newspaper, job printing Bakerv products ruff, Robert H Clatonia i Ham Cortland DeWitt Henry Holmesville ipton &amp; Swain .Flour, feed, etc Newspapi r, Job iirintinc Harm Spicer. T. R :. job printing Planing mill products Walter Paul Mfg. Co Wyatt &amp; Gray Job prlntin NHWspHptr, jol&gt; print! Dfl Liberty </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 Name of Establishment KiDduf Bnrtiw Odell W»ve Weekly Newspaper, job printing, etc Wymore Arbor Newspaper, job printing, etc Ix&gt;oomotive and car repairs, B ft M. R. R. Shops De Rock, Benjamin . Fox, Luther Cigars Hornberg. P. Bottled goods Murdock. C. M Printing and publishing I'. S. Gypsum Wymore Plaster Plaster Co. Wabasha Electric Co Waltier, LA Ele-tric light Harntss Warren. F E. Wilson ft Son Wymorean . . . Bakeiy products Newspaper, job printing Aituicial stone etc Wymore Concrete Co. tyniore Implement and Coal ft H. Mfg. Co Co. .Fee&lt;1 Stock remedies GARFIELD COUNTY Burwell Barker ft Co. (A). Bakery products Manufactured gas products Artificial stone tjrwtll Heat ft Light Co iller, Ora Miller. R B Riddle ft Coffin Sutton, A. E Tribune Artificial stone Bakery products -paper, Job printing etc GOSPER COUNTY El wood Bulletin .. ..Newspaper, job printing, e GRANT COUNTY Hyannis Grant Coubty Tribune .Newspaper, job printing e! GREELEY COUNTY Greeley Citizen . - ■ -paper, job printing, etc it at and Light Co viene gas </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 etc tc ptr etc err «■■ ptr et et fruit and HALL COUNTY Cairo . Newspaper, -job printing (Vnient blocks Record Thomp«on. D Doniphan Charles Kloue Co.. Briol. n, Henry Bioyclt Qraad Island Cigar Box Factory. .Cigar boxes Grand Island Gas Co Illuminating gas Grand Island Iron Works Foundry and machinery Vmme of Establishment Kind of Hmincw Ureeley Milling Co Flour, feed, etc. Nt-wsiiaper. job printing Scotia \i-ws|.ap&lt; r. job printinK Floir. feed. rtr. Spalding Valley Mill.. Klonr feed. Enterprise ... \ews|&gt;ap' r, job printing Kearns. Mary Ellen. Baker) products, etc. Sentinel Newspaper, job printing SpaMing Htal and high: meulen, H. O Acetylene gag Brick Wolbach Advertiser ... Dollurhide &amp; Co. .lolin E Newspaper, job printing- Coiniron building brick jranc d Island Broom C . . Bruon.s and brushes ican Beet Sugar Co. . . . Ci.i.iulaled suKar sjer Herald.. Newspaper, job printing Brandt. A. G. . .CM /.. Rich in Block Building Co... . Arliflcial stoiie Klectric Light Ca . . Kleci I i, Edwiir.l . .Bakery prodw Vi'a ib printing . Ne'v-n i|). r. job printing &amp; Etting . . Flour, ft • 1 Island Candy Kitchen. . .Confectioniiy 1 Island Canning Co.... . Canning and preserving </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 I c Kind of Busine* Hald . ..lob printing tiling * nd B.i ependent William ue W tin co. Midland Cn il Remeii «; Do. (Ira Ti Punt;,: .Windmil Bum- ■ narj reniedi Marble and granitf monuments ilintet * iilks and nil stone Solzbrum, Henry \ &lt; i«i«r, w I ..in &amp; Ruh' &amp; Baldridge Tulle Hi Inion Pacific Shops il ston \ products n wire fen n otive anil r, etc. pairs, e Henry Voight, J. B... H. J ■ hold A Culbertson ick Cigar Co .Bakery produc .Cigars Wingert &amp; Taylor Steel tanks Wood River Carter Bros Interests . . . feed, etc. iiaper. Job I y products .•aper, job printing, etc t miner, Mrs M .1 printing, etc HAMILTON COUNTY Aurora Aurora Brick v Brick Auroia Electric Light and Power lie lights Floir and grist Aurora Milling Co Burlington A Missouri R K S*iops Locomotive and paper, job car repairing printing, etc. Hamilton County Register r, job printing, etc. ial stone &lt;t, job printing, etc roducts Si Haul Cn Sch^ffel. William Sohmi &gt;'. 1 i] lnsmiim i </seg>
            <seg id="p141">141 etc etc etc pairing etc etc etc etc etc Hampton Mill Co Flour ;md feed HARLAN COUNTY Stamford Zul.iuf, J. M Flour, feed, etc HAYES COUNTY Hayes Center - County Times-Republican. .Newspaper, job printing HITCHCOCK COUNTY Culbertson Banm ■ &gt;b printing, etc Name of Establishment Kind of H&lt;- Sun Newspaper, job printing Trimpe, Fred Cigars Wood Bros Brick and ice Giltner n \e Aspaper, job printing Gazette Newspaper, job printing Hampton Bennett, Mrs. G. W Bakei j products Budler Hardware and Implement Tinware and harm ire Alma Alfalfa Meal and Mill: ..Flo.ir and meal Ainu Milling Co.. Fkmr. feed. etc. &amp; Etling Bai;. ry products Harlan County Journal Newspaper, job printing 1 Newspaper, job printing .in. ¥ Mineral, soda waier, etc Orleanc Courier Newspaper, job printing Orleans Brick Yards Brick ns Flour and Oatmeal Mill- in.; Co. Flour, feed, etc. Oxford &gt;\ford Roller Mills Flour, feed, etc. Republican Ciiy n County Ranger Newspaper, job printing. [irintin </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 Kind of Bwto Palisade Blum. H. Harness iiinl well casing Trenton Pe-nber. R H Harntss and repair work Register Newspaper, job printing, etc Tayloi Newspaper, Job printine etc HOLT COUNTY Amelia Mc&lt;;inni- i Hunt Atkinson md I-ight &gt;n Milling. Grain and Electric liijh Stock Co Orapl Flour, feed, etc -iihiht. job printing Ewing &gt;ne Works .Artificial stone People's Advocate Ne*spa|&gt;er, job printing, etc Martin T Floir. feed, etc Inman New Newspaper Job printing Middle Branch Bberly, John H Flour, feed, etc 0 Noll Al bens. V . Harness, etc. i y product Bentley. Mrs C. H Brennan. Neil -mithing, stove pipes. • r, Job printing in roof; Frontier etc Holt Cotfnty Independent l-ake\. \V. |iaik&gt;r. Job printing Bakery rroducts etc Mann. John. Sr Reka, Conrad C Stannard Harness, etc Cigars Marhle monument* Pop Warsh. R G Page Newspaper, jolj printine et&lt; Stuart I-***!*! St Aspuper. joh printing, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p143">143 Name of Establishment Kind of Bu-iness Turner Eagle Mills Mill products HOOKER COUNTY Mullen Enterprise Cattle Dip Manufac turing Co Cattle dip Hooker County Tribune Newspaper, job printing, etc, HOWARD COUNTY Boeluc Kigston, Mrs. Minnie e &amp; Co Flour, feed, etc. Flour, feed, etc. Dannebrog Jansen &amp; Hatt Moore, Egnatz Flour, feed, etc Harness and shoe repairing Newspaper, job printing, etc Farwell Lukasiewicz, Charles Harm St. Paul Kiiek, John r, Andrew . Cigar Artificial stone Brick Gruber &amp; Svoboda Killian, Mrs. J. A. Hopkins, N. A... Bakery products .Feed mill products .Flour, feed, etc. Neiman &amp; Jenkins Phonograph-Press Present Truth .... Newspaper, job printing, etc Newspaper, job printing, etc Newspaper, job printing, etc Sweet corn Butter Schmidt, Paul Soda water, cider, birch beer, etc Suntych, John F Cigars JEFFERSON COUNTY Diller Acetylene Gas Co Record Acetylene gas Newspaper, job printing, etc Harness and repairing Ravmond. L P Endicott Sugar, molasses, sorghum, etc. Iublican . Paul Canning Co Paul Creamery.. </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 Kind of Busin* Fairbury Kgron, Mrs. I. J I Bakery produc ■ produc produc KBiiinl. Harlet lier, 0 Artificial etone, planing mill l.rod ucts terus. Will; \ P Cigars Mineial. soda water, etc Fairbury Brick Co Brick Fairbury Electric 1-ight and Power Co Electric lights Fairbury Iron Works and Wind mill Co ( machinery, etc Fairbury Stock Food Oo Fairmont Creamer? Gaxen. Stock food Butter and cheese Newspaper, job printing tc Kner, I. S ell Bros Artificial .-stone Tinware, tin roofing, etc Journal Newspaper, job printing, etc Tin and sheet iron ware, well tubing McLauren &amp; McKenzie Harness McDowell &amp; Mendenhall Flour, feed, etc llcNew, B F Brooms Mendenhall, J. 1 ' Brick -paper, job printing. &lt; Nutzman, Loui • :icial stone I - . ...Marble nionumen Times sitaper, job i&gt;iiiiting. Vnited Mutual Pharmacal Co t Patent nieiliciti Harbine Harbine Cheese Co. ... .Cheese Jjnien .lansen Milling Co Flour, feed, etc Plymouth &amp; Krentze ..Ma"hine shop product Hwm* -paper, job printing t H ;:ncl repairing Reynolds Adams A &gt; Flour feed, etc Klour, feed, etc </seg>
            <seg id="p145">145 Kind of Buainaac Name of Est ablishmen Steele City E&amp; Co. (X.) , Andrew J Mill products and grain Harness and repairing Newspaper and job printing Flour, feed, etc. City Roll. JOHNSON COUNTY Cook .Newspaper and job printing . Flour, feed, meal, etc. Robertson Brc Crab Orchard Crab Orchard Electric C Herald Electricity o Newspaper, job printing, etc. Feed mill products Sharrett, F. M Elk Creek Htrald .Newspaper, job printing, etc. .Carp Irwin, Esther Sterling C Cigars Bipp &amp; McLendon and. William Buggies, tanks and repairs Bakery products Hollenback, I. P I-ange, Ben .Newspaper, job printing, etc . Flour, feed, etc. ng Roller Mills Newspaper, job printing, etc. Tecumseh Tinware, roofing, spouting, etc. paper, job printing, etc. . Harness and repairs Campbell Chieftain Eefelt, William man, Thomas i, A. E Brooms .Bakery product .Newspaper, job printing, etc. .Newspaper, jab printing, etc. . Paving Johnson County Journal. Johnson County Tribune ft Sons Bottled soda, carbonated beverages Monuments, tombstones, etc. :k, Adolph . Niedhart. Charles Phillips, Jason L. Ross, Walter Flour, feed, etc Cigars • nbenz, H .Bakery products .Flour, feed, etc. Flour, feed, etc. Teoumseh Milling Co Wirt Mill and Eleva </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 Kind of Bustnen KEARNEY COUNTY Ulyenborg. A achine shop pro* rm, John U * Son M Anderson &amp; Son I A. B Boulder Creamery Co Decker Cigar Factory Empire Milling Co. Himmenlrom, J Butter Cigars .Flour, feed, etc Harne: Minden Brick Works... Mindtn Edison Electric NewB-Gazette . Brick Co Electric light .Newspaper, job printing, et? Nt wspaper, job printing, etc Ehn.ond, G. J. . . lageter. C. F. Her * Shields Harness . Newspaper, job printing, etc KEITH COUNTY Ogalalla Bennett Dip Co .Cattle dip Keith County News Newspaper, job printing, etc KEYA PAHA COUNTY Springview Herald . . . .Newspaper job printing, etc Keya Paha News.. NVwspaper, job printing, etc. Wilson, L. A Electric light KIMBALL COUNTY Kimball McGinnl* Flume Mfg. Co Flumes Western Nebraska Observer Newspaper, job printing, etc KNOX COUNTY Bazille Mills Bmtllle Mills. Flour, feed, etc. Brooks. George A Flour, feed, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p147">147 tinware etc etc etc etc elf etc etc etc et. N'ume of Establishment Kind of Business Bloomfield Bloo.iheart &amp; l.undstrom Harness repairing and Bloomfield Brick and Tile Co Brick and tile Blooinfleld Gas Co Gas Bloomfield Roller Mill Co Emmons, F. B Flour. feed, etc. Publisher Newspaper, job printing, etc Bakery products Mrs George, Sr ttler, John B Ciga Journal Newspaper, job printing, etc Bakery products Bsteadt. J. A tor Newspaper, job printing, etc Newspaper -ka Hermanns Sohns Center Newspaper, job printing Creighton Newspaper, job printing, Flo.ir, feed, etc. Khton Milling Co Newspaper, job printing, Carbonated beverages Niobrara Bwing Bakery product Lager beer Foerster. Anna Brara Brick and Til rara Milling Co Co Brick and tile Flour, feed, etc. Tribune Newspaper, job printing, Santee Agency Newspaper, job printing Verdel Outlook Newspaper, job printing, Verdigris Newspaper, fob printing, .Flour, feed, etc. Newspaper, job printing, Electricity Wausa Kkdahl. N. O Harness Kiers' Elevator Co son. H ■ Flour, feed, etc Cigars Gazette Newspaper, job printing, (iermania a«~« Pavlick Bros ProRif ris Electric Light Co </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 inting. etc r ntin nting, etc bin intin R««d Bros, ft Lutes Kin.l i&gt;I Itu^i:,.-- \ products a Brick M LANCASTER COUNTY Bennett Hibner. George E Vnion ]i Bethany t email. I istian N nt building blocK .Priming and publishin Hardy. .1 H is ami ia Burnham .Brie College View College View Bakery Baker&gt; College View Tailoring Co Clothing, etc Nebraska Sanitaiiiin ■MU, Vsktar Firth .Flour, f Crandall. E. J leg F ■ lairin Havelock I A. M. Mfg. ami Repair Shops. .Machine ihopi velock Co . Hcni|i I Hemp mw HavelocK G Jones, R .1 Nelson, Anton E Suhl, H. W Williamson. F. E. Printing and publi Hickman Entei prise IT, JO ..Brick Hock ft Morrison Walvoord, B Lincoln Acacia Masonic Journal Alfalfa Meal Co New - Feed Anderson ft Christiansen rr,r™ lebud Co. . . Hal*. I y products </seg>
            <seg id="p149">149 Name of KstaMishnien Barwick. .1 Kind of Hiimi) monuments, etc am and cheese Hair Benton B i nd job printing Blanchanl. I Buokstaff Bro^- B. &amp; M R. R. Shoi Kiiel \V p. Jan i ml repairs iind repair: :i] City Cement C and Cuff and cuff ! run \V in ial foundry job printinj Fn • V W. K. R. 8ho| N H F 1* el manufacture b printing, etc Air Ho an 1 Rug Wearing ( Country Merchani . . I &amp; Bartlett Co. Cushman Motor Co... * printing, etc Doors, windows and screens Gasoline engines paper, job printing and hats metal work Phonographs Repairing and dealing in machine rv Cement building blocks Soda, mineral waters, etc. Bank and office fitt: -paper, job printing, paper, job printing \ew. -paper, job printing, etc. Bakery products Franklin Ice Cream C&lt; Franklin Pi mm, etc Hank and hot. ■ rv ('•inent building blocks Newspapers, job printing, etc. Brooms and whisks Bakery products Job printing products and hum. loiive and oar lppairs, etc. &lt;1. Frank J i products I reiiai h Amerikan Farmer Spangler H;i' Dudley. F. H Bexophone Manufacturing Co e Iron Works William Eck Bottling Works (C. L.) rprise Planing Mill &lt; linn N&lt; ■ - i Patriot . Kami Town, m Bakery 0 Walter F Presse Kigher &amp; Cunningham tlinger &amp; Oo </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 ill c Name of E»t«btishmeDi Kind u( Btiiinev (iillen * Boney . Confectionery Job printing binding Uillespie * Phillips Uillespie. R. H thn Butli i i rpham Bro- . Harnms »ml saddle . Shirts Harris Curtom Sfctrt Factory tlges Lincoln Iron Works ner Bros Herald H« rman Bros Mfg Co Hermingh;ius &amp; Hellwig Hlnman, H. 1. ng .Hid roofing mxteriais Hughes. Matthew F Eernatioiihl Huskrr C &lt;r-Ocean Shirt Factory en-tat?- Newspaper Co. itn. H I Corn li Shins Israel Agricultural and commercial lir.nions and job printing Job printing, book binding, etc Tin work, roofing, gutter work. Flour mill products Kellfy. John t dull-Smith Co t. H A Kioiball Bros .iults and bust Mirrors and paint Kostka Glass and Paint Co Krause. William Cornice l..-mun Publishing Co Job ami li.wik printing Hi- him. s and dusters lee Broom and Duacer Co Lincoln Artificial Stone and Tile Co. Artificial stone E-oln Bottling Works ?oln Brick Works . . . ■oln Candy Kitchen. Carbonated bottled goods Brick Confectionery Ecoln Coffee and Spice Mills.. coin Cornice and Metal Works coin Gas and Electric Light Coffd making powders, etc Cornice Unoln Ice and Cold Storage Co Lincoln Incubator Co. . . . In Leather Co .mil sh I IK work Lincoln Marble a u d Granite Works Monument Flour, feed, etr Lincoln Mill Co Lincoln Overall and Sh; Lincoln Paint and Colo: and in oil (Ifneral .ouudry products .Artificial stone . Ww-spappr. ji)l&gt; printing, etc iin&gt;:. etc Publishing Saratoga Chi; ■d electrtclt Tncuh.i </seg>
            <seg id="p151">151 Kind of Buitn— Namf of Hm ahnshnient Lincoln Paper Box Co Lincoln Paper Co Lincoln Press Printery Lincoln Rug Factory Lincoln Sash and Door Co Lincoln Shade Co. . Paper boxes Paper bags Printing Rugs Door, sash, Uliad.- Sharles tin Sinn Works. . . . In Steam Paste Co Signs Paste tin Stone and Supply Co In Tannery Artificial stone Harness, leather, curried leather and custom work Lincoln Tent and Awning Co Lincoln Upholstering Co Awnings, tents and canvas goods LoMpt, couches, furniture, etc. Vinegar Lincoln Vinegar Works Little, Adelbert D Awnings, tents, etc Hay balers Luebtn Baler Q Luedtke. R. A. A.. McVey Printing Co Maxwell Co . Machinery Job printing Confectionery, ice crean Carpet weaving Miller, Victor A Midwest Newspaper, job printing, etc Repair shops M. P. R. R. Shops Nebraska Congregational News Nebraska Cornice Works Religious publications Galvanized iron and copper co: nices: tin. iron and slate roofing Date Farmer Newspaper, job printing, etc. Newspaper, job printing, etc. Agricultural publications Newspaper, job ptinting, etc. Law magazine, job printing, etc. Newspaper Nebraska Farmer Easka Farm Journal aska Independent, a ska Legal News. . askan Nerbaska Paint and Lead Co sk* Paper and Bag Co. Nebraska Printing Co Paint Paper bag lob printing Nebraska State Capital.. i ska State Democrat Nebraska Teacher Newspaper, job printing, etc Newspaper, job printing, etc Newspaper, job printing, etc Cigars Neville &amp; Gartner Skirts Eville Skirt Factory Century Printers ell Novelty Co... Book and job printing Novelties Newspaper, job printing, etc. Books pamphlets, job printing Mattresses and pillows Patriot. . h ft Co.. Payne &amp; Leek Petersen, Christian P Confectionery X&gt; braska Dairyman and Dp-tO </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 Kw of bmblisbmeni Pilger tkertou Manufacturing Co ltry Topics -paper, job printing Job printing Ess Publishing Co lian Sunbeam dig &amp; Mossholdei e Mfg. Co .Boots and shoes Kmers * Freirt Co I. S Artificial stone, paving Bakery products Rigg Phariuacal Co Fropiietary medicine Linotype coni|&gt;o«ition traps, dc Eter Linotype Composition Co an. Charles J ivery wagi ami repair Neighbor Fraternal publication EA Packard, lenfreund. William mi W C Kth Machine Co. (R. L.) dell. Char!.- K Shaftings, hangers, journal boxt Granite and marble monument! Planing mill products Standard Planing Mill Co -paper, job printing, etc r, job printing, etc Furs and repairing Kte Journal ele. Ollis. Stuckey, John H Thorp &amp; Co. (Thomas J.)... Topical Bible Publishing Co Trade Review Topical Bibles Newspapers, job printing, etc Patent hog medicine ties Hoggette Co ker. F. E K, William eworker Newspaper •aimer &amp; Co Walthers, Louis in Furniture Co Cornice, tin work, etc Harness Mattresses Paint E stern Glass and Paint Co 3tern Medical Review Co stern N-wspaper t'nion. stern 8wine Bn. le Newspaper, job printing, t Printing Newspaper, job printing Westover. John Huil ling iron, fire escapes, etc Trunks Wirick, Clarence A Wisconsin Furniture and Coffin Co. Coffins Wissler. Gus Bakery product Eilenberg, Peur J. r ft Co. (G. R. I. . U-made. Herman. and clippin Kind of Hi.su,,".. &gt; products spaper, jolt printing Incubators Newspaper, job print in&gt;; Foundry produi r cablt Ice cieam and ices :ties Furs and repairing Min?e meat </seg>
            <seg id="p153">153 blank books, etc Harness and repairing 1 worth. John L Young RuildinR Supply Co IR Brick Malcolm Kolm Co-Operative Creamery m. Butter and cream Roca Flour, feed, etc Flour Mil University Place \V Artificial stone .lob printii; Bakery products CUlin, .1 I... Bilking ka New Randall. K. M I'nion Wo ike ;in Printing and publishing Harness, repairing. \V. C. T. U. publication Printing and publishing Waverly Flour.' feed, etc Cosgin. D. I LINCOLN COUNTY Eiif K»t»bli»hnient Kind of Busine*. Printing Co Printing ruff-Collins Printing Co Jot^ printing, hook bindin North i Platte ;rong. Mis Jennie . . Bakery products BUnkenburg. Edward Harness, saddles . . Wm. . . Soda water bottler hidings, Charles t . .Flo'ir, feed, etc. Lincoln County Journal ...Newspaper, job printing, etc. . . Bakery produ ■ &lt;n. C. M . .Rubber stamps North Platte Electric LiRht and . . Electricity Ritner, William O ..Tombstones, cut stone, etc. K . . Cigars Telegraph ..Newspaper, job printiu- Tribune . Newspaper, job printin- V. P. R R. Sli&lt;. - . . l.oc miotive and car repairs, </seg>
            <seg id="p154">154 Nhk of fetablishiurni Kind of Bu»iE LOGAN COUNTY Gandy U&gt;ga» County Pioneer Newspaper, job printin- LOUP COUNTY Almeria ■ iliiMii F. New Taylor Clarion New ub iiriiuin. McPHERSON COUNTY Tryon MADISON COUNTY Battle Creek Flour, fee oHDuers, J. £» A -A Madison A A rucle Flou Kaul. Carl F Smith. Jai; IUU r, jo Cigars intin Tamme, F Meadow Grove Felix £ Utwia Floin -ki. William Newman Grove Kk Manufacturing rs' Milling and K Well i . o . Flour, feed ( Johnson, Peter .1 Tanks, carjwnt w Madison County Reporter il&gt;er, jc intine, t ad 8tc w Thoniassen A </seg>
            <seg id="p155">155 K Business Norfolk Ba lll( \ A ■I work Rii .iinliim and printing \V. F K. \V R. R. Shoi M Artificial ston E \\ Artitic-i Hii H ( Bui K monument KU nil H E M hii ( ,1k I.iKht anil F : mill pin in. Planing Mill Planil Printin printing &amp; Klu nit ,v M Flour ed ( : A \V. H M Tilden &amp; j &gt;li printing \ N \ irintin R E MERRICK COUNTY Archer Butt &amp; Tern Central City ( </seg>
            <seg id="p156">156 Name of Establishment Kind of Business Democrat .Newspaper, job printin- Desch, R. G. . Cigars Desch &amp; Co. (William S.) Cemetery and stone work Iddings, Charles F Gas Jensen Bros. Moulding Lutes, J. C. . Bakery produc Nebraska Friend . iper, job printing, etc Nonpariel ... Newspaper, job printing, etc Record Newspaper, job printing, etc Republican iper, job printing, etc Vieregg. James. . Flour, feed, etc Clarki Clarks Electric Light Co Fnterprise . Electric lights Newspai&gt;er. job printing. etc Silver Creek Metzer, C. R . . . Flour, feed, etc Sand Newspaper, job printing, etc NANCE COUNTY Belgrade Herald Newspaper, job printing, etc Fullerton Haggs. N Bakery produ Cigars Cannon, H. R Currier, A. B. Erickson, A... Printing and publishing Bakery products Fullerton Cigar Co Cigars Fullerton Electric Light and Power Co. Electric light Fullerton Mill Co Mann, T. I Flour, feed, etc Bakery product News-Journal Pom .iper, job printing, etc tper, job printing, etc Stoddard, Joseph M Watts, Edward «... Cigars Brick Genoa Coberly &amp; Alfords Bakery product Fonda &amp; Bros (H. E.) Flour, feed, etc Genoa Brick and Improvement Co. Brick Leader a per, job printing, etc </seg>
            <seg id="p157">157 etc fruit and etc etc etc etc etc etc etc Name of ftuatilishmen O Daniels &amp; Kilton Kind of Business Bakery products Newspaper, job printing, NEMAHA COUNTY Auburn Auburn Canning Co Canned and preserved vegetables Auburn Carbonating Works Mineral, soda water, etc Granger Newspaper, job printing, etc Auburn Mutual Light and Power Co Electric light Auburn Printing and Publi ihing Printing and publishing Flour, mill products Curtis, W. I Es, Edward ion, R. E. . lm, W. H. , J. A... Cigars Marble and stone work Brick Eiha County Herald .... iha County Republican liche Beobachter Newspaper, job printing, Newspaper, job printing, Newspaper, job printing, Brock Bulletin . Newspaper, job printing . Flour, feed, etc Maynard Brc Brownville Curtis, W. 1 Letter Flour, feed, etc . Newspaper, job printing, Johnson Johnson Stone Co Artificial stone . . Newspaper, job printing, Julian Trcker, L. B Feed mill Nemaha Nebraska Advertiser Newspaper, job printing, Peru . . Brick Glaagow KM &amp; Son ter ■ Flour, mill products Newspaper, job printing, . Bakery products Raines, W. B Uakeiy products </seg>
            <seg id="p158">158 Nmm of Establishment Kind of Buy South Auburn C'roiier M« nit hi EV C. et &amp; i ir. .lam«s.. NUCKOLLS COUNTY Angus n Hardy Fli . ■ Kzia I' Lawrence I-awrencf Milling and Elevator Co.Flou Nelson Inc-ibator F Jensen &amp; - NelsoD Light, Power and li El. Nuckolls County Heral \ vspaper, job printing, e r \- Brie Oak Erns Flour Ruskm n! Superior Alfalfa Meal Co Kss Printiii. aith. J. I. 1 ;a «nd repai Educational niontt ■ Herald . Wv . Jncubator Flour, fe&lt; I fa m </seg>
            <seg id="p159">159 ( c Name of Estal»lishir Kind &gt;■ Brick W Q Philatelic West and Camera New - Herman A paper. jol&gt; printing, etc or Bottling Wort ir Omen' Bottled goods Artificial stone, etc. Electric light Electric Ught Co. Hani Harnes Marble W( Monunierr - Brick tin A: Tangdall Wo i uahed fruit OTOE COUNTY Douglas Newspaper, job printing, etc Dunbar K printing, etc Nebraska City Publishing and printing .1. K Bone. R. .1.. H oft, Lu B. &amp; M R. R. Sho| Burnett, L. C Locomotive and car repairs Harness ami repairing Baking powders, extracts, etc Bakery products Chase &amp; Co. I E. M F. H iron castings Planing mill products Erwin. E lite and marble monuments H Fl and repairs ini. W. R Western Cereal C Harrow, R. W ..¥ "II ( u.ir r &amp; Tt B ikt luct li. K. Uustav A ( gar Drn huskf rain drills Kin?! I): ill Mfg. C Koch, Clans G Cis K. Bakery product lumps, wind-mills, etc Knwit I William . products I it pairing Forbes, \V. \ jaffney, Owen }' </seg>
            <seg id="p160">160 Naint of iSMiMistameot Morton-Gregson Co. Morton Printit,. N'a-ional Surch Co Kind of Husintx Slaughtering and meat j Printing and publishing Starch liackin rraska City Brick Co.. raska Bottling Works BricK Pop. soda w Light and Gas Co.. Illuminating ga -ka r Newspaper, job printing c N*brai Kite Works Riiss, car: Nebras Kuc Works N«wt Newspaper, job printing ...Wwspai'i job printing, et Noelting, B. H Casters ing, B H Caster: O'Brien &amp; Vaughn. . . . . Cooik rage Erien &amp; Vaughn . . Cooin Canned ami ; Fruits au.l ■ gatabtoa (in H hn H Phi(. ninke * Co. (Haul) Flour, feed. etc. M . Bottled goods ir &amp; s&gt;un Phifer Kininke * Co. (Paul) Flour, feed, etc Bottled goods Wall, John, Jr.. Broon Wall. John, Jr i -nines and i «j&gt;;iii k ■ nine Shoj) Miscellaneous articles Ma?hiii- Wales Machine Shoj Wilhelni.\ W H Mlscellan Wilhelm\ W M - machine and lamps id lam Palmyra Palmyra Newspaper, job printiog . » inting t- Syracuse l&gt;emocrat - rat \. &gt; &gt;■ printing, inn &lt; Ferry, Mrs I) W Bakery jrodn. Kerry, Mrs D W Journal Bakery product Journal \. •..-,■ .;ier. Job printing. paper, job printing. • Schroeder, C. F .Flour, feed, etc. Floui Syrjcuse Heating &amp; Lighting Co ..Gasoline and | : Planing mill products Kjcuse Heating &amp; Lighting Co.. .Gasoline and . H. Planing mill Planing mill Talmage Badberd, Herman Bakei\ prudu K .... Flour mill produc Tribune Newspaper, job printing Unadilla tix. a n m Flour, feeil. ct( Si ir8|&lt;aper, job printing, et PAWNEE COUNTY Burchard Machi Newspaper, job </seg>
            <seg id="p161">161 Kind of Busine Ouboit Flour, feed, etc. Harness, saddlery i per, job printing, etc. Pawnee City Eham. ricks. J A r &amp; Franl Harness, etc Bakery products Artrtcial stone Kilton, L. M is Bru- . Broon Johnson &amp; O Bakery product Bottled goods Knee Bottling W nee Chief ■y i per, job printing, etc ■ per. job printing, etc iper. job printing, etc Marble monuments Pawnee Pr Hani' Steinauer Harness and repairs Newspaper, job printing, etc Flour, feed, etc. Table Rock Newspaper, job printing, etc Brick Harnens, pic m PERKINS COUNTY Grant Bins County News. . ins County Sentinel .Newspaper, Job printing, etc . Newspaper, job printing, etc PHELPS COUNTY Bert rand Bert rand Harness Shop Duff. R H Flour, feed, etc Newspaper, job printing, etc Indei&gt;endent-Hera Funk Bri.i Name nf Establishment R mills. Artdison en, Milo A . KpcokI Knee Republican le, Frank . . Harness, etc Ua rrabrunt Bros </seg>
            <seg id="p162">162 * ml repairing nting nd repairin nting, etc ng, e c c i c nting, e i printing, e PIERCE COUNTY Osmond n, E. \\ Replllii . Harness Pierce Brick . \ews| Flour, ft U &amp; W H Johnson, .1. T B I. -well. tarn, u mann. H&gt; V &amp; Van.:' ■ my Call. . . Milling i : irtla R Hani- Elect ri&lt; ItaWtlkMHUaw Kind of Ittninew Holdrege now ■ ...,,.. Locomo- N' •» ipftpi ioli priniin ■ Ploa :• - M ble monunienls ■li&gt;li printing. H.iki- I :■ cm) Bottling Works . Holtlins Holir . Hn Hold :ic Light I ! .trio lij;lii HoMraae Poaa ■ I'M!: Cl-'illgS Hnlc] Windmill, tiin JokUH ishin^ ler, job iirintini Loo mi* </seg>
            <seg id="p163">163 ohm. bus Bottling Wo I Kierr, W l.utz &amp; C Naylor &amp; ■ A V Hie an newspaper, job printing \ inttii _ sfh. \V. ind ronfei H smoking toliarr .inn \V( Towns, Wi I 1". Railr . Ant er. I. rind car re. \\ pairing Creston per, job prim i i Duncan Kind of Bus PLATTE COUNTY Columbus .in. K \\ ibrock. .1 I i&lt;l planing mi! Artificial stone Miner tii fry pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p164">164 Simr of KM«hli»hnipnt Kind or Business Humphrey Humphrey Bottling Works.. Humphrey Roller Mills Humphrey Steam Brick Yard Kersch, H .Bottling Flour, feed, etc Brick Cigars County : Pratt, Fred J . Newspaper, job printing, etc . . .Printing and publishing . . . Bakery products Sohumaker, Frank Lindsay Opinion .Newspaper, job prnlting, etc ...Newspaper, job prniting, etc Furtzer, John Harness and repairing Monroe Newspaper, job printing, etc lx&gt;oking Glas Republican . . Newspaper, job printing, etc Platte Center Sign .1 Newspaper, job printing, etc Thomsen, M. I. Flour,, feed, etc POLK COUNTY Osceola Emminger, George L Flour, feed, etc Mackie, D. T. . Windmills, towers, tanks Miller, Clarence.. Electric light Polk County Democrat Newspaper, job printing, etc Record Newspaper, job printing, etc Jackson ft Meenson Brick Shelby Shelby Electric Light Co Electric ligh Sun Newspaper, job printing, etc Stromsburg Berglund ft Co Brick Hoostrom ft Peters Brick Gately Bros Flour, feed, etc Headlight Newspaper, job printing, etc Journal News Newspaper, job printing, etc Newspaper, job printing, etc Stromsburg Electric Light. Heat K Power Co rn, F P.. Electricity Butter </seg>
            <seg id="p165">165 etc etc etc etc etc HC etc etc etc Name of Establishment Kind of Business RED WILLOW Bartley Inter-Ocean ...Newspaper, Job printing, Jones &amp; Crawmer Thebold &amp; A they Concrete blocks Flour, feed. ptr. Danbury Leader News Newspaper, job printing, Newspaper, job printing. Indianola Andrews ft Wadsworth Alfalfa Belt Flour, feed, etc Newspaper, job printing Newspaper, job printing Independent Reporter Lebanon Adams, C. A Leader .... . Harutss, repairing Newspaper, job printing McCook Bennett, J Blatt, Ph. Ciga . . . Bottled goods B. &amp; M Railroad Stoops Coglizer &amp; Bush Locomotive, car repairs, Artificial stone Fahrenbruck, C. C Hart, W. E . Maenine shop product . Cigars Lofenburg, John Bread and other bakery product McCook Brick Co Brick McCook Electric Light Co McCook Milling Co Electricity . Flour, feed, etc . Harness McMillen, W. W Odell &amp; Son, (E B.) Republican Pop Newspaper, job printing, X wspaper. job printing, Bakery products Tribune I'nion Bakery RICHARDSON COUNTY Barada Barada Canning Co .Canned tomatoes Dawson </seg>
            <seg id="p166">166 Namr .if KMiii.ii»hmeni Kind uf B Falls City Hii . v. a Briee W. . Villiam Fl H. H Ha , Rol&gt;&lt; \\ Kda ft \Vh. N At Ha i Kiam .&lt;. W. H Klour n Mfs « ■us. &lt; I Humboldt .\ \ E Brick ( H Knii Hi tsny. B MrConnell. H I. c </seg>
            <seg id="p167">167 Kind of llusines; I, m job piintin- • printing, etc job printin. ROCK COUNTY N e w s job printing SALINE COUNTY Dhooge, A hk us Dick &amp; Son, 1R1 • Owl Brick Harm Bat ■ products Newspaper, job printing, etc anks, tin&gt;&gt; Cigars &gt;i't'i\ Job printing, ut&lt; Brick Brick I&gt;rimiii .Printing and publishing .Butter, ehifse. etc. . Han; Fairmont Creamery ( Gordin, S. E Manning, Rober Kary. .1. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p168">168 ioda water rintir priming, etc nun titin ntin r »;i ntinp. etc printing, et Kind of Buwne- Clgan N.m. M ■MHHMB Mineral and Hani' B;e, Au*um , Frank ■ Herald., rn Bi i&gt;a|i»»i DeWitt K Stone Works 11. Dm Saline County Independent ■ \«'«&gt;[Wi|P Flour, feed, etc Z»(inarh«k &amp; Aksamit Dorchester New • Friend Flour, feed, et produ Friend Milling Co *&gt;**n t i 11 ( ! Smith. C. W ,ph Cheese Pleasant Hill Grofc Flou Tobias McFarland it. Co .Flour, feed, n .Newspaper, jo Saline Coumy Journal Western -s Bros fence Artificial s Western Stone Works Wilber Clears Hrl H Et. Frank., h, Prokop B8on, H V 1 * ( al an .Bakery produ Pospteil Bros R, ,ican . Newspapt County Democrat . Stepaneck's Harness Shop Xewspai pi </seg>
            <seg id="p169">169 Name of KMablishm Kind of Busin&lt; Bakery pro Vasak, H. .1 W liber H; H Wilier Stone \V Artificial ston Zwanechek A.- Aksami wspaper, job printing SARPY COUNTY Gretna Hrf ez Right] I 1 liKiou-s i&gt;upfi iin.l job pritttios oprietary medic. Aligns PaoiHion \ out lner, \V A. H Rf|iiil&gt;lirun N printing, etr print i D . \ v, s La Platte Rendering Ketinint; Springfield Newspaper, job printing SAUNDERS COUNTY Ashland Mi How \.- Bucknia Puller. \V H It I.. i N B .V intiiiL 1 &gt;' pl'lliliu Wit n ■ printing, t-tc printinK. etc jndera County Journi ..N « Snell. .Iain Woodruff, W. n Cedar Bluffs I </seg>
            <seg id="p170">170 Kind of IMmm Ithaca \ewspa|&gt;ei, job printing Khsca Milling Co. . Flour, feed, etc Malmo Rnvhlnd. A Broom Mead Advorate . Newspa|H-r. joti printing, et Memphis Millet. X Butler Pohacca Pr«cinct — P. O. Fremont Fuchs. August Brick Martman * Sloggett . . . Brick Prague Kaaper ft Sun. i V i Flour, feed. ei&lt; Suchy. Thoe. . Miu tal aad soda (rban, Anna Clear Valparaiao Floui Diane. I) M Vi.ltor Newspaper, job print ing. Wahoo Bahde, John O. . . . Bakery produc Democrat Newspaper, job printing Hanson A Nethaway Insecticide Haus&amp;er. John Cigars Jones, S. H Eleclric light Melum, T. 0 Bakeiy produc Ohmstede ft Son Pop Saunders County New Era Schmidt, Marcus -i ;i|&gt;er. job printing. Brick Waap Newspaper, job printing Wahoo Mills Flour, feed, eU Weston I'rban. Anton Cigars Yutan Consumers Commercial Cyclone. .. Newspai^r, job printing, etc 8C0TT': BLUFF COUNTY Gering Courier Newspaper, job printing, etc </seg>
            <seg id="p171">171 fH eit i t&lt; u nil luc tc tc Name of Establishment Daley, Charles Kind of BusioeM Brick Klour, feed, etc Minatare Sentin ..Newspaper, job priming. Mitchell li:dex Newspaper, job printing. Scott's Bluff A Harness and saddles Newspaper, job printing. Newspaper, job printing, SEWARD COUNTY Seward Cereal Mills... Meal and feed Uering Roller Mills Republican Beaver Crossing Martin. .1. P Flour, feed, etc. Pride of Heaver Crossing Newspaper, job priming, t Review Publishing Co Printing and publishing Independent Kxaininer Newspaper, job printing, t Germantown Gennanto»n Cooperative Cream- Mutter Milford .lolinson ,\ Flour, feed, etc. l.angford, S. A ISakery products Nebraskan Newspaper, job printing, e Sliogo I.ithia Springs Co Mineral water, pop, Seward Hlue Valley Blade Vmspaper. job printing, e Hulshizer &amp; Co Flour, feed. etc. Husche . Henry F Cigars Uunphy. R. E I'URgies. carriages and rep hiaghes, John M Lumber, planing mill pro,: Independent-Democrat Newspaper, job |)Hming, e Klenck, Phillip. Jr Cigars Nebraska Deutsche Fanner Zei- tung Newspaper, job printing, e William Hakery prod* Rivers. David lirooms Seward Bottling Works Bottled goods </seg>
            <seg id="p172">172 Swan ft Metz K.ts. James S. iman. William . Hrick Staplehurst MarvBville Milling Co. &lt;R F Tamora Kf-pister .New spain priming Utica ylen Fne Gas Association ier ft Son (Cha Machii. SHERIDAN COUNTY Colclesser Coldaaaer, Henry Flour, ft Gordon Gordon Mill Co. Flour, feed, e ia|&gt;er, ji printing Traub. W. C Planing mill produ Hay Springs .i|&gt;er. job printiu Enierpris Rushville Recorder Ni-« ntinK Rushvill. Roller Mill Standard Flour, fe. nting SHERMAN COUNTY Litchfield Benson, Char! Monitor Floui r. job printing Loup City Loup City Mill and Light Co hwestern Flour, feed ■aper. job printing, e Brick Ohlsen Bros dent job printing, e </seg>
            <seg id="p173">173 tionery blocks Name of Establishmec Kind of Busine: SIOUX COUNTY Harrison News 3b printing, etc STANTON COUNTY THAYER COUNTY Alexandria Argus Newspaper, job printing, etc Hubbard &amp; Co. (F. W.) Harne McDowell Bros Flour, feed, etc. Belvidere Independen Newspaper, job printing, etc Bruning Courier Xewspaper, job printing, etc Roberts Bros., Johnson &amp; Co Flour, feed, etc Byron r.ade . Newspaper, job printing, etc . building stone and sidewalk yron Hollow Wall Co Carleton Carleton Cream . Butter and cheese Newspaper, job printing, etc .Viller, J. \V Artificial stone Pilger Herald . . ....Newspaper, job printing, etc Stanton I)ewitz, Amos .... Hani, Inhelder, J. H Bakery products and confecl bautn, Fred cai l&gt;oe.ke, Robert . . . .Incubators and brooders Miller &amp; Robinson \nificial stone Xeunian &amp; Peohner . . . .Tinware Picket . . . .Newspaper, job printing, etc. er .... Newspaper, job printing, etc. Sanders &amp; Co.. ( F. L.) . . . .Flour, feed. etc. Scheele, E. C . . . .Ci- Sirahle, Carl .. ..Brick ner &amp; Bros . . . .Tinware </seg>
            <seg id="p174">174 Kind of Rusine*. Chester Herald Newspaper. Job printing, etc Davenport Kplen Journal per. .1 Newspaper, job printing, et Flour Dethler ii. K 1 Brick Chronicle Newspaper, job priming, etc Deahler Broom Factory Brooms and whisks Deshler Roller Mills Co Flour, feed, etc Seheoer &amp; Koch Butter Hebron Champion Journal . .tper, job print) Newspaper, job printing, etc Cron Hydraulic Stone Co ron Incubator Co Sidewalk and building stone Incubators and brooders Hebron Light. Power and Heat ing Co Light Mitchell, J \V . Neville, James L Nickel, Charles . Marble work Cigars Brick Wood water tanks, steel an ii &gt;n repairs m*mm Newspaper, job printing, etc Thorn**, E F. . • raid Bros Bakery products, etc Flour, feed, etc Hubbell t forth, J. M. W ■son, J. K .... Flour, meal, feed, etc Flour, feed, etc Standard Newspaper, job printing, etc THOMAS COUNTY Seneca H. Ic M R. R. Co. Shops Locomotive and onr repai Thedford Mid-Republic Stockman Newspa]&gt;er, job printing, etc THURSTON COUNTY Pender Bar&gt;i«r. H A Broon's </seg>
            <seg id="p175">175 Name of Establishment Republic Newspaper, job printing, etc Seymour, James I Cigars Sloan, Thomas L Flour, feed, etc Times Newspaper, job printing, etc VALLEY COUNTY Arcadia Arcadia Co-OpraHv Ctwum Bun Bin lei Champion News|«aper, job printing. Flour, meal, feed, etc. etc .Northern Milling Co North Loup loyalist N't wspaper, job printing, etc Kol)l)ins. F. B Ointment ami tea Ord Henck. H. D Pop Journal Newspaper, job printing, etc Misko. Frank Harness, saildles, collars, etc \V. H Cement blocks Murschels Bakery Bakery products Ord Light and Fuel Co Manufactured gas Old Roller Mills Flour, meal, feed, etc. Quiz Newspaper, job printing, etc. Svoboda &amp; Gruber Brick Williams. D. I Harness WASHINGTON COUNTY Arlington Arlington Creamery Butter Arlington Electric Light Co Electric lights Arlington Mill Co Flour, meal, feed, etc. Brinkman. Fred Brick Ludwig, A. G Doors and sash Lu4 wig, Al Concrete stone Meyer. Paul Cigars Review-Herald Newspaper, job printing, etc. Blair Acme Milling Co Flour, feed, etc. Arndt, F. W Tinware, sheet iron work, roofing i, Williams Bakery products Blair Electric Light Co Electric light </seg>
            <seg id="p176">176 c mini;, i i- l c c etf Blair Horse Collar Co Count-: col It ■ r, jol &gt;rks Religious jourr . Newspaper, jol intin Keren, i Danish) nut I Haller Proprietary Co l.utr, .1 E Medicines . Flour, meal, feed. Marble and grani Marble works w&lt; a, .1. A McMurtrie, Mrs. Sarah Martin ft N intin inting iniinu Brick Brick Brick Hani Schumacher, .' Victor .Cigars Bottled Fontanelle n. 1 K liutt Fort Calhoun Gilbert, Mrs I K Brick Kennard Newspaper, job ming Washington ntins Waterloo Creamery Co WAYNE COUNTY Carroll iper. job printir Wayne Democrat .... Cigar ia|&gt;er. job printin .Marble monuments K, Robert , J. C Carpel and rug Bakery products, etc. d and pie- job print NewKpa Newspaper, job p lioan Rhodes. I) M Rhod&gt; Richter, John son. C. H Soheffler, Cus.. Nswmpaper, job 'a|*-i\ job printing, e </seg>
            <seg id="p177">177 ind of Husine arness, etc &gt;n, Dennis K . . . . k. William k Confectionery, bakery product! Winside Winsid. Uric a|x&gt;r, job printii WEBSTER COUNTY Bladen Ruttt Flour, feed, etc ■ t|&gt;er. job printing, etc Bakery products I H a in Guide Rock Kly C"( Newmyer, a. .Brick Printer and jmlilisher Inavale well, A. F Mil Letter Milling Co Flour, feed, etc Red Cloud Milling A; 1 i Flour, ft • William Bakery products H arnes ...\ wspaper, job printini Fiinting and publishing c ment blocks n. R ( ment blocks El 4,f KMubtishmel s. John S., Jr y &amp; Craven. .1 Ipe, u-a ketlU-s, boilers, etc mill products . Harm i i*t. Job printing, etc Brick tafan, John I 1 .... ■ Brick Yards. . • trie Light en. M Klecrrie li| Flour, feed, etc N i ) i &gt; h printing, ** I c Blue Hill KHill Creamery G er A; Marsh </seg>
            <seg id="p178">178 Nmd* of FiHt ihliahmf nt mm of i Nation ation Newspaper, job printing, etc. Newspaper, job printing, etc r&gt;braskm ft Kansas Fanner and Breeder ebraska ft Kansas Farmer and Breeder Agricultural journal, job printing Agricultural journal, job printing Orering Bros, ft Co latt, E. J ed Cloud Creamery Association, ed Cloud Marble and Granite Co ner. Willjim Vhster County ArRiis Orering Bros, ft Co. Monuments, tombstones, He. Monuments, tombstones, rtt Platt. E. J. Cement blocks Cement blocks Ked Cloud Creamery Association Butter Butter Red Cloud Marble and Granite Co Niarble works .Varble works Scrlvner, Willjim Water tanks, window frame*, ate Water tanks, window frames, ate \\ Vbster County Argus Newspaixr. job printing, etc Newspa|&gt;er. job printing, etc WHEELER COUNTY Bartlett Wh^elw County liuirprinlent Newspaper, job printing, etc YORK COUNTY Benedict Benedict Electric Light Co Electricity - Herald Newspaper, job printing, etc Bradthaw -haw Electric Light Co Electric light Republican Newspaper, job printing, etc Gresham Gazette Newspaper, job printing, etc Kirby, T. J Artificial stone Henderson Cox ft Co., (Joshua) Butter HagemeiBter, F. and W Flour and feed Hnn'lerson Electric Light Co Electric light Lushton Lushton Milling Co Flour, feed, etc McCool Junction tl Valley Journal ring, L Newspaper, job printing, etc. Flour, meal, feed, etc Kely Bros . . . rgang, J. J Flour, feed, etc. Harness Thayer Millar ft Thorp Flour, feed, etc York Buer, Henry Pop, soda water, «tc. </seg>
            <seg id="p179">179 ,ic Baxter. L. j Kind of Business .Cigars Een.ien, E. F fonl, R. T in. Thomas Job printing .Awnings, tents, etc. .I'.ook binding .Newspaper, job printing, etc. .Grain elevator machinery, etc .Butter Bakery products Bakery products Confectionery Job printing, etc Brick Huffn an. I'. A. Kildow, J. M . Bakery products . Marble works .Marble works . Flour, feed, etc. Mcl-aughlin &amp; Shepanlson. amtry &amp; Cotton taper T'nion Harks Co., U A.I Job printing, book binding, etc Sheet music, books of music . Newspaper, job printing, etc. .Cigars; 'ilicar Schnltz, G. ( Aick. J. H Artificial stone Stllson, William E Book and i«mphlet, sheet mu Newspaper, job printing, etc. Bottled goods Kier &amp; Kriesmann n. Norman. F. . . Carriages, wagons, sleighs i per, job printing, etc Brick York Brick and Tile Co R Foundry and Engine Wort Engines and boilers nd electric light Artificial uh Planing mill products Downie-Wright Mfg., Co Fairmont Creamery Co. Kalkenburg. H. S Fur-nan. W. R L </seg>
            <seg id="p180"/>
            <seg id="p181">181 NEBRASKA CROP STATISTICS In the following tables will be found the Bureau's final figures rela §to the production of corn, wheat, aska for 1!H&gt;."&gt; and ISM I value of each crop in each county tats, rye. barley anj alfalfa in average yields, tote] proil ■ompose the tab; BThe compilations herein submitter &lt; hundred producers (ten in each t •tit of their judgment upon crops .1 are the results of report - ounty i who give the Bureau the when called upon. These esti- ts are made upon a conservative basis and with a conscientious de to attain as near absolute accuracy as |x&gt;ssible. This investigation was conducted at a i&gt;eriod when the eon nsured and had passed the danger of frost and consequently all M timates were free fiom speculation as to frost damages, etc . ami confined solely to the visible and demonstrated yields of the fields in inmunity. &gt;The table on Alfalfa is the result of the first complete and detailed meration made of that crop in the state. However, in past total crop li limated. and it is gratifying to note th- KThis biennial report KM prepar H&gt;7, on which date John .1. Uyd lintment of (ioveriinr She] and in the press previous to .Inly MT by i increase of this cmj </seg>
            <seg id="p182">182 CORN, 1905 Ay COINTY Acreage V Id Production* Value per Bushel* Acre THE STATK «,472, 487 87.65 248,718.244 *B7.4k Adiitns 137.483 * gET 188 1.401' 79,088 Ot Box Butte 4«, ow m B- 1J7.«7:i 37 I 4.744. 1W 1.H97.004 8O 80,953 40.7 :(. '.'»4 7H7 1.317.914 HO ss- 117.M14 37.1 1.398.7B3 1.759,806 80 Hit "&gt;.',• - ~iii 2,aon - in 033 w :&gt;.Y 741 81 IH 321. 5 ■ |:ti:.«28 80 ••nnf 7.-.. 777,919 80 2.«H7.90»i 1,075 104,84" 8«.« 8.887.400 I. .VU. 900 00 ■ S10.46! ■#&amp; 3.072 731. OS 80 1 7,", ssr UM.H03 20 1S7.344 00 K5 i 367.281 60 Fillmorr Franklin Frontier s 16,257 :il li S13.721 518.721 -Ml.". RH.530 41C 2.KIO.550 1. 1-M.280 00 HH..VK1 41(i J, 810.580 11M.880 00 i.!«. 1«4 3 - . (I 2 420.741' WiH,8»« 00 ii!l. 1W 1-2(1.7 4(1 TH.(&gt;JK» 35 ."&gt; 2,8U7,«W 1 (28 104.290 4'i 0 i 110.000 l.«HK.n0u i»&gt; Hamilton 120. -100 -11 1 I.WH 44(1 1,97'.' 4:VJ1H 80.0 l.2tW,570 ."&gt;1H.«8B 00 sa?- S9.1S8 81 « t»90.«W M* .'Hi 7 Hi '.Mti.688 40 m 11.060 00 75 1,121 - 110 509 38 1 4 210 892 1 684 «9.5»» M.0 -'.714,:«1 1.00K.744 4" </seg>
            <seg id="p183">183 CORN— Continued Av COUNTY Acreage Y ldiProdurtion Value per Bushels Acre Kearney Paha Kimball Mudisun McPherson Merrick Nemaha Nuckolls Saunders Scott's Bluff Sheridan Sherman Washington 7H.998 40.5 H. 199,419 $1,279,767 BO 7,821 33.0 268,093 103,337 20 .'H 433 26.1 768,201 807,980 40 826 19.6 16,189 8,47 127. B3H 35.8 4,569,440 l.«27,77« 00 242,368 45.0 10,906,560 4,362,624 00 H8.32H 3M.0 2.596,388 1.038.555,20 7.892! 29.8 235.181 W4.O72 40 11,087 :« 0 364,881 149,052 40 W, 653 33.7 3.358,306 l.:&lt;43,322 40 |r 38,884 J7.8 l,4!W,08T 599, 684 80 S3, 382 35.4 2,931.724 1,180.688 80 70, 681 i 39.3 2.777,763 1. HI. 106 30 114,486 36.6 4,190,18? 1.676.074 80 141.312 40.4 5,709,004i 2.283,801 (K) 79.549 38.5 3,062.638 1.225 15,867; 28 0 438,67«! 175,470 M&lt; 85,0711 42.8 3,598,508 1.439,401 20 74.886 31.8 2,343,931 987 135.952J 40.0 5,438,080 ',175 81.481 38.1 3.104.426 1.241 57.891 40.0 2.295.640 H* 25tt 00 96.389 46 0 4.433.894 1,778,! 13.156 22.0 289.432 115 108.4*7 M.1 3.9:4.57a l.SdA.an 00 ."iH.447 40.0 2. 337. 880 935 175.272 3«. 1 B. 327. 319 2.580 l,64f 42 5 70.' 28.088 HO 116.948 48.9 5.110.627 2,044 14.664^ 26.2 384.196 153.678 40 67.231 35 2 2.366.531 94«.B12 40 1.376! 25.0 ;W.4(H&gt;. 13.760 00 75.468 31.6 '.384.788 M.U8 t» 112.709 40 2 4,380, SOI 1.812.360 40 2.477 SB. 7 SH.7O4 23.481 60 Ii«.(t61 42.3 2.794.380! 1.117.752 tH i 72.271 M.I 2.623. 487 1.049 78,878 37 8 2.962.688 1.186,1 OS, 888 40 0 3.752.920' 1. 501.108 00 97.549 41 I 4.028.773 1,611 12 770 Ml M8.SM 118.506 «&gt; 1 761.808 0 m Ked Willow I" Sr W= </seg>
            <seg id="p184">184 WINTER WHEAT, I9O5 COINTY Acreage Y 'Id Production Vulm- COl'NH \&gt;ev Bn~ j«-r Bosh* A en THE STATK I.741.8MS1 &lt;M 86. 880. 81» $85. Ml THE STATE ill 7:f.r&gt;7:&gt; '.7.4 I itil 1 :7.4 l.*1.945 *H&lt;.l7.3m . ,pe I 797 19.8 73 52 • 797 : 75 B3.CM (X ;t.4«Ki ;i.4«Ki » Blaine II 1U6 i« 1M 1C414 _'(&gt;4. 114 142 - 10.4N JIM 114 14-' - Butte liuj Butte 30 750 BH •" I.S7S l-'.d 1M.HC4 18 1.573 12.0 1H.HC4 18.304 2.245 Hi. 7 :!7.4!M Ht it;. 7 :!7.4!M 88,348 71 Kuffiil.. ; 1'.' - KW 813 .■&gt;Mf,.74!) M ♦2.384 i» - ;4« it Kurt 4(13 !MKi7 (i.H4(i !•( 4(13 -' !t.(i»i7 li.H4(i Hi Bntl.r ■ Omi n '.-,17; r 177.; £ M.."i 10.879 7.615 81. 3 10 6 7.615 * ChBH 8.181 -' 38.8 2.121 83 - 1.470 1,029 i 1.470 1.099 (» .nne DM 5.748 4( 5.748 4&lt; • 1 7»«.7!tO 1.257.753 C : 1.796.7U0 I I 188. 1H« 127. .".:&lt;d 1 N44 :: \m 127,."&gt;*l CuinniK 1 .127 24.(1 i.im -M.ii 82.-108 81.5 (iiiN ..V.W 489.019 :ti 15.0 978 4HW.(ll!t &amp; 15.0 978 1.431 2:17 914 •-&gt;:17W ..-* . 1.431 2:17 'J14 28 4ti.77(i K 1.061.815 74:U7(i •"&gt; r&gt;4:! 24 (i 13,01 W. 122 4 "&gt;4:! -J4 11 18. « 9.122 4 530 17 .". H.-.»7.'&gt; H.41I-,; 17 ."&gt; U.275 H.4H2 •"&gt; 16«.«1I2 !H ■.'33. M47 16«.«!»2 2.2 11.077 7.753 i* .'2.2 11,077 7.753 9( 7 1 47,790 M.4H in 17 1 47.760 M.4N &lt;" Killmore 16.U 1.123.904 787.8 klin :i 1 110.958 777.670 tn 3(1. » 745. (Ki; 521.9 "&gt;r, 77; (iaK.- 1,781 fi&lt; 731 Bl 85,144 21.0 3IS.S12 28S 1 13. 129 7!). 1WI - Hamilton • 57.574 45,008 Hitch Holt 400.940 (X 17.5 175 M.1I </seg>
            <seg id="p185">185 WINTER WHEAT Continued. \\ • (i i ' n : r \ : • V Id Product 1»t BushWs 1.8 1.598.367 *1.115 1 1 1 . 7^1 4 , 13 : ltSH.411 «&lt;1 7,918 -on l..v MrPherson Merrick Nance N'emaha 440. MO SO Nockolla PI l t ■ H.YIP71 Hi I 4.9(] Keil Willow ,\ • ;r.i.ti30 00 263 ! . 4 l» : 1T.0M SO \v ", 1 1 i ti, l ; !&lt;1 I 17. i l.t" 21.3 :: \ A A 18.8 :i ; m v.&lt; i i " </seg>
            <seg id="p186">186 SPRING WHEAT, 1905 Av COUNTY Acreage Y 'Id Production Value jier Bushels Acre THE STATE U0.0151S.46 K713.488 $S,£ i 637 lo.ftiol I : :&gt;,744 11.1 ■ ;!.24(l 19 S 182 14.0 •".48 i.m&gt; Box Bun.- 2.721 16. 0 ;t&lt; . 9.73Q H'. 4 101,181 7(1 - 13 H 81,101 t ,".i4 13.2 M 11,578 14 1 i«;i,a4n 114,874 ll Butler 16 4 10,.-&gt;!M 4,014 44. m «.5»5 I-'" 7». 14d K 4,m&gt;\ 18.2 65, SHU 14.0 «l,72ti v Cheyenne 14. ."&gt; 116.638 4.74U »| 1S.I HiCi 10 (MminK IS 4, 224. 61( 117.691 ( 14; 171.22 ■ 1.463 15 4 15,771 ( 10.7 12.7 B7,« "I lllll 14 :i 1!»., Dundy - (50,279 Fillmore 127 Franklin Frontier 15.4 13B.813 lG.d 41 : V. 2(i&lt;.&lt; 244 1.4:i7 18. B 1 1 1(11 10.U 11.01(1 1.051 12 I 171 15.0 Hamilton 4.2I1H -'2 MdO , 22X 13 :(4ti : 13 n i 11.2 1.870 10.0 XI </seg>
            <seg id="p187">187 Av. COINTY Acreage Y Id Prodaction Value ' per Bushels Acre 1.77O| 13.4 1,364 16 6 ti.."&gt;74 16.0 28,718 $ 20,816 i6,«« 6o 14,571 20 73.628 *&gt; 8,574 16.0 105. 1*4 78, &lt;m 80 Paha Kimlmll N-K5 1H.0 -f. 10,9118 7,886 80 7.6HN M :!4.:llM 11.6 4,818 11.6 8JW.088 878,861 80 l«MBMti ~i2.'7»8 57,958 80 82.798 ■i4.»BH 10,171 1.4ti7 17.0 _'4,»3H 17,457 30 l,«.-&gt;» 10.4 80,878 14,261 10 ttt,65V 64,861 80 llcPb«ran 20 14. 2! 284 I, MO 1&lt;U 14.4 1.4H7 4,806 1.047 90 2.M4 M 90. ti 15.0 " Hl.w S.W8 i:f..» 50.811 35,567 70 5.01)) 00 DO.Mi 4.1 55,10*60 17s 15. Ol 7,128 10. 1, II n 7,170 71.SM2 78.728 HM 18.0 1,320 A illow 7.712 17.0 131,104 - 1.011 15.5 - 15.0 1.3411 17.0 15.670 31.820 22.988 16,846 17,115 £5 S 16]o:&gt;3 10 11.442 20 11,980 50 ■aunders 74Ji M.M 1.141 15.0 - Bluff « 14.0 448 Hheridai •24.409 I*. I 2.6»3 11.0 1.186 20.0 6,174 lit 378.339 29 623 &gt;A, 72(1 77,792 20. 7M 10 16.604 00 54.454 40 B 14 7 132| H2 40 168; 117 60 12 14 0 50,904 00 47,110 00 93,065 00 97.129 20 I 11.4 I 11.2 11. Ml 11.8 11.563 11.0 72.720 67,800 132,95(1 1*8,756 ngtcii 63(1 441 00 1.140 798 00 m lid </seg>
            <seg id="p188">188 OATS, I9O5 Av (df.VTV V Id PrcKhuti per STATE Boi Butu e * s ssr Dumly Ki 11 ni ore Franklin (iartield (irant (Incl.v Hall ' .'■-'.-I. 1 til 1 Hamilton Harlan Hajes Hitchcock 1,115 i« </seg>
            <seg id="p189">189 OATS Continued Av V Id Production Value COUNTY \&lt; KM ■-H«i 21 ! •ft. 7 I '.!■&gt;. 318 .V H. 11 Tin 30 (I !!»« 00 33.77B 31.1 I.I - -»4«l. HM 30 :«. 7?H 31.1 l.i D -:: . U.:U! ::i - 1 U.:UI 31.n l </seg>
            <seg id="p190">190 BARLEY, 1905 Acreage Y'ld:Production Value per Biwhel* 188, 800181. 46 5.926.831 »2. 19,' 1J.030I * 16.073 4.4.-&gt;l 10 9.762 3.611 94 B.54O 2'i, 75*1 H.417 .V l(&gt;S,-«4.-, 4d (»W U 10,422 3.-C* It 23.1JW 22. 100 g 177 Hi 104.009 19.041 7 04". 17 4,444' 104.750 156.0H5 H. 275 B.WI 38.0 MO 10 • i. tit h:.h m,2.-&gt;: 20 &lt; M.M li.s 1 IM 26. 2! 30.261 11. I 0 331. 13« .MW.920 82 12.K15 4,« 8. SOW IS. « 101.' - SIS 588.345 1UV 33.440 914 K«78 9.130 88 1B.0WI 5.842 2(1 •.Hi 8.08H 15 • M 9 242.865 «8.k; 1.174 7.-1 3. 175 ii«.-| M.MI M 111.804 »H 152.280 300.554 5.600| 13.946 12.627 I, Ml 02 4,6?1 9» 4.590 12.600 L«i H L« Hamilton 4,347 as: 32,088 Ml ' 21. H 2,W»4 33.3 II, BS 37.1 l.mj* 80.0 1H7.480 H6.713 HO5.157 39.360; E- 297. 90K 09 14.583 80 m 7."» 25 6 I, MS ;tl4' »7.5 25, 135 ■ M M 4.7B4 1 770 W 788i </seg>
            <seg id="p191">191 BARLEY Continued Av COUNTY Acreage Y Id Production Value IH»r Bushels Acre 283 ao.o 5.2«O f 21.HO5 31.556 i mi n «!H) 24 .". Pahu Kimhall 1,888 24 5 \M 80. «l 4. V.n U.74« M.T ;mi.«ci 188, 4 Itf ft4 LaMMtar Lincoln 272 26 0 7.072 4. 383 2.374 138, 4(15 - moii 80.0 24.27(1 McPhentun ■ k 4.7OK 1 *. :-mh» ."&gt; 2!M IKI Nackolh in H.0 2. li-i l.V). 25 1 2H! 20.0 8, 7iW I.SM H 560 Perkins pK 111 20. l)i 2.«20 2H.6 31.059 :(7l 1H.3 4.071 U« ;f. 442 24 0 '.Hi. 075 H2.HO8 H.798 ■,«• «M M Willow Hichardson 1-^.861 4tiH. 140 16.614 28. 200 42H ;«l 0 1.1 HO 20 0 5^ .. _., .. 4.;n« ! M M 13H 27.5 8, 740 i M M Ktt M. 1 8,210 Sheridan Sherman m m Saundere I"- &gt;U 15 0 •V&gt; 1 36. 0! 82.0 4?.:Wo N 23.6 1.180 1 IB. S 23 J4 3 ■J. 744 351 24.2 MM 1.116 31.2 HKtDIl </seg>
            <seg id="p192">192 RYE, I9O5 At. COUNTY Aireaxe Y Id Pr»du&lt;-1 Valuf i ( \:.4 (M 147 Pumlv ii."i 13 Killmorf 432 It Hin-ln ) i ■4 </seg>
            <seg id="p193">193 RYE Continued Av COUNTS Acreage Y Id Production Value p6r Biishfls Kiitti Pahu l« - 11 :■ Kimball 77? IN 77? 1- 14.- !&gt;■!■ 2,812 ia 312 IH o 43 ■ !2.5 W, 170 in 4.ft52 -'-' 579 l» 579 liM 11. a 523 15.8 H.106 523 13 M son 1.721 18 721! 1- k 4,701 11.8 ."&gt;-. ■ 7 It!* II 12.8 I in .11.(1 1.43 Nnckolb I »' B. J.V.i 3, 7 • 11. ( l."i) 20.3 :i. I."i7 1. 01 i . i 1.7 Id. - I.!, 7« r.'. j '.'.m LSI 15. U Polk illow laon 'J. 97 1 10(1.511 AV hi 17.8111 31 41 17. 2 l.-i : &gt;;mn.|. ■■- 1.1 - ~ Bluff KM SHI I 4«5 17 17.7 17.- 8, 137 •i4(l lri 132 H .". 1 ii 1 4 1. I ■ 0 :ill i- 14.: 1 . 1 . •• i (17 l h;.. lugton t&gt;.44d I. "in 15 6.750 ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p194">194 ALFALFA, I9O6 \v CX)UNTV _•■ V Id Production Y per Tons THK STATE 115.711 4.12 1 ;S(M.7HO -&gt;4U ).n;t n l.r&gt;ot; i: IM 4 .VJ.-) » :i m 4 1) in*; H44 01 1122 4-.'!i :(. l 4 :i H4. in; 4.N-.M (M4 (* 4:! 1,L&gt;&lt;&gt;1 4d 4."..;- "&gt;, (I-W 4.(h)!i •&gt;4 4.:i9.&gt; I 1 4 1 ■J4.4:* rt24 37.240 335,160 12,71 62«, 4 SSS I. ii 1 . 480 l.lio g.0 M.S 1,181 4 .". 4.."i i 41,91 li.-)7 '.''.' I ( 1T.H5S IHl.tWl 0&lt;i 4,540 ik',4 4.."i 1M.71 Ii 4.O r 4.U 4* .Ml .')1H,4OO 1.1,923 547 Hit" I 4.7 4. HIM 1.930 m 4 Ii </seg>
            <seg id="p195">BUKEAU OP LABOR 195 ALFALFA, I9O5 Continued Av corxTY Acreage V Id Production 1 Value Tons Acre Kearney Keith Key a Paha Kimball Knox Lancaster Lincoln 1 jti^an IfcPln Merrick Pawnee Perkins W 18 4.2H1 3.H lfi. 191 14"). 7 8.204 I!). - 15,260 137.34 Kcd Willow Kichardson KiK'k nKton Wayne tf.*lK 4.3 29.H0N &amp;M.: 8. lOd K.I-'.-) 73.1 1.418 8.1 4, aW :t. 854 30. ! 1,210 8.8 4.3T&gt;K 4 -' 18,889 146.9«1 00 :i.-' 12.H45 111 H4 5.0 4T(i 578 8.1 1.9(17 17. 183 00 1,528 8.4 5,174 4,m&gt; 14 14.MUH 1H4 a.718 4.5 ia,aai 110,1 1,885 4.1 7.r.« 67.7 IU.WU «).m 862 4.0 8.28S «97 2,870 8.3 IW.S86 00 1 ."). &gt;tK&gt; 137 t. ud m. ■ 3.3 1(5.3*7 147 10. 47:f 15.SH2I 140 1 5 s. 1411 7Hti 8,881 M.44I 00 ».B1« 4 7 U.WS 4tJ6,H 1.960 10 6.S78 1 . «y:&lt; H. 4:« 4 458 4 1 l!t,l«t&gt; 172, 5U 1.K70 Hi.- 4.:! 10.474 ."&gt;.'.&lt;•« t.8 U :&gt;•.&gt;.•&gt;, 386 00 101 I K I.M 32, : •"&gt; -J BUS -'.".. Hti-J -Wip t 1 10.0«l 3.3 1,880 14.- 4.'-.' RP Saumi a BlufT Sheridan Sherman ill Thurston </seg>
            <seg id="p196">196 CORN, 1906 At. Ii] Production Valui per Bushel-. STY THK STATE l.'.K)* t II. 1 '■&gt;■:: r 19.H 4J 4 1 41 I xi4.iir.-i i t*&gt; 4.") 1 l.Vm.'t&amp;i TJiT. 14- 04 44 1X1. 941 I.991.H71 li'.t Hi.4iU :::: - 557. 830 1 M.-J ■„' !MHl. J7.") 1,1 lid H.-i I. (till - '.Cif, i; 1.IMI7.I- 41 .-,0 12H.IKK) 7.") I - i r,-:. nil c&gt;-.m.-j4!' 57 Hamilton !MJ BO.715J IK. 7ti4 How anl 7-4 4! 1.094 . </seg>
            <seg id="p197">197 CORN— Continued \v COUNTY Acreage Y'ld Production \ I h ■ r I Acr Kearney Keith Paba Kimball Knux Lancaster Lincoln Logar Loup Madison McPhen Merrick 1. 107.: Pawi Kg," Willow inlwn 1. ltit;.:«4 1..1-I Satmder 41 i : S&lt;ott's Bluff Beward Sheridan SherniHn in Thurstoi Valley Washington Wayne ■ 3,447. 1CKJ I </seg>
            <seg id="p198">198 WINTER WHEAT, I9O6 Av COUNTY Acreage Y Id Production Value r*r Bushels Acre THE STATE I, KM 45.3«9,368j»29.503.(i~ • •T4.r&gt;3» H.MB.4M M 074.: 539 M. 34*. 450 S5 srr 154.179 100.816 85 100.211! 14.810 9.:&gt;&lt;il H 14.310 9.S01 tM KS ltS. 0 4(K&gt; 2H0 00 400 260 (H 16.909 23.7 4(10. »H0 260.637 00 41 Hil MO 429 (Hi l.«0&gt; U aii 19.231 BS I7« "74 4(1 a. a i. aw — 185,124 «&lt;• 1. l« • 111. 97") H&lt; I.. "STB. 876 1.036.919 4&lt; !3tt. 965 195,977 i !1.5 48. £ ii&gt;4 7 16.909 23 400. 9M0 260.637 IK Butte 41 1 16.1 »S60 429 (Hi 1.60»-| 1H.4 19, Ml 8H 5*8 m 074 40 124 6(1 £ • 21. S 4 054 43.H3M 494 70 4 St.") 4 80.1 100. 5«6 iti7 90 100.566 65.367 90 768 .V6H.-. I 69.-. "I.", 10.71.-. t)*; 10,718 ti.964 ■ IS,**! 23.4 2.47 4 IH - 2.i«B,aei 1.410.01s HiB.261 1.410.019 ti."&gt; IS,**! 23.4 311.711 202.612 1 311.711 202.612 19 B: 2.474 588.5 70.509 45.^ 70,609 45.H30 4H. lit - H-J" 1«4 K03.3I ■ -'- 4 in &lt;,. «. V*v 4Hn 2o.o r&gt;. ."&gt;vhi in ii-.'K Hi-t 603.306 HO 6.922 4HU 20.0 (KKI .")90 (Ni ter 47.HM7 25.0 1.199,873 77!i. &gt;- i'&gt;.: 14.X.-.4 ».«5.-» 1 : 25. 0 1.199.075 57M 25 9.65T. 10 H41 80 7 1H.47H 12.66t) 7 941 20 7 19.47K 12.660 7d 16.888 2ii :! 48fl,24a 178,887 M 42« 242 Killmore Franklin Frontier 13.3rfl 4 13.3** 1 ! 40 M.HI 37. e*r. M ; 17 ii 1 2ti. 1 - 20.7 20.159 1B.8 1.080.720 « -4 «lti.3Hl f,( 148,509 2&lt; :iL',743 17 ti 576, 11H 374.47H 70 K4,50« .'ti. 1 I.6H8,«»4 1.094,894 BO ■&lt;&gt;7 41.M7M 17, SM S3 159 It.S ;W3, 100 ■.'.■.,-)..-.! I 28.0 12« 88,784 !•:&gt; s 41,979 n.atM u 393, 100 235,519 on S i '."I 23.(1 - 24.9 IK. 4 734 !..", 43.2.-)M 24.9 1.1177,124 700, 180 «0 1.077,124 700, 130 60 1.399 ■ Hamilton Harlan 7ii.:«4 2H.2 2,152,836 1 ;t!W n - 15S.886 .■.7.Hti;i 1K.4 l.i«4.ti7!i 892,04185 ■42 18.1 :24 CS.1S 17.6 W4.1K7 827,721 58 1.064,679 H B Havm B.S4I 2H.647 17 Ii a. is 327.721 ,V&gt; Hitchcock Holt •"►O4 1 lo.5 5.5 4;t - -&gt;h 471 M 2K471 9.-) Hooker Hdwaid 2!&lt; - (t,412 5O4,«i 77(1.412 Mil Mil 5(M W7 SO 327.:.: </seg>
            <seg id="p199">199 WINTER WHEAT Continued. Ay COUNTY Ai-rea*.- Y'ld Prudiirtii.ii \ ]»T I - 1,117, ■. : 14,! Paha dl -'I .;... ..'I Till 21 n 0 IS « - hi Mcl'hi'iMin - - - In ■ - Pheli A illi&gt;u dson 4 :-. j '\ *h» 4a:i I l« H i IT 1. 112.fi ,;.,, - - m..n i ..in „ 2 B l'.H 74 19 - BluS ■I - v.n .; ««S 70 .v.i I n ■ - </seg>
            <seg id="p200">200 SPRING WHEAT, 1906 Av COUNTY reoge Y idlProduction Yahn 1»t Bushel* Acre THK STATE :'.l 4..")0-J ."i.TT.'i til 47 17.0 J.H43 12 0 :U 1 1t !&gt;7.li(i7 (11 I m 34. 1 ■.M. U ,,,,,.,. 4.8M IJ 8.511 lti i, «. 174 18 2 I 11M 14 1 1.(147 .M.XI7 :14_ i 117,050 B=r 4«i. (J4."&gt; 13ii W.- 41'.: 1 1 -' 47.;S'.l!) 2!». -■ Fillmnre 17 ) 44. i A&gt; 13.6 7.411 ia.0 in I 14.d 8fi : 41 l.VO 1 - 174 2,810 1 U 44 15.0 41 Hamilton Harlan m is g.410 15.0 H.150 :M'71 Hitcl :!'.&lt;7 1 1 • 509 ! -JI m 7:&lt;H 1 14.04 1 »■ </seg>
            <seg id="p201">201 SPRING WHEAT Continued Av COUNTY Acreage Y 'Id Production \ per Bushels Acre Kearney Keith 15.1 23.042 * 14. ; 7.-. 17.4 Reya Ps Kimball Knox Wi 1 I B 124 151 lii LOW it; 0 IT, B.13H 1H.4 In- Laacaatt Lincoln Logan 10 13.8 474 l( 7.S_'I Loop 1.000. 10.700 6.741 IK I Madism McPher 46 18.81 521 Naiu 100 12 0 1.200 Nemaba NockolU 81..' 19- 4ti! 14.3 4Kf !M 847 I! Pheh ,4 4H ■r, i 1 1 Piera :U.it35 83 J1.473 13.3MK 518 :f&gt;;&lt; It K.-&lt;i Wil 964 I w Kmk 694 l 1.777 17.5 3lJ ■ 20.0 11,5 2H.714 is. 8 18.4 15J :«. 14.4 6H 17.5 1.1021 M M Thontoi 12.6 B4.G71 34 ■ 2:1 i ■ 7.474 14.3 161) 8.215 12 H lay l.-&gt;2 66..' 14H 13.7 2.(XX)i II 1 Ml.* |,M </seg>
            <seg id="p202">202 OATS, 19O6 OH'XTY Acreage V 'li Production Value OHXTY ]ht BusbeU par Bushels .\&lt;re THK STATE 18 78. -Mil. 888*21. 9«9 THE STATE 12 TK. 4»il . MHH|#21 . «•'.'-■ 11,719 K 0 801 888 | [V 21.71 B07 tt36 * 17' Aikim* . :a 7iii • . r :U &gt; :«. •!« 606 Sl.S 182 6. i :iti KOl.OtW 4 (W6 81. h 13:2 »; inf. &lt;* 38 II 2. CMUt. Tlti *0 1.000 4 Box Hun. Box Butte Boyd Ml 4 Bovd JM.418 «&lt; 359.413 « bSSL Brown M.B M.W4 ■ -■ Hurt 1 M " 7 1H7 7t ; Butlt-r H S73.T38 '.» Butlt-r &lt; ;l ., 239.035 I &gt;iMfl IM.OM I £ m; tH ;i 917.272 7 ■M 5 » Vi ~ 19.i ao6 11.3 i.v.t.'.HMi 7-». 77: . mif - mi in:) :«». : : rewM ii 1( it). Hit 81.2 1.018.7M I I.0I8.7M 284.679 92 S8S.1S6 84 539.156 2 ni K 6».0:v 8H2.584 967.109 3 H21.74O - i: nil. 26. SOS ■■'.:: ; K: : 196 i:U ■ I 1.4; 18,076 :h ia.i n 44ti.K71 1 44.68W 85 7 1 .V.t.Y J.V1 »4»i.ti71 h&gt; 168.622 0 DunJy I8,*78 7 Fillmnn- I tHMi ;&gt; Franklin 94,5 •ier 1: 94.:. («1 Fumas «24. 190 lia^'- 30 8 1.526.271 127 • Id 54.H4H .-, 6. 1 IB 82. 1 1 1'." 54 V 8.303 31.4 -'tMi.iHWl 74 •m ( 816 8H 4 ■ 31.4 74.: Grant SO 1 816 '.Ml. Kill -.'H8.VJ4 941.160 263.524 hi Hall 224,275 80 M(K).985 2a4 Hamilton 7!Wi 32 Hamilton Harlan ■.m 3 i Harlan Hitchcock SS 1.170 1.1 1&gt;7 IK I !Htt.(H)4 252 - 83 000 38.6 77" -"" .'I- </seg>
            <seg id="p203">203 OATS Continued Av .'OrXTY Acreage Y Id Production Valne l*'r Bushels Acre Kearney Keith ■M.44T 1..4H8 10. 144 V, n.-,(i .-,1.414 INI 51.4M it" Keya Pa ha Kimhall ■ M.OT Knox ■ I^am-uhter Lincoln Logan Loup O.N0 - ao.061 w Madison H16 HT.O 153 T« McPhersoii Merrick 14ti 14ti i- Xance 1 . Ui!». 7H-2 N'emaha Nockolb Otoe I :t'.i 139 16 [!'.&gt;.:- Pawn* Perkins Phelpa Pierce Platte v!.-&gt;4. : Polk 756.118 811,7 82.182 Ked Willow Kichartlsun KiK-k 41, m n £S 270, 4^ 19:i,4 Saunders 857.740 Hi Soott'i Bluff Seward «9. 148 N»i Sheridan Sherman Sioux 1 hiirston 440, (N Washington Wayne 14 7t; Webster 107. 1 ; </seg>
            <seg id="p204">204 BARLEY, I9O6 Av inrXTY &gt; Id Production Vulut Busbt Acre THK STATE 142.727 *l 8,910 1.184 ih 11.155 4 li;-.' 81.6 MO 4t 9. l.-,i !iutt.' 77- 31 !t. •,'(&gt;!! Ki . •ilil 21 (I 4 :.!t!l 1,81 4U4 2f !•!'. tit; 39 1119 -,&gt;;i 1 3.SMIH V.I Ei 1 1-7 81.0 WJ 14.7 - 7 ?4O ; a H.4K3 1,051 3W.0 4Q.98U 16.: I ti 9,182 421 22 • 6,704 71,( 679 2 s=r 21,( -74 (K (i-&gt;ii !1.« 18t34H 5.3:19 * IV 4.1144 IK UN' - 1,052 IK H4 82 1,856 74'.' 41 1,215 25 1( .'1 11 87.1 2.276 18, . 1..-.I WlSOI 4.»22 8( Hamilton Harlan 87 .': ; ..:■ ::■ i : 40.180 Hitchcock ilili 4&lt; 17,780 Is IX </seg>
            <seg id="p205">205 BUREAU OF LABOR BARLEY Continued Ay _r Y Id Production Value COUNTY per ffnrimh Acre ! 169 | 1,014 ini Kt-ith . 413 18,1 K.ya I 'alia 10, 4.1 : K.ya I 'alia Ki in ball Kimball 4:'.:, ij 43.*&gt; ••■ i a ■ 1,841 80 8 41 : Hi 1,841 BOM 41.: Hi.: 24.8 7.-JWI 2.91 later 24.8 T.-Jim Lincoln r,7. : .11 :. 270 McPherson llerrick 78 85 (I 101 1,025 161 ■-' 1,028 Mil ; i L.v.is Hi ■_&gt;(! -'.4tHli Perkin Pfaelpa 18,300 8,300' B 2.381 ;ti4 r«4 ;:i Jl o 3,423 Willow Richardson Willow !4 ll.i.Mtflt «() inlson .lid 1,0 2,244 121 W. 1 121 :' 26. 1 launders s Bluff i •■ Bluff rd I s -' 2, |h 80.0 2,1- diui 1.531 31.7 49,168 lD.fii ndaii 1,531 81.7 49,166 111. ■■ Sli.iinai nan 881 22.2 4.6IM .in -V.i'.i 7. I 7. t Thayer Thoma )"i 41."&gt; M Tfaootaa Thurstun 3.51 1)1 « 42 i Thurstoi Valley 3.517 H Sllti 42 ; Valley 12.UI.1 5, II Waafaingtoo Waahingtoa . 58, ( -Ji 13. m 1,017 </seg>
            <seg id="p206">206 RYE, 1906 Ay roi'XTY Id Production Valut 1 p*r But-hels Acre H2.970 17.711 1,476.871 $ 788.185 50 THE STATE 44 17.8 770$ 507 1«5 41 20.6* 1 . Hi (i JO.IH7 111.3(18 50 228 16.2 3.HSW l.H4ti M t&gt;.-&gt;7 17 H H.5M 5.7*1 SO 8.815 16.8 47.29-.' »,64f IHi Butte 621 22. A 13.H72 6.'.'- &amp; 18.(1 2:1(194 11.547 (X) 1.229 14 li 17,2 8.603 01 41ti 21 li 4.4« 59W 13.5 4.048 IN' US 30.8 8.848 4. r. 469 1' 7.504 3.752 00 1502 15.8 W.210 4.605 Oil til 1 1 1 7.212 B,«06 (Hi i :. l' 5i.i 171 .' 4.052 1,0 635 II in 5.143 50 ■:, (i 12.I175 6,887 S », lllii 1H - 77.24M '124 5 1 );t\vt-s u:&gt; 20. 0 1.900 950 m in &lt;' h; «,0&lt;M 5 ■4 1 30." 18,808 Ml S=T Hil7 111 S 17. 140 125 2S.0 8,125 l.Sfla SO 314 18 3 5,7441 ttt on 127 20.0 2.540 1.270 (HI 806 17.7 15 .- 7.!l2!i 50 137 [t 2.534 1.2li7 oo Fillmorf Mil 12.5 1.112 55ti oo 284 17.0 111.414 00 • 15 17 O 1(1.45 927 27ii 28.3 6. 480 3.215 mi 48.1 !- 8.972 4.-W6 00 14« 15 li ■&gt;. lltd -r,"i 17(1 14.773 7,"- LOOK 20.728 10,361 Hamilton 150 r 2.H25 1.4«2 112 234 1 lil. 44li 30,723 l.lMil 14.3 942 14.021 00 Kill 16. 1 13 - 6,931 (HI 5,791 12.5 72 M, 1113*50 m 115 15.0 1.485 712 50 18. (I 4». 28.238 0(&gt; 2.' 7SO.O0 </seg>
            <seg id="p207">207 RYE Continued Av COl'NTY Acreage Y Id Production Value ]mt Bushels Acre Keya Paba Kim ball McPhers !5.0 78 1- 1,390 M ihi •JiHi 2i H.-.1 Will un.l itl 263 IK mi 20.0 _'. I r. .V.I. til I I8« 111 il-.M 17 :uh 21. ( 35« 24. ( 15.0 1,544) lot 20.0 170 :i. 4ih» ♦ I .: BIO 15. &lt; 1.558 14.0 21- in..' Hi;:( 19.0 !--&gt;. r&gt;l»T 1.31H Hi.ii 21. f 10,»89 00 ■on M.M0 20 II 4H.lilid 21, H Ift.O 110 00 18.8 ;!.Hao 1,241 21,( 108 1- 18,01 410 I Namfca 4. 1 ■ 402 7, 2»8 11.6 I.W 17.4 32. 3 Htil 84.8 !iO. - 10, • IH.H -2:. 13," 213 80. 0 4.340 708 16.0 10..' 17. i », 283 1.1* Sheridan Sherman Stan too ThoiiiMs Thnraton li-21 SO. tl 12, i 110 &lt;»' 1,299 16.0 20. 784| Id 1,098 -Mi 205 17.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p208">208 ALFALFA, \906 Av NTY A reage Y'ldProdocti Valui par Tot Acn MSS.ttSl ii ii7 1.340,64 THK STATE 2 lit, It (KI4 4.ii ii; 4 19 l'.Hi 2. 1 11,507 • Butte 4 IF 56,81 *, 1 19 8. 1 H 4.1 1 15S Dakota t; 4.1 4«a 11.548 101,239 8,718 S=T 42 HI!) 4 ."&gt;4l Pillmure 4 1 18: ■21 B.24« 411 14.51U IK 4 i«U 231 54 ;14!1. 22-1 S81.8A6 Hamilton Harlun 3 19.240 Hitcl Bolt 3.0 &lt;» H«x)ker Howard M I I </seg>
            <seg id="p209">209 ALFALFA, Continued Av COUNTY Acreage V Id Production Vahw per Tons A erf Kearney 7, 8&lt; 1 7,142 7,808 61, V . Pa ha Kimball SUM Lancaster Lincoln ■Y14;; H.8 lii. 457 131, 6.V 84fi ;i.-»hi Madison McPher»on Merrick 4.1SI.' 13i Xemaha Nuckolh 414 :i 1 K47 J. H Mlil :( u H8 4 (' Perkins ldl 1.4HX 4.4 I9.8H5 l.V). ;• 17.4!':, kU l«' ;i.' w ». 14S Ked Willow Kichardson .'4N .'It. 7 1 1 Sauiiders 4 * Bmid 8U.5I8 -'44.! Sheridan Sherman H.75O 10,811 Thomas Thurstoi Vullev a. i 174 H7 • 4."xi Washington Wayne Webster 15, lid ar His 1,128 S.1 H,!*92 I5.W88 127,4: 1«.7( </seg>
            <seg id="p210">210 I WILD HAY, 1906 At. Acreage Y 1&lt;1 Production Value COUNTY per Tons 243.221 1.18 2,i .133.621 -TATE . 1.1H 11,277 ♦ 67.S62 00 127 1.0K 41,177 MT.Ofl i .91 5 1.09 B.4SI 1 80 15,124 1.00 4.4!«l M.8M ik 111,782 (10 48, 160 lid (Kl Box Buttt- 1HI.744 OH 822 (Kl sir i i m 40 tOU 1 8« . 1 lid 1 ."ill 1 "&gt;*i. i -.'-i, lli'-f i:«.»7h (ki 14,674 14 (Kl 044 (Kl &lt;E :io. iu7 l 45, n» 27tl. «MM» (Ml B.050 1 l"i (i.'.Ti7 41.742 00 185,491 ( 'ht-vennc 30,38-! 1.08 ; l . 2h 42,120 - l.'.ir. ■ 1 (JO 281.702 (Hi 054 CHI 92. (K IIH(l INI &amp; 4.i«i&gt;; i -t.'.'tit; S9.796 (in ■) 1.12 a (M.I 144.24(1 (HI ■,'Kl .7d 11H.77I1 (Kl i 1 47 132,510 1 1)4 11.499 .-H1.H94 (Ki 10,741 H4.446 (Hi Fnuiklin i 1.31 251 1 41 142 • l.i Hi 9,407 S6.442 (mi I.V.I. H' . 1.00 18,047 1 H4 ."•(54 13 ."&gt;tix H1.40H Oil 184.27 4.."i7(l 1 3(1.71 1U7. 17" 88,511 1.44 23.69-' I. SO I 1.IKI 102 213. J ;4 oo i ."in Iil4.4:«i 00 I2O.4OU 1 . ! ."i 521 15, 120 M 19 891 116.346 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p211">211 ; WILD HAY Continued. Lancaster Liiii-iilii Logan Loup Madison McPbi Merrick Nemaha Nuikoll: Otiw Pawne Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte Polk Red Willow Richardson Rock Saline Sarpy ma i 4O.SI4I' lH.t&gt;7:' ■.Mi. (KIN W.673 4H, 12H 10. Hi"i SI. «» J4.7!H t*.843 lli.441 14 IMiil 15 820 J 1.7(17 I3.HHH 4N.fr.»l Saunders Soitt's Bluff Seward Sheridan Sherman Bub ton Thayer Thomas Thurston Valley 1.1 Mti 1(1.7411 l "&gt;:f 24.:(4!l lid '.1.4:1; 1.83 Washington Waym Webster Wheeler York At. Acreage Y lil Production Yalut l»r Tons COUNTY Kearney Keith Keya Paha Kimball Knoz 1 ?.") i ■.&gt;.-. mi iai . 1 4U 7.1)1(1 I. (HI 24.497 I4ti I 4(1 M.7H2 1 &gt;&gt; 12,191 73 h 14-' ii.7-"&gt;7 1 (XI 28 87M 1 4."&gt; 3»4 00 1 17 11.4W!&gt; 18.04(1 1 4 i 18. :»4' in!' 74.C(I4 I. 13 «■"&gt;. H'4 .*il(i ■ 2O.t»lfl 1 imp 83.44M -'(«' :!..Vjr&gt; 1 mi Nam-e i.stv 51, 7« 41 .44HI I. Hi 1 I 71 148,7-1 1 ■_• 7 4 7 1.71 IU.87H 80.018 I ti'J </seg>
            <seg id="p212">212 SPELTZ, 1906 Av. N,Y SiY - Y Id Prod ValiiH THE STATS f 78a, t7] I THE STATE 4( I 10,400 $ :■ Antalupa 16, ■ Blame K. \4&lt; ! le. Butte Boyd Kux Botta 1 .■■- 55, 1»,416 i 1 Boyd I - ■j . 32 « 11. 1 ,'ti i i . lint; IS, - 1,778 i 11,908 ; IS, - 4 :&lt;-.'. l nne 1,308 197 iiliT I Ii ng : 4. ('44 1.41H i ('timing 4 865 I i 7.V.J ! • 37,(144 ( n 22, IT:. T.Ttil S 500 41 M.3 30 I 7. -227 ; W.O 1,400 41HI I 1,176 i 1.14&lt;&gt; Ml ( 4 •M )n ii . ire 4~ 1,440 lin 17. "i 19 :-!lh ■ ( 15 14 10H 567 4 m !."l (I : </seg>
            <seg id="p213">213 SPELTZ— Conlinued Av COUNTV &gt; Id Production \ \*-r Bushek Kearney Keith S»00 $ I.i BIO 00 Paha Kimliall 2.SMII 1 19,-1 -11 00 Knox Lanoaatw Linculn 5,188 86.0*1 M Li in p 1.2H 12.1 Madisoi Mel'!,- Mejrirk 241 '-' KW Xam '. i'.W SO Xcuiahu U.i:.( | 2,070 Ot... JVrkii i.:: 4- I" ii 1.U20 iil.i IKI I'latte Polk '.i.ii-Iii «1. Red Willow Ricbardaon Bock Saline Sarjiy .;, ii 2 ,a SaumltT !.i 0 Soott'a Bluft Seward :ui; ; • 14. Thayer Thomas fhursto Valley BM (Hi B77 w 144 . \\ ashingtoi Waym 4.9M 1. ', Webete 1T.HBW ii. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p214">214 IRISH POTATOES, I9O6 Av OOl'NTV _••■ Y hi Production Value Mr Bushel* Acn- THE STATK ■i #2.*98,(&gt;kk -in m II, SOB 4 522 i« ' !!&lt;;! ■ U lti.019 i, HI It 1.0 HiU 0 H8H lln H in-.'. !« in 41 Hlltte 1 HW 17 S? M4 a 1. 112 88,272 24.HON Mil Mi x'- 1 0 ««. 12 M 98, 2HU (HI tK)..")lH 24 206 40 iE It HI »9 ■M ni m,tH SHKI (HI b«. nit) n,M *M 40 881 SI (1 :13.7H1 5()4 441 1H K2 1 94) i ' 4S.U76 1 3»0 4(1 E 9i4 10H.li 38 in- Mill 13 m i -i l.'i'.i H4 B3 . . . 51 tsr M HI ii'i -ii'j W ■M -mi SI 5W 00 Franklin 514 IX) 75 728 748 47.0 14 (r&gt;4 712 42 (i 2H.H04 11 MU M 972 40.(1 IB. H7, 100 14 40 OU .HO HO it, us •U M 472 41.(" M.d 405 42."&gt; till H6.0 N.M4 «8,7« :« wi Hamilton Harlan Hdl !)(i(i Mill' H3« (Id 7h;i ;iii.u 28.4H0 Htm (K» 11 B 600 00 Hitch «40 00 ML Ml 7* K3ti 40 E: 70 M 0 . 1 400 (Ml iti (71 20 II 9%) HO HO 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p215">215 IRISH POTATOES Continued Av (HNTY Acreage Y 'Id Production Vain ]&gt;er Bushels Kearney Keith 410 14,152 23,870 Keys Puh;i Kimball 62.0 161 4!l 11 Knox ' KM (I 70. 1' lK"i,.")(KI •VJ. 1111 Lancaster Lincoln 11 Hi 76. ( '.UI44 1411 H7.I St. 447 Mmlisol - ecPherson errii-k Nance Eemaha uckoll- 21,." Piiwne Perkin Pierce 1.-).- 4B.) 7u 11 K«l Willow Richardson 'Mi ."i7.n - Blurt Sheridan 1 ■.'."). H 4. 125 iitfton •00 1 18.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p216">216 ACREAGE AND PRODUCTION OF THREE PRINCIPAL CROPS BRASKA FOR TEN YEARS CORN Acreage Production Bushels i-Mi.903 341.888.887 243, 7 13, 244 IttM ■&gt;», 11*4 1M.6K III 516, HOI i 14.-1 I!«&gt;U 43.WiO.817 )i - 17.").Hlli.&lt;&gt;41 ".'.'. 74ii a, 940 % WHEAT Acreafp Production Bum l»»i INS 1U04 mn IMS 148.028 41.WH.757 WU II24.6U7 81.82! 48,660, 31m T.4K4 •i'~'2, l+ti!i 4h, -&gt;i:&gt; 114.."&gt;92 H . K| 452.647 OATS Acreage Production BuNhels ISM 1U04 i «oa r.'"i !■ •) 5i,7ti, in 6«. 245. 042 - . W 74-. </seg>
            <seg id="p217">217 ACREAGE AND PRODUCTION OF BARLEY AND RYE IN NEBRASKA FOR EIGHT YEARS BARLEY Wai Acre;i«H Production Bushels i,ms,mi .-&gt;. att, 72.i IS** 10ft, ISM 13 188, M) 1904 19'i 113. 8.013,500 1903 717 l»02 1.960.390 1.188.68H 414 1»OI T4 563 1900 M, H St43, 176 1MW 3.1. 374 587.88? RYE Production Bushels Year Acnagt 1SHK5 907 1,476. 87 1 GROWTH OF BANK DEPOSITS IN NEBRASKA 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 1900 141. 149 122,56s 843,067 2 474.512 -'.1135,802 Id. 105.707 483,554 155,475 61,073 62.319 H,1u:i,!t?2 ■ 997.104 ih&lt;jy 1890 1903 1904 191)5 1906 (Not. U * 43.770,311.00 10-i. 1H0, 7: 108,214,222.00 IM.tM.tlLW </seg>
            <seg id="p218">218 DISEASE STY 1U04 1905 1906 -TATE 80,794 9.5H2 TZ Box Butte Cheyenne FillmiT Franklin Hamilton 204 408 1H 4»7 2 M 385 715 Hi 102 13 180 1 151 247 371 1.070 22 24 Hi 77 5» 174 21 10 86 44S 57ll ». r ) 150 74 506 373 438 2t&gt;4 423 190 27 522 1.528 74 Mil HH W4 422 12 7» ita Ml 4 40 6 25 M7 i»7 1.404 27 «17 -11 19 ■ ■ 11H 7B ;« 69 1H7 112 1!»1 m 208 28 53 6 nit) t&gt;-'7 311 123 371 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p219">219 DEATHS AMONG CATTLE RESULTING FROM CORN-STALK DISEASE Continued COUNTY I'.tO.-. 11HI4 Kearney Keith 4yn I8H IS Keya Paha Kimball 121 *^ti 14:. t:t KlKiX M Lancaster Lincoln Lugan r&gt;i ;i .Vkl 71 a: M '.Mi Louji 14:» Ifaduon :.J4 McPhersoii 148 l.V.i ;&lt; 4 11 Nance IT Xemaha Nuckolls M j:t 543 M M ■&gt;~: 19 Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte lOti K77 «:i7 171 «!• IM a l»l Polk il Si n Ked Willow Richarilsun Rock 185 4.". M Saline Sarpy 1«3 olB 14 »1 Saunders M Soott'i Bluff Sewanl 7H4 7H ■ Sheridan Sherman Sioux M 11 !i -till Stan ton Thayer Thomas Thurstor. Valley ai2 mi w 4 211 I M\ IS :y&gt;r, I8-.J Washington Wayne .K ;( :&lt;77 J4 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p220">220 BIENNIAL RKPOrtT FROM CORN 4 i 4 i 4 * 4 1 1 DEATHS AMONG HORSES AND MULES RESULTING STALK DISEASE THE STATE Adams ss'nir Uutte BF !E enne m 8=r Dundy Fillmore Franklin £ Hamilton S </seg>
            <seg id="p221">221 DEATHS AMONG HORSES AND MULES RESULTING FROM CORN STALK DISEASE -Continued COUNTY 1SXI4 IMS Kesirney Keith \2 1 Lancastc li l Logai Loup 3 Madison lit B McPhi Merrick 1 Xar in aha « Xuckull ()t(M- 18 in IS ti U 4 4H Keil Willow Kichartlsun M 1 ■ul.ne &gt;arpy 11 21 4!l iaunder I - Bluff .ewuril Id Sheridar Shermai: us Btantoi Thayer Thoma! 1 14 Thurstoi Vllllev II 1 (Vashingtoo Wayne ; i ■ Keya Palm Kimball Knox i:&gt; Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte Polk </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>