<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Truck and Rail Transportation of Nebraska Livestock to the Omaha Market</title>
               <date value="1932-10">1932-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 275 October, 1932 i Truck and Rail Transportation of Nebraska Livestock to the Omaha Market BASIL S. WENDT AND HAROLD HEDGES Department of Rural Economics r THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burnt. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction PaGE '. o Purpose of the study. Nature and sources of the data ; Growth of Livestock Trucking. Origin of Truck and Railroad Receipts \ Livestock Truckage Rates to Omaha .ZZZZZZZ 7 Factors determining truckage rates Z" 11 Changes m truckage rates since August, 1930.... 13 Factors Influencing the Choice of the Means of Transportation....'..'.'.'.'.' 14 Comparison of truck and rail rates ■ Influence of grades of highways and of rail connections 16 Terminal differentials Transit insurance and relative risk 21 Attitude of buyers Convenience Flexibility Shrinkage " A Comparison of Truck and Rail Transportation CwbZZZZZZ 27 Conclusions Appendix '" * * * 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Truck and Rail Transportation of Nebraska Livestock to the Omaha Market ' BASIL S. WENDT AND HAROLD HEDGES 3 The advent of the motor truck into the transportation field has not been without its serious consequences. Prog - ress, m whatever line, tends to disturb the existing order of things. We are now m the period when the motor truck is seeking its proper place m the transportation system. Studies of the relationships among the transporting agencies may serve to speed the necessary adjustments. One phase of the subject is that of livestock transportation, to which this study" is devoted. Purpose of the study. — This report deals with the Omaha livestock market area. Some aspects of the problem which are considered are : growth of truck transportation of live - stock, origin of the truck and rail receipts at Omaha, com- CATTIi 1001 Per cent of numbar „ Per cent of number Tear received by truck * received by truck lo 20 y 40 so 10 a 30 40 go CALVES S H X g P I Per cent of auaber Per cent of nunber Te«r received by truck Tear received by truck _____ ip ?o y&gt; 4Q Q&gt; lp 20 *Q SO i Fig. 1. — Growth m the truck movement of livestock to the Omaha market as shown by the proportion of the kinds of livestock re - ceived by truck m 1920 and annually from 1927 to 1931. 1 The Departments of Animal Husbandry and Rural Economics co-operated m makintr this study. * The authors are indebted to the Union Stock Yards Company and to three com - mission firms at the Omaha market for access to the records and for information cheer - fully supplied and to the Livestock Exchange, the several railroads, and those truckers, livestock men, county agents, and other agencies and individuals who assisted in' pro - vldinc the data and information needed to make this study possible. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 parisons of truck and rail rates on livestock, and the factors influencing the choice of transportation agencies. It is well to recognize at the outset that it has been im - possible to find definite, conclusive answers to the questions raised regarding truck and rail transportation of livestock, ine data have been sufficient, however, to supply certain facts which should serve as a better basis of judgment than mere opinions. Nature and sources of the data. — The figures on truck receipts of livestock at the terminal markets were obtained trom reports of federal and state agencies. To secure com - parative information on the origin of truck and railroad receipts at Omaha, a complete record of all receipts for the week ending May 23, 1931, was transcribed from the records of the Union Stock Yards Company. Receipts throughout the year or at scattered intervals throughout the year would have provided much more reliable data, but the cost of securing and summarizing such a volume of in - formation was prohibitive. Seasonal and other factors cause variations in the movement of livestock from a feed - ing and producing area to a central market; however, the week selected approached the average for the year in volume of receipts at Omaha and was not unusual hTrespect to weather conditions. To determine livestock truckage rates in Nebraska at the time the study was made, data on truck shipments were secured from three of the largest and most representative commission firms on the Omaha market for the fiscal year ending July 31, 1931. The data used in the final computa - tion of truckage rates were so selected as to secure uniform distribution through the zones and to avoid giving too great weight to rates from shipping points which contributed most heavily to the receipts of the three firms whose records were used. The information on terminal charges, insurance rates, death losses, and other factors pertinent to the study was secured from various market agencies. Considerable time was spent in an effort to obtain data on livestock shrinkage from livestock producers throughout the state. Although the volume of data secured was insuf - ficient to justify drawing any definite conclusions, the con - tact with the livestock shippers provided much general in - formation on the problem under study. GROWTH OF LIVESTOCK TRUCKING Omaha receives a larger total number of trucked-in live - stock than any other market in the country, although at several other markets a larger percentage of total receipts </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Truck and Rail Transportation of Livestock arrive by truck. In 1930 Omaha received 2,412,375 head of livestock by truck. Sioux City was second with 2,333,895 head. 3 In 1930 Omaha received 68 per cent of the cattle 48 per cent of the hogs, and 72 per cent of the sheep marketed from Nebraska; hence it is easily the leading - market for Nebraska livestock. 4 T The growing importance of livestock trucking to the Omaha market is indicated by the following comparisons which are shown graphically in Figure 1. Cattle receipts ,L« r, f ck mcreased f rom 1.5 per cent of total receipts an 1920 to 31.5 per cent in 1931, and receipts of calves from 96 per cent in 1920 to 40.4 per cent in 1931. Truck re - ceipts of hogs increased from 6.7 per cent of all hog re - ceipts in 1920 to 58.1 per cent in 1931, and sheep receipts from 2.5 per cent in 1920 to 16.8 per cent in 1931. The increase in proportion of trucked-in receipts of all classes of livestock has been from 4.0 per cent in 1920 to 36.4 per cent in 1931. (For detailed data, see Table I in the Ap - pendix.) Similar increases in truck receipts have occurred at other leading livestock markets. At the sixteen principal markets the increase in driven-in receipts (mainly by truck) of all classes of livestock has been from 1.6 per cent of the total in 1916 to 25.6 per cent in 1930. (For detailed data, see Table II in the Appendix.) Some recent reports, however, indicate a decrease in livestock trucking to certain eastern market centers, which has been ascribed mainlv to traffic congestion on the highways. ORIGIN OF TRUCK AND RAILROAD RECEIPTS Distance is the principal, but by no means the only, factor entering into the determination of transportation rates. Hence it is of interest to consider truck and rail receipts! in relation to distance from the Omaha market. The relation - ships prevailing in 1930-31 were not the same as in earlier years, nor will they continue unchanged. A recent Kansas report on truck transportation 5 presented data showing substantial increases between the years 1927 and 1931| in truck hauls of livestock to Kansas City and St. Joseph from the longer distances. Improvements in trucks and high - ways during recent years are probably mainly responsible for the increase in the average length of haul of livestock. ■ Data from report of federal Bureau of Agricultural Economics on "Driven-in Receipts of Livestock". * Based on figures from Nebraska Agricultural Statistics. 1930. - Henney and Sullivan, "Preliminary Report on the Trucking of Livc«tock to Terminal Markets ", Kansas State CoDtge. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 m_^fJ a^ ifyinfir the truck and raiI receipts at the Omaha ?£ • I \£2 To. 6 g^° Upe&lt;^ acc ° rdin * to distance zones (see tig. 3, page 10). Zone 1 included all territory within a radius of 20 miles of Omaha; Zone 2, all te^itory within a radius of from 21 to 40 miles; Zone 3, f rom 41 toVo miks and so on, increasing by 20-mile distances up to Zone lu' Beyond Zone 10, the increase in radii of the zones was changed from 20 to 40 miles because of the small number of consignments. The actual hauling distances of the shin ping points w thin each zone are, of course g?eate? than the straight line distance to Omaha. For example the average actual distance by highway of the shfpg point - _•_»_ 0 -..__ H0 0 8 *"* P« cmt of Bscipt. Fsr c.nt of E.c.lptc 1 Ball ____\\ | E^^^ Truck bbbbbbmbbbbm_bbbb_ bbbbb-I I _■■ ■_■_■ bbb_b_ bbbbbbI -_■ 2 True* bbbbbbIbbbbb-Mbbbb- — bbbbb- bbbbbbI bbbbbbI bbbbbbI ■_■■ * Truck BBBBBS^-BB-P-i ■ ■ i ,, _ _ Tract bbbbbbb_bb-Mb-bbbbbbsbbbb&lt;1B bbbbb- bbbbbbI bbbb__ ■ haii mmww'e _m_m___ Rail __WE_&amp;_Z____&amp;Z___ty 'M,,;A»»wA»*n&gt;. 1 Truck — . ■ ixmi^imsyk 8 g^fc -^f^Y^f^f^ y^A^//LxA____L „ Truck -b--1 _■■■; 10 "i i^m&amp;_\__m____m__ ____%____%_________$£&amp; . • Track I u _au i^W//, ZZZ____)x___da ___&amp;zz__\ _____%____\\ 12 ££_ AAAA//}MMf-&gt;M 7777777777777. &amp;___\_____\\_\ "■ii ~ttii$ffi__y_____w____\i__&amp; ____22__2z ___________\____\ 13 Track 1 I | | j u^£____\ ___t_(az___zm&amp;a_ Ban _^______\_\______^______\__\ 14 trade I | | j r—^.^^—^ Ball _WJS_____\W__________1__\ ____ «__jt_ IIII I T^ "««rr,rrrryrrr OT ie _-^2p5^p-_-z§___i-_z_ _____________________$__\™ L-Zg-J I i I i I f^y^^j^y— Fig. 2.— Proportions of Nebraska livestock received at Omaha by rail and by truck during the week ending May 23, 1931, clas - sified by zones. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Truck and Rail Transportation op Livestock in Zone 3 having cattle consignments is 68 miles, whereas the average straight-line distance for Zone 3 is 50 miles. The percentage distribution of all truck and rail ship - ments of livestock to Omaha, for which data were secured for the week ending May 23, 1931, are given by zones in Table 1. The same data, for cattle and hog receipts only, are presented in Figure 2. In Zones 1 and 2, truck trans - portation received distinct preference. Only comparatively small proportions of the hog and cattle receipts from theke zones were shipped by rail. Sheep receipts, however, showed some inconsistency. The relatively high percentage of sheep receipts shipped by rail from these zones was almost entirely due to the large number of western sheep fed under feeding-in-transit permits. The large proportion of sheep receipts originating in Zone 1 was due to the ex - tensive feeding in the immediate vicinity of Omaha. Zones 3, 4, and 5 showed a more nearly equal division as between rail and truck shipments. These zones appeared to make up the chief competitive area as between trucks and railroads. Beyond Zone 5 the proportion of shipments by rail increased as the distance from market increased. In other words, as the straight-line distance from market in - creased beyond 100 miles, the preference for railroads over trucks in hauling livestock increased. In the transportation of livestock from Zones 6, 7, and 8, trucks were used to a greater extent for hogs than for cattle or sheep. Receipts for periods other than the week studied might show some variations from the percentages given in Table 1. However, there seems sufficient evidence to conclude that trucks were given preference in the territory lying within 40 miles (straight-line distance) of Omaha. The territory more than 40 miles but less than 100 was the chief competitive area, with the proportions of truck and rail shipments about equal. Beyond 100 miles, railroads re - ceived preference. LIVESTOCK TRUCKAGE RATES TO OMAHA The rate charged for the transportation service is the most important single factor in determining which agency — truck or railroad — is used. Rail rates for transporting livestock are available in published freight tariff schedules. They are subject to change only on order or with the ap - proval of certain governmental regulatory bodies, of which the Interstate Commerce Commission has the greatest powers. In contrast, truck rates are quite variable and are unregulated by governmental bodies, at least in Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 0maha ™**** » ending May 23 laSlSa.,. %%£??* \°? ies ' /or the we^ ~ZZA.„ , A 1931 ~only Nebraska shipments included ' "*" ' Percent~T-i^~r - , „ CATTLE RECEIPTS • a~s il J | If si 6 101-120 i'kqo «? %H 44.9 7 121-140 1071 5? 0 73 - 8 26.2 8 141-160° Jffi gj | 8 % 5 JH 9 161-180 823 ?Tc sH H- 4 10 181-200 III "o «_•_ 12A 11 201-240 ?£_ ,12 88.4 H. 6 12 241-280 122 H2 ' £'? Jf-2 13 281-320 230 7? 5 4 ' 1 15-9 14 321-360 i_ X J 95.4 4.6 15 361-400 589 'inn„ - 4 16 401-440 425 ffi ° Total I 12,490 7,054 | 'K M l HOG RECEIPTS ' i U I I || 6 101-120 2 585 IBM !f_ 65 ' 8 « -SS8 il J l I a ■' ji sss. € ™ ■ &gt;M 13 281-320 534 nnnn 9 - 4 14 321-360 868 ZZZ. 1000 '2 15 361-400 1,054 16 985 t '„ 16 401-440 141 98 n L5 . Total I 17,861 19,714 47.5 52*5 SHEEP RECEIPTS £5 J: i II aa as - " _ i ou 186 747 10 q on . * a ,1 a I 10 181-299 •" 100 -° -° 11 201-240 ok '"A 12 241-280 •"• 85 -° 100-0 13 281-320 14 321-360 518 "" inn'o "„ 15 361-400 I "•• 100 -° -0 16 I 401-440 2,122 ZZZ. 1000 "n Total I 10,009 j 10,350 4^ </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Truck and Rail Transportation of Livestock Table 2. — Average truckage rates per hundredweight by zones and by species of livestock, on 4,701 shipments from Nebraska points to Omaha between August 1 1930 and July 31, 1931 ' ; Average truckaee rate; Zono Miles to Consign- „ . per hundredweight | Omaha merits " eaa Transit Transit , insurance insurance —J excluded included CATTLE (CALVES INCLUDED) „ 0- 20 97 1,536 S 9.9 $ 9 9 | 21-40 240 L785 \ 9 .6 ? 19.8 3 41- 60 366 1,796 25.4 25 9 i IhSS 335 1853 269 2 ™ R tm'JSS 336 X ' 682 30.5 30.9 6 101-120 237 1,176 33.7 34 4 8 ffifeK )li 839 4^ 40!9 8 141-160 156 755 45.4 45 6 • 16 1-1 80 H7 462 48 0 48 4 10 181-200 69 279 53 0 534 12 S&amp;g 83 o 388 2 Si is IstHS I Ut 51 - 3 52 - 5 Id 2 °1- 320 5 33 60.0 61 7 14 321-360 3 7 50.1 eft Total 2,237 12,617 | HOGS 1 0- 20 103 1,200 17.4 17 4 2 21-40 296 3 ; 8 27 22.2 22 8 a i}' SS 398 5 '1 73 26.6 28.2 i oh™ 334 4,547 30.4 32i2 5 81-100 374 4,953 32.0 33* 6 101-120 319 5050 34 8 35*9 7 121-140 162 2495 40 0 4115 I 1«l"l«n l _. i:275 4 ™ 469 9 161-180 51 847 43 4 aq'7 10 181-200 23 354 53? tl'l 11 201-240 67 1,080 484 621 J 2 241-280 7 125 5*9 549 13 281-320 1 2 610 flfi9 14 321-360 5 0 -2 Total 2,235 30,928 SHEEP 1 °- 20 28 2,345 10.2 10 2 2 21- 40 25 L178 24.1 250 _ 41- 60 24 568 30.9 329 4 61- 80 54 1,802 31.8 346 5 81-100 28 684 37 8 425 6 101-120 30 693 46.6 551 I J_H„_ x _ 343 52 - 9 sii 8 141-160 4 74 11.7 50 2 9 161-180 13 367 53.8 59^ 10 . 181-200 4 91 112.5 1144 11 201-240 2 33 70 9 786 12 241-280 0 0 j 13 281-320 0 0 14 321-360 1 48 75.0 9'lO Total 229 8,226 Grand Total 4,701 51,771 j </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 Fig. 3. — Origin of truck consignments to the Omaha market from which the truckage rates were calculated. (The dots indicate shipping points with 1 to 10 consignments; the squares, 11 to 21 consignments; and the triangles, 21 to 30 consignments.) The information on truckage rates for livestock was ob - tained from the account sales of truck shipments received by three of the leading commission firms on the Omaha market for the fiscal year ending July 31, 1931. Not all such account sales were used in the computations. To secure a fairer approximation of rates, the number of con - signments was limited to 30 for any single shipping point. These consignments were distributed throughout the year and with equal proportions of cattle, hogs, and sheep so far as the data permitted. Consignments numbering 4,701 from 416 sTiipping points constituted the final data used in the truckage rate computations. Figure 3 shows the distribution over the state of the truck shipments used in the calculations. The largest number of shipping points and truck consignments included in this study were from the southeastern quarter of the state. This was because the Sioux City market receives a large pro - portion of the livestock from the northeastern part of the state. Then, too, there are more and better developed high - ways in the more densely populated southeastern quarter of Nebraska, thus providing a more complete network of im - proved roads. Table 2 and Figure 4 present the average truckage rates per hundredweight for cattle (including calves) , hogs, and sheep, by zones. With few exceptions, which may be noted in the table, the rates increased as distances increased. The rates are shown with transit insurance included and with transit insurance excluded. Transit insurance included only those charges paid by the farmers for insurance in </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Truck and Rail Transportation op Livestock Rates ln cents per j ewt. I ; no g L ■»■■ Cattle 100 „„ fclt L 90 ■ Xs___\ Sheep — — — — — — ——— - 80 ■ i L 70 n B - " -dof-!j6--jM Zones 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 Fig. 4. — Average livestock truckage rates per hundredweight to Omaha, by distance zones, 1930-1931. addition to the regular truckage charge and was not charged on all shipments. Factors determining truckage rates. — Distance has al - ready been mentioned as a principal factor affecting truck - age rates. It was found, however, that rates varied |for hauls of the same distance from nearly every point of origin having a considerable number of consignments. Furthermore, increases in average truckage rates were not proportional to increases in distances. Rates by species also reveal inconsistencies. For example, rates for cattle, hogs, and sheep in Zone 1 were 9.9, 17.4, and 10.2 cents per hundredweight, respectively, as compared with 30.5, 32.0, and 37.8 cents, respectively, in Zone 5. It should be added, however, that a greater volume of data than was hsed might have reduced these inconsistencies. There are numerous factors which might cause incon - sistencies in the truckage rate structure. As suggested pre - viously, truckage rates are not passed upon by any reg - ulatory agency. Therefore, it is to be expected that) in - creases in rates from zone to zone would not be entirely regular or uniform. Variations are often due to higher rate charges on "pick-up" loads that are consigned from several farms. In order to meet rail competition or because^ of large volume of business, lower rates are often charged to farmers who have carload lots available for shipment. The possibilities of securing loads of merchandise for the return trip also influence the rate charged. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 TABLE 3. — Changes in truckage rates per hundredweight from August, 1930, to July, 1931 August, 1930 July, 1981 Zone — rr r _ : — — r- Percentage Number of Average Average Number of change consignments | rate rate consignments CATTLE (INCLUDING CALVES) Cents Cents Per cent 1 5 27.0 22.5 12 -16.6 2 26 24.4 22.5 22 - 7.8 3 21 29.8 27.2 38 - 8.7 4 23 38.0 25.2 16 -33.7 5 7 44.3 29.9 35 -32.5 6 9 40.0 34.6 28 -13.5 7 3 44.0 37.3 16 -15.2 8 10 49.0 42.7 11 -12.9 9 8 48.8 46.5 10 - 4.7 10 6 53.3 50.1 5 - 6.0 11 Jj 66.3 63.1 1(5 - 5.1 Average percentage change -14.2 HOGS 1 8 23.8 21.2 6 -10.9 2 44 25.5 21.0 28 -17.6 3 46 31.4 27.1 39 -13.7 4 18 39.2 29.6 51 -24.5 5 24 39.0 30.5 65 -21.8 6 23 42.0 34.7 33 -17.4 7 7 49.3 36.3 19 -26.4 1 8 5 47.0 44.3 7 - 5.7 9 3 43.3 40.7 7 - 6.0 10 0 .0 50.0 5 11 (5 50JJ 5O0 7 - 1.6 Average percentage change -14.6 The intensity of trucking competition is greater in some localities than in others and may result in lower rates where the competition is keenest. The trucking industry is largely in the hands of individuals who do not have a strong central organization, and so little effort has been expended to establish uniform rates. Therefore, competition operates freely and often results in truck-rate wars. Many truckers lack definite knowledge regarding their operating costs and often fail to charge rates justified .by costs. Instead, they determine rates on the basis of their ability to secure the volume of business that will keep their trucks in use. There are still other factors which may account for variations in truck rates. Competition of well-organized and well-managed shipping associations influences rates in </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Truck and Rail Transportation of Livestock some areas. The effect of weather conditions on roads, especially secondary roads; the influence of well-estab - lished truckers, who have advantages in personal solicita - tion of business ; and the popularity of trucking in general, might be added to the list of factors which cause variations in rates. Yet despite all these factors of variation, Table) 2 shows considerable regularity in the changes in average rates from zone to zone. Changes in truckage rates since August, 1930. — The truckage rates in Table 2 are the average rates, by zones, for the year from August, 1930, to July, 1931, and do riot represent the rates in effect today (July, 1932). Truckage rates were declining during the year studied and have con - tinued downward since. In order to determine the changes in truckage rates over the period studied, all truck consign - ments for August, 1930, and July, 1931, were sorted out, and the truckage rates on cattle (including calves) ahd hogs were determined for each of those months. The changes in rates by zones are given in Table 3. The data for sheep were insufficient to warrant inclusion in the table. The truckage rates for cattle and hogs decreased in every zone. The declines ranged from a minimum of 1.6 per cent in Zone 11 for hogs to a maximum of 33.7 per cent in Zone 4 for cattle. The average declines of truckage rates for cattle and hogs in all zones were comparatively close, being 14.2 and 14.6 per cent, respectively. It is interesting jto compare these declines with declines in other prices during the same period. The decline in the price index of mejat animals from August, 1930, to July, 1931, was from 127 !to 92 per cent of pre-war levels. 0 The decline in the price index for all agricultural commodities for the same period was from 111 to 79. 7 The declines in these indexes were 27.6 per cent and 28.9 per cent, respectively. Rail rates were unchanged during the period. Too much reliance should not be placed on the percent - age changes by zones because of the comparatively small number of consignments on which the rates were based. However, it is interesting to note that changes ran consist - ently greater in Zones 4 to 7.- The statement was made previously in discussing Table 1 that Zones 3 to 5 appar - ently made up the principal competitive area as between the trucks and the railroads. With rail rates unchanged •The Agricultural Situation. Bureau of Agricultural Economics, U. S. D. A., Vol. 15, No. 10, and Vol. 14. No. 9. * The Agricultural Situation. Bureau of Agricultural Economics TJ. S. D. A.. Vol. 15, No. 10, and Vol. 14, No. 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 and truck rates declining, the tendency would be for the chief competitive area to be somewhat farther from the market. Contact with truck operators and livestock producers since July, 1931, has furnished information that livestock truck rates have continued their downward trend during the past year. Cases were mentioned of truck operators hauling livestock for distances of 150 and more miles at rates equal to those by rail. Changing economic conditions and instability within the trucking industry are account - able, in part, for the present rate situation, which may be only temporary. However, it should not be overlooked that the development of our system of roads, and the improve - ments and increased efficiency of trucks, especially the introduction of larger trucks, have also had a tendency to lower truckage rates. FACTORS INFLUENCING THE CHOICE OF THE MEANS OF TRANSPORTATION What are the factors which determine whether livestock shipments shall move by truck or by rail? Comparative rates are undoubtedly important but cannot give a full ex - planation of why one agency is chosen over the other. In the following pages a comparison of rail and truck rates is presented, together with a discussion of other factors which influence the choice of the transportation agency. Comparison of truck and rail rates. — Average truck and rail rates for livestock and 1 their gross and net differences are shown in Table 4. The rail freight rates given are averages of the rates to Omaha from the shipping points at which the truck consignments, used in figuring truckage rates, originated. They are weighted according to the number of truck consignments, and hence are calculated on the same basis as the truckage rates. In order to obtain an equitable comparison of rates, the expense of transporting the livestock from the farm to the railroad loading station and of local handling must be con - sidered. Based upon information furnished by truck operators and shippers, an estimated charge of 8 cents per hundredweight was considered as representative of the charges for the average local haul and for loading the ani - mals. The actual difference between truck and rail rates is shown in the "Gross difference" column of Table '4. The difference in the two rates after adding 8 cents to the rail rate to cover local haulage and loading is shown in the "Net difference" column. The net difference is of greater sig- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Truck and Rail Transportation of Livestock Table 4. — Average truck and rail rates per hundredweight, by zones, for cattle, hogs, and sheep, moving to the Omaha market between August, 1930, and July, 1931, and gross and net differences between those rates ' Miles to Average Average Gross Net! Zone market truck rate rail rate difference difference CATTLE 1 0- 20 9.9 8.6 1.3 - 6.7 2 21- 40 19.6 12.2 7.4 - 0.6 3 41- 60 25.4 15.1 10.3 2.3 4 61- 80 26.9 17.0 9.9 1 9 5 81-100 30.5 19.5 11.0 3.0 6 101-120 33.7 20.6 13.1 5.1 7 121-140 40.4 22.6 17.8 9.8 8 141-160 45.4 23.4 22.0 14.6 9 161-180 48.0 24.9 23.1 15.1 10 181-200 53.0 25.2 27.8 19.B 11 201-240 55.2 26.5 28.7 20.7 12 241-280 51.3 27.6 23.7 15.7 13 281-320 60.0 29.0 31.0 23.0 14 321-360 50.1 30.0 20.1 12.il HOGS 1 0- 20 17.4 10.6 6.8 - 1.2 2 21- 40 22.2 14.1 8.1 0.1 3 41- 60 26.6 17.3 9.3 1.3 4 61- 80 30.4 19.6 10.8 2.8 5 81-100 32.0 22.2 9.8 18 6 101-120 34.8 23.7 11.1 3;1 7 121-140 40.0 25.8 14.2 G.2 8 141-160 46.0 86.6 19.4 114 9 161-180 43.4 28.0 15.4 7j4 10 181-200 53.1 30.0 23.1 15 1 11 201-240 48.4 30.4 18.4 10J4 12 241-280 54.9 31.0 23.9 15l9 13 281-320 61.0 33.5 27.5 19,5 14 321-360 SHEEP 1 0- 20 10.2 10.6 - 0.4 - 8 4 2 21- 40 24.1 14.2 9.9 ll9 3 41- 60 30.9 18.9 12.0 12i0 4 61- 80 31.8 21.5 10.3 li.7 5 81-100 37.8 23.0 14.8 6.8 6 101-120 46.6 27.0 19.6 lli.6 7 121-140 52.9 27.7 25.2 17l2 8 141-160 41.7 29.1 12.6 4^6 9 161-180 53.8 31.0 22.8 14 8 10 181-200 112.5 32.0 80.5 72.5 11 201-240 70.9 33.0 37.9 29 9 12 241-280 13 281-320 ... """ 14 321-360 7jM) 42J5 {_5 24I5 1 These computations are based on consignments received by three of the principal commission firm* on the Omaha market. ■ Gross differences are the actual differences between the two rates as given In the table. Net differences are differences between the two rates after adding 8 cents to the rail rates to cover average costs of I trans - porting the livestock from farm to railroad shipping point and ot handling at the local point. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 nificance in the comparison of the rail and truck rates In Zone 1, on the net-difference basis, truckage rates 1SSSJTZ m t 193 J- 31 &lt;? an rail rates. In Zones 2 te In - clusive, the rates showed no distinct advantage of railroads over trucks Beyond Zone 5, rail rates were dfstinctlv lower than truck rates. The rate differences given in Tab e Jiveaddedsupport to the conclusions reached in the earlier discussion regarding the proportions of shipments moving by rail and by truck. That is, trucks had a com - parative advantage in the territory lying within 50 xnXs (actual hauling distance) of the Omaha market The area wYsTh. ,LT l6S hU \-l? SS thSn 125 miles from the market 7nTfifV_ fj !ef competitive area. Beyond 125 miles, the rail - l? 8 A a i? /, dl^ nc t advantage. Again it should be re - peated that declines m truck rates since Julv, 1931 have undoubtedly modified the situation. Then, too the Ne - braska Railway Commission has recentlv granted' the rait Tr^ "l W Snd dl l Ced ScaIe of rates on^ngle-line hauls ?h„J fv, ' h ° g f' an - Sheep When the shipments contain less than the usual minimum weights. These rates apply to dis - tances up to 260 miles and thus enable the railroads to com - pete on more nearly equal terms with the trucks for less - m 2?*k A d con^ments. (For specific rates, see Table ill m the Appendix.) Th fl p U^^,«t gra P d^ °l .% fcw *y« *"&lt;* of rail connection,. rf«2 f™« " °S the wa y s to market and the nature nr P fpr^L? nneCtl0nS shou i d ° ff er some explanation of the ZfJ-nilA? S r -° n ? agency over another. To determine their influence more definitely, the points of origin of the receipts for the week ending Mav 231931 Sm r a e ha a a n d e a d li nt? V°_ ***** ]&gt; aSed ° n rail connections to Umaha and also into two grades based on highway con- SShfeT F°I the "? c . Iassifi &lt;*tion, Grade 1 included I aH points located on main lines, branch lines, or branch lines S^SflT' . lead i n ? direc .t to Omaha. Grade 2 induded all points having better rail connections to other terminal markets or having indirect connections which involve several switchings in transit. "woive In the highway classification, Grade 1 included all post - office points having all graveled or paved highways and direct routes to Omaha. Grade 2 included those points having a large portion of their highwav route to Omaha neither graveled nor paved. 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Truck and Rail Transportation op Livestock Table 5 shows the proportions of shipments moving I by truck and by rail for the several grade classifications de - scribed above. Points having Grade 1 rail connections showed much greater preference for shipping livestock] by rail than did Grade 2 points. In the highway classification, points having Grade 1 highway connections showed greater preference for truck shipments than did Grade 2 points. There is some evidence, therefore, that the kind of rail connections and the construction and condition of the high - ways do have some influence in determining which means of transportation is used. Still another approach to this phase of the study is [the relation of truckage rates to the grades of rail and high - way connections. The question arises as to whether truck Table 5. — Percentage distribution of rail and truck receipts at Omaha for the week ending May 23, 1931, as influenced by the grade of rail and highway connections ] Classification based on rail connections Grade of 1 Number of head received | Percentage received rail j Rail [ Truck 1 Rail | Truck connection | Number \ Number j Percent | Percent CATTLE 1 I 12,222 I 6,672 I 64.7 I 35.3 2 I 268 | 382 j 41.2 | 58.8 HOGS 1 I 17,662 I 18,496 I 48.9 I 5lJl 2 1 199 1,218 14.0 86.0 SHEEP 1 I 10,009 I 10,200 I 49.5 I 50)5 2 I 0 j 150 j .0 I lOOlO Classification based on highway connections Grade of | Number of head received | Percentage received highway | Rail | Truck ! Rail | Truck connection | Number | Number \ Per cent \ Per pent CATTLE 1 I 9,625 I 6,242 I 60.7 I 39.3 2 | 2,865 I 812 | 77.9 I 22.1 HOGS 1 I 12,766 I 16,936 I 43.0 I 57.0 2 | 5,095 I 2,778 | 64.7 | 35.3 SHEEP 1 I 7,344 I 10,233 I 38.3 I 61.7 2 I 2,665 | 127 j 95.4 I 4.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 operators take into account either the grade of hic-hwAvo. %£$££ ro iMn?nr^ able ? deteiSMtSf SS age rates. An attempt was made to answer this question /wL %T~ L _ ivestock truckage rates per hundredweiaht to Zone highway Number of jiTEX Average Average connection consignments toSSSf. truckage rate to ° maha «te per mUe Number Miles Cents Cents CATTLE 2 it ?H 20 - 8 -971 9 7 ,S. i9 - 8 9-3 469 1 184 39.7 25.1 ' ~ SS SH 1 ? JK 32 I 5 ? of 2 87 - 8 30 6 849 5 i 265 ll 2 - 2 32.8 292 2 71 120.8 370 'ini 6 j 18 ° 130 - 8 ss „ ? 44 133.6 36.7 274 7 1 128 "7.9 426 169 o ? 56 162.6 419 2B8 8 I 10 J 188.7 46 5 JU 0 ? 62 186 -5 48.1 258 9 1 84 2 °1-1 475 HI m 2 33 198.6 58 6 295 10 i 68 2 is-9 5i.3 :iit 2 4 228.5 62.5 tit HOGS 1 I 67 2 l-3 20.2 .948 , ? i4 32.0 28.5 890 2 2 i fSf 24 -0 S of 65 39.1 22.6 578 3 I 3 ° 8 63.5 28.1 !442 4 1 o°-?&gt; 7" 32 - 2 -452 o 2 So 87 -° 32.0 .367 x ? 72 87-1 30.4 349 2 HH 32 - 6 SS ft 7 of?, 121 ' 7 37.2 .305 6 1 2 f2 131 - 7 36.5 .277 2 67 131.8 37.1 281 7 1 126 155.6 41.9 269 8 ? 3 S 163.0 42.0 .258 8 I £9 169.2 I 45.2 .267 q 2 fl 183.4 I 44.7 .244 9 „ 3 I 196.2 I 45.1 .229 in ? i? 189 - 7 ! 44 - 6 .235 10 „ 2 „ 219.0 I 52.3 .238 2 2 216.0 I 55.0 .254 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Truck and Rail Transportation of Livestock by comparing truckage rates on hogs and cattle for the tavo grades of highway connections and also for the two grades of rail connections for Zones 1 to 10. m The results of the first comparison — based on highway connections— is given in Table 6. Not only are the average zone rates given, but the average rates per mile, af direr basis of comparison, were calculated. No appreciable cor - relation was apparent between truck rates and grades ot highway connections. The only apparent consistency ! was in Zones 3, 4, and 5 (the chief competitive area) where higher rates per mile prevailed at points having Grade l highway connections, with the exception of Zone 4. The second comparison — based on rail connections — is given in Table 7. Again no appreciable correlation! was found between average truckage rates per mile and grade of rail connections in the various zones, except in what has been designated as the chief competitive area (Zones 3, 4, and 5). If any conclusion may be drawn from Tables 6 and l, it is that highway and rail connections probably do have some influence on truckage rates, but are not important f fLctors. Terminal differentials. — Transportation charges consti - tute the largest item of the expense of marketing livestock, vet other factors and costs must be considered. In com - paring marketing expense by rail and by truck, terminal differentials in yardage and selling charges require | con - sideration. At the Omaha market somewhat higher yard - age and commission rates are charged on truck consign - ments than on rail consignments. It has required much rearrangement and new construction at the stock yards to accommodate the increasing proportion of truck shipments. It requires almost as much labor and equipment for yarding small lots of trucked-in livestock as it does for carload lots. Sellinjr charges are higher for essentially the same reason. The rapid increase in number of small truck consignments has increased and complicated the clerical work required of commission firms and the stock yards company. J Before the advent of the truck, co-operative shipping associations and local buyers were located at Practically all shipping points. These local agencies performed the functions of assembling, sorting, and grading the livestock to a large extent. With the present system of marketing by truck, the truck operators assemble the livestock arid the sortmg and grading are largely performed at the terminal markets As a result, the local associations and. buyers have been largely displaced by a new system of marketing. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 _ Grade of . Zone rail Number of i}i". n * e Average Averaee connection consignments tooX2£ truckage rate ■ 1 rate per mile I Number MUes \ Cents f Cents CATTLE 1 i II 3 2 2° 2H ™ 2 1 233 39 Hi -781 2 oo d9 247 63g 3 i 35 'i S 3 2 :3 - 44 6 4 1 97R 12 28.8 .411 2 54 !?, I™ -364 1 24 Sl 3 3 6 7 4 5 S 7 1 146 9 | 2 88 J?9 42 /° - 2 73 8 1 97 176 £■? - 247 9 co x ' 0 46.1 9fi9 q * 58 196 479 o/a a 1 79 ioc .L'W -244 1 2 22 iS !o s :J | 2 HOGS 1 2 14 g 29 ° -952 2 2 294 39 a fit 3 1 395 W 29.3 451 4 1 295 II 40 -° 519 2 f 85 30.9 364 5 1 323 }?? 37 - 3 - 373 2 c? U1 32.9 296 6 1 297 JIS 363 -305 2 lo im 36 - 8 - 27 9 7 1 iff J 33 34.5 .259 2 44 ll? I 9 " 8 - 2 76 8 1 „ , 18 1 45.3 .250 . 2 27 io! 45 - 1 - 27 0 9 1 42 1SR «-2 - 236 2 9 IfS 43 ' 8 -235 10 1 44 III fg-2 -215 2 o ' J29 53.6 .234 1 1 236 I 50.0 1 [gig </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Truck and Radl Transportation of Livestock Table 8. — Schedule of yardage charges at Omaha * [ _ _ ■ Additional Sneeies , R ? tes 8" . v. 8 p , er . charges per bpecies head, ra ilroad head, trucked- nend trucked- receipts in receipts in 'receipts Cents Cents Cen Is Cattle 35 40 5 Calves (maximum 425 pounds).... 25 27 2 Hogs 12 14 2 Sheep 8 10 2 1 Schedule No. 3 of Charges, effective May 10, 1928. Used with special permission of thc Union Stock Yards Company of Omaha. Table 8 shows the schedule of yardage charges in effect at the Omaha market. As indicated above, additional charges are assessed on trucked-in livestock. Table 9 gives the schedule of livestock selling charges at Omaha, show - ing the higher charges on "drive-ins". Transit insurance and relative risk. — Insurance of (live - stock against crippling or death from any cause while in transit is available through a private insurance company. A comparison of such insurance rates on rail and truck consignments in force at the time this study was make is presented in Table 10. It will be noted that the rates applying to trucks are approximately double those apply - ing to railroads for the same distance. This difference is largely due to two factors: losses in truck consignments have been much greater than losses in rail shipments! and the insurance company recovers a considerable part of its losses on rail shipments from the railroad companies. How - ever, it must be remembered that the rates applying to railroads do not cover losses occurring while transporting from feedlbt to railroad loading point. Death losses for all rail and truck shipments to the Omaha market, by species, for the years 1930 and |l931, are shown in Table 11. The ratio of deaths by truck is nearly twice as great as the ratio by rail, but with less dif - ference in 1931 than in 1930. For hogs, the ratio is jibout one-half greater by truck than by rail, while for sheep it is about three times greater by truck than by rail, j If it were possible to include death losses from feedlot tojload - ing point with the rail data, there would probably be less difference between rail and truck shipments. The death losses by rail and by truck were reduced con - siderably from 1930 to 1931, with the exception of calves shipped by rail. Death losses of cattle moving by Itruck </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 5,effLl°eJuZ T^f) Ckan0ed hy S^ement No. SpeCieS Head Single deck Double deck CARLOAD lots Straight cars gfSa • • * 15 - 00 Hog? -• 15 - 00 $18.00 8&amp;"zrzrz J 2 - 0 ,?, l8 °° * -• 12.00 18.00 Mixed cars a . ttle • $0.60 |15.00 H? 3 0 *15.00 _^SS_ BS-zzzz: fl- gg gg DBIVE-INS 97 &lt; h^A^r~]° c . e . nts P CT head "with a maximum charge of $16.00 on each C^Lli r o a K C «° n 1 ? m0 £ °.V ach con «Knment of one oWner chara^flffooTr, to »«H ? el ?^'. 35 t%"i* P« head with a maximum cnarge or jfib.00 up to and including 50 head. Thirty cents n*r «H&lt;ii in O clutog ad 70 ab h°erd 50 h " d wWl 8 m^ mUm Charge of ? 19 " 0 -Pto'Sd =« H&lt; iS S r^ 0 C l n . t i pe / h^ ad ' with a maximum charge of $13.00 un to and including 60 head. Twenty-five cents per additional hlad above 60 a^ 1 mUm &amp;%§??*_» ?19 - 00 U P t0 and including 100 head Sheep.— On each 300 head of sheep or fraction thereof In n™ A™ signment, the rates shall Be determined L follows: 20 cent" Pe ■ iSad "3&amp;- B Ina t lmutn 1 . of $ 12 - 00 U P to and including 150 head? 20 cents Per , fndS^ h 00 a hea b d°. Ve 15 ° a maXhnUm ch!rge o£ A~ »?S £d Note: The minimum charge on any one shipped-in consignment of any one owner shall be $1.00 for cattle and 50 ctSts for cXs?C or «*.^ e iJ a «? i S! ,m cha fg e on a "y one driven-in consignment of any owner shall be $1.00 for cattle and 50 cents for calves, hogs, or sheep. 1 Used with permission of the Omaha Livestock Exchange. were reduced 65.2 per cent, while the reduction of losses by rail was 28.4 per cent. For hogs, the loss reduction was «27.7 per cent on truck shipments and 53.0 per cent on rail shipments. This is an encouraging situation and shows tnat both railroads and truck operators were putting forth effort to reduce these losses. No reliable data comparing losses by crippling were available. It is, however, reasonable to suppose that the losses by crippling may be proportioned between trucks and railroads in about the same way as death losses </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Truck and Rail Transportation of Livestock Table 10. — Schedule of transit insurance rates covering losses from death and crippling, from any cause, of livestock in transit 1 ; . Rail rates per head | Truck rates per head ' I Miles to Cattle Miles to Cattle market and market and calves. Hogs Sheep calves Hogs Sheep I Cents Cents Cents Cents Cents Cents Under 150 8 5 4 Up to 50 10 6 5 151- 350 10 7 4 51- 75 12 8 6 351- 750 13 9 4 76- 100 15 11 8 751-1,100 18 13 5 101- 150 16 12 9 1,101-1,450 23 18 6 151- 300 20 16 10 301- 500 25 18 12 1 Used with permission of the Hartford Insurance Company. * These rates were effective at the time this study was made. On December 15, 1931. the rates on truck shipments were reduced to the following basis : 1 to 75 miles. 10 cents, 4 cents, and 4 cents for cattle and calves, hogs, and sheep, respectively; 76 to 100 miles, 12 cents, 6 cents, and 6 cents ; 101 to 150 miles. 13 cents, 9 cents, and 7 cents ; 151 to 200 miles, 15 cents, 12 cents, and 8 cents : 201 to 260 miles, 17 cents, 14 cents, and 9 cents ; 251 to 300 miles, 20 cents. 16 cents, and 10 cents. Attitude: of buyers. — Buyers at Omaha apparently do not discriminate against trucked-in livestock. A number of commission men and packer buyers were interviewed and all expressed the opinion that trucked-in and rail-shipped livestock were treated alike. A study of this matter has been reported for the South St. Paul market. 9 This report Table 11. — Report of death losses of livestock received by rail and by truck in 1930 and 1931 at the Union Stock Yards, Omaha 1 j 1930 I 1931 | Percentage Species Rail °, h 9 SS*to Head Dead Ratio Head Dead Ratio l"" Cattle 1,133,987 161 1 to 7,043 1,075,941 119 1 to 9,041 1-28.4 Calves 74,948 47 1 to 1,594 71,393 48 1 to 1,487 6.7 Hogs 1,794,395 1,629 1 to 1,101 1,476,526 876 1 to 1,685 [-53.0 Sheep 2,976,727 1,410 1 to 2,111 2,920,491 1,253 1 to 2,330 [-10.4 " Truck Head | Dead Ratio Head Dead Ratio | Cattle 364,397 106 1 to 3,438 494,113 87 1 to 5,679 j-65.2 Calves 40,406 46 lto 878 48,398 50 lto 967 -10.1 Hogs 1,573,060 1,884 1 to 835 2,048,165 1,920 1 to 1,066 1-27.7 Sheep 424,512 641 1 to 661 589,552 823 1 to 716 - 8.3 1 Used with permission of the Union Stock Yards Company of Omeha. •E. C Johnson, "A Comparison of Prices of Hogs Arriving by Truck and by Rail at South St. Paul," Journal of Farm Economic; Vol. XIV, No. 1, January. 1932. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 ass-ass ttrS has been deemed justifiable therefore no discrimination WlSSPfiESr^^ • very i m . tunatelyisveVSiffi^ problem but unfor - for the farmer to have a tr!,nt P ls quite convenient lot, load his livestock Ld tlS° r ?°F e to his feed " market. Instead S spending S whlS 8 ?"*? B 16 terminal his livestock from thi feedfot tn^J.2 i S gettin * into the car, he need I spend [or.lv » 1* i° adln S. station, and his own fern yar? if 1? w2?i ? hort - ime in Ioa ding in truck, moving from one iw 1*° rec °S niz e that the stock of spreading disease ? ThS?,* °t^ n ° th £ r ' "i? y be a m ™™ truck is used for short hau s to &amp; £ he ? the co ""nercial as for long h*S to^nSlmwkete^^^ P ° ints as weI1 true* must be oft^tst Srfec'onlm^^ g ewen its economic ™lue becalm J ». i &lt;f' or must be «^SSu^^2?i a a^^gj»t* 50 miles considerably more flexihlp V«+L * i g of llv estock </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Truck and Rail Transportation op Livestock this range of distance can have his livestock on the day's market. Where it is practicable to ship by truck, the fact that a truck may be called to load stock at any time of the day or night gives the truck a distinct advantage. A farmer may wait for the closing report of the day's market and have his stock on the market the next morning. Under such circumstances the necessity of ordering a stock car a day in advance can be avoided. There is an offsetting factor in this matter of flexibility. The practice outlined above adds to the difficulty of making reasonably correct advance estimates of the market re - ceipts. Prior to the extensive marketing of livestock by truck the receipts for the next day's market, being re - ceived almost entirely by rail, could be quite accurately estimated. There is little reason to doubt, however,! that price-making methods are being or will be modified to meet the changing situation. There is another aspect of flexibility to be noted. The truck often makes it possible for the small feeder to get his stock, amounting to less than a carlot, to the terminal market without dealing with a local buyer or waiting for neighbors to get ready to ship. Even the feeders h&amp;ving carload lots can sometimes dispose of their stock in smaller lots of more uniform quality to good advantage. Not all animals in a feedlot reach the finish at which theyj will bring the best return at the same time. The truck permits the shipment of small lots. There is still another advantage in distributing ship - ments over a longer period of time, a practice which is per - mitted more readily when trucks are used. Prices for live - stock often fluctuate sharply from day to day and j from week to week. A large shipment marketed in a single lot might strike a bad market. Smaller shipments scattered over a number of days or weeks reduce the risk of striking a demoralized market. Like the factor of convenience, the value to be placed on flexibility is difficult to determine. Again, it is a matter of personal judgment. Shrinkage. — Comparative shrinkage of rail- and jtruck - shipped livestock has been the center of much of the dis - cussion of the livestock transportation problem. Many, and perhaps most, of the views expressed regarding compara - tive shrinkage have been based on opinions and assumptions rather than facts. There are so many different factors which cause variations in shrinkage that definite conclu - sions can scarcely be reached without sufficient and accu - rate data to cover the different circumstances. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 raJVls^ truck nd b conclusions. H^nceX resulted faTffiS? f 9 ny finaI though based on carefully select^ J „Efo £ e ,\ 2 ' even Wnthewei/htt^^^^ ra^pn\S^^^^ shrinka *e than f erent shipments Th* rr^t! va «ation among the dif - had no g^fatefrhrinkalr^ Xr, ?r, mpe^ nt „*""* operators hogs in Table is ffi^frac&amp;W th^^ 8 - The data on age on rail as on ruck P shfpmente same aver **e shrink- TABLE 12.-Comparative shrinkage of cattle and hog shiv ments by rail and by truck 1 9 P ~ -i~ "-* 1 shrink I A S te* -tea, jss-, ' l.u.ub,, &gt;!*, cent. Pound, Pounds mt~i3t CATTLE SeL g l a i s [ a Lgj-r HOGS ' ~ fed a i k | g i a. | bi g termSS tl$£g%%* &amp;&amp;_V fe*»S 8 £', Pment8 ° n w "ich both farm and" riving much weight to the AsSts. n0mber 0t » h iw&gt;«t» i» too small to more neariy .eve! ___££?£_*_ llf ______"%_ </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Truck and Rail Transportation op Livestock a comparison of truck and rail transportation COSTS The problem of deciding when it is more economical to ship by rail and when by truck requires individual judg - ment. Trucking rates and other transportation costs !are constantly changing. Such factors as convenience, dis - tance to local market, condition of roads, and size of ship - ment are highly important in individual cases, and so aver - age costs and generalized conclusions like those presented herein must not be given too much weight by the individual stockman in making his choice of transportation agency. It may be useful, however, to present an illustration which may show how one can judge the relative merits of rail land truck transportation ; hence Table 13 is presented. A direct comparison of truck rates with rail rates gives a decided advantage to the railroads. As shown in Table 4, the average rail freight rate for hogs in Zone 7 was 25.8 cents per hundredweight as compared with a truck rate of 40 cents (in 1930-31). In Zone 2 the rates were 14.1 cents and 22.2 cents, respectively. The rates above are not a fair basis of comparison, however, because trucking is a farm - to-terminal-market service, whereas railroads provide service only from local loading point to market. There - fore, the cost of the local haul from farm to shipping station and local handling must be added to the rail rates. Based on inquiry in 1930-31, this charge was estimated to be 6 TABLE 13. — Approximate cash costs of transporting ; hogs from farm to market by truck and by rail — assuming each consignment consists of seventy 200-pound hogs l Av. shipping point in Zone 2 Av. shipping point in Zone 7 (40-mile haul estimated) (160-mile haul estimated) Cost items By truck | By rail By truck I By rail Per Total I Per Total Per Total I Per Total ewt. cost I ewt. ccst ewt. cost I ewt. cost Cents Dollars Cents Dollars Cents Dollars Cents Dollars Trucking charges 22.2 S1.08 6.0» 8.40 40.0 B6.00 6.0" 8.40 Local loading cost 2.0 2.80 2.0 2.80 Freight rate 16.1" 22.66 29.5» 41.28 Transit insurance 8.0 4.20 2.6 3,60 8.0 11.20 8.6 4.90 Yardage 6.0 8.40 6.0 7.00 6.0 8.40 6.0 | 7.00 Commission 11.1 16.60 8.6 12.00 11.1 16.60 8.6 ' 12.00 Totals - I 42.8 69.18 40.2 56.26 66.1 91.10 54.6 | 76.88 Differentials favoring .»»!..»„ rail haul 2.1 2.92 10.6 14.72 1 Note that these are cash costs and the differentials are in cash costs, in | choosing the means of transportation, other factors such as convenience, flexibility, and shrinkage require consideration. 1 Charge for hauling from farm, to local loading point. * The carlot rates were 14.1 and 26.8 cents per hundredweight, respectively. Since this car contains less than minimum weight, actual hundredweight charges are higher. A recent change in minimum weights and rates on less-than-carlot rail shipments will modify the calculation above. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 weight are higher t'haTth^quo^Som Sff/TfSS the rail and truck shipments illustrated In Tatdf 13 S^nce t-^T^ d J&amp; were available, no charges were made differentials. However, it is reaTonabTe to \\nZnVL ? *,? &amp; vori ?* th * trucks on short hauls oflesstha? 50 miles and the railroads on long hauls of more than 19^ miles. Terminal market charges for yardae? and ™Ji J? sion are higher for truck shipmlnte (ste Tlolts 8 °iT$)~ mfavS d of?Ji C S h COSt + s only ' the comparteon ?s distincJ/y in favor of rail shipments, and more so for Ions hauls than for short hauls. . If it were possible to pit I monetarv favor W° n £- menC ? and Ability, the comparison mijht favor truck shipments, particularly for the shorter haul It may be well to repeat that the comparisons in Table 13 are purely hypothetical and based on charges in 1980-81 when data^for this study, were collected. Table 3 shows down 51 Ch ltT S *? *?&amp; r , at t S from August, 19lS to JX i 931 - I* w as also stated that truckage rates have co£ d w hne S1 - 1 P C .! July ' 1931 ' while rail r ates have not changed. Hence, if it were possible to present a compari - favortS r Pr -f e^ rail and *** rates &gt; »* woul d be less favorable for rail shipments than that shown in Table 13. conclusions Many people are inclined to criticize livestock trucking Some criticisms are justifiable, others are not. The truck has come to occupy a definite and important place in the transportation field. Its advent was bound to have disturb - ing effects on existing agencies. The more quickly adiust - ment is reached between the old and the new, the "less serious the disturbance. The wise plan is to study the problem critically so that correct judgments can be formed </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Truck and Rail Transportation of Livestock as to the most efficient and economical method of trans - portation. The trucking industry is not supervised by any govern - mental agencies as are the railroads. Truckage rates are. unregulated, except as they may be influenced by rail rates. History reveals that the railroads once passed through a period when unfair practices and discriminatory rates pre - vailed. To protect public interest, governmental regulation was deemed necessary. Perhaps a time will arrive when it will be considered wise to apply some form of public reg - ulation and supervision to the trucking industry. The matter of taxation of transportation agencies is of direct public concern. Railroads provide their own right of way upon which taxes are paid. Trucks use the public highway system, but pay license fees and taxes on motor fuel. The question arises whether the taxes paid by trucks are sufficient to cover the added costs resulting from the use of highways for commercial purposes. Careful studies of this matter are needed. It is well to keep in mind in this connection that most of the taxes paid by transporta - tion agencies are included in their costs of providing service and are- covered in the charges made for that service. It is not necessarily true that the one who provides the service finally bears the tax. This study does not offer any general conclusion favor - able or unfavorable to either the railroads or the trucking industry. It does point out some of the factors the indi - vidual producer must consider in making his choice between the two agencies. It suggests the conditions under which each may have some advantage. The livestock producer is less interested in which agency hauls his stock to market than in the convenience, efficiency, and economy with which the service is performed. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 275 appendix Table I.— Omaha livestock receipts by rail and by truck number and percentage of each, 1920, 1927-1931 1 I?:::::::::: iSSffi 38E £tt S3 10 f "28 1.423,258 1,203 552 219 706 84 56 1644 1929 1,444,210 1,163,031 281179 80 63 i960 1930 ; 1,484,501 1,110 487 374 014 74 81 «,„ im l-570:054 lloTSJMl 494!?" __% M Calves ' :ii:^- 1920 78,678 71,103 7 575 on S7 a cq as sjb "%» s|:|ll ss; js J928 94,496 51,765 42,731 54.78 45 22 1929 102,223 55,960 46 263 54 74 f.ol 1930 120,257 75,868 44,389 63.09 36 91 1931 119.791 71.393 4gjgg SoieO 40 40 Hogs ■ ■ '- 1920 2,708,482 2,526,836 181,546 93.30 6 70 1927 2,630,731 1,887,089 743 642 71.73 2827 1928 3,179,211 1,975,176 1,204 035 6213 3787 1929 3,165,793 1,793,452 1 372 341 56 65 43 35 19|0 3,362,875 1,789,815 1,573 060 53.22 4678 1931 3,524,691 1,476,526 4L89 5811 Sheep — ■ 1920 2,890,748 2,818,379 71,369 97.53 2 47 1927 2,603,508 2,330,555 272 953 89.52 10 48 1928 3,037,119 2,680,293 356 826 88.25 1175 1929 3,030,619 2,627,220 403 399 86.69 13 81 1930 3,410,239 2,985,727 424 512 87.55 1245 1931 3,510,013 2,920.491 589.522 83.20 16 80 Total ~~~ " ■ Livestock 1920 7,202,029 Y,117,296 283,633 96.04 3 96 1927 5,795,212 5,584,763 1,210,449 82.18 17 82 1928 7,734,084 5,910,786 1,823,298 76.42 23 58 1929 7,742,845 5,639,663 2,103,182 72.83 27 17 1930 8,377,872 5,961,897 2,415,975 71.16 28 84 1931 8,724,549 0,544,351 3,180,198 63.55 36.45 Co-ordination of Motor Transportation. State of Nebraska. I. C C. Docket No. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Truck and Rail Transportation op Livestock Table II. — Livestock receipts at sixteen leading markets* — total receipts and number and per cent of drive-in re - ceipts, 1916-1930 z [__ Total Drive-in receipts j Year receipts Number ~ P^ c t e 0 f a a i ge 1916 61,100,023 984,559 1.61 1918 67,428,304 2,114,695 3.14 1920 60,396,893 3,149,430 5.21 1922 61,182,647 4,125,049 6.74 1924 71,530,444 5,131,511 7.17 1926 61,515,894 6,593,791 10.72 1928 64,357,046 11,617,434 18.05 1929 63,039,782 13,775,905 21.85 1930 61,558,384 15,735,610 25.56 1 Chicago, Cincinnati, Denver, East St. Louis, Fort Worth, Indianapolis, Kansas City, Louisville, Milwaukee, Oklahoma City, Omaha, North Portland, St. Joseph, St. Paul, Sioux City, and Wichita. ' Driven-in receipts of livestock for 1980 from Bureau of Agricultural Economics, United States Department of Agriculture. Table III. — Distance rates on livestock (cattle, calves, goats, hogs, sheep) in straight or mixed carloads, with minimum . ' weight of 10,000 pounds. 1 (From C. B. &amp; Q. I. C. C. \No. 18003) ' Rate in cents Miles per hundredweight 10 miles or less 12% 20 miles and over 10 14 30 miles and over 20 15 40 miles and over 30 16 50 miles and over 40 17% 60 miles and over 50 18% 70 miles and over 60 19% 80 miles and over 70 20% 90 miles and over 80 22 100 miles and over 90 23 115 miles and over 100 24 130 miles and over 115 25% 145 miles and over 130 26% 160 miles and over 145 27% 175 miles and over 160. / 29 Yob TtvWea atA oncc YVb A SO ( 205 miles and over 190. ~) 31 ) m xoaVfes udA otm m ( 32 ( 240 miles and over 220. ) 33% ; 260 miles and over 240 ( 34j_ 1 Effective August 16, 1932. on Nebraska intrastate traffic Rates are published to meet truck line competition and expire with September 4. 2988. unless sooner canceled. changed, or extended. Apply on Nebraska intrastate only between Omaha and Nebraska City on the one hand and stations in Nebraska on the other hand. ISM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>