<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00032">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00032</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska Weeds (Part 1)</title>
               <date value="1921">1921</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE BUREAU OF MARKETS AND MARKETING DIVISION OF SEEDS LINCOLN BULLETIN NO. 101 NEBRASKA WEEDS (PART 1) REPRINTED 1921 BY H. FERNE PECK SEED ANALYST LEO STUHR SECRETARr.OF AGRICULTURE </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">NEBRASKA WEEDS PART 1 INTRODUCTION In this bulletin free use of manuals and monographs has been made by the author, who is greatly indebted to Professor Robert C. Dahlberg, University of Minnesota, for many of the illustrations of plants- herein described, and to F. H. Hillman of the Seed Laboratory of the United States Department of Agriculture for the drawings of seeds. Also, to the farmers and county agents who have contributed in - formation regarding weeds and means of eradication throughout this State. Strictly accurate botanical terminology has not been adhered to as it might lead to confusion which has been avoided, as the text is intended for farm and trade use. The term "seed" is applied to both seed and fruit, for instance, the so-called sunflower and ragweed "seeds" are in reality fruits. DEFINITION A broad definition of the term "weed" has been expressed in "a plant that is not wanted or a plant out of place." The worst weed in wheat may be rye; or wheat, if the wheat is too thick. Johnson grass, which is a very noxious weed in the South is a valuable forage plant in dry and sandy soils of this latitude. Quack grass, an extremely noxious weed in the North, is sometimes planted in the dry, sandy portions of Nebraska in order that its extensive root system may hold the soil from blowing, at the same time producing a succulent forage plant. Under these conditions the plant does not persist. In the pre - valent idea of the meaning of the term "weed", such a plant may not be "out of place" but in place and both useful and essential, as de - scribed in a subsequent section. KINDS OF WEED8 AND ERADICATION A knowledge of the length of life of weeds is of value to persons attempting their extermination. In case of annuals, or one year plants and biennials or two year plants, the treatment is more or less simple and in general principle is merely to keep the plants from maturing and scattering their seeds. Perennials or "many year plants" are difficult to control as leaves, roots, and often underground stems must be considered. Annuals are plants which grow from seeds in the spring, complet - ing their entire growth in one year. They are usually characterized </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 NEBRASKA WEEDS by small fibrous roots and a large number of seeds. Wild Oats, Lamb's - quarter, Russian Thistle, Wild Mustard, Sunflower, Cockle-bur and Ragweed are in this class. There is a class of plants between true annuals and biennials called "winter annuals," due to the fact that their seed fall to the ground in mid-summer or early fall and produce a considerable growth, storing food in the roots before plants are destroyed by frost. The first warm days 1 of spring bring the plant up and their development and seed production is completed early in the season. Examples of this are Pepper Grass, Shepherd's Purse, and Penny Cress. Some of these plants occassionally grow as true annuals under conditions con - ducive to seed germination early in the spring. Annuals and biennials are not difficult to eradicate, any method of cultivation or cutting will destroy them. Seeds germinating in the spring are readily destroyed by cultivation before they have become rooted, preferably when they have just appeared above ground. Seeds of these plants usually have great vitality and if brought to the surface with proper conditions of temperature and moisture will grow when many years old. Weeds which are not destroyed by early cutting may be eliminated by cutting at the surface of the ground before seed maturity. Biennials, or two year plants, such as Burdock, Evening Primrose, False Tansy and Gumweed, require two seasons to mature. During the first season food is collected and stored and in the second, flowers and seeds are produced. Where plowing is not advisable, plants should be cut at frequent intervals to keep seed from forming and to destroy later branches which will grow and produce seed as long as the plant has a store of food in the roots. In some instances the use of a spud may be prac - tical to destroy roots of individual plants if frequent mowing is not convenient. Perennials, or many year plants, call for more careful and thorough treatment according to the nature of the root in which such plants store food, and from which, in many instances, the new plants grow. These roots are of three kinds: First, those with a branching root system close to the surface of the soil, such as- Quack Grass, Blue Joint Grass, Sheep Sorrel, Yarrow, Wild Sage and Snap Dragon. Care - less treatment, such as single plowing, often does more harm than good, by breaking up the underground stems and stimulating growth because of the more favorable conditions produced. Shallow plowing which exposes the roots to the sun, and harrowing or raking out the roots and burning them, is usually advised. Second, the most trouble - some are roots which have underground stems' deep beneath the sur - face of the soil, or in many instances, have root systems at more than one depth, fibrous and running roots near the surface and another sys - tem of running roots which act as reservoirs for food at some depth below in the soil, not disturbed by plowing. Illustrations are. Small Flowered Morning Glory, White Weed, Canada Thistle and Bladder </seg>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA WEEDS 5 Champion. Deep plowing is advisable, the depth depending upon the nature of the soil, but methods of cultivation must be combined with crop rotation and smother crops to produce results. Different plants also often call for special methods of eradication. Third, some peren - nials also have large tap roots extending deep into the soil. Such roots tend to send up new shoots as rapidly as cut off, and the plants often produce seed very close to the ground, one characteristic of the plant being the production of large quantities of seed. They also pro - duce other individuals slowly, by short underground stems or offsets. Examples are Dandelion, Dock, Goldenrod, Ox-eye Daisy and Plantains. Such plants cannot withstand thorough cultivation and spudding out must be resorted to in case it is not convenient to place the land under tillage. It should always be kept in mind that the means of eradica - tion recommended in this bulletin are special methods for clearing the land of the particular kind of weed in question, or that has become very badly infested, but all kinds of weeds can be kept under control by proper crop rotation and special vigilance. USES OF WEEDS From one point of view, weeds are a decided benefit; they force tillage and compel crop rotation, which secures many other benefits other than killing out weeds. Cultivation in corn fields has probably accomplished more for Nebraska farmers in the preservation of mois - ture by the formation of dust mulch, and retarding evaporation, than in the actual destruction of weeds. It has been true in the past that the methods used by farmers have caused the land to become increasingly less productive. When soil becomes worn out so that crops do not find sufficient nourishment, many weeds still grow on it and their decay gradually renders the land productive enough to produce other plants, which, as they decay in turn add to the building up of the soil. With good farming, proper rotation of crops, reclamation of land is never necessary, but until efficient farming has universally become prevalent, we must be thank - ful for weeds. LOSSES CAUSED BY WEEDS The ways in which weeds are harmful and cause loss are numer - ous. Being hardier and usually producing more seed, they shade, crowd out. and take the place of more useful plants. They deprive the soil of the nutriment intended for the crops, increasing the effects of drought by taking up the moisture from the soil and squandering it by evaporation. The eradication of weeds is costly to the farmer in time, labor and machinery, and plays a large part in many farm operations. It retards the work of plowing, harrowing, seeding, cultivating, cutting, </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 NEBRASKA WEEDS binding, drying, shocking, and threshing. It increases the labor of threshing, cleaning seed, freighting and marketing produce. Some weeds injure dairy and meat products by the disagreeable taste and odor produced. The seeds of others damage flour and other mill produce. Some of them are poisonous 1 when eaten by animals and still others injure wool and have barbed awns, as Wild Barley, which cause irritation of the coats and injure the digestive tracts of stock. Weeds frequently compel a farmer to adopt a rotation of crops or raise crops which are not to his advantage otherwise. Such weeds as Barberry harbor the grain rust during the winter stage of its growth. All weeds cause an unsightly appearance of the farm land and cause it to be less valuable. CLEAN 8EED Too much stress cannot be laid on the economy of using well cleaned seed for all crops. Cheap seed is usually the most expensive as is shown by the following table: Percent Kind of Price per Actual I Percent r« rm i n o. Noxious Seed cwt. Cost Purity [ton Weed Seed It is imposible to estimate the loss other than the actual cost of the seeds to the farmer who plants such seed, due to the cost of prepa - ration of the soil, the loss in the season's crop, the extra labor to eradicate weeds which in case of Dodder and Canada Thistle may take several years. The American Seed Trade Association at their meeting in 1917 agreed voluntarily to give their customers the following information regarding seeds, by labeling all lots of seeds of ten pounds or over: (1) Name of seedsman. (2) Kind of seed. (3) Percentage of purity, percentage of germlnable seed, with month and year of the germina - tion test. This Information is of utmost importance to the progressive farmer who is conscientiously attempting efficient food production. The action of the American Seed Trade Association should be highly commended for this action in securing high grade seed and voluntarily offering this information. However, the Nebraska legis - lature of 1921 passed a seed law which embodies these labeling pro- I Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Red Clover Timothy &amp; Alffike $12.00 18.00 16.00 18.00 5.50 j $27.68 32.64 25.44 28.48 10.57 88 93 89 95 73 74 53 50 70 80 I Dodder Dodder Dodder Dodder Canada Thistle </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA WEEDS 7 visions, making it compulsory (or all seed vendors to fall in line and give the information which the various seed organizations have volun - teered to give their customers. Copies of the law and information regarding it may be secured by addressing the Department of Agri - culture, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. LEARN TO KNOW WEEDS New weeds are coming into the State with imported seed. A far - mer will very rarely find Dodder in his fields unless he plants it there. When a new weed appears on the farm, it should be carefully studied in order to become acquainted with its habits so that the farmer may intelligently combat its spread. Send samples of seed and weeds to the Department of Agricul - ture, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska, for analysis and identification, unless they are known to be harmless. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 1 WITCH GRASS (Panicum capillare) Other local names: — Tickle grass, Tumble grass and Panic grass. Witch grass is found throughout the State in cultivated fields and along roadways, usually where soil is dry and sandy. It is an annual plant, growing from, and maturing seed in one season. The plant is easily identified by its spreading habit of growth, the hairy leaves and fine thread-like branches which form the panicle and bear the tiny, shining, grayish brown seeds. Very often the entire plant is purple in color. The plant averages one to two feet in height. The leaves are wide, often an inch in width and varying from six inches to a foot long, very hairy and have the characteristic purple color of the plant. Like most grasses' the flowers are inconspicuous at the end of the stiff, spreading branchlets forming the panicle. At matur - ity the panicle become stiff, breaks from the plant and is car - ried by the wind, distributing its seeds as it goes. This is the reason it is sometimes called "tumble grass." The seeds of this plant become mature during late summer and autumn. For this reason they are often harvested with farm crops. Means of Eradication— This weed is not difficult to eradicate, yielding readily to cultivation. Plants should be prevented from going to seed and especial care taken to plant agricultural seed free from weed seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NEBRASKA WEEDS 9 Flff. 1. Witch Grass. Showing entii- plant; seedling: and seed, natural size and enlarged. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">NEBRASKA WEEDS 10 No. 2 BARNYARD GRASS (Echinchloa crus galli) Other local name* — Cockspur grass. Water grass and Barn grass The name barnyard grass seems a misnomer as cattle are espec - ially fond of it and graze it so closely it cannot persist in barnyards or fields where stock is kept in close range. It is closely related to the millets. The plant is found in all cultivated regions of the world. It is an annual plant with a large number of smooth flattened, leafy, stems, branching and spreading from the base and attaining a height of from two to five feet. The heads vary in color from purple to dark green. The rough margined leaves are usually smooth or bear soft hairs. The seeds are oval, polished, yellowish gray to brown in color, flattened on one side and round on the other. The seeds are fre - quently found in forage crop seeds, such as grasses, clovers and par - ticularly among the millets. Means of Eradication — Barnyard grass i" propagated entirely by seeds. Therefore prevent the production of seed by mowing or pulling before the plant is mature. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">NEBRASKA WEEDS 11 Fig. 2. Barnyard grass. Showing entire plant; seedling and seed, natural size and enlarged. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 3 GREEN FOXTAIL (Setaria viridis) Other local names — Green bottle grass. Pigeon grass and Wild millet. Green Foxtail is an annual, propagated only by seeds. It prevails throughout North America and is said to be the most numerous weed in cornfields and gardens in the United States. Its seeds are the most prevalent weed seed in crop seed. Seed test shows that agricultural seed is rarely entirely free from it and that usually its seeds are the most numerous of any kind of weed seed among crop seeds. The plant resembles millet and is relished by stock both as late pasture and cured hay. It is from bne to three feet tall. Blades are dark green and rough on the margin. The head is two to four inches long and has thick green bristles. The seed is oval, flattened on one side and usually light green, but invariably covered with a coat vary - ing from a straw color, which is most common, to brown seed mottled in appearance. The large number of seed produced renders it a per - sistent weed. Means of Eradication — Though this is a very common weed, it is not a difficult one to exterminate. It makes its greatest appearance in cornfields about the time cultivation ceases and matures soon after, seeding the ground thoroughly for next year's crop. Plants should be cut or palled while small to prevent the scattering of seed. Young plants succumb when smothered by covering with earth, as in disking and cultivating. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">NEBRASKA WEEDS 13 Flic. 3. Grern Foxtail. Showing ontire plant and seed </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 4 WILD OATS (Avena fatua) Wild Oats have several peculiarities which render it a very bad weed. It closely resembles the cultivated varieties and is probably the source from which they originated. It makes its best growth on soil tilled and prepared (or other crops. The seeds ripen at different times so that it is possible for early ripened seed to fall into the soil, infesting the land for a second year and later ripened seeds to be harvested with the crop with which it grows. Wild Oats are annual plants, and become two to four feet tall. The seed panicles resemble tame oats but are much more loose and spreading. The seeds 1 also resemble those of common oats, but are usually yellow or black and have bent and twisted awns which may or may not be present after the seed has been threshed. The principal point of identification is the collar or scar at the base of the seed which is surrounded with hairs. The hairs or bristles may be rubbed off but the collar in - variably remains. The seeds have great vitality and are found to grow when placed under favorable conditions after several years' dormancy. The bent and twisted awn fastens Itself in the earth very securely, twisting tightly when dry and unwinding when damp. In this way the seed is firmly fastened in the soil where germination takes place. The same process takes place in the wool of sheep, in - juring the wool as well as causing serious irritation to the animal. Means of Eradication — When Wild Oats are found infesting a field it is usually because they have been planted there with impure seed. The Nebraska Seed Law requires that the name and approximate num - ber per ounce (30 grams) of Wild Oats, Small Flowered Morning Glory, Wild Mustard, Quack Grass and all species of Dodder seeds which are present, singly or collectively, as follows: (1) in excess of one seed or bulblet in each five grams of timothy, red top, tall meadow oat grass, orchard grass, crested dogstail, Canada blue grass, Kentucky blue grass, fescues, brome grasses, perennial and Italian rye grass, western rye grass, crimson clover, red clover, white clover, als'ke clover, sweet clover, alfalfa and all other 1 grasses and clovers not otherwise classified; (2) one in twenty-five grams of millets, rape, flax and other seeds not specified in (1) or (3); (3) one in one hun - dred grams of wheat, oats, rye, barley, buckwheat, vetches and other seeds as large or larger than wheat shall be Indicated on a tag at - tached to all containers of 10 pounds or more. When this weed seed is found in crop seeds, it is usually possible to trace the seed to some badly infested portion of the country. Do not "sow wild oats." Clean seed is cheap beside that which will infest the land for years to come. In this State, wheat, oats and Brome grass seed are most apt to contain Wild Oat seed. On badly infested land, means which induce the seed to germinate early, so that the young plants may be killed before the year's crop is sown, </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NEBRASKA WEEDS 15 is advised. It is not an uncommon sight in some sections of the United States to see children with some older person going through the grain fields pulling the Wild Oats before harvest. Care should be taken, however, to destroy the plants, for while this would eliminate seed from the harvested crop, leaving the plants on the ground may thoroughly infest the soil for another year. Crop rotation, which in - cludes cultivated crops and alfalfa, tends to do away with this evil. Fig. 4. Wild Oats, Showing top of plant, root and »t«d </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 5 QUACK CRASS (Agropyron repens) Other local names — Couch Grass, Scutch Grass In some sections of the United States Quack Grass is by far the worst weed which infests land, especially when it finds its way into cultivated ground. Land badly infested is worth from $20.00 to $50.00 per acre less than soil free from it. The detrimental part of this perennial grass 1b its wide spreading. Jointed, underground stems often spoken of as roots, which are capable of producing new plants at every joint or about every two inches, thus taking complete pos - session of the soil and. crowding out crop plants. The plant grows from one to three feet in height, has dull green leaves, and flowering heads about four inches long, with straw colored seeds arranged in groups or spikelets containing three to seven seeds. This grass is succulent and relished by grazing animals. The plant is found to be of more or less use as a soil binder. It has been planted in the sand hill regions of Nebraska for the purpose of holding .the soil in place. In theory, it should be a wonderful plant for such regions, but it is found not to live long, probably due to lack of sufficient moisture. As a weed, the seeds are found to be introduced into the State in Brome grass, wheat, oats and barley from states north and northeast of us. Our State Seed Law requires that seed containing more than one Quack Grass seed to certain specified amounts of crop seed as in - dictated under means of eradication of Wild Oats, page 14, be labelled indicating its presence and approximate number per ounce, in order to prevent unscrupulous seed dealers making Nebraska a dumping ground for seed which it would be impossible to find market for in other states. The weed is found to be encroaching more and more on fields in the northeastern part of the State. Means of Eradication — It is far from easy to eradicate Quack Grass once it obtains a rooting. The following methods have been worked out at the Minnesota Experiment Station and are recom - mended by Professor Boss of the Agronomy Department: "Smothering by plowing and thorough bare culture is the best means of eradicating Quack Grass. The best results will follow when the treatment is given In hot, dry weather after the root systems have been somewhat exhausted by the growth of plants. The seed should not be allowed to mature, or, if mature, the plants should be cut and burned. "When a field is badly infested, it should be plowed deep, from five to eight inches or more, as soon as the hay or grain crop is re - moved, preferably not later than August 15. The plowing must be well done and all portions of the plants turned completely under. A </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NEBRASKA WEEDS 17 FI*. 5. Quack (irass. Entire plants, showing underground stems from which new individuals are produced. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 NEBRASKA WEEDS Jointer on the plow will aid in this process. The plow should be fol - lowed within a very few days by a disk harrow with disks set nearly straight to avoid inverting the sod. The purpose is to fill the spaces between the furrow slices, thus stopping the free circulation of air. Following the first disking the land should be double disked frequently enough to prevent the appearance above the surface of any Quack Grass leaves. This will be twice a week in warm, moist seasons and once a week when the weather ia dry. The disking should be con - tinued until growth ceases, usually from sis to eight weeks. To make sure of eradication it is well to disk occasionally until freezing weather in the fall. "The following spring cultivation should begin early and be con - tinued at intervals of a week or ten days until the field may be planted thickly to corn for ensilage or fodder. Thorough cultivation of the corn, with hand hoeing where occasional plants appear in the rows, should complete the eradication, but extreme watchfulness is re - quired to get all of the plants. "The intensive cultivation is expensive and is called for at times when farm labor is extremely busy, but there seems to be no other way to eradicate the weed completely. The cost of cultivation is in many cases returned in the increased yield of the crops following. "Short crop rotations are useful in keeping Quack Grass under control, and when arranged so as to provide an opportunity to attack the Quack Grass at seasonable times, will permit eradication of the weed without losing the use of the land. A good two-year rotation for this purpose uses ensilage-corn after fall rye. Plow the land after the removal of the rye, disk, and prepare it for ensilage-corn the next year. Plow the land after harvesting the corn and sow the rye im - mediately. The following three-year rotation may be used: (1) Pall rye or barley seeded to clover; (2) clover hay, first crop; plow be - tween July 15 and August 1, and disk as above; (3) ensilage-corn. A fall rye, corn, barley and clover rotation may be managed so as to eradicate the Quack Grass between the first and second years." BLUE JOINT GRASS No. 6 (Agropyron smithii) Other local names — Western Wheat Grass, Colorado Blue-stem. West - ern Quack Grass This perennial grass grows abundantly on alkali soil. Like the Quack Grass to which it is closely related, it has an underground stem system, which aids both in propagation of new individual plants and in obtaining nourishment and moisture, often under semi-arid conditions. It is very common throughout the State and is considered a desirable forage plant, when it does not encroach upon cultivated fields, </seg>
            <seg id="p019">NEBRASKA WEEDS 19 Oi-bm. Heads of plant and root, showing underground steins wnicta are capable of producing new plants. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 NEBRASKA WEEDS This grass can be easily distinguished from other grasses by its rough, rigid, coarse stems and its bluish green color. The seeds are found among many of the grass s«eds and are especially objectionable in alfalfa and clover seed. Meant of Eradication — Thorough cultivation and rotation of crops from grain to cultivated ones, exterminates this weed in almost all kinds of soil. The plant should be cut for hay before seed mature, unless the plant is desired for permanent forage purposes. No. 7 WILD BARLEY (Hordeum jubatum) Other local Name* — Tickle Grass, Squirrel-tail Grass and Skunk's Tail. This perennial weed does not produce seed the first year, only at - taining a height of about twelve inches, but the second year, some - times more than doubles this height. It has been cultivated in some places for the beauty of its silky flowers, to the detriment of land tillers in the adjacent territory. A spikelet consists of seven awns, together with one central fertile seed and two lateral infertile florets. These are readily blown about by wind and are carried by men and animals on account of the awns 1 attaching themselves to the coats of animals and clothing of people. The awns are brittle when ripe and break into small pieces which work into the jaws of stock, causing ulcerations, lumpy jaw, and other swellings. The nostrils and eyes are also affected. Professor Nelson, of the Wyoming Experiment Station, cites cases in which sheep and cattle were both injured and total blindness was caused. Mean* of Eradication — On account of this 1 grass having no run - ning stems or roots, it may be eradicated by mowing or plowing under before the seed matures. While burning should possibly never be ad - vised on account of its injury to the soil, fire is effective in destroy - ing the seeds of the weed when they become dry in the autumn. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">NEBRASKA WEEDS 21 Fl*. 7. Wild Barley. Illustrating the entire plant and seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 8 NODDING WILD RYE (Elymus canadensis) Other local names — Wild Rye, Bunch Grass and Lyme Grass. County agricultural agents report this perennial weed to be abundant in yarious parts of the State. It seems to grow equally well in all soils. The root system is large and fibrous but there are no underground runners. The plant reaches two to three feet in height and has heavy drooping heads four to six inches long with wavy awns. The drooping of the head gives the plant its common name. The plant is propagated by seeds. These are sometimes planted with Brome grass and other forage crops. Means of Eradication — The plant should be cut early and fre - quently to prevent seed formation. Hand pulling is recommended for etxerminating stray plants. It cannot survive cultivation of the soil. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">NEBRASKA WEEDS 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">■14 NEBRASKA WEEDS CURLED DOCK No. 9 (Rumex crispus) Other local name* — Yellow Dock and Sour Dock. This perennial has a very deep tap-root, often extending several feet into the ground. The plant is from two to four feet in height and has oblong, lance-shaped leaves with a wavy margin, hence the name Curled Dock. The flowers and seed grow in whorles on slender stalks and ripen in June or July. The seeds are three-sided with rounded tips, brown and shiny, surrounded by a beautiful winged pod which assists in its distribu - tion both by water and wind. The seeds of this plant are common among almost all agricultural s«ed, but especially in alfalfa and clover. The roots of the plant are commonly used for their medicinal qualities, the plant being cultivated in some European countries for that purpose. Means of Eradication — Frequent and close cutting during the year will prevent seed production and if no foliage is permitted, the store of food in the roots will be reduced and the plant will die in consequence. Spudding and hand pulling are advisable in case of stray plants. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">NEBRASKA WEEDS Fl«. 9. Curled Dm-k. Showing top of pUnt, &gt; leaf, the long fleihy root, and seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 NEBRASKA WEEDS RED SORREL No. 10 (Rumex acetosella) Other local name* — Sheep Sorrel, Sour Grass and Field Sorrel. Red Sorrel Is a perennial plant, propagated by seeds and run - ning root stalks, which are yellow In color. The stems are slender, one-half to one and one-half feet in height. The silvery green leaves are arrow shaped, one to three inches long. The flowers are not conspicuous. The male or anther-bearing plants have conspicuous anthers while the female or pistillate flowers have bright red calyx - lobes with brighter stigmas; hence the name Red Sorrel. The seeds are brown, polished, and triangular with dull edges and often have a brown hull over them. The seed are very fre - quent in clover and grass seeds. This plant contains an acid juice reported to be pleasant to the taste, and relished by stock to their detriment, as It is poisonous to horses and sheep. Reports have been received at this office of this plant throughout the State and very bad in patches on some farms. Meant of Eradication — Professor P. J. Pepal, Agricultural Experi - ment Station, Purdue University, Lafayette, Indiana, in 1916 pub - lished a bulletin, No. 197, Volume XIX, on this weed. He says: "Red Sorrel is the red flag of danger. It serves as a signal to show that the soil in which it is growing is not in proper condition for profitable growing of crops. The presence of Red Sorrel indi - cates acid soil. The application of lime destroys the weed or pre - vents it from starting its growth and renders the soil productive to all general crops." Compared to other perennial weeds with running root stalks, Red Sorrel is easily eradicated. Ordinary cultivation of crops will destroy it unless the land is acid, in which case, the condition of the soil weakens general crops and encourages the growth of this weed which is adapted to it. In permanent meadows where cultiva - tion is impossible, spraying with iron sulfate solution is resorted to and has been found efficient unless there is a large amount of clover in the field which would also be injured. Do not sow agricultural seed, containing Red Sorrel seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">NEBRASKA WEEDS 27 Fl«. 10. Red Sorrel. Illustrating the entire plint. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 11 WILD BUCKWHEAT (Polyganum convolvulus) Other local name*— Corn Bind and Black Bindweed. The writer finds that so many different weeds in Nebraska are commonly called Bindweed that it would appear that in order to .peak intelligently the term should generally be avoided. Wild Buckwheat is an annual, propagated by seeds, and is pre - valert throughout the United States, especially in grain fields, where it robs the desired crop of its food. As a means of reaching up to the sunlight, it climbs over, winds about and weights down the grain. The plant has long, trailing, winding stems, three and four feet long with an abundance of dark green heart-shaped leaves which shade other crops. The entire plant resembles the common culti - vated buckwheat. The seeds are dull, black in color and three angled. They are very prevalent among cereal crops and are listed as one of the most prevalent and noxious weeds in seed wheat. Mean* of Eradication — The following means of control have been recommended by various experiment stations. Cultivate stubbles directly after harvest so as to encourage the germination of as many seeds as possible in the autumn. The young plants will then be winter killed. Spring cultivation will destroy the early plants. Sow clean seed and be sure in the purchase of wheat or other cereal crop seed you are not also paying for a greater or less percent of this noxious weed. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">NEBRASKA WEEDS 29 F"l«. 11. Wild Buckwheat. Twinine plant; plant winding around stalk of timothy; root; seedlings; seed, natural size and enlarged. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">NEBRASKA WEEDS 30 No. 12 LAMB'S-QUARTER Other local name* — White Goose Foot and Pigweed. This annual plant occurs everywhere in rich land. It is a slender, succulent rapid growing plant two to six feet in height with a general silvery gray appearance, due to a white, mealy substance, showing more conspicuously on the under side of the leaves. The plant adapts itself to conditions of moisture and light very quickly, being sometimes tall and slender and under other conditions very branched and spreading. The flowers are light green and also have the silvery mealy appearance of the leaves. Seed are very abundant, thus enabling the plant to spread very rapidly. The mature seeds are double-convex, disc shaped, black and shiny. Often a thin envelope covers the seed leaving a tiny black spot in the center uncovered. The seeds are usually very abundant in seed of the farm crops which have not been thoroughly cleaned by a screening and blowing process. The plant Is relished by farm animals and is often cooked for greens, for human consump - tion. The dish closely resembles spinach or beets, to which the plant is closely related. . Meant of Eradication — On account of the early and rapid growth of this weed, it appears among the first in the spring and may be destroyed by any means of cultivation when young. If the weeds obtain an early start in winter wheat fields, harrowing will destroy many without injuring the deeper rooted grain. If left to become a few inches in height, hoeing and pulling should be resorted to. A few sheep will quickly destroy all young plants. Plant only clean seed. (Chenopodium album) </seg>
            <seg id="p031">NEBRASKA WEEDS 31 VUc- 12. Lamb's-quarter. Top of plant and root. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 13 SALT BUSH (Atriplex hastata) Other local names — Spreading Orache. This plant is an annual propagated from seed each year. It varies greatly in height, due to its spreading character which causes it to become a tumble weed, much like Russian Thistle. Stems are light colored with occasional purple stripes, grooved and profusely branched. Leaves are one to six inches in length, borne on petioles, lance shaped and sparingly toothed. Young plants appear mealy or silvery scurfy similar to Lamb's-quarter. Flowers are in small clusters on terminal, almost leafless spikes. The stamen and pistil are borne in separate flowers*. The seeds mature between two fleshy triangular bracts with tiny tubercles on the outer sides. The seeds are double-convex discs with a narrow margin about the edge and are often found in agricultural seed, especially in alfalfa and sweet clover. The plant has adapted itself to these fields and is reported to be spreading throughout the State. The cutting of alfalfa removes the top of these plants, which seems merely to cause more abundant lateral growth. Means of Eradication — It is necessary to remove the plant by hand pulling to be sure of its elimination. When cut off, it will need attention several times on account of budding and producing seed close to the ground. Early cultivation destroys young plants and thus rotation of crops proves its efficiency. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">NEBRASKA WEEDS 33 Vig. 13. Salt BuBh. Showing top of plant, enlarged seed receptacle and ued natural size </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 14 RUSSIAN THISTLE (Salsoli tragus) Other local name — Tumble Weed. Russian Thistle Is one of the most noxious weeds in the United States In all cultivated fields. It is said to have been imported into this country with flax seed from Russia. It is an annual from one to three feet in height and branches out profusely, sometimes cover - ing an area five to six feet in diameter. The older plants have spines or prickles over almost all parts and from this peculiarity re - ceived the name "thistle," which is altogether wrong for the plant is closely related to Lamb's-quarter and Salt Bush. The young plants have a moss or grass-like appearance, deep green in color, and are tender and succulent. They are relished by live stock. As the plant ages, however, the stems become woody, hard, rigid and are streaked with deep purple lines, as are the later leaves. The first tender leaves fall away and there appears all over the plant, the small tapered leaf ending in a spine. The flowers are thin and papery and vary in color from green, white and pink to deep rose color, but are obscured by the spines. Each plant produces many seeds which are spread over large areas, due to the plant breaking loose from its growing place and tumbling hither and thither as the wind blows. The amount of damage done to fences by them can not be estimated. The seeds are small and conical with a flat round base. Re - moval of the papery gray coat reveals the coiled embryo having the coiled appearance of a snail shell. This weed often makes a slow growth, firmly rooting itself in grain fields until the grain is cut, then given light and moisture, it produces a quick growth, filling the fields with these rolling weeds. Semi-arid conditions are favorable to its growth and Western Ne - braska especially abounds in this weed. Experiments have proven that the plant is very nutritious and relished by farm stock when cut and cured before the plant has become woody and the spines have formed, and it is believed that its use will become more and more prevalent as better means are found to preserve and cure it as forage. Mean* of Eradication — Only clean agricultural seed should be sown. Plants should be prevented from maturing seed. This may be easily done when the plants are young, by cultivation. Crop rotation destroys them as they are not prevalent in tilled fields. Matured plants should be destroyed by fire before they become roll - ing pests scattering their seeds as they travel. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">NEBRA?KA WEEDS 35 Rl«. 14. Russian Thistle. Showing branch of young plant in the renter ; one of mature plant and seed at right, and a small drawing of entire plant at left. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 15 ROUGH PIGWEED (Amaranthus retroflexus) Other local names — Red Root Pigweed, Red Root and Green Amaranth. This weed is found throughout the United States. In fact, due to its large production of tiny seeds, cultivated soil is very seldom free from it. The seed also live for long periods without germina - tion unless conditions are especially favorable. Experiments carried on in the botanical gardens in New York proved seed to retain their vitality and grow after thirty-five years of dormancy. The plant is an annual and grows one to six feet in height. The leaves and stout stems are characterized by roughness through - out. The root is long, fleshy and pink in color. From this charac - teristic it is sometimes called "Red Root." Leaves are borne on long petiols. Flowers, rough and green, are borne in panicles in the angle between the petiole and stem. The shiny, black disc-shaped seeds are usually very numerous and found in almost all agricultural seeds' before being thoroughly cleaned. Removing them, however, is comparatively easy on ac - count of their size and shape. Means of Eradication — Rough Pigweed should be prevented from going to seed by cultivation and harrowing for the plants are easily destroyed while small. Hand 1 pulling and hoeing may be found necessary in case of individual plants. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">NEBRASKA WEEDS 37 r Fl». 15. Rough Pigweed. Top of pUnt and root. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">NEBRASKA WEEDS 38 No. 16 NIGHT FLOWERING CATCHFLY (Silene noctiftora) Other local names— Sticky Cockle, Clammy Cockle. Night flowering catchfly is an annual or a winter annual. Seeds falling in the ground early in one season produce a growth which gives it a firm footing in the soil, so that seed are matured early during the next growing season. The plant is from one to three feet high, erect, somewhat branched, covered with soft hairs and sticky to the touch, for which reason it is sometimes called "Sticky, or Clammy Cockle." The lower leaves are three to five inches long, several times as long, as wide and narrowing at the base to mar - gined petioles. The upper leaves, however, are attached directly to the stem. The showy pink and white flowers have five deeply cleft petals. , They are fragrant. The plant was introduced from Europe and cultivated for this reason, but has gradually become a widely spread, pernicious plant. One of the peculiarities of this group of plants is the inflated calyx tube marked with shaded longitudinal lines. Each, upon ma - turity contains a large number of dull gray seeds, roughened with rows of small knob-like projections. The seeds are very common in clover and alfalfa seed and are very difficult to remove by seed cleaning processes. Means of Eradication — Plant only clean seed. Prevent Night Flowering Catchfly from seeding by cultivation while young or mow - ing before seed matures. Cultivation will easily destroy the roots. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">NEBRASKA WEEDS 39 Vig. 1*. Ni»ht-flow.rin| C»tchfly. Entlr. plant; KfiUngt, and •wd natural *t and snlarged. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 NEBRASKA WEEDS PENNY CRESS No. 17 (Thlaspi arvense) Other local name*— French Weed, Stink Weed, Stinking Mustard. Bastard Cress. This weed has been called, "the most hated enemy of the west - ern farmer." On account of the great loss by its presence on the soil the United States Department of Agriculture recently caused a special survey and investigation of the central and northwestern portion of this country. Sprays which destroy other mustards do not affect it, neither does freezing. It is very prolific and seeds re - tain their vitality for long periods of time. Crops cannot compete with it in the fields and when eaten by cows the meat and milk has a very sickening and disagreeable taste. Prom this characteristic it is in some localities called "Stinkweed." The plant is an annual or winter annual and seeds ripen from early spring until late fall. It belongs to the mustard family and resembles pepper grass but is larger. The flowers are white with a greenish appearance, and the seed pods are large, disc-shaped and about three-quarters of an inch in diameter. Prom the appearance of the pods which turn copper colored on ripening, the plant re - ceives its name, "Penny Cress." In fact, the entire plant takes on this copper colored appearance with age. The seed are deep, reddish brown, with concentric ridges which curve from one extremity to the other of the ovate surface. They are prevalent in the seed of clovers, alfalfa and millet, from which removal is not easy as is the case with cereals when subjected to a good cleaning process. Meant of Eradication — The following means of eradication are given by Ada Georgia in "Manual of Weeds": "Sow clean seed. If the infestation is new, hand-pull and de - stroy the plants before any fruits mature, even though the task be very strenuous. In grain fields, if seeds have been allowed to ripen, burn over the stubbles for the purpose of destroying those that have fallen on the ground. Give surface cultivation in order to en - courage germination of such seeds as are in the soil, and plow the young plants under while still In the rosette stage of growth. But never turn under any plants bearing developed pods, even though they may be green, for they go on ripening on the stalks, when under the warm soil, quite as well as, or better than above it. Autumn-grown plants are the most obnoxious since they come earliest into bloom and fruit the next season, and every effort should be made to kill as many of these as possible. Spring seedlings may be dragged out of grain fields with small-toothed weeding harrows, beginning when the grain it only about three Inches high and re- </seg>
            <seg id="p041">NKUKASKA WEEDS 41 fig. 17. Penny Crew. Showing top of plant and root. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">NEBRASKA WEEDS 42 peating the operation once or twice afterwards — a treatment which greatly benefits the crop at the same time that it kills the weeds. II practicable, put the ground to a cultivated crop, which should be given very thorough tillage before the land is used again for grain." No. 18 FALSE FLAX Other local names — Wild Flax, Dutch Flax, Siberian Oil Seed. The seed of False Flax have some of the characteristics of culti - vated flax when moist, and for this reason received its common name, though it is not closely related to flax but is a typical mem - ber of the mustard family. It is an annual or winter annual and its seeds ripen throughout the greater part of the growing season. The leaves and stems, reaching two to three feet in height, are a bluish green in color and fleshy, storing a supply of moisture and nutrition which will sometimes ripen the seeds after the plant has been cut. The flowers are yellow. The seeds yield both oil and mucilage and in some countries of Europe have been cultivated for these products. They are variable in shape, reddish yellow in color, and are borne in pear shaped pods. Means of Eradication — Farmers and county agents report this weed becoming increasingly more prevalent in Nebraska. The soil should be cultivated early and late at the times in the season when the young plants are obtaining their hold on the soil. Hand pulling is sometimes advisable in grain fields. (Camelina sativa) </seg>
            <seg id="p043">NEBRASKA WEEDS 43 Fig. 18. False Flax. Showing top of plant, seedling root, and stwlg. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 19 WILD MUSTARD (Brassica arvensis) Other local name — Charlock. It is unlawful to sell agricultural seed in the State ot Nebraska in which there is more than one Wild Mustard seed to certain speci - fied amounts of crop seeds as indicated under Wild Oats, page 14, unless the presence and approximate number per ounce is indicated on the label. The weed is a general pest throughout the country on account of its producing so many seeds and scattering them during the season from May to October. Bright yellow blossoms are con - tinually opening at the apex while ripened seed are being scattered from the opening pods lower on the flowering stalk. This annual is erect, one to three feet high, often branching near the top. The seeds are reported to have great vitality due to their abundance of oil. Instances have been cited where seed had lain dormant in the ground for twenty-four years due to being turned under by deep plowing and then upon being placed in favorable conditions, produc - ing a vigorous growth. Mustard seed are not difficult to separate from cereals by ordi - nary cleaning apparatus, but from clovers and alfalfa the results are uncertain. Means of Eradication — Young plants should be destroyed by harrowing in early spring before cereal crops are more than a few inches high. During the later growth of grain many fields have been freed of much mustard by spraying with iron sulfate. After harvest, stubbles are often disked to stimulate germination of seeds and then cultivation continued until frost to destroy the new plants. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">NEBRASKA WEEDS 45 Fl«. 19. Wild Mustard. Showing top of plant, aeed pod and flower. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">NEBRASKA WEEDS 46 No. 20 FIVE FINGER (Potentilla monspeliensis) Other local name — Rough cinquefoll. This weed is prevalent throughout the State, living on poor dry soil as well as under more favorable conditions. It is found to be both annual and biennial, blooming usually during the three summer months. Stems are spreading but occasionally reach a height of three feet. The three lobed leaves taper to the base and are hairy on both sides, as are most all parts of the plant. The flowers are terminal, five petaled, and yellow in color. The calyx forms a cup - like protection for the numerous seeds, borne on cone-like heads. The tiny seeds are light brown or tan in color and have a wrinkled surface. They are abundant in the smaller clover seeds such as white clover, alsike clover, and especially in lawn grass and timothy seed. Meant of Eradication — Sow only clean seed. A cultivated crop for a short time, or cutting before seed matures will destroy this weed. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">NEBRASKA WEEDS 47 Pig. M. Fi»e fiaftt. Top o&lt; plint; seodlingi; leaf and teed natural lite and WlMf«d </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 21 YELLOW TREFOIL (Medicago lupulina) Other local names — Black Medick, Black-seeded Hop Clover, Yellow Trefoil Is an annual plant belonging in the same family with alfalfa and clovers. The plant and seed resemble alfalfa but lies almost flat upon the ground, spreading profusely, and the flowers are bright yellow in small dense heads, about a half inch long and a quarter inch in thickness. The pods are black, thin walled and kidney shaped. The plant is common in meadows, along walks and in lawns. The seed is found in alfalfa and clovers, but especially in white clover seed used for lawns, the plant apparently thriving under the condition common to the clovers in lawns. Means of Eradication — Other clovers and alfalfa seem generally more hardy and crowd out this member of the family when condi - tions are favorable. Cultivation of the soil is efficient. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">NEBRASKA WEEDS 49 Wig. 11. Y«Uow Trefoil. Sbowisf top of plant. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 NEBRASKA WEEDS SMALL FLOWERED MORNING-GLORY No. 22 (Convolvulus arvensis) Other local name — Bind Weed (a name which should be avoided, due to its confusion with other weeds spoken of by the same name.) This perennial, trailing, twining plant is very noxious, due to deep rooted, cord-like, creeping, fleshy roots, forming mats in the ground which bud at intervals giving rise to new plants, crowding out, weighting down, and choking other vegetation. The arrow - shaped leaves are borne on slender alternating petioles. Blossoms are small, pink, or nearly white, and funnel-form in shape. The capsules usually bear four dark brown, coarsely rough - ened seeds with one convex surface and two flattened faces, joined in a broad central ridge. Seeds are seldom found in agricultural seeds and in many cases seed are not produced by the plant, propa - gation being more general from the perennial running roots. The Nebraska Seed Law requires that the presence and approxi - mate number per ounce of more than one Small Flowered Morning Glory seed in specified amounts, as given under Wild Oats, of any agricultural seed must be indicated on the label attached to the con - tainer of the seed. Mean* of Eradication — Farmers and agricultural extension work - ers throughout the State have given information regarding their ex - perience with this weed. A summary of these replies leads to the belief that eternal vigilance is the prime factor in its eradication. The land should be plowed deeply and harrowed to bring out as many of the root stalks as possible during the hot weather. Espe - cial attention should be given to the destruction of the stalks which catch on the harrow or rake. It has been found that hogs enjoy eating these. After plowing, tillage should be frequent so that no green leaves are permitted to produce food for the roots. The opinion is very prevalent that alfalfa can be sown. It tends to smother the growth, while the frequent cutting of the alfalfa pre - vents the growth of the leaves to some extent. Small patches are treated in various ways, sometimes by fencing for hog pasture, as the hogs will root out the succulent roots. Sheep will also keep the foliage down and finally destroy the plant. Parties have attempted to eradicate patches by placing a straw pile over them, but it is found that the plant often finds its way through such stacks to a considerable height. Building paper placed over patches and weighted down by a stack or other means has been found to be effective. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">NEBRASKA WEEDS 51 Fl*. 22. Small Flowerod Morning Glory. Showing entire plant with running root from which new plant* are being produced; and seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">NEBRASKA WEEDS 52 DODDER (Cuscuta tpp.) Other local name* — Hairweed, Strangleweed, Devil's Hair. Dodder is a curious leafless, thread-like plant, obtaining its food by stealing it from host plants, about which it winds itself, form - ing loose tangled masses which with the clusters of flowers, weight down the plant used as host. The plant is annual. In the spring seeds in the ground or planted with agricultural seed, germinate, sometimes after crop seed have made some growth, send up a thread-like tendril which swings around in a circle as it grows longer until it touches a plant about which it begins to wrap itself. The stem connecting the plant with the seed from which it originates in the ground soon disintegrates ro that there is no connection with the soil. Tiny suckers or haustoria are sent into the stem and leaves of the host plant and begin their work of stealing the food manufactured by the host plant for its own use. Dodder is yellow in color, has no leaves, no roots, and no green coloring matter. None of them are necessary as it obtains its food prepared, so that only assimilation is necessary. Very quickly or as soon as a good foothold is secured, the numerous blossoms and seeds begin to form. Dodder attacks many kinds of plants such as ragweed, sunflower, goldenrod, elderberry, willow and flax, but it is especially fond of the legumes' such as alfalfa and red clover. Besides the common field dodder, special varieties have adapted themselves to each alfalfa, red clover and flax. In a comparatively new country like Nebraska, a farmer is not apt to find his fields infested with this pest unless he has purchased the dodder with agricultural seed. In Nebraska it is unlawful to sell agricultural seed containing more than one dodder seed to various specified amounts according to the size of the agricultural seed as* indicated under "Means of Eradica - tion" of Wild Oats, on page 14, unless its presence and the approxi - mate number per ounce is indicated on the label. Different varieties of dodder have different sized seeds. The small seeded variety can be readily removed by cleaning processes but others similar to alfalfa and clover in size and weight, cannot. Dodder seeds are oval to spherical, flattened or pitted on one to three sides. Color varies from whitish tan to dark brown. The outer coat 1b roughened slight - ly resembling that of unfinished paper. These seeds are especially noted for their longivity. One seed turned under by the plow has been known to grow after eight years when placed under favorable conditions by plowing again, and infesting a large area in a newly planted crop. No field should ever be harvested tor seed which has </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 NEBRASKA WEEDS any dodder in it, and a crop that is badly infested should not be harvested for hay as seeds will be distributed to other fields. Meant of Eradication — Too great stress cannot be laid on the value of clean seed, for rarely will this pest take a forage crop un - less the dodder seed has been planted with it. Prevention is far more important than the cure. In case infestation is very bad, cut close to the ground in order to leave no stems in the field ready to grow with the forage crop, permit the hay to dry and then burn. Care should be taken to know that seeds which may be scattered on the ground have also been exposed to the heat of the fire, or, if the entire field is infested the spread of the pest may be stopped by plowing the crop under before the dodder seeds mature. In ordinary cases, especially with alfalfa, frequent cutting throughout the season, before any seeds ripen, will control the spread of the plant, if not, entirely eradicate it. The United States Department of Agriculture has recently published Farmers Bulletin No. 1161, entitled "Dodder," which is a thorough discussion of the plant and methods of extermin - ation. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">NEBRASKA WEEDS 54 BUFFALO BUR No. 24 (Solarium rostratum) Other local names — Beaked Night-shade and Colorado Bur. This annual is prevalent throughout the State on prairies and in waste places, but seldom in tilled fields. It is typically a barn - yard weed. The much branched stems reach one to two feet in height and are dotted with abundant yellow awn-like spines, as are the petioles and midribs of the leaves which are long and oval in outline, but made up of irregular lobes on each side of the petiole. Flowers are yellow, the stamens 1 and styles bent down. The prickly calyx becomes the bur which envelopes the seed. In autumn the plant becomes rigid, breaks from the soil, becoming a tumbleweed. scattering its seeds as it rolls about as the winds blow. Seed are dull black, flattened, usually ovate in outline and marked on the surface with small pits giving the seed a spongy ap - pearance. Seed in the prickly burs are carried in the coats of farm slock from place to place. Besides considerable damage is done by irritation of the skins and reducing the quality of hides and hair. Meant of Eradication — Remove plant before seeds mature by cut - ting, spudding or hoeing out. It is not troublesome on well culti - vated land. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">NEBRASKA WEEDS 55 •*"•*• *•• Buffalo Bur. Showing lop of plant, root and bur. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 25 COMMON PLANTAIN (Plantago major) Other local name* — Dooryard Plantain, Broad-leaf Plantain, Round - leaf Plantain and Bird-seed Plantain. This plant usually finds a place in lawns, dooryards, in meadows and among such forage crops as alfalfa and clover. It is a very per - sistent perennial due to the long vitality of the seeds and the fact that cutting does it little injury on account of its low growing habit. Each of the long, oval leaves has very prominent longitudinal veins merging into a petiole which is deep red at the base. The white flowers are inconspicuous on erect spikes often attaining a length of a foot or more. Seeds are borne in small two-celled capsules. Ordinarily each plant produces many thousand seeds which are found in grass find fcrr.ge crop seeds, such as clover, timothy and occa - sionally in alfalfa. Mean* of Eradication — When plants prevail in lawns, the quick - est means of riddance is spudding or cutting out roots and all, or If by shading, much of the grass has been killed the lawn should be plowed or spaded and thickly re-seeded. Where it is possible, thorough cultivation will remove the plant readily. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">NEBRASKA WEEDS 57 Fig. 25. Common Plantain. Entire plant. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 26 BUCKHORN PLANTAIN (Plantago lanceolata) Other local names — Rib Grass, Narrow-leaved Plantain, English Plaintain and Rat-tail. Buckhorn Plantain is usually perennial but sometimes biennial. Unlike the common plantain just described, this pest not only lives in dooryards, but is especially pernicious in alfalfa, clover fields 1 and pastures, where it crowds out forage plants. The first year the plant makes a growth of short thick root stalks with many branches and a low rosette of narrow, lance-shaped, hairy leaves, lined with three to seven conspicuous ribs, tapering to the petiole. The stalk bear - ing the head is very slender, tough and wiry. The head is club shaped, blooming throughout the summer at the same time seed are ripening in large numbers, and being scattered in hay or sticking to any damp surface due to a coat of mucilage common to the plantains. Seed merchants take advantage of this in cleaning commercial seed by passing it over or blowing it against damp canvas, where the plantain seeds stick. Removal from clovers' and grasses by other means is difficult due to the size and shape, which is boat-like and rounded at the ends. The color is brown and the outer coat gives the seed a varnished, highly polished appearance when dry. Means of Eradication — Sow only seed that is free from weed seed. Stray plants may be spudded out or pulled after a rain when ground is soft, to prevent seed maturing. Meadows and other forage crop land when badly infested, should be plowed and re-seeded with plenty of clean seed after all caution has been taken to put the land in condition that would encourage the growth of the useful forage plants. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">NEBRASKA WEEDS 59 Figr. 26. Buckhorn Plantain. Entire plant; seedling; older seedling; SCT?ds natural size and enlarged. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 27 GUM WEED (Grindelia squarrosa) Other local names — Rosin Weed, Tar Weed. Gum weed has not obtained a foothold on the soils of Nebraska since cultivation has become prevalent. The virgin prairies were in - fested with it and early settlers report that "it seemed worse every other year." It is a very persistent, both biennial and perennial plant, propagated by seeds, growing now on roadsides, waste places, on prairie land and in cultivated fields. The plants grow from two to three feet high. The stems are branched, smooth, erect, reddish in color. Leaves are oblong or spatulate and clasp the stems of the plant. The leaves with the heads are gathered, dried, and made into an external remedy for use in cases of rheumatism and asthma. The bright yellow terminal heads have a sticky, odorous, resinous sub - stance on them, soiling clothing with which they come in contact. The cream colored seeds somewhat resemble those of Canada Thistle but are flattened and angular, grooved longitudinally and lighter in color. They are found in alfalfa, sweet clover and other commercial grass seeds. Means of Eradication — Caution should be taken to sow only clean seed. Prevent plants from seeding by frequent cutting or hand pulling in case the land cannot be thoroughly cultivated. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">NEBRASKA WEEDS 61 I'-Ig. 27. Cium Weed. Top of plant and root. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 28 RAGWEED (Ambrosia artemisiifolia) Other local names — Roman Wormwood, Carrot Weed, Bitter Weed and Hogweed. Common Ragweed is annual, propagated by seed only. It is common in all parts of the State in cultivated soil, meadows, waste places and roadsides. It is from one to three feet in height, has hairy branched stems and alternate, much divided hairy leaves hav - ing almost a feathery appearance. The upper flowers bear the pollen and fertilize the lower ones. An abundance of pollen is pro - duced, giving the plant a yellow appearance. Undoubtedly this pollen is one of those which cause the irritation commonly called "hay fever." The seeds of Ragweed ripen from August to October. They have one central beak surrounded by four or five spiny points and are prevalent in the seed of red clover and cereals. Under ordinary conditions, cattle do not use the plant as food, due to its bitter taste, but in times of scarcity of pasture will do so, with the result that milk is bitter and has an unpleasant odor. Means of Eradication — Sow only clean seed. Plants are easily destroyed by cultivation or cutting in order that no seed may ma - tore. Ada Georgia recommends the use of sprays of copper sulfate or iron sulfate as the weed is very susceptible to injury by such solutions. This would often be practical in meadows and roadsides as the spray would not injure the grasses. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">NEBRASKA WEEDS 63 Ft*. 88. Rtfweed. Top of pUat, </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 29 GREATER RAGWEED (Ambrosia trifida) Other local names— Kinghead. Big Bitter Weed, Wild Hemp and Tall Ambrosia. This annual is especially prevalent in Nebraska with very little selection as to the kind or state of cultivation of the soil. It is tall and coarse, four to ten feet in height, crowding out other vegetation by its large root system and the enormous amount of shading it is capable of doing with its large, rough, hairy, three or five-parted leaves, which are often a foot in length. As is common Ragweed the upper flowers produce the pollen which fertilizes the lower ones growing in the angle formed by the union of leaves and stems. The seed is large, one-fourth of an inch long, tapering from a large top with five to six points to a tip at the base. The seeds' are found in cereals, especially wheat, in which it is noxious due to the fact that it is hard to remove for planting or for milling, in the latter case giving flour a bitter taste. Millers make a special dockage on grain when this seed is prevalent. There is also in Nebraska a perennial Ragweed, smaller than either of the others described but having creeping root stalks which make it possible for its spread to cause a real problem of eradica - tion. Means of Eradication — See Common Ragweed. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">/ NEBRASKA WEEDS 65 Vig. 39, Greater Ragweed. Showing top of plant and seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 30 WHITE WEED Other local names— Bur Ragweed, White Ragweed and Creeping Ragweed. White Weed is closely related to and resembles the Ragweeds but unlike the two specie just described, it is perennial instead of annual and instead of being dark green, is white in appearance, due to the dense white wooly hairs on the underside of the leaf. It is much more pernicious than the Ragweeds due to its creeping root - stalks by which the patches continually increase in size. White Weed is found throughout the western part of the State but is par - ticularly noxious in Phelps, Kearney, Franklin, Harlan and Gosper counties where tanners are beginning to realize that they have a real weed problem to combat. On the highland between the Platte and Republican Rivers, the plants seem to start in low, swampy places and gradually creep to higher ground. Besides sending out the creeping rootstalks to produce new plants, the roots of the plants are adapted to drought conditions, in that wiry, unbranched, woody roots run down into the soil for long distances, storing food and obtaining moisture for its growth. In cultivated fields it bids defiance to either competition with cultivated crops or small grain. Alfalfa with its long tap root and frequent cutting seems to hold the weed in check better than any other crop. The stems are from a foot to a foot and a half in height, much branched, leaves smooth and light green above but white and wooly beneath. Margins are irregular, wavy and deeply divided. Like the Ragweeds the sterile staminate flowers are borne on terminal spikes, while the fertile ones maturing in the axis of the stem and leaves produce tiny burs, resembling the common sand bur in size and the appearance of prickles. Means of Eradication — Much the same methods should be used for White Weed that have proven successful in eradication of Canada Thistle. In order to starve the roots and use up the reserve supply of food stored under ground, the most practical method is to fre - quently destroy all top growth. Since plants can assimilate food only by the aid of green leaves, the frequent cutting of the tops uses up the stored food in the deep seated roots. In case of badly in - fested large areas, plow deep during the blooming time and before seeds mature, to expose the root stalks to the hot sun's rays and follow up -with cultivation with machinery which will cut off all new sprouts below the surface, or plant a crop that can be hoed, or thoroughly cultivated every few days or as often as new shoots appear. The intervals of time between the appearance of new indi- (Franseria discolor) </seg>
            <seg id="p067">NEBRASKA WEEDS 67 F"l«. 3O. White Weed. Showing top of plant, need, and running root. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 NEBRASKA WEEDS viduals from the old roots will become greater until no top growth appears. In small areas the same general principles may be used with profit. Any farmer will find that the use of a hoe in the corn row, permitting no individuals to remain to feed underground parts will fully repay the extra labor by elimination of the pest and added crop returns, but persistent vigilance is necessary after the work is started. This should preferably not begin until about blooming time as this gives the plant time to use up the stored food in producing this first growth. No. 31 COCKLEBUR Other local names — Clotbur and Sheepbur. This annual is common throughout the State in barnyards, road - sides, waste places and especially in cultivated crops. In the corn rows it finds a very favorable place to produce a hardy growth. The plant is large, rough, branched; from two or four feet in height and has thick coarse stems, with distinct brown spots. The leaves alr.o are rough and large, shading considerable soil, thus making more room for its own growth. There are both sterile and fertile heads. The fertile ones are clustered in the angle made by the union of stem and leaf, while the sterile ones are clusters at the ends of branches and are inconspicuous and short lived. The burs which develop are about an inch long, with hooked, coarse spines, cover - ing them and two heavier hooks at the end. The burs containing the Feeds frequently become attached to the tails of horses and cattle and are scattered over the farm and country as the animals move about. Sometimes the tails become so matted with burs that cutting them out is necessary. By this means the seeds are scattered. Each bur contains two seeds and it is understood that one germinates one year and the other the next so that precautions in eradication must be taken for two years at least. Means of Eradication — Plants may be destroyed by cultivation ■when very young but if permitted to become half grown, should be pulled in order to prevent seed being produced from buds which are plentiful when the plant is only cut. In case the burs have matured the weds should be cut and burned. (Xanthium commune) </seg>
            <seg id="p069">NEBRASKA WEEDS 69 v Pig. 31. Cocklebur. Top of plant; root; and bur. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 32 SUNFLOWER (Helianthus annuus) These annual plants are typically prairie plants and abound throughout Nebraska in cultivated fields, pastures, fence rows, road - sides and waste places. It averages three to six feet in height but may be much shorter than that as plants mature in grain fields after harvest, often causing the stubble to appear a yellow mass of color. Under conditions of plenty of moisture and sunshine the plant also produces an enormous growth, reaching twelve to fourten feet in height. The plant is stout, rough and coarse. Leaves are broad, oval, three-ribbed, and pointed, from six to fourteen inches in length and are rough. Heads are conspicuous with bright yellow rays. Seeds are oval, comparatively smooth, either gray or gray and white with longitudinal stripes. Means of Eradication — The easiest means of extermination is cultivation, which destroys the young plants or by frequent and close cutting during the growing season in order to starve the roots and prevent seed from maturing. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">NEBRASKA WEEDS 71 Fig;. 32. Sunflower. Showing top of plant and seed, </seg>
            <seg id="p072">NEBRASKA WEEDS 72 No. 33 BURDOCK This biennial inhabits roadsides and waste places. The first year's growth produces a deep thick tap root, well stored with nutri - tion and large heart-shaped leaves in rosette formation, resembling very much the common garden rhubarb. The plant takes so much nutrition from the soil and shades other plants so much that few survive within some distance of it. For this reason it has been credited with producing a poison which affected the soil. This idea is now considered to be erroneous. The second year flowers and seeds are produced from an enormous plant, four to eight feet tall, stout, rough, hairy and with spreading branches. The flowers are tubular and delicate, inconspicuous, pink in color. Due to the much more showy purple anthers most persons come to the conclusion that the blossoms are purple. The heads, containing the seeds, are covered with scales ending in sharp hooks which constitute a bur. The seeds are dull brown, slightly flattened, oblong, three-angled and spotted zig-zig with black and white markings. The root of the plant is dried and used for medicinal purposes. Means of Eradication — The size of the plant makes it so con - spicuous that it would seem it could never reach its second year of growth on any well cared for land. Young plants are killed by hoe - ing or pulling. After the plant has made considerable growth spud - ding or continual cutting close to the ground is necessary as the large root keeps new leaves appearing for considerable time. (Arctium lappa) </seg>
            <seg id="p073">NEBRASKA WEEDS 73 Flgr. 33. Burdock. Top of plant leaf, and seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 34 BULL THISTLE (Cirsium lanceolatum) Other local names— Roadside Thistle, Blue Thistle and Plume Thistle. This is a large, coarse biennial plant which often gives undue alarm, bue to its being mistaken for Canada Thistle. It is, however, much larger and is propagated only by seeds. The first year a tap root is stored with food by a crown of leaves six to eight inches long. Bach of its lobes is tipped with a spine, the plant seldom be - coming over a foot in height. The second year, however, it becomes three to five feet tall and produces heads, white and purple in color with prickly bracts close to the heads. Means of Eradication — As this plant must remain undisturbed for two years in order to mature seeds, it may be eradicated by deep spudding or continual hoeing to keep it cut below the ground so that it will not continue to store food in the roots. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">NEBRASKA WEEDS 75 Vim- 84. Hull Thistle. Showing tiip of plant ; leai", and root </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 NEBRASKA WEEDS No. 35 CANADA THISTLE (Cirsium arvense) Other local names — Cursed Thistle, Creeping Thistle, Hard Thistle, and Small Flowered Thistle. Throughout the northern half of the United States' Canada Thistle is by far the worst pest among weeds that farmers have to cope with. Twenty-eight states have passed laws regarding sale of seed containing this weed seed and also the mowing of the weed to prevent its being scattered by its seeds. Nebraska has a special "Canada Thistle Law" requiring the cutting of such weeds often enough to prevent seeding and the seed law makes it an offense with a penalty to sell agricultural seed containing more than one Canada Thistle seed in five grams of such seed and if it contains any of the seed of Canada Thistle their presence must be indicated on the label. Canada Thistle is not so well adapted to climatic condklejis in Nebraska as in States farther north and where moisture is a little more abundant. It is found, however, throughout the eastern part of the State, but it is probable that the seed is very, very seldom matured as cool dry weather at blooming time is necessary. Albert A. Hansen, of the U. S. Department of Agriculture, in his excellent bulletin (Farmers' Bulletin No. 1002) states that "If the southern boundary of Michigan were continued as a line east and west, it would constitute approximately the boundary, south of which, viable seed is rarely found." The distinguishing and obnoxious character - istic of this perennial is, however, its deep seated, food-filled, hori - zontal, creeping root stalks by which the size of patches of Canada Thistle continually grow. The plant is one to three feet high, has a slender woody stem with very few spines, differing in this respect from other thistles which are often mistaken for the Canada ' specie. The leaves are very spiny, clasp the stem and are very irregular and wavy of mar - gin, green in color on both sides. The heads are borne on smooth flower stalks, usually free from spines, which is different from Bull Thistle and others similar in appearance. Heads are rose purple and small, about a half inch in diameter. The bracts composing the head are also spineless. Many of the heads are sterile as the plants are dioecious, that is the stamen or male and the pistillate or female, flowers are born on separate plants. Often entire patches will be found that bear only sterile flowers, showing that all propagation has taken place through the spread of root stalks. The brown seed is nearly cylindrical with a conical point in the center of the top. It is 1 prevalent in clovers, especially alsike clover, timothy and other grass seeds. Plants growing either from seed or budding from rootstalks at first make a low rosette growth which tends to store food for the </seg>
            <seg id="p077">NEBRASKA WEEDS 77 PI». 35. Canada Thirtle. Showing top of plant; underground root system, froi which new planta are produced; and seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 NEBRASKA WEEDS growth of stalk and flowers. Both periods of growth may take place In one season if it obtains an early start but when the rosette growth is later during the season the growth of flowering stalks usually takes place early in the second season and continues through - out the succeeding seasons. Means of Eradication — As Canada Thistle is a deep rooted per - ennial, a method of starving the food-filled rootstalks must be used. This means "eternal vigilance" through two growing seasons. The first year the ground should be plowed during June or the first of July, then disked and harrowed in order to expose as many roots to the sun as possible. Care should be taken not to carry the roots on machinery into land that is not already infested. During the re - mainder of the season, frequent use of a cultivator with knives or broad teeth that will cut the plant off just below the surface is necessary. Mr. Hansen, in Farmers' Bulletin No. 1002, states that the weather is the most important factor, as eradication is so much easier during dry weather. "The operation of plowing, harrowing and cultivating directed against the Thistle should never be under - taken when the land is wet." During the second season cultivation should be continued to keep the food assimilating green parts of the plant cut off, in order to starve the root stalks. Mr. Hansen gives instances' where eradication was complete when corn was planted the second season, thoroughly cultivated and then the patches gone over with a hoe to insure the destruction of every plant throughout the season. "The intervals between which hard work was 1 necessary became longer and longer as the season advanced." This method has proven successful in one season only when wet weather did not interfere. Small areas are sometimes smothered by placing building paper well weighted with earth or straw over them, or by the use of such poisonous chemicals as carbolic acid or arsenite of soda. These will however, kill all vegetation and care must be taken that likestock cannot graze in such locations 1 . Care should be given to plant on roadsides as well as in fields as any plants permitted to grow will find their way into the cultivated soil which they ap - parently prefer. No. 36 DANDELION (Taraxacum officinale) The dandelion is so familiar to most persons that a description seems unnecessary. It is a perennial plant which has found its way into cultivated soil the world over. It is most prevalent in lawns, meadows, alfalfa fields and waste places that have been cultivated previously but are not under immediate tillage. The rosettes of leaves are close to the ground making it difficult to cut with a </seg>
            <seg id="p079">NEBRASKA WEEDS 79 t Fig. 38. Dandelion. Entire plant. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 NEBRASKA WEEDS mowing machine and unaffected by ordinary trampling. Dry weather does not harm it as the fleshy roots reach deep into the earth, storing up food for the early spring blooming and seeding. Pro - fessor B. O. Longyear, Colorado Experiment Station, Fort Collins, has conducted an experiment in which he cut the root of a dande - lion into sixteen one-inch sections; placed them in soil under favor - able condition and produced sixteen healthy plants. The heads of the plant also remain close to the ground until a bright day when they raise their bright yellow heads which coil back close to the ground while seed are maturing. When seeds are ripe the stalk again raises the head up where the breezes may catch the seeds. each with its parachute-like projection of fine, white hairs' and bear them away to produce more plants; often to seed the neigh - bor's lawns. The seeds are brown, oblong, rigid and tipped with slender tubercules and are found in lawn grass mixtures and blue grass seed. Many tons of roots are used for medicinal purposes each year and the young plants are often used for greens, but live stock avoid the plant due to its bitterness. Means of Eradication — It is highly probable that there have been more attempts to find a method of controlling the dandelion than any other weed. The method of cutting below the crown to starve the roots and do away with the food assimilating leaves is effective and prevents the plants maturing seed if sufficient persistence is used. The pest grows so close to the ground that a new crown often supplies the roots 1 with food before the plant is observed. This is, however, the most prevalent and effective method for ordinary use. In lawns and meadows', thickly infested, sprays of various kinds have been In prevalent use, but like spudding, the process must be persistently repeated until the root is impoverished so that it cannot send out new leaves. A summary of Professor Longyear's experiment in Colorado indicates that one and one-fourth pounds of iron sulfate to a gallon of water, applied in the late summer and autumn until frost, treats the young plant of the year's seeding as well as the older ones and weak - ens the plants so much that they do not survive the winter. Better results are secured by the use of a fine force spray. The ordinary spray-pump used for disinfecting chicken houses has been found to give satisfactory results. Plants in adjoining lots and roadsides must also be given atten - tion as the wind-carried seed readily re-infest all soil not thoroughly occupied by other vegetation. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">Duration of life and means of propagation. Co1o j ° nd PIa prod°uctrr h: Agricultural Name seed found in. size jured. 1. Witch g r a s s Annual ; props- Gretn, 1 to 2 Fields and waste (Panicum Capil-i gated by seeds, ft.; seeds places. C 1 o v e rs, lawn grass and other grasses. lare). green. 2. Barnyard grass Annual ; propa- Plant 2 (Echinoihloa crus- gated by seeds, ft. tall; to 4 Roadsides, gar - green duns, corn and pur- small gnain Grasses, clovers, and alfalfa. galli). to deJp fields 3. Green f o x ta i 1 Annual; propa- Green. 1 to 3 All soils, in all (Setarin viridis). gated by seeds, ft. tall. crops. Millets. clovers, alfalfa, cereals. 4. Wild oats (Avena Annual ; propa- Green. fatua). g»ted by seeds, ft. tall 2 to 4 All soils. small Flax, all cereals, especially oats and barley. g»ted by seeds, ft. tall grains, flax and other large seeded grasses. 5. Quack jrass Perennial ; prop- Urec n. 1 to 3 All rich soils. Small grain, larger seeded grasses, flspe - cially b r o m e grass. (Agropyron rep aaated by seeds ft. tall. field. roadside, ens). land creeping and wa * t e and creeping and wa ft t footstalk. places 6. Blue joint g'. ass, perennial ; prop- Green. 1 to 3 Felds. roadsides (Agropyion smi- , if r n ted by seeds ft. tall. and waste Clover, alfalfa &amp; brome grass. 7. Wild b a r I e y -winter annual or Green, 1 to 2 Alkali soils, culti- Cereals and grasses. (Hordeum jubab- biennial; jirop- ft. tall. vatc-d fields and turn). ! agated by seeds. ! waste places. 8. Nodding wild rye Perennial ; prop- ; Green. 2 to 4 Roadsides, fields, (Elymus canaden- agate-d by seeds, ft. tall. I and meadows. S'S) . Brome grass and other coarse grasses. 9. Curled dock ( Ru- Perennial ; prop- Greenish yel- Meadows. p a s - mex crisjjus). I agated by seeds, low, 2 to 4 tures, barnyards Clovers, alfalfa and grasses. ft. tall. land waste places. 10. Red sorrel 'Ru-; Perennial; prop- Y e 1 1 o w i 8 h! Cultivated fields, mex acetosel'.a ) . ] agated by seedi green, 6 to 18 meadows, pas- All clovers, espe - cially alsike, red and white; also grasses. and rootstalks. in. tall. tures and road- sides, prefers poor soil. II. Wild buckwheat! Annual; propa- Gree n v i n e, Almost all culti - (Popyganum con-! gated by seeds. ciimbing over vated crops. Clovers, alfalfa, cereals. volvulus) . and stran- roadsides, waste gling other place's, climbing growth. | on fences. Annual ; propa- Light green. Cultivated fields, gated by Beeds. covered: yards and gar- 12. Lamb's quarter ( Chenopodium at* bum) . Alfalfa, clovers and grass seed. mealy sub- dens. stance, gives silvery a p - pearance ; 2 to 4 ft. tall. 13. Salt bush (Atri plex hastata ) . Annual; propa-;L i g h t green Saline soil, culti - gated by seeds. with red! vated fields. Alfalfa, occasion - ally in red clover. stripes, barnyards, road- s p r e a ding sides and waste forms turn- places. ble weed. pie. thii). and creeping j plates rootstalk. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">Duration of life and moans of propagation. Agricultural ezed found in. Name size jured. 14. Russian t h i 8 t le Annual; propa- Green; young A\ll cultivated (Salsoli tragus). gated by seeds. plants feath- ground, grain Alfalfa, clovers and ceerals. ery ; spread- 'stubble, r o » i ■ ing, f o r m Si sides and waste tumble weed, places. 15. Rough pigweed Annual ; propa- Green, coarse, c u 1 t ivated (Amaranthus re- gated by seeds. 2 to 9 ft. tall, ground, corn Alfalfa, clovers, grasses and cereals. troflexus) . fields, fence rows. 16. Night ■ flowering Annual and win-JGreen; flower» (InvRdcB crops o f Catchfly (Silene ter annual; pto- white &amp; pink, a ]f a lfa clover noctiflora). pagated by seeds.! 1 to 3 ft. tall. sma ll 'grain and All clovers and alfalfa. meadows. ! I 17.Penny cres»|Annual and win-Green; nowers&gt;c u ] tivate( } soj], (Thlaspi arvense). ter annual; pro-, white; 6 to 28 roadsides, mead- Clovers, alfalfa, and grasses. pagated by seeds.' in. tall. 0WS| gra j' n ne i,j 6 18. False flax (Thla- Annual and win- Bluish grpen;, Inva( ] es small spi arven?e). ter annual; pro-! rosette leaves.J ?ra in rrops. pagated by seeds.; fleshy; 16 to roa dsides and Alfalfa, flax. clovers and cereals. 36 in. tall, j waste p i aces 19. Wild mustard Annual ; propa- Green ; flcnr&lt;irs Cultivated fields. (Brassica arven- gated by seeds^ yellow; 1 to 3 roa dsides and Cereals, flax and red clover. se). I ft - to H- I waste places. 20. Fivefinger ( P o - Vnnual and bien- Greenish yel- |R oa dsides. mead- Clovers, timothy, bluegrass and other grasses. tentilla monspel- nial; propagated low; flowers ows g ra 'i n fields iensis). by seeds. I yellow; 1 to 3 and was t e places. yellow; 1 to 3 and waste p i ace s. 21. Y e M o w trofoil Annual ; pTopa-iGreen ; usual\y'T jawnSi roadside, (Medicago lupul- gated by seeds. prostrate. i mea dows, alfalfa, in:i). I waste places. Alfalfa, alsike &amp; white clover. waste places. 22. Small - flowered morning glory (Convolvulus ar- vonsis) . 23. Dodder (Cuscnta spp.). Perennial ; propa-' gated by seeds. I Annual ; propa- gated by seeds. !Dark green; Corn fi e ia Si grain; Ce r e a 1 s, but flowers pink fl c i&lt;i Si meadows, rarely occurs. ot white; a waste places, vine twining on other plants. Yellow ; p ar asite on alfal-j Alfalfa, flax and strands twine f a r ed clover &amp; clovers, about other fl ax plants. 24. Buffalo bur ( So- la num rostra turn). Annual ; propa- gated by seeds. Green; flowers prairies, b a r n - Millets, alfalfa, yellow; 1 to yards, cultivated cereals &amp; clovers. 2V, ft. high. g oil and wa8te places. Green, broad Yards, lawns, al- Alsike clover, red ridged leaves. f a lfa fields, and clover, alfalfa, waste places. timothy, blue- grass. Low gr e e n Meadows, alfalfa Clovers, alfalfa, plant. &amp; clover fields. and grass seed. 25. Common plan- tain (Plantago major). Perennial ; propa- gated by seeds. 28. Buckhorn plan- tain. Perennial ; propa- gated by seeds. 27. Gumweed (Grin- delia squarrosa). 28. Ragweed ( A m b: usia artemisii- foU«). Biennial or per- ennial ; propa- gated by seeds. I Annual ; propa- gated by seod-. Green ; flowers Prairies, mead- Alfalfa, occa- yellow and ow8 _ grain fields, g i o n a 1 1 y in sticky; 1 to 2 roadsides and clovers. ft. tall. barnyards. On en ; feath- Cultivated soil. Cereals, clovers, e r y - 1 i k e oadsides, mead- and alfalfa. leaves; 1 to 5 . w B and waste ft. tall. places. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Duration of life and means of propagation Place of growth ; products in - jured Color and size Agricultural Name seed found in 29. Greater ragweed 'Annual ; propa- Grtvn ; 3 to 5 Roadsides, fields, (Ambrosia). &lt; gated by seeds. lange parted: and waste Cereals, especially wheat and oats. leaves; 4 toi places 12 ft. tall. 30. W h i t e wee d Perennial ; propa- (Franseria die- agated by seeds G r e e n is h Prairie; small color). and creeping white; 10 to grain, corn and Cereals, rarely occurs. rontstiilks. 20 in. tall. I alfalfa fields, and waste places. Green, rough, coarse; 3 to 4 Cultivated crops, ft. tall. I barnyards, road- 31. Cocklebur (Sam- Annual ; propa thium commune). &lt; gated by seeds. Barely occurs. sides. 32. Sunflower (Heli- Annual ; propa - anthus annuus). i gated by seeds. Rough, coarse, |G rain stubble, green; flow- roadsides, fields, ers yellow; 4 and waste places, to 9 ft. tall. ! Alfalfa, clovers, and cereals. 33. Burdock (Arcti- Biennial; propa Roadsides, waste Cereals, rarely occurs. um lappa) gated by seeds. Green, rough, ground and and coarse; 1 meadows. to 9 ft. tall 34. Bull thistle (cir- Biennial; propa s i u m lanceolat- gatod by seeds, um). Leaves green Roadsides, fence above, white rows, pastures, beneath ; 2 to meadows and 5 ft. tall. waste places. Alfalfa, clovers ; occasionally in cereals. 35. Canada t h i 8 1 1 e Perennial ; propa Green; flowers Cutiva ted fields, small, purple; meadows and 1 to 3 ft. tall, waste places. Timothy, all clovers, e sp e - cially a 1 s i k e clover. (Cirsium arvense).| gated by creep ing rootstalks. 36. Dandelion ( T a -iPerennial; propa raxacum officina- gated by seeds, le). Light green, L awns, alfalfa low; grows j fields, meadows, close to| and waste places. Lawngrass seed. ground </seg>
            <seg id="p084"/>
            <seg id="p085">INDEX Description Figure Pa Be P«R» 1. Witch grass 8 2. Barnyard grass 10 11 3. Green foxtail 12 13 4. Wild oats 14 15 5. Quack grass 16 17 6. Blue joint grass 18 19 Wild barley 20 21 8. Nodding wild rye 22 23 9. Curled dock 24 25 10. Red sorrel 26 27 11. Wild buckwheat 28 29 12. Lamb's quarter 30 31 13. Salt bush 32 33 14. Russian thistle 34 35 15. Rough pig weed 36 37 16. Night-flowering catchfly 38 39 17. Penny cress 40 41 18. False flax 42 43 19. Wild mustard 44 45 20. Five finger 46 47 21. Yellow trefoil 48 49 22. Small flowered morning glory 50 51 23. Dodder 52 53 24. Buffalo bur 54 55 25. Common plantain 56 57 26. Buckhorn plantain 58 59 27. Gum weed 60 61 28. Ragweed 62 63 29. Greater ragweed 64 65 30. White weed 66 67 31 Cockle-bur 68 69 32. Sunflower 70 71 33. Burdock « 72 73 34. Bull thistle 74 75 35. Canada thistle 76 77 36. Dandelion 78 79 Summary 81 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>