<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS 1920-1930</title>
               <date value="1931-03">1931-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 255 March, 1931 NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS 1920-1930 i :■'-.-• ■ ■ ■ • An Official Drawbar Test Under Way at the University of Nebraska THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">BOARD OF TRACTOR TEST ENGINEERS E. E. Brackctt, C. W. Smith, E. B. Lewis ENGINEER IN CHARGE OF TESTS Carlton L. Zink ASSISTANT- IN TRACTOR TESTS C. F. Adams </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS With the close of the testing season of 1930 came the end of the eleventh year of tractor testing at the University of Nebraska. The number of complete tests conducted and re - ported each year was as follows: 1920 1921. 1922 1923 1924 1925 1926 1927 1928 1929 1930 Total 05 15 5 12 10 8 12 16 7 16 10 176 This bulletin summarizes the results of 64 of these tests and includes data on all tractors reported by their manufac - turers as on the market January 1, 1931. If a tractor has been tested but is not listed in this bulletin, the reader may safely assume that its manufacture has been discontinued. All tractors tested are certified by their manufacturer as being stock-model machines, conforming to specifications filed with the application for test. No special or high-test fuels are used. All results shown in reports are those actually attained in tests and are without corrections or allowances for friction, temperature, altitude, etc. These results are accomplished with the tractor in charge of skilled operators employed by the University. Beginning with 1928 the "one carburetor setting" was adopted and all results shown on reports of tests made in 1928, 1929, and 1930 were attained with the carburetor ad - justment remaining unchanged throughout all parts of the complete test. A three-page report of each test is issued soon after the test is completed, and this bulletin is compiled from these reports and from the specifications filed with the application for test. Copies of the original three-page reports are avail - able at 5 cents per report (on one tractor) from the Depart - ment of Agricultural Engineering, College of Agriculture, Lincoln, Nebraska. Those desiring future reports without delay, who remit $1.00, will receive for one year without further requests or other cost one copy of all reports or bulletins issued, referring to tractor tests; each one will be mailed as soon as possible after its release. A mimeographed pamphlet containing the full text of the Nebraska tractor law, the procedure followed in the test, and the A. S. A. E. and S. A. E. rating code is also available at 10 cents per copy. SUMMARY OF RESULTS This summary wilj be found on the large folded sheet on the inside of the front cover page. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 SUMMARY OF SPECIFICATIONS AND COMMENTS pe?hll d r SPeedS: L ° W ' a25 miles P" "&lt;»»■• Meh, 2.75 miles Comments: Replaced carburetor handle: O°p"e r n W^ r 1 v f iwrs ' "^ =&gt;»'* :«=™tr.ctin g Bated Speed: 2.50 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Nebraska Tractor Tests Comments : Line drive attachment was used. Operator had reasonably good control of tractor with 4 lines. Replaced fan belt, changed 2 spark plugs. Replaced governor springs, changed ignition timing, ground valves. Test No. 43. AVERY 25-50. Avery Company, Peoria, Illinois. July 26 to 30, 192.0. K-W "HK" magneto. Kingston "Dual" carburetor. Ben - nett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valye-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 22", width 8Vk", rated speed 700 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers. Open gear drive, expand - ing shoe clutch, own make. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour ; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: Clutch adjusted twice. New governor spring put in to replace old one which was too weak. In the test the cab needed additional bracing to hold it rigidly to the engine frame. Test No. 44. AVERY 45-65. Avery Company, Peoria, Illinois. July 26 to August 3, 1920. K-W "HK" magneto. Kingston "Dual" carburetor. Ben - nett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valye-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 26", width 10", rated speed 600 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, open gear drive, own make expanding shoe clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour. Comments: The rating of this tractor was changed from 40-80 to 45-65. Test No. 70. MINNEAPOLIS 17-30. Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. March 28 to April 2, 1921. Dixie "46". magneto. Kingston "E" 1%" carburetor. Bennett I 1 /*" dry centrifugal air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. * Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft crosswise, Detroit mechanical lubricator. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; own make disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.06 miles per hour ; high, 2.70 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 Comments: Fan belt shortened. Clutch and valve roda adjusted. Light weight on front wheels when drawbar load is heavy, interfering with steering. Test No. 73. WETMORE 12-25. H. A. Wetmore, Sioux City, Iowa. April 6 to 12, 1921. Splitdorf Aero magneto. Schebler "ATX47" 1%" carbu - retor. iNo air cleaner. Weidely fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6%", rated speed 1088 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, Fuller disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3»/&gt; miles per hour ; high, 5.9 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Hand operation of throttle was necessary to control engine speed within safe limits of loads three-fourths rating and under, when carbu - retor was set for best fuel economy. Heavy grade oil was found necessary for the engine. Test No. 104. BEST "S30" 25-30. C. L. Best Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. September 15 to 22, 1924. American Bosch "ZR4" magneto. ' Stromberg "MP3" 1 1 -." carburetor. Pomona oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make centrifugal type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 7", rated speed 850 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers; multiple dry disc clutch; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Lo^y, 1.75 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.63 miles per hour; high, 3.63 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 105. BEST "A60" 50-60. C. L. Best Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. September 15 to 29 1924. j American Bosch "ZR4Edl8" magneto. Stromberg "M4" Special 1%" carburetor. Pomona oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make centrifugal . type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 10", rated speed 650 R.P.M. Chassis : Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers ; multiple dry disc clutch; enclosed gear drive: Rated Speeds : Low, 1% miles per hour ; intermediate, 2% miles per hour; high, 3% miles per hour. Comment : At the end of the test the vacuum tank leaked </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Tractor Tests at the bottom seam. Exhaust valve on No. 1 cylinder would not hold compression. Test No. 110. CASE 25-45. J. I. Case Threshing Ma - chine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. October 28 to November 9, 1924. : Bosch "ZR4" magneto. Kingston "L" 2" carburetor. Own make water type air cleaner. Own fly-ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16i/&gt;", width 8i/&gt;" rated speed 850 R.P.M. - Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers ; enclosed gear drive ; ex - panding shoe type clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 3.2 miles per hour. . Comments: During the rated drawbar test the right cyl - inder head gasket burned out and both gaskets were then re - placed. Test No. 117. McCORMICK-DEERING "FARMALL." International Harvester Company of America, Chicago, Illi - nois. September 14 to 19, 1925. Splitdorf "Aero" 937950 magneto. Ensign "3DA600F" 1" carburetor. Pomona Model 118 oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diam - eter 14", width 6i/ 2 ", rated speed 696 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive* multiple dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3 miles per hour; high, 4 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. . Test No 118. THE MINNEAPOLIS TYPE B 17-30. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Min - nesota. October 21 to November 12, 1925. American Bosch "ED2ITC" magneto. Wheeler-Schebler A •■' li/ 2 " carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Detroit lubri - cator. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - ooi e^ £&amp; pulley: Diameter IZW', width 71/2", rated speed o&lt;so xv.ir.JVl. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive; disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.23 miles per hour; high, 2.84 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 Comment: It was necessary to drill 8 holes before the left extension rim could be attached. After the limbering-up run and before any official data were taken the engine head was removed, the carbon cleaned out, and all valves ground. Dur - ing the limbering-up run and the. rated drawbar test, the fuel line clogged up, requiring stops for cleaning out. Test No. 119. CLETRAC "K" 15-25. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 22 to May 5, 1926. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Tillotson "R2" carburetor. Pomona oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Belt pulley : Diameter 12", width 6", rated speed 860 R.P.M. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Chassis: Track-layer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, single disc clutch. . Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 4.50 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comments : During the half load brake test the oil pressure line sprung a leak. During the rated and low gear maximum drawbar tests the gear shift lever had to be fastened in place in order to keep the gears in mesh. The advertised miles per hour as given should be corrected to: Low, 2.13 miles per hour; high, 4.23 miles per hour; reverse, 1.66 miles per hour at 1375 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 120. CLETRAC "K" 15-25. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 30 to May 5, 1926. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Tillotson "R2" carburetor. Pomona oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 12", width 6", rated speed 860 R.P.M. Chassis: Track-layer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, single disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 4.50 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comments : During the rated and low gear maximum draw - bar tests the gear shift lever had to be fastened in place in order to keep the gears in mesh. The advertised miles per hour as given should be corrected to: Low, 2.13 miles per hour ; high, 4.23 miles per hour ; reverse, 1.66 miles per hour at 1375 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 121. TWIN CITY "TY" 17-28. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machic-v Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 17 to 21, 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Nebraska Tractor Tests American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Bennett dry cen - trifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Holly "257" carburetor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cyl - inder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6", rated speed 650 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, disc clutch, 6" extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 2.9 miles per hour; reverse, 1.75 miles per hour. Comments: During the drawbar tests it was necessary to place two small bolts in the gear shift lock to keep gears in mesh. It was necessary to adjust the governor several times on drawbar test to maintain proper engine speed. Test No. 122. TWIN CITY "AT" 27-44. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 20 to 27, 1926. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Wheeler-Schebler "A" carburetor. Donaldson Duplex oiled fibre type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. . . Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cyl - inder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 21", width %%", rated speed 466 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, twin disc clutch, 7" extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 2.9 miles per hour ; reverse, 1.87 miles per hour. Comments : During both the rated load brake test and the rated load drawbar test the fan belt tension had to be read - justed. Test No. 126. HUBER 20-40. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. September 7 to 16, 1926. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L3" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly - ball type governor. • Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter l&amp;A", width 8", rated speed 666 R.T.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Twin disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.47 miles per hour; high, 3.48 miles per hour; reverse, 1.94 miles per hour. Comments : During the rated brake test the fan belt broke and was replaced with a new belt. Test No. 128. HART-PARR 18-36. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. October 18 to 25, 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 Robert Bosch "ZU42" magneto. Stromberg "MB3" carbu - retor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley:. Diameter 14", width 9", rated speed 800 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Dry plate clutch. Seven-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.00 miles per hour; high, 3.00 miles per hour; reverse, 2.5 miles per hour. Comments : Before the half load brake test was . run the spark gap in the spark plugs was adjusted to 0.020" gap. During the maximum drawbar test one spark plug was re - placed. Two small screws were lost out of the carburetor air connection during the test. The crankshaft speed of the rated load and first maximum drawbar tests was low due to an error in calculation made by observer during test which was not discovered until too late for correction". Test No. 129. HART-PARR 12-24. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. October 18 to 28, 1926. Robert Bosch "ZU42" magneto. Stromberg "MB3": carbu - retor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own. fly - ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine : Horizontal, valve-:in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8", rated speed 850 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, dry plate clutch. Six-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.66 miles per hour; high, 3.33 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comment: During the varying load brake test both spark plugs were replaced with new spark plugs ; one had a cracked porcelain and the other a defective gasket. During the low gear maximum drawbar tests the gears slipped out. of mesh. It was necessary to improvise a method of holding gear shift lever in place. The low gear train of gears was burred slightly due to the gears slipping out of mesh. Test No. 134. WALLIS 20-30. J. I. Case Plow Works, Racine, Wisconsin. April 29 to May 10, 1927. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Kingston "L3" car - buretor. Wallis dry "cloth screen type" air cleaner. Picker - ing fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18i/&gt;", width 7", rated speed 476 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch dry plate with disc. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska Tractor Tests Rated Speeds: Low, 2.75 miles per hour; high, 3.331/3 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments : The rate of travel of this tractor is : Low, 2.88 miles per hour; high, 3.49 miles per hour; reverse, 2.88 miles per hour. The above speeds are calculated at the rim of the drive wheels and at 1050 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 135. HUBER SUPER FOUR 40-62. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. May 17 to June 24, 1927. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "A" carburetor. Po - mona oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly-ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15 1 /'", width 9%", rated speed 733 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.00 to 2.50 miles per hour; high, 3.00 to 3.50 miles per hour; reverse, 1.75 to 2.25 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated drawbar test and after ap - proximately 25 hours running, ignition trouble developed due to spark plugs. Two of the plugs were replaced with new ones of the same make but did not remedy the trouble. The Stitt spark plugs, which were standard equipment, were then replaced with A-C plugs and no further ignition trouble was experienced. The left spindle arm sheared off causing the front axle to bend somewhat; the axle and spindle arm were replaced with new parts; The packing gland nuts on the water pump were tightened several times during the test. The flexible oil tube leading to the clutch throw-out collar was leaking at the end of the test. Test No. 136. SHAW MODEL "T25." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7 to 22, 1927. Own make magneto. Tillotson "MS6A" carburetor. No air cleaner. No governor. Engine: Vertical, F-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 5i/&gt;", width li/v", rated speed 275 R.P.M. Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open chain and gear drive, clutch own make expanding band. Rated Speeds : Low, 0.50 to 1.50 miles per hour ; high, 1.25 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: During the brake tests the following repairs and adjustments were made: The exhaust valve stem was found to be sticking. It was removed, polished and the valve ground. The exhaust valve push rod was adjusted to give </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 more clearance and the guide reamed out. The inlet valve spring was found to be somewhat weaker than a standard spring. The inlet valve spring and cage were replaced with a new assembly. Before the official brake tests were run both piston rings stuck in their grooves. The lower ring was broken in removing and was replaced with a. new ring; both rings were given slightly more end clearance than they had previously. During the drawbar tests the following repairs and adjustments were made: The caster wheel arm was broken and replaced with a new one. The clutch shift lever broke and was repaired. The fuel line broke off at the carbu - retor and was repaired. During the limber-up run a stop clip on the cultivator beam control broke. In the advertising literature submitted with the specifica - tions for test of this tractor we find the following claims which are not substantiated by the results of this test : Exhibit "B" page 15 ENGINE SPECIFICATIONS, "POWER RATED CONSERVATIVELY AT 1 H. P. On tests develops about 1V 2 horse power." Exhibit "B" page 8, "Figure 18 showing SHAW DU ALL Model T25 running in low gear pulling a road drag with scales indicating 450 pounds direct pull on the drawbar, which is sufficient to pull a ton load on a cart or light wagon." Test No. 137. SHAW MODEL "T45." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7 to 23, 1927. Own make magneto. Tillotson "MS7A" carburetor. No air cleaner. Own make pneumatic type governor. Engine: Vertical, air cooled, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 3", width 2i//\ operates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open gear and chain drive, clutch own make expanding band: Rated Speeds: Low, 1.00 mile per hour; high, 1.43 miles per hour. . Comments: In the advertising literature submitted with the specifications for test of this tractor we find the following claims which are not substantiated by the results of this test: Exhibit "B" "T45": "DRAWBAR PULL 650 lbs. On low gear, this pulls a IV2 ton load on a light cart or wagon." Test No. 138. CONTINENTAL CULTOR No. 32. Con - tinental Cultor Company, Springfield, Ohio. August 6 to 17 1927. Ford Model "T" ignition system. Holley "Ford" carbu - retor. No air cleaner. No governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head mounted crankshaft lengthwise. No belt pulley. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Nebraska Tractor Tests Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open chain final drive, multiple disc clutch. Rated Speed: 3.00 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated drawbar test the left main drive chain broke. The broken link was replaced with a new link. During the same test two teeth were broken on the main drive sprocket; the test was completed without repair. Test No. 139. MONARCH 10 TON MODEL F. Monarch Tractors Corporation, Springfield, Illinois. August 15 to 26, 1927. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Zenith "L7T" car - buretor. United 1%" twin, dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Le Roi, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-ih-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. No belt pulley. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, partly enclosed final drive, enclosed gear transmission, chain and sprocket final drive. Clutch own make disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.5 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.6 miles per hour; high, 3.3 miles per hour; reverse, 2.5 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 140. HART-PARR 28-50. Hart-Parr Com - pany] Charles City, Iowa. August 17 to 31, 1927. Robert Bosch "ZU4" magneto. Schebler "D" carburetor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly - ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 9", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make dry plate. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 3.25 miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments : After all tests were completed and during the final inspection number 4 cylinder was found to have little or no compression. The piston was removed and the top ring was found to be stuck in its groove, also a small hole through the wall of the piston in the top groove at the lap of the ring. The ring was released and the hole plugged up. The water passage between the cylinder head and engine block on this tractor had been enlarged to permit freer circula - tion. It is understood that this change is to be made standard on all tractors of this model. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 ; Test No. 141. OIL PULL 20-30. MODEL "W." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. September 15 to £ x.) JL J dt i • ... American Bosch "DU4/2Ed26" magneto. Own make car - buretor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7&gt;/«", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make double disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.7 miles per hour. Comments: After the limber-up run and before the official belt tests were made, the lubricator could not be regulated properly. It was disassembled and cleaned out thoroughly. During the drawbar tests the compression on number 1 cyl - inder was found to be somewhat less than number 2 cylinder and there was considerable leakage by the rings on the com - pression stroke. The piston on number 1 cylinder was re - moved, the carbon cleaned out from around the rings and all valves ground. Both spark plugs were replaced with new plugs; the porcelains were found to be defective. The fuel valve and water valve required frequent adjustment during the drawbar tests. Test No. 142. McCORMICK-DEERING 10-20. Inter - national Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. October 3 to 8, 1927. Own make "E4A" magneto. Ensign "R" carburetor Pomona "Vortox" Model 118 oil spray type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 151/.", width 7" rated speed 661 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make multiple dry disc. Rated Speeds : Low, 2 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3 miles per hour ; high, 4 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 143. OIL PULL 25-40. MODEL "X." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 6 to 13, American Bosch "DU4/2Ed26" magneto. Own make car - buretor. Own make fly-ball type governor. Donaldson drv centrifugal type air cleaner. Manzel lubricator. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">:;■■... Nebraska Tractor Tests Engine : Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt bulley: Diameter 18%", width 8i/ 2 ", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.3 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.8 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 144. ROCK ISLAND 18-35. Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. October 12 to 19, 1927. Dixie "46C" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carburetor. Buda fly-ball type governor. United dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18", width 7i/&gt;", rated speed 660 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin dry disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 3 miles per hour; high, 4.5 miles per hour ; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: In order to conform to the provisions of the tractor rating code of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and the Society of Automotive Engineers, the belt horsepower rating of this tractor should not exceed 32 horse - power. Test No. 145. OIL PULL 30-50. MODEL "Y." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 13 to 24, 1927. American Bosch "DU4/Ed26" magneto. Own make carbu - retor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own fly - ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine : Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 211,4", width 10", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch .own make twin disc. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.3 miles per hour ; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.9 miles per hour. Comments : On the rated drawbar test the water pump lost prime for short intervals. At the end of the test and during the inspection of the tractor both intake valve springs were found broken. Test No. 146. JOHN DEERE 15-27; MODEL "D." John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. October 24 to 29, 1927. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 Splitdorf "246C" magneto. Schebler "DLT" carburetor. Own make fly-ball type governor. Donaldson Simplex oiled fibre type air cleaner. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter lpVi", width 7-%", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make disc. . Rated Speeds: Low, 2.5 miles per hour; high, 3.25 miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Te»t No. 148. LAUSON "S12" 20-35. John Lauson Manufacturing Company, New Holstein, Wisconsin. April 2 to 16, 1928. American Bosch "ZR4" magneto. Tillotson "R2" carbu - retor. Taco fly-ball type governor. Taco water type air cleaner. Engine: Vertical "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 697 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry plate. Rated Speeds: Low, 2*4 to 2i/&gt; miles per hour; high, 314 to 3*4; miles per hour ; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: All spark plug gaps were adjusted to 0.025''. At the end of the belt tests number 2 cylinder had a leaky exhaust valve. All valves were ground and carbon removed. The carburetor float valve was leaking at the end of the test. Test No. 149. CLETRAC "40" 40-55. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 24 to May .10, 1928. Delco-Remy battery ignition system. Wheeler-Schebler "AT" carburetor. Pomona oil spray type air cleaner. Taco fly-ball type governor- , . Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15", width 13", rated speed 851 R.P.M. Chassis : Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3.5 miles per hour; high, 5.5 miles per hour; reverse, 3 miles per hour. Comment: The battery cable insulation became defective on the rated drawbar test, causing the ignition to become shorted. The insulation was repaired with tape. Two grease cups on the clutch throw-out collar sheared off during the limber-up run. Oil was leaking from the clutch shaft in front of the transmission and also from the crankcase where the front drawbar is connected, at the end of the test. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Nebraska Tkactor Tests Test No. 150. CATERPILLAR "20" 20-25. Caterpillar Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. May 17 to 29, 1928. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "AE" carburetor. Pomona oil-spray type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly - ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 11%", width 6V 2 "» rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, clutch, own make, single-plate type. Rated Speeds : Low, 1.79 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3.07 miles per hour ; high, 4.67 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.35 miles per hour. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 151. ALLIS-CHALMERS 20-35. Allis-Chalm- . ers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. June 18 to 26, 1928. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L" carburetor. Donaldson and Allis-Chalmers centrifugal and oil-fibre type air cleaner. Own fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter- 13", width 8.5", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make expanding shoe type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2V£&gt; ; high, 3}4 ; reverse, 3!4. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 152. TWIN CITY "FT" 21-32. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Octo - ber 1 to 8, 1928. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carbu - retor. Donaldson and own make, centrifugal and cypress - moss type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7V£", rated speed 651 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.36; intermediate, 3.17; high, 4.45; reverse, 1.74. Comments: Before the maximum belt tests were run, the packing gland nut on the water pump was tightened. During the maximum low gear drawbar test, the clutch was adjusted. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 Test No. 153, JOHN DEERE "GENERAL PURPOSE" 10-20. John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. October 22 to 29, 1928. Fairbanks-Morse "John Deere" magneto. Ensign "BJ" carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil - fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Horizontal, "L" head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 61//', rotates at crankshaft speed. ■ Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch : Own make, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, '2%; intermediate, 3Vs; high, 4 i/a r reverse, 2. Comment: Before the operating maximum belt test, oil was found to be leaking from around the flywheel end of the crankshaft. This was repaired by readjusting the gasket and tightening gasket cover plate. Test No. 154. ADVANCE-RUMELY "DO ALL." Ad - vance-Rumely Thresher Company, La Porte, Indiana. Octo - ber 29 to November 24, 1928. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Stromberg "Ml" carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil-fibre type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10", width 5 l /&gt;", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speed, miles per hour: Low, 2.625; high, 3.75; re - verse, 2.875. Comments : -On the rated and maximum load drawbar tests, it was necessary to improvise a method of locking the gear - shift lever in place to prevent the gears from slipping out of mesh under load. Test No. 155. CASE "L" 26-40. J. I. Case Threshing Machine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. March 16 to 27, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Kingston "L3" carburetor. Own make oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own. make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8V4", rated speed 780 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.5 ; intermediate, 3.25 ; high, 4.00; reverse, 2.75. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Nebraska Tractor Tests Comments: Before the official belt tests were run, the weighted air valve in the carburetor was given a few thous - andths inch end ° clearance. Approximately 5/32 inch was removed from the crown of the belt pulley. Test No. 156. McCORMICK-DEERING (Model 15-30) 22-36. International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. March 30 to April 9, 1929. . Own make "E4A" magneto. Ensign "RW" carburetor. Pomona oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly - ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16.75", width 9", rated speed 593 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.50; intermediate, 3.25; high, 3.75; reverse, 2.25. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 157. ROCK ISLAND "G2" 15-25 (Distillate). Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. April 24 to May 3, 1929. Splitdorf "46T" magneto. Stromberg "M2" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, Waukesha, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6 1 /'", rated speed 675 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.75 ; intermediate, none ; high, 4.00 ; reverse, 1.75. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 158. ROCK ISLAND "G2" 18-30 (Gasoline). Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. May 4 to 8 .1929 ' Splitdorf "46T" magneto. Stromberg "M2" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, Waukesha, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6V2", rated speed 675 R.P.M: Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry plate type. . Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.75 ; intermediate, none; high, 4.00; reverse, 1.75. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 Test No. 159. CATERPILLAR "15" 15-20. Caterpillar Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. May 9 to 14, 1929. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "BeV" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10 1 /'", width 6^", rated speed 950 R.P.M. Chassis : Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Own make, single plate type. Hated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.985; intermediate, 2.58; high, 3.568; reverse, 2.06. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments.. Test No. 160. CATERPILLAR "10" 10-15. Caterpillar Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. May 6 to 21, 1929. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "BeT" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. . . . Engine : Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 9 1 / 1 ". width. 6V-", rated speed 1050 R.P.M. Chassis : Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Own make, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.02; intermediate, 2.59; high, 3.50; reverse, 2.07. Comments: After the limber-up run and before any of the official tests were made, the equalizer spring under front of engine was adjusted. Test No. 161. BAKER 43-67. A. D. Baker Company, Swanton, Ohio. May 16 to 24, 1929. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Stromberg "M4" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15i/&gt;", width 8i/&gt;", rated speed 774 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2 to 2.5 ; intermediate, none ; high, 3 to 3.5 ; reverse, 2.5. Comments: It was necessary to lock the gears in mesh during the high gear maximum and rated load drawbar tests. Test No. 162. MINNEAPOLIS 27-42. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. May 28 to June 11, 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Nebraska Tractor Tests American Bosch "ZR4Ed34" magneto. Stromberg "UTR" carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make fly-ball type. Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15V-2", width 71/2". rotates at crank - shaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Own make, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.69; intermediate, none ; high, 3.42 ; reverse, 2.52. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 163. MINNEAPOLIS 39-57. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. June 5 to 14, 1929. American Bosch "ZR4 Ed34" magneto. Stromberg "M4" carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled-fibre type air cleaner: Governor, Kingston, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 20", width 8^", rated speed 620 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 3.00; intermediate, none; high, 3.90; reverse, 2.49. Comments : During the rated drawbar test the fan belt was tightened. During the low gear maximum drawbar test the gears slipped out of mesh several times. It was necessary to lock the gear shift lever in place with a block of wood. Test No. 164. WALLIS 12-20. The Massey-Harris Com - pany, Racine, Wisconsin. June 18 to 27, 1929. American Bosch "U4 Ed2" magneto. Kingston "L3V" carburetor. Own make oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, Kingston, fly-ball type. Engine : Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft lengthr wise. Belt pulley : Diameter 17", width 6 5/16", rated speed 540.5 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, .2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry, three plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2V&amp;; intermediate, 3V&amp;;. high, 41/3; reverse, 2V3. Comments : During the maximum drawbar tests the car-, buretor and fuel tank were removed and the entire fuel sys - tem thoroughly cleaned. Test No. 167. CASE "C" 17-27. J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin. August 12 to 19, 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 Robert Bosch "FU4ARS" magneto. Kingston "L3" car - buretor. Own make, oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10i/i", width 6 1 /'", rated speed 973 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch : Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.30; intermediate, 3.28; high, 4.50; reverse, 2.59. . Comments : During the maximum drawbar tests, the clutch was adjusted. During the rated drawbar test, the fuel line to the carburetor became clogged up and was cleaned out. Test No. 168. HUBER "LIGHT FOUR" 20-36. The Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. August 19 to 24, 1929. Eisemann "GV 4" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carburetor. Donaldson oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor, Waukesha fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 17", width 8 '/•&gt;", rated speed 616 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.32; intermediate, none; high, 3.08; reverse, 1.83. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 169. CASE "CC." J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin. September 10 to 18, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Kingston "L3V" carbu - retor. Own make, oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10*4". width 6 •/•&gt;", rated speed 973 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low ; , 2.60; intermediate, 3.72; high, 5.14; reverse, 2.95. Comments: It was necessary to raise the oil level in the transmission approximately one inch for the belt tests. Test No. 170. ALLIS-CHALMERS "UNITED" MODEL "U." Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. October 21 to November 7, 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Nebraska Tractor Tests Eisemann "G4" magneto. Schebler "HD" carburetor. Donaldson, and own, centrifugal and oiled-fibre type air cleaner. Governor : Continental, centrifugal type. ' Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10", width 7%", rated speed 1095 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Rockf ord, dry plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2V3 ; intermediate, 3i/a; high, 5; reverse, 2%. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 171. MONARCH "35"-30. Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. November 4 to 9, 1929. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Zenith "6C" carburetor. Own oil filter and centrifugal type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "IV head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. No belt pulley. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, single plate type. Rated speeds; miles per hour : Low, 1.84 ; intermediate, 2.76; high, 4.01; reverse, 2.13. Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests the econ - omizer jet on the carburetor became loose at its lower end and had to be soldered twice. Test No. 173. FORDSON "F" (Kerosene). Ford Motor ■ Company, Dearborn, Michigan. March 11 to April 8, 1930. . Robert Bosch "FU" 4BRS29 magneto. Kingston "MD2" carburetor. Own make, water-type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 9Vk", width 6 1 A", rated speed 1100 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, multiple disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1%; intermediate, 3i/ 8 ; high, 7%; reverse, 3. Comments : During the preliminary belt tests, the cylinder head gasket was replaced. The original governor spring was replaced by a heavier spring after the rated load belt test. Test No. 174. FORDSON "F" (Gasoline). Ford Motor Company, Dearborn, Michigan. March 20 to April 10, 1930 Robert Bosch "FU" 4BRS29 magneto. Zenith "IN5F" car - buretor. Own make, water-type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 Engine : Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft length - en R pM pulIey : Diameter 91/2", width 61/2'% rated speed Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Own make, multiple disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2V &amp; ; intermediate, 3V6 ; high, 7 J4 ; reverse, 3. Comments: During the rated load belt test, the water pump gland was tightened approximately one-fifth turn. Test No. 175. TWIN CITY 11-20, MODEL KT. Minne - apohs-Mohne Power Implement Company, Minneapolis, Min - nesota. March 24 to April 12, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2V7" magneto. Stromberg "UT1" carburetor. Donaldson-2-unit air cleaner, centrifugal and oily fibre type. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length- R P^M P ulle y ; Diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 715 Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.1; intermediate, 3.13; high, 4.15; reverse, 1.8. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 176. OLIVER HART-PARR "ROW CROP " Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Hart-Parr Division Charles City, Iowa. April 14 to 24, 1930. American Bosch "U4 ED2" magneto. Ensign Model "K" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit, centrifugal and oily fibre tvpe air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - 700 e RPM Diameter 14J4", width 7i/ 2 ';, rated speed Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.6; intermediate, 3 2 - high, 4.15 ; reverse, 2.9. : Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. In the adver - tising literature submitted with the specifications and appli - cation for test of this tractor we find the following claims are not substantiated by the results of this test: Exhibit "B" Folder A 135— "they do end wheel slippage" and "thev do not "#" A l 43 T Same as a a n bove hey Exhibi D —Folder A144— "Positive traction at the tiptoe wheels assures delivery of every ounce of engine power to the draw - bar." Exhibit "F"— Folder A 146— "They do not slip </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 177. MASSEY-H ARRIS "GENERAL PUR - POSE." The Massey-Harris Company, Racine, Wisconsin. May 5 to 27, 1930. . American Bosch "U4 ED2" magneto. Zenith "94TO" car - buretor. Massey-Harris, oil circulated over wool type air cleaner. Governor, Hercules, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6V2", rated speed 802 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, all drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.20; intermediate, 3.20; high, 4.00; reverse, 2.50. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 179. MONARCH "50." The Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Springfield, Illinois. June 27 to July 3, 1930, Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Zenith "C-6" carburetor. Own, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 121/2", width 81/2", rated speed 952 R.P.M. •■.-■■ ■ . Chassis : Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Own, single disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.82; intermediate, 2.76; high, 3.99; reverse, 2.06. Comments: During the rated drawbar test, the water pump packing gland was tightened. Test No. 180. OLIVER HART-PARR (2-3 plow). Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa. July 7 to July 15, 1930. American Bosch "U4ED2" magne,to. Ensign "KZ" car - buretor. Donaldson 2-unit, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, weight type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 1414", width 71/2". rated speed 726 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.6 ; intermediate, 3.2 ; high, 4.15; reverse, 2.9. Comments: During the rated drawbar test a lug bolt was lost and the lug bent. The lug was replaced with a new one. Test No. 182. CLETRAC 80-60. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. October 2 to 23, 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 255 Delco battery ignition system. Two Schebler "HDX12" carburetors. Pomona-Vortox oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston governor, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 24", width 15", rated speed 477.3 R.P.M. ; Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks. Enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Borg &amp; Beck, single plate. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.75; intermediate, 2.5 ; high, 3.6 ; reverse, 2.1. Comments: After the rated load drawbar test and before the maximum drawbar tests were run, four exhaust valves were found to be leaking. The cylinder heads were removed, all of the valve seats reconditioned, and the valves ground. Due to a change in weather conditions, the S. A. E. No. 50 oil was drained from the transmission, differential and crank - case at this time, and S. A. E. No. 30 was used in its place. Test No. 183. OLIVER HART-PARR (3-5 plow). Oliver Farm Equipment Company, Charles City, Iowa. October 13 to 27, 1930. American Bosch "U4" magneto. Ensign "K" carburetor. Donaldson 2-unit, centrifugal and oily fibre type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16%", width 8!4"» rated speed 596 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers. Enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.23 ; intermediate, 3.3 ; high, 4.33; reverse, 2.63. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 184. EAGLE "6A." Eagle Manufacturing Company, Appleton, Wisconsin. October 21 to November 1, 1930. American Bosch "U6" magneto.. Zenith "96ATO" carbu - retor. Pomona-Vortox oil spray type air cleaner. Hercules governor, centrifugal type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 625 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry, double plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2V-&gt;; intermediate, 31/3 ; high, 41/2 ; reverse, 21/2- Comments; No repairs nor adjustments. [6M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>