<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE DEPUTY FOOD COMMISSIONER OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OK THE DEPUTY FOOD COMMISSIONER OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA BY E. L. REDFERN DEPUTY COMMISSIONER STATE ANALYST 1906 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 To Hi&gt; I ( I for tli </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Biennial Report of the Deputy Food Commissioner. i.v an - ounri on I rketa - to the aembly • would . but it refused to on the grounds 'ion on pun should - \V1 .vanls would unscrupulous try hav&lt; d if othe tad wait- appointed to tlic deputyship :\ on April 1st. 1906, to fill th( Mr. W. F. Thompson. He has also con - -t which position he held prior to this en published by the Commis of food products. Tin to inform the consumer and selling fraudulent or impure foods. n^ pure and honest ko&lt;" of the foods found on the markets of tli nd publish. here in this report will show ity of cases the consumer does not that - his money. When the la ontents of the package, then and not until il against fraudulent and injurious Many of the foods put up in packa. i as creamery butt. - itfht, . il whicl Qg. illegal and not ; Of the I'M samples of foods analysed or Ix'low the standard. Fruit products with t&gt; itionsare a mixture of fruit pulp j </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 h, glucose and coal-1 lining little or lr with ■ The Tin- p;t&gt;^ Th' ka which will it. jfocxl- anri ■ Expenses and Receipts. All I (Jut i ■ sury. i our Stittl. part of tl entrance of nd ilruu - mei-c-e. While this Act : ul drugs AtnoD IX'puty Com; </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 1NER is not prevent have not entered in, with oda and dru^s in ade a with jui The law r a dairy inspect - it till milk, cream product healthful cattle and e that the official iul collect valuable data on this, one rational Pood and Drag Act, from slation. National Food and Drug Act. nation of adulterated ind licjuors, of the fTbat it shall 1k&gt; un - within any Territory or kxI or drag which is aduli within t nin^ of this Act; the provisions of this nor, am b offense five hun - to one year's imprison sonment, in the dis - - •iiient offense • me thousand tioll;- or both such t. in tin rnrt. That tli m into any State or Territory ortl. rom any otl or Territory or thi om any foreign country, or shipment to any Foreign country of any article of food or drugs </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 PORT which is ado -branded, within th&lt; • 1; and any person who s or deliver foi trict or who shall any B otln-i coun' il un brok' to ai shall to an, ■ ithin tip when no then ■ tior, That ti of Agriculture, and the shall make uniform i pro\ of s] sale in t! olumbia t the Unit* in unbi packages in any S er tlianthat in which tiny shall have been »r produced, or whicl ir intent shipment to an r which </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 DEPt SSIOXEU m by tli' Ith, food, or drug of any State, umbia, or at any domestic or ii product is offered for inter - nited id any foreign port or country. foods and n thf Bureau oi ry of the Depart - meni or under th&lt; on and supervision of [-mining from such exami - (I or misbranded •his Act; and if it shall appear from ninaiion that any oi - is adult' sbranded within the meaning of this Act, the Secre- Agricultnre shal given to 11 whom Any party u an opportunity t&lt; rd, under prescribed said, of the provisions of this Act have • hen the i frriculture - dis - copy i&gt;f the ir the such article duly authenticated by the analyst imination, under the oath of such ofti- shall be given by - ch mam by the rules said. shall 1&gt;&lt;&gt; the dui orney tow! Agriculture shall report any violation I or drug officer or olnmbia shall ory evidence of any such violation, to i appn • (1 in the | ithout delay, for the of the | in such case herein provided. That the term "di i in this Act, shall include all m&lt; and preparations recognized in the United 3 PharmacopoD tional Formulary for internal or and an mixture of sul&gt;stanc(&gt;s in - tended t d for the cure, mitigation, or prevention of 1 either man or other animals. The term "food,'" as </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 herein, shall include all i for fcxxl. drink •i or other animals, whi ■old und. \ n in tlh si In ti If it malt or spirituous liquor o as to redu length. cond. If a - in part for th&gt;- Third. If any valu.i wholly or in ; Fourth. If it be n stained in a manner when Fifth. If it •*nt which may render That when in I food pro shipment they are pi il application ap plied in such manner thr </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 n iii water, or otherwise, shall be provisions of this mly when said products filthy, d&lt; any portion i or not, or if nisbrandtnl," as used herein, shall . or articles which •ion of rood, the | label or device tin' ingredients instances lich shall ■ or misleading in i to an,\ drag product which is Territory, or country product article shall also lx&gt; offered for sale under ■ iriginally put or in part, and other or if the the quantity Me, hero is indica, chloral hvdr ■ i 'i- preparation of for sale under the le. I or bri ve or foreign product when originally put up shall u whole or in part and other contents shall - or if it fail to l» tl.S I- i I &lt;&gt;t ll - </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 ment on the lalx'l of the quantity or pro] rofoi derivative or pn n of an therein. Third. If i: in terms of weight 01 ■ any - onoii- ad u 1 1 ■ of or ■ with - to plaii or hi. as tli (eluding he purpi - further, Thai in&gt;. r o foods which i &lt;» unwi their t of this Act n ■ landing. ding in the I'nitei a whom he pun </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 «inded iting it. Said guaranty, contain ad address of the 'it- to the li, in - of tliis od, diiiK. or liquor that is ■ I within the meaning of this Act, and Territory, District, or in to anothi r, havii ransport - -old or ii unbroken | ■ in the District of Columbia ons of 1 : a foreign country or if it is ijn country, shall !&gt;&lt;■ liable to Ix 1 district court of t&gt; the same is found, and seized for con- condemnation. And if such ed, or of rions character, within the meaning of ill be disposed of by d&lt; and the proceeds th&lt; d charges, shall be paid into t all not he sold in to the pro 1 ( thN Act or the tion: Provided, however, That upon the - ich libel i and tin I to the • K&lt;{ of ■i' delivered to the owner thereof. ich lihe conform, us near as m admiralty, except that either trial by jury of any i- joined in i such p lts shall be at the suit of and in th. 11. Th - tary of the Tr&lt; ball deliver to iculture. upon his request from time to </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 to tli • I for imi to the owner or of Agriculture, and i introdu and if it article of food or dru_ I this tht' I bidd&gt; or from wl to tli refused deli\ • within t unci&gt; amount of the full ji ■ or foi amount of the bond : And r delivery shall and in default of such any future in 12. That • shall incluJ - word "|m the plural and the ainffuL II in - clude corporations, lintf ami g . Act, the act. omission, or failure of ai eraon acting for or employ' .. within ti ffice, </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 I Its of the anal.v - the commission. Analyses. I '.rand. 11. Hickman, Lincoln, Nebr Kb Brand. \V. II. Hickman. Lincoln, Nebr. Oval Brand. . Lincoln, Nebr. Booth Packing Co., Baltimore, Md. Sulph Me Brand . Lincoln. Nebr. inning Co.. Oconto, Wis. ad. ''.rand. . Lincoln, Nebr. i T rice. mnd. No 1 . y. Lincoln, Nebr. Man Canning Go, Oconto, Wis. Sulpli iat ion as Dfect from • ii hundred and seven. nning Co.. Waverly. Iowa nbaugh CaoningCo.,Baltimore,Md. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Mar, S Sulpli Sulpl '• s Sulpl No. 1 i Manuiai i Lindi at. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Brand. ■ tome, X. Y. ilated us Sodium Kl amp Brand. Lincoln. Neb Indianapolis, Lincoln, Neb. - Guilliamey l-'ils, no address given, per &amp; Alumiuu) salts pr&lt; lampigm . Lincoln, Nebr. ium Sulphite. Van Camps Full weight Brand. ry, Lincoln. Nebr. Camp Packing Co., Indianapolis found. i &lt;adoga Brand Lincoln, Nebr. ga Canning Co., Ladoga, End. tory Brand. nc Grocery, Lincoln, Nebr. The Joen Boyle Co., Baltimore, Md. ad. l-2'2-2. I' 1 Brand ( 'o. , Lincoln, Nebr. Manufacl Preserving Co.. Ontario, ound. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Lab No. i Mam;: P. Ho No. I N No. I M. II I: Man N. V. Sulp No. 1: I M. 11 • H P No preserval 1231. !'• liler M. H No. I No pr&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 I I I Kill. nd. In&lt;l. . Nebr. ml Aluminui ng, Monarch Brand. Lincoln Reid, Murdoch Co., Chicago, III md Borax present. PetiU I'ois Mo.\ Rounds &amp; Williams, Wood Riv&lt; I, Bordeax, Fran&lt; md Aluniinu ■ Whit.' Wax. Monarcli Bi ry, Lincoln. BfO, 111. nt. nd. M. H. Hickman, Lincoln, N arrolton, III. A lu n Tally-Ho Brand. . , Lincoln, N Man i. iday Brand. Mai - • N. Y. No pi Extra. Lincoln. V s, Prance. I luminum sa ra White Wax, Monai </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 242. !"■ \V. H. M( Jobbers i' Copi Mai i No. i: MISCELLANEOUS ANALYSES. No. 1113a. \ A - NO. 1114 No. 1 1 l.'a. V ii, Submitted 1&gt; Add 4. 1l' i' Soliils -1.48 per Cider vinegar low in solids. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 - - ilids. cent egal. I son, M. Knapp A nt. inger Bros., Lincoli •. Chicago, III. il. Subinittc Lincoln, Ncbr. Manu Barrett, Chicago, 111. nt. ntzke. lI. . Fremont, N I romel, illt&gt;&lt;, r al </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 No. lll'-'a. I Alkali Sample is butl Subn No 1 124 No l Bought of Union Hut 1 ■ ■■ Butt- No. L12Ha. M No. 1129a. Milk. ltou^ht of W Butl .ml. No. 1130a. Milk. ght of Unioi No [ - </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 ad. Moutfht « iifon No. ."». Lincoln, Nebr., 4-19, . Milk. liouu Buti No i Milk. ind. Milk. Duir.v wagon No. ."&gt;. Lincoln, Nebr., ikI VINEGAR. ion of ial par' is the i which it contains. Tin icid is the product of th on of tl iol. Alcohol is the same whetl or fruit, corn or apples and when subjected to •■ kind of fermentation it changes into t the acetic acid of ■ dis- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 tilled malt vinegar and for all p tilled vim ing off t! rn and rye Th ■ sell it shall allowing alooi gar i Malt vim the wort froi; (jar in th changed from red to brown, an Th. ket fron 1114. Yin. Lindell I Producer EL J. B I ppt with i Acid as ai Soli. Polarization in 200 m. in Alkolinity of - 10 acid. A cider vinegar, </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Lincoln, Nebr. gar Works, Lincoln, Nebr. ■nt. 1 in. in. Tube 1.7 Vent Sol. asli from C. C. 1.1 C. C. N 10 with caroinel, illegal Mercantile Co., Grand Island, Hiekman. Lincoln, Nebr is, Nebr, Kion ii i. 1 VenUke. ash from LOO ' 5 C. C .'lit. 2.2 Veni al. i\vn Merchant, Nebr. City, Nebr. ■nt. ent. ■ • from l&lt; I, illegal </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 • ( H. 1*. I. II ppt. with Solids Alkalinii </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 ndell Gro cent •■■ I . In \ I 'a &lt; O. . li 1 N. V </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 - s 1 _ </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 turlingtoi 1 Ventzke. ■ . Lincoln, N KC. N-10 acid • ■ntzke. S 3 lincoln, I s, Mo. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 . ' s Alkalinil </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 s I'a 1.7 \\&gt;n1 Nebr. [jar Works. Burlington la C. ■_'!(■ tzke. ow in so MISCELLANEOUS ANALYSIS ■ Brand. \\. II : 08., On S ■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 N'o. 113 \- H. .1. i Color No. 1140a 1141a. • IN. i;. No. 111! r H. H&lt; I Put up l&gt;y 1 •nt. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 per cent. I' jams what ;in It will lit prod s arc I many of them by their ■n tat ion. with and for this ipelling them to Fruit Jelly," know what they : "81 r»wherry md starch paste entirely of x\ -■■(I repri i the la lifin to contain </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 • I publii - ■ eludii - In • should b The full daring th&lt; tNo. ll-M Col </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 s • -•br. S. .1 Brand. n, N&gt;br. ers (: Lincoln. NVbr, I ■ ! rand , . Lincoln. N jfO, 111. &gt;n oil, m r dye. Lab No. 1 I cam. " Producers l\u it Condensed [ Milk Co. Seattle, No preservatives found. lio. w. Butt&lt; T.:&gt; per Sol at. Asli at. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">I jii I ' No. ; lienzi S Producers ; 1 A lii. A tin No. 1 • GIuocm - millet. An imitation product. Farmi Color Red coal Gluco- -«'nt. Starch-paste pi' An imitation product. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Co.. Lincoln. N&lt; r dye. i net. a. Current Jelly. .. Lincoln, N . iiiK Co Louis. Mo. itural. ruit product. iy Jelly. • kins, Lincoln, N up Refining ('&lt;&gt;.. Kan. City, Mo, u it prod htm. Watkins, Lincoln. N R. Co., 1 ity, Mo ruit product. .incoln. ! S \lo Color n.i Not a pure fruit pwx No. 1166a. Lemon Exti . Lincoln, Nebr. Jobl : ymond Bros. Clark. Color coal tar dye. .red. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 la No. 1 A lo' No. Prod ■ Not ruit i&gt;roi! No. 1 lTi'a. I. y Jelly Proci &gt;iiiitl) Refinii . * - i 1 Bluffs. irtificial. Glucose Not a pure fruit product. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 in*? Co bard Brand." &gt;'br. Mo. ■nt. • ii&lt;-oln. N ■nt. - Dcoln, N&lt; i . Kan. &lt; - No. Lincoln, Nebr. Wo. Color coul-tiird &lt;ilUC' nd Starch </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 PORT Lab No. 1 17- hard Br ■ Prodi. lo. Color Prodi: No. I I No. 1140. .lobl&gt;ers \Y. M i|. Acid Soliu Flocculent ppt. with A cider vin&lt; | </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 &gt;NKIi found on the such large it, in oi enne pe them chan ;iny of urry with gypsum in gingers owing yellow color will hide the presence ■ I other* the ginger a pale \ or sul] . Dr. Wiley of the U. s. Department rhen continuously admit i long a? when given in large period, create disturbances of appetite, ■ u it products analysed the found to be imitation products, colored ti nd composed of starch and glucose. In pple pr» ilk of (From analine and as it is from '■'■ ibsti - value and through the body e of st I pop was found to l«' i with t i larin. • a 1&lt; I be discouraged. ir bought on the und to Ix' composed of a large percent - mixtures sold for the pure tari e certainly r for when the consumer calls for cream of tartar ' he gets it and not a cheap mixture irable eon - ind in tl • ae pepper, out of i with analine dyes and adul - with gypsum. it is that our next Legislature </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 BIENNIAL REPORT will S' I] wholes tent* ly lal &gt;• I that \ s * - ~- No. 1 pie is pu No. 1185a. M - -up. T . Ui 1 3 srrup A. ' ouis. Socr nt. y </seg>
            <seg id="p041">DEPUTY FOOD COMMISSIONER 41 with Lincoln. . Lincoln X Y. jent Sam; ( Iround Ginjfer. . Lincoln. I 'nknown. id conversion .".7. IS per cent. - pure. d Ginger. ery &lt; 'o.. Lincoln. Dwinell, Wright Co., Boston. ! Mustard. . Lincoln Jobbi \ Murdoc, Kansas ( 'ity. Mo. i Link Is Lincoln. Producers Unknown. Borax pre* Starch I with starch and preserved </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 NIAL UKI *- ■ No.l 1 No. 11 Sample is pure. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 &gt;• COMMISSIONER with _ gypsum. 1 - H Watkins, Lincoln. I'nknown. ■ shells present. es. Belmont. ery, Lincoln. Hi titrating Co., t'h ill\ &lt;-i&gt;lo'v&lt;l and with added Lincoln nt. th turmeric and gypsum. Maple S a ip." . Lincoln. - pure. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 BIENNIAL KEPOKT No 1204a. I'inc Apple I' ■liiiH, H I'. . Sulj.l I'nknov Color Producers L; Lemon oil — . NT )• Color- A it it. A low g </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 _'l&gt;lut Bros., Lincoln. - I'n known. ■ i 62.77 per 2. 15 per cent. - pure. •pper. Lincoln. known. Pop. No Stand, Lincoln. - Lincoln Hott I in^r Works. Coloi tarin pr&lt; i and co - Lincoln. Known. l:Mi </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 No. 1216a. Cream \V H. Moore, Lincoln. Phosphatt tin lL'l 7a - Rel Sulpl Sample perlb. 1 Young .loll* - Phosphate of lime pi </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 E Lincoln. V V. ad contains added starch. Lincoln. known. I with a large percent of gypsum 'epper. Lincoln. - Cnknown. !lt. gypsum 16 ■ I with gypsum and colored. ! known. nt. nt. . Lincoln of fraudulent in- </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 NOTE kl </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 ii of the furnishes addit - ional imping ground for all While some of the adulterations But in the extreme, others are both (led is the state with spur - st imi&gt;ossibk; to get an absolutely condition is entirely due to the ab - whicli prohibit such adultera - and Drug Act which was approved It on .June 30th, 1906, is just such a law It is broad in its scope and is de - li and purse of the people against With t te authorities working under and pure wholesome ad. ho is interested in the health aeni and succeeding generations r next legislature a broad food law with the National law, and sufficient it. ! . tcoln, Nebr. ranan Bros., Omaha, ■nt. cent. ;it. with itate. soluble ash from I -20.4 C. low in solids. Youngblut Mro's.. Lincoln. Pro. H. .). Heinz A: Co., Pittsburg, Pa, Acid 52 per cent. Soli.. cent. Flocculent ppt. with Alkalinity of water soluble ash from 100 C. C— 23.6 X. 10 B A ciu _ ir, legal. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Pa No 114: Jobtx 114) lolpli - 114.' 1 1 4* Subn 11 47 Suhii Acid g An uncoi' 1 1 1- Submittetl bj Acid Coloring An uncoloivil Xo 114(&lt; tiler Johnson &amp; Lind, Lincoln. »burg. Solids — 1'.44 per i A cider vineg; </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 i, Lincoln Chicago. •»r cent. • •nt. ■ ■ &lt; lored, illegal. ■ ! Vinegar. 1 ■ eery, Lincoln. r Furii' Acid ut. per cent. I low in acid and solids. .11" ar. id rich Bros., Lincoln. Lincoln Vinegar Works, t r» per cent. '■nt. hi. illegal 1 er Vinegar. H Wat kins. lVgler. Lincoln. 1.77 per cent. • ■nt. Lincoln. 4. t per cent. IH'l. No. 1 1 in ( Irocery, Lincoln. ( hnaha. Acid er cent, nt. Not a cider vinegar, colored and illegal. L -dI ids. pear. - Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Rocl No. 115«. Cider Vinegar. iler W. H. Moore, Lincoln. Producers — American Fruit Product Y. Aciii Solid - 5) 1 No. WZ- - Jobber Solid- A (id. . Acid 4.HJ |&gt; - ulcnt ppt. with A pare cider vim gjal. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 DKP 88 i'NEK ■ Grocery, Lincoln. .Jobi r. Lincoln. r cent ent. ired, illegal. gar. ii Henry Co., Lincoln. ■ .1. H.'inz Co., Pittaborg, Pa. er cent. Solid*— : lit ppt. with lead gal. illegal. V"inej?ar. icery, Lii 1 • - lt'^a! Liclit.x iy. f^incoln. &lt; )niaha. Acid ent. Solid- rent. ■ent. Color caramel. • -,. .; I i ton ( in &gt;&lt;i t_v. Lincoln. A Peeler, Lincoln. per ( ■ ent. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">B I K S N I A 1 . No. 116«. Cider Lincoln. Jobb- coin. Acid ■ Soli' • In. Prod; d Pi&lt; ingp l'i&lt; No 1 127 ( 'olor - artificial. A low t: No. Jobber*— I it id— Murdcxl Lemon oil- 7 per cent. Color- artificial. A hiffh j. Solid- </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 DEPUTY FOOD COMMISS1O I Co., Kansas City, Mo. &lt; Imago. \ lii'_ g Powder, "Calumet." I - ■ l-»;ikinjjf F*o \vt 1 1 1 r ('&lt;).. Cliicafiro, Mustard. d~ Murdock, Chicago id Iiiipcrialc. iin Bros., Omuliu. dye. Mustard. Jobbers -McCord" 'Brady, Omaha. ric. Jobb . Murdot-k, Kansas City, Mo. Producers— Burlington I'k-kle Works— Burlington, la, Color— natural. ;nount o C!', 1 . I . Jobbers*~"Allen Bros., Omaha. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 s • C'oloi A hijjh r </seg>
            <seg id="p057">ONKK Mo. :it. K I *n\v&lt; i ■ ,;iin." Mo. . Baking Powder. "K. t P: . "Manhatt oc-k. Kansas City, Mo. r with tiller. Reliable." St. Louis, Mo. iwder. \. Murdock, Kansas City, Mo. No \. Murdock, Kansas City. Mo. it. Ash insoluble in ,9H percent. er cent. Ash insoluble in 2 1.80 per cent, Total and insoluble ash an sive. - - t a tiller. ro. 1155a. Bla .lol)' .ouis, Mo. Ash— 8. 1 } per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">No. 1156a. Lemon K Subn Pro Blanke - on oil— ."J5 i" Color- Coal ' A low S Proi o. I'n Mo. (ii any tia\ and ont' with - </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 I S. 5 "= / J _ X _ it - J= 7 — _^ &lt;C-5 *OSK3J | S • S |"3 - ~ p 3 »■ |s|!l 11 hi - - u - s 7. £ i2 a i a k 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">H1ENN1AL Hi 60 (unoiuv I ■ V. U. •-. -£ -1 r. «£ </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 S c I </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 T. T. .: * y </seg>
            <seg id="p063">-5 ■ . a - ■ - X -7 B &amp; t: la '- i. V ie «- *- I : r c 1 &gt;&gt;^&gt; a S ; : , • :J5ifc ■Sr ■■i&lt;- ; </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 tb a x. cr S5 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 f. ■C ■J- B-^fiB* =fi?*-e r. &lt; J / £ </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 r. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>