<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains</title>
               <date value="1923-03">1923-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 187 March, 1923 Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains H. C. FILLEV E. A. FRERICHS I'KIWRTMENT OF RURAL ECONOMICS THE FARMERS PROSPERITY IN NEBRASKA HISTORY farmer's prosperity is measured by what his crops will buy of &gt;mmodities. Taking 191J as a base, the diagram illustrates how mu&lt;h more or lean the farmer's crops were worth in terms of other com - modities at various times in the last 45 years. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT. DIRECTOR Wheat »3t IS I COKN l«77 i«»* J«» lite tttlMI .jft_.5 i^..5 Oats &gt;77 /«#» J., MM Ari/M, '3IJ BA5£ </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY The prosperity of the farmer is measured by the amount of de - ■irable goods that he can secure in exchange for his surplus products. LTtae price of the goods that he buys is as important to him as tht e of the product that he sells. bThe farmer's purchasing power depends primarily upon the relation - l existing between the price of the goods that he buys and the lucts that he sells. tin increase in the general price level is not indicative of increased perity. Because it is impossible for the price of all articles and Income of all purchasers to rise in exact uniformity, some persons per and some lose during every rise or fall in prir&gt; A maladjustment between the price of farm products and other products is injurious to all industries. In order to compare the price which the Nebraska farmer receivt for his grain with the price that he pays for other commodities it ■•••Mary to know both the price of grain and the general price le\ In this bulletin prices paid farmers for grain al Columbus. Nebrask and the general price level obtained rroni the records of the Unite SUtea Bureau of Labor are compared. The average of prices for 191 la used as a base. Corn had a low purchasing power, compared with its purehasin; power in 1913, from 1879 to 1900. This was due in part to over production. It had its highest purchasing power in 1917 and its low eat purchasing power in October. 1921. The purchasing power of wheat has fluctuated less than the pur - rng power of corn. As compared with 1913, it was higher in lary, 1923, than was either corn or oats. Oats had the lowest purchasing power during the last 4 months of 1911 of any time in the past 4 6 years. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains H. C. FILLEY E. A. FRERICHS The prosperity of the farmer is measured by the amount of desirable goods that he can secure in exchange for his sur - plus products. When all his surplus is required to pay for absolute necessities, the farmer is far from prosperous, irre - spective of the size of the surplus or the price at which it sells. I'KIIK AND I'l lt( HASIM. POWER Price is exchange value expressed in terms of money. In measuring the value of a product in dollars it must be re - membered that the purchasing power of a dollar is somewhat variable depending upon the quantity of money in circulation, the rapidity of circulation, the abundance or scarcity of goods, the credit situation and possibly upon other factors. The amount of money received for any commodity is of secondary importance because we neither eat money nor wear money, nor use it for shelter. The amount of goods that can be bought with the money received is the real factor in determin - ing value. The true value of a bushel of wheat, for example, depends not upon the price per bushel but upon the amount of desirable goods for which the wheat, or the money received for the wheat, can be exchanged. HKiH AND LOW PRICES Much has been said concerning high and low prices, but no price can be said to be high or low except by comparison. One dollar a bushel for wheat would have been a high price in 1896 and would have helped bring prosperity to Nebraska because other products were relatively low compared with the dollar. One dollar a bushel would have been a very low price for the 1920 wheat crop because nearly all commodities were high compared with the dollar. In other words a dollar had a much greater purchasing power — in fact, about 4 times as great — in 1896 than it had in 1920. A comparison of the prices received by the Nebraska farmer for his grain with the prices which he pays for other commodities is necessary before </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 we can determine whether grain prices are "high" or "low." The term "normal times" as ordinarily used really means that a fairly definite and logical relationship exists between the prices of various articles. • tWhen the prices of farm products rise, people speak of prosperity of the farmers. Hasty generalizations are ie, but the conclusions drawn do not always reflect true ditions. For example, during 1922 many writers and akers proclaimed the return of prosperity to the Nebraska mer because his grain and livestock were selling for ap - ximately pre-war prices. The actual fact was that despite rise in the price of farm products, Nebraska farmers were i prosperous in 1922 than in the years immediately preced - the World War. RISING AXI&gt; KAI.I.IV. PRICES An increase in the general level of prices is not indicative of increased prosperity. It is very evident that if the price of the goods which a man buys increases as rapidly as his wages or the price of the products that he sells, he will not have an increased purchasing power. It is of course impos - sible for the price of all articles and the income of all pur - chasers to rise in exact uniformity. As a result, the man who is producing some commodity which is in great demand pros - pers during a period of rising prices because the price of the goods which he has for sale rises faster than the price of the goods which he buys. For example, most farmers were pros - perous from 1915 to 1919 because the price of farm products rose more rapidly than did the price of the things which they purchased, that is, their income increased more rapidly than did the cost of living. People with fixed incomes, such as teachers, preachers, and men and women who had their capital invested in bonds or other securities yielding a fixed return were affected adversely by the rising prices and were com - pelled to reduce their standard of living. A rise in prices does not create wealth, but redistributes wealth already in existence. The more rapid the rise the greater the effect on the distribution of wealth. Price inflation brings prosperity to some, but to others it brings poverty. Among the factors which may cause prices to rise are the following : </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 1. An increase in the amount of money in circulation. 2. An increase in the rapidity with which money cir - culates. 3. An increase in credits. 4. An increased demand for goods, 5. A decreased supply of goods. Conversely, a decrease in the volume of money or credits, a decrease in the rapidity of circulation, a decrease in the demand for goods or an increase in the supply of goods will cause prices to lower. War is accompanied by rising prices because all or nearly all of these causes of high prices are present; it is followed by declining prices whenever these causes cease to operate. The reaction from the activity of the World War began in the United States in 1920. Currency and credit inflation was checked. The demand for goods decreased. Buyers be - came cautious. It was impossible to sell the same volume of goods at the same price. Sellers were of necessity compelled either to reduce prices or to put less goods on the market. Farm products have invariably dropped more rapidly in price than have manufactured goods. As a result the farmer has had to pay for high priced goods with low priced products. For example, in the United States as a whole in the last 6 months of 1920, the price of farm products decreased nearly 50 per cent and the fall in Nebraska was even more rapid. Other commodities decreased in price during the same period only about 15 per cent. MA.MKACTl 'KICKS AIILK TO RESTKHT PRODUCTION When the demand for goods decreases and a price drop is anticipated the manufacturer immediately restricts production so that supply will correspond to the decreased demand. He does not continue to produce high cost goods for which the market is uncertain. By regulating the supply he exerts a measure of control over the market. For example, the pro - duction of pig iron decreased from 36,415,000 tons in 1920 to 16,544,000 tons in 1921. The average price of pig iron in 1920 was $44.47 per ton ; in 1921 it was $26.68 per ton. Pro - duction decreased 55 per cent; price decreased 40 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 FARMERS UNABLE TO RKSTRKT PRODUCTION The farmer because of the nature of his business is not able to restrict production as does the manufacturer. Re - ferring once more to 1920, we find that the farmers had planted a very large acreage of corn which produced the largest crop on record. They could not reduce their acreage because more than 6 months intervened between the time of planting and the time of harvesting. The crop was produced when labor, farm equipment, food, clothing, and practically everything else purchased by the farmer were very high in price, in fact, the highest average prices measured in dollars of which we have a record. In December when the corn was husked and ready for market it was worth only from one - fifth to one-fourth as much per bushel as was corn during the spring and summer. The farmer produced a large crop under high cost conditions and naturally expected that the crop would bring a relatively high price. The time of maturity and marketing was, however, so far removed from the time of planting and cultivation, that he was compelled either to sell his crop at a relatively low price or else to place it in storage for an indefinite period with no certainty of ever se - curing a price that would give him a better net return. In the production of winter wheat the ground is prepared for sow - ing almost a year before the crop can be marketed and in the raising of livestock the time for planning production until the animals are ready for market is considerably longer. I The farmer is seldom able to reduce his operating expense "laying off" his employees because the major portion of the rm labor is performed by himself and family. According the 1920 census there were only 36,199 hired men on the 5,000 farms in Nebraska. As a result a single year of v prices has little effect on agricultural production. The rmer continues to plow and plant, to cultivate and harvest cause he wishes to utilize his time and there is nothing e that he can do. His fruit trees continue to bear and he inclined to be even more careful of egg and milk production. Nearly all farm products are perishable or semi-perishable. The consumer demands that his fruits, vegetables, eggs, and milk shall be fresh. Livestock can be kept on the farm after it is ready for market only at a heavy cost. The storage of such products as grain, hay, and cotton is expensive, not only because of the cost of storage but because of the danger of </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 deterioration. The farmer is practically forced to sell on a fast moving market subject to rapid fluctuations. Among all producers the farmer doubtless finds it hardest to wait before selling until readjustment reaches the point where he will sustain the least loss. Another reason why the farmer cannot exercise some measure of control over prices is because he cannot regulate the rate of turnover of his capital. His income on capital invested is derived from the sale of crops and as he can market only one crop per year his turnover is limited by the nature of his product. The manufacturer can in many instances secure many turnovers each year, and can adjust his business more quickly to put his commodity on the market at the most favorable time. Again, natural forces over which the farmer has no control are always at work. A good crop in some section of the country may bring only a comparatively small return because other parts of the world have had unusually favorable weather conditions for the production of the same crop. KKFKCTS OF MAIiADJl'STMKNT A maladjustment between the price of farm products and other products is injurious to all industries. The farmer must necessarily restrict his purchases when the price of his product falls more rapidly than the price of manufactured poods. This naturally decreases the volume of goods which the manufacturer can sell and as a result he must decrease production. Men are thrown out of employment or placed on a part time basis. Their purchasing power is decreased. When many men are out of employment wages inevitably fall. This still further decreases the purchasing power of labor. A period of depression then ensues until a readjustment is secured between the purchasing power of farm products and manufactured goods. A readjustment to normal conditions and to a normal price level is of benefit to agriculture, manufacture, trade, and transportation. It enables these industries to employ men until every willing worker has a job, and the full capacity of production is reached. Trade can be revived only by the readiustment of price levels so that one class of workmen can buy the products of another class. After every crisis a period of depression and readjustment continues during which </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 the prices of various commodities either rise or fall until a general level has been reached that permits business to pro - ceed. NKI5KASKA URA1N PRICES I Nebraska is a grain surplus state. The price which the braska farmer receives for his grain is therefore ordinarily ! price at Liverpool or the Atlantic seaboard, less the cost transportation and other handling charges. The price at ich the surplus is sold which is shipped outside of the te determines the price at which the farmer must value it part of his crop which is fed on his own farm or sold ■ local use. Normally 80 per cent of our corn, 85 per cent our oats, and a very considerable portion of our wheat are lsumed within the state, but nevertheless the surplus sets s price. In a state or any locality where there is not enough any kind of grain. produced to meet local demands, the price which grain sells is the price at the nearest terminal market or source of supply plus transportation and other handling charges. Corn, wheat, and oats decrease in price from the Atlantic seaboard to Nebraska in almost direct proportion to the cost of freight and handling charges. Our average pnce for any one of these cereals is therefore ordinarily less than for any state farther east. In fact, corn sells for less in northeast Nebraska and the adjoining portions of South Dakota and Iowa than in any other area in the United States, because it is farther from market than any other region of surplus production. In the western part of the United States, including the extreme western portion of Nebraska, not enough corn is produced to supply the demand. Wheat is a surplus crop farther west, Idaho being the state with the low - est average price. Because of our distance from the world markets the price of grain in Nebraska is always less than the average price in the United States, and the purchasing power of a bushel of grain is. of course, correspondingly less than for the United States as a whole. THE FARMER'S PI K&lt; HASINCi POWKIt The purchasing power of the farmer is measured by the amount of desirable goods which he can secure in exchange for his income. The amount of the purchasing power is therefore the final indication of his ability to take the merchant's goods. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 It is the farmer's means of comparing his returns with those of the workers in other industries with whom he comes in contact. The primary purpose of this bulletin is to compare the prices received by the Nebraska farmer for his grain from 1877 to 1922 with the price which he has paid for other com - modities during the same period. In order to make such a comparison it is necessary to know both the price of grain and the general price level. I III I/HE OF INDEX XI MHERS Changes in price levels, that is, in the purchasing power of money, are indicated statistically by the use of index num - bers. The average prices of a considerable number of com - modities during some one year or for a term of years are taken as a base and are always given the value of 100. If the purchasing power of money decreases, that is, if prices go up, the index number will rise above 100, but if prices go down the index number will fall below 100. Two separate indices are necessary for determining the purchasing power of any commodity. These are the index number of that commodity and the index number of all com - modities. In order to determine the purchasing power of corn, for example, we must compare the index number of corn with the index number of all commodities for the correspond - ing time. An accurate record of prices for a considerable period is a prerequisite to the computation of index numbers. INDEX NUMBERS OK AL.L COMMODITIES The Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States De - partment of Labor is undoubtedly assembling more informa - tion upon prices than any other organization in the United States. Its "all commodities" price index is at present (1923) based on the wholesale prices of 404 commodities. During a considerable part of the period covered in this study the index was for a somewhat smaller number of arti - cles, but the list was nevertheless large enough to be repre - sentative. The data for the 1877-1890 period are based upon the report of Mr. Aldrich of the Senate Finance Committee of </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 1893, which embodies the most extensive work of its kind at that time. The yearly index numbers are given for each year from 1877-1890. From 1890 to the present time, the figures are from the Department of Labor. Indices are given quarterly for the 1890-99 period, namely for the months of January, April, June and October. Monthly indices are given for the 1900-1922 period. The Department's index numbers are prepared by compar - ing the wholesale price for each month with the average price for 19J3 taken as a base and the result is an index showing the general price level. Wholesale prices are more stable and more nearly uniform than retail prices. In covering a long period of time there is necessarily some error in the compari - son because of the changes made in the grading of farm products and other commodities, but this discrepancy is slight and a fairly accurate comparison is secured. !The wholesale price index is not an absolutely accurate lex of the price that the Nebraska consumer pays, because ; average margin added by retailers may vary during a ig period, and because the difference between the average lolsale price in the United States and the wholesale price Nebraska may increase or decrease due to changes in sight and other handling charges. The wholesaler and re - ler of necessity pass on to the Nebraska consumer the sight and handling charges on goods manufactured in the at. This wholesale price index is used, not because it is solutely accurate, but because it is by far the most nearly :urate of any data available, and when compared with the ice of farm crops gives a relatively true index of their rchasing power. The Department of Labor originally based its index number upon the average wholesale prices for the 10-year period from 1890 to 1899. As this period included the panic of 1893 and the severe industrial depression following, it made a relatively low base line. When prices rose during the war a change to a new base seemed advisable, so the last pre-war year, 1913, was selected and indices computed and published back to and including 1900. In this study it is essential that all index numbers from 1877 to 1922 be computed on the same base. To change the 1890-99 indices to a 1913 base it was necessary to compare them to some 1890-99 indices which had been computed with </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 1913 as a base. The 1913 level was found to be 25.6 per cent higher than the 1890-99 level. Therefore, each quotation of the 1890-99 base was divided by 1.256 to reduce it to the 1913 level. The results of these computations are presented in Table 1 which gives the "all commodities" price index numbers from 1877 to 1922. Tablk 1. — Iiidej- number* of wholesale prices: all commodities. Yaw Ju. F*b. ! Mar. April May June My Aof. S«pt. Oet. Nor. Die. I - 1 *! 81 81 •• i 8t ■ ■ J= 90 &gt;. g ■;. M soi 902 903 904 MIS 906 907 908 909 910 Ml 912 913 914 915 »I6 MIT 918 H« I ■ 77 77 71 67 68 ■ a ■ 80 -t&gt; 83 84 89 95 93 92 98 95 95 UK! KM) 99 110 111 185 L&gt;n:l 248 177 M 80 82 86 85 86 90 95 92 92 98 »6 97 100 99 101 112 156 186 1»7 249 167 141 " M ' 80 82 86 85 86 90 96 91 92 99 96 98 99 99 99 lit 161 187 •&gt;"! L'.Vi 162 142 80 75 77 I Hi ■ 7» E 90 H 90 93 98 95 100 98 98 100 ' 117 , 172 190 203 265 s ::::::| i 79 84 84 84 84 90 96 90 93 97 95 99 98 98 101 118 182 190 207 272 151 148 81 80 ' 84 83 83 85 90 96 90 93 97 96 99 100 99 99 119 185 193 207 269 148 150 78 76 74 ■ 64 M 74 80 80 83 83 83 86 90 96 90 93 97 96 99 100 100 101 119 186 198 218 262 148 156 M 81 83 84 ' 83 86 91 97 '• 90 95 97 96 100 101 103 100 123 185 202 226 250 152 156 W 81 86 83 83 87 91 97 I I 100 102 104 99 128 183 207 220 242 152 153 78 n 74 •• :;;:;; ;;;:: •7 n •7 78 SI SI 82 81 82 80 86 86 84 83 83 84 83 84 84 88 89 M 93 94 91 95 94 96 90 91 91 97 98 93 96 96 97 M M M 100 100 100 101 101 99 99 98 98 101 103 106 134 144 146 181 183 182 204 206 206 223 230 238 225 207 189 150 149 119 154 156 156 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 OOIAMIHS, \ Kim ASK A IMUCKS SKLKITKD tThe prices paid to farmers at Columbus, Platte County, braska have been selected for use in this bulletin as typical the grain producing region of the state. It is a representa - e location so far as soil, yield, and products are concerned, i grain prices are available for a longer consecutive period in for any other representative town in the state. The prices were taken almost exclusively from the files of the Columbus Journal from January, 1877 to July, 1917 when it ceased publication. The editor during nearly all these years was Mr. M. K. Turner, who was noted for his ability as a publisher and for the accuracy of the contents of his paper. Market reports were obtained from the local elevators on Tuesday of each week and published on the following day. From July, 1917 to December, 1922 all quotations were taken from the Columbus Telegram. Columbus is located in the east central part of Nebraska and incidentally, very near the center of the United States. The region was settled in the early fifties and grain growinsr followed the grazing industry. In 1868-70 the first flour mill was established in Columbus and it was able to care for the milling of all grain within a radius of 15 miles. In June, 1866 the first railroad reached Columbus. It was the Union Pacific from Omaha to San Francisco. In 1881 the Omaha, Niobrara, &amp; Black Hills road was built from Columbus to Norfolk and Albion. In the parly eighties the Fremont, Elkhorn and Missouri Valley road passed through the northern part of Platte County. A few years later the Burlington came to Columbus from Lincoln by way of Seward and David City. The Columbus region therefore has 4 lines of road to carry away her surplus products. That Columbus early became a good market center is indicated by an article which appeared in the issue of the Journal of December 31, 1873. It says in part : "Competition in the grain trade is making things 'red-hot' in Columbus. The New York, Chicago, and St. Louis markets are repre - sented here by wide-awake, active buyers, who have the honor to do business on the 'Live and let the farmer live' principle and the nerve to put up the last living cent for wheat. The result is that it is worth from 82 to 85 cents, and farmers are attracted here from a distance of 75 miles north and south. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains 13 It is estimated that 175 to 200 wagonloads of grain are com - ing in daily. Evidence that the city is traveling along the highway to success is apparent in a large elevator and 4 grain warehouses built this year, taxed to their fullest capacity." The Union Pacific Railroad office reports that during the winter of 1872, 133 carloads of wheat were shipped east. During the winter of 1873, 596 carloads were shipped of which 136 were in December. Tables 2, 3, and 4 show the prices for corn, wheat, and oats at Columbus, Nebraska from January, 1877 to December, 1922. As has been already stated, these quotations taken from the files of the Columbus Journal and Columbus Tele - gram are the prices offered at the Columbus elevators. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 187 Table 2.—Prire of torn of t'ohimhtiH, XrhrnAn: /.s',V-/.'A &gt; &gt; Ymr J— ■ I F»b. | Umt. April May June July Ai*. '■ Sopt. Oct. N..v lx 1877 *021 10.25 $025 $025 $0.42 $0.50 «0.32 $026 $0.33 $03) $02« ■JJi 1878 JO .19 .19 .19 20 .21 20 IK 18 .17 .17 1 1879 .14 .14 .16 .17 .22 .20 .25 2i. .15 .18 .1 !0 isao .1» .18 .IK .20 .18 .2(1 .IS IK 22 .23 .24 1881 .26 .28 .28 23 .36 M 28 .33 40 .38 .33 :t .41 .46 .44 IKH2 .41 .46 .40 .4S .5« .55 .55 .65 .45 .40 M 1883 29 25 28 JO AS .28 25 .25 .28 Ji :t&lt; M 25 .28 1884 .35 .35 .35 JI i6 28 23 It .2f. .20 1 I 1886 .19 .21 .21 .21 .2h 28 28 28 22 1186 .16 1 .16 .18 .18 .1C 16 .16 22 .19 .17 1187 .20 .20 .IS JO 20 .22 22 2\ 2\ .21 .2:&lt; .27 1 Htu. J5 .36 M M J7 .40 .30 .30 .28 ,2ft .23 .22 1H9 20 .18 .17 .18 .18 .18 .19 .20 .18 .18 .1' .is 18SKJ .14 .14 .14 .15 20 2\ 22 .32 .38 .38 JJ M 1891 .38 .40 .43 .48 .&amp;2 .12 .1(1 .40 .48 .35 .:K 111 1BW .24 .26 2', 21 26 .34 .M .S2 JI .30 Jt .27 IMS:: .26 .25 .26 J5 .25 .24 .21 .21 ' .22 .26 .2: .21 18*4 20 2\ 33. 22 26 24 2S .4S .S5 .5! .5 .50 1895 .50 .49 .45 .46 .49 .49 .48 .Ml 26 .16 .14 .14 18M .12 .16: .17 .18 .14 .11 .11 .14 .12 .11 .12 .12 i8*r 1897 .11 M .10 .10 .13 .11 .14 .16 .18 .IK .14 .16 .11 M .10 .10 .13 11 .14 1H .18 .16 1898 .16 .17 ' .18 .19 24 22 22 23 21 2l 189h .16 .17, .18 .19 2* 22 22 .23 21 2t&gt; .2:! Xi :&gt;■' 1899 .25 2b' 24 2* .25 .24 .21 2\ .21 .21 .21 JO 26 25 ' .21 24 25 24 21 21 21 [«»? .iO .*O .&amp;* ,&amp;l JS I .21 .£ 1900 20 21 23 : 20 : .30 24 24 28 20 .2 1900 20 2\ 23 .80 .30 .24 .34 2* 20 29 .28 M JI 1M1 1901 .26 .28 .29 .:13 .3:1 .VI .4:1 .45 .4« .46 .18 .56 26 .28 29 .33 .:« .32 .l:t U 4&lt;l 4f 1W2 1902 .55 .52 .50 .45 .52 .50 .50 .45 .42 .12 M JO .66 .62 .60 .45 .52 ..V&gt; M 42 .42 1903 27 28 28 24 .29 .34 M .37 .37 .31 j»l 1903 21 .28 .28 .24 29 .34 .:1S J7 .X', :.\\ .:«) 21 1W4 1904 58 .30 .S6 .38 .38 .3S .35 M .39 .19 .10 ,:&lt;1 28 .30 26 .38 .38 .35 Jf 1905 .31 .33 JU .84 .36 .37 .42 .11 .12 1905 .31 .SS .33 .34 .36 Ml .42 .11 M M .18 J1 II 12 JJ 1*06 20 .30 29 .31 .36 .36 .38 ,17 .35 .Xi .12 29 1906 JO .30 29 .31 .36 .36 .38 J7 JS Jt .12 Jt IM7 1907 J7 .30 .HO J8 .31 .»» Jt .40 .46 .48 M .1" 27 .30 .SO 28 .34 40 .39 I" 46 .48 1908 .44 .46 .47 .61 .55 .58 .59 .SB .« 1 909 .47 .49 | .54 .56 .61 .62 .55 ..M .5 1908 .44 .46 .47 .61 .55 .58 .59 .«6 .65 .55 .47 .47 H .K .« 1909 .47 .49 .54 .56 .61 .62 .55 .58 .54 .18 .51) .68 H il l»10 1910 .64 .82 .48 .44 .49 .46 .48 .51 .48 Jt XI J4 .64 .62 .48 ; .44 .19 46 .48 II 4 1911 .32 JS J2 .34 .41 .43 .50 .52 .50 .62 .611 JJ 1*11 .32 23 22 .34 .4! 43 .50 .«: 1912 .S3 .55 .66 .61 .68 .66 .S3 .C4 .«S .68 .44 JI 1*12 ..13 .55 .id .61 .S8 .86 .S3 ,«4 .«5 .5K .44 JI 1*13 .40 .40 .39 .42 .60 .49 .18 .61 .65 .6. JI .61 1914 .68 .56 .55 .00 .60 .60 .55 .68 .61 .61 JI JI 1916 .56 .66 .57 .50 .62 .61 .62 .6" .59 .52 JI JI hi .« 44 1915 .40 .40 .39 .42 .60 .49 .18 .61 .65 .6. 41 .61 .Hi 1914 .68 .56 .65 .60 .6(1 .60 .55 .68 .61 .61 :'i ' JJ JI .61 .61 1916 .66 .66 .57 .50 .62 .61 .62 .6" .59 .52 JI Ji 1916 .49 .50 i .49 .82 .58 .58 .62 .6S .7(1 .7:' .71 .7". 1917 .81 .80 J8 1.16 1.46 i .34 1.6' 2.15 1.82 1.4* 1 .41 1 . Ill 1918 1.25 1.40 ! 1.55 1.36 1.45 1.25 1.60 I .A ' 1.55 IJi I JO 1 .35 1919 1.42 . 1.25 1.30 1.55 1.55 1.58 1.62 1.80 1.50 IJi 1.2:. 1.30 1920 \2h 1.18 1.27 1.40 1.60 1.67 1.50 1.25 1.20 7i Ji M ».41 27 JJ J» I 24 .40 23 .36 28 22 J4 '.1 28 21 ! .48 2» I .43 .4.1 .47 .46 .43 .17 .57 J 1921 .41 J7 .M ! J» I J4 .4(1 .:!:' ..!« .28 22 .21 .t* Jtl .43 .43 .47 .4fi M .17 .57 .50 H </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains 15 Table :'.. -Prire of wheat of (',,hn,,b,i*, Xehrmkn: 1X77-1922. Y«r J»n. Feb. M.r April j May j Jun. July | Aug. j Sept. Oct. Nov. Dae. $1.04 I $1.03 $1.10 i $1.25 I $1.35 $1.00 j $0.S5 $0.76 $0.78 $0.80 $0.81 .75 .80 .80 i .86 ; .77 .72 | .82 .60 .66 .62 .« 1877 »M 1878 M l(7t .56 .55 .62 .56 .60 I .73 .73 .60 .60 .68 .78 M I »&gt;. i UK OO Oft IU\ TO TC on EA «-i ea in an :.h 55 I IM .95 .82 .90 .60 j .78 .75 ■ .60 .60 .« .68 .72 !«0 IM 68 .68 .68 .68! .72 .72 .79 .79 140 l.lt I 1.00 ! .96 I •.« .95 .96 .95 .90 ! .90 .90 .90 .90 .65 .64 .66 !«8 i »*i .65 .70 .80 .75 .76 I .78 ; .72 .76 .70 .70 .62 ; '.It ;■&gt;»_' 75 .65 .66 .60 .63 .63 .68 .66 1 .50 .40 .45 M I Mf 48 .50 .50 .50 .60 .60 .60 .60 j .53 .55 .56 M 1 "•'■ .58 .58 .58 .58 .64 .52 .62 .52 .62 .60 .47 .46 .54 .54 .54 .64 .58 .58 , .55 .66 .62 .68 .48 50 »55 .66 .68 .60 .62 .66 .58 .60 .66 i .75 .75 .80 .80 .75 .75 .75 .75 .65 .66 .55 .50 .60 .60 .48 18M H M 58 .58 .54 .52 .;.2 .52 .52 .50 110.7 :,l :.i .54 .54 .68 ..-,« IN .11 .44 .4ft* .50 Jl M .56 .85 .75 .76 .TO 1H91 S.68 .63 .66 .68 .75 .76 .66 .62 j .76 .70 ] .7$ I .68 65 .63 .65 .60 .60 .63 .60 .62 I .48 .48 .42 .47 .47 .47 .47 .47 .47 .48 .46 .42 I .42 | .49 .41 .41 ti.s Mi .66 .68 .75 .75 .HH M .75 .7U VMZ H M .65 .60 .60 m .Nil .52 .IX .49 .41 .42 .12 M 40 .42 .43 I ■ I .42 .42 .40 .42 .43 .38 .43 : .43 .60 .63 ! .53 .60 Um -64 .56 .52 .52 .58 .70 .65: .63 .46 .46 .46 1 .46 i -'••■ .44 .47 .64 .60 .48 ' .42 .40 .40 .40 .48 .62 .62 \m m M .4:1 M .11 I M .44 .47 .64 .60 .48 ! .42 .40 .40 .40 .48 .62 I .62 1 »l .62 .62 .58 .60 .61 .64 .54 .66 .73 .68 .66 ! .71 1 HSIt .71 .74 .76 .76 .86 .98 .53 .66 .46 .47 .50 I .60 .1(1 .40 .40 .48 I IH -71 .74 .76 .76 .86 .98 .53 .55 ' .46 .47 .50 50 ! «&lt;•■• .52 .54 .50 .52 .54 .56 .M I .52 .58 .65 I .55 .50 I*"' 5* .47 .49 .52 .50 .50 .6.1 .60 .56 1 .54 .57 M 1901 .54 .55 .56 .56 .56 .54 .56 .54 .66 ! .66 ! .56 .69 I«M .59 .65 .60 .56 .58 .60 .62 .60 1 .55 .55 .55 .60 IM 51 .54 .56 ..S6 .56 .58 .62 .60 .62 .60! .60 1 .69 I9B4 .60 M .80 .74 i .70 j .68 .68 ! .74 .92 i .97 i .96 | .88 UK i .92 .95 .95 .88 .74 I .81 .78 i .71 j .68 j .71 .70 .71 1 Mi 69 6h .63 .63 I .66 .66 .66 .54 ' .67 j .58 .58 .69 1*'" -57 .61 .61 .60 .61 .79 .75 I Jtt \ .79 .83 1 .80 .83 1 •»"&gt; 88 .83 .82 .80 .87 , .85 .78 .79 ! .85 .82 .84 .87 !•• -89 , .89 .90 1.04 1.00 ! 1.17 .85 .89 .86 .92 .99 .94 1910 1.00 .96 .99 .98 .95 .80 .85 .88 | .90 .85 | .78 M 1911 .82 .7S .75 .73 .78 .76! .76! .76 .79 .93! .87 1912 .91 .93 .91 .9* .98 .97 ; .90 M .78 .77 .7« .71 191S .73 .77 .76 .76 .77 .78 I .77 .7* I .73 .72 .67 .71 1912 M M itU .73 .77 .76 .76 .77 .78 .77 .71 I .73 .71 .67 .71 1914 .73 .74 .76 .77 : .76 j .77 .61 : .78 I .93 .88 .99 .98 n 1915 1.09 1.40 1.28 1.38 1.37 1.14 1.05 1.15 1 .91 .90 .90 .92 1916 1.03 1.12 .90 1.03 : 1.00 .90 .87 1.14 i 1.28 1.60 ! 1.70 1.55 1917 1.75 1.55 1.77 2.10 2.85 2.45 2..1R 2.70 \ 2.00 | 2.00 2.00 2.00 19tS 2.00 2.05 2.05 2.05 2.05 2.05 2.06 2.02 2.05 2.00 2.03 2.03 1916 1.03 1.12 .90 1.03 i 1.00 .W&gt; Jl 1.14 1.28 1.60 2.00 2.00 2.00 2.03 2.03 1919 2.15 2.10 2.10 2.40 2.45 2.15 2.15 2.05 ', 2.05 2.05 2.20 2.30 19M 2.45 2.80 2.30 2.15 2.75 2.60 2.45 2.26 j 2.27 ! 1.98 j 1.75 1.40 1M1 1.50 1.35 1.1.1 1.26 1.22 1.36 .98 .97 .98 1 .87 .81 .90 1922 .87 1.00 1.14 1.07 1.18 1.05 .90 .86 .80 .86 .98 .96 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 187 Table 4.— Price of oatx at Cohtmh;*, Xef,ra*A;i : 1X77-1922. *—* im - *»»- ""■ April May J— . | July ! A«c. Sap*, i Oet. Not. Dae 1*$ »?* w f 8 "S ••£ W :S? *&gt;£ «&gt;% -f 8 ! »■» ! *■•• -■•• * £ % £ % £ £ £■ iJ £ £ £ -II :H -|l -^ £ £ £ £ £ £ £ £ a .a * a ji ji .2* .20 .16 IB It II .21 .24 JS , JO M Jt 18 .18 II II 15 II .16 .16 JO | JO .2:1 .2S .20 .15 15 IB Ifi IK 16 .!• .It .11 IB I" 17 .16 17 .It II IB ••2 if •'» •'» *&gt; -21 20 JO !l8 !l9 !l6 !l8 Jt J* J4 J4 JI .27 .23 JO II IN IB IB .IS I .]« .1« .if, 16 14 15. .14 2 I*' *:l 14 12 12 II .12 .13 .13 .14 .20 .21 JI*' .23 JI JI .3:1 J4 .S3 M M M M it JO J8 jS S S 9 •S 51 -S •*? : ?' : « 3 J2 !22 JO J5 jj j4 J4 5i .2.1 s a jo :TI :5o :T5 I 11 -51 S « : " :^ a : « "■"» * * ?i ?f -?2 M • S0 25 •*' 1S u 1S -'2 12 •!! }*. !« I? 12 .11 .10 .14 .10 .11 .10 .10 .27 •27 .32 10 II 10 10 .16 .14 .14 .12 15 15 18 .13 n 13 II IB .1« .17 JO JI '? 1J •» -21 23 .20 .17 .17 .17 .18 Jo .22 -!§ -I! 1* •*» -20 .18 JO .It .18 .18 II .18 .2.1 .20 17 .17 ■ .18 JO .It .18 AH .18 !l8 .w jo , ji J2 zi : 2 3 so :» m :«2 iS :is .40 .40 .37 .S4 .35 J5 it Tl J2 izs :27 2 ■ .23 .25 Jt Jt JI JI .SO .25 JI .27 JI ji js i m ! m j&amp; s :;ro n % a *z &amp; M J3 ; JS ; .« .25 .25 .25 jS J8 liT S J^ Jt .28 M .32 .2:1 .21 .IK .21 2c i •i? -12 -H H '** M - 30 -24 J6 : 2 6 j« j* • 2 ? •?! -5 1 •»■ ■" *» m S 1? IS :tS S .*.» ; .^o ..li .j.j .41 .42 .40 .40 .42 .43 .40 .40 .41 .'IN .37 III .41 .41 .46 .46 .47 IS .35 .31 .31 .31 JI 32 Ji I .«» ; j» jt M Ji .26 .28 .27 .21 .23 Ji •?! i !* I •» ; •" '■ M '** '** ** M *0 M M .40 ' .44 .46 .46 .51 IB .13 J4 Jt .27 .27 n •S -S •»; * '^. *! « 34 J5 %6 Is ji .34 .34 J4| J4 .34 .31 .SO .33 "if « Zi \ Zl M M ■ 1t0 M S8 s « - 40 -3» -&lt;U -IS U i? ' i* »• - 311 ■« -26 26 3» JS JI JI in .33 JS ■*&gt; ! •»» -34 .35 .!2 .32 .3.1 .34 .411 .41 .4r, .46 .46 .4* i .W JI Ji .83 .66 .51 Ji .67 •2 -I 7 , -fl T* •« * :« s? :*&lt; :S« s :« .66 .68 .68 i .70 .70 .70 .70 .68 JI M M m .74 .75 .77 .W •il I iS 12 OT •** - 95 - 90 ••« -M •« .41 .36 If -S '2 oS 2 * Ji J2 .20 .20 .19 JI JI JT Jt J8 JO J9 .28 J4 J3 .31 J6 J« JI Ji .90 .62 il .i* .in .it .Bi .32 J7 Jt Jt II .211 .2" .1» .21 J8 .21 M .31 JI JI </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 INDEX MM BURN OF GRAINS The first step in calculating the purchasing power of corn, wheat and oats at Columbus, Nebraska is to prepare a proper and accurate index of the prices. To make comparisons in the price levels of different periods the prices for some certain period must be used as a base and all quotations given must be compared with that base. In this study the prices for the year 1913 are used as a base in order that the index numbers may be comparable with the index numbers for all commodi - ties given in Table 1. The prices of the 3 grains are taken each month during that year. The average price of each grain is obtained from these monthly quotations and the resulting average is used as a base and equal to 100. One of the reasons given by the Bureau of Labor Statistics for adopting the year 1913 as a base is that it was "the last full year free from unusual disturbances." In the United States, as a whole, production was neither abnormally high nor low, prices were relatively steady and no fear of war or crisis was impending. For a single product in some one local - ity these general conditions do not necessarily apply. Local crop failures due to floods, drought, or insect pests often occur in a year of average production. This was true in Nebraska in 1913. In a considerable area in the south central portion of the state the corn crop was cut short by dry weather and hot winds. The region near Columbus pro - duced enough corn to supply local demands until the end of the year, so that the prices quoted were the terminal market price less transportation and other handling charges. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">IN giPKAolvA IjArLKlMljNT 40TATION 15L ! LLtTIN loi Table 5. — Indej- numbers of corn price*. 1913=100. Ymt . 1877 1878 1879 18*0 1181 1882 1883 I8S4 ISM 1887 IS 68 36 ■ ■ M 87 M 52 48 85 41 ■ 85 I I ____^_ Y«n ISM 1891 ISM ISM ISM !SS «!&gt;7 K»X 1899 1900 IM1 IMS IMS IM4 1906 1*06 IM7 IMS 1909 1910 1911 1912 1913 1914 1915 1916 1917 1918 in* I MO IM1 IM2 Jan. | Fab. | Mar. April May Jane 27 2* 73 *r 46 tt 48 m 5? :::::::::::: 8 :::::::::::: 23 W 21 It 31 »7 42 4« 3» 41 44 58 68 52 50 52 56 64 64 62 106 100 97 87 100 97 52 54 54 46 56 66 54 58 68 73 73 68 60 64 (4 66 , 70 71 73 : 73 56 60 69 69 52 58 M 64 66 77 85 89 91 99 HIS 112 •1 96 104 106 118 119 104 100 M 85 95 87 62 64 62 66 79 83 102 106 108 122 ! 131 127 77 77 75 81 | 97 96 112 106 106 IK I 116 116 108 127 110 S7 I 119 118 95 97 95 100 112 112 157 154 ! 170 224 282 259 241 270 299 261 280 241 S74 241 ! 251 299 300 305 241 228 246 270 809 322 79 71 89 64 66 77 64 | a 83 TS 83 83 July 41 . 77 60 I 46 66 83 97 66 68 81 73 75 114 106 93 97 122 93 106 120 120 317 309 313 290 I Am. 64 87 87 71 79 71 77 126 112 99 100 124 118 131 129 133 415 315 347 241 66 88 58 76 81 ■ 89 126 104 93 97 126 126 124 114 136 351 299 290 ZVZ I 78 39 41 56 89 81 60 75 73 64 93 106 ■ 75 120 112 129 118 100 141 280 241 241 145 42 90 • j. 54 ■ 68 ■ 77 r.\ 62 106 91 97 71 116 85 116 102 100 144 280 251 241 120 IK 110 am 50 106 58 :,■_&gt; 60 61) 56 77 90 102 66 102 68 118 97 100 145 270 261 251 97 46 113 | —I — 1 —I — I — I l I l I ' I </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 IMIK\ M'MIIKRS OF CORN PRICES The average monthly price of corn at Columbus in 1913 was 52.4 cents which is the 100 base of the index numbers. Each quotation given was divided by 52 to obtain its index number. Because the index numbers for all commodities (Table 1) are given by years only for the 1877-1889 period and by quar - ters for the 1890-1899 period, the index numbers for corn, and also for wheat and oats as given in Tables 6 and 7 have been reduced to the same basis. The index number for 1877 for example, is the average for the year. The index numbers for corn and the index numbers for all commodities must be for identical periods in order to determine the purchasing power of corn at that particular time as is done in Table 8. The total of all quotations given in Table 5 if it were com - pleted by months would be 552. Of this number the index was above 100 for 121 quotations, or less than 22 per cent of the time. From 1900 to the end of 1922 the index was above 100 for 118 of the 276 quotations or 44.8 per cent of the time. The fact that the index number of corn was below 100 for the major portion of the 1877-1922 period is not an indi - cation that corn was not a profitable crop. It is simply a com - parison of prices with the average in 1913, and shows that corn was higher in 1913 than during the major portion of the period under study. In order to determine the purchasing power of corn at any time we must find the relation between the index number of corn and the index number of other com - modities. This is given in Table 8. In order to determine the profitableness of corn at any time, we must know the cost of production. The purchasing power gives of course some indication of profitableness, be - cause there is a very direct relationship between cost of pro - duction and the general price level of commodities. On the other hand, the purchasing power of corn may be very high, but because of crop failure the farmer may be buying corn instead of selling. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 187 Table »'..— / „,/,.,■ number* »f •rh.at prhm I!&gt;U=1O&lt;&gt;. Im I 112 74 77 I | I • Ywi Jan. F«b. Umr. April I May B '"n" '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'. w '.:::'■ tSM 7« 70 H W &lt;7 1 S97 84 81 1«M M Ht I H 7» 1900 70 63 66 70 67 1901 71 74 76 7* 76 lMt 80 88 81 76 77 i:«M 69 73 I 75 76 76 1904 81 82 108 100 94 1*06 124 128 128 119 100 1906 93 89 85 85 89 1907 77 82 82 81 82 1908 lit , 112 ■ 111 108 I 117 1909 120 120 121 140 135 1910 135 130 136 132 128 19)11 111 107 101 98 105 1912 123 126 123 126 132 1913 98 104 108 108 j 104 1914 98 99 108 104 I 103 1915 147 i 189 ITS 186 | 18S 1916 139 I 161 I 121 139 136 1917 236 I 209 I 239 283 386 1918 270 277 277 277 ! 277 1919 290 I 281 283 323 331 1980 SSI I 810 310 317 371 1921 203 182 198 170 165 1922 120 1S6 141 144 ISO June i 73 81 77 92 109 89 107 115 158 108 103 132 106 104 151 121 331 277 290 351 181 142 July Ti I 78 72 78 85 76 81 8t 92 105 89 101 105 115 116 102 121 101 82 142 117 HI 7 277 290 H1 132 122 ; A«&gt;. I 81 81 99 96 73 90 107 120 119 103 110 97 105 166 161 361 273 277 304 132 116 i 8, 124 T_&gt; 77 107 116 ' 116 121 107 105 •«■ 126 124 172 270 277 277 306 1S2 m Oct. 71 78 74 74 I 132 96 77 112 111 124 115 126 104 97 118 121 203 270 270 277 261 117 116 77 76 74 81 128 91 77 108 113 13 1 106 117 103 90 134 121 229 270 27 1 297 2;6 113 132 ft. 71 ■ 67 80 119 96 7!l 112 117 127 112 117 96 97 132 124 2O9 270 271 310 189 121 130 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains 21 INOKX M MltKltS OF WHEAT The average price paid for wheat by the Columbus eleva - tors for the year 1913 was 74 cents. This price is therefore used as the base for the index numbers and equals 100. Each quotation is divided by 74 to reduce it to the 1913 level. The index number of wheat was below 100 for the major portion of the time preceding 1913, and above 100 from March, 1914 to December, 1922. Wheat has therefore been relatively higher than corn since 1913, providing that the 1913 price was a normal price for both grains. It is not surprising that wheat has been relatively higher, because of the effect of the large European demand for wheat and the unusually large corn crops in 1921 and 1922. The high price in the last half of 1904 and first 7 months of 1905 was due to the small crop of 1904, the yield in that season falling below 600,000,000 bushels for the first time since 1896. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">r Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 187 Table 7.— Index number* of oat prism 1014= loo. ,^_-^. ______________ rtm .1 mill m s 1880 111 1881 102 i an io&amp; 1883 77 1884 59 1885 56 1886 49 1887 69 1888 65 iaw 46 T«r Jan. Feb. Mar. April May June July Au«. Sac*.' Oct. Nov. 1S*O »7 48 65 ... 102 1891 1P2 117 80 tt .. 1892 71 62 71 9 . I M 74 74 68 62 «t 68 108 M 18*5 105 M 77 M 1896 I 31 40 31 .n 1ST? 43 87 56 V&gt; ISM 49 66 52 56 18»9 80 71 62 56 1900 I 56 i 56 56 62 ■ M ■ ■ Vi 56 56 1901 56 62 « 68 68 71 93 98 99 99 102 1902 12:1 123 114 106 108 l'»« I(|8 111 68 71 8* 1903 71 77 77 77 80 108 93 77 80 8i 80 1904 77 86 102 99 99 at 9:1 80 71 6* 71 1908 ; 71 71 71 71 77 77 77 62 56 66 62 1906 71 71 71 74 80 83 9:t 74 80 80 80 1907 77 86 99 102 105 120 108 108 , 142 148 170 1908 127 130 123 123 131) 138 12:1 12» 127 117 114 19»9 127 127 139 142 145 161 108 96 96 96 99 1910 111 123 120 108 106 86 80 86 83 74 71 1911 77 77 71 74 77 86 108 105 108 123 123 1»12 123 136 139 142 157 142 132 71 83 83 83 1*18 86 93 tt | 93 102 102 101 106 108 111 102 1M4 106 115 106 105 105 105 93 102 117 111 12:1 1116 127 142 I 133 I 148 136 120 108 99 80 80 86 ltl« 102 120 105 105 108 99 99 102 HIS 123 133 1*17 142 139 151 185 201 201 194 201 157 161 176 1*18 222 238 250 244 210 188 188 176 191 185 185 1»19 201 !79 179 216 216 216 216 210 182 179 191 IMS 228 231 238 256 296 293 302 191 167 13:1 127 1921 99 8.1 W 77 i 74 86 74 6H 62 62 59 IKS 66 | 84 91 88 94 91 88 72 70 97 112 Dae 56 117 68 77 71 68 80 123 123 99 77 12.) 8'l 1".-, 120 102 139 207 185 2117 111 62 119 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains 23 IMIKX MMIiKIIS OF OATS A relatively small proportion of the farm income in the major portion of Nebraska is secured from the sale of oats. They are raised primarily for feed. Oats also fit well into the crop rotation commonly used in Nebraska, and are put out at a time when other farm work is not pressing. They are an important cash crop in a few counties where wheat does not do well, and rank third among grains in the number of bushels sold within the state. It has therefore seemed worth while to include them in this study. The same method of obtaining the index number was followed as for corn and wheat. HOW TO COMITTK l»l IUHASIXG POWER The purchasing power of the farmer can be determined by comparing the index numbers of farm products with the index numbers of all commodities. The purchasing power of corn, for example, is found by dividing the price index of that grain by the index number of wholesale prices at a given time. This method does not give an absolutely accurate index of the purchasing power of a commodity which has risen or fallen very rapidly in price compared with other commodities. For example, if wheat should suffer a marked decline in price its decline would have a slight effect on the "all commodities" index. The purchasing power of wheat measured in things that the farmer buys would therefore be a little less than indicated by comparing the index price of wheat with the index price of all commodities. This actually happened in 1920 when the price of farm products fell to a much lower level than did the price of manu - factured goods. The purchasing power of grains when meas - ured in commodities that the farmer buys is therefore not quite as great as is indicated in Tables 8, 9, and 10. The number of commodities used as a base is, however, so large that the resulting discrepancy is very slight. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">ix 8. — Purchtwiny potter of torn nt Columbus, Xebnixka: 1877-1922 1 . Ta, I I Anme Arerafe I 60 2? 41 69 M 51 71 ■ 1 i ', T I i i i ; ; I _. I I .. . I i J«n. F»fc. limr. I April I May Jim July j Aag. h*. Oet Not. D*. M I M j 51 i»~77 : 91 116 M §7 8 :::::::::::: S :::::::::::: S ::.: S :: .5! :::::::::::: »S £ 'II :: 34 4i 3* . . . . SI 32 W 4t 40 .. 4« M « H 61 64 « U 48 49 52 71 71 70 8S 68 71 69 67 61 6» | 65 70 81 81 77 1(&gt;4 107 110 110 US 13:1 129 122 118 104 118 115 117 105 M 95 80 71 60 63 63 51 67 , 80 82 85 86 72 70 62 65 68 80 88 87 808083 M M 92 72 72 75 75 7» 82 84 94 92 93 SS 82 70 82 81 «1 67 71 71 ' 81 78 72 69 66 59 56 61 j 60 56 64 j 80 78 79 12 98 11:1 80 91 97 100 110 118 I 115 127 140 140 118 100 100 9» 103 113 ! 114 117 129 114 118 109 96 99 110 106 | 102 j 94 87 98 90 96 102 ', 96 78 74 68 «» «7 66 | 70 83 87 101 104 101 125 121 119 119 119 110 ! 122 134 128 123 124 i 126 112 85 68 77 76 ■ 88 99 95 93 117 124 128 115 119 110 107 107 | 118 118 117 106 128 119 104 99 109 99 126 111 97 119 ! 119 11&lt;&gt; 129 115 99 97 94 86 I 87 » I 90 96 94 94 108 I 106 105 101 99 10* 102 106 ISO 155 140 170 224 192 155 15.1 148 ISO 145 160 187 147 125 156 156 144 118 122 127 1SJ 122 126 147 144 147 143 1S4 132 108 105 105 97 91 99 102 US 120 111 96 96 64 58 51 44 43 55 42 44 52 43 43 36 28 31 SO M 44 U 61 M 55 58 57 M S8 71 71 'Purchasing power U calculated by dividing the price indpx of cirr. (.Table 5i by the inde» r at all commodities (Table 1 1 for the corresponding time. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Pl'HCHAHINO POWKR OF CORN Table 8 shows the purchasing power of corn from 1877 to December, 1922. As has already been explained, the year 1913 is used as a base in finding the index numbers of corn and all other commodities. Since the purchasing power of corn is found by dividing the index number of corn by the index number of all commodities the average purchasing power of corn for 1913 is 100. When the index number of other commodities is high and of corn low, the purchasing power of corn is low, but when corn has a relatively higher index number than other commodities its purchasing power is above normal. Any number less than 100 indicates that at that time corn had a lower purchasing power than in 1913, and a number above 100 indicates a purchasing power greater than in 1913. The purchasing power of corn was low during nearly all of the early years presented in this table because the produc - tion of corn had increased more rapidly than the demand. Corn Production (Reported by U. S. Census) Bushels At no time preceding 1870 was there so great an over - production of any cereal, measured in bushels, as there was of corn in the 3 decades beginning about 1870. The Homestead Act, the ease with which the western prairies could be broken up, and the rapid improvement in farm machinery were 3 of the more important causes contributing to this rapid increase. Corn, was low in price everywhere and particularly low in Nebraska because of the cost of transporting it to eastern markets. Most of the early settlers were interested in home owning. They accepted the hardships of pioneer life and the low exchange value of their products in the hope that later years would bring prosperity. The 1890 corn crop was cut short by drought explains the high purchasing power of corn from October of that year until October, 1891 ; few farmers had corn for sale 1869 1879 1889 1899 1909...... 1919 760,940,000 1,754,592,000 2,122.328,000 2,666,324,000. 2,552,190,000 2,917,450,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 187 and many were compelled to buy corn for feed. In 1894 the corn crop was again cut short by drought which naturally stimulated the price. The average yield in Nebraska was only 6 bushels per acre, so the high purchasing power of the 1894 crop brought hardship instead of prosperity to Nebraska farmers. They were buying corn for feed and seed instead of exchanging a surplus for other products. The high pur - chasing power during the later months of 1901 and the major portion of 1902 was likewise due to the partial failure of the crop. The price was good, but few men had a surplus. The high purchasing power in 1908 was due to the in - creased consumption of corn which was caused by a greatly increased hog production. Hog production as a result became less profitable than selling corn and the lowered purchasing power in the major portion of 1910 was due to a decrease in the number of hogs. Hogs rose in price in 1910, and the rise stimulated their production and the consumption of corn, which accounts for the rise in purchasing power in the fall of 1911 and continuing through nearly all of 1912. The demand for pork and pork products was stimulated by the war and this naturally increased the demand for corn. The price rose more rapidly than did the price of most other products so that in August, 1917, when but little corn was being marketed by farmers, it had a purchasing power nearly two and a fourth times the average purchasing power in 1913. The facts are* that relatively few farmers sold any large amount of corn when it was very high in price. The corn was fed to hogs and the hogs sold at a price which returned to the farmers less than the market price of corn. When deflation began in 1920 corn dropped in price more rapidly than did manufactured goods and this decrease con - tinued during 1921. As a result a bushel of corn had the lowest purchasing power in October, 1921 that it has had at any time since 1877. The price was lower at many other times, most notably in 1896 and 1897, but there is no record available which shows that Nebraska farmers could purchase less goods with a bushel of corn then than in the later months of 1921. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains 27 Wheat has always been regarded as a profitable crop in the Columbus area. The soil is well adapted to wheat raising and market conditions have been favorable for the disposal of the crop. As will be seen by comparing Tables 8 and 9, wheat had a much higher purchasing power in the early years compared with 1913 than did corn. This does not prove that the wheat acreage near Columbus should have been greatly increased by the pioneers. The spring wheat of those years was a lower yielding and a much more precarious crop than the winter wheat of today. Greater improvements in wheat production have been made during the last 40 years than in corn production. Wheat was also rela - tively lower in 1913, which we are using as a base, than was corn, and this gives it a relatively higher purchasing power during the other years included in the table. Wheat shows neither such wide nor such rapid fluctuations in price as does corn. One reason for this is that the production in the United States does not show such variation as does the production of corn. Crop failure is apparently a little less of a menace. Another reason is that wheat is used largely for human food while corn is used largely for feeding livestock and the num - ber of people to be fed does not fluctuate nearly as rapidly as does the number of livestock. A third reason is that wheat is a world crop and the price in America is gauged quite largely by world supply and world demand. We are an export nation and in short crop years we have less for export. The European buyer will not bid up the price very high because he prefers either to buy wheat grown in some other country which may have a good crop, or else to substitute some other food. During the war the price of wheat was under Federal control and this kept it from reaching as high a level as it would have been forced by demand. The wheat grower was one of the very few producers whose selling price was reg - ulated by government action. IH'IM'HASIM. IfNVKIt OK WHKAT </seg>
            <seg id="p028">ibi,k !l. — Purchminy pnrrr of wheat &lt;it ColumbuM, Xebraska: JS77-19J". Tv I ■r Avance IM 10« IM 1M 120 118 1*4 87 90 95 M 111 104 i ii. i i ; : ; : ■r 1mm. ftfc. Mr. Ayfl Urn, J»ne July W- 8^. | Ort. M W .jp&gt;, 80 ' 7T M I tss 105 lit 114 U t •■■ &gt;S :::::::::::: ,2 :::::::::: j j 87 MM 84 n i» 116 iu : ui 1&lt;* IM 116 N '"it " "it ' "n' 85 82 88 106 101 95 90 95 9U 91 92 K M M 91 91 90 91 91 93 95 98 107 99 91 92 96 101 96 87 87 87 Ml 80 85 89 92 90 *i 101 96 101 98 M 95 98 96 127 120 112 111 111 12(1 149 159 152 141 1« 151 1S1 142 119 128 122 112 HH&gt; 109 106 111 104 99 90 90 99 9S 99 80 So HI *t SH 86 i 85 81 85 111. 105 93 110 108 105 117 128 122 122 110 ISO 128 118 119 128 1SS 124 128 ISO 130 ; 1S1 151 146 170 124 126 122 128 137 137 138 ! 1S3 ' 136 1S5 1S2 111 119 123 125 120 109 US 117 ; 112 j 95 114 111 108 107 107 101 131 122 122 128 130 126 IM 133 133 122 109 105 104 103 9« 98 104 101 105 106 105 104 9A 96 96 89 98 98 101 104 10« 105 105 82 102 121 120 1H7 135 148 187 172 I 186 183 156 140 155 125 120 107 117 116 135 106 119 104 102 98 125 134 150 159 143 156 184 148 165 202 178 170 197 148 149 148 148 141 ( 149 I 148 146 146 143 140 1:14 1:14 1:12 13:) IU 143 ; 144 1 141 160 160 140 133 123 126 124 129 IM S3 124 I 123 120 136 131 127 121 126 116 114 100 116 109 119 111 IM 124 09 87 87 79 76 81 87 M M 101 108 95 79 76 71 75 M 83 : ; : ' I I 1 1 1 'ParchMinn power n calculated hy dividing the pric-r index of wheat (Table 6 1 by the 1* number o[ all commuditie* (Table 1 1 for the correnpundinK period. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains 29 THi; I'l IM'HASINU POWEB OF OATS The purchasing power of oats is much more uniform than is the purchasing power of corn and was affected by the war far less than either corn or wheat. Their price and purchas - ing power were increased in the years when Nebraska had a short crop such as 1890, 1894, and 1901. Two short crop years, 1907 and 1908, came in succession, and as a result, altho the 1909 crop was good, the purchasing power remained above 100 until the 1910 crop was maturing. The farmers were maintaining a reserve. As has already been stated, the war increased the demand for pork which in turn increased the demand for corn. The need for human food increased the demand for wheat. These two grains rose in price and purchasing power as has been shown in preceding tables. Oats are used but little either for human food or for hog feed, and therefore the demand re - mained nearly constant and the purchasing power was below the 1913 level during the major portion of the war. Oats had the lowest purchasing power during the last 4 months of 1921 of any time in the past 46 years. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Table 10.— Purfhinnuy power of oats &lt;it Columbus, Xebriuka: 1877-1&amp;JJ 1 . ■B ! 8 72 78 I 1 _J I 1mm. Tmb. Mar. April J«ay June July A«(. g«pt. O*. Nor. ! *r 48 M 81 127 146 108 77 » at mm 9t t7 »1 83 (0 SO 158 ISO 158 187 US (8 JS :::::::::::: 8 S g 74 *7 77 82 11« •».... 83 72 67 I M 66 73 75 68 76 61 «t 68 68 67 «» 77 80 88 86 89 115 111 122 120 124 146 151 1S1 139 118 129 12» 186 117 79 8.1 97 81 82 87 87 93 95 129 11! 92 96 100 97 91 93 102 120 119 118 111 111 96 89 81 81 84 98 83 83 84 91 91 89 71 63 76 7(1 79 78 79 79 81 89 91 1(12 82 88 88 87 88 81 90 102 106 109 125 112 HI 1 lfi 1S5 181 129 136 140 135 139 144 148 137 1.17 142 130 126 129 188 138 151 153 156 162 116 101 In! 99 101 106 113 128 124 160 108 89 82 89 86 77 74 79 81 81 , 74 78 79 91 114 110 114 128 128 128 127 140 I 142 | 142 159 III 1M 7 1 83 83 83 83 86 93 94 95 104 102 102 104 106 110 108 106 105 96 98 107 107 96 93 99 112 112 125 122 128 141 134 , 148 134 121 107 99 81 77 83 96 93 i 107 97 90 91 83 83 M 82 ,92 92 95 94 89 94 107 110 109 107 110 86 89 96 114 120 128 134 128 110 96 95 97 92 91 90 90 99 91 89 106 104 104 99 93 83 80 83 87 92 93 94 97 109 109 115 97 70 59 62 59 56 50 61 60 49 , 58 50 45 41 41 89 42 48 « 64 62 63 j 61 SO 46 46 63 72 76 ' ' I I I I I I I I I I &gt;Purehaan( power n calculated by dividing the price index of oaU (TaMe 7) by the index number of all commodities (Table 1 1 for the corresponding period. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 (-HAKT NO. 1 AVBHAI.K VK.4HL1 IMH:\ M MBKKS OK &lt;&lt;&gt;I1V WHEAT, OATS, AMU 41.1. IIIMMIHIIIII&gt; The yearly average index of corn, wheat, or oats fluctuates much more than the index of all commodities used by the Bureau of Labor. This is only natural since the index num - bers of any one commodity will show a greater fluctuation than will the average of a large number of commodities. In Chart 1 the heavy dark line shows the yearly level of all commodities. This line does not show any sharp deviation in any direction, except during the period 1916-1922. Since so many commodity prices are included in the aggregate index (238 for most of the period and 404 at the present time) a change in price of any one of them would not cause a notice - able change in the line. Corn shows a greater deviation from the all commodities line than does either wheat or oats. The reason for this has been discussed on preceding pages but figures do not make the contrast quite as striking as does the graphic chart. Thruout all the years wheat kept fairly close to the all commodity line until war demand and the short crop sent it up in the spring and summer of 1917. At present it is much nearer the all commodity line than is either corn or oats. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 1 3 i 77.----- _ 51 I I 7c I ■o c OS : &lt; 1 I OQ i ■ ■ / I | | | c c I _.,- I • •j 1 s 3 c i c i y T I I e I +-^— 1 ; *'K ; I ■ A A V 1 i — ! d • 6 I X J-- 1 i a t ? | I </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 CHART NO. 2 rill(lll«IM, PVWKK UK OOHX, WHKAT AND OAT* In preparing the chart showing the purchasing power of corn, wheat and oats over a period of 44 years, it has been necessary to divide the chart into 2 parts because of the many points to be shown. To best determine whether the purchas - ing power of any of the grains has been high or low it is necessary to compare them to the heavy line in the chart which indicates the purchasing power of 100, or 100 per cent. At this point a dollar's worth of corn, wheat or oats will exchange for a dollar's worth of "all other commodities," all prices being based on the average for the year 1913. These 3 staple crops had much greater purchasing power from 1901 to 1920 in - clusive than from 1877 to 1900. Their purchasing power, particularly corn and oats, is now low. In studying this chart one cannot help but wonder what will be the future trend of the index lines. Following the Civil War they were low for many years, as evidenced on the first page of Chart 2. A chart of the years from 1815 to 1830 shows that similar conditions followed the Napoleonic Wars. Have other conditions so changed that the farmer can hope that his present period of low purchasing power will be shorter than the 2 noteworthy periods which followed preceding wars? On this question hinges the general prosperity of the Corn Belt farmer. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">■ i ,- J ; L b r i c 5 r~ U Q 1 -"&gt;* Q s. z i \ B x P 4- -, 3 —t — — . ? il rt-k ! !i V 0 I V 7 5 h i z± I i I £ 1 * i ; ■ I ? i - ..- i i ', I % i i t « i i I s ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 I ■ I: M- i I i - — i •&lt;=g j — 1 i.l~ , — i : -h \- — r o -I i * -^j&lt; .« « i_ H '"I. -• -t h- ? — =a 444 h: -VZ: --.' c *■— . =F V- ■z K ±j I + H- 4- -- r t- -• J \ I £ i_ • I '--: ■-: w\ ? I - (:- I V—^ 1 I 5J Cl I ! t- Ji t ■^ . ;:.,' = o i. &lt;3 i P I- PI i -\ I -i C- h i 3 "8 I T -h T" *^- ■+H 2 * tJ i 8 l -= « » 8 « I L_ I • </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>