<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-second Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the Nebraska School for the Blind</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OP NEBRASKA Twenty-second Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska School for the Blind NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">492 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND, NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND N. C. Abbott Superintendent Lillian Abbott Matron William S. Yager Physician E. C. Cook High School Clark Bruce Tuning and Boys' Industrial Tensie E. Johnson Prhn\ry Lillie Bischof Organ and Advanced 'iano Lri.v Rabex Violin, Piano, and Orchestra Kate M. Freeman Intermediate Fannie Bone Girls' Industrial Jennie Hughey Supervisor Fbances Harrington Supervisor Mart E. Cook Typewriting </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OP COMMISSIONERS 433 NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND, NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA To hi» Excellency, Honorable Keith Xeville, Governor, and to the Honorable Members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Henry Gerdes, Silas A. Holcomb, and Eugene O. Mayfield. Gentlemen: It is my pleasure at this time, complying with the laws of the State and your special instructions, to submit this, the twenty-second biennial report of this institution, and the fourth which I have had the honor to prepare. The period covered is from December 1, 1916, to November 30, 1918. inclusive. This biennium in a way has been a critical one for us, as it has undoubtedly been for all of the state insti - tutions under your supervision, due to the entry of our nation into the War for Humanity. On the one hand, our attendance has been greater on the average than for many previous like periods (though just now it is about normal) and on the other the cost of necessities has gone far beyopd our expectation when estimates and appropriations for the biennium were made. For us to give the wards of the State entrusted to our keeping proper instruction, proper food, and proper care in general and at the same time not to plunge the tax-payers of the State into a deep deficiency has been a serious problem. A deficiency of some degree has been unavoidable, though every effort has been made to keep it as low as possible. This has been highly regrettable, since it is the first time in the history of the school that it has not kept within the appropriations made by the legis - lature. Of course it has been due to the unexpected in - crease all along the line, for salaries and wages paid and in the cost of necessities — this increase amounting in some cases to more than one hundred per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">494 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF For convenience in following this report I have arranged the matter under the following headings: A. PHYSICAL CONDITIONS B. PROGRESS OF THE SCHOOL C. FUTURE PLANS D. RELIEF OF THE BUND FUND E. STATISTICAL TABLES A. PHYSICAL CONDITIONS The beginning of this biennium found our plant in good physical condition — in as good condition as any public institution could well be expected to be found part of which is over forty years old and the larger part of which is almost thirty years old. We had planned on fresh paint - ing of all of the buildings on our campus during the first summer of the biennium; but due to the high cost of paint and labor it was deemed wise when the time arrived to postpone this until a later period, particularly as the prop - erty would not suffer materially by the delay. The largest improvements have been effected in con - nection with our engine-room. The pit and boiler-room have been enlarged, leveled, and equipped with scales and a small coal-wagon, so that a proper recording of the ef - ficiency of the plant may be kept up according to the instructions of the Board's consulting engineer, Mr. C. O. Martz. In order to relieve the heavy pushing of ashes from before the boilers into the road — a distance of approxi - mately thirty feet, up a twelve-foot incline — there has been erected a steam ash ejector that throws out the accumu - lated ashes of half a day in approximately five minutes even in the coldest weather. Thus far the apparatus has not been tested for a great length of time, being accepted only a few weeks ago, but the present indications are that it will prove satisfactory. Another substantial repair has been the laying of new roofs on the old east wing of the main building, on the barn, and on several of the smaller buildings. A heavy fir shingle, properly dipped, was laid by day labor under </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 495 the direction of the superintendent. This has proved on the whole satisfactory, though small leaks are inclined to develop after every heavy wind and rain storm. Aside from these two repairs of consequence, there has been only the routine business of keeping up the prop - erty, such as an ordinarily prudent man would attend to, even in the stress of war, to prevent deterioration. Plumb - ing, plastering, painting, fencing, small jobs of carpentry — all as approved by you from time to time have been looked after, but are not worthy of more than passing mention. In speaking of the material conditions, as improved, I must not fail to mention the furniture manufactured by the State Penitentiary. In the reception room wicker chairs, table, desk, settee, and stand have been installed which add very materially to the attractiveness of this general room. Visitors are usually invited to wait in this room while at the school and I am very sure the impression carried away by them is much more favorable than it was formerly. An oak filing-cabinet for our office, made accord - ing to drawings prepared here, has lightened the work in the office greatly. A serious loss to the institution in the way of in - convenience, though not much in a money way, was the burning of our old ice-house, which had for many years been used for storage of coal, kindling, and coarse salt, on the night of March 5, 1918. It was discovered on fire shortly after eight and for a time the flames threatened our main building. The fire undoubtedly was caused by electric light wires strung across the cupola which in a strong wind were whipped loose from their glass insulations and pounding together and against the shingle roof brought about a short in connection at the same time with the wood. While the gale was heavy it fortunately was from the north-west, which carried the sparks as well as the intense heat between the gymnasium and the main build - ing. For more than an hour we feared that we might lose either or both of these structures. Now this fire would have been extinguished in short </seg>
            <seg id="p006">496 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF order because students assisted me promptly and in good form in the laying of hose and turning on of the hydrants, had the pressure not failed us. For thirty years, or there - about, the State has been paying for fire-protection — the total amount reaching several thousands of dollars — and as soon as the institution needed some pressure, it failed absolutely. For minutes that seemed hours we were unable to get a stream above the small doors and then it was scarcely more than a trickle. Our pleading over the tele - phone to the engineer at the plant brought only the assur - ance that he would not violate his orders and give stronger pressure lest he break the mains down town. Fortunately he finally did put on a little more pressure and with the assistance of the local fire department which had responded promptly to our call for aid, the fire was extinguished. You, gentlemen, upon my showing, visited the insti - tution and made careful tests with me, and confirmed what I had already ascertained that we had been without ade - quate fire protection. The officers of the company made the tests with me and came to the same conclusion. They promised relief and though the work has not yet been done, on account of war conditions, I am satisfied from their correspondence with us — their letters and your replies pass - ing through this office — that they will at the earliest possible moment give us the needed relief. The gentlemen now in charge of the company appear straightforward business men who realize their responsibility under the company's agree - ment with the State. B. PROGRESS OF THE SCHOOL More important, far more important, is the work car - ried on here for the benefit of our blind and defective - sighted pupils than the physical conditions under which we live. I shall describe this training under: 1. Regular Departments and 2. Supplemental Activities. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 497 1. Regular Departments The school work is carried through three depart - ments, — Literary, Musical, and Industrial, — all working to - gether harmoniously for the bringing out of the best in each individual. The pupils in attendance range in age from five to sixty and from those totally blind to others whose eye-sight is so poor that they cannot attend the common schools, though they may attend to many duties as well as any sighted person. Literary Department The Grades. Teachers, Jennie B. Johnson and Kate M. Freeman. Every effort is made in this department to promote self-reliance and independence on the part of each pupil as well as to give the same amount of book knowledge with its proper application as is expected or required in the corre - sponding grade of the common school. Methods of recitation are employed which develop conversational and speaking power, and also require the pupil to think while speaking. The most advanced educators of the blind, on account of natural conditions, are inclined to less writing than among seeing children of the same classification. It is fair to add that the blind child speaks as a rule much more fluently than his sighted brother. English in the Grades — Purpose. In the teaching of this subject our aim is identical with that of instructors in schools for the sighted, namely: to train pupils to think; to enlarge and enrich their vocabulary, that they may express themselves clearly and effectively; to establish right habits of speech ; to cultivate a desire for, and an appreciation of the best in literature. Methods. Neither do our methods differ wholly from those commonly employed in the common schools. The Course of Study for Elementary Schools of Nebraska and other text books in current use serve as guides. The latter being in embossed type, lessons are assigned in the ordinary manner and studied at a time specified. When it is desired that an exercise be written, pupils prepare the work either </seg>
            <seg id="p008">498 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF in New York Point (the puntographic tactile system now used in our school) or on the typewriter. In the lower grades our little people dramatize and reproduce the stories read or told to them with as much enthusiasm as is ex - hibited by any group of children. Throughout all the grades great stress is laid upon oral English, in the teaching of which the socialized recitation is the principal method em - ployed. Language and Spelling Correlated. All written work in every grade is carefully gone over.. Misspelled words are marked and the papers returned to the pupils, who are re - quired to write the troublesome words until their correct forms are learned. In addition, the Rational Spelling Book, by Dr. J. M. Rice, which is in embossed type, is called into service, each grade studying the book especially designed for that particular year. A portion of the recitation period in English is devoted to this sort of exercise. Value of English to the Blind. No subject in our cur - riculum is of greater importance than English. Blindness is unquestionably a handicap, alike in the social and in the business world. If to lack of sight is added lack of culture, then is the handicap double. The individual whose speech is a direct violation of the most common forms habitually used by good speakers and writers finds himself at great disadvantage when he seeks admission to social circles, since foremost among the requisites of refined so - ciety is elegance of manner and speech. In the business world, too, a practical knowledge of English stands the blind man or woman in good stead. If it is a position that is sought, the applicant is judged by the manner in which his request finds expression, whether verbal or written. The letter which bristles with misspelled words and faulty English creates anything but a favorable impression and fails to win the coveted place. Great effort is therefore made to familiarize our pupils with letter forms commonly used to give them such practice in the writing of the same as will enable them to make any desired communication in a creditable and approved manner. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 499 Tactile Reading and Writing. Disadvantages of diverse systems. For many years there have been in existence several varieties of tactile print, a description of each of which space here forbids. It is desired merely to call attention to the disadvantages of such a situation. In order to accommodate readers of all systems there has been much duplication, thus greatly limiting the scope of em - bossed literature. There has also been caused considerable inconvenience to pupils, who, due to the removal of parents or guardians from one state to another, have been com - pelled to enter another school, where, as was formerly frequently the case, they have had to learn a new system, a deplorable circumstance proving a marked hindrance in the pursuit of other subjects. Uniform Type. At last the unfortunate situation came under the consideration of the National Association of In - structors of the Blind and the National Association of Work - ers for the Blind. After much agitation and investigation it was unanimously decided that a uniform system should be adopted, and a revised form of English Braille was chosen. This action marks a great step forward in the education of the blind. Plan of Introduction. This new code will be intro - duced into the schools so gradually that it will cause no appreciable waste of time or apparatus. At the outset it will be taught only to beginners, advancing a grade each year as the pupils advance. In schools carrying the full twelve grades (our own being one of this number) the transition period will, obviously, approximate twelve years. As our bulky books, when in daily use, do not long remain intact — this being one of the factors in the heavy cost of educating the sightless — there is frequent need for re - placement. The transition period will, therefore, be of suf - ficient length to enable us to make all possible use of the books we now have, replacing them, when worn out, with those printed in Revised Braille. Present Situation in Our School. Although we have hitherto used New York Point, we have fallen in line with </seg>
            <seg id="p010">500 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF the other institutions throughout the country and are gladly doing our part toward establishing a single system. Our little beginners are being taught to read Revised Braille. In this connection the marble board is proving most helpful, for the making of which we are most gratefully indebted to Mr. Clark Bruce, head of the Industrial Department. This device consists of a board, ten by sixteen inches, into which holes have been bored in such locations, as re - lated to each other, that the marbles, when placed in them, represent the characters constituting the Braille alphabet. As yet we have not begun instruction in Braille writing, but this is deferred only until such time as we may obtain the kind of slates desired. Reading. In this, as in other subjects, the work is graded. The child that is normal, save as to sight, usually completes the primer and first reader during his initial year. An effort is made to train pupils to read under - standingly and expressively. This aim is more difficult of achievement than in the case of the sighted child. The latter readily takes in at a glance a word or group of words, whereas he who reads by touch can, with the tip of his finger, covers only a character or two at a time. Despite this fact some of our pupils become excellent readers. Although our classes are organized primarily for children, and with their instruction in mind, any adult de - sirous of learning to read, is given an opportunity. At present a blind-deaf-dumb man is learning to read, as well as to write. Guy Parkhill lost his hearing many years before his sight and received his early education at the Iowa School for the Deaf. Since blindness overtook him his means of communicating with the outside world and of making himself useful have been reduced to a minimum. Miss Johnson learned of his case, and with rare devotion sug - gested that we try to assist this young man, though possibly our school might not be expected to handle the case. While he reads with one hand, he spells out the words in the deaf and dumb manual with the other. Since Miss Johnson is herself totally blind she is compelled to follow the move- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 501 ments of his fingers by the sense of touch alone. All of the pupils are encouraged to read as many as possible of the tactile books found in our institution library. This year the younger boys and girls are indulging in a contest as to who will have read the greatest number of supple - mental books in the course of the year. Arithmetic. The work in the grades is under the direc - tion of Mrs. Freeman and Miss Bone. The latter, though primarily employed in the industrial work, has been drafted for two classes of Arithmetic which she handles to the satisfaction of all. This work is almost exclusively oral, the results of problems usually being written in either type or point. While fewer problems are assigned for an exer - cise than in a sighted grade, the work is undoubtedly more intensive and therefore results fully as satisfactory are obtained. On the whole it may be said that the blind child becomes more proficient in the arithmetical operations because of the concentration spoken of and independence from paper and pencil. Geography. — The room where geography is taught is equipped with globe and maps in relief, by means of which form and comparative areas may be studied. While ordi - nary drill work is not neglected, stories of travel from geographical readers and elsewhere are read aloud which they afterward reproduce in their puntographic system, thereby gaining a very clear idea of the countries studied. History. Much attention at the present time is devoted to current history. The pupils take a lively interest in the stirring events that have been published from day to &gt; day and their patriotism is as intense and high-keyed as that of pupils in any school for sighted. Discussion, argumen - tation, and persistent reviewing impress the history of the past indelibly upon their memories. Physiology. More attention is given to hygiene than to any other itf»ase of this subject. However, physiology proper and the simpler and more general aspects of </seg>
            <seg id="p012">502 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF anatomy receive their share of attention; so that a graduate from our eighth grade is well prepared for an intensive or detailed examination in the study so far as it is carried. The High School. Teacher, E. C. Cook. We have no rigid course of study. Each year the needs and wishes of the pupils then present are carefully considered and the work is organized to meet the actual current demand. During the biennium instruction has been given in the following subjects: Rhetoric, English Literature, American Literature, Beginner's Latin, Caesar, Algebra, Geometry, Physics, Chemistry, Economics, Salesmanship, Ancient His - tory, Modern History, English History, American History, and Civics. Purpose. Our primary object is to fit the student for life. We do not neglect, however, to encourage higher education and to provide adequate preparation for college. Every subject is made practical and vital, and is treated as a means, the ends being character combined with power of thought and expression. The college records and life careers of our best graduates attest the breadth and thorough - ness of our work. Mathematics. This course comprises the usual three semesters of algebra and three of geometry. The student reads with his fingers from embossed books, which are exact reprints of standard texts. He projects his opera - tions and diagrams on a mental blackboard and recites with ease and accuracy, thus proving that he has acquired all which the seeing do, and the power to think without a pencil besides. In no other subject is his handicap more completely overcome. Science. This course comprises two semesters of general science, two of physics, and two of chemistry. The mathematical and theoretical side of the subject is taught with unusual thoroughness, to compensate for any deficiency on the laboratory side. A large per cent of our pupils have partial sight, so that by going slowly they may follow an experiment. Even those totally blind, thoroughly grounded </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 503 beforehand, with explanations of each step in the experi - ment get sufficient to give a very good account of them - selves for every experiment performed in the laboratory period. History. This course comprises two (Semesters of gen - eral history, two of modern, and two of American. The student is taught to look upon current events as history in the making, and upon the history as recounted in the text books as past current events as interpreted in the present; and upon history and current events as the indis - pensable explanation of himself and his social environ - ment. Language. The work comprises six semesters of Eng - lish and six of foreign language (usually Latin). Correct and effective linguistic thought and expression for the practical ends of life is the constant aim and the student is never allowed for a moment to lose sight of this goal. Spelling, grammar, rhetoric, criticism, interpretation, com - position, current and classical readings, — all are made to contribute to that end, but are never allowed to become ends in themselves. The mathematics, science, and his - tory are correlated with and made supplementary to this course: every subject is treated as a means toward thought and expression. Electives. The above course of study is typical of our work, but is not rigidly adhered to when there is good reason for setting it aside. Students not preparing for college are permitted to substitute vocational subjects for the foreign subjects and part of the mathematics. In special cases, persons not regularly in high school are allowed to become associate members of certain classes, receiving the benefit of the readings and discussions without receiving the credits. With the approval and recommendation of the high school instructor certain musical and industrial sub - jects may be given high school credits. Graduation. Graduates must furnish satisfactory evi - dence of thirty semesters credits and a good moral char- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">504 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF acter. We do not find it advisable to comply with the technical requirements of an accredited high school, on account of our specialization. Our graduates, however, are always accepted in any college on probation, after our showing, and thus far have never failed to make good. Special Work in Typewriting, Business Forms, and Spelling. Teacher, Mary E. Cook. The only way in which sightless persons may correspond with the outside seeing world is through the medium of the typewriter. With that in mind, typewriting, is given a prominent place in the educa - tion of our pupils. Not quite so much ground is covered in the work here as in the ordinary business school or college. The work also is somewhat modified to meet the need of the individual. The work for the past two years has been based upon the course laid down in Underwood's From Sight to Touch, supplemented by the Rational Method and has been found highly satisfactory. During the first year the pupil is taught the key-board thoroughly. In the second year he is expected to gain speed. All work must be perfect before it is allowed to pass, which instills a desire for accuracy in the operator. Accuracy in type, spell - ing, and punctuation is insisted upon. Special instruction Is given on words used commonly in business to those who seem weak. To the more advanced students instruction in letter-writing and business forms is given with occasional dictation of selections from well-known authors. Musical Department Ever since Valentin Hauy, more than a century ago, conceived the idea that musical studies might be success - fully taught blind students in schools especially equipped, music has had a prominent place in the curriculum. Our department is in charge of Lulu Raben, violin and begin - ners' piano and Lillie Bischof, advanced piano and pipe - organ. Teaching Methods. People in general have heard blind musicians play or sing, or at least have heard of their </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 505 performances. Rarely, however, will you find a person who holds any other opinion than that these musicians must play or sing by ear. Such is not the case, however. With the exception of a few freaks (such as are found in every line) these blind musicians are guided in the inter - pretation of a composition by notes which are previously studied and memorized. The question naturally arises: How is this possible without written characters? It is true that the ordinary staff notation, used by the sighted, must be abandoned; but a substitute has been found — a device enabling the blind to read notes and derive the same impressions that the seeing person gains from the printed sheet. Just as text books and all kinds of literature are now printed in a tactile system, consisting of dots arranged in various positions to represent the different letters of the alphabet, so musical characters are notated, making it possible for a page of this embossed music to express all that is seen in the duplicate of staff notation, such as notes, rests, phrasing, expression marks, and-so - forth. With such a system the blind are able to take their place, side by side, with their competitors, the sighted teachers or concert performers, assured that the blind possess all that printed notes can render. Our school, through this system of musical notation, with competent instructors to direct the work, is therefore able to maintain high standards in all branches of its department of music — violin, voice, piano, and organ. The Violin. The violin, though one of the most delicate and difficult of musical instruments to learn can be suc - cessfully taught to the blind. When once mastered it affords them must pleasure and in many instances forms the basis for earning a livelihood. At first, especially in cases where sight is highly defective, progress is very slow, for every minute detail must be gained entirely through the sense of touch, but by perseverance and persistent efforts the final result is the same as that of the pupil with perfect vision. The violin class at present numbers fifteen pupils, their courses comprising scales of Blumenstengel, Schradic, and </seg>
            <seg id="p016">506 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF Sevcik; studies of Bohmer, Sitt, and Hoffman, besides high class solo compositions. The Orchestra. Our orchestra this year is confined to strings, due to a lack of pupils interested in wind instru - ments. It consists of ten numbers, the instrumentation being First violins, Second violins Viola, Cello, Double bass, Drums, and Piano. The work in an organization of this kind is highly essential. It develops ensemble playing, a phase too often neglected in the education of the music student. Besides this, the orchestra serves as an excellent source for enter - tainment on school programs or elsewhere. A collection of standard orchestrations are memorized and thoroly com - pleted each year. The Piano. In the beginner's piano work there are at the present nine. These pupils are taught the funda - mentals of scales and finger exercises while their solos and studies are made possible by use of the New York system of musical notation, described elsewhere in this report. In the advanced work on this instrument compositions of Chopin, Liszt, Mendelssohn, Schwarenka, and other noted composers are taught. Blind pupils, as a rule, have a keen ear for music and the technique which they display in rendering a number is often surprising. Graduates in music are very capable of earning a livelihood, teaching music, playing in picture-houses and other places of amuse - ment, and entertaining in private homes. The Organ. The School has owned a fine pipe-organ for the last twelve years which is used chiefly ior the playing of hymns each morning at convocation, and each Sunday for the Christian Endeavor. Pupils must have </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 507 several years of training on the piano before taking up the study of the organ. Some of our graduates have presided successfully over large church organs and over instru - ments in movie houses. As in work done on the piano the pupil memorizes while playing with one hand aud reading with the other, after the music has been dictated from the print by the teacher. Each pupil is given a twenty - minute lesson daily and is assigned a forty-minute prac - tice period, the same technical requirements being made as for the study of the piano. The Voice. In the voice work a systematic breathing exercise is given, together with simple vocalization. After this foundation work the exercises of Seeber, Concone, and Vaccai and songs by noted composers are taught. The accuracy in pitch of the blind while studying music is remarkable. Chorus. EAch year the students are given an oppor - tunity to join a chorus fitted to their respective voices. At this time we have two choruses — one, a little people's chorus ranging in years from five to twelve, who learn by rote child songs, such as nature subjects and action songs; the other a chorus of those older who meet daily and also learn by rote hymns, and anthems as well as special four - part selections. Industrial Department For Cirls and Smaller Boys. Fannie Bone, Teacher. We have in this work pupils of all ages. The beginners are taught bead-work chiefly. The object of this pursuit is to cultivate the use of the hands. Many otherwise normal children, we find are beld back through inability to properly use their hands. It is very necessary, for the sake of their tactile reading and writing that power along this line be gained. The handling of beads and the making of small articles from them acquaint the child with the handling of small objects very similar to the points used in their system of reading and writing. We usually spend one afternoon a week in making different objects out of plasticine, a pre- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">508 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF pared clay. This furnishes the children much amusement as well as helping them to master the use of their hands. It also aids in developing a mental picture of actual objects. Basket-making is also taught. Heretofore we have just used the raffia; but recently, upon testing, we have learned that the blind children can make very pretty baskets from specially prepared crepe paper, so that we are planning to carry on considerable work of this nature here - after. The older girls are taught plain sewing, such as darning stockings, hemming wash-cloths, piecing quilts, and many practical things necessary to the up-keep of their own wardrobes. Crocheting and knitting are also taught, some of the pupils becoming so proficient in this line that they are able to benefit from it in a financial way, as well as from their own satisfaction. We have also organized a Domestic Science Class for the older girls. This class will be trained intensively to do the practical things that come up daily about the home, as well as learning the simpler dishes in cooking. Boys' Industrial Work. Teacher, Clark Bruce. The male portion of our student body have an excellent oppor - tunity, by the exercise of intelligence and industry, to ac - quire a trade that will render them self-supporting on the outside. Of ordinary trades such as may be acquired by an adult whose blindness has reached him in later years, there are broom-making and netting, that go very well together. In the course of a year or two, practically any blind man can learn to make brooms successfully, and to net hammocks, fly nets, etc. It depends naturally upon the man himself, his business ability, and capacity to get along with people, whether one who has acquired the physical knack of making these articles can go out into the world and be successful as an individual business man. A number of our people are proving themselves successful in these lines as I shall show later on in this report. The most satisfactory trade for a blind man, if he has a keen ear and a pleasing personality, is tuning. It takes at least two years for a student who devotes himself to the work to earn a diploma in the tuning department. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 509 2. Supplemental Activities I group together now a number of activities not be - longing to any one of the departments, but having to do with the school at large and exerting a tremendous bearing upon the immediate well being and future welfare of those entrusted to our charge; as, Daily Convocation, the Chris - tian Endeavor, Care of Rooms, Regular Schedule, Library Privileges and Reading Aloud, Commencement, and the Con - servation of Health. Daily Convocation. There is a twenty-minute period each day, beginning at eight o'clock in the morning devoted to chapel exercises. Usually we sing two hymns, chant the Gloria, and I read a passage of Scripture. From this stand - ard program there are many variations. A beautiful poem, the news of the day, the Twenty-third Psalm, the Lord's Prayer, an address from some one outside, alumnus or friend, musical numbers from students, or members of our faculty, or a concert by the Victrola may be substituted for all, or part of the standard exercises. Christian Endeavor. Our Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, which is entirely non-sectarian, holds its devotional exercises every Sunday morning at eight, and its business meeting the first Saturday evening of each school month. We subscribe for the Christian Endeavor World, and use many of its topics. Some of our meetings are, however, entirely original. The official and committee work is done largely by the students, though teachers are ac - tive and associate members of the society and assist in the work. Each business meeting is opened with prayer and singing. The society has a president, vice-president, record - ing secretary, treasurer, corresponding secretary and five committees to keep up the work. Our society keeps in touch with those outside through our corresponding secretary and through delegates sent to district and state conventions. Care of Rooms. At the beginning of this school year all students were asked to take care of their own rooms. They have responded splendidly and learned much in the </seg>
            <seg id="p020">510 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF way of neatness and order. Once a week a maid goes over each room carefully, in order to keep the building in the best possible sanitary condition. Regular Schedule. Each pupil and teacher has made out a schedule of the week's duties. One copy is on file in the office and another posted on the door of recita - tion room, or private room. This assists greatly in the find - ing of each person in the case of emergency and teaches systematic application to assigned duty. Library Privileges and Reading Aloud. The pupils have opportunity, with the assistance of a good librarian, to con - sult our library and to borrow books from it. They are encour - aged to get the habit of reading the best authors. Opportuni - ties are also offered of listening to good books read aloud. Our juvenile collection has been added to recently and the supervisors are making good use of the new books in reading to the Second-floor people. A forty-minute period is assigned for each school evening for the reading aloud to the older pupils in chapel. Hugo's Ninety-Three, Private Peat, and Kingsley's Westward Ho! are the books that have thus far been read this school-year. Commencement. Fitting programs close the school - year in June. The graduates are given diplomas signed by you showing the completion of courses in an approved manner. First the little people have their exercises. Then, on the Sunday night before graduation, there is the annual sermon, which corresponds to the Baccalaureate Address of colleges. The sermon in June, 1917, was preached by Reverend Edwin Hart Jenks, of Omaha; and that of 1918, by Doctor Howard R. Chapman, of Lincoln. The graduates, 1917, In Tuning, George H. Cozad 1918, In Tuning, John E. Nutt, Edward O. Blair, Trav Mone- smith From the High School, Elizabeth Leonard </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 511 Conservation of Health. The care of the children's health, as well as of those older at the institution, comes almost entirely within the duties of the physician of the institution, the matron, and the two supervisors. We are fortunate indeed in having such competent and devoted people filling these positions. During the first year we lost through sudden death the services of Dr. Claude Watson who had been acting as our physician for many years. I can hardly express how deeply his passing affected me. Old enough to have been my father (in fact, he had been a per - sonal friend of my father's for many years before he met me) he was my personal friend and adviser, as well as the school physician. We have been fortunate in securing as his successor Dr. Wm. S. Yager, who has been prompt to answer our calls and whose service has been highly satisfactory. Miss Jennie Hughey and Mrs. Frances Harrington, as supervisors, devote themselves to the work assigned. The drugs used by the school are turned over to Mrs. Abbott, who acts as a sort of institution druggist, checking out to the supervisors and others what is needed for immediate use and taking charge directly of the ail - ments of those employed by the State. C. FUTURE PLANS Though the school may, in a general way, well go on as it has in the past and as I have described it, evolving grad - ually with the passing of time, there are three improve - ments, two of which at least should receive immediate attention and be provided for. I refer to Instruction in the tuning and repair of player pianos; Instruction in the use of the dictaphone; and Use of the phonopticon. Ordinary Expenses The ordinary running expenses of this institution for the ensuing biennium will be, judging from present con - ditions: </seg>
            <seg id="p022">512 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF Salaries and wages $30,500.00 General repairs 3,000.00 Maintenance 36,800.00 Total $70,300.00 Extraordinary Expenses FURNITURE AND EQUIPMENT Player-piano, models, parts of same, tools, and equip - ment for the tuning and repair of player pianos $ 2,500.00 Books for the library — both tactile and ink print 1,000.00 IMPROVEMENTS TO BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS Tearing out of windows and doors of the old wing — the boys' side — and installing of new windows and doors that will be weather tight 3,000.00 NEW BUILDINGS Constructing of wood shvd and garage 4,000.00 Total $10,500.00 Why Needed These statements are almost wholly self-explanatory. Our school is falling behind most of the other institutions of similar nature in the United States through not having es- tablished a player-piano department. It seems to me that we ought not to delay longer in putting this work into the school. Nor should we delay longer in making the east wing weather-tight. The windows and doors have been in for almost a half century; were never very good in' the beginning; and much of our heat during the winter time is dissipated through the cracks. Our woodshed, as noted in another place of this report, unfortunately burned last winter. We have been managing temporarily with a small improvised building, constructed largely out of salvage. A garage is no longer a luxury for a state institution — but a necessity. We have felt the need of one here for several years now. The system of tactile writing at present used by this school has been discarded (as I have explained else- where in this communication) and the whole of the United States will go as rapidly as possible to Revised Braille. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 513 This means that we must have money with which to build up our library. The Dictaphone and Phonopticon. By means of the Dictaphone I fully believe that certain pupils of ours — I refer particularly to our bright girls — might be able to do office correspondence. I know that other blind people have succeeded along this line and our graduates are not one whit behind others. It certainly is worth a painstaking tryout. Results of the phonopticon have not yet been sufficiently shown as practical to say that it should be installed immediately — but if improved and made less ex - pensive before this biennium is over we should have one. You will find each of these described in my report of two years ago. D. RELIEF OF THE BLIND FUND Directly connected with the service performed by this institution, though not included as part of the school activities are certain provisions made by the last session of the legislature for the assistance of blind people not likely to be enrolled with us. Three laws were passed having for their general purpose assistance to the sightless. They are: 1. County aid for blind, House Roll Number 68, which provides that counties may pension worthy blind people in amounts not to exceed in any case three hundred dollars per year; 2. Improvement in the condition of the blind, House Roll Number 332, which gives the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions broad powers and broad duties in the relief of the blind, but which carries no appropriation; and 3. An appropriation of three thousand dollars for the relief of the blind, an item in House Roll Number 795. By these acts of the legislature the duties formerly performed, so far as possible with the funds at hand, by the Commission for the Blind were divided among the various county boards and yourselves. The Nebraska Commission for the Blind, largely through the activities of Lyle A. Harris, field agent, had done in </seg>
            <seg id="p024">514 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF the preceding biennium a valuable service in gathering data and compiling a census of the blind in our state. Interesting tabulation of his findings may be read in the report of this institution of two years ago. With this data on file in your office you commissioned me to make investi - gations and file recommendations with you from time to time as to how this appropriation of the legislature might be most wisely expended for the purpose intended. According to the records of your office there had been expended from this fund of three thousand dollars up to the first of October, $2130.32; and since that time vouchers have been received and passed by this office amounting to $192.71, or a total has been used at the time of this report of $2322.03, leaving for use during the final four months of the biennium, $677.97. Not less than thirty blind persons have profited in the expenditure of this amount of money as authorized by you. The largest items have been as follows: Total $2,241.10 i I should much like to go into the individual cases and explain what a large amount of good this fund has done for the blind of the State. But space forbids in such a report as I am now making. Allow me, however, to invite your attention to the fact that half of this fund is assist - ing the blind by loans. Long time is given and the interest is placed at only four per cent. The borrower is permitted to return the whole of the loan, or any part of it, before maturity, if he so chooses. Under these easy terms three borrowers have taken the option and repaid their loans before the four years period was up. The largest number Loans to twelve % 11,459.42 Services and expenses of field agent Supplies furnished four 443.45 136.60 Direct assistance in money to two 50.00 Readers furnished two advanced students 50.92 Music lessons for advanced student 50.00 Assistance for surgical operations, two Assistance for 'holiday sale 44.46 6.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 515 of loans has been for the purpose of establishing broom - shops — a field in which many of our adult blind are for - tunately able to make a satisfactory living. For the new biennium I recommend an appropriation of Ten Thousand Dollars ($10,000.00) for carrying on similar activities, broadening the work as the larger funds will permit. No money appropriated by the Legislature is for a better cause, or does more genuine good. Connected in a way, though somewhat remotely, is the assistance that should be rendered by the State to such employes as serve many years on the small wages paid and whose lives are expended in such service. I am thinking particularly of three blind teachers in our school whose service to the State has been invaluable. It seems that after a period of twenty years, or possibly twenty-five, they ought to be granted a pension each so that they may live without a constant struggle to keep the wolf from the door. This is the principle that obtains in many branches of the Federal Service, in many metropolitan cities for teachers, firemen, and other branches. It would be economy, in the long run, if the State of Nebraska would plan for such sort of service pensions for its employes in the various state institutions, as it would lead to more lengthened periods of service and increase devotion and efficiency. CONCLUSION In concluding this biennial report I wish to invite your attention to the appended tables. I also wish to publicly thank my fellow-workers at the school for their intelligent assistance and co-operation. Not alone in the arduous work of conducting the institution but more immediately in the preparation of this report they have been eager to give the best that each had. The loss of Dr. Claude Watson midway in the biennium was a great shock to us all. He had been so considerate of everyone and his death was so sudden that it fell on us as a genuine calamity. We have been fortunate in having </seg>
            <seg id="p026">516 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF as his successor, Dr. William S. Yager, who has been attentive and gained our confidence through his fidelity. I am especially indebted to the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions and to your office force for kind con - sideration and courtesy; in my difficulties I have found you ready with advice and suggestions, when things have been going especially well you have been not less rejoicing than I myself. My wife, Lillian Abbott, has served for the biennium as Matron. Her zeal in her duties and her advice to me have made her services, as in the years before, invaluable. Most respectfully submitted, Superintendent. Nebraska City, Nebraska, November 30, 1918. N. C. Abbott. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 517 STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS, CREDITS. AND BALANCES OF THE PUPILS' FUND December 1. 1916, to December 1, 1918 Approximate average number of account* was 24. PERIOD Debit* Credit! Balance credit. December 1. 1916, (52.41. December, 1916 January, 1917 . February, 1917 Mareh. 1917 December, 1916 * 61.39 i 46.50 * 61.39 $ 46.50 22.00 75.30 33.21 30.00 38.17 8.00 34.55 19.25 36.29 17.90 65.60 41.86 22.00 75.30 January, 1917 February, 1917 33.21 30.00 Mareh. 1917 38.17 8.00 34.55 19.25 April, 1917 April, 1917. May, 1917 . June, 1917 . July, 1917 August. 1917 May, 1917 36.29 17.90 June, 1917 65.60 41.86 July, 1917 Aufunt. 1917 September, 1917. September, 1917 October, 1917 November, 1917 7.06 96.40 28.82 22.47 U .11 39.24 7.05 96.40 October, 1917 28.82 22.47 November, 1917. ... Total (or year 34J1 39.24 Total (or year $ Ml.** f 396.91 $ 361.39 $ 396.91 Credit balance on hand, November 30, 1917, $87.93. Balance credit, December 1, 1917, $87.93. December, 1917 January, 1918 February. 1918 March. 1918. . December. 1917 January, 1918 February, 1918 March. 1918 April. 1918 May. 1918 June. 1918 July. 1918 August. 1918 April. 1918 May. 1918 June. 1918 July. 1918 AujTMt. 1918 September, 1918 October. 1918 November, 1918 September, 1918. . 7.K 66.73 69.S2 90.77 39.34 31.34 7J* 66.73 October, 1918 69.62 90.77 :)9.)4 31.34 November. 1918 . . . Total for year Total for year $ 637.34 t 622.07 I 637.34 I I 622.07 Credit balance on hand November 30, 1918, $72.66. Grand total (or biennium $ 998.73 $ 107139 Note— These are the personal funds of pupils at the School for the Blind, are held in trust by the Institution, and expended for their sole individual benefit. 89.54 * SS.17 39.34 70.32 127.71 88.75 70 .33 | 76.38 62.60 58.55 7920 61.23 58.63 36.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">518 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMMISSION FOR THE BLIND FUND Statement of the Debits, Credits, and Balances of the Commission for the Blind Fund. This is a fund accumulating largely from interest and repayment of loans made from the Relief of the Blind Fund. It is kept in a Bank in Nebraska City, accounted for monthly to the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions, and no withdrawals are made save with the consent of the Board. PERIOD Balance, credit according to the records of this office Dec. December. 1916 January, 1917 February, 1917 March. 1917 April, 1917 May, 1917 June, 1917 July, 1917 August, 1917 September, 1917 October, 1917 November, 1917 Total for year Credit balance on hand November 30. 1917. $86.15. Credit balance according to the records of this office Dec. December, 1917 January, 1918 February, 1918 i ruiuai &gt;i i .' March, 1918 April, 1918 May. 1918 June, 1918 July, 1918 August, 1918 95.00 106.00 100.00 ! 155.18 104.90 1U.82 88.46 88.46 September, 1918 October, 1918 November, 1918. Total for year $388.36 ; $473. 1* Balance on hand November SO, 1918, $170.97 Grand total for biennium tSM.27 | $567.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 111 RECEIPTS CREDITED TO INSTITUTION CASH FUND December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918 AMOUNTS RECEIVED GENERAL SOURCES Total Dee. 1, 1916 Dee. 1, 1917 I Dee. 1, 1916 to to to Dee. 1, 1917 Dee. 1, 1918 Dee. 1, 1918 Tuition tSS?.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Network Cattle Potatoes Bead work Cmlvw Iron Fancy work Slates Printed forms Paper \ Molasses returned Sacks Miscellaneous Freight breakage Weighing ..,..'. Sewer connection Kindling Shutters Porch posts Cane S.nd Cinders *3* ::: Rope Postage Bed springs Mutes Rags Typewriter ribbon Chicken Telephone Rubber Total $ 900.00 $ 1372.67 I 1 614.64 408.25 ! 598.97 587.00 248.33 299.17 128.82 91.46 105.00 95.00 81.38 23.63 45.96 50.71 40.00 24.00 2.84 36.12 17.40 8 M 3.50 21.50 16.00 3.65 9.10 9.88 7.22 1.60 .62 7.53 .81 5.75 2.20 2.85 5.00 200 2.00 3.00 . . 2.00 1.80 1.75 1.60 .45 .90 .40 .70 .67 .*» 1.00 1.00 .70 .70 .60 .40 .18 t 28M.04 $ 3063.09 |T~ 2272.67 1022.89 1185.97 547.50 220.27 200.00 105.01 96.67 64.00 38.96 25.74 25.00 16.00 12.75 9.88 Mi H.ln 6.56 5. OS 5 00 4.U0 3.00 2.00 1.S0 1.75 1.60 1.35 1.10 1.06 1.00 1.00 .70 .70 .60 .41) .18 5899.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 520 INVENTORY OF LANDS, BUILDINGS, FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT AND IMPROVE - MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE Acres Acres Cultivated Uncultivated Total Esti- , Acre- mated Garden Farm Orchard Campus Waate af« Value Land owned by institution 4 2 4 10 t 3000.00 Land rented by institution (cash) Land rented by institution ( shares i Total 4 2 4 10 | $ 3000.00 ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF BUILDING AND IMPROVEMENT Building i Furniture Equipment Improvement! Total School building Main coal shed Gymnasium . . . t 70000.00 I 14000.00 j % 16000.00 $ 100000.00 100.00 100.00 10000.00 250.00 10260.00 Laundry 12000.00 7750.00 19750.00 Buggy shed 200.00 350.00 550.00 Small pig house Laundry coal shed Bam «0.00 20.00 7S.00 75.00 3500.00 450.00 3950.00 Cowshed Cow bam 125.00 25.00 I 150.00 500.00 60.00 | 560.00 Chicken house 80.00 20.00 100.00 Ground improvements 50.00 200.00 700.00 950.00 Total $ 96600.00 | t 14050.00 \ S 25105.00 $ 700.00 | t 136455.00 November SO, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 521 • s as v I \ m 1 S! f I 8 - -2 I 3 I 8° ° jg? I — V- 8 lW5 ! i dlh ! 1 —^l \\ j 2 : : 1 ! I I !| 1 I II \ I :; 1 !i ll || li N 11 1 m i t : i I I ]!li B i I 1 I 1 1 3i-s s l-~ S rn ■* I : : s III 1 IN 1 o ! : : g - a 8 ii h i N I ! ij ii IE i i s ; j| I £ i ll </seg>
            <seg id="p032">522 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF I lOiOOiO [to I ~ ill - = a §1 - -g "X I * 0 ! J ■= _| I I £222 I : g I j i s^"°§ j ; 4 I = sl II II I 5 I 1^ ; 1 * I I : 1 IH= — -I I ijj |«s-« i S i i !!!! i i 1 i ;;;; : ! a : : : : : | t MM J § o : : : : : ] Z : : : : : S| i h il i 1 1 I fflfflHGu u o ISf ' ' 5 2= I 2 _l IS§ggSS§§Sg IS I i 4 '£= v §^S'as j £ . § &gt; !s ° g • L^_ -j O i j j I -»£'33_o3'3*33333 ■ S 3 I i i-o-BS-B-a-e-B-a-o-B I : ? *|j|5 a33"»sa| j § 1 ■ '2=^g ei 8*sa s i Il_t^ L4 ill iUiiiiiii : 2 o I 3 I 10 axioiaN cdn— x -I H ! 8 ] S*** *" w : * : : : : : ■* e j \\\\\ [ :\\\: \ 1 3 i :::::::::::■ 22 iiNNNH 1 i; i 1 3 I I l( a. :::::: il b :.:::::::: : ofl 2 il in m:; i 11 mm; Hi ! 11 :::::::::: : jM ::::::::: * ■"» iiiliiiiil? 1 li at x — .- a^ ( c " 1 I mnu-SocKaiHB. g| l^ o&gt; 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 523 I SS IS 1 1 !i!s d !5 ". l&gt;l o i iTNii i j «• i 1 IPIl I i i *i '■ N ! i ■ ill I j |[| ! i nil 5 ij H ! If ii i it : : : -5 N: IS ii * ft r 1 ill !--- 1 X ei" § i _ I SS IS 1 t I S I -- I si • Ilkki 0 3 ' * ei - a . ' *8 H^ ' ; 1 1 S t 1 ill 1 1 N is N ; II Hi i 1 ! I ISir* " i til Z" 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">524 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OP Is i- ! |MS3i! I h I - :S2 i I I SB I I fs |_||iri|| ji lli| a """h 3 S|S82|S ish§ 2 l : I 1 h '§ 2 h hi Jill i I i * ' : ! : I ~ I Ii S 8S.3JS 1 u »ii&lt;*wi | | J j.P g|;g|J 1 is 1 1 riti i i ii 5 1 ill*-:; : ! [ I In | ij ii AMI | 2 1-s j s S8S818 1 i §1 L=_ , I . 8.8 ■ ■ 8 jjjjl 1 an a g g m\j u : : : : : 1 Wi ? I </seg>
            <seg id="p035">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 525 ft I 3|i^l5 II I is I : a- j I .1! i£IS h | I £;S»8|| n Ui?J!lL rinii"»ii I . I 98 IS 11 I I £ »£ 1 n I ™ S 1 1 «=IIfi !!M .. : {fa H i pi S 88 8 | I A I :m| 2 = 1 " z ' - I ■ •j 1 is n il S * Ii • r| I § 3 - *■ S - S - | S i 5 i! i &gt;i 8 " s 1 &gt; H ill- m|: Bili iP|i NUMnl •o -a 3 ! U 3 * !|i ;r;j j I] iiiiiMii Si JJfiH T 2s si i S 88888 18 P&gt;h — — i I I n It I . te ■ Mil I : S5 I pF "-I n i ,1. ! S ? 88 8 , ! . "888 ■ s |j|| I |S"8»|| *"Hl ■ : I •2^ I .ISSS .IT2~ i • grj.-«i 1- S *■*■*■ s - 3 JI || : : ?8 8 : Si £ I Jill I 5&gt;n u : : : : : : I uouxs ! !! linn </seg>
            <seg id="p036">526 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OP TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION •This includes all persons who had previously attended this school, or some similar one. TABLE II— SEX AND RACE OF PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST MEET TABLE III— ACE OF PUPILS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME i &gt; i MOVEMENT For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1*17 1*18 Biennium M. F. T. II. F. T. M. F. T. S2 18 S0| 37 24 61 32 18 SO Present at beginning of period Admitted: For first tim* *Re-»dmittfd * 7 16 11 4 IS 20 11 SI 6 S • » 7 16 15 10 25 47 28 75 57 SS (1 67 SS 106 Total enrollment Discharged: EipelTed For various rwaoaa I.... 1 I.... 1 t... t • 4 IS 26 18 43 34 22 56 10 4 14 26 18 44 36 22 58 37 24 61 SI 17 48 31 17 48 47 28 76 67 36 92 67 39 106 Total removal* Present at close of period Total Whit* Indian tf*fro Totals RACE For Year For Year endinc endinc Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. U. T. T. M. F. T. 9 5 14 10 4 14 19 9 28 2 2 2 2 1.... 1 1 .... 1 • 7 1* 11 4 16 20 11 SI For Y«r For You endinf radinc Total AGE Nov. SO, NovTsO, (or 1»17 1*18 Biennium u. r. t. u. r. t. m. f. t. , 1ny« 1 1 ... 1 1 »« 1 I.... 1 I.... X * Ut I.... 1 I.... 1 «s» i.... t •:::: t ta 1 1 1... 1112 CtoTCB 1 1 1 1 rhlrtten 1.... 1 I.... 1 'ourtom I.... 1 1 1 2, 2 1 t ntun 1 1 t.... 2 2 1 3 Xxttan 2.... 2 I.... 1 iarantooii 1 1 2 1 1 2 r wen ty 1 1 1 1 )nrt*«ty-OM 4 16 4 1 i. 8 2 10 Total of new admMooa * T 1* 11 4 IS 20 11 SI I I ' </seg>
            <seg id="p037">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 527 TABLE IV— NATIVITY OF PUPILS ADMITTED TABLE V-NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF PUPILS ADMITTED For Year For Year NATIVITY OF PARENTS lift No^SO ""l"" 1 OF PUPILS ENTERING FOR FIRST TIME ",e/, 7 ' , 9 ig ' Bienniu 1917 1918 Biennium United States, both parent* Foreign, both parents Menominee Indian, both parents Mixed Unknown Total M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 4 4 8 » 3 12 II 7 20 4... 4 1... 1 *.... S .... 2 2 2 t 1 1 X 1 1 2 1 1 I 1 1 S 9 7 16 11 4 15 20 11 M NATIVITY Mebraaka Jniud Sute. other than Nebnukm Denmark For Year For Yaw endinc endinr Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. T. T. 649 t I * 10 7 IT SSI « 1 7 9 4 13 I.... 1 1.... 1 « 7 It 11 4 15 20 11 Jl Total! I I I </seg>
            <seg id="p038">528 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VI— RESIDENCE OF ALL NEW PUPILS ADMITTED AND OF ALL PUPILS REMAINING AT CLOSE OF BIENNIUM For Yew For Year All ending ending Total Remaininj Nov. 30, Not. Sift, for Nov. 30, 1917 1*18 Biennium 1918 M. r. T. M. V. T. It. F. T. M. F. T. N&gt;brW«: Adam it 1 1.... 1111 Antelope Buffalo Butler I.... 1 1.... 1 1- ■■■ 1 I.... 1 I--- 1 Cue 1 1 Dakota Dim Dodfe Douglas Frontier Ga,e 1 1 2 1... 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 I.... 13 14 2.. . 2 3 1 4 6 1 Si 2 2 4 I.... 1 l.. : 1 l... ; 1 2 Greeley Hall 1 1 ••■• 1 I- ■•: 1 1 1 1 Hamilton Harlan I.... 1 I.... 1 1.... 1 1 .... 1 Jefferson Johnson Knox. ... I 1 I.... 1 1.... 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 .... 1 1 Lancaster Merriek Nemaha Nuekolls Otoe t 1 t t 1 S 5 1 « I.... 1 1 1 .... 1 1 .... 1 1 1.... I I.... 1 I.... 1 12 3 12 3 12 3 Pier« 1 2 3 1 2 3. ... S S Saundera Seward Sherman Thayer Valley 1 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 Webster Wisconsin Wyoming 1.... 1 1.... 1 » * 2 2 «... 1 Total. 9 7 16! 11 4 1S| 20 11 31 31 17 48 TABLE VII ACES AT WHICH PUPILS ADMITTED BECAME BLIND !onf enital Inder one yemr tee and under two years 'wo and under three ive and under tan &gt;n and under fifteen "if teen and under twenty-one. . &gt;ver twenty-one AGE NUMBER M. F. T. 1 t 5 1 1 1 .. 1 ;;;;;; • &gt; » 4 4 S 1 .. 1 S 1 « m u ai Totala </seg>
            <seg id="p039">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 529 13 IX TABLE IX— EXTENT OF DEFECT IN PUPILS ADMITTED NUMBER EXTENT OF DEFECT u. r. t. wo vision ... Partial vision a s i* « *0 11 81 Totals ASSIGNED CAUSES Accident Ophthalmia neonatorum Optic atrophy Fever Unknown Granulated eyelida Eyestrain Buphthalmoa Iritia and keratitia Acute infection . .• Measles Small pox If. 8 2 1 UMBE F. Ft T. 11 1 t « X 1 1 1 1 1 1 11 1 M i it Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p040">530 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE X— DISTRIBUTION OF ALL PUPILS IN SCHOOL AT CLOSE OF BIENNIUM NOVEMBER 30, INS TABLE XI— ARTICLES MADE BY THE PUPILS IN THE INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENTS DURING THE YEAR 380 pieces bead article*, small napkin rintjs, etc. 86 pieces bead .nicies, large, boxes, mats, etc. 32 bead bags 24 bead necklaces and coat chains 6 aprons 13 doilies 10 holders 6 jaeketa, crocheted yarn 56 yards lace, crocheted 34 laundry bags 2 sets quilt blocks C raffia baskets, trays, mats, etc. 8 pairs slippers 3 shawls, knitted 55 wash cloths 10 yokes, crochet 192 dozen brooms 58 hammocks 20 DyneU 2 quilts, pieced 7 pairs pillow eases 8 dresses remodeled 10 balls carpet rags 20 chairs caned 4 pain bootees 17 mate 1 Hug-roe-tight NUMBER GRADES If. F. T. UTERARY DEPARTMENT First trade t 4 4 Second trade t 1 4 Third grade 4 4 8 Fifth grade t . . 8 Seventh grade 1 2 t Eighth 2 3 6 Totmli 16 14 29 HIGH SCHOOL CLASSES History « 2 S English 6 2 7 L»t i n 6 1 « Algebra 5 .. S Plane geometry 2 .. 2 Solid geometry 3 . * Totals 26 6 81 INDUSTRIAL, MUSICAL, AND OTHER SPECIAL WORK Bead-work 11 11 Z8 Broom making t . . 8 Chorus, junior 7 "8 16 Chorus, senior 2 6 8 Crocheting 6 6 Domestic science 6 • Knitting 7 7 Netting 6 1 • Orchestra 4 8 7 Piano 11 » SO Piano tuning 8 . . 8 Plain sewing 7 7 Tactile reading 17 IX t» Tactile writing 11 1 IS Tactile musical notation 7 4 11 Typewriting IS 7 It Viola.. ._ 1 .. 1 VmHb 11 4 16 Voice 1 1 z Total. 11 S3 210 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>