<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Pump Irrigation Investigations in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1933-07">1933-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 282 July; 1933 Pump Irrigation Investigations in Nebraska E. E. BRACKETT AND E. B. LEWIS Department of Agricultural Engineering THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY 1. More than 1,000 irrigation pumps are used m Nebraska. 2. The pumps are used to supply supplementary water m a semi-arid climate where drouths occur frequently. 3. Rainfall varies from 15 to 30 inches annually m the pump-irriga - tion districts of Nebraska. 4.. Pump irrigation as practiced m Nebraska results m 15 to 66 bushels greater yield per acre for corn; 75 to 378 bushels greater yield per acre for potatoes; and .7 to 3.8 tons greater yield per acre for alfalfa. 5. The supplemental water needs of ordinary Nebraska crops are 6.5 to 12 inches. 6. A plentiful supply of underground water is found a few feet under the surface m several of the river valleys and good wells are obtained, especially m the Platte valleys. 7. Apparently the methods of construction affect the yield of wells, but data collected are not conclusive. 8. The relations between the numerous variables (such as diameter, type of casing, depth, method of construction, nature and position of water-bearing strata) as they affect yield are not thoroughly established. 9. The circle of influence and cone of depression take general forms but indications show that many influences tend to vary these forms. 10. Cost of well and pump generally ranges between $750 and $1,000. 11. Most of the pumps are the 6-inch size and the vertical type. 12. Most of the pumps irrigate a small acreage, averaging about 55 acres for a 6-inch pump. 13. Very little fall or winter irrigation is practiced. Increase m the acreage per installation (and a reduction m the investment cost per acre) can be secured by changing the cropping program m such a way as to lengthen the period of pumping and include more acres. 14. A few installations are found on ponds and streams. 15. Most of the pumps are operated by the general-purpose tractor, which is used principally for other farm work. 16. Power costs have varied widely (2.9 cents to 30.2 cents) but have averaged 6.7 to 9 cents per acre foot per foot of lift. With attendant labor at the pump included, the cost has averaged 10 cents per acre foot per foot of lift. 17. The cost of applying water (expense on field ditches and for dis - tributing water) has averaged $3.50 per acre foot. 18. Tables show costs of irrigation exclusive of investment charges. 19. The economical lift, based on average farm crops and prices over the period from 1913 to 1931, is 50 feet or less. 20. Irrigation pumps are considered as equipment for emergency use by a large proportion of Nebraska owners. Best results are secured by those who operate their pumps as a definite and regular part of the yearly program. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Pump Irrigation Investigations m Nebraska E. E. BRACKETT AND E. B. LEWIS The use of irrigation pumping plants has increased rapidly m recent years until the total for Nebraska reached; 1,024 early m 1931. 1 The extremely hot, dry weather continued m that year and caused an increased demand for information. Nebraska lies m a semi-arid region and is subjected to irregular drouth periods that are hazards to regular crop pro - duction and successful farming: Most of the land on Twhich pump irrigation is or can be practiced produces some; crops without supplemental water. 2 A method of irrigation of minimum cost and of greater flexibility than the canal sytsem is desirable for the semi-arid districts, and pumping j seems well fitted to many sections of the state. The purpose of this publication is to discuss many of the problems that confront those farmers favorably situated for this method of irrigation and to show some of the data col - lected which indicate the effects of better construction, instal - lation, and operation of the well and pumping plant, and some of the better methods of using the water. The investigations have not been extensive enough to solve many of the prob - lems. The results do, however, give some indication of the conditions to be found and show some facts peculiar to pump irrigation within the state. One characteristic of the area m Nebraska where pump irri - gation is practiced is the frequent occurrence of drouth periods of thirty days or more between April 1 and Ojctober 31. These occur about one year m two, and over a 20-year period occurred 42 times at Hastings, 44 times at Minden, and 48 times at Holdrege. During these periods less than half an inch of rain fell. Similar periods occurred m the river valleys lying north and south of the district m which these towns are located. Hot winds usually occurred only during periods of drouth. 8 Pump irrigation is being practiced on soils varying from very fine sandy loam to clay loam. These soils have a high water-carrying capacity. Water penetrates readily and very little is lost m run-off. Drainage and alkali problem^ have not appeared. The surface soils are easily tilled and produce large crops where sufficient fertility has been maintained and an optimum amount of water applied before the crop has be - gun to deteriorate from lack of moisture. Pump irrigation has been successfully practiced on large acreages ofi corn, &gt; Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1981. 'W. W. Burr and J. C. Russet, 15th Annual Report, Central Nebraska Supple - mental Irrigation Project, Department of Public Works, Lincoln, 1923-24. &gt; Burr and Russel, Report previously cited. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 potatoes, and beets. Smaller acreages of small grain, beans, onions, orchard and garden crops, and pastures have received some supplemental water by this method of irrigation in Nebraska. Apparently there is a critical time for most of these crops. The critical time for corn is the silking and tasseling period. This may or may not occur at the most serious time for other crops. Each crop must be studied and, if supplemental water is used, best results will be obtained by supplying sufficient moisture to meet the high requirements of the critical period. Increases in yields from irrigated crops are high when drouth occurs during critical periods. However, investments must be planned on a basis including the average increase in yields over a period of years and on net returns on labor, land, and crops. Table 1. — Irrigation treatment, yield, and increased yields per acre from corn, potatoes, and alfalfa for the years 1925 to 1930 inclusive at the North Platte Substation ~ZZAr_ Av. depth A v. yield ZZZZZZZt Increased pro- Year i-fSSJ_l of water irrigated aZ.__7a duction per acre irTi -- tei applied tend dryland due to irrigation CORN Acres Inches Bushels Bushels Bushels 1925 35.7 11.20 43.7 7.5 36.2 1926 39.5 10.17 40.5 2.5 38.0 1927 36.5 9.32 60.0 42.0 18.0 1928 31.0 9.80 60.0 32.7 27.3 1929 38.9 16.44 47.5 14.2 33.3 1930 33.0 18.34 96.6 3JU) 66.6 POTATOES Acres Inches Bushels | Bushels Bushels 1925 3.5 19.00 478.5 100.0 378.5 1926 4.5 26.70 253.0 102.0 151.0 1927 4.5 17.11 290.9 150.0 140.0 1928 2.0 11.69 400.0 255.4 144.6 1929 2.0 16.30 327.0 100.0 227.0 1930 2U) 21.42 215.4 109.8 105.6 ALFALFA " Acres Inches Tons Tons Tons 1925 15.0 18.30 3.5 1.5 2.0 1926 8.0 14.34 3.S 1.5 2.3 1927 3.0 9.87 4.0 2.0 2.0 1928 5.0 9.35 5.8 2.0 3.8 1929 23.0 7.70 2.7 1.0 1.7 1930 3^0 5;67 (Mi (hi 0.7 Annual rainfall for 1925 was 14.94 inches: for 1926, 16.12 inches: for 1927. 22.45 inches: for 1928, 20.63 inches; for 1929, 18.00 inches; and for 1980, 27.15 inches. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska ' Table 2. — Estimated yields on some valley farms in 1927 — annual rainfall approximately 20 inches • Z. Area Av - depth | A v. yield . „, .. Increased pro- FarmNo. irriMted of water irrigated *' »• gJJ? duction per acre ' rr ' gated applied i land dryland due to irrigation CORN Acres Inches Bushels | Bushels I Bushels 2 40 5.15 52.5 I 27.5 25.0 6 11 4.04 45.0 35.0 10.0 11 90 5.30 50.0 35.0 15.0 17 28 7.00 60.0 20.0 40.0 21 20 1.61 70.0 22.5 47.5 23 65 2.83 48.0 27.5 20.5 35 50 5.90 57.0 40.0 17.0 40 46 4.56 50.0 35.0 15.0 63 20 5^05 (HhO 35^0 25.0 POTATOES i | Acres I Inches I Bushels I Bushels I Bushels 57 I 2.75 15.00 200 I 100 100 40 35.00 4.50 | 200 | 125 I 75 21 I 15.00 I 1.61 | 200 | 100 1 100, BEETS j | Acres Inches Tons Tons Tons 33 I 35 jUl 11 7 4 Table 1, taken from the annual report from the North Platte Substation for the year 1930, gives data on increased yields of three crops, taken on a farm possibly in better tilth and of better fertility than the average farm receiving sup - plemental water. Although the results may be better j than the average to be expected, they show possibilities that can be approached on a large proportion of the pump-irrigated farms. Table 2 contains data from some of the 70 or | more farms co-operating with the Agricultural Engineering De - partment during the years 1927 and 1928. The exact amount of water to apply on each crop for eco - nomical returns is difficult to determine. The supplemental water necessary will vary not only with the crop but with the soil, tilth, fertility, water content, the time and amount of rainfall, and other climatic conditions. WATER REQUIREMENTS OF CROPS Fellows * recommends an average of 12 inches ' of supple - mental water for Nebraska pump-irrigation districts. Kies - selbach 5 has found that the corn crop requires 6.5 to 9 * Lincoln Fellows, Suggestions to Irrigators of Silt and Clay Soils, U. S D. A., Department of Public Roads, 1927. •T. A. Kiesselbach, Water Requirements of Crops, Research Bulletin No. 6, and Tech. Paper, Water Requirements, University of Nebraska, 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 TABLE 3. — The crop-producing power of 30 acre inches of water when applied to different areas of land r 1 acre 2 acres I 3 acres 4 acres 6 acres Crop 30 inches 15 inches 10 inches 7.5 inches 5 inches deep deep | deep deep deep Wheat | Bushels grain 47.51 91.42 130.59 166.16 | 226.86 Wheat I Pounds straw 4,533 7,908 10,356 13,204 I 17,916 Corn 1 Bushels grain 97.12 187.86 268.56 316.56 Com i Pounds stover 10,390 | 16,558 18,021 28,756 Sugar beets I Tons 20.82 38.90 55.89 64.84 82.68 Potatoes I Bushels 195 ! 373 456 544 I 691 Alfalfa I I Pounds 8,840 j 15,093 29,653 j 1 Data from John Widstoe and L. A. Merrill, Bulletin 117, Utah Agr. Exp. Sta.. TJ. S. D. A. co-operating, 1912. inches. Investigators at the Nebraska Experiment Station state that corn will use a quarter of an inch of water on ex - treme days during its period of maximum demand, and that this period is about one month, beginning just before silking and tasseling. While cereals and corn seldom, if ever, require the full 12 inches suggested by Fellows, potatoes and beets re - quire the full amount, and alfalfa more than 12 inches. John Widtsoe and L. A. Merrill 6 suggest 7.5 inches of irrigation water as best for corn, and state that above this amount, although increased amounts of water increased the total yield, the more water used the smaller the return per acre inch of water. Table 3 is given to show returns from different depths of water applied to different crops. The rainfall, climate, and soil represented here were very similar to those found in Nebraska pump-irrigation districts. It will be noticed that as the amount of water applied increases the yield per acre also increases but the yield per inch of water decreases. AVAILABILITY OF WATER Investigations from 1913 to 1916 T showed that a large per - centage of the irrigation pumping was from streams or ponds, and also that the territory in which pump irrigation was practiced was in the western end of the state. Much of this territory has come under canal irrigation and many of the pumping operations have been discontinued. In late years a • Bulletin No. 117, Yields of Crops with Different Quantities of Irrigation Water, IT. S. D. A. and Utah Agr. Exp. Sta. co-operating, 1912. ' H. C. Diesem's report to Samuel Fortier, Chief, Irrigation: Investigations Mim - eographed. U. S. D. A., 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska very small number have been obtaining water from streams and ponds, and a large number from wells. Most of the ,wells are in a region almost 100 miles east of North Platte. Pimp - ing from sources other than wells can be found in the south - west corner of Nebraska and east and northeast across the state. Although water is found within 20 feet of the surface in the Republican, Elkhorn, Loup, and Niobrara river vsjlleys, very few irrigation wells are found there. There are several reasons for this, chief of which is the fine texture of the water-bearing materials. To date, few successful attempts to produce irrigation wells have been made except in the gravels found in the valleys of the Plattes. In these valleys water tables at the wells vary from about 4 to 25 feet below the ground surface. The depth of water-bearing sand! and gravel varies from 12 to 200 feet. The position and thickness of either sand or gravel layers often are not the same for two well sites in the same locality, and their influence on irriga - tion wells is not definitely known (Fig. 3, page 17). I The water table has seasonal fluctuations but the supply has ap - parently not been diminished by irrigation pumping. Some investigators are of the opinion that a large increase in (num - bers of pumps may at times produce greater seasonal lower - ing of the water table and yet have no permanent effect. 8 FACTORS THAT INFLUENCE THE YIELD OF WELLSj Irrigation wells in Nebraska vary widely in details of con - struction, the differences indicating the ideas and opinions of those responsible for them. In some cases minimum cost was the objective; in others, maximum yield of water. One or more of the following factors have usually been considered in planning and constructing an irrigation well: 1. Effect of well diameter on yield and draw-down. 2. Effect of depth of well on yield and draw-down. 3. Materials for casings, design, probable corrosion or other ob - struction. 4. Perforation of casing — size, amount needed, placing. 5. Methods of construction — gravel treatment, developing. 6. Age Df well— does yield decrease with age? 7. The spacing of wells where a group of two or more are operated from the same pumping plant. 8. The relation of draw-down to the total yield of a well. 9. The use of information obtained frcm the log of a test well as a basis for making an irrigation well and specifying the pumping plant. The relative importance of the different factors has not been fully established. Information about construction de - tails on wells in service is usually incomplete and inaccurate • G. E. Condra and A. L. Lugn, Conservation Report, University of Nebraska, 1931. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 and thus nullifies efforts to correlate or evaluate influence of the various factors on performance. This is brought out in the data and discussions on the pages which follow, and war - rants the opinion that careful study and experimentation are needed to establish the correct answers to the points in question. Table 4 shows some data that indicate the difficulties en - countered in trying to determine the greatest influence upon the yield of a well. All these data were obtained in 1931 and 1932 from wells in the Platte valley. Groupings in the table are made to emphasize or minimize some condition that has at some time been offered as causing greater or less discharge per foot of draw-down in the wells. The yields of wells as shown in the table are averages of yields obtained when the wells were pumped at various rates of discharge. In the first grouping of wells, Nos. 4, 7 and 17, all in the same locality, the greatest yield was from the well of extra large diameter. However, Well No. 7, having the same diam - eter as Well No. 4 but with 11 per cent greater depth of water, yielded 39 per cent more water. Well No. 17 not only had a diameter three times as great as No. 7 but had 13 per cent greater depth, which may have been a great influence in securing the 150 per cent greater yield per foot of draw - down. Another condition, the influence of which is not known, was the fact that a large quantity of very coarse gravel was worked down on the outside of Well No. 17 in the course of construction possibly giving a more effective screening area than is indicated by the diameter of the casing. The grouping of Wells Nos. 8 and 13 shows conditions that may be of greater influence on the yield of the well than that of different material in the casings. These wells are on ad - joining farms and are about one-half mile apart. The con - crete casing not only has greater outside diameter but also has a 6-inch screen of gravel around it and 83 per cent greater depth of water. All conditions combined gave Well No. 13 a yield 97 per cent greater than that of Well No. 8. That greater depth of water in a well may be expected to cause a greater yield is emphasized in the grouping of Wells Nos. 5, 9, 21, and 22. Wells Nos. 5 and 9 are about one mile apart but show many of the same conditions, with the well of greater depth showing the larger yield. The contrast be - tween Wells Nos. 21 and 22 is emphatic. These wells were 25 feet apart. Well No. 22, although having a diameter one - half that of Well No. 21, had almost three times the depth of water and yielded almost twice as much. However, Well No. 21 was 8 or 9 years old and Well No. 22 was made the year it was tested (1931). </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska «JSsSfv. gTOUpinfif 0f Wells Nos - U and 14 &gt; man y determined conditions were very nearly the same but the yield of Well No. 14 was three times that of Well No 11 Gravel treatment of wells is often credited with influence 13 r_J?i? U T S g lt ater - £ eIds - The S rou P in * of WeUs Nos? w H ! h0W ? *5 e yield not vef y different in either well but most determined conditions widely different. Well No 13 2^ J* d diameter and greater depth of water but also the 6-mch gravel treatment outside the casing «,_ I L« com P arison in an y grouping in Table 4, doubfj as to the influence of any apparent condition was caused by lack of hftFSSh! ° n * h l SF". ° f Wells « amount of perforation We Al. Sl™**' a nd 9 e location » Position, thickness, and tex - ture of the sand and gravel formations. Table 4. — Comparative data on yields of wells ™j _ Well Material Diameter Depth Denthof I &lt;3„„.;«,. number incasing of casing pfjg "^atcr | Sffifef /ncA&lt;! * Fcit | r » GREATER DIAMETER OF WELL VS. GREATER DEPTH OF WATER ' 4 Galv. 24 58.0 I 39.3 4k 0 1? w 1V A 2! 61 -° 43-8 57 0 17 Wood ?6 70.7 I 49.7 ___ 5 KIND OF CASING VS. DEPTH OF WATER 8 Galv. 24 50.0 j 36.3 wn 13 Concrete 24 90.0 66.6 655 322 j OD -° b P-° EFFECT OF DEPTH OF WATER 5 Galv. 24 I 59.7 43 7 Jo o 9 Galv. 24 | 60.0 46*0 IU 21 Galv - 24 I 36.5 334 fn'f, —2? Galv - 12 I 102.0 llj l.j UNDETERMDJED FACTORS VS. GREATER YD3LD j " | Ga . lv - I 24 I 55.0 I 39.0 I 67 4 ' —ii l Galv - I 24 I 57.7 1 40.0 | 22.5 GRAVEL TREATMENT VS. DEPTH OF WATER 13 I Concrete 24^ | 90.0 66.6 ' J 6 5.5 15 Concrete 17 I 55.4 29.1 | Je.O ! Sf_ — ! 1 i The yield of water per foot of drawdown is called the specific capacity of . * Outside diameter. EFFECT OF WELL DIAMETER Some authorities state that where all conditions as to sand and gravel strata, well and casing construction, and ?dXw- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 down are the same throughout, the yield of a well is in - fluenced by its diameter; that is, the yield varies with the log e of R, where R is the radius of screen surface. 0 The in - terpretation of this statement shows that if a well one foot in diameter produces 500 g. p. m. (gallons per minute), a well 2 feet in diameter would produce 720 g. p. m. ; 3 feet, 850 g. p. m.; 4 feet, 920 g. p. m.; and 10 feet, 1,200 g. p. m., approximately. Roughly, then, considering diameters alone, it requires a well with a diameter almost 10 times as great as another to produce twice the yield of water. Table 5. — Well casings examined in 1927 and 1928 Number Material Diameter I Depth of casing 1 or range Inches Feet 1 Steel 14 1 " 16 33 3 - " 18 28-35 1 " 20 36 1 " 22 25 35 " 24 15-62 4 " 26 27-60 1 " 28 85 2 " 30 32 1 " 36 83 2 " 40 40 1 : " 48 40 1 | Wood 16 28 1 | " 20 26 3 " 24 26-30 1 " 26 20 1 " 18 24 1 " 25 28.b 1 Wire 24 5 Concrete | 24 23-45 1 ■ "1 25 90 1 ZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZZ " I 14 and 18 58.5 No data have been obtained in Nebraska that indicate a weakness in the statement. Neither has sufficient information been obtained to indicate the most economical diameter of well strainer for any given condition. Very few wells of re - cent construction are less than 16 inches in diameter and, be - cause 70 per cent of the pumps are the vertical type, appar - ently the dimension of the pump has influenced the diameter of the well. 10 Tables 4 and 5 show how these well diameters vary. There appears to be no definite relation between diam - »F. E. Turneaure and H. L. Russell, Puhlic Water Supply, McGraw-Hill Co. "University ot Nebraska Agricultural Engineering Department Survey (Mimeo - graphed). 1827-28. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska eter and depth. All of these wells were constructed to pro - duce 1,000 gallons per minute but vary in yield from 500 to 1200 g. p. m. It will be noted that more than two-thirds of the wells have casings 24 inches in diameter. Wells of larger diameter cost more and such hazards as caving in are greater. WELL CASINGS As shown in Tables 4 and 5, by far the greater number of wells that have come under observation are equipped with steel casings. These have differed in weight and con - struction and in methods of treatment against corrosion and incrustation. Recent installations show casings of a heavy galvanized steel (12 to 20 gauge) with galvanizing done after the perforations have been made. The jwood and concrete casings have not been standardized to any further degree than the metal. The size and shape of casings and the amount of per - foration vary with the different well contractors who have made irrigation wells. Slotted, perforations, 3/32 to 3/16 inch wide, predominate. These vary in length from the "dollar size" in some steel casings, to almost the full length of a section in some concrete casings. Formerly some of the steel casings were perforated after they were placed in the well. Most of the recently manufactured casings have the perforations punched from the inside before be - ing galvanized. Slots or holes in the concrete and wood casings are usually smaller on the outer than on the inner surface. Some of the slots in the concrete sectional casings do not go directly through but carry the water to the (joints between sections, where it is discharged inside. The amount of perforation needed in casings has not been definitely determined. It is agreed by some author - ities " that the perforated area to be ideal must present a minimum of obstruction to any water that can come in contact with the casing. Since average river sand and gravel contain about 30 per cent voids, it is suggested that the perforation should be as great as 30 per cent or {more, or that other means be provided to allow the water to enter through the casing with a very small amount of friction. Samples of some of the casings in common pse in the irrigation wells show 11 to 20 per cent perforation. In many of the wells observed, the normal pumping) rate lowered the water level sufficiently to expose many feet of perforation. In many instances water seemed to be trapped outside these exposed perforated areas, ajnd to show much less draw-down immediately outside the casing " A. 6. A. E. Imitation Committee Report, 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 than within the well. This was probably caused by in - crustation, layers of fine sand, clay tightly packed against the casing, or other obstacles to free movement of the water. In most wells observed it was apparent that little attempt had been made to utilize foreknowledge of prob - able draw-down in the well when the perforated sections of casings were placed. In many, several feet of these per - forations were exposed during the pumping operation within and after a very few minutes. In these installations the owner had paid the extra cost of the exposed per - forated casing, which, in some cases, permitted entrapped water to trickle into the well at some distance above the water level in sufficient quantities to entrain air and inter - fere with best performance of the pump. It is the opinion of the authors that there is no direct benefit to be derived from any perforated casing above the probable draw-down level of water in the well. GRAVEL TREATMENTS One of the methods of cutting down the friction as the water enters a casing, and at the same time adding to the "screening area", is the so-called "gravel treatment". Several methods are used in placing this gravel. The ob - ject sought is to provide a layer 3 to 6 inches thick of coarse graded gravel around all the perforated area of the casings. In general, it is believed that this gravel treat - ment permits more rapid flow of water into the well. How - ever, the data contained in the lower part of Table 4 may indicate that care should be used in specifying gravel treat - ment. Observations seem to indicate that the more care used in placing the gravel, the more positive the benefits. When it was known where strata of fine sand or clay were located and care taken that gravel was definitely placed between these materials and the well casing, the influence of the gravel seemed more positive. The practice of "developing" a new well has been fol - lowed by successful well contractors for many years. Usually, a good development is made by pumping slowly for a short period until the water clears of any fine sand and then gradually increasing the pumping rate until the maximum of the well is obtained. At each successive pumping rate, time is allowed for the discharged water to clear, thus assuring that most of the fine sand will be drawn from near the casing at practically every depth along the perforated portion of the casing. Very few of the irrigation wells in Nebraska have been developed in this systematic manner. In most cases the new pump was </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska installed and if a sizable stream of water was forthcoming, it was promptly "estimated" as meeting the terms of the contract. There is little doubt that many wells have been seriously damaged by being pumped at too high a rate at first. EFFECT OF ACE ON YIELD In many districts in the river valleys, especially the Re - publican, reports show that irrigation wells yield less as they become older, and city wells have been abandoned because of decreased yields. Corrosion, incrustation, and clogging of screens have been given as causes for failures in wells. In some places in the Platte valleys therd were indications that some irrigation wells were showing de - creased yields with increasing age. During the summers of 1927 and 1928 an attempt was made to obtain definite information on the subject. Only two wells could be located that had been under observation previously. These had been observed in 1914 near Kearney, -Nebraska, 12 Table 6. — Effect of age on yield | Well No. 1 WeU Noi 2 | 1914 1927 1928 1914 l 1927 il 1928 Speed of pump (r. p. m.)....| 795 1 795 635 610 I 699 Total lift (feet) 40 43 31 24.751 29 Yield (ff. p. m.) I 910 785 795 776 || 921 1 Same tractor and same pulley equipment each year but owner's estimate for speed in 1914. Well No. 1 (Table 6) produced less water in 1928 than in 1914 but had greater lift and probably less efficiency ]in the pump on account of wear. Data seem to indicate that Well No. 2 was giving good yields after 14 years of use. I Little trouble should be encountered in any of the irrigation wells in a 14-year period, provided they are located in a bed of good coarse sand-gravel formations. Just how long an irrigation well will maintain the original yield, where a large amount of very fine materials are present in water-bearing strataj is not indicated by any data available. THE SPACING OF WELLS In most installations in the Nebraska pump-irrigati&gt;n dis - tricts, the depth of water is 25 feet or more, and sand- gravel formations are such that a single well supplies the pump. Where the formations are of finer texture, the yield from a single well may be insufficient and two or more wells are con - nected to one pump, the spacing being 40 to 50 feet in most cases. U H. C Diecem, Repori to U. S. D. A. (Mimeographed), 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 fy** :___ f^ .**.-,„*. ll my. syrmmuro* — , __^_— . - _^ — _—^^— _^ __ _ -___ / ...... i rv^ __ -■i-wV .^ * \«fTto mssts^setiiswsii^Ar-. . -^ . ■•' ''■-' . '.-• :.* ■ *s '■' -'••'*.';:; -, '.-. — "~ J. ; ■'-^.^V'...'..'i . ■• J . -.-%■■■ ■:/ :■•- ,-.•-.■._-*.&gt;.,.- Fig. 1. — When water is pumped from a well, the water level is affected several hundred feet distant. The effect close to the well casing is always most pronounced. THE RELATION OF DRAW-DOWN TO YIELD OF A WELL In Figure 1, from data collected on a Buffalo county farm, is shown the shape of the water table before pumping started and after the pump had been operated •:-7: the two periods shown. The break down - "T\ -~~ .A r '--^_ ward near the pumped well, with the low- -&gt;Z$s- ea * P°* nt °* e wa t er i n the well itself, \pf',y produces an inverted conelike appearance, • ; .\\ _, Iff;: ZZ and this is called the cone of depression '"•-' - v * iti' (Fig. 2). The outer ends of these curves •'■'•.. r-'A terminate in what is known as the circle ■,'•'.': of influence, beyond which the water has ".-.-'. .-■■".'.•' not been lowered. Both the cone of de - _Iin_«' pression and the circle of influence vary 7/7 '■•'..' tn shape in different localities, because ;..'.' ,-7 of differences in thickness, position, and %'■■■■■. •••"-•&gt; texture of the water-bearing formations. £?. .7 ■'•':■- -j All this must be considered in selecting S|fe ,:-Z -'-/■ ' : ZM the best spacing for wells, if. each well is to have a minimum of influence on the ■p o ti. i- performance of another. tance the apex of In observing the performance of the the cone of de- well from which the data were obtained pression remains for Figure 1, it was f ound that 21 other above the water irrigation wells within a radius of two is influenced to miles were being P um P e d most of the time the stratifications while the data were being recorded, of water-bearing Measurements were taken at the well and material as well a t each of the sand points during the fL&amp;J5£££. period between August 13, 1928, and Sep - the welMtseff tember 14, 1928. Part of the measure- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska ments were taken while the pump was at rest, part at inter - vals during the pumping operation. At the end of each 10-hour pumping period the shape of the water table was nearly identical with that illustrated in Figure 1, and, although on some days the operation continued 12 to 13 hours, the recovery was rapid and the water table resumed a position practically parallel to the original position, being about 3 inches lower at the end of 9 hours rest, and about 2 inches lower at the end of 12 hours rest. When the pump was idle 24 hours or more, no appreciable change from the original elevation could be detected. Measurements on September 14, 1928, showed almost the identical eleyations for all points while the pump was idle as were found on August 13, 1928. During the month not only had this pump been operated several days at a discharge of more than 1,000 g. p. m., but several of the other 21 pumps had been operated at irregular intervals. No appreciable effect could be noticed at any well when others were being pumped. Although not indicated in Figure 1, it has been found that some slight draw-down can be noticed after 12 to 14 hours pumping at a distance of more than 1,000 feet from a well being pumped at 1,000 g. p. m. in some of the coarse [forma - tions. This lowering of the water table at great distances from a pumped well is usually found to be only a f ew| inches and probably will not be important in the pumping districts of the Platte valleys with present crops and supplemental water demands. In other valleys much more information is needed. It was generally found that for each well or well group there is a definite relation between the yield of water and the draw-down (lowering of the water in the well while pump is operated). This is usually referred to as the specific capacity of the well. The last column in Table 7 shows some jspecific capacities expressed in gallons of water per minute for each foot of draw-down at several rates of pumping. It will be noted that the specific capacity of each (well in Table 7 is different. Since the diameters of these wells are the same and the depth of water in each does not account for the difference in specific capacities, it can be assumed that the nature of water-bearing formations about these wells has a major influence on the yields. One engineer 1S stages that the experiences of his company show that specific capacity will hold constant until the water is lowered to one-tlhird of the original depth. Table 7 seems to bear out this statement. u E. W. Bennison, Kelly Well Co., Grand Island, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 Table 7.— Relation of draw-down to total yield of a weU x Farm — =-: . Speed &lt; Discharge No. Diam. ToU1 Depth Perfor- of Total Draw- s- ts °f depth °* ated pump u *' down Per il.J ca»ing rvw water casing P P minute In. Ft. Ft. Ft. -r.p.m. Ft. Ft. Gals, g.p.m. 10 24 47.5 23.5 21 795 24.7 0.0 0 0 0 0 896 27.0 2.3 131.0 57.0 987 30.5 5.9 279.0 47 7 1093 34.9 10.3 506.3 49.3 1195 40.4 15.8 660.5 41.9 1315 43.5 18.8 799.5 42.5 11 24 55.0 39.0 21 680 16.9 0.0 0 0 0 0 768 18.4 1.8 147.0 79^8 909 22.1 5.5 409.5 75.0 1069 26.5 9.9 715.0 72.4 1223 31.2 14.6 1038.3 71.0 1354 34.9 18.3 1260.5 68.8 1462 38.4- 21.8 1462.5 67.2 1475 38.8 22.2 1496.3 67.6 12 24 59.0 35.4 40 802 26.3 [ 0.0 0.0 0 0 900 28.6 2.4 85.0 35.9 995 32.1 5.8 219.9 37.8 1085 35.7 9.4 364.0 38.8 1182 40.3 14.0 531.0 37.9 1284 45.8 19.6 715.0 36.6 | 1383 51.0 24.8 857.3 34.6 I ' I I 1481 | 53.6 27.4 947.5 34.6 'Data from irrisration wells lu. Hall county. Nebraska, 1981. The casinars were OTlvanlzed steel in all the well, and the three pump, were turbine type^nd6-Tnch THE USE OF INFORMATION OBTAINED FROM THE LOG OF A TEST WELL The only absolutely accurate and reliable method of de - termining the yield of a well is a pumping test. Since this is impractical in most instances, and almost impossible at times, some method of estimating yields must be used by those who contemplate putting down an irrigation well. The best source of information for estimating yields is the log of a test well. In all the previous discussion in this publication the influence of casing materials, sizes, etc., was shown to de - pend partly on the water-bearing formations. Many disap - pointments and much expense would have been avoided if con - struction of wells had been preceded by a test hole which would have given some definite idea of the nature and position of materials from which the water was to be drawn. Figure 3 shows the logs of three test wells. Those with some experience in making irrigation wells would feel as con- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska 3TT71 H i I A ' h f _ ? z _ ___ __ CMOUMO LCVCl w |*1 j_ M|__i_°ilI^ZZ_ ' | s Js s .-. . LIGHT SANDY SOIL * ° S ° 21 ZjHBi_______!_ !_____ i cmXJNOLCVCL " **" '** IIM tS-"'CMSSSm CLAY 7 .-• E — jE ■Win__3_____ 1 1___.^Z. _____________ • ' ' SANO AND LIGHT '•&gt;•&amp; SANDY LOAM '..' .' GRAVEL - ■• v-» .'.•• WHITE DRIFT SAND ':. ''. ■ FINE SAND. , -. _ - _ ,- /• ;' - .'. ; •: SPRINKLE OF X-__T. L — — gjff *=«= =*= SB _____________ S§8_usc___ &gt; • ' : ■ E°*R5E BLACK f_K »' COARSE SAND AND *.____ W^J _NQ -. a •*■ GRAVEL .■.&gt;&gt;• -. ".- "ED SAND AND &lt;*"„ 77 FINE SAND r -f_, CM,a - T~ y^tr -6»Mf _*»_.- -ftav. 1 - .7.-/-.'- V*V «L 00 *"*""*"- ~~~!1" i _:i___ 5 ______ E _ i£_||____£___E £, COARSE GRAVEL I iJeS. 3 c _&amp; GRAWEL-COURSE K*? COARSE GRAVEL SJ? «=» SAND-SCATTERED g2? -» « 4*. £S» * 0 LARC£ PEBBLES 3y 7 . g-9., _ 3H IZIffS 1^ s"»yu *ip p»evu_ " 0 and rock - __ ± ___ ___________ ~ 0°= COARSE GRAVEL . _. „. °_. , _. ,. T « FINER GRAVEL-BROW ■* -^ gjg — — " D IE 2ZZB fllV Z - • 1*1 JL &lt;°° _ 2_ JI °j^ rg» GRAVEL S*J - it -— __j ;&amp;»! rne gr/wel :?' : .*; _____m. _________ *»-frf&gt;^iintv.w.c.^. ° :•", S^^*i£u Sb COARSE GRAVEL TO ■.-&gt;&gt; V.... COARSE SANO J_ *' _£._! ■/'«• COARSE AND S ** ~ _ |p i.^. FINE GRWEL , g^ %pj YELLOW- BLUE CLAY ■» «; .£■ iJS_ ,„, „„ .;.':&gt;. „ V/As :«••'•' ffi_?F SAND ' / » ."'v SMALL GRAVEL _____%__ il- r-r •..•»' SS^ EL .'.•-; MEDIUM SAND ■;. £^. FINE SAND AND 15% »}.?, .. ..';.■ FINE CRAY SANO 9IM»- .6 «» CWWEL ______ ''•'■. , ... ., • : : ; " _. _: _s a_____ s - - r^ 1 — SJfe -&gt;■+ FINE SAND AND •. » sa t. 1** GRAY GRAVEL „ _. 4 . "^i CLAY PARTICLES ■• . MEDIUM SANBLESS ' VA&amp; "Tr : •,. GRAVEL THAN ABOlrt mb \ : . FWE AND COARSE ' . ' Ul.l%a I -____-?. ??_ NOI • . . SAND ANO MEDUM ..jr. + • GRAVEL •" ■•*• GRAVEL ANO _______ __Z__\ A.f COARSE SANO I ,A- 1 1 a- \s/ess,Ae, _ I ;.\..^ N02 \ja__________M NO 3 Fig. 3. — The position of each layer or stratum of sand and gravel, as shown here, was determined by the careful operation bf a sand bucket inside a closed casing. The three holes represented were made in the Platte valley. Each hole is less than y_ mile from one of the others. fident of the output and draw-down in a well in the coarse strata indicated in the log of test well No. 1 as in either No. 2 or No. 3. Although the depth of water in No. 1 lits be - tween the 16-foot and 52-foot levels, and that for No. 2 and No. 3 is much greater, the presence of the fine sand and clay layers in the latter two can be expected to retard the flow of underground water and to cause more trouble in construction and possibly greater total lift when delivering a large quan - tity of water. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station . Bulletin 282 Unless the data for such a display were very carefully ob - tained, the log would be useless to the well contractor. The information displayed in Figure 3 is not sufficient for an ac - curate forecast of yield unless supported by knowledge of the area of the water-bearing formations, the origin and temp - erature of the water, the hydraulic slope, and general geology of the country. The best practical method of putting down test holes in Nebraska is the sand bucket and blank casing method. Best results are obtained when the casing sinks readily and its lower end is as deep as the point reached by the sand bucket at all times. This precaution produces the sample in undis - turbed or unwashed form. Some engineers have developed formulas to use in making classification of sands and gravels and calculating specific capacities. As most of these formulas involve factors of per - sonal judgment, many engineers rety solely on judgment and experience in classifying the formations as they appear in a display similar to that shown in Figure 3 and rate each depth of material as excellent, good, poor, etc. types of pump installations in wells The type of pump installation most general in Nebraska seems to have been influenced more by cost than a desire for economy of operation. Table 8 contains data obtained from the wells that were under observation during 1927 and 1928, and indicates average installation costs as found in most places in the state. It will be noted that about 50 per cent of these installations show costs for both pump and well of $750 or less. Except in the more expensive installations, about one - fourth of this amount represents the pump cost. Table 9 shows the size and type of pump in more than 100 represen - tative installations. There seems to be no definite reasons why the 6-inch pumps are the more numerous, except for a prevalent idea that 1,000 gallons per minute is a desirable size of stream (irrigating head) for one man to handle. Very few of the complete in - stallations observed in 1927-28, equipped with 6-inch pumps, snowed costs of more than $1,000. Although these costs seem relatively high in some instances, in others they are low when the acreage served is considered. The date in Table 10 were obtained from farms, the owners of which co-operated on the pump irrigation studies in the years 1927 and 1928. If the investment of from $750 to $1,000 is spread over the 80 to 100 acres, as shown by the five largest fields, or even the average of 50 to 55 acres, the invest- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska ment per acre irrigated ranges from $10 to $20. For those in the class of the five owners of the smallest fields, $35 to $50 per acre was invested. When these investment costs are (com - pared with irrigation-canal systems where the construction costs were as low as $50 in some of the older systems and as Table 8. — Investment in well and pump, engine or motor not included Number of pumps Price range Horizontal Verjtical Not over $500 5 13 $501-$750 1 ]6 $751-$1,000 12 $1,001-91,500 2 5 $l,501-?2,500 5 1 Over $2,500 1 _ Table 9. — Classification of pumps, 1927-28 Pump | Horizontal Vertical size Gear type Centrifugal Centrifugal Turbine Bucket 10-in. .. .. 2 8-in. 1 .... 7 6-in. 2 20 59 3 5-in. .. .. 1 4-in. 1 .. 1 .. 3-in. .. .. 1 Bucket ._. ._. .. l Totals i 4 20 64 10 1 'Total, all types, 99. Table 10. — Size of fields under 6-inch pumps, 1927-28 Plant Acres Times Total depth Hours Gallon's per No. irrigated over in inches operated minnte FIVE LARGEST FIELDS 3 105 2 8.81 372% 1,087.00 36 100 1 6.27 280 1,008.00 64 82 1 2.06 97% 776.25 25 87 1-J- 8.39 305% 776.25 26 85 2-f 11-37 376 969.70 FIVE SMALLEST FIELDS 27 15 1 2.57 25 695.00 571 2% 3 15.82 19Vi 946.00 47 20 1 2.50 35% 628.00 68 20 3 15.66 138 1,021.50 8 25 1 3.17 45% 776.25 1927 . |l928 Total observed acres under 6-inch pumps 1,430.8 2.219.2 Number of 6-inch pumps observed 27 40 Average acres per pump 52.9 55.5 1 The crop irrigated on all of these farms was corn, with the exception of Farm No. 57, where some potatoes were watered also. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 high as $300 per acre in some of the later government projects," pump irrigation investments seem low. in very few instances were the pumping plants being fully utilized. Usually only one or two different crops were being irrigated from one pump installation. Instead of planning to irrigate the minor crops at periods before or after irrigating the major crop and instead of investigating soil moisture in advance of planting or during the growing season, most of the pump irrigators do all the irrigating during one short period while water demands of the crop are high. After this short period they consider it too late for further benefits. The acreage for each pumping plant is materially decreased bv this program of management. Fall or winter irrigation, where the soil is not too porous, has given very good results in the Arkansas valley in Kansas. Fields side by side, the one fall-irrigated or irrigated before any crop was planted, the other not irrigated, showed 34.6 to 41.7 bushels of corn to the acre for the irrigated as compared to no gram and only 0.51 to 0.79 ton of stover to the acre of non-irrigated corn. 15 Practically no fall or spring irrigation is done in Nebraska and the possibility of irrigating more acres from one installation has generally been overlooked It may also be noted in the last column of Table 10 that one-half of the 6-mch pumps were delivering less than 900 gallons per minute because of lack of water, lack of power, etc. All of these installations were rated at 1,000 g. p. m This condition was very common in all parts of the state, giving further evidence of need of engineering supervision and testing. This supervision should include the complete in - stallation of well, pump, and power. installations other than in wells In addition to the investigational studies of well installa - tions, observations have been made on a number of scattered pumping plants which take water from sand pits, ponds, and streams. These present problems somewhat different from those found in the well installations. The cost of the well and the uncertainty of its capacity are here eliminated. However troubles do arise from trash and sand choking the suction pipes, and from friction in the discharge pipes, where water is forced tea level many feet above the pump and some dis - tance from it. Figure 4 (upper part) illustrates some of the points that need consideration in this type of installation. A similar one " Elwood Mead. Reclamation Era, U. S. D. A.. January, 1931 "G. S. Knapp. Winter Irrigation in Kansas, K. S. A. C. Circular No. 27, 1913. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska was being used on the Elkhorn river and employed a ground union at "C" and the windlass to aid in removing obstructions. When the foot valve "B" was choked, the suction pipe was raised out of the water to facilitate any remedy necessary. In many installations the foot valve is not used but a vqlve is |j||gbsl||jilli§^ A HORIZONTAL CENTRIFUGAL PUMP INSTALLATION SfiJPSgpsfSPiPlijPlf FOR STREAMS ANO PONDS mi^\ JS "'-__ = t yp?V££^^5a**^PLAN OF INSTALLATION I CROSS-SECTION OF WELL Fig. 4. — Diagrammatic plans for the most successful pump instal - lations found on Nebraska ponds and streams. placed in the discharge line as at "A" to aid in priming the pump. Many of the installations on streams have given trouble because the lower end of the suction pipe was not far enough below the water surface, or was too close to sand. jSome - times the suction pipe was in a position too near the hori- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 zontal. In the first case, air drawn down in swirls was entrapped in pipes and pump and reduced the flow of water at irregular intervals or broke the prime of the pump. In the other conditions, the obstruction of the suc - tion opening cut down the water flow into the pump. In most of such cases sumps or wells were built in the stream itself, the down-stream side being open and screened or built back from the stream bank with an opening from the stream to the sump (Fig. 4, lower part). Provision for a depth of 6 feet of water above the open end of the suction pipe and one foot of water below it for pumps discharging 1,000 g. p. m. has usually corrected these troubles. Many of these stream and pond installations have not been legally authorized. At present an adjudication of water rights is required by law for all pumping other than from wells. Very little time or expense is necessary to comply with this requirement. An application blank must be made out and filed with the Nebraska Department of Public Works. This application and the adjudication of rights that follows cost little and protect the owner of the pump installation in suits and establish a prior claim to the water allotted to him. friction in pipes In many installations of this type little recognition seems to have been given to the fact that water encounters fric - tional resistance as it flows through pipes. Pipes of too small diameter add to the required power and consequent cost of operation. The total lift or head against which a pump must operate is the sum of the gravity head plus the friction head. The gravity head is the vertical distance in feet between the water level in the well or stream while the pump is operat - ing and the level to which the water is raised for delivery. The friction head is due to loss of pressure in the pipes through which the water flows. To these losses must be added some head for loss in the pump, elbows, valves, etc. Table 11 will be found useful in selecting pipe for dif - ferent rates of flow. An example of its use follows : How much pressure is required to overcome frictional resistance of a stream of 1,000 g. p. m. in a straight, horizontal 6-inch pipe 300 feet long? In the first column the value 1,000 is found and following across to the right in the column with the heading, "6 inch diameter", is found the figure 12.04, or 12.04 feet of pressure head is needed for each 100 feet of pipe. Then for 300 feet the pressure needed will be 3 X 12.04 or 36.12. In other words, it takes a pressure </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska equal to over 36 feet of height to push 1,000 gallons per minute of water through 300 feet of 6-inch pipe laid hori - zontally. If the discharge end were 20 feet higher than the intake end, this would be added to the 36 feet of fric - tion head. Reference to Table 11 shows that this friction loss could be reduced to about one-fourth of this amount if |8-inch pipe were selected. This permits choice of pipe. Invest - ment in pipe can thus be balanced against operating cost in making the selection for any installation. Table 11. — Friction loss per 100 feet of ordinary iron pipe Gallons | Diameter of pipe per | 4-in. | 5-in. | 6-in. 1 8-in. j 10-in. j 12-in. 1 14-in. 1 16-in. minute j Friction head in feet 400 15.82 5.33 I 2.21 0.56 450 19.75 6.65 2.74 0.64 0.21 500 24.08 S.12 l 3.26 0.81 0.28 0.11 750 17.22 I 7.00 1.74 0.59 0.24 0.11 1,000 12.04 3.02 1.01 0.41 0.19 1,250 18.20 4.45 1.51 0.62 0.29 0.15 1,500 6.27 2.09 0.85 0.39 0.24 2,000 | 10.71 3.50 1.43 0.661 0.39 TYPE OF POWER USED More than one-half of all the pumping units observed were driven by a tractor. Among the others, more than twice as many stationary engines as electric motors were found. Where the installations were depending |on the tractor for power, the pumping operations were often de - layed longer than was best for the crops irrigatied. In these instances, the tractor was used primarily for field work. Many of the stationary engines were not kept in readiness, and delays were experienced. Too often poor installation or failure to keep the equipment in working order caused a serious loss in the crops. Very f^w had electric power, but where this service was used, attendance at the plant, as well as delays in starting the seasonal pump - ing, were usually less than for the engine-driven plants. COST OF PUMPING The pumped water in most of the valley installations costs little, if any, more than the annual maintenance and operating costs on many canal systems. Before showing the costs found in the investigations, the following table of equivalents (Table 12) and an example to explain costs with the use of the table are given to show cost relations. Pumps are rated at the number of gallons per minute and | flow of water in cubic feet per second or second-feet. The amounts of </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 fi?,i«H a Kt?if asUred ST ex P r essed in acre-feet. Costs are figured by the acre, the acre-foot or acre-foot per foot of Table 12.— Equivalent terms common to pump irrigation 1 ac-ft. (covers an acre 1 ft. deep). .=43,660 cu. ft. 1 cu. ft. per sec. running 1 hour = 1 acre-inch Awn C _Z\ P ° r ? ecc mn ? m B 12 hours..=l acre-foot (ac-ft.) 450 gals, per mm. running 12 hours _ = 1 acre-foot (ac-ft , me^uM^d^^^^^ F "- B P »" " "Plain, how to i«^5. eXam ? I _ J i , _ f *_. e use of these terms will aid in clarify - ing them. At the North Platte station in 1930 the electric - 5.Y 5 P^ ted P U ™P^_ Plant, producing 1,140 g. p. m., irri - gated.50.1 acres m 302.25 hours, using a total of 5,870 kilo - _T_?_M_ B i»_n , "5 [8 - ) °, f eiectricitj^. The electrical energy f!l, 2 orf-r?r? ; £, nd apply*** water, at 40 cents per hour cost $120.90. The total lift was 57 feet. * i'62 0 ci„ ranni'ngfor 802_5 WsVZZZ^Ifl X sSls" &lt;C - £ - 8 - ) ! = — =63.47 ac-ft. 6 ?o« 22? f e^ B a S , M ed s. t0 50 - 1 acres covered the fields 1.-6 feet or 15.12 inches deep (average) Total operating cost-$244.63 + $120.90 = $365.53 for 50.1 acres - -__. $365.53 _\9 Operating cost per acre, = $7 at 50.1 ' r, $365.53 Operating cost per acre-foot, : — .. =$5 76 « , , 63.47 Power (electrical[ 5,870 energy) per acre-foot, = 92.48 kw.-hrs. 63.47 Cost of power per acre-foot, .... . =$3 85 n -. s, 63 - 4 7 cost cf power per 3 85 acre-foot per foot of lift, — - =$0,067, or 6.7 cents 244.63 Average cost per, kw.-hr., =4 17 cent 5,870 t&gt; A «2.48 Power per acre-foot per foot of lift, =1.62 kw.-hrs. Power per 1,000 I 1.62 x 1,000 B *" 0M "" *"* '"*• «l?55Bi - 0 - 0049 ■"-'»• </seg>
            <seg id="p025">RECTANGULAR WEIR 24" CREST RECTANGULAR WEIR , IS ■ CREST g CALLOUS ACRC Q s CALLOUS ACRE Q "GALLONS ACRC « GALLONS ACRE * CALL0N5 ACRE * GALLONS ACRE n GALLONS ACRC rt GALLONS ACRE 3_5 PER 'NCHES J.S INCHES JjS INCHCS &lt;z\ .NCHES ?,S INCHES &lt;l¥ „„ INCHES 3zS _ INCHES ?iS ... INCHES * S PER S"S " R PER SfJ "" PER STS P " PER ("S &lt;" S'S «» Si ™ PER PS ~R ' MMUTC HOIW MINUTE HOUR _______ MINUTE HOUR . MiHUTE HOUR ~ MINUTE HOUR ~ MINUTE HOUR " MINUTE HOUR ~ MINUTE HOUR |_J 3 364.25 041 i'/. 82850 184 7 '/i 1395.00 3 10 9*2016.00 448 3 274 05 0 6 1 5 Vs 6 16.95 1.37 l'/l 1047.60 2.33 i'/s 1545.75 3.44 C i 31*38700 086 5*85723 1.90 75*142575 3.17 9 4 2052.00 4 56 3 1* 290.70 0.65 5 J /« 639.00 1 .42 7*1073.70 2 39 9 Ji 1574.55 3.51 K 314409.50 0.91 5^88650 197 7*1462.50 3 25 10 2088.25 4 64 3 * 306 90 0 68 5 h 661.05 I .47 7 3 4 1100.25 2.45 10 1603.35 3.57 3*433.50 0.96 5*91775 2.04 7 4 1498.25 3.32 » 4 212523 4 72 3* 324 00 0 72 Sts 683.55 1.52 7k 1127.29 2.51 Mil 1632.15 3.63 fo 31*457.50 1.02 5*947.50 211 8 1530.00 3.40 K&gt;!» 2162.25 4 80 3 h 341 10 0 76 5* 706.50 I 57 8 1154.25 2.57 10* 1661 .40 3.70 2 3*481.50 1.07 5 % 977.50 2.17 8 is 1563.75 3 47 0*2199.37 4.89 3% 358 20 0.80 5'/8 729.45 I 62 8* 118 1 25 2.63 10* 1690.65 3 .77 P 3*506.25 1.12 6 100775 2.24 8*1597 50 3.55 O J* 2236.50 4 97 3*376.20 0.84 6 752.85 I 67 .'A 1208.45 2 69 10^1720.35 3 .83 r_ 3*531.00 1.18 6 '* 1038.25 2.31 8*163125 362 10% 2273.62 5.05 3*394.65 0.88 6*776 25 I 73 8* '236.15 2.75 10*1750.05 3.90 O 4 555.75 123 6*106875 2.37 8*1665.00 3.70 0*2311.25513 4 41 4 00 0 92 6 li 800 10 178 8*1264.05 2.8110*1779.73 3.96 3 4*581.25 1.29 6*099.25 2.44 8*1698.75 3 77 10*2348.37 5 22 4*433 35 0 96 6*823 95 183 8*129193 2.87 10*1810.35 4.03 I— I 4*607.00 1.35 6*1130 75 251 8*173275 385 II 238800 5 30 4*45270 1.01 6*847.80 1.89 6*1319.85 2 94 11 1640.954.10 5 4*833.50 1.41 6*1162.23 2.38 8*1767.25 3.92 11*2423.37 5 39 4*472 50 105 6 5 /a 872 10 194 8*134775 3.00 H 4*660.50 1.47 6*1194.30 2 63 9 1812 00 400 11*2463.75 347 4*49230 I 10 6*896 40 2 00 9 137583 3.07 H 4*687.50 1.53 6*122725 2 72 9*183700 4.08 11*2503.12 556 4*512 10 114 6*921 15 2 03 9*140355 3 13 O 4*713.00 159 7 1260.30280 9*187200416 11*2542 50 5.65 4*53235 119 7 945 90 2 11 9*143190 3 19 j2 4*743 00 1.65 7*1294 25 2 87 9*1906 00 4 24 11*2561.87 5 74 4% 352 60 I 23 7* 969 65 2 16 9* 1460 25 3 25 g 3 771 00 I 71 7*132730295 9 !» 1944.00 4 32 11*262125 5 82 5 573 30 126 7*99540 2 22 9 '/i 1488 60 3 32 _* 3*1799.30 11.77 I7M361.25I3.O2 19*11980.00 U.40 11*2660.62 5 91 5J594.90I _____________ 2 27U?fcll5 16 ■« I 3.38 _, NOTE ACRE INCHES PER HOUR MAT BC REAO AS Cu fT PER SEC 12 2700.00 6 00 NOTE ACRE INCHES PER HOUR MAY BE READ AS CU tt PER SEC "^ I LJ 1 1 Fig. 5. — Discharge tables to be used in checking performance. Too often a well contract is closed when a "pipe § full" of water is obtained without any attempt to check upon the amount of water which was guaranteed or so implied at the beginning of the well construction. A check on the flow can readily be made by use of the gj tables and information given here. pr&gt; These turtles shniiirt^TTTIT^~ror-frilir)WM: Set w'eir-^prt.iVn11y r wit-h-hntt^m-of-Jweir_notf.h level. Widen ditch &gt; above weir to 4 feet. Still the water 50 to 100- feet upstream from weir. Drive stake in ditch 5 feet up - stream from weir. Make top of stake level with bottom of weir notch. Measure depth of water above top of stake. Refer to the above table for number of gallons per minute corresponding to inches in depth of water. Clearance between bottom of weir notch and bottom of ditch, both upstream and downstream, should be at least 8 inches when using the 18-inch notch and at least 10 inches when using the 24-inch notch. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 Tne variations in pumping costs were found to be large whether tractor, stationary engine, or electric motor fur - nished power to the pumps. The average cost of the power alone (7.0 cents) was slightly higher on the 72 installations under observation in 1927 and 1928 than the 6.7 cents per acre-foot per foot of lift shown for the North Platte station pump in 1930. The cost of kerosene averaged 12 cents and the gasoline 18 cents per gallon, and the electrical energy 4 cents per kw.-hr. (range 2y_ to 6 cents) in 1927-28. These costs compared favorably with those of 1913-16, which averaged 8.5 cents per acre-foot per foot lift and ranged from 4.74 to 13 cents, with kerosene at 9 cents and gasoline at 20 cents per gallon. 16 Data reported from the Arkansas valley in Kansas " showed an average of 2.3 kw.-hrs. and 8.1 cents per acre - foot per foot of lift (to compare with 1.62 kw.-hrs. and 6.7 Table 13. — Pumping expense per acre, 1928, including fuel, oil, repairs, labor and attendance at the pump p l* nt hSgtS S_Irf Gallons Acre-feet Cost P er No - water lifted pum P Per minute Acre-feet acre TRACTOR Fivo lowest and five highest Ft.-in. In. 37 &gt; 43-5% 6 824 38.51 $0.39 38 36-3 6 706 21.75 0.53 31 30-7 6 1,021 36.98 0.60 13 39-2 8 1,059 35.25 0.74 9 43-2 6 788 19.14 0.75 36 38-2% 6 1,008 52.23 2.98 19 39-0 10 1,741 89.54 2.50 44 53-1% 10 492 1.91 2.43 14 40-3% 6 896 19.40 2.37 43 31-2% 6 824 4.12 2.04 STATIONARY ENGINE Two lowest and two highest 60 58-9 | 8 776 18.60 0.77 53 22-6 3 225 0.83 0.61 61 38-9 6 934 40.30 2.94 56 | 32-5% 6 ... 68.80 4.27 ELECTRIC MOTOR Two lowest and two highest 70 31-5 6 573 34.71 0.88 69 37-9 6 1,035 12.46 1.04 71 35-7 6 1,021 79.45 2.43 63 23-6 4 415 13.65 1.58 "11. C. Dic-scm. Report previously cited. 1916. 17 G. S. Knapp, Paper read at Organized Agriculture meetings, Kaneas. 182S. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska cents per acre-foot per foot of lift at the North Platte sta - tion), and the use of 0.47 gallon of fuel, or 6.6 cents per acre - foot per foot of lift for engine power. The KanssTs data showed prices of 3V_ cents per kw.-hr., 18 cents per gallon of gasoline, and 11 cents per gallon of kerosene. Some labor and repairs are incident to all pumping operations, and the 1927-28 data cover these items as pumping expense. Usually the labor was a larger item for the plants operated by an engine than for the [motor - operated plants. Attendance at the pump was charged at 20 cents per hour. Where these items of cost are iricluded, the total cost of operating the plants averaged nearly $2.00 per acre or about 10 cents per acre-foot per foot of] lift. In Tables 13 and 14 contrasts are shown and the wide range in costs is evident. Much of this range was due tb difference in installations and condition of the equipment. Table 14. — Pumping expense per acre foot per foot lift, 1927-28 — investment expense not included \ Pump Gallons Vertical Invest- Pumping Plant 1 p" r Driven height ment expense a *«• Size | Type^ minute *' ]gg j^g 1927* | 1928 Ten having lowest cost, 1928 In. Ft.-in. Dollars Centu \ Cents 37 6 V 824 T 43- 5.5 600 7.2 2 9 25 6 V 670 T 43- 4.0 650 14.0 4.6 60 8 H 776.3 SE 58- 9.0 2,450 5.3 4.6 20 6 V 639 T 38-11.5 600 .... 7 7 59 6 H 650 SE 37- 8.0 650 ..]. 5.7 3 6V 1,087 T 50- 0.0 800 6.2 5.3 4 .. V 683.5 T 51- 6.5 833 .... 5.7 42 .. V 1,047.6 T 48- 4.0 630 .... 6.2 13 8 V 1,059.7 T 39- 2.0 2,500 .... 8.1 35 6 V 998.6 T 52- 0.0 800 5.2 7.3 Ten having highest cost, 1928 64 6 H 776.25 EM 24- 9.6 1,080 22. J 30.2 53 3 V 225 SE 22- 6.0 235 .... 27.6 61 6 V 934 SE 38- 9.0 495 9.5 16.9 58 6 V 1,074.1 SE 31- 1.0 535 .1 15.9 19 10 H 1,741 T 39- 0.0 3,600 11.7 15.5 63 4 H 415 EM 23- 6.0 485 41„ 15.8 14 6 V 896.4 T 40-^' 3.5 803 .1. 15.1 36 6 V 1,008 T 38- 2.5 825 1. 14.9 2 6V 872 T 43- 3.5 816 24jl 14.0 56 6 H 995 T 32- 5.5 2,100 14,9 13.0 • The letter V means vertical and H, horizontal. "The letter T yeans tractor, SE means stationary ensrine. and EM means electric motor. ttt 'Same costs as in Table 13. •■'■■'■ </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 applying the water on crops Many of the pump irrigators had not become proficient in handling water in field laterals and on crops, and the costs of this item showed as wide a range as was found in the pumping costs. Preparation of the land had never re - ceived the attention that is usually found under irrigation m the more arid districts or under canal irrigation systems. Border and check plats were seldom used. Tables 15 and 16 show the costs as found, ard are thought to be representative. Here, again, the carefulness of the farmer usually showed in cost figures. Man labor is valued at 35 cents per hour and horse labor at 16 cents. Where other factors were about equal, the larger irrigat - ing stream showed lower costs of handling. In Table 17 are shown some costs which seemed to de - crease with the amount of water the irrigator was handling About 1,000 gallons per minute seemed to be an efficient - stream for most of these men, and they were applying this at an average cost of $3.50 per acre foot. Table 15. — Cost of applying water on crops, 1928, including work on laterals, etc. — ten having lowest and ten having highest cost per acre average * Plant Gallons Total Depth of TT i No V* 1 acres irrigation c minute irrigated in inches acre | ** 416 32 53l | soil CoTH 3 1,087 210 4.41 014 Corn 2 872 120 4.16 0.39 Corn 27 fit" il JS °' 39 Corn i\\ 695 !5 2.57 0.54 Corn 24 896.4 120 4.31 0 55 Corn 38 706.5 120 2.18 0.57 Corn 15 661 140 3.21 0.65 Com 1 7g 8 148 4.18 0.69 Corn 25 776.25 146 4.20 0.73 Corn 44 492.3 5 4.58 3.84 Beets « 824 8.2 6.04 2.94 Beets H 684 34 2.95 2.85 Potatoes ll 650 8 8.46 2.50 Potatoes H 995 20 5.75 4.51 Potatoes 53 |25 8.5 1.17 1.88 Potatoes 14 896.4 50 4.66 2.33 Corn 33 1,035 42 3.85 1.94 Beefs 67 1,008 _ 177 2.89 1.67 Com 71 1,021.5 90 10.60 1.63 Com ' ' ■'■"■ -«-♦- -a ■&gt;" * n rTtr hnns. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska Table 16. — Total operating expense per acre, 1928, including cost of power and applying water but not investment ex - penses P }* nt Pumping Applying Total cost ■No.. plant water per acre TRACTOR Five highest and five lowest 14 $2.37 $2.33 I $6 27 19 2.50 0.85 4.98 36 2.98 1.07 4 70 43 2.04 2.94 4 05 44 2.43 3.84 3„5 3 0.95 0.14 125 21 0.86 0.39 ! 118 27 0.48 0.54 | 110 37 0.39 0.79 109 38 0.53 0.57 1 ll02 STATIONARY ENGINE Two highest and two lowest 47 20.47 12.00 32.47 56 2.23 4.51 6 74 49 0.98 1.13 2L11 58 1.16 0.78 1L94 ELECTRIC MOTOR Two highest and two lowest 71 ...! 2.43 1.63 406 67 1.73 1.67 3L40 63 1 1.58 0.11 l!.69 70 1 0.88 L17 2J.05 Table 17. — Cost of applying water when various irrigating streams are used p * ant Gallons per Cost per Cost per No - minute acre acre-foot 6 240 $3lH $0_ 5 512 1.39 7.39 f 776 1.21 4.57 3 1 1,015 0.65 3.97 13 1,059 1.18 4.20 28 1 1 1,127 1.80 9.50 19J 1,522 1.06 2J.51 191 | 1&gt;741 q.Q4 1 Two men shared the stream. economical lift The handling of the water on the crops, including the work on land, field laterals, and head ditches, showed costs that, although the extremes were very far apart, could be held around $3.50 per acre-foot fairly continuously. In- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 282 terest, depreciation, or other annual fixed costs for each installation showed another definite continuous cost. One factor of major influence on the operating cost of a pumping plant is the distance the water must be raised. Frequently the feasibility of the project hinges on this point. As this cost ran nearly 10 cents per acre-foot per foot of lift, each 10 feet of extra lift added one dollar to the cost of each acre-foot pumped. If the crop raised was alfalfa worth $10.00, and the increase due to irrigation to the amount of one acre-foot per acre (or 12 inches deep) was 2.0 tons per acre, all costs would need to come under $20.00. If the increase due to irrigation was but 25 bushels of corn per acre at 25 cents a bushel, all costs incident to irrigation must fall below $6.25. With investments averag - ing about $20.00 per acre, a fixed cost of from $1.50 to $2.00 per acre must be charged annually. The handling charge of $3.50 per acre-foot (see page 28) must be lowered to about $1.75 per acre for a 6-inch irrigation of corn to produce an increase of 25 bushels per acre. This $1.75 plus a $2.00 fixed cost is $3.75. This $3.75 sub - tracted from $6.25 is $2.50, or the amount permissible for pumping cost if the corn was 25 cents a bushel. This would allow a 50-foot lift if 10 cents per acre-foot of lift is charged for pump-operation costs. In general it was observed that the pump irrigators of the state had not accepted pumping as a regular or primary task. Too often repairs on wells and installations were left too long in hopes of rain or a better time to come. Crop rotations, soil fertility, and other phases of crop manage - ment were not receiving the attention essential to success. In many cases, irrigation was put off until other work was out of the way and the crop allowed to suffer from lack of water. Improvement may be expected as experience of the more progressive farmers discloses the practices best suited to the conditions and as these are generally adopted. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Pump Irrigation Investigation in Nebraska publications The following recent publications are suggested as help - ful to beginners in irrigation pumping: Bulletin No. 350 — "Suggestions Concerning Small Irrigation Pumping Plants." By W. E. Code, Colorado Agricultural Experiment Station, Fort Collins, Colorado. Circular No. 66 — "Irrigation Pumping Plants." By Mark R. Kulpl Uni - versity of Idaho, Moscow, Idaho. Bulletin No. 1404 — "Pumping from Wells for Irrigation," U. S. Depart - ment of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. Bulletin No. 271 — "Results of Pump Irrigation at North Platte.t By Harry Weakley, Nebraska Experiment Substation, North Platte, Nebr. Bulletin No. 388 — "Cost of Pumping for Irrigation in Colorado." By W. E. Code, Colorado Agricultural Experiment Station, Fort Collins, Colorado. Bulletin No. 864 — "Practical Information for Beginners in Irrigation, " U. S. Denartment of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. :sm] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>