<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  SUGGESTIONS FOR DAIRY FARMERS</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Agricultural Experiment Station LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A. PRESS BULLETIN NO. 44 Distributed September 15, 1913 SUGGESTIONS FOR DAIRY FARMERS By J. H. Frandsen DEPARTMENT OF DAIRY HUSBANDRY NEBRASKA AS A DAIRY STATE fThf growth of dairying in Nebraska has been continuous with the creased cost of land and the necessity of more intensive methods of farming. The farmers of Nebraska are, at present, milking about 700,000 dairy cows. The value of dairy products in Nebraska for 1912 was about $20,500,000. SUGGESTIONS FOR DAIRY FARMERS The older and better developed states are still far in advance of Nebraska in the number of dairy cows, as shown by the following sta - tistics: The state of New York has 30.4 cows per square mile; Wis - consin, 26.83 cows per square mile; Iowa, 24.86 cows per square mile; Kansas, 8.5 cows, and Nebraska, 7.9 cows per square mile. This shows that dairying has been developed as a leading industry in states where land is high priced and intensive methods of farming are followed. Our cheaper lands give Nebraska special advantage in marketing high - priced products, since the freight on butter and other dairy products to large central markets is very much less than the freight upon wheat, corn, hay, and other coarse products. STOCK FARMING AS COMPARED WITH GRAIN FARMING The following statistics show the average income per acre from grain farms and stock farms in several middle western states and also the average for the United States. Altho no statistics are available </seg>
            <seg id="p002">The increased income from stock farming over grain farming amounted to 18 per cent in Illinois, 24 per cent in Missouri and 48 per cent in Iowa. DAIRYING CONSERVES FERTILITY tBy marketing the products of the farm in the form of butter or am, only 5 per cent of the fertility contained in farm crops is sold the product. When marketing corn, wheat, hay, etc.. practically all ! fertility required to grow the crop is sold from the farm. By feed - ing raw materials of the farm to the dairy cows, we are not only manufacturing high priced products, but retaining upon the farm almost all the fertilizing material taken from the soil by the growing WEED OUT THE POOR COWS Eis safe to say that one-third of all our cows in Nebraska are I at a loss. If they could be eliminated from the herds, the two-thirds of the herd would produce a greater net profit than produced on the entire number. EThe most reliable guide in selecting a dairy cow is to determine actual butter fat record. This can be done .by weighing the milk uced by each cow and by determining the per cent of butter fat frequent tests of the milk by means of the Babcock milk tester. Weigh the Milk. — Keep a record of the number of pounds of milk given by each cow. Hang a spring scale in a convenient place where the milk can easily be weighed and mark down the weight of each milking on a chart prepared for the purpose. At the end of each month, add up the amount of milk produced to determine the monthly record. The year's record will show the amount of milk produced by each cow. Test the Milk. — Take a sample of each cow's milk about three times each month and test it for butter fat with a Babcock milk tester. A simple and complete outfit can be purchased for $5.00. and is so easily used that a farmer can learn to operate it in a few hours. tfull particulars regarding testing of milk, write to the Dairy De - tment, University of Nebraska, Lincoln. RESULTS OF TESTING AND SELECTION P carefully testing and weeding out the poor cows, the people nark, in five years, have succeeded in raising the average production of each cow more than 40 pounds of butter fat. b increased the profit of each cow over $12.00 per year. By ; the same systematic method. Nebraska dairymen can secure results. COW TESTING ASSOCIATIONS Eiere a sufficient number of fanners in a community are inter - n testing their cows, a cow testing association may be formed specially trained man employed to make regular testa of the I a small cost per cow. There are three such associations In ka at the present time. Grain. Illinois $10.60 Missouri 7 . 69 Iowa 8.88 United States 7.72 Stock. $12.54 9.55 13.17 11.99 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">In addition to weeding out the poor cows by systematically weigh - ing and testing the milk produced by each cow, an effort should be made to improve the young stock on the farm thru pure bred sires, which should be selected from heavy milking cows. COMMUNITY BREEDING It is highly desirable not only that each dairyman build up a good herd but that all the dairymen of a community unite on the same breed of cattle. This enables near-by farmers to unite in purchasing high class sires. As soon as a considerable number of farmers have dairy cattle for sale, they can advertise together and secure a much better market than could be done by any single breeder, since they attract more buyers and can furnish cattle in car lots where a buyer so desires. WINTER DAIRYING There are many advantages in having cows freshen in the fall or early winter. In Nebraska, butter is generally fully one-third higher in winter than in summer. Cows which freshen in the early winter and are well cared for during the winter period go on pasture at the time when they would naturally be drying up, and this lengthens the milking period and increases the annual yield of butter. The farmer has more time to milk cows in winter. The climate is more favorable in winter where good shelter is available. VALUE OF THE SEPARATOR No dairyman can afford to be without a good cream separator. A separator will remove practically all the butter fat from the milk. With the old skimming system, from 10 to 25 per cent of the butter fat was left in the milk after skimming. Butter fat is too expensive for hog feed. CARE OF THE CREAM After separation, the cream should be quickly cooled to as low a temperature as is possible, with freshly pumped well water. Have a small tank thru which the water from the well flows. Set the cream in a deep can in this tank. Stir the cream until it is of about the same temperature as the water. Do not mix warm cream and cold cream. The warm cream quickly sours the cream which has stood for a day or more. CLASSIFICATION OF DAIRY FEEDS 1 Inasmuch as protein and carbohydrates are the two feed const it u - ts with which the feeder is most concerned, and to aid the fe*&gt;d&lt;rs of this state to make a proper selection, it may be of value to roughly group some of the most common Nebraska feeds into two classes as follows: 1st. Feeds containing a high percentage of protein. 2d. Feeds containing a high percentage of carbohydrates. Foods rich in protein Alfalfa hay Clover hay Pea hay Cottonseed-meal Oats Gluten-meal Bran Soy beans </seg>
            <seg id="p004">EAb the protein feeds are required for the production of muscle, e, and milk, and the carbohydrates for fat and energy, the feeder easily see that a balanced ration must contain both classes in the t proportion. AMOUNT OF FEED FOR DAIRY COWS The following brief and simple rules will aid in determining the amount of feed required by each cow: 1st. Feed all the roughage, such as alfalfa, corn silage, etc., the cow will eat up clean. 2d. Feed approximately one pound of grain for every three pounds of milk produced per day. 3d. Give the cows as much feed as they will consume without gaining in weight. 4th. Feed some succulent feed, such as corn silage or roots, to make the ration more palatable. 5th. Be prepared to supplement the pastures by feeding silage when the dry season Bets in. SELECTING THE DAIRY COW essential points of a good dairy cow are indications of con utional vigor, food capacity, development of the nervous system, good blood circulation, and the ability to produce milk abundantly. 1. Constitution, — Well-distended nostrils and good heart girth due to breadth and depth of chest are the best indications of that quality of health and vigor commonly referred to as constitution. 2. Food Capacity.- — Great length from shoulder to hip bones, to - gether with great width and depth of barrel, indicates well-developed digestive organs, which enable the cow to consume and digest large quantities of food. 3. Nervous System, or Nervous Temperament. — A good dairy cow is active and intelligent. Large, bright eyes, set rather far apart, a broad, well-dished face, and a spare and angular form are good indi - cations of nervous temperament. 4. Blood Circulation. — A good circulatory system is necessary to carry the digested food from the abdominal region to the udder. The milk veins should be large, tortuous, and branching, entering as many large wells as possible. 5. Producing Ability. — The digested food is converted into milk only after reaching the udder. A large udder that is soft and pliable but not flabby when empty, and well developed forward and attached rather high behind, and teats of medium size and squarely placed are the best indications of the cow's producing ability. FIVE ESSENTIALS IN DAIRY HERD MANAGEMENT 1. The sire is more than half the herd. Be sure that the sire heading your dairy herd will transmit dairy characteristics. 2. Weed out the unprofitable cows by use of the Babcock test and the scales. 3. Raise and keep all heifer calres from the best cows. 4. Winter dairy as much as possible under your conditions. It gives you more milk, better prices, and at less cost. 5. Provide comfortable quarters for milch cows. orn silage larley 'Imothy hay Oat straw Carrots Sugar beets Mangel-wurzel </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>