<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>REPORT OF THE ATTORNEY GENERAL OF THE State of Nebraska FOR THE Biennium Ending December 31, 1906.</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>   
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE Attorney General THE State of Nebraska FOR THE Biennium Ending December 31, 1906. )RRIS BROWN, Attorney General. W. T. THOMPSON, Deputy Attorney General. WILLIAM B. ROSE, Assistant Attorney General </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF THE ATTORNEY GENERAL. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">L'ONTEN'l 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">.1 I </seg>
            <seg id="p007">a H&gt; ( </seg>
            <seg id="p008">.la. Jai Jat Jai Mar M Ma Apr. 11' To llarrv Mav - To Is Mav •'&gt; To Hariv Port Ma.\ S To K. &lt; . Phil 12 To Western L T i Mav \-2 To Beaton Br&lt; Mav 18 Tu Uocoln \\ . To W VI I Mai. Mai Mar Apr ' Apr. 7 To i . </seg>
            <seg id="p009">IX 1 !l2 11 40 4 4 41 IONS lit*) ("I UNI INI 100 INI 100 00 141 ."i() 111 11 Ml 47 MO IHI 14J :.&lt;l IN) INI 40 INI UNI INI 30 ini 2"&gt;O 00 10 00 200 00 4J »4.00:t H") #4.0&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p010">1 \ J \ To \V May 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">INI ■0 i0 ii'i "H ~M IKI TM (Ml TO IN) </seg>
            <seg id="p012">\Tlo.\KK Apr !!• To lit ( Ju .1 \ \ \ 27 To II. &lt; i«; To lii To To W. It. K. To \V. r. Thorn i)hod To Western irnion Ti l»i To Benton Uro&gt; * 21 To Hentoii lir, Hmm </seg>
            <seg id="p013">XIII 25 00 IKI 2.5 00 17 50 uly ( •&gt;-, INI 11 21 :u I'riii! 13 00 2i; oo 30 4 2ll . w 1 06 11 00 ( 12 (Ml 12 00 20 50 12 50 i U 00 il (Nl ■24 (Hi 13 00 2U 00 IMP 4 4". anti i 9 IK) ( I* OO 2B ik) IX IKI 25 ."hi 13 (Ml 1* IN) 111 IX) mi 4 :; IU (HI 2.'. 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">.1 ( \ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">4 .. J(HI ml </seg>
            <seg id="p016">14 T.. , aM n : - Mi H </seg>
            <seg id="p017">H'Kirn \ H I. Kol* </seg>
            <seg id="p018">MOXJ .1 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">1 A 1 K &lt; ASK&gt; 4 i n ■ i </seg>
            <seg id="p020">I \ A X In re. Schwartir </seg>
            <seg id="p021">1 • I </seg>
            <seg id="p022"/>
            <seg id="p023">I I V I 4 • World Accident A 11 13 '] '! </seg>
            <seg id="p024">i V </seg>
            <seg id="p025">&lt; &gt;IMM&lt; &gt;\&gt; \ ) i </seg>
            <seg id="p026">rge V ,\ 1 II !.. II I &lt; ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p027">1 I 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">\ \ </seg>
            <seg id="p029">90 Expiration </seg>
            <seg id="p030"/>
            <seg id="p031">Law &gt;6 Build iaint iilui t !v 177 Count] »8 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">XXXII ■ .1. L Junii J. I. .1. I.. \If Hr ltli J </seg>
            <seg id="p033">XXXIII ■ H </seg>
            <seg id="p034">XXXIV : ( I </seg>
            <seg id="p035">XXXV </seg>
            <seg id="p036">XXXVI • </seg>
            <seg id="p037">XXXVII </seg>
            <seg id="p038">\ </seg>
            <seg id="p039">I I \ \ Mc( I ( </seg>
            <seg id="p040">♦ </seg>
            <seg id="p041">t </seg>
            <seg id="p042">VMHI </seg>
            <seg id="p043"/>
            <seg id="p044"/>
            <seg id="p045">\ 1 Y () </seg>
            <seg id="p046"/>
            <seg id="p047">1 /CATION v ill .1 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">■ </seg>
            <seg id="p049">: ■oiinty, I'laiutil Plaintiffs in tri« .iinl larreny and ami larceny and •f ii\ In the penitentiary. Affiri in 1 1 if penitentiary. Affin \. W. 4&lt;'c'. &lt; &gt;n motion for rehearing tli BT and ~-i\ month IllOlltllS. XciuiAskA. No. 1-"&gt;I Iti M Ml e district court of Booue county. Plaintiff i ■litentian . Dismissed &lt;»n motion of |&gt;laii f Booue county. 1'laintilT in ilistrni court I on motion of plain- HMitiiirv \ i.iu.'ask \. No. 13643.- N ,\. in; ask \. No. I utv. I'laintilT in of I .ain inty. Plaintiff j 1 adulterating milk in violation of Ian \ nil I. 102 N. W. 25 f ratine milk in violation of law Vilirmetl. lOl* N. W. 254. N \. No. 1 •"&gt;•):")'••. York county. I'laintifF in I in nerve a tenn ln| N W. I I I I. BRASKA. No. l-'lfifi.',. \ if Hall county. Plaintiff in rl murder in the second ii </seg>
            <seg id="p050">2 :-\. N Error of till IdllS N. W \V \ district uiaii! I </seg>
            <seg id="p051">No. 13919 ri &lt;&gt;f Webster county. Plaintiff in of munler in the first degree and was teuiber 2, 1904. Affirmed, and .1 une ution. 103 X. W. 71 . June 1 5, iicd liv t lie governor until June I"'. Ni.iii!\&gt;k\. No 13931. IMaini ill in criminal libel and was sentenced in the penitentiary. Ueveraed. l"-"&gt; X. W. i of l&gt;n\ Butte county. I'laimilT ler in the lii^t degree and was i If term in the penitentiary. Attirmed N \\ I N si. Hakim \ \[\\\\ VRU \. STATI mnty. Plaintiff in - wife and &lt;&gt;f fail: I to s&lt;t\ ■ -i\ month In] \ W 1031. i Nebraska. N&lt;&gt;. Ii".»7'.i isk.v. Xo. l.".'.i."&gt;5 unity. I'laiiitilT: 1 of pku-in - on ;i re] lie United Hi"tr lieer tlm am! W( hi.i N. \V. !".'&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p052">4 Plaintiff- led t Hip. Theodoke Ro I nf cati of Iji • w lie term iji i 30, l'.tni. 100 N. W. 316. A with briefs and documi </seg>
            <seg id="p053">5 Plaintiff in I to V W. penitentiary. 11 tASKA. Nu. 1 KI'.M ity. Plaintiff itenc&lt; u K»l N. W. 276. A No. II LOT) :ity. Plaintiff intent to kill and penitentiary. Ai- Sarpv county. I'laintilt' in a i-i I 1 'i' X W. 7ti,s. No. 1 lotiS. \-k\. X". rounty. I'laintilY in intenl to commit ra|&gt;« tiled. 106 X. W. 77 i \-k \ X". 1111 li. uienl ami rm of I. 104 N. W. 7 \ No. Kill. county. Plaintiff in </seg>
            <seg id="p054">• I VMI from tlie district in error &lt; SlIKADKIt, I of t the &lt;li&gt;tiirt court of K in error was convicted of ui term of I. LO5N. W. » I. |u| X. \\ error \\;i&gt; inf hiii'l t&lt;&gt; which h • ■on ti t Enrt. win iiintifT in im.mI. |(i;i N. W Albert I)i.a&lt; &gt;■ \\'\i. II. Mn tfroin thi </seg>
            <seg id="p055">7 II KK hi lit v. Plaintiffs im f Lincoln county. I'laini I property a^ bailee and n tlif penitentiary. Uev&lt; the first degree ami was tentiarv. Affirmed. 106 i Marl: a change of venue, Sarpy county. I laintills in It' U'll' lldOll I'llll- vska. No. 1 H7ti k8K\. No. 14218 I'lielps countr. I'laintiir in i murder in 1 1 1 *• lirst decree and senti US N. W. 978. NEBRASKA. NO. I I lOZ. isirici court &lt;&gt;f Hamilton county. Plaintiff i'il uf adultery ami sentenced in pay a fine ml be confined for •"«&lt;• ilay* in the i-uunty Mi X. W. 332. \ BRASkA. N'n. 14193. istricl court uf Lincoln county. Plain till imI nf having feloniously received a stolei! a term ,»&gt;f tun yean in tlit* 106 X W. \S.\. Nebraska. No. I42&lt;M&gt;. • inty. Plaintiff in </seg>
            <seg id="p056">8 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">iv I'laimiir in tiarv. Allii I I ill Ik- •1ii] v. latorial la t ion of ■ tin l;ir as it So. i mil I'luintif N. W. li'l tv. IMaintiff ill :i i : • I tiarv. Allini No. J I'.l I 1 ' ' i N \\ \'l&gt;. I 1 1 l.'l Wim.i.v A I &gt;i &gt;« -) hiii t las county. Ap| i!\ of &lt; imalia, tii- p;i Hi- was re] igarel 10-5 V W. \. No. III'.m; oimtv. I'laiii' </seg>
            <seg id="p058">10 I a police ofli 'maha, arn I defendant w 1 1 1 ' I 1 1 if *• </seg>
            <seg id="p059">11 Y nl to the penitentiary \. W. 1066. Frontier county. Plaintiff in of (&gt;t(M' county. Plaintiff in Iv having intoxicating liquors sale. Affirmed tv. Plaintiff in l&gt;;iili ■ itt'ineil to a term 1 Pli lire ton county. PlaintifT tiarv. IVinlm v. No. lltin:; iity. Plaintiff in Nkuuv.sk \. No. I Uii'ti. iu;i&gt; v. No. I Mia] No. I Hi.Vi 'inalia county. PlaintifT in a term of llirer t - k \ N &lt; i 1 1 1 &lt; &lt; s sntenced to imprisonment Vmrined. Nkbkaska. No. 14089. hi oi county. I'laintiff in f rape an </seg>
            <seg id="p060">1 Hakim , w \ ( </seg>
            <seg id="p061">I i i I I \ I 'lainlilV i 1 1 1 of . \Sk \ ;;i Plaintiffs in i \'» 'I \ I Mi I itv. PlaintilT levice* - ;ii VSKA. No. I l&gt;." mintv. Pending countv. Plaintiff in miptly influence ;i wit- Criminal n&lt;l line«l No. lUiu.; 111." V Peiulinu \ ! iMli' Hayes county. Plaintiff in - !&lt;mi and </seg>
            <seg id="p062">14 X KltUIN ' 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">I- PARTY. \ !•'. ' "I I mt\ . Mav 24, William F &gt;itcr. a form* F&gt;iMiiisst'il bv &gt; I '.tin'. 1; &lt;y the sup il in t li ict court judgment u $1,11-. Ap| i'l time, where tin- judgment I! ty In recover ial Ii'.im in.tii; Suit Kehruarv !», I - Th L'7, \Sdt&gt; and the ul ■&gt;! •••. The jury i urt returned a ! :iL r ;iin^i de- l^e \va&gt; .1 Tlie iii&lt; ilier I'.t. listnci court I'd 1 for an </seg>
            <seg id="p064">16 I -uilileiii; i. abando ■ml left Island preciiu*t </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Slll.liil.- l:i ii' l . It I- i iii- Ma I. \V .iirt tli&lt;- fa. Is- \ M. Bui _&gt;(! ' ri mnty i&lt;&gt; wind u | tin - nil pan j for doing illlCll [!■! : r to the An appeal t" ilic ■ ii&lt; I :t 1 1 1 |&gt;:i </seg>
            <seg id="p066">■ ( I- III. I'M ■ W'll I : \l II ( i p\ \( 1 1 \ . ( Ill I"! Bui Bny«l ("iiir mtlnvi'si tiuari I at plaintifl </seg>
            <seg id="p067">aniiitf th 19 K unity for appoint ground that the hank and an unautho] Pendin ii the ground that tin HiMiirss without a H, . fune 20, 1908. Jun&lt; • s i \n: "i Nebraska. untv I Nebraska. Lan&lt; untv to lost in the Capital Xa - ■cii paid into the state t rer. Action dismis I. to •Hit on petition in error rtii, ranee 12 1 1. UK I \ . Wool' \ll \ Warwick Saunders a commission to confer hi ' I i of a North to plaintiff. ippeal tn supreme court. I X. \\ . 187. &lt; in motion of the \g lent was adher- ■ ii (listrici court. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">( W A \ \ \ A Aiii'li' IllltV, .hi! ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p069">21 liaul Mil . v X. W. L38. P&lt; r ;i new trial. r from defendant, .III of iranee business in N ii demurrer to defendant h March 17. 1904. KMi X W. 1 1 n' X. W. LO22 , and on 1 IH»lt I all' 1)V til' ■ \ii-\n\ in North Am L347O. amount of preni in t it -ii t the demur] in i ; I States land office at &lt; ' uty claimed l&gt;y plaintiff* \. \ . \ i kND I'A W1INI ' tl.DIERS' AND S.VIIjOBs' EioME. lall con in in | u i t- \iiiir the plaintilTs from tht Horu lor it ( I rant I [aland. Pending. \* ki . \ . State of Nebraska. u </seg>
            <seg id="p070">22 ( I ■ ■ ; unit* in f;i\ the nun nir! No I 1840 ; nienl in tin- supn Iitli half of the northwest quart tli of range LO, u. v &lt; I coi r 19, 1904, on the -• 1 kemujTer susta N i&gt; Hi.h in t Plaintiff i A. A i </seg>
            <seg id="p071">(ki.mmi 1370 ami ilewrilx Si So. 13710 \V r school land ilescril^eil M nn Nebraska. Judtfinent for the state \ i-.i«-. 1 October 11), 1904, on the nswer. Demurrer hubUu N. W. 241. r. Mel S unship ."'.."I, north of ska. Argued October 19, intifT's answer. Demiirrei lui&gt; N. W. 241. llOol liillil &lt;lfsclll'i township •"&gt;■"), north of idcmenl for tin 1 Mair. I.IEDKK. No. 13711. township 35 north, i </seg>
            <seg id="p072">jury, was tried ami ■ ■ ion in the dist plaintiff from the &lt; rner re •lie year i liit court of I. a l-t. Iv of till lU, | *.M I 1 !»'■ I N W I ' ** (j B 'lislrirt ( inaiuled i ■ I I I .in unlawful :i &gt;|iar&lt;li/ii M'll \v;i^ </seg>
            <seg id="p073">L'.HM. Kel&gt;. S. I'.hm;. [imling iplainaat's lull ilism \n appeal was taken l&gt; I II MS AM. \ I iiitf. t S| rircuit court November 30, uty treasurers, from collecting umarv I finding i omplainant's I &gt; i 1 1 clisni i to tin </seg>
            <seg id="p074">26 .11 in I'liittMl Stati unity iron - taxes f&lt;u- l'.tul. On motion of the Htate tJit was dismissed as to tl w. &lt; Action lintiff ii. _ 1 I . II: 3, 14216, 14217. A yd county. All filed ii the state ing mi motion of the o, Buti A. K. Caki </seg>
            <seg id="p075">27 railway com pan j I nil here ilif I i V \ I \ N I &gt; 111 ile mm collecting and state the Kill of coni- fend the amount the iiimities ilid nol e&gt; iiciiit court ilif railroad com- nt of the I nited States, \\ here IIK'll Dawen county. Plaintiff in tciii| nut for refusing ■ ram from furtln rtaiii matter, ami was sent i to jail until the line ii :mm|. In.", \. \V. 161) X Tu. in:. Cm vn Trkasi ki:k, \l w s nrt of BnlTalo eountv to cancel mIhmiI land in section ."ifi, town- iin it plaintiff to redeem -aid I t iml costs. The state tiled it led, whereupon plaintiff appealed ■ uit. No. 14525. lie versed. 109 N. W. 218. ill t . I &gt; l&gt;. I '&lt; &gt; I . K . liKI.A Kili, \ . i " sha, - No. 1 \-jr,(\ \ i . » • ■ i ' 'I'l'Mll I 'K'tlHli i sill I 1 1 rt I' ' ! </seg>
            <seg id="p076">&lt; In I \ \\ \ \ ii uija r a li No. I I: 1 . disbarred 107 N W IHASKA \. I»\S Em the tlixtriet couri </seg>
            <seg id="p077">29 ■ nil a to the supreme M \ 1 1 ■ I I.V.I. In tlie ll'7 . \-k \ Kevei ii li'il : - I ami iiinty ourl ! : 1 1 was \ \V. 751. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">i I \p])li' fr N m with plaint Mandamus. ( &gt;rigina </seg>
            <seg id="p079">31 Inien ( '\ U \v 818,872 n university No. I 1 1:' 7 in supreme &lt;•■ iiirt. Pel it ion - • &gt;[ forty &lt; lay h in the county if which he was t&gt;&gt; lit ic Lam oh v\u Uru.oiN«: land in section 1 • » 1 I Ti.' N . * \ ■ 1 i 17 X. \\\ county to compel ant for ;i claim in Ilr applied ional. Writ denietl. liihnsnii county to compel tlit unpaid portion "I purchaw r plaintiff e supreme court. IVti- of Daweis county I iii tht Hospital years and tin I to it i n l; I i \\ lit </seg>
            <seg id="p080">\ \ M </seg>
            <seg id="p081">&gt; imlainant, \ . !• . * ' I'm: unty i I' I' I \ K II i at ion. Auiiflli'i i. i &gt;n appeal to ty. I'laintil' tain real itiffi Pending illecl il.lllt. April 1, nk in N loney bteil The \^KA. N&lt;&gt;. 1 I 157. incil &lt;&gt;f ( tmaha, ■I !&lt;&gt; ilii| y days for contempt of court in rder. R&lt; md diwn </seg>
            <seg id="p082">N \p]&gt;&gt; H . \ w \ Lincoln, under tin 1 hf UTII ling. . V KX v. W. A. - iainw* in supreme court to without tuition. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">( } . 1671 t. I immitted untv. IV- f Lai I \SK\ isniac No. 14677 nl countv. Defendant &gt;l' the oil iliiiL 'Urt. it Lincoln er the dipsomaniac law. Writ mbki: Com pa* urt to enjoin defend handling of lumber tin- Nebraska I.n H.i. n \ R . Relator, v. II. Public Lands ikd Hi him mi to oompeJ : by relator and is mtv. Pending. No. L4737. llarlan county. Plaintiff in iting section 108 of the i </seg>
            <seg id="p084">\ \r \l * I *l i Ik </seg>
            <seg id="p085">37 \ I'laintilT in avmcnt (il 1 iev trial, lie applii us. which Cnlf 1 I i Nkrhaska i &lt;il' a North and jimm] in plaintiff \u[ i.\ am. The Stati recloei IfdiiH'cl I. ill 111 V Hospital for the Insam c law as being an inebriate. \^K\ I'laintilTs in of tin is through the Pending. count v i Warwick Sauntlere rifer witli </seg>
            <seg id="p086">OPLN i - ami a I. or tin - intei ie&lt;l for the c si'l..V .in \\l lirii. computation §24,18; I I ■ a county could Mnount l&gt; " ' ' ■ irifil t(. eiglitj tin </seg>
            <seg id="p087">39 Is in mandamus as other bonds may l&gt;e -till wli. surety tin :iat uf an an a Ann.; itutes, 17 Neb. 208; Ch I'.Mll iy warrant for an amount exceeding imoiini le\ ietl liv tax for t! nd for the payment of the ■pasury, whether from collections made or from mi from other county funds or IV inly deposited in i ike it to a 1 1 1 &lt;&gt; 1 1 1 1 mi limit particular \vi that the county b u list the general fund that it "in an amount n tun the county tax levied for county ilitl an&lt;l may be enfoi' ch surety may m Fidel it ij I) v. l.H'I'H 1 8, art. I, C-i &gt;iii [ &gt; 1 1- 1,1 ap|&gt;ear t&lt;&gt; In- clearly unlawful for igairwl irh iv limitation is found in tin money in tlit iwfullv in th- ro be m the pay that fund, during authorizi ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p088">iii n ■ Faithful ! II|MIII 1 will obe ily limit </seg>
            <seg id="p089">41 deputy clerk ally, Law Valid. t Law passed by tlie la-.t legislature. I that this law was bi W. 1 ( !'■•-. alid. ■ the law Laws - atutes of od for tb. m whollj - DO \ ill i of th' ii of our it !■■!■ I'd 4:i1p i j Ltt^ nnil trinil l&gt;.r hiYM le fi &gt;r tl nd land for I 191; E Richard t date requesting the intstitutionality ;&gt;f what i&gt; nlication ;is tnit^ validity. March '■•. in II \Yri&gt;jht, KH' X. W. ~A. In thai </seg>
            <seg id="p090">42 entirely independenl in t). fill I v »d&lt;&gt;| Ai - A - i thai tin- county iMKinl </seg>
            <seg id="p091">43 probabli in which iplainant, 1?\ \V. T. Thiim School Trea Lincoln in w Following nl valid ■ ntv refui Board our approval ol (fully advised thai I have exam with their history and the judgment of board of educational lauds is Brown, ■illy, NuKlilS BrOV .IlirniiiiLr the validity of them in \ en fully I 1 . 'tli inquiry: </seg>
            <seg id="p092">44 I. Nee. II .. I 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">45 V I lumber I eapric I eapric mil it ml it 11 llv, \ |!\ \V. T I 01 .M KM It I - 1 .lanuarv 2 u vour letter &lt;&gt;l' January 24. I the riirlit of X. A. Kulm of the righi of X. A. Kului of Otiiali I of Pharmacy, to February a- member of such board, l&gt;\ </seg>
            <seg id="p094">46 ■ \ .Januarv 25, l'.»M."i L. 11. &gt; Keb was duly assessed in Fn shall I Until a mi IDeai Sue I have your fa Innit to tlii- di ii the I and can </seg>
            <seg id="p095">i i 1 t ,\ i\ from Frontier a that i ranch shall !*■ in in t-ni. farm wnshi|is &lt;ir precinct*, it shall be ! which the principal pla if tlii— office that ■ized by law, provided the owner Willow county. It fol lid the ' uty and he i mallv kept, he has Frontier county i\\ N ount; and tion 10, chapter , r I'.Kil provides: with a farm shall I" - ,lay of ! For the med in th with section 0 rovide iithei- penonftl property &lt;•&lt;&gt;!&gt;' ■ situated: pro q UO | the intentii •live stork in bands or i -,.,| m the county where the the property is situated, pro&gt; .,■ the stock is to be listed sue) ' ie i ranch in such to collect 1. k fin le year. illy, Norkis Hi ittorney </seg>
            <seg id="p096">48 I &lt; tai and maintain t'rouuu foi ial of for an laws a- ' the towMb ■ i|'t- l followin - followini Tw </seg>
            <seg id="p097">49 st ha Neb., iitider the law ttiu application »a&gt; mad mentioned, but til iinuarv 10, 190R. The contract &lt;&gt;! - »■il^ dated June 1" »ry 1. 1905, ire the land wa his applic it of purch </seg>
            <seg id="p098">Ill ;u. in a omnium I 1 1 'In a a It Mi M In 1XV 1. .IILT II- Criminal v I tend in pens tei department that i ii lit il 'I. it' nf Si i </seg>
            <seg id="p099">51 saiil precincts may be changed from try." tfullv XoBUlS II </seg>
            <seg id="p100">52 ■ submit t&lt;&gt; tin iiiiin.il ( ' &lt; I id. jury will ■ You will ii iv inav I * indictnieni liy I is I! nan 1. I'.Hto. 1/ . A rli </seg>
            <seg id="p101">53 tions 7(1 tfullv itle that non-resident hapter | 'I) lands • II the ill tvides : ■■ ides that lilt' IV, if OIK i the alien. the alien the ronntrv in which lie eniintry in which til'v tin 1 i iii 1 i are unabl&lt; rtain 1 1 1 * ii. If unable to ascertain I uouM tify the S in notify tin at Wa ueither widow ihm neither wi&lt;ln\\ Nebraska, - 5 t tlnllv, X &lt; &gt; i ; i ; i - LJkown, &gt;tl. lumor to ac-know i- the honor to acknowli mitting the quest iv i- liable for the mai i instant, submitting the qu&lt; i K. Lucas, i-on\ icted of murder in the to life ii in the penitentia - iBpension "I aent4 irt. the Criminal Code | </seg>
            <seg id="p102">54 Er he may be kept au&lt; rate « b wttji i tor lia - .it law 1 ( in h;i iiikIi damiu in the dwtriet l -i ]i - that u Cl H. it Sit: I hnil said i </seg>
            <seg id="p103">55 I chaptei ir ri.dit of ai ii its duty in 11--1 i 1. nlly, Alt TIKS. lepartment the ques e duty of the county attorney to i ;i|']ifiil&lt;'d to tlic district court from the involvii ition of city and ir duties id 17, chapter 7. Compiled Statutes tatuta makes it tlie duty of county I on behalf of the stati s, civil or criminal, in party or interested, but Buch boder the laws of the state." Hy idently meant. \\ hile in wliidi you refer the state is name* for violation of ordi- E:al hut nut criminal in their character. An ordinance chuical - ulilii' law. It is a mere local rule r by-law, a polio ulation. (Village of Alta- III. J7: Cityof Gi r. // In Am. St. lie - \ en nspectfully. / Willou lepartment that it is nut the dut; </seg>
            <seg id="p104">56 thai i ■ uhaliitati; • . </seg>
            <seg id="p105">57 Mi.v guch bank ill UpOll t 1 a;iml all I irtment thai under i iiiy hoard h &gt;u to trticular banks &lt;&gt;f those making applies and thai the board is nol i, il the banks landing applying of inter By W. T. I unity, of the application to l&gt;e iintv funds of Stan ton count \ i) num. You a-k for ininis- II ma k i bid. ;u relal ive to ill f&lt; mini i -: lectfully, </seg>
            <seg id="p106">58 // M. I I »i \it Sit: We are in ting thai t'ebru ] and N l-_. Jefl I l.y ri« h I o£ 21 I he land; thai February 11, 11) made applicatii i land appraised for the pui RlVKK Hi I h lltll I &gt;.: Hon. II. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p107">59 r. &lt; In this Mat - -turn: aw in f&lt;" 1 self and the board and funds in int'i The board is trustee For the lands. In all i&lt; " &gt;l lands the kferred by the constitution upon the b etl by liuih parties. In construing conti the trust imposed by the educational lands and funds In our opinion wh&lt; I is made to sfaction of the board that fraud has been elim - ination nt educational lands by local tthe valuation fixed by the appraU aid is not the fair value of the land. the right to intervene and protect the in - e by refusing to maki This concl i the mi u rt in 1 1 iii m i. wherein it is said: rained, and Utcre*M and pro - ipport of tlif educational The power of the board ool hinds is suffii wanant for making a personal investigate tiding its ow the appraisement of the land. Such a r the pi uring information for tli r dial of reappraisement for the purptx tatute under which it I authoi tin rii'lit el ■ . , th from •"'' I ■ lislicil by an itiiiciit. Y&lt; the law of 1879 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">60 S neitl While ■ willi .% tliat ii will mi doul claim they may \u I 111 III m;. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">61 t ,11 r ( I. th inquiring whether the county rv a hank outside &lt;&gt;f within the county re I'm ■ per annum. ii that the statute authorizes rv a bunk offerin i r cent per annum. (Coin] 18. Where u bank within me a depository ami pay inti ■ iii on county funds, it may, if thesecur - i. become a law- 1 JSAT1OX. meni is i your column liut your county clerk fill - li'.'i. whicli claims were allowed bythecouni that in addition to tlii&gt; amount the clerk lary under the law, and also allowed to retai iffice the fonipensation allowed l&gt;^ univ .board for deputy and clerk hire. You submit to th mii win not the county boar ■.mi an a&gt; linn &lt; pinion thai under such circum- n of a d( the count \ cry respectfully, NoitRia Bbo • 'onnty, 7 nation foi amounting in </seg>
            <seg id="p110">of a county clerk to compel him 1 • f his orti. »Vx&gt;ve the amount he *a- To th&lt; Hv W. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">63 ntion to th isiom requir- t • stal ntli. 'I'lit 1 law appeal a I the original t rly omitted for the Attorney General. ( 'OMMII \IKM- fO A&gt;1 I.I M. favor asking for the opinion of tliis s the right of the county V r from an innial relative who is ;t pau] ten il month &lt; a purpose --liall l&gt;&lt;&gt; Mature Uws 60, |&gt; nendinent, hoi and, therefore, violates th&lt; all amendments which tl for this i thr Compiled Stab respectfully, N'ORRIS HliuUS, ty At ounty, - in which </seg>
            <seg id="p112">64 are U &gt;r 1 1 It, [90 v hwf 'ii h itli unli litju • In our &lt; &gt;| &gt; 1 1 1 1 &gt; i! 'I. ill! 'inn of tl in la\ - not onlv for die I &gt;;ti&lt;l chapter, but a I f liquors in certain for the parpaee of obi shall be filed iirA </seg>
            <seg id="p113">65 </seg>
            <seg id="p114">66 ! which 11 . ■i'i]&gt;t 11(1 . ■ which 1 of tli Ill t te rule; exempt v within </seg>
            <seg id="p115">ned to be u&lt; for the legitimate pur- n the led in the Yours truly, By W. T. Thompson, Deputy. UNKi ( within eighti be bid of the I it' that right pi mount for which it \\u- \ xpirai months. You also submit the 1 1 ■ i r fter purchasing either in member of his family, or l.tains tl land, and if r much s the he made at for tbe 30, Com] ■ nuty in Jk of tlic - 1I1IO11 Hot \ni;i;i- Brown, Attor r tn acknowli • _.,- : sales iiunle ily k ager law that one a the county or the publii </seg>
            <seg id="p116">68 I will - I V for that 1 tii in will i the I </seg>
            <seg id="p117">69 ! in like manner. In tit* 11 ■ filial b ( I - ami vill made would fa Forniance ■ 102 X. VV. It is the imp&lt; lir lirid- con- countv p&lt;ly Ix I i nary sal bv tin 1 countv Imanl of intrac'1 i&lt;&gt; repair. remedy provided by </seg>
            <seg id="p118">70 My \\ tion to | not be i until li authority to bind tJ inangement, &gt;n which would r&lt; i any portion of il for fail i. j now ii ' ■ Wailu </seg>
            <seg id="p119">71 tlif I'ullv, Norris Himwn, i rioM the • I rand Is irtmeiit 1 1 e all* • Compiled Statutes 1905. [( policy of this department " '" on from i linatkw of the h Uy submitteil to the The otliei '■ against the founded, and it is our judgment that the ition. ity. It aiily fol- rer will rum l" e - j:iin&gt;t the registration of I I uiieonstittuionality ! tin- otl paruneni ume thai statut. - d by tlie al and valid. Assuming tli. xvliu-li in he Milmiission of the nds on the authority oi ■ I o£ education, is Wry respectfully, Norris Bbo By W. T. Ti </seg>
            <seg id="p120">I II I </seg>
            <seg id="p121">( </seg>
            <seg id="p122">74 * It t "unlavvf uplib \ I imm; E.G. II Deab Sue J ha </seg>
            <seg id="p123">75 V ItlllUMU'llt VOU ( .ill act as such in a matter in which \ erv I &gt;i District :eipt oi your coiiununi - following inquiry from inty an&gt;l requi III Iihki in not pro t « from one itricts ian draw DO more funds n balanced l&gt;\ Ineooiiiig ti) determine the amount of money tenance durinc the cominc year. i ithority to ter an oath to the appli- As i If the in applicant for u mar: Public ( ' and quit ■ t fully, XoKIMS B»0 I'lllll : mount-. var\ in by lncoi « tbi &lt;-i ( .f thii ■ohm of them sitna- ipter 7'.t. Compiled Stai hpI districts on the ia&gt;t Mon- follow </seg>
            <seg id="p124">• i t Neb. :'..", I \ \ </seg>
            <seg id="p125">of the t believe lie will limit I.Tk 24, ( t authority Foi v lltV Sv - worth more than : r in&gt;t \Y. T. TlloM I'M iN. I &gt;&lt; the 29th ult., submit! ( -tiii^r an opinion then ill ue anil - </seg>
            <seg id="p126">foil for I L9O3 Annul - 1903 ; ■ . - </seg>
            <seg id="p127">law l 79 l.init. SuUi- U ll mal |iro| t thai itiiiiicil in il 1 in cctlullv me ii intv You say thai ? . ned l&gt;v the liank ;enipt from tit and i laiina thai xi'i'.-'iiK) is tin the bank should be listed for whether or not this is tht ist thi ignati wii pro] 10,4: - Annol al property of stuli i acknow l&lt; stating that the I ai.il.. §30,000, which </seg>
            <seg id="p128">" 1 ■ pita X \ </seg>
            <seg id="p129">iii in ."I I ■ ". Compiled Statutes, ■ I lands under contract follows tin' ■ law or the pro- It will 1" letween these two aectiona i covering the 'ii of tlie hi be followed. t tfully, By W. T. Thompson, Deputy niir n r the opinion of this of taxing an "ordinary corporation" uler the law, you spectfully rporatio it • and which arc do I by an- provision of the revenue act designai irticular method with re- their assessment shook 1 under the general pro i; that \t (II their property Bhould be listed, including moi I all other items of property owned by them oji r&lt; .'///. l-'iiir- 'iii instant re Nokhis 14ij&lt;&gt; '//. Fair- </seg>
            <seg id="p130">82 nue a I i first .lay of April. Section 68 of the rev f aooooGi . and rloe of peraonal j ! !&gt;&lt;■ Iwt tion 1 13 r given the righl ment p If mi,!, Wi .,,. ,| l( , | imilroads, for instance, l&gt;_v ttx •88eKKin&lt;'iit would l&gt;e wliollv roid, be&lt; &gt;uni almost double tin I'lio Mune n ■wrnsors tliat ooverm dfpntv doe* fix the value of the pi not bind tl mil if ti the value fixed by the taxpayer, h poratioiiK wliic-li you describe LTlie law i&gt; \,i\ tted. F the Kutty assessor, for i jress terms that "I tity anocao \ er il 12, 1'.'' Twvn .1. M. Wa Hill, A Dsj ■ "Doer, the count v assess lo raise the assessed valu;r sworn scnedule to the da board of equalizatio: </seg>
            <seg id="p131">83 ut'iit of property be uniform and that the property be assess* it end he shall be authorized to alter made by any deputy assessor bo that form tn law." The in all fairness, til'y the taxpayer of whatever increase he has rued by the deputy. If the act of u ie wrongful, the tax] y appearing before the board of equalization. Very respectfully Noftitn Bbown Attorney Gen i \\ KSIMF.M ■- AlTIIOlUTY Of BOABD PlOOEDDBK. J. I.. Me State Superintendent of Public Int •oln. fins i lcpart incut in in receipt &lt; 't your commui ii'th instant, requesting an opinion on the propo I in a letter addressed to your department ■ f Randolph, as follow ttendent of Public Jnetnu. rtnient i^ 111 receipt ot vmir coniinuni- lstant. requesting an opinion on the pr tter addressed to your department by is follow o 11, of the school laws of 1!K&gt;3, bei n 11. of the school laws of li)03, being Statutes li»05, is authority to the school ituto l!Ki, r ). is authority to the schc hoard i ■ t the investment of the bo fund of the si-hool district, in the hands of the county treasun trict to direct the investment of the bond ai strict, in the hands of the county treasurer, ich (1 - lift, warrai tanner of procedure under said section. inner of procedure under said section. eply to your first question, vou are advised it is the opi - department that tlii* section furnishes authority I nt, not exceeding 50 per cent, of such sinkii ■eply to your first question, you arc advised it is the opin- lenartnient that this section furnishes authoril ■")() per cent, (jf such sinking t, not cxcccilm the title nl the act in which said section appeals hein^j at in which said section appears beir act to authorize the investment of sinking funds in the hand* of t thorize the investment of sinking funds in the hands of the per of any county in registered warrants issued by county, city. Mr of any county in registered warrants issued by county, eft town, township or school authorities of such county under direction of the town, township or school authorities of such county under direction oft board of - ntj romm and to confer li itv on city am: ;istrict aul board of - and to confer like </seg>
            <seg id="p132">autli t wliiili ha ait'! mil | on dailv I it t( all oUier regulation Statutes, i-h. 18, art without complying « itl lUIltV III violation </seg>
            <seg id="p133">itodv of |)ii ■Hi, inty or maintain an u &gt;/. /; &lt; only account for the holding a countv clerk i'il and Tailed tii turn it u amount which the v law, "iintv. I 1 1 hanks, as &lt; l( ■ounty could not and funds ai •r'a ■ Th ii lime the f K' '/ 54] of t ( 'riminal . becomes lingly. ■/. 62 Neb. ill'. Under &gt;r the I I. In my opii ilic Kanks XoilHI </seg>
            <seg id="p134">86 illmv ji i it with the enmity board ti ollectible hills fi ruti vidcil the hills are found to he lawful after hat u 'it. were api furth R opinion of tliis department that if t instituted with I nt of the oiuity b .'I iii thoc i I.V t April Deab Sue Tlii&gt; d( April 13, l*q </seg>
            <seg id="p135">87 ming i s liable to &lt;ame with the assessor for bed that a &gt;r not, repres nt ami taxation. »f fact for tin iarty would be liable to criminal prosecution -ucli a note fur taxation with the assessor would and circumstances of the particular i forgetfulnesa on the part uxation, it would illv maintain &gt;r list it for t uist him. &lt; hi the other band, it intentionally and corruptly urned to tin ■ ote had an actual value, then ill within the provisions of the law I IV I l/.i aril of education of state normal m - t. On a certain . motion carried, which on roll call re- Noli I! IS i By YV. T. Thompsom, Deputy. ■ I ' 1 1 vith two votes recorded against the moti&lt; ■: </seg>
            <seg id="p136">88 El order and hil abs. *rd a, &lt;l ma\ ■acli lli( t I blic- Ik paid m tttion of i i p. i] </seg>
            <seg id="p137">89 Midi, 324: /'.- ertfullv Iliiu Fn.i i V ilttt'lltloll I I I. chapti Laws ii I do not feel at liberty . and it w the (li NoRitis r&gt; I'llhli 1 111 &gt; * ■&gt; - itxlivision, I low ing provision .all bt ■ 'PI" </seg>
            <seg id="p138">90 elected as a member oft! within tin; time required by law. The j apply i riny after qu ]. It is our opinion i ami 40 of chapter 77. article 1. C ii dutv of 2. It is his duty to list tli&lt; lay of April. April l&gt;\ W a]ipai (1 both ]ii i by hol through (illcil by the board ol &gt;n under from doubt, Inn I think it A . A J &gt;l ; .| i if \ &lt; iiir (■■ 1)1111 I 7i i an opioii roM imn </seg>
            <seg id="p139">91 x i men of the Nebraska National Guard shall working on roads and highways, and from the payment ir that purpose, and shall be exempt from sitting •it-tit jury within this state while an active member." in be very little doubt, if any, about hi quoted. The exemption provided in benefit of citizi nr state \vi. Nebraska National Guard. It xtend the exemption to citi/. I men of the Guard, and Nuitiiis Brown I &gt;\\l M, !■ i, Pawnet ■ trackand right ol way of the "Bur - built Bince 1881 ; that in the il notice ae required by Bection 18 that no personal notice \&gt; el company or it&gt; agent, and that a Few Mkm uci Nationai M IT. r ' Nuekolla County, Nelson, il; the i ij)iiin m ol cam 56, Com- V(M&gt; tfllllj Ait" if till ic ti: :itv board !&lt;&gt;■ Statui published, ami all pi ind I </seg>
            <seg id="p140">92 </seg>
            <seg id="p141">93 id while it is suhicii iff the land-" ami who hail do actual notice of 1 1 ling claims i land taken from the niav wate. any rail - ic or private road shall make » am 9 on all such road-.. ;ind culverts that may be nee- Ill', was an application fur mandamus I liin . &gt;r.i|.iTt\ vering I iou within a ■ &gt;!' th tmeiit that a raili damages for land taken or api iiihlii- r&lt; &gt;a&lt; I . In i • ■ No. I 1,240, opinion this state held: a|&gt;|ii-. the railroad track I, the width ol It. n I In of chapti :■&gt; /'. dk I,'. Lihc respondent to construct a cr </seg>
            <seg id="p142">94 I "Under that act it is the duty of a railroad company to make ar repair suitable crossings with approaches, notwithstanding- thi h way was laid out after the railroad was built. Tl .1 required to build that part of the highway within the r\g\ would have been required to make had the railroa slructed." April lit. Tl in which 1. WUeth- juli a establishment or alteration of a ■ .I- ment of one or more of its members as a expediency of such propm or alters) the board of su|»- make a blanket a whereby each - r is man - expediency of pro|«)sed roads within \, E Where the con appointed l and unfavorably as to the remainder of a pi the proposed road it will be ved on the owd&lt;-i or abutting thereon? &lt; &gt;n the iii- &gt;n it is I Within the limitations indicated in the duty &lt;&gt;f ■ railroad cotnpai nd ki ii muml. Si'b of cli Etition such as is required by the pro US Jill </seg>
            <seg id="p143">95 irv that the petition be filed I l the premises, die appointment of a i.li petition would l&gt;e without in, it is our opinion that the By W. T. Thompson, Deputy. Mi ,ia Pu BUC Com Eipibation. I'lii- department is in receipt of your commani - i date submitting the following question and commissioned a notary public on March 20, 1906, will ■xi. ire on March 'lo. LU2, or will it expire on March 19, nor tin 1 derisions ol the made from an act performed. The Btatutet i] thin which an act may !&gt;•• performed. It becomea for guidance in this ind the weight of authority, how.- . to lay down tbi computation of time is to be made Imm n act is done, the day on which the- act is done ild include Buch portion only oi uiuended in the conimi Very respectfully, Nouiiis Biiows, Attorney General . Lincoln ithoritv &lt;&gt;r tlie law for the conipul t port ! '1 |( ' compute - arc not harmoniouH. The l&gt;cst authoi be in 1:&gt;&gt; l S. i' L47 U. 8. 6* </seg>
            <seg id="p144">( - full term of t» piivd?" liable for premiums paid bj January 1, 1902. tfullv. No A W. T </seg>
            <seg id="p145">97 \VR\ grand inrv is in and r still ! jury r county tn ;i| )| ifiir at the nev ■ nil pai burglary a in I k&gt; ■ liir-t an opinion the defemla il by the grand jury before tin trit't court, or whether an information i i ided tli. i I unless the jud_ - I inn I '.&gt;."'. of the ( 'iimi i. I b term of court in whirh - 1 1 x &gt;t 1 1 -&lt; I to appear, the clerk shall liih ■ he names of all uring tin' vacati iV I lie j This the law 'and |ii; 22 Neb. 1 17. it was held bj .nit 1 by tin 1 county icamiued h\ action. While • i &lt; &gt; i i — may nut In- had iipxiii i </seg>
            <seg id="p146">h \ \\ i» </seg>
            <seg id="p147">tiihlisliii In t i i t ■ / \v nt u that all </seg>
            <seg id="p148">Ill t V I ■ist t ■ t t :. tin- limit X I Hill tllllt Imt n Iv |)ai 'lie t V </seg>
            <seg id="p149">101 Illlt t(&gt; tilt' Illll:. Midi as mav l&gt;t llltv of tile &lt;&gt; &gt;n nt \ e con n t \ ploved, and the i Biio\ '/ (Irnen \\ T. / -ilmiittin nil liuiliiiu^ of iht nun •ed in i Statutes of l'.Mu, creating Follow ;i nor </seg>
            <seg id="p150">a I III t laixln ami lmil&lt;l Buihli and l&gt; tit ■ ) i ft I * i " ' </seg>
            <seg id="p151">\\ /; 7 Sell, ll' 2Xti 'U 1 1 ral authority mJ liiiililiims fciund in I tin- dtvisi dial tin- original jurist! linst the superintendent the Norfolk at-vlum t after haviui; i board to report ll»e i-hnr^; - </seg>
            <seg id="p152">104 mine wheth&lt; 1 1/ liink ulitleil i iiiiiing ft W e </seg>
            <seg id="p153">105 •O.). iirovidc ime they shall b (&gt;rt .1111 (if till • thai diei I'lii&gt; section "f tii shall in li in a county lia\ an U\ isam It t&gt; ami lullai num. It per annum this compensate that Iv W. T. 'I icli purchaser, lii&gt; hei ugns, the with K I MM I'l I"V 1 1 f Frontier &lt; 'nun: nt has the honor to ackuowl .'I'nil instant wherein inions thereon: 77. article 1. of the old Bold for taxes or any person lia\- Mi same at an\ le by paying the county </seg>
            <seg id="p154">all ol Hi] law it inun liavinu ii h the par) i 'litai i 3. What i </seg>
            <seg id="p155">V nt i \ I itv t ami 1 it i\v which lirnvi this chapter ■ i ill the c \v Ik&gt; listed am II I iv the I UlioW S, .1 h \V. T. Thompson, /'■ n Platte and ( 'olfax counties by a i ntv line Inii win eaniiig of tin Tlii&gt; i&gt; r\ idcllccil I. ■ hi) district « d by the following provision of moving fn lunty, lowi ■ iay nf April and i </seg>
            <seg id="p156">108 "I'll We i I </seg>
            <seg id="p157">109 the Win: it mization ami are iri table pur] I not to 'M'lll i II ! llti'ill which i let-lares thai il pur- M lie :&lt;&gt; taxation' iniounl id i led ran fi it&lt; I in tin* statute I'.v W T. T followii </seg>
            <seg id="p158">110 </seg>
            <seg id="p159">IV trans i- par - annual ) h I tin I i,L. r iii hi !inli\ i I&gt;V tl I I wnships, n-li tin I ,1 • Ivan sulxlivisii hi i' i if il owner hum jiializution that the nty I uutlioi ■ lin-i i' 'ii i it in nllv. i \ w T T </seg>
            <seg id="p160">Whit Ft: I 'I Silt I; As he mill ilid &lt;lf til levy 1 inaci( die | until tlic action of the i-ountv )&gt; if tin &gt;;il'l had I* </seg>
            <seg id="p161">rk may, at rom for ! authority lint that by 1 l&gt; ■unty l!Mf| and i i fully, l\\ W. T. Thou i - uty. tij Att / -I' 1 ' the l.Ml i. calling I, callin i". 1".-,. 10,511), 10,520, 10,521 10,51!&gt;, 10,520, 10,52] In. In.", ed S I! lit:;. Vour question i An lint; 1 ,. Vour questioi ■ the &lt;&gt; th [ualization" found in tli ni interpolated into the statute bv th the act a- passed bv tin ■ he act di hat "the county b tlic county clerk shall constituti alization, and the county clerk shall b ih/.at When terra "county board ted, down to the in li'i; and 136 of the act, we understand tin ird "f r opinion, t: </seg>
            <seg id="p162">nornia biiiMinu al Keai Imililiim. lint mav iiMt In n- - illy aj'i'i Imt nut utiicrwiM Xoi 20 to li'fi. iucliix tof 11J03 by rd ni' n.. ••I a Hsk ] I „,- </seg>
            <seg id="p163">115 Property acknowli I'lst iiisiiint. in which you suhniit and in this count) .ml the t 30, I'.hh). The two assignments «• ■ until I'.' 1 ;il in- K. for • ill unpaid. A Statutes 1899: also t&lt;&gt; tin l&gt;. 17i', wherein the court held ;in lien upon all of the irtineni that you must look first by tin from and the county treasurer. If cient tn pay I hi '&lt;•&lt;■ county board ma; net the same agains suit tn collect the &gt;an ■ ii 81), Btipra. You supra. N enue law of 1903 ane law of I &gt;1 taxes under the old - under the &lt;&gt;li \ &lt; : tl'iillv. By W T </seg>
            <seg id="p164">116 \ • - • ih a ■ ■ *. ll i- it from which provides "Within ." for 1 malivi' D, or fa)- - or a )&gt;enalty or forfeitui. so limited. " ■ C. .1 Equity attorney m ivil ; </seg>
            <seg id="p165">117 N. II. 97; P, &gt;ni|i;my. officer, and ;i in your thin] proposition att tiiui for the penalty ( Compiled rt .M ( in the (]n find unite a lull di 15 Neb. U8; tfi v M 10WK, .1 Bv W Placi 3 huilh bmitting the fnl - iii: ICilt v for /.'. taking a note i and 1. l'.HK r moneys, credits, bonds, ill ii; ..I otlier pei nv rncv ( 1 • Brigg I^ouia I,'. It'. &lt; 'o. r. /'. V c HI Wll V. /.'. ( T. Thompson, De/ntty. Compiled Statutes L905 in! mind, being a »c controlled l&gt;y him ;is the iv other person or person--," I </seg>
            <seg id="p166">II Ik the e ( n. e. ii. w of ;i mi nary examinati limliii- there being probable can Under oar statute, beii n iM I'.ki.'i, it |uired thai a specific lining magistrate that th&lt; there is probable cause to believe that mitted the ofl </seg>
            <seg id="p167">119 i that case baying xaniination having rotigation that the own relative to the mi nations, and the ililiLT liv the in V \ iplement 1006, change the conn who « d prior to tlit- ■ Mich. Com l'KXs.vi ion ' '&lt;&gt;it ut I/, ll'ir- the I'Sth nit., submitting tlie v this department that a | nr to tlic compensation t : m • ■ cific tiiulii - :: Imt 11 mi to hail or i • the I lamination* and recognizance, tha T ,n informal hold tliis plea in abatemei -11 aixl autl id 1 1 nit a n-ctfully, \i i I'.v \V. T. Thompson, Deputy. </seg>
            <seg id="p168">beinua publii /.'. h. h / 'I II Killy f opinion that . l'.t Neb. G1I5, it • </seg>
            <seg id="p169">121 enter nee limitary, it i- oar opin- mleatr I'.v W. T. Thompson, Deputy. unty, pinions there* proposition to ■ourt house and jail. - -itinn I ijuired? 158, liapter 18, authoi ntion, deals with the que&amp; il fund for tin ourts &lt;&gt;f th Brows, Attorney ' the 30th ult.. submitting ter 18, Compiled Statutes - of the county --tituti' ma] by ajoritv vote is Mill county court eneral or a special elei </seg>
            <seg id="p170">122 1 bolide tutii. • that ! in ti which ili' will i with 'illly Bv W T </seg>
            <seg id="p171">123 RAM . ■ • ."nli instant submitting .in opinion then F '■'&lt;') Neb. HI 1, as author - distinction can K.alt and a pi une, and it is our opinion that ,iin-~t tin' provisions of the section that pa herein are Norms Brown, Attorney I By W. T. Thompson, Deputy. Lisi i L'axaiim I . •&lt; Annotated Statutes for 1903, tlie eounty K taxable land before 1 ly 1 ! that under the section cited the ; the taxable lands and April of state is to be made. The i|i'."&gt;n| liat "all real property in on the first daj four years thereafter, which a - shall be used as a bj iluation for taxation until the [uadrenniaJ epl as hereinafter provided. 1 that tlie county clerk i- M'Ctfllllv, </seg>
            <seg id="p172">124 ■ In l'.'i' ublic lauds ami buil of the arc-hit' si, I'm. 'I ami - </seg>
            <seg id="p173">125 stra draftsman and I for allow- I am in- iblie lands and buildings that ■ Iniildinirs and n ■ ■ ins I spocifical and a si tailed drawings wit :inl that under these cireum- public lands and buildings direfted the I raftsman. I f publii I the fum Is, apj&gt;ropriated For authorizing the construction and lit' publi and buil This I ■ ■i| by statute, had such other . Iditional I t he and timely construi I. I think t: I of public 1 their employment. Tl the e.\i : the lir-t fiscal quarter istitutii SI to make further appropriation - into effi </seg>
            <seg id="p174">126 I If it is round thai tin- additi •erf M&gt; an strati While it ■ iniiiL ill t would I" </seg>
            <seg id="p175">127 ' where the ant i&gt;f premiuii roperty within during the pre- •f propei or to mar particular period of time does die term It will »m1 tliat sections iiuc law, which immediately follow the II el which pertain t&lt;&gt; tlie the time for which the mid appear to furnish si ■ the call I a^ the time 58 on 1 ! iiitenf i dation would tend An examination of tlie record would finally drawn and introduced bya :t»' I for tlie ;i - ,v &lt;&gt;f February. This ami put back tn April I ■tii &gt;ns nally drawn by the statute will be driven theii I meaning, unless - manifest lh of Octol&gt;er we speak of the preceding ' he IDOlltl - </seg>
            <seg id="p176">128 ■ Mil A erii 11 _ liav( hoarding ■ I inl, ami I k,&gt; itui </seg>
            <seg id="p177">129 Since the statute does iv officers of the county or county 1. 1 am of the opinion that do - ml thai therefore the claim of the sheriff of oh Admin i Mai As (lulv probated will authorizing the executor I md lease without an order of the district court or An administrator, under a valid order from the Child Sn mim i\e voiir favor calling my attention t' Si i f chapter \ of the Criminal Code and requesting the lepartment thereon. \'\[r aectione quoted became the law l»y legislative 1 enactment , 30, L901. They are found as an amendatory act entitled tunty jail il or valid Vei t fullv SORRIS HlioWA ■"/ lillll'i eplv nt inouiry from your office I Im'lt follows rty, lit- may make a valid assignment »v make a I. gnment 'Mil land the district court. 136; Mulloy r. Kyle, 26 V.p. fully \oi;iii&gt; Brown ity, Fall* ill! .\ </seg>
            <seg id="p178">'If a deceased person at th let may l&gt;e sold, on tlie »pp! . in the same manner as if he had i.v l&gt;e had for that | prorU lii reply I b &lt; piled Statute The proceedings referred t Biniiiistrator. in al </seg>
            <seg id="p179">131 )(-•'•'. it IS I .' tract for the in your i r or an admin- t district court. tfully, \ei v Norris Brown. Cn.MI HNoK It-i :knowled{ •( of your favor of th requ&lt; pinion o£ iliis departmen due the lieutenant-governi the opinion &lt;&gt;f tins department dary of this officer is fixed by tin article •"&gt; of the constitution pro' ■v ot tliis otlic I by tin tide 5 of the constitution pro t the lieutenant-governor shall n ■ enator. The salary of a senator i e 3 of the constitution, which provide* of the legislature shall he two year* nstitution, which provides: - of the legislature shall be two yean, &gt;■ |&gt;a.\ at the rate of $o per day iliirinjr their &gt;ay at the rate of $o per day iliirinjr thei mile they shall travel in going to and ry milt- they shall travel in going to am sitting of the !■ on the most usua tting (if the lej (&gt;n the most "*«»' hat they shall not receive pay for more tha at they shall IK I pay for more than nor more than Umi days during their t&lt; r. nor more than 1(«» days during their h employees shall receive an \ - . in or employee* shall receive any lan their salary and milea_ provi gether, it is dear that tli ior is limited to *ln a day durin Any compensation in Tether, it is clear that the limited to % 10 a day during •i islature. Any oompenaation in i olation of tlie express provisions of th ilatioo of the I the tute which in the salary beyond itute which ii the salary beyom v ni named would be clearly unconstitutional and void. I )&gt;&lt;• clearly unconstitutional and voit the honor to remain, Yours very truly, Norris B«ow« </seg>
            <seg id="p180">N / r Dear Sue I hav&lt; ii, countv an v that ■ tlie three county drew from the count&gt; should 1 I ' H I I "III I'O paid i :ilf uf in li giving his individual reeeipi t drawing funds from i 1 duly allowed bv the c n\ art. 1 The money with which to raeet tl ;tt ami paid out with the same formality, a ajrencies. as are the ordinary county fui: provision of statute author be legallv made only on 'warrants ii &lt;linjr to law.' ' Ft N ■ for. Tlie count &lt; &lt;&gt;ni|iilfi: While tl Iraw count \ sion of the county, the money must ate |ini\ ides othi p. Thorn,'. 9 Neb. H </seg>
            <seg id="p181">133 I i'l law \va be i mil v In r t 11 I t ii ;i tat I it r t tut a warrant on the county nion that the funds were the unlawful acts of the timwn was legally expended for the da, the county treasurer in his settlement owed credit for the amoani ed l&gt;y banged in I'-' 1 dlow one-half paid in labor Compil 1903, mi inquire whether road taxes not ly to tli is inquiry 1 beg to advise I already ruled that road taxes must be in labor within the time required by Opinions of Attorney General, 1901- Verv respectfully Nonius Brown. rtiiieni is in receipt of your letter of &lt;l an opinion upon the construct* ue law «&gt;f 1903. Your inquiry, more ritrht. uml. -non. to remit or release I that it I T tl, ( iiitliuri/. county treasury t: fund asurer does not p cannot be sancti county and commissionei required by statute must afterw; Attorney uitif "ty, Bats- </seg>
            <seg id="p182">134 inhibit i wllirli l'.Ml I ll.M riinioi _llt (&gt;t hi lam! unit- Illp Tlie statutory pi aiitliori lows: In all cases wh&gt; .1 for each tax re. </seg>
            <seg id="p183">135 tate, the i &lt; 1. I am unable to find lakitiu tlii&gt; fee a lien on n within tl tiring the closed awfully imported from another wl ( &gt;ul)di ilic Ban all fish except trout begin April 1 of said section 4 is as follows: on , 10 for more n by f the - by him- land ;il ; If, the 1 : but when the I land purchased, and a &gt;, and I do nol think i the I &gt;l(&lt;&gt;\\ N. AttOT nil, l&gt;v VV. T. Thompson, l&gt; Law illow ~h law. can a |*&gt;rson lawfully e plain. Section I. article 2, . t lawful td tak- </seg>
            <seg id="p184">136 unlawful for an\ ami t "T** Mird of ea&lt;-h .-ounty may grmat lie is and vjdous liqno ■ii of a majorit inder township or^ani/alicm. a oivani/.ation. then a majority of where the sale of such Iiquoi I The foregoing provisions show that the | a majority of the reaideni treehol imty i&gt; not under township organizatio act the reaideni freeholdei considered n E (luring the wing. I The authority miitv •orjM.ratcd territory of tht&gt; «■ rsion .. 6 Li //. M. I l&gt;&lt; ••it 1-atexl rilla the limits of an&gt; ould the reaidenl in deu-rmininj; ■leader who ha~ </seg>
            <seg id="p185">t I lar Statutes, eh. 18, art. I that the resident freehold) I in determining the number cif B of the county &gt;f the precinct by a valid order Bank v. Hay Neb. 394 Nobris Bbowm, unty Attorney of Dundy Ct your favor requesting the opinion of thi&gt; her or not the county jui putj r without relinquishing the ullv advised thai the general rule is i cannot hold two offices which are ffices. in this state our constitution divide nt into three distinct departments, the legislative, ex ind judicial. It also forbids any officer in one depart - tlie dutii the other irtnii illow '■mis upon tlie divide the county in- ilier. inferred i juiry, a homesteader who has freeholder within the meaning of tlif 'cmpbdl r. Moran, 99 X. W, &lt;i. 1-: Fore v. I! Mo. App. iT)4; D list. Very respectfully, Attoi eral. a Public Ot! 31, Ch. 4.) The r not the offices are incompatible is the character </seg>
            <seg id="p186">138 'The powei s of the verm he le • ■ am I ion of iK-i ■ -taut la! f tl of th. Ill' . menl venue law which in ii- lie public im Statutes for 111 IO,42&lt; appr if the count} I am 1 and county aaaemor arc in </seg>
            <seg id="p187">139 ( whether- rtain K you thai it ie the opinion of this tv i if a ."i'.i Neb. 7(16, this provisii and in relation thereto the ■ inient; or limit.-. il thecounty int. the sanction of a majority ol at arjniroent could I t'illniore county credit for the state sate made under the prov •bapl -I ami 21 mlariesof tlu* countii tide K&gt;of tin II- ll n to Such a division an &lt;&gt;nh !*■ made by ectfully, Norms Btow», ELLATION- CltEDIT /,/ flCOl H Your inuuirv or • &gt;"' i Statutes for L9O3, is </seg>
            <seg id="p188">140 You an I that there is no law; it. Tin ■ I under which - ide hi unconstitutional by tl ourt, :;t. 101 N. W. 1039. mtliori n of t t ' quiry: Can a board ii the tax tali th&lt;- ■ Tlie; 3, eh. 77 w thority upon the - helil n tioiKi fd 1) therefore the opinion of ti with the count \ March 28, L905. Ha: Line tfullv By W </seg>
            <seg id="p189">141 'ii Friday and meets the next and Fn. Friday afternoon and meets on N slative day as contempkr ■ 'or the of the constitution? mor l «■ law's calendar. Tin me by holding half-day IV ilav8. Under the I I Monday lavs final &lt;hr. n 'loc- nut limit the Oill ■ is] ■ . . • may draw pay. alary a|i]ilirs alone to the memtx days of serrice of the employ lim - rmined bv the Ii fl \&gt;\ the employees for certain days. 1 ani advh it authorizes the H pay anybody for aenricet oeral proposition die salaiy of employees is ill the 1 1&lt; &gt;i )&gt;.«' and •■ the final dav of adjoin •f (be House entitli ;tfter •nil qu involve | nswer. Days are nol Bubjeci &gt;!' the law. I.. Speaker to ap| ver tli- which - that tin Bervi&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p190">142 t u n aL'a ,t \ \ ■ nn. I.ca It lliis 1 1. inil inhere in tl pt them fro]] it li held that i ht arrear is a chase in actum and taxabl grow due is a part of the land and incident 1 grantee, and is therefore not subject t&lt;&gt; taxatio land which is also taxed. The taxation of renl of something included in the taxation of the lai ■ ■ liai; not distinct item of proj </seg>
            <seg id="p191">notion I oonly ui bui when - It or fruits of a i that right. A presuni| Mtial cli.: I property inhen 'lit due tlic land it ami taxation of the land &lt; --incut and taxat the conclusion woul i and paid for i uant land fora definite period wi n as an independent element of i ;. ;ilnl a tin- distinction i ilt or fruits of a i it ri^ht. A presuini i property inhen t due tlic lainl owi ! taxation of the laml ssmeiit and taxation e conclusion would &gt;• paid for bv a wiied ai uant land for a definite period independent element of i A on the 31st ui March has $1,000, and on the - { i $1,000 to tenant a farm for on.' • ntly maintained that this right evidenced by taxation, and that toonotwiUu 31sl of March has $1,000, and on th&lt; is burdened with an i ar? There could 1" the same year? There could I s 1,im m i I I by tin - I .inmi been retained by the in any other non-exempt property, such monej mpt property, such mon&lt; ect to taxation. It will not do would lie subject to taxation. It will not dot mid be double taxation simply because the grai M-.| 81,000 by such transaction with - tli being added to the community. M-tion only the xl.OOO pJog the \ in would be suliject to taxation, while after t ! ! to the community. It i \ inly the sl.(HM) plug the value itlol hi' buI taxation, while after the e vali subject to taxation ii. . while the money paid therefor plus the t property of the I in Peo\ -I. had the owl &gt;nallv use&lt;l and would be subject to taxation in the hile the money paid therefor plus the : i rtv of the lessor. As said in and. it would not lie thought Such use and I he land, it would not lie thought such us. would he taxable aside from and in addition to the la ild lie taxable aside from and in addition to the I;, lent rolls where no actual value ■ncrease in tl nent rolls where no actual valu. added to the community, results under almost all rev* ed to the community, results under almost all revenue jpect to transactions concerning real prop « lien ; - it. hut doin_ uch farm </seg>
            <seg id="p192">144 in order to raise sufficient fu fjiriii It is I !H Wt * 1. If tin il inl t n of any father, mother, husband, w or widow and or childi price. Before tlie tr; there w subji (I fill money. After t' II — tl - I.INH ' amount reo •10,000 limit rid that It may lie prop ■ tln j limit above whi( one person m taxati </seg>
            <seg id="p193">1* Iv r t V ( A law tc iillliltiol). IK- null i </seg>
            <seg id="p194">146 li mi ty of tile land i iwner in - in that behalf to se*' that th&lt; ii|m 'li they might have V //. 1/. / a public highw ami tin county board ha- pro Then a highway. ■ t fully. Brows </seg>
            <seg id="p195">147 I ! tli&lt; for all Levy. • •d against a township on a &gt; • p to aid in tl town pui MMliDg I - axable value of pawnem thereof in any one year? a ;, la annual town m&lt; •d up i it] board or can the county board If from tlii - nity cha pur - a judgment against a township within the and the expression "for all i untl i 1,579 is to be construed as inclu such tax. art of con mm of money against d di&gt;triit, town or city Uoani iv municipal corporation, or when ai ml now remains unpaid, it shall be the district board of education. or rrtl nay require, to make wnpt payment of the same of law must be construed, however, in with other statin. tion 1,579 places a limit the authority of the township and upon the taxing oil intv in relation to the levy for the payment, an things, &lt;&gt;f such a judgment. The limit fixed lor townships lollar valuation for anv one j i if tlie illowing sonably certain thai the ex| town purpos 1 to distinguish in Li&gt;85 i&gt;l tlic &gt;t;itii' red to is a town 1903, </seg>
            <seg id="p196">148 </seg>
            <seg id="p197">149 I ami tick) thai in the ction for each \ i i lie party polling \V I &lt;l 1/, I ir an Miii ■ -t fall. 11 the &lt; &gt; 1 1 i « by virtue of the - ilnl by then -lilll- Wliil. 1 1 1 it i in </seg>
            <seg id="p198">It i- iii.m that if tin' v E thi •elf, Mich contract within 1 11 '}'• ' ■ It Will ! work ' 1 After ill' ami the * 1 , ( " N • &gt; while at the name l ill added to the coniinunitj 'I I 1M 111. 275, it i \va f tiic law i- edit Tl than foi Ill V Double taxation . burden, wl -n' 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p199">151 id of the land and has a_ and in his v a promissory note. ORRIS [ill It tor tie ti General. to acknowl receipt of your \vs ■ «nd North Platte or to remove them ■ il by those who op it ion that if I! md North ii i opinion on : in this matter I may do in »r iiormal schools, one in 1 1 1* A rict of Valentine. In HO\ 11.-—1 &gt;ISCX&gt;N1 INI \N t I .. t ion '2 of the junior - are as inior normal s ilit about tin 1 meanii your letter. Th&lt; IiimiIs providi - an of Nt-hratka inior that there shall iii the school distrii thai two additional junior normal </seg>
            <seg id="p200">until \ Ml I ■ III. 1."' i • I N'ati i mi i </seg>
            <seg id="p201">It til. tat tw I i I lnS W 1 11 l.l.ilv I t t til I I I a |&gt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p202">It i- iii'Hl of t If ( In li If anv ix I ne&lt;l . a i ■f any anv ' he value of ti ft work </seg>
            <seg id="p203">155 I. tlic burnii kin-lien, warehouse, mail- without i( ■ (' t lie must h: the value wa- 'I tilt ted art' bunied. iiiiinii a ( 'riminal I hie of the pmpem that a ham or stable il legation as t&lt;&gt; tin mil any evidence on tlie Hid irrelevant i II V Brown \ st— Bank Credits owled pt "f i opinion upon tlie nw to compel a bank to submit of credits of de i if t by thr assessor in </seg>
            <seg id="p204">I ■M a </seg>
            <seg id="p205">I i v t MMI v.\ ! t ]|ol tl St till' Illlll'l the ca U). If ill. </seg>
            <seg id="p206">158 V inv. - them until such tin rule announced in 1 1, \arn&gt; ownii H City, Neb. DSAI Sue ] have your let O|)inion upon the followii &gt;l)Olll&lt;l III If tl II April 28, 1905 Lii6 same rule a: </seg>
            <seg id="p207">mav - ire of value of ra iteni|itiii_ enue law aluation which I to the court inadi i iii itiiin: ■ iind witli • ins applyi: nor with the sections applying t' :'|&gt;ora- staml is that the legislature said loo much when it pro - id he valued and the (jn la taken as anil is that the legislature said ton much when it rallied and tta&lt; 9 taken a iilue. The . he taken as a pru|&gt;er - may be taken as a pro|&gt;e ii'il upon av not lie arhitrarilv taK sure of the value of arbitrarily taken as the measure of the va renue law relati rain bn J ■II. Until tlif Bupreme cou I ntil the Bupreme court erwise it will l&gt;c the policy &lt;&gt;f this offii the provision of the revenue law for in brok( \ ei v n-prctf ully, Norris Bbowk, Ah il, By W. T. Thompson, Deputy. will be the policy of this oil f tlic revenue law for the Tax Sali s K'i dempi ion. KMI'I ION f I hi ■ ave your let t • 20th inst.. requestii in '21 df tli' law ■n Laws of l!t&lt;i:{. ircel of land required to pay in order to same tioni tax </seg>
            <seg id="p208">1 1 / . \ - 1. II </seg>
            <seg id="p209">161 ■riiiiut in five ant iui dormant 1 It IS nt would it. It is incut should I'liiui laws It. hat I thi- pun-hi conditions of tip and the general government ;i- will justif . ■ liBOW By W. T. Thompson, Deputy. </seg>
            <seg id="p210">property. There law of this &gt;• ijitii know i if do reason \vl N </seg>
            <seg id="p211">163 - nil*' ii winch ner of public lands and luiildii mly. I ihli-r the trtment ruled that tli lould Illl- p. '•'- i that ruling mu anm &gt;u ■ Following ■ ■nt. the r to the 3 sufficient to authorize ■I land ii;e final pay- rleira ! itly facilitate the uli a •ss in yoni is ample authority /. \- Ma—. 1 It!, 1 17; .11 Mo. 303; Th Uanhfidd, L0 Pick, Norbis Bbown, .!'■ </seg>
            <seg id="p212">//. 1/ - II all railroa liK'lnilini; I i IUI11MLJ t Ill fu the pi </seg>
            <seg id="p213">165 I or held shall be th&lt;&gt; diitv of and il pit i the track of \v \ -I'd to nerti But tl rating i na pond t'&gt; the 1st I itd t that \vn, t lits in tliestate, i 1 1 terminals it u id •rstand, : it to rii'lit trim .Nil I- t it; i ik /,'. Co., Hi' r. s., 22 cm I s Hi' railroad company rifflit under section 87 of tin lpany to return under oath to in •' in detail all the ned a used in tlii — . v trackagi Hid hull ml their t. n I will t tlif formation a ■r i ii the ! "llierstl for 1 1 lith and i imi&gt;t till i\Vll t </seg>
            <seg id="p214">/ \ \ ! t rty. 1'ai 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p215">\l.l \r&gt;\ Mass. I * ( / t t r i tlV, tv. IV Ilil WIH'l N </seg>
            <seg id="p216"/>
            <seg id="p217">acknowli II nplllMIl by bond ami m holding thai pai - • utioiial which jieniiii - unount which he mbt8 I I would ii that iiiii i i unit which he i wqrth. franchise, which should !»■ added c telephone company in such valuation of the fran- c-ompany. Being refusal the - lie may consider the 1 1 1* • l it mi what time. You understand unde 1 coiui that tli- iaii'1- the f ranch ia maha, 103 X. \V. 84. Thej ems which — -1 »n I i be ( 1 by Franchise value from all the &lt;-t fully. Nokbis Biowm, .1 ■' </seg>
            <seg id="p218">:i iinil car \ ba a alt-i-a 1 ii Mav 12, I'.mi. ll'^l </seg>
            <seg id="p219">Itioil 1 i ntalil i&gt;t les I Me. I / &gt;/. I \ 1/ // Y / V I &gt;ka for amount of i I t t i""l mtv clerk - ' Illl I till r th. </seg>
            <seg id="p220">l t M ; t ciMiniv trea fully or negligently time required there) 11 liis ( niav sustain l&gt;v rea </seg>
            <seg id="p221">173 an opinion tin ministrator, antl in what imb^r ■f way "i -eel l&gt;v the local ■ i »r for tl required </seg>
            <seg id="p222">174 ■ : i '.mr.. Deai Sib: Tl nt, making inquiry regardin; </seg>
            <seg id="p223">late in the that, as |!v VV. T. Thompson, V in this law which declares thai 1 1 lit V File alx. tlizal authority to lit mistalf .f real | Tin-. ily. No [die Jmh ununication [ndiistri I for Girls at Oe i,|,artinrul wrhetl oinmitted t&gt;&gt; that in^titu- juvenile court. K juvenile ling to bearingaud I industrial schools ol tution, tlic girls to ti ,n 111 this law which declares mai &lt;i&lt;&gt;ui- nstr 1 to couflici with what w in the </seg>
            <seg id="p224">176 - ■ I'lii&gt; I; kill&lt;' !.'.. l'.i. L. Urn - </seg>
            <seg id="p225">177 / li question: ■n-taxable paper, tu maki I it in the land Knal Ban] : 1 1 — - 1 the &lt;-;i|iu nl in lait against the bank itself, but iirainst tlii' c;i|uial stock of tlit* hank, which Lholders. The dank corporation tareholdt ink liabl&lt; paymei apital stock. The bank is protected in I law whii In ti tthorizing the detlucl iv to make such deduction iting that a I inty clerk and tlie count) I Kimball County a&gt; tu whose duty it i» to correct the ization lias made chai any deduc- unt lit'lW by the I &gt;atik in t fully. </seg>
            <seg id="p226">178 111(1 I in tli' lllltV t // of I'.* ■ through ntit opin It is law now in f 121, make such chang </seg>
            <seg id="p227">[ualizatii to the f fraud ity board of equalization may by townships tin Taxes and; that the line law does estate until October of th&lt; the stafc under the facts stated ■ me injuBtiei valuation I, Slll'll r in which t ; ctfully, IS lll»&gt;\\N, .1 By W. T. Thom March 1, 1906; thai noth ,r the year L905. On tb liable for the taxes levied for 1905. had l» d. Any lien until *&lt; for L9O5 itle, the vend .it under the facts Btat« wa n |iin,LT nut of the pui ectfully, Nohbi9 \&gt;i- </seg>
            <seg id="p228">V D. MM*, I. I I. EIh nt. — 1 1 1 n 11 i an opinion ' enue law "I L9O3 I with in </seg>
            <seg id="p229">181 \&gt;\ W. T. Thompson, Deputy IKM the lionor to acknow taut submitting the follow- i . — 1 1 1 1 - ■ ll een that &lt;late and : let], ueil • quantity tli in value or diminution in inn- rne by all taxpa aw. i i-al rule ap] be that 1903, which, with n mprovemeuta made betv rsi of April. 1906, and like - h improvements are in the value of the leal estate, and uade bj &gt;!' tire, flood - r improvements which i valuation of the land &lt;&gt;r I"' ■ ill- luthoriti uali, nit any relic tort ion of their real I F April ami the .late when i are authorized to lioM their </seg>
            <seg id="p230">1 A f Ml If a I 11 tt pin 44 to I in'! I in i &lt;rini'iii value tlic a </seg>
            <seg id="p231">t &gt;, r t mtv It 1 mitv &lt; 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p232">an land be taxed upon « man could make tinal proof in i .111 t'l'lie answer to this ilihcv s Ann I X </seg>
            <seg id="p233">185 make final proof of Ins fact, a competeot claim - road law, in opening and ti tit IniiO land I law and the decisions with the county clerk are dam nstained l)v the i ■ I i 1 department that tlie lands hi by ititled i) i In - ■ f W'h miii. Ba is the honor to acknowli nitting the following qu&lt; - i that damages for which principle of law full taxa- llcd to make tinal id mav t*&gt; c-oll' in the na ry plain and km| by you are subject to full eof I entitle*] to make permit the hold* vithholrii I of his claim. authorities to decide </seg>
            <seg id="p234">shall </seg>
            <seg id="p235">187 ;it an I illows inniui ourths ! thai il .\I\ answi listm ial in ilistiift ui a law miii in stric mill \ UltOW N. //&lt;&lt;// 7. liny* L'litli instant, as follows </seg>
            <seg id="p236">188 nutate ■ inioti of the attorn* ,d out what lai January 1 - ••If la' it la: 1st and '■ Tiled or i entitle ilv I tal pn Verv \V A. M </seg>
            <seg id="p237">189 leparti mine the miry foi lection of ta collect the ta x rvice in tatute. I tin* 1 in) authority in the i deputy for the county t i deputy tor the county t • ion or ivii collect under a disl iv there can be a fee lection before there can be i - ted in an opini&lt; that a county treas 38 warrant unless the property The Bheriff is acting as depul • law i&gt; well settled, as stated in an opinion that a county treas nut warrant unless the property i&gt; tr« iiade. The sheriff is acting as deputy er u stress warrant; a deputy serves a distress warrant; a depul re than the principal for whom he ■ctfully, Xouitis IJidiwN, Attorney General. I .1 f Hamilton. ;r letter of the iiiestion of the taxation of thi I on the tirst i lay of April. ■ain Now county treasurer has t when he has made the collection and le has made the collection. Tht !" which a county treasurer is entitled f. amount I. It would aj lamination of the -tatute on this subject that he would • ted to deduct the </seg>
            <seg id="p238">190 l! 821»UJ ■ . ■ lie &lt;liMn the tin livl collected prii ami I </seg>
            <seg id="p239">191 By \V. T. t;itin«_r that the I ad up i by t lie I ■ . publish ami certify tt •rovid an appropria- s (J. ■ did class i\ ut. I ney ! sed for t lit tlic appn ipriation ordinance i to make it clear that tin w it any time during the firei venae law of provides that any taxes of iniuiit i wade i' - </seg>
            <seg id="p240">i </seg>
            <seg id="p241">193 utentiary tiarv, or in tlit 11 ii tlit arising from supreme court in act appropriatii ii ili&gt; 1 pent uactins tin that the pro Mild be available for the imme- i while tin- legislature did iU df similar vhile tin- legislature did not &gt;■ tl won I h of similar ;it the statue makes a valid statue makes a valid ertfully, N'ohris Brown, Al //. Vpportionji i \- \ I'll i|&lt; I'll &gt;N \| l.\ I Madi as tlie honor to acknowli hi opinion upon the ■' . ( 'ompiled Statin. - 'ii to pan upon this r to acknowli in opinion upon the sion to jia&gt;s upon this n thereon, a copy of which 1 i thereon, a copy of which 1 be found on pages I'll' 1901-2. n as to whether or not I on pages 212- f At I d for 1901-2 poii tin' question as to whether or not ning among the present own- I &gt;ince t lie time ig among the present own- mi» </seg>
            <seg id="p242">I tliat under the pi liapter 111 nt : 10,51 "1 of &lt; '"lili.v •■ ■ 'II IIKllv - a-^&lt;-» : part r . Vour city /. McKillih, part your letter of the I 1 whet cut I ir wl. </seg>
            <seg id="p243">195 4. a I l turn i it I i v a r X iw of I '.mi;; p, t&lt;&gt; taxation shall be assessed iverj fourth vear thereafter. Which valuation for taxation until the next r-einafter provided ualization and assessment on the tOr the purpose &lt;&gt;f eijtiali ind to that emi lecreatte the valuatioi increase or de ction lie la ii of the legislature, ower in the equalizati •c tin ■ ■&lt;! valuation of any ierty whenever in the judgment of air in order to make tht - for the t'ljiializa - nt counties of the State, and n any county, for the pin valuation fixed bv the county tfullv in suiistmicp, l'»i" thf int't'i- _ ■ i i 1 1 iz thai tin- state board of equal- ni) authority iuthoritv to take the . increase ur decrease tin pinion of this depart lalization and as&gt;c&gt;sint'nt ar at any of its annual meetings ii ition, to im-i &gt; ~. the i- Brown, Attorney General l&gt;\ W. T. Thompson, Deputy </seg>
            <seg id="p244">196 uncut may change al will t tliat body, and make the legislati unditionn ii- ii"t n itract and i- not i constitution against 1 ■&gt;n J'n B&lt;UR1&gt; uh Ilddi, I EKTII Tli' is fiititlnl in an </seg>
            <seg id="p245">197 ■ ii procured WlllllV abide by the provisions ii 'in&gt;. applies alike i I tli is qi ■ treasury bi into tli&gt; easury I &gt;ard &lt;&gt;f irrigation is authorized to i-(| of irrigation is authorised M ol water, and I am of tli riatioD of water, and I am of the &gt; the adjudications mad&lt; ntly made. t fully, N'OBRIS HlioWN. .1 " t api kI indications made I lentlv mad&lt; SllllSt lv peetlll N'oi in- Brown, - 1 1; \ rii in Fl Ltincaln. I from Mr. II. E. Frederickson, letter in regard to the m Mr. II. E. Kreilerickson, a ipter 1- i Laws of 1905 pter 129 Laws .if l'.iu." ■ation uf motor vehicles am f motor vehicles and &gt;n u|iiiii the highway - . vehicle owned - H -h vehicle owned tar\ I i&gt;f his name arv of tatement of his name in of the vehicle to be iVL'istered. tin ehicle to be ivu-istervd. on a t itn'h se&lt;'ivtitr&gt; lor that purpot titry for that purpot 1 « \vitli other provisions of the - I a OtOtOf vellic: provisions of tin Wltll oil r motor vehicle to pay \ nei by him one dollar, regardless ie dollar, recardh &gt;r which the vehicles are k t making the rule different whe vholesale nactment ol the It r.- for each vehicle </seg>
            <seg id="p246">198 from ■ iiothih with th«-&gt; wi~ ilatioi nothing uirernentc - opinion then lulv 21, I'.t'i.",. llv \V. T. Til 1 M. JohiitVHi, r. \i'' Fully X"! h I ' opim :u within ami Bucfa it is Brow \. .1 </seg>
            <seg id="p247">199 irho shall, on Sunday, en^a^re iu i| in a iinjr twentv dollars or be ding twenty days, or both. ■ within the definition of sporting. the punishment pro- Morris Brown, Attorney Gen //. .1/ ebraaka, Lnn-nln. acknowledge receipt of your ion of this department as to the extent of i\ ol who ha\ lected U to do so. Iii reply t&lt;&gt; your ,V lint \v! follow in liiiuii tlit irst place.it must !»■ concede*! that as governor yoa itrol the action of local offici sen by y and wholly independent of your pleasure or liave p&lt;&gt;" iny otticer whom he may duty, or malfeasance in office: it. and till the same as herein provided of the Constitution.) Jv the provision quoted oHicers who are your appoint© ject i I by your command, should they he either in - liil of duty, or guilty of malfeasance in not aiil us to determine what your power I - statute w;is interpreted and Nel). ri held: ■ fully, &gt;u I/icai. Laws -Powers. i of their selection in tlie discharge «&gt;l their inferred by law, either expret The constitution in express terms vests in t lie chief II i • iit t"&lt; &gt; I ilie ii unmet of such officers as arc \v It </seg>
            <seg id="p248">200 I maybewhei oof appointed bj ■ tlit'ir duty under tli&lt;- law. Neither r by in It ram liis own power ol I nr inipeachmenl "1 otl ini&gt;&lt; is by lat not in 1 Is, ill tin- li-LTI&gt;lil! Therefore ii mder tin |g than I r tribunal or court th evi'i I ilu lint tllilllv tile COllBtitlll araand to t! complain) shall .'&gt; of ' Win it him 1 1 which form point' ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p249">201 r bold ing local office] •urte and the citi/en - i he &lt; ifficers. Such has i and interpretation of the law by the judicial departments I nii'ii instant touch with the county attorneys nal advice of the work tl loin^ ■ be informed of a single iiity prosecutor has failed or rel - I on him in the prosecutions of offend - w. If vim know or arc advised i&gt;f any such lartmeni will immediately act on yon pi-oper oouri npel such officer to md punish him. I another remedy against official \ny citizen may apply to the courts for a writ &lt;&gt;f ipel a derelicl officer to |&gt;erform liis official •f the burden - that !)«■ should act when \\&lt; I official malfeasance. The chief executive ler the law to do more than any other citizen introlling the official conduct nf selection t he governor is in an I a tin tnition the governor N'orhis Brown Attorney Gen an I a Im &gt;it it n &gt;n the s»overnor rs, I) itli local llriirv; hill the law uplic ition aittln i E rs, or to d rrnmeatal affairs in tim&lt;&gt;&gt; ■t fully. </seg>
            <seg id="p250">202 Taxation —Le\ v — ( !n 0. /:' It is the i)|iiiiiuii of this departn pqumlization had do lawful righi i idjournmenl us such board until I rd of equaliz tml a it had &lt;■ alized the \ alue of | liroii^rliuut tl •Ink any in. : I &gt;i.\K Sin: I Ins ili ■ count July ma ami fiirti third Xfoi time !■ -nail hav« lay of sittiny ■&lt; necessary taxes for I piwiin'i ay la» </seg>
            <seg id="p251">203 - until the action l&gt;v the : taken. It is further the opinion nty board of the purpose of making the u&lt; inty and otl - after the state I" smenl shall have finished its labors tion to the county clerk, as above indi i illy. Xcn; Ittorney \U W. T. Thomi'sun, Deputy. -Reparation -Bids Notice. Bparttnenl is in receipt "I your communi - hc -- nit containing ropy of a noti&lt; aled ill reparation of county bridges in - iihvient becsuM it oinit- to iiaitvd and the pro] #-iX) may ii hoard shall have .1 of irrigation print-. ■ iml o &gt;|&gt;ii-s of §uch plans - In- ki'pt on tile in the office of the itributioD U ra and tax payers l&gt;eforv ;i»fully lie entered into !&gt;y the count] board. notice which you inclosed fails to give the number or the location &gt;&lt;f the 1 » i-i &lt; t i_r« -^ prop be built Sectioi chapter 126 pro vi n^t other things that the nutice shall of the work, the number and kiml of ilt and their proix&gt;sed location as near rney of I &gt;&lt;il; ' chapter 1 1' 1 Session [jslws to be ;wl\ - </seg>
            <seg id="p252">204 bridg .i kind ■ Ollt!.: - - - I I)' I Mil I I 1 1 i &lt; &gt;ii. lie A- to your thin! q &gt; '•' ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p253">205 I t itorv the 1 I I think ion l&gt;; k to |n- I i now n i \ Board. knowledge your favor tttating thai tin - ounty desire to abolish James- the territory thereof to l-;unar precinct opinion of tlii&gt; ollh ivhetlier they have i ii the absence of a petition aukiu a • from your statement that only li ■lection board attend tlie election ind that the e*»t to tli i-ounty is almul si at the elei'ti • 1 1 unquestionably confers upon the county com - abolisli a precinct and attach the nother precinct I End no statute which lent upon a petition, ndently of a petition. ity |iriui&gt; of tfa in &lt;&gt;iir Ifiii tuthoritv of the county aration of bridges S l'l N I illy, i- Broh s. Attoi llv \V. '['. Thompson, Deputy. I il"rin } ij o) i 'hat riiil, ■v board in precincts oontj inu may requ mbdWidc praeinct - n[&gt;ile&lt;l </seg>
            <seg id="p254">206 I II In addition to what I ha general rule that an election must be held at Bated by is having statutory power t' ithority for holdi 118; H III. 6 IT III :'■ I kn of thi ■ act in sucli authoritx exists. Ill ! ■ 1 following 1. "Can tin* ma&gt; offeti- '2. "(an the mayor am police judge l»y appnintiti. </seg>
            <seg id="p255">207 int Mime justice of the | within the corporate limits i (lisa- Mat . cli. 14. art. 1. itcl I am unable to liml in the chart -inn authorizing the mayor incy in the office of polio the only i itliin tlic city is absent, &gt; nut authorized by the charter t&lt;&gt; i person to fill the vacaiK lorl must l»- Iiltc on tlir subject uf filling I _■ u ; statute on the subject menti&lt; ill Ik' lilleil "in i'itv an 1 \illa_ i council "f board of trut i that there may l&gt;e no vacancy in tin- - net' of the resident lustier &gt;r and council may, in my opinion, appoint i temporarily. Ven fully Nor r is Brown rney Gi i r imiuirii "If i A land in Nebraska and ■ irlaiul, and a resi- Qterruptoi. An examinatioi low that the r the lilliii. s IIiiic — Treaty Kh.h ikat. ■it i/ Ait* tunty, &lt; 'hn[&gt;- </seg>
            <seg id="p256">208 I'lhler tl which 1 1 f i I: until i i:, wit I /■■ This yoor letter &lt;&gt;l i' </seg>
            <seg id="p257">and main- crirnina] pri iiticin for tliis offense would the Criminal Codt r lectfullv i;&gt; N, At I By \V. T. Thompson, Deputy. - ' up and in offense within t lie meaning titutes an offense within the i i in u Koads Damages Appeal. ■ 15, I 1 • tent &lt;»)' this department an a] .ml of ilaiiKi Itiny i public highway does not the road. power to di ■lish a public mil jam- subject matter acquired l&gt;y the board. The authorized to open and prepare the public travel, although an appeal lias been taken by - Tlie law does not require that the shall wait until the court has finally determined the unt of the da Very respectfully, Xoiuus Btowa, d. ust 19, 1905. </seg>
            <seg id="p258">Dims Holdreqe, A ::: This authorit\ r oi ■ in 1 nnty authority may be ;i-- li ■ IIM.K'1 </seg>
            <seg id="p259">211 l'AXh Levy Attor Kearney County, fill 1: honor to acknowledge 28th instant, in which you make tlie and pinion thereon: village hoard of trustees of Axtell recommended neral fund, and the same was certified to tbe .".. 1M5. tin June T.. 190.",. the new village board of •d a 10-mill levy, and a letter wa- &lt;1 to have it was not received by the county clerk after the county board had adjourned. On A mill levy in accordance with the only ard mad hat a K-mill levj is needed in the village. Under the above ounty clerk have authority under the proviso annotated 8t»1 \t«-nd the 10-mill levy on revenue law of 1903, provide in taxes for the current year. Including all couDty rict. precinct, village, road district and othe certified to Ihe county clerk and levied by the iat any rack taxes regularly voted at d certi T the county hoard -hall have nwide such levy : shall have completed the tax list shall be t if within the limit of the law, and extende* aw authorized by a vote of the pi u For ordinary county revenue r. not more than nine mills on the dollar than five miles on the dollar valuation: e than four mills on the dollar valuation: &gt;re than four mills on the dollar valua- . ide&lt;i in the following section !' tlii — department that under t lie provision ion, the county clerk, after the countv board shall previously certified, may levy rtified to him by the pr n«: as a l&gt;oard of equalization the count J board .i. The rmt at- and Bfl u the </seg>
            <seg id="p260">212 tnct • I i i 1 authorities of cities, viliaj.. - and &lt;lis rtified t&lt; nty clerk by - paliti&gt; nl tlie limit allowed by law, a ipriatioii ordinam ami - \ii; tfully H eiling. The role i- thai the p ami can onh the nullity for want iction ii jurisdiction "f ti i and ol lubject in collateral a) on l: 1 l&gt;y you, a writ of bal eeding in error. Church on liabea down tlr il rule that when hv law of the offense charged and oi ti judgment it&gt; not void darit\ I during the trial " in ex&lt; ■ been n - Tin irt "I this rule: \. .1" August •".&lt;». Li) By W. T. Thoii k l&gt;. Mr In re i of this depart l&gt;y a ln_ </seg>
            <seg id="p261">213 a h N I foil - not a corrective remedy, and is never or an appeal or writ of error." In He Langgton, ■ ill not lie on behalf of a convicted prisoner on the id tha to imprisonment is in I the statutory . and not void." I In re the Criminal Code is unconstitutional, then gment of the court thereunder is a nullitj i writ of habeas corpus would lie Er {xirte Thamamm, It but in' If to m« why tli; held unconstitutional. The fact that it • time than section 2,066, under which the convictioi to the validity &lt;&gt;f the law. You will that section 2,63 general statute, and it applies, ii ■ all misdemeanors and not alone to offenses ted u hin 2,066. my authorizing a sentei and water is not in conflict with section ntution, which forbids « lines and nd unusual punishments. I am not advised of any court i law unconstitutional on the ground that it ■ &lt;&gt;n a bread ami water diet. While to icnce might appear to be cruel and unnec - stion was for the legislature to settle. advised that in my judgment the courts ■ writ of habeas corpus on the facts stated by you. 'i tfully, Norkis Ruoun, L905. meij General. t This department has the honor to acknowledge 'lli ultimo in which you submit the thereon: IH III US. 7 J. Ho [ttorneyofGr urtty, Gn Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p262">t a trail - i t la &lt; tnil cil 1 1 a 1 1 \ il in 1. "Under the ». aw will we Jh the sale a- than the the tmxes are more than the land is worth?" value and then let 11 and tax levied a?ai than three yea 1 taxes or MMMneni - may bM ■ shall tie for an amount i penally a i X 1 1 ■ lilt lint 1 land for whicli I city ta tlian tlit' inder tin By &gt;;tiil - ] 1 1 ( ' j 1 J i 1 *•• I I ' i t ll*' "Tin all ol ■ •hall imm. . id amount In repi] inatioii of li. I «t w I lunr </seg>
            <seg id="p263">215 \ li tli B8t, penalty and i opinion that a negative ad proposition, unless than the tax. KKDIT. your letter of the 31b1 ultimo submitting sition and ting an opinion thereon: m of the inten 00 county tii :nn banks has Hirer to the bond sinking at fund, contrary to section il 1903 In August, 1905, the county conn _ the count; treasurer to credit to the count ited to the • fund, which the county treasurer ;il fund of l!*t"&gt; being the only county D which tl ■ ■ unity commissioners after allow claims and draw nit mi transferred to 1 1 . fund of 1906. Can nuns to obey the order of the ibey's Annotated which relates to the deposit of the state moneys in hi we take it ha&gt; ■ uslv named I &gt;v you, and tliat the section you reallv in - 10,871, which bean directly on r opinion the question you submit should be anan e affirmative. It was the &lt; mler • | ( . r ,,.]ji ilimptlv t (unit ot tlip I'i'iici'il fin ally, Xuuifis Bkoun. Attorney By \\ I. I ii'i\i I'm i\ ;, I &gt; tnty Attorney '"','/. Taylor, </seg>
            <seg id="p264">taiitaiix miit td a demand, u|»&gt;n failure to comply with wl Ver hilly Norhis Hum \v. t. t niiitcl hv tli. turc lias expn i, 1-} Neb. 305. Prior I supreme court in 1883. Th ae by making the count' ■ ■ miity all iir -hcIi moneys and tin- duty, in our judgment, until discharged bv nerd rder of the board requiring him to &lt;!i a in mandamus against bim ti • r ~&gt;, l:n DeakSib: , coanf examinati courts have Ik'IiI thai - but must be by expn riiiiinal' I the i witn until, I I Neb. 1 ■ amended the old law bv ■ Criminal Code, which tnodil - in ;i f&lt; This provision of tlie Crimina </seg>
            <seg id="p265">217 i. as amended, a county is liable the defendant in proa -ndan! d and is unable acquitted, only when there has been tiled w ired by that section, and an order of court ■ '.at: the number limited, be sum- affida it * from the county treasurer." ( l\'ortkin to I pinion of tlii&gt; department that a county i&gt; witu I by the accused at a immat Very respectfully N0RRI8 Bl!o\\\ l'.IO.") In reply to your letter requesting the opinion &lt;&gt;f i 'Hi 1 titutionality of section 17, article •"&gt;, r 1903, 1 ay that in my is valid and constitutional. mini led Stal tatui ■ -I to loubt that whetl could arise with respect to the not it contravenes that pi which forbids the expenditure of public te purposes. Hut I think the rule is well that a cuiintv may id devastation of flood waters or rebellious if necessary for such protect ion, moneys in the by taxation may he used for that purpose \lr. Cooley on taxatioi edition, page 620, lays down the - turn of embankments to protect low lands bordering upon from overflow ia a public object of the highest importance U No doubt general taxation is Attorney ' reneml. I'axatiun I .u \\ Lands -Protection. '// Attorney of C timing County, I 3 territory against the </seg>
            <seg id="p266">MknttN . 110 ( -alar. per da - Till- In iw* iii force pr In othei their salary would be reguli rate, for that portion of tin rul foi I by chapter 1 10 ■ &gt;!' the &amp; By the 17 the legislatur I think the able. ; fully XoKI I'.Hlfi. . ruly, XoUHIS 15l(n« By W ing a | HipulatH'ij i ion of frim </seg>
            <seg id="p267">219 ir favor relating to the establishment iws that the mad was surveyed and pi nit 1 established by an order of the county 1 that claims were tiled hv the land oh e controversy, the land owners receiving that the plat made by the surv&lt; iifhwav as actually established of in places; that the field notes show the ■nail i&gt; now traveled; that the road as indi- i ie time it was established; that some of the \ nership since the road v road a^ shown bv the field notes hat nt me of the present owners insist that the line indicated by the plat, and ( &gt;n this statement of fact* to whether the road as located and tnr liwav tv for two reasons may legally inain- nt I'K-at hi: the present highway ws that itinuously since March 18, 1888, a period The continu of a road by the ilarity of the proceedings under i. The rule ha- stated l&gt;v \ moceedings under the statute and traveled by the public for more than ten years, the pub- lereby acquire a l therein, and the court will not examine the :,rmiDe wl Aitor Greeley County, part of &lt; Ireelev countv ■ n traveled and used l&gt;v t lie tlie county a permanent ri^ht th&lt; ghway w; court as I'olluw ami &lt;&gt;i&gt;ei) </seg>
            <seg id="p268">220 w r interfere with th&lt; &gt;&gt;f tl '2. When allowed bv the county l&gt; ii ■ i in . \ ■Within ten da ■hall tak&gt; Dimrs of all the childrei district. In cas appoint, and a i eh list such i affidavit ap|&gt;en that 11 the ayes of ."&gt; and twer within ten days pro annual rr annual re|x&gt;rt of the dii-et-tor to / the first and second class- for la owners of tlit 1 adjoining land 1 l.ui'l taki liin^ for da III,. ; l'.ki:;. pi ■hall </seg>
            <seg id="p269">221 i n 1 1, Compiled Stai ally, on or before tbe third Mod- HI niber. make a complete exhibit fund of the state, as returned to r with ihe amouui ily certified to the state superin- ty davs thereafter I i|&gt;eri*,tendent shall said t - ich counties accordini: to the ach county last returned from the ami certify the apportionment of each to the tl i- county and to the state auditor, who nit on the state treasurer in favor of the various state superintendent. chapter and subdivision providi ijieriii! &gt;liall immediately and within portionment. and after adding tli- iintx treasurer on account of tines and unit a&gt; follows, to wit: One-foui th of Iributed equally to the -.everal districts in the urths of the whole to I* distr'bub inty pin ruta, according to the enumeration the directors of the various districts, and no r village which shall have failed to sustain a school for Mm 14. subdivision II. of this chapter. i in portion of the fund." unit that the enumeration is 'IT makim (li&amp;tiiltuti f the temporary Tii &gt;tl 4 tide VI ii of the constitu- - .it tlic distribution is the number of u to" the district between th. ; five nl this department that the term "belonging bool law should he taken and meanm lent of" such schixil district. The re6i nt or the guardian of the child with whom it is the legal residence of the child. If the child irily in the city of Lincoln for the purpose of attend i -ity. it i&gt; still entitled ■ Id in the eniiint : eh i Id re i school </seg>
            <seg id="p270">inten iialti* district of it- | nienl in Lincoln w </seg>
            <seg id="p271">223 N v t f, ( II t I 150), and while the constitution the or iiist'1).: 1 . 1 know of no law which pro- authorizing the discharge of tax liens Be. It is a common practice of legis- 1. If tliey have power to remit a par we likewise power to remit all of it - 329; Maryland v. Balti- I. S. 534; Auding r. l*evy, ~&gt;~ }\\&gt;-. ,s N. .1. I.. 39; Snttt v. CamjibeU, 24 islature t«&gt; remit penalties. bow&lt; of land at a tax sale thi it the time required l&gt;y l.~&gt;7; Commonwealth t. .iml make thi applk HI Co., Kil Pa. St. 119: Seh ma t. \ contractual b purchaser of land at a tax Bale and ic purchaser lia&gt; ri^'lit in the when lie makes the pur- withool power to impair the obliga- Foley, 30 .Minn. 350; .1/. i ley, Taxation. I'd ed. .")-}.'.; /■ i X. V. IM tally, II mn: 13 Wi have not been sold I ay be discharged by payment •n I without interest or penal iling ta ■ nly lie tli i by payiueni oi rith the interest to which the hoi tfully, </seg>
            <seg id="p272">224 lion. E. I&gt;KAI " art- i () * well tln~ with tli //. \l . I: "Will you pli h\ tliis mini) of tlii&gt; department on 9 ri^lit to allow deductii i^lit of w ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p273">11) till v l! r w hi the tirst i lay shall lie spired b \ trtment tliai or in ottiee I'lMK nh FlI.IM acknowledc !iinu requi by law etion will law it filed on tl 7 tli of N ■mli- mil a tin the rule ap] n the computatii Tuthill, 17 Xeb. m Kled &lt; tetober 18, when than I.'* 1 ttullr, Bbow s. .1 i /•((/. Bi W. T. </seg>
            <seg id="p274">that the act makes it obliga the claim duly and ap] tion is in direct terms mam execution and approval ol Ji.ill direct tl • treasurer in i </seg>
            <seg id="p275">227 mom tit:; paid by one who U i this department that he cannot, lie tion, "the corporate authorities by whom pav ti f the sum actually collected," reward t I violation of tlie with a Former opinion rendered Report and &lt; 'pinions 19*11', which is still believe 1 to bt eceipi of y ■ leti dlowing rjuestion, and usk i the complaining witn&lt; le &gt;iun actually &lt;-. &gt;J l«^*-r. ■&lt; I " ectfully, 8 Brown, Attorney General, l!.v W. T. THOU </seg>
            <seg id="p276">/. A - ;: I P Matm i i | ' t&lt; Ji I, Dear Sih Eeipt o </seg>
            <seg id="p277">229 11 ( i i r and without any dan damages in the ordinary wa tl xl was i, lawfully ad has been located for w 11 Payment \ which you say that the Bur - ninty treasurer to on inquire whether i 1111 IKlt 1&lt; »H i »[ I : ' if t lit ngupon these prnpositions nut entirely satisfactory, or de&gt; Finn: leration, how- By \V. T. Thompson, !&gt;■ 1/'"/ \ etnaha that have apparently ring ii])dii questions relatii operty for public roads, it is iwning land in tliis state who r iiis nav within a reasonable It aunty board making such lotice ami performance of tin- unity board, i in your irisdiction and authority i id td public highway, iiml' leration maj ihed ,.„.. fl </seg>
            <seg id="p278">td took a ; tes declined to met ention, and duri </seg>
            <seg id="p279">231 ' of nominal iitic minority trinity to the pro - jection was ti I * -« I .VI ( :ats mi tions tin ic in ■ rmitv with i a within thi • i; Statutes, eh. 2«, sec. 136 within three dmyi with law, will !*&gt; &lt;i. \ ii 1 with tin- county tajority &lt;&gt;f lemocrati lforrnitv witli the tifieate was t i I *-• 1 I Neb. 40, to a certifi- amlatory. and must Ix* strirtly uslv announced in th&lt; 1 Neb. 299, wherein the ommittee, ' or ■ 1 not the </seg>
            <seg id="p280">232 in the mam and if at • if tl ■ will li ll inn Dead Sib: I ha itiona riminal ( -ul.i.-i lii reply I beg to ad turns arc valid and ghoul </seg>
            <seg id="p281">233 ,1 VTION that in twentVH tlllllv a tution. which dec-lai n in i&gt; imiioiiwi il Is of the state. I lildren l&gt;etween the ajres of ti within the lim lardiii 14 on minted is entirely silent ivious that the letrisla- u i the children of pai thev all "live," and nut a &gt;8idence of the parent or guard - will is further shown by the education law, i . This law charges the o /'//'»//&lt;" Inn I this - in Lincoln but &gt;r ambiguity about the meaning . absolute itution, the legislature litan cities' with tl it their iliiMreu </seg>
            <seg id="p282">A it tn be . r 1 r t N l/. S i Sir: I 1 -Hill I IN .11 X . </seg>
            <seg id="p283">235 I thai iHty, llnijt ml n that n tatfd Stat; will amount to *:! on ea. •at-h lot. wh are tit n - :inv bit! the a riyht to sell it for county i art, in the follow - sul» fill tin 1 llutii lecti - Bkowx, voiir l( mt part of tbe dookt that tli- </seg>
            <seg id="p284">236 and tfc 1. t 1 til \V am t h mi ■ law, uni- imount iif tin affect </seg>
            <seg id="p285">237 f Haye* County, Hayes y .1 person residing in k your county. went tliat if tlic tax sale certifi t your countv on tin let tion tlierein the same as any other certificat* side the jurisdic- t day "f April, it \"i-| tllllv By W. T. Thompson, Deputy. i &gt;ctober 10 you call attenti inly know • r law lit: i|ui mI ask for opinions • for the diffen l\ a .tion of the county recOl th which counties may hecrt iyh to allow the audit' ir ought it to retjuire addi : the 4th instant. ■r not a certificate vour countv, eral rule. NoRRIS l&gt;[ f I'll' ti.lt' </seg>
            <seg id="p286">238 I'l • P until ■ 1 ill iiiv attention I that In him who c-ol in blank bj parture. ou inquire if thii bit </seg>
            <seg id="p287">239 // tfullv i the 1 1\ to the policy 10,546, i - Anno) ■ inducting hi^ office in t lit* man r, I am clear the boi easurer will he county for any ami all h stained by the mliict and management of t lie in ty board or the bondsmen hare liability of the bondsmen. The bond is public and I by th&lt; to the knowledge or endorsement &lt;&gt;t' - liv the countv board or any other officer. In law the conduct "I the person left in charge of the countv ti surer liii i hi&gt; l&gt;ondsmen can be heard ity board cannot become liable Form Ins duty and the failure iiintv. The bondsmen arc the only - T i and lawful conduct of the v Nokhi8 Brown, \ii:&gt; — Capitai Assei inion &lt;if tlii&gt; of a foreign mutual fire insura any, undi &gt;n -'■'&gt;. chapter 43, 1 tate where ii -1 si'im i.ik Ml in cash. in) ! maty mpeachmeni ori &gt; led by the treas i illy, Liitctihi </seg>
            <seg id="p288">240 "It shall not he lawful I parti,' vd for an this ■ to taf poueMed of t» by the K eal writfi - wherein it ma L. K. A. ' ■d • ;i)i|ili(M' of til' 1 ■ s </seg>
            <seg id="p289">241 » in jiisiu'. tapital of which is composed in addition to the foregoing, exhibit tha ital. and also what proportion inpany and considered capital." i and the other cited tal" ;is therein used by the legislatun k. " Tlie ectionti imports the same meaning. ire, tluit the tenu "capital" as the insurance law i.- noi applicable alone but ap] tn mutual insui - n compa n the mutual - • m in this slate W tin.- reqi .nice laws Vcr\ tfully XiPiiins Brown Attorney General. IIlC.HV IIENTS. lepartment honor to acknowledge ■int. req ,n opinion ami 85h uf chap- ■ ild include work dOM with ! icintract under the pro- and S.ili of ehap- , 127 of chapter 18, article 1, Compiled i-ific questions raised by you umler </seg>
            <seg id="p290">By the \ or re] ■ such . in \ it in \ iti. I - tinpr - id impr </seg>
            <seg id="p291">243 where in the statute id if none found, then - Sinned l&gt;y the surveyor under MM ll 'Kin. If it provides DOM, B accepting » public office takes those !■ &gt;ufferably opp jiiate remedy which a w - gnation a m that the owner nf the ill pay the amount paid by the pur- : time, as penalty. ion. linion of this depart raent that the amount of the ■ may have but little, if anything, to do with the amount old l&gt;f perfoi ■ •tlully, i'lisnu s. Attorney &lt; By W. T. Thompson, !&gt;&gt;■&gt; 21, 1905. Tas Redemi \ttoriictj of Md'i i: T rtment lonor to acknow it of tlie 17th instant relative to the f the iat portion lieli sa; liall li' rii the ill mount "f said sale with </seg>
            <seg id="p292">44 V tint oft I w w \ </seg>
            <seg id="p293">245 Dam a /..Mc/.-i and liuilt- pinion of tliis it K'uwiaii who is occupying a par- e state* in his letter that the ideinning a ri^ht of way its he will be greatly the irrigation of two hundred points of inquiry are tht upv the land and les upy school la inipai cupy school lam \i--tt''l for many j 105; Compiletl Statuti usted for manv \ unpiled Stal 10f) ( tatutf conferring? tliis right o Piie statute conferring this right of irjx iral ions is as follows: niiorations authorized to pa - - ICCU] ■-.ity. saline or other land- of th -hall !«■ taken than ■h corporation: anil pro other lam al me or iki-n than ■h corporation: and pro i|&gt;ant or owner or other o any occupant or owner 01 provementa od said land shall 1 ■nient-. on said land shall lie irovided in com pan \ b any to ut-quir nt in uniiiistakable terms in tli istakable terms in this itatuti [uestione&lt;] in tl B.ii 0. /■'. Co. rEnglehai tat ute did not conflict with iVIDLC ii railroad companv to go upon its a line of road thereon cannot 1m at the rijrht to compensation for - landoned, but if it cannot, then the state But certainly one he public land encumbered with a :i f. nor substituted to its </seg>
            <seg id="p294">246 //. y. /■; ■ u at Tinier tin Tip idoubtedly may i V&lt; the takh !' i sliall !■ ■ I M </seg>
            <seg id="p295">247 land i- ailvei I ll the tliinl ]&gt;r iblic lands and build ind i iii_ r ht of redemption Si usts iii the lawful holder ■I t&gt;&gt; 1)6 • tlii&gt; department that mtil such adver- it therefoj it can he law- I for in i nt condition there nil t Fu 1 1 v Brow n. Attorney General / \V. T. Thompson, Deputy. Di ii Kearney r tlie opinion I outside I the mi r neglect to hill on ti mtv. or where the tianks nt capita •k to receive said th ifty !- cent that ha n hanks outside of the - line conditions am: </seg>
            <seg id="p296">\ able and ; contract with tlie raili |&gt;an\ - for it, that the | 'I in I. paid bis railroad fare from I'; ami slniiilil ii-&lt;ci\ e it froi The intenl opinion li fiimls on hai ll'. 1 McBrid &lt;&gt;l liis wlin the 11 -11.11 tii'l frank </seg>
            <seg id="p297">249 ty and liable itute, and mpen8ation belongs to the itutt'-. i attempt to regulate fees wit within the I- id contract to charge no I X.I.. 109: B ilid than tli Illlint UL'I- ii provided by law. nut as follow - isation in excess of that ti •i faith ami &lt; per and lecided alone on ; it i&gt;f that iiiP is without authority to extend ity, in: 1 . N. W. K)77 lilroad company no fees in \-- already stated the county I; ■ ion of tin- sheriff. Hi mnlcl on public \ lll"ll, til in lie obtainei tftlly lifld to Ik- l&gt;t a lea t he cannot mak&lt; ■-■••■•■'• I - : </seg>
            <seg id="p298">250 . - and h&gt; :ii|&gt;ensati&lt; of an official duty i 1 l 'I &lt; v ■ mlv authorit a 12 v ma in f.v. </seg>
            <seg id="p299">251 allowing live inhabitants for all include said sum in its annual e treasurer of the county to pay the tin* agricultural society i paid out of the general fund i t i ii &lt;r the issuance of a war o die making an estimate of the amount The method is arbitrary. Taxes are not authorized by the plain import of the gislature. The statute ■ Hue a warrant on the ts being allowed for cadi; and the nmn - termined by estimating five | tter of the statute the county to base its estimate on the id the amount of the warrant on a subsequent -nit it would not follow, how - ecial election should be disregarded. rtl frequently the amount of hi ex] it an excessive I' warrant i expenditure* hoard in disbursing the amount to ntitled can find in the statute t the last vote for member of i i! a special election. Very respectfully Norms Bkow n xamination of tin* &lt;'i&gt;ti IwiH'lit hi the agricultural society is which «&gt; entitled cornea liiiiiiLT the amount which iety relati lv t&lt;&gt; the ue&lt; •id tlio statute should ii"t action to permit a greater expentlitui f the warrant the nui </seg>
            <seg id="p300">252 /.. /, 1. \v&lt; of tl iii En A - i that it. by uiki no vacancy in ofl 1(»1 UKJ I 1, II- </seg>
            <seg id="p301">253 - py i 'ourUy, PapA- ir inquiries relating to the meaning r law Compiled Statute iinioo of tlii- I. A F $1.00 is a part of the i it clear by declaring tliat lull aim unit of taxes and . iay of &lt; 'ctolier of the current 11-111 in the petition, together with a dock - iption." Compiled ■ iginallv i it did not confer upon any officer authoril ti &gt;n the contrary thi inal act excluded from the fees allowed mpiled statutes 1903, ch. 77, art. 9, • ut in l'.ii authorizt inty • I in the amendment to erk of die &gt;listi-ict court, land therein. With - liiililer doos not assume bid. sts Lom - 13), and lik I iken out of the bid before applying th&lt; in illy. </seg>
            <seg id="p302">254 Hebr I liav. I III Ml Whi ■ failun \ //. I: I &gt;l </seg>
            <seg id="p303">255 it t t t 1 nitami tatutorv f ueh tial tatui. . L'nder the dipsomaniac law The 1 n provide Mnmitting and caring for said pat ■ ■in which the\ iiiiiin- ty refuse to detain quired to depend upon the county tor the support of the insane. The at nte regardless of the state of the al tax lor the rare of the insane, an I ay properly require the county idtnitting dipsomaniacs to the juiry relates to the liability of Wayne county their legal - u( in \-^ 1 understand the statutes of this are maintained at one of the county tribunal go hospital, and provision making the county li. ine ich institutions. In ilit\ :ie county i&gt; aty to | I liable for th and exj uire the county to pay lilt'd without atrainst whom the information was 6c terms in li - : caring for shall be paid by the counties In my opinion th&lt; in caring iii an asylum in ( mtv. laintenanee &lt;&gt;f in For within the county by din orities or ;irr maintained at one of the </seg>
            <seg id="p304">256 in Illii. lian ami In tl: w \ 1. W"l th ■ A was . I ■ ■ |«arty k it and batt* led. \ </seg>
            <seg id="p305">257 limn uiia- •h the u ■uplaint." tilt ni' in 'obuble cause t&lt;&gt; believe tic vil. and il bond for trift c'.iut. This i^ the interpretation court in Latin miming magistral ni uo riirlit t(» turn the prelimi- id tli I guilty of a - done with the i accii- law \n m. stating that in 1905 iw for tin clear i trial. The xamination. All that the in. complaint" for tht&gt; purpose mmitted, fhis i ulaiit did ii"t Nokris Brown, Ittorney General. i'liot I h &lt; 'ounty, Ainmeorthj trtmenl ha* the honor to acknowledge </seg>
            <seg id="p306">Will illt'll I quell! ite ta -till 1 &lt;l tin mati' illv a ii suvonl Mich "tin f all i </seg>
            <seg id="p307">ler tin let in real estate, or in en le\ y VV T . T. Thompson, ]&gt;■ the honor to aeknov tart, submitting tlie follow pinion th' e linal \n ■ er an open one in tin by our supreme court that ixation under the constitu This is true, we think ion in th ie law i if pro- such land until r. Tucket tlit- |&gt;re-emption, homestead, and which linal proof ha&gt; tlif persooi owning such im- Ix ims Brown, .1// // Gent ■SON. /' nit Hv W. T. Tiium </seg>
            <seg id="p308">it i&gt; i|M&gt;intnienl i only until tin tilled liv election Ver ., </seg>
            <seg id="p309">261 I'm ill- unication of recent date - for the utitieti &gt;f their duties, in addition ierfi&gt;rmai a - i .uiy for team hir Compiled Statutes 1905, tixtvs tlit The compensation bo fixe&lt; lay and three dollars for on d l'.tii."). fixee the compensation bo fixed three dollars for out &gt;n l' ention is made of mileafi tion 2 piled Statute ipiled Statutes 1905, allows to ap 1905, allows to a]&gt;- i day actual! day actual! mile Tor each mile necessarily trav I company, where educational raili ipany, where educational. tural r..l: ither lands belon ral college, or other lands i a. We understand th - hi apprai - inad&lt; If w ilwav purposes. We understand tin tion, i i of law last abov on, the provision of law last abov no application, hut the law applies - lion of the statute &amp;T8 no application, but the law applica - - tion of the statute first i entitle* m to their per diem and team hire. their per diem and team hire. tnmunica coinmumca- ,v ii-eomi&gt;a rt fully, - Brow s. AU \\\ VV. T. Thompson. Deputy. llv - Brow s. Att s \\\ VV. T. Thompsox, Deputy. I'uwiMi: Chickexs — Pi itsi it. \rden, Lincoln. \'\ I!S1 IT iting that certain parties </seg>
            <seg id="p310">I lapter 31, ( </seg>
            <seg id="p311">263 We rtain, an«l tliat Ittoi \V. T. Thompson, Dei \ sulmiittiiu imon What amount of ii I'.Mir, arv t &lt; I dollar* in exc latin r hil.livn rior to lii&gt; nt, or t&lt; -d and value, t dollars oi to an tax V\ . I . I </seg>
            <seg id="p312">264 rll . M. K l.i in I &gt;i:\i! Sib: I ! follow in lowii islatiiic to lin connection \vr 11 applicant i Ilmi. A. Gain 1 'km( Sir: I lia\ ■ mill </seg>
            <seg id="p313">265 t i t t daily - ■ l&gt;uhlioati' newspaper in each con in a ne« • * * * published once a newspaper Ion &lt;&gt;f s, at which election (hi approval or rejection." rel Brigltam p. South Omaha, 33 Neb. publication was made under section 2, chapi • tea, pertaining to notice of application for a e law lequiring the publication of notice to l&gt;e ■■k-&gt; in a newspaper before action illicit betaken • in by the licensing board . it was held that I daily, then the notice must l&gt;c pub - aper is published weekly, then weekly pub- si flicient." From analogy, then ;&gt;iil)licatiiin of a constitutional notice is I mtinued in such daih ■iiths next preceding tin election; in a tri-weekly, that it should be publisheil tri - i for the three months; and if published in a kly during ~-;t i&lt; 1 period, and thai it would be to another. st publication in a newspaper sup - iil a&gt; "that which supplies that which tills up, completes, or makes an addition something aln j^anized, arranged, or set apart; a par! r a continuation This definition was appi </seg>
            <seg id="p314">266 - - I 'n duty &lt;&gt;f i </seg>
            <seg id="p315">267 ml of money iiounl of i nutation "I s liH&gt; where the num- l'our or - than sixteen children all nut nut: and ;i further limita- ry 8100 1 1 . chapter 70, subdivisii &gt; ■ i I I, 1 districts in cities, and has no application Subdivision (•"&gt;, chapter 71), auth Is I ii rtain pur li\ imoh 1.) it is made the duty ol the nty t'i levy annually pay th&lt; I &gt;ut it will Im&gt; i in IS'. 1. 1 tha r an] holding in men ■i lM put this limitati &gt;n the a ir. In ■ ■• //. ( '". v. I &gt;' 254, it was held that a I &lt; • %■ \ »&gt;1 tax it liar valuation was unauthorizei ■ i; but in tha the authority this I, in ii i lit I not author ly inill&gt; | &gt;l;i&lt; iiili\isiiiii I I </seg>
            <seg id="p316">268 "Any s&lt;-h(&gt;&lt;&gt; ay at any annual tax on the tax a of th. Uiai-t: II will l'. el. liniital of tli. ■ nano I &gt;illki n II. Mi I h mi Sue I ha from this department mplainl filed witl ■ in- board with fmilun </seg>
            <seg id="p317">269 E-:uil coma »aduc i tnav tile with nor written ffuiltj &lt;&gt;' net it 'ile time. ■ re him. and shall mak&lt; i his judsrniei' judged by him to lie •he i-omiii ■ i fill the vai'ancv (fa have full [Kiwer and authority to OOCnpel the attendani-e iduction of l&gt;ooks and paper - tintr at t; . ation. " - of Nebraska tlie chief of police ami police 3( mill &lt; 'maha have the power and it is rnad&lt; ~i all offenders against tiie laws of tin - 2, ch. 13 . It is an offense against the I intoxicating liquor &lt;&gt;n Sunday •f South &lt; hualia is given super utrol of the polici &gt;t the city subject to tin ■ I cil fire and police commissioners Section 64 ! • chief of police and all police officers are sub board of fire and police commissionei i of fire am I the city of South Onia »ponsible ■ he law. this department that if the board of fin 5 1 1 1 1 « hnaha kuowingli vilfullv permit the law to U- violated with respect to thi IBc in intoxicating liquor on Sunday they are sub ooval for misconduct in nd that you have th&lt; the cha madi nd and to make such finding and take sue! as tiie facts in the case and the law warrant. Very respectfully, Nobbis 1&gt;i:&lt;&gt; ' leneral. </seg>
            <seg id="p318">270 1 ill (in, ill. "Tli </seg>
            <seg id="p319">271 nother ■ ii h mid i I ]&gt;&lt;&gt;- &gt; in and 1. It pointment m the ! and h rough th*- rovlded In this r wltkonl at In dis - be im- Illtinll. I ny officer, wlioin ha iiy. or ti </seg>
            <seg id="p320">272 public li In the rase of / 111', ami in th&lt; i Km tin vv in c 1 and i - public I, mil uii'l- jh wai.'i inion ;is to tin- ity in th&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p321">i in repair suitable mding the highw;* Id out ubllc authority within the right of way which the railroad not been eon- mty for if put building wing fences, plank - approaches at a public lotild be through all or nearly all. the width of the side ol the track, the railroad company should null- I hut under tht^c decisions a public highway a« 11 1 company that it has t" open or e land "I private individuals. While sent, we take it from it of the railroad company was not of th&lt; a it&gt; right of way. In sarv that yon Follow 78, ( ' piled Statutes 1905, highways, giving the notice unpany I nt its claim for ted upon l&gt;y the county boar stahlislinienl or alteration of a WilV gpectfully Nohris Brown, Attorney General By W. T. Thompson, Deputy. </seg>
            <seg id="p322">) </seg>
            <seg id="p323">275 in county In which •ly apparent - authoi -.11 i n. ami i ~i tli ilullv . IJy W. T. Thom i ■ IK-klll&gt;\vll nt. -iiliinitti How nion tliei mnty or tuntjr or i i Statutes I'-" 1 "* Illtill lOW II : liv t;i\;ition far tin I ! ii i.'i 1 1) Mill lOWII liv taxation for tin town elork within ten had For raisiuu leliver to the county clerk a certified eopy of all nade tlie duty </seg>
            <seg id="p324">276 rjualization I rtitir.l I iv li lliP i n ty &lt;•)( ik after I :\\ . It. II IK If]' tl lul 1 1,111 i&gt; undertaki thfii , in our judgment, ,iml supervision &lt;&lt;( llie fecli I&gt;I.AI. &lt;licli thai In "J ( 'imvin-v I.'. in lit' 1 Tl:- w hi&lt; h authorizes or |i </seg>
            <seg id="p325">277 Inn |irioi lain lot in th' u this I .1 upon the count wt mail ing ihf eounty'i claiin ■II II. r 7, article L, Compile*! Statutes 1905, a lien from and incluriii in wliicli they arc levied _ islatiou Cooley mi Taxation, land in question was sold to tin - lien for taxes had attached to tlie was authorized to attach land was ow net! by the I'nited ibjeti to ia^ land, ami there is no lien r delinquent taxi ullv, \'&lt;\ W. T. Thompson, Deputy. I'akmit. submit! i illowni^r | )r °P" ■ i &gt;u : North PI mnty and ii r. " Will. .").") N. .1. I.. ."i,S; (J nimby lit I.'. I. .17 1 i tit of fin by \ iitnc of this fact, 1 1 1 * Nonius I '//.-•. Lin- </seg>
            <seg id="p326">278 ■ ■ I </seg>
            <seg id="p327">! i ! I i nan i I, I ivith i - n law - a I" t ! a ih - ii&lt; lament animal* - 1 1 1 - </seg>
            <seg id="p328">280 - - ■ • valhlii l 'i ■ Von n iiiiiiii if tlii- 1. T! </seg>
            <seg id="p329">281 tion of tin- catching of "lisli" with - rule nl construction - to auiend a slat ion imt germane i seel prop «ed to l&gt;e clu nr opinion tliat tbe amendatory ad i which it purported to amend, atntt to fixes a minimum penalty of intent in the county jail of not lesa i 'If No maximum penalty i&gt; ~ shall have jurisdiction of an\ iiinal case where the punishment ma mprisom - one hundred the one hand and the maxi &lt;&amp; S. I ~&gt;'i, and the courl in that case held hundred dolla ase involving a i| ■ court held: I ■ 'lie. tin Rs Amu ■ urolreri in the ir catching of contained in the ""I 'I 1 It will Im tattitt' referral to fixes ;i miniiiuini nenaltv ..i loll troversy shall exceed two Inn statute &lt;m which tin utioii in limit. m| to twenty-live dollars ther. A similar que» I of South ( 'arolina in tin '. a &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p330">i r i hi </seg>
            <seg id="p331">hi'timi i mil and 1 1 1 1 v \ , 1 i\. 1 1, \h ill I 1 ■il in show ourl had notwithstanding \&gt;- not I'Jn.-), providi 1 'i;it it the </seg>
            <seg id="p332">( lit I'.: I I // / M !ll(i Hot III- I, </seg>
            <seg id="p333">N tinei ipplication to purchas • laml under the ad i &gt;f Ilk ••"&gt;. 1 87!l tin ( m&gt;| i) it any ti ner than 01 87!l tl i' than once in y in writing to the county treasurer t&lt;&gt; hav (lie pur I purchase tli ■ I from time to time until in 1811 m ithdrawn from sale. ( ' . tin c | hi r - sale, anil purchase tlie . ired under conti iiiirt'il miller contracl t&lt;&gt; parties prior to the taking prior to tin- takii 1 1 1 ■ I i;i iiiinoM in- leaned lain) mds &gt;m ?*ale. At the lasi F tli At the IohI session of the ut was passed providing, among endatory act was _ unoii| t all tin' educational lands of ma! lands of I iuprove&lt;l prior to July 1, i pon, occupie&lt;l and improved prior to July 1 d in person* who settled upon, ocvupied am ho ■ttled upon, occupied and &gt;, n»»l exceeding a quarter section. It i- on fact* stated, that .Mary Law would lia&gt; tny time prior to January 1. 1905 unite i section. I Mary Law would have had prior to Jaimarv 1. llMIti, al Illl 'I land appraised I'm- the purpo* cordance with the law in for« e&lt;l her lease. That right, however, wa and tli ill, in our judgment r the pin with the law in I li That right, however, wa- ■application for and received a new lease fo The lease she n un«le receive*! a new lease for under i ditional time could not lawfully contain ai hi' I not lawfully contain an ber to purchase the laml a&gt; she mijjlit havi lease. Any misrepresentation of tin s to the law that may have influenced her ti the law that niav have intlneiireil her to iot entitled to purchase under the origina purchase under the original t 1 not bind the state. She sought for and acci iiml the state. She sought for and ao (unity tieanurer on such question at her peril tv treasurer on such question at her peril ii ie applied for and received the new lease, she plied for and 'I the new leaa i| any ami all rights she hail umler her forme inv ami all rights fshe had under her former iw estopped to claim the right to pun-hast ind fimn the state. It is further the opinion of thin de- tuieiit that Mary I .aw cannot iiiM-t upon the right to </seg>
            <seg id="p334">( A </seg>
            <seg id="p335">with sin Id; l'i And fun I conn] ' aining li api» I it'll upon tilt 1 I* tutli &lt; Iniaha the ri^rlii b\ le nf intoxicating liqi Lt I a HI. I itio! I pfiiah apply to an ■ i In • liiii leration | ivould 1 1 ' it m by a li&lt; sf withoul a con\ iction in - &gt;nth » hi </seg>
            <seg id="p336">288 'Ill' Im ivictl • ■ dins i&lt;i \ If the iHiard of tin of infraction of tl he | granting * Whi: Ks my opinion ihi rant a lii il tin 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p337">289 a i'it mm le liv a tli, tlic property is subject la </seg>
            <seg id="p338">t In iik I Fiinil « ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p339">291 ■ ■ ■ triit . i | &gt; i i 1 1 &lt; i | &gt; a I ami ii i |&gt;rii)(-ipal ami ii strict in said v&lt; mnU . maty treasurers &lt;\i-.A\ I'l-limi and disl)i </seg>
            <seg id="p340">of said ' .uitially . </seg>
            <seg id="p341">293 </seg>
            <seg id="p342">,\ * </seg>
            <seg id="p343"/>
            <seg id="p344"/>
            <seg id="p345">297 upon i such portion of and by hii ional ; ii wri ! &gt;twill form a led with tl he county mdidates and w such |&gt;olilical | </seg>
            <seg id="p346"/>
            <seg id="p347"/>
            <seg id="p348">300 </seg>
            <seg id="p349">if tilt' I I'll l! 1 id as a hoard, ou a^k a ! 7. article I. Com I iincoimtitu fill the unex in sm-ceetl In </seg>
            <seg id="p350">302 ml tile I </seg>
            <seg id="p351">303 ■ III SO eal)lf ite mini I Hitnl : ! tit-' 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p352">304 Kr shall cause him t </seg>
            <seg id="p353">tfall? of tiii&gt; liis wife. . nor mon levic&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p354">INDEX A 1 A K A A A, </seg>
            <seg id="p355">i .S3 M 1 6 6 » </seg>
            <seg id="p356">308 Bonds Bunds Bonds Bond of Bond Bounda • or w killed Bridges fron contract Bridges SutBclf Bridges days prior er into Bridges Plans should I Building and Loan Av </seg>
            <seg id="p357">platform or without 130 of direction by ■ irt. .142 </seg>
            <seg id="p358">f guardit offl&lt; he count Conn i A Corporation Costs audit County County County County May maintain . illegally deposited. County for cost c County Not liable fur premi after expiration of term. County Premiums paid on county term, not a charge against County ■ board. </seg>
            <seg id="p359">311 »» 1 at either a 131 Irawn by voucher 139 tion of state t;i 13» hai mty houndaru lemeanor a county 160 st countv b : jrmant in flvt- 167 1 without vote of 213 : '■ , • I ' I I ; . 21« witnesses at preliminary { III ion its e for e % f &lt;Ji IS* .hmitting </seg>
            <seg id="p360">312 I. ., --, term. Couni County attorn^ ordinances. Count violation of Slocum law County Board by Ux. </seg>
            <seg id="p361">upon 146 hool lands 147 a tax Mon of bank books. 160 lormant judgment. 174 made. </seg>
            <seg id="p362">314 U County &lt; County Clerk County Clerk County Cotnni </seg>
            <seg id="p363">315 ■ 74 ■ tion • lit Incam \ alid. ta 7u "5 . 99 .. 99 Niinn- • county board .134 pt when receipt is mailed to a foreign purchu County Treasurer .134 No st. e for tax receipt lien on land County Treasurer .167 Has n nte of the people. </seg>
            <seg id="p364">316 ■ ■ Criminal Criminal Law probable cause. </seg>
            <seg id="p365">317 256 :.tl by jury line suilt or • ;minary hearing. Uool land collectible by state. with- I land failure to under (1 </seg>
            <seg id="p366">318 ■i on firt Qua ' </seg>
            <seg id="p367">319 i blaiu ontract of sale of nf his ild be a </seg>
            <seg id="p368">320 . irpus Highways </seg>
            <seg id="p369">321 1 ■ ■ final proof. </seg>
            <seg id="p370">322 </seg>
            <seg id="p371">323 136 of a village within 136 not a freeholder. 181 181 ;i franrhi 183 should be refunded. 183 d unea 268 Sunday a violation of law. iiii la w viola- ill be paid by a&lt; 286 196 61 li di'. 51 surrendered by 160 </seg>
            <seg id="p372">Judg: ■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p373">325 . llut.V iquor </seg>
            <seg id="p374">326 Offii •. ■ I OfBc </seg>
            <seg id="p375">327 when </seg>
            <seg id="p376"/>
            <seg id="p377">329 41 ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p378">330 ' - </seg>
            <seg id="p379">331 . </seg>
            <seg id="p380"/>
            <seg id="p381">1 4 1 ■ ■ • </seg>
            <seg id="p382">Ta* i . T </seg>
            <seg id="p383">1 1 1 134 :» 1 14 44 HI 1 14 14 bo;ird on II H i town eh 149 </seg>
            <seg id="p384">336 </seg>
            <seg id="p385">337 i hie as upon 174 rrors have been whpre .176 valuation on township county board. made by 179 11 1st 181 aloon made. 184 rMfiration fro to county y until after certification from which final proof has been made after April 1st paper </seg>
            <seg id="p386">338 Taxation Taxation bidders. re no Taxation Taxation Taxation Taxation Taxation Taxation Taxation Taxation Asi-essnven t of tax sale i« i'.i - : • I i 'i ■ • - il*:,* Taxation Amount of taxes under r law cai until time of redemption ha:- Taxation 4X mination of rate of ,&amp;er law. Taxation Ai&gt;i&gt;&lt; i ixes to st i real </seg>
            <seg id="p387">339 ■ ( - Qgulshed from city • property . r not held rnment pi .289 temptation of death are subject to .168 company's property. rerae law With art of suprenn . 191 of municipal I .. 38 Limitation is X5 per cent of levy in counties. </seg>
            <seg id="p388">340 - - ward iin.: of a li </seg>
        
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>