<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirtieth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1917-02-01">1917-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA THIRTIETH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 1, 1917 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">THE OFFICIAL ROSTER OF THE STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY HON. VICTOR G. LYFORD, President, Falls City Term expires Jan., 1919 HON. FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha HON. EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey HON. JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln HON. PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln HON. HARRY D. LANDIS, Seward Term expires Jan., 1919 Term expires Jan., 1921 Term expires Jan., 1921 Term expires Jan., 1923 Term expires Jan., 1923 SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor •J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director; Animal Husbandry C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc., Director of Extension Service FLOYD WAMBEAM, B. Sc., Bulletin Editor ■^ W. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany F. W. UPSON, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering W. W. BURR, B. Sc., Agronomy J. H. GAIN, M. D. C, Animal Pathology J. H. FRANDSEN, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Brlner, B. Sc., Entomology H. C. FlLLEY, A. M., Farm Management R. F. HOWARD, A. M., Horticulture G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology W. P. SNYDER, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte T. A. KlESSELBACH, A. M., Agronomy H. J. GRAMUCH, B. Sc., Animal Husbandry GEORGE K. K. Link, Ph. D., Associate in Agricultural Botany J. W. Calvin, B. Sc., Associate in Agricultural Chemistry ! C. B. Lee, A. M., Associate in Animal Husbandry M. H. SWENK, A. M., Associate in Entomology L. L. Zook, B. Sc., Assistant in Dry Land Agriculture, U. S. Department oj Agriculture 'H. A. McComb, B. Sc., Horticulturist of Experimental Substation, North Platte Erwin Hopt, B. Sc., Assistant in Agronomy J. A. Ratcliff, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy E. G. WOODWARD, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry R. R. SPAFFORD, A. M., Assistant in Farm Management J. R. COOPER, B. Sc., Assistant in Horticulture James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine 'Fritz Knorr, B. Sc., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell ■By an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska, approved and in effect February 15, 1899, the State Treasurer became ex officio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1, 1899 = Resigned </seg>
            <seg id="p004">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, Keith Neville, Governor of Nebraska: Sir — In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith to submit the Thirtieth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. E. A. Burnett, Director. February 1, 1917. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, Executive Department Lincoln, February 1, 1917 Mr. E. A. Burnett, Director Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station: Sir — I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Thirtieth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. Keith Neville, Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CONTENTS Letter of Transmittal. Governor's Certificate The Official Roster of the Station Director's Review — Experimental work Sheep feeding. Cattle feeding . Cow testing associations . . Farm management studies Marketing farm products . Winter wheat selections . . . An early hybrid wheat . . . Oat selections Water requirements of crops Competition in cereals Crop rotation and fertilizer experiments Spraying apples xvn xvii xviii Potato disease investigations . Hill selection of seed potatoes Pump irrigation xvni xviii Serum production Poultry work xix xx Technical investigations The North Platte Substation The Valentine Substation . . . The Scottsbluff Substation The Station staff XXI XXI! XXV XXVI xxvm xxviii Improvements Publications . XXIX Acknowledgments xxx Annual Refort of the Agricultural Extension Service Lines of Extension work carried on The Extension force Extension meetings in 1916 County agent work Women's extension work Junior extension work County fair exhibits Bulletins Reports of specialists XXXI XXXI .xxxii xxxiv xxxv xxxix xli xliii xliii xliv Financial Statement 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">THIRTIETH ANNUAL REPORT EXPERIMENTAL WORK The work of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station for the current year has been as follows: The funds of the Station are obtained from three sources, namely: The Hatch and Adams appropriations are received from the Federal Government in amounts shown by the Finan - cial Statement of this Report. In addition, certain funds appro - priated for general University maintenance are set aside by the Regents for agricultural departments and used for experimental work. Direct appropriations are also made by the Legislature for certain specific purposes, such as hog cholera serum produc - tion and investigations conducted by the State Entomologist and State Botanist, who are respectively Entomologist and Botanist of the Experiment Station. These appropriations are under control of the Regents of the University and are expended for the purposes authorized by the Legislature. The State makes direct appropriations also for the mainte - nance of the Substations at North Platte, Valentine, and Mitchell, Nebraska. An appropriation is also made for the Agricultural Extension Service of the College of Agriculture. The farm of the Nebraska School of Agriculture at Curtis is available for demon - stration purposes. Plans of work are prepared by each department at the be - ginning of the calendar year, covering the lines of investigation proposed for the current year, so that the work of the Station may progress systematically in accordance with approved plans. The urgent necessity for entering into new lines of investiga - tion not permitted by the present appropriation is the basis of the request by the Regents for a specific appropriation to the central experimental plant comparable with the appropriations now made to the various Substations under the control of the Board of Regents. A few of the more practical lines of investigation conducted by the Station which should have an immediate bearing upon the agricultural practice of the State are as follows: Sheep feeding — Two experiments were carried on during the past year. Three hundred Wyoming lambs were purchased in December, 1915, and placed on a 75-day experiment which'con - tinued until March 14, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Agricultural Experiment Statioti oj Nebraska The objects were to determine the amount of corn which may most profitably be fed in connection with alfalfa, also the character of supplementary rations in addition to corn for fattening pur - poses. Feeding in the open versus feeding with sheds for protec - tion was also tested. The results indicated that a medium ration of corn approximat - ing .86 pound per day with alfalfa gave cheaper gains than with heavier or lighter rations of corn. Lambs receiving silage with corn and alfalfa showed more finish than any other lot and were appraised at the highest value per pound. The cost of 100 pounds of gain with corn, alfalfa, and corn silage was $4.95 per hundred; with a medium ration of corn and alfalfa hay, $4.90 per hundred; corn, oil meal, and alfalfa hay, $5.43; corn, cottonseed meal, and alfalfa hay, $5.15; corn, cold pressed cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay, $5.18, respectively. The addition of oil meal, cottonseed meal, and cold pressed cottonseed cake to the ration increased the gains sufficiently so that the profit per head was larger than where no supplementary feed was used, the profits being as follows: Alfalfa hay and heavy corn ration, $2.13; alfalfa hay and medium corn ration, $2.27; al - falfa hay, corn, and oil meal, $2.48 ; alfalfa hay, corn, and cottonseed meal, $2.65; alfalfa hay, corn, and cold pressed cottonseed cake, $2.60. Where hominy feed was substituted for corn with alfalfa hay, the profit was $2.14. The lambs fed in the open yard made a somewhat greater gain than those in the shed but consumed more feed. The profit per head was $2.34 compared with $2.13 for a similiar lot fed in the shed. The lambs on the self-feeder were held but 40 days whereas the other lambs were held 75 days. The gains were 20.05 pounds in 40 days. The daily feed consumed was approximately 1 % pounds of corn, 1 pound oil meal, and \ pound of prairie hay per day, and the cost of gains was $7.34 per hundred, which was the highest cost in the experiment. In June, 1916, three hundred Oregon lambs were purchased and run on grass pasture until August 21, when they were divided into eight groups of forty each. The principal object in this experiment was to determine the relative cost and amount of gains made in dry lot compared with grass pasture or feeding off corn in the field. The results of this experiment showed that lambs on grass pasture again made the cheapest gains. These lambs received corn and oil meal during the last three weeks of the experiment. One hundred pounds of gain on grass with grain during the latter part of the period cost $3.55. Where lambs were fed in a dry </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Thirtieth Annual Report 9 lot with a heavy ration of corn, 1% pounds per day, they consumed If pounds of alfalfa hay, their gains costing $7.45 per hundred. Where fed a medium ration of .65 pound of corn per day in a dry lot, they consumed 2.07 pounds of hay and made gains cost - ing $7.43 per hundred. Those on a heavy ration of corn made .331 pound per day against .238 pound for the lambs on a medium ration. Where lambs were used to feed down corn in the field, they made gains at a cost of $5.80 per hundred with a total profit of $2.46 per head compared with a cost of $3.55 per hundred for lambs on grass with a total profit of $1.77 per head, while lambs receiving a heavy ration of corn in a dry lot made a profit of $1.65 and lambs receiving a medium ration in a dry lot made a profit of $1.34 per head. The clipping of lambs increased the gain and decreased the amount of feed per hundred pounds. Clipping also reduced the selling price $1.50 per hundred pounds, which made the undipped lambs more profitable than those which were clipped at the time the feeding experiment began. Previously conducted experiments are reported in Bulletin 153, Lamb Feeding Experiments, 1915. Cattle feeding—Cattle feeding experiments have been carried on for the last seventeen years to determine the most efficient rations in fattening cattle. During this time the following bulletins have been published : No. 75. Feeding Experiments with Cattle and Pigs. 1902. No. 85. Feeding Experiments with Cattle. 1904. No. 90. Cattle Feeding Experiments. 1905. No. 93. Cattle Feeding Experiments. 1906. No. 100. Economical Rations in Beef Production. 1907. No. 116. Economical Beef Production. 1910. No. 117. Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska. 1!)11. No. 132. Beef Production. 1912. No. 143. Feeding Baby Beef. 1914. No. 151. Corn Silage and Alfalfa Hay for Beef Production. 1915. The experiment of 1915-16 was conducted to compare corn and alfalfa hay with corn, alfalfa hay, and silage, and corn, alfalfa hay, and supplementary protein foods. Six lots of cattle were fed. The experiment continued 126 days. The steers weighed an average of 950 pounds at the beginning of the experiment and varied from 1,260 to 1,344 pounds at the close of the experiment. The gain per steer for the 126 days was, for shelled corn and alfalfa hay, 341 pounds; for ground corn and alfalfa hay, 346 pounds; for shelled corn, alfalfa hay, cottonseed meal, 384 pounds; </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 10 for shelled corn, alfalfa hay, cottonseed meal during the last six weeks, 338 pounds; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, and silage, 305 pounds; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, silage first four weeks, Tarkio molasses fed the last fourteen weeks, 352 pounds. The costs of gains were as follows: For shelled corn and alfalfa hay, $10.04; ground corn and alfalfa hay, $10.71; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, and cottonseed meal, $10.38; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, cottonseed meal last six weeks, $10.74; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, silage, $11.44 ; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, silage first four weeks, Tarkio molasses fed last fourteen weeks, $12.12. The pork produced by hogs following these steers varied from 10 pounds per steer on the lot fed ground corn and alfalfa hay to 93 pounds per steer on the lot fed Tarkio feed. The average pork produced per steer was 55 pounds. The net profit per steer, including pork produced, was as follows: Ground corn and alfalfa hay, $11.18; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, and silage, $13.71; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, $14.22; shelled corn, cottonseed meal the last six weeks, $15.16; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, silage first four weeks, Tarkio molasses fed the last fourteen weeks, $15.47; shelled corn, alfalfa hay, and cotton - seed meal, $16.79. All of these cattle gave a good profit and all of the methods used could be recommended under different conditions. The use of ground corn, however, would seldom be profitable where hogs are following cattle in the feed lot. The difference in profit between shelled corn, alfalfa hay, and cottonseed meal, and shelled corn and alfalfa hay is $2.57. Other experiments have not always showed as decided an advantage for the use of cottonseed meal when alfalfa hay is fed as roughage. As a rule the profit from using protein concentrates with corn when alfalfa hay is fed as roughage will increase as the price of corn increases. Where prairie hay, timothy hay, corn stover, silage, and cane must be depended upon for roughage in feeding cattle, protein concentrates should always be more profitable than the use of corn alone as a grain ration. Experiments conducted at many stations, but notably at Illinois some years ago, showed that the protein of the ration might be supplied either in the roughage or in the concentrates and that a fairly definite relation should be maintained. The use of alfalfa hay for roughness in fattening cattle furnishes sufficient protein to supply the bodily wants of the animal's feed and produce economic gains. Increasing the protein con - centrate generally increases somewhat the rate of gain and fre - quently increases the bloom and sale price of the animal. Where this result obtains, the use of such concentrates is profitable. In </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Thirtieth Annual Report 11 general, the large feeder who can buy cottonseed or linseed meal in car lots finds the use of a limited amount of such protein con - centrate advisable. The small feeder who buys in ton lots, paying local freight and retail prices for small quantities of these feeds, may not find them especially profitable. If only a small amount of protein concentrate is to be fed, it should be given during the latter part of the feeding period, since it will stimulate the appetite of the animal, increasing the amount of grain con - sumed and the rate of gain. Men with limited experience in the cattle feeding business frequently have misfortunes in placing their cattle upon feed. These result from the feeding of moldy and improper roughness, too large an amount of grain during the early part of the feeding period, and possibly other causes which cannot be determined without specific information. Wherever difficulty in putting cattle on feed occurs, the use of a protein concentrate will help to correct digestive troubles and should be used in preference to stimulants, stock foods, etc., which are offered upon the market for that purpose. Cow testing associations — Four cow testing associations are organized in Nebraska to assist in determining the production of individual cows in the various herds included in the organizations. Each association includes about twenty-five herds of dairy cattle. The cow tester visits one of these herds each day during the month, making records of the production, butter fat tests, and feed con - sumed by each cow. At the close of the year the records taken show with considerable accuracy the pounds of milk and butter fat produced by each cow and the pounds of feed consumed, so that a debit and credit balance can be made against each cow in the herd. The results of the cow testing associations have been to give the farmer an accurate idea of the value of each cow being tested, enabling him to dispose of such cows as are unprofitable and thereby increase the average profit of the herd. Every farmer is sure to revise his estimate of the value of different cows in his herd after the completion of a year's record. Many cows not before looked upon as especially valuable have shown themselves to be the most profitable in the herd. To illustrate, — a nine - year-old grade Jersey cow tested in the Gage County Association produced last year 8,391 pounds of milk containing 454 pounds of butter fat. Her owner says: "Before I went into the Cow Testing Association I had offered to sell this cow for $50. She is not for sale now, as I value her at many times this price." In the first year's work of the Gage County Association, 40 cows were found unprofitable and sold during the year. The total profit </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 12 to their owners was increased by disposing of these 40 unprofitable cows. Two tables are here inserted, — one to show the individual differences in the ten most profitable and ten least profitable cows; the second to show the average difference in the fifteen best and fifteen poorest cows. Total profit $1,032.88 Total profit $57.82 TABLE 2' — Fifteen best and fifteen poorest cows Total Feed cost Feed cost Lbs. milk Lbs. fat ■ cost per lb. per 100 lbs of feed fat milk One of the cow testers working in a cow testing association in Nebraska reports that after three years the average butter production of the 800 cows in the association has been increased fifty pounds per cow, which at the present price of butter would mean an increase in the profit of approximately $20 per cow com - pared with the condition which existed prior to the organization of the cow testing association. Farm management studies — For the past five years the Experi - ment Station has made each year a survey of the business carried on upon farms in one or more areas in Nebraska, for the purpose of determining what types of farming are most profitable, and also to determine, if possible, how the types of farming which now produce the smallest net revenue or the smallest labor income may 'Quoted from the report of Professor D. H. Propps, Dairy Extension Assistant. Table Ten most profitable cows 1 $123.58 2 166.96 3 108.74 4 108.10 5 104.15 6 96.66 7 95.59 8 94.97 9 92.11 [0 92.02 1 Ten least profitable cows 1 (Loss) $13.73 2 1.62 3 2.84 4 3.85 5 7.10 6 9.09 7 10.27 8 11.14 9 12.07 10 13.57 t 5 best cows . poorest cows 8,555.5 3,105.6 365.4 129.1 &gt;1 l.UV/ 29.58 .229 .101 .952 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Thirtieth Annual Report 13 be modified so as to increase the income from these farms. Nebraska farmers to whom the survey has been explained have nearly all been greatly interested in the project and more than 600 have furnished to us an account of a year's business. An investigation of 200 farms in eastern Nebraska, published as Bulletin 157, "Farm Management Studies in Eastern Ne - braska," led to the following conclusions: 1. In figuring farm profits, the farm must be placed upon the same basis as any other business. 2. The 80-acre grain and stock farm of eastern Nebraska does not utilize man, horse, or machine labor as efficiently as do farms of a larger size. 3. The family farm which provides work for approximately two men or the equivalent seems to be the most profitable. On the farms surveyed, approximately half of the work, aside from that done by the operator, was performed by boys under 21. 4. The best paying farms found in this survey had crop yiejds from 15 to 30 per cent better than the average of all farms, while of the farms whose yields were as much as 15 per cent below the average of their community, few gave satisfactory returns. 5. The most profitable farms included in this survey sold two or three major products and from two to four minor products. Those selling but one or two products were not profitable as they did not furnish productive labor for a large enough part of the year. 6. If 5 per cent interest is allowed upon all capital invested by the operator, owned farms returned an average labor income of $203 and tenant farms an average of $806 to the operator. 7. The better showing made by the tenant farms is largely accounted for by the fact that they returned to the landlord only 3.5 per cent interest upon the land valuation, while the owner-operator is charged 5 per cent upon his valuation. The low rate of return is due primarily to the security of the invest - ment. 8. Owned farms in Richardson county contributed $509, and tenant farms $405 toward the farmer's living, in addition to the "labor income." This is somewhat above the average of farms covered by the survey. 9. Placed upon the same basis as the city wage earner, with interest upon land figured at the landlord's rate of return, tho average farmer of eastern Nebraska receives between $1,000 and $1,200 per year for his labor and management. Marketing farm products — With the improvement in methods of production which has more than quadrupled the efficiency of the American farmer has come a demand for a like improvement </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 14 in methods of marketing farm products. At the present time the farmer feels that the margin between the price which he receives and that which is paid by the ultimate consumer is too large, while the men engaged in distributing these products main - tain that they receive very modest pay for their services. Practi - cally everyone admits that the consumption of fresh fruits, vege - tables, and other of our most wholesome foods is limited by their high retail price, which in its turn limits production. Products such as grain, the wholesale price of which is best known and for which there is an established market, are handled upon a much lower margin than seasonal products for which the retail and wholesale price is less widely known. In part this difference is due to the perishable nature of the products, but possibly in part to inefficiency in the system of distribution employed. In order to determine the factors which enter into the cost of distribution of farm products, the Station has undertaken to collect data from producers, consumers, wholesalers, and retailers. So far, more attention has been given to the marketing of fruits and vegetables from box cars than to any other subject. This information will later be published in bulletin form. The Agricultural College and Experiment Station are ready to give assistance to both groups and individuals regarding the marketing of the products of Nebraska. Winter wheat selections — About three thousand selections of the common Turkey Red wheat have been made at the Nebraska Station and several hundred of these developed to a stage where their yield and quality could be determined. Of the one hundred selections now being carried, three or four promise to be of high economic value. None of these selections are ready to be dis - tributed. An early hybrid wheat — An early hybrid winter wheat, known as Nebraska No. 28, was distributed to be grown by a number of farmers during the past season, in order to determine what special merit it might have under conditions where wheat tends to grow too rank and lodge or rust. This wheat is about ten days earlier than common Turkey Red and has considerably shorter straw. For normal upland conditions it is considered inferior to the common Turkey Red wheat, but, for bottom lands and soil upon which wheat tends to grow too rank, this hybrid wheat is being looked upon with favor. Oat Selections— About one thousand selections of oats have been made in an effort to secure a more desirable oat than the original Kherson importation or the other varieties of early oat now in common use. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Thirtieth Annual Report 15 From these selections we have developed the White Kherson, Nebraska No. 21. This oat during the last five years has pro - duced seven bushels per acre more than the original stock. This is about ten per cent increase, which is sufficient to indicate that the White Kherson oat will be a very valuable addition to our present list of desirable varieties. About eight hundred bushels of this oat were produced at the Station in 1916. Most of this seed is being distributed to farmers for planting in the spring of 1917. Water requirements of crops—The water requirement investi - gations were very satisfactorily continued in 1916. One hundred new potometers were added to the 325 previously in use. The relation of soil, climatic, and crop characters to the use of water by crops was studied. Several of the more important conclusions follow: Transpiration is essentially evaporation. Changes in climatic conditions affect somewhat similarly the rate of water loss from a corn plant and that from a shallow physical free water surface. Variation in the water requirement from day to day is very marked. Occasionally this daily variation amounts to 300 or 400 per cent in successive days. The maximum variation ob - served in two successive days has been 600 per cent. On days of extreme temperature in very dry years there may be an atmospheric demand of 10 pounds of water from a single average corn plant during 24 hours. The greater part of this exists for a period of about seven hours in the driest, hottest period of the day. Such days are exceptional, but they are very critical for corn in case there is not sufficient moisture in the soil to supply the demand. In a comparatively short time the corn may receive injuries from which it never fully recovers. Bearing this in mind it is evident that a period of brief duration may affect yields more than the annual amount of rainfall. A marked variation exists in the water requirement of different years, due to natural climatic differences. There is a rather consistent relationship in the relative seasonal variations between (1) transpiration per unit of dry matter, (2) transpiration per unit of leaf-area, and (3) evaporation from a free water surface. There is no such thing as a definite water requirement which is constant for any one kind of crop. A reduction in soil-moisture content below the optimum dur - ing three years reduced the water requirement per pound of ear corn 4.3 per cent, and per pound of total dry matter 7.9 per cent. This reduction in water requirement was, however, accompanied by 37.3 per cent reduced stalk yield, 28.5 per cent reduced yield of ear corn, and 30.7 per cent lower yield of total dry matter. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 16 It appears that it would be impracticable to lower the soil-mois - ture content intentionally below optimum for the sake of so slight a reduction in the water requirement, because yield is reduced relatively so much more. An increase in the soil-moisture content above the optimum during three years increased the water requirement per pound of ear corn 13.5 per cent, and per pound of total dry matter 8.2 per cent. This increase in water requirement was accompanied by 11.3 per cent reduced stalk yield, 21.1 per cent reduced yield of ear corn, and 16.7 per cent lower yield of total dry matter. The increased water requirement in the production of dry matter is not due to an effort on the part of the plant to get rid of surplus water or to greater ease in obtaining it, but rather to a less thrifty growth due to some detrimental effect from an overabundance of soil moisture, and consequent reduced available fertility. The water requirement per pound of dry matter is much larger in an infertile soil than in a fertile soil. Increasing the fertility of the soil reduces the water requirement for grain pro - duction and for total dry matter. An application of manure has a much greater effect upon an infertile than upon a fertile soil. Thus, as an average for two years, equal applications of sheep manure to infertile, intermediate, and fertile soils reduced the water requirements for ear corn production 42.6 per cent, 25.4 per cent, and 10.5 per cent, respectively. For total dry matter these water requirements were reduced 28.9 per cent, 17.1 per cent, and 8.1 per cent, respectively. However, the total water requirement per plant was increased by an application of manure to infertile, intermediate, and fertile soil respectively 106.7 per cent, 42.6 per cent, and 28.7 per cent. From these figures it is apparent that increasing the fertility does not reduce but rather greatly increases the total amount of water necessary per plant. This is due to increased plant growth. The reduction in water requirement per pound of dry matter is due, not to some effect of a denser soil solution upon the need for a rapid transpiration rate, but rather, simply to a more thrifty and vigorous growth of the plant, resulting from a more favorable supply of food materials. It appears to be more a matter of nutrition than of transpiration. The water requirement for milo was the same as the average for 11 corn varieties, while it was considerably higher for Black Amber sorghum. It appears that the drouth-resistant qualities of certain crops must lie elsewhere than in a markedly low water requirement per pound of dry matter. Competition in cereals Many data have been accumulated upon the relation of size and reserve food of seed to yielding qualities. Small seed compared in equal numbers with large </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Thirtieth Annual Report 17 seed appear to oe at a disadvantage, but when planted in equal weights the yields are practically the same. Twelve years' tests with wheat and oats indicate that the fan - ning mill is no wheat breeder. Its advantageous use may prac - tically be restricted to the removal of trash and weed seeds when present. When grown in competition, plants from large seed have a slight advantage in yield over those from small seed. Crop rotation and fertilizer experiments — The 224 yield test plats included in this investigation were very successfully cropped in 1916. All prescribed treatments were applied and a good crop was harvested. It will take a number of years before conclusions may be drawn from these experiments. A great need exists for similar tests made on soil representing the average eastern Nebraska farm in degree of fertility. Our soil is so productive to begin with that the results may not be applicable to typical farm conditions. Spraying apples — Apple spraying studies were discontinued after the results of 1915 were obtained. The data are being pub - lished as Research Bulletin No. 10. The results show that in spraying for the control of codling moth the petal-fall application, while not in itself sufficient, is by far the most important in the schedule, and, unless this appli - cation is thoro, clean fruit cannot be expected. In controlling plum curculio it was found necessary to make an application of arsenate of lead before the blossoms open, in addition to the regular codling moth schedule, and to supple - ment spraying with summer cultivation. In controlling fungous diseases lime sulphur was found as effective as Bordeaux except in the case of apple blotch. Where serious infections of blotch occurred, it was necessary to use Bordeaux. In orchards where blotch was negligible lime sulphur proved much more desirable as the injury to fruit and foliage was much less than where Bordeaux was used. The use of mist nozzles proved as effective in controlling both insects and fungous diseases as nozzles of the solid stream type and more economical. The cost of spraying varied to a great extent with the capacity of the machine, ranging from about 30 cents a tree for machines operated by hand to as low as 20 cents a tree for the largest type of engine-driven pumps. The average cost for power machines ranged from 20 to 25 cents a tree including labor and material. During the three seasons just past an average of 86.6 per cent of the apples in unsprayed orchards were injured by insects and fungous diseases. Practically all of this injury was prevented where thoro spraying was done. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 18 The average value of fruit in unsprayed orchards, determined by harvesting, grading, and marketing the fruit from average trees in several orchards, was $1.67 per tree. The average value of fruit in sprayed orchards was $7.38 per tree. With spraying costing 24 cents a tree, this leaves a net gain from spraying of $5.47 per tree. Potato disease investigations — For the last three years co - operative experiments have been carried on between the Station and farmers in Scottsbluff County in an effort to develop dis - ease resistant strains of potatoes. Hill selection of seed potatoes — By selecting hills of potatoes during the growing season which are free from all appearance of disease, it has been possible to obtain seed which is practically free from disease and which will reproduce clean seed the follow - ing year. It now seems possible by proper methods of selection to eliminate most of the diseases which we have been unable to control thru treatment. The rotation of potatoes with other crops which will free the land from infection of potato diseases is con - sidered essential. Spraying for blight and wilt is still recommended, but the greatest promise for eliminating disease seems to be along the line of selecting seed when the plants are approaching the maxi - mum growth, and by the rotation of crops to free the soil from infection. The production of seed potatoes in Nebraska for the use of states farther south promises to be a growing industry and awaits only the production of pure varieties of clean seed and the develop - ment of methods of winter storage which will enable our farmers to furnish high quality seed in car lots. This industry has already developed to a considerable volume. Pump irrigation — The last Legislature made an appropria - tion to encourage the development of pump irrigation in western Nebraska. A bill was passed making an appropriation which was available to assist communities in putting down irriga - tion wells under certain conditions. Any community making application for such assistance must agree to pay one-half the original cost of the well, the state paying the other half of the original cost. If the well upon being tested furnishes sufficient amount of water to irrigate the area estimated by the engineer in charge, the community should then reimburse the state for the money invested. This appropriation was placed under the Regents of the University. Under this arrangement a well was dug at Sidney, Nebraska, for the purpose of irrigating a tract of land in the valley adjacent to the town. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Thirtieth Annual Report 19 A well was also dug on the Experiment Station farm at North Platte, Nebraska, where water must be lifted from 40 to 50 feet. As both of these wells were completed late in the season of 1916, they have not yet been tested out to determine their capac - ities. It is expected, however, that the well upon the North Platte Station wilj easily furnish sufficient water to irrigate 40 acres of land. This land will be put under a rotation of crops to determine the crop-producing capacity of such land under irriga - tion and the cost per acre of applying water where it must be lifted 50 feet by a rotary pump. Serum production — At the beginning of the year 1916, a large amount of serum was on hand from the previous year. Some of this serum was tested and ready for distribution, but much of it was still untested, this work being done before its distribution during the early part of the year 1916. Three hundred and six - teen pigs and 38 calves were used in 1916 in testing serum made the previous year. About September 1, 1916, we began to prepare the plant for a fall run and really began operation about October 1, and since then practically all of our 1916 product has been manufactured. The product we have on hand at the present represents about half of the serum we will manufacture from the hogs we now have on the premises; that is, by April 1 we will have 4,000,000 c. c. or more on hand, of which just enough is tested to supply the de - mand until warm weather, when it will be tested on pigs and calves before marketing. The following figures represent what the plant did in 1916 and up to January 25, 1917, inclusive, but a very large per cent represents work done since October 1. 1916. Amount serum produced 1916 1,658,317 c. c. Amount serum produced 1917, to January 25 inc 310,055 c. c. Amount of other serum on hand January 25, 1917 64,350 c. c. Total amount serum on hand January 25, 1917 2,032,722 c. c. Number hogs hyperimmunized 1916 341 hd. Number hogs hyperimmunized 1917 55 hd. Number hogs hyperimmunized that died, in all 18 hd. Number hyperimmunes bled from tail 1916 759 hd. Number hyperimmunes bled from tail 1917 59 hd. Number tinaled at Lincoln Packing House 1916 75 hd. Number tinaled at Lincoln Packing House 1917, to January 25 46 hd. Number hyperimmunes in actual operation January 25, 1917. . 59 hd. Number of hogs admitted to premises 1916 1,741 hd. Number of calves admitted to premises 1916 85 hd. Number immunes on hand for serum purposes January 25 .... 87 hd. Number stock hogs (immune pigs) on hand 48 hd. Number pigs used in testing serum made in 1915 (39 tests) . . . 316 hd. Number calves used in testing same 38 hd. Number pigs used in testing serum 1917 24 hd. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 20 Number calves used in testing serum 1917 6 hd. Number pigs inoculated for virus purposes 1916 952 hd. Number pigs inoculated for virus purposes 1917 130 hd. Number pigs destroyed for virus purposes 1916 720 hd. Number pigs destroyed for virus purposes 1917 110 hd. Amount simultaneous virus produced 1916 164,413 c. c. Amount simultaneous virus produced 1917 8,000 c. c. Amount hypering virus produced 1916 612,680 c. c. Amount hypering virus produced 1917 66,000 c. c. Number calves used in testing virus 1916 38 hd. Number calves used in testing virus 1917 2 hd. Number pigs on hand for virus purposes 168 hd. Number virus pigs condemned on post-mortem 1916 23 hd. Number virus pigs condemned on post-mortem 1917 4 hd. Amount hypenng virus sold to establishment No. 59 14,306 c. c. Amount serum and virus sold during 1916 3,398,828 c. c. At the time the State serum plant was established the pro - duction of commercial serum was still in an experimental stage without Federal supervision or other inspection to guarantee the quality of the serum produced. Since that time large commercial companies have been established, Federal inspection of all plants doing interstate business is required by law, and the volume of serum produced is fully equal to the commercial demand. Well - established plants under Federal inspection will doubtless produce as good a quality of serum as can be produced at a State plant. The Regents have therefore suggested to the Legislature that the energies of the Experiment Station be used in the investigation of animal diseases which menace the live stock production of the State rather than in the production of serum which is now avail - able thru commercial channels. • Poultry work — In 1915, a poujtry plant was established at the College which will also conduct investigation in poultry. feeding and management. At the present time the plant consists of 600 hens, made up of Barred Plymouth Rocks, White Plymouth Rocks, Partridge Plymouth Rocks, White Wyandottes, Partridge Wyandottes, Single and Rose Comb Rhode Island Reds, Single Comb White Leghorns, Single Comb Buff Leghorns, Black Langshans, Light Brahmas, and Anconas. A poultry house has been erected, capable of caring for 600 laying fowls, and sufficient colony houses to care for the chicks which are brooded in these houses during the spring and summer. Four acres of land has been set aside for the poultry plant, and an effort is being made at the present time to purchase six additional acres of land to extend the capacity of the plant. Sales for 1916 #0,972.49 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Thirtieth Annual Report 21 TECHNICAL INVESTIGATIONS The following lines of technical investigation are in progress at the Station. Some of these lines have been carried for a number of years. Adams Projects: No. 2, A Study of the Stem End Rot of the Irish Potato Tuber. No. 3, A Study of Leaf Curl, Leaf Roll, and Rossette and Related Diseases of the Potato Plant. No. 4, A Study of the Life History and Parasitism of Rhizoc - tonia as Related to Irish Potato Diseases. No. 5, The Study of Nummularia Discreta as the Cause of the Blister Canker of Apple. — Its Prevention and Control. No. 6, The Study of the Anatomy of the Potato Plant No. 7, The Water Soluble Constituents of the Soils of the Transition Region. No. 8, A Study of the Chemical Factors Concerned in the Formation of Pigments in Certain Varieties of Corn. No. 9, A Study of the Formation and Persistence of Prussic Acid in Kafirs and Sweet Sorghums. No. 10, Methods of Determining Humus. No. 11, Corn Breeding Experiments. No. 12, Water Requirements of Crops. No. 13, Competition in Cereals. No. 14, Alfalfa Pollination by Insects. No. 15, Food Requirements of Growing Cattle. No. 16, Winterkilling Investigations. No. 17, Heredity Investigation. No. 62, Chemical Studies on Silage. No. 67, The Life-History of Wheat-Infesting Sawflies. No. 69, The Life-History of Several Common Cutworms, Hatch and State Projects : No. 18, Determination of Experimental Error. No. 19, Variety Testing, Breeding, Acclimatization, and Cultural Studies with Small Grains. No. 20, Classification of Oats Varieties. No. 21, Soy Bean Tests. No. 22, Crop Rotation and Fertilizer Experiments. No. 23, Cooperative Fertilizer Tests. No. 24, Soil Moisture Investigations. No. 25, Rodent Investigations. No. 26, Investigation and Control of Injurious Insects, Mam - mals, and Birds. No. 27, Treatment of Illinois or Blister Canker of Apple Trees, No. 28, Spraying Apples, Pears, Grapes, and Bush Fruits </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 22 No. 29, Pruning Apples, Pears, and Small Fruits. No. 30, Principles of Orchard Culture. No. 31, Hill Selection of Potatoes. No. 32, Home Production of Seed Tubers. No. 33, Fruit Breeding. No. 34, Corn Silage vs. Alfalfa Hay as Feeds for Milk Pro - duction. No. 35, Corn Silage vs. Alfalfa Silage as Feeds for Milk Pro - duction. No. 36, A Study of the Soiling System under Nebraska Con - ditions. No. 37, A Co5perative Study of Dairying under Conditions of Western Nebraska. No. 38, A Study of the Underlying Factors Necessary for the Operation of a Successful Cobperative Creamery. No. 39, Factors Affecting the Efficiency of Hand Separators and Causes of Variation in Cream Tests. No. 40, Forage Crops for Hogs. No. 41, Fattening Cattle. No. 42, Farm Survey. No. 48, Farm Survey. No. 44, Handling Silage. No. 46, Hog House Investigations. No. 46, Draft of Wagons. No. 47, Pump Irrigation. No. 48, Nursery and Orchard and Nursery und (ireenhouse Stock Inspection, under State law. k. • ill M • . I . I No. 49, Serum Production. No. 63, The Organic Constituents of Soils. No. 64, Sweet Clover Hay vs. Alfalfa Hay um Feeds Tor Milk Production. No. 66, Rations for Fattening Lumlw. No. 66, A Study of the Efficiency of Various Ty|x* of Creum Cooling Tanks. No. 68, The Relation of the Colloidal Pro|&gt;erlies of (Jluten to Problems of Milling and Making. No, 70, Plant Breeding. No. 71, Umb Feeding. THE NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION Tht North Platte Substation began operation in the soring of 1904. Since that date the Substation has built up and equipped an efficient and substantial plant for carrying out the purposes for which it was twtuhlmhwl. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Thirtieth Annual Report 23 It has contributed its part in gathering accurate knowledge of agricultural problems upon which the science and practice of the agriculture of the future is being founded. As evidence of this we cite the following facts: One entire publication of this Station on Soil Moisture has been translated into a foreign language for use among farmers and in schools in foreign lands. Recent books on various phases of agriculture quote freely from the North Platte Substation bulletins. The leading agricultural papers of the United States frequently refer to results of the work of this Station. The results of work at North Platte are being used more or less in practically every agricultural college in the United States and Canada. Many facts have been demonstrated or emphasized that are of immediate value to the community and region. Some of these facts have been established elsewhere but not heretofore demon - strated in an accurate manner under these conditions. The following brief statements are based on data collected in care - fully conducted experiments. A permanent system of agriculture must be based on live stock in order that the unmarketable products of the soil may return a value and that the effects of drought may be distributed and thus minimized. Weather condition is a greater factor in crop production than method of tillage or variety of crop. The value of extreme dry land methods such as summer tillage for general crop production and unusually intensive cultivation for the inter-tilled crops is questioned if not disproved. Rather extensive systems of farming which permit the maximum of field operations per man are indicated rather than intensive methcxls which depend for profits on maximum yields. Extremely intensive tillage may cost more than it is worth. That is, a part of such labor expended in other ways would bring greater profit*. The source of greatest preventable loss of moisture is the growth of vegetation having no value. The amount of moisture stored under various conditions and its behavior in relation to crops has been definitely determined. Proper tillage of the soil tends to increase the amount of moisture collected and retained in the soil. Fall plowing and spring plowing give practically the same yieW". lxx-al adapted varieties of corn yield better than imported vurieties. Kurly varieties of oats yield better than late variet ie*. Winter wheat yields more than spring wheat. Durum wheat </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nftlv Ayrirultunil hit iinminii Nltitltin nf Nrlmittktt Id nut MNfiwliilly W*ll hiIh|iU&lt;iI In I hi- t'lihilllliifiN, Hum* commiin viiHHIw ylflil a* wdl, Cnmmiifi ll-cnw \mWy ylHil* tnut* lh*fi nlh«»r MmlmiHil .vI«*WIm tn.iM- fi'i-il limit Mill* Wlnii'i wtimec mm«I wlnlw lf»«r-l**y m wHI m wImiw hhIn &lt;im» mil ItMHly. NtlMf Iff III* HHW VltHHI«l (if tfhtlM NllfKltllffiN hNVf |/f«V«l •••I'ffi'" ••• ffutimiift NMt-Mliuiti fur 7(»nuji». Hrt-h fl(lll»WlH|t NM H»ll»!»l(l fillip M«#»-f hlHl H«»M&lt; IflHH »•»»&gt;•« TH0 |&lt;l«('»* MH(l VNJtl** «f «|f«lfM III r-Mf ItfMM f»»f |tf«M« fiHVH f(W{( u«lt«&lt; ilttiHily mImMIihhI. Alw( ih»&lt; vmIiim i»f vnHmiM *h*im«, mill lw*l k M«»l «V«I WH«» Mf MIlHM. I It*" »■»&lt;•! tif m\hw\uh Hhi\ Imhuit H"tf* "|t vHHuim f^l* «♦«»! Ill** |//h||I« f|(ll|l TIlMf MJ^f-HllMMH IlMVC )mvt\ (iMHIfllHWI T i» himltiii *l»l(*HHtf I»H«»I «i** III VHH((II« WM^H MH'I "f J»M»W IHV h» tut Htf liltf Iinv^ Itwii mInnIMikm T *•» N* ft mwum h|»»I fHllwdHn &gt;'Nlflf hh vmhhii* fw&gt;U m/kI 111 nil V »WnMHH»»«i MllllflMl* I Im»I HlfNlfH dl|(l VIMlfl limit If* f*'l IHifhlHMj* Id «liw»|f I)H« lf«f(l (lcill/i/lilfNlC(l l'll|(l||(||«ll«(| fl^lM Till' 'ff MINII if »|(W.-|W ((( IIVIW ||M« •ll)(W/| MlHl «|l||* (KlKIIKfll Mlllf* HIN l((|«llf Mllllllwl f(/l lllMK (.((llfllllKIIII WllilH ((lllMI* m)vk |(i((li|lw iff iwidimiiwiiI miii |//((I|IhI(Ih iwiilln 'nil* *((llf Will MMHi.ll ill fUlliif III* /kImIIhj VMlliM MM'I III (|*l*liiil»illix III* \W»\ l(l*lllll»l fff UlllWlim IIIHII* M/hIh Iff llMfd IH I III* imiUih \mnHHl\W l|l* IMWIIN llMf lIlMWII (llHl lIlWJ* M(* IMM/tf ullllflm uinl Ikwmm wliM'ii mic IimmIv Mini yivif h«c«IImiii mn\\» w\m llHll/lwl IfllfjIMllv I IC MHIlJvil WMll» ||M« (|K)IM/lmlfMlM| lllMl HlMllflll IfDMll* IKIO Im imImIiimI &gt;*illi mihiv Mii'U n\ jMiimi vni^ImM** mimI fixiln wIlMID WlflMI fl(l IMIKH IKII '1 MVMHMMll* A i|nitf |«m«miiImI&gt;« (fKliHid Iim# Kiywii mv'"I Hfld* «/f iflidii* ml i-Iiwi im him mIvm MHtim it! h n\*\n ut »\t\m wIi»h&gt; »h\v &gt;\l* inlll\HiH KlKjIldilo IMV* IfKWIl l((«(.||(wl A llMllV held Iim# l»wfi wl«l(IUl)uil Iff im «• M (|Klii((Kiill»*l|(fii llWIll Iff lllimlmlK lf&gt;'(H'll»'Ml IIIMllddlli (ff f|»ll&gt;llliJ III III* IKKlffjl WlJlMJWII Iff lilfMlMtl'/ll A filnl i:\Htm t\H\iy \iUllt WH* Iflflll, Wllli illOlltir &gt;jlMl|» MllMfflMJ, »ff &lt;lt«l ''"*• (1**11 llfll l(* H*|'l l»l Ml* HI&gt;M« *l»i*|(l l|l((llltf Ml* IMllblllK IfMllKfl Hllfl Wllll* llMllliC l*fl KIMKl "I •|(»&lt;flt»l MfllKII" </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Thirtieth An mini Hv)mrl 25 Hdwlwl nnflvp t-tmn are Iwlfitf ftmpttmi Inr milk iirmliiHlim with |iur»' lirwl llMl«U'|ti e»iW«, Id ilHi'Miiinc IIm&gt; ri'liillvi- ccuiKimv nt iiriiiliiillnii A mmlwn iliilrv wllh ilitlrv i'i|til|iiii»-ii( imil mmipm fnHliiiil* of fwdlhjf iiml «inlni/ fur Mil He iind liiirt'lllhtf milk him iiwfi lh»»Mll«l. Thin 'liilry In Mhx «»|wnl«l ni h |irirflf, iifln \tttf\U* fur nil feed, liilidf, nidi II immiiml |iiIm- tnf I he IIH I nf Die flitlry |iln»ii Ah iniiiMiiiiii idiiiii nf xfiiiiii c»i|(Miliv Inn («&lt;».ii in u**&gt; tut imi y»-nri tuilHtf |iM'|lmlfiii»-v wdik in -u r 'f ''"""■"'"' v Irrlxiillnn A IrtMT^ |&lt;WM&lt; mwJ? ''"■ o|*Hilli»»i h«*»* wf^lh^ will ilxmnhNiMiii. Mil. l»Mt»'ilH»Mlljv i»f |iimi|ilM« *nlw- tut ntHijtiMmmhrir \rr\tu\um lit Ik him m, !»MT ( 1 1«. ton, hnilumhir, |aa i^imMMl/; '//&lt; 'wk n&lt; umliwl!, iiuhHiiin, mmm WhW, H/&lt; hu *ti**u*t *n**mnm \Uh \m\m [)tm nl mirk mtiiwiwi hi \U» Vh\»MUw Huh iL twit,!, \m\mj mMwUf luihut m nt iHiihiiw in mm' h/mI * p#k nuii* mn»i »iti\nh\n hi} Hiimlitu n on, *HHi\i&gt; \m\ In »miwml Ih nnlh» \W[W» nml n/lHttH &lt; Inn wiiitim*, MwHh, mmj) »)»«», nmi k\hm hn*» nil hmi tmmn hh h^ uknlt hi i\w Vnmiiinn mnim i m »Mnw l» \mn «• m ml nl m timM mnnn Un lli» i|hIU nun! H" 'IwitlHlf In HUM \mu ml III wMiih &gt;&lt;nlhilinl mm (hi •!l«w A*j « '«0//f '"' 'W'* »-MiM#* 11/ I Id* ii^/ U ), tilnu,, L (l . i" imifiitummi 'Vlixix iKdj* liwf ihIIwhih itnmii hmJ wiw h mi\f» wt &gt;""' "l'"lf« liHf »«" n^iiIhM). mi 4 1 /'/ ♦»&gt; i/w I/*// i«i / rtwfc, /(w iimlHrlftiii in mini Im nlhun mmm itnihiltl* m i» innmnii\», n*tinilHl\v It HlNltn I'milil \w inniliiiwl m ntl\\,.i» ,t ififiHiiHiM hi \nnilMt urn liilHi ill ilin iinttihHn* iimumiik Im / i« 'I ll// «/l/Wll/ Ml MW#tMM l» IIMX &lt;rf Mw ICMdlOM UtiUlMlk* Hi \h* Hnwl lllll» iniumi Hi LiuM)i* lim in ih» ihmwiI In &gt;i ihinn n&gt;,, i»*i fiimuiHn hi IWIff, \m lilMi i h\i\i\»i imlHlii wn» »imni\m u, »ll nhiM* \u»\m\ In l\it&gt; ym Hf\jh h hm mnvlt/llw k(, t ,,,i h 'I IhkiiIiiwI, »iM) viwMw) Ibn ln»[i( inniM tiy lUm iin»iinU im u,:^ A* Im Mtmii wh* inline rnuliU' Im k»wl* nl millwi nl l)inw </seg>
            <seg id="p026">mvi Atftimllutiil Mtimlmml MHMiiii nf Svhtiitlm vwm/m *w &gt;i|&lt; in Mfmil, .'»&gt;.(♦** wtoy ttminmi H\,h Idi.hxl* itftf aw* hh&lt;) Ihh m»li roMik tffft l-i/.Ul. wliile Hie frill jj ' 'Ml" |l»Ol|ll»-*d ((III Illl l|ll»ll*l« |)W M&lt;&lt;l* Til* •'♦I'*""""" 1 " *l lh "ll(llll*l| ilOlMlOM hit HlC frl'MI HO'I MtfMlll |&lt;M'VW| ill* •&lt;l|l*lll II II* ,,f llil. IwriluNJ IM «/-^l/^ |(MlMlOM [m^iow r»y wfWlMtf ihf mnnI &lt;"i im* •"'&lt; mm&lt;I WMritiMK wlfh n &lt;l(*l» llttMH* M&gt; ' Ml* Idfllliwl &gt;'«l »'I*»VW )'MIM* (01 in I WO yUMhl m» hi ill iWHUW* M M'«"' •IpWI 1(1 &lt;M« )IMllV« MCNM, Mw««l n\n*U) iUi{ iihI •Im»w k|' vt»&gt; M'fM null! MHO wliioi II \m*\m wm\ mImIiIihIiw) III lilK ((MlfVK (&lt;fM&lt;Ni Wllll'll WDl ('Ml Ml mwU I Imp M I" MMVf lll« •WK«I ('llfVKf Millifl Until lIlMIHllVtftfMHMllMV l / !»|/«»(ll»ll«llU l&lt;( III Him*' ill*' *W«p I HoVKI III tlMllVM Mf'MM IMKM(|l(W* Will )m&lt; mill llllW'l Wlill*«Hi«'MKcf&gt;'MMl&lt;&gt;liMM&lt;»lrv Hi UikMhimI !llll» ivututi \» iimicIi IIM(|K K»l»»ll»IV»« UlMII lIlK (ImIIV IIMlimllV I IlK (|mI|&gt; llUlli Will ll»' i((lllll(l»»«l M« M (IWIM&gt;»l»f»MMMll Ill'Ml hi lIlll.llMl*' IMKIIuhI* witl«'ll (mii lix iimnI hy ll^ KliiMl'f jummim im In \iiiuUn \ny h iiin«Ii»miim imwiimk mii m liiMliw! urm in ImikI MkIIhiii \M cmii \m Iih/I m|&gt;oii Hf(|(ll''Mll'"l I" til" K»»IK(I( | Mir .N/IKKIlll .I'B.MIlnl, Tli* wtrt'h nf Hi* HtinH*h\\ift KniwriiMniiiMl MuIwImHoii &lt; mkiwI (III III C(/l&gt;|(WMllMII Wllll lll« I'llHKl MlMlM r&gt;K|(MIIIIII&lt;l|l ((f A«ll ( till di* mm* ('(iiiilimwl mIoiiu ill* mm I mm m« liirnwrly IniKMiioii lolMlKdi W(»/fc mikI d»&gt; ImikI (kImiI(«(i uikI nli.it/c work »IMV»» Imwm «.»«IJmh*«I MIC (Iwvolwl Id IKlMlKdl *I|(W'|MM&lt;MU III ilTlMMli((ll Kldll ffil\m mic umm! iii lit* mi#lij»M#, T»*f* Mr* mIm* |»ImI» i\twAm\ Ui mm I|||M((I»» (I((I&gt;|&gt;IMK "W« Mr* MlM( *I*V*II j&lt;/*MI IMlMl !((((«, Him-.. (( v*«r roiMl «»»»•, few' 4&gt;*Mr (dlMlKdi*, mikI four 'I ymi roiuiium T'l K |«(l !»»»&lt;• "' III**, liMIHXd'l liiMKiiic U M|/|/|UN| |(C(M«l|('Mlly Ml ilm I'm I* of iy i"ii» |(*&gt; MJ&lt;i'* In ill* il y*Mi ikImiiooii, on* Irnlr lli* ImikI )• III u\ln\k mu&gt;\\ y«w. 1 1 wm« uliowii iIimI iin\m an itmml ImikI •tm*i &gt; iiioi* ««v*r*ly '""" *i'k'»'"'"i» Kimii K|»((ii fMll |d((WM(| lu ii&lt; I AKmIIm muM im mi niulilil* in lit* full yi*l(U mw'h nutr* i lie mlliiwli|tf immtu Kimii wIikii mnmImI nu/md Im lit* »|»iIiim TIi* r*»MhiMl *&lt;t*»'U iff MlfMlfit m|iom mii'i'*wlliiti «ro|w In v*ry UncltclMl under IitIhmImiIi, IiicikmaIiik Him yl#ld Im *(iiw» IiihImik wi mi IcmhI M |M»r wni AlfidlM |»mkIii»c will) m mi|/|/lciiiiiiilMiv ((/ill I Ml Ion iiimMk* mii hIi'mI i mi loll l"i Itottn, WIm'I «&lt; Uuy* w*r* red H,IHHl |imilld» nl rum, </seg>
            <seg id="p027">TlmiMli AhuhuI lh,m,i 27 Iliw itmiumi HMt \mmiU nt tinri* twin nun nt nil, ill &gt;i \m\MU mill Inn *HMlWI*ltlHHt fHHllH f« Hiiuill yninm '('!»« H\mUmin\ witrk with /himH min* wm&gt; umiiwimi hi mM* i«*»u wiilj *\im* »lmt, IwW, ttwi wl» Hini hi h lw* iif Ihn Hiiml iltHtUHhiv I Hit* jut *»w\\nu Tlin How nf wuttum tmtt wM It iI/mw* i(i«i v^'lf MwdMiy, hum Mmh p In Km \\, pnv« liltfU H"M» I»)H(» lH/«f TMMf of mw'IMik l«»l« will) with U&gt;i\\nt)wl l\ml Mi H4\*hiiIhk» rmt\\m\ limn ti\niitinu mlim limn Mm* in HhiIhik uIhiiIIHv \mi**n tmilm lhnn fimniiim will* m U*Im I'ultiloM Hn*nuimi *hi\vI\v* w«* Iwiiwl, #^#«» /lfl/l« Miyinn I runt IW4 &gt;/»&lt;ft(H«lii »(» Oft i^niwl* |w *m'^, 'H»»» hl*li i'ii\ih\»i AHtiiiit, mill VimitjfM wm ih» Him imium wnviiu* ami Muf/ui ml* '\m miMtfi iml win* w«« limiimi In ihiuhHhu umi I'uiium inviUwi* HmHim nn\n*ntinn ifmm nun hi&gt;i\ nun mil Ui Iwn [\w\mi \imw\ «• \u»uunm\ »* i\mm mmsHiUM Al fulfil Tito tm nf imtiurf Univumi Ihn *Mi\ ul hIIhiIh nun Hiul minimi! Inti* fiui uw* \itylliiw\nv With H •l/fM/K Innlh lim nm fill i\iWH tit* ti»\i\ nun \iu\f inn \mi mm lh»hnu fill linwn i)m i/Mi\ nm urn \mr mn, tIm» v\nm *mm\ Imm f'lh in H ill tuna \mr m* wild ililiwvni *m)uI\*», t'lMiuiv yum* null Iihiiuiwh rniml I'ln^m \mi*w\ l\\* \»niliuti uHtUtyn ifium (nr i\u)ry imllin. tn iinmmml)** Im»i«, \\M hum* in m\%m ur**** funiituwi \mMwu Uh iw i&gt;n* i!«m, hiu) M mn nf tmmti fin^ff (um»Um\ umIm* Im ft* in* i(mv» t'lmn in\» \m»\», H.Hl Hum nl mm! i'\nvw wnniii Imv* ftmti»mi imlitiv mi inmiiHVf! huh\uM \Wi mm-iki/* hie m\m\ vih**» I, iiv Hliii'k imifk Tim llv* »t4H'h wnn wh* \iin)im\ in Imv, »Utm\i, hi\i\ imrv mw», \l\ n%\i¥fUnni\lHI *nrU ifaiiwt Ihnmnn mm nf M/MI, 'Ml unm nf \iuu» *wu \tH»Uim\ U»\mil» nl lhl» *wU uix \m)imm\ \u (UmnlUiHn I/W hi mutt Immwmt wlw* \um» w*r* uH*uirm\, mm\ nr \iHr\ny wm M h» h *imi\wunuiu\ Hi h\ii ruWnu llwtv/ nit Inn* n( ym)u umvo Ihiumi VmiU unr Ht'fn iiml iuiunr Inlm \mm\ , nun tu'i'u ni uiJuilu, will* m '/ In \\ iw t&gt;*til mm rnl Uiiihmh wtnimml , hirnMwii uhbI urn Im I w»my 7ft \umi\ I»im» ifitjn Muy I \*i hi\y I inn mmn uivu wliii Ihn mim umin luium fuinwiwl imtturn fiir furiy Hh nnunii |&gt;l«w I mm hiivi nil ihu i&gt;\imf in Ihv m&gt;umm KfnMilfltf I'ig* mi *\(»Hu |/M«&lt;t/»»' MU'i m /i»ii mii^n "i "&lt;»». </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Ayricutturul Ksinrimint Slulinn uj Sebruuku 28 required Uhh pound* of corn per 100 pound* of gain. When linihhwi in a dry lot, nimilar pig* required 515 pound* of corn per 100 pound* of gain. Where hog* were lined to pasture down corn, it required 446 pound* of corn, estimated weight, to produce 100 pounds of gain. Sheep /fed ing Ten lot# of sheep were fed at the Station on ditrerent rations to determine the value of by-product* of the beet-sugar factory when fed with alfalfa hay. THE STATION STAFF Within the past year the following changes in the Station staff have taken "place: Mr. Frank C. Dean, Agricultural Editor, resigned, effective September 1, 1916. Mr. C. A. Helm, Assistant Professor of Experimental Agron - omy, resigned, effective September 1, 1916. Miss Florence A. McCormick, Assistant in Agricultural Botany, resigned, effective September 1, 1916. Mr. H. E. Vasey, Assistant in Agricultural Botany, resigned, effective September 1, 1916. Mr. C. B. Lee, Associate Professor of Animal Husbandry, resigned, effective November 1, 1916. Mr. Fritz Knorr, Superintendent of the Scottsbluff Experi - mental Substation, resigned, effective January 1, 1917. Mr. H. A. McComb, Horticulturist of the North Platte Experi - mental Substation, resigned, effective February 1, 1917. Mr. W. W. Burr was appointed Head of the Department of Agronomy, effective July 1, 1916. Mr. Floyd Wambeam was appointed Agricultural Editor, effective September 1, 1916. Mr. F. M. Colcord was appointed Assistant in Dairy Hus - bandry, effective February 1, 1917. Mr. James A. Holden has been appointed Superintendent of the Scottsbluff Experimental Substation, effective March 1, 1917. IMPROVEMENTS Dairy Industry Hall—The new Dairy Industry Hall recently dedicated is built with gray brick exterior and fireproof thruout. It has terrazzo floors in the halls and laboratories, the stairways being of steel and slate. The walls of the first floor of the build - ing are glazed brick, the floors being red tile laid in cement. Above the first floor the walls and ceilings are plastered. All laboratories are furnished with water and gas. The building is well lighted thruout. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Tlntinih Annual lir/iorl 29 The mam building i* 140 feet long by 84 faet wide, Hire* hiiwiw* high, with a full basement. A wing 60 by 70 f«*i, ont* story hign with basement, x&gt; attached. This annex will be used for practical butter making, ic« cream making, and handling market milk. There are room* also for refrigeration and for the vale of dairy product*. On the firwi floor of the main building are laboratories for butter making, cheese making, market milk, ice cream making, and farm dairying. These laboratories are equipped with the latest machinery and are constructed in the most sanitary manner. On the second floor are the main offices with library and read - ing room, lavatories, a milk testing laboratory equipped to accomodate seventy-two students, an official testing laboratory, rooms for experimental work, and supply rooms. Two class - rooms also occupy this floor. The third floor contains dairy bacteriology laboratories, an auditorium seating 250 persons, and classrooms and offices which are temporarily assigned to work in Field Crops. In the basement a modern refrigerating plant is installed which supplies ample cold storage facilities for use in connection with the departmental work and additional cold storage facilities for other departments. Facilities are also provided in the base - ment for student locker rooms, lavatories, rest rooms, etc. The facilities provided in this building make it possible for Nebraska to offer thoroly up-to-date instruction in all branches of the dairy industry. Agricultural Engineering Hall Agricultural Engineering Hall, plans for which were completed during the year, was advertised for bids twice during the year 1916, but on account of the advance in cost of materials and labor both of these bids were rejected by the Regents in the hope that more favorable building conditions would obtain during the year 1917. It is expected that bids for the erection of this building will be asked for in the near future and a contract let for the construction of the building. PUBLICATIONS The publications of the Station since those named in the last Annual Report are as follows: Twenty-ninth Annual Report. Presented to the Governor February 1, 1916. 5,000 copies. Bulletin No. 157 (Volume XXIX, Article I.) Farm Manage - ment Studies in Eastern Nebraska. By H. C. Filley. Distrib - uted October 15, 1916. 17,000 copies. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 30 Bulletin No. 158 (Volume XXIX, Article II) (Popular Edi - tion of Research Bulletin No. 10). Why, When, and How to to Spray. By J. Ralph Cooper. (In press.) 20,000 copies. Bulletin No. 159 (Volume XXIX, Article III). Pork Pro - duction on Irrigated Lands in Western Nebraska. By James A. Holden. (In press.) 12,000 copies. Research Bulletin No. 8. The Colloidal Swelling of Wheat Gluten in Relation to Milling and Baking. By F. W. Upson and J. W. Calvin. Distributed June 30, 1916. 5,000 copies. Research Bulletin No. 9. A Physiological Study of Two Strains of Fusarium in Their Causal Relation to Tuber Rot and Wilt of Potato. By Geo. K. K. Link. Distributed September 15, 1916. 500 copies. Research Bulletin No. 10. Spraying Experiments in Nebraska. By J. Ralph Cooper. (In press.) 4,000 copies. Circular No. 1. Measuring Silage and the Capacity of Silos. By L. W. Chase. (In press.) 12,000 copies. Circular No. 2. Pump Irrigation in Nebraska. By E. E. Brackett and 0. W. Sjogren. (In press.) 12,000 copies. Extension Bulletins of the College of Agriculture Extension Bulletin No. 37. Short Courses, or Extension Schools in Agriculture and Home Economics. By C. W. Pugsley and P. L. Gaddis. Distributed June 15, 1916. 10,000 copies. Extension Bulletin No. 38. The Marketing of Mixed Grains. By H. C. Filley and P. L. Gaddis. Distributed August 15, 1916. 10,000 copies. Extension Bulletin No. 39. Pit, Semi-pit, and Bank Silos. By L. W. Chase. (In press.) 10,000 copies. Extension Bulletin No. 40. Wooden Silos Used in Nebraska. By L. W. Chase and Ivan D. Wood. (In press.) 10,000 copies. Extension Bulletin No. 41. The Farm Inventory. By H. F. Williams. (In press.) 5,000 copies. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The agricultural press and the daily and weekly newspapers, especially those papers located within the State, have shown their appreciation of the work of the Experiment Station by giving liberal space to experimental work reported and in every way facilitating the extension of useful agricultural knowledge. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Thirtieth Annual Report 31 ANNUAL REPORT AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION SERVICE Extension work in Nebraska is carried on by the Extension Service of the Nebraska College of Agriculture in cooperation with the United States Department of Agriculture and local organizations of farmers and farm women. During 1916 the following lines of Extension work have been conducted: County agent work Agricultural agents Home economics agents Women's extension work Short courses Women's institutes Special meetings Women's club work Home demonstration work Junior extension work Junior short courses Junior institutes Special junior meetings Boys' and Girls' club project Calf-raising project Chicken-raising project Corn project Egg-producing project Home-garden project Home-school garden project Pig-raising project Potato project Sewing project Sow-and-litter project Agricultural and home economics meetings Short courses Farmers' institutes Special meetings Exhibits State exhibits County exhibits Special exhibits News service Extension bulletins Special circulars News service for county press Daily news service Service for agricultural papers Extension specialists Agricultural engineering Animal husbandry Agronomy Dairy Farm management Horticulture </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 32 It is the general policy of the Extension Service to send workers to a community, provided expenses are paid by the people of the locality. The Service pays the salary of the workers and furnishes necessary apparatus and equipment for the work. During 1916 the following money was available for Extension work. Federal Smith-Lever funds State funds by appropriation $29,645.80 25,000.00 18.000.00 Contributions by United States Department of Agriculture Total $72,645.80 In addition to this, much was contributed from localities for farmers' institute, extension school, boys' and girls' club, and demonstration expenses. In administering the work, it has been the policy of the Exten - sion Service to conduct at the central Extension offices all ad - ministrative correspondence. The correspondence of specialists, except in the case of the home economics work, has been largely conducted in the special departments, and is not included in the following statement of work done by the Extension stenographic force. The following is the report of the office work during the past year: Personal letters typed 26,634 Pages typed 35,356 Duplicated letters sent 390,841 Multigraph pages printed 402,325 Mimeograph pages printed 722,520 It has so far been the custom of the Extension Service to take care of a large part of the special duplicating needed by the county agents. The Extension office is equipped with duplicating machines and with folding and stapling machines, and it is there - fore in position to do duplicating work quickly and cheaply. It has been impossible, however, to handle all of the work really needed by Extension workers. THE EXTENSION FORCE The Extension force now consists of 39 persons employed full time, and 16 employed part time. In spite of the fact that this force is kept constantly busy and that the faculty of the College of Agriculture and the force of the Experiment Station devote a considerable amount of time to the Extension work, it has been impossible to supply all of the demand for Extension workers. It was impossible to aid many places which asked for meetings </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Thirtieth Annual Report 33 during the last year, and the special demonstration work both in agriculture and home economics should be greatly extended. Following is a list of the Extension workers for 1916. Others were employed for special lectures and demonstrations. C. W. Pugsley, Director Extension Service A. E. Anderson, State leader County Agent Work 'Huldah Peterson, State leader Boys' and Girls' Clubs 'Frank Dean, Agricultural editor (4 7 time Extension) Floyd Wambeam, Agricultural Editor (j time Extension R. E. Bothwell, Farmers' Institute and Voucher Clerk H. C. Filley, Professor Farm Management ipart time) W. W. Burr, Professor Agronomy (part time) R. F. Howard, Professor Horticulture (part time Maud Wilson, Assistant Professor Home Economics (Extension) I. D. Wood, Assistant Professor Agricultural Engineering (Extension I P. L. Gaddis, Assistant Professor Agronomy (Extension) Kenneth Warner, Assistant Professor Animal Husbandry (Extension) D. H. Propps, Assistant Professor Dairy Husbandry (Extension) E. H. Hoppert, Assistant Professor Horticulture (Extension) H. F. Williams, Assistant Professor Farm Management (Extension) R. R. Spafford, Assistant Professor Farm Management (Extension) Mary Rokahr, Instructor Home Economics i Extension) Emma F. Ort, Instructor Home Economics (Extension) Aural Scott, Instructor Home Economics (Extension) Louise Meredith, Instructor Home Economics (Extension) L. T. Skinner, Assistant Boys' and Girls' Clubs J. G. McMillan, Assistant Boys' and Girls' Clubs I pig clubs C. W. Watson, Assistant Boys' and Girls' Clubs J. F. Hendricks, Assistant Farm Management Leo F. McShane, Assistant in Gardening Work L. B. Rist, County Agricultural Supervisor 'O. H. Liebers, Agent, Gage County C. E. Gunnels, Agent, Seward County Geo. O. Unruh, Agent, Thurston County A. H. Beckhoff, Agent, Dakota County A. G. George, Agent, Madison County R. E. Holland, Agent, Kimball County F. M. Seidell, Agent, Boxbutte County A. C. North, Agent, Sheridan County R. H. Camp, Agent, Thurston County Marie L. Hartwig, Head Stenographer W. H. Vining, In charge duplicating department Gertrude Taylor, Stenographer Eula M. Anderson, Stenographer Amelia Wekesser, Stenographer Mary Clark, Stenographer 'T. H. Ashton, Statistical clerk &lt;D. F. DeTar, Clerical assistant L. C. McNeal, Clerical assistant Leo H listed, Clerical assistant 'Resigned </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska During the year past the following meetings have been held with a total attendance of 205,663 at all sessions. Report of Extension meetings — 1916 Number Aggregate - t A T 1 !J!| a *V of sessions attendance !"™1"?« Meetings held per session 15 combined short courses Men's sessions Women's sessions .... Evening sessions 258 13,365 52 116 3,919 :!6 120 5,479 49 3,967 22 ISO 121 farmers' institutes 325 36,792 11. -i Men's sessions 114 9,836 M Women's sessions Evening sessions 115 9,742 u 175 9fi 17,214 60 special meetings (estimated i l Total aggregate attendance HO 3,000 53,157 50 The following meetings were also held County agent meetings 977 Attendance ... 33,479 Junior workers' meetings. . . 642 .... 36,650 Home economics meetings. . 530 " .... 35,648 County fair attendance at exhibits 46,829 Total 152,506 Total attendance at all meetinp 205,662 The doti show the locations of various Extension activities as described In this report. The counties with stars have county agents. So many meetings and demonstrations were held in these counties that they could not be shown by dots on so small a map ■Special meetings include Farmers' Union and Grange meetings, schoolhouse, and specially arranged country meetings but not conventions or other city meetings. They are of the nature of institutes, but more specialized. This does not include people met by specialists in their demonstration work or the personal work of county agents and other extension workers. Neither does it include those reached by correspondence or thru circulars, bulletins, and special lessons. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Thirtieth Annual Report 35 COUNTY AGENT WORK County agent work is now in its fourth year. During 1916 the following nine counties had agents: Boxbutte, Dakota, Dawes, Kimball, Madison, Seward, Gage, Sheridan, and Thurston. In addition ten counties have made application for funds to assist in employing county agents. The county fanners' associations, thru their boards of direc - tors, in conference with the county agent and the county agent leader, selected definite lines of work at the beginning of the year. The principal projects were as follows: Hog cholera control and eradication Farm management record work Potato improvement work Corn improvement work Oat smut eradication Boys' and girls' club work Live stock feeding Home economics work Orchard renovation and improvement Marketing problems In addition, considerable work was done in other lines of agri - culture as occasion demanded. In hog cholera control and eradication work, it is the aim of the county agent to give demonstrations and explanations of the use of serum and virus and to teach farmers how to use them. The results this year show that where serum is used in time there is less than one per cent loss of animals. In the counties where county agents have done work, there have been only three cases which spread from the original source of infection after the county agent was advised of the outbreak. All of the counties have undertaken farm management demon - stration work, and a large number of farmers are cooperating in the keeping of special farm record books, which have been distrib - uted to them free of cost. These farm account books will be assembled and summarized by the county agent and the farm management specialist. A number of cooperators in a potato improvement project were obtained in the four western counties. The following table shows the counties with the number of cooperators, the yield on the plats where the usual method was practiced, the yield on the flats where the new method was used, and the increased yield, n addition, the potatoes from the demonstration plats were free from scab and of better quality. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Agricultural Experiment Station uj Nebraska UhiiI method Incresied yield Coopewtoni Sheridan county 11 89 101 12 Dbwm county 11 92.1 97.6 5.6 Roxhutte county 6 76 86.9 10.9 Klmbill county 4 28.6 An ever increaaing amount of the county agent's time is occupied with problems of marketing. During the last year the county agenti in western Nebraska in cooperation with the Office of Markets and Rural Organization of the United States Depart - ment of Agriculture detailed a man to furnish to the potato growers of western Nebraska a daily market bulletin, giving the shipments of potatoes, the prices paid at the potato buying centers, and the prices paid locally. At the time the first potato service was sent to 2,000 growers on September 21, the local price of potatoes at Hemingford was 60 cents a bushel, while the price paid at Omaha was $1.10. Within three weeks the price at Hemingford had increased to over 90 cents a bushel, while the price in Omaha remained practically the same. The potato growers estimate that they have profited by 1260,000 because of the market news service. Over 700 letters nave been received from the growers commending the work. The agents u*»int in organizing cooperative associations and furnish market information on all classes of farm products. Each county farm bureau maintains a farmers' exchange where residents of the county may list anything they have for sale or articles desired. During the year these exchanges resulted in the direct sale of over $60,000 worth of live stock, seed, and grain. The exchanges also placed 164 farm laborers. The oat smut control work which was started three years ago in (iage and Seward counties has resulted in an entire change of practice among the farmers. At the beginning of the work nobody could be found who was treating oats for smut. Now it in exlimuted that from HO per rent to 90 per cent of the farmers are using the formalin treatment for oat smut control. Thjs estimate is based on the amount of formalin sold for this purpose in the county. The following are the average yield increases secured in plats during the last year: County Incrested yield (bu»h«li) Hhtrldsn 6.2 Dswea 4.6 ThumtiiTi 8 Boxhutta 8.6 Klmlmll 8.6 Mn.liw.ri 8 Dftkots 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Thirtieth Annual HtjHirl 37 In cooperation with the Extension specialist in animal hus - bandry, a number of the county agent* took up demonstrations in the use of self-feeders for fattening hogs. These demonstrations have proved very popular in some of the counties, and it it honed to make live stock feeding one of the major projects in several of the counties next year. In Madison county on one of the demon - stration farms, the cost of 100 pounds pain was $5.19 for the self - fed lot and $5.50 for the hand-fed lot. Four other farmers carried on similar demonstrations with practically the name results. Dur - ing the time of demonstrations several meetings were held, and in addition one field trip was taken by 12 farmers who visited all of these herds in one day. In Gage county, 3 such demonstrations were conducted, and pigs from both the demonstration lot and the pig lot were shown at the county fair. Results from these demonstrations have not been tabulated as yet. In Seward county, 5 farmers undertook feeding demonstra - tions. On one of these farms, the cost per hundred pounds gain on the self-fed lot was $4.85 and on the hand-fed lot, $6.83. Other reports not yet available. A pocket gopher eradication project was undertaken, partic - ularly in (iage county, because of the estimated annual damage of $75,000 to $100,000 each year. One entire township formed a pocket gopher extermination club to work on this project exclusively. Every n an in the township undertook to follow out definite regulations with regard to poisoning and trapping. Eight other areas ranging from a school district to an entire town - ship undertook similar organization and work, tho not as definitely organized as the Blakely township area which was considered the demonstration area of the county. This campaign did not com - pletely eradicate the gopher, but the results were very valuable and the estimate of farmers in that township shows that the pest was decreased by at least 75 per cent. This work will be con - tinued next year in (iage county, and also taken up in a number of other eastern Nebraska counties. Orchard pruning and spraying was undertaken in a number of the counties by the county agent, assisted by the Extension specialists in horticulture. In Seward county, 9 pruning demon - strations were held early in the spring attended by 65 people. Five demonstration orchards were cared for in as many different communities where trees were sprayed at the proper time. The fruit from these orchards was exhibited at the county fair and attracted a great deal of attention. Five orchard demonstrations were also carried on in Dakota county with similar results. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Agricultural Rrprrimrnl Station of Srhmnka Km Improvement along dairy lines, the county agent* In co« nii'ifiiimi with the Kxu-imiiiii *i&gt;*&gt;r in I 1*1 In dairying have been iimiriiMwiiinl In Importing |wr»&lt; lir»-&lt;l ami lnuli«nuli' dairy cow* from Wiwotmin ami Ohio. In (imp county, u total of I III llnlstelns have been brought In during the pant year, Hlxty-flve of these were nure«bred cows, IN having Advanced K*»ui*irv rwnrdu, In audition, In Oage county a cow imiiitK association lm» l&gt;een formetl with too cow* on i »&lt;*i*, Knur yearn w&gt; there were only two purebred cown In Oage county, At the present time, there are over SMM) pure-bred cown on 'in different farm* In the cimnty. In Hherldan count, v two carloadH of dairy cattle were brouuhl In for distribution amonK the farmers, The Name wa» done in Dmmi county. Karly in the mr MIhm Maud Wllwm, head of the home economic*! KmenHiiin work, undertook to do home demoriHtration w&lt;»rk four dayit each month with four different vrouiw of women In MadJMin county, In the 7 month* during wnlch »he did HiIh work, there were W meelinKH held with a total attendance of (M)A women, In iwiiiitiun one home demonstration auunnobile tour wax taken In the county, which wan attended by 2A0 peoiile, liural women 'h short courses were held In Thurslon, Imkota, and Heward counties, either at school houses or in farm homes, Those were well attended and well received, They will be con - tinued next year, Heward county this fall undertook to secure a home demon - stration agent, I'onseo.uently, the women oruanixed an associa - tion with a #2 membership fee and secured aid from the United HUtex Department of Agriculture for that pur|&gt;ose, MIm Ksther Warner was employed as woman county agent on November 1, IWlli'ully all of the count y ukuiiu uMisLed In I he boy*' und girli' club work carried on In their respective counties, Ktt*uli» art not yet at hand with the exception of Home potato work and pig club work, In the western counties, the potato club boys nave more than doubled the average potato yield in the county, In the pig club work, some of the boys have made unusually good gains on their pigs and a good profit, In Madison county, a junior short course was held in connection with the work, Numerous other lines of work were carried on in the various counties which have added a great deal to the general agricultural Improvement work, with the betterment of rural conditions. Farmers' institutes and farmers' meetings of various kinds have been held in all of the counties. In a number of Instances, a scheduled series of country farmers' Institutes has been held with unusually good success, In practically all of the counties, </seg>
            <seg id="p039">ThirtU&gt;th Annual HrfHiTl 39 it number of automobile lour* have )»&lt;*&gt;n taken io «indy *ome fHiiiirPD of Npedal HlKnlflcnncv to the people of the county, Thin v«'nr the vnrimm detmrtmenl* or the agricultural mMw hnvp given a mo*t hwiri y *upt»ort to county agent*. The Kxt*&gt;n - hIuii n|m&gt;HhII»in In every cmw mmvp devoted their time «nd energy lowttrd iiMUiiiiK the county MitenlM In their vhHouh (trojecln, 'l'li»' Kxt«n»lon h|&gt;i«'IhII»Im ur* kIvIiik l)r«i confederation to county uttvnU In outlining their Kxtennlon work. Siimimiru nf fimtilu Agttil Work fur Witt riimii' i'«|t» "ltd i. i mII&gt; I'ufin. vl«lli«l 11 #H«f» wrllloti MOV I'lri'iilnr Ittllwm m&lt;mI K,«l«li»|iili *|)»l&lt;l»liltU' vkll. Kiwlit mnellfitf* &gt;'■-. I in AlUinilmii'i' I, HIM AH.h.Im.m. #f» liny* In irftji'* |i»y» in llwlil W» ),7M Kttrrrt rwi'onU UI»kii rurtn mi'iinU r«i urni'ii l'r«M uriii'lMi wrliun i»n IHILhI HIkIx. ImllfUli. illnlrlliiili'il Mnir Indicium rtlHlrllmUd Ml'hlNll vl.ll. nimlt Aurli'iiliiiml iiiiir* AllKiuUni'* !.«4 llnu&gt; VHirlimltol HI»«'kl*V mrrliii.lli.il ( 'nvm iMtltNt, iiriiiluiliiin ('mm I Ml »i|, iulwrruliMla w|» Y*tn\»r*' «xi'hiifi(jti, liv* »uwk luHtichl or Mild Kitrmwr*' wxi'lutngti, mnwIk, vritlim, *ii&gt; l'urti-lir&lt;«l liv« atiii'k liilniilini-.l K»rm l»liur»r« |ilitr»il WOMEN'S KXTENIION WORK Tht hum* economic* Kxt*n«ion work In developing very rapidly. During the pout yew there wm a total of Mven home economicH worker*, Four were home economic* niwiallut*. and one devoted time to club work, one to Junior work, and one to county agent work. The number of meeting* held by extra worker* (in addition to the meeting* held by the worker* Ju*t enumerated) waa SO. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Aijnniliiinil /■;,»■ iiviuiiv ni Station nf Spbrimku V\ i irti«&lt;»i «• nlniri cour*e* were held in connection with men'* i iiuim'miihI uImi M&lt;|mruit)|y if) town* und Inform home* and country churche*, Hoeclttf rn**«&gt;t InuH for women were held Ml nil farmer*' iimliliili'n Muny »|ti'ciiil niffiint/MiilliiT tliuii ni liiniicrx' iiinIHuIcn »iii' lu'ltl In Inwim ihhI I'oiini r.v dUtrlcl*, Talk* anil ilt'itnui Miration* were iilven hi UMWH'luiliinN, fulnt, unri f**tlvul*. Muny himicIhI i'iiiiiiiiiu ilniiiiiiHiruiloniiunil n|mn'IhI meeting* with wiimint dub* were h«l&lt;l, Tin- iiiii'iidiinri' of nil home wonomlc* meeting* out*lde of i lif chili work mid junior work wu* fifUMH. Tht&gt; numW of women rvuchwl ni club nu««&lt;i iim* wtm 1 1 MM. In wddli ion It In Mtlmutud i hui women rMM'hed by corrvupondence ami women uiilnii club Mludy nmiiTiiil wm iK.IMft, Thin miike* » lolul of ilO.NHO rent-bed ihni i In' club work, Nine I houwnd live hundred ninety-nine irlrln were reuched hi •iuviiiI meetinKH held In connection with the junior work, wnd U.M2O ulrln were enrolled for niieclttl «y»»lemi*llc work In connec - tion with junior project*, Thl* mukp* t» Uitnl of 4M.7JMI women und ulrl* reuchtxl by Hit- home pconomlcH KkIi'Mkihh work, 'rhe line* of home economic* work lire ileNcrlbed in Hpeclnl bulletin* mill circular* which ure *enl upon requent, The *hort cour*e work I* reully h whool of home economic* iMtinit four liny*. It may be held In town* or in country home* or country *cnool - hou*e*, The plnn* for country nnd town &lt;&gt;our*e* differ *lluHlly, but they ure mevtlnif with itreHt *ucce**»nd the Mervlce I* unitble to HUpply the denmnd for worker* itlontf the*e line*, CiHinly Hifenl work for women I* meet Inn with *|m»H»»I fwvor, One wiiiiuin county Hiteni hit* nlremly been eNluhll*hed In Hewnrd county where there I* h Momemnker*' A**oci«iion of over 2(K) iMi-mlu'iK Petition* Iimvp l&gt;een received from the women of Mndl*on county »*klnu that mm Kxlen*lon worker be locHted there lo devote full lime In home economic* work, It I* expected ilmi In I he future I hi* work will meet with rapid development, In the women'* club work 142 country club* huve Innw MMl*le&lt;l durlnK I he ImmI yeitr, Mini llOof lhe*e riNve been oriftinlKed by the Kxlen*lon Mervlce, The*e club* are miule up entirely of fiii'ini'iV wive* mid dMUtfhf «*rn living from II lo HO milim in i h«* country, Home of Ihe member* it" I'' &lt;o \'i mile* lo Mliend club int'Ki \wu* Mom) of Ihe tneetlfttt* ttre held In home*, Home, how - ever, Hre held In country m'mooIIioom'* hihI churche*, Theiie i'lulm iuki&lt; up ihe Mludy or home economic* *uhjecl*, The*iudy of Ihe iirepHrailon of food hH* been of *peclitl intere*! lo them durlfiu Ihe IftMl vm»ii Home of the club* hold *ltorl cour*e* In the l.lllll llOUHOR, Kltfhl mile* wiuth of An*ley In (!u*ter county, m plMy«round </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Thirtieth Anniiiit Ifr/mil 41 win. i&lt;hIuIiI|hIh&lt;i| wlii-re nil of I In- nn'inbem of rumilie* In (In 1 iii-U/IiImh IhmmI Iiuw Inn I ilHii/hi fill I iiik&lt;*&gt; all »ummer, S'eur &lt; ili'iin In Hioux ( 'imiiiI.v, ii club imvhmizmI IiimI your look &lt;-iii in- rluirv "I thu furmer* 1 ln*tltule work Ihl* full. Ne«r I'uliuyi-it ili»&lt; stub wointrn ummIhI i hf country M'hool u&lt;u&lt;iu-i nil they e»n, Their united effort* re*ulled In I hf cleunlnif «nd repwperlnu of the M'hoolhouMi him! Hid iiuM'liiiHiiiK of ii fine, new *iove, Nmr Morrlll h country cluli Hum i|ihh« kooiI home economic* work in It* Junior orKunlxution* of the children, There th* ludle* take lunm In telllnu Mlorleit ttnd pluyinu uHtnui, In w&gt;m« loculltleft, urou|m of country clulw ur* orgMnixwl, tiuikinu out ii oroKrutn for ih»« Iwllormenl of country life In thut vicinity, Much a uroup lm» been orKunlxwl in HcollMlilulf, Mhmv Of I Ili'W dubH MM- Illiclll \\vn tO I III' iiryiilil/.Ml him Of ill Ill'l rllllm In neur-by communltlm, S|h&lt;cimI (iImmo for mi-xI yi-ur'n work Includt* Ih* vUltlnK of MU'h country club mi IwkhI onci&gt; durlnit the ypur and th« holdinu of Itroup club mwllriKN wh««r»' lh»'r«&lt; mv u nuMiclent number of clulm In m Inciiliiy to wiiminl mjch it meellny, Thin meellnu would prolmbly Im&gt; held twice h yeitr, with perhitpmt picnic In IheHummer ioi'l H midwinter meellnu In town, Hpeclitl elfort In made to niiikf the clulm community clulm rut her Ihitn wom^n'* Hub*, i Iimi i in- whole family mny Join, The object of ewh will («■ the •i ml v of w&gt;mD iiroblem In Kifricullure or home et'onomlcn «M|&gt;eclMlly relufed to their community, In the women'M club work 411 women'w clulm were tnml*\pt\, Of ilii'w, :ihv were In lowrm of lew limn 2,/WM) IiiIimIiIImmi. und 142 In I hf country, Only 24 were In town* of over 2, WM), JUNIOR RXTENIION WORK Tin' Junior eNl*&gt;nnlon work In Imwd itpon home project n In Htfrlculluro und home oconomlc* itnd i» » vmIumIiIk mtpplemeni lo the work of local whook The work provide* h definite pltm for home work coverlnu »i definite period und reiiulrlny »y»teinni ii •i in I v Mini report », 'I lie children enuNtffd In the wort Mre ormui i/i'il IiiIimIiiIii With IochI hi l/Hiil|i lender* I'urlnu If'IH there h«ve been four junior worker* devoiiny full lime in i he work, They Imve devoted their effort* to lnlere*f- Iriw boy* und «lrU between the H«e* of III und IK nm» In u *y*iemMilc nimlv of »Kririiliiiie und home economic* Thene effort* look form In *pecl»tl iMlk* lo boy* xnd «lrl* ulmiii home protect *, I he conduct lnt&lt; "f Junior *hort cour*e« und Junior ln*lllule*| Mpeclul tMlk* lo imrent* und lewher*, conference wild •upeiintendent*, bourd* of educullon, und civic ofKMnlxullon*, </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Ayrlrulturttl K /fieri mm I Sluiiiui nj Srlirimku uinl Milirinnu mmiI wrmnuinu premium* uiul award* for wrhiuvu - iiikiiI In home |troJ«H'i« Iti Hull work. Aiioi li»&lt;r form «if uri ivii v wim i lie promotion umi guidance of hoys' uml girls' I'lulw wli(m»&lt; mi'inlu&lt;r&gt;ihl|i prerequisite wan active ipiimci in inn of wiiiii' mil' of i lu- Ihiiih- projects, HMsisled dy I lit* Kxlenslon Hervice, During II'IH the enrollment In lh« vurlouit i»rojwi» whn u» foltOWl I H#w|nf 1.M7U CiNiklny 47(1 iUrfltKilim i, I ftft 47(1 ;i,iftft I'lg ntbtim ft«(i 'urn Krnwlng AAA I'nuiii uruwlMK SOT ftftft Thu lttr««* |&gt;*r&lt;'»nluu&lt;* iihown In th« u&lt;tr«li«ninu work In &lt;Im* lo lh* fwl thul KHrilwnlnu •nrollmvnl U lo \n&gt; found In 2A M'ho&lt;il «l ImI rlc*l», imi'h of whlcn ftnploywl u homv-Mchool uunlwi Hupvr - vinor for Ihv KiinliuilriK MHMin, In ••imIi of t.h« rupwvIhmI (lUlrii'U i he ImmI.v of worker* wim Ruhillvl(l*&lt;l Into neighborhood urouiM, •'lull hiii'Ii tfroup IwImk provlili'd with a volunt««r l&lt;n-nl li-iif|«&gt;r Thprc wrri' iiltoul 'M) mich liiml rlulm with iMdMV. Anothtr lypp of Mtlvlty In which Junior »xt*nnlon workeri* wwf tnmttfiKl wm th* lnntructlon of Hub m»mlwni and local club ImtdfrH. Thin ln»t ruction whh kIvi-m In Hh- form of pwrninttl work and In print ml follow-up Inn) ruction. I 'rrmmn\ Instruction wm ylvm whprpvw powlblp, and printed follow-up IrmlruHlonn wt&gt;rt&gt; dlnlrllnili'd by lh&lt;* Kxti'Hulon ofticc In Hirpp form* bullet In*, Hrculura, and leitmn, Th# HrculHllon 'if aiirli folloW-Up ItilllPrllll Wim Hppf-nxitfiiilHv t ,000 Imllcl iii». m2,(NM) Hrculnm. 10,000 Ipiipm MppHnlly plHnnfd rword \mnU* wen- dlNtrlbulMl for work In Kwttlpnlnu, corn Krowlnii, polHto nm* Im«, «fi»l plK rulolnu Durinii Hip vphc, Junior p»ipimion worker* Iihv»&lt; ptirllclpHled In 04V meeting* with hm Httendnncp of ;i(i,r ( r.n The*e meet Inn* were held In 02 count le*, Of the*e, HO were concerned with junior *horl course work, iM with junior Institute*, 70 with cHnnlnit demons) rul Ions , The other* were speclttl meeilnii* lMr«p|y for the purtMine of helping or eNplNlnlnv projects, Moth in town mmiI country dlslncls, m'himiI cre«lll I* now belnit ImijiHv Mlven for the home timJeH work, mid In n number of plitce* pNld supervisors lire provided by I he IimmIHv I'nUlii urnvkliiK Ml Chli'tton rNlilriK WS &lt; mU rnUlriK &lt;W KlfK iiriHlui'lriK SlftO T.rt«i t,m </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Tktrthlh Annual \U\hhI 43 COUNTY FAIR EXHIBIT! Tim following l» w HuitiniurlKwl ui iwidttiire mood of itic Agrl iuIiuiuI Khikiihiiiii i 'mini v I'uir Kxhlbil fur th* If) HI ««H«on: Polk f'iMiiily Ilillfitlii Ciuiiily ft.ltOO II ', M«|il ID ti I.I &gt;ln I'ifuriiy ■I.MKI I!,'. H«|il KW-illi Ki'Mli CiMinly J,WM) (I. », IM. IM-ft Kimlmll Ciiuiiiy MM II. ', &lt;M, 7-M* Kiiiu* Cnuiiiy tf,l4&lt;&gt; &lt; N W H«|ii 7 n (i llMttml'miMly ftillMI ( N W »t! I'i-lft Tn Hut.. M»« r'N.W H»\H.W-'iru MiullMiiiC.miily U.htn I ' H«|il ,M 4* Tliiir.l.ihl-u.inlv I !'•&lt;» ■ 1 «. &lt;i I «. I t •• ToUl 4»,»'J« I 'nor wi'ii! lu«r wild n&gt;H|iniiMilili' for I hi* wnall ul li'iuluiirc ul wnni' of i In- fuit-M. In iIh 1 wiwi 'mhI of i In- Mini*, Nnow »i(»rm» wtr» riiriMiiiiiTi'ii him I ui lumlKnr* Hi «om» of Lh« fulnt In th* mmI tnri of tht utttU w«rt &lt;*ul down by cold, rulny wimthw, In u f«w of th« gmmm, th« Hlt*nduni'D wim mrrlounly lnt.«rf«r«il with by th* IhU Arrival of th« cur containing th« wxhlbli ; and at on* point, dun to th« d«luy of th* cur In irmmli , but on* day of th« fair r* - mitlnml whtn ih* var rvuchvd town. At another point, It wum ntN'Mwury to hire u Npwlul vngln* In order to arrlv* at th* *xhlbit pUMfi th* exhibit ww» w*ll w*lv*d at wiry point, b*lng th* main exhibit ui M&gt;v*rul of ih* fain, Many of th* fain which w*r* vIhIImI thlii fall hav* again appllvd for th* exhibit n«xt ytar, Th* n\UH'mm of th* exhibit* nur*ly Hhown that th«r* U room for devtlopm*nl In th* educBtlonnl »ldp of th*typlral county fair, At *M'h fair vuiiwl, ih* wim«' p*otil* hav* r*tum*d mor* than one* and Mim* of th*m ren*at*(lly In order that th*y might rimilllHrlw IhemiwIvM an mucn om poiwlble with th* \emm* nhown In th* exhibit, ■ULLKTINI During Ih* la*l year th* following Kxiennion bull*! Inn hav* been prlniwli Nm TIIIk MHIi.ti NT Mhii/) &lt;'iiuf»«*, tif KniMwiiiti »i'h»MiU In AiflHilliif« hhiI Mimic Fli'iitiimilw|, t , »• 'thf Mn^fllim nf Ml»wl HtnUm •Mi [Ml, NhmI (ill, ifiil Mmik mm ih whimIhi win* i&gt;»Mi iii N^ifMhit 41 TM ¥»m (itvuHliify 11,(10(1 n.iiiin (i.iiiKi (i.iKiii MIKI i .noil II I' , Auk !&lt;«» M*jiI I 7,/MM) (I, K M*|7t, I'i 1(5 |)K»wih &lt; 'utility </seg>
            <seg id="p044">ftlh \itiiHiHtnnl NtftHmnt tMitui nl Mimlm *mmi* »«► m&lt;miaii»i» lllK(ll»l|llM^lll IHIlHll Hllll ll^»lH«llwllHfi»lll»fll»|lW.|H.lMln, jHHIill *H||»H)n, Hllll flHlllH WIIIIHIIlll* William HIM |HlMi»llwl »H|)HI«^I* Hllll HIM* Im llHll II|IMII (MijIIWl \lltliillhinil itiutiiutiitu Tim I'UlWlijlMll niwIhIW IIimuikhI imiiiI HfiKliiwiiiiy llil)il»» llmin mijm Ittii lily i/iii iIhi/i* Hi .((III II Illllllllfl Ml mllllll' HUM TllX lll»l IllM iIIiIiIhh Im llt-ll III Hit' M.nlnl fill /Mllll Hum Im Ml'lllllf ■ |Iim llMIIIIIIIM Hl\&gt;i "(H •■mik hum fiiini liiillilliiMii All xlfiiii I* Imliiu iihiIm lii mm|*i ilm f»iinmi»» III llm Millllji/ll n! Wimi liliilili'liio ilk IliililillK »|im| i»»l lii»'»'l HiunmimI iImi|ihik»H»iIIihi»', liv nil Ifiiiw mill um»»i&gt;ni\i\ iii.ihmi^, iiihI hk »m\uiH mil * in nliii'M/tiiil liiim'i n» {'ii^rliiu »Hnuu» |)Iiii»»'» ill Hm »iili|wl In I'liinmilliiM *llli I i»' I'iiiiii Inillilliiu |ni(lil»'iii. Km Kil l»lun iirinl* uj Inillillnui inn whih In lniiii»'i» Ml mm, mul M IIiKJiImII l/l WImMUIi ||mI|III|I*&gt;HhII"Ii IhIIMrIxUiIn ||| lining IiikiIi |)M ill MlM RlMlf A IIHIIlllMI "I lllMM&lt; ll«Wi llllMHlU IlKNll H«ImI| Illllfll AiiniliMi ihiiIiIkii III MMrli-iiliiiifil xiiMiiiMfi'lnu In torm iIimIiimm»&lt; hi/ widI llnlili Iimvn men iliHliifil [hi ilfiiiiiii*lri«iMiii |iih|mim&lt;» hiiiI I Iii'kk nu&lt; i mhiiII Iliu || iii'ImIiIiih Him fill lll«l» |H|I I Him III m h Hikh*' In HlllMI |MHI'M lIlWW » H l|H»'"llHl| III HllMMllull I III' l|l|Ml|ull III Immii •miiiiiiHhm him funii Huiiliiimrv in, uf vummi, mIwuv* ucmIw. I II I \\¥ t'lfni I III liwlll Mil VK I lldM |il hMkIII* I Im IIUI'll'llll III'hI t'UMllH'M Inu I'lmmmlnii wivlin Iimh llm |m«l M ( «i 'Inim llm fulln^iiiM *ml« ■\ iii mill Ilitpliiiitiliu Tim miiIihm! Iiii«»Iihii»Ii v f'iilnnjtlnii «|mi'lHl (•I f|Mf|« Hull llm Mill* IHHihHhiiI HIHlimill In llm l/IHllliil/lf yum IMM "' jf'ttdM •litt'l Hp ImllfVM I ill* hi Im MimMMlly I nm lm(^n«&lt; llm nlimi n/iii'lt fm|»niii|« mi hhh Ii hm llm IicmMIi »*»mI vluor "I llm ti'lllitf nHicI* Tim VHllMV nIh»'I» In ifiMi'f im|(iim*Ivk Im fKMI iiihI I'Mf^ ,n\tni» kMliy HiIiimiihIIhii tii | line |illlil» n^nl mi! IiiIIhhik "till mil I. lM.||l«l»»l|HIW I'NIIlHt'Hll ImiImIIiiihi Wii(H N SMt*&lt;Mi Mt*«lMl)»« llHll jllllll MIHMM «iiff 'ilw»i»/M«(m(ii(»i. I iiIhI hMMiiIhOH. Hi Hill Hlr^- liiinii l« 1,11110 I •i ■I ...I "yffn 1 I* </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Ihhitnh AnniiHl Ih in a I 45 Hihii *h hM hiiMmhU Hfi'l llw i/mm »l //»•!♦ I* »»i»((^ hh*||* liyii *)»M| HimiIw|jimIh Mlllill* H»^ JllHliflW Nil') I* IIIMIH (•IJ*M&lt;|illM*. i" t\}»»m 7 dp i»i«n * in '•mi mid *j I |/i»/|iwl* mih m kwm »Uni W\\\ WHl&gt;'ll III* /ill) fl)»)'l» H« WNll lit M))ilni)(»i in (In*/ lliwi* m mut niliw |(imJ(Iwh» imy \w i»ik|iI |)(iin)f iIik |/)u))iHiiiiK »/l |/|(iMnwi( llvK »i»».l, h« wm\ hm din *mi|. in MwumlHU wmi m \m\ «»i»l m» »*f Hid mmIw NHHWk Ihi/iiiK Mix |i«»i vmmi U| I^iIihu il&gt;«iii)«(i.*lrNll)Oi» Iihvk wko imiimI mmI )u m«imi|iImIk)I h»i|i Imu (^iIdim ImhIn |im^&gt;&lt; w»&lt;ii inDtlllKlKil P'»l|l nwl .(MKIOlllllK MKM|M»t#»*#"M* »*#ll*» Wlfll m» •Old ((ltd Wlllj chIvmii imvn Iinmii i»(liii/lwlwl Tllt&lt; MIKVlMlM* Iim|iI I#V I ll« MIlilllHI llM»lmil/llV »|/M)I«||»I Ullll III*. IMHflllMI HllMIMIIIIK lllMf lll&gt;JMll/IM» HIM «• r»lll)lWii: *""']'|jtll/* Wtitrl rniMr** I nu I hjllW llt^llDM n UMlNI iln)(iiiii»l»Hii'in-. mIm III^IMIM* liwltl I'l'l I/U MllHMlfilW (I Illll Ill » ■ \ynimimu I'iilvMNl'iii w (»»■!• lii Mtfi'i(iiiinv III N*&gt;Imh«1*m IiivuIvm H (Mllllliwi III I'hiMfllla, VHI&gt;lllU i'l|ll»lilniMlllv III HMMIMI'lDf Mll)l illlt«l|*lly wllh llm MftfMl vhiImIiiki III wild Mllil iIiimhU' (muni In Tin* l'i«lHn*lui| nimi'lMlliil HiimMluM will fmllllH' idiiIimMv I|ik KICHlMl |ll'l|llkll III UlN MiMlllXHHlflM |IMI'I flf ill* •IhU Hll'l III lIlK IIMIullXI Mllll HMII'llt'l M'«|llll|» III lIlK »|lll 1 1 j»&lt;«(»l HI II |IMll, WMl M fMC im rimiH i&lt;iii(iiiy iih/mih» iiimMki hiiiI iiHhinpii mik iiwwIhiI hi liiliiK I lii« Mill liHi'lt In Mr Ikiimh •&lt;«!♦' "'(""'Itii'lly II » In p»mI"H» w\i*lf hUii'U I* Niliiilll^llv |mhI)ImI(I», IIiM |iliilili&lt;fli la M&gt;lkllVI&gt;j^ dl\*\ Illll Itl |IMll«ll( (ll* *»M|lll»W.lM IM HI IIM llf HlX-lMlW MIMlll HUM If) vwv ImcmkU riilliiw*))] Mini l« Mi»m|i|i»»wl mkim* lifiifHulik Ml Im«' '"'"I Of* 4fMti&lt;l|"iltil ill lite l^iiMiil fHlliiKl b\(n\fn IdM'iI III f«y"i Iwf'NiiMi II ifiKMX* M'HM iclMll'iiin ici'l jjm&gt;mm II woflnii -imIiiIiiiiH Iim'UM IIimI II Id it'll nmMiHu\» Im vmIiik or dWt^l '•IMVW Hd N Mtll III'I'XII'IH H'JM|»lwl I" nll'lll |IM«llll)* Kll«llH»M mIoiiiM U i^nuiii*n»ini\ A dK^MM'l liM'lilHIl 'if \tmiHI\H}l(&gt;» III *NM(«&gt;HI N«ftffM«lft« Id (llMl ill \m\MW\\ |»H«I'"N iiiUIiiIm Tlll'^ IlKVC Imnti I'm/lV |»ii|iii»n - lltr M »«ll«fM«'l"/&gt; IMl»lllfK A IN "f llllllMIM l|M&lt;l| WllN tf'"«l iMIill* iiimIki 'IKTx'kiiI i'ikkIii )iitd ■IniiiM )m kihiI* hm'I /mmiWiwI IM llllKIMlwl imiliw A dlMH ll»l« IfCKII IHWlx Ml lI'Hl 'lllW Him </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Ayiirulluml HsiitritHnil Slulion of Nthrutku A problem rorifriiiii uif i In- liirnii'i of ilu- south central part mi i In Miuii' U noi how in ImiiI'I up In* Mill with u legume but what in i|o with Hi' 1 ground thai ha* l»i'i'ii in alfalfa a number of ywtrt* ami iniiti t)f broken up. Home complain i hai i hey an- un.ilili - lo grow ol her crop* on the land saii*f(tciorily fora number of yearn. Sunn- ili'iiiodkirui lonal t#*U should \m made showing ilu&lt; merits of shorter eolations, the unu of ililfwnl vurit*liw» im tea i mm, ami Illi- HfwrlM Of (lllfiTl'Ml method* of tillttg*. In thin *itm« region ami uIho north to Holt county und «a»t lo hull* uml Ktfwurd counti&lt;w, I lmr»« U Hom« ililliruliy in getting Hlund* of ulfitlftt, The value of the well'pfirked, molMt need bed *hould \w thoroly demon*lrut«d, mi_ LI I l i m Mil li a I , The problem In the wewtern half of the Htttte in to wure more feed from the Hum* ucreiige, l)ilferent vurietie* of corn were i / !••'! out in Nome of the we*t#rn countieo the punt Mummer. Home varieties were found to be well iulitpted and probably ituperior to ihoHe commonly grown. The demonstration will be continued, Cooperative work in growing itweet clover wan *larted and ithould l»i- coniinuwl. The main work done by the Kxtennion MpvcialUt the pant year wait to make a *urvey of the otate and determine the problem* that moot need attention. Advice and demonstration* were given wherever pomible. Twenty -one call* were made on county agent*, a»*[»ting with the work in their respective counties. Five farms were visited to make Aeld examinations and assist with field problem*. A number of demonstrations of oat smut treat - ment were given. Three tours of counties were made under direction of county agent*, the combined attendance being about 200. Two field meetings were held, the number in attendance being about 30. The specialist in agronomy gave courses at five senior short courses and three junior short courses. The combined attendance at all sessions of the senior courses was about :J,OOO, and of the junior courses about 1,080. Agronomy work was given at 25 farmers' institutes with an aggregate attendance of 5,560. Seventeen special meetings were held with a combined attendance of about 1,050. Dairy The chief problem in dairy Extension work in Ne - braska, according to the dairy Extension specialist, is to secure better dairying rather than more dairying. Dairy farming is practiced more or less in every part of the State, and the only way to make the industry permanent is to made it profitable. The two main factors of better dairying are better cows and better care of cows. The specialist feels that the very best way to en - courage the keeping of better cows is to insist that careful records be kept and that cows profitable only be retained in the herd. Retter care of cows will come only thru the process of education. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Thirtieth An mini lU/mrl 47 Owing i" Kit- iiomuri'l for •■&lt;iw» in th« MUtU*, there i* at tin - prevent Utn« a tfr«mi deal r»f siwulaiion in dairy mnii- i,y un wru|(ij|uu» dealers, This prociic* will eveniually Injure the dairy industry urid should ihwwfore \m discountped. In ih« solution of these problems, the Kxtension dairy mitn iriwl ii» find on* «&gt;r more successful duiry farmers in each taffy munily uw\ io um ihwir furrnw mm &lt;l»moni*l ml ion turmn, It i« fiBcwwttry lo have thaw furnwt* kiwp lh«ir rwonl* in unlur to tftt ,11-fuiiiic -1, 1 1. 1 concvrninK ilu«ir \&gt;u»lntnm. l)ttmon»iruiUn) mwUnit* run Iht-n («• h«kl ui iIh'm- p(MM tfld uuio iri|m lukfri io vinit variouM dairy furirm in th« community, — -r ' wwmw^ i www r-r wr- -fmi r vsr * r r»-» »»r m*rw » •■ruir im r f r • _; ' I'ulilic lii'inoriMirui ioriM in juduinu duiry cuiilf i-un tw iifld in connection with \\w xnwl\n\i*, Wtwnuvttr u mufiing ckn l&gt;» h»ld to iwlviintHtf*, Iwttw cowh und \mlUn duiry mirthodH nrw ditu'UMMNl, arid if poMMibl« it locul uri/uni/ui n»n i» formiMl to pro - mot* bttt«r dttiryinu in the community. The whooU art utmi wh«r« it Im rxMwibl* to coOpcrst* with them, During 11MH, IM/i cattUr w«r« purchuiMtd for Xebriwktt fitrmwH, MOO cowh w«rw UmUkI in cow l«Htinu utmH'inlionn, 7 junior cow twttinK club* wcrt HuptrviiMNl bv th*- KxUrnMion Npwialint, 14 public d«monHtrHtion« w«r« held, and &lt;'t uuU&gt; excuntion* w«r« conducted with 'MH) pre««nt on the trip*. farm managtnwnt The farm management Murvey ban an Km object the demonstration to farmer* &lt; in connection with their own farmm the profitable method of mammaming and analyzing the farm businew* an a mean* of meavuring the profit or Iomm incurred in conducting it, and of deciding upon modification* which promiw to increaM the net income. Ultimately by thin means it w hoped to demonstrate to farmers the importance of an efficient organiza - tion and administration of the farm survey work as conducted by means of farm records taken by survey specialists, county agents, and local leaders, and by securing records in account books which are furnished to farmers who will promise to keep an accurate account of their farm business. These records are summarized, factored, and returned, thus calling the attention of each individual farmer to the phases of his business which are paying best or which are losing money. During the past year 573 records have been taken in 11 different areas, and 529 have been summarized and relumed. There are 1,021 farm record books in the hand of farmers. These will be called for at the close of the year and will be summarized and returned with factor sheets to the farmers. In addition to the survey work, there is a great deal of work in farm management Extension along the lines of marketing and cooperation. There are many calls for talk* on cooperation, </seg>
            <seg id="p048">xlviii Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska especially where assistance is needed in the organization of co - operative elevators and other cooperative enterprises. The de - mand for courses in farm management at the movable schools and for lectures at farmers' institutes has been very marked dur - ing the past year. Horticulture — The work in horticultural Extension has been largely confined to the handling of demonstration orchards in various parts of the State. A number of farmers have cooperated with the Extension specialists and have properly pruned and sprayed portions of their orchards, leaving the rest as they were found by the specialists. These orchards were used for meetings and served as an indication of what could be done by proper cultural methods. Fruit growing in Nebraska is for the purpose of markets and for home consumption. The Loess Bluff section along the Missouri River from the southern part of the State to north of Blair is admirably adapted to commercial fruit growing, especially to apples, grapes, and small fruit. In spite of this fact, this phase of agriculture will never be popular unless it can be con - clusively shown that by proper management and proper methods orcharding is reasonably profitable over a term of years. Be - tween 80 per cent and 90 per cent of the home orchards in the State receive no care after they are once set out. Home orchards are rapidly vanishing, but as a matter of fact they should be established on every farm. In order to help in the solution of these problems 8 different circular letters were sent during the course of a year to about 150 growers. Three orchards in the fruit section of the State were selected in which to carry on demonstration work. Verbal agree - ments were made with the men to the effect that their orchards were to serve as demonstrations in orchard management in their community for the ensuing three years. The Extension specialists were to supervise the orchard operations, and be present at each application of spray and at pruning time. In return, the orchard owner or lessor was to furnish the necessary apparatus and materials and help to spray and prune the orchard. A few trees were to be left unsprayed as a check on the spraying. At the Barrett orchard at Papillion in 1915, 1,500 bushels of apples were sold at 25 cents to 75 cents per bushel. Fifty bushels were taken to South Omaha but rotted before they could be sold. The orchard did not pay operating expenses. In 1916 this orchard received the treatment advocated by the Extension specialist and yielded 3,446 bushels of salable apples, and instead of a loss a net profit of $134.21 per acre was made. The orchard served its purpose well as a demonstration. Several meetings were held </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Thirtieth Annual Report 49 during the pruning and spraying operations, and a picnic was held in the fall to look over the results of the work. In the Beck orchard at Peru in 1915, apples were picked and shipped to the cider mill, bringing 25 cents a hundred. Arrange - ments for a cooperative demonstration were made for the 1916 season, and during that year 5,292 bushels of apples were raised which sold for $4,392, as against 4,500 bushels of the year before for $540. In the Sanders' orchard at Brownville, the work of 1916 resulted in a yield of 1,721 bushels of apples that sold in bulk tree run at $1.25 a hundred, or a total of $1,181.75, as against 1,666 bushels last year which brought $425. Details of the orchard work can be secured from the horticultural specialists. During the course of the year, 49 different demonstration meetings were held in orchards in the State, 291 people being in attendance. At these meetings, methods of pruning fruit trees, grapes, and cane fruit were discussed and demonstrated. Spray - [ng, too, was discussed altho not demonstrated. These meet - ings were in addition to the ones held at the demonstration orchards and were known as the home orchard demonstration. News service — The agricultural editor issues weekly what is known as the Extension News Service. This goes to all of the editors of the weekly papers in the state of Nebraska and is designed especially for the country press. Ninety-five per cent of the papers are using the service, either in part or entire. In addition to this, a service is sent to the Agricultural papers of this and adjoining states and also a service to the daily papers. The agricultural editor also edits all extension bulletins and regular circulars. In addition, he writes many special articles for papers in the State covering problems of local interest. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Agricultural Ejcfwriment Station of Nebraska THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT HATCH FUND RECEIPTS Received by the University (State) treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1916, under the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887 (Hatch Fund) $15,000 00 Financial Secretary EXPENDITURES [UKU&gt; Salaries Labor Publication Postage and stationery Freight and express Chemicals and laboratory supplies Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies . Feeding stuffs Library Tools, machinery, and appliances Furniture and fixtures Live stock Traveling expenses $7,292 79 3,104 28 1,953 80 489 54 80 51 50 47 150 66 1,528 98 1 40 22 48 128 66 150 00 46 43 $15,000 JM)_ $MM&gt;0q_ 00 January 29, 1917 J. S. Dales, </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Thirtieth Annual Report 51 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued Financial Secretary ALiftma rvji^u RECEIPTS Received by the University (State) treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1916, under the act of Congress approved March 16, 1906 i Adams fund) $15,000 00 EXPENDITURES Salaries $11,428 58 Labor 1,118 80 Postage and stationery 16 85 Freight and express 39 23 Chemicals and laboratory supplies 940 55 Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies 344 55 Feeding stuffs 202 99 Tools, machinery, and appliances 169 02 Furniture and fixtures 8 06 Scientific apparatus and specimens 495 88 Traveling expenses 212 49 Buildings and land 23 00 $15,000 00 $15,000 00 January 29, 1917 J. S. Dales </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA EXPENDITURES FINANCIAL STATEMENT HATCH FUND RECEIPTS Received by the University (State) treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1916, under the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887 (Hatch Fund) $15,000 00 Financial Secretary Salaries Labor Publication Postage and stationery Freight and express Chemicals and laboratory supplies Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies Feeding stuffs Library Tools, machinery, and appliances Furniture and fixtures Live stock Traveling expenses $7,292 79 3,104 28 1,953 80 489 54 80 51 50 47 150 66 1,528 98 1 40 22 48 128 66 150 00 46 43 $15,000 00 $15,000 00 January 29, 1917 J. S. Dales, </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Thirtieth Annual Report 53 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued Financial Secretary auaivio r\jr*u RECEIPTS Received by the University (State; treasurer from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1916, under the act of Congress approved March 16, 1906 (Adams fund) $15,000 00 EXPENDITURES Salaries $11,428 58 Labor 1,118 80 Postage and stationery 16 85 Freight and express 39 23 Chemicals and laboratory supplies 940 55 Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies 344 55 Feeding stuffs 202 99 Tools, machinery, and appliances 169 02 Furniture and fixtures 8 06 Scientific apparatus and specimens 495 88 Traveling expenses 212 49 Buildings and land 23 00 $15,000 00 _$15 i 000 00 January 29, 1917 J. S. Dales </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Continued SUPPLEMENTAL FUNDS RECEIPTS Moneys received by the University (State) treasurer from other sources than the United States, for the use and benefit of the Experiment Station and Sub - stations, for the year ended June 30, 1916. Balance July 1, 1915 $6,939 45 Sales of stock, produce, etc 39,474 89 EXPENDITURES Salaries $3,578 83 Labor 6,358 81 Publications 26 60 Postage and stationery 532 15 Freight and express 424 55 Heat, light, water, and power 156 19 Chemicals and laboratory supplies 1,449 92 Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies 1,498 80 Feeding stuffs 9,663 35 Library 67 76 Tools, machinery and appliances 691 85 Furniture and fixtures 640 47 Scientific apparatus and specimens 204 36 Live stock 3,123 24 Traveling expenses 592 51 Contingent expenses 59 00 Buildings and land 2,445 28 Balance, June.30, 1916 14,900 67 $46,414 34 $46,414 34 January 29.J1917 J. S. Dales Financial Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Thirtieth Annual Report 55 FINANCIAL STATEMENT— Concluded APPROPRIATIONS BY THE STATE EXPERIMENTAL SUBSTATIONS Balances, July 1, 1915, of legislative appropriation from the State general fund for the benefit of the Experimental Substations, for the two years end - ing March 31, 1917, North Platte $27,221 20 Scottsbluff 7,775 48 Valentine 8,834 29 $43,830 97 Expenditures, year ending June 30, 1916, for superin - tendence, supplies, labor, live stock, feed, seeds, machinery, tools, and betterment of the plants, North Platte $18,754 01 Scottsbluff 4,393 39 Valentine 6,034 40 Appropriations balances July 1, 1916, North Platte $8,467 19 Scottsbluff . . 3,382 09 Valentine 2,799 89 AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION Balance, July 1, 1915, of legislative appropriations from the State general fund for maintenance of Agricultural Extension and Farmers' Institutes, for the two years ending March 31, 1917 Expenditures, year ending June 30, 1916, for superin - tendence, clerical service, labor, lecturers, and workers' services, and expenses printing supplies. . Appropriation balance July 1, 1916 18,448 99 $44,290 85 $44,290 85 January 29, 1917 J. S. Dales Financial Secretary </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>