<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Chopped Alfalfa vs. Bran in Grain Ration for Dairy Cows</title>
               <date value="1918-07">1918-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">M'iIImh. IN lulr l'M»i Chtppid Alfalfa vi, Iran In Onln Ration l»r Dairy Cowi ii • ft * H AiiHIil'l II'MAI Itl'IMIMINMIAIHlN ill HII I iNI VI IN hi II ■ NIHMAHKA HNHMN. NMOMUKA I' * A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OP NEBRASKA I II* MI»MIM»I, Illl Will I I lit. KM.k.M« UK I'lIK IINIVWii.ll VI uniiMauMl J K MIM.KN, t l«« I'mutint, [.limulu itNnHAl.l-k. iKANh L llAI.I.KH, Ulnulitt HuNuNAMMC Vli K&gt;M U, I.»H*H, Mill I lly HUMUHAUU I'llll.lf I. llAI.I., I.llifi.li, HuNllNAUIt llAKKV U. l.ANPW, HhWHIiI. i hi .1 » i ins til t I. t li» 'Mamuu. AVWV, »'h. I)., I.I. I)., Chiuinllur, «x oltleio W. Q. Hahtinuk, A. B., -4cti»« Chancullor, E A. BUKNHTT, U. BC., DWtctur OKAS. E. UUNNKLH, 0. 8C, Unnlur »/ Kxletmiun Servic*. J, g. Dalbm, M. Ph., finoneio/ Secrttary. C. A. Lcwrn, B. 8c, Uulletin HUitu, I life. VIIIIIKIM. kTAKK F. W. Uphon, Ph. D., AffrumiJuru/ CA#mu&lt;ry. 'L. W. Chahe, M. B., A. E., Af ricw/tura/ Engineering. W. W. BUM, B. BC, Agronomy. T. A. KlHKLBACH, A. M., Agronomy. H. J. Gramuch, B. 8c, Anima/ Huibandry. J. H. GAIN, M. D. C, Antma&lt; Pathology. H. M. MARTIN, V. M. D., /Imma/ Pathology. J. H. FRAND8EN, M. S. A., £&gt;atry Hutbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Entomology. H. C. FILLEY, A. M., Farm Management. R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture. G. A. LoVELAND, A. M., Meteorology. E. Mead WlLCOX, Ph. £&gt;., Plant Pathology and Phyialogy. F. E. MU88EHL, B. Sc, Poultry. W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Subttation, Noru. PUtU. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Subttation, Valentin* James A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation Mitchell. 'L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomitt, North Platte. 'J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Aceoetate in Agricultural Chemittry. *G. K. K. LINK, Ph. D., Associate in Plant Pathology and Physiology. W. B. Nevens, M. S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. 'R. R. Spafford, A. M., Assistant in Farm Management. 'Granted leave of absence for military service. 'Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Depart merit of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. 'Granted leave of absence. 'Resigned. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">0H0FF1D ALFALFA VI, MAN IN TNI ORAIM RATION FOB DAIRY OOWI Till' |M'nli|it|ii uf iMiliii'illV Ilii' MUil lit llir nil Him fur lilt' • 1 &gt;• t #-&gt; uuw i» nl iinii'li llil|nil'lillli'n, Wheiv riMltfllH|{i&lt; limy tie »ub»lllulBil fur ft Ifi'Hin or .1 li&gt; i • i ■ •■ 1 1 1 &gt; i i'oiii'uiiU'hIi', tin' I'imi nf I lie niliitii i" lilu'ly when I'lili'iihtli'il on n* |ii'ufi&gt;in iilfnll'ii iiii'iil it nuiy In' »lii|i|iin I'HIlt III till' Mil*wiwMi|l|»i I'ivi'l' ill I'imi of ii mill uroduefttf liki&lt; ft&lt; or I'iM'i'iry uiiiu, In th«» form of iiiin n Ihi'ui' |niri of llu&lt; country ,i I'Okt imii'li Imw |u&lt;r ion limn tliu ililllT wtlin- The \i rlh I'litiii- Kiilikiitlii'ii f I hi' liilwinlly nf Nflmmliii liu» ooniluotad mi 0X|*#rim«nl t" • I «*t t*t*ni i n&lt;* whether uhupptd .iii.iiia limy lit) lubititulatl for mIu-hi Ih-mii in tin* iluiry uow Kmin ritlion of 4 |iiiiis corn, 2 \mv\u hmn hikI I purt oil iihmiI, iiiuI llir ttffuet uf niii'Ii Hubatitution on the |ierform»»ff of tin* t'own, The firat tfKt I'xtcnilcil from December 1. IBlti, tu January 30, 1917. Duriuy ilii- time tin- rows were fed uliotit :t(l pound* uilHK" P&lt;*r IumiI daily .mil IiiuI iirri'hh to a rack i-oiit it i ni ii^r ii I i'ii Ifii hay. Tin- Mcond tekt whn befftin March 1. 1917, and were fed Hilttift' him I alfalfa hay ki'hmh during the lust few week*, on tin- milk How— one pound of i ■loved May :«&gt;, 1917. The eow* thrilOUt the text ami hud Motile The amount of grain irai Imwd rain for -I to 4 poumlH of milk. Six pairs of cows were selected for each test. Kaeh pair wan matched as closely us possible in respect to breed, lactation period, previous record, milk flow, percentage of fat. and other factors that woidd be expected to affect production. One cow from each pair was put into Group A, the other cow into Group B, The six cows of Group A were fed a (crain ration constating of 4 part*, ground corn, 2 parts bran and 1 part oil meal during the first period of lf&gt; days while the six down of Group U were fed a grain ration consisting of 4 parts ground corn, 2 parts chopped alfalfa and 1 part oil meal. During the second 15-day period the A group iii lir ilin'i'i'HM'il, TIii'iimiii u Ui'tftt purl nf Ilii' wukIki'm Imlf of llm I'niii'il HtHli'n iilfiilfii liny i» hImiimIhmi himI ■-■ .hi |*&lt;i i-j* i i * •-!&gt; i'lm»»|i </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 16 U received the alfalfa ration while the B group received the bran ration. The test was extended thru four 15-day periods, during two periods of which the cows of Group A were fed the bran ration and two periods the alfalfa ration. The cows of Group B were fed in a similar manner, only that when the cows of Group A were getting the alfalfa ration those of Group B were getting the bran ration, and when the cows of Group A were being fed the bran ration those of Group B were being fed the alfalfa ration. During the third period of the first test one cow in Group A, being fed the bran mixture, went off feed for a few days, and during the fourth period another cow in Group A, being fed the alfalfa mixture, dropped in production for a few days. As one cow was off when on bran and the other when on alfalfa, these deficiencies do not influence the final results. During the second test one cow became sick. She and her mate were taken out of the test, leaving only 5 pairs of cows. RESULTS OF THE FIRST TEST The six cows in Group A while on the bran mixture during two 15-day periods gave 3,972 pounds of milk containing 144.3 pounds of butter fat, and lost 32 pounds in weight. The same six cows while on the alfalfa mixture during two 15-day periods gave 3,952 pounds of milk containing 138.7 pounds of butter fat, and gained 223 pounds in weight. The six cows of Group B while on the bran mixture during two 15-day periods gave 4,244 pounds of milk containing 158.4 pounds of butter fat, and gained 128 pounds in weight. This same group of cows while on the alfalfa mixture during two 15-day periods gave 4,332 pounds of milk containing 163.6 pounds of butter fat and gained 1 pound in weight. Bringing together the results from both groups we find that the twelve cows while eating the bran mixture during two 15-day periods produced 8,216 pounds of milk containing 303 pounds of butter fat and gained 96 pounds in weight. The same twtlv* </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Chopped Alfalfa vs. Bran for Dairy Cows 5 cows while on the alfalfa mixture during similar periods pro - duced 8,284 pounds of milk containing 302.3 pounds of butter fat and gained 224 pounds in weight. RESULTS OF SECOND TEST The five cows in Group A while on the ration of corn, bran and oil meal during three 15-day periods gave 7.43CJ pounds of milk containing 250 pounds of butter fat and lost 3 pounds in weight. The same five cows while on the ration of corn, alfalfa and oil meal during three 15-day periods gave 7,147 pounds of milk con - taining 245 pounds of butter fat and lost 52 pounds in weight. The five cows of Group B, while on the ration of corn, bran and oil meal during three 15-day periods gave 7,239 pounds of milk containing 241 pounds of butter fat and lost 125 pounds in weight. The same five cows while on the ration of corn, alfalfa and oil meal during three 15-day periods gave 7,309 pounds of milk containing 239 pounds of butter fat and gained 68 pounds in weight. Combining the results from the two groups we find that the ten cows while being fed bran with corn and oil meal during three 15-day periods gave 14,669 pounds of milk containing 491 pounds of butter fat and lost 128 pounds in weight. The same ten cow* while being fed alfalfa with corn and oil meal during three 15-day periods gave 14,456 pounds of milk containing 484 pounds of butter fat and gained 16 pounds in weight. TWO TESTS COMBINED Twenty-two cows while being fed a forage ration of silage and alfalfa hay, and a grain ration of 4 parts ground corn, 2 parts bran and 1 part oil meal during an average period of 75 days, gave 22,886 pounds of milk containing 794 pounds of butter fat and lost 32 pounds in weight. The same cows during a similar period and under similar conditions, and fed the same ration ex - cepting that chopped alfalfa replaced bran in the grain ration </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 16U gave 22.741 pounds of milk containing 786 pounds of butter fat and gained 240 pounds in weight. During these tests with twelve cows for two months and ten cows for three months chopped alfalfa was substituted for bran in the standard dairy grain ration of 4 parts ground corn, 2 parts bran and 1 part oil meal without any appreciable unfavorable effect. The slight decrease of 14.") pounds in milk and 7.."&gt; pounds in butter fat production while the alfalfa was being eaten was more than overcome by the gain of 272 pounds in the weight of the cows. It is evident that in these tests alfalfa was fully e&lt;|iial to bran. If these results are the same as are found in general practice, then alfalfa fed in this manner has the same feeding value as bran. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Chopped Alfalfa vs. Bran for Dairy Cows 7 FIRST TEST Table 1. — Chopped Alfalfa vs. Bran in Grain Ration for Dairy Cows. Grain ration: 4 parts chopped corn, 2 parts bran of chopped alfalfa, 1 part oil meal. December 1, 1916, to January 30, 1917—60 days Change in Total Total PERIOD r milk butter fat lot Lot A — 6 cows Pounds Pounds Pounds Bran ration First period, December 1 to 15 16 2068.5 77.41 Third period, January 1 to 15 j —48 1904.0 66.93 Total of two periods —32 3972.5 144.34 Alfalfa ration Second period, December 16 to 30 222 2049.5 75.75 Fourth period, January 16 to 30 i 1 1903 63.00 Total of two periods 223 | 3952.5 f 138.75 Lot B — 6 cows Bran ration Second period, December 16 to 30 191 2132 79.58 Fourth period, January 16 to 30 — 63 2112 78.78 Total of two periods 1 128 4244 158.36 Alfalfa ration First period, December 1 to 15 | — 80 2221 79.99 Third period, January 1 to 15 81 2111 83.60 Total of two periods | 1 i332_ 163.59 Lot A and Lot B, 12 cows fed bran in grain ration 30 days Lot A— 6 cows —32 3972.5 144.34 Lot B— 6 cows 128 4244.0 158.36 Total— 12 cows | 96 8216.5 302.70 Lot A and Lot B, 12 cows fed alfalfa in grain ration 30 days Lot A— 6 cows 223 3952.5 138.75 Lot B— 6 cows i 1 4332.0 163.59 Total— 12 cows f 224 8284.5 302.31 Total results from Lot A and Lot B Lot A— 6 cows, 60 days I 191 7925 283.09 Lot B— 6 cows, 60 days I 129 8576 321.95 Total— 12 cows .... I 320 | 16501 605.04 Total results from bran and from alfalfa Bran —60 days 96 8216.5 302.70 Alfalfa— 60 days I 224 8284.5 302.34 Total 320 I 16501.0 605.04 Difference in favor of alfalfa | 128 68 — .36 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 16 U LA I LA © | I OLQOkfi NH CQ CO © OS LO I&gt; a T ■* TT IMrt^lOJ ft ]i S3 i 39 WW Out I 1O 22 °* i cot-co c S "a id © co &lt;n od cc e4 oo cc id tj« Tt oc tt 3 us t» us oi o o &lt;&lt;j" ig to t- ei £ * io q o us o us io wlooololoo AOO « rt « Tf CC CC N * " I CO — - s o o -« =- "3 M Ba* 9 «» •^ -&lt; o ss s* o 5 i 00 00 CC t- CO C^l CO O O O &lt;N 00 i-H A OJ J| O»«»i0t-0 i JtJ'D?0000^hS'-i q a - B w w « w m i* *- ' j^prccaoHiCH ■3 LOiAioooLoq qoiaioooo g ooooNccgis co ao ej i-&lt; us 1-! &lt;-&lt; £ N eg co in co ** c» (N eg eg co c- co « i- 1 eg a. « a ji oisoiaoLOio LQioqioioqo ■3 t~ tn 6 ia 10 0 JB 06 eo co 10 eg e» eg »! co 00 1- 1- &lt;o eg 2 us co us i-c -h 10 co eg eg co eg ■»• o eg eg eg co t- co &lt;h w LOLOLOCJC&gt;IO LQ LO LO 1A LQ LO O S 00 go to 06 ■* eo J£ 00 co 10 eg 00 e4 •-&lt; E 10 00 &lt;e «D 00 O &lt;P 00 co 91 eg o c~ eg M egegcoeg-^'j'O eg eg eg co t- co eg -N * a * I 3 I •a isoioqaioa a oqaouioe •g n g- d eo 10 ig us *oinoiodt&gt;&lt;N^ r^ »-t '-t 00 HHC4H0O </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Chopped Alfalfa vs. Bran for Dairy Cows 9 SECOND TEST Table 3. — Chopped Alfalfa vs. Bran in Grain Ration for Dairy Cows. Grain ration: U parts chopped corn, 2 parts bran or chopped alfalfa, 1 part oil meal. March 1, 1917, to May 30, 1917—90 days Change in SJB3 «- JSH., Lot A, 5 cows [ Pounds ' Pounds I Pounds Bran ration First period, March 1 to 15 53 2734.0 87.71 T^iwl nAM/u] Anvil 1 +n 1 ~. ~". Q£A£ K QafiA Third period, April 1 to 15 75 2506.5 90.60 Fifth period, May 1 to 15 —131 2190.0 71.81 7K Fifth period, May 1 to 15 —131 Total of three periods —3 7430.5 250.12 Alfalfa ration Second period, March 16 to 30 ] 29 2620.0 89 Fourth period, April 16 to 30 — 2 2300.0 81.89 Sixth period, May 16 to 30 —79 2227.0 73.37 Total of three periods ] —52 7147.0 245.03 Lot B, 5 cows Bran ration Second period, March 16 to 30 27 2592 87.60 Fourth period, April 16 to 30 1 12 2431 80.97 Sixth period, May 16 to 30 1 —164 2216 72.21 Total of three periods | —125 | 7239 240.78 Alfalfa ration First period, March 1 to 15 105 2695 83.92 Third period, April 1 to 15 | 116 2455 81.77 Fifth period, May 1 to 15 —153 2159 73.13 Total of three periods | 68 | 7309 238.82 Lot A and Lot B, 10 cows fed bran in grain ration 45 days A— 5 cows i —3 7430.5 250.12 B— 5 cows —125 7239.0 240.78 Total— 10 cows —128 14669.5 490.90 Lot A and Lot B, 10 cows fed alfalfa in grain ration 45 days A— 5 cows —52 7147.0 245.03 B— 5 cows | 68 7309.0 238.82 Total— 10 cows , 16 14456.0 483.85 Total results from Lot A and Lot B A— 5 cows, 90 days —55 14582 495.15 B— 5 cows, 90 days I —57 I 14548 479.60 Total— 10 cows —112 29130 974.76 Total results from bran and from alfalfa Bran —90 days —128 14669.5 490.90 Alfalfa— 90 days I 16 I 14456.0 483.85 Total —112 29125.5 974.75 Difference in favor of bran — 144 213.5 7.05 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska 164 Webraska Experiment Station Bulletin £ I O LA LA O LA IA LA LA 2 w coco &lt;c la la &lt;c t~ SrtlA t- N h IS 01 0 &lt; ' •"• «H »H ,-H "e a ®P ® us 10 © " | 22? 5 §1 8 8 lOOitqo © ftiSOOO u- i J* UlAOOt' •« 0) LA tA &lt;O tA C4 •&lt; — f&gt;H *-• 1-H i— " 1H t* »-^*-&lt;f-^»-( t- CJC O Tf O IA W N 1A LA A -C »o c x cc •— &lt;N oo rc xk^ooh o J, B «t-ONt- O^lOlAW CO O TgrHrH^-lrtr-1 t- &lt;h M M &lt;1 M t- "— ■ -J eeOlAlA p IAIAiAIOLA IA &gt;• X 00 04 US 9» t&gt; C4 W &lt;© l&gt; &lt;0 00 5 ■ *9'"9* '•-• g'SLOppo | e -a: £ m "a ~T &lt;c o&gt; oi x te uai o&gt; — oi i- tc d&lt; ; § _1! n _ « i "«"o S e ? e !9 lft . u ? ® 'S u ? u ?"?9 a ; "? ~* * "• 3 eoS«w 5 M « 1 1- o&gt; l?S to U3LSOOO O LAppOlA O isqurois us p p p p p p £ piftpp© in eepeu: us •&gt;fiCOUS«!USM M CINNICI- » VIACC^W (0 W IA U5 Ift U5 LA eqeeia la p la a la la la S IT 6 00 t" t* 00 O!4t*CC&gt;* LA I 8 * 'SSS3SS I JSSSSS | </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Chopped Alfalfa vs. Bran for Dairy Cows 11 Table 5. — Results of feeding a grain ration of corn k parts, bran 2 parts, and oil meal 1 part; or corn U parts, chopped alfalfa 2 parts, and oil meal 1 part, to 22 cows 75 days. 'SIS — ;ButUrr.« Bran ration I Pounds Pounds I Pounds Eleven cows, 75 days I —32 22,885 793.6 Alfalfa ration Eleven cows, 75 days I 240 22,741 786.1 Increase from alfalfa. I 272 Increase from bran 144 7.5 [7-10-'l»— 10M1 </seg>
          </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>