<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Variety Tests of Oats, Barley, and Spring Wheat</title>
               <date value="1931-03">1931-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 253 March, 1931 Variety Tests of Oats, Barley, and Spring Wheat T. A. KIESSELBACH AND W. E. LYNESS THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION . LINCOLN W. W: IH-rr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY The acreages of the three principal spring small-grain crops grown in Nebraska in 1930 were: oats, 2,485,000 acres; barley, 725,000 acres; and spring wheat,' 188,000 acres. The outstanding change in acreage among the spring small grains in this state has been the threefold increase in barley acreage during the last three years. The increased popularity of this crop can be ascribed largely to the introduction of superior varieties, to the greater use of the combine in harvesting, and to a growing appreciation of its relatively high productivity and feed value. The importance of growing well-adapted varieties is illustrated by a 15 per cent superiority during a 24-year period in the average grain yield of three standard early varieties as compared with four late - maturing varieties of oats. Nebraska No. 21 and Burt C. I. 293 are the most extensively grown varieties of oats. Certified seed of both is available in large quantities. During an eight-year period, their yield has averaged 3 per cent more than that of Kherson. Several more recently developed selections not . yet available for distribution have given evidence of greater superiority. A number of relatively new smooth-awned varieties of barley intro - duced from other states have proved very desirable for Nebraska conditions. This type predominates in eastern Nebraska where harvest - ing methods require the handling of sheaf grain. Smooth beards eliminate much annoyance and greatly increase the feeding value of the straw.' In the western portion of the state where grain is ex - tensively harvested ' with the combine, rough-bearded barley pre - dominates. Among the smooth-awned sorts, Comfort and Glabron are most ex - tensively grown and have yielded approximately 20 per cent more than the Common Six-row, which was largely grown prior to their introduction. Trebi has proved unsurpassed during eight years of testing by the Experiment Station and is decidedly the most popular of the rough-awned sorts. Other more recently introduced varieties ■ arc .promising. Ceres Has proved the most desirable of the spring-wheat varieties available for production in this state. During four years, it has yielded 18 per cent more grain per acre than Marquis. Its yield rather closely approximates that of the durum varieties. This fact together with a lower market value of the durum grain would seem to justify a more extensive substitution of Ceres for the durum varieties. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Variety Tests of Oats, Barley, and Spring Wheat T. A. KIESSKLIIACH and W. E. LYNESS The use of superior varieties is of first importance in the production of spring small grains. The comparative merits of the different crops and their available varieties may be best determined through tests extending over a period of years. Tests of oats, barley, and spring 1 wheat have been made on the Experiment Station Farm of the Nebraska College of Agri - culture at Lincoln. 1 Similar tests preceding 1923 were re - ported in Nebr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 201. Most of the less-promis - ing sorts were discontinued in 1923. The plan has been to have these variety trials include the most promising sorts obtainable from Nebraska and other states. Most of the varieties grown have originated in the breeding experiments of various state and federal experiment stations. A number of standard varieties have been retained to serve as a measure with which to compare the newer sorts. DISTRIBUTION AND IMPORTANCE OF THE VARIOUS SMALL GRAINS The distribution and acreages of the various spring small grains and of winter wheat are shown in the four accompany - ing maps. According to the 1930 crop report of the Nebraska State and Federal Division of Agricultural Statistics, the acre - ages of oats, barley, and spring wheat were respectively 2,485,000, 725,000, and 188,000 acres. The acreage of oats has remained fairly constant during the last ten years, while that of spring wheat has lowered approximately 25 per cent. Spring wheat- has been giving way to winter wheat. The acreage devoted to barley has increased nearly threefold in the last four years — from 246,000 acres in 1927 to 725,000 in 1930. This change is due to the introduction of superior varieties, the increased use of the combine, and to a growing recognition of the high productivity and feed value of this crop. . OATS ADAPTATION The most important principle to bear in mind in the choice of oats varieties to be grown in this state is that the climatic conditions normally favor the early-maturing sorts. The late varieties are at a distinct disadvantage because danger from heat, drouth, and rust increases as the season progresses. • These varietal comparisons have been made in standard field plats approximating 1 30-acre areas and replicated annually two to five times according to the amount of land available. . The plats were the width of a craiii drill and could be harvested with one swath of the binder. Uniform cultural practices have been maintained to insure comparable results. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin. 253 Fl( V'~T? a i tS di8tril &gt;ution &gt; .1930. Total production, 2,485,000 acres This is quite in contrast with the more northerly oats regions, LvSr S n f a N a&gt; K Vh ? ? e late - mat «"ng sorts are in greater^ Si ; a rL«« • T ka i fa T ers in * eneral should avoid these Table 1 clearly shown by the results reported in «»«te ? Sr i y vai : iet . ies have b een compared during 24 years with four late-maturing sorts. The Kherson, Burt, and Texas 5&amp;42Bte aWra| $$* M - 8 bUSh6lS Per aCre &gt; « ~"p5S 8 Sill- I Q b V Sl l els * as t} ? e avera « e for the four late varieties Swedish Select, American Banner, University No. 6, and FlG Ff;"T^ a f rley distri 1 bu t i ° n . 19 30. Total production, 725,000 acre* Each dot represents 1,000 acres. Data supplied bv Nebraska StatV and Federal Division of Agricultural Statistics ebraska Sta^ . . ' • • :•■ .■• ■ - : </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Variety Tests of Spring Small Grains FIG. 3.— Spring wheat distribution, 1930. Total production, 188,000 acres. Each dot represents 1,000 acres. Data supplied by Nebraska State and Federal Division of Agricultural Statistics. Lincoln. Considered as a group, the early sorts ripened an average of six days in advance of the late varieties and yielded 7.6 bushels per acre or 15 per cent more. Although the seed of these varieties has been grown con - tinuously at the Experiment Station for 26 years, no tendency for the two groups to become more similar has been noted. The less-adapted sorts have not tended to become better ac - climated because of long-continued growing under these con - ditions. COMPARISON OF VARIETIES OF OATS The annual and average yields obtained from 32 varieties Fig. 4. — Winter wheat distribution, 1930. Total production, 3,622,000 acres. Each dot represents 1,000 acres. Data supplied by Nebraska State and Federal Division of Agricultural Statistics. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 253 Table 1. — Early vs. late-maturing varieties of oats — tiventy - four-year average, 1905-1918 and 1920-1929 Average Type of oats time of Yield per acre ripening i Date Bushels j" Per cent Three standard early varieties 1 7,7 50.3 100 ■ Four standard late varieties- 7 13 ■ 42.6 • .85 Difference i . . 6 days ! 7.5 15 'The early varieties consisted of Kherson, Burt, and Texas' Kcd. The latter variety has been grown under this name for many years and differs from Ked Texas of southern states. It somewhat resembles Burt. 3 The late varieties included Swedish Select, American Banner, Lincoln, and University No. 0 (Minn. Agr. Exp. Sta. No. 6). tested during the last eight years are reported in Table 2. Some of these have not been grown throughout the entire period but were added as they gained prominence either in our own small-grain-improvement nursery or elsewhere. The last column in the table shows the yield of each variety in percentage of the yield of ordinary Kherson oats for the same years. Selections from the Kherson variety. — It will be noted that ten selections made by various state or federal experiment stations from Kherson oats have been included in the test. The range in yield among these has been from a decrease of 2 per cent to an increase of 5 per cent, as compared with the original variety. Nebraska No. 21 averaged 3 per cent better than Kherson. This is the only one of this group which is being grown extensively in Nebraska. Its grain is white, whereas that of the original Kherson is yellow. There have been no material differences in the yields of related Nebraska selections. Other outstanding sorts are Iowar and Iogold, which were developed by the Iowa Experiment Station, and Edkin and Kherson No. C. I. 459, which were distributed by the U. S. Department of Agriculture. The Iogold and Edkin are characterized by a high degree of resistance to stem rust. Selections from the Burt variety. — There is somewhat greater promise in a number of the new Burt selections. Although these have been tested for only two years in field plots, their previous record in nursery tests substantiates their apparent superiority over both the original Burt and the original Kherson. The best of this group of seven relatively new Burt selections surpassed the Kherson by 15 per cent and the poorest was 3 per cent better. While seed of none of </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Table 2. — Oats varieties — comparative results in field tests — eight years; 1923-1930 Summary 1U2!M93O Yield of grain per acre . Variety of' • I Annual Average „„.,! •! Dale- Date Test r I — : in • ripe Height weight . • Act- Rela - head 1923 1924 1925 192G 1927 1928 1929 1930 ual Jtive &lt;&lt; In. Ikt. III'. flu. Hit. liu. llu. Ilii. flu. Ilu. 111,. P.rl. h (1) (2) . (3) I (1) (5) I (6) (7) (8) (9) (10) (U) (12) .(IS). (11) (15) (16) G KHERSON ■ . S Kherson (common) Nebr 6/10 7/5 35 32.1 66.4 42.fi 27.0 11.5 44.6 43.5 62.0 70.5 46.0 100 3 Nebr No 5 Nebr. .. fi/9 7/3 .34 32.2 69.fi 45.8 26.8 1-0.2 45.8 39.6 65.2 71.7 46.8 102 "• Nebr'No'21 •'" ' Nebr 6/11 7/4 31 32.9 66.O 1 49.7 28.5 11.1 47.3 41.7 66.7 69.6 47.6 103 .j Nebr. No 23 Nebr 6,9 7/3 34 33.3 68.9 49.4 29.5 12.0 42.5 42.3 69.0 64.7 47.3 103 £&gt; Nebr No 33 ' " Nebr. .... 6/9 7/3 34 33.2 68-1 48.0 27.6 10.7 43.7 46.0 68.5 66.8 47.5 ■ 103 £ C I No 459 U.S. I). A.... 6/10 7/4 . 33- 32.9 70.1. 45.7 29.5' 10.2 47.5 45.5 69.4 70.2 48.5 105 £j Iowa No' 103 . ..'. Iowa 6/9 7/3 34 33-1 69.7 47.2 23.9 8.8 42.1 38.3 62.2 70.2 45.3 98 w l ow ,, r Iowa . .. 6/13 7/4 34 ' 31.7 70.7 47.2 26.6 9.8 52.0 41.1 64.3 66.3 47.3 103 Gonher Minn. ... 6/11 7/5 34 32.8 60.2 43.7 27.1 10J 50.9 40.7 66.2 72.2 46.4 101 O IoeoM .... Iowa 6/10 7/4 33 32.5 47.3 42.5 68.5 71.3 .... 104 "*! E&amp;iSn.'.'.'... U.S. D.A... . 6/11 7/4 31 34.4 .... 65.7 71.4 .... 103 Burt (common) : .... Nebr 6/6 7/3 34 33.7 69.9 42.2 28.8 8.8 43.6 42.9 64.1 76.1 4-7.1 102 2 C I No 293 . " .. U.S. D.A.... 6/8 7/3 34 36.2 70.8 47.7 24.9 9.1 '45.3 44.4 66.8 74.4 47.9 104 S Nebr.No.517 Nebr 6/7 7/3 35 32.9 , 71.6 80.4 .... 115 Z Nebr. No: 218.... Nebr 6/6 7/1 36 34.2 ■ 65.9 69.0 .... 109 n Nebr. No. 519 Nebr 6/8 7/1 36 35.4 68.9 72.7 .... 107 NebrNo.520 Nebr 6/8 7/2 34 35.2. .... 69.9 75.7 .... 110 K) Nebr. No. 521 Nebr 6/6 7/2 35 33.4 ' 64.5 78.1 .... 108 g C I No 2491 '.. U.S.I). A.... 6/7 6/30 33 34.0 ....' .... .... 67.1 69.7 .... 103 ? Akron No. 6076-16 U.S. I). A... 6/8 7/4 34 35.1 .... 69.9 75.5 .... 110 j5 MISCELLANEOUS EARLY VARIETIES f 1 Texas Rod Nebr 6/10 7/5 34 33.8 68.4 41.6 27.9 10.7 48.5 45.1 66.6 72.7 47.7 104 K»nota " Kan 6/11 7/5 33 35.3 71.7 30.1 23.6 9.9 45.3 33.9 61.3 70.4 43.3 94 Q Red Rust Proof ■■'■■ Mo 6/12 7/7 37 33.2 65.4 30.2 29.5 13.5 46.9 43.6 60.4 67.2 44.6 97 Sj Alaska .....:.: Canada 6/8 7/1 39 37.7 30.1 49.4 72.5 .... 86. £ MISCELLANEOUS LATE VARIETIES K Swedish Select .... Nebr 6/16 7/9 37 31.3 63.5 29.3 29.7 14.0 46.9 47.9 602 56 3 42.1 91 f&gt; RedAleerian ■■•■• Kan 6/10 7/8 35 32.8 49.6 24.5 27.7 11.6 48.4 39.9 64.2 64.5 40.0 87 w Green Russian' ..'. Nebr 6/16 7/8 36 31.8 61.7 27.1 26.7 10.3 52.9 45 2 62.2 62.4 42.3 92 Wren .. .. Iowa 6/17 7/8 36 32.3 26.4 8.6 Ah2 46.3 49.3 692 .... 91 MaSton ' U.S. D.A... . 6/16 7/8 36 32.9 12.3 44.6 42.1 48.2 68.3 .... 93 NewVictory' Nebr 6/18 7/13 38 34.8 53.7 46.7 .... 75 HULLESS" Liberty I Minn I 6/10 I 7/4 I 37 I 45.4 I .... I 31.7 I 32.4 I 9.4 I 43J I 42.9 I 59.4 I 77.7 I .... I 98 S.Dak.'No.'7. I S. Dak I 6/7 | 7/3 | 35 I 41.7 | .... | .... I .... I .... I 52.4 | 47.7 | 61.7 | 75.7 | .... | 108 ■The yield* of hulless oats have been calculated on the basis of 30 per cent hull and 32 pounds per bushel. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 253 '7^|^V^^^^^P^9^^^^^^^^^£M^^ tit' 4 "' '' - ' *~ ' ' ' ■ - ' '^^Aiti^Ej^^DBBSIfim^ftiSIESmfiEflff Fig. 5.— Test of oats varieties. Left, Nebraska No. 21; center, Burt ?i : N R f 9 o : r al Vi ri 5no' Burt C - L No - 293 - The Nebraska No. fl and Burt C. I. N,o. 293 are the most extensively grown varieties in this state. these is now available commercially, it is probable that several will be increased for co-operative tests on farms • The common Burt has been grown at the Nebraska station since 1905 while tike Burt G. I. 293 was obtained from the experimental farm at Amarillo, Texas, in 1916. The Burt C I. 293 variety is being rather extensively grown on Nebraska Table 3.— Average yield of selections from Kherson oats i?i comparison ivith the original Kherson and other earlii varieties — 14 years, 1916-1918 and^ 1920-1 930. ■ I ■ . ~~ \ •.■■• . ■ ,.]•■ . . Yield per acre Variety _^ Actual I Relative Kherson, Nebraska Common... .. 8 P ZZ e ? 1 Kherson, Nebraska No. 5 Igo jSo? Kherson, Nebraska No. 21 4«d 12f? Kherson ; Nebraska No. 23.... i H% Jnf-i Kherson, Nebraska No. 33 ; 404 JS12 Kherson, Iowa No. 103... . 479 jmi Iowar ' ■ ****** ±\t i.i Kheraon,'c.'L No.' 459 '.'.y.'. .7 i 47a inti' Burt, Nebraska Common........ 470 joni Burt, C. I. No. 293 400 }nA TexasRed fA K Kanota; , \ \ \ \ \ _\ \ [ [ [ ; ; ; ; ; ; ; j 48 - 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Variety Tests of Spring Small Grains farms, having been distributed from the Agricultural College in 1927. With the exception of a small percentage of black kernels, the grain is white. It has been hand-picked several times to reduce the proportion of dark seed. The U. S. Department of Agriculture selection known as Burt C. I. 2491 is the earliest-maturing sort of oats grown in the Nebraska field-plat tests, and appears to be extremely lodge resistant. It would seem to merit trial under conditions where oats are subject to severe lodging, such as fertile bottom lands or following legume crops. Miscellaneous varieties. — While most of the promising varieties tested have been of Kherson or Burt origin, a num - ber of others, some of which have gained prominence here or elsewhere, have been included in the tests. The most pro - ductive of these is a reddish-grained variety which has been grown at the Nebraska station under the name of Texas Red for about thirty years. This must not be confused with the late-maturing Red Rust Proof grown in southern states. Because of its dark color and failure to excel in yield, it does not seem to merit farm distribution. Although Kanota has proved admirably suited to Kansas, where it was distributed by the Experiment Station several years ago, it has averaged only 94 per cent as high in yield as Kherson in the Nebraska tests during eight years. This variety normally requires very early planting (Table 4) for best results. Seed of the Alaska variety was obtained from the Macdonald College, Canada, in 1928. Although the yield has been 14 per cent below that of Kherson, it is quite outstanding in that it ripens unusually early and yet is the tallest growing of all the different sorts tested. Markton* developed in Oregon, is dis - tinctive in that it has proved entirely resistant to local smut throughout the five years that it has been tested in this state. It might be. of value for trial wherever medium-late varieties such as Green Russian and Iogren are in favor. Victory is a popular Canadian variety recently brought to this state by a local seedhoiise. It ripens altogether too late for Nebraska conditions and yields only 75 per cent as much as Kherson. Hulless oats. — Two varieties which thresh free from hull, as does wheat, have been tested for several years. One of these, known as South Dakota No. 7, has yielded 8 per cent more than Kherson during a four-year period, with allowance made for 30 per cent of hull, which is the approximate per - centage for Kherson and similar varieties. In case the feed value of hulless oats proves satisfactory, such a high-yielding variety may be attractive as a special-purpose crop. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Table A.— Difference in response of Nebraska No. 21 and of Kanota oats in a time-of -planting a .____ _t_ e sf— three years, 1928 to 1930 £ Yield of grain per acre Date , M Variety Date in Date Height Test Annual Average * planted head ripe weight — - r 1 ___ ■ 1928 1929 1930 Actual Relative g In- Lbs. lin. Ru. /?». Hit. P. ct. M (1) ' I (2) (3) (41 (5)' (6) (7) (8) ■ (9) (10) (11)' 2 1 PLANTED EARLY H Nebraska No. 21 J 3/16 | 6/7 I 7/5:. 33 32.0 [ 46.4 I. 80.1 | 59.9 I 62.1 I 100 E? Kanota | 3/16 | 6/3 I 7/1 [ 31 |. 36.5 | 43.2 j 75.0 | 68.6 | 62.3 100 &gt; PLANTED MEDIUM EARLY S Nebraska No. 21 .' 3/30 ! 6/12 7/6 j 32 -I 32.7 48.3 76.4 58.5 ' 61.1 100 | Kanota . | 3/30 6/9 7/6 31 34.5 42.7 76.3 58.2 59.1 97 PLANTED MEDIUM LATE W Nebraska No. 21 .; .4/10 I 6/16 7/8 | 31 32.7 49.6 71.2 I 52 2 57 7 100 Kanota | 4/10 | 6/13 7/10 30 33.0 48.6 70.5 52.7 57^ 99 S PLANTED LATE H Nebraska No. 21.. 4/21 j 6/19 7/13 31 i 30.9 53.7 55.3 50.7 53 2 100 2 Kanota. ■■■■■■■■■..,■... 4/21 ' 6/19 ,7/14 30. 31.6 574 . 50.4 36.9 48.2 91 i ■■ . •■ 03 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Variety Tests of Spring Small Grains RECOMMENDED VARIETIES Of all the varieties tested by the Nebraska Experiment Station, Nebraska No. 21 and Burt C. I. 293 oats are the only sorts that are extensively grown on Nebraska farms. As shown in Table 3, these have ranked highest in yield during the period, 1916-1930. The Nebraska No. 21 should prove somewhat more lodge resistant than the Burt in case of severe lodging conditions. While several others are about equally productive, they do not merit substitu - tion on the basis of present indications. These will be con - tinued for a number of years, together with other promis - ing new selections which are about to be advanced from the nursery breeding plats to the larger field tests. An ex - tensive oat-breeding program is maintained at this station which, together with similar work at other state and federal institutions, should prove a continual source of new improved varieties. ' VARIETAL RESPONSE TO TIME OF PLANTING Comparative tests of Nebraska No. 21 and Kanota oats planted during each of the last three years at early, medium, and late dates indicate a rather striking difference in varietal response to such treatment (Table 4). As an average for the period the Kanota has ripened four days earlier than Ne - braska No. 21 when planted early in March, and one day later when planted April 21. Although the yields have varied somewhat with the seasons i he averages for the period indicate a greater advantage from early planting in the case of Kanota. In 1930, Kanota sur - passed Nebraska No. 21 by 8.7 bushels per acre when sown early in March, while it yielded 13.8 bushels less than Ne - braska No. 21 when sown near the middle of April. As an average for the three years, the two varieties yielded equally when sown early, while the Nebraska No. 21 excelled by five bushels per acre, or 10 per cent, when sown late Both varieties decreased in yield with delayed planting, but the Kanota more than the Nebraska No. 21, These differences in behavior may be associated with their respective winter and spring growth habits, since the Kanota is typical y a southern-grown winter variety and is less suited to normal northern conditions. BARLEY ADAPTATION The adaptation of barley to Nebraska conditions is much better established now that decidedly superior varieties have ?non &lt;it veloped ? nd distri buted for farm use. Prior to about 1920 the prevailing varieties were Common Six-ro,w, Man- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 253 churian (Minnesota 184), and Oderbrucker. These three sorts ar !i n u 0^. surp f ssed 15 to 20 P er cent b y a number of improved and better adapted varieties which are of recent origin and have come into extensive farm use since that time Their introduction was an important stimulus to the increase of «frfJ ey VQ^ ea^uM Om , on , e - tenth to nearlv one-third that of oats since 1927. While barley appears, to be a suitable crop wher - ever oats are grown, its relatively more extensive production in western Nebraska suggests a special adaptation in that Barley grown in this state is used largely as feed for live - stock. Feeding experiments recently reported by W J l^oeffel - of the Animal Husbandry Department indicate that the coarsely ground grain has 84 per cent of the feeding value of shelled corn, pound for pound, when fed to hogs. Because of its early ripening this crop may provide a satisfactory corn substitute far in advance of the time that corn matures ,ro^«f u e re . cent development of the smooth-awned Rn»2!l 8&gt; barle y St^w has been considered objectionable. Rough awns or beards are likely to injure the : mouths of live - stock, and may cause much annoyance in the handling of sheaf gram or straw, Straw of the smooth-awned sorts is a satisfactory roughage and approaches oats straw in value. COMPARISON OF BARLEY VARIETIES The results from testing 23 varieties of barley at the Ex- T«w me K a *? dur j n * the last seven years are reported in X e J- . An effo , rt has been made to bring together in this collection the most promising varieties available for this state Jwn^" 3 I a y f al1 ln e° three rough-awned, smooth - awned, and awnless. Some of these have been grown during ffl 2 '8? rtlO1 L of 4*^ peri0d ' Since Co ""non Six-row was in - cluded throughout the test, it is used in the last column of the v» • V 8 f basis &lt; 100 P^ cent) for evaluating the other varieties during the years that they, were grown . twT 7fe " ( l W;ned variet i es — Four of the rough-awned varieties pi }*%? b *?- en gr i OW - n i, or the entire six years, namely, Odessa, Coast Trebi and McClymont, yielded from 17 to 25 per cent 3n th £ Comm ° n S^-row. The McClymont, which is a Lincoln county variety, is exceptionally lodge susceptible A Sta'tfoTFfr^'f by Nort \ Pla * te ' Nebraska, E^perimeni fetation Farm from McClymont and known as North Platte No 1 yielded very well in the one-year test. Of the varieties Treif vfS ft** h T b - e I n tested durin * the entire perSd! irebi yielded the most with a 25 per cent greater yield than Common Slx - r &lt;™ This is a comparatively g stiff-st/awed Sd 'See Nebr. Exp. Sta. Bulletin 261. -Barley a. Hog Feed. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Table 5.— Barley va neties—c^i^arative- results in field tests— six years, 192J-19S0 ' . ' • Summary 1928-1930 Yield of grain per acre ~ Annual Average &gt; Variety .. ,„ Source Date ' Lodging - . Act . Rela . g ,,°!d_ head ripe hefght 1928 | 1930 wght _!«*_ _jgj JgL JJgj JgL jgi J!^. Jl!f- J* ■ (1) (2) (3) (4) (5) (6) |(7) (8) (9, (10) (11) (12, (13) (M) («) d«&gt; H HOUGH-AWNED VARIETIES • . " • g |5^-: jjfiSilf] II I II II III ill ! McClymont, North Plane No. 1 . Nebr .. •• 1* : 48 , ' ,,9 g Horn Mont •• ' ■ £, SMOOTH-AWNED VARIETIES Q I H till Hi I BonAmi Ohio. 6/8 7/6 36 5 0 47.6 n3 KlSiL : » ::: :: wg-:::::::: W, ?» S «? , £S :::: :;:: :::: " ■« «j - :: &gt;g fe 1 gSS^ 1 ::::::::::::::: Elailr 8 :::: ::■:: :::.: :: :: ? :::s :::: : :: :::: ;"■ ■■■■ ™ ■■ 129 \ AWNLESS VARIETIES S 'Crop de»troyed by chinch bugs in 1926. The yield« of hulle» btrley have been calculated on the basis of 16 per cent hull, and 48 pounds per bushel. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 253 very productive variety developed by the U. S. Department of Agriculture. It has come to be the most widely grown barley in the western half of Nebraska. Although at first recom - mended only for irrigated land in western Nebraska, it has also proved especially well suited for dry-land culture in all parts of the state. The rough awns are not so much of a factor in the western portion of the state where combine harvesting is more common. . Fig. 6. — Comparison of varieties of barley. Left, Flynn; ctnter. Spartan; right, Comfort. During the three years, 1928-1930, the respective yields of these varieties have averaged 50.2, 47.5, and 48.7 bushels per acre. Smooth-awned vari-eties. — During the last few years, the smooth-awned type of barley has come to predominate in the eastern half of Nebraska. This is quite remarkable when one recalls that the first tests in this state were made by the Ex - periment Station in 1923. Of the eleven smooth-awned vari - eties grown in 1930, five have been included in the tests since 1924, while the other six have been added at various times since. Most of these have recently originated as hybrids in the breeding nurseries of several state experiment stations and the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Of the smooth-awned varieties tested for six years, Comfort and Minnesota No. 450 have been outstanding in yield. These have averaged 19 and 25 per cent higher yield than the Com - mon Six-row. The Comfort was distributed for farm use in 1927 because of its somewhat smoother awns and greater uni - formity as to type. Another selection of the Comfort which does not grow quite so tall and whose yields averaged 1 per </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Variety Tests of Spring Small Grains cent more during. a two-year comparison, 1928 and 1929, has also been distributed within the state. These have come to be designated as Tall Comfort and Short Comfort. The former ripens somewhat later, is more lodge resistant and smoother awned, and is the type grown in other states as Comfort. Flynn is. the earliest-ripening variety of the entire collec - tion. Although it has averaged only 13 per cent better yield during the six years than that of Common Six-row, it was the highest-yielding variety in 1930. The climatic conditions of that year especially favored the early-ripening sorts. This short, . stiff -strawed, early-maturing variety should probably be tested more extensively in the state. - HiiiMiii ' hi in I 1 1 Mi \ I 1 1 iTHFlffffiii TFHPr Fig. 7. — New varieties of barley are continually being introduced from other states and compared with standard local varieties. Left, \ elvet ; center, Ezond ; right, Vaughan. The last two were first grown here in 1930, when these three varieties gave the respective yields of 28.1), 52.1, and 51.8 bushels, as compared with 47.7 bushels for Comfort and 48.3 bushels for Trebi. The Glabron variety" is a decidedly stiff-strawed, tall Min - nesota selection with extremely smooth beards. It ripens at about the same time as Comfort. During the four years that it has been grown in these tests, it has yielded 23 per cent more than the Common Six-row. It has a strong tendency to shed its beards when ripe and should be cut when still slightly green in order to avoid shattering. The Spartan is a very attractive Michigan hybrid of the two-row type. Its average yield for the last three years has been 13 per cent above Common Six-row. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 253 A high-yielding variety known as White Barbless. No. 37 from Wisconsin has proved rather lodge susceptible on very fertile soils. The Vaughan and Ezond varieties obtained from the California and Idaho Experiment Stations and tested here for the first time in 1930 exhibited attractive vegetative characteristics and yielded 128 and 129 per cent of the Com - mon Six-row. Awnless varieties. — Hulless barley which threshes free from the chaff the same as wheat is not suited to Nebraska con - ditions. In the six-year test, it has yielded only 76 per cent as much as Common Six-row, with a 15 per cent allowance made for the hull. Colsess is an early-maturing, stiff -stra wed, hooded, hybrid selection made by the Colorado Experiment Station. It has averaged 14 per cent better than the Common Six-row for the last six years. So far as is known, awned varieties in general surpass the awnless sorts with respect to yield. RECOMMENDED VARIETIES The varieties recommended by the Nebraska Station as out - standingly productive under Nebraska conditions are Trebi, Comfort, and Glabron. Certified seed of all of these is avail - able in large quantities from members of the Nebraska Crop Growers' Association, which has its central office at Lincoln. The Trebi is especially popular under irrigation. But it is also unsurpassed in productivity under dry-land conditions elsewhere in the state. Trebi may be regarded as better suited for combine harvesting than any other available sort. Comfort has given satisfaction wherever handling of the sheaf grain is required and where the straw is needed for feed. The relative merits of the tall and short types of this variety have ' not yet been fully established. Both are extensively grown and have yielded exceptionally well. Glabron has been the latest of the smooth-awned varieties to be distributed in its home state, Minnesota, where it is recognized as unsur - passed. The splendid performance of this variety in Nebraska tests gives it a very favorable endorsement. Undoubtedly we may expect still greater improvements in the group of smooth-awned barley varieties since their de - velopment has been of such recent origin. SPRING WHEAT ADAPTATION Spring wheat is better suited to western and northern Ne - braska than to any other part of the state. Even there it is gradually giving way to winter wheat, which is more pro - ductive. The medium-early varieties are better adapted than </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Variety Tests of Spring Small Grains fa^Sot^Vf 6 S -° rtS - T^, s m £ y be wdl illustrated by the tact that the late-ripening Blue Stem variety (Table 6) has yielded only 69 per cent as much as Marquis during eight rfnJn'H ?O ?* Prelude &lt;**** 7 &gt;&gt; which has ripened 10 days earlier than Marquis, has yielded only 80 per cent as much as Marquis. VARIETIES OF SPRING WHEAT Awnless varieties.— Marquis was for many years regarded as the leading variety in both Canada and the United States FWH™ t C &lt;° t mmon sp . rin * wheats teste &lt;* at the Nebraska Experiment Station prior to 1925, it was surpassed only bv Kearney, which is a bearded variety. A more recently de - veloped ear y-maturing variety known as Garnet has been distributed in Canada and has been tested in Nebraska. During Maquis T ** haS yieldCd 14 Per Cent mOre grain tha " Awned varieties. — A number of recently introduced awned S™1 ?w Q V\ en Promise of being well suited and pro - ahn &gt;t '" S* 8 st{ }t e - barney, Progress, and Java all appear about equally well adapted, and have yielded from 14 to 20 per cent above Marquis. The Kearney originated in 1911 as an unidentified early-maturing variety grown in Kearney siL U n fl Y v -pi!* ? r ° Ved . e **ptionally resistant to Hes - sian fly in 1930. The Java herein reported was grown from seed introduced into Colorado from Kearney Sunty £2 mTtm^l^ltb^ 61 , 7 / 686 "! 15168 the Kearney exce^ that h as S?iSS v Gr - In a " earlier test ' durin^ the years Ulfa to 1922, the Kearney ripened two to three days earlier l a o"hnTi r ° m S1X ° ther S0U^ ces and yielded approximately two bushels more per acre. Progress is a selection made by the Wisconsin Experiment Station from Java wheat Ceres a tp n n?v,,Tw y of hybrid ori si n w hich is rather resistant to stem-rust, has recently been distributed by the North Dakota feTv tation ' , Be^ se of its Performance In nSfnA lt , 1S + n ? W also bein .f ? rown as a certifi ed seed crop. During the last four years it has yielded 18 per cent more N a L^ r i5o 1S k. T fi T 4 Ot^ r M Pr TiT g North Dakota S e?ectk&gt; n ; gffig t 2 h 4 e a t n h d re 2 e 8 Per^^t y sTa r ti P on HOdS W been t-wPafu^S. A rather new variety by the name of Hope yielded onlv 73 ETlSo a^ UC f»." Ma -T S - in u^ e Ex Periment StSon test! m 1930. Since this variety is being exploited to some extent elsewhere its inferiority may well be borne in mind The chief </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Table 6. — Spring wheat varieties — comparative results in field tests — eight years, 1923-1930 a Summary 1927-1 0:iO ■ . Yield of grain per acre . W Source ■ . ■ — : : ■ ■ r? Variety of Annual Average i&gt; seed Date Date Plant Test — 1 — : in ripe Height weight I Act- Hela- ' \T\ head .1923 1924 11125 l!12li 1027 1928 1929 19:10 ual tive jxj In. y.(.«. llu. liu. Hu. Hu. tin. Hu. Hu. Hit. Hu. I'.cl. pd (1) . (2) (.'!)■ (I) ■ (5) I (6) (7) (8) (ill (10) (111 (12) (13) (14) (15) (IB) JO COMMON AWNLESS VARIETIES . g Marquis (home grown) '. . .! Nebr.. 6 10 7/11 35 I 57.4-1 18.S I 10.9 3.8 1 1.0 10.8 15.2 20.3 13.8 11.8 100 M Marquis (northern grown) Minn 0 16 7,11 3G 57JL 18.2 8.9 1.2 1.1 12.6 16.3 19.9 12.5 11.7 99 g Hluestem . Minn " 6,21 7/15 34 51.8 13.1 8.2 2.9 l.:l 5.6 14.2 15.1 4.6 8.2 69. ~ (Jarnot '..' .'. . Canada ... « x 7/6 33 RS.fl .. | 16.5 19.1 16.9 15.8 114 ■ COMMON AWNED VARIETIES Cfl Kearney I Nebr . ,1 fi'IO 7/7 I 35 57.8 19.6 I 12.:i | 6.5 2.1 14.3 11.4 16.4 22.0 13.5 1.14 H Preston : I Minn ..015 7/13 :I6 5!l.2 17.2 9.9 5.2 1.8 11.6 182 16.8 15.0 12.0 102 &gt; KoU C. I 6248.! •"•' U.S.h.A..'.. 6 16 7 11 36 58.9 13.1 8.1 2.9 0.6 7.0 13.0 15.9 13.7 9.3 79 £3 ProKresa Wis 6/13 7/9 36 60.0 4.9 1.2 15.3 16.8 18.5 16.8 .... 114 o Java ■'•'..'.'.'.'. Colo " ' 611 7,9' 36 57.9 2.Z 13.4 16.6 18.8 22.7 .... 120 ►£ Ceres '..'.'.'. '.'.'. N. Dak 6)13 7 11 -35 59.0 .... .... 15.8 1H.7 22.8 13.7 .... 119 N.D.1656.84 N.Dak... . .' ■! ■ 20.7 25.2 15.2 .... 124 w N.D.1650.48 N. Dak .... lT.b 128 g- Hope ..' S. Dak... . .. i .... .... I 10.1 .... '•' b) . DURUM VARIETIES . r Araautka C.I. 1493 .: Akron, Colo... 6.14 7/KI 39 59.8. 19.2 11.6 6.1! 2.2 15.6 19.2 25.6 18.9 14.9 126 K KubankaC. 1.14.0. Dickinson, .,,.,.,,, ,,,, ■ r9 ., „,, ,,, ,,, 12 . 7 ,„., 2r ,. o )8 . () ,.,., ,19 g Pellss North l'iatle 6/15 7 13 39 ■ 57.9 .7.9 | 5.4 _]J^ 114 17.7 23.4 18.5 .... U3_ . ■■■,• .■■•.•..■•;■- - ■ cn </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Variety Tests of Spring Small Grains Table 7. — Spring wheat varieties discontinued after 1929 Yield per acre, , . ; . Years relative to Marquis ; Variety in (100%) for time test in test Red fife..... 7 85 Red Bobs C. I. 6255 9 84 Red Bobs 222 , 3 80 Red Bobs Supreme *. 3 79 Early Triumph . . 3 81 Java, Lancaster Co^ ....:.... 15 97 Java, Minnesota 15 94 Prelude . 11 80 Norka C. I. 4377 ... 9 82 Romanow ■. ■. . . . 7 gl Sevier [.'. $ 72 merit of Hope wheat seems to be its extreme resistance to stem-rust, which makes it of special value as a parent in hybridization experiments. Durum varieties. — The Arnautka and Kubanka varieties of durum wheat have been tested throughout the last eight years. In comparison with Marquis, their respective yields have been 26 and 19 per cent greater. Due to the superior market value and high yield of several recently introduced varieties of common spring wheat, these will doubtless replace the durums in this state. Fie. 8. — The two most popular varieties of spring wheat grown in Nebraska. Left, Marquis, and right, Ceres. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 253 Discontinued varieties. — Eleven varieties grown for various periods in these station tests but discontinued in 1929 because of apparent inferiority are reported in Table 7. This list may prove of interest since some of the varieties have gained con - siderable publicity elsewhere. • . RECOMMENDED VARIETIES Of the varieties available for farm planting, Ceres is recommended as outstanding in productivity, and is desirable in other respects. Marquis is a standard, extensively-grown variety of excellent milling quality and may be grown until replaced as a result of local experience with more productive sorts. ! NORTHERN VS. HOME-CROWN SEED Inquiry is frequently made concerning the comparative seed value of home-grown and imported seed wheat. Such a comparison with Marquis spring wheat was made during the 11-yeariperiod, 1920 to 1930, between seed grown continuously TABLE 8. — Comparison of the crop from home-grown seed and northern-groivn Marquis spring wheat-*— eleven year*. 192(^-1930 ' First six years Last five years Av. for 1 1 years, 1920-1925 1926-19:10 1920-1930 Crop characters — — • ] —, Home Northern Home iNorthern Home Northern grown | grown grown I grown : grown grown Date in head j 6 13 6 11 6 15 fi IB i i; 14 , 6 15 Dateripc.,1 7 9 ■ 7.9 7 11 I 7 11 7 10 7 10 Plant height (inc/im) 25 25 35 :i(i " :)() 30 Test weight.'tpoumM .. 58.1 58.2 67.4 "&gt;7.:i 57.8 57.8 Yield per acre (buthrM 11.8 11.5 .12.2 12.5 12.0 12.0 Relative yields (prr cent) . ! 100 97 ■ 100 102 100 99 'Marquis seed obtained annually from Minnesota on the Experiment Station Farm and northern-grown seed introduced each year from Minnesota. The similarity of re - sults reported in Table 8 indicates that the locality of seed production has had no effect upon the seed value and the crop has undergone no hereditary changes which may be associated with a change of environment. COMPARISON OF VARIOUS SMALL GRAIN CROPS An eleven-year summary of crop yields on the Experiment Station Farm is shown in Table 9. This period has included several \ very unfavorable crop years. Although oats yielded the most in terms of bushels, winter wheat and winter rye actually produced the greatest number of pounds of grain per acre. Since some of the grains are regularly threshed free of the chaff or hull, and others vary in the percentage of hull </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Variety Tests of Spring Small Grains Table 9. — Comparative grain yields of various crops — eleven ■ years, 1920-1930 • • Standard Yield per acre ,.. weight ■ Kind ot crop per A. Without '• bushel threshed hull' &amp;^ rt h; ::::::::::::::;::ii:::: I I 1 •'» «§ Spring emmer, white ..... 48 "1 991 7&gt;lS ko Spring rye, common 56 18 , 019 j^ g| Spring wheat, Java 60 17 lOOl 1001 (U Winter wheal :. Nebraska BO G(i 36 2?89 2?E 9 183 Winter rye, Rosen 56 35 ,^ g {{» 'Oata, barley, and emmer arc regarded as having 30, 15, and 24 per cent hull, respectively . left adhering to the kernel, the best comparison of the grain yields of the different crops is in pounds per acre of hull-free grain. On this hull-free basis, the order of yields is as fol - lows: (1) winter wheat, (2) winter rye, (3) Comfort barley, (4) Nebraska No. 21 oats, (5) spring rye, (6) hulless oats, (7) white spring emmer, and (8) hulless barley. [5M1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>