<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA.  PART I.  FOODS SUPPLEMENTARY TO CORN IN FATTENING PIGS.  PART II.  THE EFFECT OF FOOD ON BREAKING STRENGTH OF BONES.</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">F XEI 1 KA BULLETIN Agricultural Experiment Station NEBRASKA XXI. A PART I. SUPPLEMENTARY TO CORN IN FATTENING PIGS PART II. EFFECT OF FOOD ON BREAKING STRENGTH OF BONES BIKNKTl 1 11MIS \ </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATION AuKlU'LllKAL hAP hKlMhNT NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD \V\1 c; WHITMOU1 V B CHICK 11 ABBOTT. Aui H (I. LYFORD, Kails VH (II \&gt; ». ANDERSON (n (il.oKci; (XH'PL \\H THE STATION OFFICERS BBrRNETT BJ* (ALES, M I'm / V MARSHALL. THE WORKING STAFF F. .1 \l.\\ \\. 1'H l» I A I. II \Ki kKK. B.S \ l.\\\ HKVIK 1*1(1 N 1 Montgomery, H Kk \nk .1 rniii.ii'&gt; M I ■ II Hakhui k. 1'n I Chatbckm. AM .. // H A Emekhon, B.Sr.. Hi o V 1' Srotrr. i 1. / 'in ■ I.()VKL.\M). H Si \l Ketsbb, A.M., Soil* J II Gain, M. D. C, Amsoeiait in An I. H Sri kdkvant. A. M At ■s W. Pool, A.M. Atntlani Tkimbill. A.M.. Atmittai Little. B.Sr., Assistant in Dm M. H. Swknk. A.M.. AtriMani in En *Maktin Nelson, M.S., A**i»lant in I ■Hahkek. A.M.. AautatU m S» . HlKK. H Umt ,11 Sin (II \&gt; S. ALLEN I'r II K Smith, I A I l'i n M I). V M. Ah, mat I E Ms ad Wii.oox. I'm 1 1 \\ . P. Smiikh. M.S.. Sit/ C \\ I'll.Sl.KY H &gt;• B. W, 1'kkin, harm Supi </seg>
            <seg id="p003">)ODS SUPPLE \ MENTARY TO CORN IN FATTENING PIGS experiment wa lent was to scenic further hich furnish the most profitable he farmer growing pork for the ]'.»)/ 1908 is reported in this bulletin. us used were kept simple in their character y tanners in case they proved growing breeding stock will i those used iii the: TEST &lt; H 1906-1907 October, MMKi the pigs had reached a in the (2.7 pound of pijjs with four \ ne-hred Duroc-.Iersev October 11. 1906. The experi - 1906. The initial weights iccesaive davs lo\V.~ in. wheat shorts l&gt;~) per cent nt. tankage Hi per cent. nt. steamed ground hone 10 pel K. A. BuRNET] irried on in 1904 1905 and in VJOo l!»')ti (•tin No. (14. Experiment IV*. The periment. It is expected that a practical the previous or later pounds each to 96.5 pounds than four pounds. I \l&gt; si \Tlo\ ( ,| NKBR. VOL. XXI, ART. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">All lots were on pastui X they were removed from open were on cement floors with an i&gt;\ No alfalfa pasture or liay was f&lt; Mini x l&gt;v 24 The results of th&lt; are riven in the following Table I. Fulh Experiment began October 13, 1906 Ration XuiiiImt in loi \\ i&lt;k&gt; on experini Average l:i -t uciirl Average first weurl Average kmo. Avenutc daily Toial consumed |x Daily untin consumed |« drain for KHI lh- Cd&gt;t (il jrrain for HHI lbs price as is used in the l&gt;e compared. The a l'.MIT l'.HIs pertinent. Corn is charg per ton. tankage at MO The alfalfa pasture is no ti) All the pijis in tin during the entire period of fee from the lots in one of the pi clusivelv on corn did not relis good gains during the last two In this test it will lie seen the lowest cost, with corn am In this experimei </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I" th* The i. c on pasture, since they started late • last weeks while they were running ine.l little or no feed from this source. i hones for these lots will lx&gt; given in I i SI OF I«HI7 lots of pigs with four pigs in each lot this experiment. As in the previon^ since it was thought l&gt;est not to introduce A fifth lot was added in order to test the in growing pigs and its effect on the illows ■_'.■&gt; per cent, skim-milk &lt; ."&gt; per cent. 90 per cent, tankage 10 per cent. cent, steamed ground hone IC it !t per cent solid.-.. the tankage fed. and thruout the lie same a/ that fed to Lots 4 • week of preliminary feeding, the Is each, while the heaviest lot avi e heaviest and lightest of the lots at the b beginning and the close of the weighings taken on three ing taken on the day he iv aft&lt; it indicated as the beginning cut. All pigs made a nice gain from the \ iltalfa pasture from the beginning of the \ ()( r for the first twelve weel \tter that they were connm comfortable pen in mpariaon of the cms; during shorts li."&gt; per cent. verage difference of but two pound </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Weeks mi experiment _■ last wi'inht. ll» _• first weight, ll)s Average gain. ll&gt;- ;. s ts dram for KKI pounds g*jm, His .{4.i Average daily gain, ll&gt;&gt; Total cruin consumed per |&gt;u. I Daily p :iin consumed per pip. ll» iirain tor uxi pound* gam. ll&gt;&gt; .U.i :«(i .»4&lt;i 7(14 0m* of grain for 100 pounds g&amp;in K2.38 K.«M C the hog harii with a yard about 16x32 feet, and \\ hay or other roughness. They were ten weeks before the close ,,f the test, which was completed .1 They were slaughtered at South Omaha by Swift &amp; 7. 1908. The results runs, food requirements an are given in Table II and Table III. In figuring tin gains in these tables. figured at 40 cent- per bushel, or S14.2N per ton. si ton. skim-milk at twenty cents per KM! pour* £40 per ton and steamed ground lx»ne at s.'-iu per t&lt; for the shipment of tankage and ground bone t" in leae than car ki LABLE i 1 . r 1 &lt;' * mi I . nls on alfalfa pastu ■ . \mnist _' to ( let, .her '_'.'&gt;. !*.•(»" </seg>
            <seg id="p007">I of I Lot 2. Lot 3. I.ni l Con Corn Corn Com !MI\. ik,', IOT &gt; * 4 4 t 4 III 10 1(1 10 in milk s 2 forn ."» s 15 7 cent com and 75 per cent skim-milk, the in the milk is somewhat less than the dry lentarv food where tankage or ground bone inds of skim-milk to one of corn-meal mvenientlv l&gt;e used in making a thick \ vas decided on as the ration for Lot 3. The fed to Lot 3 in pounds was the same as that fed 4 id the skim-milk was figured as about equal in the supplementary feeds used with these lots. xperiments are carried on. it is probable the amount of "'.I I' i ml lupi hi a dry lot. -'■"&gt; to January 3, 1908. Shorts Skim- Tankage Cmuix! milk H)', 219 _M(t 256 •_&gt;:{•_' &gt;jl m 1*2 a iao.7 us .-. Vn .5 ""&gt; 7fl •"&gt; M.3 N .', 1 &lt;Hi l 00 1 96 1 lit 1.09 '■|.i!r. H'- W7 U)7 :&lt;»i7 corn »&lt;I7 107 11(11 milk milk 88 U 18 14 sT UK H.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">s &lt; Ft milk used will In- reduced in ai of milk with corn will oj v( &gt; the largt used. Weeks on expcrmx Average laa&lt; Average tir^i weurfa Averace (tain Cci^t dI grain for HKI n&gt; Compared with lank. a value of 13 eenta per 100 poui Avenge daily Total grain consum Daily grain consumed p&lt; Grain for Hki pi </seg>
            <seg id="p009">I 9 I «//(/ ro»7 of gmUM in th, id in Bulletin Xo. 94, \i hni.sk, i I: tiilmti. ami this bull- s ii 7.V , Com !'."&gt;' , Corn !».V , Corn !«!' , C, V, Corn I'.V , Corn !».V , Corn !«!' , Corn W borti skim- Tankage Tinlr^p (.■ inilkT.V I,)., |, in', i,,.,. ,:; 1 _•» i s II s 1 1 1 ■i 15 com r:i &lt;L'.*i milk 301 nil m.-, 925 milk 391 nn 105 M 10 |3.44 $3. L x •4.10 v.( it that whenever the pip in these experimenta whenever the pip in these experiment* the exclusive corn rations m:i,le cli..-,i ivc corn rations made cheap bese gains were cheaper than entarv f &gt;"ils. ami the excess in cost, if the use of tankage as about 5 illy reduced the cost of the pork sreiu nt ankage lias l&gt;een used, as in the bulletin in Table IV. page 8, the va where corn was fed alone. tend to show the suitability of corn d indicate that this ration inav is for cattle. The amount of is always reduced by the use of tankage. st may lie increased by the high cost of the tankage No. II reported in this bulletin, the food required does not vary greatly in the different lots, as shown in Table IV. on Dace 8. Not unite ■&lt; full r..t;.,r, .&gt;c .,,..,; s . Not quite a full ration of grain </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Foods Supplementary to Corn in Fattening I' v fed in this experiment. It will be seen that Lot I much grain as those lots having a suppl i? probable that the lots receiving t&lt;&gt; corn would have consumed cum alone if they had been fed all thev would col slightly have affected th rthe cost of gain. Lot .") in Tal.le I\ chow gains at i corn. This is due rl required for 100 For the entire m \ ration fed &gt;i 'A iioiluction Table \ the cost is higher thai It will lx&gt; notei the hogs generally made weighta in a given length market at an earlier ag since it shortens the peril ments reported </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 THE EFFECT OF A: ( cleat 1 K.( s hr weight required PAHT II. FOOD ON BREAKING STRENGTH OF BONES K. A. BCRNETT experiment was to determine the effect food on the breaking strength of bom (tieation of the food requirements for breeding pur] trength of the leg hones in the pigs hrin»r- out some interesting facts. An lection of all the pigs in each lot to secure ter and weight. All the pigs used were 11 considerable difference in the breaking 11 different individuals of the same lot which an individual difference and which we have nine by selection. As there were eight leg ig, or thirty-two hones in each lot. thi ic average breaking strength can only \&gt;e if difference in the food of the animals experiment. en pigs put on experiment October 13, IMS, larv 9, 1907. and were killed in South Omaha February 12, 1007. They were allowed to r about forty-eight hours after slaughter, ir the market and the humerus, radius and ia of each hog removed, and l&gt;eing properly ted to the Experiment Station, where they were •n in a testing machine under the supervision of burn (if the Department of Applied Mechanics. 1 _&gt;. pp. 14 and 1.").) which these hones were in hreaking each hone. Tahle VI shows the uhjeeted and gives the </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 ■VI. Break ing rfn ngth nteen week* mi &lt;l about '.C&gt; KKt PER ( i:.\l niHVMKAl Liv« Feb. 9. I'.M)7 \, i"i j :.". n i; i \-mi \ _' t."&gt; Average 245 I"l I. '.mi PER CENT &lt; ( iRX-MI NT 1 215 \:u\ «.i_'( i Experiment began Oct. 13. I'.mm I.hs JV"&gt; I I'll I. '.*&gt; PER i i:.\ I ( ( )I!N 235 1190 1220 820-910 980 1280 HI -*•&gt;."&gt; M90 960 865 S6() 1251) I I in lui 82 _'in 940-11 I ■&gt; in K)7i </seg>
            <seg id="p013">y strength nj bonet per KM) pi hoaa at Hint &lt;ii da ghter. Ratlin* Hutnerua. ami ukie. All l« nes I .'li!l .N."&gt; 281 IX) Jtii JT4 381 3M :51I 75 376 :c&gt;:! 522 4()J m 75 154 H7.'&gt; :,M &gt; ."Kit K&gt;7 75 ntinuallv increasing average strength of continually increasing average strength of order given. No chemical examin; order to determine tlio thickness of t lie ;tl Mm tent, as was done in the ti ler riven. No chemical examination i ii order to determine the thickness of the eral content, as was done in the I TEST i T 1907 1MB I'KST ( &gt;!■ MMI7 1906 i put on experiment August 2. 1907, put on experiment August 2. 1907, i weeks until January ■\. 1908. They weeks until January 3, 1906. They &amp; Co., Smith Omaha, January 8, 1908. Like .. South Omaha, January 8, 1908. Like hung for forty-eight hours in the hung for forty-eight hours in the lius and ulna were removed from each fore mil ulna were removed from each fure a from the hind leg. These were bn the hind leg. These were brought t Station and cleaned bo that they could tiiin and cleaned so that thev could s before, under the supervision of the nder the supervision of the Mechanics. Every effort was made to \pnlied Mechanics. Every effort was made to !. The point- of contact in the machine or all bones of the same claa . tho liuineni' the l&gt;eantiK ; were Di and the radiuses and ulna*. In two in - found to have been previously rrackrd The point; of contact in the machine and ulnas. In tv. shown in Table VI 1 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 OImm'i Improved Teatii riiiient were broken M To break the bones and g&lt; Improved Testing Machine with Dial \ The poise on the beam was operated with a hand \vl perfect balance could be kept Ml Power for the machine was furnished by an alternating current three-phase motor. Altho this machine did not I reak the hones with a blow, sue! as might l&gt;e expected when broken in the animal, they wei — - ...» "■"■'■•ii, i in » »U M ,11 broken under exactly the lame conditions and hence their relative strength could t&gt;e carefully determine* </seg>
            <seg id="p015">7 15 anvils of testini; nuu-liiiir. after lire \vt </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 n rBLE VIII. -Breaking drengtk of !„, week* &lt;m Offer* nt foods. Initial w Experiment began Aug. _'. H1117 Pia Closed .Jan. :■&gt;. Hills LOT I 100 I'i H ( i X CORN Live Wt. l'ciii Til, I.I,. I 22&lt; .&gt; 5K0 «&lt;*&gt; 320 ;,, , )1( Mil &gt;&gt; 840 (Mi im ;u |,,;j, -'-U (i .V)!! lndkcll lilll 510 C||(; ]lr3 I - - • 215 fi WO 550 530 l&lt;*\ etc 97c Ivrragr 219 6 807 .-,:,_' 95] LOT 2. 75 PER CENT CORN-MEAL, 25 PE1 -- ;i 0 580 610 590 tilii 1 100 1 i&lt;» 310 '&lt; 0 670 SO |::.-(i 121 4 215.6 .&gt;li .-,.-,( 1 A\i r 219 6 LOT 2. 7:, PER CENT CORN-M ■i-iX s 182 .1 S70 Averse 219 n 753 1,77 | Ji( ; l.oT 1 25 |&gt;| 1; CENT CORN-MEAL. 7.". l&gt;i R Aver: 219 LOT 3. 25 I'l H ( INT CORN-MI I -''Jit n 1090 11.711 7H) 790 |.t4o I i'^i !9 n U&gt; II .79 11 279 11 II I -71 1; UFO 1 |30 -71 (i IIMMI Averse 256 (I i im ;ijj , 7 -, I."T ». 90 P. I! 1 ; NT CORN-ME.AL. 10 !\ li 246 ii I6F0 Ki7(i 1060 10.50 1570 Him J."&gt;ii 11 LOT J. !HI I&gt;, I! I ; \T (ORX Ml -Hi &gt; IBfO 11,7(1 1 1 ins 1; ; s7o 7i« I :lls i; ; S70 790 7.-(&gt; 1550 I6MJ 219 n 1250 1250 940 950 ]x;n |goo '■'' -'I!* 11 1250 1250 '.U&lt; !l. 111 ; ! 1330 1040 lli!t( II I 1330 1040 1090 970 1850 177(1 Average 232 11 1298 950 , 7 | S LOT :-. M IM K ( NT OORN-MEAL, 10 PtH ( 218 3 Nlin 1450 950 1000 2050 1940 -■"&gt;1 0 l(i-c 1560 1130 11711 2150 22K0 Avenge ::!.' 11 |298 050 LOT «i I'l-K ( NT CORN-MEA1 M I • 24A.6 1300 |£00 980 1040 20K0 21(KJ • IW ii 1420 1360 990 970 KM) 1590 irerage 221 () Mix 1029 •^1 *('hi|i|)«-&lt;l by nx tMissing. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">per KM) p *ltiu&lt;iht Raiiiu I'umr. Tibia. Humenm. ami AH banes ulna 134 :J4l 308 ■'&lt;:,:, 6 Ml 462 360 685 ."iJfl M tint 7ln 611 one. « i 4 » • Hi.'i s!K 7I"&gt; lilp that there is :i gradual incn indred weight of hoc and that atter simply of the more rapid eight of the pig resulting from tl these bones also reve ickness of the walls as shown bv the 4 to !) inclusive. ve also shown that there is BO apparent own that there is no ap] surements of the bones resulting when added to the food nutrients, hut that of thi' bones resulting when nutrients, hut that so far as thev are assimilated, I lione walls !j\- accretion on &gt;erebv reducing the marrow iliont .")() per cent in ncrease The per cent of mlv c pecific eravitv in the green hones inci hiekness of the wall renrth of the bonea t lots indicates that the skim-milk, the tankage and ic substance in which the corn ontau hone building purposes. Sine* n the bones is largely pbospbsi nkage and ground hone mi look upon the phoephai letermining factor in the building u]&gt; of the &lt;!!&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p018">/.' There can l&gt;o n tit amount of ph 1 a deficiency of teriallv affect tin ,ph &gt;1|O tips in Part I economically \' 1h&gt; incurred 1 protein and m ; good feel w i That fo&lt; the strene That an mineral mat actually n&lt; possible, tho bo That on his pasterns grow out with will generally | all pigs unfavorabl This Station ha I phosphate! in the f I m and foot. but investigatii .-(•ems probable that by | nials sufficient time to mai use of foods like lione-n i\vn with strong bone and k of these precautions will In order to answer .-on Ference in strength, the Depi ler the direction of Dr. 1- . ghings and measurements of shown in the following I These experii t liiatiuii of the pa iod pii;s with si </seg>
            <seg id="p019">INVESTIGATIONS 1 TEST FOR 1907-1908 of each bone is given in milli- 1 11 the case nf the right tibia. ml ulna &lt;&gt;f No. 12, of the No. 13 and of both tibiae of No. 20. the house. From some six- e length is not given, sections had been c Table XI are those of the bones h tie XI 1 wirr determined by measur- ubmerged in a vessel oiies were XI II were reduced in some caai explained above. sea the density of the bones ( he weight of the bones ,e ni water. One cubic centimeter fable XV) was determined between the ends, remov- e wall with calipers. ime thickness on all the average thick lie difficulty of arriving at great in the case of the in the table of these b ifference in appearance « his class that is indi V in the case of the other three i he tibia a two-inch section the fractures being lex lieu split lengthwise; the marrow wa me wiped carefully with a cloth before The dried section after being </seg>
            <seg id="p020">_&gt;ii Th&lt; &lt;l "a Breaking St out. To contii burned bone m value from the \ XIII. XI </seg>
            <seg id="p021">llimctt i PER CENT CORN-MEAL. Tibia. Humeiu*. Kadius and ulna. I light Left. Right. Left. I: ;■_• ,i 153 4 H9.:i 162 0 -,s s I S3 l 155 i 158.8 l"' v s 162 ii 158 8 158.8 I71.fi 171 6 Ui; ii 1 13.0 I4ii n 1 •"&gt;■") 4 nil S l tii ■ I CORN-MEA1 I EN1 8HOBT8. ; i i.M SHORT Hi (i 155.5 ORX-MKA1 Hi 0 146 ii II' 1 : '&gt; 146.0 155 .". IV, 5 1 ."&gt;."» .". 1 1 65.1 158 8 152 1 1 •'&gt;-'. 4 171 .."&gt; 165 1 171.5 165 1 1 I ti.-, i 162.0 155.4 1 ."&gt;•') 4 Hi"&gt; 1 105 1 182 1 t .-,_&gt; | - g 165 I S 165 I 57 i |58 i 153 1 1 ■"&gt;:: 1 Ml ■&gt; 1*1 - i 1 in 3 n;i CORN-MEAL, 7;. I'll; CENT SKIM-MII.K 1 16.1 1 M 1 171 s 168. 1 Mvs 1 171 -&gt; 62.1 165.1 155.5 158 8 168 52 1 162 1 158.8 155 5 152.4* 152.4* |«2 s Itil 'J CORN-MEAL, 10 PER CENT TANKAGE. ; U) 1 14d 3 158 8 IK-MEAL, 10 PE1 CENTT \NKA(I Yl 1 II I J8 8 |5§ v 171.5 52 1 l Hi l No.u 14:( 0 158 8 1 1 1 1 162 1 155.5 1 •"&gt;•"&gt; 5 171 .5 155.5 140 -I 1 N 3 158 S M3.« 162.0 CORN-MEAL, 10 PER CENT BONE-MEAL. 146 1 156.5 155.5 166. 1 BONE-MEAL. 166.1 171.5 162.1 loo 5 155 5 1 .i.3 . 5 s 152.4 152.4 16 1* 152.4 loo. 5 I 155.6 1*4.8 154.7 163.3 163 3 161.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Rig 1 W '.i 7.' I Average H I M.7 Avenge 1 Table XI. i LOT I. I(H) PER (INI ( i &gt;1:\-MI Miir. Til&gt;i:i lliinicrii- ■ LOT •"-. M PER CENT CORX-MEA1 TJ I SQ.S Ifl li'.l.'.l M • 7J 4 63.fi M.7 for \ 09. 9 M H.O 70. a 71 8 , I LOT 2 . 75 PEB MAT I 66 7 80 7 M 0 72 l ' 72 l M 8 72 I 86.7 A vi i 70 t LOT : I 2a H II i I N I ( n|;\ 72 I iai 7 10 » 7.' : - Ami LOT t. . BO PEB CENT miiN \ n m 7 :.i •' 1 1 1 :&gt; i ,, 7 ( - 7"&gt; 0 78 7 Average 71.2 71.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 &gt; III I nil tl i: ri-.vi ■ORX-.MEA1 Hid ulna Total 1'ir _!ii Left. Right Left. R%)M 8 \:,l 152 MB KB WU i »■_• lao u sa &amp; 'i:. l.il 1.".) Iihi MB .11 1 -"» 4 1 1 M&gt; 1IK.' Til 130 123 84 7s s| 7s 821 5 88 111 .1 I Id '.il .'&gt; !U III .1 I 1(1 !ll .'&gt; Ill i:.M cnHVMKU.. .'.■&gt; PEB (KM SHORTS 75 134 128 91 s7 86 I Hi I3§ 'H s7 77 l-'ii !_'."&gt; 02 80 M RX-MEAL. 25 PER (KNT SIHtH' M 128 91 s7 1 Hi i:is Ml 77 i:il i:U !Hl 7'.i 133 131 U W 92 I.M (X)RN-MEAL, 7.'. I'MH CENT SKIM-MILK. 83 128 130 71 83 M ( ( &gt;I PER (EXT SKIM-.MI1 K 100 lsti 17s 112 vi Him H KKl 151 UNi 100 KM 77 1 12 1 12 7ii 77 si l I.*) 1 1 Mi UN) 1 1 M 1."&gt;1 151 K2 85 V I.M ( ci!N MKAI Hi PER CENT TANKAGE s| 138 130 'Hi B3 9li 133 128 86 81 84 IX-MEAl v"&gt; 1 M 1 13 !'■-' I M 1 1 U I 17 111 !"i \&gt;7 '17 si in |3fi ."&gt; (ii r,.~&gt; ENT CORN-MEAL, Mi PER CENT BUNE-MEA1 78 158 132 in-' H 100 1"&gt;| nil 71) li)l - Ill Its 98 88 X-MEAL, 10 PER (KNT BOXfc-MEAl I 156 152 102 mi M4 i:. i mi 7o ion 5-111 1 IN !•-' ss ( 117 11.' H til 117 11.' H in Ml I.", 1 12 til 7s 145 142 '■'! 7n •, s:; ii i a '.i I3t &gt;i 92. 1 si si </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Table XI II. II, LOT I. Hki PER f'l.M CORN-MEA Ffiimi No. Left. Hifrlit . Left. Kit; 1 IT:; (I 175.0 120 0 120 r&gt;. 192 it 102 ii 121 0 1 LOT .V BO PER I'KXl 17 '.'(HI I) 1M (I 1^ 210 :. 204.5 133 It lvJ ii 182 ii 120 30 HKI n 151 (i si tMuch 1 I Mi-&gt;ii 15 l'.'l A\c. 188 (t 180 n 1110] 13 for | LSI (I 17!l 0 113 0 1 12 &gt;n hogi J *Parl of &gt;-iiil &gt;:i«n &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p025">/. 25 ;ic gravity of tin I loo I'KR CENT CORN-MEAL. Til.ia. Humerus Kailiusamlulna. Average of N-MI..VI Radius and ulna. Aver ft. Right. Left. Right. Left. Right. 8 bone*. Left. Right. Left. Right. 8 bone* 212 1 130 1 17! 1 107 1 Ml 1 IM 1 174 1.1(17 l.ltil 1 158 1 120 mi 1.227 i . i.vi i.i42 i oaa i.ua 1 u? 1.258 1 17.". 1 17s l 12.1 1.143 1 IM 1. 264 1.1X4 I 17(1 I.8M I. lit 1 urn J16 1.227 1 !.).-&gt; 1 1 f.» I.CM3 11. VJ 11. 17 258 1 17.". 1 17s 1.125 1 1 12 1 lvj 2&lt;il 1 1st 1 17(1 1.083 1.115 1 ltm .':57 1.240 1 l.V.t I. Ml I.MH 1.143 1 Id ;.M CORN-MEAL, iS PEB CENT SHoHl DRN-MEAL, 25 1 ER CENT SHORTS K CENT ( !&lt;&gt;2 1.273 I. MB 1 21."&gt; 1 (Ins 1 1_&gt;I) 1.196 l 1 UK) 1 215 1 nss l I2t&gt; 1.196 _'(i7 1.287 1.113 1 177 1.127 1 1 t!t 1 17.1 1 1 .113 1 177 1.127 1 Hit 1 17.1 247 12 247 1.299 I. MS 1 -'(is I (M&gt;."&gt; 1 17.1 I Ml v.i 1 182 1 20s I (M)."&gt; 1 17."&gt; 1 His 342 1 142 1 :i!Kl 1.183 1.182 1.077 1. 103 1 228 CM I 1 182 I 182 1 077 1 152 1 178 1 .307 1 154 1 Hi". 1 071 1 150 1 IM KNT CORN-MEAL, 7."&gt; PEB CENT SKIM-MII.K. 279 1 107 1 154 1 195 1.071 1. 150 1 IM ER CENT col X-MEAL, 7"&gt; 1 ER CENT SKI MM U.K. »os 1.387 1 381 1 207 I.SM I.2M 1 J71 1.230 I .292 1 271 II IS 1 :&gt;s7 M 1.207 {.-&gt;■_&gt; 1.380 1 301 1 27.'&gt; 1 268 1 :i.'&gt;o Nil nil 1.275 1 268 1 :{.Vi l Mi itv.s 1.3M 1 2M 1.227 1.224 1 -'•"&gt;•". 1 27s 11.". 1 .428 1.2*4 I.3H 1 M8 1 Ml 3M 1 :i"is 1 .27* 1 2.V) 1 .231 1 S34 7ii 1 250 1 J.\.i 1 .W4 PER ( EN ! ( INT ( ORN-MEAL, 10 1 EB &lt; I NT TANKAGE. I ( ( UN Ml I A I.. 10 1 1 R ( 1 N 1 TANKAGI 40 1 1 W2 1 3X3 1 :«1 1 2.V&gt; 1 .^H) 4111 1 152 ;:« 1 :«l 1.255 1 .^H) :i7.". 1 4lii 1 271 l 282 1 2(i7 l l :uo nil 1 112 1.316 1.278 1 :«7 1 27(1 1 313 14ti 1 71 1 2N2 1 2(17 1 308 l :no 404 1 tu 15 1 .278 1 HH7 1 27ii l :u;5 :57(1 1 12 1 1 347 1 313 I.3M 1 :&lt;7(&gt; 1 341 l.'l t 7 1 .'(12 :i!to 1. 133 1 :il!t 1 sol 1 2'tti 1 m i 3M iiH) 1 v.\:\ 119 1 M\\ 1 296 1 3K3 1 :!2ii i im:h cent CENT CORN-MEAL, 10 PER CENT BONE-MEAL. 1 342 1 272 1 27(i 1 .2M 1 1 311 col X-MEAL, 10 I Kit CENT BONE-MEAL :i tJ 1 276 1 .299 1 1.315 1 1 145 1 :«4 1 .298 1 :i 1 7 1 :i7 1 H."&gt; 1 :«4 I 298 1 HI7 1 :571 1 412 1 :il!l 1 412 1 402 1.415 I :i7 1 n-J 1 :il!i 1 412 500 1.338 I.2M 1 -i-M) 1.286 1 :&lt;7."&gt; 1 :«."» VMI I Ive. i 293 1 :52."&gt; 1 . 42.". 1 :iM 1 29S 1 :52&lt;t 1.326 1.386 1 346 A l :u:i l 1 241 1 2 W 1.210 1 27". 1 271 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">I /. Left. Rich) Hie I Vvera l.oi s \VIT l.i 'I 3. 23 PER ri:\ l i . i|;\ II 12 I - •) i it 111 t (i LOT .".. BO PER CENT CORN-MEAL, 10 PER CENT BON 10 ( " *! 3.5 5.0 i.s .]" »■« *•• 3.5 5.0 50 s : : J :: : : ; i : j : » i for | .", 3 ,, S i able A \ Fhieknes* o) tin hum walls LOT 1. KM) PER CENT (\&gt;RN-MEAI Hog No. I ,.,„,„.. •,■:,-., PER &lt;T.V| i i »R\ M] LOT I. BO PER CEJTT (X)RN-MIM W 5.0 .", (i :j ,| ;{ 14 :{ii in trerag ( Average 3.9 i i ;{ , </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 two- inch section of tmto 'if marrow in gram* (IT 1. I(K) I'KK ( KNT ( dUN-MKAI. Total weight four Tibia Kitr Left Right 12 II II 53 5 1 l.d 12.0 12. U 11 n 19 S 47 5 s Hi i I I 17 4 in PKR CENT CliHX MEAL PER CENT SHORTS in ii U (i II) II 4.") II II i) ii 1 1 11 ii 11 ii 53.0 50 13 s 1 1 11 1 PKR (EXT CORN-MEAL. 75 1 ER CENT SKIM-MILK 12 II KMi 59 n ill 15 15 II 00.0 is (I 1 ■. 13 13.6 til 6 13 '.i I'KK CENT ruIi.N MEAL, in I'KK CENT TANKAGE 17 ;&gt; n ii Hi II 12.0 13.0 ill •') 17 0 7J.0 14.0 I I 1 4 .') 15. 4 till Id PER CENT CORN-MEAL, 1" I ER CENT BONE-MEAL. 14.(1 13. S 60.0 23.0 17.5 20.0 Hi ii l'.t I) 12.0 13.5 Hid 14.0 19.4 18. « !•"&gt; 7 15.1 60.1 Ay 13.3 50.7 16.3 13 -' </seg>
            <seg id="p028">/ 28 &gt; / Table XVII. Weight &lt;&gt;j mineral matter m tu h, a I l.R CENT CORN-MEA] LOT 1 HKi No. lemur Left. Right K 1 (I liMi.'i (I _»7li&lt;&gt; -&gt; j:iTii S 2310 s :{ -. .".'.lid 5 liitai 5910 ■i I 7 (il'.il 7 77m krmec n 11 Hi 7.9707 LOT 2. 75 PER CENT (X)RS 1 7 8191 7 77 Average s 1 1 Hi It (IN LOT .-, 8 ."&gt;ii.'(i 8 H170 B si'.ii7 'i 5' B -'!."&gt; I 9 ■_'».'• I s Hi _'»:.:! 'i71 Av.t:ij;i- '.) I7'.i-&lt; 9 ti LOT I. 2fi PER CENT (X)RN ' s LOT 3. 25 PER CENT CORN MEAL. 7:. PER CEN 9 ii .v.»o n : II .V,ll • in 12 :il(Ki 1 1 H 14 m i S 11 12 121 1 1 1 8056 1_&gt; in 512* I-' 3266 Avcr;ii;r I 1 I7M I 1 7H97 LOT I. W I 11! CENT CORN- in :.r.M LOT I. W) I 11! &lt; KM CORN-MI 13 1 1 21 10 I I 8612 13 I I 21 10 I I H612 14 Miaing 1! l " &gt;ll(i If 12. I HH&gt; 13 M86 If 12. I HH&gt; 13 him Hi 13. MH 13 8830 \vcnce l- : &lt;'&gt; 13 ; LOT ."&gt;. W PER CENT COHN-1 13 K660 I \verase 12 M CORN-MI 17 13 1140 13.7776 I1II1MI II 7M* IS If 13 -'.")7ii i:MKM&gt;( jii I 1 L'/Vx.-) Ill !HHi me 12 9119 13 177s in 1793 Average U.r the 11 in II II I23&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p029">/■ 29 ml matter in two-inch s&lt; aw i til 0 i III 1 1(1" ( lixi I'KH NT CORN-MEA1 Krmtm I 7 r g f,i g uit i &gt;.i .;.-, i i 111 !l I'Kl! CENT CORN-MKAL, .'.-, I&gt;K|{ CENT SHOUTS -v lit !l li.-, s 1 4 65 s I •"&gt; 62 li 83. fl 1 7 liii li 1,7 | U s lil s PER CENT CORN-MI 71 I I'KH CENT ■ KIM-M1I.K ii."i I 117 7 ii.-, s ii.s II '.i t t t III i IN I CORN-MEA1 in I'KH ( KNI TANKAGE &gt;7 .'&gt; (,.". :i til l B»i II i tit; i, li!l i tit • .ii til Mi lij s I'KH CENT CORN-MI VL, I i PER CENT BONE-MEAL. I is S r.i li. ii 7:5 !l 111 !l III) II f,7 s I is I II 65 1 ill) 66. I A ii.'&gt; I ti7 II h r.l li 06 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">It 30 i I Table XIX. II eight of mineral matter in thi I.i )T 1. l(H) I'l CENT CORN-MEA1 lluniirii- Radiu Femur Til in Left. Kieln Left. Kielit. Left 41 u tl (i 32. ( Left Kiel 1 1 411 I) II 38.o ae.5 ■_&gt; 28 () 28 ii :&lt; tt.3 ».5 :«i ii :«i Ii S »ti (T ii :{x ;i (if 38 5 27 5 27 N I Sllnl! LOT 2. 7S PER ('EX I • I N'-MEAI PKR I 36.0 IU.O H 5 30 0 M £2.5 I! o 27 5 a g 13.0 13 ii 30 11.1 11 I.i 1 1 25 1 1! (! \ X mi: \ 75 PER &lt; TINT SI ts ii 17.5 33 S 27 ■". in 63.5 (i: I.i 11 58.0 58 ii tl ii II 12 54.0 .'.) 55.9 i LOT l. 90 PER CENT CORN-MEA1 13 55.0 ».O IT ll U f* .')1 :&gt; 15 •') 35.5 "&gt;1 ,V&gt; i) SO ■"&gt; in n 11 5 ii:i :■ 9» 0 II •"&gt; II •"&gt; 72 . (ill (I II ."&gt; II .-i 7J ."&gt; S6.0 59.2 41 s 111 til . M.O -V.i 2 11 ill LOT .V §0 PER CENT CORN-MI til :&gt;+ :&gt;!i :&gt;t ;{:.:&gt; 36 o M W.O 7(1 ."&gt; 56.0 53.0 7ii •1.5 S3 0 •"&gt;:&lt;•"&gt; -Vi ii 88 LOT .V '.HI 1'KH ('ENTIX)RX mi: a i (PERCENT BOX KM 17 til .51 50 -"&gt;t ;{7.."&gt; M'&lt; (i »&gt;&lt;» i'.i is 80.0 7(1 ."i 55.0 53.0 .-&gt;:&lt; it 51.0 B.O :« n ."&gt;:! i in 44 :&gt; v.i :&gt; Hi, 9 51.1 36.0 35.9 .■)."&gt; I </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 h \ \ X. I'irn ntagt oj mineral matU KHt PER CENT CORN-MEAL. Tibia. n» ■ R:nliu&gt; anil ulna. Am for Left. Kinlit Left. Kiglit Left. Kiclit. &gt;&gt; !&gt;■■ &gt;2 ;, 22 ■ 23 § M (I M : * -•'« -' 25 it 23 7 29 § -"■• I : *» ' 25 S ■-'•"&gt; 1 '-'•"» • 30.7 : &gt;n •"' 27 I! 24 ii - s 7 i i- ; 25 7 J4 _' -ii 0 29 s 29 s -•' 4 (» _•:{ 8 ii _M» 29 I :«• I ■v i, :tn 7 :«&gt; 1 28.7 ■' I ii J4 ii J'.l s _".! s 1 4 2ti 1 1 CENT CORN-MEAL, 2S l'KK CENT BBORT8 PER CENT CORN-MEA1 I'Kl 4 CENT SHORTS j, s j (i i 24 1 -'•"' i : «" s - &gt;s i; 30 8 28 ii 24 s _'«i 1 24.1 27 a 1~ '■&gt; 27 ■"&gt; 27 7 31 •&gt; 32 •"&gt; il 6 &gt;t 2§ 8 29 ii 28 3 27 5 II. 4 27 :, II » jo 4 M ■"&gt; 28 i • » I t 27 i&gt; 27 !• 27 ii 27 0 33 0 :&gt;l 7 :VJ ii :il T •t 11 (i CENT CORN-MEAL, 75 PEH CENT 8K1M-M1LK. 31 .3 K it 38. 5 38 • 37 I 39 ; i 31 | :i| '.i » I 32 3 37 3 39 0 31 :, 33 3 30 3 32 4 0 I 31 1 PER CENT CORN-MEA1 ", PER ( NT SKIM-MILK i :;; » :iii :i ;n ;ii i) i .; :s:i I :;:; g 34 5 33 9 33 9 W.I '.i ).; 3 »t 1 31 8 32 I ; !1 ■'&lt; '■'- • ;T 7 ; " ' ;:: J7 6 '.i 31 CENT CORN-MEAL, in I'KH CENT TANKAGE ER CENT TANKACE « PER CENT CORN-MEAL 111 I 37 | 39 it 39 2 :i7 S 44 2 39 0 44 .' 39 0 «i 0 :«&gt; 33 5 33 1 32 2 34.4 39 1 39 1 4 M 1 39 1 1 1 t :{■_&gt; ii :{4 5 32 B :i4 8 39 9 ■ II i s 34 7 34.0 39 i&gt; 37 3 12 s 41 s I :;:, | 41 ii 99 7 (J 8 41 s ■ M.O 36 i« i\ ii 38 7 \i CENT CORN-MEAL, 10 PER CENT BONE-MEAL :j4 (i 34 9 35 B Si 9 U 9 ENT BONE-ME.X1 PER CENT CORN-MEAL, 10 1 1! ( ag ii 13 9 II" 3 4(1 0 35 ii 39 ii 99 B 45 &gt;&gt; it ;, l 39 1 33 3 4(i 7 (2 2 It ;, 44 I M 1 31 1 4(1 7 4L' 2 :;s i M 8 M 0 15 I 40 I M I tn | to S ;:, r, 39 5 39 7 B 7 9&gt;2 43.2 5 SB 7 B ' »'• - 4:&lt; - :!l 7 :u t 30 ■"&gt; M :i 99 1 31 4 il y 31 1 M 1 :iii 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">After the ash content of the first so lx&gt;nes had been det&lt; mined, it was decided to secure X As the X-rays permit of photographing ill closed within obje&lt; oped that would permit of animals under expel development in obtaining any ii i ibtainetl 1 'ii :t sensitive plate on which lay t ■Icctcil containing site of the pace. &lt;&gt;f thi bulletin do duction of an entire plate on a pi The three plal I he photi 1 and 19, ■_' and 18. .4 and 17. The tin . 1 and 1 i part of t lie boue, which la appears dark in appears dark in the photograph, while the fays to pas . ap the rays to pa lioiies have both thick' in the ends. The re mail given. The reproduction of the r ietaded discussion ot all ai i\\ e :in' indebted (o Mr. \ </seg>
            <seg id="p033"/>
            <seg id="p034">:u </seg>
            <seg id="p035">I H </seg>
            <seg id="p036">t Fie. (i X-ray pli 1-i rtii king s1 rciiiri li </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 Breaking Strength &lt;&gt;i B </seg>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039">\-r.iy phot&lt; graph &lt;'l left liiimrru- w hcg ■ " ' Breaking strength. iil.Vi poMadt. r««a. **' l'*" r "" I 1 o Food on Breaking Strengtk oj «&lt;"»■- </seg>
         
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>