<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00012.00007">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00012.00007</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>SEVENTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Hospital for the Insane TO THE GOVERNOR For the Period Ending November 30, 1904</title>
		             <date value="1904">1904</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-20</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-28</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
SEVENTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT 

OF IBM 

SUPEEINTENDENT 

or thb 

Nebraska Hospital for the Insane 

TO THB 

GOVERNOR 

For the Period Ending November 30, 1904 

BT 

JAMES L. GREENE, M.D., Superintendent </seg>


            <seg id="p002">
Hon. Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner Public Lands 
and Buildings President 

Hon. Geo. W. Marsh, Secretary of State Secretary 

Hon. Prank N. Prout Attorney General 

Hon. Peter Mortensen State Treasurer 

RESIDENT OFFICERS. 

James L. Greene, M. D Superintendent 

John T. Hay, M. D First Assistant Physician 

Mabel Dunn, M. D Second Assistant Physician 

George A. Young, M. D Pathologist 

Albert D. Gilmore, Esq Steward 

Miss Cora L. Damrow Matron 

NON-EESIDENT. </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
REPORT. 

Bon. John H. Mickey, Governor: 

Sir — The seventeenth biennial report of the Nebraska Hospital 
for the Insane, at Lincoln, for the period beginning December 
1, 1902, and ending November 30, 1904, as provided 
for by law, is herein submitted. 

MANAGEMENT. 

The official staff has continued in service since the last report, 
without change. 

NUMBER OF PATIENTS TREATED. 

At the beginning of the biennial period there were present 
516 patients (194 males and 322 females). There have been 
admitted and returned from parole during the period 1,087 
patients (649 males and 438 females), making a total of 1,603 
patients under treatment for the two years. At the close of 
business, November 30, 1904, there were present 588 (214 
males and 374 females). The greatest number present on 
any particular day was 629, on June 17, 1903. 

During the entire biennial period just closed this hospital 
has received and cared for all patients offered from the entire 
state, and there has not been delay in a single case when the 
law has been complied with. This course of procedure has 
crowded the house far beyond its capacity, and rendered the 
burden of all concerned much greater than it would have been 
had a normal number been under treatment. This crowded 
condition was directly responsible for an accident, in which 
one patient, a male, lost his life. 

GENERAL HEALTH. 

There has been no epidemic disease present here during the 
past two years. An occasional case of erysipelas has oc- </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
70 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

curred, generally during the winter months. There were 
seven cases of enteric fever this fall, all of them occurring in 
patients who had more or less freedom of the grounds, and, 
consequently, opportunity to partake of food and drink without 
suitable observation and supervision. In the main the 
ailment was mild, and all save one patient recovered. One 
of the oldest employees in point of time of service became infected 
and lost his life, after an illness of three weeks. 

With the foregoing exceptions, the health of all detained 
here has been better than could reasonably have been expected, 
considering the crowded condition. 

REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS. 

The plan formulated at the beginning of the previous biennium, 
when the present management took charge here, viz., 
to put the entire plant in first-class order, has been followed 
most assiduously, and results are now apparent. 

The surgical operating room mentioned in the last report 
as being under way has been finished, furnished and equipped 
with every material thing required for modern surgery in all 
its branches. Visiting physicians and surgeons have commended 
and pronounced it the best in the state. Operations 
of all grades of importance have been performed, some of 
tkem to relieve conditions of pain and suffering that had existed 
for years. 

The pathologic laboratory has been furnished and equipped 
with all of the instruments of precision needed in modern 
medicine. This addition to the hospital's armamentarium 
does more than all else toward modernizing its methods. 

E? last legislature increased the appropriation for wages, 
the distinct understanding that night nurses would be 
ded in all departments of the hospital. This has been 
done, and has contributed more than all else to the comfort 
of the patients. It enables us to care for them in unlocked 
rooms, and is another advancement in modern care of the </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
71 


lature for new plumbing. The amount has been expei 
under the direction of the Board of Public Lands and Build 
ings, and the entire hospital plant now has new plumbing of 
a modern type. 

Two vertical water tube boilers, of 100 horse-power capacity 
each, have been purchased and installed. All the work 
of removing the old boilers and erecting the new ones was 
performed by the hospital's regularly employed force, under 
the direction of the chief engineer, Mr. George Blakely. 

The funds for rebuilding the barn, which was destroyed by 
fire more than two years ago, have been expended, and the 
barn has just been finished. It is a very satisfactory structure 
and will meet the requirements for many years. 

The greenhouse has been repaired and enlarged in such a 
way as to render it better suited to the needs of the institu- 

tion. 

The work of general repairs has been carried on constantly. 
A painter, with two or three patients, has worked constantly 
for two years. The institution's carpenter, with patients for 
helpers, has been steadily employed. An item of repair that 
deserves special mention is steel ceiling. These have been 
placed in all the bathrooms of the main building and upon 
two of the wards. They are both ornamental and durable, 
and will stop a constant expense of repairing plaster. 

The grounds about the hospital, in both front and rear, 
have had constant attention. New curbing along drives has 
been provided in many places, making an ornamental and 
permanent improvement. 

Several hundred fruit and shade trees have been planted, 
given good care, and are doing well. 

THE FABM, GARDEN AND STOCK. 

The yield from the farm and garden has been quite satisfactory 
for both years covered by this report, and has contributed 
more than at any like period in the past toward the 
maintaining of the patients. The policy of keeping all of the </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
72 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

place. This year the farm has furnished beef for the entire 
institution for about thirty weeks, and we have left 242 cattle 
of all ages on the place, with an abundant supply of feed to 
carry them through the winter. 

The hogs have been carefully managed, and the breeding 
brought to a higher standard. The farm now produces both 
Poland China and large English Berkshires of pure blood, 
and these herds are drawn upon by many farmers in this and 
adjoining counties for the purpose of improving their herds. 
There has been no sickness among our swine during the past 
two years. It is thought that this result has been obtained 
by careful sanitation. There is now being slaughtered from 
day to day hogs eleven months old, weighing 320 pounds each. 
This meat will be cured upon the place and will aid materially 
in reducing the expense during the coming year. 

FINANCIAL STATEMENT. 

The legislature of 1903 appropriated |172,600 to pay salaries 
and maintain and improve this hospital for the period 
beginning April 1, 1903, and ending March 31, 1905. The 
amounts thus appropriated for this period were estimated 
upon the number of patients likely to be present. At the time 
the matter had final consideration it was thought by the committees 
in charge of the appropriations that the Norfolk Hospital 
would be open and care for patients from that district 
for at least ten months of the period. As it has terminated, 
that institution will not be occupied before May 1, 1905. This 
hospital has continued to receive all of the patients offered 
from the entire state, with the result that expenditures from 
several of our funds, that depend entirely upon the number 
of patients present, have been unusually large, and deficiencies 
in board and clothing, drugs and postage have occurred. 

The following table shows the condition of the various 
funds at the close of business, November 30, 1904. The balance 
in these funds is supposed to pay expenses to April 1, 
1905. That it is inadequate is obvious. I suggest that you </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
73 

STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

request that they do as they did two years ago, viz., by special 

act, passed early in the session, transfer from the funds ap- 

propriated for Norfolk two years ago, or appropriate outright 

by special act at least $18,000 for a general deficiency fund, 

to carry these current expenses to April 1, 1905. 

Appropriated Bal. Nov. 5», 1904 

Employees' wages $ 48,000 00 97,711 r&gt;4 

Services chaplain 300 00 75 00 

Board and clothing 70,000 00 764 64 

Fuel and lights 15,000 00 465 26 

General repairs 4,000 00 16 54 

Paints and oils ,. 1,200 00 84 2 7 

Horses, harness, garden and 

farming implements 1,000 00 8 82 

New range and kitchen furni- 

ture 1,000 00 92 93 

Returning patients and burial 

expenses 1,250 00 5 48 

Drugs, books and instruments 3,000 00 4 74 

Postage, stationery, freight 

and express 1,250 00 74 64 

Building barn 5,000 00 218 97 

New plumbing 3,000 00 90 

Repairing and improvements 

on greenhouse 1,000 00 107 26 

Totals fl55,000 00 f 9,645 99 

PEB CAPITA COST. 

The per capita cost of this biennial period has been as fol- 

lows: 

First semi-annual period, December 1, 1902, to May 
31, 1903 $ 76 76 

Second semi-annual period, June 1, 1903, to November 
30, 1903 90 06 

Third semi annual period, December 1, 1903, to May </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
74 


The above statement represents the cost from funds appro- 

priated by the legislature, and does not include the value of 
farm products consumed or expenditures from our cash fund, 
which fund comes largely from the sale of the products of the 
farm. It does, however, include the expenditure of $17,000 
for permanent improvements, such as barn, boilers and en- 

gine, greenhouse, etc. 

IMPROVEMENTS NEEDED. 

Fire Protection. 

The reservoir, on top of the hill south of the hospital, is of 

Ky solid masonry, but inadequate in capacity. It can have 
addition of eight feet built on its present wall with safety, 
1 thus increase not only its capacity, but the pressure in 

the mains. 

Neic Boiler 8 and Dynamos. 

Two additional boilers will be required. When these are 

installed, in addition to the two provided for by the last legislature, 
this item of repairs will be finished, and nothing in 

the same line will be required for at least fifteen years. 
The dynamos having been in use for sixteen years, the 

greater part of which time they have carried an overload beyond 
their rated capacity, as a consequence are worn out and 

must be replaced. 

Neic Building. 

Your attention is called to the fact that the arrangement 

of this hospital provides for more women than men. There 
are present to-day 374 women and 214 men. This hospital 
owns the largest and best tract of farm land belonging to any 
state institution ; yet, owing to the small number of male patients 
kept here, it is always difficult to find enough help to 
carry on the work of the farm. An appropriation of f 50,000 
would provide room for 175 more male patients, and provid- 

Fourth semi-annual period, Juna.1, 1904, to Novem- 

ber 30, 1904 79 0&lt; 

Total |336 9 </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
75 


ing for that number here, would lessen the annual per capita 
tost of maintenance at the hospital, besides, before this building 
could possibly be erected, there will be a pressing need 
for room. 

Conclusion. 

A report from the pathologist and a series of tables of interest 
to those who wish to compare this with former periods 
follows. The steward's report contains a statement in detail 
of all the funds received and expended during the period covered 
by this report. Vouchers, properly executed and approved, 
for each item of expenditure, are on file at the hospital. 


The lasting gratitude of all the officers of this hospital is 
due your Excellency and the Board of Public Lands and 
Buildings for valuable advice and aid at all times, and for 
the constant evidence of confidence yon have shown the management 
; also for the privilege of having administered its affairs 
untrammeled by the spoils system of politics. 

Kespectfully submitted, 

Jamks L. Greene, 

Superintendent. 

Asylum, Neb., November 30, 1904. 

REPORT OF PATHOLOGIST. 

To the Superintendent : 

The laboratory, as at present equipped, has been in existence 
since November, 1903, and has proved its purpose of 
practical utility. While there are yet improvements to be 
made, and while the work is still rather unsystematic, it 
is to be hoped that, with the coming biennium, the pathological 
department will be fully organized and its work will be 
carried on in close co-operation with that of the clinical side 
of the hospital. 

At the disposal of the worker here can be found the necea- </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
76 


urine, and gastric analysis, bacteriology, and for the demonstration 
of pathological anatomy and histology. 

This apparatus has been constantly employed by the pathologist, 
blood examinations and gastric analyses being made 
when called for; urinalysis, as a routine measure with every 
patient admitted; bacteriological examinations of the blood, 
urine, and feces in cases of typhoid fever, acute delirium, and 
such other cases as present the clinical picture of an acute 
infection; microscopical examination of the sputum when 
pulmonary tuberculosis is suspected, and of the membrane 
in cases of suspected diphtheretic sore throat Airtight, 
sealed tubes of the different culture media are kept on hand 
to be used for emergencies. Whenever autopsies have been 
allowed, the same have been performed by the pathologist, 
and the findings recorded. The different viscera and cranial 
contents, when affording specimens of interest, have been preserved 
to form the nucleus of a hospital museum. In every 
autopsy sections of the central nervous system have been 
made for microscopical examination, and further examinations 
have been made more or less exhaustively, according to 
the findings as shown by the result of the routine procedure. 

A useful measure of importance in a hospital for the insane 
is lumbar puncture and a careful examination of the cerebrospinal 
fluid, according to a prescribed technic. It affords a 
means of differential diagnosis between functional and organic 
nervous disease, and at times is of a distinct therapeutic 
efficiency. It is of especial utility in distinguishing between 
the early stages of paresis and the acute so-called functional 
psychoses. Lumbar puncture has been introduced here with 
satisfactory results, and will doubtless remain as a recognized 
aid in the hospital work. There have come to autopsy during 
the past eighteen months ten cases, of which two were 
complete, including the thoracic and abdominal viscera, as 
well as the central nervous system. The rest were partial, 
the cranial contents only being examined. When possible, 
it is to be desired that the autopsies be complete, more comprehensive 
and reliable statistics thereby being obtained. </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

77 

In this series there were several instructive cases, one of 
which deserves mention. The patient was a man of 68, a case 
of mild alcoholic delirium, who rapidly became convalescent 
and, to all appearances, healthy. A month after his admission 
he developed stupor and a left hemiplegia, and, passing 
into, coma, died, seven days after failure in health was first 
noted. The clinical diagnosis was cerebral thrombosis. The 
anatomical and microscopical diagnosis was a gelatinoform, 
small-celled sarcoma, infiltrating in character, involving the 
right frontal lobe, and extending from the pre-frontal pole to 
the anterior extremity of the central ganglia, and laterally 
to the cortex of the Rolandic area. The absence of clinical 
symptoms, indicating destruction of brain tissue, in the presence 
of so large a growth, is certainly indicative of the latent 
character of the frontal lobe. 

Needed improvements in the pathological department include 
a special record book for inscribing the results of all 
examinations and analyses made in the laboratory, together 
with the name and case number of the patient examined. 
This will provide data for future statistics, and a means of 
comparison with clinical records of the physicians' office. 

A new morgue is urgently needed along with the necessary 
post-mortem table and other facilities appertaining thereto. 
An ice cabinet, for preserving the cadaver, is of the utmost 
importance to preserve the integrity of the finer structures 
of the nerve cells from post-mortem change. The importance 
of an active co-operation between the clinical and laboratory 
departments of the hospital can not be too strongly emphasized. 


The pathologist wishes to express his sincere thanks to the 
superintendent for the encouragement he has given the work 
in this department, and for the material way in which he has 
added to the equipment of the laboratory. 

Respectfully submitted, 

G. A. Young, </seg>


            <seg id="p012">
78 


n\j. v. 

eneral Statement for the Thi: 

ity-foto Years Fnding November 

30,: 

904. 

p 

! 
1 
&lt; 

1 
I 

-a 
1 
I 
I 

¦3 
I 

•a 
i 
S 
'a 

§ 
s 
w 
o 

1 
i 
z 

•o 
§ 
I 

1 
¦ 
1 
2 

I 

1 
o 

.1 
Q 

L871 
L872 
L873 
L874 
L875 
L8TO 
877 
.878 
879 
.880 

8H4 
.885 
8*; 
887 
1888 
.889 
X90 
891 
H92 
893 
.894 
895 
K96 
.897 
.898 
.899 
.900 
1901 
L902 
1903 

56 
49 
56 
46 
61 
93 
99 
120 
160 
193 
230 
273 
282 
360 
358 
374 
400 
392 
309 
326 
346 
273 
317 
341 
348 
351 
360 
330 
369 
365 
531 
516 
513 

87 
29 
38 
17 
46 
72 
52 
83 
117 
114 
124 
161 
206 
204 
185 
202 
202 
219 
194 
201 
189 
200 
242 
269 
255 
225 
216 
226 
253 
250 
968 
476 
530 
524 

87 
85 
87 
73 
92 
133 
145 
182 
237 
274 
317 
394 
479 
486 
545 
560 
576 
619 
586 
513 
519 
550 
518 
587 
598 
573 
572 
586 
589 
619 
732 
1012 
1062 
1064 

8 
20 
14 
15 
20 
30 
24 
38 
42 
44 
48 
71 
74 
74 
81 
97 
96 
72 
72 
83 
81 
67 
92 
90 
115 
101 
93 
73 
106 
90 
80 
106 
166 
113 

3 
5 
10 
6 
4 
5 
6 
11 
18 
11 
16 
18 
47 
22 
33 
46 
19 
21 
30 
a 
19 
21 
:i9 
41 
128 
22 
27 
14 
14 
17 
47 
60 
91 
79 

1 
4 
2 

5 
1 
2 
1 
2 
7 
6 
6 
52 
19 
37 
19 
22 
8 
5 
2 
41 
40 
16 
26 
28 
22 
8 
8 
4 
9 
7 
20 
23 
20 

1 
2 
1 

i 
4 

1 
4 
2 
6 
2 
1 
2 
4 
4 
2 
3 
3 
3 
2 
2 
3 
7 
4 
7 

12 

"i" 

5 

1 
1 
1 
1 
1 
1 

i' 
l 

2 
4 
2 
2 
1 

1 
5 
2 
5 
2 
3 
13 
11 
14 
15 
17 
25 
23 
20 
36 
21 
31 
25 
19 
32 
27 
31 
21 
24 
30 
19 
23 
30 
36 
28 
27 
52 
61 
54 

I 

! 

97 
131 
86 

56 
49 
56 
46 
61 
93 
99 
120 
160 
193 
230 
273 
282 
330 
358 
374 
400 
392 
309 
326 
346 
273 
317 
341 
348 
351 
360 

3 
4 
4 
3 
1 
2 

2 
2 
2 
1 
1 
1 
2 
2 
3 
1 
4 
1 
4 

12 
41 
4 
14 
1 
17 

100 
26 
42 
61 
30 
57 
107 
54 
89 
32 
182 
186 
109 

5' 

34' 

6 

9 
5 
16 
17 

19 
2 
16 
4 
66 
17 
80 

365 
531 
516 
513 </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
STATB HOSPITAL FOR INSANR 

79 

TABLE NO. 1. 

Melancholia — 

Acute 136 86 222 

Sub-acute 15 33 48 

Chronic 9 17 26 


OVEMENT OF 

'OPULATION. 

1903 

1904 

Tou: 

for 

'ears 

m 

I 
"3 
§ 
ft. 

I 

1 
3 

8 
I 

I 

I 
S3 

v 
"3 

1 

n hospital at beginning 
of year 
Returned from parole . . . 
Vdmitted 

— 

194 
7 
308 

322 
9 
222 

— 

516 
16 

330 
Q 

M 

513 
17 
524 

d 

— 

322 
18 
420 

516 
33 
.054 

183 

8 
3:6 

Under treatment 

509 

553 

1062 

517 

537 

1054 

843 

7ed 

I 1603 

Discharged recovered . . . 
Discharged improved... 
Discharged unimproved. 
Discharged not insane. . . 
transferred to Hastings. 
absent on parole 
Sloped 
Died 

98 
48 
12 
4 
127 
8 
] 
28 

68 
43 
11 

166 
91 
23 
4 
186 
17 
1 
61 

77 
44 
15 
4 
99 
35 
4 
25 

% 

113 
79 
20 
7 
109 
80 
4 
54 

175 
92 
27 
8 
226 

104 
78 
16 
a 

279 
170 
43 
11 
295 
97 
5 
115 

' '59 
9 

A 

54 

33 

-id 

A 

¦&gt; 

Total removed 

326 

223 

549 

303 

466 

629 

1015 

163 

Remaining Nov. 30. . . 

183 

330 

513 

214 

374 

588 

214 

374 

« 

Av. number treated 

227.7 

360.9 

588.7 

365.5 

575.8 

215.2 

TABL] 

B NO. 2. 

HType of Disease o\ 
r- 

1 Patients Admitted. 

Males. Females. 

Total. 

Acute 

91 44 

135 

Sub-acute 

68 18 

86 

Chronic 

46 39 

85 

Recurrent 

19 19 

38 

Puerperal 

3 

3 </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
80 


Dementia — 

Primary 4 1 5 

Secondary 20 43 63 

Senile 35 23 58 

Organic 24 7 31 

Acute delirium 5 5 

Circular insanity 3 3 

Paranoia 15 22 37 

Paresis 32 8 40 

Epileptic insanity 51 22 73 

Alcoholic insanity 24 1 25 

Drug habit 8 9 17 

Imbecility 18 6 24 

Not insane 11 3 14 

Totals 634 420 1,054 

TABLE NO. 3. 

Counties From Which Patients Were Admitted, 

Males. Females. Total. 

Adams 13 10 23 

Antelope. 8 2 10 

Boone 4 . . 4 

3 9 

2 10 

4 18 

2 16 

2 6 

5 12 

13 24 

1 3 

2 8 

Cheyenne 2 . . 2 

Clay 3 4 7 

n 

Colfax 2 7 9 


BoxButte 6 

Brown 8 

Buffalo 14 

Butler 14 

Boyd 4 

¦** » 

°- » 

Chase 2 

Cherry 6 </seg>


            <seg id="p015">
81 

Caster 12 5 17 

Cedar , , 7 5 12 

1 • 

Dakota » 3 . . 3 
Dawes 5 16 

4 8 

1 


9 19 

49 132 

Dundy 3 . . 3 

Fillmore 7 6 13 

Franklin 10 1 H 

Frontier 4 . . 4 

Fumas 6 4 10 

Gage 12 12 24 

Eeld 

2 .. 2 

Greeley 3 14 

** 3 » * 

er 4 . . 4 


Hall 10 8 18 

Hamilton 5 6 11 

Harlan 4 5 9 

Hayes 3 . . 3 

Hitchcock 3 2 5 

Howard 3 6 9 

Holt 6 6 12 

Jefferson 9 10 19 

Johnson 5 3 8 

Keith 1 1 2 

Kearney 7 6 13 

KeyaPaha 2 .. 2 

Kimball 1 .. 1 

Knox. 10 6 16 

Lancaster 90 66 156 

Lincoln 3 . . 3 


ftTflQI8OTl ••••••••••••• • 1 5 

?awson ,. 4 

*nel 1 

ixon 3 

ouglaa 83 </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
82 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Merrick 7 4 11 

Nance 5 2 7 

Nemaha 12 5 17 

Nuckolls 7 5 12 

T 

Otoe 16 11 27 

Pawnee 7 4 11 

Perkins 1 . . • 1 

Phelps 3 . . 3 

Pierce 6 4 10 

Platte 7 5 12 


Polk 8 3 11 

Red Willow 1 1 2 

2 

7 18 

1 2 

11 15 

2 3 

13 24 

Seward 6 5 11 

Sheridan 4 . . 4 

Sherman 2 2 4 

_ 

Sioux 1 1 2 

Stanton 4 8 12 

Scotts Bluff 1 1 2 

Thaver 12 5 17 

Vallev 6 4 10 

Washington 9 5 14 

Wayne 9 3 12 

Webster 5 8 13 

Wheeler 1 1 

York 8 7 15 

TABLE NO. 4. 
'Ages of Patients Admitted. 

Age— Males. Females. Total. 

15 to 20 28 20 48 

20 to 25 64 35 99 

25 to 30 74 47 121 

Richardson 

Kock 

1 

Saline 

4 

Sarpy 

1 

Saunders 

11 </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

83 

30 to 35 81 55 136 

35 to 40 74 62 136 

40 to 45. . . , 72 46 118 

45 to 50 61 39 100 

50 to 55 47 37 g4 

55 to 60 39 21 60 

60 to 65 24 20 44 

65 to 70 23 11 34 

70 to 75 23 10 33 

75 to 80 12 8 20 

80 to 85 9 5 u 

85 to 90 2 1 3 

Unknown 1 3 4 

Totals 634 420 1,054 

TABLE NO. 5. 

Civil Condition of Patients Admitted. 

Males. Females. Total. 

Married 235 238 473 

Single 323 98 421 

Widowed 57 62 119 

Divorced 14 21 35 

Unknown 5 1 6 

Totals 634 420 1,054 

TABLE NO. 6. 
Nativity of Patients Admitted. 

Males. Females. Total. 

Austria 8 5 13 

Bohemia 12 13 25 

1 13 


4 16 

1 

47 123 

Canada 1 

Denmark li 

England 1 

France </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
84 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Holland 1 l 2 

Italy 1 . . i 

Ireland 20 4 24 

Iceland 1 i 

Moravia 2 4 C 

Norway 4 4 8 

Poland 3 2 5 

Prince Edward Isle 1 1 

Rumania 1 . . l 

Bmnsi 4 9 13 

Scotland 1 .. l 

Sweden 36 23 59 

Switzerland 1 2 3 

* * dlCS •¦••¦••••••••¦••••••¦••»••.. £ o 

K 

i&gt; 

United States 423 277 700 

Unknown 4 6 10 

Totals 634 420 1,054 

TABLE NO. 7. 

Occupations of Patients Admitted. 

Males. Females. Total. 

Agents 7 1 8 

Bartenders 3 . . 3 

Blacksmiths 7 

•7 

7 


Barbers 6 . . 6 

Boarding housekeepers 1 1 

Bookkeepers 1 1 

Bookbinder 1 1 

Boilermaker 1 . . 1 

Broker 1 . . 1 

Batchers 2 .. 2 

_ 

Carpenters 22 . . 22 

Canvasser 1 . . 1 

Clerks • 7 7 </seg>


            <seg id="p019">
¦ 

STATE HOSPITAL FOE INSANE. 

Contractor 1 . . 1 

Collectors 1 . . 1 

Cooks 3 . . 3 

Domestics * 23 23 

Dentist 1 . . 1 

Dressmakers 8 8 

Draymen 2 . . 2 

_ 

Druggists 3 . . 3 

Electrician 1 . . 1 

Engineers, stationary 3 .. 3 

Engineers, locomotive. 3 . . 3 

Farmers 239 . . 23H 

Farm laborers 66 . . 66 

Fireman, stationary 1 . . 1 

Firemen, locomotive 2 . . 2 

Gardener 1 . . 1 

Hack driver 1 . . 1 

Horse trainers 2 . . 3 

Housekeepers 309 309 

Laborers 118 2 120 

Lather 1 . • 1 

Lawyers 4 . . 4 

Masons 6 . . 6 

Matron 1 1 

Merchants 8 . . 8 

Musicians 3 . . 3 

Music teacher 1 1 

Miller 1 . . 1 

Machinist 1 . . 1 

Miners 2 . . 2 

Missionary 1 . . 1 

Painters 7 . . 7 

Peddlers 2 .. 2 

Physicians 7 

Plasterers 2 . . 2 

Policeman 1 . . 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
86 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Porters 2 

1 


Printers. 8 . . 8 

Postal clerk 1 .. 1 

Railroad conductors 2 . . 2 

Railroad laborers •. 6 . . 6 

Sheep herders 2 . . 2 

Shoemaker 1 . . 1 

Steamfitter 1 . . 1 

Street car conductor 1 . . 1 


Stenographer 1 1 

Teachers 15 6 

Telegrapher 1 . . 1 

Trapper 1 . . 1 

Traveling salesmen 6 .. 6 

Tinners 2 . . 2 

- 

Tailors 3 . . 3 

Veterinary surgeon 1 . . 1 

Waiters 2 . . 2 

Wagonmaker 1 . . 1 

Well digger. 1 . . 1 

Washwomen 2 2 

No occupation 34 56 90 

Unknown 3 . . S 

Totals 634 420 1,054 

TABLE NO. 8. 

Causes of Death. 

Males. Females. Total. 


Anaemia 2 2 

Cerebral apoplexy 2 5 7 

Brain tumors. . 2 . . 2 

Carcinoma of intestines 2 2 

Acute delirium 4 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

87 

Diabetes millitis 1 1 2 

Dysentery 2 '2 

Erysipelas 1 3 4 

Epilepsy 2 1 3 

Exhaustion of acute mania 8 1 9 

Exhaustion of chronic mania 1 1 

Exhaustion of acute melancholia 4 4 8 

Exhaustion of senile dementia 5 2 7 

Epithelioma of face 1 . . 1 

Enteritis 1 1 

Enteric fever 2 2 

Meningitis cerebro spinal 1 1 

Organic brain disease 13 2 15 

Organic heart disease 1 2 3 

Pneumonia. 1 14 15 

Pleuritis 1 . . 1 

Paralysis of the heart 2 2 

Pachymeningitis 1 . . 1 

Paresis 7 4 11 

Pulmonary tuberculosis 3 3 

Senile gangrene 1 1 

Inanition 1 1 

Suicide 1 . . 1 
Tuberculosis meningitis 1 ... 1 

Totals 43 62 115 

REPORT OP STEWARD. 

STATEMENT OP INCOME AND EXPENSES OF FARM, QABDEN AND 
PIGGERY FOB TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1904. 

FARM. 
Expense. 

Inventory : Live stock, implements, etc., December 

1, 1902 | 4,000 00 

Wages and board 3,240 00 </seg>


            <seg id="p022">
88 


Seed $ 387 09 

Repairs, horseshoeing, blacksmith ing, etc 866 51 

Threshing, shredding, bailing, binding twine, etc. . 386 46 

Machinery 533 82 

Veterinary 43 50 

Stock purchased 1,365 40 

Miscellaneous 30 00 

Kent 1,122 00 

Total 115,150 08 

Income. 

Millet, 100 tons f 600 00 

Hay, alfalfa, 100 tons 700 00 

Hay, prairie, 150 tons 900 00 

Cane, 100 tons 300 00 

Corn fodder, 100 tons 300 00 

Com, in ear, 5,725 bushels 2,003 75 

Sugar beets 457 24 

Wheat, 1,872 bushels 1,569 99 

Potatoes, 4,011 bushels 1,002 75 

Milk, 56,708 gallons 6,804 96 

Rye, 200 bushels 80 00 

Oats, 3,046 bushels 761 50 

Sundry sales, rents, hides, etc 1,285 40 

Beef, butchered and delivered to kitchen, 22,870 

lbs 1,600 90 

Use of men and teams 4,608 00 

Inventory, December 1, 1904 6,898 00 

Total |29,872 49 

Total income |29,872 49 

Total expemw 15,150 08 </seg>


            <seg id="p023">
89 


PIGGERY. 

Expense. 

Stock on hand December 1, 1902 f 906 00 

Wages and board 1,224 00 

Feed 1,255 00 

Repairs 340 40 

Building fence. 365 75 

Miscellaneous. 6 00 

Stock purchased 142 50 

Total $4,239 65 

Income. 

Sale of hogs $2,033 28 

Sale of stock hogs 310 00 

Hogs butchered and delivered to kitchen, 7,495 lbs. . 524 65 

Stock on hand December 1, 1904 2,426 00 

Total |5,293 93 

Total income |5,293 93 

Total expenses 4,239 65 

Gain |l,054 28 

GARDEN. 
Expense. 

Wages and board $2,688 00 

Seed i 379 42 

Implements 22 00 

Feed. 150 00 

Repairs 10 00 

Total 13^49 42 

Income. 

Apples, 930 bushels f 639 00 

Asparagus, 72£ bushels 298 25 

Beans, 333 bushels 353 60 </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
90 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

.Beets, 180 bushels $ 128 8 &lt; 

Cabbage, 9,698 head 335 88 

Carrote, 272$ bushels 67 93 

Cauliflower, 16£ bushels 12 75 

Celery, 1,020 bunches 59 12 

Corn, sweet, 451 bushels 391 25 

Cucumbers, 533 bushels 177 00 

Egg plant, 21 bu 5 25 

Grapes, i bushel 2 00 

Green pepper, 1£ bushels 1 50 

Hubbard squash, 545 head 38 30 

Mangoes, 17 bushels 12 75 

Oyster plant, If bushels 1 75 

Parsnips, 308 bushels 74 75 

Peas, 311 bushels 467 00 

Pie plant, 242 bushels 121 50 

Potatoes, 3,844f bushels 1,604 47 

Pumpkin, 7 head 70 

Radishes, 121J bushels 45 06 

Rutabagas, 124£ bushels 31 00 

Salsify, 8$ bushels 2 88 

Spinach, 40 bushels 10 00 

Tomatoes, 1,009 bushels 620 37 

Turnips, 189J bushels 40 29 

Summer squash, 3 head 15 

Sweet potatoes, 113£ bushels 217 15 

Total $5,760 52 

Total income |5,760 52 

Total expense 3,249 42 

Gain. $2,511 10 </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANH. 

91 

RECAPITULATION. 

Income. 

Farm $29,872 49 

Piggery 5,293 93 

Garden 5,760 52 $40,926 94 

Expense. 

Farm |15,150 08 

Piggery 4,239 65 

Garden 3,249 42 22,639 15 

Gain $18,287 79 

CASH FUND. 

STEWARD'S REPORT — A. D. GILMORE, STEWARD. 

Receipts — 1902. 

Dec. 1, Balance on hand $1,925 87 

Dec. 3, Mr. Box, services of bull 1 00 

Dec. 3, Sale of one boar pig 10 00 

Dec. 3, Harman, sale two syrup barrels at 50c. . . 1 00 

Dec. 4, G. W. Dishong, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 3 00 

Dec. 4, Geo. Underwood, same as Dishong 3 33 

Dec. 4, Maude Williams, same as Dishong 1 13 

Dec. 4, Zenobia Doty, same as Dishong 2 67 

Dec. 4, T. H. Slattery, sale of coal 4 98 

Dec. 20« A. H. Merkel, sale one boar pig 10 00 

Dec. 20, B. R. Harrison, sale one boar pig 10 00 

Dec. 22, John Shea, sale one boar pig 10 00 

Dec. 27, John Luckhardt, weighing load of hay. . . 10 

Dec. 27, C. W. Jester, services of bull 1 00 

1903. 

Jan. 10, J. C. Cherry, time lost after pay roll was 

sent to Secretary of State 22 

Jan. 10, G. F. Ellis, same as Cherry 20 </seg>


            <seg id="p026">
92 


Jan. 10, Zenobia Doty, same as Cherry $ 32 

Jan. 10, E. Tyrer, sale one load cobs 50 

Jan. 10, Robt. Bear, sale one load cobs 50 

Jan. 10, Robt. Bear, coal 10 30 

10 88 

5 80 

1 00 

100 

8 00 

10 

43 50 

15 00 


24 00 

Jan. 29, E. S, Davis, warden penitentiary, hauling 

175 loads ice at 10c 17 50 

Jan. 30, Standard Oil Co., sale 5 empty bbls. at 95c 4 75 

Jan. 30, Standard Oil Co., 1 empty linseed and 2 

lubricating bbls. at 75c 2 25 

Jan. 30, Weighing 2 loads hay 10 

Jan. 31, O. D. Rosencran, sale 2 bu. wheat at 50c. . 1 00 

Feb. 2, Weighing 2 loads hay 10 

Feb. 5, N. R. Poole, time lost after pay roll was 

sent to Secretary of State 22 

9,o 

Feb. 5, Bertha Ludwig, same as Poole 3 63 

Feb. 5, Minnie Meneese, same as Poole 1 29 

Feb. 10, Geo. Barber Co., sale 38 hogs, 8,330 lbs., 

80 lbs. dockage, at |6.25 per cwt 515 62 

Feb. 10, 2 dead hogs, 370 lbs., at fl less freight 

charges, 40c 3 30 

Feb. 19, Walter 8. Duncan, services of bull 1 00 

Feb. 20, Walter Seidell, weighing load hay 10 

tlO, Geo. Rheinschield, sale coal 
10, J. H. Weart, sale coal 

an. 12, Clara Wells, sale medicine 
an. 22, Geo. Reed, five loads ice at 20c each 
an. 24, Yankee Hill Brick Yard, sale 40 loads ice 

at 20c each 

Weighing 2 loads hay 
24, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 7 No. 1 green 

hides and 5 calf, 600 lbs., at 7£c per lb. 
(an. 24, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 3 No. 2 green 

Chides, 240 lbs., at 6£c per lb 
26, J. J. Peterson, sale 3 empty coffee boxes 

at 10c 

fan. 29, E. 8. Davis, warden penitentiary, hauling 

1ft irtQrla ino 

it&gt; loaas ice </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
93 


Feb. 20, Wilber Mills, 150 bran sacks at 4c each. .| 6 00 

Feb. 23, Clarence Chittenden, weighing load hay. . 10 

Feb. 25, Cash sale 1 pork barrel 1 00 

Feb. 28, Jas. Read, sale 2 empty syrup bbls 1 00 

Mar. 1, Wm. Vogt, services of bull 1 00 

Mar. 1, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 8 syrup bbls. 

at 50c 4 00 

t. 5, Jas. HarlaD, time lost after pay roll was 
sent to Secretary of State 1 07 

Mar. 5, Geo. Rheinschield, 2,920 lbs. coal at $4.65. 6 79 

Mar. 5, J. A. Weart, 3,360 lbs. coal at |4.65 7 81 

Mar. 5, E. Tyrer, 1 load cobs 50 

Mar. 5, Kobt. Bear, 1 load cobs 50 

Mar. 5, D. A. Campbell, pasture 3 months, 1902. . 3 00 

Mar. 11, Weighing 1 load hay 10 

Mar. 21, One ton millet hay to Nelson 4 00 

Mar. 26, One load cobs 60 

t. 26, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 8 hides, including 
3 calf, 343 lbs., at 6£c, No. 1 22 29 

Mar. 26, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 8 hides, includ- 

ing 1 calf, 485 lbs., at 5*c, No. 2 26 67 

Mar. 30, Sale 2 bu. oats at 35c 70 

Mar. 30, Two bales hay at 30c 60 

Mar. 30, One pair young rabbits 1 00 

Apr. 8, Maud Williams, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 4 39 

Apr. 8, Jas. Harlan, same as Miss Williams 24 

Apr. 8, J. R. Burroughs, same as Miss Williams. . 5 32 

Apr. 8, Alma Peterson, same as Miss Williams. . 1 29 

Apr. 8, Kate Wilterding, same as Miss Williams. 65 

Apr. 8, Robt Bear, same as Miss Williams 89 

Apr. 8, Zenobia Doty, same as Miss Williams ... 32 

Apr. 8, Mr. Sullivan, weighing 2 loads hogs 20 

Apr. 8, Sale 1 cow and 1 calf skin, 45 lbs., at 6$c. 2 92 

Apr. 18, Error made in duplicating act. H. E. Gra- 

ham. (See vouchers 11382 and 84) ... 8 78 </seg>


            <seg id="p028">
94 


Apr. 18, Chittenden, weighing load corn I 10 

Apr. 24, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 1 cow and calf 

hide, 67 lbs., at 6£c. 4 35 

Apr. 21, Harriet Crabtree, 8$ weeks' board at $3. . 25 00 

Apr. 21, Humphrey Hdw. Co., rebate on listers 2 00 

Apr. 21, Humphrey Hdw. Co., rebate on farm 

wagon 5 00 

May 4, Mrs. Robinson, cash for 1 bottle medicine. 2 00 

May 6, B. &amp; M. Ry., rent on land for sheep barns. 250 00 

May 8, Julia Christianson, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 1 67 

May 8, Harriet Crabtree, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State. 3 00 

May 8, Alma Peterson, same as Miss Crabtree. . . 1 47 

May 8, Eva Harnish, same as Miss Crabtree 73 

May 10, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 6 syrup bbls. 

at 50c 3 00 

tlO, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., No. 1 Q. S. cow 
hide, 29 lbs., at 7c 2 03 

May 12, T. H. Williams, sale 1 pig 4 00 

May 14, J. P. Higgins, sale 12 hogs, 3,500 lbs., at f 6 210 00 

May 16, D. Morland, pasture cow and colt, season 

1902 6 50 

May 19, Dr. Wente, sale 2 brood sows 30 00 

May 27, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 7 bbls. at 50c 3 50 

May 30, D. Moreland, sale 4 loaves bread 20 

June 5, Alma Peterson, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 35 

June 5, Eva Harnish, same as Miss Peterson. ... 5 68 

June 20, Payment services of bull 1 00 

June 23, L. H. Lawton, payment 1 month's main- 

tenance Ralph Lawton 12 50 

June 25, Geo. Hoburt, payment 1 month's pasture. 1 50 

July 3, Thompson, pasture 1 cow 1 month 1 50 

July 10, T. P. Currie, time lost after pay roll was 

sent to Secretary of State 25 

July 10, Celia Dempsey, same as Mr. Currie 83 </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
95 


July 10, Alma Peterson, same as Mr. Currie f 37 

July 10, Mabel Houck, same as Mr. Currie 2 50 

July 10, Annis Wilterding, same as Mr. Currie. . . 42 

July 10, Sturdivant, same as Mr. Currie 3 75 

July 10, T. H. Williams, sale 1 pig 4 00 

July 10, Geo. Blakeley, 1 piece lumber 2x4x16. ... 25 

July 10, T. H. Williams, sale 840 lbs. damaged com 

at 15c 1 80 

July 10, May E. Jester, pasture cow May and June 3 00 

JuJy 17, Wilson Steam Boiler Co., payment for 2 

second-hand boilers 200 00 

July 22, C. W. Huyck, sale old lumber 15 00 

July 22, L. H. Lawton, 1 month's maintenance 

Ralph Lawton 12 50 

July 28, J. L. Greene, sale 10 lbs. butter (fl.60), 

cabbage (f 1) 2 60 

July 28, Mr. Dutton, cash for services of bull 1 00 

Aug. 1, B. Hawkins, pasture season 1902 9 00 

Aug. 11, G. F. Ellis, sale 2 sow pigs 15 00 

Aug. 11, Geo. Blakeley, sale 11.4 bu. corn at 35c. . 4 00 

Aug. 11, Mabel Houck, time lost after pay roll was 

sent to Secretary of State 2 42 

Aug. 11, E. Tyrer, sale 6,504 hay 2 27 

Aug. 11, Mr. Hood, pasture 2 cows May 11 to Aug. 

11, 1903 9 00 

Aug. 11, E. Longacre, time lost after pay roll was 

sent to Secretary of State 6 45 

Aug. 12, Geo. Underwood, sale 4 bu. cane seed at 

50c 2 00 

Aug. 17, J. Hoffman, sale 2 bu. seed rye at 75c .... 1 50 

Aug. 20, Obed Stettler, sale 3 boar pigs at $15 45 00 

Aug. 20, M. Bettes, 2 months' pasture 1 cow 3 00 

Aug. 26, L. H. Lawton, 1 month's maintenance of 

Ralph Lawton 12 50 

Aug. 27, Mrs. Person, 7 meals at 25c . 1 75 

Aug. 29, W. S. Dutton, rent of pasture Farnam 

land 15 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
96 


Sept. 1, Nannie Taft, sale 1 ba. tomatoes f 50 

Sept 7, Wilson Steam Boiler Co., bal. on boilers. 100 00 

Sept. 11, Dr. A. P. Ferguson, sale 1 bu. cucumbers. 40 

Sept 12, K. Tyrer, sale 2 runt pigs 2 00 

Sept 12, T. H. Williams, sale hay 4 60 

Sept. 12, Robt. Bear, time lost after pay roll was 
sent to Secretary of State 44 

Sept 12, G. H. Walker, same as Mr. Bear 1 21 

Sept 12, T. P. Currie, same as Mr. Bear 48 

Sept. 12, Henrietta Hammond, same as Mr. Bear. . 1 42 

Sept 12, Duncan Campbell, 1 month's pasture of 

cow 2 00 

Sept 16, Nannie Taft, sale 3 bu. tomatoes, 1 bu. cu- 

cumbers 1 90 

Sept. 16, Cash for services of bull 95 

Sept 21, John Ulcek, sale 1 boar pig 15 00 

Sept 22, L. H. Lawton, 1 month's maintenance of 

Ralph Lawton 12 50 

Oct 1, W. J. Hampton, sale of hay and oats. ... 60 

Oct. 9, W. Critchfield, pasture 1 cow 2 month*. . 3 00 

Oct 9, P. O. Wilson, 1 bu. seed rye 75 

Oct. 10, Earl Longacre, time lost after pay roll was 
sent to Secretary of State 3 00 

Oct. 10, Sadie Striker, same as Mr. Longacre 2 20 

Oct. 10, Bessie Reed, same as Mr. Longacre 73 

Oct. 10, Lukhart, sale 1 boar pig 15 00 

Oct. 10, Cash, services of bull, balance 05 

Oct 12, Mr. Wiers, sale 1 bu. rye 75 

Oct. 18, Mrs. Person, for meals 1 60 

Oct 21, Mr. Bobbie, sale 2 bu. rye 1 50 

Oct. 24, L. H. Lawton, 1 month's maintenance of 

Ralph Lawton 12 50 

Oct. 29, W. Critchfield, pasture 1 cow 2 months. ... 3 00 

Nov. 7, David Barry, sale 10 young bogs 55 50 

Nov. 10, R. L. Hood, 2 cows 2 months' pasture 6 50 

Nov. 10, E. L. Snyder, time lost after pay roll was </seg>


            <seg id="p031">
97 


Not. 10, L. H. Richards, same as Mr. Snyder $ 1 61 

Nov. 10, Mabel McGaw, same as Mr. Snyder 4 03 

Nov. 10, C. N. Skoglund, same as Mr. Snyder 4 64 

Nov. 13, T. H. Williams, sale 3 shoats at $4 12 00 

Nov. 15, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 5 No. 1 

hides, 66 lbs., at 7c 4 62 

Nov. 15, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 5 No. 2 

hides, 86 lbs., at 6c 5 16 

Nov. 16, American Beet Sugar Co., sale 48,639 lbs. 

beets at $4 per ton and 108,036 lbs. 
beets at $4.25 per ton, less seed $30, and 

rent implements $6 290 86 

Nov. 20, F. Stafford, weighing 1 load hogs 05 

Nov. 23, John Bard, weighing one load of corn. . . (»."» 

Nov. 26, L. H. Lawton, for maintenance of Ralph 

Lawton 1 month 12 50 

Dec. 1, Otto Anderson, sale cracked kettle 1 00 

Dec. 4, Lincoln Mill Co., 612.50 bu. wheat at 62c, 

$379.70; less freight on car, $5 374 70 

Dec. 5, Griswold Seed Co., sale 2,879 lbs. seed 

sweet corn, 64 lbs. per bu., at 75c 33 89 

Dec. 5, Humphrey Hdw. Co., sale 27 6-7 bu. seed 
corn at 75c 20 88 

Dec. 5, Sale 3,000 lbs. rags at lc 30 00 

Dec. 10, E. Ramey, time lost after pay roll was 

sent to Secretary of State 3 00 

Dec. 10, Harriet Crabtree, same as Ramey 1 00 

Dec. 10, W. P. Ramey, same as E. Ramey 67 

Dec. 10, Lonetta Wanser, same as Ramey 1 33 

Dec. 10, H. G. Schmidt, same as Ramey 42 

Dec. 10, H. E. Austin, same as Ramey 21 

Dec. 10, Annis Wilterding, same as Ramey 38 

Dec. 10, Bessie Reed, same as Ramey 73 

Dec. 10, Lou Crooks, same as Ramey 5 13 

Dec. 10, Maud Williams, same as Ramey 37 

Dec. 10, H. F. Railsbach, sale 6 lbs. fresh pork 

at 10c. . 60 </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
98 


Dec. 10, Robt. Bear, sale 4 bu. oats at 30c $ 1 20 

Dec. 10, Robt. Bear, sale 5 bu. corn at 30c 1 50 

Dec. 10, E. Tyrer, sale 40 lbs. tallow at 3£c 1 40 

Dec. 10, E. Tyrer, sale 5 bu. oats at 30c 1 50 

Dec. 10, Jas. Coen, sale 39 qts. milk at 5c 1 95 

Dec. 10, Jas. Coen, sale 28 loaves bread at 6£c .... 1 75 

Dec. 10, Jas. Coen, sale 1 bu. corn 30 

Dec. 14, W. Critchfield, 2 months' pasture 1 cow. . 3 00 

Dec. 14, E. R. Slawson, 2,905 lbs. old iron at 25c. . 7 35 

1 tec. 14, E. R. Slawson, 30 lbs. old iron at lc 30 

Dec. 18, E. R. Slawson, 2,300 lbs. old iron at 25c. . 5 75 

Dec. 18, E. R. Slawson, 3,840 lbs. old iron at 20c. . 7 68 

Dec. 18, J. R. Burroughs, sale 1 hog for J. A. 

Weart 4 00 

Dec. 19, P. T. Wilson, for pasture 10 25 

Dec. 19, Cash for services of bull 1 00 

Dec. 31, L. H. Lawton, maintenance of Ralph 

Lawton 12 50 

Dec. 31, Mr. Nelson, sale of field of cornstalk 10 00 

190J,. 

Jan. 8, Dess Hoffman, time lost after pay roll was 

sent to Secretary of State 5 64 

Jan. 8, Lonetta Wanser, same as Dess Hoffman . . 81 

Jan. 8, Anna Elliott, same as Dess Hoffman 30 

Jan. 8, Carrie Storkan, same as Dess Hoffman ... 27 

Jan. 8, Jeanette Misener, same as Dess Hoffman . 32 

Jan. 8, Cecelia Murphy, same as Dess Hoffman. . 24 

Jan. 8, Hattie McKelvey, same as Dess Hoffman. 48 

Jan. 8, James Harlan, same as Dess Hoffman. ... 48 

Jan. 8, J. E. Williams, same as Dess Hoffman. . . 24 

Jan. 8, M. E. Higgins, same as Dess Hoffman. ... 87 

Jan. 8, Dora Packwood, same as Dess Hoffman . . 40 

Jan. 8, Nannie Taft, same as Dess Hoffman 4 84 

Jan. 8, Bessie Reed, same as Dess Hoffman 52 

Jan. 8, Maud Williams, same as Doss Hoffman. . 1 60 

.Tan, 8 Ethel Campbell same as Dess Hoffman . . 1 48 </seg>


            <seg id="p033">
99 

Jan. 9, Jag. Coen, sale 2 bu. corn at 30c f &lt;&gt;() 

Jan. 9, Jas. Coen, sale 28 qts. milk at 5c 1 40 

Jan. 9, Jas. Coen, sale 14 loaves bread at G^e. ... 87 

Jan. 11, lbs. Bpirey, sale of medicine 1 00 

Jan. 23, E. S. Mickey, sale 1,800 lbs. millet and 

cane hay 6 75 

Jan. 27, Sale 65 head hogs, 13,580 lbs., at 

$4.80 f651 84 

Freight charges 18 40 

Yardage 5 20 

Corn 2 00 

Inspection charges 15 

Commission 6 00 620 09 

Jan. 30, Mr. Clause, sale 9 loads from ice pond 
at 10c 90 

Jan. 30, Mr. Deal, sale 5 loads from ice pond at 10c 50 

Jan. 30, Mr. Wins, sale 1 hog, 90 lbs., at 5c 4 50 

Jan. 30, L. H. L&lt;awton, for maintenance of Ilalph 

Lawton 1 month 12 50 

Feb. 2, E. Walworth, cash for services of boar. . . 1 00 

Feb. 3, Carrie Storkan, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 1 37 

Feb. 3, A.. C. Pentico, same as Miss Storkan 97 

Feb. 3, Jeanette Misener, same as Miss Storkan. . 65 

Feb. 3, Bertha Berryman, same as Miss Storkan. 2 54 

Feb. 3, Bertha I-udwig, same as Miss Storkan. . . 81 

Feb. 3, Nannie Taft, same as Miss Storkan 1 21 

Feb. 3, Liou Crooks, same as Miss Storkan 18 

Feb. 3, Bessie Reed, same as Miss Storkan 18 

Feb. 3, Nettie Shirey, same as Miss Storkan. ... 2 84 

Feb. 3, Ellen Bowery, same as Miss Storkan. ... 2 65 

Feb. 3, T. H. Williams, sale 1,220 lbs. ear com at 
30c 5 10 

Feb. 3, James Coen, sale 24 qts. milk at 5c 1 20 

Feb. 21, Mr. Westover, cash for damage by stock. . 1 00 

Feb. 21, L. H. Lawton, for maintenance of Ralph 

Lawton • 12 50 </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
100 

. LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

Mar. 1, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 3 hides, No. 
1, 94 lbs., at 7±c $ 6 81 

Mar. 1, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 7 hides, No. 

2, 432 lbs., at 6*c 27 00 

Mar. 1, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 1 green 

hides, 38 lbs., at 6|c! 2 37 

Mar. 1, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 9 No. 2 green 

hides, branded, 576 lbs., at 5Jc 30 24 

Mar. 7, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 3 No. 1 G. 8. 

hides, 91 lbs., at 7£c 6 59 

Mar. 7, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 6 No. 2 G. S. 

hides, 408 lbs., at 6£c 25 50 

Mar. 7, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 2 G. S. 

hides, 103 lbs., at 5-Jc. 5 41 

r. 7, W. A. Campbell, time lost after pay roll 
was sent to Secretary of State 1 25 

Mar. 7, Bessie Heed, same as Campbell 35 

Mar. 12, James Coen, 4 runt pigs 4 00 

Mar. 12, James Coen, sale 40 qts. milk at 5c 2 00 

Mar. 12, J. Clakerell, services of bull 1 00 

Mar. 12, E. Tyrer, sale old stone 1 50 

Mar. 12, E. Tyrer, sale 5 bu. oats at 35c 1 75 

Mar. 16, Alex. Bramer, sale 4 cans fruit at 15c. ... 60 

Mar. 16, Alex. Bramer, sale 1.000 lbs. old rags 10 00 

Mar. 17, W. A. Campbell, sale 1 gal. vinegar 25 

Mar. 17, John Hanggi, sale 21 lbs. candy left from 

Christmas 3 15 

Mar. 19, Geo. Underwood, sale 1 syrup bbl 50 

Mar. 19, Geo. Underwood, sale 2 bu. rye at 75c. ... 1 50 

Mar. 24, Mr. Derry (an attendant), sale 20 lbs. 

sugar at 5c 1 00 

Mar. 24, E. Hager, sale condemned tinners' tools. . 5 00 

Mar. 26, Swan Aldeen, for maintenance of Alb. 

Lindberg, from Jan. 17 to April 17, 

1904, 3 months, at $12.50 37 50 

Mar. 29, Mr. Derry (an attendant), sale of lemons. 19 </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
101 


Mar 

29, J. K. Perbaugh, sale 34 hogs, 6,230 lbs., at 


Apr. 
Apr. 
Apr. 
Apr. 
Apr. 
Apr. 
Apr. 
Apr. 
Apr. 

£ 

Apr. 

Apr. 

May 1, G. R. Critchfield, pasture 1 cow 1 month. . 1 50 

May 2, M. Langley, sale 2 bu. rye 1 00 

May 4, E. Tyrer, time lost after pay roll was sent 

to Secretary of State 23 

May 4, W. W. Wash, same as Tyrer 92 

May 4, T. B. Barnes, same as Tyrer 2 29 

May 4, Ellen Bowery, same as Tyrer 2 28 

May 4, Annis Wilterding, same as Tyrer 41 

May 4, Marguerite McClung, same as Tyrer 92 

May 4, Josephine Kelly, same as Tyrer 77 

-- 

May 4, Bessie Reed, same as Tyrer 83 

May 4, T. H. Williams, sale 5 runt pigs at 1.50. . 7 50 

May 4, E. Tyrer, sale of wood 5 63 

14.35 f 

1, Lonetta Wanser, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 
9, Anna Elliott, same as Miss Wanser 

40 
60 

9, H. W. Keith, same as Miss Wanser 
9, H. G. Schmidt, same as Miss Wanser. . . . 

89 

9, W. W. Wash, same as Miss Wanser 

2 66 

9, Sadie Striker, same as Miss Wanser 

37 

9, Ethel Campbell, same as Miss Wanser. . . 
9, Jas. Coen, sale 7£ lbs. stock food at 8c ... 
9, Jas. Coen, sale 28 qts. milk at 5c 

5 19 
60 
1 40 

9, E. Tyrer, sale 10 bu. oats at 40c 
9, L. H. Lawton, for maintenance of Ralph 

Lawton 

12 50 

9, Cash for service of bull 

1 00 

9, Cash for sale of 2 valves 

H 

!3, B. &amp; M. It. R., rental on land leased for 

sheep sheds 

52, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 14 No. 2 

hides, 820 lbs., at 6£c 
!5, L. H. Lawton for maintenance of Ralph 

Lawton 

12 50 </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
102 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

9, Jas. Coen, sale 20 qts. milk at 5c $ 1 00 

May 16, Geo. Blakeley, sale 108 lbs. pork at 4£c. . . 4 86 

May 19, L. H. Lawton, maintenance Ralph Lawton 

22 days 8 87 

May 21, Alb. Lindberg, ] month's maintenance. . . 12 50 

June 3, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 1 G. S. bull hide. 

&gt; 

96 lbs., at 6c 5 76 

June 6, B. Hawkins, sale 3 bu. rye at 40c 1 20 

June 9, Lena Dishong, time lost after pay roll was 

sent to Secretary of State 3 71 
June 9, Sadie Striker, same as Miss Dishong 40 
June 9, J. W. Riggs, same as Miss Dishong 2 51 
June 9, W. A. Campbell, sale 2 bu. rye at 50c 1 00 
June 9, W. A. Campbell, sale 10 lbs. meat at 5c. . . 50 

June 9, T. H. Williams, sale 2 bu. corn at 44c 88 

June 9, T. H. Williams, sale 100 lbs. bran at 63c. . 63 

June 9, J. A. Weart, error in wages on pay roll. . 5 00 

June 11, Jas. Coen, sale 4£ lbs. lard at |7.35 30 

June 22, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 3 G. S. hides, 

176 lbs., at lie 13 20 
June 22, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 1 calf skin. . 40 

June 24, J. A. Weart, first payment on sale 1 cow 

at |25 5 oo 

July 1, Sale piece of ice 10 

t2, Sale to Mrs. Young and Mrs. Gilmore 8-lb. 
spring chicken 1 60 

July 2, Mrs. C. W. Jester, 2 months' pasture 1 cow 3 00 

July 8, J. A. Weart, second monthly payment on 
cow 5 00 

July 8, Margaret Hankins, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 1 90 
July 8, Jas. Coen, sale 6 lbs. bacon at 12c 72 

July 8, Jas. Coen, sale 500 lbs. coal at $4 1 00 

July 8, Jas. Coen, 1 months' pasture of cow. .... 1 50 

July 9, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., 1 G. S. hide bull, 

85 lbs., at 6£c 5 52 </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
103 

STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

July 9, P. Slatts, sale 50 lbs. ice I 10 

July 17, F. Slatts, sale 50 lbs. ice 10 

July 22, F. Slatts, sale 50 lbs. ice 10 

July 26, Sale 1,380 lbs. old rags 13 80 

July 26, Cash for long distance telephone 2 05 

July 27, F. Slatts, 50 lbs. ice 10 

July 29, R. F. Bruce, maintenance from April 30 

to July 29 36 29 

July 31, F. Slatts, sale 50 lbs. ice 10 

Aug. 1, Edgar Ramey, sale 1 bu. oats 40 

Aug. 1, Win. Haas, his share of expense of sur- 

veying for line on sec. 9-9-6 7 00 

Aug. 3, T. H. Williams, sale 2 bu. corn at 45c 90 

Aug. 3, Susie Castle, time lost after pay roll was 
sent to Secretory of State 2 90 

Aug. 3, P. A. Henry, same as Miss Castle 3 27 

Aug. 3, J. E. Williams, same as Miss Castle 4 03 

Aug. 3, L. Gentile, time lost after pay roll was 

sent to Secretary of State 4 03 

Aug. 3, Ellen Bowery, same as ( lentile 40 

Aug. 3, Nora Weart, same as Gentile 81 

Aug. 3, Henrietta Hammond, same as Gentile. . . 2 42 

Aug. 3, Sadie Striker, same as Gentile 5 64 

Aug. 3, Ethel Campbell, same as Gentile 5 94 

Aug. 3, James Harlan, same as Gentile 4 03 

Aug. 3, F. Stoats, sale piece of ice 10 

Aug. 5, J. A. Weart, third payment on cow 5 00 

Aug. 5, F. Stoats, sale of ice 10 

Aug. 5, E. Ramey, sale 1 bu. oats 40 

K 

Aug. 9, E. Wolworth, sale of cinders 2 30 

Aug. 9, F. Stoats, sale piece of ice 10 

Aug. 9, James Coen, pasture of 1 cow 1 month ... 1-50 

Aug. 9, Mrs. C. W. Jester, pasture 1 cow 1 month 1 50 

Aug. 11, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale of hides — 

3 No. 1 G. S. hides, 148 lbs., at 8c 11 84 

3 No. 2 G. S. hides, 2 calf, 91 lbs., at 7c. 6 37 </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
104 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Aug. 11, 1 bull hide, 80 lbs., at 6c f 4 80 

Aug. 19, 2 hides, No. 1 G. S., 100 lbs., at 7£c 7 50 

2 hides No. 2 G. S., 102 lbs., at 6^c. . . . 6 73 

Aug. 22, Mr. Sanfrancisco, sale 1 bu. corn 50 

Aug. 27, J. H. Smythe, sale 2 shoats at fo.Of) 10 00 

Sept, 5, H. K. Frantx, sale 15 hogs, 2,475 lbs., at 

6J,c 160 87 

Sept 5, Bartle McHugh, sale 4 hogs, 710 lbs., at 

64c 46 l.'i 

t. 5, Bartle McHugh, sale 1 boar pig 10 00 

Sept. 5, John A. Stiller, sale 1 boar pig 10 00 

Sept. 9, Celia Dempsey, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 81 

Sept. 9, James Coen, 6 lbs. bacon at 12c 72 

t. 9, J. A. Weart, fourth payment on cow 5 00 

Sept. 9, Geo. Blakeley, sale 2 old sows, 750 lbs., 

at 44c 33 75 

Sept. 9, E. Tyrer, sale 2 yds. sand 2 00 

Sept 9, W. A. Campl.pl!, sale 37 lbs. beef at 8c. . . 2 96 

Sept. 9, W. A. Campbell, sale 29 loaves 

bread at 4}c fl 30 

Old lumber 2 00 3 30 

Sept. 12, W. J. Miller, sale 3 boar pigs at $10 30 00 

Sept. 15, C. Sbafer, sale 1 boar pig 10 00 

Sept. 16, Alb. Lindberg, maintenance 50 00 

Sept 16, Dr. A. S. Ferguson, water rent 1 year to 

Aug. 1 4 50 

Sept. 25, John Barratt, 1 month's maintenance. ... 12 50 

Sept. 25, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 3 No. 1 G. S. 

hides, 146 lbs., at 74c 10 95 

Sept. 25, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 5 No. 2 G. S. 

hides, branded, 288 lbs., at 64.C 18 72 

Sept. 25, W. L. Seidell, sale 1 boar pig 10 00 

Sept 25, Louis Stein, sale 500 lbs. old rags at f 1. . . 5 00 

Sept. 26, C. E. Cunningham, sale 1 boar pig 10 00 </seg>


            <seg id="p039">
105 

STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

Sept 29, Otto Elfelt, sale 1 boar pig I 10 00 

Oct. 3, Vaclav Kastanak, sale 2 Berkshire boar 

Pigs 60 00 

t, Vaclav Kastanak. sale 1 
, J. B. Harris, sale 17-lb. ham, 
bacon, $1.25 

Berkshire sow pig U."&gt; M 
|2.55; 10-lb. 
3 80 

Oct. 3, J. B. Harris, sale 17-lb. ham, |2.55; 10-lb. 

bacon, f 1 .25 3 80 

Oct. 3, J. B. Harris, sale bu. onions, 25c ; 1 bu. 

, J. B. Harris, sale bu. onions, 25c ; 1 bu. 
sweet potatoes, 50c II 

sweet potatoes, 50c II 

&gt;, James Coen, sale 6£ lbs. bacon, 70c; 2 

months' pasture of cow, $3 3 70 

Oct. 5, Bertha Berryman, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 2 (to 

Oct. 5, Harriet Crabtree, same as Miss Berryman 50 

Oct. 5, Evalyn Bronelle, same as Miss Berryman 1 53 

Oct 5, J. A. Weart, fifth and last payment on cow 5 00 

Oct. 5, E. Tyrer, sale 2 bu. onions 1 00 

Oct. 13, J. Langley, sale 3 bu. rye IH 

Oct. 13, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., salo 4 syrup bbls. 2 00 

Oct. 15, Mrs. Barratt, 2 weeks' maintenance of Mr. 
Barratt 6 25 

Oct 15, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 7 No. 2 G. S. 

hides, 368 lbs., at 6^c 23 !••_' 

Oct. 18, W. L. Weekley, sale 4i yds. sand 4 50 

Oct. 18, F. B. Cross, sale 1 rooster 50 

Oct. 20, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 6 No. 2 G. S. 

hides, 322 lbs., at 6 : k 20 M 

Oct. 20, Standard Oil Co., sale 2 bbls 2 20 

Oct. 20, Standard Oil Co., sale 8 corn bbls B M 

Oct. 24, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 1 No. 1 G. S. 

hide, 56 lbs., at 74c 4 20 

Oct. 24, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 1 No. 2 G. S. 

hide, 61 lbs., at 6£c 3 96 

Oct. 27, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 1 G. S. 

hides, 96 lbs., at 7Jc 7 60 

Oct 27, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 2 G. S. 

hides, 107 lbs., at 6^c 6 95 </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
106 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Oct. 27, C. G. Finney, sale 2.18 yds. sand | 2 72 

10 00 

N&lt;&gt;\. 2, P. Fagan, sale 1 boar pig 

Nov. 2, Mrs. Barratt, for maintenance of John 

Barratt 12 50 

Nov. 2, Sale 11-lb. turkey, dressed, at 12c 1 32 

Nov. 3, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 4 No. 2 G. 8. 

hides, branded, 207 lbs., at 6£c 13 45 

r3, Crete Mills, sale 1,260.20 bu. wheat at 96c, 
11,209.92; less excess freight, f 14.63. . . 1,195 29 

Nov. 9, Sale of old rags 100 

Nov. 9, G. R. Critchfield, 5 months' pasture of cow 7 50 

Nov. 14, Mabel McGaw, time lost after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State 3 02 

Nov. 14, James Coen, sale 2 lbs. lard at 10c 20 

Nov. 14, James Coen, sale 10 lbs. bacon at 12£c. . . 1 25 

Nov. 14, James Coen, sale 8£ lbs. bacon 99 

Nov. 15, Preston Baker, for cash paid to W. C. 

Gray for 4 days' special attendance. . . 3 42 

Nov. 17, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 1 G. S. 

hides, 109 lbs., at 8c 8 72 

t. 17, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 2 
branded G. S. hides, 165 lbs., at 7c 11 55 

Nov. 19, Otto Anderson, sale 20 chickens at 25c ... 5 00 

Nov. 20, G. A. McCandless, sale 1 boar pig 10 00 

Nov. 20, American Beet Sugar 

Co., sale 56.419 tons 

sugar beets at $4.50 $253 88 

Less seed $75 00 

Less rent of drill 

and cultivator. . . 12 50 87 50 166 38 

Nov. 23, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., sale 2 No. 2 G. S 

hides, 119 lbs., at 7ic 8 92 

Nov. 23, P. M. Judge, sale 9 runt pigs at $3 27 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
107 

STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

Disbursements, 1902. 

Voocher 


l, 

Nelson Taylor, plastering barn 

Dec 

19, 

J. L. Greene, expense of transfer- 

ring patients to Hastings 6 25 11214 

Dec 

22, 

Chas. H. Plummer, instructions 

for making soap 3 00 1121" 

Dec. 23, Amer. Dist. Tel. Co., services 60 11216 

Dec. 23, 

J. T. Hay, expense of transferring 

patients to Iowa 26 40 11217 

office f 

i 6 95 

11198 

Dec. 5, Marguerite Gates, services as 

waitress 

97 

11.99 

Dec. 5, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 
Dec. 5, Ernest Taylor, furnishing music 
for weekly dances 

4 63 
12 50 

:::: 

Dec. 5, Chapman Drug Store, drugs 

1 00 

115 

Dec. 5, A. D. Gilmore, 16.1 doz. eggs from 
J. W. Miller..". 

3 30 

Dec. 5, E. Karrer, services for 11 days as 

baker 

14 67 

11204 

Dec. 5, J. Holm, pay in addition to pay 

roll 

5 00 

Dec. 5, Otto Anderson, laying cement 

sidewalk 

30 00 

moe 

Dec. 5, Jonas Ilolm, freight and express . 
Dec. 5, Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co 
W. A. Campbell, services as cook . 
8, E. B. Kucker, services as carpen- 

6 93 
7 50 
4 00 

E 

ter 

25 50 

11210 

Dec. 16, Lincoln Hide &amp; Fur Co., robe 
Dec. 16, E. L. Brown, 24 lbs. turkey at 12c 

6 00 
2 88 

E£ 

Dec. 19, J. L. Greene, recovering horse and 

buggy 

3 00 

1121.1 </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
108 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Dec. 23, B. O. Kostka, drugs f 55 46 11218 

Dec. 23, Frank Rawlins, part purchase 

price of carryall 140 20 11219 

Dec. 23, John Sullivan, turkeys 16 12 11220 

Dec. 23, C. E. Weed, purchase of chickens 10 00 11221 

Dec. 29, Otto Anderson, services as mason 18 00 11222 

Dec. 29, B. &amp; M. R. JR., demurrage 3 00 1122 :', 

Dec. 30, Melshans Mantel &amp; Tile Co., ma- 

terial 9 48 11224 

Dec. 30, R. H. Woodward, wages as fire- 

man 3 50 1122r&gt; 

Dec. 30, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 1 73 11270 

J90S. 

tl2, Q. W. Dishong, services as attendant 
4 03 11271 

Jan. 14, F. Thompson, hay 2 04 11272 

•Jan. 19, J. Holm, freight and express. ... 12 45 1127.' 

Dec. 19, J. Holm, extra pay for December 5 00 11274 

Jan. 29, G. W. Felton, hominy 4 00 1127H 

Jan. 30, H. S. Stoner, plastering 4 00 11276 

Jan. 30, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 1 08 11277 

Jan. 30, H. J. Penfold Co., drugs 3 63 1127&gt; 

Jan. 30, Western Tel. Mfg. Co., 'phone for 

barn and engine room 21 00 11279 

Jan. 31, John A. Alhstrom, tile in operat- 

ing room 40 00 11280 

Jan. 31, Otto Anderson, laying tile in 

operating room 36 00 11281 

Feb. 5, G. F. Underwood, plumbing 52 00 11348 

Feb. 9, J. Holm, extra pay for January. . 5 00 11349 

Feb. 9, J. Holm, freight and express 4 85 11350 

Feb. 13, Ethel Hoffman, time after pay 

roll was made 2 90 11351 

Feb. 13, Celia Denham, time after pay roll 

xtraa mailo 1 AK 11'*V&gt; 
W8U5 ilXuUC •¦¦•••¦•••*•¦••••• X tiO lluu« </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
109 

STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

Feb. 13, E. O. Robb, time after pay roll 
was made f 5 23 11353 

Feb. 13, H. O. Folts, tuning two pianos. . 6 00 LUS4 

Feb. 13, Miller &amp; Paine, carpets, etc 178 60 11 

Feb. 15, Peter Spadt, purchase 3 roosters . 1 50 L13M 

Feb. 20, Otto Anderson, laying cement. . . 9 00 ll.?."&gt;7 

Feb. 20, E. G. Wigg, cornstalks 8 00 11 

Feb. 24, L. V. Quick, corn hominy 34 82 lKJ.V.t 

» 

Mar. 9, J. Holm, extra pay for February. 5 00 114M 

Mar. 9, J. Holm, freight and express 4 51 1 14.*7 

Mar. 11, Lincoln Corn Food Co., hominy. . 18 75 1 14:*s 

Mar. 11, Lincoln Corn Food Co., hominy. . 28 13 11439 

Mar. 11, H. W. Stanley, services 89 11440 

Mar. 11, E. B. Rucker, services 1 34 11441 

Mar. 11, Will H. Green, papering 18 00 11442 

Mar. 11, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 6 r&gt;0 11443 

Mar. 11, Wm. N. Parka, upholstering 10 32 11444 

Mar. 11, American Dist. Tel. Co 55 1144". 

Mar. 13, F. G. Richards, repair sewing ma- 

chine 3 25 1144i; 

Mar. 17, J. R. Eddie, yardage and water. . 7 00 11447 

Mar. 26, G. B. Simpson, game warden 5 00 114 1&gt; 

Mar. 28, David Barry, turnips 3 60 11449 

Mar. 30, Hoye's Directory Co 5 00 11460 

Mar. 31, B. &amp; M. R. R. Co., rent of land. . . 10 00 114." 1 

Mar. 31, Dess Hoffman, services 3 00 114.".2 

Apr. 7, H. 8. Stoner, plastering 39 40 1 l.ioo 

Apr. 7, Geo. Wright, plastering 39 40 11501 

Apr. 7, J. Holm, pay in addition to pay 

roll, March 5 00 11502 

Apr. 7, J. Holm, freight and express. ... 4 29 11 

Apr. 7, E. B. Rucker, pay in addition to 

payroll 6 33 11504 

Apr. 7, Dess Hoffman, pay in addition to 

pay roll 3 00 11505 

Apr. 7, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 30 11506 </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
110 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

t. 14, Lorena Gqre, wages in addition to 
pay roll * 40 11507 

Apr. 16, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 4 11 11508 

Apr. 25, H. E. Graham, feed 8 66 11509 

Apr. 27, E. B. Dunlap, expense of buying 

team of Wall 13 20 11510 

Apr. 27, A. D. Gilmore, railroad fare to 

Loup City and return 8 48 11511 

Apr. 30, Dess Hoffman, wages in addition 

to pay roll 120 11512 

Apr. 30, Ethel Hoffman, wages in addition 

to pay roll 1 70 11513 

A. D. Gilmore, expense of patients 
to see President 1 25 11572 

May 1, Bertha Secrect, wages for labor in 

May 75 11573 

TK 

May 4, J. Holm, extra wages for April. . 5 00 11574 

.May 4, J. L. Greene, expense of stenog- 

rapher and entertaining legis- 

lative committee 9 75 11575 

May 5, J. H. Gore, wages for labor in 

Mav 3 48 11576 

May 21, J. R. Burroughs, wages for labor 

in April 10 80 11577 

May 26, J. E. Miller, crop of ice from pond 25 00 11578 

Mav 30, Peter Spadt, expense to Wilber 

and return 1 86 11579 

June 1, W. C. Davidson, for Poland China 

boar 32 50 11660 

June 8, Jeanette Misener, in addition to 

payroll 3 00 11661 

June 13, J. L. Greene, replacing patients' 

clothing lost 7 08 11662 

June 13, H. M. Brown, wages in addition 

to pay roll 8 17 11663 

June 13, W. L. Weekley, services 10 50 11664 </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
111 


June 17, Evans Laundry Co., caustic soda. f 6 00 11' 

June 20, Evans Laundry Co., caustic soda. 4 50 11 

June 23, J. F. Swihart, for strawberries.. 1 00 lH.tiT 

June 26, J. A. Weart, wages in addition to 

payroll 5 00 11668 

June 26, J. L. Greene, pay consulting phy- 

sician 5 00 11 ¦ 

June 24, Peter Spadt, services 1 17 11754 

July 7, F. Thompson, purchase of hay. . 4 54 11753 

July 7, B. &amp; U. B. R., demurrage 1 00 117M 

July 7, L. Keller, team, work, etc 11 46 11757 

July 7, Cora L. Damrow, services as rna- 

Aug. 14, T. H. Slattery, same as Unger. . . 6 4" 11847 

tron 

75 34 

11758 

July 7, Benton &amp; Benton, printing 
July 11, C. M. Wilson, hanging paper. . . . 
July 14, Otto Anderson, services 

9 50 
2 65 
1 40 

11759 
11760 
11761 

July 14, American Dist. Tel. Co., services 
July 14, Julia Christianson, services.... 
July 17, Western Union Tel. Co., services 

2 10 
5 00 

11 

April 

1 85 

11T6, 

July 17, Western Union Tel. Co., services 

May 

4 75 

July 17, Western Union Tel. Co., services 

June 

5 07 

July 18, W. G. Houtz, fruit trees 
July 22, W. G. Seidell, music for Fourth 

7 00 

- 

of July 
July 24, Lola Danforth, services 
July 27, A. D. Gilmore, cash and circus 

8 00 
9 00 

tickets for patients to Ringling 

Bros.' circus 

15 00 

11771 

July 27, A. D. Gilmore, chickens, etc., 

bought 

5 46 

Aug. 13, Louie Unger, services after pay 
roll was sent to Secretary of 

State 

3 55 

11846 </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
112 


t. 22, Western Union Tel. Co., services 
July f 4 65 11848 

Aug. 17, T. K. Wilson, cigars for patients 

on trip to Hastings 2 50 11849 

Aug. 17, Fischer Mach. Works Co., balance 

on new engine 52 82 11850 

Aug. 22, A. J. Charles, shelling 620 bu. of 

corn at 10c 6 20 11851 

Sept 3, E. E. Joyce, services as seam- 

stress 1 33 11927 

Sept 5, Woodruff-Collins Printing Co., 

printing 1,000 attendants' re- 

ports 6 00 11928 

Sept 5, Nebraska Sanitarium Food Co., 

breakfast foods 5 72 11929 

Sept. 5, H. F. Safford, services stacking 

oats 4 00 11930 

Sept 5, F. E. Owen, 1 thoroughbred Eng- 

lish Berkshire sow 35 00 11931 

Sept. 5, Lonetta Wanser, services as cook 

8 days at |25 per month 6 45 11932 

Sept 5, O. C. Mastin, 100 lbs. hominy at 

15c 15 00 11933 

Sept 5, New York Bakery Co., 10 lbs. Al- 

mond Paste at 29c 2 90 11934 

Sept. 5, B. Hawkins, services 57 hours, 

laying brick on new cave at 

55c 31 35 11935 

Sept. 5, Lola Danforth, services as physi- 

cal culture teacher, 27 days ... 27 00 11936 

Sept 5, Earl Longacre, services as super- 

visor 3 39 11937 

Oct 5, G. W. Burge, purchase 10 acres 

shock corn 90 00 12013 

Oct. 6, B. &amp; M. K. R., switching charges. 5 00 12014 

Oct 13, Wohlenberg, P. J.. 63 lbs. tobacco 

stems 1 26 12015 </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
113 

STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

§13, Western Union Tel. Co., services 
for August f 3 73 1201.; 

t29, Woodruff-Collins Printing Co., 
for printing laundry lists 3 50 19117 

Oct. 29, Paul Herpolsheimer Imp. Co., 1 

Columbus carriage 290 00 12018 

Not. 16, Robt. Bear, services and expense 

to State Fair 1 33 12W6 

Nov. 16, H. E. Austin, services after pay 

roll was sent to Secretary of 

I State 
. 23, C. J. Roman, painting 
and blacksmithing 
. 30, W. S. Scott, county 

4 44 1209&lt;&gt; 
carryall 
94 00 12097 
surveyor, sur- 

Nov. 23, C. J. Roman, painting carryall 

and blacksmithing 94 00 12097 

veying 17 10 12098 

Nov. 30, Woodruff-Collins Printing Co., 

for 5 receipts for warrants. . . 5 00 12099 

Nov. 30, Creighton Morris, payment com- 

bination fund record 11 25 12100 

Nov. 30, Nelle Anthony, extra pay as 

charge of attendants 3 76 12101 

Nov. 30, H. O. Folts, tuning 2 pianos 6 00 12102 

Nov. 30, Geo. O. Loss, threshing 610 bu. 

wheat at 3£c, 1,796 bu. oats 

at lfc 52 78 12103 

t. 3, A. D. Gilmore, expense of patients, 
etc 7 55 12186 

rl8, Schaffer Bros. &amp; Powell Mfg. Co., 
I bbl. oil 15 33 12187 

Dec. 21, Cudahy Packing Co., freight paid 

by them 164 12188 

Dec. 21, Esther Brown, services as stenog- 

rapher 7 00 12189 

Dec. 31, State Journal Co., printing blanks 18 00 12190 

Dec. 31, J. Holm, glucose and crackers 

bought 80 12191 </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
114 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Dec. 31, Woodruff-Collins Printing Co., 
for printing blanks $ 19 00 12192 

Dec. 31, May Wiles, services after pay roll 

was sent to Secretary of State. 1 33 12193 

Dec. 31, Nannie Tait, same as Mrs. Wiles 47 12194 

Dec. 31, Josephine Kelly, same as Mrs. 

Wiles 23 12195 

Dec. 31, Nettie Shirey, same as Mrs. 

Wiles 5 13 12196 

Dec. 31, New York Bakery &amp; Coffee Co. . . 2 90 12197 

19QJ,. 

Jan. 2, W. B. Campbell, services 1 day as 

attendant 81 12276 

Jan. 2, J. H. Seid, purchase 1 thorough- 

bred Poland China boar 25 00 12277 

Jan. 9, J. B. Harris, services as painter. 26 13 122 7&gt; 

Jan. 15, Dess Hoffman, services as cook. . 5 64 12279 

Jan. 15, Will H. Green, wall paper, and 

hanging same 83 22 12280 

Jan. 26, W. A. Ozenbaugh, purchase 1 

mare 110 00 12281 

Jan. 27, Geo. Underwood, services as 

plumber 92 00 12282 

Jan. 30, Otto Anderson, services laying ce- 

ment 35 00 12283 

Jan. 30, Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., general re- 

pairs 166 36 12284 

Jan. 30, Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., general re- 

pairs 151 03 12285 

Jan. 30, Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., plumbing 

supplies 39 38 12286 

Jan. 30, Evans Laundry Co., 1 bbl. caustic 

soda 20 98" 12287 

Feb. 1, W. P. Ramey, services 1 day as 

cook at S40 1 40 12361 </seg>

            <seg id="p049">
115 


Feb. 3, P. Bartlett, plowing U days at f3. .? 10 50 12 

Feb. 3, T. H. Williams, expense trip to 
South Omaha with car of hogs 2 55 12; 

Feb. 12, C, B. &amp; Q. R. R., for rent of land. 10 00 12 

Mar. 2, J. E. Williams, services 24 124 40 

Mar. 2, J. 8. Hammond, services 81 12441 

Mar. 2, Gelia Murphy, services 1 03 124 12 

Mar. 2, A. S. Williams, purchase of bull. 45 00 12 

Mar. 7, J. S. Kahl, breeding thoroughbred 
sow 15 00 12444 

Mar. 7, Otto Anderson, purchase of tiling 

for steward's office 69 85 124 US 

Mar. 7, Hoye Directory Co., purchase 

1904 directory 5 00 1244f, 

Mar. 19, New York Bakery, purchase al- 

mond paste 5 80 12447 

Mar. 21, J. B. Trickey, purchase spectacles 

for H. Fleshauer 2 00 12 

Apr. 1, Everett Spencer, services 5 32 12 

Apr. 4, W. L. Weekley, services 12 31 12500 

Apr. 7, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 23 52 12510 

Apr. 7, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 6 11 12," 11 

Apr. 7, Woodruff -Collins Printing Co. . . 4 00 12512 

Apr. 7, J. B. Harris, purchase of 2 barber 

chairs 15 00 12513 

Apr. 9, Max Storkan, services 2 90 12514 

Apr. 9, Marguerite McClung, services. . . 12 77 

Apr. 9, A. D. Gilmore, cash paid for haul- 

ing ice 2 65 12." 1 «"&gt; 

Apr. 9, W. A. Campbell, services 86 12. r &gt;17 

Apr. 9, M. C. Shirey, services 2 82 12518 

Apr. 15, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 2 15 12r&gt;l!t 

Apr. 15, Harry Porter, stationery 4 85 12520 

Apr. 15, Lola Danforth, services 10 00 12521 

Apr. 15, John Armstrong, rent of land ... 65 00 12522 

Apr. 15, American Berkshire Registry Co., 

registering 6 pigs at f 1 6 00 12523 </seg>

            <seg id="p050">
116 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Apr. 15, Jas. Whalen, services f 5 00 12524 

May 9, J. B. Harris, services more than 

payroll 5 00 12617 

May 9, J. A. Weart, same as Harris 5 00 12«ils 

May 9, C. Wettlaufer, same as Harris. . . 5 00 12&lt;&gt;1 '.» 

May 9, C. Wettlaufer, same as Harris. . . 5 00 1J619 

May 9, E. M. Kurtz, same as Harris 1 21 12C&gt;L&gt;o 

May 9, E. M. Kurtz, same as Harris 1 21 12820 

May 9, E. L. Snyder, same as Harris 2 50 12«;i'l 

May 10, J. B. Harris, for 60 ft. picture 

moulding 3 60 12622 

May 10, Saml. Hall, for crepe paper 80 12623 

May 10, J. E. Miller, payment for ice 13 40 12624 

May 14, Hall Bros., payment steel ceiling 

wards 2, male and female 449 18 12»&gt;2.~&gt; 

May 20, Geo. Underwood, services as 

plumber 19 00 12626 

May 20, American Dist. Tel. Co., services. 90 12627 

May 24, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 6 95 12628 

June 6, O. F. Lambertson, dental work 

for patients 17 00 12708 

June 6, G. F. Swihart, purchase 2 bu. seed 

corn at fl 2 00 12709 

June 10, Otto Anderson, services as mason 45 00 12710 

June 11, Martha Headman, services as 

waitress 65 1271 1 

June 11, J. W. Riggs, services as barn man 3 10 12712 

June 17, J. R. Megahan, purchase 7 crates 

strawberries at f 1 7 00 12713 

June 25, Ernest Tyrer, music and violin 

strings 7 50 12714 

June 25, C. H. Huyck, tuning piano in 

chapel 2 00 12715 

June 30, J. Holm, services 1 13 12716 

July 6, Woodruff-Collins Printing Co., 

for stationery 4 50 12801 

July 6, G. H. Gray, extra pay as charge 

of Ward 1 5 00 12802 </seg>

            <seg id="p051">
117 


July 6, A. D. Gilniore, money advanced 
patients f IS 1- 

July 6, G. A. Young, purchase of b*ef tea 98 12n &gt;4 

July 6, Union Dairy, cream for Fourth 

of July 7 50 12805 

July 6, T. H. Slattery, purchase oil can. . 50 12- 

July 18, Dess Hoffman, extra services. ... 1 29 12807 

July 18, C. E. Shirey, extra services 1 00 12808 

July 18, P. A. Henry, extra services 3 00 12- 

July 19, F. W. Quirin, purchase of shoe 

shop tools 3 55 

July 26, G. A. Crancer, purchase of pic- 

ture moulding 9 72 12811 

July 28, Eddie Williams, services 2 00 12M2 

July 28, A. D. Gilmore, freight paid 71 12813 

July 28, Dierks Lumber &amp; Coal Co., lum- 

ber purchased 268 76 12M4 

July 28, Dierks Lumber &amp; Coal Co., lumber 
purchased 136 22 12- 

July 28, Dierks Lumber &amp; Coal Co., lum- 

ber purchased 74 95 12816 

July 28, Dierks Lumber &amp; Coal Co., lum- 

ber purchased 20 04 12817 

July 28, Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., material. . . 187 M 12- 

July 28, Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., material. . . 78 61 1- 

July 28, Harry Porter, stationery 8 15 12820 

July 28, Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., desk for 

steward's office 45 00 12- 

July 28, J. A. Wiles, services in beet field. 11 00 12- 

July 28, Esther Brown, services as stenog- 

rapher 10 00 12823 

A'ig. 6, Jas. Whalen, services stacking 

B" 

wheat 6 00 12906 

Aug. 11, J. R. Megahan, purchase of 

.-i 

peaches 3 75 12907 

Aug. 11, Jas. Harlan, services stacking </seg>


            <seg id="p052">
118 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Aug. 11, E. L. Cherry, services after pay 

roll was completed $ 1 61 12909 

Aug. 11, Bertha Heald, same as Cherry... 81 12910 

Aug. 11, C. H. Gray, pay as charge Ward 1 5 00 12911 

Aug. 11, W. C. Gray, services after pay 

roll was completed 121 12912 

Aug. 11, Anna Schmidt, same as Gray. ... 2 42 1291.5 

Aug. 11, Zaida Brown, same as Gray. ... 5 94 12914 

Aug. 11, Western Union Tel. Co., services. 7 80 1291.1 

Sept. 2, E. L. Cherry, services 81 13004 

Sept. 2, W. R. Holt, purchase of 1 thor- 

oughbred Berkshire boar 35 00 13005 

Sept 2, C. N. Noatz, purchase 3 head 

thoroughbred shorthorn cattle 200 00 13006 

Sept 2, W. L. Reynolds, 2 gross chair 

fasteners 4 00 13007 

Sept. 2, J. R. Megahan, purchase of 

peaches 13 75 13008 

Sept. 2, C. A. Schaaf, polished oak floor 

in reception room 91 75 13009 

Sept 9, W. W. Wash, purchase throwing 

harness 7 50 13010 

Sept 9, Earl Longacre, services 81 13011 

8ept 9, G. H. Walker, services 80 13012 

Sept 9, C. H. Gray, services 1 14 13013 

Sept 9, Margaret Neely, services 2 42 13014 

Sept 20, J. B. Harris, paper purchased. . . 14 90 13015 

Sept 26, C. Schafer, butter purchased 2 55 13016 

Sept 26, James Reed, purchase 1 Deering 

corn binder 40 00 13017 

Sept 26, Harley Drug Co., drugs purchased 65 70 13018 

Sept 26, Geo. W. Reed, seed wheat pur- 

chased 52 00 13019 

Sept 26, Hall Bros.' Co., purchase and la- 

bor on steel ceiling, reception 

room 72 32 13020 </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
119 

STATE HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. 

r26, R. L. Smith Mach. Works, material 
and labor, engine room, .f 97 77 13021 

Sept 26, Q. A. Crancer, moulding for re- 

ception room 6 72 13022 

Sept. 26, Bauer &amp; Black, drugs purchased . 7 75 13023 

Sept 26, H. O. Folts, tuning piano in 

chapel 3 00 13024 

Sept. 26, State Journal Co., stationery 15 50 13025 

Sept 30, A. D. Gilmore, freight and ex- 

press 7 01 13026 

Oct. 1, W. F. Strong, purchase 18 chapel 

chimes at 30c 5 40 13093 

Oct 1, Louis Madeciki &amp; Co., purchase 3 
sacred Orch. coll 1 20 13094 

Oct 1, C J. Roman, repairing rockaway. 43 50 13095 

Oct 5, D. Cushman, purchase 23£ bu. 

seed rye at 70c 16 45 13096 

Oct. 5, Otto Ranter, rent of corn planter 2 00 13W7 

Oct 5, New York Bakery Co., purchase 

10 lbs. almond paste at 28c. . . 2 80 13098 

Oct 13, James Harlan, services after pay 

roll was sent to Secretary of 

State 5 50 13099 

Oct 13, Marie Samuelson, same as Harlan 5 19 13100 

Oct 18, Geo. O. Love, for threshing 77 44 13101 

Oct 18, American Dist. Tel. Co., services. 65 13102 

Oct. 24, Waterbury Chemical Co, 44 89 13103 

Nov. 3, N. E. Spruck, purchase 4 bu. cher- 

ries at |2 8 00 13147 

Nov. 3, J. B. Harris, material for upholstering 
3 chairs 2 77 13148 

Nov. 3, C. E. Shirey, cash for repairs 1 20 13149 

Nov. 3, E. L. Snyder, services in addition 

to pay roll 5 00 13150 

Nov. 3, Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., carpet and 

rockers for female Ward 2 147 98 13151 </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
120 


Nov. 3, Nebraska Tel. Co., services $ 2 05 13152 

Nov. 3, Sol A. Ksensky, purchase 2 gal. 

whiskey 6 00 13153 

Nov. 3, P. J. Wohlenberg, tobacco stems. 3 70 13154 

Nov. 3, Wm. Krause, repairing soap tank 4 00 131. "&gt; 

Nov. 25, Chas. Burns, purchase 43.07 bu. 

corn at 36c 15 51 13156 

Nov. 14, G. R. Critchfield, purchase 27.07 

bu. corn at 35c 9 47 13157 

Nov. 14, B. W. Hawkins, laying brick on 

hog house 11 05 13158 

Nov. 21, Alb. D. Gilmore, expenses of pa- 

tients attending State Fair. . . 23 00 13159 

Nov. 25, Peter M. Judge, purchase 8 doz. 

brooms 27 00 13160 

Nov. 18, 8. E. Stillman, purchase 2 steers 30 00 13161 

Nov. 19, Otto Anderson, services laying ce- 

ment 80 25 13162 

Nov. 21, T. P. Hassler, purchase 6 door 

stops 4 50 13163 

Nov. 21, Bessie Reed, services 1 81 13164 

Nov. 21, M. P. Sullivan, dehorning 134 

cattle at 8c 10 72 13165 

Nov. 26, Korsmeyer Co., purchase electric 

supplies 29 10 13166 

Nov. 26, Kny-Scheerer Co.. purchase mdse 2 00 13167 

Nov. 26, Bercherdt Ext. Co., purchase 

drugs 47 44 13168 

Nov. 26, Troy Laundry Mach. Co., repairs 33 85 13169 

Nov. 26, Remington Typewriter Co., pur- 

chase typewriter 42 75 13170 

Nov. 26, Bauer &amp; Black, purchase medical 

supplies 47 18 13171 

Nov. 26, Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., 

stone chips, etc 225 93 13172 

Nov. 26, Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., rugs and 

chairs for reception room .... 212 64 13173 </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
121 


Nov. 26, Harley Drug Co., medicine f 16 95 13174 

Nov. 26, Lincoln Telephone Co., services. . 16 50 13175 

Nov. 26, E. A. Pegler, purchase stock food 40 00 13176 

Nov. 26, Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., purchase 

merchandise 15 04 13177 

Nov. 26, J. K. Megahan, purchase 1 steer 

calf. 6 00 13178 

Nov. 26, Albert D. Gilmore, cash paid to 

patients 12 50 13179 

SUMMARY OF CASH FUND. 

Total amount on hand December 1, 
1902 $1,925 87 

Total amount received from December 
1, 1902, to May 31, 1903 1,402 70 

Total amount received from June 1, 
1903, to November 30, 1903 987 23 

Total amount received from December 
1, 1903, to May 31, 1904 2,089 90 

Total amount received from June 1, 
1904, to November 30, 1904 2,354 23 

Total receipts $8,759 93 

Amount disbursed from December 1, 
1902, to May 31, 1903 f 1,195 35 

Amount disbursed from June 1, 1903, to 
November 30, 1903 1,056 50 

Amount disbursed from December 1, 
1903, to May 31, 1904 1,697 91 

Amount disbursed from June 1, 1904, 
to November 30, 1904. . ... 3,103 98 

Total disbursed $7,053 74 

Balance 1,706 19 

$8,759 93 </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>