<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00022</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  THE DISTRIBUTION AND USE OF HOG CHOLERA SERUM</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA Agricultural Experiment Station LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A. PRESS BULLETIN NO. 43 Distributed July H, 191.1 THE DISTRIBUTION AND USE OF HOG CHOLERA SERUM By J. H. Gain and Fred E. Johnson DEPARTMENT OF ANIMAL PATHOLOGY Telephone B 2490. It has been estimated that the loss from hog cholera in Nebraska for the year 1912 was 11 per cent of the total number of hogs. This would total at least $3,000,000, sufficient to cause a careful study of the best methods of combating the disease. A study of hog cholera will show a greater variety of symptoms and of post-mortem lesions than in any other disease that affects farm </seg>
            <seg id="p002">recover. These animals may infect the entire herd and the outbreak become general before there is any suspicion that the trouble is cholera. While the first one or two hogs, owing to their greater resistance, may have had cholera in the chronic form, other animals in the herd may quite generally have the acute type and die rapidly; or again, the whole herd may have a slow or mild type of cholera with only an occasional death. In this case cholera is not always suspected and yet this herd may be the center of a wide infection. The acute type leaves no doubt as to the disease, the hogs dying rapidly and most of them showing the symptoms commonly associated with cholera. Where the acute type of cholera has once visited a farm, the farmer is often slow to believe the slower, or chronic, form of the disease to be cholera, and before he is aware, the whole herd is more or less affected. In hog cholera there is sometimes found a condition commonly called "swine plague" or "infectious pneumonia" where the lungs seem to be the only part of the animal affected, and many have believed that this condition could not be combated by the use of serum. At the Nebraska Serum Plant, blood from typical cases of swine plague in - jected into susceptible pigs developed the acute type of cholera without the lung complications. It was found that serum would protect against blood from these pigs as well as against the blood from hogs showing normal cholera symptoms. Serum has been used against several out - breaks in this state where the post-mortem lesions were those of swine plague, and was found potent to protect against this form of cholera as well as against those cases where the lesions were entirely those of hog cholera. Whenever a disease that is contagious appears among hogs, spreading more or less rapidly and quite uniformly fatal, it it quite safe to assume that it is cholera. i Where cholera Is suspected, it is well to get a thermometer and the temperature of a number of those that are apparently well, normal temperature is from 101 to 103 degrees in winter and about gree higher in summer. Where there has been one or more sick i in a herd for some days, it may be found that while most of the i are apparently well they have a temperature of 105 to 107 degrees, og Infected with cholera may have a high temperature for three ve days before it shows other signs of being sick and during this i will be looking for its feed and have every appearance of health, sty per cent of an apparently healthy herd have been found with temperatures. Make a post-mortem on a hog that has just died and examine the kidneys for small dark red spots resembling those on a turkey egg Look for small bright red spots along the small intestines and some - what larger ones on the lungs. The lymphatic glands, which are found in the flank, along the intestines, and between the lungs, and which are a light amber color in health, will be found congested and varying from a pink to a very dark color. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">There are two general methods of using hog cholera serum. The Serum Alone method consists in giving the well hogs in an outbreak serum at the rate of 25 c. c. (cubic centimeters) per hundred pounds weight of hog. Those hogs carrying a high temperature but showing no external symptoms of disease should receive 40 c. c. per hundred pounds. In order to acquire a lasting immunity, a hog receiving serum must lfected with cholera within a few days after treatment with a. He may either be injected with a small amount of cholera . or get infection by running in an infected herd. This infection up a slight reaction, or, in other words, produces a light attack of ra. Where serum is used without either injection or natural in - &gt;n the protection will last only three or four weeks, when the hog i becomes susceptible to the disease. I Where only a few hogs in a large herd are sick at the time the im Alone method is used, it is not possible for all the hogs to ime sufficiently infected to acquire a long time immunity. This mnts for some hogs dying with cholera several weeks after receiv - the Serum Alone treatment. At best the Serum Alone method is emergency treatment, and the most satisfactory results must come 1 the Simultaneous method. The Serum Simultaneous method consists in giving 40 c. c. of •erum per hundred pounds weight of hog and at the same time from % to 2 c. c. of virus to each animal. Except in sucking pigs it is believed that this gives immunity lasting as long as where the animal has recovered from a natural infection. iThe Double Simultaneous method consists in giving 25 c. c. of m per hundred pounds, and in a week or ten days 40 c. c. per hun - 1 pounds and from % to 2 c. c. of virus to each animal. This lod is suggested for valuable pure bred herds or for brood sows are soon to farrow. The loss has been found to be less than two cent and the extra cost is not great. I In most cases where sucking pigs are given the Simultaneous tment, the protection passes away shortly after weaning, when it lid he repeated. Unless cholera breaks out among sucking pigs, it &gt;est to leave them until after weaning before giving them the ultaneous method. Pigs from immune sows are not immune to era altho some seem to have a considerable resistance to the ase. Some of them will get cholera as early as ten days old. Where the breeding herd has been immunized and the pigs after weaning are given the Simultaneous treatment, cholera cannot get a foothold, and it is by this means that a community can be kept free from the disease. Where the Simultaneous method is used in a healthy herd there is liable to be some loss, and those that die will die of cholera and thus infect the premises. Hogs which die from any cause should at once be burned, so aa to lessen the danger of spreading disease. This can be done quite easily by digging a trench and placing across it a few bars of old </seg>
            <seg id="p004">they will burn almost entirely. Cholera hogs that are buried with but little dirt over them are easily dug up by dogs. Dogs and birds, especially crows, are common carriers of infection. Dogs that are supposed to be at home nights very often range over a considerable territory, and may bring home infection from a distance of several miles. Public stock yards are always more or less infected with cholera and the infection may be carried home on the shoes. K Where the services of a qualified veterinarian can be obtained, he ild be called to make a post-mortem and to give serum. Ordinarily, b (cholera blood) for simultaneous work is sent only to veterinarians. If serum is wanted, use the telephone or telegraph. Do not write a letter requesting serum. The mails are uncertain and slow for such purposes and the larger part of the herd may become infected before serum could be received if ordered this way. K Always give the number and weight of the well hogs in the herd, certain number of doses are ordered it will be assumed that the mum dose is meant. The serum is put up in bottles containing 100, 125, 200, 250, 500. and 1,000 c. c. It will be shipped by express, C. O. D. This Department will endeavor to deliver serum at the express office promptly upon re - ceipt of orders which it can fill, but the delays en route from sending material by express are frequent and sometimes unexplainable. We cannot be responsible for delays of serum in transit. Read carefully the directions enclosed with each shipment of serum At present the price of serum and virus is one cent per c. c. We have discontinued the practice of refunding for serum not used. Owing to the possible deterioration of serum thru standing in the sun or in other places where it is subject to high temperatures, we have decided to send out no serum for use except that going directly from our refrig - erators to the user. From this time on. serum which has been ordered and shipped will be the property of the purchaser and not subject to return. We do this for the protection of the users of serum. We do not feel safe in sending out to the trade serum which possibly has stood in express offices or in hot granaries or sheds for a week or two and is then returned to us unused. Order just what serum is needed, use it immedi - ately upon its being received, or, if it must be kept for a few days before using, place it in a cool cellar or in a refrigerator. DOSAGE (of Serum and Virus). Serum Alone. Serum Simultaneous. t Serum, up to 15 pounds 10 c. c. 30 pounds 15 c. c. 50 pounds 20 c. c. i 100 pounds 25 c. c. e 100 pounds, 25 c. c. 100 pounds. Serum. Pigs up to 15 pounds . 15 c. c. 15 to 30 pounds ... 25 c. c. 30 to 50 pounds ... 35 c. c. 50 to 100 pounds. .40 c. c. Above 100 pounds, 40 c. c. per 100 pounds ! </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>