<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00027">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Pump Irrigation and Water Table Studies</title>
               <date value="1932-05">1932-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 271 May, 1932 Pump Irrigation and Water Table Studies HARRY E. WEAKLY Bulletin 32 of the North Platte Experimental Substation W. P. Snyder, Superintendent UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burnt, Director . i </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Pump Irrigation and Water Table Studies at the North Platte Substation HARRY E. WEAKLY &gt; The first section of this bulletin reports costs and returns from pump irrigation at the North Platte Experimental Sub - station for the eight years from 1924 to 1931. Results for three years, 1924 to 1927, were previously reported in Bulle - tin 227. The second section reports the results of preliminary studies of variations in the water table as caused by pump - ing. THE PLANT The equipment installed in 1918 consisted of a 6-inch horizontal pump operated by a 30-horsepower single-cylin - der kerosene engine. The pump was set in the pit of a central well, just above the average level of the water table, which lies about 31 feet below the surface at this place. Connections were made to two other wells, one on either side at 50-foot distances in a north and south line with the center well. The casings are 24 inches in diameter and extend about 22 feet below the level of the pump. They are of galvanized steel with 10 feet of heavy-gauge galvanized wire screen strainer on the bottom. In 1925 a 40-horsepower electric motor was installed to take the place of the kerosene engine. Also, a fourth well was added in order to supply the pump with sufficient water, be - cause the motor, with its higher speed and more efficient power transmission, increased the discharge from the pump to such an extent that the first three wells did not supply it under sustained pumping. This fourth well is 50 feet east of the central well. It is an uncased well, having a 6-foot wire screen strainer fastened to the end of a 6-inch suction pipe. In 1930, because of the failure of the old pump, new equip - ment consisting of a double-suction No. 6 centrifugal pump direct-connected to a 25-horsepower- electric motor was in - stalled. This type of pump is much more efficient than the one which it displaced. The discharge pipe is equipped with two outlets, one into a ditch at the ground surface and the other into a flume at a level approximately 5 feet higher. The total lift when a stable draw-down has been reached varies according to the height of the water table, but on the average it is approxi - mately 52 feet at the lower outlet and 57 at the upper one. fte^^O^nrlK/L^/iSa^ ***"""«*»&gt; Substation, detailed from </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 271 The capacity of the original plant was from 900 to 1000 gallons per minute, or approximately 2 second feet. With the fourth well added and with the electric motor instead of the kerosene engine, the flow was increased to between 1100 and 1250 gallons per minute, or approximately 2.5 to 2.8 second feet. When the present equipment was installed, it was so placed that the center line of the suction opening of the pump is 11 inches above the level of that of the old pump, which increases the suction lift by that amount. Since with an average discharge in excess of 1100 gallons per minute, the draw-down or suction lift for the old pump approached 18 feet, it may be seen that an additional 11 inches would have a tendency to offset the increased efficiency of the new pump. But in spite of this factor and also the fact that the water table was extremely low during the season of 1931, the average discharge for the new pump was approximately 1150 gallons per minute, or slighly over 2.55 acre inches per hour. Total suction lifts as high as 18 feet and four inches were quite common during the 1931 season. COSTS The cost of irrigation by pumping is usually divided into two types of charges, operating costs arid fixed costs.. The chief items which may be classified as operating charges are power, attendance at the plant, lubricating oil, and distribu - tion of the water. The fixed cost is a charge made to cover interest on investment, depreciation and upkeep of equip - ment and distributing system. As such it is charged against the land irrigated rather than the water pumped, as is the case with the operating charges. OPERATING COSTS A summary of operating costs for the eight years, 1924 to 1931 inclusive, is given in Table 1. The power cost in 1924 included mainly fuel and oil for the engine. For 1925 and the succeeding years the power cost was for electric current. The charge for electric current for power is based upon a sliding scale of rates which has been revised several times during the period covered by this bulletin. These revisions have air been downward. The scale operated under during the season of 1931 is as follows: First 200 kilowatt-hours per month $0,060 Next 400 kilowatt-hours per month 0.055 Next 1000 kilowatt-hours per month.. 0.045 Next 6000 kilowatt-hours per month 0.030 Next 6000 kilowatt-hours per month 0.0275 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Table 1. — Operating costs, number of hours pump was operated, number of acre inches of water _ pumped, and cost per acre inch of water -■■'-;' g Yrinr Total cost T^t/Jf- Total operat- Hours pumj Cost per _„£,"$"' Total Cost per £ Year of power " h " r g" g in(? charge was operated hour P pumpc ' d acre inch •$ Hours • Acre inches Acre inches 2 1924 $178.20 $167.67 $457.65 ' 310.50 $1,470 . 2.00 621.0 $0,737 &gt; 1925 404.74 187.60 592.34 469.00 1.260 2.20 1031.0 .0.574 g 1926 381.72= 178.00 559.72 445.00 1.260 2.42 1076.0 0.520 O 1927 209.48= 87.80 297.28 219.50 1.350' 2.78 G09.5 0.488 ' 1928 " 251.31 139.20 390.51 348.00 .1.120 2.75 957.0 0.409 &lt; 1929 284.20 207.80 492.00 519.50 0.947 2.20 1142.9 . 0.431 %. 1930 " ' 244.63 120.90 365.53 302.25 1.210 2.52 . 761.6 0.479 M 1931 " 192 57 194.53 387.10 432.25 ' 0.897 2.55 1102.2 0.351 w ™^ _ _ — — — Av 268.36 | 160.44 442.77 380.75 1.189 2.413 906.8 0.4986 &gt; "This includes an attendance charec of $111.78. . M ' Costs of some irrigation the previous fall chanted to crops of these two seasons. w . . . . . , : : — . , . ■ . : — ,_ _ — ■ — H-- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 271 Table 2— Total number of kiloivatt-hours of energy used, the fraZ C i°oh a t ,K? cost per unit for the seascms from 1925 to JL931 inclusive Year Total electricity Total cost of Average cost per U3ed power kilowatt-hour „ ~"1 Kilowatt-hours ~ : I Cents \Hl • IW $403.70 - 3.762 \H% 9-560 373.82 3,910 \1%L 3,690 162.39 4.401 \H* 5,760 251.31 4.363 \IB 7,880 284.20 3.607 *•£? , 5,870 244.63 4 167 1931 1 5,080 192^ 3.790 Total | 48,660 [ $1,912.63 Average ,| 6,951.3 ! 273.23 j 3.9306 All electricity used at the station for power purposes other than irrigation is charged off first. The result is a lower power cost for irrigation than would be the case on farms where less current- is consumed or where there is no power used for purposes other than pumping. Table 2 gives a summary of electric power used for irriga - tion for each of the seasons from 1925 to 1931 inclusive When current is charged on a sliding-scale, calendar-month basis, the distribution of its use throughout the season mav be a greater factor in determining the unit cost than the total amount used. A given amount of current consumed during S?rfJfh°t 5 obviously cost less than the same amount' distributed over a period of two or three months Since an electrically operated plant requires very little attention, no charge for attendance was made after 1924 The distributing cost covers all labor involved in getting the water nm'rS fV ♦ *?. m » de ° n baSlS ° f aCtual t[ ™ re - quired, this total distributing cost will vary with the num - ber of hours the pump is operated per season, but the cost per acre inch of water will vary with the amount of water pumped per hour The cost will be high if the irrigator h^oSfa fraction of the amount of water he can handle properly and of course will be lower as the amount, approaches the limit SSfpJl 1 "^ and u m ° St e ffi cien «y- This point is well illus - trated by the results from the seasons of 1925 and 1926 The operating cost per hour for these two seasons was the same Rftj? °;22 acre inch per hour more water pumped L i&amp;tw,S and the cost per acre inch was 5 4 ce «ts less. That this difference was due almost entirely to the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Pump Irrigation and Water Table Studies variation in distributing cost per unit of water is obvious, for the cost per hour for power differed only approximately 0:5 cent. The low costs per unit of water for 1927 and 1928 are also very largely the result of the increased discharge of the pump. This increase was due to the unusually high water table of those two seasons and to the fact that relatively small de - mands were made upon the ground water, so that the level of the water table about the plant was very little affected by the operation of the pump. In 1930 the old pump was used during the early part of the season but was replaced by the new one in July, and hence the cost figures for that season are not especially represent - ative. In 1931 with approximately the same amount of water pumped per hour as in 1926, the lowest cost per hour and per acre inch of water during the eight-year period was recorded. This cost was approximately 15 cents per acre inch less than that for 1926. The fact that practically all the electric power was used in two months (55.6 per cent of the total in August, thus causing much of it to fall under the lower prices in the rate scale) is accountable for the low price of water. FIXED COST Fixed costs for the project at the North Platte Substation have been calculated on a valuation of $2500, which was the approximate original cost of the plant. In 1924 six per cent was allowed for interest, 10 per cent for depreciation and 2!/ L &gt; per cent for upkeep, making a total of 181/4 per cent of the original valuation. In 1925, in order to care for the added expense of making the change from the kerosene engine to electric power, the fixed cost was continued at 18^ per cent. As the original cost, rate of depreciation, and upkeep Table 3. — Total fixed cost, acres irrigated,, and fixed cost per acre for the years from 192U to 1931 inclusive V v^^°L Total fixed Acres ! Cost per ' $000 cost irrigatedj acr * Per cent, \ Number' 1924 ...i 18V&amp; $462.50 42.2 $10.96 1925 ! 18% 462.50 | 74.2 1 6.23 1926 1. 12 300.00 79.0 3.80 1927 ......| 12 300.00 61.0 | 4.92 1928 1 12 300.00 64.0 I 4.69 1929 1 12- 300.00 89.9 3.34 1930 1 12 300.00 50.1 5.99 1931 1 12 I 300.00 | 78.0 | 3.85 I | . . Av 1 .... I $340.63 67.3 $ 5.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 271 are much less on a motor than on an engine, the fixed cost has been calculated since 1926 as 12 per cent of the original valuation. The rate of fixed charges, total fixed cost, num - ber of acres irrigated, and fixed cost per acre for the eight years are given in Table 3. As the fixed cost other than upkeep is chargeable to the plant whether the plant is operated or not, it is obvious that it does not pay to let it stand idle. For most economical opera - tion, it should be made to serve the greatest possible number of acres consistent with good irrigation practice. COSTS AND NET RETURNS FROM THE IRRIGATION OF MAIN CROPS Table 4 gives a summary of costs, yields, and gross and net returns from the irrigation of corn, potatoes, and alfalfa. Annual rainfall is also shown. The increased returns for corn do not take into account the increased yield of fodder, which certainly is of considerable value. The average increased yield of green fodder as harvested for silage has been slightly over 6.5 tons per acre. Nearly all the corn grown under irri - gation at the North Platte Substation is grown for silage and consequently is planted thick. This undoubtedly reduces the yield of grain to some extent but it gives, a larger yield of silage and the stalks are not so large and coarse as from thinner planting. Ordinarily the corn is given three waterings of from 3 to 5 inches each. Potatoes are watered usually from 3 to 5 times during the season. The average application is somewhat lighter than for corn. In 1931 the potatoes required 7 appli - cations or almost 36.5 inches of water per acre. This was due to the extremely hot, dry season and the large growth of vines, caused by favorable early growing conditions. Alfalfa uses large amounts of water and responds readily to irrigation: Outside of a 3 acre field in which an alfalfa variety test is being carried on, the irrigation of alfalfa at the North Platte Substation has been of a rather incidental nature, water being applied to alfalfa whenever it is not necessary to use it on the silage corn, etc., but the results indicate in a general way what may be expected from the irrigation of alfalfa. Applications of from 5 to 8 inches of water seem to give best results with alfalfa at the North Platte Substation. Usually alfalfa is watered three times during the season. Easier and better distribution may be obtained immediately after each crop is harvested, but thi* permits a greater loss by evaporation. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Table 4.— Acres irrigated, ivater used, total cost, average yields on irrigated and on dry land, increase per acre, and increased net returns per acre forjhejkreejmncipal crops irngaied__^ AveraKP Avernne Averace yield Increase r-.' r -., e j' . , creased Pro- per acre . . : " " J* COKN g M, I I /Jk. £ta. ' I Bu. Inches Bu. *o 1925... '.. 35.7 11.20 $12.65 43.70 ■ 7.5 36.20 $12.69. 14.04 3.23. „ 1926 39 5 10.17 9.09 40.50 2.5 38.00 21.63 15.12 3.74 g 1927- 36.5 9.32 9.46 60.00 42.0 18.00 1.86 22.45 1,08 g 1928 310 9 80 8.06 60.00 32.7 27.30 12.41 20.63 2.79 j£ 1929 Z'Z'Z 38.9 16.44 7.25 47.50 14.2 33.30 17.88 18.00 2.03 H 1930 33 0 18.34 14.80 96.64 30.0 ' 66.64 26.54 27.15 3.64 O 1931 32.3 14.56 9.21 49.07 14.0 35.07 3.06 10.10 2.40 Z Av. ...'.'.'I .'■'..'■' 35.3 12.83 10.07 56.77 I 20.4 36.47 13.72 18.34 2.83 &gt; ~~' 7 ALFALFA . O I | | Tons | Tons Tons J F Lbs. . 1925 15.0 18.30 I 16.73 I 3.50 | 1.5 2.00 3.27 219 1926 8.0 14.34 11.26 | 3.80 | 1.5 2.30 18.00 321 &gt; 1927 3.0 9.87 9.73 I 4.00 | 2.0 .2.00 6.27 405 M 1928 •"■■„ 5.0 9.35 11.47 5.76 2.0 . 3.76 26.11 800 W 1929 23.0 7.70 3.30 2.70 1.0 1.70 13.83 442 H 1930 3.0 5.67 8.71 0.82 0.1 0.72 -3.54 254 &gt; 1931 4.0 14.21 9.09 I 5.00 2.5 2.50 9.66 ........ 352 » a;,,:;:;::: —8.71- 11.35 10.04 i 3.55 1.5 2.15 10.52 1 -^- 400 ■ w ~ POTATOES 7 W I I Bu. Bu. Bu. I Bu. c 1925 3.5 I 19.00 I 17.14 478.5 100.0 378.5 304.29 19.92 g J926 4.5 26.70 15.68 283.0 102.0 181.0. 283.66 6.78 a 192? 45 17.11 13.26 290.0 150.0 140.0 91.87 8.18 w laog 2 0 11.69 8.84 ! 400.0 255.4 144.6 , 77.92 12.35 {929 i 2.0 16.30 6.99 I 327.0 100.0 227.0 376.77 13.93 1930 2.0 31.42 10.28 I 215.4 109.8 105.6 24.48 3.36 1931 2 0 36.46 17.29 408.0 78.0 330.0 114.71 9.05 A V 29 22.67 12.93 343.1 . 127.9 215.2 181.96 I 10.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 271 Maximum yields of corn, potatoes, and alfalfa under irri - gation have been 127 bushels, 600 bushels, and 5.7 tons per acre respectively. Yields in excess of 50 bushels per acre of corn, 350 bushels of potatoes, and 3.5 tons of alfalfa hay per acre may logically be expected in the average season if the crops have been properly watered. The variation in cost shown in Table 4 is due to (1) the total number of acres irrigated, which determines the fixed cost per acre (2) the amount of water applied, (3) the average cost per unit of electric energy, and (4) the amount of water pumped per minute. Net returns from any crop vary from year to year because of the variation in irrigation cost, the fluctuation in the markets, and the efficiency of irrigation expressed as a ratio of crop units to units of water used. The latter is probably the greatest single factor in determining cost and net returns. It is also probably the most variable factor affecting these- items. These ratios are shown in the last column of Table 4. In addition to the variations from year to year in the re - sponse of each crop to irrigation, there is a very noticeable difference in the various crops within a given season. In l \ ' \ : " 0 T£ 3 T *£LL 0^ O • lAttiOATiO* WCll I ■ © — »&lt;&gt;■ — ©^ * i ~~^%Jr y® — io ° — ®" ao °' •© \ t — " 1 i -■■■■■. I Fig. 1.— Arrangement of the irrigation wells and the test holes. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Pump Irrigation and Water Table Studies 1926 the ratio of bushels of corn to inches of water was the highest for the seven-year period, while with potatoes it was next to the lowest and for alfalfa it was third from the low - est. In the year with the best ratio for potatoes, the ratio for corn ranked third and that for alfalfa the lowest of the entire period. These differences show in some measure the relative adaptation of the various crops to a given set of con - ditions. For example, in a hot season corn generally gives good results, while potatoes respond better in a cooler season. The time of irrigation also has a pronounced effect upon the ratio of increased yield to water used. This is illustrated by the results with potatoes in 1930, when the next to the high - est amount of water was used and the lowest increase in yield and the lowest ratio of increased yield to water used were recorded. This was caused by a delay of several days in the second watering of the crop while a new pump was be - ing installed. This brings up the question of the best time to water a crop. Probably the best answer is that it should be done just as soon and just as often as that crop begins to need water and before it has actually begun to suffer from a moisture shortage. An examination of the soil will show this, but for all practical purposes the condition of the crop is the best index. The purpose of all supplemental irrigation is to keep crops growing and in condition to make the best use of rainfall. WATER TABLE STUDY The irrigation plant of the North Platte Substation is situated at the foot of the bluffs on the south side of the valley and about 200 yards east of the mouth of a rather large can - yon. There are four wells arranged as shown in Figure 1. The permanent water table in the Avells stands at approxi - mately 31 feet. The water-bearing material has a depth of approximately 22 feet at the central well but has approxi - mately half this thickness at a distance of 300 feet south. The upper 10 feet of this material is so fine that it is of very little value in supplying large quantities of water for pumping. Below this there is a layer of about 12 feet of fair gravel mixed with several thin layers of fine sand and one or two of clay. In the last four feet the gravel is rather coarse and permits of comparatively rapid movement of the water through it. AREA OF WATER TABLE AFFECTED BY PUMPING It was found that while the pump was running, the water table behaved very differently on different sides of the wells, </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 271 h — ■»• 1 '«■ ■i;j)-sow)-io--i-jo— | — loo--' j ' ' joo ! g ,o A . I ■ , , i*—\ u=zx==i' 1 i - I ! 1 = r ■'■'-! I ' ill I/T""" ~| ~ .'— ! j\| I—-hrt^—^— - i i ii • ~ I • ■— [L I . r i« ' i zz:li_zz: g.-!-== B = : : — j==p= ■ 2 ==^ I i |\|/ \^ 1^~~^^ 2 ~~ 8^^ 115 $'!fr,7&amp;' **? thr0U - gh the site of the ir "ga - tion plant at the end of 14 hours of pumping. A represents north and south; B represents east and west. lepresents, north as shown by Figure 2. The depressed area was very narrow and broke abruptly on the west side. It was somewhat wider to the east and the downward curve was more gentle. On the north side the curve was quite similar to that on the east, but for some reason there was appreciably more draw-down wilt tv? n&lt; £ ° f I 50 . J eet J han at 50 feet from- the pumped well, while beyond this there was no noticeable effect To of e 2^n Lf !,Tr 5 dedd ? d drop indi^ted to a distance ot and the depressional curve was very Kentle as compared with that for the other directions. It ta^teSdS +« Lf M^ b !i r «° f . A addltlonal tes t wells be put down in 1932 Stv ti 1 definitely the configuration bf the water plane within the entire area affected by pumping </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Pump Irrigation an-d Water Table Studies ■— :»■ r^l^i^zUl RAT^ OF DRAW-DOWN :..l ;:,,:,| 1 1 j__J '-T Figure 3 shows the :..•— ■■ r. ;' ;. j 1 ' . | . -\ [ rate iand amount of 4 r 2Z ~Z draw-down in the cen - [ XX" : i ' j I j tral well of the pump - :, _Jsl_ i'.,;i. I 14 in £ Plant (curve 1), *■' —-^i^^ — .j^^r.i7^irj 1 — the test well 25 feet I' '" ITt^^ I I I — I ! west of it (curve 2), «- V~j ' T~~ i 1 • I ■ j j 1 and the one 100 feet ; ,-V- — 4_; — , — -I I Z west (curve 3). Fig - „ --NU j . ■ \ — I—- 1 1 1 — ure 4 shows the rates " v^&lt;-^_ i [ ~ — 1 of draw-down for the '.;~ r^~j """- y'^pgfr""! ' i sout h well (curve 1), 1 ; 3- — : — i j_ 1 1 1 1 Zj. the test well 25 feet PIG. 8— Rate and "extent of draw-down Uth ! rf ** ( CU ™e 2) west from the central well of the pump- tne one I 5 " teet south ing plant. . (curve 3) , and the one 250 feet south (curve • it may be noted that r2~ ~ U " : "i~ : "°'|- LL — 4^— there is no significant '.'JTZ ~ j difference between the *ft ■ two wells of the i\ ' . | pumping plant, but a'pr \ there is considerable ;• T&gt;^ZZ~~ " — h — h difference shown in the °' I ' ' ' "^-^ 9 *7"'^" '"uggaajatiajyip behavior of the water J . A— -■ ! in the two test wells ""AH — ; 1 at a distance of 25 feet "rNr~j — 1 H from them. During " •. . r'*- ~-~- ___ ' fTn the first hour, the one .. — 7- — *~agY?-'-p..c..p ..l^_^ to the south dropped ■" J ' — }-^J "- — J \ 1 — J — 8 1/2 feet, while the one ■ HOU "i to the west dropped FlG - 4 - — Rate and ex *ent of draw-down The' IhS 2 in nC vSe *™^™^- ""^ ° ? of drop is also much more abrupt toward the south than to - ward the west. The apparent irregularity in the rate of draw-down in the first test well of the south series seems to be caused in some manner by the movement of water from farther out in the area, for it may be noted that this irregu - larity came at the same time that the water plane began to dr6p in the more distant wells. This peculiarity was not the occurrence of a single instance but was noted every time measurements of the . rate of draw-down were made. This also occurred in the string of wells to the west but was not so marked. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 271 recovery of water table after heavy pumping During the past season some study was made of the re - covery of the water plane following a period of pumping The data from a typical instance for the south line of wells are shown in Figure 5. Early in the season when the water table was high, the original level was reached sooner, while later, when the water table was Jower, the rate of recovery was slower. After a short period of pumping, as should be expected, recovery was much more rapid than after one of longer duration. No satisfactory data were obtained concern - mg the rate of recovery in any direction other than south The present plan calls for carrying on this phase of the work in a more comprehensive manner during the season of 1932. • J'W L 1 ' | I -» ' • ,^i ; — : ' 1 — — - — :. s , ■ ' - ; - ' ■ I I * ' I — — — ' Sif : : -I 1 \ j ~' i ■ . ~~~ j ■ Fig. 5.— Rate of recovery of water table to the south of the pumping plant after a 14-hoiir period of pumping. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>