<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Seed Potato Treatment Tests for Control of Scab and Rhizoctonia</title>
               <date value="1929-12">1929-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 44 Seed Potato Treatment Tests for Control of Scab and Rhizoctonia R. W. Goss and H. O. Werner LINCOLN, NEBRASKA DECEMBER, 1929 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS SUMMARY , 3 INTRODUCTION 5 METHODS OF EXPERIMENTATION 6 Location of plots and cultural conditions.... 6 Size and arrangement .'..: 7 Field methods '. : : 7 Seed :■ :..... 7 Seed treatments _. 8 Method of harvesting and recording results... 10 RESULTS : '. 12 Scab experiments . 12 Emergence and stand 12 Effect on yield.... : 11 Effect on scab 18 Rhizoctonia experiment-; at Lincoln _ 25 Emergence and stand „ 25 Stem lesions ;.. 26 Sclerotia on tubers 28 Effect on yield.. : 14 Relation of seed treatments to seed piece decay and plant vigor 32 DISCUSSION OR RESULTS- 33 Consideration of seed and soil infection...., 33 Effect of seed treatments on scab 36 Effect of seed treatments on Rhizoctonia..... 37 Effect of seed treatments on yields 39 General considerations ; 40 LITERATURE CITED 42 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY 1. The experiments here reported were conducted during the years 1926, 1927, and 1928. Those on scab control were made with the Irish Cobbler variety at Lincoln and North Platte and with the Triumph at Alliance. The Rhizoctonia tests were made with the Early Ohio variety at Lincoln. 2. The three locations used were considered representative of three different potato-growing sections of the state, the Lincoln plot repre - senting the early potato section of eastern Nebraska, the North Platte plot representing the irrigated midseason section of south-central and western Nebraska and the Alliance plot representing the western dry-land commercial seed and table-stock region. The experimental plots consisted of 5 to 8 replications of 25-hill rows systematically distributed to equalize soil differences and competition. 3. The seed treatments tested included hot formaldehyde, mercuric chloride, and a number of commercial organic mercury preparations. These were used chiefly as dips on uncut seed. A few tests were made with cut seed and several organic mercury treatments were also applied as a dust. In addition, sulfur was tested as a soil treatment for scab during two years, acidulated mercuric chloride was used for scab con - trol in one test, and treatments were made for Rhizoctonia control during two years, both with and without a presprinkle of water. 4. Hot formaldehyde was consistently the most effective treatment in controlling seed-borne scab. Mercuric chloride failed to control i cab. The addition of 1.5 parts of HCI per 100 parts of mercuric chlor - ide solution failed to increase its effectiveness. The organic mercury treatments applied either as a dip or a dust on either cut or uncut seed likewise failed to reduce consistently the amount of scab. Sulfur applied to the soil decreased the amount of scab in 1927 but failed to do so in 1926. 5. Seed tubers severely infected with scab and treated with hot formaldehyde equaled or exceeded the percentage of scab-free potatoes produced by apparently healthy seed untreated. 6. Apparently healthy tubers of the Bliss Triumph variety treated with hot formaldehyde produced more scab-free potatoes than such seed untreated. 7. With increasingly large amounts of infection from the soil of cither scab or Rhizoctonia, the benefits from control of the seed-borne disease by seed treatment becomes progressively less. 8. There was no indication of reduced' yields due to scab infection. 9. In the control of Rhizoctonia all the treatments resulted in in - creased yields. Hot formaldehyde gave the best control as judged by stem lesions and the sderotia on the new tubers. Mercuric chloride and the organic mercurials were much more effective against Rhizoc - tonia than against scab, the mercuric chloride, however, giving the best results. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">10. Presprinkhng the tubers infected with Rhizoctonia 24 hours before treating with mercuric chloride failed to increase the effective - ness of the treatment. The small size of the sclerotia probably rendered this presprinkle treatment unnecessary. 11. In the Rhizoctonia tests with the Early Ohio variety, the hot formaldehyde retarded emergence in two of the three years and the beneficial effect due to disease control was not as evident: when a period of hot, dry weather prevented the plants from overcoming the handicap of delayed emergence. Such injury did not occur in any of the 9 scab tests with Triumphs and Cobblers. The treatment of the seed a ferw weeks before planting is recommended to eliminate this retarded emergence. 12. The organic mercury treatments cause some seed-piece injury unless care is taken to allow the cut seed pieces to dry rapidly. 13. There was no consistent increase in yields resulting from seed treatment with the organic mercury compounds other than thru the control of Rhizoctonia. The organic mercury treatments did not in - crease stands or vigor nor did they prevent seed-piece decay in the one test recorded. No correlation was found in this test between seed - piece decay and vigor of the plants determined either as green weight of the tops or total yield. 14. Due to the fact that much of the seed planted in eastern Nebraska is infected with Rhizoctonia and in western Nebraska with scab, the hot formaldehyde treatment is a profitable investment to be recommended for all seed potatoes. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Seed Potato Treatment Tests for Control of Scab and Rhizoctonia R. W. Goss and H. O. Werner Potato scab annually takes a very large toll from the potato growers of Nebraska. Scabby potatoes of market - able size, which have to be culled but, when conservatively estimated amount annually to between 15 and 25 per cent of the crop. Rhizoctonia causes considerable loss each year* particularly in the early-potato sections, where it decreases stand and yield. These losses are caused by in - fection from both the soil and the seed. The investigations reported in this paper deal only with the control of the infection arising from the seed. Even tho potato seed treatments have been recommended for many years, the diversity of recommendations being made at present by various agencies is very confusing to the grower and research worker alike. Many of the reports from different parts of the United States have been quite contradictory and a survey of the literature indicates that in many cases the conflicting results may have been due to local conditions. It was the purpose of the present investi - gations to determine the relative value of various seed treatments under the several conditions existing in the potato-growing sections. of Nebraska: Prior to 1926, when these tests were started, it was com - monly observed that the cold mercuric chloride treatment was not very satisfactory and was not giving as good results in Nebraska as had been reported from other states. Many growers had abandoned the use of this treatment because it did not control scab. The hot formaldehyde treatment, devised and recommended by Melhus and Gilman (9) in Iowa, had the distinct advantage of shortening the length of time required for treating from li/ 2 hours to from 2 to 4 minutes. Neither of these treatments had been tested ex - perimentally by the Nebraska Experiment Station. Several organic mercury compounds on the market that appeared to have some desirable features were included in order to determine their effectiveness under Nebraska conditions. While the chief purpose of the experiments was to test the above-mentioned treatments, a few other treatments were added as time and space permitted. It was at first considered desirable to continue all tests for at least three years before attempting to draw definite conclusions. Later it was found that this was not possible </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 or advisable with all treatments, due to the fact that cer - tain commercial treatments tested one year were not avail - able the following year since by that time they had been replaced by other preparations purported to be more effec - tive. Other minor changes in the methods of experimenta - tion were made but the basic methods used were carried out thru all three years so that the data would be as com - parable as possible. The uniformity of the results obtained was such that definite conclusions can be made regarding the relative effectiveness of the various treatments tested. The work has therefore been discontinued and the results which have been partially reported elsewhere (4) are here re - ported in full. METHODS OF EXPERIMENTATION LOCATION OF PLOTS AND CULTURAL CONDITIONS The experiments were conducted at three different loca - tions, which are representative of three of the principal environmental conditions under which potatoes are raised in Nebraska. Plot 1. Lincoln. — This plot, located on the Experiment Station Farm, is representative of the early potato crop grown for home consumption in eastern Nebraska. The crop, planted between April 1 and 15 at an altitude of approximately 1,200 feet, is usually under conditions of low temperature and fairly high precipitation during the emergence period and shortly after, but it often suffers from hot, dry weather during the later period of tuber formation. This sometimes results in the death of the vines from 1 to 4 weeks before normal maturity. r,,^i 0t o 2 V North Platte — Thi s Plot, located at the North rlatte Substation, represents the early commercial irrigation region. As the altitude at North Platte is about 2,800 feet, the crop, while planted in April, does not usually suffer from nigh temperatures during the period of tuber formation. It is also supplied with sufficient moisture by ditch irrigation. Plot 8. Alliance. — This plot is representative of the west - tern Nebraska dry-land commercial seed and table-stock region where potatoes are raised as a late crop, planted in June. At Alliance lower temperatures prevail than at the other points, due to the higher altitude (about 4,000 feet). The annual rainfall is in the neighborhood of 19 inches, plot was loc ated on the same farm in 1926 and 1927 but on a different farm in the same localitv in 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">■ Potato Treatments for Scab and Rhizoctonia SIZE AND ARRANGEMENT The various treatments tested in each plot were replica - t i u om 5 to 8 times, except the untreated checks of healthy and scabby seed, which were replicated jtwice the number of the treated lots. Each replication consisted of a single 20- or 25-hill row. The treatments- were distributed thru the plot by use of a modified "Latin square" system. By the use of this system of planting the possible variations in soil infestation as well as in nutrients, moisture, tempera - ture, texture, reaction and culture are largely compensated tor by the uniform distribution of the tests thruout the plot. In addition, the factor of competition and its effect upon yield is partially equalized by the position of the several replications, which are so arranged that each treat - ment is adjacent to every other treatment somewhere in the plot. FIELD METHODS All seed pieces were cut to a uniform size of one-tenth of a pound. In all except one instance (Plot 3, Alliance, 1928) the seed was hand-planted. Hills were spaced 15 inches apart with rows 3 feet apart, except at North Platte in 1927 and 1928 when the hills were spaced 12 inches apart. The Lincoln plot was planted about the middle of April and harvested the last week in August. The North Platte plot was planted- about April 20 and was harvested Sep - tember 1 in 1926, October 7 in 1927, and October 1 in 1928 In 1926 the plants at North Platte were mature about August 15, in 1927 by September 1, and in 1928 about August 1. The Alliance plot was planted the first week in June and harvested the first week in October. SEED Irish Cobbler potatoes, grown in Minnesota or western Nebraska, were used for the scab experiments at Lincoln and North Platte. This variety is the most practical for commercial midsummer production in those regions. West - ern Nebraska certified Triumph potatoes were used for the scab tests at Alliance, this variety being the predominating one in the western part of the state. In the Rhizoctonia tests, Early Ohio seed from the Red River Valley was used, as this is the most common source of Early Ohio seed for eastern Nebraska plantings. The scab on the Irish Cobblers was of the common sur - face type, with but a small amount of pitted or deep scab. On the Triumph variety the scab was much more severe, due to the presence of more lesions, which were both larger </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 and deeper than on the Irish Cobbler seed. All seed listed as healthy was carefully washed and examined and did not contain any tubers with visible scab lesions or Rhizoc - tonia sclerotia. Because of the darker color of the skin and the more severe scab infection of the Triumph seed it was probably impossible to secure as clean seed for the healthy lot of that variety as for the lot of Irish Cobbler The Rhizoctonia on the Early Ohio seed was mostly in the form of small sclerotia (from 1 to 3 mm. in size) which were well scattered over the surface. The seed used in each plot for any series of treatments was always from the same source for both healthy and in - fected lots and also for both the treated lots and the un - treated checks. SEED TREATMENTS The various treatments used and the methods of employ - ing them are listed in the tables. A few notes concerning these treatments, which cannot be included in the tables, In Plots 1, Lincoln, and 3, Alliance, all the seed treat - ments were made either the same day or the day previous to Planting, unless otherwise noted. The seed treatments for Plot 2 were usually made at the same time as for Plot 1 and were treated and cut before shipping. This required holding the seed from 7 to 10 days after cutting. As Cobblers were used in Plot 2, and as the cut surface of this variety heals over quickly, this system was found to be entirely satisfactory. In the other plots it was necessary in one year to hold cut seed a few days before planting, due to unfavorable weather. All the seed for each treatment in a plot was treated at the same time. All seed of any. one treatment was cut into the required number of seed pieces of equal weight and was then divided at random into the desired number of replications. This method gave a fairly good distri - bution of seed pieces from individual tubers thruout the different replications. Cutting was generally done after the seed had been treated and allowed to dry Treatment of healthy seed.— In addition to the untreated healthy checks, it was advisable to include some treatment of healthy seed to determine the amount of disease being carried on the tuber in a form not visible to the naked eye. Such a check also served as a basis for determining more accurately the amount of soil infestation and also as a basis of comparison when used on infected seed for all the other treatments. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Potato Treatments . fob Scab and Rhizoctonia In 1926 the cold mercuric chloride treatment was used in ™w S ». P !£ p08e '* b * emsr employed as a l-to-1,000 solution m which the potatoes were dipped for 1V 2 hours The results obtained in 1926 indicated that the hot formalde - hyde treatment might serve as a better basis of comparison and it was therefore used in 1927 and 1928. This treat - ment was. employed as a l-to-120 solution in which the ?22° to S i^ e ir dlPI £ d for 4 minutes at a temperature of ££• *?£ •,', afte J whlch they were covered for one hour and then allowed to dry. iois a i d - itio i n i° these checks it was deemed advisable, in w fhl ~ °l e x f the . o r? anic mercury treatments to lest the possible effect on yield, exclusive of possible yield effects due to scab control. Accordingly, one lot of healthy seed was treated with Semesan Bel and another lot was i-X « eated wl i h , h0 Lformaldehyde and afterward treated with Semesan Bel. The Semesan Bel treatment was made tion SeG aS an mstantaneous di P wi th a l-to-20 dilu- In selecting the healthy checks for the 1926 tests in Plots l and 2, it was found impossible to obtain enough healthy tubers to provide the double number of replications cE sired. Potatoes were therefore selected for one set of replications with as few scab spots as possible and tested untreated and with the mercuric chloride treatment. These t^H -t ed m - th vfi tabl - es ?« J 11 * 1 * scab. The results obtained made it desirable to include an untreated lot of similar seed the next year as a check upon the results. Treatment of scabby seed.— In addition to the hot formal - dehyde and mercuric chloride treatments, a. number of or - ganic mercury compounds and acidulated mercuric chlor - ide were tested at various times. Among the organic compounds Semesan Bel as a dip was used m- every plot each year and Bayer Dip Dust was used each year in all the plots with the exception of the 1926 plots at Lincoln and North Platte. Additional organic mercury compounds were used during the various years as follows : in 1926, Du Pont No. 12 ; in 1927, Du Pont D D D Sn ™ ? aj T 1S } ; and f P 1928 ' Du Pont 76B and Bayer JSL ? X F u^ 1^ 1^^ made at the strengths indi - cated in the tables. The dilution was made by slowly shak - ing the dust into the required amount of water while rapidly whipping the liquid with a beater made of heavy wire This was found to be an excellent way of obtaining a good mix - ture without any caking or lumping of the material and resulted in a minimum amount of sediment. The dust treat - ments were made by thoroly shaking the potatoes and dust </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 in a container until the surface of each tuber was thoroly covered. In 1927 the organic mercury dips were used on cut seed potatoes, the seed pieces having been allowed to heal for 18 to 24 hours before treating and also allowed to dry after treating and before planting. Unfavorable weather conditions caused a delay in the planting of the Lincoln and North Platte tests in 1927 and this caused some damage to seed pieces with some treatments as will be noted later. In 1926 and 1928 the organic mercury treatments were made on whole (uncut) tubers. Inasmuch as no data were available as to the possible effects of a sulfur treatment of the soil under Nebraska conditions, this treatment was also included in the 1926 and 1927 tests. Inoculated sulfur was used only in 1926. In all the tests sulfur was applied to the soil by distribut - ing it evenly along the furrow before planting at the rate of one ounce per hill, calculated to be approximately 600 pounds per acre. In the 1928 tests at Alliance, Plot 3, one additional treat - ment was used by acidulating the standard mercuric chlor - ide with the addition of HC1 at the rate of 1.5 parts per 100. The treatment was used exactly as with the unacidu - lated. Treatment of Rhizoctonia seed. — Many of the treatments used in the scab tests were also used in a similar manner i'or the Rhizoctonia tests. The sulfur tests and the acidulated mercuric chloride test used in the scab experiments were omitted. In 1926 two tests were made with the . presprinkling method advocated by Raeder, Hungerford, and Chapman (12). In these tests the seed was dipped in water and after being drained was covered for 24 to 48 hours and cut before treating with mercuric chloride or Du Pont No. 12 Bel Dip. All other treatments in 1926 were made on uncut seed. In 1927 all the organic mercury tests were made on cut seed, handled as in the scab tests. Another test with the presprinkle method using mercuric chloride was included. In 1928 all tests were made on uncut seed with the excep - tion of one-half of the extra replications used for a count of stem lesions and notes on preservation of seed pieces as indicated in Table 7. METHODS OF HARVESTING AND RECORDING RESULTS Emergence records were taken twice weekly. Notes on the relative vigor of the plants with the various treatments were made each year. In 1928 special effort was made in determining the vigor of the vines in relation to seed- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Potato Treatments fok Scab and Rhizoctonia S P T^ r I at lr^ total . weight of green tops, and final &gt;ieid. The methods used will be presented later with the discussion of results. Each replication of a treatment was dug and sacked as a unit and later was graded over a commercial grader into U. b. grade sizes. Disease records Scab.— In recording the amount of scab present, each replication of 20 or 25 hills was considered as a unit. After being graded by sizes, the tubsrs were examined individually for scab lesions and classified ac - cording to the severity of infection into the following five scab classes: Class 0 — scab-free tubers Class 1 — less than 5 lesions V 8 in: or 1 lesion V, in in size . Class 2 — more scab than Class 1 but less than V± the surface scabby Class 3 — from 1/4, to % o f the surface scabby Class 4 — more than % of the surface scabby In 1927 and 1928 Classes 3 and 4 were combined and the results for 1926- are presented on this basis. Also, only the potatoes of U. S. No. 1 and No. 2 sizes were graded tor scab. Inasmuch as there is always a possibility that small pm-head scab lesions escape detection, the greatest error undoubtedly occurred in differentiating between Classes 0 and 1. Since most of the potatoes in Class 1 would be graded commercially as healthy, these two classes have been combined in many of the following tabulations as "commercially healthy or scab free." Rhizoctonia.— In 1926 the tubers were graded for size as in the scab experiments and then classified in 4 groups : Class 1 — healthy Class 2 — slight infection, i.e.; a few small sclerotia Class 3 — medium infection, i.e., a few large sclerotia or many small ones Class 4 — severe infection, i.e., most of the surface covered with sclerotia In 1927 no records were made of the sclerotia on the tubers. The effects of the disease and of the treatments were measured solely in. yield. In 1928, in addition to yield data, the effect of the treat - ments was also measured by the number and severity of stem lesions. Six additional replications of 25 hills each were planted for every treatment. The hills in the different replications were dug on three different dates. The stems </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 seed. All of these eventually produced good stands except the hot formaldehyde treatment No. 5, altho the same treatment on healthy seed gave a 98 per cent stand without retardation of emergence. In Plot 3, Alliance, there was considerable variation in the effect of treatments on emergence. Practically all treatments except Semesan Bel and Bayer 190 caused some delay in emergence. The only treatments affecting the final stand were hot formaldehyde and mercuric chloride. These data do not exhibit any profound effect of the various seed treatments on stand altho, as noted above, most of the treatments slightly retarded emergence. While several of them resulted in poor stands, it should be noted that the same treatment often produced good stands in the other plots. Sometimes, even in the same plot, a treat - ment gave different results with healthy and scabby seed. The hot formaldehyde treatment of healthy potatoes caused no injury, while with scabby potatoes in the same stage of dormancy and treated in the same solution at the same time, it reduced the stand considerably. In Table 1 the results do not indicate that scabby pota - toes cause decreased stands. By comparing healthy and scabby potatoes untreated, Nos; 1 and 11, it can be seen that there was very little difference in either the rate of emergence or the final stand. In some of the tests, espe - cially with Triumphs, seed potatoes that were so scabby as to render the finding of the eyes very difficult gave a perfect stand. Effect on yield. — In order to conserve space and to pre - sent all the yield data on a comparable basis, the results are summarized as in Table 2. The actual yields with the probable errors are given only for the untreated scabby checks (Table 2, No. 21). The difference between the mean yield of each treatment and that of the untreated scabby check with the probable error of the difference is presented. In order to give some idea of the significance of the results, the ratio of the differences to the probable error of the difference is also given. The formula used for the calculations is given on page 12. The plus or the minus sign is used to indicate the increase or decrease in comparison with -the check. The data in Table 2 show that there was no consistent difference between the two untreated lots, Nos. 1 and 21, indicating that scab had no direct effect upon yield. If this conclusion is correct, then the control of scab by seed treatment would have no effect upon yield. There were, however, .55 instances of increased yields and 35 of de- </seg>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 creased yields in comparison with the scab check. It should be noted, however, that 5 of these decreases followed-seed - piece injury as noted on page 13. While some of these differences might be considered mathematically significant, the authors believe that the use of an arbitrary standard such as 3 or 4 times the probably error, to determine sig - nificance, would in this case lead to false conclusions. It will be noted that none of the treatments gave consistent increases for the 3 years in all 3 plots, and that some of the greatest increases were accompanied by decreases in other years or in other plots for the same treatment. For example, mercuric chloride No. 7 gave an increase at North Platte in 1927 (page 16) as shown by the ratio of +2.6, but in 1928 there Was a decrease with a ratio of -2.6 and the same year at Alliance (page 15) of -4.4. The fact that there were more increases than decreases and that the increases were slightly larger indicates a tend - ency toward increased yields which may have been due to the control of Rhizoctonia, which possibly was present on the scabby seed. The only consistently increased yields occurred not with any one treatment in repeated tests but rather with all but one treatment in a single year, for example in 1926 and 1928 at Alliance (page 15). The chief difficulty in explaining these increases as being due to control of Rhizoctonia lies in the fact that the only treatment fail - ing to show increase in these two years was mercuric chlor - ide and this treatment, as will be shown later, is one of the most effective in controlling Rhizoctonia. The only con - clusion that seems tenable to the authors after analyzing the data in Table 2 and considering all the factors involved in these tests, is that there is no significant difference in yields due to the control of scab by any of these treat - ments but that there is a slight tendency toward increased yields due to control of Rhizoctonia, which occurred in variable amounts on the seed tubers. Effect on scab. — The effectiveness of the various treat - ments in controlling scab is presented separately for the three different plots in Tables 3, 4, and 5. As the data previously presented failed to show any appreciable differ - ences in yield, these data are based on the percentage of commercial scab-free potatoes of U. S. Grade No. 1 size. The results were obtained by sorting the potatoes into the three standard grade sizes and again into the various scab classes given on page 11. It would not be feasible to pre - sent this mass of detailed data in tabular form. An exam - ination of the data showed .that the method used in com - piling the following tables is quite representative of the </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Potato Treatments for Scab and Rhizoctonia records. In order to illustrate this fact, the detailed data for the 1928 plot at Lincoln are presented in Fig. 1 as a typical example. The order of the treatments is based upon the percentage of Class 0 and 1 combined, as in Tables 3, 4, and 5. It can be seen from this figure that the relative effectiveness of the various treatments is much the same when based upon the combination of Classes 0 and 1 as when Class 0 is considered alone. There would be minor changes in the order of the .treatments but it is clearly evident that with both methods the same treat - ments, 1 to 5, are the only ones showing satisfactory control and that the only treatment of scabby seed which falls in this group is the hot formaldehyde treatment No. 2. As previously noted, it was considered that the greatest error in making scab readings occurred with Class 0, due to the difficulty of detecting very small scab spots, and for this reason the combination' of both classes is considered to be more accurate. While there are some differences in the order if No. 2 size potatoes are considered, it is not great enough to alter the general results obtained if the total yield is con - sidered. There is also very little difference in the percent - age of No. 1 size potatoes produced with the various treat - ments. The only great difference in total yield occurred with Bayer Dip Dust No. 8 and in this case the decrease was due to seed-piece injury as previously noted. From the commercial standpoint we are chiefly interested in the weight of No. 1 size scab-free potatoes produced, rather than the total weight or number of potatoes or the percentage of scab-free tubers of No. 2 size. For these various reasons, the authors feel that the method of pre - sentation in Tables 3, 4, and 5 gives an accurate picture of the results. A glance at Tables 3, 4, and 5 will show that most of the feed treatments failed to control scab effectively in all the tests. While some of the treatments apparently controlled r.cab to an appreciable extent in certain tests, the only con - sistent control in all three plots for the three years was obtained with the hot formaldehyde treatment. The amount of infection coming from the soil as evidenced by the amount of scab occurring with both untreated and treated healthy seed was especially great in the Alliance plot and as a result the effect of the hot formaldehyde treatment was not so evident, particularly in 1926 and 1928. (Table 5.) The results with mercuric chloride explain why the grow - ers of Nebraska had discontinued the use of this treatment. </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022"/>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 It was effective in only one out of the three years at Lin - coln and North Platte and the increase of healthy tubers resulting from the treatment at Alliance in 1927 and 1929 was not enough to be considered very significant. The acidulated mercuric chloride tested in 1928 at Alliance also failed to control scab. Likewise the various organic mercury compounds were lacking in effectiveness in the majority of the tests, and even in the few tests where they gave some signs of con - trol the ratios were very slightly more than three times the probable error. In 1926 none of the organic mercury com - pounds tested gave any evidence of control. In 1927, Bayer 181 at Lincoln and Alliance and Semesan Bel Dip at North Platte gave a ratio of more than three times the probable error, but these ratios were only about one-half of those obtained with the hot formaldehyde treatment in the same plot. | In 1928 the results were significant only in the case of Du Pont 76 B at Lincoln and none of these treatments was effective at North Platte. The results at Alliance in 1928 are pf doubtful value with all treatments because of the amount of infection from the soil. Sulfur failed to have any effect on scab in 1926, but in 1927 some control was evident in the Lincoln and North Platte plots. It failed to have any appreciable effect in either year at Alliance. . . One interesting fact was the result obtained by using slightly scabby seed. Such seed, having only about three scab lesions per tuber, produced consistently more healthy potatoes than any of the treated scabby seed lots, except those treated with hot formaldehyde. It is probable that this seed did not cause enough infection to be evident in comparison with that coming from the soil. In other words, this seed gave about the same results, as the healthy un - treated lots, two of the tests having higher ratios than the healthy and three lower ratios. The mercuric chloride treatment of such seed did not produce measurable differ - ences. The healthy seed treated with hot formaldehyde pro - duced a larger proportion of scab-free potatoes than the untreated healthy lots in four out of the six tests made, altho the difference was very slight in two of these cases. The greatest difference occurred at Alliance, where Bliss Triumph potatoes were used. These potatoes were from a lot of severely scabbed seed, and it was very difficult to select a sufficient amount of healthy seed. The color of this variety and the conditions under which they were selected very probably resulted in the presence of a cer- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Potato Treatments for Scab and Rhizoctonia tain amount of scab on the supposedly healthy seed, which would account for the increase in the percentage of scab - free tubers produced when such seed was treated with hot formaldehyde. In the Lincoln and North Platte tests, potatoes of the Irish Cobbler variety were selected in the laboratory. It was much easier to detect and discard pota - toes with small scab spots on this white variety and as a result the treatment of this seed did not result in an in - crease in the percentage of healthy potatoes. In general, the healthy, untreated seed produced a larger percentage of scab-free seed than the scabby seed treated with any of the treatments except hot formaldehyde. We can conclude from the above data that: (1) the hot formaldehyde treatment resulted in the greatest and most consistent increase in the number of scab-free potatoes pro - duced in comparison with the other treatments and the untreated checks; (2) scabby potatoes treated with hot formaldehyde were equal or superior to apparently healthy seed untreated; (3) the treatment of apparently healthy potatoes of the Bliss Triumph variety resulted in an in - crease in the percentage of scab-free potatoes; (4) none of the mercury treatments consistently decreased the amount of scab; and (5) with heavily infested soils and favorable conditions for scab, such as occurred in 1928 at Alliance, none of the treatments was beneficial. RHIZOCTONIA EXPERIMENTS AT LINCOLN Emergence and stand. — The rate of emergence and the final stands are presented in Table 6. In 1926 the most rapid emergence occurred with the healthy, untreated lot. The slowest emergence followed the hot formaldehyde treatment. All of the treatments either reduced the rate of emergence or failed to control completely the disease which, judging by the Rhizoctonia untreated check No. 16, materially reduced the rate of emergence. The final stands did not show any great variation;: the hot formaldehyde and Semesan Bel treatments were the same as the untreated Rhizoctonia checks. In 1927 there was no appreciable effect upon the rate of emergence except in the case of hot formaldehyde, Nos. 2 and 4, which retarded emergence. These two lots event - ually caught up with the others and produced a good stand. The untreated Rhizoctonia lot emerged slowly and also produced the poorest stand. The stand resulting from the Bayer Dip Dust treatment No. 13 also showed consider - able injury. In 1928 the hot formaldehyde treatment did not cause any injury and its effectiveness was quite evident in re- </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 lion differed greatly so that certain consistent differences can be noted when the amount and severity of infection are considered together as in Table 7. The healthy seed, both untreated and treated with hot formaldehyde, and the Rhizqctonia seed treated with hot formaldehyde, mercuric chloride, or Du Pont 76 B, were consistently the healthiest, the mercuric chloride treatment being the poorest of these five lots. At the time of the third digging, June 28, the amount of soil infection was so great that the differences between the different treatments were not so evident. The other three organic mercury treatments, Semesan Bel, Bayer Dip Dust, and Bayer 190 were infected about the same as the untreated Rhizoctonia check. Sclerotia on tubers. — Under average conditions, the chief injury caused by Rhizoctonia in the eastern section of Nebraska, as represented by the Lincoln plot, is due to the effect upon stand and yield caused by infection of the underground stem. The production of sclerotia on the new tubers is usually not important, but this type of infection is often used to gauge the effect of seed treatments. A record was therefore made of the severity of infection on the tubers in 1926 and the results are presented in Table 8. All the tubers were washed at digging time and graded as of slight, medium, or severe infection, depending upon the number and size of sclerotia. Practically all sclerotia Table 8. — The effect of seed treatments as judged by the formation of sclerotia on the tubers in 1926 at Lincoln Percentage of total yield Average yield per hill Healthy Slight Medium Severe Treatment infection infection infection I Gram* Percent Percent Percent Percent HEALTHY SEED (1) Untreated I 193 I 66.5 I 29 1 I 41 I S (3) Mercuric Chloride 1:1000 | 210 | 78^2 | 2o!6 | 1J 1 '.0 KHIZOCTONIA SEED \t\ S ot ForcnaMehyde 1:120 ..... 160 61.5 30.1 8.3 . 0 ' (B) Mercuric Chloride 1:1000 181 ! 64.6 31.8 3.8 .0 (6) Mercuric Chloride 1:1000, presprinkled 1. 208 69 7 29 4 q n (7) Du Pont 12 Bel Du.t, 9 ° (Bj.DuSnf^feb^ "' 31A IM o) siS'SfW I85 4M 291 20 - 8 »•♦ 2 ox. per Im.............................. 202 37 l v\ i oa a * n !m SSSEd 1 " Dip l!l °" — ••"• 4! *"» «•* »3 " (16) Untreated _ 155 1 6-1 BS6 20l sl ' Seed tubers cut before treating. All other treatments were made on uncut tubers. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Potato Treatments for Scab and Rhizoctonia were of the small type, averaging about Yq of an inch in size. Severe infection refers to tubers having such sclerotia abundantly scattered over the entire surface of the tuber. It is evident from treatment Nos. 1- and 3 wih healthy seed that there was considerable infection originating in the soil. Nevertheless, there is a marked difference be - tween the small percentage of healthy tubers produced by the untreated Rhizoctonia check No. 16 and all of the treated lots. The mercuric chloride with a presprinkle pro - duced the largest percentage of healthy tubers of any of the treatments with infected seed. The mercuric chloride without presprinkle and the hot formaldehyde treatments were also very satisfactory. The organic mercury com - pounds were better than the untreated checks but were far below the mercuric chloride and hot formaldehyde in effectiveness. This is even more noticeable if the severity of infection is considered, as shown in the last two columns of Table 8. The hot formaldehyde produced the lowest yield due to retarded emergence, as previously mentioned in connection with Table 6. The percentage of healthy tubers was so high, however, that the actual weight of healthy potatoes produced was greater than with the un - injured, higher-yielding, organic mercury compounds with their low percentages of healthy tubers. On the basis of the formation of sclerotia on the new tubers, mercuric chloride was the best treatment and hot formaldehyde was a close second. Effect upon yield.— From the standpoint of practical results, the effect of Rhizoctonia and the various treat - ments tested to control it can best be judged by the yield of potatoes. For this reason the yield was made the chief consideration in these tests. The data previously discussed ana presented in Tables 6, 7, and 8 are then important only Jls a means of explaining the effects upon the yield. The data on yield are presented for the three years in Table 9. The actual yield for the untreated Rhizoctonia check, No. 16, and also the increase or decrease following the various treatments, based upon' the untreated Rhizoc - tonia check with the probable error and the ratio, are given. In 1926 all the treatments showed an increase in yield. While the increase with the hot formaldehyde was the smallest, it was the most uniform in all the replications of any of the treatments with Rhizoctonia seed. This small increase was probably due to retarded emergence, as noted in Table 6. The final stand was uninjured, but the late emer - gence, combined with a period of very hot, dry weather which killed all the plants several weeks before maturity, as indi- </seg>
            <seg id="p030"/>
            <seg id="p031">Potato Treatments for Scab and Rhizoctonia cated by the low yield of the checks^ resulted in a very small but uniform increase for the hot formaldehyde treatment. In 1927 all of the treatments again resulted in increased yields. The hot formaldehyde treatment again retarded emergence as shown in Table 6, but, apparently because of more favorable weather conditions later in the season as compared with 1926, the plants were enabled to over - come the delayed emergence and the yield was materially increased. The low yield with Bayer Dip Dust was prob - ably due to the seed-piece injury previously noted, which reduced the final stand (Table 6). The results obtained in 1928 are more difficult to inter - pret. The effect of the various treatments was much less than in the two previous years. The hot formaldehyde for the first time did not retard emergence as shown in Table 6 and, judging by the amount of stem infection (Table 7), it controlled the disease better than any other treatment; and yet the yield (Table 9) was slightly less than the check. Mercuric chloride, which did not reduce the amount of stem infection as much as did hot formaldehyde, resulted in the highest yield. Bayer 190, which gave the next high - est yield, showed very poor control as judged by the amount of stem infection. The lack of any increase in the yield of the untreated lots of healthy over the untreated Rhiz - octonia seed is evidence that the disease as carried by the seed was not much of a factor in determining the yield. It was undoubtedly a factor in the: number of stem lesions found at the time of the first two samplings (Table 7) but, as shown in the same table, the amount of infection from the soil was so great by the time of the last sampling that there was very little difference in the treatments. This large amount of infection front the soil, which may have resulted in injury to the stolons, combined with hot, dry weather during the later part of the growing season, prob - ably was the cause of the inconclusive results in 1928, as based upon yields, presented in Table 9. Considering all the data presented in Tables 6, 7, 8, and 9, the following conclusions can be drawn. The hot for - maldehyde and the mercuric chloride treatments were quite effective in controlling the disease, altho the hot for - maldehyde retarded emergence in two of the three years. Even with this retarded emergence, the yield was materially increased over the untreated Rhizoctonia seed. The organic mercury compounds reduced the amount of infection on stems and tubers and increased the yield, but not so much as the mercuric chloride treatment. The presprinkle method did not show any advantage. The disease was </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 found to decrease the stand materially in only one of the three years. The amount of stem infection, however, re - sulted in reduced yields. When infection from the soil was severe, as in 1928, it was sufficient to obscure the effects of seed treatment. . ■ RELATION OF SEED TREATMENTS TO SEED-PIECE DECAY AND PLANT VIGOR The question of seed-piece preservation and stimulation of growth was not considered as part of the original pro - ject, but in view of various reports which have been made, indicating that certain seed treatments stimulated growth and increased yields, a few additional tests were included. Quite often reports of experiments conducted for scab con - trol are presented on the basis of yields, even tho there is practically no evidence indicating that the scab disease has any appreciable depressing effect upon yields. The experi - ments on scab reported in this paper have failed to dis - close any consistent tendency for the scab disease to de - crease yields or for any of the seed treatments to increase yields (Table 2). In the Rhizoctonia tests the effect of the disease upon yield is quite evident and the possible effect of seed treatments in stimulating growth cannot be separ - ated from the effects caused by disease control in such, ex - periments. Tests of the effect of seed treatments on growth stimulation with cereal crops at this station, as reported by Kiesselbach (7), have been entirely negative. It was thought possible, however, in the light of Denny's (3) work on seed-piece preservation and decay that certain seed treatments might have a favorable .effect upon the growth of the potato. In 1928 an additional test was inserted in all three plots used for the scab tests. In addition to the healthy un - treated check and the healthy lot treated with hot for - maldehyde, two additional lots of healthy seed were planted. One of these was treated with Semesan Bel and the other with hot formaldehyde first and then Semesan Bel. It was thought that with these four lots of healthy seed it would be possible to obtain any evidence of in - creased yield due to the organic mercury treatment ex - clusive of disease control. The results are included in the data presented in Table 2 on yield, and in Tables 3, 4, and 5 on scab control. In the Lincoln test the healthy seed treated with Semesan Bel was the highest-yielding lot in the experiment. The Semesan Bel, used after hot formaldehyde, produced slightly less than the hot formaldehyde alone, both being higher than the healthy, untreated check. In the North </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Potato Treatments for Scab and Rhizoctonia Platte tests the reverse was true; all three lots of treated healthy seed produced about the same and all of them less than the untreated check. The results at Alliance were similar to those at Lincoln with even a greater increased yield for the healthy seed treated with Semesan Bel. Again the double treatment with hot formaldehyde and Semesan Bel was slightly less than that of the hot formaldehyde alone. It is also noticeable in Table 2 that in the Alliance plots two organic mercury scabby-seed treatments, Semes- Bel and Bayer 190, gave' the largest increases in yield in 1928. They failed to show any significant increase in the Lincoln and North Platte plots, however. In addition to the data mentioned above, some informa - tion was obtained in the 1928 test at Alliance on seed-piece decay and plant vigor. On July- 26, two 25-hill replica - tions of each treatment were dug. The condition of the seed pieces was noted and the green weight of the tops determined. These data are presented in Table 10 along with the stand percentages and the actual yield of the other six replications for each treatment upon which are based the ratios presented in Table 2. The greatest amount of seed-piece rot occurred with the scabby seed untreated. This may not be very significant, however, as all but two treatments resulted in the complete rotting of 70 per cent or more of the seed pieces. Scabby seed treated with mercuric chloride and scabby seed with Du Pont 76 B showed the least amount of rot. Scabby seed treated with Semesan Bel also resulted in a large per - centage of sound seed pieces. There was no close correlation between the amount of seed-piece rotting and the vigor of the plants as indicated by the green weight of the tops. Neither was there any correlation between either seed-piece rot or vigor and the total yield of the other replications with similar treatments. When the green weight of the tops was calculated per plant according to the condition of the seed piece, there was very little uniformity in the results. If anything, the vine growth seemed to be greater when the greatest amount of rotting occurred, but this was not consistent. The results presented do not show any correlation be - tween seed-piece rot and vigor of the vines or yield. Neither did the organic mercury ; compounds as' a whole appear to prevent decay of the seed pieces. DISCUSSION OF RESULTS Consideration of seed and soil infection. — The disinfec - tion of seed potatoes to prevent scab and Rhizoctonia is a long-established practice. Many investigators have re - </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Potato Treatments for Scab and Rhizoctonia ported beneficial results from various treatments and have recommended their use. Recently, however, Clayton (2) has questioned the advisability of using seed-potato treat - ments under conditions where relatively scab-free seed can be used and where the soil is heavily infested. He con - cludes from his experiments conducted on Long Island that "Regardless of the amount of scab infection on the tubers, if these were planted in the normally acid soils used for potato growing on Long Island, the crop was prac - tically clean, while if planted on land that had been limed, the crop was heavily scabbed, the main source of infection being the soil. The treatment of the seed reduced the per - centage of infection, but hardly enough to justify the bother." Likewise, Vaughn (14) states regarding tests in Wis - consin that "The limited tests with organic mercury at the Spooner farm showed no value over the untreated seed in Triumph variety where a slight scab infection was pres - ent in the soil." While it may be interesting and worth while to deter - mine that various seed treatments do control, at least par - tially, the scab borne on the seed, the point made by Clay - ton is well taken, that if such treatments do not return an adequate profit it is useless to employ them. It is certainly essential to determine the efficacy of the treatment as a practical control measure, and in deciding this the amount of soil infection becomes of prime importance. The conditions of the experiments reported in this bul - letin varied considerably as to soil infection. With high pH values and with the predominant soil type in the large com - mercial area being a fine sandy loam, as represented by the Alliance plot, it is apparent that conditions are favor - able for scab and that the amount of scab will vary accord - ing to climatic conditions and the amount of infestation in the soil. While these areas have not been cropped to potatoes for many years, this factor is apparently not im - portant under Nebraska conditions, as the writers have often observed practically 100 per cent infection from the soil on land never before cropped to potatoes. With this amount of infection occurring from the soil, it becomes difficult for the growers in some sections to obtain scab-free seed potatoes, especially in view of the fact that the most severe soil infection occurs in some of the areas considered most satisfactory for seed production. As a general practice, we may assume that with a large amount of scab produced in any one year we will have a proportionately large amount of scabby seed planted the </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 next year. This is particularly true when good-quality cer - tified seed has to be culled out solely on account of scab. The effective treatment of such scabby seed becomes of great financial interest to the grower. In eastern and cen - tral Nebraska the seed potatoes are usually imported from the North and usually carry a heavy infection of Rhizoctonia. It can therefore be seen that even tho the soil is heavily infested, as has been shown in the tables, the probability that the seed is infected makes a profitable return from seed treatment a greater likelihood than in sections where scab-free potatoes are always available. It is true that under conditions of heavy soil infection, as have occurred at Alliance, especially in 1928, the value of the treatment is greatly reduced. Nevertheless, the consistent increase in the percentage of healthy potatoes resulting from seed treatment shows that even with this smaller margin it may still be profitable to treat such scabby seed. It must also be remembered that in a number of other sec - tions of western Nebraska the amount of soil infection is not so great as is indicated in the results from this plot, which in all three years happened to be on heavily infested soil. Effect of seed treatments on scab. — Of the different treatments used, the results show that the most consistent control was obtained by the hot formaldehyde treatment. The mercury compounds, including mercuric chloride, failed to decrease the amount of scab appreciably in most of the tests. These results are quite the opposite of those published by various workers. For example, Martin (8) in New Jersey has reported consistent results over a period of years showing the effectiveness of the organic mercury compounds in controlling scab and he recommends their use as a practical control measure. He found that the or - ganic mercury compounds were more effective than the standard mercuric chloride treatment, while in the tests re - ported herein they were about equally ineffective. It is difficult to arrive at any theory that will satisfactorily ex - plain the differences in these results. The experiments reported here were planned and carried out in much the same way as were those reported by Martin. The differ - ences in soil infestation can hardly account for the results when checks and treated lots are systematically replicated as they were in these experiments. The materials used for the treatments were similar except for the water used in making the solutions. While the water used in these experiments, particularly at Alliance, was strongly alka - line, tests failed to reveal any precipitation of mercury in </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Potato Treatments for Scab and Rhizoctonu the mercuric chloride solutions. If the hot formaldehyde treatment had been included in the experiments reported from New Jersey, it is possible that a better comparison of the results obtained with the mercury treatments could have been made with the results here presented. The only conclusion to be drawn at the present time is that, as the authors have previously stated (5), "The necessity for determining locally the relative efficacy of various treat - ments is clearly apparent, and a treatment which has been iound to be effective in one section of the country is not necessarily going to yield similar results in other sections." Certainly more detailed experimental work is necessary before the factors causing these marked differences in results can be determined. Another surprising result obtained in these investigations was the lack of control obtained with the mercuric chloride treatment. This treatment has been reported by many work - ers as satisfactory in controlling scab and for years was considered the standard treatment. For scab control it has been displaced in most sections by the hot formaldehyde or organic mercury treatments, not because of any great difference in control but rather because of the disadvantages of the slow, time-consuming nature of the treatment. The re - sults reported in this bulletin are in general accord with the results obtained by potato growers, who have largely abandoned this method. Contrary to the statement previously made by the authors (4) which was based upon the 1927 results, it now appears from a summary of the three years' work that the only significant difference between the treated and untreated healthy seed occurred at Alliance! with the Bliss Triumph variety. The difficulty of detecting small scab spots on this as contrasted with the Cobbler variety used in the other tests probably accounts for the difference. It must be re - membered, however, that the healthy seed selected for these experiments would be much better than seed ordin - arily considered healthy on the farm. A large percentage of the seed used in commercial plantings is infected with scab, the amount varying in the different sections, so that the treatment of such apparently healthy seed on the farm particularly of the Bliss Triumph variety, would probably result in a decrease in, the amount of scab that would more than repay the cost of the treatment. Effect of seed treatments on Rhizoctonia. — Considerable conflicting data regarding the control of Rhizoctonia have been presented by various workers. White (15), in sum - marizing experiments reported from various states and </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 Canada in 1926, concludes that "In general, although by no means consistently so, the Semesan Bel compounds used as a 10 per cent dip have given satisfactory control of stem lesions, have resulted in at least 20 per cent increases in yield and have yielded a crop as free of sclerotia as the standard corrosive sublimate treatment." Raeder, Hungerford, and Chapman (12) reported that the organic mercury compound, Du Pont Dust No. 15, gave better control than any other treatment tested. Further tests by Raeder and Hungerford (13) showed that the results with this and other organic mercurials were not con - sistent. Hungerford (6), in discussing the results of these seed-treatment experiments in Idaho, states that "the hot formaldehyde method of treatment has been recommended because it has given year after year the best control of both Rhizoctonia and scab." Clayton (2) states that "the organic mercurials con - trolled seed-borne scab infection about as well as mercuric chloride but were less effective against black scurf." Miles (10), summarizing experiments conducted in Washington, states that in no instance was there any effective control of Rhizoctonia as measured by sclerotia on the tubers at harvest with either Semesan Bel or Bayer Dip Dust, while mercuric chloride gave some measure of control in every test except where heavy soil infection occurred. Moore and Wheeler (11), from tests conducted in Michigan, also conclude that mercuric chloride is more effective in the control of Rhizoctonia than the organic mercurials. In reviewing these and other papers, it is clearly evident that the tendency of the recent work is to consider the or - ganic mercury compounds as less effective against Rhizoc - tonia than against scab. The results presented in this paper, however, are direc - tly opposed to this view, as the organic mercury com - pounds and the mercuric chloride treatment were more effective against Rhizoctonia than against scab. Increased yields were consistently obtained with all the mercury treatments. A decreased number of infected tubers was produced, altho here the results were better with hot for - maldehyde and mercuric chloride than with the organic mercurials. On the basis of stem lesions, the hot formal - dehyde was the best treatment. In the final analysis, the practical usefulness of these treatments in the early table - stock potato-producing area of Nebraska must depend up - on increased yields. On this basis the mercuric chloride treatment gave the most consistently satisfactory results. Hot formaldehyde, while controlling the disease more </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Potato Treatments for Scab and Rhizoctonia effectively than any other treatment, retarded emergence in two of the three years and when this was combined with unfavorable weather, as in 1926, the beneficial results obtained by disease control were somewhat reduced. Gen - eral practice has proved that the hot formaldehyde method, carefully used, results in increased yields thruout east - ern Nebraska, due to the control of Rhizoctonia. The re - tarding of emergence due to hot formaldehyde treatment ' can be eliminated by treating the potatoes several weeks or months ahead of planting time or before the sprouts have developed. When proper precautions are taken to allow the potatoes to dry off properly after treating, there should be no undesirable results. The variation in the results obtained by different work - ers may be due not only to different criteria of control depending upon whether the potatoes are being produced ior seed or table stock use, but also to the type of sclerotia present on the seed tubers.. This latter fact is probablv responsible for the difference between these results for the prespnnkle method of treatment and those reported by Iiaeder, Hungerford, and Chapman (12). In these experi - ments the sclerotia were small and presprinkling was evi - dently not necessary. The 1928 results also showed conclusively that when a heavy infection from the soil occurs, the beneficial effect of the treatment is reduced to a minimum or may not be at all evident. As the seed planted in eastern Nebraska is rather generally infected with Rhizoctonia, the use of a seed treat - ment in most years returns a very satisfactory profit. Effect of seed treatments on yields. — In regard to in - creased yields obtained by the use of the organic mercury treatments other than thru the control of Rhizoctonia the evidence presented is largely negative. Certain workers have reported increases due to organic mercury treatments that are not correlated with disease. Most of these claims have been made by workers in Europe. In the United States very few experiments on this point have been made Clayton (2) states that in his experiments, "The organic mercury treated seed has outyielded the mercuric chloride treated and the untreated seed. These differences have not been attributable to disease control, since, in this respect, the mercuric chloride was superior." Brann and 1 Since the preparation of this manuscript, a recent publication (Wkii. » v Potato Experiments for the Control of Rhizoctonia. Scab and 1 BlVckTeg 1922 to lali' Kans. Agr Expt. Sta. Tech. Bui. 24. 37 pages. 1928) has been received White notes similar injury caused by hot formaldehyde and refers to It Vk "lnHi.,.S dormancy" resulting in delayed emergence. To overcome thi The "recommend? fall -or early spnn B treating at least one month before planting recommends fall </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Expt. Sta. Research Bulletin 44 Vaughn (1), in a report from Wisconsin in which the de - tailed experiments are not recorded, state that the organic mercury compounds resulted in slightly higher yields. They recommend that when scab or Rhizoctonia are prevalent the mercuric chloride method should be used, and when these diseases are not serious the organic mercury treat - ments will give beneficial results. In the experiments reported in this bulletin there was little evidence that scab had any effect upon yield. Differ - ences in yield due to the treatments rather than disease control might therefore be expected to show definite re - sults. The data presented in Table 2, however, do not show any significant and consistent increase in yields from the organic mercury treatments. The only outstanding in - crease obtained from, these treatments was in 1928 at Alliance, and this was the only time the plants of these treatments were perceptibly greater in size than those of the other treatments. The results for the nine tests cer - tainly do not indicate that the use of these treatments for the purpose of increasing yields would be profitable. The results obtained in 1928 also failed to show any correlation between these treatments and seed-piece decay as reported by Clayton (2). Neither was there any correlation be - tween seed-piece decay and vigor of the vines as judged either by green weight of the tops or total yield. General considerations. — Seed treatments to control scab and Rhizoctonia are generally recommended for Nebraska because of the prevalence of these diseases on the avail - able seed tubers. Where soils are heavily infested, the beneficial effects of the treatment will be greatly reduced. Inasmuch as it is almost impossible to obtain potatoes entirely free from both diseases, and as the cost of such treatment is comparatively small, the use of a seed treat - ment is to be recommended for all seed potatoes. An in - crease of only one or two bushels of healthy potatoes per acre will repay the cost of the treatment. While mercuric chloride gave satisfactory control of Rhizoctonia as judged by increased yields, the lack of effec - tiveness of this treatment in controlling scab places it sec - ond to hot formaldehyde as a general seed potato treatment for all sections of Nebraska. It could be used to great advantage in the eastern part of the state where Rhizoc - tonia is the more severe disease than in the western portion where scab is more prevalent. Hot formaldehyde is recommended for general use be - cause of its greater effectiveness in controlling both dis - eases. The treatment should be made a month before </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Potato Treatments for "Scab and Rhizoctonia planting, if possible, to overcome the retarded emergnce sometimes caused by the treatment. This treatment is the only one tested that conrolled scab satisfactorily. The organic mercury treatments have failed to control scab and while these treatments have increased yields thru the control of Rhizoctonia, they were not so effective as mercuric chloride and hot formaldehyde. They have also failed to show increased yields due to stimulation or seed-piece preservation. They also had the added dis - advantage of causing seed-piece injury if the seed was not handled carefully. If cut seed is treated, it must be allowed to heal over before treatment and to dry off rapidly after treatment. If treated whole, injury may occur after cutting if the cut surfaces come in contact with the treated surfaces and are held under moist conditions for any length of time. It is possible to use these treatments without injury if proper care is taken regarding these points. Some of the organic mercury treatments were used as a dust and gthers as a dip. There was little difference in the results as regards the control of the diseases studied. The dust method is rather cumbersome unless special equip - ment is available and does not seem to have any advantage over the dip method. The danger of seed-piece injury is even greater with the dust treatment of cut seed unless the cut surface has healed over, so as to be completely dry. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Expt, Sta. Research Bulletin 44 literature cited 1. Brann, J. W., and Vaughn, R. E. 1929. Organic Mercury Disinfectants Tested in Potato Disease Control. Wis. Agr. Expt. Sta. Bui. 405, p. 78. 2. Clayton, E. E. 1929. Potato Seed Treatment Experiments on Long Island With Special Reference to the Organic Mercury Instant Dips. N. Y. Agr. Expt. Sta. Bui. 564, 32 pages. 3. Denny, F. E. 1929. Role of Mother Tuber in Growth of Potato Plant. Bot. Gaz. 87: 157-194. 4. Goss, R. W., and Werner, H. O. 1927. Seed Potato Treatments for Scab Control. Potato Assoc. Amer. Proc, 14th Meeting, 109-116. 5. Goss, R. W., and Werner, H. O. 1928. Seed Potato Treatments for the Control of Scab. Amer. Potato Jour. 5: 3—6. 6. Hungerford, C. W. 1928. Seed Potato Disinfection in Idaho. Amer. Potato Jour. 5: 98-99. 7. Kiesselbach, T. A. 1927. Field Experiments With Seed Corn Treatments and Crop Stimulants. Nebr. Agr. Expt. Sta. Bui. 218, 15 pages. 8. Martin, Wm. H. 1927. The Value of Organic Mercury Compounds in the Control of Seed and Soil Borne Scab. Potato Assoc. Amer. Proc, 14th Meeting, 102-108. 9. Melhus, I. E., and Gilman, J. C. 1919. An Improved Method of Potato Seed Treatment. low* Agr. Expt. Sta. Cir. 57, 8 pages. 10. Miles, L. E. 1929. The Efficiency of Organic Mercury Compounds in Potato Seed Treatments. Amer. Potato Jour. 6: 9-15. 11. Moore, H. C, and Wheeler, E. J. 1928. Seed Treatment Experiment in Michigan. Amer. Potato Jour. 5: 100-103. 12. Raeder, J. M., Hungerford, C. W., and Chapman, Naomi. 1925. Seed Treatment Control of Rhizoctonia in Idaho. Idaho Agr. Expt. Sta. Res. Bui. 4, 37 pages. 13. Raeder, J. M., and Hungerford, C. W. 1927. Seed Treatment Control of Rhizoctonia of Potatoes in Idaho. Phytopathology 17: 793-814. 14. Vaughn, R. E. 1928. Potato Seed Treatments in Wisconsin. Amer. Potato Jour. 5: 97. 15. White, R. P. 1926. The Efficiency of Organic Mercury Compounds for the Control of Rhizoctonia on Potato. Potato Assoc. of Amer. Proc, 13th Meeting, 81-96. [3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>