<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fall Lamb Feeding</title>
               <date value="1918-10">1918-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 1 70 October. 1918 Fall Lamb Feeding Clipping lambs for fall feeding. Light vs. heavy feed of corn. The use of the self-feeder. Fattening lambs on grass. Finishing lambs in the cornfield By H. J. GRAMLICH AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THK OOVBBNINU BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Honorable E. P. Bbown, President, Uavey. Honorable J. E. Miller, Vice President, Lincoln. Honorable Frank L. Haller, Omaha. Honorable Victor G. Lyford, Falls City. Honorable Philip L. Hall, Lincoln. Honorable Harry D. Landis, Seward. THE STATION OFFICBK8 'Samuel A very, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex officio. W. G. Hastings, A. B., Acting Chancellor. E. A. Burnett, D. Sc, Director. Chas. E. Gunnels, B. Sc, Director of Extension Service. J. S. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. C. A. Lewis, B. Sc, Bulletin Editor. THE nilKklM, STAFF F. W. UPSON, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. 'L. W. CHASE, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. "W. W. BURR, B. Sc, Agronomy. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Agronomy. H. J. Gramlich, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. GAIN, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. L. VanEs, M. D., V. S., Ani)iial Pathology ami Hygit H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Animal Pathology. J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology M. H. Swenk, A. M., Entomology. H. C. FlLLEY, A. M., Farm Management. R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture. G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. E. Mead WlLCOX, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology. F. E. MUSSEHL, B. Sc, Poultry. W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. James A. Holoen, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell. •L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte. 'J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry 'G. K. K. Link, Ph. D., Associate in Plant Pathology and Physiology. W. B. Nevens, M. S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. 'Granted leave of absence for military service. 'Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Depart - ment of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. 'Granted leave of absence. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Fall Lamb Feeding ■ &gt; SUMMARY I. The clipping of lambs for full feeding on corn ami alfalfa hay inn-cased the daily uain by .07ti |K)iiiul and decreased the cost of KM) pounds gain l&gt;y $1.1'). but the discrimination on the market against shorn lambs caused a reduction in price per KM' pounds of $1.40 and consequently less profit l&gt;y 2 cents per head than where unshorn. (Lots 1 &amp; 2. table 2.) II. The clipping of lambs fed on corn and oil meal in a self - feeder with prairie hay in addition increased the rate of daily gain by .O2."&gt; pound, increased the daily feed consumption slightly, decreased the eost of 100 pounds gain 12 cents and decreased the profit IS cents per head, due to the reduced price per pound in selling, -lodging by the above it would seem that the fall clipping of lambs is not justified unless the price of wool is sufficiently high to more than offset the discrimination which the shorn lambs en - counter when marketed. In both instances of shearing reported here a greater daily gain was secured and a slightly less cost per KM pounds gain. (Lota 4 &amp; 5, table 3.) III. As regards the limiting of the corn ration in fall feeding, it was found that lambs receiving a full feed of corn gained .093 pound more than those receiving a half feed of corn at a cost per 100 pounds of gain of practically the same, and at a profit per lamb of 'M cents greater, due to increased finish and conse - quently 40 cents per hundred better selling price. The con - sumption of alfalfa did not increase in direct proportion to the reduction in the consumption of corn in lot -i, as compared to lot 1. (Lots 1 &amp; 3, table 4.) IV. The use of the self-feeder containing corn and oil meal in comparison with a heavy feed of corn supplemented with al - falfa hay did not prove economical. It resulted in an increased gain, a greater consumption of corn and concentrate, but a much higher cost per 1&lt;X( pounds gain, the increase amounting to $2.0"&gt;. The profit was decreased H3 cents. In the case of the clipped lambs the self-feeder again proved uneconomical in comparison with a straight corn and alfalfa ration. In this instance the lainl&gt;s gained but slightly more, did so at a higher feed cost by 21 cents per hundred, and showed a profit of 79 cents per head less. The self-feeder proved its worth as a producer of quick trains and ex - cessive flesh, even tho it did not prove economical. (Lots 1 &amp; 4, table 5.) V. Rape did not prove to be a satisfactory ration for fatten ing lambs. (Lots 4 &amp; 6, table 6.) VI. Blue grass pasture supplemented with a limited amount of corn and oil meal at the close of the test gave a verv satisfae- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 170 tory gain, altho the gain was mostly growth and the lrnnbtt at the finish did not carry ticsli to permit them to Bell well. Blue grass produced by far the mimt economical gains of any ration used. (Lots 7 &amp; 1, table 7.) VII. The i-nnitii'ld feeding of lambs gave h large daily Kiiin. reduced the cost of gain in compariMon with tlie dry lot feeding nl corn and alfalfa by +l.&lt;i'» pur KK) pounds and increased the profit by 81 ewtti per head. These lambs carried the most flesh uT iniy lot in the experiment, mid Hold at the highest value per 100 p.tunds on the market. (Lots 1 &amp; 8, table 8.) VIII. Three lots of lambs fed green feed show in this tent rela - tively high daily guiiiH, and lit the Name time, with the exception of the rape fed lamlm, a very cheap gain and as a result u relatively higb net profit per hem I. The blue truss and cornfield hits show the two highest profits of any in the test. ( Lots (i. 7 &amp; 8. table 2.) </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Fall Lamb Feeding 5 ■£ ■± 3 m K *«aa ? &amp; « ; .i j «* •» s iMsniii 5! •? t- i M «• slJls! "M MH a« a s &amp;iass s a 1 rjHfwr • i 1 • 5 I i " rf 5 ? *n s « ««ca« t * k «- 5 a i 41 slit j«v ! sswag 35 2 •■ « ~ - —. ifdl »s* 1 111 fl aina* s 3 1 s 3 « 1 ii "I'i &lt;c S 5 3 1 i H f 1 lit 1 i ulii , | I m 1 j iIIjj J I I i I r It m 333' h i r» | s i . jfji jgfi « • » s r ■ * — = - a i« iiif !!J" sisi !5I!5"»J S IJ ] ! \ I t &lt; I! iiJi !,ui iiil ! I Mil. i </seg>
            <seg id="p006">S'fhrauku Exiwrimvut Station llnllrtin 170 6 A 67-DAY LAMB F11DIN0 EXPERIMENT AukuM 21 to October 27, INK) II J. liHAMI.UM INTKODl TTION During ri'i'i'iil yciii'N there Iimm lieeu n t « • l n 1 1 • i n • \ ■ In fatten miimuls in fields (luring the foil months. Thin prat'tipf luis been found tn III' i|l|ltr II pi'lletieiil HIM' mill 111*1 1 1 \ ' I'ei'ili'l's nlV Mow 1'i'Not'tinu In riii'tilti'lil f lint;, i'K|ii'i'inlly of liimlm. r'eediiiK in the eomtit'lil Iiiin tin' mlviiiitnui' iivcr dry lot foiling in tt'Otiomlllng in the labor of liiiNkinir earn mid in the feeding of the corn to tin- iini - iiinlx. UkrwW the fertilizer in Mciitti'i'i'il evenly over the 1 1 « - 1 « 1 mul nil iindci'ui'owth xiii'li us wcciIn mul other veitetHtion is pIomI) irimii'i-t'il I i,v tin' Ui in tiM. With the thought in uiiiul of iiMeet-tiiin nitf tin' reliitivi mutiny of cornflfhi ■ml ki'hhn feeilhiK vermw dry lot feeilliiK, the experiment illwUNHAd iii this bulletin win planned mill I'oinllli'teil ■ I ii i-iti ix the full of l!MHi, A M'l'ii'M of i'X|ii'l'iliii'iit-&gt; elleekintf till 1 Work eitullleteil ill |Iun test will lie em-rieil out over II |ierini| of yeilfH, OHJKCTM The priuniry iturpuM 1 of iln* ex|ieriment who to iiMeertiiin the reliitise ettleieney of ilry lot feeding iliirlntr the lull moutliN when I'liiniitireil with the fiiHeniiiK of Imnlm miller |uiNtui'e nnil eoriifielil eoliiiitioiiM, A neeiuiil olijei't xolltrllt ill enrryiiiK out this experi nient WM to HNi'i'i'tiiin the inlv iNiilillity of elippinit Iniulm prior to itarting them on feed in the full, A third olijeet whm to Hxeertnin the iiih IxMlilllty of liiniiinu the corn in n eorn mul nll'iill'ii rat ion. mid the fourth olijeet WM to Neeiire further ilntn reliitlve to the economy of the Nelf-feeder in eoiupHi'Uou to dry lot mid eoruMeM llletllilil« of feeilinif. I)KH( MII'TION (U I \MHs The Inuilm uxi'il in tins expci'linent were |iurehiiNed eiirly in the Miiiuiuer on the OiiihIiii miirket mid nllnweil to um/.c in one xrotlp upon the IoIn mul Ihiii'm of the eolleiie fiiriu. At the time pur elniNi'd I heir eoxt wmn $hx&lt;{\ per UN) poiindN mul their avtflff vu'llfht ,'iH |iiiiiiiiU lletweeu the time liMI'i'linxeil mul the open Ititf of the experiment they wet hiii'veif &gt; j eent per dn.v for p«i Hire. While the iietlllll eimt of thexe IhmiIih nl the time the&gt; were tinloiided lit the eolleire fiirm WM H*H,HII, the uniiis on kI'hnn iluriiu till' Inti'i'veuluK pnrlod I'l'dlieed till 1 eimt no Hint nt the opeuiuu of llie i'X|n rlmenl they Were eliMI'Hi'il nl $H,M, They were Wynmlnii Imiilio, iiiiikti.v of hltiekfnee exti'Metloii mid itnnled hn "irnod" on i lir fevder IhiiiIi murkvt, At the lime tlnit the experiment opened, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Fall l.nnih Frvilhiy 7 I AuiriiNt 21, tlic average weight &lt;&gt;r the lamlm wan h|&gt;|&gt;i oximtitrly li.'i pnumU, KATIONH IHKI) Tiif viiiioiiN IntM id' Ininlm were I ' I tin 1 following rittwiti Lnt I. Corn (liciivy feed), alfalfa. Lot II. Corn (heavy iVi'.l . ull'iili'n. i &lt; *1 i | &gt; | »••&lt; 1 ImmiIim, Lot III. Corn Iil'Ii'i feed), niralln Lot IV. lorn anil oil meal in tell' id ili'i', prairie buy. li"i V. Corn ami oil inoul in self-feeder, prairie hay. (Clipped liitnlm.) Lot VI. Rape pasture Brsi seven weeks) then corn and oil mcnl in self-feeder, prairie hay. Lot VII. Or mm pasture) porn anil oil meal Iiini three week*, Lot VIII. Cnniieldi alfalfa and &lt;&gt;il meal after l'i " DEATH loss of tlu&lt; U2o lieu I of lamlm started in thix experiment. H died during tho '7-day tt'wt , which \n u 21/u pel tit low, BoflM Ol thcNi' lamb* died from causes which were not tlitiirtioitiihlc*. It appeared pertain i hut the feed wu not the pause of death in any particular Instance, In other words we mitiht nay that the meth ■ id of handling the Iambi in any of these lota did not sflbet tin death Iomn nnd for the total group of lamlm the rate of death wan nliont an average with that incurred by moat f lera in fall feed inir. It will lie noted that in lot 2 there were II deatha ami in lut 1 there were 2. Hy com|Mring the Brti '&lt; lotN with the la»t II, which were fed on green feed and in the cornfield, we Itnd n relatively higher per centage of Iohn in the lamlm fctl in the dry lot. Mix nut of 2&lt;iil in the dry IntM died, or n M per pent Iohn, and 2 mil of the 12(1 in the la-i II loin, or a 1,7 per limn, VV.KU VAHDM AM) KIJIII'MKNT LotN 1 to 0 were I'ed in the experimental lamli yarda at the University Farm. These yawls each, contain IKX1 M|uare ftet ami HP there were hut ■&lt; IntM fed in the nIiimI We were alile to allnw hscIi lot two yards. In other words, the in lamba in eiieh yard ha«l I iiiiii wiuarr feet id' yard and ahed apace or '-'"i ai|iiare feet nvv lamb. The lot running in rape imaturi&lt; had ai as to about 1 V-j Horea of Dwarf Rwcx rape which wim in very gtiod shape at thi time they were tnrneil npnii It. The tract used for lut 7 on dim KI'iim contained some three acrca and the grass Was a inlxtun of blue grass with nohic lirome ami Nome white clover, The ei rn Held lot had a us tn iwn acres of resaonabty gnod nnrn, Theai lotN were clime to the IiiiIIiIIiiun and we were aide to keep the lnnil'« supplied with fresh water at all limes, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nrln-tmht h\n&gt;nimnil Slnllmi lltilhtiit ITU 8 KM I II Ml IIIMIIMIINK A* IttMM IhihIi* mi'I'k kImi'IimI mi AniinM 11 1 lliej WfN mi IV'" I illH'lHH DtllllM I'MlllIM 1 Wlll'lll W I'M) III".', l'»pl&lt;l'lllll,V III I III' III -I llrtlf "I NtiplMllllll'l Till' lilllll"" III Illi' ill) lulu »l'l'lllill III lllllll'K |||&gt; 1 1 •' M I nilli'li iiihI'i' limn lliii'i' III Iliii I'lii'iilli'ld Mini lliimii mi luixlni'i' UmlllH III" IhIIi'I' plll'l Of I III' Mill Mil' Wl'llllll'l' Wll» llll'lll, Ill'llIU MIIIIIIIMI'MIIh'I) ill) Illlll I'lllll, Ml Hull Illl I III' Illlllll* •I'l'IIH'll III pilMI'M u i ii|i|ii'l!li'« Mini illil "I'll l'll|l|ll'l» tlllll +I |P fill' Illl' HIM"' prli'i' Mii'iilitf Irnui ♦ll.i'ill fin Illi IimiiIi. In ♦! I fin 1 IIiiidii Ciilli'iii'il In tin i ulii'l'l I'HHKN UK KKKIIM Till' |il'|i'i'* n»i'il fill' I'i'iiU III lhl« li'M Mi'l'c Illimi' |ni'\ mlliiu nil llii&lt; nuii'lti'i iliniuM Ilii' iiiiijiii 1 f i*i ri Hi ill" i'H|inrliiii'iil, Tin' ih'W •'iil'll III Illi' III III Him \n lui'il ill III I'i'iiU I'l'l' Initlii'l IwM Hutu Illi' nlil MM* Ceil In Ilii' Imiilii In Ilii' ilr&gt; lulu, Tin' ih'm ''urn «n» "l 1 wry W""il ■ 1 1 1 M 1 1 1 &gt; , Illll H« IM'MI'ly II* W9 I'Hlllil I'Mllllllll', HI I'i'iiU I'l'l' IiiihIii'I «Im mm |iii iliHliii'ii'il in iilluw fur ilii' iHiM ill liuxl-iim mill llii* nil rl nh ii hi' iliH 1 In i'iiiuMi'I'iiIiIm wiiliic Mill i'uiiImIim'iI in It nl tin* I Iiiii' tile Imnlik I'ulKiiiiiii'il II Tin' iliiii'iii' iiuiili' fur |imMiii'i', Imlli UIH»« Mllll I'MIII', M'MN 'y I'IMll |l'l' I I ■ iImII), TIlU llllll«l'» M M'l&gt; fllll' llU'lHIH' I'nilll |ill«IIIIV lilllll IK Illl Ml'l'l' llf Ifl'MM Will I'MI'I'y III I It III I im llli'i'ly, til 1 w iiiilil I'i'llll'li n I'i'Mla i •■• i* 1 1 m&gt; OVM ii |ni Inil hI liVl ilii,v« III U w hiiIiI miiniiiil In ifT.^II fur Ilic iiii*I ill 1 )'. Ax m unit I i&gt;r • if flll'l, llll'«l' ImIuIiM WI'I'C pMMlll'I'll IlI'MVllT lilllll III lll'llll |"'l' Ml'l'l', mill II «m» Illi' ImIIi'C I'iiiI of Ilii' |iiiMiiri&lt; RMMOII, Mllcr i'iiIIIc IihiI imi'il llic tfi'MKD iliirlnif Hit' pi'liui' pin 1 ) uf Hie MMOtii The prli'im iim'il fur fi'i'iU mi**' llMi'il im fiilluwN lllil I'ui'ii Vl'» I'lll'll III Illl' Drill nil ini'iii Trii' pi' i' lumlii'l lli"&gt;c pi'l' lillMii'l I'i'i 1 Inn A I fulfil Iim&gt; I 'I'M It'll' Illl* ♦"Illl pi'l' Illll *i l|p l pi'l 1 lull UfMM puMili'i' llnpi' piiMlll'i' I yr pi'l' Illlllll illlll) l{i' pi'l' ImiiiIi iliilly M'NATMlft n» MHI'HHIMKNl Till' i'*|i|i|'lllll'lll H|H'||in| ,SllUII»l 111, I'MH, Mllll I'ImmmI IIhIiiIhiI 1 -'i Hiiil.lllM il 117 llll&gt; ll'kl Till' IiIImIix Wl'l'ti Illl'll I, . I ■ . I Ml ii </seg>
            <seg id="p009">bull I mull ti'ppilhiu 9 ItOKN IT \'\\ to i |||&lt; I.AMHN WMHN Mil, I^MII UN i UNM ANII AdMIM MAY? i... i i ..i u NiimiIihi III lilt in 411 t'KfH NAII i (!••&gt;• fi.nl M Avimmmm Mnitl Wi'ltflll Avmimum ImIIImI WMlnlll AvkI'HHH HHlM &gt;\niy* sin JUJI Avxi'hh* iwily hmHi in HIT AVl'IMUM lUlU IHlllHI, IIIIUIIlU I I.I PI i.r MiMir,, \&gt;'»m\ imiiuIIhI |i»i iiimiimI iimIii, III* I'llI'M t:U II Ml* MI..H.. &lt; ••• i'ikI nf Hill inmnila HHlM •T.4A HW Illlllltl I. I.I (I |N,AH |IMI Illllllllinl ImMm.1,117 ilitk- 11 MM Mill 4M mi III! MmiIii I MMt |im litmli K*»il tuiat pwr Umli 'I'hImI i'ii»| |ixr ImmiIi Jl MM Mm Li" 4,4ft n/ MnlllMtr |Mli'» |mr huntli'wil »iomi Htil|i|iliiK .til Ink |imi ImmiIi. |miiiiiiI H»i'nl|iti pur ImmiIi I HO NAh »H.yy I 1 1 III I |IPr (SIM II Ill,, MM I, Mi ftl.lMI Nutrlltvn mtln of riitlnn f»il I ,11 Dnmlnv |t»ri'KiilM|f» pur Imnli 40 11(1 uwiiitf lii Ilii' i' h t I'imiii' hi'iii ufttMi I'liriiiniii'i'i'il »lii'ii InmliN nn&gt; ini'li'il mm li'i'il h. i'MI'I.v ii. Ni'iili'inlii'i, II I* ili'i'ini'il mU l.nlili' liv HlMMI' fl'I'lll'I'H |M xlll'lll' llll'lll, lilt' I'llMll'MlllIM lll'llIU Illlll III*' lillllli. Mum nlh'iii'nl Mill unin iiihi'i' ni|i|ill&gt; mill m. ii iv.iiIi will kIimw ii ui'i'iili'i 1 in'1 |H'i III VN' lilt ii ili'.li'i' |m •I'i'iiiv iliiln I'liU'i'lhu IliU lulu I Mini !l H'l'h 1 IVI mi CHlli'lin nl I'lirii Mini I'lliiM.i Inn ImI I lit'liitf iimi'II|i|m'iI iiimI ImI J IhImu i&lt;ll|i|ii'il, A. In I In 1 i'miiIi'IiIImii iImii ImimI'x i'll|i|n'il fiic full Ci'i'illnit Mill iimIii iimiiv rn|ilill,v, He Ilinl lIlNl ill l"l I 1 1"' llllll,V UlllH Hllltlllllll'il |M Mill |lMllllll IMIll III I'll U III ,'|i7 IMIIIH'li Ml 1 i|lllli' II llllll'ltl'll MllVMIIlMMI 1 III Illli' Ml Ifttlll III r/Mnr "I I hi' I'llplii'il InIIIIWi I'll"!' l*HMItlhtlM|f III' 1 illlll) I'llllMM MMltill I Wl&lt; Illlll \l&lt;V\ Illlll' illlV. linn lli. . ll|i|ni| lillllli. I'llll 'UNI,* II I, Hi* I IIMl/ </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 &gt;i/imi4m Hull, h Ml ((III 11/ ihtliiu i NinilliiM ii nIiihIi Him iimih Iml iln iiHlinl liHiii I i|i| iiiiiiiiiIn ill Iii! tl, iiilil Hi! iiiiiiiiiIn ill iiltnllii '•lli'M limit'*, \* ii I'l'tiili ni iii ttlllll Ii mh It nl MM |||i&gt; i|!|iiim| |||| ll|l'|M|ll||HIIHllN|IH f U |l iIhiu I'Hiii ii iiiniMii iih nr lint III Miiiini-i In I li iiiiiiiiiIn ||i i hiiiihni iii i r iihiiIhU in iIm H MleillM ilillli um In hum Niiiin&lt; lil/n, «!■ « mill iniliiiiilh i.&lt;|iiinl 'iIim-iiii-IiIhiiIiI* Inn In Ihi* immi Hll'f I'l'Hlllllh Illllll'llll' lIllN ||||. HIIiIn ill' I III II l|| illlllliNl III ll'jH itlilili ii Hi' iI||i|ihI I llu^lur '1*1! IH'IIIIiIn ill 1 H HI 1 1 il, m iMkmn ll Illlllll'll III IllllH Mllll N, llll. illliil m! Kiilii. H« luiiiiiil ii ih|ii Illi ill; iih.'MnII* ifWim Mini tin Hi 1 1 in il mii'il IhIiiIin iiml ilii (lit mil' l|j|ini iiiiilm iM|uiihii I ii i Hill lll« lll'illtf I'HjHll'I'll l« I HIM) III li i|Hlh il |IM | ill! I II III 1 tfhlM i/l i lM|ii!iH Iml I 'II liiillliiU i 'li|j|ilii# nimh I |n in mi in i |,i. Hill Mf IHillliI II Hlhilhi |||4 | HM«| (if llll imp mil Hill M Ii tflll III i! f Illill III fill I ] \% l|IW'llH « HI *l IUlhi.il m NIlHj &lt;&gt;&gt;l MM I' llbl N M : lll|!ll|l H|i|i lllM. Il .MM/.K IH'l. Im ill|iil Kill! Ill Hi Illill HU li JlllllkiHiil »llll|«i IIMU All'U 1 «lljfllllll(.|lll|i Illill. Ijillllriil, fill HU, In! Mll| III) ill; I II "'Iii/ 1.. in., in bill ii unit iili i« fii , I in/ iimi i Tim « I; lllvIlM li&lt; il iIIIIhIiImiiIiIi, Hull i^iiii'M m ki h\ mill *ii'&lt;n 1 1 iiffii Mil \m hioiiiihli iii Hu .Him lll'l IIHlNl III. MIHlliI I Hit Ik .llll; I iNfllllllllllllllll «I|hmh 1 I , IiiIIimIinIiiiii.i. Hu iiiinli» Hull n *,l Illi.. i lull Illi ...llll II llll. , M|..lllM hi ■ .IHlljl Hi IIHM ilJ'l.''' 'HI nil III., ill (/III llljlll HI Till |.|, |i ! l.i.n,. I I' I 1. II HI; In-Ill I L Hi Mil Jill I ij IJ |l Iffji If I, i 111 II (I'll III k\ I uil.iJI I I 1 "If 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">hill l.mtili hwlUiu 11 IMIM I I'M MM I II' I M||t« |* Mil IMNIIMI MM Ml,* HCiHMHN niMi u^il^i MMm »nh (HI 4IMM r^Hi.m ii /.m#« i Mm/ i .I i ifl •i i t.i.i i I- 1 IIIKUHl 0 in Mil ! Ii I»H 1 1 it mi II! IM II 111 I fir M II M I f 1 II Hi MW If ill! Mllflf »lll|l|il!i|i I lililil Rlllll i I i-iiiil: umiiii.. minim iiiiiiiii Him ii « mil arm </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Hililli"!illffi-iiini-iiiii ml iilii'li lull 4 lill- II II \ll[* I Hlli j&lt; in M-j |'ii" iijfij'iij c "ii n| hi did Hi " "K iIMhI I Till i/i if Mil Hi III l|i|i/i||fl|j|l'» ill lUll illl I 1 ll/fHllI ll/lll* I|I"|II|/IU MllHHtMlKlllll I'lNff [(III Mil • I I ml hi m i imii llM III III AT i In A i I'll! tn ii Illl HJKllll ' ;i" i Mil I'll "I MliHlrt. [Illl IImIII ii'i'il i'ihIH imt -♦nwwii 'llljli II !• "I'll I* ll(l*lt iililiilHMl ii^Iii "mIiiiih, ||,,, f,,|||/i r Ml III hi! H liiiHHiii Mil Bin LnadHwnHHHHW ipilil'il II 'iilliil iiMil i 1 1 , w I III lit I 'i'" I;/ uA </seg>
            <seg id="p013">III! ilWHii I Hi",, Ml IIUkhiiii \nm i (In Hill |M Iiiiii C ' ,. miiHIl i'W 'Will IU WI/.M I |v ill i, #1,1 l ! I II III I H INI I ll I I Hi 1 (III I II I II II Hi H I II M |: I f ll| I Ml. If u i.l ill i) i 1 1 nil ii i ipUil ll I, yj i! H II i ! 1 1 I ji In | i| ui i iu 1 Ml MUMP 1 ihl|l *» ' fit mm r Wit mini Millie </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 ilntHkH III) in 1 1 hi in I Hhillnii Illillillii tin HH.IIIM til Ill/i M'IhIMx illinium** id iillnlhi ff^» mii/I Mir mm \ ("di'lllf » liiwli mill |i|l/r |iImii|I||i* illllll|» HiHil «/ni. IIih* l» i/|/||«Ii hhIiIi liii|li!H mnl i||«i iimIihi filiiil. i lii llii h/MhhIhIiu 'I I I/ill iim lln miiii iniiMii mi/I Mini (ifi/iiiM hiiiim- I// mi mini ii fulfil / lulliiillltf )m l|n nniiM H Illl n i|i»||i * # # hi [Unit n ■'ii i-U tM|uilllltf Illl' HiltlHillilllU nf Illlfllllltf fill' cm il'fllllM H" C II dd'dllljti Id) I HHf fMil il ll'if^ CMllllll Illlll ll(l I II llHll 1 liill'flf &gt;if »um Tfii' ImiiiIi» in I'll l Hi'M Nllimiol nil nf i if Mini *Iim&lt;)i I *lfl/|l| t-/f|f»*tf»#f- ilHl-f Illftl Ittl'llltf il IlilHilmli i HUH* ||| tfHl liilii III II fill IWfl 'I'llf'lf ll^l'NMX illlll/ I'WW i'il\l*l\\ll\i\vi\ «H»»»»I/J.ImI Ik I 'H |&lt;kimii|ii »I|»HM» I U» \Hlll\m III lul 'I n i;m*m 'i(l) ltd iniiiiiil 'llii* t»XH' lixlil nil H lldlli'il IMllnii illlll ilii.»»(rt»«i »M J^'il'll,l(lll» *ll \fllll Hi \\li- &gt;\ii*i IU&gt; MW If'/'MMliM I (iMlOd i&lt;M lint \hi \im iillifHinl ill Mil in »*»## ff ld»lNiii'»'» In l"l I fid* HtmiHii Mididdii'ldiii /m*m/**mi &gt;*l hi \ l&lt;i \hiiiii\h nl/ili. m l»n il II hm« vdiid'HliNl wnii\i&lt;f, limn im\ ii« mm h Himivr «• mi mukM mimt, ilif llviiH I'linw vif/ jiiiiiin\» NhIki'mII* IIic liiiiilm rrr/u mi^ h full niiddi ###■ mini «ldiM»il iln. KIWMlur ililib VUUli i\li&lt; IlKUM lirlnw 'HI jii'llliil fHWM lltt |i'idM&lt;l hi lln IimIiI hri\, M illlfrn •)(»•)■ id |il'Mi llnilll I |m&gt;imii| i|.«iI&gt; Till* i* il HI) llli\l\tn\ lUttni'lWli Hllli Hill' »'inri'l&gt; ».n|iirlnl II |» ■/&gt; 'lllil'»l III l^lllllir Him lln IIkhik. mi |||ii»ii |Mii lul* id IihhI'I &gt;»iuti lii lln lux i!i»j/ii/ll» ill llic yiilii Ilio iiimiIc Ww IIimI iimlMf I'l'l |h I \llllHll] U&gt;llh Illlll t\lH Illlllll* Illl Illl ll«lll Wl'llll Mlh'll ci.iiiiirnl i,n\i) iMUUMHW ni i'iiiii in i"iilni»l In Ui\ iiiimimI* n 'iiilri'il Id IIic hill riil liiiiiii* ii ilirtVrnnT nl I 17 |i"Min)» I inlw» iln' -ilfiillii Hi' liinl Iliiil Ilir liyiii mii'ii fml l»(inli» ri'iuirnl n k»w«» ■IkiI hi'iii in Curl iilimml ilmililt' Ilir niiiiiiiiil, iln- IfgiM'*'* Ik-imo ''iiii iiifiimU iiml V2 |imiiiii|» rc-.|ii'rlhr|&gt; rimryinjf mm ,,i 1&gt; "P|||» |ll'l' lill»lll'l Illlll ll\Ut\U Hi M |K'I' lull, Ml' Illlil Ilir MWl l&gt;f W'lHi III Iliior iHlf |ll|» III III' |/l)|r||i l|||&gt;' lilrlilK ill, In UlU mil) U iiiil* ii-»» In lni |), Tlii* Hk'"'' Mi'iil'l niiiiinill) wir&gt; ilii'i&gt;i'il&gt; Hllli lln ii'luiivr cii»i ni I'lii'ii mill nlCiili.i. Win ||||&gt; ,i i r .1 &gt; r ,• \n \w »hIm«iI ■ Hll»li|r|lllil&gt; IlilflliT, I Id' Illllllii III Illl %, Inl Illl ,| I mill "I ItHUlll lit I'llfll. Mlllllfl »ll&lt;lM II IMIU'll MUM l'*|ll'||»ivi' 1/lllM ill i iilll|illll»illi Milll Illl I \|||III'nII&gt; Illl' Illllllm fllll I'l'l I Illl I'llI'M l'HI'1'il'il inuli ' Ulllliliilll mill M» H l'l'*llll mill fur ♦JII.IMI ill i'illll|IHI'i«.llll Milll •ll'i'l l»m»l foe Mm IiiimIi* wliuli IiiiiI lii'i'ii iiii m Iii/Ih d ril nf ('urn I'lii. Ull'IVHUI'll illl' |i|li||| Illl t|||' full fdl ImIhIin Ml Illlll il Mil" II i I'ltl* |irr lii'iiil vrnili r limn Iliiil nil |||i&gt; llylil fill limilik Kriilll illl* lc»l il Uiilllil M'l'Hl |in»*ill|i' III ill'HM' Illl' rill|i'll!*ll/l! iiml liinilinif tile i'lii'ii 1'Hllmi iiiiili'inill&gt; I'i'iliii'i'* llii' i« 1 1' nf ilmly iruin. ri'iluii* Hie i'iikii |icr jiounil u»in mtil \wrmmm ihc iilCulfn \wr |iiiiiinl of yum, wliirh mI |ii'li'c* iiai'il iliu'» nut iiifiTi tin' ii«»i n1 iirniliK'inir UK! |iiMiiiiU nf i/iiiii HnwiMi'i', W$ nni&gt; ■&gt; h f &lt; • I &gt; infm iiml the cimt of 1IHI pniiiiiU »t ifitiii Mlitfhl In; imiiIitimII.v hITi'i'Ii'iI wtra tlii' CHlin Ih-Ihi'i'ii (lie corn iiml iilfnlfn |mVm In iliffit nut •'■iiiill&gt; fnnn tlitti UMtl in ilii» li'*l. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">/ nil I mull I IliUI 15 I "wimifflwmmtm munii i« mim Vm* H huh I inn! ♦ I »i I 1u\ ) Hill III III m a II am II ♦fir 'MVI ' M/lM WM»I»I mm &gt;H "ft ttfl m .I.m ♦ kxmim" tlHlU »mM»*ii. It/ ' w» I Mil n.i hI » A»f»r» i -i «"h &lt;r ♦ «l .1, "if wh\ •in ♦"«'.., !V»IH» i I'd • H» mm MM IdlMwl m*»I */ |k.(»« liumltml tff'/W Mi4rl»«(iiii( »•»/»( l»n/ti I i/»l l/f fdcil |/i I IMMIM I i/ImI hi»I f/*.-* Unit/ im a, U u W tt «H/i«» «ni.».. 4 4* I -« 4»4# HM1 HM NMirillVK rutlw i»f r*u&lt;*» r«d I 4 ' Mr«Mfnir |M&gt;rc»nUir« |wr l»»tl/ 4«M hi lll&lt;»&lt; Im/i |ol» He llMVi' (hi' IHI/ MMNNMW HM'IImxU of f&lt;-» 'Illlg ImIhIin fid' IIIHkilllMMI UUUl- ill U&gt;\ I Hi'' IlllllU Hl'N' |IM( III M Cull fi'l'll of I'llCM Ilk i|lli''kl&gt; »l» |«»»»llllr, Wiled' fill Illl H tunm illl'l iilfiilfii niiMin Tln&gt; wi'Ci' llii'M iilluwdi till I li**&gt; womIiI &gt;M»Wim 'litrinir (lii&gt; IinIniii'i' of tin' li-iiil In In) 4 die ImhiIi* wurn »i*ni«'il nil ii full fi'i'il uf nil iiii'mI, ill H ti'W liny Hol'bi'il In M fllll fn-il nf inru iiml nil iiii'iil Mini fi'il iiriiirli' Inn fnr i'iil|/li ((*■•• J*'wnI \mM\t*&gt;\ \m ftmtml MM, \k I H»i ill |Mi luniliit- n»"i MHny tniv* \mt UHl l*&gt;». NMpplHg »h&gt;K»l» \m&gt; \miAt, \inniti\- Hwu)\ii&gt; \mr \uiu\i </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraaka Experiment Station Uulletln 170 We noli* iIihi (1r»t of nil the self-feeder lamb* nimli- h somewhat. putltV rMti- of gain, tin- difference befog .OHM pound. Wi imHi - iIih! while tile aclf-fecder IhiiiIi* consumed li'HN corn jut ilny by .11 pound, tln-j iiiiiKimic'd in addition .x'i pound of oil mm[ TIiiu their i-uiii-ffit rut ftl feed amounted to 2.07 pmirulN, in eomporiMn to l.'-te pounds of corn alone consumed in lot 1. The hay coti - suined by the two lot* mIiown a big vHriation aUo. The prairie hay in lot 4 amounted to practically ** pound daily, whi-n-aH I he IhihIi* in lot 1 consumed tin average of 1.72 pouiuU of alfalfa. Thus, while the total feed coiiNUmed amount* to h I i vf 1 1 1 1 &gt;- over '■'&lt; puiiiidh in lot 1, it amount* to only 2.'&gt; poiiiuU in lot 4. However, in lot 4. MO per cent of the daily ration i* concentrate (corn and oil meal; whereas in lot 1, 40 per cent of the ration consisted of corn and the balance roughness. This illustrate* the chief ilifT ereuce between the two nit-t IhkIs of feeding. The advocate* of the Helf-feedcr method aritue tliHt the ImmiIis on tliih ration will coiiuume a great deal more grain and give a proportionately greater daily gain. Naturally the grain required to produce 1 pound of gain was considerably higher in lot 4. We find that while 4.01 pounds of corn Bre required in lot 1, lot 4 required 3.36 pounds of corn and -.-'!•'! piruiuU of oil meal, or a total of 5.61 pounds of concen - trate, which represents an increase of 1.68 pounds over that re - quired in lot 1. The amount of roughage required in reversed, it being but Mil pounds in lot 4 againitt 4.20 pounds in lot 1. Hence, the total feed required amounts to only 7 pounds in lot 4, in rout rant to H.21 pounds in lot 1, the difference being due to the relative proportions of grain and concentrate. Owing to the higher price of gnnn and concentrate in comparison to the rough - ness, we would expect the cont of 100 pounds gain to show eon - •.idcrHbly higher in lot 4. It actually shows a difference of &gt;|&lt;2.17. With so much difference in the cost of grain and with both lots ■f lainlis returning the same price, namely sMO.W) per hundred, we would expect a material increase in the profit per lamb in lot 1 as compared with lot 4. the figures here being M.C&gt;~) find 1)0.02. This xhows fiU cents per heml lead for lot 1. a difference of suffi - cient moment to warrant giving the ration used in lot 1 con - siderable credit. From the hIiovc it would teen that the self-feeder method, while increasing the rate of daily gain, likewise increases the cost of 100 pounds gain, due to the fuct that so much more grain and concen - trate is consumed in proportion to roughness and that unless the rate of gain is materially greater the self-feeder method will not prove as economical as the straight corn and alfalfa ration, such as that used in lot 1. While there arc times when, owing to a shortage of alfalfa the price of it may be such that the self-feeder </seg>
            <seg id="p017">lull Lamb Feeding 17 i— thod wmiUI hi-i uhI)&gt;- product Um ebMpw g*in», &gt;&lt;-t under mu&gt; dition* iim they iiNimlly are in Suhmnkn tbe rt(furi&lt;» yiven in thin t««t would hold, CoitMqtMntlf, uiiIcmm h ff&lt;«di'r Iihn a »p«ci»l purpoM in erowdtDg IhiiiIw for m &lt;i"i«'k mKrkct, th« u»\1.h*4er ■Mtkod cuuld not In- ri'cominiMidi'd km mm i'i&gt;oiiorni&lt;'iil mi-Him of futti'tiintf liimlix. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 170 (LIPPED LAMBS FED A HEAVY RATION OF CORN AND ALFALFA IN COMPARISON WITH THOSE FED CORN AND OIL MEAL IN A SELF-FEEDER Table 6 — Lots 2 and 5. Lot 2 Ix&gt;t 5 Xumber in lot 40 40 Corn Corn oil meal RATION I Light feed) in (elf-feeder Alfalfa Prairie hay (Clippmll (Clipped) Average final weight 88.55 87.08 Average initial weight 62.62 60.68 Average gain 25.93 26.40 Average daily gain , .387 .394 Average daily ration, pounds — Corn 1.31 1.31 Oil meal .89 Alfalfa 1.7 Prairie hay .60 Feed required per pound gain, lbs. — Corn 3.39 3.33 Oil meal 2.25 Alfalfa 4.89 Prairie hay 1.54 Cost of 100 pounds gain $6.29 $9.50 Initial cost &lt;S $8.58 per hundred $4.55 $4-37 Interest, 67 days @ 6% .05 .05 Marketing cost per lamb .23 .23 Cost of feed per lamb 1.63 2.51 Total cost per lamb 6.45 7.16 Selling price per hundred $9.50 $9.50 In comparing these two lots we find the rate of daily gain to be very similar, the porn consumption per day being identical but in addition the lambs in lot ."&gt; taking .89 pound of oil meal. The hay consumption is naturally much greater in lot 2, it amounting to 1.07 pounds daily in comparison to .6 pound in lot 5. The total pounds of feed required to produce one pound of gain amount to ihippiriK shrink per lamb, pounds. 3.55 1.83 !eceipts per lamb. $8.08 $8.00 'rofit per lamb.. $1.63 $ .84 Nutritive ratio of ration fed.. 1:5.9 1:4.4 ressing percentage per lamb 4&amp;M 51.84 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Fall Lamb Feeding 19 7.78 in lot 2 and 7.12 iu lot 5. Howexer, in lot 3 the proportion of grain and oil meal to roughness is much greater than in lot 2, the figure being 43 per cent in lot 2 and 70 per cent in lot 5. As a result of this vastly greater consumption of concentrate in lot •'&gt;, the cost of 100 pounds of gain is over $3 per hundred higher, the figures being $9.50 in lot 5 and $6.29 in lot 2. Naturally with so much disparity in the cost of producing the gain on these two lots of lambs the profit would show materially greater in lot 2, even tho they sold at the same price, namely, $9.50 per hundred. The profit is practically double in lot 2, the figure being $1.63 in contrast to 84 cents in lot 5. In drawing conclusions from the feeding of these two lots, it is very evident that the self-feeder method even with clipped lambs lias no advantage over straight corn and alfalfa hay for fall feed - ing. The results indicated here virtually duplicate those secured in the preceding table where undipped lambs were fed in the same manner as these two lots. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 170 20 THE SELF-FEEDER METHOD THRU THE ENTIRE TRIAL COM - PARED WITH RAPE PASTURE THE FIRST PERIOD AND THE SELF-FEEDER THE LAST 18 DAYS 'Fed only last three wreki of experiment. Lot 6 was fed with a view of ascertaining the value of rape in putting gains on lambs where no additional grain is fed until the final period. The lamhs in this lot had access to splendid rape pasture during the first seven weeks on trial. During the remain - ing 18 days they were placed upon self-feeders with corn and oil meal and hammed identically as the lambs in lot 4. It will be ALBE 8 U anc 6. Lot 4 Lot 6 dumber in lot. 40 40 RATION Rape pasture. Corn ft Corn and oil meal oil meal in telf-feeder in self-feeder 1 Prairi- hay Prairie hmy 1 86.77 79.83 62.03 61.83 24.74 18.00 .369 .268 Average final weight Average initial weight Average gain Average daily gain Average daily ration, lbs. — Corn Oil meal Prairie hay 1.22 .85 .48 1.16 1 1.16 1 .60* Feed required per pound gain, lbs. — Com Oil meal Prairie hay 3.36 2.33 1.31 2.04 2.07 1.07 Cost of 100 pounds gain $9.62 $8.60 Initial cost @ $8.58 per hundred.... $5.32 $5.35 Interest, 67 days @ 6% .06 .06 Marketing cost per lamb Cost of feed per lamb Total cost per lamb .22 2.35 7.95 .21 1.55 7.17 Selling price per hundred. $10.90 $10.25 Shipping shrink per lamb, pounds... 4.46 1.83 Receipts per lamb.. $8.97 $8.00 Profit per lamb. $1.02 $ .83 Nutritive ratio of ration fed. 1:4.3 1 :3.7 l Dressing percentage per lamb. 49.84 46.89 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Fall Lamb Feeding 21 noted that the gains on the lambs in lot 6 were materially less than those in lot 4, the difference being .101 pound daily. During the 18 days at the close of the trial lot 6 was receiving corn and they averaged 1.16 pounds together with 1.15 pounds of oil meal and .60 pound of hay. Prior to that their ration consisted entirely of rape pasture. The lambs in lot 4 on the self-feeder took an average of 1.22 pounds of corn, .85 pound of oil meal and .48 pound of hay. The cost of gain in lot 6 is $1.02 per hundred less than that of lot 4, due largely to the fact that the lambs in lot f! had made rape pasture the larger part of their ration, which was charged to them at Vk cent per head daily. It may be stated, however, that the rape pasture did not produce gains which were satisfactory, as will be shown later in cr.mparing gains made or. rape pasture and those made on blue grass pasture (lot 7). The profit resulting from these two lots is slightly in favor of the lambs in lot 4, there being 19 cents to their credit. This is accounted for by the fact that there was over $1 margin in the selling price on the lambs and the cost of gain which they put on. Consequently, the difference in this margin on the additional gains made by lot 4 caused the increased profit. The lambs on rape pasture were not entirely thrifty. There was a tendency for many of them to scour at times, and they did not compare favorably in thrift and condition with lambs in lot 7 and 8, on blue grass pasture and in the cornfield respectively. The gain made by these lambs during the 49 days on this pasture was 11 pounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 170 FEEDING LAMBS ON GRASS PASTURE SUPPLEMENTED AT THE CLOSE WITH CORN AND OIL MEAL VERSUS CORN AND ALFALFA FED IN THE DRY LOT Table 8 — Lots 1 and 7. Lot 1 " Lot 7 umber in lot 40 40 GrmM RATION Corn pasture ■S'rd only but three weeks of experiment : Kxcluaive of rape. In this comparison the plan was to ascertain the relative cost of making gains on blue grass pasture where the lambs were fed n limited amount of grain at the close of the feeding period, with the dry lot feeding of lambs on a heavy ration of corn and alfalfa hay, the primary object here being to ascertain the rate of gain which might be secured under the first method ; secondly, to sec whether lambs fed on grass in this manner actually became fleshy lovy fe, Alfalfa Corn and oil meal' Average final weight Average initial weight Average gain Average daily gain 87.79 66.68 22.21 .331 83.56 65.27 18.29 .273 .verage daily ration, lbs. — Corn Oil meal Alfalfa 1.33 1.72 .65' .25' ?eed required per pound gain, lbs. — Corn Oil meal Alfalfa 4.01 .8* .27 5.20 Cost of 100 pounds gain... $7.45 $3.56 Initial cost @ $8.58 per hundred.. $5.63 $5.40 Interest, 67 days @ 6% Marketing cost per lamb Cost of feed per lamb Total cost per lamb .06 .23 1.65 7.57 .06 .22 .65 6.33 Selling price per hundred.. $10.90 $10.00 Shipping shrink per lamb, pounds U 2.54 Receipts per lamb.. $9.22 $8.10 Profit per lamb $1.65 $1.77 Nutritive ratio of ration fed. 1:5.9 1:4.9" Dressing percentage per lamb.. UM 45.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Fall Lamb Feeding 23 or whether the increased weight was growth ; and third, to ascertain the relative cost of gain* secured in the two cases. With this in mind lot 7 was allowed access dur - ing tin' entire 67-day trial to bine grass pasture. Th-* lost 21 days of the trial they were fed corn and oil meal. These feeds were started in small amounts and worked up until the last week, at which time the lambs were petting slightly better than 1 pound of corn and .33 pound of oil meal. The average corn and oil meal consumption during this last three weeks amounted to Xu pound of corn and .25 pound of oil meal. Aside from this the lambs had no other feed than the grass. In lot 1 the corn consumption amounted to 1.33 pound* per day and the Alfalfa to 1.7 pounds. Hence, we see quite a contrast in the amount of grain consumed by the lambs in these two lots. The corn, for instance, required to fatten the lambs in lot 1 actually amounted to !K) pounds per lamb, or slightly over 11/2 bushels, whereas in lot 7 the total amount of corn required per lamb was only 14 pounds and the oil meal •*&gt; pounds. By alluding to the gain made by the lambs in the two lots we find that the lambs on the grass show a relatively high gain, altho not quite as large as that made by those receiving the corn and alfalfa, the diff - erence being about .06 pound. However, considering the feed which lot 7 had. the .27 pound gain per day made by them is certainly very gratifying. The feed per 1(X&gt; pounds of gain is naturally rather misleading as no accurate figure can be given on the grass consumed by the lambs, this having been charged to them at the customary pasture rate of l/j» cents per day. The grain required to produce the gains amounted to 4.01 pounds of corn in lot 1 in contrast to .88 pound of corn and .27 pound of oil meal in lot 7. Hence, a very marked reduction in the amount of grain necessary to put on the gain where on grass. Lot 1 at the same time required 5.20 pounds of alfalfa which was doubtless offset by a much greater quantity of grass consumed by the lambs in lot 7. The cost of 100 pounds of gain amounts to $7.45 in the case of lot 1 and it is but +:!.."&gt;;&gt; in the ease of lot 7. This makes a difference of $3.90. In other words, the gain in lot 7 eost less than one-half what the gain in lot 1 cost. This doubtless substan - tiates the common belief of many men that no feed makes gain as cheaply as grass. The gain made on gram is of necessity mostly growth rather than fat and as a result the lambs in lot 7 at the conclusion of this trial were not in any sense fat. They were appraised by market men before shipping and were sold separately on the Omaha market. The discrimination against them was rather severe, due to the fact that they were very large framed, and earned a very limited amount to finish. They sold at $10 per him- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebianka Experiment Station Bulletin 170 FEEDING LAMBS ON GRASS PASTURE SUPPLEMENTED AT THE CLOSE WITH CORN AND OIL MEAL VERSUS CORN AND ALFALFA FED IN THE DRY LOT Table 8 — Lots 1 and 7. Lot 1 "Lot 40 miber in \o 10 Corn paature KATION (Heavy feed) Corn and Alfalfa oil nnl&lt; Average final weight 87.79 83.56 Average initial weight 66.68 65.27 Average Rain 22.21 18.29 Average daily gain .331 .27:* Average daily ration, lbs. — Corn 1.33 .65' Oil meal .25' Alfalfa 1.72 Feed required per pound gain, lbs. — Corn 4.01 .88 Oil meal .27 Alfalfa 5.20 Cost of 100 pounds gain $7.45 $3.55 Initial cost @ $8.58 per hundred $5.63 $5.40 Interest, 67 days 6 6'/r .06 .06 Marketing cost per lamb .23 .22 Cost of feed per lamb 1.65 .65 Total cost per lamb 7.57 6.33 Selling price per hundred $10.90 $10.00 Shipping shrink per lamb, pounds 3.2 2.54 Receipts per lamb $9.22 $8.10 Profit per lamb $1.65 $1.77 Nutritive ratio of ration fed 1:5.9 1:4.9" Dressing percentage per lamb 48.66 45.55 i-Yd only Imit three weeka of experiment. Kxcluiive of rape. Tn this comparison the plan was to ascertain the relative cost of making gains on blue grass pasture where the lambs were fed a limited amount of grain at the close of the feeding period, with the dry lot feeding of lambs on a heavy ration of corn and alfalfa hay, the primary object here being to ascertain the rate of gain which might be secured under the first method: secondly, to lee whether lambs fed on grass in this manner actually became fleshy </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Fall Lamb Feeding or whether the increased weight was growth; hikI third, to ascertain the relative cost of gains secured in the two '■axe*. With this in mind lot 7 was allowed aeeeaa dur - ing the entire i&gt;7-day trial to blue grass pasture. Th - lost 21 da.vn of the trial they were fed corn and oil meal. Them- feeds were started in small amounts and worked up until the last week, at which time the lainhs were getting slightly better than 1 |M&gt;und of eorn and .JW pound of oil meal. The average eorn and oil meal eonsuinptiou during this last three weeks ■mounted to ,K7 pound of corn au&lt;l •-■"» pound of oil meal. Aside from this the lamb* had no other feed than the gran*. In lot 1 the corn eonsiiiupti&lt;.n amounted to 1.5M pounds per day and the .ilfalfa to 1.7 pounds. Ilenee, we see &lt;|iiite a contrast in the amount of grain eonsumed by the lambs in these two lots. The corn, for instance, required to fatten the lamhs in lot 1 actually amounted to !HI pounds per lamh. or slightly over 1 ' .■•&gt; ImsheU, whereas in lot 7 the total amount of eorn rei|iiired per lamh was only 14 pounds and the oil meal •"&gt; pounds. Ity alluding to the train made liy the lambs in the two lots we find that the Iambi* on the crass show a relatively high gain, altho not quite us largo as that made by those receiving the corn and alfalfa, the diff - erence being alnnit .06 pound. However, considering the feed which lot 7 had. the .27 pound train per day made by them is certainly very gratifying. The feed per KHI pounds of gain is naturally rather misleading as no accurate figure can he given on the grass consumed by the lambs, this having been charged to them at the customary pasture rate of 1/2 cents per day. The grain required to produce the gains amounted to 4.01 pounds of eorn in lot 1 in contrast to .88 pound of corn and .27 pound of oil meal in lot 7. Hence, a very marked reduction in the amount of grain necessary to put on the gain where on grass. Lot 1 at the same time required ~&gt;.2O pounds of alfalfa which was douhtless offset by a much greater quantity of grass eonsumed by the lambs in lot 7. The cont of 100 pounds of gain amounts to %~A~t in the case of lot 1 and it is but &gt;M."&gt;."&gt; in the ease of lot 7. This makes a difference of &amp;-J.90. In other words, the gain in lot 7 cost less than one-half what the gain in lot 1 cost. This douhtless substan - tiates the common belief of many men that no feed makes gain as cheaply as grass. The gain made on grass is of necessity mostly growth rather than fat and as a result the lambs in lot 7 at the. conclusion of this trial were not in any sense fat. They were appraised by market men before shipping and were sold separately on the Omaha market. The discrimination against them was rather severe, due to the fact that they were very large framed and carried a very limited amount to finish. They sold at $10 per bun- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebranka Experiment Station Bulletin 170 In order to accustom the lamlis to corn they were fed some green fodder before being turned in the field. Thi8 was prior to the opening of the experiment. They seemed to relish this and upon turning them into the field they experienced no evil results. There whs considerable growtli of vegetation in the field, and the lambs cleaned this up nicely before bothering the corn plants very much. They gradually acquired a liking for the corn leaves, and after most of these were consumed they took to the ears and gradually worked themselves onto a full feed of grain. In comparison with the lambs in this lot. we have those in lot 1. which were fed « full feed of corn and alfalfa hay in the dry lot during the same period. We find that the corn consumption did not vary materially in the two lots, being slightly greater in the case of the lambs in the cornfield. The daily ration wmk 1.33 pounds in the dry lot and 1.39 pounds in the field. The aver - age daily oil meal consumption of the cornfield lambs amounted to .3 pound and their alfalfa ration thruout the period amounted to 1.27 pounds daily, which was considerably less than that con - sumed by the lambs in lot 1, where it amounted to 1.7 pounds. The rate of daily gain of the lambs in these two lots was higher with those in the cornfield, it amounting to .358 pound there versus .33 pound in the dry lot. With new corn charged against the lambs in the field at (&gt;•"&gt; cents per bushel and oil meal at $40 per ton, their gain actually cost .+."&gt;.H(i per KM) pounds. In contrast, it cost $7.45 in the dry lot where old corn was charged at 75 cents per bushel. The lambs in the cornfield were appraised at the highest figure of any lot in the experiment. Market men who saw them pro - nounced them ax carrying splendid condition and a uniformly choice group. &lt; 'areass men at the packing plant ' later graded the carcasses as prime. The cornfield lambs were sold at $11.00 per hundred in con - trast to $10.90 for the dry lot lambs. As a result of this differ - ence in price and the cheaper gain, in lot 8 we have a profit of $2.46, which is the highest profit of the entire experiment, in con - trast to a profit of $1.56 in lot I. From the results secured in this test it would seem that the feeding in the cornfield is worthy of considerable practice. The lambs made a \ery satisfactory gain, did so with a relatively economical use of feed and showed by far the largest profit of anv lot fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Fall Lamb Feeding 27 FEEDING LAMBS ON FORAGE IN THE FALL. LOTS 6, 7 AND 8 Hy comparing lota 6, 7 and 8 in table 1, one may get a fair idea of the value of the rape pasture versus grass pasture versus a cornfield for the fall fattening of lambs. It will be noted that i lie lambs in the cornfield made a considerably higher gain than those in either of the other two lots, and while their gain was not ax cheap as that made by those on blue grass they sold at a figure so much higher that the profit was increased 50 cents per head, due largely to the fact that the gain on the cornfield lamb* wan more in the nature of fat and that they came off the experiment highly finished, whereas the blue grass lambs had grown and not developed fat. By comparing the rape lot we find evidence pointing in favor of the latter. The lambs on the blue irrjiss were thrifty thruout the trial, whereas those on the rape were inclined to be off feed and require more or less attention. In •so far as rape is concerned as a fattening feed for sheep, this test would not seem to show very favorable results. The profit on the blue grass lambs, it will be noted, is practically double that on the rape-fed lambs. An ideal combination might be made by plac - ing lambs that have been handled as these in lot 7 in the cornfield for a period of 40 to 50 days before marketing. In this case they would not only be well grown, but would be fleshy. 9-24--18— «M </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 170 28 S I &amp; I i SS*| SSS | SSC si ?« I i S S Mt^K I lA*r^ ~N*Q » »i w 3 181 S 13 I 3 181 1111 m\ m\ isTgj MS I i I i M.HSJ S] SfljjJUM 858 S |S B 181 3 1 3 I 3 isl 1351 §111 3331 181 333 : 5 ■ 9 |S| * I S I 3 |S| F = * I 3PJ5I =22 1 |S| S« ' M 3 I 3 I 3 I B I1?I 3331 931 9aai»| if| : 18| s 1 3 1 5 12 1 333 3311 2211 111 m ■ s S I- d N •» •» i f ««- iiji ".».* • *S « H ~ ••Was ~ &lt;1 s H V SB* ■ 9 «C9 v&lt;tr s t- y) KS8 ■ * »»» o B*S 5 a - mmW rid i *•• « 3 111 1 1 1 I IHTTIJ SSfTSir " M 8 1 3 I STiTSS 1SES! 5^ |ft| !52 111 3 I 3 I 3 isi III 3311 S531 1st S!2 I |S| 2 I SJ J III 5531 533 1 2:2|_ |S| 52s i^rri"! rrf^rsssi sin njnasi*! m mi s is rrrii iii i p5i is3i m hs l«l 3 I 3 I 5&gt;| s|il 3131 SHTSSS|»1 555 ~ II 9 I 9 I S Isi 3S2 Bssl 3951 Isl 3 !5 M y M s»«&gt; * ft •&lt; w « ■id - «•• n !*rr[^T52Hi sssi sssr~sssi«i m »&gt; *Bi: _« I ■ » - 5MM i-- «i» riSM- »: / M« « «x« i I .4 '"- ' *^s sz* cat J«x III II •I* 1 i ; ' i. 2 » dlii M »:». MM« isi J IJ JJ isi 3331 ii§ I 5521 iii m III 9 I 5 I 9 |2| SSI 3191 9531 181 322 5 •: '-?- M"tt « M fi 4~4 *-* ,.» X •i r- h 1 « |s| 9 I S | 8 111 3331 5851 &amp;fl |i| 52! B txs BSt * ? • « F^s •rf.if * ' IS - P 5 i- • S «i^»i ••- i^«!«* I fi •; SIM 3S2|"!35I«I 225 (tfl ' :«. X ■- i, ►- H S¥3 WWW t m in m 231 221 H ! 1 ] ! I i £ E £ £ t I i I alls i J , slijl 5lj| 2f!s j I Mi ill iil </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>