<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE State Industrial School AT KEARNEY, NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">SEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT — OF THE— State Industrial School —AT— KEARNEY, NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 190a 1KB Th« Frimoht Tbibuiic Fbbhoht, Nib. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">N Kearney, Neb., December i, 1902. To the Honorable Board of Public Lands and Buildings, Lin- coln, Neb. : Gentlemen: — I herewith enclose a copy of my biennial report covering a period from December 1, 1900, to November 30, 1902, inclusive. The report has been compiled from a careful study and analysis of the institution and the work done therein since I have been superintendent. The figures relative to dis - bursements have been carefully taken from the books of the institution and will be found absolutely correct. I take consid - erable pride in the financial showing which I have made during the last six months. You will notice on page 13 that my per capita is $123.92, the lowest per capita which is shown by the books of the institution since its foundation. This reduction in expense has not been at the expense of good service nor thor - ough work. If there is anything about the report which is not clear enough or complete, if you will call my attention to it I will make an explanation thereof. I said in a former letter that we would not need single copies of my report printed, as we have our own printing office and can do that without expense, and my printer informs me that we could very easily print some of the reports from superintendents of other institutions. I desire to thank the members of the board for their kindness and consideration shown me since I have been superintendent, and the aid they have given me in properly conducting the institu - tion. Yours very respectfully, J. V. Beghtol, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT. Kearney, Neb., November 30, 1902. To the Honorable Board Public Lands and Buildings, Lincoln, Neb.: Gentlemen : — I have the honor to submit the following report as superintendent of the Industrial School for Juvenile Offend - ders (boys) for the biennial period ending November 30, 1902. I assumed the duties of superintendent of the State Industrial School on the fifteenth day of June last, and have therefore been in charge of its management only a part of the time cov - ered by this report. After thorough study and investigation, I became convinced that the number of employes could be materi - ally reduced without weakening the service or interfering with the efficiency of the work, and believing that a public institution should be conducted economically and on the same principles that govern successful private enterprise?, I discontinued the ser - vices of six employes and officers whose aggregate salary amounted to $2,120.00 annually; this, together with their board and keeping, reduced the annual expenditures at least $3,000.00, or $6,000.00 during the biennial period. This reduction, coupled with other lines of retrenchment, which may be found in my monthly reports, will bring the cost of maintenance within the amount appropriated by the legislature. There is an unavoid - able deficit in the fuel and light fund, but there will be enough turned back into the state treasury from other funds to fully cover this amount. No reduction in salaries can be made con - sistent with good service. Experience in this and like institu - tions has shown that competent and experienced officers and employes are necessary in all the departments to insure efficient and thorough work. FUEL. Ktie consumption of coal is an item of considerable expense large public institution, and in order that no mistake might ir as to the quantity and quality of coal or other fuels </seg>
            <seg id="p004">314 received, I have instituted and maintain a system of receiving, weighing and checking up which prevents the possibility of error. With a view of practicing economy and studying the relative value of the different kinds of coal and other fuels, a daily "log-book" is kept by the engineer; the amount consumed each day is carefully weighed or measured and a daily report is made to the superintendent showing the amount and kind of coal used, the number of hours run, the number of pounds of steam carried and the amount of work done. By these measures no discrepancy of any consequence can appear between the amount of coal paid for and the amount consumed. Besides encour - aging the engineer in the practice of economy in the use of fuel, it also furnishes the superintendent a record from which he may derive an accurate knowledge of the daily expense for steam power and heating purposes. During the present biennium a gasoline engine has been put in which is used for pumping and lighting purposes. How much saving it will effect, if any, in the cost of fuel is not yet determined. The steam plant, water and sewage systems having been in use many years are now beginning to need considerable repair, and I am informed by competent engineers who have made careful examinations of the steam plant that two new boilers are needed and that the old ones being too far from the grates should be lowered and reset, which would result in a great saving in the cost of fuel. SUPPLIES. I very article of supplies received in the institution is care - r inspected, weighed or measured, checked up with the and contract price and issued only on requisition and receipt i the heads of the different departments. From this actual wledge may be had of the daily running expenses. Fre - nt invoices of storerooms and departments render a ready wledge of the amount and condition of goods on hand and care taken in the distribution of goods and use of articles in lal service. While it has been sought to reduce expenses by ing off an excess of employes and discriminating closely in purchase and distribution of supplies, no effort has been or </seg>
            <seg id="p005">315 to render good and efficient service to the state and achieve the object for which the institution is maintained. BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS. The state has been liberal in the past in permanent construc - tion and equipment of buildings. Seven large brick structures occupy a high hill overlooking the beautiful valley of the Platte and the city of Kearney. The site is an ideal one. Sanitation and drainage are perfect. These buildings, however, are in a bad state of repair, and it is poor economy to allow them to further decay. Superintendent Campbell in his biennial rrport in the year 1900 called attention to the condition of the build - ings at that time, and the appropriations made by the last leg - islature were not sufficient in amount to permanently repair them. I have had careful examinations and estimates made by competent builders and contractors, and from their reports I am satisfied it will require the sum of $12,000.00 to perma- P r repair the buildings, steam plant and sewage systems. : asked for that amount. I earnestly request the Board blic Lands and Buildings and the Legislative Committee it the institution and personally inspect the buildings and eed of repairs asked for. The grounds, walks, drives, wer beds, lawns and campus are in a good state of repair, I kept, and the whole presents a beautiful and pleasing :arance. Perhaps no institution in the state during the mer months will surpass this campus in arrangement, metry and beauty. People from the city and other parts of state express delight in a visit to this institution when the ers are in bloom and nature is clothed in her greenest garb, ding on the front porch of the administration building and ing out over the valley of the Platte no finer view is pre - sd anywhere in the state. PURPOSE AND AIM Boys under the age of sixteen years who are incorrigible, delinquent, under vicious environment or who have been con- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">316 victed of some infraction of the law of the state, are sent to this school for the purpose of reformation, education, guidance and training. The idea is to reclaim them. They are instructed in the principles of morality and such useful branches of knowledge as are usually taught in the public schools of the state. They are instructed in the principles of mechanical arts, and practical trades best adapted to secure them a liveli - hood after leaving the school. They are taught in the theory and practice of agriculture, gardening and stock-raising. The purpose and aim therefore in maintaining the Industrial School is to make out of the boys sent here good and useful citizens of the state. The number of boys in the school November 30, 1900, was 136. The number of boys in the school November 30, 1902, is 145. Over seventy-five per cent of the number of boys committed here turn out well and finally enter the ordinary avenues of social and business life. RELIGIOUS SERVICE AND TEACHING. There are five chaplains connected with the school who reside in the city of Kearney. They represent the different leading denominations of the Christian religion. They alternate with each other in holding religious services each Sunday at the hour of 2 130 p. m. The chaplains are regularly employed at the institution and rank among the best talent in the state. Sermons are prepared specially and peculiarly adapted to interest and teach the boys the principles of religion and mor - ality. The plan of supplying the chaplaincy from the resident ministers of Kearney has met with special favor in the school, and an increased interest is manifested by the boys and all who are in attendance, who are thus brought in touch with the churches and Christian societies of the city. Sunday school is conducted regularly every Sunday morning at the hour of 10 o'clock. The school is taught by the grade managers and other officers who alternate with each other in this service. They are all moral, Christian men and are experienced in Sun - day school work. That natural and laudable desire to excel leads each of them to make special and thorough preparation, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">317 the result of which is an increased interest by all concerned and a more thorough and efficient work. The boys love to sing, and when all the companies join together in singing it gives to the service a beneficial inspiration. The Pilgrim series of lesson helps and papers are used and each boy has an intermediate quarterly for study and preparation. The lessons are studied and prepared in the grades during the week and many of the boys become well versed in Bible history. EDUCATIONAL. A rational system of education teaches and employs the hands as well as the mind. It is the theory and practice here to divide the boys' time between school work, labor and play, Rhat all may become profitable and agreeable. The teaching rades and the principles and practice of agriculture, garden - flower culture and stock raising are found to be important ors in reformatory work. If the work in these lines are intelligently directed it creates an interest in the boy's mind K : "h follows him after he leaves the school. The idea is to the boy's mind and hands constantly employed, and for purpose the work is divided into the school, the shop and arm. THE SCHOOL. The school is divided into four sections, companies or grades, according to the age and size of the boys, and each grade is pre - sided over by a grade manager or teacher. The managers are experienced teachers in the public schools of this and other states, and are selected because of their skill in order, discipline and management. For reasons which are obvious the boys who are sent here are not advanced as far in school work as those of the same age in the common schools. A persistent effort is made to drill the boy in the common branches, and he is taught in the studies which will be of the most practical value to him in everyday life. The curriculum embraces reading, writing, spelling, arithmetic, grammar, geography, history and physiology. Occasionally more advanced work is given when </seg>
            <seg id="p008">318 a boy is found capable of receiving it. The school work is so divided that two grades are in school during the forenoon, while the other two grades are at work in the shops and in the fields. In the afternoon the order is reversed, thereby giving each grade a half day in school and a half day in indus - trial training. The session begins in the morning at 7:30 o'clock and continues, including a short recess, until 1 1 =30 a. m. Each evening a session of one hour is held in all the grades where lessons are prepared and various programs taken up. This year a new system of books has been adopted in ex - change for those old and worn out. The method of teaching is about the same as found in our best common schools of the state. Each boy is required to attend school daily. TRADES DEPARTMENTS. These departments are shops or training schools under th management of skilful mechanics and teachers. The boj even at an early age learn rapidly and soon become proficient i the work they are engaged upon. This work well directe&lt; alternating with the school, so blends their education that the are prepared for the practical duties of life. From these depar ments have gone out many boys who are working on good sala ries or managing business enterprises of their own. PRINTING OFFICE. This office is under the management of a practical printer and editor. It is probably as well equipped as most of the newspaper offices in the country towns. It has a steam power press and material for doing good work. All kinds of job work, stationery, blank forms and pamphlet work are done equally as well as in the larger offices. Most all the blanks used in this institution are printed here, and considerable work is done for the other institutions of the state. The boys are encour - aged by receiving many orders for work by corporations and private citizens, yet no effort is made to secure patronage and thus come in competition with private printing establishments in the state. A neat 32-page magazine is issued monthly filled </seg>
            <seg id="p009">319 with the best selected and original matter well adapted for boys' reading. It is neat in appearance and is one of the best reform school journals in the United States. In this depart - ment quite a large number of boys learn the art of printing, and. may of them go out from here fully competent to do the work of a practical printer in any of the larger offices in the TAILOR SHOP. The tailor shop is a very necessary and important factor in the industrial department. In it is manufactured and prepared all the boys' clothing, caps,' underwear, sheets and pillow cases, table cloths, towels and" everything in that line used in the school. It is managed by an experienced tailor, who teaches the boys under his charge the principles and practice of cutting, fitting and making. From eight to ten boys are engaged in this department and many of them become very proficient and skilful. There is now and will be in the future a great demand for tailors, from the fact that few boys in this country are learn - ing the trade. Several boys who have become good workmen have gone out from here and hold good positions in this and other states. Some idea of the amount of work done in this department may be formed from the following list taken from the foreman's report covering a period of twelve months; new work, uniform pants 193 pair, uniform coats 134, vests 42, jeans pants 47, shirts 300, sheets 260, pillow cases 350, towels 350, underwear 300 suits, overalls 60 pairs, dining room coats 48, mittens 75 pair, overcoats 4, table-cloths 36, aprons 130, coats repaired 720, pants repaired 1,080. The work is done by the boys in a neat and workmanlike manner, and will compare favorably with the best work done in the towns. SHOE SHOP. This department is under the management and control of an experienced workman, who has under his charge from eight to twelve boys who are learning the trade. This work is very important in utility and the economy of the school. Boys wear out shoes rapidly in the field and on the p'ayground, and it </seg>
            <seg id="p010">320 requires constant repairing to keep them in order. The man - ager's report shows that in his shop thirty pairs of shoes are repaired every week, and over 300 new pairs are made during the year. Some of the boys begin work in the shop when very young, and at the end of two years have a fair practical knowledge of the trade. They also keep in repair harness, balls, gloves, suspenders and every article made of leather used in the institution. CARPENTER SHOP. In the basement of the main building is located the carpente shop. It is well equipped with a full assortment of all kinds o tools used in repairing and building. It is in charge of an expe ienced carpenter, who has with him a number of boys. The keep the buildings in ordinary repair, repair furniture, plaste paint and hang paper. The work done in this department very valuable to the institution and a great saving to the state. LAUNDRY. This department is in the hands of an experienced laundry - man who, with a number of boys, do all the laundry work of the institution. It is supplied with all the modern machinery neces - sary for turning out good work. The work done will compare favorably with the work done in any first-class laundry. The boys working in this department learn the business rapidly and will be able to secure good and paying positions when they BOILER HOUSE, LIGHTING PLANT AND BLACKSMITH SHOP. I his department is managed by two competent and exper - :d engineers. Steam is used for power, heating and cook - purposes, and gasoline is used for pumping water and run - the dynamo. A number of boys assist in firing, running :ngine, repairing water pipes, sewers and light plant. In blacksmith shop the farm machinery is repaired and the jies and carriages kept in order. Repairs and changes ed in the boiler house are referred to in another section of </seg>
            <seg id="p011">321 KITCHEN AND BAKERY. An experienced baker and cook has charge of the kitchen and bakery. Several boys assist in the work and soon become proficient in plain cooking and baking. All the bread used in the institution is baked in this kitchen in a Hubbard portable oven. Over 150 loaves of bread are made every day. Steam is used in cooking vegetables and from three to four bushels of potatoes are used daily, and other vegetables in proportion. Many boys have learned the trade in this department and now receive good wages cooking in hotels and restaurant?. FAItM, GARDEN AND STOCK. The land belonging to the state consists of 320 acres, mostly upland, there being only twelve acres below the ditch and capa - ble of irrigation. The buildings and grounds occupy a consid - erable portion of land and the amount under actual cultivation is not sufficient to meet the demands of the School. It has been therefore necessary to rent 160 acres or more every year to bring the acreage up to what it should be. A fine tract of land lying below the ditch belonging to the Watson ranch has usually been obtained at a cost rental of rive dollars per acre. It has been customary for the superintendent to assume an obligation of $800.00 or more annual rental on this land. The uncertainty of obtaining a crop makes this transaction somewhat hazardous. Rearing this in mind, no more land should be rented than can be well and profitably tended. Again, if the acreage is too large and attempt is made to increase the income from the farm to a point beyond good judgment, it defeats the object for which the School is maintained. An acreage too large requires the boys to begin work early in the spring and continue late in the fall, in which case the school year would necessarily be short - ened, a fact which must not be lost sight of. While it is desir - able to derive as much income as possible from the farm, the main object to be kept in view is to teach the boy to do his work thoroughly and well, remembering that soil culture is now being rapidly reduced to an exact science and the time has gone by for unscientific farming. If the land between the ditch could be </seg>
            <seg id="p012">322 Eiased at a proper price it would certainly be a profitable ttment for the state. The farm, garden and stock are under management of the assistant superintendent, Mr. H. D. ff, who is an experienced farmer, gardener and teacher with several years' experience in reform school work. He is I ted by the barn-man, farm-man, force- man and a number of i. Boys are selected for farm work who are most suitable who are likely to follow that vocation. Thorough and per - nt effort is made to teach them in every branch of agricul - and the theory and practice of every step is carefully ained to them. Owing to favorable conditions this year the has been a bountiful one and the excess of grain will be for use next year in case of a failure of crops. Sixty-five s of wheat have been sown this fall, is all up and looking All grains and vegetables are now harvested and in store except the corn, which is now being husked. The following is a list of farm and garden products raised, consumed, sold and now on hand during the year 1902 : Bushels Raised. Consumed. Sold. On Hand. Potatoes 1,768 268 1,500 Onions 83 28 54 Lettuce 18 18 Turnips 95 15 80 String beans n 11 .... Gooseberries 6 4 2 .... Cauliflower 10 10 . . . . Shelled peas 11 9 2 Beets 101 21 80 Cucumbers 102 42 pickles 60 bush Carrots 98 18 80 Spinach 4 4 Tomatoes 48 48 Cherries 5 5 Grapes 5 5 Currants 4 4 Plums 2 2 1 firsnins ac\ a &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p013">oTATR INDUSTRIAL oCHOOI.. 323 Bushels Raised. Consumed. Sold. On Hand. Mangel wurzel 320 80 240 Peppers 4 4 Beans 20 20 Corn (estimated) . .4,500 100 (est.)4,4oo Oats 3,6oo 275 3,325 Wheat (machine measure) 1,441 .... 1,292 149 seed Sweet corn 80 50 30 Cabbage (heads) . . . 1,930 680 ... In kraut 1,250 Celery (doz.) 211 91 120 Squash (doz.) 45 25 20 Radishes (doz) 1 ,200 1,200 Strawberries (qts.).. 102 102 Hay, alfalfa (tons) .. 143 33 no SKKDS. The following seeds were raised on contract with D. M. Ferry &amp; Company, of Detroit, Mich.; Sweet corn, 3,185 lbs.; Hubbard squash, 158^ lbs.; cucumber, 158*4 lbs.; musk melon, 1,20634 lbs. These were all cleaned, dried and shipped to the contractors at Detroit, Mich. Complete settlement has not yet been made, but the receipts will not be far from $220.00. Owing to the attack of bugs and an early frost the cucumber and squash failed to properly mature, and the crop of seeds from these plants was therefore almost a failure. SI 'OAK BKETS. The yield of the sugar beet crop the present year was very satisfactory. Twenty-five acres were planted, and owing to the favorable season the crop was raised without irrigation. They were grown under contract with the American Beet Sugar Com- pany, and were shipped to their factory at Grand Island, Nebr. The harvest began on the 20th of October and ended on the 5th of November. There were shipped in all 17 carloads. The total gross tonnage was 430 tons; tare, 21 tons; net, 409 tons. Settlement has not yet been made in full. The lowest price per </seg>
            <seg id="p014">324 ton paid was $4.00; the highest price paid was $4.40. Returns from ten cars show net receipts of $888.65 after deducting $103.75, the price of seed for the entire crop. Estimated amount yet due, $700.00. Sugar beets are a very profitable crop, and within certain limits Industrial school labor is well adapted to growing them. The acreage must be within certain bounds, for the reason that beet culture requires careful, particular and thorough work, and must be done just at the right time. Twenty-five to thirty acres is about the limit which can be handled successfully under present conditions. STOCK AND FARM IMPLEMENTS There is on hand at the present time: Cows, fifteen; bulls, one; horses, thirteen; brood sows, twenty-one; shoats, four; pigs, thirty -seven ; boar, one. It is the intention to increase the number of milch cows and bring the quality of the herd up to a higher standard. I found several very old cows in the herd which were very unprofitable, and they are being fattened and replaced by younger and better animals. Last August butter was made in this institution for the first time in its history, and at present about forty pounds is being made per week. The present high price of that article will warrant the improvement of the herd of milch cows sufficient to manufacture all the but - ter consumed. Owing to the ravages of cholera last year the stock of hogs was much depleted. It is expected, having plenty of corn, to increase the herd as rapidly as possible. I note that some of the horses belonging to the state are getting old and becoming unfit for the services required of them. They should be sold or traded off and replaced by younger and better ones. The stock of farm implements and machinery is quite complete and in good order. The best and most of it has been purchased during the last two years; previous to which time it had run down in quantity and quality, which required the expenditure of considerable money to replace it and bring it up to the proper state of utility. A binder, corn-planter and wheat drill have been purchased this year. On examination of the standpipe of the water system, I find </seg>
            <seg id="p015">325 that it needs painting, and this should be done during the com - ing summer in order to preserve it and prevent decay. The ice house having been in use a great many years, is now giving out and a new one should be built next year. It will probably be sufficient to hold the crop of ice to be put up the coming winter. I believe it would be wise to build a vegetable or root hous •reserving the roots and vegetables during the winter. Th on the grounds offers a splendid opportunity to build ; basement for this purpose, on the top of which could be an implement and seed house. The caves which hav in use as cellars for many years will soon be unfit fo ter use unless repaired at considerable expense. RECREATION, AMUSEMENT AND ENTERTAINMENT. The boys are great ball players. Outside of the campus a large play-ground is situated, where they play baseball, football and other games and enter into the sport with that vigor and dash which characterizes the American boy. As often as seems desirable, lectures and entertainments are given in the chapel by talent secured by a fund provided for that purpose. Home entertainments are sometimes gotten up by the boys, and some very good talent is developed. The playrooms in the grade buildings are provided with numerous games in which the boys indulge during the long winter evenings. A library of several hundred volumes, selected with great care, furnishes books which are issued to them every Sunday morning, and a sufficient num - ber of the leading and best periodicals suitable for boys are dis - tributed in the grades every week. It is thus seen that the Industrial school boy has a proper and sufficient time for work, study and play, and under such training and environment the best results are obtained. HEALTH. The health of the boys during the present biennium has been good. No zymotic diseases have prevailed with the exception of scarlet fever. Early in September of the present year several mild cases of this disease appeared, but by prompt segregation </seg>
            <seg id="p016">326 K quarantine it has been brought under complete control, medical department is in the hands of Doctor Bell, a promi - thorough and reliable physician and surgeon, who visits chool every day and treats every sick boy carefully and :rly until he is well. PAROLE SYSTEM When a boy is committed to the Industrial school he is under the control, management and supervision of the superintendent until he arrives at the age of twenty-one years. It is seldom, however, that a boy is retained in the school until he is twenty - one years old. When received a certain number of demerits are given him, of which a certain number may be cancelled each day or month by good behavior and deportment. If a boy is obedient and his work and deportment are reasonably good, he will cancel his demerits in from one and one-half to two and one-half years. This length of time marks about the usual length of the boy's Industrial school life. After canceling his demerits and it is found that the boy is in a proper condition to go out, he is paroled to his home if he has one, and if not, a suitable home is found for him. Under proper conditions he is usually paroled for a period of four months, during which time his progress, deportment and environments are carefully observed by correspondence and visits by the officers of the school. If it is found that he is doing well, his parole is extended. In the selection of homes, or even when paroled to parents, great care is taken in the investigation and study of home environments, for therein lies the secret of his success or failure. If he should not do well and the home is not a suitable one, he is taken to another, but if it is found that his reforma - tion is not complete or if deemed best by the superintendent^ he is returned to the school for further instruction and training. COMMITMENT. ■n the first day of February, 1897, there weie in the school boys, and on the first day of February, 1901, there were boys, showing a decrease during a period of four years of </seg>
            <seg id="p017">327 ioo boys. This decline in number during that time can only be accounted for as the result of indiscriminate parole regardless of demerits cancelled or home environments. At this time there are 145 boys in the school, and if the increase shown during the last six months is sustained during the next semi-annual period, it will be necessary to open another grade. This can be done at only a slightly increased cost. There are many boys now in the cities and towns of the state who should be here under the discipline and training this school affords. Some ambiguity of the laws exist, which renders commitment irregular in certain cases. It is desirable that the law should be plain on this point and it is hoped it will be amended during the next session of the legislature, so that the interest of the boy can be more clearly determined under the law. Having in the past been known as the "Reform School" instead of Industrial school, a precon - ceived idea prevails that odium attaches to the name of a boy when sent here. This error is unfortunate and has been the means of depriving boys of advantages to be obtained here. It is purely a training school, the object of which is to guide the delinquent to a better life and lay the foundation for his future usefulness as a citizen of the state. Friends, parents and guar - dians of delinquents should know that boys are not sent here for punishment, but for guidance, teaching and improvement, and should embrace the opportunity to guide the boy in proper lines. Sometimes in the crowded and congested condition of court business the interests of the boy or girl are lost sight of. Care - ful provision is made to care for their inheritance, but in most cases the home and environments are not sufficiently studied and have little influence in their disposal and destination. This leads me to the conclusion that a juvenile court might be established at least in the larger cities of the state. Such courts are estab - lished in some of the eastern states and the results obtained have been most satisfactory. I do not know whether or not such a court could be established under our constitution as a part of our judicial system, but it would in my judgment more definitely determine the best interests of the boy or girl and more intelli - gently place them in proper lines. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">328 appropriations: The appropriations for the biennial period from April i, 1901, to April 1, 1903, were as follows: Salary of superintendent $ 3,600.00 Salary of assistant superintendent 2,00000 S il try of bookkeeper and stenographer 1,600 00 Salary of chaplain 1.600.00 Salary of physician 1,200.00 Salary of five grade managers 8,000.00 Employes' wages 1 7,500.00 Fuel, electric lights, water supply and boiler house expenses 14,000.00 B &gt;ard, dining-room expenses and kitchen supplies . . . 24,000.00 Clothing, bedding and furniture 8,ooo 00 tary books, periodicals and papers, school books d stationery, medicines, paints, oils and druggists pplies, telephone, telegraph, postage and office pplies, fugitives, freight and express, incidental penses, traveling expenses and music and amuse - ents 4,000 00 Equipping trade departments 1,000.00 Two laundry tubs, repairing outside closets, building hog house, plumbing, sewerage and steam fitting, cow barn, flooring for school buildings, labor and other expenses for general repairs 4,900.00 For gasoline engine 1 ,100 00 New armature 200 00 $92,700.00 COST. It will be seen that the appropriation was made to cover a period of two years or twenty-four months. During the adminis- tration of my predecessor, covering a period of fourteen months, from April 1, 1901, to June 1, 1902, there was expended out of the appropriation ($92,700.00) the sum of $62,572.67, or an average monthly expenditure of $4,469.47; consequently there was a balance of $30,127.33 left of the appropriation to be </seg>
            <seg id="p019">329 expended during the period of ten months, that is from June i, 1902, to April 1, 1903, or a monthly expenditure of $3,012.73. Out of the fuel and light fund ($14,000.00) there was expended during the fourteen months, from April 1, 1901,10 June 1, 1902, the sum of $12,054.07, or an average of $861.00 per month, leaving the sum of $1,945.93, out of the appropriation to be expended during the succeeding ten months, or an average of $194.59. Out of the board fund ($24,000.00) there was expended $16,338.14, or a monthly expenditure of $1,167.01, leaving out of the appropriation the sum of $7,661.86 to be expended during the succeeding ten months, or a monthly expenditure of $766.18. My first semi-annual report, covering a period of six months from June 1, 1902, to November 30, 1902, inclusive, shows a total expenditure of $17,257.73, or $2,876.29 per month. This shows a cost per capita of $123.92, the low- est per capita which the books of the institution disclose. RECAPITULATION . Total amount of appropriation for 24 months $92.7' 000 Amount expended from April 1, 1901, to June 1, 1902 (14 months) 62.572.67 Average monthly expenditure 4,469.47 Balance left in funds to be expended from June 1, 1902, to April 1, 1903 (10 months) 30,127.33 Average monthly allowance for ten months 3,012.73 ITEMS From the fuel and light fund, expended in 14 months $12,054 °7 Average expenditure per month 861.00 From the board fund, expended in 14 months .... 16,338.14 Average monthly expenditure 1,167.01 Amount remaining in fuel and light fund, for 10 months 1,945.93 Average monthly allowance remaining x 94-59 Amount remaining in board fund for 10 months. . 7,661.86 Average monthly allowance remaining 766.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">330 From the above table it is seen that the funds left in the appropriation at the time I took possession of the institution are disproportionately small in comparison with the amount expended during the preceding months. PER CAPITA COST FOR FIVE SEMI-ANNUAL PERIODS. June i, 1900, to November 30, 1900 $ 163.25 December 1, 1900, to May 31, 1901 I 9 I -35 June 1, 1901, to November 30, 1901 x^5-49 December 1, 1901, to May 31, 1902 175-87 June 1, 1902, to November 30, 1902 (Dr. Beghtol) . . . 123.92 CASH ACCOUNT. Balance on hand December 1, 1900 (Supt. Campbell) . $336.32 Receipts from December 1, 1900, to February 1, 1901 504.38 Total $ 840.70 Disbursements from Dec. 1, 1900, to Feb. 1, 1901 .... 335 81 Amount paid over to Supt. Mallalieu Feb. 1, 1901 .... 504.-^9 Receipts from Feb. 1, 1901, to June 15, 1902 2,040.0 ; Total $2,544.92 Disbursements from Feb. 1, 1901, to June 15,1902 . . 2,48460 Amount turned over to Supt. Beghtol, June 15, 1902. 60.32 Received by Supt. Beghtol from June 15, 1902, to Nov. 30, 1902 2,025.45 Total $2,085.77 Paid out by Supt. Beghtol to Nov. 30, 1902 1,616.26 Balance on hand Nov. 30, 1902 :p 469.51 BILLS RECEIVABLE. Balance due on sugar beets (estimated) $ 700.00 Amount due on seed contract (estimated") 22c o Amount due on printing x 3-5° Tota! $ 933.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">331 BILLS PAYABLE. Amount owed to B. H. Stoufer 75-oo Amount due for corn husking (estimated) 100.00 Amount due Carpenter Paper Company 6.00 Balance rent on land 150.00 Total $ 331.00 ESTIMATE OF AMOUNT OF FUNDS REQUIRED FOR THE BIEN- NIAL PERIOD BEGINNING APRIL 1, 1903. Salary of superintendent $ 3,600.00 Salary of assistant superintendent 2,000.00 Salary of bookkeeper and stenographer 1,600.00 Salary of chaplain 600.00 Salary of physician 1,200.00 Salary of five grade managers 8,000.00 Employes' wages 18,000.00 Fuel, electric light, water supply and boiler house expenses 1 5,000.00 Board, dining-room expenses and kitchen supplies . . 24,000.00 Clothing, bedding and furniture 8,000.00 Library books, periodicals and papers, school books and stationery, medicine, paints, oils and druggists supplies, telephone, telegraph, postage and office supplies, fugitives, freight and express, incidental expenses, traveling expenses and music and amuse - ments 4,000.00 Equipping trade departments 1,000.00 Permanent and general repairs of the administration and all the grade buildings, repair of boiler and coal house, smoke stack, brick tunnel, new mains for part of water system, two new high pressure boil - ers, new hot water tank, resetting five boilers, ce - ment and brick work, etc 12,000.00 $99,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">332 In submitting the above report I have endeavored to recite the facts as briefly as possible. During the six months which I have served as superintendent I have given the management my per - sonal and undivided attention. I have made a careful and con - scientious study of the institution and all that pertains to it and believe the state is doing a great work in maintaining the State Industrial School. The financial management of a state institu - tion requires the best economic efforts to be exercised in all the avenues of purchase and use of supplies. The management, control and direction of the work in all departments call for con - scientious endeavor and executive ability of a high order. TWe object and intent of the work done in the Industrial school is to reclaim the boy, and I know of no higher or nobler work which man can be engaged upon. It shall be my constant aim and desire while I am superintendent to so conduct the school that it may rank with the best in our country and its work meet the expectations and approval of the people of the state. In clos - ing I desire to express my appreciation of the kindness and cour - tesies extended to me by the governor and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings during our official relations. Very respectfully submitted, J. V. Beghtol, Superintendent. CONCLUSION. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>