<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA	Twenty-First Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska School for the Blind To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Twenty -First Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THK Nebraska School for the Blind NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">N. C. Abbott - Superintendent Lillian Abbott _ — - - Matron Claude Watson - Physician E. C. COOK - History and Mathematics Clark Bruce _ Piano Tuning, Broom Making JENNIE E. JOHNSON „ Primary Ruth Sexton _ Literature and Geography Naomi Enyeart Organ and Advanced Piano Mildred O. Hanks Voice and Piano Henry J. Gierau .Violin and Beginners' Piano Catharine Bosworth Domestic Science Jennie Hughey ___ Supervisor Fannie Bone _ .'-..- Supervisor C. F. Oston Typewriting </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Q I I ■ w^ - ./- I s 4 X o ■ c i X I BE </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 413 NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND Nebraska City, Nebraska To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions, Howard Kennedy, Henry Gerdes and Silas A. Holcomb: Gentlemen: It is my pleasure at this time as well as my duty under state laws to submit to you the Twenty-first Biennial Report of the Nebraska School for the Blind, the period ending with November 30, 1916. During the whole of this time I have had charge of the institution as superintendent. In order that you may the more readily follow this report I shall take up the various matters that deserve your attention under the following headings : 1. The Physical Plant To Date. 2. The Physical Plant As Contemplated. 3. The School And Its Progress. 4. Future Of The School. 5. Miscellaneous Items. 6. Necessary Appropriations. 7. Commission For The Blind, 8. Statistical Tables. 1. PHYSICAL PLANT TO DATE The plant is on the whole in much better physical condi - tion than it has ever been before. Nothing has been allowed to fall into decay and steady improvement has been fostered by the Board. By prompt repair when anything gets out of order and by constantly adding new improvements as we </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF feel the State can afford the expense, the whole plant is rendered sanitary and more pleasant for the people com - mitted to our charge. To be specific I shall devote a few words to the addition to laundry building, to repairs in general, to the installing of new equipment, and the purchase of a city block. (A) Addition to Laundry An addition to the laundry building, size 19x28' ■_• ft., two stories and basement, was decided upon by the Board and the superintendent during the winter two years ago. There was urgent necessity for additional room. Early in the spring, this addition was constructed under the direction of the Superintendent, costing the State slightly over two thousand dollars and giving great satisfaction to the employ - ees who were cramped for room. In the basement were placed an additional vacuum and &gt;-ater pump for the heating system, lathes, etc. ; on the second floor we had an extension to the laundry, and this, being built doubly strong with special precautions taken against the shaking of the floor, contains the mangle, two washers and an extractor. On the third floor there is a stor - age room for the surplus brooms manufactured in the broom shop. (B) Other Repairs Aside from the construction of the addition to the laundry, which was the chief improvement to our physical plant dur - ing the past biennium, the following has been accomplished : (1) The outside buildings have been painted in a gray slate color to conform to the scheme previously planned and spoken of in our Twentieth Biennial Report on page 7. Dur - ing each summer an average of two painters has been employed on the inside, freshening up halls and living rooms. (2) A high grade battleship linoleum, green in color, has been laid on the second floor, central part, and in the outer office. All of this linoleum was varnished with lino - leum lacquer and the whole pasted to the floor with a special </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 415 linoleum cement, so that the heat of summer will not cause it to buckle. Altogether this is the most satisfactory floor covering for institutional use that we have yet found. (3) Two dozen screen doors, windows and storm doors have been installed. (4) Oak flooring has been laid in the officers' dining room and the superintendent's apartments. (5) The chicken house has been repaired and made weather-tight. (6) Plumbing has been generally overhauled and the wash-room on third floor, unused for the past fifteen or six - teen years, has been completely overhauled with new equip - ment installed and made into satisfactory and much needed bath room for the teachers. (7) The partition on the third floor, central part, which separated the boys from the girls, was removed during the first summer and the material used in the new laundry build - ing spoken of elsewhere. The removal of this partition has added greatly to the appearance of the hall. The rooms for - merly occupied by girl pupils have been assigned to teachers and the girls have been placed in the west wing. The parti - tion was built many years ago when the crowded conditions, as well as the general morale, possibly, made it necessary. It has been almost two years since members of the Board suggested that it would be well to remove this partition and, after advising with them several times, we reached the con - clusion that it might well be done and I am very glad to report at this time that no detriment has been observed from the removal, but, in fact, benefit. (8) Last spring, during a heavy rain, our basement, kitchen and serving room, were flooded to the depth of six or eight inches through the failure of our sewer pipes to carry off the overflow. A small board had become wedged in the mouth of the main sewer pipe. That we may not suffer a like difficulty again I have had constructed a large manhole near the outside kitchen door. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">(C) New Equipment E Associated with these improvements to the phyiscal plant the comfort to our people might be classed the new furni - re and other equipment. This consists of one dozen rugs, three dozen mattresses, one dozen kindergarten chairs, thirty chiffoniers, fifty rocking chairs and a large industrial cabi - net. Most of the furniture mentioned was constructed under the direction of Warden W. T. Fenton at the State Peniten - tiary. I wish in this communication to congratulate the war - den on the excellent work turned out by his men and to thank the Board for their courtesy in allowing me to look over the various patterns and to secure for the pupils exactly what was needed. (D) New Land Purchased bFor several years past the State has rented, for raising tatoes, lots lying northeast of the institution and sloping the creek. This spring these lots were sold and we imme - diately began searching for other land that might be obtained. No other lots were available for rent, but we learned that Block 96, Greggsport addition, three blocks east and one block south of our institution, was for sale. After communica - tion with the Board, the result was that within a few weeks the same was purchased for four hundred fifty dollars. It is a slightly rolling tract of land containing more than an acre and a half, just such a piece of land as the State has been needing for a number of years. 2. PHYSICAL PLANT AS CONTEMPLATED The one large repair for the immediate future is a new roof in part on the old east wing. This new roof ought to be of slate or some similar material in order to conform to the covering on the remainder of the building. This wing Ci now covered with common wooden shingles, the only part f the building of such construction. A large deck which forms the center of this roof is in trood state of repair and will not demand much attention. The sides from this deck down to the gutter will need the new shingles referred to. In </seg>
            <seg id="p008">II ■ X ■ c 5 c X &lt; a: &lt; x H U s &lt; 0 H ■- i X 7. E </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 417 these days of fluctuating prices, it is almost impossible to give an intelligent estimate of the cost of any needed improve - ment. A year or so ago we estimated that this repair would cost in the neighborhood of six hundred dollars and anticipate that through the higher cost of labor and material it will reach a figure fifty percent higher if done during the ensuing summer. (A) New Fence* I Part of the fencing for the cow pasture and chicken ,rd at the northwest corner of the institution grounds is bad state of repair and ought to be thoroughly gone over id renewed in part. I suggest also in this connection that substantial wooden fence enclose a large part of the grove *st of the school building and that this ground be used for sture. (B) Minor Repairs Until the cost of all material reached such a high plane, I had intended to recommend that the State purchase paints and oils and renew with a new coat all of the paint on the outer walls of our buildings. High prices have caused me to change this recommendation. This is a time, it seems to me, when we ought to sing low in the matter of incurring expense. Our buildings can go, with no detriment to the property, for another year or two without fresh paint. 3. THE SCHOOL AND ITS PROGRESS I The school is divided into three departments, — Literary, sical and Industrial, all working together harmoniously the bringing out of the best in any pupil. Teachers are igned to a certain department, but if an emergency arises, ist in another. At the present Mr. Gierau and Miss Bos - rth each carry a class in the literary " department. The )ils in attendance range in age from five to sixty. A dent may carry work concurrently in all three depart - nts or be assigned to only one of the three, the assign - nt being determined by careful study of the individual I his needs. Those who come to us early in life, normal in </seg>
            <seg id="p010">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF every respect save as to sight, are given a trial in all three departments and in some cases a graduate has secured a diploma from each. Frequently adults come to us, too far advanced in years to take up successfully literary studies by means of a tactile punctographic system or musical studies. Such a one is assigned to the industrial department and fre - quently in the course of a year or two is able to go out and make a respectable living with a little broom shop or through other means. The name of our institution is in a way misleading. Our mother tongue unfortunately has no word that signifies both complete loss of sight and also such defective vision as handicaps one for ordinary pursuits. Our school is intended for these two classes. The word "blind" is the nearest ap - proach to a description and it is used in our official title, just as it is in other states. Yet it is misleading. Our courses are intended just as much for those whose eyesight is defec - tive in such a degree as to prevent their securing an educa - tion in ordinary channels as it is for those totally blind. In the course of time this information may reach every part of our State but it is a slow process of education when our name itself is misleading. (A) Literary Department The course of study for the literary department follows as closely as the peculiar conditions will admit the line of work laid down by the state department for the common schools. From year to year we vary the actual work offered, dependent upon the character and advancement of those in attendance. Reading, writing, spelling, English, arithmetic, geography, history, physiology, typewriting in progressive degrees of difficulty furnish the subjects pursued in the grades. In the high school courses is added such work in higher mathematics — algebra and geometry — as can be han - dled ; advanced work in composition and interpretation of English; the sciences corrolated and illustrated by specimens and experiments and history pursued in its broader aspects. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 419 (a) Literary Teachers The teachers in this department are E. C. Cook. Jennie E. Johnson, C. F. Orton and Ruth Sexton. Einar G. Niel - sen, one of the advanced pupils, is assisting, as a normal training course, without compensation, in some literary work. Mr. Cook has been connected with the institution for twenty - two years ; Miss Johnson for seventeen years ; Mr. Orton for four years; and Miss Sexton for three years. Mr. Cook and Miss Johnson are totally blind and are graduates of this institution in which they are now honored teachers. I wish at this point to make acknowledgement of suggestions offered at my request for this report by each of these teachers. Some of these suggestions I have embodied with slight changes and others unchanged, adopting their ideas as my own. (b) Retirement of Mary F. Morton Last spring the school lost from this department a most devoted teacher, Miss Mary French Morton, who had spent many years in this her chosen work. Of a distinguished family — a family culture and ideals — Miss Morton brought to our school much more than mere scholarship. Her influ - ence over the pupils, and especially over the girls who came close to her, was ideal. It was a genuine grief to us all when Miss Morton, through ill-health, was compelled to resign the position which she had so admirably filled and to which she was giving her best endeavor. (c) Tactile Reading and Writing In our school we use the New York Point system of punc - tographic reading and writing, described in detail by me in an earlier report. This system is much better than none, though no tactile invention can compare with sight-read - ing. Enormous expense is ever present. A Bible in New York Point consists of eleven enormous volumes worth five dollars each. The possibility that this system may soon be discarded renders the situation worse. From Miss Johnson I have secured information as to the present status of tactile </seg>
            <seg id="p012">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF writing and printing, as well as its historical evolution which I submit. (d) Evolution of Tangible Type The first tangible type was the raised print, the charac - ters being modeled after the Roman letters. Later there was devised for the use of the blind a system of raised dots, which was superior to the raised print, or Line Letter as it was called, in that it could be written as well as printed. Ftom time to time, both in Europe and America, these two original types have undergone various modifications. Line Letter and its modification, Moon Type (because they can - not be written) have been almost entirely displaced by the modified forms of the raised dot system ; namely, English Braille, American Braille, and New York Point. (e) Disadvantage of Diverse Systems This diversity of punctographic systems gives rise to certain disadvantages. Perhaps chief of these is the fact that the necessity of publishing the same books and maga - zines in three different systems gives to the blind considerably less reading matter than could be supplied were there a universal type. Also, a pupil who is transferred from one school to another is frequently hindered in his work by having to learn a system of reading and writing different from that employed in the school from which he came. (f) Agitation for Single Type With the hope of eliminating these conditions, the adop - tion of a single type was suggested as far back as 1890, the assumption of the agitators being that all other existing sys - tems would give way to the uniform type. Tn 1905, at the Saginaw meeting of the American Association of Workers for the Blind, a committee was appointed, known as the Uni - form Type Committee, whose duty it was to make thorough investigation of the various tactile prints and to secure, if possible, a universal type. For several years little progress was made, but in 1911 an active campaign was begun. At the Jacksonville convention of the A. A. W. B., 1913, the Uniform </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 421 Type Committee recommended the adoption of the British Braille alphabet and the American Braille capital prefix, with such other modifications as the committee might deem advan - tageous, the development of the whole to he. known as the Standard Dot System. The above recommendation was adopted by the association. (k) Uniform Type Commission In 1915 there was created the Uniform Type Commission whose chief duty is to secure the adoption of the Standard Dot System. To accomplish this, so the editor of the Ziegler and superintendents of institutions predict, will require sev - eral years. There are those who maintain that the intro - duction of the Standard Dot would not displace the three systems already in general use, but would merely become an additional system, thus making more complex the problem of furnishing the blind with literature. It is further argued that the books and apparatus for writing now employed rep - resent the outlay of large sums of money ; hence to discard and replace them with the apparatus necessary for the teach - ing of a new system is another phase of the question to which some are giving serious consideration. It is desired that a single type be adopted not merely in our own country, but throughout the English-speaking world. At present the realization of this hope seems doubtful, as the English do not regard the proposed new system as superior to their own British Braille. A meeting of the Uniform Type Commission was held in New York on September 7 of the present year. At this conference it was explained that certain recommenda - tions have been made to the English relative to a few changes in the British Braille, which are thought to be advisable. The English have appointed a committee to investigate the matter. In spite of the doubtful situation, a few of the institutions are beginning to teach English Braille in some of the grades. Since in our school we are waiting until some definite decision has been reached, our attitude may, perhaps, be expressed in the familiar couplet — "Be not the first by whom the new is tried, Nor yet the last to lay the old aside." </seg>
            <seg id="p014">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF (h) Spelling Our instruction in spelling is carried from the beginning right along with the work in reading, English and type - writing. The texts in reading that we use have groups of words at the head of the different exercises and these are used as a basis for the spelling tests. When a pupil has advanced far enough to take up typewriting (and we begin this sort of work while the pupil is still young) an effort is made that he may learn such words as are used in ordinary letter-writing. (i) English Great emphasis is laid by our teachers on oral English, as a blind person does as a rule much less writing than his seeing brother. From the beginning our teachers try to cor - rect the errors in speech that creep into the habits of our pupils. Later on the students are led to write paragraphs and short themes on interesting subjects. Outsiders, who have seen exhibitions of our work at the State Fair and elsewhere, have been surprised at the proficiency of our pupils' writing and their fluency in Mother Tongue. (j) Arithmetic Arithmetic, or number work, in the primary grades of the school is entirely oral. The beginners are taught to count and then to combine numbers using concrete objects in the various operations. As soon as the pupils have become suffi - ciently advanced in their point reading and writing they are given arithmetic text books, but their work continues to be unwritten. The blind child becomes much more proficient in mathematics than the sighted child, because he is independent of paper and pencil. Concentration usually becomes second - nature to a sightless child. (k) Geography Geography seems to be one of the most difficult subjects to teach to the sightless. The seeing child, sepecially in pri - mary geography, depends so much on his observations. The </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 423 blind child, being deprived of these, has, sometimes, rather queer conceptions. He is deprived of the many pictures which make geography such a live subject to the sighted child. It is true our pupils have maps, raised maps and sec - tional maps, but they are limited in number and show few details. Their cost is excessive. In spite of these handicaps, the blind pupils gain a thorough knowledge of geography and can point out and name the different states in the United States, for instance, almost as quickly as the seeing pupil. (1) Physiology Physiology in the 8th grade is brought out as a con - tinuation of the work done in the Hygiene and Physical Cul - ture classes of the lower grades. We emphasize the idea of personal hygiene, urging and in some cases requiring exercises for the general developement of the body. We are heavily handicapped in not being able to take advantage of the illus - trated lessons as given in print texts. Models are a great help in this connection and furnish a tangible working basis. As in the other branches of school work we conduct spelling classes along with our recitation work, a great help in familiar - izing blind pupils with new words. (m) History In a simple, informal way, the study of history is begun in the lowest grades; the pupils are made familiar with the myths and legends and hero-stories necessary to a proper understanding of literature. The subject is taken up in a formal way in the grammar grades, McMaster's text books being used as a guide, and culminates, in the eighth grade, in a comprehensive survey of American History and Civics. It is the aim to make this course complete in itself, while, at the same time, it is made preparatory to a more extensive course pursued in the high school. The interest for this sub - ject is keen in all grades, and the progress highly commend - able. I </seg>
            <seg id="p016">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF (n) Typewriting The only way in which sightless persons can correspond with the seeing world is through the use of the typewriter. With that in mind, typewriting is made an important part of the schooling of our pupils. Not quite so much ground is covered in the work here as in the ordinary school or college. Everything is committed to memory before the writing is started as otherwise they would be obliged to stop and read with their fingers and then place them on the proper keys again. The work for the past two years has been taken from the "Underwood 'From Sight to Touch' " method which is highly satisfactory. To the more advanced pupils, instructions in letter-writing, dictation from a speech of a well-known speaker, etc., have been given at different times. Accuracy is considered first. During the beginning year they are taught the keyboard thoroughly. During the second year they are expected to gain in speed. All work must be perfect before passed upon, which instills a desire in the operator for accuracy. A test was given by dictating from some entirely new matter and was copied at the rate of 46 words a minute; the time for writing was thirty minutes; and a penalty of three was deducted for each error made. Several hovered around the 40-word-a-minute mark. (o) Reading Aloud Supplementing the regular formal classes in the literary department are the periods devoted by the seeing teachers to reading aloud to groups of pupils. Standard books are chosen and these various courses are intended both for recrea - tion and the widening of the horizon of the pupils. (B) Department of Music Ever since Valentin Hauy, more than a century ago, conceived the idea that musical studies might sucessfully be taught blind students in schools especially equipped, music has been a prominent part in the curricula. Our depart - ment is in charge of Henry Gierau, violin and orchestra; </seg>
            <seg id="p017">I I j 7. 4 I &lt; IB 'A z I; i c ■ E E a ■ — </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS Mildred O. Hanks, voice and piano; Naomi Enyeart, piano and organ. Mr. Gierau is a graduate of this school. These teachers have furnished me material and kindly assisted me in this report. (a) Teaching Methods People in general have heard blind musicians play or sing; or at least have heard of their performances. Rarely, however, will you find a person who holds any other opinion than that they must sing or play by ear. Such is not the case. With the exception of a few freaks (such as are found in all classes of society) they are guided in the interpreta - tion of a composition by notes which have been previously studied and memorized. The question naturally arises: How is this possible without written characters? It is true that the ordinary staff notation must be abandoned; but a substi - tute has been devised by which they are able to read notes and from which they derive the same impressions as the musician with good eyes derives from his printed sheet. Just as text books and all kinds of literature are now printed in a tac - tile system consisting of dots arranged in various positions to represent the different letters of the alphabet, so in a similar manner musical characters are notated, making it possible for a page of this embossed music to express all that is seen in the duplicate of staff notation; such as notes, rests, fortes, pianos, crescendos, diminuendos, etc. With such a system, the blind are able to take their place side by side with their competitor, the sighted teacher or concert per - former, with the assurance that they possess all that printed notes can render. Our school, therefore, with this as founda - tion, is able to maintain high standards in all its musical departments, such as violin, voice, piano and organ. (b) The Violin The violin, though one of the most delicate and difficult of instruments to learn, can be successfully taught to the blind ; and when once mastered, affords them much pleasure and in instances forms the basis for earning a livelihood. At first, progress is very slow, especially in the case where the </seg>
            <seg id="p019">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF sight is very defective for every minute detail must be gained entirely through the sense of touch ; but by perseverance and persistent efforts, the final result is the same as that of the pupil with perfect vision. Seven are at present taking up the violin, following a regular course in Sevcik, Kayser, Maza, etc., together with high class solo compositions. (c) The Orchestra A school orchestra consisting of thirteen members is main - tained with an instrumentation of violins, 'cello, clarinet, cor - nets, trombone, drums, and piano. Besides being a source of entertainment on school programs as well as on occasions in the city or neighboring towns, it is an essential factor in the education of any pupil studying music, developing quali - ties which are hard to gain in any other way. Operatic selec - tions and works from good composers are taken up throughout each school year. (d) The Piano In the beginner's piano work, there are at the present time seven, all, with the exception of one, using the New York Point System of musical notation. These pupils are taught the fundamental work of scale and finger exercises and works of Loeschorn and Hanon. In the more advanced work on this instrument, exercises are kept up and the serious study of compositions and more pretentious pieces of well-known composers form the basis of the work. (e) The Organ Our school has owned a fine pipe organ for the past twelve years and excellent results have been obtained from it. Some of our graduates have served successfully as organ - ists in large churches. This instrument is taken up after considerable proficiency has been attained on the piano or other instrument. Teaching the blind how to play the organ is essentially the same as teaching sighted pupils. The same composers are studied and the same technical work is used. Possibly the progress of the students is slightly slower due </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 427 chiefly to the fact that a large part of the music must be dictated. As in the piano work they memorize while playing with one hand and reading with the other — a process which, to those unfamiliar with the method, seems very slow. How - ever, memorizing one hand at a time is now being taught to normal students by many teachers. We now have three pupils studying the organ. Each is given a twenty-minute lesson daily. (f) Voice In the voice department, there are four girls and one boy. First, breathing exercises are given, the simple vocali - zation and the exercises of Sieber and Concone, and later songs by well known composers. The accuracy of pitch in the blind while studying voice is very remarkable. (g) Chorus We have in the school three choruses, one of these a little people's chorus of eleven children ranging from five to thirteen years of age. These little people learn children's songs of Jessie Gaynor, Orth, Johns and others, entirely by rote. We also have a chorus of ten girls which meets twice a week and studies and learns four-part works of good composers. The most advanced and extensive work is done by the older mixed chorus of fourteen young women and men. This chorus meets three times a week and learns, also by rote, four-part numbers by composers of well known repute. This chorus learned during the year 1915-16 twelve good four-part works and also know word and note perfect about one hundred hymns. (C) Industrial Department The work along industrial lines is carried by Clark Bruce, totally blind, who has been a teacher here for twenty-seven years, and Catharine Bosworth, who has been connected with the school for six years. I feel that I can best describe the work done in this department by following the courses taught by these instructors. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF (a) Miss Bosworth's Work During the biennium the industrial room has been removed to more adequate quarters and a cabinet added for the storing of materials used in this department. Three tables were installed, one for the older girls and boys and a kindergarten table supplied with a new set of chairs. The object of the work for beginners in this department is to cultivate the use of the hands. Many otherwise normal children are held back on account of their inability to use their hands, a very necessary item in the learning of the point system. Bead work, handling and fashioning articles from beads, C:quaints the child with the handling of small objects very milar to the points in their system of reading and writing. The small articles made by them aid in the development of a mental image, which in most blind people is very vague. Clay modeling, as a definite course, is not offered. We use plasticine, a prepared clay, to further aid in the develop - ment of the hands and as a tangible method of teaching the physical aspect of the commonest objects. Finger play, as used in all other kindergartens, is also a very great aid in developing a mental image for actual objects, and furnishes amusement as well as valuable training for the child. The older girls are taught plain sewing. They sew on buttons, darn stockings, patch clothing and do many other practical things necessary to the upkeep of their own ward - robes. Crocheting and knitting and other forms of fancy work are taught from a renumerative standpoint as well as for the other benefits derived. Some of our girls are prac - tically self-supporting while in school as well as after leaving from their efforts along these lines. (b) Work Under Mr. Bruce The male portion of our student body have an excellent opportunity, by the exercise of intelligence and industry, to acquire a trade that will render them self-supporting on the outside. Of ordinary trades such as may be acquired by an </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS adult whose blindness has reached him in later years, there are broom-making and netting, that go very well together. In the course of a year or two, practically any blind man can learn to make brooms successfully and to net hammocks, fly - nets, etc. It depends naturally upon the man himself, his business ability, and capacity to get along with people, whether one who has acquired the physical knack of making these articles can go out into the world and be successful as an individual business man. A number of our people are proving themselves successful in these lines as I shall show later on in this report. The most satisfactory trade for a blind man, if he has a keen ear and a pleasant personality, is tuning. It takes at least two years for a student who devotes himself to the work to earn a diploma in the tuning department. (D) Closing Exercise* So much then for the description in general of our school work. At the close of each school-year we have fitting exer - cises. These consist first of the program by our juniors on the Thursday preceding the graduating exercises. On the second Sunday in June, the annual sermon is preached to our people. Our effort is to secure a representa - tive minister from out in the State selecting members from different denominations from year to year. During the past biennium, Rev. W. H. Buss, a Congregationalist of Fremont, and Rev. T. W. Jeffry, a Methodist of Lincoln, have given us eloquent sermons. On Monday evening there is the grand concert under the direction of the teachers in the department of music. The graduating exercises are held on Tuesday evening, the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions being pres - ent in full force on both occasions during the past biennium. (a) Class of 1915 From the Eighth Grade— Albert H. Cozad, Einar G. Niel - sen, Dale Walter Jones. From the Piano Department — Leona Jennings. From the Tuning Department — Einar G. Nielsen. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">LECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF (b) Clua of 1916 In Organ — William Koch. In Tuning — Arthur J. Floyd, Juan Mestas. 4. FUTURE OF THE SCHOOL So far as I can judge of the future, the school ought to be conducted along the same lines practically on which it now is running. The State is giving the pupils about all that they can acquire. Possibly if our attendance were thrice or four times as much as it is there might be an occasion to branch out and add new departments. But already the cost is very heavy and instead of increasing the cost to the State through additional departments or innovations to the scholastic work, I should be glad if some way were apparent to cut down expenses without curtailing the amount and character, — with - out lowering the high standards, which we have maintained. At the same time I feel that there are certain expendi - tures that ought to be made for the school in order to keep our work up to what is being done in adjoining states for the blind. (A) Additional Books There ought to be an expenditure of at least one hundred dollars for ordinary library books that our teachers may have a larger field from which to read aloud to the pupils as well as for general reference. Our tactile books are built up stead - ily through the grant of the federal government, but there has been no steady building up of the ordinary books so that those which we have are in many cases ready to be discarded through use, or have been read so many times that they are lacking in interest. (B) Pwckue of Phonoptieon If the new invention whereby blind persons are able to read ordinary print should prove on investigation to be all that it is recommended, our school ought to secure the appara - tus and begin instruction along this line. Already, I have been informed other schools are handling such classes. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 4.;i This mechanical eye is called the Crystal Phonopticon and Is described in detail in the Scientific American, Vol. 113, No. 7, by E. F. Dodd. Light passing through a lense over selenium crystals causes the crystals to give forth tones which vary in accordance with the black background. These tones are carried to the ears of the blind reader by electric telephonic apparatus. A blind person of acute hearing will learn in a very short time to distinguish the respective sounds of the letters of the alphabet and thus will be able to read any ink print book that a seeing person is able to read. The invention is still in its infancy and needs further testing before its worth is ascertained. It holds out a great hope for the sightless. This invention has been worked out largely by Dr. F. C. Brown of the state university of Iowa to whom great praise is due. At the annual convention of the American Association of Workers for the Blind held at San Francisco July, 1915, they made a test of the invention on thirty blind persons and all those tested save two or three were able to make the distinction in sound so as to tell such letters as, a w, 1, o, and i. (C) New Typewriters Since there has been a greater demand for typewriting lessons this year, I would recommend the purchase of at least two typewriters for the school, costing approximately one hundred and ten dollars, so that all may have more work along this important line. (D) Player-Piano and Models I also recommend the purchase for the school of a player - piano and models for the same. The cost of equipment along this line will reach approximately eight hundred dollars. In this connection I may say that more than one million player - pianos are now being manufactured yearly in America . The output is becoming steadily greater. Last year one of our strongest pupils went out as a tuner and from him I have had a number of letters telling of his success. He has been able to make a living and in addition is building up a clientele </seg>
            <seg id="p025">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF that will in a few years allow him to lay money away in the bank every month. I quote from a recent letter of his deal - ing particularly with his unfamiliarity with the player-piano : "It is the one obstacle which seems to block the path of my tuning business. There are so many player-pianos in use, as the sales records of every piano firm will show, that a tuner cannot hope to be successful unless he understands the mechanism of them. Very frequently I am confronted with this kind of a job, and am forced to confess that I know nothing about the piano player. Inasmuch as a large per cent of the boys who leave school take up this profession for a livelihood, it seems to me that every effort should be put forth to make the tuning department of our school complete." 5. MISCELLANEOUS ITEMS Under this heading I shall group a number of items that seem to me worthy of your attention as they have a bearing upon the success of the work prosecuted here and yet cannot come well under the other headings of our outline. (A) Physical Health Every effort is made by us to safeguard the health of those who come to us. There is a competent supervisor for the boys and another for the girls who look after their wel - fare, giving them medicine for slight ailments, looking after the care of their clothing, and nursing them in ordinary sickness. Whenever a pupil appears under the weather or reports to a supervisor of some indisposition, something is immediately done. Dr. Claude Watson, physician to the school, is ready at a summons by supervisor or superintendent to visit the institution and prescribe. Frequently he appears at the institution without summons to look over the general condi - tions. In addition to this there are regular periods for exer - cising under the supervision of one of our instructors. (B) Elementary Phytical Culture We have been especially well pleased with some work along this line carried by Miss Sexton for the little folk. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 433 A class of pupils comprising the first three grades, which include some children of the average age and physique that we ordinarily find in these grades and then a few who are backward and have not developed as they should, has been organized and dubbed the "Elementary Physical Culture" class. These children spend a forty minute period each day, out of doors, unless the weather is too stormy. When the weather will permit their getting out at all, they are taken out for a short walk at least, and the rest of the period spent in doors. They have been taught several little song-games, or folk-dances. Games are chosen, of course, in which the players keep close to each other, preferably in a circle, so that the totally blind children do not "get lost." Part of the period is devoted to running. It is a pathetic fact, but true, that some of the little pupils who come to us, do not know how to run. The teacher takes them out to an open, level space on the campus, where there are no obstacles and then as the teacher runs ahead blowing a whistle, 30 that they have a definite sound to follow, they try to catch her. Since the definite aim of our school is to teach the blind pupil to engage as nearly as he can in the same physical activities as does his sighted brother, this exercise is of great importance. A few simple calisthenics are given to the class - individual exercises for the correction of special defects, being given to certain pupils. (C) Christian Endeavor Each Sunday morning at eight o'clock we have a very interesting and inspiring Christian Endeavor meeting. The work, which is nearly all done by the pupils, is copied in the New York Point system and this takes considerably longer time than is used in the regular Christian Endeavor socie - ties . Nothing sectarian is permitted at these meetings. Up to a few years ago we were not engaged in active work along this line, but now we send delegates to district and state conventions, write letters, ask questions, and get information and the views of other societies. We find that we can accomplish more by doing this. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">4::-! SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF We have need of fewer committees than the ordinary societies. Besides the officers, president, vice-president, secre - tary, treasurer, and corresponding secretary, we have only three committees, prayer-meeting, look-out, and missionary and good literature. Out of the total enrollment of approxi - mately fifty in our school, we have about twenty-four active members and about twelve associate members. (D) Library The library is a very important part of a school, even though it is small. Our library is not large but it is plenty large to meet the needs of the school. It had been the custom for years to save all books even though they could not be used and were left on the shelves and had gathered a great deal of dust. It seemed to be a much better way to discard the old books in order to have room for the new books that are purchased. Accordingly during the summer months, while the pupils were away on vacation, the library was thoroughly gone over and all books that could not be used in anyway were gathered and sold to the junk man for old paper. The library has 31 cases, averaging seven shelves to the case; 21 for point books and the remainder for print books, such as histories, encyclopedias, etc. (E) Former Students' Success in the World The term "successful" is here used in its broadest sense, being applied not only to those who are rendering service which brings direct returns in dollars and cents, but also to those who are making themselves so useful in the home that they are saving to their parents or relatives money which would otherwise have to be expended in the employment of outside help. Of the various lines of work pursued by the blind, the greater number of our boys seem to find tuning the most remunerative. In consequence of their thorough industrial training, together with pluck and industry on the part of the individual, some of our graduates have become very success - ful tuners, having extended routes and a business that pays. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 435 Some of our best known and most prosperous graduates engaged in this line of work are to be found at Beatrice, Blair, Broken Bow, Columbus, and Omaha. One of our former pupils is employed as tuner by a large firm in Chicago. Another is an enterprising piano salesman in Auburn, Ne - braska. Still others are gaining a livelihood by making brooms. One man has a little shop at Auburn ; another at Springfield ; a third at Petersburg and a fourth here in Nebraska City. Three young men, at one time students here, have made business ventures not frequently undertaken by the blind. One of these three is conducting a harness shop at Dixon. The other two have entered into partnership and have started a novelty store at Grant. In both instances the ventures are proving successful. Two of our boys, after completing the work here, took courses at the University of Nebraska. One of these is now a prosperous magazine agent in Seattle, Washington. The other, having added to his university training a thorough course in osteopathy, is an able doctor and lecturer. . Another of our graduates is a Baptist minister. Another is employed as industrial teacher in the school for the blind in Kansas. One of the most successful grain and coal dealers in the state is located at Auburn. He is a wide-awake business man, and we are glad to claim him as a former student of our school. In one of Omaha's best picture shows, performing on both pipe-organ and piano, is a young man who is one of our graduates. It is gratifying to know that he was one of a dozen or more applicants, of whom all the others were sighted, and the selection was based purely on the merits of those seeking the place. The teacher of music and elocution in the public schools of Geneva is a young woman who is a graduate of our school. Particular mention may be made of three of our girls, two of whom live in Lincoln and one in Omaha, who are supporting themselves through the sale of useful and fancy articles which they make. Two of our former pupils, sisters, residing near Hershey, assist so efficiently with the general house-work that their relatives have come to realize they could ill afford to </seg>
            <seg id="p029">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF dispense with their services. Another of our graduates, liv - ing at Wolbach, has, because of her usefulness in the home, become the chief stay and help of her widowed mother. Some of the girls who have married are successfully meeting the responsibilities which devolve upon them in managing their own homes. One, whose home is at Blair, not only performs her household duties, but is also a very enterprising agent, handling various toilet articles. This catalog of our successful former students is by no means comprehensive, but merely suggestive as to what has been accomplished by some and what may reasonably be expected in the future. (F) The Matter of Pensions As indicated in other places in this report, three of our teachers have been connected with this institution for long periods. One has taught here twenty-seven years; another, twenty-two ; and a third, seventeen years. These three teach - ers are totally blind. While for the present they are doing ex - cellent work and are able to perform the service for which they receive compensation to your satisfaction and to mine, the time must come when, under the laws of nature, they will be compelled to give up their class-work. The compensation which these teachers have received during their many years of service has been very modest. Others have been depen - dent upon them for support. It has been humanly impossible for them to lay aside during the nine months of each year while they have been teaching and for which they have received pay, a sum sufficient for their support during the summer vacation and for the years of age when their earn - ing power will be gone. I have been thinking seriously of this matter, and especially since this era of enormously high prices has come and with it no corresponding increase in salary. I respectfully suggest that the time is ripe for the State to consider the matter of pensions for the faithful employees who spend their lives in the service of the State at the various institutions. The details of any such pension system would </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 437 need to be worked out with care. Such a system, if adopted, should be hedged about with restrictions and conditions that would not lead readily to abuse. As a basis from which to figure there is a pension law as applied to the teachers of Omaha; a pension system in Minnesota; the pension systems of certain railroads and other service corporations ; and the pension system of the United States army and navy. It seems to me reasonable that the State should provide somewhat for those whose earning days are over. If two-thirds of the amount of the salaries last earned were to be paid to each person who, after a service of twenty-five or more years, was compelled to stop work, the amount would never be burden - some upon the tax-payers and at the same time such action would promote an ever increasing efficiency and faithfulness ; so that the State, through this simple act of justice, would in the end be more than re-imbursed. 6. NECESSARY APPROPRIATIONS In these days of fluctuating prices, with the cost of living, the price of staple articles of food, daily advancing, it is almost impossible for an executive officer, no matter how hard he try, to look forward to the future, to tell what amount of money will be needed to conduct an institution for the ensuing biennium. I have gone over the figures which I now submit to you carefully no less than six times and the result is my deliberate judgment. The last legislature appro - priated $49,600 for the present biennium. With this amount we are going to be able to finish the period, without a deficit, I believe, though the cost of running the school during the past year has been largely increased over what any of us expected when I submitted estimates two years ago. The figures that I now submit are somewhat in excess of the estimate for two years ago, an increase of almost thirty-three per cent. Unless the cost of living materially decreases during the biennium, I do not see how we can possibly get through on less appropriations: </seg>
            <seg id="p031">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 7. COMMISSION FOR THE BLIND Though strictly speaking the work of the Commission tor the Blind is not properly a part of this report, its activities are so closely connected with the school that I have thought it wise to incorporate a brief record of the work accomplished in this report rather than write one entirely separate. (A) Organization The Commission for the Blind came into existence through an act of the legislative session of 1915, House Roll Number 50, appropriating $2,000 for the Relief of the Blind, and designating how it should be expended in a broad and general investigation of the condition of the sightless of the State and the gathering of statistics for further assistance, if necessary, for this class of people, in addition to rendering immediate aid as was deemed wise. The executive committee of the Nebraska Association of Workers for the Blind and the superintendent of the school for the blind were named as an advisory committee to act in co-operation with the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions in determining the expenditures from this fund, no amount to be expended from the same without the approval of the Board. This advisory committee shortly after the passage of the act resolved itself into the Nebraska Commission for the Blind and adopted a tentative form of administration which, upon the approval of the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions with certain modifications, became the actual body for administration, each step having first the approval of the supervisory board. I. II. II. Maintenance a. Salaries and Wages $28,800.01 b. General Repairs 4,000.0i c. Other Maintenance 29,700.01 Equipment and Furniture 2,200.0i Permanent Improvements: roof, walks, etc l,000.0&lt; Total $65,700.01 165,700.01 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 439 (B) Field Afent at Work The first step toward carrying out the purpose of the law was the appointment of Lyle A. Harris, a graduate of this school who is totally blind as field agent. The superinten - dent of the school for the blind was named executive officer under the title superintendent of the commission for the blind. Beginning August 1, 1915, after consulting with the others interested, Mr. Harris went out into the field to carry on the work assigned him. With commendable zeal he has traveled from one end of the State to the other gathering information wherever it might be found and submitting his results to the superintendent of the commission, in weekly reports now on file and which have been looked over from time to time by the members of the supervisory board. Through personal visitation in perhaps one-fifth of the larger communities of the State, correspondence, interview - ing of relatives, friends, ministers, commercial men, educa - tors and through speaking before schools, churches, and other assemblies wherever he might get a hearing. Mr. Harris has obtained the names and a comprehensive idea of the capacities of four hundred four persons within the State either totally blind, or with such defective vision as to be handicapped in the pursuit of a livelihood or an education. Of about fifty more he has secured some word, but not with sufficient accuracy to be certain in classifying them as dependent or independent. (C) Dependence and Independence Self-supporting blind he has found in every pursuit it would seem possible to a blind person. There are in Ne - braska blind farmers ; gardeners ; stock-men ; hotel-keepers ; restaurant-men ; confectioners ; cigar-vendors ; clothiers ; gro - cers ; coal and grain merchants ; music and novelty dealers ; broom-makers; harness-makers; music-teachers; osteopaths; general salesmen ; solicitors ; teachers ; printers, both of tex - tile and print; concert players and singers; piano tuners; managers of livery lines ; news correspondents ; general house - keepers ; conductors of bands and orchestras ; news agents ; and one engaged in a matrimonial bureau. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF This is the classification made by him of the blind : It is highly gratifying that there is such a large number as these figures disclose of the entirely self-supporting blind people within our State. Their success ought to be a stimulus to others. Since it will largely be impossible to assist those in the third class, — those who are entirely dependent, — as their dependence springs generally from physical or mental difficul - ties which, added to loss of sight, may not be overcome, it should be the second-class, — those partiall independent, — that should be encouraged to increase their capacities and with increased power to increase their independence. If through a little assistance now they can acquire independence per - manently it will be a grand thing and a noble accomplishment for the public generally. (D) Home-Teaching In addition to spreading information among the sightless of the possibilities at the school for the blind in the way of education and in gathering the data spoken of, Mr. Harris has done some home-teaching. This is a field that may be cultivated to a great extent possibly if the State continues to appropriate for such activity. In other states this field is pretty comprehensively covered. There are undoubtedly many people of defective vision in this State who on account of home conditions or other reasons cannot get away to attend the sessions at the school for the blind. Some teaching within the home is often a veritable God-send to such. It opens up AS TO DEPENDENCE Male i Female I , Total Independently self-supporting Partially self -supporting Entirely dependent 107 56 22 65 69 129 121 154 Total 248 24* 156 156 404 404 AS TO AGE Male : Female Totaf Adults .... Minors .... 204 44 124 32 328 76 Total 248 404 156 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 441 vistas and gives employment to those who would otherwise be brooders, with every tendency toward melancholy. (e) Assistance Financial In one case there has been a loan of seventy-five dollars to a worthy blind man, who has been overcome by a series of unexpected reverses. This money has assisted in starting a little broom-shop and it is hoped that the proprietor will be able within a year to repay the loan with a small per cent of interest. (f) The Future I am satisfied that the funds entrusted to the Board for this work have been worthily expended. For another bien - nium it is undoubtedly true that there will not be needed a field agent for full time. The statistics have been gathered and it will be necessary for us to devote ourselves to some other one or more of the great problems now being taken up by other states. For the work before us I recommend that the same amount as previously be appropriated for the Com - mission for the Blind — namly, two thousand dollars. ACKNOWLEDGEMENT OF THANKS In conclusion I again acknowledge my thanks to the loyal assistants in the school, — teachers and other employees; to our physician, Doctor Claude Watson ; to Miss Catharine Bos - worth, who acted for half the period as matron ; to my wife, Lillian, who both as matron and when not serving as an offi - cer, has been my chief adviser and confidant. The Governor and members of the Board I have felt at all times to be sympathetic and appreciative. The authority that is yours and that you have been entitled to exercise has been used in a manner implying helpfulness rather than masterfulness. I thank you sincerely for your kind assistance. All of which and the statistical tables serving as an appendix are respectfully submitted. N. C. Abbott, Superintendent. Nebraska City, Nebraska, November SO, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">I \IU.K 1. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Year For Year eudlnir eudiug Total MOVEMENT MOTKMKXT X&lt; v. :w. Nov. 30, for 1915 1916 Bienuium jZ f\ t7^~m! f\ t!~i m. f. t. M. P. T. M. F. T. I M. F. T. l'reseut at lH&gt;Kiuiiiug of period. Admitted: l'reseut at IK-Kiuniug of period. -'.S !•:) 51 31 20 il * a 51 -&gt; SI 51 31 20 51 L»- a ."1 Admitted : For first time.. ."&gt; :; |] ( 3 11 13 6 19 For first time. He admitted* I v 3 11 13 6 19 He admitted* _ _ _ ... 7 • IS 3 4 7 1O1O2U Total enrolliueut 40 31' "-• 42 -T IS 51 99 90 6 13 3 4 7 10 10 -JU Total enrollment 40 3-J 7." 42 IT t» 51 X) 'JO Discharged : Discharged : CrnciUHted - - 2 ..... 2 2 ...... 2 (iriiiliiiitwl - I 2 ..... 2 2 ..... 2 Transferred to other institutions 1 1 1 1 Transferred to other institutions 1 1 1 1 Expelled 1 _.... 1 1 — 1 2 — 2 bMM - l ...... 11 — 1 2 — 2 Ml sehool for various reasons I 8 10 IS 7 9 1« 15 19 34 Left scbool for various reasons S 10 18 7 9 ]« 15 19 34 Died _ _. 1 1 1 1 Oled _ _. 1 1 1 1 ToUl removal :&gt; S -M 1" '•' 1!' , 5 -'! 40 Total removal !&gt; 1J Jl 111 !&lt; l'.l , lit -Jl 40 Present at end of period 31 20 51 32 18 50 32 18 60 Present at end of period 31 20 51 32 18 50 ! 32 18 60 ■Includes all pupils who had attended previously this or a similar school. •Iniiiidea all pupils who had aitcn.lc.l previously this or a similar school. TABLE 11. \«.K OF FCP1M ADMITTED FOB FIB8T TIMK Kor Year For Year eiHliiii.' enililitf '!'ot:il For Year For Year t'lxlin^ ending Total Nov. 30, Not. 30, for AGE Sot. 30, Not. 30, for AGE fnr 1915 l'.'lt; Bienuium 1915 rut; Bienuium M. K. T M. F. T. M. F. T. M. r. T. M. F. T. I M. F. T. 5 years - 2 2 2 2 5 yearn 2 2 | 2 2 6 years!.-. - 1 — 1 1 1 2 ..... 2 7 years 1 1 1 III 1 2 8 ye«r» _ 1 1 _ 1 1 10 and under 16 years 1 1 ; 1 1 2 ..... 2 15 and under 21 years.. Over 21 years. 2 1 34 1 5j6 2 8 Totals t 3 8 8 3 11 1 13 6 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 443 TABLE III. NATIVITY OF PI I'll.* ADMITTED FOR FIBST TIME For Ve«r For Ye«r ending ending Total NATIVITY ill v. :w. Nov. :«&gt;, for Nehrnskn Initfil Smirs, ntber ihan N'elir«»ka Total liiitivt* Imrii Total fiTeiifii l&gt;or:i TABI.K IV. NATIVITY OF I'IHK\T&gt; OF PIPILS ADMITTED FOR I 1K&gt;I leun l urn U. F. T. *. F. T. M F. T. I '2 1 I 3 4 1 ■ :t &gt; 3 T 3 10 5 S 8 ra»ka t* liorn :i T .! 10 IJ .; ]£ tiorn 1 .. 1 _ Tamln .'. :; :: 11 ■ ii 19 For Year ending Xi v. :hi. Mi Knr Year ending Xi&gt;v. .10, 1918 Total for Blenuium NATIVITY OK PARENTS i. y. t. ! M. F. T. 11. F. T. M K. T M F. T. United States, both parents. Foreign, both parents Mixed 4 2 1 1 « 7 2 1 2 1 9 11 4 2 3 1 li Tottli I .1 I 2 11 14 5 ■ s </seg>
            <seg id="p037">I \lll I V. KI-olliKM t. OF I'l'PILS ADMITTED FOB FIRST TIlIK AM) OF ALL MFILS REMAIN IX. AT KMl OF 1LIK For Year For Year t-niliiiK t-niliiiK All Total UriiinintiiK COUNTY for n.iv. :;o. l'.ilti Uieuuluin r.'ii; M. K. T. M. r. T. M. K. T. M. F. T. TABLE VI. A&lt;iE AT WHICH ITP1IH ADMITTED FOR FIRST T1MK BECAME Niiv. :si&gt;, Xuv. .10. n»ir» nil a :\ I I n 11 13 0 19 32 18 BO Nebraska : Adams - Buffalo Butler . Cass Clay _ Cutter ... . Dakota .. . I 'i«lt;&lt;- Douglas Franklin Front Kt . Gage Greelej- _... Hall Hamilton . . Holt Jefferson . Kearney _ Knox Lancaster Otoe Pierce ..._ Platte - Richardson Saline _ „. ■ Sewanl Valley ___.._.. State of Wyoming 1 .... 1 1 1 1 .... 1 1 1 • Totals •"&gt; :t 1 1 X 1 ... 1 1 ... 1 1 ... 1 ... I 1 I T i i i i i i i i i ■2 i i i i i i .... i ................... i i 1 — 1 _ i l 1 1 2 ■i | n l :; l 4 1 -1 1 3 I 3 5 8 1 L' I 1 1 1 1 1 ... . 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 l :&gt; 3 i :: -J s 1112 1 i l 1 .... 1 l 1 l 1 1 l l 1 AGE Number P«r Cent M. F. T. M. r. T. i "onir*'tiit:tl 'i anil uiiilcr 10 ypari 1." nml umlrr 20 year*.. ill nni) M 4 4 2 1 5 2 8 21 03 21.(11 42.10 2 10.50 1050 1 .'&gt;.:«&gt; 5.30 I ;l &lt;&lt;&gt; tUt 42.10 ToUlu IS &lt;; 19 |»v4.-&gt; HI ..TO 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS I XIM.K VII. ASM1UKED CAISE OF DEFECT IN PIULS AIIMITTKI) FOB I IK.-I TIME Number Per Cent CAl'SB OF DEKKCT M. f. T. M. F. T. AcclUeut Ft'Vef .... Ophtbaliuia nfonatorum... 1'iiknowti TABLK VIII. EXTENT OK DEFECT IX PI MM VIIMITTF.1) FOK FIRST TIME EXTENT OF DEFECT Xo vision I Tartial \i»im 1 10 1T..T. ■".-.". 5-J..10 Tutnl&gt; a I ■ 1.73 100.00 4 4 I'l.OO _ 11.00 1 .! 1O..VI o.M 16.00 I 4 T l.V.Vi tUH 3W.30 4 15 -'1.(10 .-,..-&lt; p -ur&lt;p Total* ■ u i!&gt; U8.ni) :k;.iiu 100.00 Xuuil«er lVr t'ent m. r. r. m. r. t. •.I Jl.MI ■.•IJ..-MI 47.JII </seg>
            <seg id="p039">TABLE IX. IllMKIHlTIIIN OF ALL PI I'll.* IN SCHOOL AT KND OF HIEXNll M NumUcr GBADE m r. t. Kl**iu*'iit jtrv .... _ - — .' 7 •► I— I ."Inl t'r:iilc 4tb jrrad**. 5th grade _ - 4 15 *lth gradr. :s 7th grade ■stii urade — ...... — ~._-~ 3 14 loth aud 1-th icradett _ - - 4 ("ngraried _ : 12 0 IS Tot»U 32 1~ jii Industrial. Music nl and other Special Work: Basketry ...._ - 13 4 Bead- work _ 14 17 Ml Hr.i. in making 17 ...... 17 Caning - - * * » Morus, Junior _ 7 4 11 nniru». sHiilcir...- _ _ 4 10 14 Chorus, i:irK _ _ 10 10 Clarinet 1 1 ( -..rnct _ - 1 1 Cr.'l.lK-tinif . 2 10 12 • — . — - — — Harmony Horn ..." „_ 1 1 VettillK — 21 21 • H'"^ — --~ - — ... .. _.. _• . .. _m NVw York Point rr»ndinir lrt 10 26 \v» York Point writing I « 14 NOT York Musical notation •_' 1 3 Orchestra. _ _ 11 2 13 Physical culture, elementary _ 7 « 13 Phj-Klcal culture, advanced - 16 H 2S Piano - — - 10 12 piup-orifHii ~ 2 1 i^™.. . - — Piano tnnlnjr ~ * 8 Plain uewli.tf " 1" 10 K IIC- II LT 1 1 Violin _ 4 3 7 Violoncello 1 1 Voice 14 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABI.K X. AKT&lt; II. K&gt; MADE AND WORK DONE BV PUPIL* IN INDIHTRIAI. KK1MKTMENT DIKINC BIENNUM SlfullllllM ■ VM piMM small articles of bead-work 83 large article* of bead -work. Hnr.ns Is head-hai:s 11 doilies 11 holders wash &lt;-]otb* :t yokes. croti-hete&lt;l 2111 dozens I. room* .13 hammocks Lii fly nets quilts, piecei] 1 pillow top 1 pnir pillow r-ast 1 dress 1 me 24 bolls carpet r:i^ corset covers TARLK XI. SOIRCE OK FISDS COI-LECTED AND Tl KSE1) INTO 8TATK TRRAKI'RY IIIKIM. BII.WII M Brooms Network Head work Fancy-work Tuition cows calves HO hoes Mi**el!flneous Total W177.21 28 l&gt;eail ntM-kliK-es and MM rluiliu. 3 i-rnTclieted raps II dlnfa towels, litMunifMl I .i.-ii ttathM 4 jnrket*. crut&lt;'li«'t»»»l &gt;arn H v;inl&gt; Ix &lt;■•■. MkMri 1 lnrmlry linn 3 sets quilt Mocks .13 nirtia IdiMkets, trn\^. Hint*. oi( "I pairx »lipi»Ts 6 ntaawln. knlttril 3 holts Inrritaf, iiimlt- up 4© rhnirx. rantnl 5 pairs hooters 15 mats </seg>
            <seg id="p041">i TABLE XII. FARM PRODICTS RAISED AND CONSUMED Apples, - _ - _. 2B0 lushels * 12S1.00 Reds _ _. — Iui8liel» 22.00 Brans :» Ifimhel* 4.V00 riHrries 1." I ushflx 22.RO PupiinitM»rsi H I'linheH 25.00 I&gt;"ltur» - - 400 bunches 30.00 Milk OHIO uallftiK lsm.i»» Onions 11 I utheN 11.00 Pears ImxhrN 30.00 Potatora SS« bushels _ 3S0.00 R&lt;rwt &lt;-orn _ 60 hnsheln «M» Tomatoes 2R V.u»hel«._ HO.Ot) Tom«toM 2R V.u»hel«._ TO.OO Turnip* _ _ _ MImMl. H».nn TABLE XIII. FRIIT AND VECETABLKK CANNED IN OIK KITCHEN FOB INSTITUTION USE Ita-ts 32fl nnnrts Rlar-kherrie* SO Blaokherry jam V* Bnttpr, plum and npplf - 3fW Cherry jnm rhwiM 50 Ohow-rliow „ SO Corn relish. JHliM _ - _ „ «W&gt; TVirn , 100 PNrhM. siloed \-y I'#*fl«hep _ 320 Pie plant... .. . _ VI0 Plums ... . _ WO Raspberries Rasp her ry jnni g V* Rtn wherries 700 Stra wherry jam _ _ J53M Tomatoe* „ „ 100 Watermelon plrklen _ _ 75 </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>