<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00041">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00041</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twelfth Annual Report of the State Fire Marshal of the State of Nebraska for the Year 1920</title>
               <date value="1921-01-01">1921-01-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TWELFTH ANNUAL REPORT « of the State Fire Marshal of the State of Nebraska C. E. Hartford- _. H. J. Hauser E. E. Hayduk __ F. P. Dowling __ L. J. Butcher __ D. M. Trimble __ State Fire Marshal Deputy Fire Marshal Inspector Inspector Inspector Inspector Eva V. Anderson Clerk and Stenographer </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TWELFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATE FIRE MARSHAL Office of the State Fire Marshal, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. January 1st, 1921. To His Excellency, S. R. McKelvie, Governor of the State of Nebraska : Dear Sir : — Complying with the law in this state, I herewith submit to you the twelfth annual report of the Division of Fire Pre - vention. The last report of this office was called the tenth annual report, however, we have been informed by the State Librarian that a mistake was made in 1917 as the reports for both 1916 and 1917 were called the eighth annual report. Con - sequently, all reports following 1916 have been mis-numbered. It is our desire to rectify this mistake by calling the report for 1920, the twelfth annual report. In submitting this report I am fully aware that owing to the immense amount of work that I have been trying to handle in all parts of the state in connection with this office and the limited time at my disposal for the office part of the work, this report will be somewhat brief but complete. We understand fire prevention is a subject that must be popularized with the people before the best results can "be obtained. Our aim has been to so popularize the subject as one of vital importance to everyone in the state so that each individual will feel a personal responsibility in conserving life and property from destruction by fire. This office issues every month a bulletin on fire prevention, its causes and how to pre - vent them. We have endeavored to awaken an interest in the unnecessary fire waste and have tried to have each community work with the end in view of having their town take pride in </seg>
            <seg id="p003">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 2 having the lowest fire record in the state. In these bulletins we have cautioned the public in regard to electric wiring, de - fective chimneys, combustion of soft coal, waste, and oily rags, sparks from bon fires, carelessness in the use of matches, lighted cigars and cigarettes, overheated stoves and furnaces, and the use of gasoline. The gasoline and kerosene hazard is the most deplorable of all fire dangers because in nearly every gasoline and kerosene fire, lives are destroyed, by filling gas - oline stoves when the burners are lighted, starting fires with kerosene, etc., the result being a yearly toll of life that is most appalling. A report of the work in the Division of Fire Prevention is hereby respectfully submitted for your information. C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal. Inspection Work Four regular inspectors are employed by this office who devote their entire time to inspection of business buildings in towns throughout the state. Each inspector has a territory to cover, and fills out the regular inspection blank for each building inspected, writing his order or orders on the back of the blank, also, indicating when special notice is required from this office. These blanks are returned to the office and all orders, both kind and number, are recorded in our inspec - tion record as well as the number of inspections for each town. Also, a card index is kept of each town inspected, the date, number of inspections, and by whom inspected. At the time of inspection, the inspector solicits the assist - ance of the local fire chief, mayor, or some interested city official, to accompany him on his inspection tour, and we are notified by the inspector to deputize the interested party as special deputy inspector which gives him the authority to enforce the orders issued by the inspector or to issue such orders as he deems necessary. During the year 1920, our records show 338 cities and towns which have been thoroughly inspected, and a total of 21,695 inspections. A total of 13,947 orders were issued in the interest of fire prevention. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 3 Buildings Condemned and Repaired One of the most important tasks of this office is the con - demnation and repair work on buildings. The complaints are generally filed by the inspector during his regular inspec - tion tour and each town inspected averages about two build - ings which must either be removed or repaired. A date is set for hearing at this office and the owner notified he may appear or take the matter up by correspondence if impossible to appear. This gives the owner a chance to state his side of the case and what he is willing to do so either myself or deputy is in possession of the facts of the case before either of us make a personal inspection of the property complained of and make a finding, which determines just what should be done. After the finding has been made a regular blank of finding is sent the owner which notifies him just what must be done with his property and a date set when the finding must be complied with. If the owner refuses to comply, the papers are placed in the hands of the county attorney with instructions to commence prosecution. As proceedings of this kind, embrace a fine for each day, the owner does not care to allow too many days to slip by and get busy. During the year 1920, 522 complaints were filed requesting condemna - tion or repair. Out of this number, our record shows 159 buildings of this number which have been removed or wrecked, 92 buildings repaired and put in good shape, 5 complaints dis - missed as complaints were unwarranted and unjust, and 266 complaints which are still pending by reason of unexpired time, unreported action, or by reason of findings not yet having been made. News Bulletin This office issues a news bulletin each month giving the items of interest, in connection with this work which is pub - lished and circulated to the fire chiefs and newspapers, of Nebraska, special agents of insurance companies, insurance companies from whom fire marshal tax is collected, state fire marshals of North America, and a large miscellaneous list. Our mailing list contains about 1200 names. For State Fire </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 STATE FIRE COMMISSION \ Day a 16 page booklet was published calling special attention "to fire dangers. We endeavor to get tables compiled each month showing the inspections made, the orders issued, and totalling the number of fires and the number of losses, believ - ing that the people have a right to know what is being done and from reports received from numerous sources we are satisfied that our efforts in this line are appreciated. These bulletins also contain different subjects on fire prevention and we are always willing to publish anything to educate the people along these lines. Our bulletin today is just four times the size of the first bulletin published by this office entitled "Our National Folly" under date of July 3rd, 1911. We will endeavor to make the News Bulletin of the Division of Fire Prevention larger and better the coming year than heretofore. Fires Reported The worth and efficiency of this department is steadily gaining from year to year, and as the official, whose duty it is to cooperate with us, is becoming acquainted with the law and its value to the state, the effect is more efficiently being rec - ognized. During the past year the fire chiefs throughout the state have reported to us promptly and completely 1,193 fires occurring in their localities. Whenever, special information has been requested, they have willingly offered their services. All fire reports are recorded in the register each month and a total of the fire losses is taken for each issue of the bulletin. Special mention is made of lives lost, injuries, etc. The firemen of the state greatly assist in the prevention And extinguishing of fires. They are heartily interested in giving us every assistance possible and it is our desire to thank them for their assistance. Fires Investigated We have been called upon during the past year to make investigations of what were reported to be suspicious circum - stances in connection with 40 fires. In the. majority of these fires very little evidence could be secured and none that would </seg>
            <seg id="p006">STATE FIRE COMMISSION o seem to indicate that they were of incendiary origin. In a number of cases, there seemed to be no question but what the fire was incendiary, but insufficient evidence could be secured to justify an arrest. However, in a few cases, we have been successful in securing the arrest of so-called fire bugs. The majority of these cases are still pending. While the total fire loss in Nebraska for 1920 is much greater than in 1919, the fire losses of incendiary origin have increased about the same extent. This is due chiefly to the present financial conditions. The fire loss for Nebraska dur - ing 1919 was $1,422,943.62. About 2.5 per cent of the fire losses during 1919 were due to incendiarism. During 1920, the fire loss, totals $2,679,029.71. About 3.4 per cent of the fires during the past year are due to incendiarism. Fire Escapes During the past year, we have made a special effort to see that school buildings, two or more stories in height, hotels, stores, factories, etc., be equipped with proper fire escapes as required by the Nebraska statutes. The fire inspector serves a notice on the party responsible for non-compliance with the law and sends a duplicate to this office. It is our intention to also have a bound record of fire escape orders, in order that we may have a more accurate check on fire escape orders for 1921. We have been successful in having installed quite a number of fire escapes as will be seen in a more detailed report. I herewith respectfully submit a report of the work accomplished by the Division of Fire Prevention during 1920. I have already given you a synopsis of the different phases of the work and the following will contain a more complete report of the phases already briefly dealt with. C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 STATE FIRE COMMISSION FIRE PREVENTION DAY November 5th, 1920 November 5th was observed in Nebraska as patriotic fire prevention day. Governor Samuel R. McKelvie caused to be issued a splendid proclamation which is reproduced here. State of Nebraska Executive Department Office of the Governor PROCLAMATION— By the Governor The Legislature of the State has set apart a day as STATE FIRE DAY— namely, the first Friday in November, and has ordained that the day shall be observed by all the schools, public, private and parochial, with exercises appro - priate to the subject and the day. NOW, THEREFORE, I, SAMUEL R. M'KELVIE, Gov - ernor of the State of Nebraska, set apart Friday, November fifth, Nineteen Hundred Twenty, as STATE FIRE DAY, and call on all the people, either by themselves or by someone duly qualified, to make strict examination of their premises — the electric wiring, flues or inflammable substances ; also, the proper care and storage of oil and gasoline. Nothing should be left undone that will preserve us as individuals and com - munities from the folly of inexcusable and sinful waste. (SEAL) Given under my hand and the Great Seal of the State, this 7th day of October, 1920. (Signed) Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor. (Signed) D. M. Amsberry, Secretary of State. This department sent out thousands of pamphlets and bulletins for use on November 5th. They were sent to mayors, fire chiefs, school superintendents and teachers, business men's organizations, etc., and judging by the scores of press notices the appeals fell upon listening ears. In many munici- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">STATE FIRE COMMISSION *+*. 7 palities, preliminary meetings were held and many organiza - tions perfected that will make for fire prevention 365 days in the year. All mercantile and manufacturer's associations should have meetings addressed by experts. Ministers should sound warnings about fire dangers from their pulpits. School children should be given a special course of instruction on that day. Labor unions should observe the day, as fire causes loss of work and destruction of life. Civic and commercial associations should participate, mayors and all officials should take an active part. Fire prevention is primarily an individual question. The obligation resting on each property owner is one of good cit - izenship. It is the duty of every man to protect not only himself but the public from disaster and loss. Fires may be classified singly as accidental and incendiary in a proportion of about 70 per cent and 30 per cent respectively. That is 30 per cent dishonest. How can the fire waste be reduced ? Not by the insurance companies surely, except by their with - drawal from business, which would be utterly demoralizing. Business could not be transacted without insurance. But while insurance enters into the question of fires necessarily the solution of the problem should be entirely independent of that feature. The main point is to reduce the percentage of accidental fires to the minimum and to absolutely stop the dishonest ones. Now how can it be done? By applying the principles of good citizenship first, and second, by a vigorous public policy supplemented with proper statutes or ordinances, or both. At least 75 per cent of the accidental fires are unneces - sary. Stop them. The committee from the Fire Marshal's Association waited upon the President of the United States and Secretary of State, and were awarded by a proclamation issued and set - ting apart October 9th as Fire Prevention Day in the United States. The proclamation gave a tremendous impetus to the observance throughout the country. Never before were the </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 8 fire prevention forces brought into such full play. Never did the people respond so well. Organized and well directed efforts were the rule rather than the exception. A resolution was adopted recommending the passing by all legislatures of laws for the compulsory teaching of fire prevention in public schools. In view of the demonstration in recent fire preven - tion compaigns of the educational value of the singular and striking symbol the convention approved the standardizing use of the fire prevention day emblem consisting of a red seal bearing a large white letter "F" upon which appears in the red the words "Fire Prevention Day" and also bearing in white the date "October 9th, National Fire Day." The Annual Convention of the Fire Marshal's Association of North America was held in New York City on December 8th, 9th, and 10th. I attended this convention and from the reports and business transacted, find that it was one of the greatest conventions held. It is readily to be assumed that with the tightening of money markets and the general ten - dency of all values to slump, we will face an increasing ten - dency on the part of the large property owners to feel them - selves caught in the wedge to sell out to the insurance com - panies. This belief is grounded on the fact that statistics prove that 75% of all fires are the result of carelessness. Partially, non-intentional carelessness and mostly purposely carelessness. The slump in values creates the tendency to over insure which in turn brings on the epidemic of fire sales which have been so clearly proven by history. In keeping with the recommendations of the association, I would suggest that the Legislature of Nebraska, now in session, repeal the present law and adopt October 9th instead of the first Friday in November, as Fire Prevention Day. Rural Fire Protection One gratifying feature of the year 1920 is the fact that rural communities over the state are being equipped with modern motor driven fire apparatus. This is in accordance with my idea that there should be a motor combination, chemical and pump for each six miles radius, outside of the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 9 larger towns. Many of the machines now being purchased are of the chemical type only because there is no ava~able water supply in the district in which they operate. We suggest that each farmer construct cisterns of concrete and save the rainfall now wasted by piping from the house, barn and other available roofs to the cistern. It is time that we realized the possibilities of our paved' roads as an arm for rural fire protection. With motorized fire apparatus and the quite generally distributed water supply from streams throughout the country, it seems reason - able to suppose that well equipped township fire-fighting organ - izations may be established, and, therefore, from the fact that through concrete pavement, miles are reduced to minutes, dwellers along county highways may be ultimately afforded a measure of protection against fire such as heretofore has been within reach only of city dwellers. This is true in Nebraska and we believe you will realize the great good and benefit the rural residents and farms will derive from fire protection that could be offered them by the county having a chemical motor apparatus that could respond to any call in a moment's time as nearly everybody now has telephones and each county could keep their fire apparatus at some convenient place. Advice to Farmers The barn is a bad place for the automobile. Build a garage. Grain is safer in a granary than in a barn. Rod all tall buildings using standard equipment and see that it is properly installed. Inspect every inch of rodding at least once a year. Put up "No Smoking" signs about barns and out buildings and enforce the rule. Ventilate the bara but also see that tight doors and windows are provided against the invasion of sparks and blizzards. If you have nothing to fight fire with, get something if only a bunch of buckets. Do not put the well pump too close to the barn. You may need that "water to save your property some night. Get non-freezing pumps. Know where the axe is and have two ladders on hand long enough to reach over the eaves of the tallest buildings. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Keep the oils out of house and barns. Watch for spontaneous combustion in the barn. There is no rural fire protection more effective than the hand chemical fire extinguisher. Spring Clean Up t. The 1920 clean up week was without doubt the most successful in the history of the department. It is realized that in reconstruction times a state free from fire and disease breeding hazards, is in a position to do its best for the wel - fare of the state. This department called for an early clean up in the spring of 1920. We request each municipality in the state to organize strong fire prevention communities not only for the clean up in the spring but for all the days of the year. Nebraska has had a good spring house cleaning and thousands of dollars' worth of rubbish, worthless and useless in attics, cellars and store rooms, were sold and the proceeds in many instances devoted to the purchase of seeds, flowers, paint, etc. The first week in April is spring clean up week. Summer Fires A fire during the summer is more serious possibly than at any other season of the year. Careless bon fires, sparks from locomotives, campfires, cigarette and cigar stubs, thrown from automobiles by pleasure riders, matches and oily rags kept where they should not be kept, all enter into the big figures of the loss column. In cities roofs are dry, the heat takes away the toilers' energy, and thought grows lax. Guard all roofs from sparks. The fire proof roofing is coming into prominence more and more. A fire during the heated term will spread like a plague and run like a race horse. Be sure and conserve the water supply for one cannot tell when the red peril will attack. Keep the weeds and grass down and away from buildings and fields, watch out for smoking in dangerous places. In order to protect the wheat and other crops the farmer </seg>
            <seg id="p012">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 11 should move his shocks and stacks back from the right of way and plow two wide belts, one over near the fence close to the railway and another 30 yards back. This would serve to check an ordinary stubble fire. Keep water buckets and )rooms or blankets handy. Fire Prevention Suggestions "The time to fight a fire is before it happens.' Rules for Cooking and Cleaning 1. Don't leave the stove while boiling is being done. 2. Don't pour water on burning fat; use earth, sand, flour, salt, or a metal cover. 3. Never let a stove get red hot. 4. Be careful not to use stove polish on a hot stove ; wait until it is cold. 5. Don't use any kind of stove polish or other cleaning mixture unless you know what is in it; buy the safe kinds. 6. Don't leave sweepings in a piece of paper; put them in the stove. 7. In handling oil or wax, use only small quantities at a time; wipe thoroughly the surfaces you have rubbed with rags, and then burn the rags. 8. Don't put ashes in wooden receptacles nor where they can possibly come in contact with wood. Rules for Rubbish 1. Keep things tidy; don't allow rubbish to accumulate anywhere in the house or near it. 2. If you keep oily clothes, put them into a metal box or can with a cover. 3. If you learn that anyone is keeping oily rags outside of metal containers it is your duty to report it. 4. Don't pile dead leaves against anything that will burn. They sometimes ignite of themselves. 5. Bury leaves; don't bum them. 6. Don't have old pieces of lumber cluttering up your basement. Have them cut up into kindlings and then piled in a proper place. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Garages A constant source of worry to the Department of the State Fire Marshal are the numerous complaints which come to it from congested sections with reference to the flimsy construction of garages. A poorly constructed garage is not only a daily menace to the owner, but surrounding property as well. The construction of an automobile, the fuel necessary to furnish the propelling power, the oil for its lubrication, all of these highly inflammable materials should have every safe - guard thrown about them in order to prevent ignition. Just why a person is willing to spend several hundreds of dollars, and even thousands on a vehicle and then trust its housing to a structure which may at any moment become a pyre, destroying the vehicle, the home of its owner and that of his neighbors, is hard to understand. It is a splendid exemplification of the "penny wise, pound foolish" policy which can only be driven from the heads of some people by bitter experience. A garage should be substantially constructed of non-in - flammable material, roofed with slate or metal, the floor cemented or bricked. The only light which should ever be permitted therein is daylight or electric light. Those living in incorporated cities and towns before build - ing garages, should obtain from the proper authority, a copy if the building code and strictly adhere to its requirements. Better be safe than sorry. Some Garage Don'ts Do not permit smoking about the garage, or near cars when tanks are being filled. Do not permit open lights or flames in the garage. Use only incandescent electric lights. Do not permit motor to remain running while gasoline tank is being filled. Do not yourself, or permit anyone else to light a match \o see how much gasoline is in the tank. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Do not handle gasoline except in approved safety cans. Do not use gasoline for cleaning purposes except in a room separated from the main garage by fire wall. Do not permit accumulations of oily waste, but deposit such waste and rags in approved waste cans. Do not fail to provide a sufficient number of fire ex - tinguishers, pails of sand and other fire retardants. Do not fail to keep the garage clean Do not permit cars to be stored in barns, nor in other frame buildings with wooden floors. Special Warnings Shortly before Christmas and July 4th both of which are productive of special hazards, the department sent out timely bulletins to all parts of Nebraska, calling attention to the wiring of store windows, the protection of holiday shopping crowds, the elimination of candles and inflammable material for windows, house and Christmas tree decorations, and held that modern non-inflammable material be used, that electric bulbs should take the place of the hazardous candles. At the approach of July 4th a strong appeal was sent out to eliminate all dangerous fire works. As a result several municipalities that heretofore had no ordinance governing the sale, distribu - tion and use of fire works, passed such safety measures. Fourth of July a Safe and Sane One Celebration for Independence Day, generally speaking, was a success as reports all show and the number of comments from various sources throughout the state regarding the noticeable change and the scarcity of fire works indicate a scarcity of fires as well. In fact, there has been very little if any reports of fires from this source so far. But we had a number of letters of inquiry regarding the law on the handl - ing of fire works which no doubt had its effect. So if we have prevented one or more fires it is well worth the while. So much for co-operation and fire prevention, say nothing of the loss of life and limb. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 STATE FIRE COMMISSION GASOLINE Gasoline, like kerosene, is derived from crude petroleum but is far more volatile. What does volatile mean? You know that water in an open dish will dry up after a while be - cause it slowly changes into ah invisible gas and disappears. Gasoline does the same thing but it vaporizes much faster than water and that is what is meant when we say it is very volatile. We believe we have accomplished our purpose in exerting our efforts to have all merchants handling gasoline, bury it in excess of five gallons underground, or if in carload lots, store in the large storage tanks at a safe distance from property. An exception is made to gasoline stored in gasoline pumps at filling stations as well as to allowing more than five gallons being poured into the tank of an automobile, provid - ing the engine of an automobile is stopped while the tank is being filled. The oil companies of the state are assisting us in "every way possible to eliminate the gasoline hazard in Nebraska and are complying with our ruling in all the towns of the state and we believe there are very few cases where gasoline is kept above ground in xcess of five gallons. A full barrel of gasoline is not dangerous unless it has a severe fire around it and is sufficiently hot to form a pressure and burst the barrel. A full barrel of gasoline will not explode, and by placing it in the open air, 50 feet from a building, it is perfectly safe. It is very dangerous to allow empty barrels to set around, owing to the fact that there is generally a sufficient amount of gasoline left in the barrel to form a combustion that will explode. A spark applied to an empty barrel that has former - ly contained gasoline is very liable to cause a violent explosion. GASOLINE RULES AND REGULATIONS FOR NEBRASKA All oil houses which are built and enclosed with galvan - ized iron shall be put up on props or posts to the height of 314 or 4 feet ; said houses shall have galvanized iron siding to run within 2 or 3 inches of the ground. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 15 These houses shall be built not less than 200 feet from any other house, except by special permission of all parties living in property nearer than this number of feet. Each house shall be enclosed with a fence, either iron or wire, with double -gates sufficient for a wagon to drive through and load from the house. The outside gate of this fence shall be locked at all times and also the house, except at the time that the agent of the oil company owning the house is there personally to look after gasoline stored therein. All dry weeds, grass and rubbish shall be kept cleaned up within a radius of 20 feet of said building, and under no condi - tion will the agent, or any one in his employ, be allowed to smoke within the enclosure of this building or yard. All gasoline, except what is shipped in steel cars, must be shipped in iron, air-tight packages or drums, and upon ar - rival at station shall be immediately emptied into the under - ground tank of the consignee, but in case the underground tank is not sufficient to empty the entire shipment, then the re - mainder, not to exceed five barrels, must be placed on a vacant lot and in the open air, and not less than 50 feet from any other building. Employes must not be allowed to carry matches around the oil houses. There should be no trash, oily rags, or rub - bish around the premises. If any oil is spilled on the floor and cleaned up with sawdust, the sawdust should be removed from the premises at once, to avoid spontaneous combustion. There should be no smoking of any kind in or about the oil house. There should be no weeds or grass allowed to grow around the oil house. The weeds and grass should be cut with a shovel very close to the ground. In a case where a railroad agent receives a consignment of oil and finds barrels are leaking, then said agent should im - mediately notify the local agent of the oil company, and he shall immediately dump said barrels into an air-tight package. It is also requested that as soon as a barrel containing gasoline is emptied, it must be taken to the depot and shipped back immediately. All merchants handling gasoline in excess of 5 gallons </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 16 must have the same buried not less than 3 feet under ground. Every person within this State retailing gasoline, benzine, and other kindred high explosives in less than carload lots shall deliver the same to the purchaser only in barrels, casks, packages or cans, painted vermilion red, and having the word "Gasoline", "Benzine" or whatever name such explosive is known by, plainly printed thereon in English. All such words above referred to shall be in letters sufficiently large to attract attention. No person shall deliver kerosene or what is known as coal oil in any barrel, cask, package, or a can painted or stamped as above required. Every person within the State purchasing gasoline or other high explosives of that nature for his own use shall procure and keep the same only in barrels, casks, packages or cans painted and stamped as above. Provided the provision of this act shall not affect sales, purchases or the keeping for use of the explosives herein mentioned, where the quantity is one quart or less. No person keeping for use, or using kerosene, otherwise known as coal oil shall put or keep the same in any barrels, cask, package or can painted or stamped as above required for explosives to be painted or stamped. Rules For Kerosene 1. Study the lamp rules under "Lights." 2. Be sure that oil heaters and cookers do not leak and that they will not overturn. 3. Keep their burners clean and do not turn the flames too high. 4. Keep the oil can outside of the house, if possible. 5. Do not let the floor beneath the can become oil-soaked. 6. Make sure that the can does not leak nor drip. 7. Never leave oil uncovered. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 17 GASOLINE DISPENSERS The fire marshal rules that in presenting the modern equipment of gasoline dispensers, they must meet the re - quirements and bear the underwriters label. They should have an interlocking device concealed in the body of the pump where they cannot be reached or tampered with. We favor an air pressure filling device. All motors should be totally enclosed. It should be moisture and liquid proof. A totally enclosed cast iron housing which is liquid and vapor proof should be provided for both motor and light switches. The filling station should be kept clean. No smoking should be allowed in the station, all leaks stopped, all automobile drivers, should stop their engines while filling cars. Hand chemicals should be kept handy and every pre - caution taken to make a station safe for life and property. DRY CLEANING AND DRY DYEING During the past year, we have been called upon often to give information in regard to dry cleaning establishments. This office has taken particular pains to investigate the laws, rules and regulations of other states. We are in hopes that this legislature will pass a law governing dry cleaning, which we believe is best illustrated bv the laws of Ohio in regard to this subject. These laws state that no building or establish - ment shall be used for the business of dry cleaning or dry dye - ing until an application for pel-mission to do so has been filed with the state fire marshal. When an application is filed, the state fire marshal or his deputies shall make an inspection of such building or establishment to examine the equipment, and shall issue a permit for the same. The heating of such buildings shall be secured only by the use of steam or hot water system. Drying rooms if under the same roof as the dry cleaning and dry dyeing rooms, must be separated from such rooms by a fire resistive wall. No storage tank shall be placed or constructed or maintained under a public sidewalk, or any sidewalk area. All tanks shall be buried under ground to such a depth as to secure a covering of earth at least three feet above the top of the tank at the surface level of the ground. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 STATE FIRE COMMISSION One approved hand chemical extinguisher especially efficient for such conditions shall be provided for each 500 feet above floor space. In some smaller cleaning plants our inspectors find a small galvanized bucket which holds about 2*/&gt; gallons of gasoline. The owner takes the skirt or jacket, dips it into the bucket so as to thoroughly saturate the garment. He then takes the garment up, wrings it out with his hands, places it on a hanger and hangs it up in the back room. When he finishes, he pours the dirty gasoline back into the can, puts the cork back, sets it under the stairway and goes back to his pressing machine. Now anyone who understands proper cleansing of gar - ments, will know that the garment was not cleaned. Yet the surface soil may have been removed or spread evenly over the surface, and the general appearance might be fair until it is worn for a little while. The same thing is done with suits. This condition exists in quite a number of localities. This is often found by our inspectors. The main purpose of my theme, however is not only to show the danger from the il - legitimate use of gasoline but also the extent of frauds being practiced on the public. THE OVERHEATED ELECTRIC IRON One of the growing causes of household fires is the elec - tric flat iron. In the last few years it's use has become quite common and many fires have been credited to the careless handling of the same. In nine out of ten cases over heating has been responsible for the fires resulting. The heating element of the iron is a coil of wire of special composition used because of its high resistance and of its property to stand high temperature without injury. Part of the electrical energy used in overcoming this resistance is converted into heat. This production of heat continues as long as the cur - rent flows through the iron. Part of the heat is transmitted to the surrounding air by radiation and connection, and part of it is used in heating the goods ironed and in driving out tfie moisture by converting into steam. If the iron is not dis - connected when out of use all the heat must be transmitted to </seg>
            <seg id="p020">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 19 the air and the iron will gain heat until it is hot enough to get rid of all the heat in the only remaining way of transmitting it to the air and to the ironing board or anything that will re - ceive it. The importance of guarding against this condition cannot be overstated. A properly designed metal stand will afford some pro - tection but the best safeguard is always to see that the cur - rent is disconnected. In addition to turning off the current at the switch the cord should always be disconnected before leaving the iron. If all users could be trained always to dis - connect the cord of an electric iron before leaving it, the fires from this cause would be reduced to a minimum. A man recently took an electric iron and placed in his bed for the purpose of warming his feet. The iron not only warmed his feet nicely, but while searching for other fields of endeavor, set the bed on fire. This particular citizen novr has "cold feet" whenever this method of obtaining bodily com - fort is being considered in his presence. SOME CONDITIONS FOUND BY THE FIRE INSPECTOR It is amazing to find conditions as they exist in small towns as well as larger cities. Rubbish and paper boxes will be piled up against their own and neighbors' buildings; boxes packed full of paper to the top with no cover on; old store boxes thrown on a pile eight to ten feet high up against the building and ashes on the same pile. What can a man be thinking of to indulge in such hazardous practices : Upon explaining the danger to the owner, he often retorts something like this. "Why, I've done that for twenty years and never did have a fire." But, though he does not know it, he may have a fire within twenty minutes. In one place a garage was inspected located next door to a hotel. Here the man throws oily waste, old paper boxes, and all refuse on one pile. It quickly accumulates and soon he has three or four wagon loads dumped up against the back of his garage. Upon being ordered to remove this trash, he replies that it is none of anybody's business as he does not </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 STATE FIRE COMMISSION carry any insurance and he would be the loser. He entirely forgets the adjoining property. The inspector inquired of him, "Are you the only man in town?" Carelessness at the filling stations is one of the greatest present evils. Patrons of the oil stations will drive up to the oil filling station smoking, as was illustrated while at Fremont a few days ago, when a man drove up in a Ford car, threw the cushion off the seat, opened the tank and while it was being filled, was sitting in the car smoking a cigar. He took the cigar out of his mouth, knocked the ashes off, placed the cigar back in his mouth and bent over to look in the tank to see if it was getting full. The gas fumes were coming out of the tank in his face. Had a spark fallen from the cigar into the oil, what chance would this man have had ? Another violation of the law was revealed when it was discovered that some of the filling stations were selling gaso - line in any ordinary can, regardless of the law that all gaso - line must be sold in cans painted red instead of cans unpainted or painted various colors. These parties were promptly noti - fied that they were breaking the law and have promised not to let it occur again. They claimed they were unable to get red cans during a certain rush season but were painting them red themselves to be sure the law would be respected in the future. HOW TO REMOVE SOOT Large numbers of shingle roof and defective flue fires are being reported, due to the increasing use of soft coal. The accumulations of soot on heating surfaces reduce the value of the fuel, and frequently clog the flues and start fires. The following plan for removal is suggested: The fire is put into good condition with a substantial body of hot fuel. Common salt, thoroughly dried, is then thrown or sprinkled on the incandescent fuel bed in a quantity depend - ing entirely on the size of the furnace. In the case of a house heating furnace, one pound at a time is ample, in the case of a large power plant boiler, four or five scoops full may be re- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 21 quired. The dampers are kept open so as to maintain the turnace temperature and the salt is allowed to remain until the fumes have entirely disappeared. Immediately upon charging the salt, the furnace becomes filled with dense white fumes which may require as much as half an hour to entirely disappear. If results are not se - cured on the first application, it should be repeated as many times as necessary. Once the heating surface is thoroughly cleaned a small application every few days is usually sufficient to keep it so. RULES FOR STOVES AND FURNACES In Placing 1. Place stoves, furnaces and pipes far enough from walls and woodwork to avoid overheating. 2. Cover the nearest wooden surface with sheet asbestos, sheet iron or tin; if iron or tin is used, leave an air space be - hind it. 3. Where stove pipes or heating pipes pass through walls, enclose the pipes in galvanized iron, double-walled, ventilated thimbles at least twelve inches wider than the diameter of the pipes. 4. Protect the floor beneath the stove with sheet metal, and have it extend forward at least twelve inches directly beneath the door to the ashpit. 5. Surround the base of the furnace with brick, stone or concrete. 6. Make sure that all pipes are free from rust, and that all joints and connections are sound and tight. FIRE DRILLS IN SCHOOLS Many states in the Union have compulsory fire drill laws, covering schools. Every school in this state should at least hold one fire drill per month, oftener if necessary. There is no word in the Eng - lish language which carries greater terror and panic to the hu - man heart than the crv of "Fire!" </seg>
            <seg id="p023">22 STATE FIRE COMMISSION It is a word which we may expect to hear at any moment, for fire plays no favorites, it creeps in wherever the careless leave an opening, and for this reason we should at all times be prepared to cope with its appearance. The very first thing to do is to remain cool ; this especially applies to the teacher, for to her the children look for protec - tion and leadership. The next thing is to get the children out of the threatened building in as orderly and rapid a manner as possible. Never mind hats, coats or books. The moment the fire signal is given all children should' be taught to immediately dis - continue whatever they may be doing, line up in the alleys, and at a given signal from the teacher march out, one alley "line" following the other. It is essential that fire drills should be frequent and at ir - regular and secret times. See that all exits are unobstructed and that all doors swing outward. Keep fire escapes clear, and in damp, slippery weather, sprinkle with ashes. Use fire escapes often, both for regular drills and dismis - sals. Let the childi'en become accustomed to them. Use a special bell for fire signals. Be sure that the sig - nal is DISTINCTIVE. Teachers should follow the children after first assuring years and turn the amount saved to the payment of the war themselves that no child has been left behind. The movement of the children should be by the shortest route, and there must be no crossing of lines. Fire drills should conclude with the continued march of the children out and away from the building not less than fifty feet, in DIFFERENT directions. This prevents interfering with the other. HOW TO PAY WAR DEBT IN THIRTY YEARS. The people of the United States will be paying taxes to reduce the war debt for which the great war was responsible for probably a hundred years. But if the American people could prevent their fire losses entirely for the next twenty </seg>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025">24 STATE FIRE COMMISSION debt it would be cleared by 1940. This was pointed out in one of the late News Bulletins. The fire loss in 1919 was $317,000, - 000. For twenty years this would amount to about $6,400, - 000,000 while the direct cost of the war was little more than this figure. If two thirds of the loss which is known to be clearly preventable, was actually prevented, the saving would be sufficient to wipe out the war debt by 1950. WORLD'S PER CAPITA FIRE LOSS 1920. Canada $2.73 United States Spain __■ 2.26 1.86 Belgium Russia France England Norway Italy L Japan _ 1.02 .97 .74 .64 .55 .53 .51 Sweden Austria Germany .42 .32 .28 Netherlands .11 MOTOR DRIVEN FIRE APPARATUS A DECIDED SUCCESS. Fire departments wherever the motor is in use have ac - quired a new enthusiasm and interest in the work and are giv - ing great service to the community wherever used. In the small town as well as the large, it is the means of great savings in the protection of life and property, so don't get discouraged boys, but keep it up. Go after your council and have them equip your department with a motor truck and save your city a bad loss and reduce your insurance as well as protect your home and loved ones, for the hour is coming and you know not when the demon fire may visit you even ever so careful and cautious you may be. Your neighbor may be in trouble and </seg>
            <seg id="p026">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 25 the insurance he carries may cause a combustion and thereby lead to destruction. A WORD TO THE PUBLIC. Assist your fire boys in every way you can. Help them acquire better equipment and help yourself in the end. Don't stand around in their way when they are on duty, but keep away and give them the street or the alley or whatever they may need. Go to their assistance whatever it may be, you may be the next to want their aid, so do what you can. CHEMICAL EQUIPMENT. If you haven't a chemical equipment truck you don't know what you are missing in the way of the saving of property in your community, not only from fires, but water as well, say nothing of your own convenience but the awful destruction that ]s caused by turning on the water in a nicely furnished home or a business housfe. Why not go to your merchants and have them equip their stores or places of business with a quantity of chemical extin - guishers for their own convenience and protection which so often prevents a fire of great destruction. Have your city fur - nish the chemicals and the chief to inspect and recharge the extinguishers as often as necessary. This will not only afford the protection but in time will help to reduce your insurance if put in general use, so get busy, boys, and try it. It may save your Sunday suit some day and prevent some of those large and disastrous fires that occur here and there throughout the state. The chemical is one of the essentials in most of the small departments as well as the large ones and is in more general use today than ever before during my thirty years in the fire service. Does the chemical corrode the tank of a fire engine? This is a question often asked. In reply, we wish to say that the chemical tanks are so lined with lead or other metal that does not corrode. A great many departments grease the threads </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 STATE FIRE COMMISSION for the cap of the tank with vaseline which prevents corrosion and stripping of threads. The benefit of chemical apparatus to a town or city is that it can go beyond water mains. Coal fires are strengthened by water while a chemical will extinguish the fire. The chemical engine should be kept properly cleaned and in perfect operat - ing condition. Care should be taken to use only the best grade of bicarbonate of soda and the purest grade of sulphuric acid. At least 80% of all fires in the United States are being fought with chemical apparatus. Nearly all factories of size are equipped with chemical apparatus and nearly all fire depart - ment equipment contains chemical apparatus. Chemical ex - tinguished fires are more satisfactory as there is very little water damage. GREAT WORK OF INSURANCE COMPANIES The average layman does not appreciate the wonderful factor for the financial upbuilding of a community that the fire insurance company plays. They are the very foundation stone of business credit. They are constantly working to preserve from destruction the wealth of this great nation. Fire insurance men are glad to see a town flourish because new buildings are good business risks and they deplore fire losses because they are the ones who pay for the fires. The Division of Fire Prevention of Nebraska has always received the hearty co-operation of the insurance companies doing business in Ne - braska and in turn we have always endeavored to satisfactor - ily perform our duty towards them. The average citizen has no idea of the many dishonest fires that the insurance com - panies have to pay for. The purpose of these dishonest fires are to collect insurance or in other words to sell out to the in - surance companies. The companies become factors of dis - honest policy holders and are some of it's agents. Over - insurance is the cause of practically every case of arson that we have investigated. We absolutely know that every fire insurance company pays it's honest losses gladly but we have deplored the fact that they have so often been called upon to pay dishonest losses. For the maintenance of the fire mar- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 27 shal's office, every fire insurance company with the exception of Farmer's Mutuals are required to pay to the State Treasurer of Nebraska annually three-eighths of one per cent" of their net fire premiums realized from business written in Nebraska. This year the amount of fire marshal tax paid for the main - tenance of this office amounted to nearly $21,000. ELECTRICAL HAZARDS (1) The Misuse of Fuses The misuse of fuses of all kinds is the big question of today because of the process of easy substitution. The pur - pose of a fuse is to protect the line or circuit from being over - loaded and to protect the building from a dangerous fire. Some people are of the opinion that if the fuses blow, almost any - thing will be good enough if it will keep Jthe lights burning or the motor running. This seems to be one of the worst troubles. These substitutes are used without figuring on the weakness of some other part of the line. The weak points are switch and socket contacts and wire joints. A fire started by one of these defects does not start immediately, but will smolder away for" periods varying from one to forty-eight hours before breaking out. (2) Some Wiring Hazards. In taking up the subject of the hazards created by wiring, inasmuch as the wires are the carriers of the current, they should be perfect in design and be properly installed in order to avoid all unnecessary trouble. Rubber covered wire is the type most commonly used and the one with which we have the most trouble, not because it is rubber covered but because of its misuse. It is used for all interior work, with the ex - ception of moving picture machines. The greatest trouble so far resulting from wires is the failure of dropcords and the way they are installed, repaired and misused. Drop cord should never be used for wiring purposes and where it is used for that purpose, it should be taken out and replaced with rubber covered wire no smaller than No. 14 B. &amp; S. gauge. This No. 14 rubber covered wire must not carry over 660 watts </seg>
            <seg id="p029">28 STATE FIRE COMMISSION on one circuit and must not be fused to carry over 10 Amp. FROZEN WATER PIPES To thaw out water pipes that have become frozen, wrap the frozen section with cloth and pour boiling hot water upon it until the ice in the pipe gives away. Rags on the flow at the base of or under the pipe will absorb the waste water. If the freezing is too severe to yield to this treatment, send for a plumber. A burning match, torch or open flame of any description should never be employed for the purpose of thaw - ing out water pipes. Wrapping the pipes with oil soaked rags and setting them on" fire is worse than folly. It is incendiary. FIRE HYDRANTS Fire hydrants whether public or private should be of a standard thread with a barrel of not less than six inches in diameter and be fed from the water main of not less than the same diameter forming a complete circuit of the system with - out dead ends or any obstruction to free the flow of water. SHIFTING RESPONSIBILITY During the past year some of the members of the school board in a small Nebraska town called at this office and re - quested that an examination be made of their school building which they considered unsafe and dangerous. Upon inspec - tion, I found it in bad condition and ordered it discontinued for school purposes. This aroused the indignation of the wealthy, retired, farmer taxpayers who began to feel they were about to be obliged to part with some of their hard earned coin so they got busy and when the time for the election of a new school board came, they were Johnnie on the spot to see that the new board was composed of themselves and their brother farmers rather than the business men of the town. Together they made a strong kick against a new school buil'ding, claim - ing the old one only needed a few repairs and would suffice very well. Then an appeal was made to the state superintendent's of - fice to allow the old building to stand with a few repairs. To - gether with that office, we made a second trip to try and settle </seg>
            <seg id="p030">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 29 this matter satisfactorily. We found strong opposition and everybody kicking against putting up a new building. They were told that we had made our order from here and did not feel disposed to change it, however, if they insisted that this building was still good enough to hold school sessions in, we would recommend the necessary repairs, but shift all the re - sponsibility from our shoulders to theirs, and they would them - selves be liable for whatever might happen. This created an - other stormy kick. Oh, no, they didn't want to be responsible or liable in any way. Finally they conceded to make the repairs and assume the responsibility for one more school year, with the intention to have a new building the following year. It is the same way with hundreds of people. They do not want to be responsible for not complying with the law neither do they want to be responsible for what the conse - quences are from their not complying with the law. However, they think they know what they want and are perfectly will - ing to have ail responsibility put on the shoulders of someone else. GOOD HOUSEKEEPING The attic, the cellar, closets, yards and outbuildings should be cleaned at least twice a year, in the spring and in the autumn, and all useless material and rubbish removed or burn - ed. Store all remaining articles away neatly and see that passages are not blocked. In storing away clothing, furs, etc. first remove all matches and other combustible materials from the pockets. Do not go into clothes closets with lighted candles or matches. Use an electric flashlight. Do not hang clothes near stove pipes, hot chimneys, steam pipes or stoves. Get rid of rats and mice. They are disease carriers and their nests are fire traps. The furnace room and heating apparatus in the home or factory should be in first class order and clean - liness and be absolutely free from accumulations of combust - ible refuse. MOVING PICTURE THEATRES This office has its inspectors make a very thorough and careful examination of moving picture theatres in the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">30 STATE FIRE COMMISSION In some places the inspector finds that there is no attempt made to comply with the law. In one instance the theatre was closed and the proprietor was compelled to turn his keys over to the local fire chief who would open the theatre and re - turn the keys when he had complied with the order. This goes to show that some people must be made to comply with the law. If they think there is a possible chance of getting by they will just simply make a promise but our inspectors make a second inspection to see that the law has been complied with. This office issues specifications for moving picture booths, which explain the law in detail. These specifications deal with the frame of booth, the covering of booth, flooring, openings, shelves, ventilation, brick, tile or concrete booths, portable booths, exits and the moving picture machine. At least two standard chemical fire extinguishers should be provided, one on the inside of the booth and the other just outside the booth. Smoking or the use of matches is not permitted in any booth, room, compartment, or enclosure where a motion picture ma - chine is installed. Each machine while in operation shall be in charge of an experienced operator. The entrance door to the motion picture machine booth must be kept closed but not locked when an audience is in the building. The doors and exits in every theatre, moving picture gallery or other place of amusement where combustible films over ten inches in length are used, shall have not less than one exit, 3 feet wide by 6V&amp; feet high and where the seating capacity shall be more than 200, there shall be two exits which shall in all cases be located at the opposite end of the room from where is located the operating booth. I would recommend to the legislature the passage of a law licensing all moving picture houses in the state, and making compulsory the hiring of first class operators to comply with the ruling of this department. All moving picture owners must apply to this office for a permit. This is being done in most of the states and was highly recommended at the State Fire Marshal's Convention. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 31 The World Realty Company, operating the Moon, Sun and Muse theatres of Omaha, announced some time -ago they would act on suggestions of State Fire Marshal Hartford, in handling crowds in order that patrons may be subjected to as little in - convenience as possible. The Sun was sold out on a Sunday night in November and owing to the throng in the lobby, and congestion in the approaches to the theatre auditorium, In - spector Hayduk of Omaha was called to assist in relieving the congestion. A uniform method of handling the crowds has been adopted, as a result of a conference between the state officials and managers of the Sun, Moon and Muse. CHIMNEYS The largest per cent of fires are caused from sparks from chimneys. A chimney fire will be extinguished by pouring buckets of sand or earth down the chimney or by igniting a handful or two of common powdered sulphur in the chimney. All openings should be closed and if there is an open grate, hang a white blanket in front of the fire place so the sulphur furr.es will go up the chimney. The sulphur forms sulphurous acid with oxygen of the air and thus renders the latter incap - able of supporting combustion. The walls of chimneys used for stove ranges, fire places, heating furnaces or other heating appliances whether the fuel used is wood, coal, oil or gas, shall be built of brick, concrete or stone. All chimneys, irrespective of what materials the walls are built, should be lined with fire clay, flue lining or fire brick. The lining shall be made for the purpose and adapted to with - stand high temperatures and the gases from burning fuel. Solid brick or concrete chimney walls ought not to be less than four inches thick, exclusive of the flue linings. Chimneys shall not rest upon or be carried by wood floors, beams or brackets, or be hung from wooden rafters. In all buildings, the chimneys should be built from the ground up or rest upon the basement walls. All mortar used in chimney construction shall be cement mortar, proportioned as follows: 2 bags of Portland cement, 200 pounds and one bag of dry lime, 50 pounds thoroughly mixed dry. To this mixture shall be added </seg>
            <seg id="p033">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 32 three times its volume of clean sand and with sufficient water to produce proper constancy. Chimneys must be built at least three feet above the frame roof and two feet above the ridge of peak roofs and shall be properly capped with terra cotta stone, cast iron or other approved material. All flues lead - ing from cellars or basements, shall have proper clean out doors below the smoke intakes. After a chimney has been com - pleted all flues shall be thoroughly cleaned. The header joist or beam carrying the tall joints of a floor and supporting a trimmer arch, shall not be less than ten inches from the chim - ney breast. The chimney that becomes too hot to hold tKe hand against comfortably, is dangerous if there is woodwork touching it. Have it carefully inspected by a reliable mason or notify your fire chief. NOTES FROM THE NATIONAL CONVENTION OF STATE FIRE MARSHALS I, as State Fire Marshal of Nebraska, attended the Nation - al Convention of the State Fire^ Marshals held in New York City at the Astor House on December 8th, 9th and 10th. I desire to make the following report of items of interest which took place at the convention. "The two organizations of State Fire Marshals composed of officials, one group being those who were acting as both Insurance Commissioners and Fire Marshals, and the other be - ing those who were acting solely as Fire Marshals compromised and formed a new organization with one set of officers. A number of able addresses were made. The members passed a number of resolutions among which were the following : "In spite of all fire prevention activities the American fire loss still continues to be excessively high and before it can be ma - terially reduced the co-operation of the general public must be enlisted. It is becoming increasingly apparent that fire pre - vention education in public schools is one of the most effective means to this end. Therefore, be it resolved, that the Fire Marshal's Association of North America recommend the pas - sage by all state legislatures, laws for the compulsory teach - ing of fire prevention in the schools of their respective states </seg>
            <seg id="p034">STATE FiRE COMMISSION 33 and urging upon all its members the introduction and promo - tion of bills along such lines. The experience in promoting observance of fire prevention day indicates the educational value of a simple and striking symbol that is capable of being identified with the lessons on that day. Therefore, be it re - solved, that we approve for this purpose, the standardized use of fire prevention day emblem consisting of a red shield bearing the large white letter "F" upon which appears in red "Fire Prevention Day" and bearing, also, in white the date, "October 9th." Fire film hazard was also discussed and the Fire Marshals will be ready to make a strong stand shortly against the use of nitro cellulose the flammable film, except where complete booth protection is available. Women's work along fire prevention lines was discussed thoroughly. A paper was read on fire prevention enlisting the aid of women and children. The opinion among the Fire Marshals was that the aid of the women could be most effectively secured by the safety to life appeal. One Fire Marshal told of the plan in his de - partment of employing two women to promote interest in fire prevention among women's clubs and the school children. During the year these women will teach 200,000 school chil - dren the importance of fire and accident prevention. These women have organized 1600 safety leagues among children. A discussion of women's work in fire prevention by Miss Lloyd Marshal of New York started a great discussion among the Fire Marshals. They all agreed that enlisting the aid of women and children will be of great help to preserving safety from accident to life. The resolutions expressed appreciation for the co-opera - tion and assistance given by the press, particularly to fire pro - tection, which was the official organ of the association. The next meeting will be held at Chattanooga, Tennessee. C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal. I, as Fire Marshal of the State of Nebraska, wish to ex - press to the Hon. Governor S. R. McKelvie our sincere ap - preciation for the advice and co-operation given in this work. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 34 Likewise, I wish to extend my thanks to Mr. J. E. Hart, Secretary of Trade and Commerce, who has not only shown His interest in the work but has taken an active part in some of the duties of this office. INCENDIARY FIRE RECORD The following is a list of towns where fires have been in- vestigated during the past year making a total of forty fires. Though this office has been called upon to investigate a great number of fires during the past year, it was found in most cases that evidence could not be secured to justify arrest and prosecution of parties who were supposed to be guilty of performing the crime of incendiarism. Though circum - stances may seem to point to fires being set it is often hard to convict the supposedly guilty party as the Nebraska laws are very incomplete in regard to arson cases. The following are a few illustrations of conditions found by the investigator of arson cases which are of interest: On March 1st, a fire occurred about 10 :00 p. m. at Fair- Eagle (5 mi. S. W.) Martell Mead (2 investigations) Thedford Sargent Omaha (2 fires) Table Rock Duncan Long Pine (2 investigations) Glenwood Leigh Ansley Grand Island Sutherland Edgar Fairbury Bayard Lodge Pole Bassett Kimball (3 fires) Odell Emerson Sweetwater, (2 investigations) Gordon Wilsonville Stamford York B v oadwater Edison Blair Wilber Herman Norfolk Hemingford College View </seg>
            <seg id="p036">be 5 c I 2 -4-&gt; C5 : \i li wm -4-J c I « s 5 5 T- e c DO 3 8* 1 £ o c g </seg>
            <seg id="p037">36 STATE FIRE COMMISSION bury in an apartment occupied by Russel Bills situated over a moving picture theatre. The prompt arrival of the fire de - partment prevented much loss. This fire was set while the theatre below was crowded with people. Three separate fires were burning in three different rooms. Mr. Bills was bound over to the District Court. He was tried in December and declared Not Guilty by the jury. Another fire was found to be of unknown origin and it was believed the fire was incendiary owing to the fact that the owner carried two insurance policies and neither company knew of the policy held by the other company. The building was small but over insured. However, it was not possible to secure sufficient evidence to arrest the owner of the building. On July 30th a fire occurred at Herman (2 J /^ mi. N.) be - lieved to have been set by the Tom Kelley gang of Omaha. Farnam Djureen, a member of the gang had been arrested a couple of weeks previous to the fire for stealing a car, and was refused permission to be released on bond. One of the interesting fires which was investigated dur - ing the past year occurred at Thedford on October 14th, where the court house was entirely demolished, and it was thought to be incendiai'y by reason of the warm sentiment existing be - tween Seneca and Thedford for the county seat. However, in - sufficient evidence could be secured to indicate who might be guilty, if the fire was not accidental. On July 14th a fire occurred at Hemingford starting in a livery barn. It was soon discovered that fire was burning in the office part of another building owned by the same parties. A third fire was discovered in the flour mill owned by one of these parties. The water pressure was not effective so it was impossible to save any of these buildings. The mill and hotel buildings were over insured. In this case, also, sufficient evi - dence could not be secured to arrest any parties. On October 13th, a fire occurred at Duncan which com - pletely destroyed the building and contents. The building was occupied and owned by rivals in the merchandise business. The owner of the stock had been conducting sales during the </seg>
            <seg id="p038">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 37 summer, owed a great many people, and a number of suits were pending or threatened to effect payment of his debts. He had also had three fires within the last sixty days preceding this fire. Oil cans which were supposed to contain oil were found empty. The case is still pending. Some assistance is being given by a representative from the National Board of Fire Underwriters on this case. At Kimball several fires were reported as having occurred on October I5th, November 6th and 16th, supposed to have been set by Kansas farm hands who were dissatisfied with their settlements. These fires were all in the wheat fields. The case was left to be settled by the county attorney and sheriff. One arrest was reported in this case, the party hav - ing been brought back from Colorado. On October 13th a fire occurred at Emerson which destroyed the school house 3 miles east of town. A school house at this location had been burned down last year also, it was reported. Investigation revealed, an Indian boy about 11 years old, was suspected of setting these fires. On No - vember 25th another fire* was reported in the newly construct - ed school building. William Crow, the same Indian boy as was suspected of setting the two previous fires, was again ac - cused and was taken to the county jail, where he confessed to setting all three of the fires. He afterwards denied setting them. He has been sent to the reform school. His dislike for school prompted his crimes. A fire occurred at Sweetwater on November 25th, the owner, A. R. Stevenson having left town for Thanksgiving. Loyal C. Highland and wife were left in charge of the store during the owner's absence. It was reported goods had been stolen from the store by the Highlands and thought the store was set afire to cover up the loss of these goods. The High - lands acted very peculiarly and made conflicting statements in regard to the fire. On December 10th, Loyal Highland was arrested and brought to Kearney where he was released on $3,000 bond. The case is still pending. On December 16th a fire occurred at Wilber in a general </seg>
            <seg id="p039">38 STATE FIRE COMMISSION merchandise store causing a $30,000 loss. It was found goods had been hauled away before the fire. However, the inves - tigation has not been completed at this time. One of the most interesting fires investigated during the past year, occurred at College View. The prompt arrival of the fire department prevented the fire from gaining headway as was evidently intended. Investigation revealed that eight different fires were burning through the residence. The fur - niture and fixtures had been saturated with kerosene. The owner was out of the city and the remainder of the family had moved over to his wife's parents. The investigation has not been completed as yet. Regarding the fire which occurred in the hotel at Nebras - ka City July 13th, 1919, owned by Frank Popel Sr., and left in charge of Frank Popel Jr. on night of fire, in the early part of 1920 Frank Popel, Jr. was tried and declared guilty by the jury and sentenced to the penitentiary to serve a term of from one to twenty years. However, this case has been appealed to a higher court. In regard to Frank Popel, Sr. his trial has been set for February, 1921, in the district court where he will be tried for conspiracy in this arson case. This fire will be remembered as the instance where eighteen separate fires were discovered, the furniture saturated with kerosene, and nearly every circumstance pointing towards incendiarism. On October 31st the Blue Mills at Glenwood were entirely destroyed. Warren A. Ewell was arrested and confessed to setting the fire. Mr. Ewell had a good reputation and wanted to do all in his power to atone for his crime. He had recently purchased the mills, was doing a good business, and did not know why he committeed the deed. He was bound over to district court on $1000 bond and pleaded guilty. Before sen - tenced he will have to plead guilty in a higher court. FIRE ESCAPES INSTALLED We are pleased to report the following places have com - plied with the fire escape law of Nebraska and either contract - ed or have already installed fire escapes by reason of order is - sued from this office. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 39 PUBLIC SCHOOLS West Point Wauneta (2) York (5) Atkinson Aurora Alliance Anselmo OMAHA PUBLIC SCHOOLS South Lincoln Beal Burwell (2) Bruno Webster Bayard Bladen Bethany Walnut Hill Highland Lake Central City (2) Clatonia Mason Saunders Madison Field Cowles Doniphan Dix Kellom Grand Island (3) Gresham Florence Hawthorne Long Annex West Side Gar-field Grafton Gering Gandy Hoskins Hubbell Imperial Indianola Millard South Franklin Lake Annex Farnam PAROCHIAL SCHOOLS Minatare Monroe Marquette Milford Omaha — St. Bridget's School Omaha — St. Winsislaus Omaha — St. John's North Platte Ogallala Snyder — St. Leo's School Raeville — Odell Polk OTHER BUILDINGS Aurora — Lyons Hotel Alexandria — Opera House Axtell — Bethphage Mission 3 Fremont — Midland College Friend — Coronado Hotel Grand Island — Nebraska Cen- Paxton Raymond Stapleton Scottsbluff Sterling Tamora tral Office Building </seg>
            <seg id="p041">40 STATE FIRE COMMISSION On Friday, October 1st, Fire Chief, Neil T. Sommer and three firemen were injured while on duty. The accident oc - curred in the heart of the business section of the city of Lin - coln. On the following day, Chief Sommer succumbed to his injuries. The loss of Chief Sommer is keenly felt by this office as well as by the Lincoln Fire Department. He was a man who drew the sincere admiration and friendship of all who knew him. We found him ever ready to assist and lend a helping hand, and he never shirked a duty. We feel with the deepest regret the loss of one who had the honor and respect of all who knew him. He was a gentleman, quiet, fearless and tireless in his work. He asked no odds in his favor from anyone. He leaves in the memory of his friends, the kindliest remem - brance. We miss you, Neil. May your soul rest in peace. OMAHA FIREMAN LOSES LIFE On October 31st, fire destroyed the Schmoller &amp; Mueller Music Co. warehouse at Omaha, causing a loss of $300,000 and the death of Fred Blazek, a fireman of Engine Co. No. 1. The loss is keenly felt by the citizens of Omaha as well as by the fire depai-tment of the city. Mr. Blazek was a fearless fireman, and although we have never met him personally, all reports indicate he was held in high esteem by his friends. There are left to mourn his loss, Island — A. G. Guy Minden — Opera House Rooming house rand Island— Voegel Room- Norfolk — Auditorium ing house tastings — Lepin hotel tastings — Kipp Cigar factory rincoln — Rooming house, 235 Norfolk — Eagle Lodge bldg. West Point — St. Joseph's Home South 9th. West Point — Auditorium CALLED I BY DEATH </seg>
            <seg id="p042">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 41 a wife and Six Children. Mr. Blazek was found by his brother - in-law, E. E. Hayduk, our inspector, who worked tirelessly for hours to unearth him from the burned debris. DEATHS RESULTING FROM FIRE DURING 1920 On May 20th, Chas. Roesky of Omaha, was killed when two fire trucks collided while making a run to a fire. Mr. Roesky was a member of the Omaha Fire Department. On October 1st, Chief Neil T. Sommer of the Lincoln Fire Department, succumbed to injuries in an accident caused by the collision of the Chief's car and the ladder truck in the heart Of the business section of Lincoln, while making a run to a fire. On October 31st, Fred Blazek, a fireman of the Omaha Fire Department, was suffocated in the Schmoeller &amp; Mueller Music warehouse fire at Omaha. On January 13th, Kris Kreuch of Norfolk was burned to death when the gas plant was destroyed. On January 5th, R. Hirschman and C. O. Eby of Harting - ton died from injuries received in a gasoline explosion. On March 1st, Mrs. E. S. Marks of Columbus, was burned to death in a gasoline explosion. On June 17th, Mrs. H. B. Young of Bethany was burned to death when her clothes caught on fire from an unknown cause, presumably a gas stove. On September 18th, Ray Price of Fairbury, met his death when he neglected to shut off the engine while filling the gaso - line tank. On September 19th, Earl L. Keck of Norfolk, an agent of the Standard Oil Company, was fatally burned when he crawl - ed into a railroad gasoline tank car with a lantern to see if tlie car contained gasoline. On October 20th, Mrs. Florence Detweiler, of Osceola, came to her death by what is presumed to be suicide, she be - ing an invalid and setting the house on fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">42 STATE FIRE COMMISSION INJURIES RESULTING FROM FIRES AT OMAHA During the past year, E. E. Hayduk, fire inspector at Omaha, reports, a total of sixty-eight firemen who were in - jured; three firemen died of illness, and two lost their lives while on duty. LARGE FIRES DURING 1920— LOSS OVER $40,000 June 23 — Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., Lincoln — Cause unknown. December 24 (1919) — Elevator at Hickman — Cause un - known. March 4, — Hague Candy Factory, Hastings — Cause, de - fective furnace. March 16 — Wilson Co. stock yards, Nebraska City — Cause, stove or wiring. May 7th — O'Connell &amp; Burke Hardware Store, Gordon — presumably incendiary. June 21 — Columbus Roller Mill Co., Columbus — Cause, unknown. February 27 — Schmoller &amp; Mueller Music Store, Omaha — Cause, unknown. February 27 — Brunswick Balke Collander Co., warehouse, Omaha — Cause, communication from Schmoller &amp; Mueller building. August 14 — Tony Reccari and others, stores, Omaha — Cause, matches. July 20 — Swift &amp; Co., smoke house, Omaha — Cause, un - known. FIRE LOSSES FOR 1920 During the past year including December 1919 up to De - cember, 1920, our records show the following losses : Number of Fires Loss 225 $ 298,681.20 Lincoln Omaha 496 966,460.26 472 1,413,888.25 Balance of state __ Total _ 1,193 $2,679,029.71 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">| OB I I ■ | '-4J I § I = </seg>
            <seg id="p045">44 STATE FIRE COMMISSION FIRE LOSSES FOR 11 YEARS 1910 $2,181,058.00 1,788,123.30 2,251,774.3S 1,715,676.10 1,873,071.25 1,789,269.00 1,908,297.46 2,895,935.00 2,158,204.81 1,422,943.62 2,679,029.71 47 Bonfires and rubbish 28 Backfiring of engine 13 Candles 2 Chimneys, defective 85 Cigars or cigarettes 25 Communicated 41 Electric Irons 7 i Electric wiring, defective 47 Fireworks 2 Fire Place, defective 6 Furnace, defective 32 Gas 17 Gasoline and kerosene 91 Grease 22 Incendiary, presumably 18 Lightning 17 Matches 73 Miscellaneous 25 Smoke stack 5 Sparks from chimney 293 Sparks from engine 42 Spontaneous combustion 48 Stove 46 1911 1,78 1912 2,25 1913 1,71 1914 1,87 1915 1,78 1916 1,90 1917 2,89 1918 2,15 1919 1,42 1920 2,67 CAUSES OF FIRES DURING 1920 Ashes </seg>
            <seg id="p046">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 45 Thawing- out pipes Unknown 4 177 Total 1,193 INSPECTIONS DURING 1920 During the past year, 338 cities and towns of Nebraska were inspected by our regular inspectors. One inspector is stationed at Omaha and the other three have their territories in various parts of the state. During the past year, we are pleased to report that over 21,500 inspections were made, and nearly 14,000 orders issued in the interest of fire prevention. The inspection record shows the following orders issued: Total orders issued 13,947 Total inspections made 21,695 Fires investigated 40 Buildings condemned and in process of con- demnation 522 Our record of inspection work shows a total of 4,555 in - spections made in Omaha by Inspector Hayduk, and 1,299 orders issued. All these orders were complied with as the inspector returns within a few days after the first inspection to see that they are given prompt attention. kerosene and gasoline 43' ilean up 5,21' Ihimney 90 llectric wiring 3,23: letal, asbestos and stove 1,80; led light and fire escape 34&lt; liscellaneous 1,20' Repair building 31 1 Recommended condemnation 48 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">46 STATE FIRE COMMISSION The following is a list of cities and towns that have been inspected during the past year. The figure in parenthesis following the town indicates more than one inspection. Also, this office has compiled information in regard to the fire pro - tecton in the way of fire fighting for quite a number of towns, such as the number of feet of hose, water works system, number of miles of mains and hydrants and fire alarm system. Following is the list of cities and towns having a record of: Abie Adams Agnew Ainsworth Albion 1900 ft. hose — Waterwork system, direct pressure — 7 mi. mains, 50 hydrants — Fire alarm system — Bell and whistle. Alexandria Alliance 2600 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam — direct pressure — 10 mi. mains, 78 hydrants — Fire alarm system, siren whistle. Alma Anselmo Ansley Arapahoe (2) Arcadia Arlington Ashland Atkinson Atlanta 1900 ft. hose — Waterwork system steam, direct pressure — 11 mi. mains, 89 hydrants — Fire alarm system, siren and steamboat whistle. Auburn Aurora 1500 ft. hose — Waterwork system steam, direct pressure — * * * 39 hydrants — Fire alarm system, siren whistle. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 47 Avoca Ayr Bancroft Bartley (2) Bassett Battle Creek 900 ft. hose — Waterwork system gasoline, direct pressure — * * * 18 hydrants — Fire alarm system, whistle Bayard Bloomington Beaver City- 800 ft. hose — Waterwork system gasoline, direct pressure — * * * 15 hydrants — Beaver Crossing Fire alarm system, blymer bell. Beatrice 6000 ft. hose — Waterwork system steam, direct pressure — 12 mi. mains, 160 hydrants — Fire alarm system, telephone and whistle. Bee Beemer Belfast 1000 ft. hose — Waterwork system gas and steam * * * 12 mi. mains * * * Belgrade Fire alarm system, bell, steam whistle. Belvidere Benedict Bennett Benkelman (2) Bennington Bertrand Berwyn Bethany Big Springs Bladen (2) Blair Blue Hill (2) Boelus Bradshaw Brady </seg>
            <seg id="p049">48 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Brainard (2) Brayton Bridgeport Broadwater Broken Bow 1750 ft. hose — Waterwork system fuel oil, direct pressure — 6 mi. mains — 60 hydrants — Fire alarm system, telephone and whistle. Brule Bruning 100 ft. hose — Waterwork system distillate — direct pressure, 21 hydrants — Fire alarm system bell. Bruno (2) Burchard Burwell Bushnell Cambridge Campbell (2) Oleton Carroll Cedar Rapids Central City 1300 ft. hose — Waterwork system electric — direct pressure, 54 hydrants — Fire alarm system telephone and siren whistle. Ceresco Chadron Chappell Charleston Chester Clarks Clarkson 1500 ft. hose — Waterwork system gasoline and electric power — 2 mi. mains — 22 hyd - rants — Fire alarm system, whistle and bell. 1500 ft. hose — Waterwork system gasoline and eyectric, direct pressure, 30 hydrants — Fire alarm system, steam whistle and bell. Clay Center (2) Clatonia Clearwater College View (2) Colon </seg>
            <seg id="p050">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 49 Columbus 2500 ft. hose — Waterwork system steam and electricity — direct pressure — 14 mi. mains — 92 hydrants — Fire alarm system telephone and whistle. Cordova Cortland Cozad Craig Crawford 1500 ft. hose — Waterwork system gravity — direct pressure — 8 mi. mains — 67 hydrants — Fire alarm system whistle. Creston Crete 2100 ft. hose — Waterwork system steam and waterpower, direct pressure — 7 1 /) m i. mains — 75 hydrants — Fire alarm system bell and whistle. Culbertson (2) Curtis "Dnlton Dnnnebrog Davenport Davey David City (2) 1600 ft. hose — Waterwork system steam, direct pressure — 8 mi. mains — 46 hydrants — Fire alarm system bell, whistle and telephone. Dawson Daykin Deshler 1000 ft. hose — Waterwork system electric motor, direct pressure, 26 hydrants — Fire alarm system, whistle, bell and telephone. 1000 ft. hose — Waterwork system coal oil, direct pressure — 3V-&gt; mi. mains — 38 hyd - rants — Fire alarm system, electric siren. 1000 ft. hose — Waterwork system gasoline, direct pressure — 4 mi. mains — 26 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell and whistle. DeWitt Dodge Doniphan Dorchester Dunbar </seg>
            <seg id="p051">50 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Dunning Dwight Eagle Edgar Edison Elba Elgin Elkhorn Elmwood Waterwork system gasoline, direct pressure — 1 mi. mains — 16 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell. Elsie Elwood Ericson Eustis Ewing Exeter Fr rbury Fairneld Falls City (2) Farnam 4800 ft. hose — Waterwork steam, direct pressure, 28 mi. mains, 147 hydrants — Fire alarm system, telephone. Fremont 1300 ft. hose — Waterwork system, electric and steam, direct pressure — 5^4 mi. mains, 60 hydrants — Fire alarm system, siren and Friend bell. Fullerton -Garrison Geneva Genoa Gering Gilead Giltner Gladstone Glenvil Goehner </seg>
            <seg id="p052">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 51 Gordon 1100 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gas, diiect pressure — 6 mi. mains, 38 hydrants, Fire alarm system, bell. Gothenburg 1500 ft. hose — Waterwork system, electric, direct pressure, 8 mi. mains, 37 hydrants — Fire alarm system, electric bell. Graf ton Grand Island Grant cJreeley Gresham Gretna 600 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gasoline, direct pressure, 6 mi. mains, 19 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell. Haigler (2) Hallam Hampton Harrisburg Harrison Harvard Havelock 1800 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gas and motor, direct pressure, 9'/o mi. mains, 115 hydrants — Fire alarm system, whistle and bell. Hay Springs 1000 ft. hose — Waterwork system, mill and gas engine, direct pressure, 9 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell. 1500 ft. hose — Waterwork system, electric, direct pressure, 41/2 mi. mains, 50 hydrants — Fire alarm system, whistle. Hebron Henderson Henry Herman Hershey Hildreth (2) Holbrook (2) Holdrege (2) s Homer Hooper Holstein </seg>
            <seg id="p053">52 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Hordville Howells 850 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 13 hydrants — Fire alarm system, telephone, whistle and bell. Hubbell Humboldt Humphrey 1500 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gasoline, 3 mi. mains, 31 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell and whistle. Hyannis Imperial (2) Indianola (2) Inman Johnstown Kearney Kenesaw 1200 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 6 mi. mains, 34 hydrants- Fire alarm system, bell, whistle and phone. Kennard Keystone Kimball liawrence Leigh 800 ft. hose — Waterwork system, oil, direct pressure, V/2 mi. mains, 18 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell and whistle. Lewellen Lexington 2100 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gasoline and electric, direct pressure, 16V£ mi. mains, 57 hydrants — Fire alarm system, telephone, whistle and bell. Lindsey Lincoln 11,800 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 115 mi. mains, 924 hydrants — Fire alarm system, telephone and 25 boxes. Lisco Litchfield Loma Long Pine </seg>
            <seg id="p054">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 53 Loup City Lushton Lyons Madison Madrid Marquette Mason City Maywood McCook (2) McCool McGrew Meadow Grove Melbeta Merriman Milford 1200 ft. hose — Waterwork system, electric, direct pressure, 2V2 mi. mains, 26 hydrants — Fire alarm system, electric siren and bell. Millaid (2) Milligan Minatare Minden 1500 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 6 mi. mains, 61 hydrants- Fire alarm system, whistle. Mitchell 11,000 ft. hose — Waterwork system, crude oil engine, 4V&amp; mi. mains, 50 hydrants — Fire alarm system, whistle and bell. Monroe Moorefield Morrill Murphy Naponee Nebraska City 3,000 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 20 mi. mains, 100 hydrants —Fire alarm system, telephone and whistle. Nehawka Neligh 1200 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gasoline, direct pressure, 4V2 mi. mains, 40 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell and electric siren. Nelson </seg>
            <seg id="p055">54 STATE FIRE COMMISSION / Newman Grove 1000 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gas and electric motor, direct pressure, 2V&amp; mi. mains, 22 hydrants— Fire alarm system, bell, whistle and telephone. Nickerson Norfolk 4000 ft. hose — Waterwork system, electric driven, direct pressure, 26 mi. mains, 212 hydrants — Fire alarm system, telephone and whistle. Norman (2) North Loup 1000 ft. hose— Waterwork system, distil - late, direct pressure, 5 mi. mains,28 hyd - rants — Fire alarm system, bell and air whistle. North Platte Northport O'Neill Oak Oakdale Oakland Ddell Dgalalla Omaha 46,922 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 2,890 hydrants — Fire alarm system, telephone and alarm box. 3,200 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 12 mi. mains, 42 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell and whistle. 1,200 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gas and electricity, 5 mi. mains, 30 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell, whistle and siren. Old Osceola Oshkosh Otoe Overton Oxford (2) Orchard Page Palisade Palmer </seg>
            <seg id="p056">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 55 Palmyra (2) Pauline Pawnee City Paxton Pender Peru 500 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 19,825 ft. of mains, 41 hyd - rants — Fire alarm system, bell and tele - phone. 800 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gas and electric, direct pressure, 4 mi. mains, 16 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell. Petersburg Pilger Platte Center Plattsmouth (2) 2,750 ft hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, l\/-&gt; mi. mains, 92 hydrants — Fire alarm system, shop whistle. Pleasant Dale Polk Potter Primrose Raeville Ragan (2) Ravenna (2) Raymond (2) Rising City Rockville Rosalie Roseland (2) Rosemont Rulo Rushville Ruskin Republic City Royal Salem Sargent Saronville Schuyler </seg>
            <seg id="p057">56 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Scotia Scottsbluff 2,100 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam pumps, direct pressure, 14Vfc mi. mains, 90 hydrants — Fire alarm system, private tele - phone. Scribner Seward Shelby Shickley Sidney 1,650 ft. hose — Waterwork system, electric, direct pressure, 18 mi. mains, 39 hydrants — Fire alarm system, whistle and phone. Silver Creek Smithfield Snyder Spalding Stanton Stamford 600 ft. hose — Waterwork system, electric motor, indirect pressure, l 1 /^ mi. mains, 18 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell. Staplehurst Sterling St. Paul Strang Stratton (2) Stromsburg Surprise Sutherland Sutton Swanton Swedeburg Syracuse 1,600 ft. hose — Waterwork system, electric, direct pressure, 3 1-8 mi. mains, 38 hyd - rants — Fire alarm system, bell and whistle. Table Rock (3) Tamora Tecumseh Tekamah Thayer </seg>
            <seg id="p058">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 57 Thedford Tilden Tobias 700 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gas, direct pressure, 6,820 ft. mains, 19 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell. Touhy Trenton (2) Uehling Ulysses Unadilla (2) Union University Place 1,800 ft. hose — Waterwork system, electric, direct pressure, 14 mi. mains, 70 hydrants — Fire alarm system, whistle and telephone. (2) Upland (2) Utica 1,000 ft. hose — Waterwork system, air pressure, direct pressure, 2 3-4 mi. mains, 25 hydrants — Fire alarm system, electric, siren and bell. Valentine Valley Valparaiso (2) Penango Waco Wahoo 3,000 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 6 mi. mains, 63 hydrants — Fire alarm system, steam whistle, telephone and siren. Walthill Washington Waterloo Wauneta (2) Weeping Water Wellfleet Western Weston (3) 750 ft. hose — Waterwork system, gasoline engines, direct pressure, 2 mi. mains, 19 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell. West Point (2) </seg>
            <seg id="p059">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 58 Wilber 1,550 ft. hose — Waterwork system, steam, direct pressure, 3 mi. mains, 40 hydrants — Fire alarm system, bell and steam whistle. Wilcox (2) Wilsonville Winslow Wisner Wolbach Wood Lake Wymore York (2) Respectfully submitted, C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal. </seg>
          </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>