<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA Sixth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Orthopedic Hospital To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Sixth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent t)K THE Orthopedic Hospital LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30. 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF OFFICERS Dm. H. Winnett Orh Superintendent Dr. J. P. Lord Chief Surgeon Carrie M. Ben brook „ Matron Louie M. Corse Head Nurse Zella Smith Surgical Nurse Grace M. Eddy Assistant Nurse Rose Deahn Stenographer </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL Lincoln, Nebraska To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morchead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions, Howard Kennedy, Henry Gerdes and Silas A. Holcomb: Gentlemen: In compliance with the statutes, the sixth biennial report is, herewith, submitted. HISTORICAL The Orthopedic Hospital was created by an enactment of the Legislature of 1905. $10,000 was appropriated for the establishment of the institution and its maintenance for the first biennium. The hospital was provided for the care of the destitute crippled and deformed of Nebraska. A preliminary survey showed that a considerable number of Nebraska children were diseased and crippled and needed hospital care of a kind for which there were no facilities. The new hospital was located in a portion of one of the buildings of the Home for the Friendless in Lincoln. The summer of 1905 was spent in preparing the building for hospital work. The first patient was received on October 1, 1905. The following table indicates, in figures, the activ - ities of the hospital by biennial periods since that time. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 336 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">,; ■&lt; o I l' \] o Q H - O as o in r as fc'- O - *s ? r# Ct 1&lt; J — ' i </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS In the second biennium additional space was provided by further remodelling for our use the entire building of which we had formerly occupied only a part. Further improvement and extension occurred also during the third biennium. About June 1, 1911, the entire group of buildings, (four in number), was taken over for the work of the hospital. In 1912, at an expense of about $6,000, a fireproof laundry building was erected. This building is giving good service. Substantial sleeping porches for nurses and employees were built. The Legislature of 1913 appropriated $45,000 for a new hospital building. This building was finished during the present biennium and will be referred to again. SCOPE OF THE WORK The hospital is designed primarily for the free treat - ment of children who are crippled or deformed or suffering from disease or defects likely to eventuate in deformity. Such conditions are infantile paralysis; tuberculosis of bones or joints, (hip joint disease, white swelling, hunch back, scrof - ula, etc. ) ; hare lip, club foot ; hernia ; fractures ; dislocations enlarged tonsils; adenoids; rickets, (bowlegs, knock knees etc.) The subjoined table indicates to how large an extent these are surgical patients. SURGICAL WORK DONE AT THE HOSPITAL DURING THE PAST TWO YEARS 3 Abscess, acute 2 Abscess, pulmonary Abscess cold, (see tuberculosis) 1 3 Adenitis, cervical Adenoids *21 1 Amputation, toe 1 imputation, painful stump 1 Ankylosis, congenital, knee 1 Ankylosis, acquired, knee </seg>
            <seg id="p007">338 Appendicitis _ 9 Arthritis, osteotomy 1 Arthritis, deformans, forcible correction 2 Arthritis, deformans, tenotomy .: 2 Bow legs 4 Burns 6 Calcaneum, spur of _ _ 1 Cleft foot 3 Cleft palate _ 8 Club foot acquired _ 3 Club foot, congenital 19 Congenital affections: Club foot 1 Elbow 1 Rectum 1 Uterus 1 Dislocations, congenital, (hip) 6 Dysmsnorrhea 1 Empyema _ 2 Epilepsy 3 Fissure, anal 1 Flat foot 4 Fracture of: Elbow 3 Femur 7 Humerus _ 2 Jaw 1 Radius and ulna. 3 Suspected „ 1 Tibia 3 Goitre 1 Hammer toes 1 Hare lip 5 Hernia, inguinal 14 Hernia, umbilical _ 4 Hydrocephalus 2 Hypospadias _ 6 Intussusception 1 Mastoiditis 1 Masturbation 1 Needle in foot 1 Oesophagus, stricture of 1 Osteo-arthritis. hip 1 Osteo-arthritis, knee _ 3 Osteoclasis 6 Osteomyelitis, acute infective 10 Ovary, cy-t of _ _ 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 339 Paralysis, infantile, club foot, arthrdUesis 20 Paralysis, infantile, astragalectomy _ 7 Paralysis, infantile, forcible correction 38 Paralysis, infantile, tenoplasty 23 Paralysis, infantile, tenotomy 13 Paralysis, infantile, other contracture deformity 9 Paralysis, pseudo-hypertrophic _ 1 Paralysis, spastic, club foot Arthrodesis _ 1 Forcible correction 6 Tenoplasty 5 Paralysis, spastic, contracture deformity Paronychia X Phimosis 20 Pigeon-toe _ 1 Polyp rectum .-. „ 1 Pylorus stenosis 1 Sarcoma of eye _ : 1 Scapula, congenital elevation of 1 Spina bifida _ 1 Syphilis, acquired _ 1 Syphilis, hereditary 4 Teeth extracted 1 Tonsils 113 Tuberculosis: Hip &lt; Knee 1 Spine I Uterus, prolapse of _ 1 580 The hospital care of these children is excellently supple- mented by our school work All patients from kindergarten to high school age have lessons and recite every day Our four teachers conduct classes in the school rooms and give individual instruction to bed patients in the wards The school operates the full twelve months of the year. The nurses' training school with 18 to 20 pupil nurses enrolled is an important feature of the work of the institu- tion. The State Library Commission has installed and super- vises a splendid institution library which is available to pa- tients and employees. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Diversions are provided for the children in various ways. Occasional entertainments are given by visitors to the hos - pital and down town theaters are frequently thrown open to the children. The Oliver and Orpheum theaters and Capital Beach have been especially generous and Mr. J. M. Bramlette of the Lincoln Traction Company has frequently provided street car transportation for the children to and from down town entertainments. ACTIVITIES OF THE PAST TWO YEARS tThe institution has reached a stage of greater usefulness at any previous time. Under the administration of the d of Commissioners of State Institutions the hospital not only expanded to a 140-bed institution but its effici - has also been materially increased. I The new building was finished and has been occupied ce March 1, 1915. This building contains new and modern ce rooms, library, reception rooms, dining rooms, school ims, laboratory, surgical department complete, and three rds with a capacity of forty beds. The building is fire - &gt;of and the different floors communicate by inclines instead stairways. During the past year one of the striking changes in our methods was that of converting our separate children's, nurses' and employees' dining rooms into a single cafeteria. This enables us to serve meals in a moderate sized dining room and the food is served more promptly and economically and in better condition than under the old system. In January, 1916, we were honored by having with us for several days Dr. E. W. Ryerson of Chicago, Dr. Emil Geist of Minneapolis, Dr. M. S. Henderson of Rochester and Dr. A. Steindler of Des Moines. With Dr. Lord and the sup - erintendent these gentlemen spent two days in a clinical and surgical study of methods in infantile paralysis. About twenty separate surgical procedures were done and a collec - tive report will be published in due time showing the methods used and the ultimate results obtained. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 341 This institution, in common with other Nebraska insti - tutions, has enjoyed and profited by the several conferences of officers of Nebraska institutions with the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions. These conferences have twice been held at our hospital and we are very glad to have their influence and enthusiasm brought close to us in this way. About 50 '/r addition to our boiler room was made during the past year. This will enable us to heat the new adjoining building of the Nebraska Home for Dependent Children and will give us better service. Some painting has been done in the interior of our buildings. Minor building, plumbing, and electrical repairs have been made as required. RECOMMENDATIONS A sprinkler system for the old hospital building and old main building. Fire escapes for the new building and sun parlors of old building. Removal of the x-ray room to the new building and exten - sion of x-ray equipment. Employment of definite part time assistant physician and laboratory assistant and the addition of a night supervisor to our graduate nursing staff. To make provision for teachers and equipment for teach - ing at least three or four of the following: Carpenter shop work, watch making, shoe making and repairing, painting, and brace shop. A superintendent's residence. Extensive painting both inside and outside of all the buildings. Tear down the old laundry building and put cement plat - form over boiler and new coal bin Tile floor and side walls in kitchen and cold storage. Replacement of all wooden stairways with stairways of fireproof construction. Removal of the old pavillion. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">342 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF New coal bin to the west of the boiler room. Fireproof roof on the old part of the main building. tTo make our maintenance appropriation for the next nium upon a basis of $1.40 per day for an average of 140 ;nts. CONCLUSION I The superintendent desires to extend his thanks espec - to Hon. Howard Kennedy, Hon. Silas A. Holcomb and . Henry Gerdes, the members of the Board of Commis - ers of State Institutions, who have exerted themselves ringly during the biennium in behalf of the Orthopedic pital and all of the other State institutions. The hospital specially indebted also to other State officers and to many r Nebraska and Lincoln citizens and to Miss Billie Burke to the Lincoln committee with Mrs. D. F. Easterday as rman, for generous gifts and attentions at Christmas other times. More children have been helped to physical and mental independence than during any previous biennial period. It is a great satisfaction for us to feel that now considerably more than 1000 children have been cured or greatly benefitted by the hospital and educational care they received at this institution. We respectfully bespeak for our children and our work the same liberal and enthusiastic support which has been accorded heretofore. Respectfully submitted, H. WlNNETT ORR, Superintendent. Lincoln, S'rbraska, S'ovenber SO, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 343 •SO first admissions; 8 readmitted. TABLE II. \«.K OF THOSE ADMITTED FOB THE FIE8T TIME Fur Year ending Nov. 30, r.u.-. Kor Year ending Not. SO, r.'ii; Total tor Bienuium MOVE.MKXT M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Present at beginning of period 5© Admitted : For flret time _ ~ 81 Readmitted 57 Transferred from other institutions* ... 30 48 107 M 57 121 ! 69 48 107 73 1J4 122 101 223 203 174 3TT lt&gt; 12« 61 80 141 118 148 207 W S7 22 !i 31 52 38 88 Total under treatment 1 227 ..227 217 444 i 2« 247 516 4.12 407 88» 217 444 1 2«9 247 516 432 407 88» Discharged : Cured - Improved I'nimproved Died m ?-' 140 75 50 125 143 122 2tt 75 «0 144 108 122 225 178 191 MB 14 14 28 15 14 29 29 28 57 6 5 11 6 f 13 12 12 24 Total dlwhartrert ." i«:i i»m :ca ino ia&lt; .ies ! *c sb us Remaining at end of period M Average under treatment , I 61 57 121 TO .'« Ill 74 .vi 124 35 129 70 ■ M 131 52 120 «. For Year ending NOV. 30, 1915 For Y(*ar endlDK Not. SO, 1916 Total for Biennlum M. F. T. M. F. T. .11. r. T. I'nder 1 month 1 and under 3 month* 3 and under 6 months « and under 12 months 1 and under 2 years. -. 2 and under 5 years I and under 10 years 10 and under 15 years— IB and under 20 years 20 and under 2S years 25 and under SO years SO and under 40 years •0 and under SO year* Over 50 vears ...... ..._....-_ 1 2 _.. 1 2 1 S &lt;■ 6 Ml 1.% 22 21 32 22 14 IS 6 4 1 4 4 4 5 1 I 2 4 12 31 m 54 30 10 I 1 I ,- 1 1 2 8 11 16 42 23 IK 8 4 • 2 2 i 2 2 2 3 11 20 as 13 11 2 s 2 2 s! 3 4 10 14 26 SS 49 29 1» « 12 4 4 s 1 4 9 17 31 84 56 30 14 5 M&gt; I s s • 3 4 2 S 5 14 » M 26 57 47 111 48 108 2» 59 is a • 11 10 20 2 7 2 5 Tota)s_ 100 109 98 98 207 141 109 250 250 207 •497 isrr tar 109 28O~ 250 207 '487 •SO from other Institutions. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">344 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE III. CIVIL HT ATI S OF THOME ADMITTED FOR THE FIKMT TIME For Ye«r For Virar CIVIL, BTATfS Married _ 7 3 10 1 5 8 13 12 11 23 intiwi Divorced |1 2 3 '2 1 33 3 6 Separated a 2 _ 2 5 Unknown 1 1 1 1 Totals 108 98 20T 141 100 250 [ 250 207 «"• •90 from other institutions. TABLE IV. EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FIRST TIME Totals 10G 98 207 141 106 250 260 207 467* •§0 from other institution*. eadliiK vudiui; Total Nov. 30, Nov. SO, for 1915 1916 Biemiiuin M. F. T. M. F. T. M. r. T gingle mm 101 91 192 j 134 90 233 236 19O 426 • Tor Yeix ending Not. 30, 1915 For Ysar ending Not. 30, 1916 Total 1 for Biennium ■DtJCATION M. F. T. M. r. T. M F. T None _ 32 29 Primary _ 3 3 1st to «h grade 29 23 4th to 8th grade I S7 35 *h to 12th grade. _ 6 8 College or university 1 Unknown _______________ 1 61 55 26 6 5 3 52 33 31 72 36 36 14 Id 14 1 1 1 2 80 87 54 141 8 8 g M 64 «_ 54 116 71 73 70 14S 24 16 22 38 1 1 1 I as s </seg>
            <seg id="p014">M C I ; I y. Q •t I ■ -:, H * V V £ Q u b 2 :\ ■^ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 345 TABLE V. NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED FIRST TIME For Year For \ -Mr ending ending Tola! for NATIVITY Not. 30, Not. SO, Ml 1»1« Blenuluw M. r. T. M. F. T. M. F. T Nebraaka _ T» 71 160 10« 77 1M 186 1« JM rnttod States, other than Nebraska M ■£&gt; 51 31 M 57 57 51 HJ8 Total native boru MS 9« 201 137 108 240 242 1» Ml Poland |_ _ —. 1 1 1 1 Porto Rico _. . 1 1 I 1 1 Russia 1 1 1 11 1 2 Switwrland I 11 11 Total foreign born •» 2 «4 6108 81* Totals 109 98 207 : 141 109 250 2» JOT mf i •80 from other Institntions. Hohfiiiia __... ■■ , { , , „ _ — Canada Denmark 1 England 1 &lt;iermany 1 Greece In-laud - 1 Italy Xetherlanda - ._.. 11 1 112 11 1 1 . 1 _ ______ 1 1 I _ 12 ..._ 1 __. 1 1 _.. 1 | i a _ i i _. .... _.... i i i </seg>
            <seg id="p016">346 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF nBLfc VI. (UlNTV OF KKhlDKME OF THOSE ADMITTKU FOR FIBST TIME AMI OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIXNNIUM Fbr Year For Year All euuiug .inline Nwr. ;m. xov. 30, Total Remaining CHIXTV for Not. 30, 1916 ' BieuDlum 1U1« 1»15 M. ¥. T. M. ¥. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Adams 1 — 1 ' 2 1 3 3 1 4 2 — 2 I Airtelope _ LI 1 1 1.1 1 Arthur !' 1 — 11 1 I - 1 1 _ 1 1,_ 1 1 Booue a 2 2 |. t — i Box Butte 1 2 5 1 6 2 : Buffalo 4 4 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 1 Burt 1 1 Butler 3 3 1 4 S 1 7 8 2 I im -.. 1 1 2 1 1 2 (XUr ! — 1 II — 1 1 1 1 1 3 3 1 3 4 1 1 Cherry tTwyenue - _1112SJ1S421J Clay I •• I 2 1 1 112 ■' 2 13 I 6 1 1 1 1 1 1 112 s 1 10 3 3 I __ 1 1 11 1 1 1 3 2 2 I lodge 1 1 1 1 Dandy 1 2 3 1 2 t Douglas 5 2 7 e 12 11 S 19 • « 15 FUlmore 3 1 4 ■2 0 2 5 1 6 112 Franklin 1 1 1 1 ■ 1 1 2 l l Frontier — i 1 — 11 — 1 Fullerton 1 1 1 — 1 J-urnas 1 l! 1 1 Gage 8 'i 1 8 M 10 *18 1 1 Garden ' i 1 11 1 Uosper _ _ 1 1 (irrelfv _ __ 2 2 2 2 3 3 Hall 1 ill 1 3S 1 4 1 _... 1 2 _ 2 2 13 3 14 1 _... 1 Hamilton 2 2 ! _ j 2 2 2 2 4 2 _ 2 2 - 2 2 Harlan ' 2 2 1 1 i 2 1 8 I Hares 1 , 1 1__ 1 1 1 1 Illrrhwk 1 ..__ 11 1 2 2 Unit 1 1 ' 1 1 1 1 Howard _ 2 2 — ■_ 2 2 1 1 •j Jefferson 13 44266510123 Johnson 2 2314616123 I Kearney 1 1 — 1 11 1 2 Klmhall 1 1 _ 1 1 Knoi |,1 1 LaBraRter _ 62 «712&gt;6» 50 119 131 117 248 13 8 2H l.mrnlr _.... 1 l'j 2 4 2 8 Bit—.. 2 ■olfax 1 ] :umiuK 112 _ _ .■u«er 1 — 1 4 4 Dakota _ — 1 1 [Him 1 1 Jmwton 4 — 4 4 2 « &gt;uel _ 1 1 Jiion ....„ 1 ] 'C.I </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 347 TABLE VI. (OI'NTV OF KK&gt;II&gt;KM E OF THUHK \IIM1I TKI&gt; FOK HK.-T TIME AND OK THOSE REMAINING AT BSD OF BIENNll'M— |C«I1im4) For Year For Year All ending ending Total Remainin Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for Nov. 30, IMS Iil6 Blenoium 1MB Total Remaining corxTV M. P. T. M. F. T. i M. F. T. M. 1". T. Logan 1 j] l i] 2 .... 2 Lopan — ~ _» .. _______ 1 11 12 Loop 1 1 11112 Loup I 1 l 1111 Ma&lt;li»t.h MiMlison _ 2 2 2 2 MiPheraon j i i x 1 1 MiPhereon ! i i x 1 1 Merrick I _' i i j Merrlck _ ! i _ Nance 2 2 2 2 11 Xemana __ 2 1 SI 18 141 Nuckolls „ . _ i Otoe I ] l 2 1 l ...... i 2 13 1 1 Otoe 1 l ■&gt; \ \ 2 I I 1 i-avnre _ 3 2532511 1'iwnee .! 2 3323112 riu-ipn i _ Pfcatpa 1 i rtf"-* _ _ i i _ i i ' 1'ierw 1 l ..... l l I'latte _ _.. 1 1 1 i i I'latte _... i i 1 ii i I'olk 1 l 11112 1 Polk 1 i 11112 — 11 Red Willow _ 1 i i i i Ked Willow. 1 » 1 1 1 1 Kirbardson 2 2 1 1 3 S _. 1 Kirbardson — 1' j 1 i 3 j _. 1 1 Saline 1 l i i Saline 1 l i i 2 2 Sarpv _ _ 1" j garpy „ „ _ 1 Siiuiiilers _ i :t 2 ".' 4 4 3 7 _I Rootts Bluff. 1 . l 1 i _,_'_ Sootts Bluff. 1 1 1 1 Seward 1 ._. . 1 2 2 3 S 1 i 2 Seward 1 ._. . 1 2 2 3 111 I Sherman 2 2 2 2 1 1 Shermnn 2 2 2 2 1 Sioux . J^...__ ■ Thayer _ _ 1 12 1 1 2 1 _ Thomas 1 1 11 2 1 Tnarston ] 3 2 5 3 2 5 12 S Tnarston 3 2 ."&gt; S 2 5 ~1 2 Valley _. 2 1 3 2 1 J ( 1 Wehster __ — _ — 1- 1 2 2 2 1 3 Wheeler — 1 1 1 1 2 j [ Washington 2 2 __ 2 * ] . York _. 1 121322412S 2 2 Other states.. 2 2 Total* 111 100 211 144 110 254 2» 210 •4« 70 54 124 •SO from other Institutions. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">348 TABLE VII. 1IIKH OF I)I»K\&gt;I. OF THOUE REMAINING IN HOSPITAL MIVKMKEK M, 1*14, AND ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME IMI.1D1M. THOSE FROM OTHER INnTITI TlllN&gt; For Year i'or Y&gt;nr ending ending Total Not. 30. Nov. .TO. for IJISEASK Far 1913 191« Bleu ilium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T Abscess on bam) I 1 1 1 1 Atitces* psoas.. — 1 1 1 1 Adenitis, see tlx\ mi&lt;1 syphilis - 2 2 _. I 2 •' Adenoids _ 52721S73 10 .-. Adenoid* and tonolls _ 28 18 44 29 *) S&gt; 54 49 KM Ankyloals. knee _.. _ _ 1 1 1 1 AmiR. fissure of _ _ 1 1 _. 1 1 Anus. Imperforte coniwiilul _ 1 1 , 1 1 Appendidtta _ - 2 2 2 II 2 4 lniun.lU'ltli 2 ? ? 5! ? 2 4 Arthritis, deformans. _ _ 1 1 1 1 Arthritis, lieformann multiple 1 1 1 1 Aathms _ _ _ 1 1 1 1 Birth, premature 1 1 1 1 ... -' 2 Bow tor* — 2 2 4 3 S I •-' 7 Broii-liir is 2 2 2 2 Bronchitis chronic 1 1 1 1 Broncho pneumonia Burn _ _ ! 1 1 1 1 Caleaneum. spur on 1 — 1 1 — 1 Chest, deformity of 1 1 — 1 1 Chicken pox.... .. 1 1 i 1 111 1 * Chorea 1 1 2 1 1 ! * 1 « ; Cleft palate 1 1 2 1 1 I Club hand and feet 1 1 ! 1 1 Clo«&gt; foot, congenital _. « 1 7 S 5 IS 14 « 30 Congenital defect foot - _.... 1 1 -.... 1 1 | 2- 2 I Congenital elevation scapula _. " 1 1 1 1 Contracture deformity, nee ateo paral.T alt - 1 Ill 2 * 3 Coxa vara Ill 1 j 1 1 Cywovarl.ii' 1 1 1 1 Deaf and damn _ _ 1 1 ' I 1 1 niplitherin niplegrla (due to aplna hiflda) _ 1 1 1 1 Dipleela 1 1 1 1 Dislocation, congenital, (nee hlpt...._ 1 1 ' 1 1 2 5 Dislocation, elhow _ 1 1 1 _... 1 2 2 • • Dislocation, shoulder Joint..._ 1 1 _ 1 1 Elbow, ankylosis. - _ _ 1 1 1 1 Rmpyema 1 _.... 1 1 1 j 1 1 Endometritls __ - „ 1 1 1 1 Epilepsy *lttl4lt1 ■&gt; Erysipelas _ 1 1 i _ 1 1 Flat foot__ _.._ 2 2 4 1 1 2 1 3 « Fistula, reetnm _ - i 1 1 1 1 Foot, strain i 1 1 i 1 l Foot. weak, (due to injury^ _ 1 1 1 1 Foreign body in eye*- 1 1 „_... l i Fracture. clav!c«l__ _ _ ' 1 1 11 Fractnre. tibia, cong _ 1 1 1 l Fracture, condyle, ext. and Inter 1 „.. 11 — 1 Fracture, elbow | 9 1 S 2 1 « I Fracture, femnr I 1 11 1 2 2 1 I 2 2 Fracture, lower Jaw_ 1 1 1 i Fricture, jaw _ 1 _ l l .._ l Fracture, knimrai | I I 2 2 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">&lt; HI 0 x u - 0 0 a &gt;■ s Or a P M 0 5 5 r" ■ 1 a as &lt; M OB 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 349 TABLE VII. FORM (IF IH-»K.\»fc Or THOSE REMAINING IN Hn»rll VI NOVEMBER M, »14. AND ADMITTED FOR IIKM TIME 1M I.I HIM, THOSE FBOM OTIIKK &gt; s TITl T1O&gt; &gt; — (( onttnurd I For Year For Year ending ending Total Nor. 30, .Nov. m, for f«.r 1915 1918 Bienninm M F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Fracture, radius and ulna 1 1 3 3 13 4 Gastroenteritis _ _ _ 1 1112211 Grippe 112 112 Hammer toea _ - 1 1 2 2 3 3 ■' Hand, eontracture deformity j 1 1 2 2 3 — S Hare lip _ 3 14 3 1 4 Hare Up and cleft palate_._ I I — &gt; 3 — S Goitre _ I 1 1 — 1 1 Heart, valvular disease 1 1 1 1 Heinipleftla. spastic... __ 112 2 2 13 4 Hernia, congenital 3 3 3 3 Hernia inguinal 1 1241552T Hernia Inguinal 112 4 15 5 2 7 Hernia umbilical - 2 2 '1 2 Hernia umbilical.. Hernia ventral _ — 1 1 . 1 1 Hernia ventral — 1 1 1 1 Hip. Joint disease _ 1 _... 1 1 1 Hip. congenital misplacement of , 3 3 _.. 3 1 Hip. congenital misplacement of , 3 3 _.. 3 3 Homeless .. 2 2 _ _ 2 2 H T&lt;lr&lt;H*ephaln8 134112249 Hypospasldas _ 1 1 _ 1 1 Infection, finger _ - — 1 1 1 Infection, finger _ _ 1 1 1 1 Infection, patella, following operation elsewhere .... 1 „ 1 .__....._.„. ... 1 „.. elsewhere _. 1 1 1 1 Injury, hlrth 1 1 1 1 Injury, birth 1 1 X Injury, knee. 1 1 11 Injury, knee. 1 1 1 Modeling disease _ _ 1 1 1 Modeling disease _ __ 1 1 11 Limp, unex pi jiineii .. _...„.„ .........._..... „ _______.. __. 1 1 ..__ 1 Limp, unexplained I _______.. 1 1 1 1 Lordo«is clavlcal 1 1 - 1 I.onlosis clavlcal ..— i _.. 1 1 1 1 Masturbation - ! _... 1 1 11 Masturhatiou - 1 1 , .,, m mm m \ Mastoidltis _ _ . _.. 1 1 _.... 1 1 MlHtoidltis - - — 1 1 -.... 1 Mentally defective _ _ _.... 1 1 .._. 1 1 Mentally defective _.. _ _.... 1 1 1 Mother of haby_ „ _... 1 1 1 1 Mother of haby_ „ 1 1 1 Multiple deformity, congenital ... _ 1 1 1 1 Multiple deformity, congenital _.. _ 1 1 1 Myeliti** 1 1 1 1 Needle In foot _ - _... 1 11 1 1 Myelitis — 1 1 1 Needle in foot _ - _ — . 1 1 1 Xmirltln 2 2 1 11 * | Neuritis 2 2 1 11 2 Oesophagus, stricture of „ 1 1 ' 1 1 Oesophagus, stricture of „ 1 1 1 1 Osteo arthritis knee....™ , ' 1 1 1 1 Osteo arthritis knee I ' 1 1 1 1 Onteo arthritis shoulder 1112 lit Osteo arthritis shoulder 112 1 1 J O»teo arthritis spine. __ 1 1 3 1 4 S O»teo arthritis spine. _ _.... 11 X 1432ft 1 Osteomyelitis 10 » 1.1 2 2 4 12 5 17 Osteomyelitis 10 3 1.1 2 2 4 12 5 17 Ostitis media ..... 1 1 1 1 t 2 Ostitis media 1 1 1 1 I 2 Pan ophthalmitts _ 1 11 1 Pan ophthalmitis _ 1 1 1 1 Paralysis, infantile acute S 1 4 S 1 4 Paralysis, infantile acute 3 14 3 14 Paralysis, infantile. _ 19 2ft SB 19 13 » 38 33 71 Paralysis, infantile. _ _ 10 2ft 3S 19 13 K 38 3S 71 Paralysis, spastic » 6 25 • « 25 « tl Paralysis, spastic » 6 25 • 8 28 « 31 Paralysis, due to fracture- 2 2 2 2 Paralysis, diphtheritic _ 1 1 1 _ 1 Periostitis _.. 1 1 _.. _ 1 1 Perlotfltls 1 1 _ 1 1 Perltonttl, 1 1 _Z"_.__ ." ._' 1 1 Phimosta _ • • 4 — 4 1* 10 Pltnitary Kland — 1 1 1 i Paeudo muscular hypertrophy S * i 2 1 Rr.-MH* 17 3 10 « 1 7M 4 IT 10 • 1 T 13 4 IT Sarro llenm dislocation 113 _ 11* Sacrn Uliac strain. ' -. 1 1 1 Sarro tlenm dislocation. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">350 TAKI.K VII. IIIRM OF HMM •* THONK KKMAIMNO IN HOSPITAL NOVEMBKB W. 1»14, AND ADMITTED FOK FIK.ST TIME IMIIDIM. THOSE FROM OTHER 1NST1TI TION&gt; — UonHudrd I Fr&gt;r Year For Year ending ending Total Not, 30. Not. 30, for for 1915 1916 Biennlum M. F. T. M. F\ T. M. F. T Scarlet fever __._ j 1 1 1 1 Sclerotic amyotrophic, lat _ 1 1 1 1 Sclerosli, tpinal cord_ _ 1 1 1 1 Scrofula, _ - 1 1 _ _ 1 1 1 1 1 1 Scolioala 7 8 15 1 8 • 8 16 24 Shortening leg 1 1 1 1 epira hillda 111 — 111 - pruin. ankle 1 1 1 1 Stniui'. painful _.. 1 1 1 1 STphllU I .- 1 2 * 1 2 S Tonull*. tulnm* 11 1 1 2 * Tonsilltla S 2 1 1 3 S 1 u I &gt;«'r'"U IonIk — ..-. — 1 1 -„--— 1 1 TuIh&gt;ku1oiiIh .-lanrts 1 1 ...._ 1 1 Tuberculosis liij. _ 11 4 15 1 2 1 12 6 18 TuberculioiM knee 5 7 12 !!?•*&gt; 14 Tnhemilnalu imilliple Ipone and Joint* 1 1 1 .... 1 5 7 12 S 4 12 U 11 74 Tll'MTCUiniiia Kl'llll'. Tl'l.ennlnsis ;.i, ' nmimry Varii'OKe i l&lt;*er _ 1 1 „ _... 1 1 1 1 1 1 Tiit.il&gt; 170 14* :\\s 144 110 2M .%14 2W !(72 Inclnrteo those preoent at the t&gt;eicinnliiir of the lilenuium •From other Institntlnns. TABI.K VIII. OFKRATION DURING BIENKIUM F»r Year For 1 «ar ending ending Total Nrv. 30. Not. SO. for ol'KKATlON for 1915 1916 Biennlum M. F. T. If. F. T. ; M. F T Surgical operation*- 119 85 204 148 115 2«3 287 200 467 Plaster dreMingx. 410 47!" 888 Surelral dresaingiL ! __ 7401 -... 9TB* 1718B X raj- pioturea. _ 178 _.... 1M 374 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE IX. ..DURATION OF HOSPITAL KEMIDENCE OF THOSE DISCHARGED DIKING BIENNll'M eliding ending Total Nov. 30. Not. SO. for CAUSE f..r Acute dilution of the heart 1 — - 1 _ 1 — 1 Anne meningitis, encephalitis 1 1 I 1 1 Fatty embolism of lungs _ 1 — 1 _ — 1 — Gastroenteritis 1 2 S I 1 » * 2 4 • Hydrorephalus _ -..- 1 1 — 1 1 — 1 * Intussusception ._ _ '1 1 1 1 Onrlan cyst_ _ - ! 1 1 ...... 1 1 Pneumonia 1 1 ' 1 11 1 * Premature birth 1 1 i — 1 1 Pulmonary congestion— _ 1 1 ..... 1 1 Pyellti* 1 11 1 Pyelonephritis _ _ 1 1 1 ..... 1 Pyloric stenosis _ _ I 1 ..-.. 1 1 -. 1 San-oma ireneni! _ _ - , 1 1 1 1 Tuherenlodi. pulmonary -.. 1 1 *j 1 1 t Total* • 5 11 « T 1.1 1? 12 M 1915 191« Blennium M. r. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Tntwrrnlosls. «renera! 1 — 1 1 1 RESULT Arerair* loured 1 niproved _„ .„ B I* nini proved _____-«„_« Died , Average residence of all discharged MS ,layi 134 days 14 day* 118 days S7 i.y« TABLE X. SUMMARY OF BK81LT OF THOSE DISCHARGED RESULT Nnmber PtreMt ?ared [DiprnvtHl . . "nimprovtMl 9ted I — MS M S S7.0T 51.61 ».4» Totals. 715 100 '10 T15 TABLE XI. CACHE OF DEATH I For Year For 7^«r </seg>
            <seg id="p023">352 TABLE XII. AGE AT DEATH For Year For Year Pendl»« ending Total AGE \i t. 3d. Nov. !», lor 1815 1916 Blennlum M. F. T. M F. T. M. F. T. Iniler 1 month _ ...... 1111212S 1 and under 3 months - — 1 1 1 1 3 and under 6 months- _ 1 _.. 1 1 1 2 2 « and under VI mouths- 112 - 112 1 and under 2 years 112 2 2 13 4 and under I years...- •_ _ i 2 2 2 — 2 5 and under 10 years — 2 2 1 112 3 10 and under 15 years 3 3 2 2 3 2 5 15 and under 20 years... L*i» find under 25 years... 25 and under 30 years.. 30 aud under 40 years _ „ „ 1 1 1 1 4(&gt; and under 50 years— _ _ 1 1 1 1 oO and over... Totals « 5 11 S 7 IS 12 12 24 I Illl K XIII. KATIO OF KMri.Ol KK&gt; TO CM IKS I- M F T NiiiiiIht of physicians, including superintendent _ Ratio of physicians to patients 1:34 1:20 1:00 Number of day nurses.. _ 13 13 Ratio of same to patients 1 :15 1 :3.5 1 :8.5 Number of nipht nurses- - 3 3 Ratio of same to patients- 1 :23 1 :17 1 :40 Total officers _ _.._ 9 43 52 Ratio of same to patients 1:1.J» 1:1 l:2.*0 </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>