<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00015">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00015</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA</title>
			            <date value="1903">1903</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
The Univkrsity of Nebraska. 

BULLETIN 

or the 

AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

or 

NEBRASKA. 

Volumk XVI, Article I. 

EXPERIMENTS IN MULCHING GARDEN VEGETABLES. 

By U. a. Kmerson. 

Distkibiteh Jilt 15. IMS. 

LINCOLN, NKBRASKA. 

r. s. a. 

\ </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
CONTENTS. 


Introduction 

Plan of experiments 4 

Results of experiments — 

Lettuce 7 

Cabbage 

Tomatoes 9 


Means 12 

Cucumbers 14 

Muskmelons and watermelons 16 

Sweet corn 17 

Beets 17 


Carrots and parsnips 19 

Onions 19 

Potatoes 20 

Special potato test 21 

Sweet potatoes 24 

Discussion of results 25 </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
BY R. A. EMERSON.* 

INTRODUCTION. 

The use of a straw mulch in place of cultivation to conserve 
soil moisture and prevent weed growth in gardens is no new 
thing. Mulching has found restricted use in vegetable and fruit 
gardens for many years. Potatoes and strawberries have 
probably been mulched more than any other crops, but several 
other vegetables have been occasionally grown in this way, and 
cultivation in small-fruit gardens, vineyards, and even orchards, 
has been not infrequently supplemented by mulching. In many 
cases very satisfactory results have been reported from the use 
of mulches. Considerable attention has been given the subject 
by experiment stations in various parts of the country. A 
majority of the tests resulted in favor of mulching, and yet, 
notwithstanding all these good reports, the practice has never 
become generally popular and must therefore have some serious 
drawbacks. 

The fact that excellent results have followed the use of 
mulches in many cases, makes it desirable to test the practice 
thoroughly in order to determine what vegetables can be grown 
successfully by mulching and what ones cannot, and to determine 
in general, if possible, the conditions under which mulching 
can be successfully practiced. It is also important to learn 
whether this method of culture cannot be modified so as to do 
away with some of its bad features. 

ilost farm gardens are made with considerable enthusiasm in 
spring. Manv of them are tended carefully at first, but 
1 the approach of dry, hot weather, just when they need 
ntion most, they are usually neglected. Any method of 
den culture, therefore, that requires practically no labor durthe 
summer months when the rush of farm work is greatest, 
ainly invites careful attention. 

A test was therefore begun at the Experiment Station in 
1900. During the first year, a nearly normal season, mulching 

•In presenting thl« hulletln. the writer wishes to acknowledn the assistance be has 
recelTPd from Mr. Val Key«er. who ban kepi most of the record" here reported. Mr. 
Key«er has also aided, by helpful suggestions, in planning the experiments and in preparing 
the results for publication. 

BULL 80 AGR. KXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XVI, ART. I. </seg>



            <seg id="p004">
4 

i compared with thorough cultivation in growing a consideranumber 
of vegetables on upland without irrigation. In the 
t dry summer of 1901 the comparison was made on both irri:d 
and unirrigated upland. In 1902, mulching was tested 
omparison with thorough cultivation on both bottom land 
upland, but naturally neither mulched nor cultivated ground 
irrigated during this very wet summer. 

PLAN OF THE MULCHING EXPERIMENTS. 

In 1900, the vegetable garden was divided lengthwise into 
two plats, each about twenty rods long by two and one-half 

Ftf. &gt;¦ Partial view of the low land garden in 1902. showing tomatoes, cabbage, onions, 
ano been- The mulched plat is seen in the foreground and the cultivated piat just back 

twide. One plat was mulched and the other cultivated, 
vegetables were planted in rows across the two plats, 
plats were cultivated several times, the mulch in most cases 
f applied nearly a month after the garden was planted, 
mulch used was, for the most part, old straw. Partially 
I blue grass hay wa&lt; used for a few vegetables. After </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
5 

Eing, the mulch was about four inches deep. The unmulched 
was cultivated thoroughly as long as the vegetables 
ed it. The comparison therefore is not of mulching versus 
ect, but of mulching on the one hand and the most thorough 
vation on the other. 

In 1901, five plats of vegetables were grown, each plat being 
about twenty rods long by two rods wide. Two plats were 
irrigated and three unirrigated. One of the irrigated plats was 
mulched and the other cultivated. Owing to the small size of 
the plats, irrigation by the "furrow" method was impracticable. 
Resort was therefore had to the less satisfactory method of 

Tig. t. Partial view of low land garden in 1908 The cultivated plat la In th« fora 
frouod and the mulched plat buck of it. The vegetables are carrots, parsnips, salsify 
beeU. and onions. 

"flooding." The slope of the ground was so pronounced that 
it was more difficult to apply sufficient water at one irrigation 
to the cultivated than to the mulched ground. The mulched 
plat therefore received more water at each irrigation than the 
cultivated plat, but was not irrigated so frequently. Of the three 
unirrigated plats, one was mulched and two cultivated. The </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 


The mulch consisted entirely of old straw and was spread about 
four inches deep, as iti the previous year. It was applied earlier 
than in iooo, in some cases being spread soon after the plants 
came up. The cultivation given the unmulched plats was, as in 
the first test, as thorough as possible, no weeds being allowed 

In 1902, two gardens were laid out, one on rich bottom land 
that was rather low but well drained, the other on moderately 
rich upland with a slight southwestern slope. Both gardens 
were divided lengthwise into two plats, each two and one-half 
rods wide, the plats on the low land being twenty rods long and 
on the upland seven rods. One plat was cultivated thoroughly 
and the other mulched as in previous years. The low land 
garden was plowed in the spring and worked down with disk 
and harrow. The ground dried out badly, causing delay in 
germination of the vegetable seeds. The high land garden 
was fall plowed. The ground was therefore moist in the 
spring, favoring prompt germination. Moreover, on this 
garden site cane had been grown the year before, leaving the 
ground comparatively free from weeds. The vegetables were 
planted in rows across the plats, care being taken to have the 
same number of plants in each plat. The mulch consisted of 
old straw and was about four inches deep after settling. In 
most cases it was applied about a month after the plants or 
seeds were planted, the ground being cultivated two or three 
times before the mulch was spread. Figures 1 and 2 present 
partial views of the low land garden. 

In addition to the general tests noted above, a special experiment 
was conducted with potatoes in 1902. A comparison 
was made of different depths of mulching, different materials 
for the mulch, different times of applying the mulch, etc. 

Besides the tests carried on in the gardens of the Experiment 
Station, the value of mulching as a method of garden culture 
has also been tried by the Experiment Station in cooperation 
with farmers in many sections of the State. The results of 
these cooperative tests are to be reported in a separate bulletin. </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
7 

RESULTS OF THE MULCHING TESTS. 

LETTUCE. 

In 1900 a heading lettuce, Iceberg, was grown, and in 1901 
a loose-leaved variety, Grand Rapids. In 1902, two sorts, 
Grand Rapids and Tennis Ball, the latter a heading lettuce, 
were raised. The first season, the seed was sown April 19 
and the plants were cultivated until June 9, when one plat 
was mulched, cultivation being continued in the other until the 
last of June. In 1901 the seed was sown April 27, the plants 
being cultivated until June 1, when the mulch was spread. 
Cultivation was continued in the unmulched plats until late in 
June. In 1902 the seed was drilled March 25 in the low land 
garden, but owing to very dry weather in the spring, did not 
germinate for several weeks. The mulch was applied May 22, 
the plants having been cultivated only once. The unmulched 
plat was cultivated twice afterwards. No lettuce wan grown 
on the high land. The results of the test with lettuce are as 
follows : 

1900. 

1901. 

INK 

Irrigated. 

Not irrigated. 

Variety and 
method of _ .s 
culture. : ~ 
t* 

.c 
b 

ID • 
"1 o&lt;2 || S| 

*- oo : Ja Sfjg *- no 
Lbs. Lbs. 

if 

¦ 

— 

Lbs. 

L6«. L6». L6». 

Lb*. 

r 

57 
vation 73 

37 

.S4 

Rapids: 

. ... 64 37 .58 
. ... 83 51 .61 
•• •¦ 

84 37 .44 41 
78 34 .44 46 

¦ 

14 
30 

Tennis Ball: 
Mulch 
Cultivation . . . . 

.... 140 
.. ..' 130 

ax 
50 

1 

The mulched pla 
•nes in 19CO, but cc 
iroveri very difficu 
ler plants, the stan&lt; 
ver, this vegetable 

nts were a trifle e 
nsiderably later ii 
It to mulch lettuce 
1 usually being hu 
is of such short 

at Her than the cultivated 
1 1901 and 1902. It has 
without injury to the ten- 
rt by the practice. More- 
duration and requires so </seg>


            <seg id="p008">
8 

few cultivations that mulching is of doubtful value in growing 
it, even where the size of the heads is increased by the mulch. 

CABBAGE. 

|!*he Surehead variety was grown in each of the three sum's 
from 1900 to 1902 inclusive, and Early Jersey Wakefield 
900 and again in 1902. In all cases the seed was sown in 
s in the greenhouse. In 1900 the plants were set in the 
i May 17 and cultivated until June 12, when one plat was 
ched, cultivation being continued in t.ie other plat throughthe 
summer. In 1901 the plants were set out May 15, the 
ch being applied very soon afterwards. In 1902 they were 
May 15 and mulched June 12, after having been cultivated 
:e times. The clean cultivation plat on high land was culted 
seven times and the one on low land six times. 

The results of these tests with cabbage are as follows : 

1900. 

1901. 

IMS. 

Irrigated. 

Not Irri. 

Highland. iLowland. 

I Variety and 
thod of culture. 

w -a 
- I 
O o 

T 
•a 
— 

¦s 

•s f 
i b 

i 
1 

«3 

d 
S5 

&gt; 6 

1 

&gt; 6 

-- 

i 

i 

d i 

i 

i 

a a 

Surehead: 
Mulch 29 241 
Cultivation 16 L» 

8.8 
5.2 

M 
21 

160 4.1 
(MJ3.1 

28102 
27 81 

3.6 31 
80 17 

172 
Kit 

5.2 19 

* 

Early Jersey 
Wakefield: 
Mulcb 65 180 
Cultivation 72 151 

2 2 26 
-».:! 18 

53 2.0 
28 1.6 

2.8 
2.1 

M 
23 

61 
54 

{'he most noticeable feat 
relatively larger size of 
bage. In 1902 on the t 
ween mulched and culti 
ds. The cultivated cal 
1 the mulched, decreas 
the low land the early 1 

ure of the tests of 1900 and 1901 is 
heads of mulched than of cultivated 
high land there was little difference 
ivated cabbage in regard to size of 
bbage, however, rotted much worse 
ing the total yield very noticeably, 
cabbage, Wakefield, produced some- </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
Experiment* in Mulching Garden Vegetable*. 

9 

E larger heads by mulching than by cultivation and also 
much worse on the cultivated plat. The summer cab- 
Surehead, however, grew much larger on the cultivated 
n the mulched plat. 

A late variety of cabbage planted in 1901 gave no returns. It 
was noticed that grasshoppers attacked the mulched plants more 
than the cultivated ones, as was to be expected from the habits 
of this insect. The same thing has been noticed in some of the 
cooperative tests of mulching, to be reported in a later bulletin. 

in the whole, these tests are very favorable to mulching, 
bage plants are not easily mulched when small, but the work 
be done readily enough within two to four weeks after 
ting, at any time when farmers are not especially rushed 
1 work. It is quite evident, however, that mulching cannot 
uccessfully practiced where grasshoppers are very abun- 

TOMATOKS. 

Ierfection tomato was grown in 1900, Stone in 1901 and 1902, 
Dwarf Champion in all three seasons. The seeds were 
n in flats in the greenhouse in all cases. In 1900 the plants 
e set in the garden May 24 and the mulch spread June II, 
r all plants had been cultivated three times. Cultivation was 
inued in the unmulched plat until about the middle of July. 
901 the plants were not set out until June 12, the mulch 
g applied only a few days later. The unmulched plants 
e cultivated carefully throughout the summer. In 1902 the 
splanting was done May 15 and the mulching June 12, after 
e cultivations. The unmulched plat on high land was culti¦d 
seven times, the one on low land six times. 

The results of the three years' testa of tomatoes are as follows : </seg>


            <seg id="p010">
10 

Dwarf Champion 

24 121 5.0 16 7H4.7 14 4.. 3 2 :1U 
4.0 16 61».8 IT 55S.I 30 

Cultivation 

K2.8 30 

Perfection : 
Mulch... 

Cultivation 

S S 

14122!8.7 3 10 3.8 

28100!8.6 

2H .-)!!•». 0 

16136 ; 8.6i 15. 81 8.1 1 28' 

48 1.«i 28 27 0.9 

Cultivation 

It is worthy of note that in the rather moist season of 1900 
and the wet season of 1902 the use of a mulch increased very 
decidedly the yield of fruit per plant. The difference was less 
in case of the upright growing Dwarf Champion than with the 
"viney" Stone ard Perfection. In our rich soils tomato plants, 
particularly the large growing sorts, when provided with an 
abundant supply of moisture, are apt to make vigorous vine 
growth at the expense of fruit production. Probably by keeping 
the soil too cool and wet and by preventing proper aeration 
in seasons of heavy rainfall, mulches decrease vigor of vine 
growth and thereby increase fruitfulness. In 1902 the cultivated 
plants were decidedly ahead of the mulched ones in vigor of 
growth, the mulched plants being smaller and their foliage 
much lighter in color than the cultivated ones. 

In 1 901 the mulched tomatoes on irrigated land yielded more 
than the cultivated ones, the difference being considerable in 
case of Dwarf Champion and slight in case of Stone. On unirrigated 
land, the Dwarf Champion tomatoes yielded the same on 
both plats while the Stone yielded almost twice as "much per 
plant by cultivation as by mulching. This season, unlike the 
year preceding and the one following it, was very dry. The 
results, however, do not necessarily mean that mulching is 
unsatisfactory in a dry season. They are rather to be 
explained by the fact that the mulch was spread too soon 

19 222 11.7 
20136 6.8 </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
Experiment t in Mulching Garden Vegetable*. 

11 

after the plants were set out. Tomato plants are especially 
sensitive to cold. Frosts are more apt to occur on 
mulched than on cultivated land and are more severe by from 
three to five degrees. While in this case the mulched tomatoes 
were not actually frosted, they must nevertheless have been subjected 
to considerably lower temperatures at night than the cultivated 
ones. The early growth of tomatoes was plainly retarded 
by the mulch. Some of the plants afterwards recovered, 
though several of them died. The mulched plants of the early 
and hardy variety, Dwarf Champion, suffered comparatively little 
at first and finally overtook the cultivated plants. With the 
later and possibly more tender variety, Stone, only a few plants 
survived and they were never able to overcome their early 
handicap. In fact, the plants in all plats got such a late start in 
1901 that few fruits ripened, the figures for 1901 in the table 
representing largely the yield of green fruit. 

(Mulched tomatoes are usually less subject to rot than cultied 
ones, owing, probably, to their being kept free from dirt in 
iy weather. The mulched tomatoes are also larger as a rule 
1 more regular in shape. On the other hand, tomatoes, like 
very tender plants, are injured worse by early fall frosts 
en mulched than when cultivated. 

Ei general, then, mulching has given good results with toma, 
both in yield and quality of fruit. Care must be exercised 
to mulch such tender vegetables as tomatoes until they have 
&gt;me well established. 

PEAS. 

American Wonder peas were grown each of the three seasons 
during which mulching tests have been carried on. Champion 
of England were grown in 1900 and 1901, but in the latter 
season yielded no crop. In 1900 the seed was sown April 21 
and the mulch spread May 18. Cultivation was continued in the 
unmulched plat until the 1st of June. In 1901 the seed was sown 
April 22 and the plants mulched June 1, cultivation being continued 
in the unmulched plats as usual. In 1902 the seed was town 
April 5, straw being spread on the mulched plat May 22 and cultivation 
being continued on the other plat throughout June. 

The following results were obtained with peas: </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 


Weight of pods. 

rety and method 
of culture. 

1901 

1902. 

1900. 

Irrigated. 

Not Irrig. High land Low land. 

Lbs. 

Lbs. 

Lbs. Lbs. 


American Wonder: 

U4 

10 

y 

I 
•&gt; 

t&gt; 

In 1 901 the yield was somewhat in I 
&gt;2 even more so. The mulched 
lerican Wonder on the irrigated Ian 
unequal start that the yields are not 
m the mulched plats, however, wert 

in favor of cultivation and in 
led and cultivated plats of 

d land in 1901 obtained such 
e not comparable. The pods 
were cleaner, better filled, and 

I lined fresh longer than those from the cultivated plat. In 
&gt; mulching was decidedly ahead in case of American Wonpeas, 
and cultivation somewhat ahead in case of Champion 
England, the yield of the latter variety, however, being very 
• on both plats. The vines grew much larger on the 
:hed than on the cultivated ground, but were not provided 
. supports and therefore matted down, causing the pods to 
,y before they were fully developed. The mulched peas 
: somewhat later than the cultivated ones. Further trial is 
issary to determine the value of mulching in growing this 
ly, early vegetable. 

BEANS. 

In 1900 and 1901 the varieties grown were Golden Wax, a 
snap bean; Navy, a dry bean; and Henderson's Bush Lima and 
Burpee's Bush Lima, both green shell beans. In 1902 the dry 
and green shell beans grown were Navy, Henderson's Bush 
Lima and Dwarf Horticultural, and the snap beans Challenge 
Black, Wardwell, Stringless Green, and Mohawk. In 1900 the 
snap beans were planted May 5, the green shell beans May 1 2 
and 19, and the dry beans May 23. All kinds were mulched 
June 12, after being cultivated two or three times. The unmulched 
plats were cultivated three or four times after the 

Mulch 
Cultivation 

Champion of Eng. : 
Mulch 
Cultivation 

¦ </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
13 

Ich was spread on the other plats. In 1901 the seed was 
ited May 28, the mulch being applied two weeks later after 
cultivation, the unmulched beans being cultivated throughtheir 
growing seasons. In 1902 all varieties were planted 
f 17 and cultivated three times, the mulch being applied 
; 12. The unmulched plats were cultivated three times 
e on the low land and four times on the high land. The 
ilts with beans are shown in the table below. Where the 
ds are in favor of the mulch the figures are in black type. 

Where the difference is in favor of cult 
italics. Where the yields are the saint 
culture the figures are in common type 

ivation the figures are in 
for the two methods of 

dr 

eighi 
7 bei 

of 

Weig] 

it of green 

is. 

,ns. 

Year and method of 
cultivation. 

g3 
¦a on 
a 3 

1 
— ce 
I- 

I III 
± J_ ¥\ 
&amp; ill 

i5. 

« I 
2 
"3 
O 

I-s 
¦3J! 

IS 

3 

4 

i 

j 

Ich 1« 
tivation 7 

16 
16 

2.0 
Z.d 

S 

1901. 
irrigated land: 
Mulch : 0\ 
Cultivation 0\ 

I: 

o 
o 

o 
o 

Jnirrigated land: 
Mulch 0 
Cultivation 0 

d 

0 
o 

o 
o 

Cultivation l.t 
Low land: 
Cultivation 1.0 

" 

2.31 
2.3 

66 
4.1 

1.6 2.&amp;I 
O.» 1.8 
*.« 9.* 
9.« 

it 

d 

3.5 

7.5 
7.8 

t 

In these tests with beans, cultiv 
;han mulching in six cases and mu 
ivation in ten cases. In the remai 
ierence in yield between the two m 
In 1900, mulching was decidedly 

atioi 
lcbii 
ininj 
eth« 
¦ ahi 

' P 
'g 

rodui 

bette 

ases i 
of tr 
in c 

ced better yields 
r yields than cul- 
ihere was no dif- 

ids 
ad 

eatment. 
ase of Navy and </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 


Golden Wax beans. With the Lima beans there was little difference 
in yield between mulching and cultivation. The snap 
beans were a few days later on the mulch than on the cultivated 
ground but continued in bearing somewhat longer. The pods of 
the mulched plants, moreover, were larger and more uniform in 
size and color. In 1901, late planting coupled with severe drouth 
made all but the Henderson's Bush Lima a complete failure. 
The Golden Wax beans on the mulched plats remained green 
longer than those on the cultivated plats, but owing to the 
extremely dry, hot winds at blossoming time were unable to set 
any pods, even where irrigated. The leaves of Burpee's Bush 
Lima were badly burned in the cultivated plats by the last of 
July and much less severely injured in the mulched plats. This 
Lima and the Navy grew more vigorously on the mulched than 
on the cultivated ground and set many more pods, but late 
planting, together with delayed development at blossoming time 
on account of hot dry winds, made it impossible for these varieties 
to ripen before frost. The same difference in vigor of 
growth and numbers of pods set was seen in case of Henderson's 
Bush Lima. The mulched plants, however, being later than 
the others, did not ripen so well before frost. In the wet season 
of 1902, mulching proved better than cultivation, as a whole, on 
the high ground, but poorer on the low ground. 

It seems fair to conclude from these tests that in normal seasons 
mulching produces better yields of beans than cultivation 
does, except in case of late planting or of naturally late growing 
varieties. In such cases, by delaying maturity, mulches 
increase the possibility of loss from early frosts. 

CUCUMBERS 

White Spine cucumbers were grown in all the tests, and in 

addition Boston Pickling was raised in 1900. The first year, 
the seed was cultivated about May 10, the mulch being spread 
June 12, after both plats had been cultivated three times. The 
fruits were picked about every third day during the greater part 
of July and somewhat less frequently during August. The 

White Spine cucumber yielded as follows: 

Mulch 1065 fruits weighing 718 pounds 

Cultivation 823 fruits weighing 522 pounds 

There was then little difference in size of fruits, the important 

difference between the plats, aside from the yields, being in the 
uniformity of the product. During dry periods, the cultivated </seg>


            <seg id="p015">
15 

Eimbers decreased in numbers and those that grew were of 
irregular shape, many of them being very poorly devel- 
I. Tne mulched fruits, on the contrary, were always 
ght and evenly filled out to the end. 

I Che Boston Pickling cucumbers in 1901 were picked while 
y small, no account being taken of their weights. The 
Iched plat produced 1298 fruits as against 984 on the cultied 
plat. The mulched plants were somewhat later than the 
ers, the yield for the first three weeks, from June 26 to July 
being 364 fruits from the mulched plat and 445 from the culu 
ed one. 

In 1901 the seed was planted May 28 and the mulch spread 
June S, before the plants had made much growth. The small, 
tender plants were plainly injured by this early mulching and the 
dry weather came on before they had recovered. Plant lice 
hurt the plants of the cultivated plats worse than of the mulched 
ones and were especially injurious on the irrigation-cultivation 
plat, reducing the yields decidedly. Whether this difference in 
insect injury was due to differences in methods of culture or 
merely accidental cannot be told, though later experience points 
to the former as being the most probable. ' The only method of 
culture that gave good results was the combination of irrigation 
and mulching, which produced a yield of 68 pounds of cucumbers, 
as against only about 10 pounds from each of the other plats. 

In 1902 the planting was done May 12 and mulching June 12. 
The mulched plats were cultivated three times and the cultivated 
ones six to seven times. The cold, wet weather was very unfavorable 
to these tender plants. The plant lice were also a very 
serious hindrance. The vines on the low land were sprayed once 
with resin compound, with fair results, and once later with tobacco 
infusion, with absolutely no beneficial effects, the crop being 
an entire failure on both plats. On the high land the plant lice 
were also very bad, attacking the mulched plants first. All 
plants were sprayed twice with resin compound, which reduced 
the injury from these insects materially, especially on the 
mulched ground, which later in the season from the few hills 
yielded 25 pounds of cucumbers, the cultivated vines producing 
absolutely nothing. Entire failure from cold, wet weather and 
from insect attack was very common throughout the state in 
1902. It is therefore especially noteworthy that in these tests 
the mulched plants lived and finally yielded some return, while 
the cultivated ones produced nothing. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
Experiments in Mulching Garden Vegetables. 

16 

MUSKMKLONS AND WATERMELONS. 

In 1900 the melons were planted May 12 and mulched a 

Eth later, after having been cultivated three times. The un:hed 
plats were cultivated eight times in all. The variety of 
srmelon grown was Ice Cream and the muskmelon was 

Princess. The watermelons yielded as follows: 

Mulch 163 fruits weighing 1324 pounds 

Cultivation 87 fruits weighing 910 pounds 

The mulched fruits, though more numerous, were smaller 

»i the others and of poorer flavor, especially the later ripenones. 
They were, as a whole, somewhat later than the cul- 

tivated melons. 

The results with muskmelons were as follows 

Mulch Ill fruits weighing 328 pounds 

Cultivation 91 fruits weighing 305 pounds 

The mulched fruits ripened earlier than the cultivated ones, 

but were somewhat smaller. 

The same varieties of melons were grown in 1901 as in the 

Ivious year. The seed was planted May 28 and the mulch 
sad about a week later, when the young plants had barely 
ted growth. Such tender vegetables as melons were very 
ously injured by this early mulching. The mulched plants 
e not killed by frost, but the cooler soil under the mulch and 
greater extremes of temperature above it so weakened the 
its that many of them succumbed to the dry weather later 
Hout having grown more than a few inches in height. Some 
he plants, however, lived and in time nearly recovered. The 
d of fruits, however, was less on the mulched than on 
cultivated ground, except in the case of the irrigated 
s, where the plant lice destroyed most of the plants 
the cultivated ground. In 1902 the Triumph watermelon 
Green Nutmeg muskmelon were grown on the low ground, 

twere complete failures on account of the cold, wet weather, 
cannot be said that the tests here reported have proven 

whether or not mulching can be used successfully in growing 
melons. They have certainly shown that if mulching is to he 
practiced, the straw must not be applied until the plants have 
become thoroughly established. They are too tender to stand 

early mulching. </seg>


            <seg id="p017">
17 

SWKKT CORN. 

Red Cob Corey sweet corn was tested in 1900, but there was 

ft difference in yield between the plats, the results being 
htly in favor of mulching. In 1901 Stowell's Evergreen was 
wn. The unirrigated plants were almost an entire failure. 
; mulched corn, however, remained green somewhat longer 
1 the cultivated corn. On the irrigated ground a much betyield 
was secured by mulching than by cultivation. The 

cultivated plat, however, was not so thoroughly irrigated as the 

mulched plat, hence the results are not comparable. 
In 1902 Stowell's Evergreen was planted May 12 and mulched 

June 12, the mulched plat being cultivated three times and the 

unmulched one seven times. The yields follow: 

Mulch High land, 90 pounds; low land, 76 pounds 

Cultivation. . High land, 191 pounds; low land, 113 pounds 

The mulched plants were smaller and less vigorous throughout 

the summer. Much of the time their leaves were yellowish 
green, just as corn leaves often are when the plants stand in 
low, poorly-drained soil. The mulch, in short, affected the corn 
plants much as it did the tomato plants, but decreasing the vigor 
of sweet corn in this way decreased the yield of ears instead of 

making the plants more fruitful as in the case of tomatoes. 
In both 1900 and 1901 it was noticed that chinch bugs 

attacked the cultivated corn sooner and injured it more seriously 
than the mulched corn, the straw apparently making it diffi- 

cult for these insects to reach the plants. 

It is doubtful if mulching will ever prove of practical use in 

case of a crop that can be grown as easily as sweet corn can by 
cultivation, even should the yield be increased somewhat by the 
practice. Mulching is certainly undesirable for sweet corn in 

wet seasons. 

BEETS 

Columbia and Half Long beets were grown in 1901, being 
planted April 19 and mulched June 9. The actual yields were 
somewhat in favor of mulching, but the stand was so uneven 
that the yields should not be compared. The beets from the 
mulched ground were a little better in appearance than those 
from the cultivated land. 

In 1 901 Columbia beets were planted April 20 and mulched </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
18 

MC~mm\4*f'Ji/j/ )j / V in V r iif('ft til ft ( i 1 1 I'll f ft \ i t ft 1 1 1 1 1 ! t V 

June i. The stand was too uneven for comparison on the irri- 

gated land. Where unirrigated the yields were as follows: 

Mulch 78 pounds: average per beet, .6 pound 

Cultivation t&gt;7 pounds: average per beet, .5 pound 

In 1902 the seed was sown April 24 and the mulch applied 

June 12, the mulched plat being cultivated three times and the 

unmulched one seven times. The yields follow: 

Mulch High land, 143 pounds: low land, 85 pounds 

Cultivation High land, 14* pounds: low land. 172 pounds 

The results of these three tests have not been decidedly in 

Kir of either method of culture except that cultivation was dedly 
ahead on low ground in 1902. Beets, however, are 
y easily mulched and probably require less labor when 

grown by mulching than when cultivated. 

SALSIFY. 

Kandwich Island salsify was tested in 1901 and 1902, being 
wn only on the low land the second year. It was planted 
-il 20 and mulched June 1 in 1901, and in 1902 was planted 

til 24 and mulched June 12 
same as for beets. The yiel 

Cultivation was practically 
were as follows: 

yields 

1901. 


Irrigated. Not Irrigated. 

Method of culture. 

it 

i£ 

¦r 

&lt;* 

5 

&amp; 

\~: 

? 1 it 


58 6 I 



&amp; 

Lbs. \Lbt. \Lbs, 


165 26 .16 183 40 
149 23 .16 185 30 

Mulch. 

'.It 40 

Cultivation. 

No difference has been apparent between mulched 

and culti- 

vated salsify with regard to shape of roots, number of 

side roots, 

etc. In general, salsify, like beets, shows 

no marked differences 

in favor of either mulching or cultivation. </seg>


            <seg id="p019">
19 

CARROTS AND PARSNIPS. 

These vegetables were tested for the first time in 1902, being 

Kwn on the low ground only. Hollow Crown parsnip and 
leart carrot were the varieties grown. They were planted 
¦il 24 and mulched June 12. The cultivation was much the 

same as for beets and salsify. The yields were as follows: 

Mulch 143 pounds parsnips, 110 pounds carrots 

Cultivation 160 pounds parsnips, 74 pounds carrots 

The figures indicate that on low ground in a wet year carrots 

ri better by mulching than by cultivation, while the reverse 
ue of parsnips. The latter vegetable not only yielded less on 
mulched than on the cultivated ground but was also of poor- 

er quality, many of the roots being fibrous and spongy. 

ONIONS. 

In these tests with onions the crops have been grown in two 

ways. In some cases the seed has been sown in the garden with 
seed drills in the ordinary way and in some cases it has been 
sown in flats in the greenhouse and the seedlings transplanted into 
the garden later, as is usually done with early cabbage and tomatoes. 
In the following account of mulching experiments with 

onions the two methods are considered separately. 

Drilled onions. — In 1900 seed of Red Wethersficld onion 

was sown in the garden April 12 and mulched June 9, after 
having been thinned and weeded by hand and cultivated four 
times with a wheel hoe. The mulch could not have been applied 

&gt;lier without hurting the stand of plants. The unmulched plat 
i cultivated or hoed four times after the straw was spread 
the mulched plat. The yield was the same, 94 pounds, on 

both plats. 

In 1901 Red Wethersfield and Prize Taker onions were 

grown. An attempt was made to decrease the amount of labor 
required in growing mulched onions. The mulch was therefore 
applied earlier, fewer cultivations being given the mulched plat 
than in the previous year. This early mulching, however, 

killed so many of the plants that the yield from the mulched 
plats was reduced especially in case of the irrigation-mulch plat. 

The yields follow : 

Irrigated. Not irrigated. 

Red Wethersfield: 

Mulch 5 pounds 13 pounds 

Cultivation 12 pounds 14 pounds </seg>


            <seg id="p020">
20 

Prize Taker: 

Mulch 5 pounds 13 pounds 

Cultivation 28 pounds 14 pounds 

Transplanted onions. — This method of growing onions 

was used in the mulching tests of 1901 and 1902. Red Weth- 

ersfield and Prize Taker onions were grown the first season and 

Prize Taker alone the second. The seed was sown in flats in 

the greenhouse March 2, 1901, and the young plants trans- 

planted into the garden May 8, when the bulbs were about as 

thick as, a lead pencil. The mulch was spread June 1, after one 

cultivation. The unmulched plants were cultivated only twice 

afterwards. In 1902 the onion seedlings were transplanted into 

the garden May 7 and the mulch applied June 12, the mulched 

plants being cultivated three times and the unmulched ones seven 

times. The yields for the two years were as follows : 

1901. Irrigated. Not irrigated. 
Red Wethers field: 

Mulch 20 pounds 13 pounds 

Cultivation 18 pounds 13 pounds 

Prize Taker: 

Mulch 30 pounds 16 pounds 

Cultivation 27 pounds 14 pounds 

1902. High land. Low land. 

Prize Taker: 

Mulch 25 pounds - 17 pounds 

Cultivation 27 pounds 31 pounds 

In general it is seen that mulching has slightly increased the 

yield of transplanted onions in a few cases and decreased it in 

others. There is little, therefore, to be gained by mulching, ex- 

cept that the labor required for mulching is perhaps somewhat 

less than for cultivation. In the case of drilled onions, mulching 

is out of the question, owing to the difficulty of spreading the 

straw without hurting the stand of plants 

POTATOES. 

Early Ohio potatoes were grown for the mulching tests each 

of the three years that this method of culture has been under 

trial. In 1900 the planting was done May 3 and the mulch 

spread June 12, after the potatoes had been cultivated three 

times. The unmulched plat was cultirated three, times more 

during the season. In 1901 the tubers were planted April 20 

and mulched June 1, after one cultivation, the unmulched plat 

being cultivated frequently throughout the remainder of the 

season. In 1902 the date of planting was April 4 and of mulch- </seg>


            <seg id="p021">
21 

ing May 22, the potatoes having been cultivated once between 
these dates. The unmulched plats were cultivated four times 
afterwards. The yields of marketable tubers in bushels are 
given in the following table: 

lfloi. Mfc 

-= 

3 

1900. -6 S i 
I Hi 

- 

Method of culture. 

a z k L3 

Lb». \Lbt. \IA». \IM. \Lb*. 

Mulch 88 98 75 82 74 

Cultivation 83 77 64 \ m « 

In 1900 not only was the crop increased about 6 per cent by 
mulching, but the mulched tubers were larger and smoother 
than the cultivated ones. In 1901 the yield on unirrigated land 
was increased 17 per cent by mulching. The difference would 
undoubtedly have been even greater had not the unmulched 
potatoes been given very thorough cultivation, thus producing 
a fair yield in this unusually dry year when the potato crop 
failed in many parts of the state. The mulched tubers were also 
fully as good in quality as the cultivated ones. On irrigated 
land in 1901 the mulched potatoes yielded 27 per cent more than 
the cultivated ones, but owing to the soil's having been kept too 
wet while the tubers were maturing, they were rough and watery. 
Moreover, they did not keep so well as the tubers from the cultivated 
plat when stored for winter. In 1902 mulching decreased 
the yield 5 per cent on the high land and 10 per cent on the low 
land, little difference being noticed in regard to quality of tubers. 

SPECIAL POTATO TEST. 

{In addition to the general tests noted above, a special test 
s conducted with potatoes in 1902, the Early Six Weeks vari' 
being used. The potato garden was four rods wide by 
ren rods long, and was divided into fifteen equal plats, twelve 
which were mulched the day after the seed was planted, the 
ler three being cultivated. Of the block formed by these </seg>



            <seg id="p022">
22 

twelve mulched plats, the east third was mulched with four 
inches of coarse stable manure, the middle third with four inches 
of straw, and the west third with eight inches of straw. In the 
north half of the block the potatoes were planted 18 x 36 inches 
apart and in the south half 18 x 18 inches. Each of these halves 
was again divided lengthwise into two equal parts, in the north 
part of each the tubers being planted four inches deep and in the 
south part one inch deep. The three cultivated plats joined the 
mulched ones on the north. Two of these were given thorough 
cultivation throughout the summer. The east one was cultivated 
until late in July and then, after the new tubers had begun 
to form, mulched with about four inches of straw. The yields 
of the various plats in pounds are given in the following table: 

36 in. Hills 18x18 in. 

n"-* 

2.-.:! 356 386 
202 291 300 
133 123 212 

The figures in the left column show that in this test a 4-inch 
mulch of straw applied after the potatoes had been cultivated 
throughout the early part of the summer increased the yield 
about 11 per cent over cultivation the entire season. A 4-inch 
straw mulch applied as soon as the seed was planted decreased 
the yield about 11 per cent, and an 8-inch straw mulch applied 
early decreased it 34 per cent. The early 4-inch manure mulch, 
however, increased the yield over cultivation by 29 per cent. 
The mulched tubers were not so smooth as the cultivated ones, 
but no other differences were noticeable. 

Lbs. Lbs. Lbt. 

Hills 

x: 

Mi in. 

Method of culture. 

( 

¦ 
r 
a a 
S" 1 

Lbt. 

Lbs. 

Mulched early without cultivation: 
4-inch manure mulch 
4-inch straw mulch 
¦ti straw mulch 

246 
169 
126 

S,2 
202 
133 

Cultivated in early summer: 
Late 4-inch straw mulch 

211 

Cultivated entire season: 
No mulch 
No mulch 

189 
191 </seg>




            <seg id="p023">
23 

Considering now only the plants that were mulched early, it 
is seen that the best yields were obtained in all cases from 
the use of coarse manure as mulch. The four manure-mulched 
plats yielded 29 per cent more than the four plats mulched to 
the same depth with straw. Whether this will prove true in a 
season of less rainfall has not been determined. The tubers that 
were mulched with manure were more seriously injured by scab 
than those that were mulched with straw. This was especially 
true of the shallow planted ones. As between 8- inch and 
4-inch straw mulches, everything this year was in favor of the 
shallower mulch. The total yield of the four shallow-mulched 
plats was about 62 per cent more than that of the four deepmulched 
plats. The deep mulch hurt the stand of plants very 
noticeably. The differences between shallow and deep planting 
were almost as pronounced as those between shallow and deep 
mulching. In all cases the potatoes that were barely covered 
with .soil when planted were better than those that were planted 
at the usual depth, the total yield of the six shallow-planted plats 
being 13 per cent greater than that of the six deep-planted ones. 
A further advantage of shallow planting where potatoes are to 
be mulched is the ease with which the crop is harvested. The 
tubers are formed practically at the surface of the ground and 
when the mulch has been raked off can be picked up without 
any appreciable effort in digging. 

Iince early-mulched potatoes are not cultivated, no inconvene 
results from having the rows close together. In all 1 
one in this test the close-planted potatoes yielded more than 
al areas planted twice as far apart, the total yield of the 
close-planted plats being about 48 per cent more than of the 
;r six plats. For equal amounts of seed planted, however, 
close-planted plats yielded less by about 26 per cent th;m 
se planted at about the usual distance. Whether close plantwill 
prove as good in a dryer year has not been determined. 

r~ 1 n j j 
On the whole, mulching has proven a very satisfactory way of 
growing garden potatoes. The yield is usually increased and 
the quality not hurt by mulching, except in very wet seasons or 
places, both of which are unusual in Nebraska. Though the 
yield last year was better when the plants were mulched late 
than when early mulching was practiced, the latter certainly deserves 
further trial, since it reduces very materially the labor 
required in growing the crop and may therefore prove preferable, 
even if the yield is reduced. </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 


SWEET POTATOES. 

Sweet potatoes were tested in iooi, Yellow Jersey being the 
variety grown. The plants were set in the garden early in 
June, the mulch being applied before the vines began to run and 
the unmulched plats being given careful cultivation as long as 
possible. One half of the plants of all plats were grown on ridges 
and the other half by level culture. The following yields were 

total yield of the four mulched plats being 19 per cent greater 
than that of the four cultivated plats. 

Ehe sweet potato tubers from the mulched plats were longer 
more slender than those from the cultivated plats, this being 
cially noticeable on the irrigated land. This tendency is 
linly not desirable and if it proves common may make 
:hing an undesirable method of culture for sweet potatoes. 

I he vines on the mulched plats were injured much more 
rely by frost occurring soon after the middle of September 
those on the cultivated plat. The cultivated plants were 
¦ed somewhat, many of the leaves being blackened by the 
. The vines recovered entirely, however, long before the 
frost. The mulched plants, on the contrary, were so 
rely injured that they never fully recovered. The frost, 
ever, did not hurt the quality of the tubers, and since the 
I was even greater from the mulched than from the cultid 
plats the injury to the vines from frost was no great 
rback to the use of mulches in growing sweet potatoes. 

I'weet potato vines d&lt;$ not take root through a straw mulch 
they do on bare ground — an unquestionable advantage of 
Iching. Furthermore, thorough cultivation of any vine 
p, like the common varieties of sweet potatoes, is a difficult 
lertaking. Such a crop can be cultivated easily until the 
es begin to run, when the mulch should be spread. 

Irrigated. 

Not irrigated. 

Method of culture. 

l 

1 " 

Ridge. Level. 

Ridge. Level. 

Lbs. Lbs. 

Lbs. Lbs. 

Mulch : 
I u It i vat ion 

72 47 
52 40 

42 47 

I I I 

' 

The mulch increased the yi 

field over cultivatioi 

in all cases, the </seg>


            <seg id="p025">
25 

Ehis single test may be said, then, to have given results 
jedly favorable to mulching. Further tests, of course, are 
ssary before definite conclusions can be reached. 

DISCUSSION OF RESULTS. 

Whether mulching will prove satisfactory depends in part 
upon the location of the garden and the character of the 
season. In general, mulches may be expected to give better 
results in normal or rather dry years than in seasons of unusually 
heavy rainfall. Similarly, in very wet seasons better results 
may be expected from the use of mulches on high land than 
on low land. Such seasons, however, are not common in 
Nebraska. The effect of a mulch in conserving soil moisture 
during dry periods is very noticeable. During July and August, 
1900, soil moisture determinations were made in the mulched 
and cultivated plats of cabbage, peas, beans, cucumbers, watermelons, 
sweet corn, and beets. Soil samples taken at a depth 
of from six to nine inches in the mulched plat contained an 
average of 18.2 per cent of moisture, as against 17. 1 in the cul- 

IVhether mulching shall be used in a particular case 
tends also upon the vegetables to be grown. Early spring 
[etables requiring only a few -cultivations can usually be 
wn more cheaply by cultivation than by mulching. Furtherre, 
very early mulching, before the ground has become 
roughly warm, is apt to retard the development of the vegiles. 
On the other hand, summer or fall vegetables that 
uire frequent cultivation throughout the season are grown as 
lie with less labor by mulching than by cultivation. Furrmore, 
the mulch can often be spread at a time when other 
n work is not especially pressing. If cultivation alone is 
tended upon, the garden may be cared for well enough 
ly in the season but is almost sure to be neglected later, when 
rush of summer's farm work is on and when, owing to dry, 
weather, the need of proper care is most imperative. 

E'he fact that most vegetables, especially the more tender 
Js, cannot be mulched until they have become well estabed 
and the weather has become warm, thus requiring some 
liminary cultivation, certainly increases the labor required in 
wing mulched vegetables over what would be necessary if 
mulch could be applied earlier. But, if the impracticability 
tarly mulching is a serious drawback to the use of mulches, 
s the impracticability of midsummer cultivation under farm </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
E.r/i&gt;riiiifntx 

Mulching Garden Vegetable*. 

26 

Ill 

Ilitions a serious objection to dependence upon cultivation 
c. For most vegetables, mulching should be used to suplent 
cultivation rather than to displace it. Such cultivation 
¦; commonly given farm gardens is better for most vege;s 
in early spring than mulching, but mulching is just as 
ly better in midsummer than the neglect which is the comthing 
in f.irm gardens at that time of year. The Experit 
Station tests have indeed shown mulching to be better in 
y cases than the most thorough cultivation throughout the 
mer. 

(ot only are many vegetables grown with less labor by 
:hing than by cultivation, but the yield and quality of the 
uct is also often improved. In several cases yields have 
i decreast d by mulching. In some of these, however, the 
•y was due not so much to the use of a mulch as to its being 
ied too early. 

I "he vegetables which, from the tests at the Experiment Stai, 
it is thought unwise to mulch are drilled onions, lettuce and 
:et corn. With drilled onions, the stand of plants is usually 
t by mulching. With lettuce, it is also difficult to spread the 
Ich without injury to the stand, and the crop is harvested so 
y that it is not worth while to mulch. With sweet corn, the 
ds are about the same in a normal season whether mulched 
cultivated, but this crop requires so few cultivations that 
Iching is hardly profitable. In a wet season mulching 
reases the vield decidedly. 

Ecase of transplanted onions, beets, salsify, carrots, parsnips, 
, and melons, the results are not decidedly in favor of either 
e two methods, both the yields and the required labor being 
it the same. 

Iesults very favorable to mulching have been secured with 
•age, tomatoes, beans, cucumbers, potatoes, and sweet pota- 
In all these cases the yields have been increased on the 
le quite decidedly by mulching and ihe required labor desed 
at the same time. Mulched cabbage produced larger 
Is than cultivated cabbage, and there was less injury 
i rot. The vigor of tomato plants was decreased by mulchbut 
the yield of fruit increased. The fruit was also cleaner 
less subject to rot. Mulched cucumbers produced perfect 
s during dry periods when the fruit from the cultivated 
ts was small and imperfect. The quality of potatoes has not 
i hurt by mulching except in wet places </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

OF 

NEBRASKA 

THE GOVERNING BOARD 

) 

t.KO. F. KKNOWKU. PrmUmU, Wisner 
K. v. FORF.LL, Aurora 

KDSON C RICH, Omaha 
JOBS L. TEETERS, Lincoln 
K. C. CALKINS, Kearney 
C .1. ERNST, Omaha 

THE STATION OFFICERS 

fA. BURNETT, B. Sc, Direct,, ,¦ ami Infmirl Husbanimm* 
L. LYON, B. S. A.. AmttMtt IHt-ector ami AiianiltnriM 
S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary 

\VM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk 

THE WORKING STAFF 

IT. Peters. 1). V. M.. Anini'il nriUhfM 
AKI.KS K. BESSEY, PH. D., 1 &gt;&lt;&gt;ln lli.it 

s. Avkry, Ph. D., CKmnM 

A. L. Haecker. B. Sc. A.. Dairy Husbandman 
Lawkknxe Bruxer. B. Sc. . JMMMtofM 
Kkwin H. Barbocr. Ph. D.. Geolotjixt 
EL A. Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulturist 
o. v. P. Stout. C. E.. frrijpaMM Stafi 
(J. D. SwtZEY, M. A., Meteorologist 

H. R. Smith. B. Sc, .dnoctate Xnim«i Hustjandnian 
J. H. Gain, M. D. C, .l.i/m-i/ I'utholngiM </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>