<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SIXTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Girls Industrial School For Juvenile Delinquents AT GENEVA, NEBRASKA FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">SIXTH BIENNIAL REPORT — OF THK — Girls Industrial School For Juvenile Delinquents AT V GENEVA, NEBRASKA FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902 1902 Tas Fbemiiht Tiibd» Fruiwt, Neb </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Hon. Ezra P. Savage Governor BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. Hon. Geo. D. Follmer President Hon. Geo. W. Marsh Secretary Hon. F. N. Prout Hon. Wm. Steufer OFFICERS AND EMPLOYES OF SCHOOL. Horace M. Clark Superintendent Nellie M. Curtiss Family Manager Lena E. Ward Family Manager Emma VanCleave Matron Mrs. E. Jayne Cooking Teacher Mrs. M. A. Tysor Sewing Teacher. Mame Harbaugh Laundry Teacher Tilla Clark Housekeeper W. G. Hannis Engineer G. E. Whittle Engineer P J. Hall : Farmer </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Hon. Ezra P. Savage, Governor, and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings: Gentlemen: — I have the honor to herewith submit the sixth biennial report of this institution. The cordial treatment and kindly assistance of each of you is gratefully acknowledged. Every effort put forth by the present management for the advancement of the work of helping these wards of the state has been most fully seconded by yourselves; and, whatever may have been our measure of success, we feel that we owe in no small degree a goodly portion of it to this fact. The active charge of the work of the school devolved on the present management February i, 1901. Owing to a peculiar construction put upon a late decision of the supreme court in regard to commitments to the school, we found that a number of inmates had been paroled and otherwise discharged, regardless of the fact that they were wholly unfit to go. This had a tendency to unsettle and in a measure demor - alize those that remained. However, with care and firmness, order was brought out of a seeming chaos and we were delighted with the progress made. Moral training of course is the underlying feature of our work. To take children whose entire moral nature is perverted, and create within them a desire for a better life, is indeed a serious work. In this institution the state has established a school calling for the most delicate reformatory work. Only those who will deeply feel the need of right living, and who are led by more than human aid should venture to undertake the task. In securing assistants for this work we were extremely for - tunate; and our entire force of teachers are exemplary Chris - tian women, each one peculiarly fitted for the department over which she has charge. The school work was in a neglected condition, and girls that </seg>
            <seg id="p004">336 had been in the school long enough to have been very fair scholars were on examination found to be sadly deficient. We are glad to be able to say that this defect has been remedied. We have in charge of the two schools, teachers who hold good certificates as teachers in graded school work, and who have each had several years experience in such work before coming here. Under their direction the girls in the two sections of the school have made very rapid progress. The best and latest text-books have been used, and every effort put forth to advance the girls as rapidly as possible, for we know that very few, if any of these girls will ever attend school a day after they leave here, and we desire to qualify them to care for themselves in life's rough battle. While we have laid particular stress upon the question of moral and intellectual training, the matter of industrial pursuits has not been overlooked. The kitchen, the laundry and the sewing room have each received full attention. In order that a fair comprehension of our work may be obtained from this report, a statement of how we employ the time will not be amiss at this time. Our work is divided into details. A girl serves three months in each detail as follows; three months in the kitchen learning cooking, bread-making and dining-room work ; three months in laundry learning the different features of domestic laundrying, such as is practiced in the ordinary household; three months learning house work, i. e., sweeping, scrubbing, mopping, dust - ing, making and caring for beds properly, and the numberless things a girl should know about making and keeping a house looking neat and tidy ; three months in the sewing room learn - ing dress-making, cutting and fitting. The hour for rising is six o'clock during the winter month?, and half-past five o'clock during the summer months. Four hours of each school day is put in in regular school work, one section of the school having school in the forenoon and the other section in the afternoon. The other half of the day is occupied in the industrial work. A great many of our / </seg>
            <seg id="p005">337 girls develop a great talent in needle-work, and become very proficient in that line. The school had a very creditable display at the State fair, of plain and fancy needle-work that was much admired. We have received inquiries since the fair asking on what terms we would accept pupils for instruction in our dress-making depart - ment. Of course when we explained the method to be pur - sued in order to obtain admittance as a pupil the matter was very suddenly dropped. In all these departments much progress has been made, and the result has been that the girls that have been placed in homes during the past twelve months have invariably rendered good account of themselves. The only girls who have not done well after having been in the school a term of years are girls that were sent here too late for their reformation. I mean by this that we have not near so much hope for the reformation of a girl that has been allowed to run wild and do as she pleases until she is fifteen or sixteen years old, as we have for the girl that is sent here at the age of twelve or thir - teen before she becomes vicious and hardened. About eighty per cent of the girls sent out from ihe school are giving a good account of themselves; and it is pleasing to know that the per cent of failures is apparently diminishing. The religious instruction of the girls is non-sectarian, the pas - tors in charge of the various churches in Geneva very kindly alternating with each other in holding religious services each Sabbath afternoon. We hold one hour of Sabbath school and one hour of chapel each Sabbath day. The girls are fond of music and take part very heartily in the song service. During the late spring and through the summer and early fall I have been in tht nabit of taking the "A" family one Sab - bath and the "B" family lue next to attend divine services in one of the city churches. For this purpose each girl has been fitted out with a neat attire for the Sabbath day, and has taken much pains to appear neat and tidy. And I confess that we all feel somewhat proud 34 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">338 of their lady-like appearance, for a neater, better behaved lot of girls and young women will not be found anywhere on the Sabbath day. It has had a splendid effect in encouraging them to do that which is right. I know the Governor and the members of the board will par - don a slight digression on my part, and allow me to say that if the work done at this school was fully understood the officers of the law would cease being so lax in looking after the juve - nile delinquents in our fair state. The law on our statute books for governing, restraining, and commitment of juvenile delinquents is a good one. There is only one slight change that I would suggest in it. And yet boys and girls are per - mitted to run wild and become a scandal and a menace to the peace and safety of numberless communities throughout this commonwealth, because, we are told they are only children. And then after a while the entire state is shocked over some act of youthful depravity committed by a youth who is little more than a child. It is but little wonder that charitable organ - izations are seriously considering the matter. And, with all due deference to the various organizations that have recently been discussing the prevalence of youthful depravity in the various cities in our state, I will say that they have but slight knowledge of what Nebraska stands ready and willing to do for the boy or girl committed to her care. I have had no visits or correspondence with the officers or members of any of these local organizations during the two years I have been here at this school; but when I have occasionally met one elsewhere, I have been astonished to find that they knew so little of what the state was doing for its delinquent children. Our situation here is an ideal one for growing girls. The surroundings are healthful and pleasing, and the course of instruction one that arouses an interest in the dullest girl. We have received several visits from members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings and have been pleased with the interest that they have manifested in our work. The secretary of the State Board of Charities and Correc - tions, Mr. John Davis, paid us a very pleasant visit and we were </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Cjirls Industrial ochool. 339 pleased with the suggestions offered by him. Two other assist - ant secretaries of the State Board of Charities and Corrections made us a short visit between trains. On taking charge of this institution we found a great deal of repairing necessary in order to save the property of the state here. The roof of the school building was in very bad order; several unsuccessful attempts had been made to repair it, but all were failures. Under advice of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings we secured the services of a competent architect and builder, and at an expense of four hundred and fifty-five dollars had the roof put in first-class condition, and the large chimneys remodeled so that they were no longer a menace to the population of the institution. We had turned over to us as the state property, a small bunch of poultry that was housed in the barn with the horses and cat - tle, and horses and cattle were both infected with mites from the poultry. We have built a good, comfortable poultry house, and this year have raised several hundred fine Black Langshan chickens. We expect to make poultry-raising a prominent feature in the maintenance of the school. We also erected a commodious hog house, and from the pro - ceeds of hogs sold at the prevailing high prices of last summer, we have put new steel ceilings in both play-rooms, have paid for part of the work and all the material used in painting the poultry house, hog house and storm houses, and for painting and calsomining the play-rooms, kitchen, lower dining rooms and halls, sewing room and third floor bath room and closets. The plumbing was in a deplorable condition, and my engi - neers have overhauled and repaired it most thoroughly, until we now have it in very fair condition. We have had a carpenter at work this fall closing up the great openings that were around the numerous windows and doors of the institution. These doors and windows were not properly put in originally, and during the ten years that have elapsed since the construction of </seg>
            <seg id="p008">340 this building the openings around them have become worse, until last winter we found it almost impossible on cold days to keep the building comfortable. We believe now that we have this trouble largely overcome, and hope to get through the coming winter with less coal than we had to use last winter. The health of the inmates has been excellent. There have been no serious cases of illness, and no deaths. It has been a rare thing to have any girl feel badly for more than three or four days. We were fortunate in the selection of a physician for the school, securing for this place the services of Dr. B. B. Mozee, who is an experienced practitioner, and he has been very suc - cessful in his work with us. We had a few cases of goitre that seemed to defy all ordinary methods of treatment, and becoming somewhat acquainted with the effective treatment of such difficulties, rendered by the Van Vleck Animal Extract Co., of Kansas City, Mo., we put one of the worst cases under their treatment ; also the case of a girl afflicted with an inherited disease that promised to blight her entire life. The result was beyond our fondest expectations. Both girls are apparently entirely cured. Neither one of them had been able to assist in any detail work at any time since their commitment, yet both are now rugged and hearty, and one of them has been out at work as a domestic for three months. The result in these cases having been so satisfactory, we are now treating three others and they are doing nicely. There have been no cases of running away during our two years of management. I believe this is the first two years in the history of the school in which there has been no chasing after runaway girls. In sending girls out into new homes, or putting them into the homes of their relatives, we have made every effort to place them in other communities than those they came from, remov - ing them as far as possible from 61d associates, surroundings and temptations, thus making it much easier to lead a right life. The population of the school having become materially </seg>
            <seg id="p009">341 reduced from what it was in former years, in June, 1901, by and with the consent of the Governor, we dispensed with the ser - vices of the steward and find that the plan works nicely, the superintendent being able to attend to the work of the steward very easily. for the eleven months, from April, 1901, to March, 1902, we only one family manager, and she taught both schools; we e not satisfied with the results of this experiment, and since later date we have had a family manager for each school. t/e have dispensed with the man employed for several years wn as extra man, as his only duty seemed to be to carry the I, and that seemed to us to be a needless expense. The king force of teachers and employes is reduced to the mini - n. It could not be safely reduced farther. As to the needs of the school I shall only suggest what I am convinced is absolutely called for in the interest of economy and good business management. The question of disposing of the sewerage of the institution has become a serious one, and we have it to meet right now. Cess pools are a failure and will not answer here owing to peculiar nature of the subsoil. The cess pools that have been put down at various times since the estab - lishment of the institution here, have all filled up in a short time and overflowed. Lying directly north of the school ground and adjacent thereto is a tract of land with a ravine running through it; the head of this draw or ravine is in the school ground, and the cess pools for holding the sewerage from the school are located at the head of this draw, the result being that when these cess pools overflow, as they do continually, the overflow runs down across the tract of land mentioned above. My suggestion is that the state should own that tract of land. The matter of disposing of the sewerage could then be arranged for permanently and this source of continual annoyance be for - ever disposed of. In connection with my suggestion that the state purchase this additional land, I will farther state that I believe it will prove a profitable investment in the matter of help - ing in the item of maintenance. No private individual would for one minute think of managing his business after the methods </seg>
            <seg id="p010">342 pursued by the state in caring for its various institutions. In other words, if a private individual were compelled to pay the bills for the maintenance of these various institutions he would at once seek for some method that would look toward their being at least partially self-sustaining. Now in the case of this school we have about twenty acres of land under cultivation; and a little garden stuff with a small amount of feed is all we can raise. We can keep only five head of cows, and a few head of hogs, yet we must keep a farmer for this work. We must purchase all the butter used, all the meat, all the flour and nearly all the feed. If the school owned a quarter section of land we could keep twenty-five or thirty head of cows and make butter-making a feature of our work. The girls would attend to the milking of the cows and the caring for the milk as well as learn the art of butter-making. We have our own engine and could run a sepa - rator and power churn with very little if any additional expense. The meat supply for the institution could nearly all be raised at the school, for the surplus milk from a good herd of cows would prove an important factor in raising and feeding a drove of hogs. I am thoroughly convinced that the price of this tract of land would be saved in the maintenance of the school in at least ten years. It would requite an appropriation of a few hundred dollars for the purpose of stocking the place and an additional outlay of not to exceed $300.00 a year for extra help in the busy season. But in the years to come there would be no trouble over the disposi - tion of the sewerage, and what will otherwise be a continual item of expense will be eliminated from future appropriation bills. The appropriation for repairs and improvements made by the last legislature was all that we asked, but we are willing to con - fess we did not know how much repairing was absolutely needed; so we will ask for an appropriation this year that if granted will, we believe, be sufficient for the present needs o the school. We think that $2,500.00, if judiciously expended </seg>
            <seg id="p011">343 will thoroughly repair the institution and provide all needed improvements except what we shall ask. for the engine room. In the engine room we have but one boiler that can be used For some reason an additional boiler that was wholly inadequate was installed several years ago. It is so small that it will not furnish steam to run our engine, and in the winter time we are sometimes sorely puzzled how to keep from freezing while the one large boiler is being washed out as is required by the rules governing our institution. We consider it unsafe to allow the matter to run longer as it is, and we urgently request that a new boiler be provided for this session. The expense of a boiler such as we need, including setting, will be something like $1,250.00. I shall not take up a great deal of space with valueless statistical tables; they are of no value in a straight business report. I take it that you desire to know in as compact form as possi - ble what our work was when we took charge of it, what we have accomplished and what are our urgent needs. Without exaggeration we have tried to give some idea of the condition of things February 1, 1900. The style of economy that we found had been practiced rather impressed us as being of the character denominated as being "penny wise and pound foolish," and in remedying the defects arising from such practices our expense account was rather large at first, but we believe now that we are in a condi - tion to administer to the needs of the work as economically as can possibly be done while accomplishing the ends sought, t. e., teaching the wayward girls committed to our care a nobler and better way to live. As to the future needs of the school, I append herewith my estimate of expenses for the ensuing two years, based on what I believe to be a fair estimate of the actual needs : Salary, superintendent 1 yr., $1,500.00; 2 yrs&gt;. .$3,00000 Salary, two family managers, 1 yr., 1,600.00; 2yr.«.. 3,200.00 Salary, matron, 1 yr., 60000; 2 yrs. . 1,200.00 Employes' wages 6,240.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">344 L^AflU OMMlSSXOFl JSR. S I\ErvRTi Incidental funds as follows: Medical attendance, estimated $480.00 Medicines, estimated 170.00 Placing children in homes, estimated 350.00 Music and amusements, estimated 200.00 Telephone rent, estimated 140.00 Live stock, carriage and harness, estimated . 200.00 Incidental extraordinary, estimated 200.00 Expenses chaplain, estimated 250.00 Total incidental $ 1,990.00 Fuel and lights $ 4,500.00 Board and clothing 8,500.00 Water supply 1,200 00 School and library books 400.00 Repairs and improvement 2,500.00 Furniture, kitchen and diningroom ware. . . 1,000.00 For purchase 160 acres land 10,000.00 $43,730.00 In the event of the failure to secure the appropriation for the purchase of the land mentioned in this report, it will be neces- sary to appropriate $2,000.00 for remodeling our sewerage sys- tem. And I am not sure that this amount will give the needed relief. It certainly seems to me that it would be economy to put this $2,500.00 into the purchase price of land, for a very small amount will ever be needed for the sewerage after this land once becomes the property of the state. The total number of girls admitted to this school has been . .441 Paroled and otherwise discharged 380 Died 2 Sent to insane hospital 3 Sent to Beatrice Feeble Minded Institute 1 Girls under control of the school Nov. 30, 1902 55 The age of the youngest girl ever committed to the school was seven years at the time of commitment; the oldest at the time of commitment seventeen years. The average age of the 441 girls at time of commitment has been thirteen years </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Girls' Industrial School. 345 Average time spent in school, three and one-third years. Average number of days in school per year 200 Hours in school per day 4 BRANCHES TAUGHT Arithmetic — oral and written. Geography. Reading. History. Orthography. Physiology. Penmanship. Grammar. English composition. DAYS ENGAGED IN INDUSTEUAL PURSUITS PER YEAR. In the laundry 208 In sewing class 275 In kitchen 365 In housekeeping 365 As each girl serves a three months term in each detail it gives her an average of 303 days in industrial training with an average of four and one-half hours each day during a year, the work in the kitchen and housekeeping details being of such character that some work is required on the Sabbath just as in the ordinary home. There has been made by the sewing room detail since Febru- ary 1, 1 901 : Dresses 358 Skirts ' 271 Undergarments 310 Night dresses 311 Aprons 274 Other garments 405 Miscellaneous sewing, such as sun-bonnets, ironing sheets, laundry bags, bed comforts, curtains, towels, etc., etc. 1,506 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">346 Mended in sewing room : Dresses 3»589 Night dresses 1,809 Undergarments 3&gt;°55 Skirts 788 Aprons 445 Hose 3,834 Work done by laundry detail shows that since Feb. 1, 1901, there has been laundered : Dresses 4,800 Night dresses 3,160 Skirts 3,000 Drawers 4,160 Under vest? 2,760 Hose 3,920 Towels 6,240 Tea towels 3,080 Aprons 3,360 Table cloths 640 Napkins 4,640 Doilies 320 Mats 80 Sheets and pillow cases 1 1,080 Bed spreads 560 Shirts and waists 680 Other articles too numerous to mention 7.642 Work done by the kitchen detail : Loaves of bread baked 1 2,480 Cookies baked 5,ooo Pies baked 2,320 Sauer kraut 60 gals. Cherries, canned 200 qts. Pie Plant, canned 50 qts. Jam of various kinds 30 qts. Peaches, canned 150 qts. Nectarines, canned 11 qts. Plums, canned 45 qts. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Cjirls industrial ochool. 347 Sweet pickles 20 gals. Chow-chow 25 gals. Every effort is made to teach the girls how to prepare food properly and economically. The proper manner in which to arrange the tables, place the food on them and wait on them, is also diligently taught. My financial report covers the entire biennium and the closing period of the former administration. Total amount expended in two years for different purposes is as follows: Officers' salaries $ 7,190.80 Employes' wages 5,600.00 Fuel and lights 3&gt;693-5i Board and clothing 7,924.32 Furniture, bedding, kitchen and dining room 793-6$ Incidentals, medicine, medical attendance, music and amusement 1.460.55 School and library books 371.55 Repairs and improvements- 1,690.42 Water supply 1,200.00 Total for all purposes $29,924.80 The average cost per day per person, including all expenses of every kind, 80^ cents. We were compelled to incur numerous expenses that should have been borne by the previous administration, such as the pur- chase of a new kitchen stove, the putting in of a new dynamo, the putting up of outbuildings. All these items have materially increased our total expense account, but will not have to be met again soon. 1 have the honor to remain Your obedient servant, Horace M. Clark, Superintendent Girls' Industrial School. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">348 PHYSICTAN'S REPORT. Geneva, Nebr., Nov. 30, 1902. Hon. H. M. Clark, Superintendent of the Girls Industrial School at Geneva, Neb. Dear Sir: — Following is my report as physician of the Girls Industrial School. I began my work on February 4, 1901. Since that time there have been no malignant diseases to con tend with. But several cases of nervous disorders and a num ber of common diseases, which require months of close atten tion, have been the extent of the sickness. There have been no deaths, and the girls are now in a comparatively healthy con - dition. Allow me to say that under your oversight every thing about the institution has been kept in the best condition conduc - ive to the health of the inmates, and the association with your - self, the teachers, employes and inmates of the school has been most pleasant. I will offer a few suggestions in regard to conveniences in the hospital, which I feel will meet your approval. E^irst, that a case be put in the hospital where the drugs may securely locked away. Also that a bath room be built in 1 part of the house. Both are not only conveniences, but essities. Ewish to express my appreciation of the faithful work done the matron of the school, and am indeed grateful to you for courtesy you have shown me in all our dealings together. Yours respectfully, B.B. Mozee, M. D. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>