<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00026</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Wooden Silos used in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1917-02-15">1917-02-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. 40 BULLETIN OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE WOODEN SILOS USED IN NEBRASKA L. W. Chase and Ivan D. Wood SINGLE-PIECE FIR STAVE 3ILO, AT BEEF CATTLE BARN, UNIVERSITY FARM LINCOLN, NEBRASKA LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. Distributed in Furtherance of the Purposes of the Cooperative Agricul - tural Extension Work Provided for in the Act of Congress of May 8, 1914. University of Nebraska Agricultural Extension Service and the United States Department of Agriculture Cooperating. C. W. Pugsley, Director of Extension Service Distributed February 15, 1917 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">University of Nebraska College of Agriculture THE EXTENSION SERVICE THE GOVERNING BOARD (The Regents o( the University) Hon. Victor G. Lyford, President, Hon. John E. Miller, Lincoln Falls City Hon. Philip L. Hall, Lincoln Hon. Frank L. Haller, Omaha Hon. Harry D. Landis, Seward Hon. Edward P. Brown, Davey THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor E. A. Burnett, B. Sc., Dean, College of Agriculture; Director, Experiment Station J. S. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc., Director Floyd Wambeam, B. Sc., Agricultural Editor A. E. Anderson, A. B., County Agent Work L. T. Skinner, B. Sc., Junior Ex - tension Work Maud Mathes Wilson, B. Sc., Home Economics P. L. Gaddis, B. Sc., Farmers' In - stitutes, Short Courses, and Exhibits EXTENSION SPECIALISTS I. D. Wood, A. M., Agricultural En - gineering Mary A. Rokahr, A. B., Home Eco - nomics K. F. Warner, M. S., Animal Hus - bandry Emma Ort, B. Sc., Home Economics [Junior Work) J. G. McMillan, B. Sc., Pig Clubs E. H. HOPPERT, B. SC., Horticulture Aural Scott, B. Sc., Home Economics Louise Meredith, B. Sc., Home D. H. PROPPS, B. Sc., 'Dairy Hus - bandry H. F. Williams, B. Sc., Farm Man - agement Demonstrations Economics C. W. Watson, B. Sc., A Junior Extension Work R. R. Spafford, B. Sc., Assistant, Farm Management Emma Reed Davisson, Women's Clubs County Agent Work COUNTY AGRICULTURAL AGENTS F. M. Seidell, Boxbutte County A. G. George, B. Sc., Madison County A. C. North, B.Sc., Sheridan County R. H. Camp, B.Sc., Thurston County L. Boyd Rist, B. Sc, Gage County R. E. Holland, B. Sc., Kimball County THE EXTENSION COUNCIL (Heads of Departments) E. A. Burnett, B. Sc, Dean J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A. Animal Husbandry Dairy Husbandry C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc, Director Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D. Agricultural Botany Entomology H. C. Filley, A. M. Farm Management F. W. Upson, Ph. D. Agricultural Chemistry Alice M. Loomis, A. M. Home Economics L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E. Agricultural Engineering R. F. Howard, A. M. Horticulture W. W. BURR, B. Sc, Agronomy J. H. Gain, M. D. C. G. A. Loveland, A. M. Meteorology Animal Pathology H. E. Bradford, A. B., Principal, School of Agriculture 'Resigned. F. D. Keim, B. Sc., Agronomy Fred L. Taylor, B. Sc., Assigtan ■A. H. Beckhoff, B. Sc., Dakota r v r,^^, a r &lt;j^ e^ j Countv (jUNNELS, rs. sc., Seward 'G. 0. Unruh, B. Sc., Dawes County A . C^North, B. Sc.. Sheridan Countv </seg>
            <seg id="p003">WOODEN SILOS USED IN NEBRASKA BY L. W. CHASE AND I. D. WOOD INTRODUCTION Tho this bulletin relates especially to the construction of wooden silos in Nebraska, and consequently the main text deals primarily with problems peculiar to such silos, the authors wish to call attention to the essentials of any well-designed silo for the benefit of the man who is building his first silo : 1. The walls should be practically air-tight. 2. The inner surfaces of the walls should be smooth and perpendicular. 3. The inner surfaces of the walls should be free from corners. Round silos are more efficient and economical than other types. 4. The walls should be sufficiently non-conducting to prevent excessive freezing, — especially so when the silage is to be fed during cold weather. 5. The walls would be sufficiently firm or sufficiently well anchored to prevent cracking due to settling or racking due to wind. 6. The doors should be so designed that a minimum amount of silage has to be removed before they can be opened. 7. A good ladder should be provided with steps from 15 inches to 18 inches apart and at least 3J inches away from the silo or walls of the chute. 8. The foundation should be heavy, well made, and reach below the frost line. 9. A good roof makes the silo more durable, adds greatly to its appearance, and if tight assists materially in keeping the silage from freezing. Silos which have the above features will be found convenient, cause little trouble, and when properly filled will keep the silage in perfect condition. TYPES OF SILOS There are two general types of silos: 1. Pit silos, or silos built partially or wholly below ground. 2. Silos above ground, built of wood, masonry, or metal. Wooden silos are commonly built of two-inch staves, of two - by four-inch lumber laid flatwise, or of one-inch flooring nailed to wooden hoops. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Bulletin No. Jfi, College of Agriculture WOODEN SILOS Wooden silos are apparently more popular with the public than any other type. This is no doubt due to their portability, ease of construction, and availability on the market. During the few years silos have been in use in Nebraska, stave silos have been constructed more extensively than any others; while crib silos have come in during the past few years, and recently several wooden hooped silos have been erected. SILO WOODS Silos have not been in use long enough in Nebraska to warrant the drawing of any definite conclusion as to lasting qualities of different kinds of wood. Two white pine homemade plain stave silos near Omaha, examined after having been used eight years, were found very badly decayed at the lower ends of the staves. A cheap white pine silo on the University Farm was practically rotted out at the end of five years' use, while a better grade of white pine silo had been in use eleven years before it was neces - sary to saw away 18 inches of the decayed lower ends of the staves and build the foundation up an equal amount. An examination of several silos, built of a good grade of fir five years ago, discloses no indication of decay. STAVE SILOS There are three general types of these silos, the homemade !)lain stave, the homemade tongued and grooved, and the manu - actured tongued and grooved. The first type mentioned is somewhat cheaper than the other types, but it is harder to hold the staves in place. Probably this is due to the fact that in the summer when the silos are empty the air gets on all sides of the staves and causes them to dry out faster than if tongued and grooved. The second type of silo is as strong as any stave silo and as easily cared for, but is more trouble to order than the third type, which also is likely to have more convenient doors. ORDERING STAVE SILOS The Manufactured Silo — In ordering a silo it must be borne in mind that the custom of silo manufacturers is to sell only the silo proper, or outside wall, with the necessary anchor rods and also the rafters for the roof. In order to complete the silo, the following materials are needed: silo floor, foundation wall, sheathing, roofing, paint, and chute. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Wooden Silos Used in Nebraska 5 The Homemade Tongued and Grooved Stave Silo — This silo needs all the material just mentioned under ordering " The Manu - factured Silo" and in addition needs the material for the silo proper with the anchors and rafters. In making up a bill of material for such a silo, the following items which are listed in the tables should be given consideration: floor, door materials, staves, hoops, hoop lugs, guy wires, bolts, loop bolts, eye bolts, rods, bottom anchors, rafters, sheathing, shingles, headers, and nails. FOUNDATION Stone, brick, hollow brick, concrete blocks, or concrete may be used for the foundation, but because of the ease of handling and the inexperienced help required concrete is preferable. The most common style of foundation is shown in figure 3, but there is this objection to it, that in order to keep the staves from slipping off the foundation a ledge of at least five inches must be left on the inside, and this ledge prevents the silage from settling properly, thus causing it to spoil just above and below the junction of the silo and foundation. CONSTRUCTING THE FOUNDATION If the ground is not level where the silo is to be located, roughly locate the outside of the foundation and level the ground; then set a stake where the center of the silo should be, and, by means of another stake and a string, scratch on the ground the lines for the inside and outside of the foundation (fig. 1). If a Fig. 1— Laying out the lines for the foundation Fig. 2 — The trench dug, ready for the foundation stave silo is to be set on the foundation, the inside diameter of the foundation should be about 10 inches less than the diameter of the silo. Theoretically the two should be the same, but because the staves of the silo shrink and because it is hard to get the inside of the silo round there must be a wide surface for the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Extension Bulletin No. 40, College of Agriculture silo to rest upon, even at the expense of some spoiled silage at this place. When the foundation is marked out, then dig out the trench as shown in figure 2, using care to get the inside smooth and keeping it firm. The sides of the trench are the forms for the concrete. In making the forms for the foundation above the ground, use almost any kind of scrap material for the stakes. Use care, however, to keep the insides straight and vertical and true to the edge of the excavation. If the edge of the trench caves badly when driving the stakes, the concrete can be put into the trench before the stakes are driven; but before the remaining concrete is put in, the surface of the set concrete should be swept and washed clean and covered with a coat of pure cement and water. Be sure to set the anchor lugs AAAA (fig. 3) before the concrete is filled too high in the forms. Do not leave the forms out of level expecting to level the concrete in the forms. It is much easier to level the tops of the forms by raising and lowering the stakes than to level the surface of the concrete within the forms. Before throwing the dirt out of the inside of the founda - tion, scratch a line on top of the foundation by means of a Fig. 3 — Illustrating the form and foundation cord and nail, which will tell where the staves are to be set. This line is shown by BBBB in figure 3 and by AAA in figure 4. One-half inch lumber or common weather boards can be used for the forms above ground, but they should be left out in the rain or be soaked before using. ERECTING STAVE SILOS The most practical method of erecting stave silos is by means of the single post staging. This method consists (fig. 4) of erecting a six, seven, or eight - sided staging around the foundation of the silo. When the staging is completed it forms a cage the sides of which brace each other. The planks which are used for walks and are placed at different elevations in the staging assist also in bracing the tem - porary structure. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Wooden Silos Used in Nebraska 7 Material to be used in staging for all silos 16 feet and diameter and from 28 to 30 feet high: less in Posts, 12 2x4's, 16 ft. long. Cross-braces, 24 Ix6's, 16 ft. long. Cross-ties, 9 2x6's, 12 ft. long or longer. Planks, 18 2xl2's, 12 ft. long or longer. Fig. 4 —The single post stage method of erecting stave silos To erect the homemade silo, first select a straight stave. Lay out the points for the top and bottom of the doors and saw part way thru one of them as shown at A, figure 5. (These saw kerfs are made so that the saw may enter when it is time to saw out the doors.) Nail another stave temporarily to this one to stiffen it. Set these two staves in place where the door should come, and plumb and stay them in at least three different places. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Extension Bulletin No. 40, College of Agriculture Set staves up on either side of this stave and nail them to - gether by means of water-soaked lath or barrel staves. Plumb the staves occasionally and stay them to the staging. A row of the soaked cleats should be nailed on at the top, the middle, and the bottom. Keep every stave exactly on the line scratched on the foundation. If the silo is a manufactured stave silo, set the door frame first and proceed in the same manner as described above. Place the top and bottom hoops in position and tighten them first. Then continue with the others. Measure across the top of the silo in several places and see if the silo is round. If it is, the roof can be put on right away or it can be left until the silo is filled. The latter method is the easier way. Should the silo not happen to be round, it can be trued by forcing timbers of the proper length in between the staves on opposite sides across the narrow diameter. If the silo is not round both at the top and bottom and is not plumb, it will settle out of shape and cause a great deal of trouble in the future. Never fill a new silo until it is both round and plumb. Every stave should be stapled or nailed to the hoops in at least two places and preferably in three. SILO DOORS The silo door is not as vital a part of the silo as many people are wont to make it. However, it is operated more times than any other part and should be convenient and yet durable and tight. The opening should be large and easy of access. The inside of the doors should be smooth and the doors should fit against the silo wall so tight that there is no opportunity for the entrance of air. It is well to nail felt or some type of gasket material around the doors where they rest on the silo, as this will make the joint tighter. When the doors have become \ ■ I • I ; 1 5 \^m. 4 :i ■ IE : u B V Fi; ', 5 — Door details </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Wooden Silos Used in Nebraska 9 warped, it is often well to smear a layer of thick clay around on the door frame so that when the door is put in place it settles into the clay and makes a tight joint. HOMEMADE DOORS The doors should be about four staves wide (fig. 5). By means of the square, lay off the top and bottom lines of each door, being careful to have the lines pass thru the saw kerfs that were made in the first stave set up. Saw out the door pieces, nail them together with the 2*x2* cleats, put the button on the lower end and the T hinge on the upper end; then put the door in place and by means of a claw hammer bend the upper end of the hinge so it will hook over the hoop. When the I*x4* strips have been nailed to the staves adjoining the doors, the silo is ready for the roof. To open the doors, turn the button and by means of the fork handle spring down the hoop over which the hinge is fastened and the latter will unhook and the door fall in. mmmmJ /» rwatr a Fig. 6 — Showing construction and details of roof SILO ROOFS Many silos are built and used without roofs, but this is no doubt false economy. The roof serves three purposes. It strengthens the silo, keeps out storms, and when built tight, as it should be, assists very materially in keeping the silage from freezing. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Extension Bulletin No. 40, College of Agriculture ANCHORING THE SILO The anchors are almost if not quite as important as the hoops of the silo. They should be at both the top and the bottom. Many silos are erected with no anchors at the bottom, but they nearly always give trouble by blowing in. Manufactured silos are nearly always equipped with sufficient anchors and cables. There are two methods of anchoring the homemade silos. One is shown in figure 7 with the details in figure 8. The cable clamps around the rod D and into the eye-bolt B which in turn passes thru the tank lug. The loop bolt A can be fastened to a post or a deadman as shown. Fig. 7 — One method of anchoring silos CHUTE AND LADDER A chute for conveying the silage from the top of the silo to the ground should be constructed on all silos. They save feed, tend to keep storms out of the silo when the doors are open, and add greatly to the appearance of the building if neatly made. A convenient size is about three feet square, but the chute makes a better appearance if it is at least four feet square. If the ladder is a part of the door frame, it saves the trouble of constructing one, altho it is a question whether a good ladder built onto the side of the chute and at right angles to the door is not more convenient. The rungs of the ladder should be from 16 inches to 18 inches apart and at least four inches from the walls of the silo or the chute. They can be made of I*x2* pieces nailed to 2*x4* « * I. M pi [I r ig. 8 — Details of anchor showr in figure 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Wooden Silos Used in Nebraska 11 pieces sitting edgewise up and down the sides of the silo or chute, or a better way is to nail them onto the studding of the chute. PAINTING Silos have not been in use long enough in Nebraska to deter - mine whether it pays to paint the staves on the inside with some form of pitch or tar. It is quite true that when the staves are painted on the inside the silage does not settle quite as well; neither do the walls of the silo clean as well. There is no doubt but that the silo, like all other farm buildings, should be kept well painted on the outside. It will add to the life of the building and also add very much to the appearance of the place. CARE OF WOOD STAVE SILOS The hoops on wood stave silos should always be kept tight when the silo is empty and be gradually loosened after the silo is filled. It is essential that the anchors always be in place and tight. TABLES OF MATERIALS FOR WOOD STAVE SILOS Table 1 — Materials for Four-inch Concrete Floor Mixture Mixture 1:2:4 1:5 Diameter of Sacks Cubic yds silo, in feet cement sand Cubic yds stone Sacks cement Cubic yds. sand 10 I .45 .90 1.2 7 12 8.75 12 .62 1.24 9.25 1.62 14 .88 1.64 12.5 2.19 15.6 1.09 2.88 1« 2.18 16.4 lh 19.75 24.4 1.38 2.74 20.8 25.65 3.65 20 1.71 3.42 4.50 Table 2 — Materials for a Twelve-inch Concrete Foundation Wall, One Foot in Height 1 1 If the silo foundation is to be more than one foot high, multiply the above quantities by the depth of the foundation in feet. ixture :2: ixtui Diameter of silo, in feet 10 12 14 16 18 20 Sacks cement 7.30 8.85 10.82 11.68 13.30 14.63 Cubic yds. Cubic yds. sand stone .51 1.03 .62 1.24 .72 1.44 .85 1.65 .93 1.86 1.03 2.06 Sacks cement 7.7 9.3 10.75 12.30 13.82 15.38 Cubic yds. sand 1.35 1.63 1.89 2.16 2.43 2.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Extension Bulletin No. Jfi, College of Agriculture Table 3— Door Materials for Silos of Various Heights -a iM i «ii : J m ! mil .8 8 .8 ' 8 ill ii .-I |l H J fi X*~ Z° x- J- Z° S3~ ,3~ «*- z° a- JS- z° a- 3~ h (£" cS 00 *; N 18 2 1x4 12 1 2x4 6 4 1 } 4 20 2 1x4 14 1 M.I I tl 5 22 2 1x4 14 1 2x4 8 5 1J 1 5 24 3 1x4 12 1 2x4 9 6 1J 1 6 26 3 1x4 12 1 2x4 9 6 li 1 6 30 4 1x4 12 1 2x4 12 7 2 17 86 { 1 1,4 14 J} 1 2 * 4 " I * «t * * Table 4— Material Bill for Stave Silos SILO 10 FEET IN DIAMETER Table 4— Material Bill for Stave Silos SILO 10 FEET IN DIAMETER Height Height 16 18 30 22 24 26 30 16 18 30 22 24 26 30 Number of staves 1 73 73 73 73 73 73 , 73 Number of staves 1 Board feet in staves Board feet in staves 1,168 1,314 1,460 1,606 1,752 1,898 2,190 Number of hoops 2 (}' steel) 8 9 10 11 12 13 Number of pieces 24 27 30 33 36 39 Number of hoops 2 (}' steel) 8 9 10 11 12 13 15 Number of pieces 24 27 30 33 36 39 45 Length of pieces, in feet Length of pieces, in feet 12 12 12 12 12 12 12 Pounds of steel in hoops 192 216 240 264 288 Number of \ ' hoop lugs 24 27 30 33 36 Pounds of steel in hoops 192 216 240 264 288 312 360 :i60 Number of \ ' hoop lugs 24 27 30 33 36 :iU 45 24 27 30 33 36 39 45 Gal, of paint (2 coats outside) 2.25! 2.60 2.90 I 3.20 S.50 8.78 | 4.00 Gal, of paint (2 coats outside i 2.25 2.60 2.90 3.20 3.50 3.75 4.11(1 SILO 12 FEET IN DIAMETER SILO 12 FEET IN DIAMETER Height 16 18 20 22 24 26 30 Height 16 18 I 20 22 24 26 30 Number of staves 1 88 88 88 88 88 88 88 Number of staves 1 Board feet in staves Board feet in staves 1,408 1,584 1,760 1,936 2,112 2,288 2,640 Number of hoops' (J' steel i 8 9 10 11 12 13 15 Number of pieces 24 27 30 i 33 36 39 45 Length of pieces, in feet 14 14 14 14 ! 14 14 14 Pounds of steel in hoops . . . I 224 252 280 308 336 364 420 Number of \ ' hoop lugs . . . 24 27 30 33 36 39 45 24 27 30 33 36 39 45 Gal. of paint (2 coats outside) | 2.75 | 3.10 3.50 3.80 4.15 4.50 5.25 ■Staves to be lj" with tongues and grooves \ " deep. 'Hoops to lap 8 ' at each lug. Note — One or two extra staves should be ordered to replace those which are defective. 8 10 12 14 !6 10 16 2 2 2 3 3 4 / 2 I 2 1x4 1x4 1x4 1x4 1x4 1x4 1x4 1x4 12 14 14 12 12 12 12 . 14 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 2x4 2x4 2x4 2x4 2x4 2x4 2x4 6 8 8 9 9 12 14 i 4 5 5 6 6 7 9 1 11 l| U 2 21 i 1 1 1 1 1 s 5 6 6 7 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Wooden Silos Used in Nebraska 13 Table 4— Material Bill for Stave Silos — Continued SILO M FEET IN DIAMETER Height Number of staves 1 Board feet in staves Number of hoops 2 (J 'steel) I 9 10 11 12 Number of pieces I 27 30 33 36 Length of pieces, in feet Pounds of steel in hoops 288 320 352 384 Number of £ ' hoop lugs 27 30 33 36 27 30 33 36 Gal. of paint (2 coats outside)! 3.60 I 4.00 1 4.40 I 4.80 SILO 16 FEET IN DIAMETER Height Number of staves' . Board feet in staves Number of hoops 2 117 117 117 2,340 2,574 2,808 10 11 12 18 21 21 9 9 12 Number of \ " pieces in hoops Number of \ " pieces in hoops Number of J ' pieces in hoops Length of pieces, in feet 3 3 3 18 18 18 Pounds of steel in hoops Number of J * hoop lugs Number of | " hoop lugs Number of \ " hoop lugs 466 502 558 18 21 21 9 9 12 3 3 3 Gallons of paint (1 coats outside) . . 4.50 I 5.00 I 5.50 SILO 18 FEET IN DIAMETER Height Number zt staves' . Board teet in staves Number of hoops 2 Number of } " pieces in hoops Number of f * pieces in hoops Number of } ' pieces in hoops Length of pieces, in feet Pounds of steel in hoops Number of J ' hoop lugs . Number of | " hoop lugs Number of 1 " hoop lugs Gallons of paint (2 coats outside) . , I 5.10 I 5.60 •Staves to be If* with tongues and grooves J * deep. 'Hoops to lap 8 ' at'each kig. 18 I 20 22 24 108 103 103 103 1,854 2,060 2,266 2,472 27 30 33 36 16 I 16 16 16 20 22 24 26 30 36 103 2,678 13 39 16 416 39 5.20 103 3,090 15 45 16 479 45 6.00 103 3,708 18 54 16 576 54 7.20 26 30 36 117 3,022 13 24 12 3 IS 594 24 12 3 6.00 117 3,510 15 27 15 I 18 687 27 15 3 6.80 117 4,212 18 30 21 3 18 835 30 21 3 8.25 20 22 24 26 30 36 ... ITT" 132 132 2,640 2,904 10 11 18 21 9 9 3 3 20 20 518 558 18 21 9 9 o q 5.10 5.60 132 3,168 12 21 12 I 20 620 21 12 3 6.10 132 3,432 13 24 12 :i 20 660 24 12 3 6.70 132 132 3,960 4,752 15 I 18 27 30 15 21 3 3 20 20 763 928 27 30 15 21 3 3 7.20 9.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Extension Bulletin No. Jfi, College of Agriculture TABLE I— Material Bill for Stave Silos — Concluded Pounds of steel in hoops Number of J ' hoop lugs Number of J " loop lugs . Number of J * hoop lugs Gallons of paint (2 coats outside) 6.25 6.75 I 7.40 8.50 10.00 ■Staves to be 1 1 " with tongues and grooves \ " deep 'Hoops to lap 8 * at each lug. Table 5— Bill of Materials for Roofs Diameter of silo, in feet Rafters Sheathing Bunches Patent roofing of shingles No. No. Size Length No. Size Length 16 2'x4' 6' 6}' 25 I*x8' 7'lj* 16 2"x4' 7'8J' 29 I"x8" 8'4}' pieces Length 10 H 12 14 () 16 IS 20 2*x4' 11'5}' 42 I'x8" 12' J' 14 11 12' 6 20 |2"x4 &gt; 12' 8« " 46 I"x8' 13' 31" 17J 12 If 8 120 689 734 805 896 1,059 24 28 28 36 44 12 12 16 16 20 8 8 t S 8 16 1 2 *x4 * 9' 34 I'x8' 9'7i' 9 9 18 |2"x4' 10'2J" 38 I'x8" 10' 10" I1J 10 a i in nil A.Y1 ! :eight 22 24 26 30 36 lumber of staves' toard feet in staves lumber of hoops 1 [umber of J " pieces in hoops [umber of f " pieces in hoops lumber of J * pieces in hoops length of pieces, in feet '■\ 147 3,234 11 24 12 8 17 147 3,528 12 28 12 8 17 147 3,822 13 28 16 8 17 147 4,410 15 36 16 8 17 147 5,292 18 44 20 8 17 Table 5— Bill of Materials for Roofs— -Concluded Diameter BrnOm 2 ft No. Size »*S Lbs. 4d. Nails | Lbs. lOd. | Lbs. 20d. i 10 2 ! 2"x4' 10 5' 3' , 2 /I 2'x4' 12 -.,„, 1J \1 2'x4' 10 6 2 14 fl 2'x4' 16 -, 14 \1 2'x4' 14/ 7 16 2 2'x4" 16 7' 10' I 18 2 2'x4' 16 8' 9" 20 2 2*x4' 18 9' 8' 4 I 8 10 12 15 5 1 7 1 9 1 12 2 14 2 17 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Wooden Silos Used in Nebraska 15 If the system of anchoring as illustrated in figure 7 is used, the material necessary for the silos of various heights is given in Table 6. Table 6— Anchor Materials Where Cable Is Used For silos of all sizes and diameters, four each of A, B, C, and D, and eight of E in figure 8, also four \ *x2^ * bolts for fasten - ing E, figure 7, to the lower ends of the staves will be needed. CRIB SILOS The crib silo is constructed of two-inch by four-inch lumber laid flatways. Each layer is nailed to the layer beneath it. Generally there are six or eight sides, depend - ing upon the diameter of the silo. About the only care necessary in their erection is to have the lower three or four feet well anchored, to have each layer well nailed to the layer beneath, and to break joints at the corners. If good material is used in its construction this makes a very dura - ble silo. By lining it with ceiling nailed vertically the silage will keep perfectly, the walls will clear easily, and when the exterior is covered with weather boards it gives an excellent appearance. THE WOODEN HOOP SILO Fig. 9 — Mr. Claason's crib silo which is covered with weath - er boarding. Gage County The wooden hoop silo has been used in Nebraska only about two years but it has the appearance of making a fairly good silo where it can be used in small, low units. Its principle consists of making wooden hoops out of barn battens, placing these in position, and nailing vertically to the inside Sleight of silo, in feet 16 r 18 l 20 22 24 26 30 36 Feet of 7-strand No. 9 wire cable 70 i l 80 100 no 120 130 150 | 170 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Extension Bulletin No. Ifi, College of Agriculture a good grade of flooring. If the lumber is not too dry when used, there is very little danger of injurious swelling; and when the boards dry out, each one dries independently of the others, thus causing only a very slight tendency for cracks to appear at the joints. MAKING THE HOOPS The hoops are made by laying out a circle, driving stakes about every three feet around the circle, and then temporaily nailing a $*x2£* barn batten to these stakes. Nail others over this batten, breaking joints at inter - vals until the hoop is made up of six layers of battens. Continue this construction until all the hoops are made. There should be one hoop for each two feet of height and one extra. ERECTING THE SILO Place all the hoops on the founda - tion; then erect the staging. This can be placed either on the inside of the silo or on the outside. When placed on the inside, it is more con - venient to erect the silo, but the staging is much harder to remove. When the staging is in place, raise the hoops to their proper place and temporaily suspend them from the staging. The flooring can now be put in place and nailed to the hoops. It is not necessary to blind nail the boards but each one should be Fig. 10. — A partially completed wooden hoop silo in Fillmore County kept plumb both ways. If this is done, the silo will be perfectly true when complete. The top should be anchored the same as a stave silo and a good roof will make the building stronger and give it a better appearance. Table 7— Bill of Material for Wooden Hoop Silos 16 Feet High and 10, 12, and H Feet in Diameter Diameter of Square feet Linear feet Pounds Pounds silo, in feet ' of 6 " flooring of barn battens of 6d. nails of 8d. nails I 4 603 723 845 2,262 2,714 3,168 3 3} S 16 19 23 (U-18-'1S— 1OM </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>