<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00012">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00012</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA</title>
			            <date value="1903">1903</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
The University of Nebraska. 

BULLETIN 

OP THH 

AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

OK 

NEBRASKA. 

Vol. XV, Article in. 

POISONING OF CATTLE BY COMMON SORGHUM AND 
KAFIR CORN. 

{Sorghum vulgare.) 

Distributed Jahuikt 25, 1908. 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. 

U. S. A. 

A. T. Peters. H. B. Slade. Samuel Avery. </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
AuRICLLTLRAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

OF 

NEBRASKA 

THE GOVERNING BOARD 


GEO F. KENOWER. icsidtnt, Wisner 
E. v. FORELL, Kearney 

EDSON G. RICH. Omaha 
JOHN L. TEETERS, Lincoln 
E. C. CALKINS, Kearney 
C. J. EKNST, Lincoln 

THE STATION OFFICERS 

E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Directorand Animal Husbandman 
T. L. LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist 
J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary 

WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk 

THE WORKING STAFF 

A. T. PETERS, D. V. M., Animal Pathologist 
Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist 

S. Avery, PH D., Chemist 

A. L. Haeceer, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman 
Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc., Entomologist 
Erwin H. Barbour, Ph. D., Geologist 
R. A. Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulturist 
O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineer 
O. D. SwBZEY, M. A., Meteorologist 

H. R. Smith, B. Sc., Associate Animal Husbandman 
3. H. Gaiw, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist 
S, W. PlUUX. Assistant to A*, vulture and Foreman o/Fann </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
{Sorghum vulgare.") 

Part I. 

FIELD OBSERVATIONS AND REPORTS. 1 

BY A. T. PBTEHS. 

kThe Nebraska Experiment Station has for a number of 
are collected reports of cases of loss of animals from eat 
I green sorghum. 

I Special experiments to determine the cause of death from 
ttle running in sorghum fields were undertaken by the 
epartment of Animal Pathology during the summer of 
01, as the result of numerous inquiries which came to the 
ation asking for remedies and reporting deaths of animals 
at had been pastured on sorghum or had broken into 
rghum fields. In most cases these animals did not regurly 
pasture upon sorghum, but broke into the fields from 
jacent pastures or as they were being driven past fields 
sorghum. Investigation proved that the animals did not 
b from bloat as has been reported by many agricultural 
pers. Many cases were reported where death occurred 
thout bloat and in so short a time that no other theory 
cept that of poison seemed tenable. In most instances 
iere' losses of this kind were reported, the sorghum had 
en stunted in its growth and was not entirely healthy and 
jorous in its appearance. 

tWe visited many fields where animals had died, but genally 
found these animals in so advanced a stage of decom- 

tPart of the material here presented is from the 15th Annual Report 
this Station. 

BULL. 77, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XV, ART. III. </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
* A(/l$€/rti-7lg Oj I .dlllc Oy tSOrgflmrrl iZflCZ _/\ djlr {^.(/fft* 

position that satisfactory post mortems could not be held. 
Often the animals had been buried, and when other animals 
were turned into these fields they refused to eat the sorghum 
and no information could be secured. 

In the spring of 1901, special effort was made to further 
the investigation of sorghum poisoning. A notice was placed 
in the leading State papers to the effect that the Experiment 
Station would send a veterinarian to investigate all cases 
of so-called sorghum poisoning, if notified in time to be of 
assistance or to secure any information. We responded to 
numerous calls of this kind, but in most instances where 
animals were turned upon the sorghum for the express purpose 
of poisoning them they refused to eat, and no data could 
be secured. 

In response to one of these calls, I reached the farm of Mr. 
Bert Foss, near Aurora, at 7 :30 a.m., on August 3, 1901. 
Two days previous, fifteen head of his cattle had broken 
into a sorghum field, where they had remained twenty minutes. 
They were then driven into another field and were 
not seen again for several hours. When seen, three were 
sick, all of which died within a few hours. Th&lt;&gt; symptoms 
were drowsiness, running at the eyes, twitching of the nius 
cles, numbness of the limbs, staggering gait, inability to 
stand, involuntary passing of urine. On August 2, two MR 
cows broke through the fence and were on the sorghum ftdd 
five minutes. One hour later, one of these animals, a fouryear-old 
cow, was very sick, but finally recovered. 

We turned a small yearling steer on the sorghum at 8:30 
a.m., August 3, but he refused to eat any sorghum, and after 
thirty-five minutes two more were turned into the sorghum, 
where they remained until 10:00 a.m., when only one. ¦ 
small, red steer, had taken any sorghum, and he had eaten 
only a few leaves. They were then turned back with the 
herd. At 10:35 a.m. the small, red steer acted somewhat 
drowsy, but soon recovered. 

At 11:00 a.m. we turned one red heifer and one yearling 
steer on the sorghum. The heifer was the only animal that 
ate any quantity, and, as subsequent examination showed, 
she ate only one and one-half pounds of green sorghum. At 
11:10 a.m. this animal dropped to the ground. Upon ex- </seg>

            <seg id="p005">

5 


amination it was found that she had stopped chewing her 
cud and there was a peculiar twitching of the muscles of 
the nose and head and also of the body. The animal was 
very dull. At 11 :15 a.m. she was taken out of the sorghum 
field and allowed to lie in a stubble field. When lying dowu 
her head was turned toward the abdomen, presenting the 
symptoms shown by a horse having the colic. The eyes 
seemed dull and gave off a watery discharge. There was a 
partial paralysis of the tongue and great quantities of saliva 
ran from the mouth. The limbs and ears were cold. The 
pupils of the eyes dilated, pulse not perceptible, mucous 
membrane of the rectum protruding, involuntary discharge 
of urine and faeces. Upon pricking the animal with a knife 
on the lower limbs it showed no feeling. This animal was 
closely watched in the field by Mr. Foss and myself and we 
observed that she did not take any weeds, but simply a small 
amount of sorghum, eating only the tops of the leaves. At 
1 :30 p.m. the animal was still lying on its right side; all the 
muscles of the head were contracted and showed involuntary 
twitching. The limbs were paralyzed and the animal 
was unconscious; the mucous membrane of the mouth was 
of a salmon color. At 2 :35 p.m. the animal was in great 
pain, and it was apparent that she would not recover. At 
the suggestion of Mr. Foss the animal was killed in order to 
hold a post-mortem examination. 

Post-Moutem Examination. — Animal still warm. The 
bowels were opened and contents of paunch carefully noted ; 
there was in all one pound and a half of sorghum leaves to 
be found in the paunch. No sourness of the contents. The 
same was immediately put up in Mason fruit jars with clean 
water and brought to the laboratory. The mucous membrane 
of the intestines normal, all other conditions of the 
animal normal. Made particular examination of the pharynx 
(throat), epiglottis, and esophagus, and found that there 
were no leaves lodged over the same. If this had occurred 
the animal would have died instantly and not within three 
or more hours as our record shows, and would have died in 
the state of asphyxia and not presenting the symptoms of 
acute poisoning. In eleven post mortems that we conducted, 
careful search has always failed to reveal any leaves ob- </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 


structing the pharynx, epiglottis, or esophagus, which would 
have caused death by asphyxia or strangulation. 

I One case of sorghum poisoning is reported from sorghum 
at had been cut several hours before feeding. Mr. E. F. 
oner, of Chester, cut sorghum at 8 K)0 o'clock p.m., August 
which was fed to three milch cows at 8:00 a.m., August 3. 
&gt;out 9:00 o'clock a.m. these animals were first noticed to 
sick. One died within an hour and fifteen minutes. The 
lier two recovered within twelve hours. On August 6 I 
tited this sorghum field and made an examination of the 
rghum, which was not fully matured. It was comparaely 
free from weeds. At 5:45 p.m. we placed a cow in 
is sorghum field and allowed her to eat as much cut 
rghum as she would, up to 8:00 p.m., when she had conmed 
about twenty pounds. At 7 :00 a.m., on August 7, the 
imal showed no effects of sorghum poisoning, and no bad 
ects followed. 

I The season of 1902 was unusually wet in most sections of 
e State. As a result of the vigorous growth of sorghum, 
iv cases of poisoning have been reported. On July 24, Mr. 
illiam J. Smith, of Cambridge, lost two cows as the result 
feeding green sorghum. On the 30th of July, Mr. H. B. 
ade and 1 visited the farm of Mr. Smith and made a physiojical 
test of the effect upon a cow of the sorghum growing 
the field. A full-sized Jersey cow was turned into the 
rghum patch shortly after 9 :00 o'clock. At 9 :10 the aniil 
began to eat the sorghum and kept quite steadily at it 
p the next few minutes. She soon ceased, became uneasy, 
d in ten minutes after she had taken the first mouthful of 
rghum she was seen to lurch suddenly as if she had lost her 
lance. From that time on the symptoms of poisoning 
pidly developed, and the cow passed into a semi-comatose 
ndition. After five hours the effect of the poison appeared 
isened and the cow recovered. 

Pe fresh air acted to some extent as an antidote, and by 
o'clock the animal was able to rejoin the herd. Samples 
rghum taken from the locality where the cow had eaten 
examined in the laboratory and found to produce pruscid. 
The symptoms and the presence of prussic acid in 
sorghum afford unmistakable evidence of the cause of </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
7 

the poisoning. The action upon the heart, respiration, and 
nervous centers as well as the incipient diarrhoea are all 
characteristic symptoms of prussic acid poisoning, and tho 
smell of the acid about the mouth was sufficient by itself to 
identify the poison. 

The sorghum from this field gave chemical tests for prussic 
acid. 

[While no later reports of poisoning in the State have been 
ceived, the Chemical Department continued the study of 
e occurrence in plants of compounds capable of liberating 
ussic acid. Prussic acid had just been obtained from 
ifir corn growing on the University farm when the folding 
letter was received : 

"State Agricultural College and Experiment Station, i 
"Department of Veterinary Science. Geo. H. Glover. \ 
"Fort Collins, Colorado, September 17, 1902. ) 
"Director Experiment Station, IAncoln, Nebr.: 

"Dear Sir — We have recently experienced a fearful loss 
of cattle in this State from eating Kafir corn; twenty-one 
head of dairy cows out of thirty-two dying within an hour 
after first being placed upon the feed. This corn was a 
stunted growth being above the ditch. Will you kindly inform 
me if you experienced any such difficulty in Nebraska 
or give any further information bearing on the subject? 

"Yours respectfully, 

(Signed) "Geo. H. Glover." 

[As the result of the correspondence with the Department 
Veterinary Science of the Colorado Agricultural College, 
was arranged that this Station should co-operate in instigating 
the outbreak. Accordingly Dr. S. Avery visited 
e Colorado Station for this purpose. The cattle belonged 
Eugene F. Pitman and his mother, Mrs. Susan R. Pitman, 
Brighton, Colo. Mr. Pitman kindly furnished the followg 
information : 

("The cattle died on August 20 last. We lost 21 head out 
32 head which had been turned on the corn. Eleven head 
ed, but 4 of the 11 head had violent spasms, but recovered. 
te other 7 head were not affected. They were only on the 
rn 5 or 6 minutes. The first cow died in 15 minutes; </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
8 

Poisoning of Cattle by Sorghum and Kafir Corn. 

nearly all within an hour. One yearling lived over 6 hours. 
I gave it several doses of aconite, thinking possibly one 
poison would counteract the other, but it died in great 
agony. The cattle seemed to all go crazy at once, then stagger 
like a person intoxicated, fall in all directions, and die 
where they fell. I stuck all of them with a knife, the same 
as in alfalfa bloat, but there wasn't any gas in them. The 
Kafir corn was planted on sod ground above irrigation. It 
was from 6 to 15 inches high and was burnt brown from the 

Shortly after the poisoning, Dr. Glover visited the field 
and collected samples, which he generously placed at our 
disposal. These samples yielded prussic acid in greater 
amounts than any yet examined in Nebraska. 

More definite information in regard to the conclusions 
drawn from the chemical investigations, as well as observations 
in regard to the conditions under which sorghum 
becomes dangerous, will be given in Part II of this bulletin. </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
9 

Part II. 

CHEMICAL INVESTIGATIONS.' 

BY S. AVERT. 

The investigations of the Department of Animal Pathology 
have been given in Part I of this bulletin. That work 
furnished the basis of chemical investigation. 

Some three years ago Dr. A. T. Peters arrived at the following 
conclusions regarding the loss of cattle from eating 
green sorghum : 

1. Animals do not die from bloat or indigestion. 

2. They do not choke to death. 

The deaths result from a violent poison in sorghum of 
inted growth. 

4. The symptoms are those of prussic acid poisoning. 

tThe chemical investigations on the subject here recorded 
plain and confirm the conclusions drawn by the veteririan 
from his field work. 

Definite knowledge of the poisonous principle in these 
plants was wanting till very recently. As late a publication 
as the Yearbook of the Department of Agriculture for 1900 
contains the suggestion that in many cases death may result 
from choking. In 1886 Berthelot and Andre* ascribed the 
cause to excessive amounts of potassium nitrate (saltpeter). 
Williams 4 of the U. S. Department of Agriculture also suggests 
saltpeter as a cause of the trouble. Hiltner 5 has shown 

'The chemical work on prussic acid in Sorghum vulgare (common 
sorghum and Kafir corn) was begun by Mr. Henry B. Slade and has been 
continued by the writer. Mr. Slade, who is no longer connected with 
this Station, has fully authorized the writer to present his part of the 
work. In view of the pioneer work of Mr. Slade his name is published 
on the title page as one of the joint authors. The writer is, however, 
responsible for the form of presentation of all of Part II. It should be 
added, also, that part of the work here given is due to the labor of Dr. 
Peters and is presented in the chemical part for the sake of convenience. 

•Abstract in Biedermann's Centralblatt f. Agrikultur-Chemie, Bd. M, 
1886, p. 473. 

'Farmers' Bulletin No. 50. 

•N«br. Exp. SUUoa Bulletin No. 18, p. 75. </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
6 J • 6 J 

iat the amount of nitrate in Nebraska fields was too small 
o produce fatal results. This writer suggests that the plant 
nder certain conditions develops a highly poisonous chemial 
compound. Slade* in the Annual Report of the Station 
or the present year put forward the theory that such a com- 
K)und might be produced by the action of an enzym upon a 
ucoside found in the plant through a process of abnormal 
growth. On June 27 of the present year the Chemical News 
' London contained an article on Cyanogenesis in -Plants 
&gt;y Dunstan and Henry. This article, which fully confirms 
lade's prediction, was not known to Mr. Slade or to the 
riter till October 10. In brief, the England Chemists isoated 
from Egyptian Sorghum vuJgare a glucoside capable 
! liberating prussic acid. In the meantime Mr. Slade had 
etected prussic acid in fatal sorghum grown in western 
Nebraska, determined the per cent, and secured strong evience 
in favor of the glucoside theory. 

I On July 26, Mr. William J. Smith, of Cambridge, Nebr., 
I sorghum to a herd of cattle with the result that two died, 
le sample, received by Mr. Slade on the fourth day after 
tting, was weighed, ground up in a vegetable cutter, mixed 
th water, and distilled as long as prussic acid was evolved, 
le prussic acid found in the distillate amounted to .014 
r cent of the weight of the sorghum taken. As later re- 
Its show that most of the acid is in the leaves, it is proble 
that the entire stalk here submitted to analysis conined 
a lower per cent of prussic acid than the part which 
e animal actually consumed. At this per cent, seven or 
fht pounds of sorghum might cause death. 

[During the first two weeks in September, the writer disrered 
that prussic acid could be obtained from leaves of 
althy sorghum in the fields about the Station. As the 
st season was abnormally wet, nearly all of the fields had 
ide a vigorous growth. By distilling water from a suffisnt 
quantity of leaves, determinable amounts of prussic 
id were evolved in all cases, though the amount was well 
low the danger line. Of the common Nebraska forage 
mts, sorghum and Kafir corn alone yield prussic acid. 

•A Study of the Enzyms of Green Sorghum, 15th Annual Report, Nebr. 
Exp. Station, 1902, p. 55. </seg>


            <seg id="p011">
I On the 7th of October the writer visited Colorado to instigate 
the outbreak of poisoning from Kafir corn described 
page 7 of this bulletin. By the courtesy of Dr. Head 
n, Chemist of the Colorado Station, leaves from the fatal 
Id were tested for prussic acid. The large amount obined 
was in keeping with the deadly character of the plant 
the field. Parts of the dried sample were found, on dialing, 
to yield as much as .1 per cent of prussic acid. At 
is rate, one pound might contain the fatal amount. 

As both sorghum and Kafir corn are important forage 
plants, and as the investigations of the writer show that they 
contain as normal constituents compounds yielding prussic 
acid, the important question naturally arises, In what conditions 
of growth are these plants dangerous? The following 
have been suggested: 

1. Young plants. 

2. Second growth. 

3. Frosted plants. 

4. Stunted plants. 

Unfortunately sufficient data have not been secured to 
enable the writer to give a final opinion on all of these 
points. They will, however, be discussed in the light of the 
facts at hand. 

Young plants of vigorous growth contain a higher per 
cent of prussic acid than the bright, green leaves of plants 
reaching maturity. As the stalks and seeds contain no prussic 
acid, the young plants contain a much greater per cent 
of acid than the mature plants considered as a whole. 

Second growth is not more deadly than first growth, although, 
as falls in the West are often bright and dry, conditions 
may be favorable for the elaboration of excessive 
amounts of poison during the second growth. 

Frost is without influence except as the forerunner of a 
riod of bright, dry weather. 

Growth arrested by dry weather before the plant begins 
to mature presents a condition very favorable for the elaboration 
of the poison. Growth stunted by too much water, 
sterile soil, shade of trees, or hardness of ground does not 
result in the formation of dangerous quantities of poison. 

A study of the data at hand, field observations, and chem- </seg>


            <seg id="p012">
ical analyses, indicates that the poisoning is most deadly in 
Missouri, Nebraska, Kansas, and Colorado, and that it is 
rare east, north, and south of these states. The danger increases 
in Nebraska as one proceeds from the Missouri river 
westward. This cannot be attributed entirely to a dryer soil, 
as some irrigated fields have proven fatal. In general, however, 
we can say that the analyses of numerous samples show 
that dry, clear weather, T&gt;y arresting the normal development 
of the plant, is the chief cause of the formation of abnormal 
quantities of poison. 

The following table gives some of the analytical data on 
which the conclusions above given are based. The figures 
K represent the amount of prussic acid obtained by diswith 
water 100 grams of the sample. The dates repthe 
time of cutting the plant </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
Cattle by Sorghum and Kafir Corn. 13 

* 

j »— t r- t^ r- c? 2C — ' " 
oS"S © oooio SO © 

o. 

« 

7. 

R ' ' S 

"V. 

i iii.j 

•3 


t- 

5 

-3 


I :i %%il 11:28 

-^ 

*&amp;'. §§ :S&amp; 

«&gt; 

"o 

I J 

C 

I * 

r ¦ s 

s ¦«! S^S^S 0B-SS3 : 

v w ; : : : : ; 
f i'A s:s: : 
E % Is = - -' - 


u .-I.-I&amp;5SJ « u 
it 1 1 
5. &amp; o z </seg>


            <seg id="p014">
The investigations made at this Station show that the 
&gt;russic acid is not present as such, but that it is liberated 
rom a glucoside, (1) by an enzyin in the plant as in the 
ase of sorghum poisoning, and (2) by the action of boiling 
ater on the plant Glucosides of this sort are in themselves 
harmless and are dangerous only when they liberate 
&gt;russic acid. Now the above table shows that even dried 
•lants may contain a very large amount of combined prussic 
cid. We should expect that such a fodder would be as fatal 
o stock after curing as when standing in the field. Experiuce, 
however, seems to prove the contrary. Enzynis rapidly 
become inactive when dried in the presence of proteid subances, 
as Mr. A. F. Woods, Chief of Division of Plant 
athology, informs the writer. In other words, the subtance 
capable of breaking up the glucoside into prussic acid 
nd other compounds is no longer active. This, now, is conirmed 
by the following experiment. 100 grains of Kafir 
orn were ground in the vegetable cutter; of this, one half 
as mixed with 200 cc of water and allowed to dry. The 
ther half was mixed with 200 cc of water extract of green 
sorghum leaves. After drying, this sample yielded on analys 
only one-half as much prussic acid as the sample that 
lad been treated with water only. This signifies that the 
nzym from the fresh leaves had liberated a considerable 
mount of acid. In this case the acid had escaped in the 
:mosphere; in cases of poisoning the enzym allows the poison 
to enter the system of the animal. 

I Well-cured Kafir corn containing a large amount of prusz 
acid was fed to several animals. In no case could any 
mptoms of prussic acid poisoning be observed, although 
ie animal consumed material representing 1.2 grams of 
mbined prussic acid. One-third of this amount of free 
id is highly dangerous. In concluding this phase of the 
bject we do not wish to put ourselves on record as stating 
at plants become harmless on drying. We can, however, 
ate that there is at hand strong evidence pointing to such 
conclusion. 

t There is a general opinion among stockmen that cattle 
ttening on corn may be allowed the range of fields of 
inted sorghum without danger of loss. During the sum- </seg>


            <seg id="p015">
mer of 1901 when instances of poisoning were very numerous, 
the writer watched for a number of days forty head of 
steers, on full feed of corn, that were allowed the range of a 
sorghum field that to all appearances was highly dangerous. 
No loss or symptoms of poisoning occurred. It is 
doubtful if in the presence of more palatable food stunted 
sorghum is consumed in any great quantity. At the same 
time there is no doubt that partially digested grain acts to a 
certain extent as an antidote for prussic acid. 

The following series of experiments were carried out on a 
barren heifer in order to determine the effect of carbohydrates 
in lessening the poisonous action of prussic acid. 
Sufficient time was allowed between the experiments for the 
animal to reach a normal condition. 

Result. 

Prussic acid administered. 

0.2 grams Slight symptoms 

0 4 grams Animal very sick but recovered. 

0.8 grains in 15 grams of glucose (se 

[lected as a type of carbohydrate 
6 grams in 30 grams of glucose. . . 

Very slight symptoms. 

Animal very sick, had severe convnl- 

sions, but recovered. 

ANTIDOTES. 

I Prussic acid has a tendency to unite with certain carbohy¦ates, 
forming additional products. These compounds are 
uch less poisonous than the free acid. Both glucose and 
ilk sugar unite with prussic acid to some extent even in dite 
solutions. Aside from this action these carbohydrates 
tard the action of the enzym in liberating prussic acid, 
lese facts suggest that, in case the animal is not in such a 
ndition as to render medical treatment out of the question, 
e following may be effective: 

I A strong solution of glucose, which nearly every farmer 
a at hand in the form of "corn syrup" or inolass&lt;&gt;s, may be 
ministered. 

Large quantities of milk have in a number of instances 
been administered apparently with good effect. 

I In all cases the animal should have as much fresh air as 
ssible. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>