<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00058.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00058.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Secretary of State of the State of Nebraska for Twenty-Four Months Ending June 30, 1926</title>
               <date value="1926">1926</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR TWENTY-FOUR MONTHS ENDING JUNE 30, 1926 Charles W. Pool, Secretary of State TO THE GOVERNOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Office of Secretary of State Lincoln, Nebraska June 30, 1926 To tile Honorable, The Governor, Adam Mf?iMullcii, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. My dear Governor: ■ Conforming to the statutes of the Commonwealth, 1 have the honor present herewith my report as Secretary of State for the State of Nebraska for the twenty -four months ending June 30, 3926. This report contains an exhibit of the affairs of the office and tiie method of conducting the same during the teiin now closing. It further sets forth a statement of the number of corporations incorporating, qualifying, withdrawing or dissolving, the registration of trade marks, the registration and renewal "of brands, a classified statement of all money's received by the office as fees, the amount of moneys expended by this department, the granting of rfluirters to chai - tel loan organizations, and a report of the Board of Pardons. In the interest of economy, we have abridged the report as much as possible, eliminating some features that have heretofore been em - bodied, which "would increase the cost of publishing and are in them - selves not of vital public interest. Respectfully submitted, CHARLES W. POOL, Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 the re REPORT OP THE SECRETARY OF STATE SECRETARIES OF STATE TERRITORIAL 1. •j. ;;. Thomas B. dimming, August 23, 1854, to March 12, 1858 J. Sterling Morton, July 12, 1858, to May 6, 1861. Algernon S. Paddock, May 6, 1861, to Feb. 21, 1867. STATE 4. 5. Thomas P. Kennard, from Feb. 21, 1867, to Jan. 10, 1871 Win. H. James, from Jan. 10, 1871, to Jan. 12, 1873. Acting Governor, from June 2, 1871, to Jan. 13, 1873. John J. Gosper, from Jan. 13, 1873, to Jan. 11, 1875. Bruno Tzschuck, from Jan. 11, 1875, to Jan. 9, 1879, S. J. Alexander, from Jan. 9, 1879. to Jan 4, 1883. Edward P. Roggen, from Jan. 4, 1883 to Jan. 6, 1887. Gilbert L. Laws, from Jan. 6, 1887, to Nov. 20, 1889. &lt;i. 7. 8. 10. Resigned to fill unexpired term in Congress caused by death of James Laird. Benjamin R. Cowdry, from Nov. 20, 1889, to Jan. 8, 1891. Appointed by Governor Thayer to fill vacancy caused by 11. signation of Gilbert L. Laws. 32. John C. Allen, from Jan. 8, 1891, to Jan. 3 1895. Joel A. Piper, from Jan. 3, 1895, to Jan. 7, 1897. William F. Porter, from Jan. 7, 1897, to Jan. 13, 1901. George W. Marsh, from Jan. 3, 1901, to Jan. 6, 1905. A. Galusha, from Jan. 6, 1905, to Jan. 3, 1907. Geo. C. Junkin, from Jan. S, 1907, to Jan. 5. 1911. Addison Wait, from Jan. 5, 1911, totJan. 7, 1915. Charlf-s W. Pool, from Jan. 7. 1915. to Jan. 9, 1919. Darius M. Amsberry, from Jan. 9. 1919, to Jan. 4, 1923. Charles W. Pool, from Jan. 4, 1923, to Jan. 6, 1927. 13. 14. 15. 16. 17. 18. 19. 20. 21. &lt;&gt;. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 STATE OFFICERS DURING BIENNIUM Adam McMullen, Governor ; Beatrice -j. Geo. A. Williams, Lieutenant Governor .Fairmont Charles W. Pool, Secretary of State Lincoln Geo. W. Marsh, Auditor Lincoln Dan Swanson, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings— .Fremont Charles D. Robinson, Treasurer Red Cloud O. S. Spillman, Attorney General Pierce Thorne A. Browne, Railway Commissioner Lincoln Charles A. Randall, Railway Commissioner Newman Grove H. G. Taylor, Railway Commissioner Central City John Matzen, State Superintendent Fremont UNITED STATES SENATORS George W. Norris McCook 1925-1931 R. B. Howell Omaha 1923-1929 CONGRESSMEN John H. Morehead Falls City First District Willis G. Sears Omaha.... Second District Edgar Howard Columbus Third District M. 0. McLaughlin York. Fourth District Ashton C. Shallenberger Alma Fifth District Robert G. Simmons Scottsbluff Sixth District ADMINISTRATIVE BOARDS Of Which the Secretary of State is a Member Board of Equalization and Assessment. Board of Educational Lands and Funds Board of Canvassers. Board of Pardons. Board of Depository Bonds. OFFICE FORCE OF DEPARTMENT OF STATE Charles W. Pool, Secretary .' Lincoln Fred C. Ayres, Deputy Lincoln E. C. Parsons, Book keeper Lincoln Charlotte L. Reynolds Lincoln Mabel Loveland, Recording Clerk Lincoln Florence Meduna, Correspondence Clerh. Wahoo </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 5 CORPORATION DEPARTMENT The table below sets forth the number of articles of incorpora- tion, amendments to articles of incorporation, appointment of agents, dissolutions, etc., handled during the pas L twenty-four months: Domestic Corporations Total number of domestic corporations registered 3736 Number domestic corporations incorporated during biennium 602 Number domestic corporations filing amendments 32-4 Number domestic corporations voluntarily dissolving 322 Numbers of domestic corporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes , ....... 252 Foreign Corporations Total number foreign corporations registered 540 Number foreign corporations qualified during biennium..... 150 Number ammendments to appointments, filed : 62 Number foreign corporations voluntarily withdrawing 54 Number foreign corporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes 63 Non-Profit Corporations Total number non-profit corporations registered 623 Number non-profit corporations incorporated during biennium.. 123 Number non-profit corporations filing amendments 35 Number non-profit corporations voluntarily dissolving 1/ Number non-profit coiporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes , 29 Grand total all corporations, domestic foreign and non-profit, en - gaged in business at this date in Nebraska 4901 TRADE MARKS AND TRADE NAMES Total number of Trade Marks and Trade Names 717 Number of Trade Marks and Trade Names filed during bien - nium 121 STOCK BRANDS This department is charged with the assignment and registration of brands used for the purpose of marking live stlock, as by the statu- tes provided. The year 1922 was the year in which all stock brands were renewed. This renewal comes but once in five years. A sum- mary of the business for the past twenty-four months is as follows: Total number of brands registered 5959 Number brands issued during biennium...* 2322. FINANCIAL STATEMENT Xh|is office collects fees for filing articles of incorporation, cor- poration permits, notary public commissions, registration of brands, certificates of transcripts, trade marks, and loan licenses. The fol- lowing is a true and correct exhibit of moneys Received during tihe past twenty-four months from all sources: </seg>
            <seg id="p006">RECEIPTS JULY 1, 1924 JULY 1, 1925 JUNE 30, 1925 JUNE 30,1926 Corporation Filings, Domestic- $ 20,140.15 $ 24,572.45 Corporation Filings, Foreign 3,336.75 4,990.65 Corporation Permits, Non-Profit 536.00 511.00 Corporation Permits, Domestic 112,572.65 111,045.25 Corporation Permits, Foreign 26,377.75 25,067.50 Notary Commission Fees 2,454.00 2,842.00 Brand Registration 748.50 2,810.85 Loan Company Licenses 540.00 600.00 Miscellaneous Fees 3,145.56 2,420.73 Total .$169,851.36 $174,860.43 Total receipts for biennuim $344,711.79 EXPENDITURES Salary, Secretary of Stale $ 5,000.00 $ 5,000.00 Salary Deputy Secretary of State 2,640.00 2,530.00 Salaries, Clerks 5,836.50 5,503.01 Maintenance 2,748.59 1,747,95 Printing roster of ex-soldiers 3,855.42 Administration of initiative and referendum laws 6,660.00 Registering brands and publishing book 99.00 Reproduction of State Banner 100.00 Total $ 26,740.51 $ 14,979.96 LOAN AGENCIES Sec. 2846. Compiled Statutes for 1923, provides for the licens- ing of loan agents or loan agencies, and is designed to regulate the loaning of money in small quantities upon chattel securities, salaries. etc. The bond to be given by the company is in the sum. of $2,000.00 to be renewed and filed annually on March 1st. The companies now operating are as follows Peoples Loan Company Omaha March 1, 1926. Provident Loan Society Omaha March 1, 1926. Popular Finance Company Omaha March 1, 1926. Industrial Finance Company Omaha March 1, 1926. Rex Company Omaha March 1, 1926. Omaha Loan Company Omaha March 1, 1926. Community Finance Corporation Omaha March 1, 1926. Farmers Loan and Investment Company....Lincoln March 1, 1926. Midwest Finance Company .Crete May 10, 1926. These companies have been examined annually, as provided by law, and reports of examination are on file in this office. Respectfully submitted, CHARLES W. POOL, Secretary of State </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT CF THE SECRETARY OF STATE BOARD OF PARDONS Below is showii a list of the number of applicants heard by Hi? Board of Pardons from the Penitentiary^ Reformatory for Men and the Reformatory for Women from December 1st, 1924, to Dei-ember 1st, 1926: Total Number of cases heard 4tx) Total Number of cases denied lly PENITENTIARY Discharged by expiration of term 28«i Pardons granted 0 Commutations granted. 4/ Paroles granted lVd Number of violators 26 Violators returned 13 Violators in custody (awaiting return) 4 REFORMATORY FOR MEN Discharged by expiration of term _ 174 Pardons granted • Commutations granted 7 Paroles granted 159 Number of violators 25 Violators returned 18 Violators in custody (awaiting return) 0 REFORMATORY F EN: Discharged by expiration of terra 52 Pardons granted 0 Commutations granted 0 Paroles granted 4 Number of violators 0 This board is composed of the Governor, Attorney General and Secretary of State. The board meets the second Tuesday of each month during the year, except in the month of August. The percentage of violations of paroles in Nebraska during the past biennium is very low — 15.75 — or in other words less than sixteen out of every hundred persons granted clemency have violated the confidence reposed in them by the Board. This is a creditable show- ing as compared with that of many other states. Respectfully submitted, CHARLES W POOL, Secretary, Board of Pardons. </seg> 
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>