<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00043.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00043.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Ninth Biennial Report of the Nebraska State Board of Charities and Correction and State Prison Board Report for Biennium Closing November 30, 1918</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Ninth Biennial Report of the Nebraska State Board of Charities and Correction and State Prison Board Report For Biennium Closing November 30, 1918 »»"'«» "«. CO.. LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Nebraska State Board of Charities and. Correction Governor Keith Neville Supc!i:itendent W. H. Clemmons Land Commissioner G. L. Shumway Chief Clerk E. M. Johnson Assistant Clerk Matilda Heagney After January 9, 1919, the State Board Will Consist Of Governor S. R. McKelvie Superintendent W. H. Clemmons Land Commissioner Dan Swanson </seg>
            <seg id="p003">NAME AND LOCATION OF NEBRASKA STATE INSTITUTIONS 1. State Penitentiary Lancaster W. T. Fenton Warden 2. State Industrial School for Boys Kearney R. V. Clark, Superintendent 3. Girls' Industrial School Geneva Paul McCauley, Superintendent 4. Nebraska Industrial Home Milford Miss Lena Ward, Superintendent 5. Nebraska Hospital for Insane Lincoln Dr. J. D. Case, Acting Superintendent 6. Hospital for Insane Norfolk Dr. G. E. Carlton, Superintendent 7. Nebraska State Hospital lngleside Dr. W. S. Fast, Superintendent 8. Orthopedic Hospital Lincoln Dr. B. A. Sinkle, Superintendent 9. Nebraska Soldiers and Sailors' Home Burkett J. F. Walsh, Commandant 10. Soldiers and Sailors' Home Milford W. N. Hensley, Commandant 11. Nebraska State Institution for Feeble Minded Youth Beatrice Dr. D. G. Griffiths, Superintendent 12. Home for Dependent Children Lincoln Amy V. Stevens, Superintendent 13. School for Deaf Omaha Frank W. Booth, Superintendent 14. School for Blind Nebraska City N. C. Abbott, Superintendent 15. Hospital for Tuberculous Kearney Dr. L. T. Sidwell, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p004">PRIVATE INSTITUTIONS Bethphage Mission Axtell Rev. C. A. Lonquist, Superintendent Child Saving Institute 42nd and Jackson, Omaha Miss M. Troth, Matron Christian Orphans' Home Holdrege H. A. Gustin, Superintendent Crowell Home Blair Rev. Wm. Esplin, Superintendent Good Shepherd Home 40th and Jones, Omaha Sister M. Raphael, Superintendent Home for Aged Negroes 3029 Pinkney St., Omaha Mrs. Annie Bowler, President House of Hope - Florence Miss Schempp, Superintendent Immanuel Deaconess Institute 34th and Meredith, Omaha F. A. Under, Superintendent Lutheran Orphanage Fremont J. F. Gnuse, Superintendent Mothers' Jewels Home York Rev. W. F. Dudman, Superintendent Mother Hull W. C. T. U. Hospital Kearney Mrs. Anna Gallington, Manager Nebraska Children's Home Society 514 Brown Block, Omaha Rev. E. P. Quivey, Superintendent Nebraska Masonic Home Plaitsmouth W. S. Asquith, Superintendent Nebraska Masonic &amp; Eastern Star Home for Children. Fremont and Plattsmouth Mrs. Sadie D. Boorman, Superintendent Odd Fellows' Home York J. W. Pittman, Superintendent Old People's Home 1325 Fontenelle Blvd., Omaha Mrs. Anna R. Butter, Superintendent Salvation Army Rescue Home 24th and Spaulding, Omaha Lillie E. Ness, Matron St. James Orphanage Benson Rev. John Roche, Superintendent St. Joseph's Home for the Aged West Point Monsignor Joseph Reusing, Superintendent St. Thomas Orphanage Lincoln Franciscan Sisters in charge Sunnyside Home Hastings Elizabeth Y. Henry, Matron Swedish Lutheran Orphanage Stromsburg P. V. Ek, Superintendent Tabitha Home 45th and Randolph, Lincoln Rev. Ernest Walters, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Ninth Biennial Report State Board of Charities and Correction To His Excellency, Keith Neville Governor of Nebraska. Dear Sir: It affords me great pleasure to present herewith the report of the Department of Charities and Correction, including the State Prison Board and the Advisory Board of Pardons for the biennium ending November 30, 1918. As Chief Clerk of the State Board of Charities and Cor - rection I have visited every county in the state, officially in - spected every county jail and poor house, many city jails and all private charitable and correctional institutions. There are fifteen state institutions directly under the management of the State Board of Control — all of these were visited, inspected, and recommendations made to the Board concerning improve - ments, sanitation and treatment of inmates. Wherever possible, the county commissioners were per - sonally interviewed and the conditions of their jails and poor farms were discussed. In these cases recommendations were made personally. In the others, letters have been written to recommend needed changes or improvements. Where jails or poor houses were found to be unfit for the purpose foi which they were intended, unsanitary or endangering th« lives of those committed to them, they have been unhesitatingly con - demned. Much good has been accomplished by these inspec - tions and recommendations; jails have been cleaned up and poor houses made more comfortable, and no doubt when these places are again visited it will be found that many more of our suggestions have been carried out. Having visited all the private charitable and correctional institutions and inquired into their condition and manage - ment, our records concerning these places are more complete than heretofore and we are better able to give information in </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT regard to the work being accomplished by them. We found the Homes for Old People under private control better fitted to properly care for those in their charge than most of the county poor houses. They have endeavored to make the place a real home for the inmates. That word "home" means everything to the aged and feeble even though it "Be ever so humble". For the unfortunate class found at the poor farms the only home they have is the one provided by the county. The amount of money expended by the various counties for this purpose if invested in a State Home for Aged and Indigent People would be sufficient to build, equip and support a modern institution of this kind. We, therefore, recommend that such legislation as is necessary for the establishment and maintenance of a State Home for Aged and Indigent People be enacted by the coming legislature and that such state home take the place of the several county poor houses. As Secretary of the State Prison Board and Advisory Board of Pardons, and as State Parole Officer, all the duties devolving upon these positions have been performed. Such correspondence as was needed to gain information concern - ing cases coming before the above boards was given careful attention. Every meeting of the Board was attended and a record of the business transacted was faithfnlly mada. Employment was secured for the men who were placed on parole and during the biennium not one had to remain in the prison a day over the date set for his parole on account of not having employment. Every effort possible was made to assist the paroled man to regain right relations with so - ciety. When one flagrantly violated the conditions of his parole he was returned to the prison for further discipline. Some escaped from our jurisdiction and some became delin - quent in the observance of their parole agreement. Many of the paroled men entered military service with our permission. We have recommended for final discharge only those who complied faithfully with the provisions of their parole agree - ment during the required period of time. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 7 We find that 91% of those paroled during the biennium were faithful to the trust reposed in them. STATE INSTITUTIONS There are fifteen institutions under the supervision of the State Board of Control. There has been notable improve - ment in the equipment and work of these institutions rince the Board has been in operation. Superintendents and assistants are selected and retained because of capability and efficiency. During the biennium just closing new buildings have been erected or are under process of construction at the following places: Hospitals for Insane at Norfolk, Ingleside, and Lincoln; Boys' Industrial School. Kearney; Institution for Feeble Minded, Beatrice; Old Soldiers' Home, Bnrkett, and the Peni - tentiary at Lincoln. The Department of Charities and Correction has an in - specting relation to the institutions under the care of the Board of Control. We have inspected each place and made such recommendations as seemed practical and beneficial. At each of the hospitals for insane, there was a very crowded condition, but the new buildings will relieve that con - gestion to some extent. At none of these hospitals is there proper provision for the care of the criminal insane. This class is a dangerous element and should be so quartered and guarded that it would be difficult at any time for them to commit violence upon themselves or their fellow patients. Barred doors and windows are but reasonable precautions against attempted outbreaks by these inmates. The new building at Ingleside supplies a long felt need for better kitchen arrangements and quarters for the attendants. Some improvements have been made at the Old Soldiers Homes. The Superintendent at Burkett has by his wise man - agement utilized some old material about the institution in Eodelling and repairing several of the farm buildings. A structure just completed adds very materially to the king equipment of the Home. Several cottages give com- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT fortable living quarters to married couples receiving the care of the institution. In the main buildings some parts have the individual room plan, used especially for married couples; in other parts the ward plan is used. The old folks at these Homes are the most difficult to deal with of any of the state dependents. They are childish, complaining and irritable and cannot be dis - ciplined as those at correctional institutions nor closely con - fined as those at hospitals. We believe the single room plan is much more satisfactory than the ward arrangement. At the Milford Home the repairs on the heating plant has overcome the difficulty of keeping all the buildings comfortable in severe winter weather. We believe that shower baths for institutions of this kind are preferable to the tub. It is necessary to have the most favorable conditions possible for preserving the clean - liness and sanitation of these Homes and their occupants. At the penitentiary the remodelling of the buildings neces - sary to the installation of the broom factory and changing the location of the laundry has improved the inside working facili - ties of this institution. The new boiler house has completed the fitting out of the power plant. The management is of the very best. Every inmate has employment and the products of the inside factories bring large returns. The farm supplies the institution with vegetables and there is a surplus of grain and stock to put on the market. The Boys' Industrial School, with a population of about 200 boys, never has had a hospital building until the comple - tion of the new structure being erected there now for that pur - pose. The general assembly room is on the third floor of the main building. It has a low ceiling and cannot be used for motion picture shows and entertainments of that kind. This institution never has been equipped with a gymnasium which is generally conceded to be a very essential feature in the edu - cation of boys. A band composed of about 30 boys is main - tained at the school under a competent instructor. They meet in the school room of one of the cottages each day for practice. We found the institution so crowded that there were 49 boys quartered in one building. For the best work with this claas </seg>
            <seg id="p009">BOARD OP CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 9 there should never be more than thirty in one cottage. We conclude that there is need at this institution for a gym - nasium which could also be used for an auditorium, a band room, and one part be fitted up for a library and reading room. There should be another cottage so the crowded con - dition of the present ones could be relieved. Most splendid conditions exist at the Girls' Industrial School. It is impossible to measure or estimate the life re - sults of this institution. The girls go out from here to become home makers and their training at the school fits them for their future responsibilities. The Industrial Home for Girls, under the efficient man - agement of capable workers, is contributing its part in en - nobling those who find their way to this institution. It reaches into the home life of its inmates and lends its splendid in - fluence to the bettering of family conditions. The general dining room at the Institution for Feeble Minded is in the basement under the main building and is so arranged that several attendants have to be on duty during the meal time. We are hoping that a large, light and well ventilated dining room will have a place in the new building which is being erected there at this time. The Orthopedic Hospital with its splendid equipment is doing good work in its particular line. The Home for Dependent Children was placed under the same management with the Orthopedic Hospital. The kitchen and laundry at the latter place serve for both institutions. Recently, however, a Superintendent has been placed in charge of the Home. The food prepared in the Orthopedic kitchen must be brought in a cart more than 200 yards through the open air to the Dependent Home dining room. We have rec - ommended that arrangements be made to build an addition to the Home and equip it with kitchen facilities sufficient for the use of this institution. The quarters used for the care of babes, who are old enough to play, we found to be inadequate and have recommended that a sun-room be built above the east porch to supply the needs of this part of the work. The children who are old enough to go to school have no place </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT at home to study except in the dormitories. The play room facilities are meager and we have recommended that an annex be built, part of which can be used for a library and study room and part for a play room. The Home has nearly 300 children placed out for adoption and the Superintendent is the only Field Agent. It is all one person should be obliged to do, to superintend the Home with its more than two score of children and its multiplicity of problems, without having the burden of the field work also. It is necessary that the homes where the children are placed be visited to determine their fitness and the character of the people who apply for a child — also to visit the child so placed to determine whether it is receiving the proper treatment. This field work requires the full services of at least one person. The Hospital for Tuberculous is now splendidly equipped to do effective and successful work. The new hospital build - ing has all modern conveniences. The institution is under competent management. The School for the Blind is doing an educational work that fits its students to be self-supporting in such vocations as piano tuning, broom making, basket and mat weaving ; fly net and hammock making, as well as the education in common school branches and music. The work at the School for Deaf is proving that the lip method of education for this afflicted class is more prac - tical than the old sign language plan. The institution is sup - plied with a competent corps of teachers and is doing a splendid work. Their class in printing operates a well equipped plant and does all or nearly all the printing for the Board of Control to supply the other institutions with letter - heads, report blanks and other printed matter. The buildings which are comparatively new are supplied with up-to-date modern conveniences. The old buildings are not so well equipped. In many of the institutional buildings we found inade - quate provision for fighting fire. It is not only necessary to have a sufficient supply of often tested fire hose easily ac- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 11 teraible, but there should also be chemical fire extinguishers placed in convenient positions in each building where they could be available at any moment. Fire escapes should also be provided on all buildings where inmates are obliged to con - gregate. We have tried to make reasonable and practical sugges - tions as the result of our observations at the various institu - tions with a desire to be helpful in making the work done at each place equal to any of like kind in the United States. The physical equipment of our institutions is only to be used to obtain the best life results from their work. We are anx - ious that we shall never overlook the desire for life betterment in all our institutional work. PRIVATE INSTITUTIONS There are 23 institutions in the state doing charitable work and supported wholly or in part by philanthropic con - tributions. Great good is being done by these Homes. The aged are given kind and tender care, surrounded with com - forts which help to make their declining years bright and happy and given considerate treatment which their feebleness requires. Orphan or dependent children are given protection from a cold and unsympathetic world, supported and educated through their developing years, provided a home until taken under the care of foster parents and through !oving interest brought to a realization of high ideals. The sick and af - flicted are taken in and nursed back to health or cared for through their continued helplessness. The workers in these institutions are warm-hearted, sym - pathetic and loving ministers of human kindness. The cheer - ing helpfulness resultant from their care and influence is be - yond measure. These institutions are kept in first class condition They are clean, sanitary, well equipped ani splendidly managed. Five of them care for old people exclusively, seven receive old people and children both, two do hospital work in connection </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT with the Home feature, nine care for children only and two are exclusively for unfortunate girls. "We should be pleased to include pictures of these Homes in this report, but our space will permit us to use but a few cuts. Bethphage Mission, Axtell The Bethphage Mission at Axtell is owned and operated by the Swedish Lutheran Church. It is designed to care for epileptics, insane, aged and incurables. There is a children's department and a day school is conducted for those of school age. The work is supported by voluntary contributions. A fee is charged for the care of patients who are able or whose friends are able to pay. The standard is as reasonable as the institution can afford. The management is vested in a Board of twelve Trustees, including the President of the Swedish Lutheran Association, the Deacon Superior and the Superin - tendent of the Mission. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION The Odd Fellows Home at York is supported by this fra - ternal order. They have a farm of 160 acres. The institu - tion is governed by a Board of nine Trustees, six of whom are men and three women. The place is a home for aged and in - digent Odd Fellows and their wives, Rebekahs, and orphan or dependent children of Odd Fellows or Rebekahs. Children who have one parent living may be released from the Home at the age of sixteen years, those who are completely orphaned may have this for their home so long as they have no other. The children attend the York public schools. The buildings are in splendid condition, well '-quipped and excellent work is being done. The Sunnyside Home at Hastings is under the auspices of the Hastings Woman 's Club. The building, a two-story stucco, is located on North Hastings Avenue, and is equipped with modern conveniences. The city donates light, water and heat. The business affairs of the institution are in charge of a Board of Managers selected from the Woman's Club. A matron eon - ducts the inside work of the Home. Any enfeebled or home - less person may be admitted and if they or their friends are able to pay for their care, Sunnyside receives $5.00 per week for their maintenance. What is needed for the expenses of the institution beyond the regular income from fees is secured from voluntary contributions. The single room plan for in - mates is used and it is highly satisfactory. It is the desire of the management to make the place a real home for those who are there. The place is in excellent condition. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT St. Joseph '8 Home for Aged, West Point St. Joseph's Home for Aged, located at West Point, is under the control and ownership of the Catholic Church. Per - sons are admitted to the Home without regard to their re - ligious affiliations. If the applicant for admission has no rela - tives who will take the responsibility of their care during their declining years they enter into a contract to relinquish all their funds to the Home, whether much or little, and the Home agrees to keep and support them for the rest of their life. Support is given to the institution by voluntary contribu - tions also. Children as well as old people are received and cared for at the Home. Everywhere about the place was found perfect order, cleanliness, modern conveniences and sani - tation. The plan is to have a separate room for each inmate that can be called their home. A very commendable work is being done at this home. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">BOARD OP CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 15 The Tabitha Home, located in Lincoln, is owned and oper - ated by the German Lutheran Church. Old people, cripples, and children are admitted upon application. A preference is given to those of Lutheran faith, but under some circum - stances others may be admitted. After an application has been favorably acted upon it is decided by the Board of Trustees how much the applicant shall pay for his care. If the person is unable to pay a reasonable amount the church from where the person comes assumes the financial obligation. Orphans or half orphans are admitted on a similar plan. Funds are solicited by a field agent for the support of the Home. The place is in excellent condition and the very best possible care is being given to those in charge of the institution. The Masonic Home at Plattsmouth is owned and operated by that fraternal order under the direction of a Board, in - cluding president, stockholders and trustees. Aged or in - digent Masons .their wives or Masons' widows are received into the Home. The place is splendidly fitted up with all modern conveniences for the comfort of those having a home there. Provision is made for attending the sick and feeble in whatever way they need. A Children's Home is conducted in connection with the institution. A cottage in the care of a matron is used for this department. Everything about the house was arranged with the idea of making it a real home for the children occupy - ing it. The place was neat and clean and we have nothing but words of praise for this Home. The Immanuel Deaconess Institute in Omaha is composed of the Nazareth Home for old people, an orphanage and a hos - pital. Several buildings are occupied by this institution which is owned by the Swedish Lutheran Church and in charge of the Emmanuel Deaconess Order. One building is occupied by the Sisters who have charge of the various departments of the institution. The building used for the old people was erected many years ago and is not so modernly equipped as the others. The </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT large number of helpless and mentally unbalanced old people in the Home makes the work very difficult. The hospital is well equipped and receives patients from Nebraska and other states. There are several doctors on the medical staff and one house doctor gives his whole time to the work. The orghanage was clean, well arranged and the children receive loving care. The institution is supported by volun - tary contributions, some fees from patients who are able to pay and by an apportionment contribution from the Swedish Lutheran Churches. A great and good work is being done at this institution. Old People's Home, Omaha Old People's Home, located at Fontenelle Boulevard and Bedford Avenue, Omaha, occupies an elegant new building fitted with all modern conveniences. Every room has outside windows. Anyone over 65 years of age may be admitted to </seg>
            <seg id="p017">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 17 the Home for the remainder of their lives by the payment of $500.00. It is a delightful place with every possible attention given to the comfort and happiness of those spending their closing years there. The House of Hope was established by Rev. Chas. W. Savidge for the purpose of providing a home for old people who are unable to care for themselves. The work outgrew the quarters at 1713 California Street, and now occupies an ele - gant brick structure on the Main Street of Florence. Spacious grounds surround the building and it is proposed to erect cottages for occupancy as the institution's work expands. It is managed by a Board of Trustees and supported wholly by voluntary contributions. The Crowell Home at Blair is owned, operated and supported by the Methodist Episcopal Church in Ne - braska. It receives old people who are Methodist ministers or affiliated with that church. The one beautiful building eon - tains 19 large rooms, two baths, three toilets, closets and fitted up basement. The Home is modern throughout and is doing an excellent work. A Home for Aged Negroes is located at 3029 Pinkney Street, Omaha. It is conducted by the Negro Woman's Chris - tian Association and is supported by contributions and leg - acies. At the present time they are receiving only women. The work is under the direction of a Board of Directors, with a Matron in charge. The equipment is only sufficient to ac - commodate six inmates. This Home supplies a long felt need among the Negro people and soon must have more room to care for those who will avail themselves of this haven of rest for their declining years. At Kearney there is a hospital called the Mother Hull W. C. T. r. Hospital, which does charitable work, gives a home to the destitute and cares for the friendless who are ill. Patients who are supported by the county are frequently kept there. The place is inspected by a representative of the Board of Health at intervals and is kept in very good condition. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT 18 The building has electric lights and city water, but is heated with stoves. A woman who acts as manager and head nurse is in charge. The work is supported by voluntary contributions. The Good Shepherd Home, at Fortieth and Jones Street, Omaha, is conducted and supported by the Catholic Church, (iirls are received without regard to nationality or church affiliations. School is conducted to the eighth grade and a special commercial course is given for those who desire to take that wort. The institution is practically self-supporting by operating the Good Shepherd Laundry and a boys' suit factory. Girls are trained and fitted here to make their own living in an honorable way. A great and far-reaching good work is being accomplished. The Home is under the supervision of Sisters cf the Good Shepherd. The Salvation Army Rescue Home, located at Twenty - fourth and Spaulding Street. Omaha, is under th«.' super - vision of the Salvation Army, with Major Anna Caldwell in charge. The building has capacity to accommodate 25 girls and is usually fully occupied. After the girls leave the Home the management assistes them to secure congenial employment and keeps in touch with them to guard them from future mis - steps. The work is supported by voluntary contributions. The Nebraska Children's Home Society, with headquarters at 514 Brown Block. Omaha, has been doing work in Ne - braska for twenty-eight years. The organization does not have a Home in which to keep dependent children, but places those who come into their care in homes where they may be adopted according to law. Rev. E. Pj Quivey is Superinten - dent. The work is supported wholly by voluntary contribu - tions. The Child Saving Institute, located at Forty-second and Jackson Street, Omaha, is a private institution governed by a Board of Directors, with a Matron and a head nurse in charge. Children from birth to thirteen years of age are received. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION Homeless, dependent children are given a home utnil they can be placed in families where there is a probability of adoption. In some cases when those who are interested in a child are financially able, a fee is charged for the child's care. Medical attnetion is provided by students from the University Medical College. The Home is supported by voluntary contributions. The St. James Orphanage, at Benson, is supported and conducted by the Catholic Church. Homeless, dependent chil - dren are received without regard to church affiliation. A school is conducted up to and including the eighth grade. "When children are entirely surrendered to the Home they are adopted out. A Superintendent is in charge, assisted by Sis - ters of Mercy. The institution is in excellent conditior. The Lutheran Orphanage at Fremont is owned and oper - ated by the Lutheran Church. It is managed by a Board of Directors with a Superintendent in charge. Support is derived from contributions from all sources. Any homeless child may be admitted upon application and a child may be re - ceived for a definite period of time, but while at the Home is under the complete jurisdiction of the institution. When a child is placed for adoption the Superintendent retains over - sight until the proper legal proceedings are completed. The Masonic Orphanage at Fremont is owned and oper - ated by this fraternal order. The plan is to have a number of cottages with a company of about twelve boys or girls in the charge of a matron occupying each house as a family. Two such cottages are now in operation. Orphans of Masons are received. The Masonic Board becomes guardian of the child and this is their home until of age or self-supporting. The children attend the public school and are taught practical industries at home. The St. Thomas Orphanage at Lincoln is owned and con - ducted by the Catholic Church, with Franciscan Sisters in charge. Children of any religious denomination may be ad - mitted, but a preference is given to Catholic children. The institution is well equipped and splendidly managed. A day school is conducted where the common branches </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT are taught as high as the eighth grade. Children living near the Orphanage may attend the school and are admitted as day pupils. The institution prefers to receive only children who are orphaned. Those who are completely surrendered to the Home are adopted out when suitable places are found for them. Mothers' Jewels Home at York is an orphanage under the jurisdiction of the Women 's Home Missionary Society of the Methodist Church, with a Superintendent in charge. It is sup- Krted by voluntary contributions secured by the Missionary ciety. The institution has several buildings and school is conducted for those of school age up to the high school. The children are also taught practical industries. A music teacher from York donates her services to those who desire to take advantage of that culture. The institution is well equipped and is doing a splendid work. The Swedish Lutheran Orphanage at Stromsburg receives destitute or orphan children irrespective of their nationality or religion. The orphan child remains under the jurisdiction of the Home until eighteen years of age — the destitute child may be taken back to its parents at any time they are able to support it. The building is modern and in good condition. The work is supported by the Swedish Lutheran Church and governed by a Board of Trustees with a Superintendent in charge. The Christian Orphans' Home, near Holdrege, admits homeless children between the ages of one and sixteen years, without regard to nationality or religion. School is conducted as high as the eighth grade. The Home is under a Board of nine Trustees, with a Superintendent in charge. Voluntary contributions received from all sources, together with the proceeds from the half section of land connected with the in - stitution, make up its support. Some of the buildings were in need of repairs and in some parts new equipment would make the work easier. A large number of children are receiv - ing the care of this Home. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 21 • COUNTY POOR FARMS In discussing these county institutions the first considera - tion is the inmates. They are defective or dependent. The defectives are feeble-minded, blind, deaf, or epileptic. The dependents are diseased, poverty-stricken, aged or crippled. They are erratic, opinionated, prejudiced and childish, and necessarily are not easy to manage, but require care. The next consideration is the kind of equipment needed to successfully accomplish the work expected of the county alms house. The inmates whose health will be affected by changes in the temperature of the building can be protected only by a heating system that will warm the whole house and keep the temperature regular. It is dangerous for trembly old people to handle oil lamps for light, therefore a lighting system for each alms house is essential. It is difficult under the most favorable conditions to induce inmates of these insti - tutions to bathe frequently, and the health of the occupants of the place very largely depends upon cleanliness. A water pressure system that will supply bathing facilities is very necessary in county homes. Many of the county charges are sick or diseased and some arrangements should be made for a hospital section in the house where proper nursing and care can be given. Sufficient and respectable clothing should be provided by the county for its dependent charges. Because a person is receiving charity support is no reason for his being clothed in rags or insuffi - cient apparel. Every home where indigent people are main - tained should have ample fire protection, in the way of fire escape and fire extinguishers. In Nebraska there are 46 County Poor Farms in opera - tion, Three other counties own farms, but do not maintain county charges there. The Douglas County Poor House i« operated as a hospital and is so called. Sioux County owns a block of ground at the county seat upon which is a house to be used for caring for poor people when necessary. Pawnee and Lincoln Counties support their dependents by contract with a </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 I TH BlfcjN^ I A I j rlfcjr^OrvT private liome. Douglas and Lancaster Counties have Deten - tion Homes for the temporary care of juveniles. The farms are operated under various plans. Twenty - four superintendents receive a stated salary and the- county furnishes everything needed for the farm and the care of those consigned there, all proceeds being turned into the county treasury. Six pay cash rent for the farms and receive pay from the county according to contract tor the ho ml &lt;mil care of the inmates. Three receive salary and furnish extra help when they need it, the county furnishing all supplies and equipment. Three rent for one-third of the grain and cash for the pasture and hay land, the inmates being boarded and cared for by contract. Two receive salary and furnish their own teams &lt;in&lt;l machinery. One gives one-half rent and is fur - nished half of stock and equipment, the inmates being boarded by contract. Another receives salary and furnishes horses and extra help. One pays two-fifths of the corn, one-third of the small grain and cash for pasture and hay land as rent, the county eharges being boarded by contract. Another pays two-fifths of the grain and cash for the pasture, with a con - tract for bearding the poor who are sent to him. One pays $."&gt;.(MI per month rent and has a contract to board the county charges who are consigned to the home. One receives $475.00 per year and the use of the farm for taking full charge of the inmates at the home. Another receives +1.'J( KhliO per year and the full use of the farm in payment for boarding and caring for the dependents sent to him. Another is given the use of the farm and is paid a stated amount for the board of each inmate. A few of the county homes have modern equipment. Only two, Douglas County and Lancaster County, have provision for hospital care of the sick. Three are heated by a plant sep - arate from the other buildings; 14 have furnace heat and 29 use stoves; 39 of the buildings are frame structures, six are brick and one stucco. Forty-one are more than one story and five are one-story houses. Nineteen have water pressure sys - tems and the same number have inside toilet arrangements. Twenty-five have bath equipment, nine are lighted with elec- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION trieity, and two with gas. Thirty-five use oil lamps: 27 have outside toilets and 21 have no bathing facilities. There are several of these Homes worthy of special men - tion because of their up-to-date equipment and excellent man - agement. We should be pleased to insert several pictures but ran only jrive two which are distinctive types: Cass County Poor House This Home is a two-story and basement brick structure containing 14 rooms, halls, pantry, clothes closets, two bath rooms and toilets. It is equipped with a heating plant sep - arate from the main building, electric light and air pressure water system. A frame cottage is used for the care of untidy inmates. The whole place is kept in excellent condi - tion. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Red Willow County Poor House This bmikting is a one-story frame house, containing 11 rooms, halls, pantry and clothes closets, with a full base - ment. The Home is equipped with furnace and electric light. There Ls a bath room, but the water pressure system has not been installed. The condition of the place deserves commenda - tion. We call especial attention to this house because it is all on the ground floor, more commodious than many two-story buildings, and well arranged for the care of those receiving county support. We favor the one-story house because it is a hardship upon feeble old people who are occupants of these homes to climb stairs. There is also constant danger of some one who has dim eyesight falling from the top of the stairway. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 25 We cannot mention at length each of the nine others which are fully equipped with modern conveniences, but cite them as follows by the name of the county: Douglas, Lan - caster, Saunders, Otoe, Nemaha, Coster, York, Hamilton and Colfax. Others that are splendidly managed lack some one of the modern conveniences, such as a lighting plant, a water pressure system or a heating plant. In order that all those who have by misfortune or other causes become dependent upon charitable support may have proper eare and comforts we favor the establishment of a State Home for Aged and Indigent People where those who otherwise would be county charges may be sent and cared for at county expense. Two counties, Douglas and Lancaster, have Detention Homes where juveniles who have been taken into charge by the Court are kept until some disposition is made of their cases. The Douglas County Home has 20 acres of land which is cultivated by the inmates. Besides the institutional work at these plates, the children are given some common school in - struction. Under a competent superintendent at each Home splendid work is being done. COUNTY JAILS In these days we have risen above the old idea of a prison being a place for punishment. The modern method of dealing with criminals has for its purpose reformation. A law violator is incarcerated to protect the man and society — while he is restrained from his freedom he is expected to learn his rightful attitude towards others and his surroundings and employment while in jail will have more to do with his reformation than anything else. To lock a man in a dark, dirty, ill-smelling, damp and vermin-infested jail will make him more vicious toward law and society, and to place a number of prisoners in close quar - ters with nothing to do but exchange stories of criminal ex - periences, gloat over perverted justice and brood ov -;r real or imaginary wrongs done them, will multiply their criminal pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 pensities. Men in jail, like other human beings, have natural impulses and enforced idleness represses the normal outlet of these impulses and results in some perverted expression of them. The congregate system enables young men to learn criminal practices and methods from oli^pr and more hard - ened law violators. \ ■. In order to meet the up-to-date requirements for modern jails, they should be constructed of fire-proof material, well lighted, even to the interior of the cells, with plenty of ven - tilating facilities, bath and toilet conveniences, furnace heat and electric lights. The doors and windows should be as secure as the cells. The room should be thoroughly cleaned from time to time, disinfectants used at frequent intervals, decent and sufficient bedding supplied, which should often be aired and fumigated. Arrangements should be provided for the separation of prisoners: juveniles from adults, first of - fenders from those experienced in crime, and those awaiting trial from those under sentence, and separate quarters for women. Other work should be provided besides the care of the jail room and cells. In the custody of the Sheriff or Deputy a number of prisoners could be profitbaly employed on some county work and by this means assist in the reforma - tion of the law violator. There are 90 county jails in the state. Three counties. Harlan. (iarfield and Frontier, do not have jails. During the bienniuni the following new jails have been built: Burt. Dodiie, Gage, Greeley, Knox, Sioux and Arthur. In Burt. Dodge and Greeley Counties the jails are on the top floor of the Court House. Gage County erected an excellent two-story and basement jail building with living rooms for the jailer and his family, a section for women prisoners, one for juveniles, as well as the main cell room. It is equipped with all modern conveniences, fire-proof and altogether an up-to-date jail. In Knox and Sioux Counties their new jails are a one-story cement block structure, strong and well arranged. Arthur County built a jail of 2x4 's laid flatwise, which suffices for the imme - diate needs in that new county. "We favor the plan of having the jail on the top floor of the Court House. There is </seg>
            <seg id="p027">BOARD OP CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 27 greater security from outside communication with prisoners and sanitation is easier. Of the 90 jails. 48 are separate buildings, 29 are in the basement, 3 are on the first floor, and 10 on the top floor of Court Houses. Of the separate buildings, 18 are one story, and 30 are more than one story hijrh. 23 are built of brick. 14 are frame, and 11 of cement stone. In equipment. 69 have electric lights. 20 use oil lamps, ami one is lighted with gas. Forty-six are heated with stoves and 44 from furnaces. Twenty-six have some kind of bathing facilities and 54 have none. Forty-six have the toilet in the corridor, 16 in each cell, and 28 use the bucket system. Only 18 have separate quarters fitted up for women, and but 6 have juvenile sections. We should be pleased to publish the pictures of the up-to - date jails, but cannot do so in this report. We present two herewith which are very good types: Seward County Jail This is a two-story building, made of red fire brick, fire - proof, modernly equipped with living rooms for the Sheriff </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT and his family, a cell room floor and one for women on equipped with cot. toilet and are provided on each floor. for men prisoners on the first the second floor. Each cell is lavatory, and bathing facilities The building has furnace heat and electric lights and is in splendid condition. Boyd County Jail This building is one story high, made of fire brick and equipped with modern conveniences — bath, lavatory, toilet and electric lights. It is fire-proof and heated with stoves. Wom - en's quarters are fitted up completely separate from the main cell room. This is a strong jail and worthy of commendation. CITY JAILS We inspected and reported on 35 city jails and lock-ups as follows : Albion, Alliance, Auburn, Aurora, Beatrice, Blair, </seg>
            <seg id="p029">BOARD OP CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 29 Falls City, Fremont, Fiillerton, Geneva, Genoa, Grand Island, Hastings, Kearney, Lincoln. Madison, Minden, Nebraska City, Norfolk, Omaha. O'Neill, Plattsmouth. Schuyler. Scotts Bluff, Seward, South Omaha. Stockville, St. Paul. Tecumseh, Te - kamah. Valentine. Wahoo, Wayne, West Point, and Wilber. These jails are located in various places — basement of the City Hall, back of the Fire Department room, on the first floor of the City Hall, at the Police Station, or in a separate build - ing. One jail was built of cement blocks, another of brick and another with sheet iron for siding and roof. The walls in many of them were covered with lead pencil drawings and obscene writings. Few of them are kept clean and sanitary. However, these lock-ups have seldom been used since the saloon evil has been abolished in the state. A short description of these places of detention will be of interest: 8 have stove heat, electric lights, lavatory and toilet. 12 have electric lights, steam heat, lavatory and toilet facili- ties. 8 have stove heat, electric lights and no lavatory or toilet equipment. 1 has stove heat, lavatory and toilet and oil lamps. 1 has steam heat, electric lights, but no lavatory or toilet. 1 has stove heat, electric lights, but no lavatory or toilet. 1 is heated from a pump engine, no lavatory or toilet, and with oil lamps 1 is supplied with a badly broken stove, a toilet out of work - ing order, with no lavatory, and with oil lamps. 2 Omaha jails are in large, well equipped buildings. These two and the Lincoln City Jail were the only places where any bathing facilities were provided. 7 have provision for separate quarters for women prisoners. 18 are equipped with two cells each. 2 are equipped with three cells each. 1 is equipped with four cells each. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT 2 are equipped with six cells each. 1 has two cells enclosed with 2x4 's two inches apart. 3 have two solid masonry cells each. 6 have one room with no cells 2 in Omaha have many cells. In consultation with Mayors, Chiefs of Police, and Super - intendents of Public Welfare, and by correspondence, we have called to the attention of the proper officials where necessary the unsanitary, insecure, dangerous or immoral condition of their city jails and have suggested needed repairs, renova - tions or changes. We know of some good results obtained. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 31 3C n Ml 192 99 76 367 7S6 616 1160 ■ir,&lt;x 325 54 144 4.i^ 596 553 1*9 4S 65 MM MOVEMENT OF THE POPULATION OF THE VARIOUS 8TATE INSTITUTIONS INSTITUTIONS B II L S.Z State Penitentiary 397 434 831 538 State Industrial School, Kearney Girls' Indus'rial School, Geneva Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford 202 288 490 115 86 201 74 209 283 391 583 974 298 102 207 Total for Industrial Schools Ml Neb. Hospital for Insane, Lincoln.. Hospital for Insane, Norfolk Nebraska State Hospital. Ingleside 731 464 1195 569 329 908 409 292 1150 490 1640 2450 1283 3743 480 Total in Hospitals for Insane 1181 Home for Dependent Children Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 331 186 517 124 671 795 192 741 Soldiers &amp; Sailors' Home, Milford .Soldiers &amp; Sailors' Home, Grand Island 139 78 217 463 147 610 602 225 827 ::! 158 231 Total in Soldiers &amp; Sailors' Homes Inst. for Feeble Minded Youth. Beatrice Nebr. School for Deaf, Omaha 527 136 663 184 64 248 50 56 106 52 278 330 110 79 Nebr. School for Blind, Nebr. City Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney M Mi Total for all Institutions 5108 3916 9034 4002 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT c •r D. I t ■a -s "2 £ - I " -i i I = s IS £ i8 n Si &gt; C 6 z t 3 II I* 1« i: o£ •• •= II 2 £2 E 5S2EEa* ££££££ £ £ SoooSfeoo oooooo o o Is i! i ' : i i is i i ! i i I i i ! « i I ! ! ! i ; &lt;&lt;&lt;!BBIS«BBHaBOOOOOOOOOCQa </seg>
            <seg id="p033">IARD OF CHARITI IES AND C CORRECTION f, I 1 •=£a la o o a o o a I | ill a a gg£g£ ! o 1 a = a a a £5asa| iiiiii I ■noisaaj pans : : : : : :S : :5 : : : :55 : : : e&gt; o :es ; : i § I« Hill 1 1 I I I I II MM i i i i i Mi I _______ l • noiaasa .uMnoM I j is I is ;§§ ;§.§ IS8. :§§§IS§§§§i i i is i iS Zf i§S iSS iSSSigSSSSg I I I I I I i i i iTis ! r {"-s r- {•" i^^-s- ;- I"-" : i i »■* i : : • | J8|l»j apirino •Jo; pi»d g i jSS 111 § [t ;S8 It IS.8 jS iSSS s j i§s isgi I 1 Hi is \ri is is|| i |i i j j i ;« j |- j | | V; j"? | j | | j jS M" J P»PIB 3S|J» -Jrfqlci ox joj pajso ok I '■ i S I : I : ; ! i ; ; : i i ! i ! : I I Ml : : : : : • ' : : : : ■ ; ■ : • I m i | | " mltifiiilliifaHHfllllif </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT I «i &lt;- E 5 u u ? u. u 6 °° I ■ 5 I »« . S i 1? ~s 5 II 1 5 a g g g gE'a a|s go* g a £ |£ g, gl I — ccc r ooo coo ooo o o a o c a o a o o « fcZfc 222 222 22fc 2 2fc2fc2 26. S8 y I suoi^aej PUIIU M - I g§§ ;§!§§§§ !t ;§§ It ooo : o ce o o o o :o : o o :o mote ; na&gt; io eaon :« :«coo ; o «■ n m :»imhn&lt;o :eo : &lt;e o :o 1 MHilSH-'.l .UrfqtoK « : .-I : . o :o ;oo ; ;oo ;o :oooo S :S iSS : :5p :O :OOOO ooce'oo i io'o !oj :o :oo i iooo IV iooioo jau»J dpjKjno &lt;h i o ioe : Irio i » I o n o o rn IX ! o US : : « » I &lt;» ■ P. * °. P. jo; p|Ba 3 ■« ; :i-«^r ■ • Vrtri v "■ it PSP1« 381.11 -J,iq4" o\ JOJ pdJBO 0\ « r H z I *a u:u:u:"jjjSSSSzzzzco.ii.ii.&amp;.cuBuf:a:aJaitn II "I SI 10 § i ISSS ri : : N rt « M : "S §§ IS IS is i a © © : t- : &lt;d 2S I- iS §§§!§ ; :§§ ootoce : : © co &lt;o &lt;e r* o o : : o o co ia 10 : : « p4 rtns : © : : : &lt;o : m : &lt;e : is ih : :M £ : i !- ! j iS i i !S !• !" I" !• jl" </seg>
            <seg id="p035">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 35 JO] paj«o o\ ■ 1 1 I £ - t S. Z. 0 0 0 0 0 000 0 K ZZ ZZZ ZZZ Z "~~i IS ; i ! IS 1 i§ ! i ! ! IS 5 I r i i I I 1 : : :::::« puna | ; i 111! ■ ; ;;■■■**• i ! I- i i I ;~ i !- i ! ! i iS j j i i i i M I I I I I :§§§ i ;g§ i : :§S§ :§§ j 5»* : :oe&gt; : : :euio s — £5 c i ■«• io : n« : t-isa i *i •^ \ r* e* rt ilON MM KJJI1IOK ■ ■ : : : : ■ ill i rs iooo i o o § ! :ioi«8oo o w o iooo ! o t-^ n o o o oi jauoj dDisino ■ o m oo . ua o o : ; © w w © © o •*• J/.I nni N»«O :«00iN : •*ffJ&lt;O©lO©CI I I s p^p,.,*^ i^s- |« |" I [•at-* [| J&lt;ll|)O uj; ; w 1*2 joj paj«o ox ; • ; ; ; ; ; ; ; | S ! i I j | i I I I { I I I I I j I | IP aw-Sa g 1 "*- «»«• •&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p036">• 10 committed elsewhere. The following shows the report rei of the state relative to the number o the biennium ending November 30. 19 ceived from the various counties t prisoner* in their jails during 18: COUNTY I I I a II L m Idams 120 Intelope 16 Irthur 5 tanner 16 JUine Joone 16 3ox Butte 104 »oyd 0 Jrown iuffalo 86 Jurt 37 Jutler 0 '*" 50 'edar 'hase 1 'herry 34 'heyenne 145 Jlay 'olfax burning 40 duster )akou 42 hwei 99 )awson 83 &gt;euel 5 Wxon 1» Xxige 233 Jouglaa 4401 )nndy 4 •'illmore 17 ■'ranklin 3 ■"rontler 21 Jage iarden 4 Jarfield Joaper 0 Jrmnt 2 Jreeley 22 Ull 118 iamilton 24 Harlan 10 iayea 0 -litchcock 8 lolt 12 looker 1 16 t 145 0 7 22 10 6 0 t 18 No re port 0 0 16 7 10 121 0 1 No re port 1 t 96 0 17 54 0 0 0 4 6 60 No re port 0 0 I I 3 2 39 4 32 152 No re port No re port 2 S 45 No re port 3 4 49 8 15 122 11 i 22 115 0 I 0 G 0 ! 2 21 20 6 259 (31 189 5229 0 15 0 1 18 0 14 No jail 0 0 i 21 No re port 0 2 6 No jail 0 0 | 0 0 0 2 8 7 ! 31 13 8 139 0 • j 24 No jail 10 0 0 0 0 0 8 8 6 26 0 0 1 5 2 2 1 4 12 1 1 " 9 6 1 5 0 2 1 1 3 1 8 1 ; 4 7 2 1 14 155 2 0 o 2 3 4 1 0 1 1 25 &lt; 1 0 0 1 o 5 4 0 0 0 4 0 0 1 0 2 0 1 2 0 0 1 0 0 2 12 98 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 10 0 0 0 s 0 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">BOARD OP CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 37 *■■ ** 1* - _ is ft 3 - . s s I -I *ii z~. COUNTY • 8 «S as -^ Howard 13 | 2 1 i 17 3 a Jefferson 10 I 0 4 14 2 0 Johnson No re port 3 Kearney 11 1 ! 0 I 12 3 0 Keith 14 I 0 7 21 4 0 Keya Paha 6 0 0 16 1 0 Kimball I 73 2 I 77 3 2 Knox I 20 0 4 24 3 0 Lancaster 1075 99 188 1362 21 17 Lincoln 404 19 11 425 7 9 Logan No re port 1 Loup No re port Madison 12 I 1 8 21 1 4 McPherson 4 0 0 4 0 0 Merrick I 27 I 0 4 31 0 0 Morrill 16 2 0 8 3 1 Nance , 20 1 2 23 0 0 Nemaha No re port 1 Nuckolls i 45 1 4 60 1 1 Otoe 110 21 0 131 8 3 Pawnee 13 0 1 14 2 0 Perkins 4 0 0 4 1 0 Phelps 8 0 0 8 2 0 Pierce I 15 0 0 15 4 0 Platte I 12 0 0 12 3 0 Polk 7 0 0 7 0 1 Red Willow No re port 3 Richardson ....: 17« 12 10 1»8 11 2 Red Willow Rock 8 0 4 12 0 0 Sarpy | 24 0 2 26 1 0 Saline 10 0 0 10 2 0 Saunders 53 2 8 63 6 0 Scotts Bluff 30 4 8 42 10 0 Seward 22 2 0 24 2 0 Sheridan 109 6 5 120 8 6 Sherman Jail not used 1 0 Sioux 40 3 1 44 2 2 Stanton 6 0 0 6 1 • Thayer J 0 0 0 0 0 0 Thomas 0 0 0 0 2 0 Thurston No re port 2 Valley 7 0 2 10 1 0 Washington No re port 2 Wayne 9 1 J 12 1 1 Webster 39 1 1 41 I 0 0 Wheeler No re port York 28 0 i 6 32 4 0 Total 8277 913 649 9798 433 193 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT MOVEMENT OF POPULATION OF THE VARIOUS PRIVATE INSTTITUTIONS OF THE STATE BETHPHAGE MISSION Axtell, Nebraska Rev. C. A. Lonquist, Superintendent No. I :ng cared for Dec. 1, 1916 66 Since received 62 Since discharged 41 No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 76 CHILD SAVING INSTITUTE Forty-second and Jackson Streets, Omaha, Nebraska Hiss M. Troth, Matron No. of children at the institute Dec. 1, 1916 55 Since received S2t Total No. given care and protection for biennium M4 No. placed in homes under adoption during biennium HI No. of deaths during biennium IS No. that otherwise passed from our care 204 No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1J18 U </seg>
            <seg id="p039">BOARD OP CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 39 CHRISTIAN ORPHANS' HOME Holdrege. Nebraska H. A. Gustin. Superintendent No. of persons in the institution Dec. 1, 1916 66 No. since received 30 Total number given care and protection during biennium M No. placed in homes under contract ( No. of deaths : 0 No. that otherwise passed from their care _ tl No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 58 CROWELL HOME Blair, Nebraska Rev. Wm. Esplin, Superintendent No. of persons being cared for Dec. 1, 1916 .'... 15 No. since received 18 No. passed from our care - t No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 M HOME OF THE GOOD SHEPHERD Fortieth and Jones Streets, Omaha, Nebraska Sister M. Raphael, Superintendent Reformatory Department No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1916 1W Since received 1M Since discharged '. 137 Died 1 No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 181 Preservation Department No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1916 tt Since received H Since discharged 71 No. died 1 No. being eared for Dec. 1, 1918 4* HOME FOR AGED NEGROES 3029 Pinkney Street, Omaha, Nebraska Mrs. Annie Bowler, President No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1916 4 No. since received _ • No. died _ 1 No. at Home Dec. 1, 1918 - 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT 40 HOUSE OF HOPE Florence, Nebraska Miss Schempp, Superintendent No. of persons Dec. 1. 1*16 22 No. since received .' 60 No. since discharged 32 No. died 8 No. being cared for Dec. 1. 1918 _ 34 IMMANUEL DEACONESS INSTITUTE Thirty-fourth and Meredith Streets, Omaha, Nebraska F. A. Linder, Superintendent No. of persons in our charge Dec. 1, 1916 — Children .._ 23 Hospital patients 61 Old people 38 No. since received — Children 10 Hospital patients 60 Old people _ 14 No. in our charge Dec. 1, 1918 — Children 31 Hospital patients 46 Old people 40 LUTHERAN ORPHANAGE Fremont, Nebraska J. F. Gnuse, Superintendent No. of persons in the institution Dec. 1, 1916 14 No. since received 66 Total No. given care and protection during biennium 86 No. placed in homes for adoption 30 No. placed In homes under contract 36 No. of deaths 2 No. that otherwise passed from their care 12 No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 8 MOTHERS' JEWELS HOME York, Nebraska Rev. W. F. Dudman, Superintendent No. of children in the Home Dec. 1, 1916 74 No. since received 51 No. gone from the Home 40 No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1918 86 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 41 MOTHER HULL W. C. T. U. HOSPITAL Kearney, Nebraska Mrs. Anna Gallington, Manager No report. NEBRASKA CHILDREN'S HOME SOCIETY 514 Brown Block, Omaha, Nebraska No. of persons in charge Dec. 1, 1916 4 No. since received M Total No. given care during the biennium IN No. placed in homes for adoption 135 NEBRASKA MASONIC HOME Platsmouth, Nebraska W. S. Askwith, Superintendent No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1916 44 No. since received 34 No. died 13 No. who left for any cause 16 No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 44 NEBRASKA MASONIC AND EASTERN STAR HOMES FOR CHILDREN Fremont and Plattsmouth, Nebraska No. of children in the Homes Dec. 1, 1916 SO No. since received v 16 Total No. given care and protection during the biennium 49 No. that otherwise passed from their care IS No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 36 ODD FELLOWS' HOME York, Nebraska J. W. Pittman, Superintendent No. at Home Dec. 1, 1916 78 No. since received H No. died 4 No. who left for any cause S3 No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 (8 OLD PEOPLES HOME 3325 Fontenelle Blvd., Omaha Mrs. Anna R. Butter, Superintendent No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1916 - U No. since received _ It No. died _ U No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1918 40 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT SALVATION ARMY RESCUE HOME 3824 North Twenty-fourth Street, Omaha, Nebraska Lillie E. Ness, Matron No. of persons cared for Dec. 1, 1916 26 No. since received 170 No. passed from their care 171 No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1818 „ 23 ST. JAMES ORPHANAGE Benson, Nebraska John Roche, Superintendent No. of persons in institution Dec. 1, 1916 140 No. since received 374 Total No. given care and protection during biennium S14 No. placed in homes under adoption during biennium I No. placed in homes under contract during biennium IS No. that otherwise passed from care of the orphanage 328 No. being cared for at the present time, Dec. 1, 1918 170 ST. JOSEPH'S HOME FOR AGED In charge of Sisters of St. Francis, West Point, Nebraska Monsignor J. Ruesing, Superintendent No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1916 60 No. since received 60 No. died .• If No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1918 14 ST. THOMAS ORPHANAGE Lincoln, Nebraska Franciscan Sisters in charge No. of persons in the institution Dec. 1, 1916 90 Since received 71 Total No. given care and protection during biennium 160 No. placed in homes for adoption 4 No. of deaths 1 No. that otherwise passed from their care 67 No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 104 SUNNYSIDE HOME Hastings, Nebraska Elizabeth Y. Henry, Matron No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1917 - 16 No. since received 6 No. died I No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1918 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 43 SWEDISH LUTHERAN ORPHANAGE Stromsburg, Nebraska P. V. Ek, Superintendent No. of persons in the institution Dec. 1, 1916 14 Placed in homes for adoption „ 1 No. being cared for Dec. 1, 1918 IS TABITHA HOME Forty-sixth and Randolph, Lincoln, Nebraska Rev. Ernest Walter, Superintendent No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1916 73 No. since received 30 No. discharged M No. died IS No. at the Home Dec. 1, 1918 70 FINANCIAL STATEMENT From an unexpended balance of appropriation for 1915-1916 Salary of Chief Clerk * 500.00 Salary of Stenographer 880.9* Office expense 289.40 Traveling expense 277.65 From appropriation for 1917-1918 Salary of Chief Clerk J2.600.00 Salary of Assistant Clerk and Stenographer 1.6M.M Office expense 477.81 Traveling expense , 591 JO Total $6,582.62 Balance of appropriation for 1917-1918 unexpended Salary of Chief Clerk $ 500.00 Salary of Assistant Clerk and Stenographer '. 333.34 Office expense 122.19 Traveling expense - 408.80 Total 11,364.33 Respectfully submitted, E. M. JOHNSON, Chief Clerk. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT 44 STATE PRISON BOARD and ADVISORY BOARD OF PARDONS Dr. F. A. Sedlaeek _ Omaha Dr. J. M. Talcott Croftou E. G. Maggi Lincoln E. M. Johnson Secretary Matilda Heagney Stenographer To His Excellency, Keith Neville, Governor of Nebraska Honorable Sir: We take pleasure in presenting to you the report of work done by the State Prison Board and Advisory Board of Par - dons for the biennium ending November 30, 1918. In accordance with the indeterminate sentence law, those committed to the penitentiary for crimes other than murder, treason, rape and kidnapping, receive a sentence designating a minimum and maximum. After serving the minimum the prisoner is subject to parole, at the discretion of the Prison Board. The previous career of each applicant is carefully investigated and becomes a part of the records in the case. The circumstances surrounding the commission of ihe crime receive due consideration. When all the facts obtainable concerning a prisoner are on file, it is decided when it is best to place him on parole. It has been the policy of the Board to hold a man under its jurisdiction, on parole, a sufficient length of time for him to prove his intention to conduct himself in right relations with society. The law states that the period of parole shall not be less than six months, but the Board has ruled that eight months is a short enough time and in some cases it is </seg>
            <seg id="p045">BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 45 considered best to hold them much longer than this. During the biennium a discharge has not been recommended except for those who have complied with their parole agreement for the time specified. The Advisory Board of Pardons has been very careful in dealing with applications for pardon, commutation of sentence or furlough. No one has been recommended for executive clemency except those who, by their prison record and evident trustworthiness, merited favorable consideration. In some cases, upon investigation, extenuating circumstances were discovered which influenced the Board to recommend execu - tive aetoin. In others it was found that a family was de - pendent upon the convicted man for their support and by hav - ing supervision over him it was deemed wise to permit him to go out to work. Suh cases were recommended to the Gov - ernor for conditional furlough. All meetings of the Board are held at the penitentiary and each applicant is given an opportunity to personally pre - sent reasons for his release. These meetings are held two days each month, usually the first Thursday and Friday. During the biennium 35 hearings for commutation df sentence or pardon came before the Board. Of these 17 were favorably recommended for commutation of sentence. No one was recommended for pardon. Nine were given unfavorable recommendations and were denied, and 9 are in th'e hands of the Board at th'e close of the biennium. Fourteen furlough* were recommended and were granted by the Governor on con - dition that each one make regular monthly reports to the Prison Board and be under their supervision. Every possible encouragement has been given to the men on parole. Employment has been secured for them and if there was found to be dissatisfaction on the part of the man or his employer a new place was found so that the man could have opportunity to "make good". However, in case of a violation of the parole agreement by misconduct the parole has been cancelled and the man returned to the prison. The </seg>
            <seg id="p046">NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT 46 records show that 91% of the paroled men conducted them - selves creditably. This estimate does not count those who were marked "delinquent" on our list because of failure to make their monthly reports, or for having left their places of employment without permission. Counting this number as failures we still have 77% that made an exemplary record. The Secretary of the Board, who is also State Parole Officer, frequently makes trips to different parts of the state, where our paroled men are employed, to discover the condi - tions under which they are working and in some instances to investigate reports of alleged misconduct on the part of the paroled men. We find that a great deal of encouragement can be given the men by frequent correspondence with them while on parole and for this reason a friendly letter is sent each month on receipt of their monthly reports. If any misunderstanding should come up between the man and his employer he is urged to communicate the matter to us. Many of our men are holding positions of honor and trust and their letters of appreciation for the privilege of having their liberty are gratifying to the. Board, making us feel that we have a field for doing a vast amount of good for our more unfortunate fellow men. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">BOARD OP CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 47 The following statistics are taken from the records for the teennium: On parole November 30, 1916 153 Paroled from December 1, 1916, to November 30, 1918 443 596 Returned to penitentiary for parole violation 11 Committed to other penitentiaries 2 Died S Deported 2 Dropped from list 1 Escaped 46 Delinquent 86 Discharged 343 On parole November 30, 1918 107 596 I FINANCIAL STATEMENT From an unexpended balance of appropriation for 1915-1916 Salary of three members of the Board $1,500.00 Incidental expenses of members of Board •. 128.31 From appropriation for 1917-1918 Salary of three members of the Baord 14,500.00 Incidental expenses of members of Board 331.88 Total H.460.19 Balance of appropriation for 1917-1918 unexpended Salary of three members of Board $1,500.00 Incidental expenses of members of Board 268.12 Total $1,768.12 Respectfully submitted, E. M. JOHNSON, Secretary. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>