<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>SEVENTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Superintendent and Board of Trustees OF THE Nebraska School for the Deaf FOR THE YEARS 1909 AND 1910 TO THE GOVERNOR HON. ASHTON C. SHALLENBERGER.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE Superintendent and Board of Trustees OF THE Nebraska School for the Deaf FOR THE YEARS 1909 AND 1910 TO THE GOVERNOR Hon. Ashton C. Shallenberger. THE CLAFLIN P8INTINC CO. UNIVERSITY PLACE, NEM. </seg>
           
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Xebi School for the 1 &lt; Honorable Ash ton '. Shallenl tmpliance ( Dear Sir: — In piled Statutes, tin the Deaf has tin I of i'rustees of the Nebraska School for transmit herewith the seven! ution, embracing the progrea it biennial repot his insti irmjr t Very CHARLES R. SHERMAN I). O. DWYER, If. II. HANKS. (ii.uha. Nebr., Dec. 1. 1MM. •reer with section 12, chap. 22. tin- Cum- work accomplish* period ending December 1. 1910 ipectfully, </seg>
            <seg id="p003">: Aslituii C. Shallenl Governor BOARD OF TRUSTEES ■\. Sherman. President Hank- Omaha, Nebraska Nebraska City, Nebraska 1 &gt;. O. Dwyer Plattsmouth, Nebraska OFFICERS Saperintendant and Steward Matron and Hooaekeeper </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Head Teacher, Academic Department J. \V. Sowell Head Teacher, Intermediate and Primary Department Alberta Regnier Librarian Maud Roath Literary Society W. II. Rothert Boys' Christian Endeavor Society J. H. McFarlane Girls' Christian Endeavor Society Maud Roath ACADEMIC DEPARTMENT R. E. Stewart, A.M., Principal. Tenth Grade. Ninth Grade... Eighth Grade Eighth Grade Seventh Grad INTERMEDIATE AND PRIMARY DEPARTMENT R Grade, Oral Grade, Oral h Grade, Oral Fourth Grade, Manual Third Grade Miss Emma Anderson Miss Ethyl Rogers Alberta Regnier Mrs. Ida Hendee Mrs. Ota Blankenship Miss Mary Woodson Fourth Year Third Year... Second Year Lillian Bamford Miss Mary Goddard Beginners, Oral Miss Helen Waite Miss Maud Roath Beginners, Manual J. W. Bowell, M. A. (has. II. Eldridge W. II. Rothern, B. A. Mrs. lfaj Gregory J. H. McFarlane, B. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">294 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT DEPARTMENT INDUSTRIAL J. F. Rogers J. II. Parry Lloyd Blankenship Mrs. Edith Johnson .Miss Anna Byrne Miss Rachel Hemvig Laundering Farming Win. H. Chapman Domestic Science Gardner DOMESTIC SCIENCE Matron and Housekeeper Clerk Miss Xora O. Johnson Miss Jennie E. Jones Miss Sue 8. Frazer Girls" Supervisor r Supervisor, Assist. nit Supervisor Mis.s Clara Jensen Mrs. Ann Richards Miss Jennie Hambel Boys' Supervisor (small Boys' Assistant W. E. Sabin Boys' Assistant I small William Clai. Physician Nun. Millard Langfeld, M. D. Mrs. Jane Whitacre I." |iiri|i.ij&gt;f I t I I _ I I 1 • ( I Frederick Head W. L. Hackett rstant Engineer man Night-watefa Janitor John Stodola Miss Amanda Kline Miss Albcrtina Ericksoii 'id ( imik Laundrei Miss Helen Kinder Miss Maude Calvin Dining Room Girl Dining Room Girl House Girl Miss Margaret Stillahn Miss Nettie Boon &lt; larpentry. Printing Shoemaking Drawing ing P. F. Seely Samuel Goveia J. A. Jensen .Miss Jennie Hoelstad .Miss Maggie Mekkelsen Girl </seg>
            <seg id="p006">NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF 295 TRUSTEES' REPORT Nebraska School for the Deal, Omaha, Nebr., December 1, 1910. fJHs Excellency, Governor Aahtoo ('. Shallenberger : The Hoard of Tru.st.es of the Nebraska School for the Deaf has the honor to rabmit the following report I The following table shows status of appropriations made the Legilsatare for the biennium, 1909 and 1910. Approp. Expend. Bal. Salary of superintendent .tii »i 00 MOO 00 I 600 00 Salary of matron Salaries of teaehera, etc 1,600 00 1,000 00 1,333 34 2:U2:i 31 266 66 6 69 Employes' wages ll.ooo 00 9,946 30 1,063 70 Repairs and improvements Gallaudet students 1,800 00 300 00 3,329 in 242 50 470 72 57 50 Maintenance 33,275 00 26,578 To 6,696 30 axi *j jl. x x v iivn vnwu. Balance on hand from last report • Cash received since from sale of farm products: tuition of non-resident pupils, receipts from industrial shops, etc 2.4 Total * 2,739 :&gt;7 Amount expended 1,470 ~&gt;2 Total * 1.2' Deposited with State Treasurer +1.127 •"&gt;:; Cash on hand 141 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">ESTIMATED EXPENDITURES FOR BIENNIUM FROM APRIL 1, 1911, to APRIL 1, 1913. rof Superintendent and Steward of Matron and Housekeeper Salary of Teachers. Physician. Nurse. Supervisors Esenographer, and all Employes airs and improvement 44.000 00 3,800 00 Gallaudet Students .Maintenance ... 300 00 .•;."&gt;.( loo oo SPECIAL APPROPRIATIONS $ 3.000 00 . ."")( i.DOO 00 New Boys' Cottage Foundation to School Building 4.OH0 00 Equipment for Gymnasium and Chapel More Grounds 5.000 00 $ 4,000 00 1,600 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT To the Honorable Board of Trustees Gentlemen: — I have the honor to submit to you the Kven- teenth biennial report of the Nebraska School for the h covering the peri 1910. r 1st. 1908, to December 1st, the founding number have dred seventy »1 mpils are now in attendance — 04 hoys and 34 girl Th Ilties of th state have sent pupils to this school as foil Adams ws Buffal Burt Butler •&gt; Douglas Box Butt Dundv Boyd .j Brown Cedar Cherry 1 Fillmore Franklin Polli 16 13 1 Red Willow Richardson Rock • s 11 Cheyenne Clay Saline 10 12 Sarpy Furnas 9 11 1 from Deeeml K During the l)ienniuni we have enrolled 22n pupils. Forty- ree new pupils have been admitted since the last report. Tw inpils have been awarded diplomas of graduation. Eight hundred and twelve pupils have been enrolled since institution, 1869, and eighty-eight of this warded diplomas of graduation. One bun- 14 Coster 4 Dakota 1 Dnv 17 D;iv 13 Deuel . 12 Dixon 13 Dodge fntelope anner . Boone sst </seg>
            <seg id="p009">298 (i*ge Muekoln Oto e t temper reelc ;. Hall Pawnee Perkins Phelpa Pierce &lt;&lt; Hamilton Il.trlan &gt; s lla vex I'latte in Mitch.- .k Holt Sherman Stanton Th u niton Thaver •&gt; Howard Jefferson thnsoo arsey iox I Villcv Washington Sanndera LancastiT Lincoln Sewartl n Sheridan Frontier Wayne -Madis; 11 Mcrrick McPhPKoi N'ancc 1 N'etnaha Tut a I From I Grand 81] howii in the following tabli Apoplexy 12 14 Fall (in infancy 'i Errahal fever era infantum 1 Fever( kind unknown Kits 17 4 I 13 Head hurt (in cyclone Inflammation of drain Inflammation of ear Intermittent fever Btrenit :1 nips 207 •&gt; 1 Congestion of Inngx ■&gt; 1 2 WVI.st. i 4 York The nausea of ileafnetw, as rvportmi by parents, ar 1 Diphtheria " Dropsy of 1 rain - Diabetes Brain fever Bronchitis &lt; 'atarrta </seg>
            <seg id="p010">NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF 299 The general health of our pupils has been good, excepting among our older hoys. There was considerable sickness among those rooming in the older boy a' cottage, and this we attribute to an unsanitary condition of the building. In October, 1!MMI. We had (Hie ease of scarlet t'ever. .Numerous cases of lesser ail - ments kept our hospital much in use. Not a death occurred. E 1 has any serious accident occurred or pupil maimed or crippled this institution in ten years. Our medicine and drag bill the hienniuin has been very light. DENTISTRY I No special provision lias been made for dental work for children. We believe tilling of teeth and special treatment should l&gt;e provided by parents daring the summer vacation. Hut often children have tooth ache which annoys and retards progreM in school and must be attended to. Once a year we engage a den - tist, who visits our school, examines all children, extracts teeth that should be pulled, and recommends fillings and such other dentistry as he finds needful. 1!) Scrofula Lung fever • &gt; Sjiasins Membranous eroap 1 Spinal mengingil i H .Malaria - Spotted fever 1 -Measles •'{2 Sunstroke 1 K limps iralysis 2 Typhoid fever :i Tubercular affection 17 1 Pneumonia 2 Whooping eough 2:! Quinsy 1 Yellow fever 1 Scarlet fever 67 I'nknown 144 Total 7! Ml Hotea a Grand total HEALTH. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">300 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT EDUCATIONAL DEPARTMENT The literary department pursues the •■Combined System." W. have oral and manual divisions. Every child on entering ■1 is given an opportunity in the oral department to learn h and lip-reading. "Signs" are not taught in the school imr wed in the school room except to a limited degree in ad - vanced classes where considerable language has been acquired. We Ihv stress on teaching the English language and its use. We have n for teaching language which is strictly "Ne - braakan." The foundation for this work was borrowed from the Iowa School, and is a combination of the "Toy Object Lea - and the "Sequence Work." This was introduced in the Nebraska school in 1001 by the present superintendent. The work has been modified and enlarged so that now we have a complete series of language lessons for daily recitations cover - ing the first eight years of school life. The results of this rn have been very satisfactory in teaching language in this &gt;1 and we have contemplated putting the work into print for the benefit of other schools that might wish to use it. We might name it the "Inductive Method:" leading from that which is known — that which the child sees— to that which is unknown and abstract. Our entire graduating class of 1010 are accepted pupils at Gallaudet College, the National College for the Deaf. Washing ton, D. C. and the only university in the world where the deaf are given a college education. Nebraska has nine representa - - at college this year. This fact we mention as evidence of the excellent standard of our educational department. Ehe oral department needs encouragement. I would n adding more teachers in order to lessen the number of en in oral cla- GALLAUDET STUDENTS' FUND We recommend the small appropriation of $300.00 to defray transportation expenses of graduates from our state school to college. It encourages pupils with good minds to fit themselves for college, knowing that the mere matter of expense need not deter them. It is distinctly understood that this fund does not in ai apply to pupils whose parents can afford to </seg>
            <seg id="p012">301 LIBRARY Our library needs repleniahing with hooks suited to th« appreciation and understanding of youth. For this pur| recommend an appropriation of $2(10.00. INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENT Pupils old enough to be admitted to tin- industrial shops are instructed in carpentry, printing, thoemaking, farming, painting, baking, free-hand drawing, laundering, dressmaking and fancy needlework. To this should be added a cooking school for the girls. This has been recommended for many years, but our salary appropriation never included the pay for a teacher of thif partment. We would also recommend a teacher of slovd so that boys may receive a training in wood work and use of tools before they are old enough to enter the carpenter shop. In all our industrial lines we believe in the practical. Aa far as possible the skill of the pupil and foreman is directed in making something useful in the economy of the institution; to mend damaged furniture, to repair the building, or if time per - mits, make new furniture or construct a building. We oppose the policy of wasting time and material in copy ing a trirlin^r model or making some jimmy-jack for "John] carry home as amusement. We consider the product of the time and skill of the pupil belongs to the State in return for the training given. During the past two years the carpenter boys with the help of the foreman made several pieces of new furni - ture, did a great deal of repairing and are building a new green liiiiise. The shot-shop does all the mending for our pupils. The painter boys an- decorating the school house inside. Tln-y keep the windows glazed and expect to do all the painting on our new building. I Thus it is with each department ; while the pupil learns, is a help to the institution. It teaches industry and respect labor. LThis department needs encouragement and a liberal appro ion for teachers and equipment. ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT Two years ago we ekanged heads in this department. Th plant was almost a wreck. Every piece of machinery had </seg>
            <seg id="p013">302 overhauled. The wieBee of mechanical engineering had evident - ly not been understood. Mr. Head, our present engineer, being a practical boiler-Baker and steam-fitter as well as engineer went about to remedy the faults. The first year. 190!). we burned 400 tons of coal less than was used the year before and 1910 bids fair to reduce the amount 100 tons more, yet we have better light and heat than in former years. This department needs $1. odd. 00 for further improvements in the next two years. WATER SUPPLY Our large 6-inch well ga\&gt; out a year ago. In the emergency • igged up an old 2' L . inch well that had stood idle for nearly twenty years. This gave temporary relief. A new 4 inch casing was inserted in the old ti inch well and connected with new strain - er and working barrel. So that now we have two wells to draw from, but these are barely sufficient to supply our every day needs. We must therefore, have a better supply of water. Either the city water will have to be brought out to our grounds or we will have to put down a larger and deeper well. SALARIES ■ quote from my printed report of this Institution for thf 1 !»()."&gt; and 1906: Phas been customary with us for yean to employ teachers a gradually increasing scale of wages. Experience counts ich in teaching and caring for the deaf. Kven the most iful teachers in public school work are helpless among the It requires several years mingling with the deaf and work - ing with them to make of them real successful teachers. There - fore, it does not pay the State to train new teachers annually. Teachers of ability and experience are Knight by Institutions of this kind all over the continent. MANNERS AND MORALS The school discipline is good. Pupils are taught to respect authority and are encouraged by wholesome advice from teachers and officers alike in right ways of living and nobility of character. Generally our pupils respond willingly so that by kindness and firmness there i» seldom need for punishment. We insist </seg>
            <seg id="p014">NEBRASKA SCHOOL, FOR THE DEAF that pupils remain in the institution continuously through the school term as home-goers disturb the disciDline and order of tme-goers disturb the discipline and ord&lt; I schoolroom \v nd endanger the whole institution to con tagious dist tThe statements in the above paragraphs applied to conditions this school when I reported the facts in 1906 and they apply now. hut conditions were woefully below the standard wk resumed the superintendence- in 1 !)()!&gt;. Work lias progressed slowly on our new building for which K 0,000.00 was appropriated by the Legislature of 1909, hut it is arin&lt;r completion. The plastering is being put on at this time. The Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings, Governor Shallen - berger, and all who had a part in designing and constructing this addition to our buildings, deserve much praise and credit from the people of this State and especially the deaf people for this handsome, substantial and useful building. Some further help will he asked of the coming legislature We ask for an appropriation of $5,000.00 for seating the auditorium, installing Btage furnishings, fitting up the gym- LOCATION OF BUILDINGS This new building was faced to the west which is the prin ipal street. The older buildings face east. For future guidance ] would surest that a plat of our grounds and buildings he made showing where new buildi differei -Mould he &gt;mplete the work of this building lUAini&amp;nAnuii. Our maintenance fund will be short this biemunn t\\ three thousand dollars. This is due in part to the total failure Kthe fruit crop this year, shortage of potatoes and garden st utT. aeeount of drouth, and an inereaae in cost of milk, meat and t«l products generally. The le&lt;rislaiure of 1909 appropriated two thousand i ndred and twenty-five dollars less than the Board of Trust risked for two years ago. This amount would probably cover nil our deficiency. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">304 placed, following a definite plan. and symmetry to the group win erected. To pal up buildings a1 will keep the grounds in ;i disorder This would insure uniformity i ;ill necessary buildings are haphazard as has been done, d manner perpetually. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS ■ an institution of this kii mand for repairs. id t!i list nut deteioration During the past two yean and dormers of the mi 1909 ■ workman, while repairii injr. set tire to the cornice w narrow escape from burning we have painted the decks of all in buildings. In the summer of [ a down-spout on the main build h a blow torch, causing a very own the entire plant. Hut our force of workmen overcame the tire and with the aimintam f the Omaha Fire Department extinguished the flames. Damage was done to the roof, rafters and joists above a portion of this building. Below this are the living rooms and dormitories of the older girls. These quarters were water soaked, with damage to walls and plaster. All this hris been replaced in good order, a parquet floor laid in the public parlor, the ice house completed. much painting and decorating done throughout the building, the entii [ screens renewed. The interior of the school house decorated, and an entirely new greenhouse built. The greenhouse in June 1909 was a complete wreck so we were forced to rebuild. The east wing is in use now. and the central portion nearinjr completion. A west wing similar to the one on the east is contemplated in this plan, but the work on this part ft to be done later. It will be a very pretty and useful building when finished We put down a large amount of concrete sidewalk. The floors and furniture were varnished and made to shine Wells, pumps and machinery in the engine room and boiler boum put in order. All this and many minor changes were aceom plished with the appropriation of two years ago. Kask the same amount for the coming bienniura, $3,800.00 irs. ■here should be washrooms and bathrooms constructed in the winjr. similar t: those placed in the south wing five yean The north wb :upied by our girls and they need the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR UK DEAF Kl\ Cllll'Ilt S IlH'Ilt lOIll'i { allOY inlicr of new. concrete or ■ for genera] comfort and health, tile floors should be placed in the isiineiit of this wins wing needs further improvements ding should be redecorated. and the halls of the main buil A new roof must lie put o he dining room. A great deal of repairing must In- done t plumbing and in the engineer- ing departmei The chapel iii the school Ik ■ will need to be partitioned off ditorium is ready for use. fur school room u r new NEEDS our older boys. The pr t be made wholesome without unsafe as the west end ms ready to fall apart at any not suited for the use required. The steam heating system is no installed properly and now it The fences around our rounds have been torn down or rotted away. \V&lt; 1 a ae w, strong fence to enclose our orchard and garden. At pres ut we have absolutely no prott tion from \ issers. \\ fence such as w iroiind fair grounds with strong, barbed wire guards on top. It should put up substantially and paint- he ed. There should also be a In lit r, more ornamental fence built about the campus and west fro We ask +:',.&lt; MM MM) for this nt improvement MORE LAND If this school expects to remain here and educate the deaf f our state, provision should now be made for ground. It ihortaightedness that land was not added to this plant thirty yean or more ago when it could have been bought cheap. But annot undo that mistake. We have now an opportunity to buy .")(l acres adjoining our grounds. It is worth $1,000.00 an acre. The owners of this land have placed an offer in my hands The hasemeni of the sout We need a new building fo building is unsanitary and eann tearing out tin- entire bottom. time. Its present arrangemen Kid Mem to l&gt;f economy in the long run to rebuild a modern, troof, well arranged building to etaua with our new j.'ym- um building. We ask for $50,000.00 for this purpoi ild have ;i high, ti^ht. hoard </seg>
            <seg id="p017">306 Bto the state at the above price. The party owning the •s on the south is ready to plat and erect houses on his xt year if tin- state doea not decide to purchase. Be forty acres on the east is also ready to he platted and r city lots, and we may never obtain this tract unless re taken by this legislature to buy it for the State. e'e have rented these pieces of land fur several years. They e only tracts of land close to our institution left unplatted, would urge the coming legislature to appropriate enough to iis ."&gt;() acres for our school. Ethe next fifty years the State would be well repaid in the s to the farmer hoys growing up in our institution, and nd will have increased in value many fold. $."&gt;&lt; (.000.00 &gt;riated for this purpose would be well invested. Ehe school building put up eleven years ago should have a solid foundation placed under it. I would ask for $4,000.00 tall a concrete hutment under the entire wall. This should iced so deep that the inner earth could he excavated and the converted into basement rooms. We should have an increase in Salary fund of at least 0.00. We need more teachers in the oral department, a teacher of sloyd. a eooking school teacher, a physical instructor in the gymnasium, and a night watchman. Our engineer should have better pay. In this department it is the worst kind of • liny to have a cheap man. This salary should he raised to $100.00 a month. It is now 080.00. Our teachers ought to get an increased maximum rate, and our dining room girls and house girls should he raised to $2(1. (Ml a month. CHANGE OF NAME By Act of the Legislature of 1909 the name of this institu - tion wa-. changed from "Institute for the Deaf and Dumb" to "Nebraska School for the Deaf." This change was recommended by me to four successive legislatures and now all the deaf of I rejoice in that the name of our institution displays the true purpose of its founding that it is a ''School'' for training the Deaf. an«l classes us with the educational department of the In submitting this report I thank you for your assistance and iragement given our work. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF 307 I thank our Governor, Honorable Ashton C. Shallenberger, personally for the stand he took when giving me my appointment, affirming his purpose to consider "fitness and ability" before I thank all our teachers, employes, and helpers who have done their duty faithfullv and loyally. I thank the parents and friends for moral support in en - forcing necessary rules. tin all the years of our management of this school we have »d for that which is noble in principle, decent and moral in racter, efficiency, honesty, order and economy. To these influences and to kind Providence that watches over all, we owe whatever success our school may have accom - plished during this time. Trusting that the coming legislature may appropriate abundantly for extending and carrying on the work, I respect - fully submit this report of the Nebraska School for the Deaf for the years 1909 and 1910. H. S. STEWART, Superintendent </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>