<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Potato Flea Beetle and the Potato Psyllid in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">May 1940</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">The POTATO FLEA BEETLE and the POTATO PSYLLID in NEBRASKA BULLETIN 327 MAY 1940 MYRON H. SWENK and H, DOUGLAS TATE Department of Entomology The AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION of the UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE iW.W. _u_. Director LINCOLN. NEBRASKA </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTEXTS PAGE j The Potato Flea Beetle 3 ' Type of injury 4 ' Relation of beetle damage to disease 5 Host plants 5 Overwintering 5 Stages of development 6 Life cycle 7 Distribution in the field 7 Time of planting as related to injury 7 Control 8 The Potato Psyllid and Psyllid Yellows 9 Distribution 9 Host plants 9 Plant symptoms 10 ; Description of the insect 11 ; Life cycle 12 Overwintering and migration 12 j Feeding habits 14 i Temperature in relation to psyllid injury 14 i Control on potatoes 15 ; Control on tomatoes 16 ; Summary . ... 17 \ Literature Cited 19 ] i i; i: 1 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Potato Flea Beetle and the Potato Psy Hid in Nebraska MYRON H. SWENK and H.DOVGLAS TATE 1 Department of Entomology . . ' TTNSECT DEPREDATIONS are, a chief limiting factor in profitable —¦potato production in Nebraska. Each year both quality and yield are greatly reduced as a result of the attack of one or more insect pests. Prob - ably the two most important of these pests are the potato flea beetle, Epitrix cucumeris Harris, and the potato psyllid, Paratrioza cocf{erelli (Sulc). In many cases the abjmdance of insect pests depends almost entirely upon immediately preceding and current weather conditions. As a consequence, destructive populations are intermittent in occurrence. This may encourage a tendency on the part of the growers toplace undue reliance on the possible intervention of weather unfavorable to the insects. For this reason preven - tive measures oftenl are neglected, and under Nebraska conditions control of these two pests is largely a matter of prevention rather than cure. Investigations concerned with the biology and control of the potato flea beetle were conducted in western Nebraska during the summer of 1928. Similar studies were continued in 1930. In l°3sj 1936, and 1937 further experiments were conducted on the control of flea beetles, .psyllids, and early blight of potatoes. From the standpoint of insect control, the pur - pose of these tests ivas to determine the effect of the planting date on the severity of insect d;mage and the extent to which flea beetles and psyllids could be controlled by spraying. The effectiveness of the insecticide appli - cations was checkec at intervals through the growing season by comparing the density of the insect population on the treated and untreated plots. However, during the course of these experiments the populations of both flea beetles and psyllids were quite low, particularly in the locality where the work was conducted.- As a result the differences in yield between the treated and untreated plots usually were not great enough to justify definite conclusions as to the effectiveness of the treatments. Nevertheless, in the progress of these studies considerable information was assembled regarding flea beetles and psyllids, and the purpose of this bulletin is to present the more salient established facts concerning the life history and control of these two potato pests. • . ¦ -.-.. THE POTATO FLEA BEETLE . . The potato flea beetle has long been an important pest of potatoes in Nebraska. Although commonly found throughout the entire state, it is of greatest importance in the commercial potato growing sections of western Nebraska. Damage; does not occur uniformly in this area. Available in - formation shows that previous to about 1930 highly destructive flea-beetle populations often developed in the Pine Ridge section, particularly in 1 The authors wish to acknowledge the helpful work done by Mr. Karl Koch during the summer of 1928, and by Mr. Don B. Whelan during the summer of 1930. </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 327 Dawes county. In this area commercial potato production has been greatly reduced during recent years. Drouth conditions probably were largely responsible for the reduced acreage, but undoubtedly the severe flea-beetle damage was of some importance in lowering the yields below a profitable level. According to reports from various individuals closely associated with the potato industry in the western part of the state, at no time has flea - beetle injury become an economic problem in the dry-land farming sec - tion of the Alliance district. Although some damage occurs throughout the remaining districts of the Panhandle section of Nebraska, generally speaking far more severe injury has been evident in the irrigated sections of the North Platte river valley, particularly in the vicinity of Scottsbluff, Gering, and Mitchell, Nebraska. Records supplied by the Nebraska Certi - fied Potato Growers Non-stock Cooperative indicate that losses due to flea beetle damage in Scotts Bluff county in 1938 and 1939 amounted to four or five per cent of the total crop. The extent of damage varies greatly from season to season. Type of Injury Both the larval and adult stages of this insect produce a characteristic type of injury. The adult feeds on the leaves, more commonly on the under surface, eating holes through to the cuticle of the upper surface. The remaining cuticle soon dies and falls out, leaving a small hole about one-sixteenth of an inch in diameter. When heavy infestations are in- Fie. 1. —Tubers damaged by potato flea-beetle larvae. Characteristic "pimples" and j "worm track" are shown. I volved, the holes may become so numerous as to destroy a considerable '¦ pan of the leaf surface. In such cases the foliage turns brown and the j plant may die prematurely, either directly or indirectly as a result of the &lt; flea-beetle attack. fi </seg>
         <seg id="p005">: Potato Flea Beetles and Psyllids From a commercial standpoint, injury by the larvae in Nebraska is far more serious than that produced by the adults. Their feeding activities are confined to the underground portion of the plant, where they attack the seed pieces, roots, and developing tubers. On the tubers the larvae may tunnel along the surface, producing a condition known as "worm track.7 Often they penetrate the tuber a quarter of an inch or more at right angles to the surface. This results in a type of injury commonly re - ferredjto as "slivers" or "pimples." Such damage frequently is confused with scab (Actinomyces scabies). j . Relation o£ Beetle Damage to Disease A jnumber of workers have reported that frequently there has been observed a relationship between flea-beetle population density and the abundance of potato scab. MacMillan and Schaal (8) state that flea-beetle larvae) were found to carry the scab-producing organism both internally and externally under field conditions. They also experimentally demon - strated that the larvae are capable of transferring the scab organism from infected soil to healthy potatoes and from diseased to healthy potatoes. Goss (2) secured transmission of both spindle tuber and unmottled curly dwarf by means of the potato flea beetle. ¦¦ Because injury to potato tubers in western Nebraska usually is accom - panied by scab infection it is quite likely that the presence of flea-beetle injury often is not recognized as such by the growers. ¦•'•'•! Host Plants r Thp adult beetles show a decided preference for plants of the night - shade family {Solanaceae). Among the solanaceous plants, potato, tomato, peppers, egg plant, and ground cherries often are damaged severely. The beetle also attacks a wide variety of other plants, including beets, cabbage, carrot,] celery, clover, horse-nettle, lettuce, plantain, radish, spinach, turnip, and numerous other cultivated and.wild plants. During the early part of the season the adults appear to be rather general feeders but they become more selective as the season advances. The larval food plants other than potato are riot well known. However, ground cherry (Physalis sp.) has been found to serve as a host, and evi - dence also indicates the probability that buffalo bur (Solatium rostratum) and oi wr nightshade species are attacked. ..'.;.". '¦¦ ¦'¦:"[ '¦ Overwintering • :..•¦ A review of the literature reveals that most workers have found that the adult flea beetles overwinter in the soil under the protection of a sur - face covering of plant debris, and that such a covering generally is con - sidered as essential for survival. Hoerner and Gillette (4) in Colorado found diat as a rule the beetles live through the winter at a depth of from three to five inches in the soil. Investigations by Daniels (1) in the same </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 327 state showed that they were unable to survive the winter under plant debris on the soil surface. Webster (12) states that in lowa "during the winter the beetles hide away under leaves, rubbish, or some other protection." Stages of Development Egg.—The eggs are oval in shape, translucent in color, and about one - fiftieth of an inch long. They are deposited singly, but frequently in close proximity to each other, in the soil near or in contact with the host plant, and usually at a depth of one-half to two inches. The number of eggs deposited by an individual female varies considerably, but the average is approximately 100. The incubation period of the egg depends principally upon temperature and soil moisture. In July, 1928, Koch found the incu - bation period of 87 eggs contained in six groups to range from four to six days. In dry soil the incubation period may be increased to 10 or 12 days. Larva. —At the time of hatch - °^v 1 y****° 2 /~~\ ing the larva is about one- VV y f \ ' twenty-fifth of an inch in length, \ jrff n \ I whitish color, and scarcely visible | jjlflfrj - v^/' to the unaided eye. When fully JjPfjPaL. x — v matured, it is approximately one- *j\ f\ sixth of an inch long. Matur - 'Mff'tfiwll &gt; &gt;Sf!i3 'tv 's atta'ne^ m three to five f«Sl»l\ vitSpf 1 weeks. Larvae of the first gen - u wujjp^ | M\]W eration occur approximately from jj \ \3~!y 'ate June unt" early August, and / \ those of the second generation from the first of. August until late ..I, — ; —- _^^ September. /rjj&amp;»Jn*^.&lt;*i'it*i^£\ cm. Pupa.—Pupation occurs in a /jpP 3 small earthen cell, constructed by the larva, from one-half, to !•¦„¦, 2.-P..UU. flea benk (Epilrix cucumtr.s): . surface o f tl) adult, enlarged 18 times; (2) eggs, , " , . &#132; enlarged 30 times; (3) larva, enlarged 9 the soil, in the immediate Vicm - times; (-li pupa, enlarged 18 times. (From ity of the plant upon which the Daniels. Bulletin -437, Colorado Experiment | arva had been feeding. The Slation) duration of the pupal stage is : from one to two weeks. Under field conditions in western Nebraska, the ; pupal period of the first generation (progeny of overwintered females) was ; found to extend from about the first of July to the first of September, and | that of the second generation from about the last of August to early in j October. Adult.—Upon emergence from the pupal stage the adult is light col- ; ored, but it soon develops the characteristic black appearance. The first j overwintered adults were observed in the field during the latter half of j. May, but the peak of their abundance extended from late June to the I middle of July. Adults of the first generation occur in greatest numbers f I </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Potato Flea Beetles and Psyllids ... in late August and through the first half of September. Adults of the second generation begin to emerge during the latter part of September. At the time of emergence from hibernation, the beetles may feed to a limited extent on practically any plant foliage available to them, such as lambs-quarters and alfalfa. If no potato or closely related plants are avail - able in the immediate vicinity, migration soon begins, during the course of which they may become dispersed for considerable distances. Egg laying begins soon after the beetles emerge from hibernation and may continue for a period of 45 to 60 days. Under experimental con - ditions egg laying readily occurs in moist soil, whereas in dry soil such activity is greatly retarded and in some instances prevented. life Cycle In 1930, in mass cage experiments with overwintering adults collected on Ju le 23, Whelan found that a generation was completed, including the emergence of adults, in 48 to 63 days, and with adults collected on June 26 in 5.1 to 62 days. Obviously the developmental period varies markedly with :emperature, moisture, and soil conditions. The number of genera - tions annually varies to some extent in different parts of the country. Webs:er (12) concluded that there is strong evidence of a partial second generation in lowa. On the basis of cage tests, Jewett (5) obtained evi - jdencej indicating that two. generations are produced each year in Kentucky. Laboratory experiments conducted in Colorado by Hoerner and Gillette ;(4) demonstrated the development of one complete generation and a par - tial sejcond generation, the latter being so small that it was not considered important. Daniels (1), in the same state, concluded that' in the field 'there jordinarily is only one complete generation, but that in particularly favorable years a second generation may develop. Both cage experiments and field observations indicate that in Nebraska a fairly complete second generation develops rather commonly. : . '&#132;-.:... . Distribution in the Field ' OlKervations and field counts repeatedly have demonstrated that there is some degree of correlation between flea-beetle populations ' in the potato fields and the wild and cultivated vegetation in adjoining and nearby areas. Also, the population, particularly where large acreagesj are involved, becomes increasingly less in progressing from the border to the center of a field. I Supporting this statement is the fact that out of 74 fields examined by Wjhekn in 1930, with the exception of two plantings, the population proved to be significantly greater in border areas than in the'center of the field. These observations emphasize the advisability of preventing, when - ever practical, the growth of vegetation that may serve as hosts of the flea beetle in the vicinity of potato fields. • I j Time of Planting as Related to Injury I Tjie severity of tuber injury is influenced to a considerable extent by the date of planting. Damage is far more likely to occur to early-planted </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 327 than to late-planted potatoes. Generally speaking, "early" potatoes in west - ern Nebraska are those planted before June 10, and "late" potatoes are those planted after about June 20. This difference appears to be largely due to the fact that among early plantings tuber formation occurs during the peak of larval activity in the soil, while late plantings tend to escape this period to some extent. Control As evidenced by published reports, a wide variety of materials have been recommended and used in an effort to obtain effective control of the flea beetle. In many of the states east of Nebraska, the more common flea - beetle control recommended is a spray composed of calcium arsenate and Bordeaux mixture; this material acts in the dual role of a repellent and a stomach poison. In view of the fact that under Nebraska conditions the time of appli - cation of control measures for the potato flea beetle and the potato psyllid more or Jess coincide, practical considerations demand the use of a com - bination spray, that is, a material which is compatible with lime-sulphur spray. The present flea-beetle control recommendation is as follows: Zinc arsenite 2 pounds Water 40 gallons When psyllid control is necessary, 40 gallons of diluted lime-sulphur spray (one gallon of concentrated liquid or four to five pounds of dry lime - sulphur to 40 gallons of water) should be substituted for the plain water in the above formula. Although many growers in western Nebraska have not experienced satisfactory flea-beetle control with the zinc arsenite spray, it appears to be the most practical control measure available at the present time. Experi - mental evidence published from other states indicates that certain other materials have considerable promise. Among these are some of the fluorine compounds including barium fluosilicate and cryolite. These circumstances unquestionably indicate an urgent need for further experimental work on the control of the potato flea beetle in Nebraska. Time and number of sprays.—Successful flea-beetle control involves thorough and timely spraying. Since the chief objective under Nebraska conditions is to protect the tubers against attack by the larvae, it is neces - sary to kill the adults before they have had an opportunity to deposit eggs. This can be most satisfactorily accomplished by maintaining effective spray coverage from the time the first beetles occur on the potato plant until the peak oi adult activity has terminated. In localities where flea-beetle damage commonly occurs, it is considered advisable to apply at least one protective spray each year. This application should be made when the plants are six to eight inches in height. Follow - ing this, field observations offer a fairly dependable basis for determining the desirability of additional sprays. During seasons oi moderately heavy </seg>
         <seg id="p009">¦.-.- ¦¦¦¦"•'¦ {- ¦'.¦¦¦: ¦:'¦'¦ Potato Flea Beetles and Psyluds to leavy outbreaks, three to five applications at 10-day to two-week in - tervals may be necessary. In the latter part of the season whenever plant growth is such that the space between the rows is completely filled, me - chanical injury resulting from the use of spray equipment may be so severe as :o offset any advantage of a spray application. THE POTATO PSYLLID AND PSYLLID YELLOWS The potato psyllid was first associated with a disease of potatoes by Richards (8), who submitted evidence.to show that this insect is respon - sible for the disease. now designated as psyllid yellows. Although the causal agent had not been determined, the symptoms of the disease had been recognized for several years previous to 1927, usually being referred to as "blight" and "purple top." Undoubtedly it often had been confused with Rhizoctonia, leaf roll, and other diseases having somewhat similar symptoms. The findings of various workers demonstrate that the disease develops as a result of the injection of a toxic secretion by the insects dur - ing the normal process of feedings, v [The years 1935 and 1938 stand out preeminently as "psyllid years" in (Nebraska. During comparatively mild outbreaks marked reductions in yield result, and whenever heavy infestations develop the crop may prac - tically be a total loss, unless effective control measures are properly applied. ¦¦¦/.-'¦ Distribution : . .'.¦ | The potato psyllid has been recorded from South Dakota, Nebraska, Kansas, Colorado, Utah, Idaho, all states to the west of these, and in west - ern Canada. ; ¦¦¦¦••':,:. In Nebraska the potato psyllid is of greatest economic importance in the commercial potato growing sections of the western part of the state. It occurs, however, throughout the entire state, and in 1938 some damage was definitely recorded on tomatoes and potatoes as far east as Lancaster county. More complete surveys and an increasing familiarity on the part of the growers:with the insect and the disease it causes quite likely will show that the potato psyllid is of greater importance on small garden and truck crop plantings than has been previously realized. . The irregularity of the occurrence of destructive psyllid populations within a given locality is.particularly noticeable. Inspection records of the Nebraska Certified Potato Growers Non-stock Cooperative establish the fact that the average percentage of potato fields within a county which show psyllid yellows may differ 50 per cent or more from that of an adjoining county. , ••'•: 1 .'. '-':¦::¦'¦.'/:. . Host Plants : ¦¦'¦:¦¦¦'. In general, plants of the nightshade family (Solanaceae) are preferred hosts, potato and tomato being particularly susceptible. Infestations have been observed on practically all of the more common wild solanaceous plants, among which are included several species of wild ground cherry or </seg>
         <seg id="p010">\i bkaska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 327 wild tomato (Physalis spp.), buffalo bur {Solatium rostratum), some other species of nightshade (Solarium spp.), egg plant (S. melongemi), pepper ( Capsicum spp.), and matrimony vine (Lyciitm halmijolium). Some of the perennial ground cherries, such as the prairie ground cherry (Physalis lanceolata) and the long-leaved ground cherry (P. long - ijolia) offer favorable hosts for the psyllids in the early spring. Because of its wide distribution and abundance in potato-growing sections, the buffalo bur, which is quite susceptible to psyllid attack, is considered as a par - ticularly important factor in psyllid propagation. It is generally assumed that wild host plants exert a significant influence in that they permit a rapid increase in the psyllid population, thus supplying an important source of infestation for potatoes. Plant Symptoms The symptoms of psyllid yellows vary considerably with the variety of potatoes, the density of the insect infestation, and the stage of development hi the plant when attacked. The first symptoms appear on the lower leaves in the form of a slight yellowing along the mid-rib, followed by a rolling and cupping at the base. As the disease progresses the entire leaf may be - come curled. The normal color usually changes to a light green or yellow, but occasionally it fades '--^ to yellow and then \. almost to white. In some X^gfcfr. l...jh' **rgrr-/. V~^&gt;&gt;v varieties a redd'isVi-pur - fcsSMrJ&amp;'^l,,-*.' -^ / \ p''s'l discoloration ap - if*S^^^^S^ 7 ars&gt; P articu'ar'yat the 11 iffiSSJSaSSk-ir^F^^ ":" s tips and margins of II I] *"&gt;&lt;/j, "^ leaves and at the nodes f "*» soon after the leaves be - gin to roll, thus giving 1 „ v- .vli.ll fcm.lt pawn pqrllid, l»cral view, en- ris£ « fc l.ir^id jlmut 2t times. (From Kmnvkon, Leaflet 36, „ „. v • Lull i \|.crimcnt Station.) tOP- blr"je tnere Is a distinct disease of pota - toes commonly called "purple top," horticulturists and plant pathol - ogists are inclined to discourage the use of this name in connection with the disease caused by psyllids. Stem elongation in aerial shoots is retarded and small tubers, or rosettes of leaves, may develop in the leaf axils. In advanced stages curling of leaves may occur on all parts of the plant. The leaves become harsh and have a characteristic rustle when brushed with the hand. After remaining in this condition for several weeks, the plant may turn brown and die. Underground symptoms vary with the stage of growth of the plant when psyllid infestation occurs. If the attack occurs previously to tuber formation, a typical response is the development of numerous small pota - toes of unmarketable size. Frequently small tubers form at intervals along a single stolon, producing a chain effect. When infestation occurs after t </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Potato Flea Beetles and Psyllius I . tubers are partially developed, further enlargement may be retarded. The I rest period of tubers from plants affected with psyllid yellows usually is greatly reduced. Occasionally sprouting may occur before harvest and quite commonly the tubers sprout in storage during the winter or in early spring before planting time. Description of the Insect Adult—The adult potato psyllid is grayish in color, about one tenth of an inch in length and, in general outline of body, resembles a very small , cicada. A number of light-colored markings or bands are present on the ' upper side of the body. At the base of the abdomen is a well defined trans - j versi white band and at the tip a Y-shaped marking. ¦ Tfte potato psyllid belongs to a family of insects commonly known as jumping plant lice or chermids. The adults are quite active, the hind legs [being modified for jumping, a response which usually occurs at the slightest disturbance. The wings are membranous and colorless, and when the insect is at rest are held roof-like over the body. FicJ 4.—Adult male potato psyllid, dorsal view, enlarged about 20 dmes. (From Knowl - ton and James, Annals Ent.Soc, Amer., xxiv, pi. 1, 1931.) .Egg.—The eggs are small, about 1/32 of an inch in length, elongate and supported on a stalk or stem which is about an eighth to a quarter inch ;' ¦ i&amp; length. The psyllid eggs should not be confused with those o£ the aphis- I lions or lacewing-flies, which are beneficial insects in that they feed on various pests including plant lice and probably psyllids. The eggs of the lacewing-fly are supported on a stalk or stem similar to that of the psyllid, but they are considerably larger and the supporting stem is longer, usually being about one-quarter to one-half inch in length. They may be de - posited on either side o£ the leaf, along the margin and occasionally on the petioles and stems, but more commonly on the veins and margins of the tinder side of a leaf. By holding the edge of the leaf in strong sunlight and| on a level with the eye, the eggs may be observed projecting like small pegs. Recently deposited eggs are shiny yellow, but as hatching time approaches they develop an orange color. </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 327 Nymph.- —Upon hatching, the nymphs are small scale-like insects. Around the entire margin of the body is a well defined band of short horizontal spines. Their color ranges from orange-yellow at first to green in the mature nymph. In the course of development they shed and renew their skin five times before the adult stage is attained. In the late nymphal stages the wing pads become clearly visible on the upper surface ot the scale-like body. When feeding, the nymphs are quite inactive and lie close to the surface of the 0 if r Q 0 'ea^' usua"y De'ng so firmly attached \~ '^'.¦(Li^^^fl'^^L instrument is necessary to dislodge r*^V%s them. They occur in greatest abund - f '^o^^^7?^^i^^o^^S ance on £^c un&lt;^er sl^e °^ c Jower Wf?'' :^&amp;P§^':/-iL leaves, but on shaded portions of the W* ' '-M^*'/ '¦'Jr P^ant may become numerous '3r'' £r a'so on l^e uPPer surraces °f the *P leaves and on the stems. The pres- Fie. 5. —Epps of the potato psyllid at- ence of a white, granular, sugar-like tached to leaf of potato plant, enlarged material, corresponding to honey - about 37 times. (From Daniels, Bulletin dew am Wd { requent l y aids ¦111, Colorado Experiment Station.) , . ° ,r , '. -. ' , in detecting infestations. Since the nymphal stage alone is responsible for the production of psyllid yellows, it is particularly desirable that growers acquaint themselves with this stage of the insect. Life Cycle According to various workers, the life cycle may be completed in from 15 to 30 days, the average being about three weeks. The duration of the various stages depends largely upon temperature and moisture conditions. The egg-laying period of an individual female may extend over a period of two to three weeks during which time 300 to 400 eggs are deposited. As shown by List (7), the number of eggs laid is greatly influenced by tem - perature. Because of an overlapping of generations, all stages are present in the field during most of the season. The incubation period of the eggs ranges from three to eight days with a majority hatching in three to five days. The five nymphal stadia usually are completed in 15 to 20 days. Upon emergence the adult is pale yellow but gradually assumes the deeper color characteristic of the mature insect. Available evidence indicates that during favorable seasons in western Nebraska, adult psyllids appear on wild hosts about the middle of May. They continue feeding and breeding on these plants until the growth of potatoes is sufficient to support an infestation. During more favorable years there may be several generations. Overwintering and Migration Information relative to these phases of the potato psyllid's existence is quite incomplete up to the present time. It has been reported as living </seg>
         <seg id="p013">¦ Potato Flea Beetles and Psyllids ' FIC. 6.—The five nymphal instars of the potato psyUid, showing relative size and shape. (From Knowhoa and James, Annals Ent. Soc. Amcr., xxiv, pi. 1, 1931.) through the winter in the adult stage on evergreens, but more data are needed to establish definite statements on its hibernating habits. It is the opinion of some workers that the spring infestations may be the result of migration from distant breeding grounds. List (6) submits some evidence to this effect in connection with collection records from insect traps operated in Colorado. .: Romney (11) states that limited observations indicate that the potato psyUid breeds along the Rio Grande drainage above Laredo, Texas, over an area of several hundred miles. He concludes that there is a possibility .¦[ . . : ¦ ¦ ' ¦-:¦ : ¦ '.. . ; ¦ '¦'.'¦¦¦ 1 ¦ ¦ ¦ " ¦ ' ' ¦ ¦ ' :¦'"--¦. '¦ ' ' • </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Acricvltural Experiment Station Bulletin 327 thac this is the main source of spring infestations that occur east of the Continental Divide as far north as Colorado. Feeding Habits ; The psyllid nymphs more commonly feed on the under surface of the leaves of the lower third of the plant. On heavily infested plants with dense foliage, occasionally they may feed on the upper surface of the leaves and on the stems. During early development the nymphs remain close to the site where the eggs were deposited, in a comparatively inactive state, but as maturity is approached they become relatively mobile. The mouth parts are of the sucking type. Evidence indicates that a salivary secretion is injected into the plant during the feeding process and that this is responsible for the disease, psyllid yellows. The relationship between the insect and the disease is unique in that only the nymphs are capable of producing the disease. Richards and Blood (10) presented evidence to show that under experimental conditions in - festations of adults consisting of 1,000 or more individuals per plant failed to produce psyllid yellows. On the other hand, it has been found that the (ceding of five or six nymphs on a small, immature potato plant may pro - duce disease symptoms within a few days. On larger and more mature I'l.ints the- feeding of fifteen or more nymphs over a period of two or three weeks is necessary to produce definite disease symptoms. The time re - quired to produce symptoms, as well as the intensity of the symptoms, is dependent upon the abundance of the feeding nymphs. Although the initial symptoms may appear within a {e\v days, a complete symptom pic - ture usually does not develop unless the nymphs feed continuously for. several weeks. Temperature in Relation to Psyllid Injury In general, relatively cool growing seasons are conducive to heavy psyllid populations, whereas seasons having numerous hot days exert an opposite effect. Hartman (3) in Wyoming submitted data showing that there is a significant correlation between temperatures prevailing during certain periods of the growing season and psyllid injury. During the years 1932 to 1935, which comprise the period covered by his records, only mild psyllid injury occurred when the average maximum temperature for j the 20-day period including the last 10 days of June and the first 10 days ; of July exceeded approximately 92° F. Conversely, the severity of the dam - age increased as the temperature level receded from about 90" F. Lab - oratory experiments conducted by List (7) indicate that the optimum developmental temperature for the species is approximately 80 SF. Severe psyllid damage occurred in Nebraska in 1935 and 1938. In 1935 psyllids were scarce until near the middle of August, following which there was a rapid increase in their numbers, attended by heavy losses to the potato crop. An examination of the temperature records for western Nebraska, as presented by Werner (13), reveals the fact that in 1935 ter- j ' il </seg>
         <seg id="p015">..! '¦'".. Potato Flea Beetles and Psvllids. peratures were comparatively' high in July but low in August and Septem - ber. ¦ ' ¦ . :¦¦.¦¦. ¦.¦¦'¦•;':' ¦ ¦ The forepart of the spring of 1938 was characterized by relatively low temperatures and an abundance of potato psyllids. Coincident with the occurrence of numerous hot days in July and the first half of August, the psyllid population was greatly reduced. A second peak of abundance, accompanied by severe damage, developed following mid-August when temperatures again were comparatively mild. Control on Potatoes Experimental evidence.and practical experience among potato growers h: :ve shown that effective psyllid control can be obtained by correctly lined and properly applied lime-sulphur sprays. The following propor - tions are recommended: •'.'¦¦. Liquid lime-sulphur (Baumc test, 32 degrees)........ 1 gallon Water ....-'.;. 40 gallons (Four to five pounds of dry lime-sulphur can be substituted for the liquid lime-sulphur.). ¦ . :'•., \ i If a combination psyllid and flea-beetle control spray is desired, add two pounds of zinc arseniteto the above formula. \ : Although sulphur dusts and wettable sulphur sprays have proved effec - itve in controlling psyllids on tomatoes, published reports up to the present time have indicated that liquid lime-sulphur is somewhat more effective on potatoes. The superiority of the latter on potatoes has been attributed to the fact that dusts do not adhere well to the.relatively smooth surface of potato foliage. Improvements in the sticking qualities of sulphur dust and greater efficiency in machinery for its application may eventually justify its usage on potatoes. . ; '..'¦¦" Materials.—Lime-sulphur can be obtained in either the liquid or dry form. However, the liquid form is more commonly used and it is con - sidered as being the more desirable form to apply under Nebraska con - ditions. . . : The combination spray, for both psyllids and flea beetles, should be prepared as follows: (1) Combine the lime-sulphur and water, (2) prepare af uniform mixture of zinc arsenite by stirring in a small quantity of water, and (3) after the lime-sulphur is in the spray tank and the agitator is in in motion, add the zinc arsenite slowly through a screen. In no case should the dry zinc arsenite powder be placed in the spray tank. It has been estimated that 80 to 90 gallons of diluted spray are enough to spray one acre when the plants are 12 to 14 inches in height. Equipment. —For effective application it is necessary to use spray riachinery that will develop 300 to 400 pounds o£ pressure and deliver adequate amounts of material for complete coverage. Because mainten - ance of sufficient pressure with traction sprayers is difficult, particularly at </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 327 that this is the main source of spring infestations that occur east of the Continental Divide as far north as Colorado. i Feeding Habits The psyllid nymphs more commonly feed on the under surface of the leaves of the lower third of the plant. On heavily infested plants with dense foliage, occasionally they may feed on the upper surface of the leaves and on the stems. During early development the nymphs remain close to the site where the eggs were deposited, in a comparatively inactive state, but as maturity is approached they become relatively mobile. The mouth parts are of the sucking type. Evidence indicates that a salivary secretion is injected into the plant during the feeding process and that this is responsible for the disease, psyllid yellows. The relationship between the insect and the disease is unique in that only the nymphs are capable of producing the disease. Richards and Blood (10) presented evidence to show that under experimental conditions in - festations of adults consisting of 1,000 or more individuals per plant failed to produce psyllid yellows. On the other hand, it has been found that the feeding of five or six nymphs on a small, immature potato plant may pro - duce disease symptoms within a few days. On larger and more mature plants the feeding of fifteen or more nymphs over a period of two or three weeks is necessary to produce definite disease symptoms. The time re - quired to produce symptoms, as well as the intensity of the symptoms, is dependent upon the abundance of the feeding nymphs. Although the i initial symptoms may appear within a few days, a complete symptom pic- . ture usually does not develop unless the nymphs feed continuously for several weeks. I Temperature in Relation to Psyllid Injury ; In general, relatively cool growing seasons are conducive to heavy j psyllid populations, whereas seasons having numerous hot days exert an j opposite effect. Hartman (3) in Wyoming submitted data showing that there is a significant correlation between temperatures prevailing during certain periods of the growing season and psyllid injury. During the years j 1932 to 1935, which comprise the period covered by his records, only I mild psyllid injury occurred when the average maximum temperature for [ the 20-day period including the last 10 days of June and the first 10 days •¦ of July exceeded approximately 92° F. Conversely, the severity of the dam- s age increased as the temperature level receded from about 90° F. Lab- £ oratory experiments conducted by List (7) indicate that the optimum developmental temperature for the species is approximately 80" F. Severe psyllid damage occurred in Nebraska in 1935 and 1938. In 1935 ! psyllids were scarce until near the middle of August, following which there was a rapid increase in their numbers, attended by heavy losses to the potato crop. An examination of the temperature records for western j: Nebraska, as presented by Werner (13), reveals the fact that in 1935 ter- f </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Potato Flea Beetles and Psyllids peratures were comparatively high in July but low in August and Septem- I The forepart of the spring of 1938 was characterized by relatively low temperatures and an abundance, of potato psyllids. Coincident with the occurrence of numerous hot days in July and the first half of August, the psyllid population was greatly reduced. A second peak of abundance, accompanied by severe damage; developed following mid-August when temperatures again were comparatively mild. :-...- ¦ Control on Potatoes .!.-.-. : Experimental evidence and practical experience among potato growers hsive shown that effective psyllid control can be obtained by correctly timed and properly applied lime-sulphur sprays. The following propor - tions are recommended: ;. Liquid lime-sulphur (Baume test, 32 degrees)....',:. 1 gallon Water .. ¦:..::....;............. ...,', ......:........ 40 gallons (Four to five pounds of dry lime-sulphur can be substituted for the liquid lime-sulphur.) If a combination psyllid and jlea-beetle control spray is desired, add two pounds of zinc arsenite to the above jormula. . Although sulphur dusts and wertable sulphur sprays have proved effec - tive in controlling psyllids on tomatoes, published reports up to the present time have indicated that liquid lime-sulphur is somewhat more effective on potatoes. The superiority of the latter on potatoes has been attributed to tne fact that dusts do not adhere well to the relatively smooth surface of potato foliage. Improvements in the sticking qualities of sulphur dust and greater efficiency in machinery for its application may eventually justify its usage on potatoes. . Materials.—Lime-sulphur can be obtained in either the liquid or dry form. However, the liquid iprm is more commonly used and it is con - sidered as being the more desirable form to apply under Nebraska con - ditions. • . , The combination spray, for both psyllids and flea beetles, should be prepared as follows: (1) Combine the lime-sulphur and water, (2) prepare a uniform mixture of zinc arsenite by stirring in a small quantity of water, aid (3) after the lime-sulphur is in the spray tank and the agitator is in in motion, add the zinc arsenite slowly through a screen. In no case should the dry zinc arsenite powder be placed in the spray tank. It has been estimated that 80 to 90 gallons of diluted spray are enough to spray one acre when the plants are 12 to 14 inches in height. Equipment.—For effective application it is necessary to use spray machinery that will develop 300 to 400 pounds of pressure and deliver adequate amounts of material for complete coverage. Because mainten - ance of sufficient pressure with traction sprayers is difficult, particularly at </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 327 the ends of rows where psyllids are most numerous, power machinery is practically essential. For the first spray, which should be applied when the plants are six to eight inches in height, two nozzles per row—one on each side — are sufficient to obtain adequate coverage. Three nozzles—one from each side and one from the top —should be used for larger plants. It is advisable to arrange the side nozzles so that one is pointed slightly toward the front and the other toward the rear, rather than directly opposite, thus produc - ing a whirling effect on the foliage. Time and number of sprays.—ln order to obtain effective control, spray materials should be applied before symptoms of psyllid yellows appear. The environmental factors which determine psyllid abundance are not well enough understood at the present time to permit forecasts relative to the probability of the development of destructive psyllid populations. For this reason it is considered advisable to apply a protective spray each year when the plants are six to eight inches in height. This statement applies principally to the commercial potato-growing sections of western Nebraska where the potato psyllid has already proved a major pest. De - velopments later in the season may show that the protective spray was unnecessary, particularly in some localities. On the whole, however, the experience of growers has convincingly demonstrated that this is a desir - able and economical practice. The advisability of additional sprays can be determined, with a fair degree of dependability, by examining plants in the field for the presence of psyllids. Such examinations necessitate complete familiarity with the insect in its various stages, particularly the egg and nymphal stages. It may easily be confused with any of a number of other insects or overlooked entirely because of its small size and inconspicuous coloration. Unless growers are thoroughly acquainted with the insect, it would be advisable to obtain the advice of the county agent, or others who have had experience with the problem, in determining the need for further sprays. In view of the fact that temperature exerts an important influence on development, a period of several days or more of temperatures below 90° F. should be considered as indicating the possibility of an increasing psyllid population. Under such conditions special care should be exercised in making field inspections. If eggs and nymphs are numerous and the days cool, sprays should be applied as soon as possible. Conversely, an extended period dur - ing which the temperatures range above approximately 90° F. for several hours or more each day is likely to retard psyllid development, and such a condition may greatly reduce the psyllid population. During favorable psyllid years it may be necessary to apply three to five sprays, especially on early planted potatoes, at about two-week intervals. Control on Tomatoes Although the spray recommended for controlling psyllids on potatoes is quite effective, tomato plants often are severely damaged by lime-sulphur </seg>
         <seg id="p019">. . Potato Flea Beetles and Psyllids spray. List (6) has found that in Colorado satisfactory control can be obtained with sulphur dusts without any visible injury to plants. For control of the potato psyllid on tomatoes in Nebraska, either one of the two following treatments is recommended: 1. Dusting with a 325-mesh dusting sulphur (98 to 100 per cent pass - • ing a 325-mesh sieve—equivalent to former grade of 99 per cent passing a 300-mesh sieve). . 2. Spraying with a 325-mesh wettable sulphur, 1 pound to 10 gallons I of water (for smaller quantities, 1 heaping tablespoonful to 1 gallon J of water). : " ¦ In localities where psyllid infestations commonly occur, it is advisable to treat the plants a few days previous to or at the time of trans - planting in the field, and then follow with another treatment about 10 days later. Whenever heavy infestations are involved, applications should be repeated at about two-week intervals as long as the infestation persists; If destructive infestations are more or less sporadic in occurrence, the under side of the leaves, particularly near the base of the plant, should be carefully examined at frequent intervals and, whenever psyllid nymphs are found, control measures applied. . ; SUMMARY -.¦.¦•;", The Potato Flea Beetle '."' : The adult and the larval stages of the potato flea beetle, Epitrix cucum - eris Harris, both produce a characteristic type of injury. The larval injury, whi:h is confined to the roots and tubers, is more serious in Nebraska than the toliage damage by the adults. . ; ¦¦'...¦ Evidence indicates that injury to the tubers by the flea-beetle larvae may) greatly increase the extent of damage by potato scab. Plants of the nightshade family (Solanaceae) are the preferred hosts but a wide range of other plants are attacked. . V Available information shows that overwintering occurs in the adult stage in the ground at a depth of three to five inches, probably under a covering of plant refuse. The potato flea beetle passes through four stages in its development: the egg, the larval, the pupal, and the adult stages. Under experimental conditions during June and July, 1930, the life cycle was completed in 48 to 63 days. : ; ¦:¦'.. In Nebraska early-planted potatoes or plantings made previous to June 10 are more likely to be damaged by flea beetles than plantings made after about June 20. The present control recommendation consists of a zinc arsenite spray applied at a strength of two pounds of zinc arsenite to 40 gallons of water. The Potato Psyllid Symptoms of the disease now referred to as psyllid yellows have been recognized for a number of years, but it was not until 1927 that the potato psyllid, Paratrioza coc\erel\i (Sulc), was identified as the cause. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">¦ v i! Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 327 ( % The potato psyllid occurs throughout Nebraska and frequently causes damage to garden and truck crop plantings of potatoes and tomatoes, but it is of greatest economic importance in the commercial potato-growing sections of the western part of the state. The principal host plants are members of the nightshade family {Solan- I aceae) but a limited number of other plants are attacked. Definite disease symptoms are produced on both above- and below- ; ground portions of the potato plant. As a rule there is a clearing of the : veins of the leaves accompanied by a rolling and yellowing. A character - istic underground symptom is the production of numerous small tubers. There are three stages of development of the insect: the egg, the nymph, and the adult. Only the nymphs are capable of producing the disease. The life cycle may be completed in 15 to 30 days, the average being about three weeks. As a rule, the nymphs feed on the under surface of the leaves of the lower third of the plant. The mouth parts are of the sucking type. Evi - dence indicates that the disease is produced as a result of a salivary secre - tion injected by the insect during the normal process of feeding. Apparently temperature is a chief limiting factor in the development of destructive psyllid populations, comparatively low temperatures being most favorable for the insects. Effective control on potatoes can be obtained by correcdy timed and properly applied lime-sulphur sprays. In western Nebraska where psyllid damage commonly occurs, it is considered advisable to apply a protective spray each year when the plants are six to eight inches in height. The need tor additional sprays can be determined by field inspections. For controlling the psyllid on tomatoes, it is recommended that either a sulphur dust or a wettable sulphur spray be used. </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Potato Flea Beetles and Psyllids .. literature cited . 1. Saniels, L. B. . '. . . ... ¦ "' ' i ' 1937. Controlling Colorado Potato Pests. Colo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 437. 2. Goss,R.W. "..¦¦¦¦ . ' • ¦ ¦;¦¦.¦:' r 1931. Infection Experiments With Spindle Tuber and Unmottled Curly Dwarf of the Potato. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 53. 3. rlartman, Glen. 1937. A Study of Psyllid Yellows in Wyoming. Wyo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. '¦" -: 22&lt;&gt;- . ; ¦••:•";¦¦:' :¦ . ' . ¦ " ¦' ¦¦ .&lt; ¦'¦ 4. Hocrncr, John L., and Gillette, C. P. 1928. The Potato Flea Beetle. Colo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 337. 5. Jewett, a H. 1929. PqtatoFlea Beetles. Ky. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 297. 6. List, GeorgeM. 1939. The Potato and Tomato Psyixid and its Control on Tomatoes. Colo. .•¦•: Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 454. '•''¦. '-7. ———-— '"'; ¦¦'.'¦¦¦'; ;".-.. ". . 1939. The Effect of Temperature Upon Egg Deposition, Egg Hatch and Nymphal Development of Paratrioza Cockerelli (Sulc). J. Econ. Ent 32: 30-36. ¦ j ... 8. MacMUlan, H. G., and Schaal, L. A. . . 1929. A Pathological Feature of Flea Beetle Injury of Potato' Tubers. J. Agr. Res. 36: 807-15. \ . ¦9. Ricnards,!B.:L. '¦¦:'', ; , ' : 1928. A New and Destructive Disease of the Potato in Utah and Its Relation to the Potato Psylla., (Abs.) Phytopath. 18: 140-41. 10.— i—, and Blood, H. L. ' -. : '. V : •.' 1933. Psyllid Yellows of the Potato. J. Agr. Res. 46: 189-216. 11. lomney.lv. E. . : : 1939. Breeding Areas of the Tomato Psyllid, Paratrioza Cockerelli (Sulc). J. Econ. Ent 32: 150-51. 12. Webster, R. L. : 1915. Potato Insects. Bui. 155, lowa Agr. Exp. Sta. pp. 367-75. ; 13. Werner, R a . . ¦',:¦, . ; 1939. Occurrence of High Temperatures in; Western Nebraska and Their - Relationship to Occurrence or Psyllids. Better Potatoes in Nebraska, y. Vol. 2, Nos. 6 and 7. . : ¦ ". : ¦ ¦ . ..¦ &#132; ¦ ¦¦- ¦ ¦.'¦:¦ : ¦ ¦¦¦ '&#132;':¦ .-. '.s&gt;*l </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>