<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00038.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00038.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Eighth Biennial Report of the Nebraska State Board of Charities and Correction</title>
               <date value="1916-11-30">1916-11-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT of the Nebraska State Board of Charities and Correction November 30, 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION Governor JOHN H. MOREHEAD Superintendent _A. O. THOMAS Land Commissioner FRED BECKMANN Chief Clerk J. W. SHAHAN After January 4, 1917, the State Board WILL CONSIST OF KEITH NEVILLE Governor W. H. CLEMMONS Superintendent of Public Instruction O. L. 8HUMWAY Commissioner of Public Lands and Building* </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Name and Location of Nebraska State Institutions NAME OF SUPERINTENDENTS IN CHARGE 1. State Penitentiary Lancaster W. T. FENTON, Warden 2. State Industrial School for Boys Kearney R. V. CLARK, Supt. 3. Girls' Industrial School Geneva MISS LYDA J. McMAHON, Supt 4. Nebraska Industrial Home Milford MISS LENA E. WARD, Supt. 5. Nebraska Hospital for the Insane Lincoln Dr. B. F. WILLIAMS. Supt. 6. Hospital for the Insane - Norfolk Dr. G. E. CHARLTON, Supt 7. Nebraska State Hospital I'gleside Dr. W. S. FAST, Supt 8. Home for Dependent Children Uncoln MISS ETTA CATON. Agent. ». Orthopedic Hospital Lincoln Dr. H. WINNETT ORR. Supt. 10. Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Burkett Commandant J. F. WALSH 11. Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Milford Commandant, D. C. ROWDEN 12. Nebraska State Institution for Feeble Minded Youth Beatrice Dr. D. G. GRIFFITHS. Supt 13. School for the Deaf Omaha FRANK W. BOOTH, Supt. 14. School for the Blind Nebraska City N. C. ABBOTT, Supt 10. Tuberculosis Hospital Kearney Dr. L. S. B. ROBINSON, Supt, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE State Board of Charities and Correction To His Excellency, John M. Morehead, Governor of Nebraska. Dear Sir: I have the honor to present herewith the report of this Department for the Biennial period ending November 30, 1916. Under the law as it existed two years ago. the Chief Clerk of the Board of Charities and Correction was also Secretary of the State Prison Board and Advisory Board of Pardons. At the last session of the Legislature, another duty was added— that of "State Parole Officer." The work of the Chief Clerk, without this added duty, was enough for any one man, and since this last responsibility was added I fear that at times some phases of the work have been neglected, to a certain degree at least, because I could not be at two places at the same time. Chapter 63, Section 2, of the Revised Statutes of the State of Nebraska, provides that the Board "Shall inquire into the whole system of public charities and methods of and practices in the correctional institutions of the state and counties, and to ascertain the condition thereof from time to time by inspec - tion or otherwise, especially of prisons, jails, infirmaries, pub - lic hospitals, asylums, reformatories and industrial schools." In accordance with that law and the instructions of your execellency, I have visited and inspected the State Institu - tions and the Jails and Poor Farms in all of the counties of this state except three, and have visited eighteen counties the second time. There are ninety-three counties in this state, and in less than a dozen of them is what would be classed a first class jail. A few counties have none at all. Some are located in low basements, dark, without city water, toilet accommodations or ventilation, and are of necessity very unsanitary and un - healthy. A large number are in old buildings, which are very unsafe, and where prisoners have to be kept locked inside the iron cages where they are deprived of exercise, in order to keep them at all, it being an easy matter to dig </seg>
            <seg id="p006">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD 6 through the walls if allowed the freedom of the corridors. Such jails as this I have unhesitatingly condemned and recom - mended that they be torn down and new up-to-date ones erected. We are now at the commencement of an era of jail building in this state. We are passing into the second stage of our history. Three new jails were completed last year and at least two more will be erected next spring, with the prospect of more to follow. In this rebuilding it is hoped that a step may be taken in advance: if not we may in a few years find ourselves again away in the rear. The modern county jail need not be designed as an ornament to the town, though it may be. Its interior should not be sacrificed to its exterior — its utility to its appearance. It should be a fire proof structure capable of holding securely its prisoners, and prac - tically protecting them from cremation. It should have modern sanitary improvements to protect not only the health of those confined therein, but also that of the community in which it is located. It should also be so constructed that suitable rooms for sex separation be provided. Few of the jails of the state are provided with separate rooms for female prisoners and with matrons to have charge of them. I say few — in the others the female prisoners are either cared for by the Sheriff's wife in her home, or locked up in an adjoin - ing cell in the same room with the male prisoners. At least one-half of the jails of the state are heated with stoves, and have no bathing facilities at all. These conditions should not be tolerated in any community, and one would think that the county boards would have pride enough to see that they are corrected. POOR FARM BUILDINGS Since my last report I have visited all of the Poor Farms in this state, and I find the great majority of the inmates are old people, and among them will be found the deaf, blind, feeble-minded, epileptic as well as the intelligent dependent, but by force of circumstances this is their home and all the home they have, and as I said in my last biennial report: ""The most sacred place to any one. whether rich, or poor, is home" and it should be as attractive and clean as it is possible to have it, and some of the Poor Farm buildings are clean, but some of them. I am sorry to say, are not. It is not altogether the fault of the Superintendent either, but get right down to </seg>
            <seg id="p007">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 7 the root of the evil and it is easily ascertained that the greater fault lies with the County Boards. They want to make a pood financial showing, so that they may be continued in office, and let the Poor Farm take care of itself, well knowing that not one in fifty of the legal voters of his district ever visit the farm. I wish that all of the County Boards and Super - intendents might hold a meeting and assemble at the Poor Farm at Plattsmouth, in Cass County, where I think some of them would get their eyes opened. The buildings and beds at this farm are absolutely clean; the chicken house is swept out, and the cow barn is washed out. every morning. The cement platform where the hogs are fed is washed off after each meal and the farm implements cleaned off and put in their place in the implement shed, and everything about the premises is in excellent shape and idicate a well kept and prosperous institution. Thanks to a good County Board and Superintendent. While this place receives praise (and I love to give credit where credit is due) there are some others that are very poorly managed, both by the County Board and Superin - tendent : in some instances old wooden bed steads are used. the bedding dirty, no bathing facilities, and the house full of vermin. In these cases I have tried to have conditions im - proved by advising with the County Board and the Superin - tendent and I hope that some good results have been accom - plished. INDETERMINATE SENTENCE AND PAROLE. In the year 1911 the Legislature of this state passed ami enacted into law, what is known as the Indeterminate Sentence Law and at the same time created a State Prison Board. This law became effective in July of that year. The Indeterminate Sentence Law provides that, "Every person over the age of eighteen years, convicted of a felony or other crime punishable by imprisonment in the peniten - tiary, excepting murder, treason, rape and kidnapping, if judgment be not suspended or a new trial granted, shall be sentenced to the penitentiary : but the court imposing such sentence shall not fix the limit or duration of the sentence, but the term of imprisonment of any person so convicted shall not exceed the maximum nor be less than the minimum term provided by law for the crime for which the person was </seg>
            <seg id="p008">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD 8 convicted and sentenced." Such a law, in substance, is now in force in twenty or twenty-five states of this union. In some states there is no minimum sentence — a prisoner is given the maximum sentence only ; while in other states no minimum or maximum is fixed but the person is merely sentenced to the peni - tentiary and in both of these instances the length of time to be served is determined by the State Prison Board, and we think this is just, for the reason that a crime has no com - mercial value. A judge who has possibly never seen the prisoner and knows nothing of his past history or tempera - ment cannot estimate the amount of punishment to equal the offense. One person suffers ten times as much as another from the effect of a blow equally inflicted upon them, and one prisoner suffers more in one month than another does in a year, and it is left to the Prison Board, after watching the prisoner's actions and learning of his past, and his desire to rehabilitate himself and become a good citizen, to determine the length of his confinement in the penitentiary. During the last two years paroles have been granted to 419 prisoners, mostly to those known as first termers, and since July 1, 1911, when the Parole Law became effective paroles have been granted to 869 prisoners. Of this number eighty - two per cent have made good. Of the eighteen per cent who failed to make good, a great number have been returned to the penitentiary by the Board for violation of the terms of their parole. While these 869 men were out on parole, serv - ing time under restrictions, they have earned for themselves, and those dependent upon them, the sum of $156,785.18. STATE INSTITUTIONS The State Institutions are all in excellent shape. They are without exception clean and sanitary and in as good condi - tion as it is possible to have them. The Superintendents, while their work varies according to the different institutions, are doing their best to make their wards comfortable. The question of labor for the convicts at the Penitentiary, since the contract system has by law been abolished, seems to be an unsolved problem. Under the heading of Peniten - tiary, in this report, I recommended that three or four hun - dred acres of land be purchased so that more of the convicts might be employed upon the farm, but even if that is done, it will be inadequate to give employment to all the men con- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 9 fined in the penitentiary. I desire to suggest another remedy which is this: Let the state buy twenty or forty acres of land in the eastern part of the state, upon which is a good stone quarry, and if thought best, another such piece in the extreme western part of the state, (for the purpose of saving freight:) equip these quarries with the necessary tools and crushers and establish a camp for the convicts as is done in Colorado and other states, and have the stone quarried and crushed and sell it to the different counties, townships or towns at actual cost for the purpose of building roads. If this stone could be bought at actual cost a greater amount of it would be used for road building than is now used. First build one good road across the state, and then branch off an other roads; pay the convicts a reasonable wage, a part of which could be paid to those dependent upon them, and the balance placed to their credit as is now done at the peni - tentiary. This plan would give employment to a large number of men for the whole year, winter as well as summer time. I sincerely hope that the Legislature may see their way clear to do something along this line. The State Institutions are under the direct supervision of the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions. I here - with append a short biography of each institution, together with the movement of the population of each, which will give a good idea of them, and the work accomplished. PENITENTIARY, LANCASTER. NEBRASKA W. T. Fenton, Warden. There has been no change in the official family of this institution since our last report. The many reforms adopted in the institution within the last four years have proven a success and notably so in the good discipline of the institu - tion. The men by their good conduct guard their many special privileges, namely : (1.) The freedom of the prison yard each Sunday morning where they are allowed to associate and converse with each other. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD 10 (2.) To talk with each other while eating their meals. (S.) The baseball sanies which are played in the prison yard two evening* of each week during the summer months, after the daily tasks are performed, between the prison teams and visiting teams from the city. (4.) During the fall and winter months a picture show is given to the inmates. These with other privileges have aided much in maintaining good order. The Legislature of 1915 enacted a law empowering the Hoard of Commissioners of State Institutions to give one month good time each year to those who attend school or work outside of the walls as trusties. Many have reduced their sentences, and at the same time improved themselves mentally and physically by availing themselves of these op - portunities. Within the last few months arrangements have been mad'* whereby the Warden has furnished each inmate with a dark bine uniform to be worn only on Sundays ami special occas - ions. Their uniformity of dress Bad neat and clean appear - ance is an incentive for each man to look up and in spite of the conditions, feel that he is a man. The industries of the prison are farming and manufactur - ing furniture for other state institutions and the general market. In addition to these two mentioned, a few men ar&lt;" employed in the making of brooms. The home farm consists of 296 acres. 2!) acres of which are taken up with buildings, yard and railroad. In the year 191"&gt; an additional 97 acres was rented: and during the year I91C, 198 acres extra was rented. The total value of the farm products during the biennium was $24."&gt;0f).:J6. For lands rented the total rental paid was $2,017.00. and the crop on the re.ited land was valued at $5,605.00. In the outside work, hog raising is one of the important industries. There was sold during the biennium $2,200.70 wortli of hogs, and slaughtered .")9,99O pounds of pork for home consumption, the value of which was $6,231.61. In the two years there were canned, pickled and preserved home grown vegetables valued at $815.20. I am strongly of the opinion that the State should purchase </seg>
            <seg id="p011">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 11 more land for the use of the Penitentiary, not less than three or four hnudred acres. With increased pasturage facilities and an increased acreage for the production of food, a better herd of cattle, more hogs for pork, bacon and lard could btj raised and fattened and in this way meat bills, which are always large, could be materially reduced. With ample land, properly improved, a system of farming and rotation of crops could be inaugurated which would go far toward making this institution self sustaining, besides lessen the expense to tax payers of maintenance. It would serve to furnish healthful employment for the men in outdoor labor, also afford an opportunity for the most progressive, systematic and up-to-date farming. By such methods, with diversified crops, and proper rotation in planting, much more satisfactory results could be secured and a greater profit realized than at present. A complete new power plant at an approximate cost of sf&lt;i&gt;0.( 100.00 is being installed in the prison yard whereby it furnishes light and power for the institution, and in addition to same, it furnishes the light for the Orthopedic Hospital, the Lincoln Insane Hospital. Capitol Building, and grounds and the Governor's Mansion. The evening school continues in a most satisfactory manner. The enrollment and average attendance has increased to such an extent that it is difficult to find room for the classes. The law contemplated holding school nine months each year, but owing to the transeient nature of the student body, entering and leaving at all times on the Indeterminate Sentence of from one to a number of years, they being par ol able in ten months, it was found that having but nine months school each year many could not attend more than six months. To avoid this difficulty and to give to nil the full benefit of the school as well as the extra good time allowed, three days off for each month's attendance, it was thought best to continue the session practically throughout the year. In all. about four hundred different men have registered : the enrollment at times reaching as high as one hundred fifty, with .in average attendance of one hundred and twenty - five. When it is considered that one-third of the prison popu - lation, because of the nature and time of their regular work, can not attend, the number that do is somewhat remark - ;ib'e. Another gratifying feature is the excellent deportment. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD There arc no formal rules to be observed. The school is an honor to the institution and there were but six cases of discipline during the biennium. The lively and sustained in - terest shows elearly that most of the men really desire to take advantage of the opportunity offered. The original course of study prevails, and is all the com - mon branches, with especial emphasis given to the most es - sential. The most special attention is given to the illiterate and those of but little education. The aim is to have all able to read, write and spell, and to use the fundamental opera - tions in numbers. The commercial course is popular, attract - ing many of the better educated. During the past year a new interest was noticed in the countries of South and Central America, a number expressing a desire to pt there when released. As these are all Spanish speaking states an elementary course was organized to enable those who may go. to speak, read and write the language. The class now numbers about twenty members and is certain to increase. The course is likely to be the most profitable in the school. Last year the policy of having all inmate teachers was adopted. There are many men received who have the neces - sary educational &lt;|iialifieations and it was thought advisable to give them these positions of honor and trust. It was also thought that under their instruction the men would feel and exercise a larger degree of mental freedom, a condition neces - sary to intellectual and spiritual growth. The plan is proving very satisfactory. No. of inmates Dec. 1. 1914 :16T) No. since received. 569 Xo. discharged, died, escaped, transferred, etc 537 No. inmates Nov. 30, 1916 397 STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL FOR BOYS, KEARNEY, NEBRASKA. • R. V Clark, Superintendent. The Nebraska State Legislature established this school in 1879 for both boys and girls. In 1891 the girls were removed to Geneva. Nebraska, leaving the boys. only, in the Kearney </seg>
            <seg id="p013">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 13 Institution. The first building was completed and the first inmate received in 1881. The Institution is now composed of seven large buildings besides barns, ice-houses, etc. At this date. November 30, 1916, the total enrollment is 200. At the commencement of the present biennium. December 1, 1914. there were 203 boys enrolled : 218 have been- com - mitted to the School, while 3 were received from other institu - tions: 4 were re-admitted, 45 returned from parole and 4 re - turned after having escaped, making the total number of boys received during the biennium 274. Four boys have gone out from the school having reached their majority, 4 have been transferred to other institutions, 6 have been released to parents or friends: 257 have been paroled and have not returned during the period; 6 have escaped and have not been returned during the period; making the total number of boys having gone from the School during the biennium 277. Three more boys have left the school than have been received so the enrollment has been reduced from 203, December 1, 1914, to 200. December 1. 1916. The school work has been very tatiafaetory and efficient in the instruction up to and partly including the tenth grade. Other than school work the boys are trained in the various trades of laundering, printing, carpentering, shoe making, tailoring, painting and farming. The school is proud of its band composed of 42 boys who have done much to advance themselves in their knowledge of music. Twelve boys compose the State Industrial School Orch - estra. The needs of the school are a hospital, a new chapel and gymnasium. It is a great undertaking, for the Superintendent when you stop to think of it — to reform this little army of boys in their habits, to teach them how to take care of their bodies, to give them an education, and at the same time to teach them a trade so that when they go out into the world again they are equipped to battle for themselves. GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, GENEVA, NEBRASKA. Miss Lydia J. McMahon, Superintendent. In the year 1891 the Girls' Industrial School was estab - lished. Before that time both boys and girls were at the Industrial School at Kearney. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD 14 During this biennial period the New Auditorium was com - pleted, which is of great benefit to the school. It was erected at a cost of fct5.000.00 and is a reinforced concrete, fire-proof structure, 48x120 feet, and consists of four floors. The base - ment of the old building, formerly used as general kitchen and girls' dining room, has been transformed into a spacious playroom, with bath and dressing rooms. The school now has three large recreation rooms for the special family di - versions, and the girls are classified as follows: Family "A," re - ceiving ward and girls who need to be segregated ; Family "B," the bright, intelligent, normal and progressive girls; Family "C," children from three and one-half to fourteen years of age. This classification of the wards has made it possible to carry on the work with a greater degree of efficiency. I agree with the Superintendent when she says that these very young children should be transferred to the Home for Dependent Children at Lincoln, and the feeble minded to the Feeble Minded Institute at Beatrice; and the same thing should apply to other institutions who have inmates of these classes. The steam heating plant and the machinery in the laundry has been greatly improved, and the septic tank is disposing of the sewage which in the past years caused so much serious trouble and annoyance. Some of the girls admitted are seventeen years of age or over and all of them must be discharged when they become of age, or at the age of eighteen years. With this class very little can be accoplished in the way of reformation in so short a time. The girls are required to attend school four and one-half hours each day. They are also instructed in music, domestic science, sewing, house work, moral and religious training. Sunday school and chapel services are conducted every Sun - day afternoon or evening, and at 8:30 every morning they have general assembly and morning prayer. The school is fortunate in being supplied with instruments, and a brass band of twenty-four pieces and an orchestra of fifteen pieces are maintained, which under the instructions of J. Wm. Fagan, Director of Music, are doing marvelous work. The band was assembled the evening I visited the school and four or five pieces were rendered which would do </seg>
            <seg id="p015">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 15 &lt; i-redit to a much older and more pretentious organization. The buildings are clean and sanitary in every respect and Miss McMahon. "Mother," as the girls call her, and of the name she is proud, is doing a wonderfully good work and is the right person for the place site occupies. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION No. present Dec. 1. 1914 HX&gt; No. since received 91 No. discharged 62 No. transferred to other institutions 5 .) 191 191 INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD. Miss Lena E. Ward, Superintendent. The purpose of this Home is two-fold: first, to give care and training to young girls, who have been unfortunate, or who, through lack of parental care are in danger of going wrong. Over sixty-five p«?r cent of the girls, who come to this Home, come from broken homes, where it was impossible for them to obtain the schooling and training necessary to develop in - telligent, upright, self-sustaining young women. Second: to give the unfortunate child a chance to be born under the best possible conditions, so that it will not, through neglect and improper nourishment, be forced to go through this world physically disabled. Also to see that it is placed in a home when the conditions are such that the mother can - not keep it, where it will have an equal chance in the world with children of more fortunate birth. Some of the children born in this Home are now university graduates, business men. holding positions of honor and trust, faithful house-wives, teachers, bookkeepers and stenographers; surely the state has been well paid for the kindness shown them. The training given a girl while in the Home enables her to go out into the world again and live a new life. She sees life from an entirely different viewpoint. No. released to parepts No. paroled No. present Nov. 30, 1916 . 8 .115 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD In the Home is a school of letters, where the girl who has not had school privilges, or who has not taken advantage of them, may be taught. Then there are special classes in sew - ing, domestic science, nursing and caring for children, where any one who has had school privileges and who desires to take up these lines of work, may do so. The girls are not only trained mentally and physically, but morally and spiritually. Each evening the girls assemble in the chapel, where the Bible and other books are read, and talks along the line of morality and right living are given. During the past biennium a great many improvements have been made. Perhaps the one most appreciated is the splendid quarters provided for the children, where they have an abundance of fresh air and sunshine; also a nice, neat little hospital for the care of any sick babies. The two main buildings have each received a coat of stucco, which adds very much to the appearance of the buildings, as well as making them much more comfortable. At the beginning of this biennium, there were 65 inmates in the Home ; 142 have been received, making 207, who have been cared for. 101 were discharged, 22 paroled ; 10 died, leaving in the Home at the close of the biennium 74. HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN Miss Etta Caton, Agent. At the close of the biennium, Nov. 30, 1916, the Home is temporarily located at 1345 G Street, Lincoln. Shortly after the beginning of the biennium, Dec, 1914, the Home was burned out at 1425 F Street, and it became necessary to find another location at once and to accept what could most readily be secured, so the vacant house at 1345 G Street, was secured at a rental of $40.00 per month. The house was old and out of repair and much too small. This is the third move since adopting the boarding plan of caring for dependent children, and the fact that it has been necessary to do institutional work for seven years without a permanent location and without working facilities has been a great handicap, rather expensive to the state and a hardship upon the children. Hence it gives a feeling of pleasure and relief to know that the new institutional building for the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 17 Home for Dependent Children at 10th and South Streets, Lincoln, is nearing completion and will soon be ready for occupancy. The Legislature of 1915 appropriated $27,500 for the erection of this building, and $2,500 for the purchase of land. Notwithstanding the inadequate facilities, the Home has been called upon to handle an increasingly large number of cases each year. During the biennium just closing there have been applications for the admission of 456 persons. Of this number 212 were received into the Home and the remaining 244 were provided for in other ways. In the same period of time there has been received 421 applications from persons wanting to take children. Before the placing of a child the home is carefully investigated, and if found satisfactory, the child is placed on trial. If, at the expiration of the trial period, there is general satisfaction, the child may then be adopted. The plan of the Home is to place every child in a permanent family as soon as it is ready for such a home and a suitable home is secured. Children who have been placed in homes are visited at in - tervals of a few months to a year. During the biennium 628 visits to homes is which children have been placed, were made, and the Agent has visited 336 prospective homes. ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL, LINCOLN. Dr. H. Winnett Orr, Superintendent. The Nebraska Orthopedic Hospital was created by an act of the Legislature of 1905, its object being to provide for the care of the destitute, crippled and deformed children of Nebraska, a preliminary survey showing that a considerable number of children in this state were diseased and crippled and needed hospital care of a kind for which there were no facilities. The new hospital was then located in a portion of one of the buildings of the Home for the Friendless, in Lincoln. The first patient was received on October 1, 1905. \o. being cared for Dec. 1, 1914 *Jo. received during biennium \ T o. discharged from custody &lt;o. in charge of Home Nov. 30, 1916 .22: ..2i: ... 9: .34 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD In 1911 the entire plant formerly occupied by the Home for the Friendless was turned over to the Orthopedic Hospital, and remodeled throughout for the new work. The Legisla - ture of 1913 provided a new Hospital building at a cost of $4o,000. This building has been finished and occupied since March 1. 1915, and contains new and modern office rooms, library, reception rooms, dining rooms, school rooms, labora - tory, surgical department complete, and three wards with a capacity of forty beds. The building is fire proof and the different floors communicate by inclines instead of stairways. A substantial addition has also been made to the boiler room during the last year. The Hospital is designed primarily for the free treatment of children who are crippled or deformed or suffering from disease or defects likely to eventuate in deformity, such as tuberculosis of the bones or joints, hare-lip, club foot, hernia, fractures, dislocations, enlarged tonsils, adenoids, etc. The great interest in this work manifested by the state officers, members of the Legislature, members of the medical profes - sion and even by the people at large, has been in a large measure responsible for the rapid development and progress of the institution. In return, the hospital can point to a record of more than 1,000 children who have been cured, or greatly benefitted by the hospital and educational care they received at this institution. It is hoped that the generous support, both moral and finanical, already accorded the Ne - braska Orthopedic Hospital will be continued to assist in its further usefulness. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Number of surgical operations performed during this bien- nial period 467. HOSPITAL FOR INSANE. LINCOLN Dr. B. F. Williams, Superintendent The hospital for the Insane, at Lincoln, was established in the year 1870, and on the 26th day of November of that year &lt;o. patients Dec. 1, 1914 107 'io. since received 732 &gt;Jo. discharged 715 ■Jo. enrolled Nov. 30, 1916 J 124 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 19 the first patient was received. A narcotic ward for the treat - ment of inebriates was provided for by the Legislature of 1905. This law provides that this class of patients shall not be placed in the same ward with the insane. This feature of the law has been ignored for the reason that no housing facilities have ever been erected. i A fire proof addition to the male division of the Hospital, costing $30,000, has been erected but not yet completed. A sun porch has been added to the male hospital building, and a corridor connecting this with the new addition. New tun - nels are being constructed connecting the old kitchen to the new addition. A new laboratory and morgue building is being constructed also. Religious services are held each Sunday morning at 9 :30. The Institution orchestra and choir, made up of persons con - nected with the Institution, supply the music. A library for the patients has been provided. Patients are given library privileges, making their own selections, and are permitted to go to the library to read current periodicals and litera - ture, or listen to readings given by the librarian. On Tuesday evenings a moving picture show is given; and on Friday night a patient's dance is held. An occasional entertainment is secured outside of these, and the large amusement hall is quite generally occupied. During the day - time when not used, for these purposes, it is made to serve as a gymnasium, where tennis, basket ball and other games are played by the inmates. The population at this institution is gradually increasing, and while new buildings are being added each year, they soon fill up, and new ones will have to be provided. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION of inmates Dec. 1, 1914. 724 'Jo. since received 679 &lt;o. died 142 &lt;o. discharged. _ 510 *o. enrolled Nov. 30. 1916 751 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD 20 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, NORFOLK, NEBRASKA Dr. G. E. Charlton, Superintendent. The Hospital, which was established by an act of the Legis - lature of 1885. was burned to the ground in 1901, and all patients were removed. This was followed by four years of disuse and inattention. The Hospital possesses a site which in its natural beauty and possibilities is unequalled in the state, and the pre-de - termined plan has been well carried out in the rebuilding of the institution, so that there is at this time seven modern hospital cottages and the administration building, all well situated. Besides these buildings there are the power plant, laundry, general kitchen arid dining room, and store room. These units are all well situated in the rear center of the ad - ministration and cottage buildings. One new building, which was provided for by the last Legislature, is nearing comple - tion. This building is of fire proof construction and will provide for about one hundred patients. These buildings are all connected by an underground tunnel. The population for the last biennium shows the largest increase of any biennium since the establishment of the Insti - tution, and at the present time there are no vacancies. MOVEMENT OF- POPULATION Population Dec. 1. 1914 Admitted for first time Re-admitted 457 293 1 1 On parole at beginning of biennium Escaped at beginning of biennium ... 52 i:s 892 Discharged during biennium 149 Died in Institution 90 Died on parole 3 Paroled and not returned 66 Escaped and not returned 15 Population Dec. 1, 1916 569 892 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 21 NEBRASKA STATE HOSPITAL, INGLESIDE Dr. Wm. S. Fast, Superintendent. Following an act by the Legislature during the session of 1887, purchase of a small tract of land two and one-half miles west of the business section of Hastings was made, and soon thereafter the erection of the main building of the Nebraska State Hospital at Ingleside was begun. The appropriation contemplated the erection of a building sufficient to accommo - date approximately three hundred patients. During the years past there has been added much room to the original building until, as it stands, this one building accommodates about six hundred forty patients. There has also been added, for the accommodation of patients, three large buildings, known as the South Annex, the North Annex and the Northeast Annex. These buildings accommodate approximately five hundred ten patients, making a total capacity for patients of eleven hun - dred fifty. With the above number of patients present, which there are, it means a crowded condition of the Hospital. During the time the main buildings were being erected a gen - eral kitchen and dining room was also built. The last named building was constructed in such a manner, both from a standpoint of plans and material, that it has several times in the past twenty years been repaired and strengthened, and considering the fact that in this building, cooking for a patient and employee population of nearly thirteen hundred people must be carried on, the old building has long since outlived its usefulness. It is hoped that some arrangement can be made soon for the erection of a suitable building to take the place of this structure and that the sanitary diffi - culties of this old poorly constructed building may be elimi - nated. The state maintains at this Institution a modern laundry building with good equipment, wholly sufficient for the needs of its large population. Recreation and Amusement. Some ten years back the state constructed on the Hospital Campus a large Auditorium, the same being used almost daily for the amusement and recreation of patients. Non-sectarian religious services are regularly held in the assembly hall. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Generally once a week moving picture shows are given for the amusement of the patients, as is also other forms of amuse - ment, such as amateur theatricals, musical concerts, occasion - ally dances, etc., etc. Farm and Dairy More land has been added from time to time until at present the State owns six hundred forty acres adjacent to the Hospital. A dairy herd of Holstein cattle is maintained on the farm. Seventy-five cows are now being: milked. A modern sanitary dairy barn is used, and up-to-date measures are being used concerning the care of dairy barn and cows, also the latest approved methods in milking and caring for the milk are being practiced. The Hospital now is furnishing a large quantity of wholesome milk for its patients. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Male Female Total Patients present Dec. 1, 1914 722 405 1127 Patients received during biennium 277 136 413 Patients returned from parole 140 75 215 Patients returned from escape 48 48 1187 616 1803 Patients discharged during biennium. . 119 58 177 Patients paroled during biennium 138 76 214 Patients escaped during biennium 40 1 41 Patients died during biennium 144 77 221 Patients present Nov. 30, 1916 746 404 1150 1187 * 616 1803 During the past ten years all classes of insane have been admitted to this Hospital. Prior to ten years back this Insti - tution was used primarily for the care of the incurable insane, therefore many of the older patients of the other State Hospi - tals were transferred to Ingleside. The above fact makes our population yet appear to be composed principally of aged people. We have several hundred very aged patients. The death rate has been high, due to the fact that the majority of the population are aged and due to the further </seg>
            <seg id="p023">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 23 fact that many Senile Dementia cases have subsequently been admitted. The oldest patient committed to the Hospital in the past year was ninety-four years. All that the Hospi - tal can possibly do for such cases is to give them comfortable care. Many most gratifying results have been obtained in the treatment of the cases of Acute Mania. Hardly a week passes but that patients are sent home to their families with their mentality restored. The Medical Staff of Ingleside has in the past year, been doing much research work and are ever alert in giving atten - tion to the newer methods in treating and caring for the insane. At present the Staff is giving much attention to the treatment of certain forms of Epilepsy. While they are not yet ready to announce results of the research work they hope, within the next year, to be able to announce some definite conclusions. The tubercular patients of the Hospital are segregated and are receiving the benefits of special diet and pure air com - bined with the necessary medicinal measures. There has been no epidemics among the patients during the past biennium, the general health of the population is good. Officers and employees are working harmoniously and are ever keeping in mind that the State Hospital at Ingleside was built and is being maintained solely for the care, comfort and treatment of that part of Nebraska's population who are mentally ill. NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE MINDED BEATRICE, NEBRASKA. Dr. D. G. Griffiths, Superintendent Following an act passed by the Legislature in the session of 1885, the first building of the Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded Youth was soon thereafter commenced and on May 27, 1887, the first children were received into the institution. During the first year after the opening of the Institution about sixty children were received into the Institution. Within a short time more room was needed to shelter and care for the mentally defective children of the state and from time to time more land and buildings have been added until at present the farm comprises 300 acres and there are </seg>
            <seg id="p024">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD 24 eight large brick and stone buildings, used for the purpose of caring for the children. Also a new building erected during the past biennium which is used entirely for school purposes. These buildings are exclusive of the store rooms, laundry, boiler house, barns, etc. The Institution has under its care two classes of children. Out of the 527 present, approximately 250 are able to receive only custodial care. These are either idiots or low-grade im - beciles. The remainder of the 527 are able to benefit by the facilities held out to them by the institution in the way of education, both literary and vocational. The new school building which whs completed and ready for use on Sept. 15, 1916, has made it possible for the teachers to do much more in this line of work than the Institution has ever been able to do here-to-fore. This is made possible by being able to do for a greater number. A new picture show machine has been installed in the auditorium and about 300 children attend these moving picture shows on Tuesday night of each week. They enjoy it very much and it is quite a factor in their education, as at least one picture in each show is of an educational type. The health of the colony during the past biennium has been uniformily good. There have been no epidemics of any kind. A new dairy barn is at this time under course of construc - tion and everything is being done that is possible by the man - agement to make for the best communal life possible for this unfortunate class of our population both from a sanitary and beneficial standpoint. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION No. of inmates present Nov. 30, 1914. 470 No. of inmates received during biennium- 135 No. of inmates died during biennium. 42 No. of inmates discharged during biennium 36 No. of inmates on vacation Nov. 30, 1916 29 No. of inmates present Nov. 30, 1916 527 No. of inmates enrolled Nov. 30, 1916 556 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 25 SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF, OMAHA, NEBRASKA Prof. F. W. Booth, Superintendent. This Institute was provided for by the Legislature of 1869. During the first school year 12 pupils were enrolled : the number of all those who have attended this school is at date 957. At the close of this biennium there were 184 pupils in attendance, of whom 112 are being taught orally and 72 by means of silent methods. The school is now in process of change whereby more of the children are taught to speak and lip-read as from year to year the old manually taught pupil* are graduated to be replaced by younger orally taught chi? dren. The new primary building, completed a year ago, is now occupied. It is a modern building in every appointment, of reinforced concrete construction, hence as nearly fire-proof as a building can well be. The youngest children are eared for here, remaining four or five years, when they are trans - ferred to the main building. All the children attend school in the central school house and take their meals in the central dining room. The school has an industrial department in which cabinet making, wood carving; printing and gardening are taught to the boys and sewing, dressmaking, embroidery, domestic science, basketry, wood carving and laundrying are taught to the girls. Trained~and skilled instructors are employed in all departments of the school, it being recognized that the school can be excellent only to the degree that its teachers are thus thoroughly trained and skilled in the difficult work they are called upon to do. The school term extends from the middle of September to the middle of June, and the course of study requires twelve years for its completion, the pupils taking up in the final years American and English History, Physiology, Physics, Civil Government, Arithmetic, Algebra, Grammar and English Literature. The school is free to all children residents of Nebraska too </seg>
            <seg id="p026">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD 26 deaf to attend the public schools, no charge being made for board or tuition. No. of students at the school Nov. 30, 1014 168 SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND, NEBRASKA CITY N. C. Abbott, Superintendent. The name of this institution used to be "Institution for the Blind" but has been changed to "School for the Blind." The name often leaves t lie impression with different people that this institution is for the totally blind only. It is, however, as much for those with defective sight as for the totally blind. All people who are playing a large part in a community should write the institution whenever they hear or see a boy or girl that ought to get an education. If ministers, teachers, and public officers would make it a point to send in the names of those that ought to come to the institution, it would be doing a pood thing. There is a home-like atmosphere about the School for the Ulind. Teachers and pupils work together so harmoniously that there is no ill feeling whatsoever. When the pupils are in doubt about anything they feel free to go to the teachers for help. Not only is there a home-like atmosphere about the place but also a Christian atmosphere. Weekly Christian Endeavor meetings are held and a great deal of interest is shown in them. Pupils all go to Sunday school or church at least once every Sunday. Parents need not fear that their children are going out of a Christian influence for nine months of the year while down at the School for the Blind. The cost of having a boy or girl enrolled as a pupil is very small considering the amount of good received there. The parent or guardian must furish clothing, transportation to and from Nebraska City, stamps, and little incidentals such as hair cuts, hair ribbons, etc. The state gives free of charge board, room, bath, laundry, medical attendance and an edu - cation along literary, musical and industrial lines. The liter- Xo. sinee received No. graduated No. left for various reasons No. died No. at school Nov. 30. l'llfi . .. .18 .... 11 .... 30 .... 1 ...184 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 27 ary work follows, as nearly as possible, the work prescribed by the State Superintendent of Public Instructions — Arith - metic, Language, Grammar, Physiology and Hygiene, Read - ing. Spelling, History, Writing, and Nature Study. In the music .department there are three teachers. Besides the in - dividual lessons there is chorus work and an orchestra. In the girls' industrial department, they are taught needlework, the making of bead articles, knitting, crocheting and cooking. The boys are taught chair-caning, making of hammocks, fly - nets, brooms, carpet weaving and piano tuning. Each of the above courses is thorough. No person, for instance, can re - ceive a diploma in tuning unless he is prepared to tune and repair any piano that should come to his attention. Adults, who are not too old and who are anxious to learn a trade, are also admitted under certain conditions. The population of the school has remained about the same. There were 51 pupils at this school Nov. 30, 1914, and there are now 50, although the personnel has changed largely. SOLDIERS AND SAILORS HOME, BURKETT, NEBRASKA J. F. Walsh, Commandant. This Home was established in 1887, near the city of Grand Island. Here the state owns 640 acres of land. The people at the Soldiers Home are mostly soldiers of the Civil War (1861-1865) together with the wives and widows of such soldiers, and are now on the shady side of life, and as a con - sequence the death rate is large — 109 having died during the last two years. It is gratifying to know that our state has provided such good Homes for our disabled soldiers as are now found at Burkett and Milford. A great many changes and improve - ments have been made during the last two years, tending to make the Home better, and the out buildings more sanitary and convenient. The Hospital building which is nearly always filled, is in good shape and the physician and help are obliging and painstaking with the patients. In fact, there is a general </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 CHARITIES AND CORRECTION spirit of good fellowship prevailing in the Home, which is gratifying. On November 30, 1914 there were (313 males and 251 females) 564 No. since received (116 males, 77 females) 193 No. died (67 males, 42 females) 109 No. discharged (53 males. 23 females) 76 No. enrolled November 30. 1916 (309 males, 263 fe - males) 572 SOLDIERS AND SAILORS HOME, MILFORD, NEBRASKA. D. C. Rowden, Commandant. By an act of the Legislature in 1895, this Home was estab- lished. Here the state owns 35 acres of land, several acres of which is covered with natural timber. During the last biennial period the new Hospital building has been completed and is now well filled with patients. A new laundry building, for which an appropriation was made at the last session of the Legislature, is being erected and is now nearing completion, and when finished will he a credit to the Institution. The new well has been completed which affords plenty of good water. An elevator has been installed and is a great convenience, especially to the aged people. The main building has been painted from top to bottom and new floors put in. I am pleased to say that harmony seems to prevail at the Home. Males Females Total No. of members December 1, 1914 129 17 146 No. since received &gt;. 100 23 123 No. discharged or died 90 4 94 No. at the Home November 30, 1916.. 139 36 175 HOSPITAL FOR TUBERCULOUS, KEARNEY, NEBRASKA Dr. L. S. B. Robinson, Superintendent. This Hospital was provided for by an act of the Legislature in 1911, and the present site was selected by the State Board of Public Lands and Buildings. It is situated within the limits of the city of Kearney. The original site contained about 15 acres, but more land </seg>
            <seg id="p029">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD 29 has been added to it until now there are about 30 acres, upon which is a large sandstone building, originally built for a residence, and when purchased was used as a private hospital. Since the purchase by the state other buildings were added, among which was a large frame pavilion, with wide screened in porches, upon which the patients sleep the greater portion of the year. The Legislature of 1915 made an appropriation of $16,250.00 for a new hospital building and laboratory equipment, and a central heating plant and laundry buildings. These have all been erected and are now in use, which adds greatly to the usefulness and convenience of the institution. Much criticism has been made about the name of this in - stitution — "Hospital for Tuberculous" — and many think it should be changed to "State Tuberculosis Hospital" or "State Tuberculosis Sanitorium." either of which would be prefer - able to the present name. Co. of patients November 30, 1914.. Co. since received (o. died ■Jo. who otherwise left the Hospital \'o. of patients November 30. 1916. . 25 .165 . 31 .107 .. 52 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Movement of the Population of the Various State Institutions ll I it s f Slid . III? mi INSTITUTION - •= B £ s » . - INSTITUTION .g-ia" h~ o^lz^ State Penitentiary I 366 569| 934 537 397 State Industrial School, Kearney 203~274 ~477 277 200 Girls' Industrial School. Geneva 99 92 191 76 115 Total for Industrial Schools 302 336 668 353 315 Total for Industrial Schools Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford 65 142 207 133 74 Nebraska Hospital for Insane, Lincoln 724 679 1403 652 751 Hospital for Insane, Norfolk 457 435 892 323 569 Nebraska State Hospital, Ingleside J1127 676 1803 653 1150 Total for Hospitals for Insane 2308 1790 4098 1628 2470 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 222 212 434 93 341 j | 107 732 839 715 124 Soldiers and Sailors' Home. Milford Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett 146 123 269 94 175 564 193 757 1851 572 Total in Soldiers and Sailors' Homes no |_3X6 10M 470|J36|J05 78 527 168 58 226 42 184 Institute for Feeble Minded. Beatrice Nebraska School for Deaf, Omaha Nebraska School for Blind. Nebraska City 51 29 80 30 50 Tuberculous Hospital, Kearney 25 165 190 138 52 Total in all Institutions 4793 4514 9307 4026 5281 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 31 The following is compiled from the reports received from the county clerks relative to the care of the poor in the various counties for the year ending Nov. 30, 1916. Name of County Remarks Adams 10 8 20 Antelope Arthur Farm not operated. NF | 1 NF L__ Banner Blaine Boone NF Farm rented — income suffici- ent to care for poor. Box Butte Rents farm — pays $4.00 per week each inmate Boyd NF Brown NF I S Buffalo Burt Rents farm. Butler Cass Cedar j 61 61 j | NR Farm rented — pays $3.50 per week each inmate. Chase Chei ry NF I 1 NF I 30 NF I Cheyenne Clay (i 4! « 2.000 Farm rented — pays $3.50 per week each inmate. Colfax Cuming Cus'er Dakota Farm rented — pays $4.00 per week each inmate. Dawes Dawson Deuel XF Dixon Dodge 6 5 14. 13 Douglas Dandy .. 1214 269 NF Fillmore Franklin Frontier Furnas Farm rented — pays $5.00 per week each inmate. Cage 19 1 17 10 NF : I ! Garden Garfleld Gosper Grant _ NF ! 1 NF | 2 NF; I 1 Greeley Hall Farm not in operation. 3 2 8 •I «l Hamilton 9,300 10,500 Hill 4 41 24 2,000 fF I 5 350 350 6 5 61 1,541 2,541 5 5 5 1,000 2,240 5 5 ' 1.000 20 14| 18 3,315 4,485 36 36 1,700! 1,700 ! 1.283 9 5 6 500; 1,280 131 6! 7! 840 1,840 14 II 1 | I 660 6 4 1 1,226 5 4 5i 5! 10 1.484 5,000 NR 800 I 2.»3 I 62,000 8. 8| 51. 2.005 2.845 3 J' I 800 NK I 2! 487 487 3 3 2 1.683 1.200| 2,220 56 30 30 180i 180 1,280 9(10 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD larlan NF Hayes NF Hitchcock _| NP 141 8401 840 Holt NF Hooker NF toward | ) | Farm rented. Johnson | 2| 2| | NR Farm rented — pays $2.50 per week each inmate. Jefferson 11 S 161 1,100 1,820 Kearney j NF | | 43 1,168 1,168 Keith ! | j 21 150| 150 Farm rented— pays $10.00 per month each inmate. Kimball | NF | I 31 100| 100 Keya Paha NF Knox NF ; 10 2,300 2,300 Lancaster 241 26| 201 2,280 3,060 Lincoln NF Logan NF I 1 125 125 Loup NF | ! 7! 120 120 Madison 10 5 10 1,000 1,720 VIcPherson NF 5 240 240 Merrick 6 41 15J ' 1,275 Pa y* $*-00 Per week each ill' mate — Farm rented. Morrill ' NF | | j NR Nemaha 11 11| 6| 475 Pay $3.50 per week each in mate — rent farm. Nuckolls 3 I] | i NR Farm rented -pays $3.00 per week each inmate Nance | NF I ' I I Otoe 16! IB | 20| 5,958 6,798 Pawnee NF ] 10| 1,200 1,200 Perkins j NF | | I : Phelps ' NF | ' | NR Pierce ] 21 1| ' 350 Farm rented — pays $3.00 per NF week each inmate Ptatte ! 8' 7 7| 2,600 3,500 Polk I II II I 186 Farm rented — pays $3.50 per week each inmate Richardson S 8 20 2,500 3,700 Bed Willow..' 7 i 8 1,000| 1,660 Rock I NF I 51 350 1 350 Saline | 101 10 | \ 1,000 Sarpy I 1 1| 20 1,600 1,660 P»y» $3.00 per week Saunders ...I 14 14 33| 5,400] 6,600 Scotts Bluff..! NF I 3,600 3,500 Seward 11| 111 35! 1.350J 2,350 Sheridan ...J NF I I 27 2,709 2,709 Sherman NF 201 1,000; 1,000 Sioux |NFI | 1| 25 25 Stanton li | I 40 Pays $5.00 per week each in mate — farm rented. Th»yer | 3| 2| ] | 720 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 33 Thomas |NFJ |. I Thurston ....I NP I I NR 1,600 Valley 10 664| 654 Not In operation. Washington 6 7 5 2001 1,200 Wayne | 1| l| 4| 67l[ 931 Rent a farm — pay $6.00 per week each inmate Webster 1 1 . I NR | 600 Wheeler NP 14 576" 676 York &gt; 7 101 1,646 3,128 Total ! 1558 ! 558 1 671 1 64,745| 164,716 NP— No Farm NR— No Report NR— No Report </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD The following shows the report relative to the number of prison various county jails for the year ■ received from the various counties, prisoners who have been confined in the ending Nov. 30. 1916. Have K« Mia Have Kc Mia Hi.. Fa Mm Hate F. In. COUNTY |ail M.I- male on Adams Yes 62' 21 5 Antelope Yes 13' II 2 COUNTY COUNTY lail Mai* Mir on COl'NTY Jail M.lr male an COINTY Ull M«k lute on Adams Yea 62' 21 5 Johnson Yes 101 II 1 Johnson Yes 101 II 1 Antelope Yes 13' II 2 Kearney |Yea] 71 0| 0 Kearney |Yea] 71 0| 0 Arthur I No i 0 0 0 Arthur No | 0 0 0 Keith Tea| 8 1 0 2 Keith Yea 8 1 01 2 Banner !Ye»| l; 0 0 Banner |Ym| 1| 0! 0 Keya Paha 'Ye»| 6 0! 2 Keya Paha !Yesl 6 0! 2 Blaine jYes H oi 0 Blaine ]Yes V OJ 0 Kimball |Yesl 20 0 0 Kimball |Yes| 20 0 0 Boone |Ye»l 8.0 0 Boone |Yesl 8i . 0 0 Knox |Yes] 6 0 0 Knox |Yes! 6 01 0 Box Butte lYesI 221 01 0 Box Butte !Ym| 22| 0| 0 Lancaster Yes 684 62 0 Lancaster Yes 684 62 1 0 Boyd JYes! 2 0 0 Boyd |Yes! 2 0 0 Lincoln Yes 364 7' 15 Lincoln Yes 364 7 1 15 Brown |Yes 10 0 0 Brown |Yes 10 0 0 Logan Yes 1 21 01 0 Logan Yes 1 21 0| 0 Buffalo lYes 51 12 Loup |Yea! 2! 0 1 0 Buffalo JYes 51 1 2 Loup |Ye«! 2 0 1 0 Burt I No 20 (i 4 Burt ! No 20 01 4 Madison Yes 7! 0: 0 Madison Yes 7| 0: 0 Butler Ye«l 2 0 0 Butler lYeal 21 01 0 McPherson Yes 2 0| 0 McPherson Yes 2! 0] 0 Cass Yes 64 2! 3 Cas« JYes 64 2! 3 Merrick Yes 30 1 1] 0 Merrick Yes 30 1 1! 0 Cedar |Yes&gt; 21 0| 0 Cedar JYeal 21 0| 0 Morrill Yes, IBi 0 3 Morrill Yes, 161 0 3 Chase lYes! 1| 0 0 Chase 'Yes 1! 0 0 Nance Yes 20 0 3 Nance Yes 20 0 3 Cherry |Yesl 52! 1 3 Cherry |Yeal 521 1 3 Xemaha Yes' 121 0! 0 Neman* jYes' 12 1 0| 0 Cheyenne |Yes 132 0 3 Cheyenne iYes 132 0 3 Nuckolls iYes 40 31 0 Nuckolls IYe« 40 3| 0 Clay |Yes' 11 1 1 Clay |Yes' 11 1 1 Otoe |Yes! 44! 11 2 Otoe JYes| 44 1 1| 2 Colfax lYes 181 0 3 Colfax IYes 18 0 3 Pawnee Yes 16] 4! 1 Pawnee Yes 16 4 1 Perkins Ww 1 0' 0 Cumlng !Yes; 26' 21 3 Cumlng !Yesi 26' 2! 3 Perkins lYw 1 0| 0 Custer |Yw' 12| 0 0 Custer lYes 12! 0 0 Phelps Ye» 8 0J 5 Phelps Yes 8 0| 5 Pierce |Yeai 61 0' 0 DakoU Ye«| 10] II 0 Dakota ]Yes| 101 II 0 Pierce |Yes| 51 0' 0 Dawes Yes 20| II 1 Dawes lYes 20 l! 1 Platte jYeai 63; 3| » Platte !Yeaj 63; 31 0 Dawson iYes| 41' 3 2 Dawson IYes| 41' 3 2 Polk iYes 21 0 1 Polk iYes 21 0 1 Deuel lYes 2 0 0 Deuel lYes 2 1 0 0 Red Willow 'Yes| 7 0' 2 Red Willow 'Yesi 71 0! 2 Dixon Ye«; 10 1 0 Dixon Yes 10 1 0 Richardson Yes 83 4 4 Richardson Yes 83 4 4 Dodge Yes 1 1501 21| 15 Dodge Yes' 1501 21| 15 Rock Yes 3; Oi 0 Rock Yes 3 0! 0 Douglas |Yes 1450 6911 48 Douglas |Yes 1450 691 48 Sarpy |Yes 34 1 0 Saline lYea! 5 0 0 Sarpy |Yes 34 1 0 Dundjr Yes' 2' 0 0 Dundy Yes 2' 0 0 Saline |Teal BOO Flllmore 'Yes&gt; 61 0' 0 Fillmore Tm! 61 0! 0 Saunders |Yesl 22| 0| 3 Saunders lYesl 221 01 3 Scotts Bluff !Yes| 106 7 0 Franklin Yes 2 0| 0 FYanklin Yes 2 0! 0 Scotts Bluff 'Yesi 106 7 0 Frontier ! No ! 61 01 0 Frontier I No 51 01 0 Seward Yes 15 0 1 2 Seward Yes 15 0 1 2 Furnas |Ym| II 1 0! 0 Sheridan Yes! 501 31 2 Sheridan Yes! 501 3| 2 Furnas I Tea I 11! 0! 0 Gage Yes 51 0i 2 Gage Yes 51 0i 2 Sherman (Yes 4 0 0 Sherman |Yes 4 0 0 Garden lYes 2 Oi 0 Garden Yes 2 1 Oi 0 Sioux 'Yea| «| 01 0 Sioux 'Teal 81 0 0 Garfleld |Yesl 0' 0 0 Stanton Yes 71 2 0 Garfleld ITeal 0' 0 0 Stanton Yes 71 2 0 Gosper lYes I 1 0 0 Gosper IYes I 1 0 0 Thayer !Yea| 18 0 2 Thayer iYeal 18 0 2 Thomas Yesi II 0| 0 Grant lYes 1 SI 0' 0 Grant IYes! «l 0 0 Thomas Yesi II 0| 0 Greeley lYes! 201 2 2 Greeley lYes! 201 2 2 Thurston |Tea| 32! 01 0 Thurston I Teal 321 01 0 Hall lYesI 107 8 12 Hall ITeal 107 8 12 Valley Yes' 6| 0! 0 Valley Yes' 6| 0! 0 Hamilton lYes 16 1| 2 Hamilton lYes 16 II 2 Washington Yes 10 1 0| 0 Washington Yes 10 0| 0 Harlan I No ' 2! 0; 0 Wayne Yes! 5| 0', 0 Wayne Yes] 5 0', 0 Harlan I No ' 2 0| 0 Hayes Yesl 1! 0! 0 Hayes Yesi 11 0! 0 Webster Yes! 17! «j 1 Webster Yes 17' 2 1 Hitchcock IYe«l 71 01 0 Hitchcock lYea! 71 01 0 Wheeler |Yea| 1! 01 0 Wheeler ITeai 1! 01 0 Holt |Y«.I 16! 5 4 York lYea| 5| 0 0 1 1 York lYea| 5| 01 0 Holt lYea! 16! 5 4 Hooker |Ye«l 1! 0 0 Hooker ITeal II 0 0 Howard |Yes| t] 0| 0 Howard |Yes| (j 0| 0 Total 4286 845 168 Total ' 4286 845 168 Jefferson lYes 24' 0' 0 Jefferson IYes 24' 0' 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 35 I have made some inquiry into private charities, and have visited several of those finding homes for children, and here- with give the movement of population of those from which reports have been received. CHILD SAVING INSTITUTE, OMAHA, NEBRASKA 42nd and Jackson Streets. Wm. A. De Bord, President. Alma N oilman, Office Secretary. No. of children at the Institute Not. 30, 1914 44 Since received 1061 Total number given care and protection during the biennium 1505 No. placed in homes under adoption during bien - nium 73 No. of deaths during biennium 9 No. that otherwise passed from our care 1368 No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1916 55 They accept children who are legally relinquished or com- mitted by order of the court and find for them permanent homes. They also give temporary shelter and care to de- pendent children, receiving such payment as those responsible for them are able to make. HOME OF THE GOOD SHEPHERD. OMAHA, NEBRASKA 40th and Jones Street. Mother M. Raphael, Secretary. No. cared for at the Home Nov. 30. 1914 182 No. since received 139 No. discharged 156 No. died 5 No. being eared for Nov. 30, 1916 160 No. in protectory (children from 3 to 15 years old) 39 This is a large institution for the reclaiming and education of young girls, who have strayed from the path of virtue and dut.v. It is non-sectarian, and grants admission to girls and women in need of protection, regardless of creed, and they are permitted to profess and practice whatever religion they </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD choose. Application for admission should be made to the Secretary. SALVATION ARMY RESCUE HOME, OMAHA, NEBRASKA 3824 North 24th Street. Elizabeth Caldwell. Matron No. of persons being cared for Nov. 30, 1914 * 31 No. since received 188 No. passed from their care 193 No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1916 26 Homeless and fallen women willing to reform are given care. Money is secured by donation of friends and by small fees from those who are able to pay for their care. None are refused admission whose cases are deserving LUTHERAN ORPHANAGE, FREMONT, NEBRASKA J. F. Gnuse, Superintendent. No. in the Institution Nov. 30, 1914 9 No. since received 59 Total number given care and protection during biennium 68 No. placed in homes for adoption 24 No. placed in homes under contract ,....16 No. of deaths 1 No. that otherwise passed from their care 13 No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1916 14 Orphans or dependent children are received provided they are relinquished or legally committed and are subject to adop tion or are given to the Home's care until past school age or until of legal age. Money for maintenance is secured by charitable donations of Lutheran church members in Nebraska ST. JAMES ORPHANAGE, BENSON, NEBRASKA John Roche, Superintendent. No. being cared for Nov. 30, 1914 130 No. since received 247 Total number given care during biennium 377 No. placed in homes under adoption 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 37 No. placed in homes for adoption hut not yet legally adopted 6 No. placed in homes under contract 3 No. that otherwise passed from care of Ophanage.,224 No. being cared for Nov. 30. 1916. 140 Orphans, half orphans or dependent children arc entitled to admission. They are supported by voluntary contributions. During the past year a nursery whs completed at a cost of $17,000.00. This boildiag ■ capable i f taking care of from thirty to forty infants. TABITHA HOME, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA 46th and Randolph Streets. No. at the Home Nov. 30, 19M No. since received :.:? :&gt;:} No. discharged .26 No. died (all old people) No. at the Home Nov. 80, 1!)16 in Til Of this number thirty-one are children and thirty-nine are old people. Six of these old people are entirely helpless, others partly helpless or feeble minded and fifteen are be - tween eighty and ninety years old. ODD FELLOWS HOME, YORK, NEBRASKA. J. H. Wilson. Superintendent, Of this number fifty-five are children and twenty are adults. Those admitted are ageil and indigent Odd Fellows and their wives, widows and orphans of deceased members, and children where father and mother .ire both deceased. The above rule applies to members of the Rebekah Degree. All children at the Home are attending the public school in the citv of York. \o. being cared for Nov. 30, 191 Jo. since received Co. died &gt;«o. who left for any cause tfo. at the Home Not. 30, 1916 .... .65 f&gt;0 .11 ..:*9 .75 ;i </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD NEBRASKA MASONIC HOME, PLATTSMOUTH NEBRASKA Wm. S. Askwith. Superintendent. No. at the Home Nov. 30, 1914 60 No. since received 3\&gt; No. died 11 No. who left for any cause 15 No. being cared for Nov. 30. 1916 titi Of which twenty-two are children and forty -four adults. Superannuated members of the Masonic Fraternity, their wives, widows, mothers, sisters and children are admitted. Another Home for hoys and girta lias been erected at Fit mont, Nebraska, but I have no report from it. MOTHERS JEWELS' HOME, YORK, NEBRASKA B. Spurlock, Superintendent. No. of children in the Home Nov. 30, 1914 63 No. since received 70 No. jrone from the Home 48 No. in the Horn.- Nov. 30, 1916 85 This Home receives and cares for dependent children and is under the auspices of the Women's Home Missionary So - ciety of the M. E. Church, and is supported by this society and by voluntary contributions. BETHLEHEM CHILDREN'S HOME, OMAHA, NEBRASKA 34th and Meredith Avenue. P. M. Lindberg, Superintendent. No. of persons in the Home Nov. 30. 1914 16 No. since received No. being cared for Nov. 30. 1916 17 This Home is maintained by the lmmanuel Deaconess Insti - tute. Contributions and free will offerings are received from individuals anil from the Sunday schools of the Nebraska Con - ference of the Augimtana Synod. No. since received 7 Xo. discharped 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">CHARITIES AND CORRECTION 39 FINANCIAL STATEMENT During the biennium this department has expended the following amounts : Respectfully submitted Chief Clerk. -^5£&gt; J. W. SHAIIAX, From an unexpended balance of appropriation of 1913 and 1914 $ 406.51 For salary of chief clerk 625.00 For salary of stenographer 350.00 [ft Appropriation of 1915 and 1916. For salary of chief clerk $3,000.00 Amount expended Dec. 1, 1916 2,500.00 Balance unexpended 500.00 For salary of stenographer 1,680.00 Amount expended Dec. 1, 1916 1,400.00 Balance unexpended 280.00 For office expense, books, postage, etc. 600.00 Amount expended Dec. 1, 1916 310.60 Balance unexpended 289.40 For traveling expense 1,400.00 Amount expended Dec. 1. 1916 574.01 Balance unexpended 825.99 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD List of Societies, Institutions, Homes or Corpora - tions Supported Wholly or in Part by Benevolence Name and Location. Supervised and maintained by Special claw cared OMAHA House of Hope Peoples Institutional Home (or aged 968 N 27th St. Church Voluntary contributions Salvation Army Rescue Home, 3824 N 24th St. Home of the Good Salvation Army Penitent (alien women Voluntary contributions Sisters of Good Fallen and wayward Shepherd Shephe-d Women and girls Immanuel Deaconess In - stitute, 34th and Mere- Immanuel Lutheran Care and education of Deaconess Association friendless children. dith Ave. Child Saving Institute Private Corporation Care of and finding homes (or homeless and neglected children. Temporary care of and finding homes for 619 So. 42nd St Mother Jewels' Home Womans' Home Mis - sionary Society of M. E. Church Grand Lodge of Nebr. York, Nebr orphans. Nebr. Masonic Home Indigent Masons and their families. Plattsmouth, Nebr. Odd Fellows' Home Grand Lodge of Nebr. Members of I. O. O. F. Rebekahs and widows and children of Odd York, Nebr Fellows. Tabitha Home Lutheran Synod Cares for aged and in - firm $300 entrance lee. Also finds homes for dependent children. Care of orphans and de - pendent children. 45th and Randolph, Lincoln, Nebr. St. Thomas Orphanage Sisters of Mercy South 27th St., Lincoln, Nebr. Christian Orphans' Private Corporation Care of orphans and destitute children. Home, Holdrege, Nebr. Care of orphans Lutheran Orphans' Ger. Ev. Lutheran Orphan Home. Society Home Fremont, Nebr. St. Joseph's Home for Aged, West Point, Nebr St. James Orphanage Indigent deserving aged Sisters of Mercy Care of orphans and de - pendent children. Sisters of Mercy Benson, Nebr. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>