<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Economic Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley (Keystone) Reservoir</title>
               <date value="18??">October 1937</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Economic Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley (Keystone) Reservoir Bulletin 311 . October, 1937 .Frank Miller and H. C. Filley Department of Rural Economics *'T T ——- OAWSON ' I lumu HALL Location of the Kingslcy Reservoir on the North Platte River The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln . . W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
         <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page Sumnur\ and Cumlusions Widespread Interest in Irrigation Location and Size of Kinsley Dam and Rt-.crvoir y Irrigation Arr.i Q Climate 10 CrmviDjt Season Incn-ase in Yields Soii Productivity Crop Rotation Y.el.ls Under Present (imdiiinns and Estimated Yields under Irrigation . ifi Eiumatnl Increase- in Pr™lu t -ti,,n &lt;\ j 1 lie Rcser\oir Area , . 4-1 Population c . . c -18 Size ot Farms ... 49 I ranspart.it on 19 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">SUMMARY AND CONCLUSIONS ... Crop production in central and western Nebraska is uncertain. Lack «£ dependable moisture is the most important limiting factor. Irrigation is successfully practiced in several areas of the state. Rainfall shortage over a long period and extreme drouth in recent years have stimulated interest in its extension. , &#132; .' .',¦¦¦. ¦ , Most of the strcamnW in areas suited to irrigation is now appropriated for use. Extension depends upon the storage of water now lost as "runoff 1. Most of this loss occurs during the dormant season. ', ¦¦ Numerous irrigation projects that must depend upon stored water have been outlined. One of the most extensive is the Central Nebraska Public Power and Irrigation District. The water supply for this project will be drawn from the Kingsley reservoir. Kingslcy dam is located on the North Plane river nine miles northeast of Ogallala in Keith county, Nebraska. Water impounded by the dam will form a lake with about 32,000 acres of water surface in Keith county. Storage capacity is approximately 2,000,000 acre-feet. It is anticipated that Adams, Buffalo, Dawson, Gosper, Hall, Kearney, Lincoln, and Phelps counties will benefit from irrigation made possible by the dam. These counties have 2,083,372 acres of high-grade soil, of which 1,672,894 acres are cultivated. Approximately 900,000 acres oE this land may be placed under irrigation. The climate of the area is semiarid. Weather is a distinct hazard in crop production because of extreme variability in annual and seasonal rainfall. Average crop yields without irrigation for the ten-year period ending 1935 were as follows: ..¦¦'•. ': . . ¦ :. ¦ Crop -.' Tons or bushels per am Alfalfa .;..;;¦.;,............................. .....1.82 Barley ..:......; :20.8'f Corn .17.67 oats; ....;¦.. ;.... :. .22.90 Potatoes ;.........'¦¦;..;.- ....'. ..64.80 Wheat ........... .... / ........ — ... —... 13.00 ; Crop yields under irrigation should average not less than the.following: :' Crop ¦¦..:;¦.¦¦ . Tops or bushels per acre Alfalfa ...;. i.:.. ...Y.: .&lt; 3.0 Barley j:................... .- ... 45.0 Corn .: .. &lt; ;........ 40.0 Oats .;..... ..,.......:............. .'..'.. 45.0 Potatoes ........... ...:... . ..... .170.0 Sugar Beets .... \..^.....:.......................... 10.2 Wheat | '. :.;..'.:.;..'........................... 20.0 , Fattening livestock enroute to market from the western range country should be - come a dominant farm enterprise. . The estimated net increase in production due to irrigation in the area is 25,805 carloads annually.¦ , ..'.. '.¦... Outshipmcnts: from stations serving the reservoir area, excluding livestock which were grazed on; the surrounding territory, averaged 42.7 carloads annually over the | : ten-year period ending in 1936. . ; v Total outshipments, including livestock, averaged 523.4 carloads. •:¦ It is estimated that construction of Kingslcy dam alone will add 11,395 carloads o£ freight to the traffic of the railroad serving the reservoir area. This is 290 times the average outgoing carload freight, except livestock, from the four stations serving the reservoir area.' ! ¦. ;. ¦'-. An additional 6,530 carloads of material and equipment from outside sources will be used at various places in completing the irrigation project. </seg>
         <seg id="p004">c,on°,7«o°cal Cdr rUCtiOn tak'C" fr°m WitHn thC ar" Wi" a^" 3" addi- Scorn Bluff county has 10.2 per cent as much area as the eight counties that will benefit from irrigation water stored in the Kingslcy reservoir Freight forwarded from all stations in Scotts Bluff county during the ten-year ncriod )t?0.0 M3^ 10 '752-3 C"loadS annUa"y- 'n th-^t gco"ravePra^ Incoming freight at all stations in Scotts Bluff county for the ten-year period end!™ a g 9eJ2 a9 V," B TrcaSs 2 MP " '» ** " S*tt actiWty SC°ttS BUff C°Umy 'rrißation haS bcC" a Vhal faCtor in stimul =«"S business fam^and inrfof"! T™ 0 ""'T'-' "5C °f ''" °" Probabili'y will lead to smaller larnis and increased farm population. Electric current generated by release of stored water will probably be a source of Lhcap pmver ihrouj;hout central Nebraska. ' r" °' patcd" rSisiinL. nf faC'Ori" ,tO P'°«ss farm products grown within the area is antici - pated. Lxisiinß plants may be enlarged or plants may be constructed at new locations II .n.luslnal expansion takes place as anticipated, additional labor will be required and urban population will increase. required ccntS\vbr 1a C s t^li 1 I lndr7 al acvclo e™n. b -"'""S from irrigation within Ac central-Nebraska district may be far more extensive than is indicated in this study. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Economic Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley (Keystone) Reservoir . FRANK MILLER AND H. C. FJLLEY ; Nebraska rainfall varies from year to year and from season to season. There are periods of deficient moisture in every section of the state but, in general, the mean annual precipitation decreases gradually from 32 inches in the southeast corner to 16 inches oh the western border. ; On the basis of rainfall the state may be divided into three areas, .which include a subhumid zone to the east and a semiarid zone to the west, with a broad intermediate area between them. Normally rainfall in the eastern part is sufficient to mature crops, but a large acreage o£ fertile soil lies within the semiarid and intermediate zones where crop production is uncertain. Lack of moisture is the. principal limiting factor. ' This deficiency over a long period and extreme drouth in recent years have stimulated interest in irrigation. ¦¦': ;-: ¦¦."' Nebraska irrigation began as early as 1866 when small enterprises were organized to serve tracts of land adjacent to the Plane river. Development was gradual; only 12,000 acres of land were being watered in 1890. At present there are approximately 500,000 acres under irriga - tion within the. state. More than 200,000 acres, or 40 per cent of the irrigated areas, lie in Scotts Bluff county. 1 The major part of the remain - ing acreage is found along the Platte rivers, extending as far east as Buffalo county. Smaller areas are watered along Lodgepole creek in Kim - ball, Cheyenne, and Deuel counties; along the Frenchman river in Chase,. Hayes, and Hitchcock counties; in the Hat creek and White river basins of Sioux and Dawes counties; at scattered points along the Niobrara, arid in the Plum creek valley of Brown county. There is also an appreciable acreage at various places in the state now under pump irrigation. .¦¦;' .:¦¦. . : Intensified and specialized farming has been profitable in these areas. Where soils and topography are favorable there is an increasing demand for their extension. The possibility of any material increase in those projects that depend upon surface water is limited, because most of the streamflow during the growing season is already appropriated for use. Pump irrigation is increasing in sections where an adequate water supply in coarse pervious.material is found near enough to the surface to permit economical pumping. Expansion in irrigation from streams depends upon storing water now lost as "runoff", and using it in the late fall and early spring to saturate the subsoil, or retaining it in reservoirs until needed to carry crops. through the hot summer months. : : Figure 1 shows existing gravity irrigation areas and the proposed projects that will depend upon stored water.: Some of these new enter - prises are now under construction. One of the most extensive is the Central Nebraska project, which will draw its water supply from the Kingsley reservoir. It is the purpose of this study to outline the agricul - tural and economic benefits that will accrue to the Platte river drainage area because of irrigation from this reservoir. 1 Nebraska State Planning Board, Water Resources of Nebraska, 1936, p. 117. * : </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nnuau tamnm Einuuwr Smm Buium 311 r rOMW 11 b r~i |f ill* i. I? m i 2 l/i j'_.ifflf | /ijfi | tr |r~—"f"' /' -¦{-} !1 ! | </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Benefits of Irrigation trom the Kingsley Reservoir |.| The Kingsley dam site is located on the North Platte river nine miles northeast of Ogallala in Keith county, Nebraska. The dam it - self will be 9,940 feet long, 1,150 feet wide at the base, and 30 feet wide at the crest. The maximum height will be 162 feet from the river bed. When completed it will be a vast pile of earth reenforced by sheet steel piling which has been driven through a layer of porous sand and gravel into impervious clay. Into the construction of this dam 595 carloads of steel, 1,000 cars of cement, 10,000 cars of rock riprap, 2,780 cars of gravel and 28,000,000 cubic yards of earth will go. Gates and controls will re - quire an additional 300 cars of material, while tonnage for contractors' equipment and dredges totalsoo carloads. ¦• ¦;. ¦¦ : . Table I.— Carloads of materials and equipment required jor the Central Nebraska Public Power and Irrigation project. 1 Protect and material | Carloads || Proicct and material | Carloads 1. Kincslcy Dam ' ' . 5. Johnson No. 1 Power House Rock riprap 10,000 : . Cement 95 . Sheet piling :... 470 ¦ Gravel &#132; 44J . Cement 1,000 . Steel .' 40 Reinforcing ... . 125 , Miscellaneous equipment....- 50 Gravel 2,700 CoMftClor'l equipment.....' 40 Gates ...,...,.. 300 ¦ - . " • . . . Contractor's equipment...... 300 .¦¦¦¦ Subtotal 670 Dredges ¦...-,... .I—".. 200; ; . . . ' ¦ ' 6. Johnson No. 2 Power House : Subtotal ............... . 15,095 Cement ...;... 125 2. Upper Diversion Dam . ¦ Gravel: .575 Ceracut 65 feel 50 Gravel . . ... 525 ¦ - ¦ Miscellaneous equipment — 50 , Slcc j '_ '.'.'.]'...-'."'.'[ 20 Contractor!' equipment 50 - . Ripran 130 - -¦ ' , ' -. ! Sheet piline 550 " ; . s»bIoaI • 850 Equipment ..... ....... 10 . _ - . ¦ '. Subtotal .. 1,300 7. Phclps and Adams county ¦ . ¦ . '¦:.¦ Canal and Irrigation System ¦ . Cement 475 3. Supply Canal , m Gravel ; .2,250 Cen,e.« 330 , SlMl . ;.-.. •„„, JW '•"¦¦ IISS • PiPC etc 75 wptp-::::::::::::::::::::^2.300 ; ; con.rac.or-, equipment,....__». •. Equipment ,100 . ," Subtotal ............... JJJSO Subtotal " 4,330 8. Transmission Lilies and 4. Jeffrey Power House '. . ' Subsuiioiu .¦: . Cement 95 Poles and cross arms 1,200 Gravel! ;\ 445 ' Condudori 50 s, cc l 40 ' Concrete and miscellaneous.. 250 .Miscellaneous-equipment!.... 50.. . Contractor's equipment..... .50 Conttactor's equipment '¦¦ ' . and supplies 40 . Sobtoul 1,550 Subtotal ..... ......' 670 Grand Total Entire Project ..27,415 ' Estimates made by Central Nebraska Public Power and- Irrigation Project. Power houses, generators, transmission lines, and substations will take 3,740 carloads of building matrial, supplies, and equipment. Diver - sion dams, supply canals, and irrigation ditches will require 8,420 car - loads of construction materials and 160 cars of equipment, ranging all the way from picks and shovels to great excavators that scoop up six cubic yards of earth at a single sweep of the giant steel arm. Details of the materials that will be used in each part of the project, subtotals for ' •¦-'•¦ '¦¦:'¦¦ -..¦¦.'¦¦¦•.¦¦. .'. / </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 \ ] \ these parts, and the grand total for all construction are shown in Table 1. \\ Water impounded by the dam will form a lake 20 miles long, cover - ing an area of 32,000 acres. From this storage of some 2,000,000 acre , feet of water, normally lost in runoff during the dormant season, 600 ) miles of canal will carry irrigation water to 500,000 acres in the Platte j river watershed of central Nebraska. The estimated return flow, taken ' ) from the river lower in its course, will supply water to an additional ! • 250,000 acres. ! ¦ I _[ ¦ ; mm ZZZZ~ J TO%^Sf ] I [ . j j ] Fu.. 2.--Rxisting and proposed irrigation within the Platte river watershed area. * Electric power that can be generated by release of the impounded : water will result in the construction of three power plants in which five '¦ generators with a capacity of 60,000 kilovolt-amperes will be installed. ¦ Seven hundred miles of transmission line will carry this current through ; 32 substations to Nebraska users of electricity. It will be an additional \ source of power for both home and industrial use throughout central i : and south-central Nebraska. Maximum generating capacity will be reached during the growing season when water is turned into the canals ,J , for irrigation. This surplus will undoubtedly be available at low rates for i I operating pumps along the valley in those areas where an abundant water ; \ supply can be secured from relatively shallow wells. It is estimated that \ j 150,000 acres can be watered from electrically driven pumps when well ]¦ irrigation in the area is fully developed. In addition to these benefits the i \ supply of power, which will doubtless be available at low rates, should H pttract industries to towns throughout the valley. ; ; Irrigation Area • The area that will receive irrigation benefits lies within the Platte river j watershed in Adams, Buffalo, Dawson, Gosper, Hall, Kearney, Lincoln, and j 5 Phelps counties (Fig. 2). It is a small part of the vast belt of land, tilted &gt;| against the east base of the Rocky Mountains, known as the Great Plains \\ Region. Settlement in this area was under way as early as 1870, but the | main part of the land was homesteaded or purchased by actual farmers if between 1880 and 1890. 2 { IA. Lincoln Fellowi, A Rcpon of Some Agricultural EnßineetinK Phases of the Proposed Tri- } county Irrigation Project of Central Nebraska, p. 1. j ¦-¦jj </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Benehts of Irrigation from the Kingsley Reservoir These settlers plowed up the native vegetation which was adapted to the climate. For centuries it had been adding humus to the plant nutrients found in the soil-forming material. The vegetative carpet had retarded run - off during infrequent rainstorms and had caused moisture to be stored in the soil. During the early years of cultivation the reserve of decaying vege - table matter left by the native grasses held the soil particles together so that rainfall was easily absorbed. The mineral elements in the soil, its humus content which supplied nitrogen, and the reserve subsoil moisture all con - tributed to crop yields. Unfortunately the productivity of the land has de - clined with cultivation and its earning power has decreased. The silty soil is losing or has already lost its virgin porous structure, and is less receptive , of rains than it formerly was. The surface is powdery. It forms an in - ferior natural or artificial mulch and loses water more rapidly. Wind and water erosion have taken their toll of fertility. As a result of these changed conditions, it probably takes more water to produce a pound of dry matter in crops than it took under virgin conditions. It is not possible to maintain productivity without irrigation in a region that is subject to frequent drouth. In the upland area of the irrigation dis - trict there are only 3.7 acres of alfalfa for each 100 acres of land under cul - tivation (Table 18). Other legumes are less common. It is hazardous to grow them, for crops "burn up" quickly on legume land. : \ Alfalfa, which is well adapted, is deep rooted. It has the highest water requirement for producing a pound of dry matter of any of the common farm crops and draws heavily upon subsoil moisture. When a stand is left for a six-year period the moisture is removed to a depth of 20 to 35 feet. Normal rainfall may not replace a like amount of water for at least a generation. 3 Yields on reseeded land depend largely upon annual precipita - tion. They are usually so light that reseeding is not Considered a profitable farm practice. The practice of using this important crop in a rotation is seldom found on the unirrigated land of the area. Sweet clover can be grown successfully on most of the land but is little Used. Nitrogen which is added to the soil stimulates growth. In the early part of the season, when water is available, crops which follow clover grow vigorously. Later, when dry weather comes, there is little or no moisture reserve in the subsoil and the crops suffer. The roots of the grain crops commonly grown in the region do not penetrate the soil as deeply as do the roots of alfalfa and sweet clover. But continuous cropping to corn and small grain, under present practices, has depleted the humus left by centuries of natural vegetative growth. Humus is an important constituent of a fertile soil. It performs three important functions! In the first place this decayed organic matter binds the soil particles into granules so that the erosive effect of wind and water is materially reduced. In the second place, humus has a large water-hold - ing capacity and absorbs rainfall in much the same way that a sponge •T. A. Kicssclbach, J. C. Ruikl, and Arthur Anderson, The Significance of Subsoil Moisture in "Alfalfa Production, journal American Society of Agronomy, Vol. 21; No. 3, p. 2-15. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Xtaji.uKi .\&lt;;rh:iltvh\l 1-.vpicriml.vt Station Bulletin 311 takes up water. Lastly, humus nourishes bacteria which make nitrogen available for plant growth. This important constituent has been disappear - ing from the soils of central Nebraska. It can be returned by the use of alfalfa and sweet clover in rotations, but fanners do not use these crops extensively because of the reasons previously given. Some of the soiis found in the irrigation district have been formed on the alluvial plains of the Platte river and its tributaries, but the major part of them lie on the Peorian loessial deposits that cover a large part of the dre.it Plains :\rea. These soils under proper management are long-wear - ing, like those of the fertile regions of China that have continued to pro - duce imps lor mere rh.in live thousand years. They are medium in texture, ranging mostly from sandy loams to silt loams. The subsoil has definite columnar structure or \cry shallow zones of compactness that break apart leadily upon drying. Die underlying soil-forming material is deep and has excellent water storing capacity. It has been shown by saturation plot tests in the field thai two lo two ami one hall inches ot water available to plants can be stored m each loot of subsoil. It is possible to store in the upper six feet of soil, within reach (.1 corn and wheat roots, one acre-foot of irrigation water. 1 I he Hoor of the Platte valley is relatively smooth, but has an eastward slope ol six to eight feet to the mile. The upland in the Platte river drain - :,gc basin which will he watered south o( the river is level to rolling, slop - ing to the north and east. High points within the area cannot be reach - ed with ditches, but a large percentage of it lies beneath gravity flow. On the whole it would he difficult to find an area more completely adapted to irrigation from the standpoint of soils and topography. Climate I he climate of the central-Nebraska irrigation district may properly be called semiarid. Lincoln county has the lowest average annual rainfall and Kearney county the highest. Table 2 gives the average annual precipita - tion in tath ol ten counties lor the periods of years shown in column 2. As a group the eastern counties of the area receive more rain than do the western counties. If their average inches of moisture were a constant supply properly distributed for greatest benefit to crops, it might be suffici - ent for satisfactory yields. The weather hazard is great because of extreme variations in annual and seasonal precipitation. For example. Adams county has had an average rainfall of 25.3 inches over a 5S year period. Taking the group of years as a whole, those with precipitation above the average and those in which the moisture supply has fallen below have varied 25.9 per cent from the average. Of. course there have been wide variations from this percentage in individual years. Rain - tall from May to August, the months in which crops pass their critical stages of development, averaged 13.3 inches in Adams county, but there • I r 8..~l IV l.\. &#132;( si. n .|nwni,l «¦„„. AtricKhur.! F^nccrinc. Vol. XI. No. 3, p. %. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsi.ey Reservoir was a variation during these months of 405 per cent. July and August rainfall averaged 6.4 inches, but varied 455 per cent. The mean precipi - tation for August was 3.2 inches while the variability from this figure was 613 per cent. Table 3 shows the variability in annual rainfall in another way. In 44 years of records for Adams county there were 15 years when the annual Table 2.—Amount and variation of precipitation in certain counties of '.: Nebraska. 1 :'¦•¦ - ' Annual May-August /u/y-Auguit August ' County Period Aver- I Vari- Aver-I Vari- Aver-1 Vari- Aver-1 Vari - • age I ation : age | ation age I ation age [ aiion .'.'.'¦'•¦ In. P.ct. In. P.ct. In. P.ct. In. /&gt;.«, Keith 1899-36 19.4 29.1 11.3 33.1 5.4 37.8 3.0 55.8 Scotts 81uff..... 18S9-35 15.9 26.1 8.8 31.6 3.4 50.5 1.5 73.7 Adam. 1880-35 253 IS9. 133 ¦: 40.5 6.4 45.5 3.2 613 Buffalo 1849-35 24.2 252 143 36.8 6.6 45.2 2.9 55.9 Diwwn 1890-35 22.4 24.7 125 38.4 5.9 45.8 2.9 51.1 Goiper 18S5-35 22.S 24.6 13.3 36.1 6.2 -(0.7 3.1 55.5 Hail 1888-35 .26.7 26.2 14.8 40.7 6.7 48.2 3.4 55.4 Kearney .:..... 1878-35 27.0 31.0 15.3 42.4 7.0 52.8 3J 63.2 Lincoln ; 1874-35 183 26.9 10.9 31.1 5.1 41.7 2.4 57.5 Phelpi -.. 1890-35 23.4 27.8 13.4. 40.4 5S 43.0 2.9 56.9 . 'Compiled from div of U.'S; Weather Bureau by L. F. Garcy, Department of Rural Economic], University of Nebraska. ¦.---¦ ; ; . • ... Table 3.— Annual'precipitation in certain counties in Nebraska^ ! ~~ ! : ~- ~ : ~~~ ; Periods Periods ¦ ' . Years Years (3yr». (3yrs. . County Average Period above below or more) or more) * ... .. average average above below ¦ ¦ . ' ' average average )». Yrj. Yn. ¦ Yrj. No.. No. Keith ..-..„...:.. . 19.4 27 13 ¦¦ . 14 . 0 2 Scotts Bluff. 15.9 47 23 24 0 2 Adam. 25.3 . 44 :. 15 29 0 4 Buffalo 24.2 : ..' 59. : "25 .34 ' .2- 4 Dawson 22.4 46 21 , 25 3 3 Gosper 22.8 : '.'. 41;. 20 21 ; 1 1 Hall .26.7 43 : 20 23 3 4 Kearney :.. 27.0 .58 26 .: 32 4. 5 LtoSff 183 61. 30 31 3 3 Phelps 23.4 46 16 30 0 5 1 Compiled from data of U. S. Weather Bureau by L. F. Carey, Department of Rural Economics, University of Nebraska. ;. . - ¦ . [ precipitation wasabove average and 29 years when it was below. There were no periods three years or more in length when rainfall was above average. Four periods were recorded, three years or more in length, when it rained less than the average for the 44 years. Similar comparisons for May to August, July and August, and August precipitation are given in , Tables 4, 5, and.6. ; Annual precipitation and rainfall during the growing season for central Nebraska from 1910 to 1935 are;shown: in columns 2 and 3 of Table 9. Natural moisture was probably adequate for nearly optimum crop growth in only four years of this 26-year period and no two of the four seasons </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 Table 4.— Precipitation from May to August in certain counties in Nebras\a} Periods Period) Yean Years (3 yrs. (3 yrs. V «• Coumy Average Period above below or more) or more) average average above below . average average '"¦ &gt;'&lt; Yn. Yn. No. No. Keith 11.3 27 10 17 0 2 Scotts Bluff 8.7 -17 22 25 1 2 Adams 13* 45 22 23 1 2 Buffalo MJ 62 25 37 4 5 Dawson 12.5 46 25 22 I 2 Cosper 13J -II 19 22 0 2 Hall 14.11 41 1H 25 I 2 Kearney 15.3 5« 26 32 4 4 Lincoln 10.9 61 29 32 4 3 Phelpi 13.4 46 16 30 1 5 Compiled Jrtim (Iji.i of I. 5. Wc.nhcr Bureau by L. F. Garcy, Department of Rural Economics, University o( NclTaika. Table s.— Precipitation for July and August in certain counties of Nebraska. 1 Periods Periods Yean Years (3 yrs. (3 yrs. County Average Period above below or more) or more) average average above belou* average average /¦¦. 1" »/ &gt;/i. .Vo. No. Keith 5 !9 &gt; II 17 (| 1 Scorn Bluff 1 -111 4" 2H 27 I 3 Adams ft.4l 45 I" 2* 0 3 Buffalo r,M ',-' 2&lt; 3V 3 4 Dawson 5 '(II 4', 25 21 1 4 Goiprr "I 5 4" II 25 1 3 Hall I. to 4i 15 2» 1 5 ' Kearney '"I 5» -- 36 4 J Lincoln 5.H7 '.i 27 34 1 2 Phrips 5.W J'' -'II 26 2 5 ¦ Compiled train tl.i'.i of I b. Wtuihct [iurcju l&gt;\ 1.. F. Garcy. Department of Rural Economics, L'nivcrsity ol Ncbrjsk.i - j Table 6.— Precipitation for August in certain counties in Nebraska. 1 Periods Period Year! Years (3 yrs. (3 yrs. :j: County A\cragc I'ctiods above below or more) or more) J' p average average above below I average average /¦.. )¦, »¦ )&gt;s. No. No. j Keith 3.01 12 16 1 0 ' Scott! Blutl 154 47 20 27 0 3 ( Adami &gt; 1» *'• IS 2« 1 4 . I Buffalo 2.W 62 25 37 2 6 , Dawion 2 93 46 22 24 4 3 Cosper 3.911 41 Id 13 I 3 ¦ !'| Hall 3.3H 43 2H 23 3 3 Kearney 3 2« Sd 19 39 1 8 Ij Lincoln 240 61 24 37 1 4 f Phelp. 2M « 21) 26 I 4 [ ' L F, darcy. Dcparlmcnl ol Rural Kconomics, University of Nebraska. .. ;! ij I: i </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley Reservoir came in sequence. From these data, it seems evident that increasing avail - able water through irrigation will materially increase the possibility of crop yields and will insure continuous production which is essential to farm prosperity in this section of Nebraska. Only a few years are scattered through the record in which supplemental water could not have been used to advantage. ¦.-.. ' Growing Season The frost-free period of the irrigation area varies with change of either altitude or latitude. It shortens gradually as the position is shifted from the southeast to the northwest corner of the district. In Adams county, at the southeast corner, the average date of the last killing frost in spring is May 1; the first killing frost in fall usually comes about October 6, making a growing season of 157 days. The average date of the last killing frost in the northwest corner of Lincoln county is May 11 and of the first killing frost in the fall, September 25. The growing season averages 136 days. Scotts Bluff county, which is used for comparison in determining irriga - tion benefits, lies outside the district to the northwest where the elevation is approximately 4,000 feet above sea level. It has a mean frost-free period of 133 days. Increase in Yields ¦ How much will irrigation increase crop yields in central Nebraska? This question arises naturally and involves consideration of several factors. For the purpose of arriving at crop-yield increases, the counties that will benefit are divided into two groups. The first includes Buffalo, Daw - son, Hall, and Lincoln counties. In this group there is considerable bottom land with a water level within range of the root development of some im - portant farm crops. For this reason they are referred to as the valley counties. There is also at present in this area an appreciable amount of irri - gation, both from ditches and from wells. The water supply in many instances is inadequate but it does affect crop yields. Water from the Kingsley reservoir will augment the supply now available here and in several instances will bring additional acres under the ditch, but in calcu - lating irrigation benefits it seems reasonable to use as a base existing condi - tions within the area where there is no supplemental water. Such condi - tions are found in the other four counties of the district. In Adams, Gosper, Kearney, and Phelps counties the acreage of bottom land is small.; Over the major part of that portion of their area which is within the Platte river drainage basin, the water level is at considerable depth, and there is little or no irrigation at the present time. These may properly be called the upland counties. For the most part data on crop yields here reflect actual production from existing rainfall. Averages from these counties: are used in calculating production without irrigation in Tables 34 to 37. ;-' V : • -\" v ' </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Acrici/ltl-ral Experiment Station Bulletin- 311 Soil Productivity The matter of potential soil productivity is important in forecasting irrigation benefits. No amount of water applied to land that is void o£ power to produce will bring a harvest. Fortunately information concerning Nebraska soils is quite complete. Detailed surveys have been made in prac - tically e-ery county where the growing of crops is a major farm enterprise. Using this information along with data concerning yields, taken over a period or years, the Land Utilization Division of the Resettlement Admin - islration has classified the soils of the state according to their general pro - ductivity. These classifications for Scotts Bluff county and for the indi - vidual counties that will receive irrigation water are shown in Table 7. In working out the several classes, the soils, as mapped in the field by men who arc technically trained in such work, are placed in five broad groups according to their capacity for corn production. Group I includes the most productive soils under existing farming conditions, and group V the least productive. Group I soils, with one or two exceptions, are limited to the more productive bottom lands and terraces. Group II soils, in general, consist of the better grades of upland. Both groups are productive and yield excellent crops when conditions are favorable. Groups ll[ and IV arc less productive soils and group V consists of dune sand, extremely sandy soils, nverwash. rough broken land, and other unproductive soils. 5 A comparison of soils in the valley counties and in the upland counties is given m Table 8. By referring to Table 7 it will be noted that Scotts Bluff county has a total area of 462,720 acres, of which 36 per cent is Table 7.-Classes oj sods ,n Scotts Bluff county and in counties affected, by trnganon from Kmgsley reservoir according to productivity. Class "¦ I is highest; V ,s lowest} |i. (11 i L ,,.,.... ! |i . r n1 Percent ,„',, ( A.rn ! '", "" A.res o f 3 || Percent | , „, eulmatcd cultiialed of pade - ! j '-""' hn.l tullivunl ; , Stnns lljuff „„„,,. I "! S i 1 i a |: V 131.5 M ;, J-S - 10-0 i !«:« m 4U ' ¦&gt; Ad.ims count) i L ™l :° s ABric B u "mn! n/°"°a"°° '"' ' Uml Lie Prosram (u"P"bl,&gt;!, t d). Univmlq, of Scbralka Collcsc of .!{ i i- I </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Benefits of Irrigation pkom the. Kingsley Reservoir Table 7.—Classes of soils in Scotts Bluff county and in counties affected by irrigation from Kingsley reservoir according to productivity. Class lis highest; V is lowest?- {Concluded) __ ¦'•V:-tg'.:|,,&lt;--| l. 1g|.j8..|.,51.3a . - ... Buffalo county /I,:::::::::.::: B . 9 .¦"., M \ |j : !U::::::::::::: S H » 1 V ; -..- 46,144 8 3.807 l ¦••*¦ Toui ::::;::... «000 im 3m,856 i» «j Dawion county I ....„ 210.128 38 216.11S 58 «•&lt;&gt; II 107,072 17 63,014 17 58.9 HI &#132;. 13,424 4 8.690 2 37.1 V .........' 144,384 23 69,748 19 483 V :.. 115,392 18 13,56* 4." . . 11'!• Toul .'. 630,400 . 100 371,135 100 58S ¦¦. ¦ ' ¦. . ' Gospcr county . I ....:.. 17.912 6' 16,121 10 90.0 I X 119412 .40 95,530 57 80.0 ' HI !.¦'¦¦ 8,956 3 6,269 4 70.0 ' : IV .....'.. - 59.559 30 35,824 21 40.0 V ....... 62,691 21 13,433 8 . 21.4 Toul 298,530 100 . 167.177 100 56.0 . ¦ " ¦- HaJI county I 99,520 29 84,816 37 855 II ............ 47,424 14 43,466 19 91.7 ¦ 111- ..1...:.. 67712 20 .47,257 .21 69.8 IV ¦¦¦¦¦'¦ ...:..¦ 86,912 26 44,709 20 51.4 v :;::.... 36352 v 7,226 3 ws ¦¦.¦ Toul 337,920 100 227,474 100 673 1 :. ...'.:¦¦ . Kearney county . . . '¦ I ....... 1,088 .3 979. .4 90.0 II ........'... 176,768 53.5 156,524 66.1 88.5 . . m¦ " 16,384 5.0 11,469 4.9 70.0 IV .....,..'.l. 82,752 25.1 63,713 265 77.0 V 53^48 16.1 4,058 1.7 7.&lt; Toal 330,240 : 100.0 236,743 100.0 71.7 :,--'¦&gt;-.:¦; '•¦'.'•".- Keith county ; ¦'¦¦''.' I 54.016 8 37,737 15 69S II 173,312 25 143,708 55 . 82.9 • ' HI 44,224 6 ;. ¦¦ 25,423 10 \ 575 IV 70,912 10 24.394 9 34.4 V .:.. 351,936 51 29,366 11 8.3 Toul ...;..:... 694,400 100 ; 260,628 100 37.5 ¦ - . : .¦ Lincoln county I .......;...;. 179,712 11 88^29 21 49.5 | 174,912 11 149,273 34 85.3 HI ...;...... 42,880 3 ¦'•/ i 7,465 - ..9 87.4 IV ....... 140,224 8 36,330 8 KS V --. 1.085,312 67 120393 28 11.1 Total .....:.... 1,623,040 100 : 432,390 100 26.6 . Phelps county .' . I ..;..... 33,856 10 32,163 13 95.0 II : 228,928 . 66 192.362 75 84.0 !v".;;;;""": &amp;m - io i&lt;wi » . »i V 47,616 14 3,005 1 6.3 Tout ¦¦¦;¦¦.... 344320 100 254,461 100 73.9 ¦Buic Information for a Und tlx Program (unpublished), College of Agriculture, University of &#132;,.¦ Nebraska. : ' /¦ / '.' :". ;.. ¦ : </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 Table B.— Classes of soils in counties of the central Nebraska irrigation district grouped according to amount of upland and valley land. 1 Product,™, P«ccnt AcrM "^ Percent index Acre. orall cultivated cultivated of trade land land cultivated Adams, Gospcr, Kearney, and Phelps counties combined ' "3.272 5.5 66,162 7.0 90 3 II 773,041 57.9 654,467 69 3 84 7 111 28,284 2.1 19,210 2.0 . 679 IV 278,679 20.9 181,914 19 2 65 3 v 181,-fll 13.6 23,256 2.5 12 8 T«al 1.334,690 100.0 945,009 100.0 70.8 Buffalo, Hall, Lincoln, and Dawson counticl combined I 666,560 20.8 529,700 37.4 79 5 &gt;• 570,496 17.8 422,565 29.8 741 "¦ 156.736 4.9 103,076 7.3 658 'v 525.568 16.4 217,520 15.3 414 v 1.283.200 40.1 144,594 10.2 JJJ T°«l 3,202.560 100.0 1,417.855 100.0 44.3 1 Basic Information for a Land Use Program, College of Agriculture, University 0* Nebraska. group I and II soils. The total area of the valley counties is 3,202,560 acres. Within the upland counties there are 1334,690 acres. A fraction more than 38 per cent (38.6) of the total acreage in the valley counties and 63.4 per cent of the area in the upland counties are group I and II soils. In other words the irrigation district as a whole has a higher percentage of high-grade soils than Scotts Bluff county. There are in the total area 2,083,372 acres of land that is highly productive under favorable growing conditions. The valley counties contain 1,237,056 acres of it and 846,316 acres lie in the upland counties. In general, these soils are friable with ' ample drainage. They warm quickly in the spring, making it possible to '.1 take advantage of the entire growing season. ?{ Crop Rotation ii The sequence of crops now commonly used in the area can scarcely be | classed as a rotation. Usually corn is followed by oats or barley and two or '¦ more years of wheat follow the spring grain. Under irrigation the cropping ?| system will probably change to a true rotation including alfalfa and sweet I; clover, intertilled crops, spring grains, and winter wheat. J i ¦ Yields under Present Conditions and Estimated Yields under Irrigation &lt; Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season in centr.il ! Nebraska, and acreages and yields of principal crops in counties within the I irrigation area from 1910 to 1935 are shown in Tables 9 to 18. Ten-year '; (1926-35) combined figures, with total cultivated acreages for eight years, X for the valley and the upland counties are given in Tables 19 to 23. Data fe for Scotts Bluff county, where most crops are irrigated, are also included. if From the 26-year period the four years of highest rainfall have been select- % cd. Yields in these years are presented in Table 24. \\ | </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Table 9—Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, and acreages and yields of alfalfa in Scotts Bluff ;'. "..."¦..¦¦ county and in Adams, Gosper, Kearney, and Phelps counties, 1910 to 1935 x {thousands of acres; ions per acre). y . Precipitation, central Nebr. Scotti Bluff Adams Gosper Kearney Phelps W .¦'.-.; Annual | ' Acreage | Yield Acreage , | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield gj , 1910* 19.89 13.77 11.0 4.2 15.0 2.57 4.0 1.7 12.0 2.0 12.0 1.0 *j .1911 23.61 14.53 13.0 3.5 15.0 2.00 4.0 2.1 12.0 1.5 11.0 1.9 . 1912 18.75 9.88 11.0 3.5 14.0 2.60 4.0 ¦ 2.0 11.0 1.5 9.0 1.2 g : - ' 1913 24.78 14.85. 37.0 .3.5 14.0 . 1.50 4.0 1.6 11.0 1.4 10.0 1.0 . . .1914 22.26 16.55 39.0 3.8 14.0 2.20 3.0 3.0- 11.0 2.1 10.0 1.5 S&lt; .V. 1915 35.62 24.28 39.0 3.0 15.0 3.70 , 3.0 3.3 11.0 2.8 9.4 3.7 &amp; 1916 18.86 13.02 34.0 3.0 16.0 ¦ 2.70 3.0 2.5 . 11.0 3.1 9.4 3.2 £ 1917 21.95 : 14.29 56.0 3.0 15.0 1.90 3.0 1.7 9.0 . . 15 8.5 1.2 &gt; : : 1918 22.52 13.62 43.0 2.5 13.0 ' 1.60 3.0 12 10.0 \5 19 25 S 1919 25J8 16.26 39.0 3.0 11.0 2.80 2.1 2.9 10.0 2.8 6.8 2.8 g 1920 28J4 20.74 38.0 2.8 12.0 2.80 4.0 2.6 8.0 22 ..-' 7.4 2.2 a '¦ ' ¦¦¦'•¦ 'IHI ¦.;'¦¦ 21 JO' ' \6S3 34.0 2.8 11J) IJO 2.4 . 22 .. (Ml W 7.0 1.8 ut 1922 20J6 14.69 32.0 2.9 12.0 1.70' 2.5 1.8 9.0 1.9 7.0 1.9 » .¦.;¦ 1923 30.19 21-79 31.0 2.9 .13.0 2.70 3.0 2.6 9.0 2.5 7.9 2.7 2 1924 23.46 17.79 28.0 2.6 14.0 2.10 3.0 1.8 11.0 2.0 8.2 1.8 5 ¦•¦:¦¦; 1925 . 20.54 14.79 .35.0 3.0 ,15.0 2.00 3.0 2.0 12.0 1.8 8.5 1.8 rt ; 1926 20.89 13.40 34.0 3.0 13.0 1.20 3.0 1.4 11.0 1.1 9.0 1.1 § 1927 ¦ 22.16 15.08 37.0 3.0 13.0 2.40 3.0 2.3 11.0 2.3 8.4 2.3 » ""'' 1928 20.60 12.65 35.0 2.8 11.0 2.60 3.0 2.2 10.0 1.8 7.5 2.0 S5 ¦'•'.." 1929 21M 13J17 .35.0 3J&gt; ! 1U . 2.20 2.1 ' 22 SS .1.8 . 65 IJ . C 1 ¦ 1930 . 29J2 . 20.86 30.0 3.0 12.0 2.50 2.5 2.8 8.5 2.5 62 2.7 2 1931 18.75 9.30 40.0 2.0 13.0 1.40 2.4 1.7 9.7 2.5 62 1.7 5 ;¦¦.•»• 1932 2255 1627 38.0 3.0 . 12.0 2.20 22 1.9 9.6 2.0 6.2— 2.0 C 1933 2138 14.24 36.0 25 12.0 1.80 2.0 2.0 10.0 1.8 6.5 1.7 S 1934 13.68 622 33.0 2.5 13.0 50 2.6 .3 11.0 .7 • 7.1 2 I ¦ 1935* 24.08 \9si 33.8 2.9 10.9 ¦ 1.80 2.4 2.3 93 2.0 6.0 1.8 SO 26-year . ¦ H I;.. : average 2235 14.62 33.76 3.0 13.07 2.13 2.9 2.12 10.15 1.95 8.1 1.91 M 10-year .¦.-'* '.-..¦ .¦.. " .¦. . 5 average 21^7 14.06 35.78 2.77 12.09 1.86 232 1.91 9.89 1.85 6.96 ' 1.68 o , 'Baric Information for a Land Use Program, University of Nebraska College of Agriculture. * ¦ J 'Nebraska Blue Book. 1936, p. 417. - if"-" '1935 yield figurej preliminary. 17 </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Table 10.— Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, and acreages and yields oj alfalfa in Scotts Bluff ~* county and tn Buffalo, Dawson, Hall, andj.mcoln count.es, 1910 to 1935 ' (thousands of acres; tons per acre). f V Precipice, ccmra! Neb,. 50,,, Bluf! ~ BuffaU, u„~ — ~ g . I Growing II " pr &amp;; Al"""' I «»¦¦ *""«' I Yield Ac,c«c | Yield Ac,c JB c 1 V.eld a c ,c JE c 1 Yield A.,c B e | Yield £ '!"2 18.75 9.88 11.0 3 5 42 0 |, |?'S H »¦" ? '« 2.3 2 1913 24.7* I4.SS 37.0 |.1 «.,| 2 4 i'° " '&lt;¦» " 17-0 3.3 O WM 22^6 16.55 39.0 in tt.il !„ JJ-J '•' ".0 1.8 19.0 3.6 S 1915 35.62 2-1.28 39.0 31) 45 0 3 4 A ,n ii «S 3 4 160 3" 6 !"« ».»« 1302 34.0 3.(1 Sin 27 12 |? 5f2 »-| l9 ° 2-» S 1917 21.95 H. 29 56.0 3(1 45 0 19 «n li ?iS 29 17 ° 33 S ? 1918 22J2 13.62 43.0 2 5 310 « ,SS 1? ?¦? 20 l«-0 2.7 ? •919 25.38 16.26 39.0 30 'SO VI ,?„ H 7 ° '•' '50 2.7 1920 28.24 20.74 38.0 28 290 In nn H IB' o 2- 9 I3 -° " t«1 1921 21.70 16.53 34.0 2? 36:5 2? |JS |i 2?'2 " IS-» »•« 8 1922 2036 H. 69 32.0 2 9 36 0 2 3 n IS ?J'S 26 13 ° 2- 6 B 1923 30.19 21.79 31.0 2.9 460 27 ffn 1 7 Mn U "° 2" 8 X •9J4 23.43 17.79 28.0 2.6 510 In 390 II «- n 2 5 15jl 2- 9 g 1925 20.54 14.79 35.0 io 54 0 21 Inn H 1 32 l5 ° 2- 4 5 192« 20.89 13.40 34.0 3.0 490 17 I?'? {n Hi 2B 19 -&lt;&gt; 3-0 § 1927 22.16 15.08 37.0 3.0 460 26 !in I'? 2SS 20 18 -° 2-« H 1928 20-60 12.65 35.0 2.8 430 22 Inn H IH 2C 18 -° 2- 7 CO 1929 21.88 13.07 35.0 3 0 40 0 20 Sn I'J 25 -S 2J l8 ° »•« H 1930 29.52 20.86 36.0 3 0 «o , VA f° ?4.0 2.5 19.0 2.6 g 1931 18.75 9JO 40.0 |.o 430 I? mn f« "» 2-' 19.0 2.6 g '932 22.95 16.27 38.0 3.0 430 26 Ijn A VA i 0 160 2-0 i 193^ r 24.08 ,9.54 33.8 2.9 gj S Hi g g5 S gj g f r&amp;£ 2" 5 M" X 3"° 3" «¦» 2-5 «.O 3.0 23.8 2.6 15.9 Q I avenge 21.57 14.06 35.78 2.77 44.09 2.21 ' 52.18 2.92 27.50 2.39 16.76 2.44 5 |!| &gt;lt%!£°Z*?V kJ?! m^t W. ''r °Bram' UniVCr" tV ° f Ncb' 3Ska CO" CEC ° l ABricuLurr. " "~ tf |;j • 1935 yield figures preliminary. , \\t MjJM—MMMl—¦—^ii^— — I ¦ - —¦— i ; l' 18 </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Table 11. — Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, and acreages and yields of barley in Scotts Bluff county and in Adams, Gosper, Kearney, and Phelps counties, 1910 to 1935 x (thousands of acres; bus. per acre). Precipitation, central Nebr. Scotis Bluff Adami , Goiper * Kearney :.""'¦. Phelps W Annual | season^ Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield W "WO 19.89 13177 1.0 48^8 .1 26\5 .&gt;.,• ~l .¦~ ~2 34.0 ~T~ — 3 1911 23.61 1453 1.0 42.5 J 15.0 .1 9.0 .2 10.0 2 100 1912 18.75 9.88 5 50.0 — . 25.0 . 10.6 .1 25.0 .1 106 O 1913 24.78 14.85 3.8 45.0 .1 20.0 — 10.0 ;l 10.0 .2 5.0 "" 1914 13.26 16.55 2.2 . 43.0 .5 27.0 .2 27.7 .3 23.3 .5 275 •"-¦ 1915 35.62 24.28 1.6 51.4 , .7 20.0 .2 35.0 .7. 27.7 1.5 336 3 1916 18.86 13.02 3.1 41.1 .7 23.1 .3 25.0 S 31.6 13 387 g 1917 2155 14.29 4.0 41.0! 10.0 27.0 .5 17.0 6.0 24.0 6.1 25 0 2 1918 2252 13.62 4.0 34.0 14.0 10.0 . 1.3 13.0 10.0 12.0 ' 9.0 12 0 ¦" 3 1919 2538 16.26 3.3 ¦ 41.0 6.0 27.0 .9 26.0 5.0 24.0 63 260 5 1920 28.24 20.74 .3.4 35.0 • . WJI- ¦ 32J) . . 1.5 28.0. 4.0 28.0 8.9 27.0 Z 1921 21.70 16.53 4.0 ' 32.0 7.0 . 26.0 . . ¦ •. 13 24.0 3.0 24.0 6.7 23 0 -w 1922 20.36 14.69 4.0 39.0 15.0 17.0 -2.0 13.0 12.0 20.0 8.6 ¦ 130 S 1923 30.19 21.79 5.0 40.0. 9.0 . 30.0 3.0 26.0 12.0 25.0 12.0 270 g 1924 23.43 17.79 9.0 36.0 6.0 27.0 3.0 21.0 6.0 24.0 13.0 240 S 1925 20.54 14.79 15.0 . 44.0 5.0 17.0 .7 21.0 3.0 17.0 80 180 -it 1926 20.89 !3.40 13.0 39.0 2.8 7.0 .6 . 10.0 IS 9.0 62 60 8 1927 22.16 15.08 16.0 46.0 3.0 32.0 .5 30.0 1.6 28.0 5.1 270 " 1928 20.60 12.65 22.0 51.0 . 3.0 29.0 1.3 29.0 2.0 32.0 60 270 *• 1929 21.88 13.07 25.0 50.0 6.7 28.0 2.7 30.0 4.6 20.0 no 240 J? 1930 29J2 • 20.86 29.0' 47.0 6.7 30.0 . 4.4- 33.0 , 5J 29.0 13.4 330 5 1931 18.75 »J0 27.0 42.0 8.0 19.0 4.4 . 22.0 SS 21X) 130 210 9 1932 22 S5 16.27 24.0 45.0 6.2 26.0 32 23.0 4.1 26.0 12 0 240 P 1933 2138 14J4 21.0 45.0 7.8 9.0 5.6 16.0 10.7 13.0 22.0 150 S 1934 13.68 622 19.0 33.2 5J 3.6 1.7 - 3.9 3.0 95 24 1935 • 24.08 19.54 18.4 35.0 6.6 24.0 2.8 26.0 8.2 27.0 16.6 3l!o W ¦ 26-year •.'.• ¦ -..'¦¦ .-¦ ¦ . . .'¦ ¦ ¦ .. ¦ ¦ .... ¦: ."- . m average 2235 .14.62 10.74 42.4 258 22.2 1.8 21.9 4.28 21.8 7.8 212 m average 2157 14.06 21.-J4 4332 5.61 20.76 2.72 21.90 4.78 20.80 12.08 21.04 S 1 Balic Information fcr a Land Use Program, University of Nebraska College of Agriculture. ¦ . . ¦Nebraska Blue Book, 1936. p. 417. '•¦... • 1935 yield figures preliminary. .. .. ¦ * ...*-. ;- .' . 19 </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Table 12.— Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, and acreages and yields of barley in Scotts Bluff -, county and in Buffalo, Dawson, Hall, and Lincoln counties, 1910 to 1935 ' (thousands oj acres; bushels per acre'). » YMf ITec.pi.,.i.n, &lt;*n.»l N0!.,. 50... Bluff Buff.lo »,"^n~~ H.ll Lincoln | Annual | ,™°.' Acre.i B e | Yield Acroßc | Vid.l »,-,r.i B e | Y.c1.l Accuse | Yield Acrea B e | Yield * 1910 19.89 13.77 I.I) «.K (I 1 77~ 77\ T~, JT^ 71 7TZ &gt; I I 1 I I I I ill %%&lt; 24.08 lU, ,£, 35.0 3,» jJJ !lj £J JJ 2 « « »;' C .-.vernce 21.57 H. 06 21H4 4 3 . M | 9 . M 22.f,7 12.72 2^.f,« 9.1H 21.88 8.12 20.6 0 1935 yield figures preliminary. 20 </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Table 13.— Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, and acreages and yields of corn in Scotts Bluff county and in Adams, Gosper, Kearney, arid Phelps counties, 1910 to 1935 1 (thousands of acres; bushels per acre). Precipitation, central Ncbr. Scotti Blufl Adams -' Gosper . Kearney Phelps M *&lt;ar Annual | °™sorT» Acreage | Yield 'Acreage ) Yield Acreage j Yield Acreage I Yield Acreage | Yield g 1910 1989 13.77 6.0 23.3 • 77.0 33.0 71.0 12.3 75.0 22.7 102.0 15.0 £jj 19 1 23.61 14.53 5.0." 12.5 65.0 ¦.!¦ 20.7 69.0 17.5 69.0 11.1 86.0 16.6 M 912 18.75 9.88 -1.0 30.0 66.0 21.2 79.0 14.0 66.0 12.5 86.0 15.0 2 1913 24.78 14.85 6.0 32.5 65.0 3.6 77.0.: 1.7 75.0 2.0 93.0 0.5 1914 22.26 16.55 H.O 35.0 ¦¦, .60.0 : 24.1 83.0 12.3 66.0 19.7 81.0 123 5* 1915 35.62 " 24.28 15.0 35.5 . 57.0 35.1 ¦ 76.0 30.0 61.0 33.3 76.0 36.0 » 1916 18.86 13.02 10.0 31.1 «9.0 24.9 75.0 24.8 66.0 22.4. 88.0 23.9 O 1917 ' 21.95 14.29 18.0 22.0 122.0 22.0 91.0 18.0 76.0 19.0 107.0 17.0 g" 1918 22.52 13.62 13.0 23.0 75.0 8.0 75.0 18.0 71.0 12.0 82.0 16.0 2 1919 25.38 16.26 19.0 24.0 67.0 27.0 72.0 31.0 68.0 34.0 82.0 33.0 g 1920 28.24 20.74 17.0 26.0 84.0 33.0 89.0 25.0 82.0 28.0 ¦ 93.0 J5.0 z 1921 21.70 16.53 15.0 20.0 82.0 20.0 80.0 17.0 77.0 10.0 86.0 12.0 V 1922 20.36 14.69 17.0 26.0 93.0 IS.O 72.0 13.0 91.0 17.0 84.0 13.0 g 1923 30.19 21.79 20.0 30.0 96.0 29.0 90.0 30.0 92.0 30.0 95.0 31.0 8 1924 23.43 17.79 24.0 23.0 97.0 30.0 95.0 22.0 88.0 . 24.0 99.0 22.0 ¦•" 1925 20.54 14.79 28.0 28.0 108.0 . 18.0 102.0 14.0 104.0 12.0 104.0 13.0, H . 1926 20.89 13.40 25.0 26.0 100.0 5.0 99.0 6.0 91.0 4.0 110.0 6.0 X ¦:':. 1927 22.16 15.08 20.0 25.0 102.0 32.0 100.0 29.0 88.0 31.0 116.0 30.0 w 1928 20.60 12.65 17.0 30.0 98.0 24.0 101.0 18.0 86.0 20.0 111.0 16.0 * 1929 21.88 13.07 18.0 30.0 108.0 21.0 107.0 17.0 93.0 9.0 118.0 12X1 • U ¦¦¦ ; : 1930 29.52 20.86 23.0 32.0 ¦ 105.0 : 22.0 106.0 31.0 88.0 25.0 115.0 30.0 1931 18.75 9.30 34.0 28.0 109.0 11.0 108.0 22.0 93.0 18.0 121.0 26.0 S 1932 22.95 16J7 39.0 32.0 114.0 22.0 113.0 12.0 99.0 23.0 129.0 17.0 E :¦¦'¦¦¦.' 1933 21.38 14.24 36.0 30.0 113.0 14.0 108.0 27.0 106.0 20.0 135.0 J5.0 S 1934 13.68 6.22 30.0 18.1 . 95.0 4.8 91.0 12.0 76.0 4.7 103.0 33 „ 1935» 24.08 19.54 43.8 29.0 775 6.6 71.9 7- 7 58J 3J 74.5 4.8 8* • ¦ 26-vcar ¦' ¦ ' ¦ ¦¦.¦¦'..¦¦¦ -;' S» average 22.35 .14.62 19.88 " 27J&gt; 88.6 20.25 88.6 18.59 80.97 18.02 98.88 18.13 W • average 2157 ' 14.06 28J8 28.01 102.15 16^4 100.49 18.17 87.83 15.86 , 113.25 17.01 O •Basic Information (or a Land Vte Program, University of Nebraska College of Agriculture. ....'' ' .' •Nebraska Blue Book, 1936, p. 417. ¦1935 yield figures preliminary. J . ¦ 21 </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Tabu; 14. — Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, and acreages and yields of corn in Scotts Bluff — county and in Buffalo, Dawson, Hall, and Lincoln counties, 1910 to 1395 ' (thousands of acres; bushels per acre). g Precipitation, central Nebr. Storts Kluff Buffalo Ibwion Hall Lincoln &gt; Annual j °™sTn"» Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Ace.me | YielJ Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield &gt; 1910 19. 89 13 77 6.0 23.3 146.0 25.0 135.0 17.8 64.0 12.5 69.0 22.2 5* 1911 23.61 14.53 5.0 12.5 141.0 15.2 129.0 23.3 64.0 18.7 97.0 16.2 W 1913 18.75 9.88 4.0 30.0 148.0 10.7 128.0 18.3 51.0 22.0 108.0 25.6 O 1913 24.78 H. 85 6.0 32.5 155.0 4.7 127.0 3.6 71.0 4.5 130.0 9.0 C 1914 22.26 16.55 14.0 35.0 149.0 17.7 122.0 13.5 64.0 29.7 100.0 15.0 E 1915 35.62 24.28 15.0 35.5 157.0 30.9 123.0 27.3 80.0 29.3 131.0 26.8 3 1916 18.86 13.02 10.0 31.1 151.0 24.1 108.0 22.3 71.0 27.1 128.0 19.3 W 1917 21.95 14.29 18.0 22.0 180.0 24.0 150.0 25.0 99.0 18.0 133.0 21.0 £ 1918 22.52 13.62 13.0 23.0 144.0 22.0 117.0 21.0 75.0 13.0 119.0 23.0 1919 25.38 16.26 19.0 24.0 150.0 28.0 122.0 25.0 71.0 28.0 124.0 24.0 pi 1920 28.24 20.74 17.0 26.0 152.0 32.0 140.0 28.0 89.0 36.0 134.0 27.0 X 1921 21.70 16.53 15.0 20.0 188.0 18.0 135.0 26.0 90.0 24.0 135.0 12.0 2 1922 20.36 14.69 17.0 26.0 1710 15.0 111.0 13.0 85.0 20.0 138.0 18.0 3 1923 30.19 21.79 20.0 30.0 178.0 31.0 145.0 35.0 87.0 29.0 185.0 34.0 5 1924 23.43 17.79 24.0 23.0 180.0 25.0 154,0 20.0 93.0 32.0 163.0 18 0 C 1925 20.54 14.79 28.0 28.0 186.0 19.0 162.0 20.0 99.0 28.0 182.0 17.0 Z 1926 20.89 13.40 25.0 26.0 188.0 9.0 166.0 12.0 104.0 5.0 175.0 80 ¦-) 1927 22.16 15.08 20.0 25.0 189.0 34.0 170.0 32.0 100.0 32.0 178.0 28.0 .„ 1928 20.60 12.65 17.0 30.0 197.0 15.0 186.0 25.0 104.0 17.0 179.0 28.0 H 1929 21. 811 13.07 18.0 30.0 192.0 12.0 184.0 21.0 100.0 18.0 186 0 17.0 &gt; 1930 29.5! 20.86 23.0 32.0 132.0 26.0 177.0 30.0 96.0 29.0 186.0 25 0 2 1931 18.75 9.30 14.0 28.0 191.0 20.0 185.0 22.0 104.0 14.0 194.0 17 0 O 1932 22.95 16.27 39.0 32.0 194.0 19.0 185.0 17.0 104.0 31.0 234.0 13.0 * 1933 21.38 14.24 36.0 30.0 187.0 24.0 180.0 26.0 104.0 22.0 242.0 23 0 rfl 1934 13.68 6.22 30.0 18.1 165.0 10.4 147.0 8.3 85.0 5.7 193 0 OJ 5? 1935" 24.08 19.54 43.8 21.0 163.3 10.2 143.9 12.8 81.6 8.7 187.1 11.3 r 26-year r* average 22.35 M.62 19.88 27.0 171.3 17.3 133.19 20.97 25.28 22.08 155.0 19 4 3 111-year 5 average 21.57 14.06 28.58 28.01 184.83 17.96 172.39 20.61 98.2(1 18.24 195.41 17.66 Z 1 Basic Information for a Land Use Program, University of Nebraska College of Agriculture. '—' 3 Nebraska Blue Book, 1936, p. 417. H - * 1935 yield figures preliminary. 22 </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Table 15.— Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, and acreages and yields of oats in Scotts Bluff county and in Adams, Gosper, Kearney, and Phelps counties, 1910 to 1935 * (thousands of acres; bushels per acre). Prccipilalicm, central Ncbr. Seoul Bluff Adams . Goipcr / Kearney - . p hclpi , * Annual | %£%"f Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield"" 3 TiTo 19J89 13.77 . 14.0 45.0 22^0 T- 358 ISO 9~5 ~ 2TO 23? wn . 7T; — 8 1911 23.61 . 14.53 11.0 . . 47.S ¦•: .21.0 "5 . io lIS 180 Jn Sin Iti r. 1912 1K.75 9.88 S.O 70.0 15.0 2l.fi 4.0 175 HO 2il no !«1 °. 1913 24.78 14.85 14.0 53.6 17.0 20.0 5.0 ISO ISO lie win inn _ 1914 22.20 16.55 14.0 53.0 14.0 350 60 50 40 21 n ?' Sr ? 1915 35.62 24.28 10.0 50.0 17.0 343 50 324 , «1 7? Jf'S 2 1916 18.86 13.02 14.0 46.6 17.0 426 50 321 no 111 96 «j I 1917 21.95 14.29 30.0 52.0 56.0 29 0 8.0 250 200 27n 1 li J?n 5 1918 22.52 13.62 13.0 38.0 25.0 HO 60 140 140 13 n inn S'S 8 1919 25.38 16.26 13.0 43.0 19.0 if 0 3.0 320 90 J!o 6? M 0 I 1920 28.24 20.74 14.0 43.0 24.0 39.0 3.0 310 120 !!n 7? l?n ' 1921 21.70 16.53 18.0 38.0 25.0 28.0 5.0 270 30 27n 70 «n H 1922 20J6 14.69 12.0 . 41.0 32.0 200 40 150 240 an «? ?IS o 1923 30.19 21.79 10.0 42.0 32.0 330 40 330 Tro ?nn ri Hi I 1924 23.43 17.79 11.0 38.0 27.0 29.0 SJD 220 160 2o'o so mo 1925 20.54 14.79 12.0 40.0 32.0 20.0 3.0 230 50 Mn «n Sn 3 1926 20.89 13.40 12.0 43.0 . 14.0 7.0 4.0 90 HO §n IS S 1927 22.16 15.08 14.0 41.0 .21.0 35.0 40 290 l|o 300 57 3?0 1928 20.60 12.G5 13.0 52.0 24.0 360 40 310 110 ' « n" 2"&lt; 'Sn ¦ W »29 21.88 13.07 14.0 46.0 27.0 32 0 4.7 3 0 . MO 240 si «'S 3 1930 29.52 20.86 13.0 45.0 24.0 33.0 5.6 ' 400 40 35 nII ?&lt;n c? 1935^ 24.08 19.54 15.8 48.0 . 28.6 31.0 H. 5 . , 2K°O s" "l 360 j? W^r M' 35 M- 62 "• 28 43J «-» ; -2SJ2-- _¦_-&#132; SST ¦ 23J7 15J1 . 24.03 1OJ» . 23.05 | nveraee 21.57 14J6 13.04 42.79 23.48 23.86 . 6.61 25.01 14.70 ' 23.40 7J4 24.1S - 'Baiie Information for a land Uu Program, Univenity of Nebraika Collese of Agriculture ' C~" ~" " 'Nebraska Blue Book, 1936, p. 417. -* . 1 1935 yield figures preliminary. " ' .. . ........ 23 </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Table 16. — Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, and acreages and yields oj oats in Scotts Bluff 5/ county and in Buffalo, Dawson, Hall and Lincoln counties, 1910 to l')iS ' (thousands oj acres; bushels per acre). g :| Prccipilalion, central Ncl.r. Scon, Mult BufTjlu Di»»ii Hall Lincoln 5 Annual | ''r°,™ n "f Acre.ije | Yield .Vrr-iEe | Yield Acreage | Yield Acicafie | Yield Acrease | Yield 1910 IM.H9 11.77 H.n 4vo 4I».O 17 H 16 0 15. H 2Z (1 316 17.1) 20.5 f) !j 1911 2161 1-451 11.11 -17.5 -toil ][' 0 27 n II S 210 12.11 17.0 10.0 » : 1912 18.75 9.8K 5.0 70.0 25 11 X" 1611 20.1] 11.11 2-1.5 13.0 30.0 O 1913 24.78 14.85 H.O 51 6 27 (1 1"S 20 0 17.0 17(1 24.0 18.0 18.0 G ; 1914 22.26 1655 HO 510 |«.n I'M 2(11) .15(1 10.0 44" 14.(1 30.0 1 1915 35.62 24 2« 10.0 511(1 «) II I. I 25 0 14 f, 17.0 32 8 17.0 40.0 G ! 1916 1«.X6 11.(12 H.n 4d (&gt; 2^.11 _1(. I 2&lt;l 0 40.^ 16.1) 42.5 15.0 32.0 g J 1917 21.95 14. 29 .1(1.0 SMI 56 0 111! K6 0 .14.(1 37.(1 .16.0 17.0 26.0 £¦ i 1918 22.52 13 62 1.1.0 3VII 17.0 25(1 2* CI 23 0 27.0 20.(1 17.0 24.0 ' 1919 25. 3» 16.26 13.0 41.(1 22.0 12 n 17.0 .11.0 17.0 36.0 12.0 26.0 W 1920 28.24 20.74 14.0 41,(1 29.0 15.0 26 11 16.0 21.0 3K.0 15.0 35.0 S 1921 21.70 16 51 IS.n 3H.11 35.0 2" 0 26 11 31.0 24.0 32.0 19.0 22.0 m 1922 20.36 14.69 12.0 41.0 31.0 19(1 19.1) 15.(1 20.0 25.0 17.0 16.0 g 1923 30.19 21.79 10.0 42.0 36.0 15(1 22.0 38.0 19.0 35.0 13.0 36.0 V 1924 23.43 17.79 11.0 3K.0 31.0 10.0 21.0 28.0 2.1.0 36.0 16.0 27.0 M 1925 20.54 14.79 12.(1 40.0 2»0 25.0 10.0 25,0 21.0 28.0 20.0 24.0 Z 1926 20.89 11.40 12.(1 43.0 26.0 H.n 18.0 15.0 22.0 8.0 19.0 H.O H 1927 22.16 15.01 14.(1 41.0 2H.11 15.0 17.0 29.0 20.0 34.0 20.0 29.0 m 1928 20.60 12.65 H.n 52.0 26.0 31.0 15.0 36.0 21.0 36.0 19.0 34.0 H 1929 21.88 13.07 H.d 46.0 27.0 27. n 19.0 2H.0 21.0 34.0 21.0 25.0 g 1930 29.52 20.86 1.1.0 45.0 27.0 38.0 21.0 40.0 21.0 38.0 20.0 30.0 3 1931 18.75 9.30 9.6 39.0 23.0 17.0 18.0 27.0 19.0 25.0 17.0 20.0 2 1932 22.95 16.27 11.0 43.0 20.0 13.0 20.0 30.0 20.0 36.0 20.0 17.0 * 1933 21.38 14.24 13.0 35.0 25.0 13.0 25.0 17.0 22.0 10.0 29.0 13.0 pj 193-) 13.68 6.22 15.0 35.9 22.0 3.5 20.0 13.0 18.0 5.3 17.0 15.2 &lt;- 1935" 24.0S 19.54 15.8 48.0 33.6 32.0 34.1 35.0 21.2 25.0 23.8 25.0 P ! 26-year C averacc 22.35 H. 62 13.28 .43.1 30.24 25.51 24.8 26.5 20.7 28.0 17.8 24.6 ~: (, 10-year g averacc 21.57 14.06 13.04 42.79 25.76 24.35 20.71 27.00 20.82 25.13 20.58 22.22 ! : . W j 1 Oaiic Information for a Land Use Program, University of Nebraska College of Agriculture, 'Nebraska Blue Book, 1936, p. 417. • 1935 yield figures preliminary. • ¦ •. ' f 24 </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Table \7.—Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, acreages and yields of wheat in Scotts Bluff county and in Adams, Gosper, Kearney, and Phelps counties, 1910 to 1935 * (thousands of acres; bushels per acre). Annual | %%"? AccMC | Yield Acrc^c | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage) yield Acres* | Yield | 1912 18.75. 9.88 2.0 27.5 108.0 18 8 370 111 tin i*"? ?,?n ,?S ° 1913 21.78 14.85 2.0 23.3 125.0 117 39 0 A 4 Isn H' fi'S U4 1914 22.26 16.55 2.0 28.5 134.0 59 370 3 2 iron i?' 2 S2 ,9 Z S? 1915 35.62 24.28 3.0- 24.4 139.0 I?. |so iol 950 fi'l in«n J'? S I 9'« IB^ 13-02 4.0 26.5 123.0 17.6 39 0 164 «a . ill ofn ,1^- 1 S 1917 21.95 14.29 10.0 , 22.0 5.0 10 0- 60 10 ?5n ¦M VA H S 1918 22.52 13.62 24.0 . 20.0 121.0 80 430 90 lin 5'S ,ifj 12 ° - 1919 25.38 16.26 27.0 22.0 136.0 80 450 lno in§n £2 122*2 9' 0 g 1920 28.24 20.74 23.0 20.0 107.0 11.0 350 S&amp; 95 0 ?'X '2™ .^ 1921 21.70 16.53 27.0 22.0 123.0 9 0 45 0 SO iron n"S ,S» 12 "2 •" 1922 2036 14.69 34.0 16.0 88.0 13 0 52 0 120 «n ?"S JSS"R 7-° § 1923 30.19 21.79 29.0 16J . 73.0 93 200 85 22 12 s i ¦ 1«-° '2-» | 1924 23.43 17.79 , . 21.0 . 20.6 97.0 20J 250 Uo nn £i Hi ,H 1925 20.54 14.79 20.0 19.7 81.0 9% 22 0 30 «2 ?"2 S'2 4-2 d 1926 20.89 13.40 20.0 24.9 100.0 5.9 210 70 ISft 'i' 2 !IJ n -° S 1927 22.16 15.08 20.0 24.0 109.0 : 215 21.0 14 9 |Sn 170 »?n ,11 1928 20.60 12.65 18.0 23.0 116.0 16.9 ISO 70 IDln YA Hi \SA W 1929- 21.88 13.07 18.0 .21.8 95.0 12.0 60 29 Wn Inn S'2 I 6 B 1930 29.52 20.86 19.0 . 24.4 103.0 15.0 8 0 200 Kn S'S SS 10 -° 2 1931 18.75 9.30 19.0. . 15i 94.0 20 0 ' 60 190 " Sl'2 K'2 ?"2 20 -° 1932 22.95 16.27 11.0 17.4 91.0 13 0 140 59 ||-g «•» JB-0 21.0 g 1933 21.38 14.24 9.2 IS.O 87.0 10.0 94 ]! 0 s|° "-J «•» ?.» S 1934— 13.68 6.22 14.0 103 92.0 3 5 15 0 i« - Sin 'i- 2 i?' 2 12 -° .935^ 24.08 19.54 3.1 US 94J I2 J }|S llj ,JJ «;» « g» jvenee 21J7 14.06 15.13 19.2S 98.13 13.11 16.65 13.10 87.92 12 7] 7095 12 30 2 •1935 yitld figures preliminary. .... ¦ . . "."'-..' 25 </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Tablk 18.— Annual precipitation. ram\all during the growing season, atnages and yields oj wheat ,n Scons Bluff county andjn^ugalo^aws^Ja^andJ^nc^coHtU^cs. I')/0joJ9{i &gt; (thousands of acres: bushels per acre). f W5 Kf,2 24 211 in V( .-. ': ''"' N4 M-« 26 3 2^.0 17.0 r" '»'» 22.52 H.(,2 240 BUI « * " V " "'" l6 ° IZ-° r 1919 25.38 X..26 27 0 J&gt;. I™n ,-, , " " 7I" " " 6"° B-° 10^? 2" S M H-' 7 21i 52C8 »•" « 13.86 55.6 H.4S «» 12 . W § '¦'•""' 2'" 57 '•|OG IS- 13 '"» 38.66 14.02 2.5.09 15.20 -16.66 ¦ 15,26 60.22 12 S3 S 3 1935 yield figures preliminary 26 </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Table 19.—Total cultivated acreage of all crops, acres, and yields of alfalfa in Scotts Bluff county and in groups of ; counties in central Nebraska, 1926 to 1935 (thousands of acres; tons per acre). c „. - . ' Valley counties , Upland counties ¦ . acmti mull Uullalo. Dawion, Hall. Lincoln Adams. Gospcr. Kearney. Phelps Year Total I Acres ."...". Total Acres I , Total Acrci... cultivated ¦in Yield 3,, _ cultivated .v. • - in- :. I Yield 3 cultivated In Yield 3 acreage* I alfalfa' i ___ — acreage * alfalfa 3 ~|- ' ¦'"¦ - —--. .-acreage 1 alfalfa 3 1926.... 164.2 . 34.0 . 3.0 ¦'¦•¦¦ 1,152.4 . H8.5 . 2.32 ' 828.3 . 36.0 1.20 ta 1927.... 175.5 37.0 .3.0 1,144.2 144.0 2.78 854.2 35.4 ; 2.32 2! 1928..;. 183.8 . . : 35.0 2.8 . 1,188.6 . , 136.0 ' 2.48 846.6 ¦ 31.5 2.15 ™ 1929.... 184.4 35.0 .. 3.0- .¦¦... 1,080.5 - 130.0 2.52 850.9 28.4 1.88 H 1930.... 186.6 : 36.0 ,3.0 1,232.3 132.0 2.82 . 853.2 29.2 2.62 S 1931.... 157.4 40.0 2.0 ' 1.228.3 136.0 2.15 856.5 313 1.83 Q 1932..:. 150.1 38.0 3.0 ¦ 1,196.8 139.0 2.90 .853.1 . 30.0 2.02 &gt;0 1933.... 156.8 36.0 2.5 1,191.50 140.0 2.68 856.i1-. 30.5 1.82 ¦ _ 1934.... . ... : ¦¦¦ 33.0 .'¦¦ 2.5 ...'.'¦ ...; 150.0 '¦ 1.58 ...... . 33.7 0.42 S? - -1935.:;: ..: ¦¦.;.; 33.8 2.9 .' ¦ ' ¦ .... /.: 149,8 2.68 :: / ..... " .28.6- 1.98. 2 Average 169.85, 35.78 2-P 1,177.08 -140.53 2.49 849.96 31.46 1.82 &gt; cultivated .. ' .'¦. ¦ '. ..... ' '.." ¦•' • ' . " . 2 acreage.; ;... 21.1. .. ¦ . :.... ; . 11-9 . .;: .... 37 Z 1 Nebraska Agricultural .Statistics, 1930 (1931*33 preliminary), p. 10. ... ¦'_'..., W : 3Compilcd from other tables. .¦ . ' . ¦¦.- ..; ' § Table 20. — Total cultivated acreage of all crops, acres and yields of barley in Scotts Bluff county and in groups of* ri ; counties in central Nebraska, 1926 to 1935 (thousands of acres; bushels per acre). w ' .¦¦¦ : . ' _rt Valley counties ¦''. . Upland counties ¦ Scons Bluff .. . Buffalo, Dawson. Hall, Lincoln Adams. Gospcr. Kearney, Phdps 2 Year Total I Acres 1 .. Total Acres . . Toul j . Acre* j'~" S cultivated in I Yield 3. cultivated in '.Yield 3 cultivated 'in Yield" ' g acreage- I barley* I acreage 1 barley a ' acreage ¦ I barley 3 I ¦ X 1926.... 164.20 13.00 39.00 1,152.10 15.00 10.75 8283U 11.50 9 00 68 1927... 175.50 16.00 . 46.00 1,144.20 15.70 28.00 854.20 10.20 24.25 (M 1928.... 183.80 22.00 51.00 1,188.60 25.00 30.50 846.60 12.30 29.25 (S 1929... 184.40 25.00 '.. 50.00 1.080.50 50.30 27.50 .850.90 .31.00 25^0 8 1930 ... 186.60 29.00 47.00 1.232.30 72.00 33.75 853.20 29.80 31.25 1931.... 157.40 27.00 42.00 1,228.30 73.00 20.50 856.50 30.90 20 75 S 1932.... 150.10 24.00 45.00 1,196.80 62.20 25.00 853.10 25.50 24 75 " 1933... 156.80 21.00 45.00 1,191.50 76.90 13.00 , 85650 . 46.10 .13*25 1934 19.00 33.20 .... 47.80 7.20- ... 20:40 225 1935. 18.40 35.00 73.30 26.00 ... 34.20 27.00 Average.. 169.85 21.44 43.30 1,176.82 51.12 22J0 849.96 25J9 20.60 P.ct. of ay. . : cultivated acreage . 12.60 .. ¦ ¦¦¦¦ 430 .^ 3.00 'Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1930 (1931-33 preliminary), p. 10. 3 Compiled from other tables. </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Table 21. — Total cultivated acreage oj all crops, acres and yields of corn in Scotts Bluff county and in groups oj counties in central Nebraska, 1926 to 1915 (thousands oj noes; bus It eh per acre). "" Vjllty counties Upland countici Scotis Illull lliHlalu, Pawmn, Hall. Lincoln Adams. C.ospcr. Kearney. Phclps Year Total Acics Tut.il Acres Tula! Aero cultivated in Yield ' mlliiairJ in Yiel.l • cultivated in Yield ¦ acreage ' corn * acreage ' . i.m j acreage ' corn ' 1916 164 20 25.(10 26.00 1.152. 10 (.Ji.tm ¦&gt; 5u »2» «) 400.00 5-25 2J |y-&gt;7 | 7 j 50 14 IXI &lt;1.00 1.144.20 1,(7. iki II.W 854. 211 -406.00 30.50 g 192S 183 30 17.HU JO. Ol 1.185.6U G66.M) 2125 846.6" 396.00 19.50 » 1929 184 40 ISHO 3'&gt;."o 1.0H0.W W.2J111 |-|«I 'Kri.w 426. IX) H. 75 * 1930 186 00 23 00 J2.00 1.232.30 Ml. TO 27. 5U »5].20 4M.00 27.00 * 19ji 150 10 3900 32.011 1196H0 M 7.00 1».2i 856.50 131.00 19.25 &gt; 1931 157 40 J4 "0 2».0U 1 22K.30 717.00 M.im S'iJ.lO 455.00 19.50 1931 156.S l(,i»i 2.5 1.191.5 713.1)0 2 175 «56.&lt;J0 462.00 21.50 J^ 1934 30.00 18.011 5911.00 7.M 365.00 6.20 jl 1935 43.8(1 29.00 575. ¦&lt;!) I'l.ri 282.20 5-75 ~ Avcrase lt»M 3i.78 2.77 1.176.82 648 .I'J 1862 849.9(5 403.72 16.82 cullivaieil ~ acreaec 16.80 . ... 55.10 47-50 &gt; 'Nebraska Asticultur.il Siati.t.cs. 1930 (193133 nrchmiiury). p. 10. fr) 3 Compiled from other tables. Tauli! 22. — Total cultivated acreage of all crops, acres and yields of oats in Scotts Bluff county and in groups oj g counties in central Nebraska, 1926-1935 (thousands oj acres; bushels per acre). 5 " " Valley counties Upland counties 2 Scotts Blurt IlulTalo. Dawson. Hall. Lincoln Adams. Gospcr. Kearney. Phclpi H Year Total Acres Total Acres Total Acre« Cf&gt; cultivated in Yield * cultivated in Yield * cultivated in Yield 3 J acreage ' oats 3 acreage ' oats a acrcap.c ' oa» a 164.20 IM) 4Toi) 1.152.40 85.00 12.75 828.30 36.70 7.50 S 1927 175.50 14.00 41.00 1.144.20 85.00 31.75 854.20 42.70 30.75 1928" 183.80 13.00 52.00 1.188.60 81.00 34.25 846.60 43.60 33.75 CO 1929 161.40 14.00 16.00 1.050.50 88.00 28.50 550.90 51. 10 33.25 c 1930 ' 186.60 13.00 45.00 1.232.30 89.00 30.50 853.20 49.10 36.00 P 1931' 157.40 9.60 39.00 1.228.30 77.00 22.50 656.50 46.70 24.00 jj 1932" 150.10 11.00 43.00 1.196 80 80.00 29.00 853.10 50.70 29.75 2 1933" ' 156.80 13.00 35.00 1,191.50 101.00 13.25 856.91) 72.00 14.75 2 1934 15.00 35.90 . 77.00 9.25 ... 50.30 3.55 (9 3 5 ;;;.' ;;. is.co 45.00 . 115.70 29.25 ... 78.40 25.62 j« Average. 169.85 13.04 42.80 1,176.82 87.87 24.70 849.96 ¦ 52.23 23.80 l~" P.cc. of ay. cultivated acreage 7.70 ._ 7JO ¦__ ¦¦¦ «;!&lt;&gt; ¦¦ •Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1930 (1931-33 preliminary), p. 10. 9 Compiled from other tables. </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Table 23.— Total cultivated acreage of all crops, acres and yields of wheat in Scotts Bluff county and in groups of $ counties in central Nebraska, 1926 to 1935 {thousands of acres; bushels per acre). ° '¦ ::~"~ " ~ ~~. Valley counlici ~ •~. Upland counties :J&lt; Scorn Bluff llultjlo, Dawion, Hall. Lincoln Adann, Goiper. Kearney, Phelps g Year Total Acrci ~ ~~- " ' ' Total Acrej I Total Acre! I o cultivated in Yield. 1 cultivated in Yield 1 cultivated in Y'eld» !» acreage 1 ¦¦ ' wheat a . . acreage 1 , wheat 3 I acreage * . wheat s I • O 1926.... IMJO 20.00 24.90 1,152.40 186.00 7.88 828.30 297.00 5.92 j. 1927. .. 175.50 20.00 24.00 1,144.20 188.00 19.40 854.20 309.00 17.65 1928 .'. 183.80 . 18.00 23.00 1,188.60 . 200.00 17.68 846.60 320.00 16.42 H 1929.... 184.40 18.00 21.80 1,080.50 ¦ 209.00 13.20 .850.90 272.00 "•£ ¦'¦ S 1930.... 186.60 19.00 24.10 1,232.30 215.00 21.90 853.20 295.00 18.00 g 1931.... 157.40 19.00 KOO :'¦¦; 1,22830 202.00 20.10 85650 283.00 20.50 .; 1932.... 150.10 11.00, 17.40 " 1,196.80 147.00 11.52 853.10 275.00 9.98 g 1933.... 156.80 9.20 15.00 1,191.50 - 107.00 12.00 856.90 208.40 ll.'S - g 1934.... ... 14.00 10.30 .... 135.00 5.15 : ... 249.00 4.08 1935. ..'¦ ... 3.10 16.50 .... '¦¦ 149J0 15.18 ... 246.10 14.45 W Average.. 169.85 ,15.13 19J0 1,176.82 136.23 14.40 . 849.96 273.65 13.00 § p.ci. of ay. . ... ' ' . 5 cultivated ¦ . ¦ ¦.-¦.'. .. ' . r acreage. ... 8.90 ... .... 11.60 .. ... 32.20 .. to •Nebraika Agricultural Sutinici, 1930 (1931-33 preliminary), p. 10. . M ¦ Compiled from other tablet. •¦ ¦ ~ ¦''.'.'_. ¦' w ¦.-.."'- •' .¦ " '-'•¦¦. ¦¦¦¦ ¦¦•¦.¦. •• 29 </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 ' It is interesting to note that the average alfalfa yield in the eight counties fef? yeB".r^ 8 n 7 tODS ' Which is but sli^htly lo^er than the Zfit V h^ ramfall WaS aPProxim«ely equivalent to «sffl7n hWWe? c ral "v Pr?° Sed suPP'e™l i^tion water riff m uS)' aVer3ge y'dd m the ci Sht co^nties exce^ed the Scotts Bluff y le ld by more than one-third of a ton per acre. The yield in the Up - land counfes, in that particular year, was 337 tons, while the valley ZXVTui f tOnn' k " alt°gether P °Ssible *" -^tion wiU make the table land equally as important as the Plane valley in alfalfa producon. Professor Russel, writing on the use of supplement water L th,s area says: We can soak the subsoil 35 feet deep and pump it all out agam w,th alfalfa in five years; then soak it up again and pump it out 7n en-year penod was 4.62 tons. The increase due to irrigation .Isllulns vi d o Cf°T y t aVerage °Ver a teu' year Peri°d W3S 277 tons- An «foated yield of 3.0 tons per acre on the irrigated land of the area is above this county figure by nearly one-fourth ton per acre, but the grade of soils found in he d.«n« combined with a longer growing season and plenty of nature should produce it. Results at North Plane probably cannot be equalled over so large an area. They indicate, however, that S £«T ton estimate is not unreasonable. Corn yields in the years of favorable rainfall were 29.68 bushels 1? bushels lower than the Scotts Bluff yield and 1.67 bushels above the tn" - year average for that county. The ten-year average yield for the va kv counties was R62 bushels; the upland counties iveraged 168 bu h J the so,l through the use of legumes in well planned rotation 3 Sot n '/. C. ,„,«,. The LV „, Sol&gt;p , cracnul ImßMion Wi(er Awl Enc . nct . ns f) s6 </seg>
         <seg id="p031">...¦..' Table 24. — Yields of crops in years of favorable rainfall. 1 « Precipitation, central Ncbr. , . . jj . ' :¦ ¦'.. Year . I Growing Bluff Buffalo Diwion. Hall Lincoln Adam* Co.per Kearney Phelp. Q ' .' ; • __ Annual I -season ___. ' ___ __ "'. ' __™__^__ tI) ¦.¦¦ .' . - .. ;¦" ." ' ¦ Alfalfa (tohf per acre)' ¦¦ ¦ g 1915 ....;. 35.62 . 24.28 3.00 ' 3.&lt;0 3.90 3JO 2.90 3.70 3.30 2.80 3.70 g :....' 1920 28.24 20.74 2.80 3.00 3.20 3.20 2.80 2.80 2.60 2.20 2.20 &gt; 1923 ; ..; 30.19 21.79 2.90 2.70 2.70 2.50 2.90 2.70 2.60 2.50 2.70 Sj 1930 29.52 20.86: 3.00 2.80 3.00 2.90 2.60 2.50 2.80 2.50 2.70 g ¦ Average .:.... 30.89 21.91. 252 2.98 3.20 2.95 2.80 252 2.82 2.50 2.82 S! 10-year average 1926-35 21.57 14.06 .2.77 2.21 232 2J9 2.44 1.56 1.91 1.85 1.68 w : ''¦ ' Increase in years ¦*.•¦'.,.. .. • ¦ ¦ ¦¦¦•'.¦. ¦ ..' -g -¦;•. . of favorable rainfall.. .... .... 0.15 . 0.77 0.28 0.56 0.36 1.06 0.91 0.65 I.M 2 Per cent increase .''' ,' " ¦ . ' .' " over 10-year average.. ...; .... 5.42 . 34.84 9.59 23.43 14.79 5659 ¦ 47.64 35.14 67.86 y ¦ ' . * . Corn (biiihcli per acre) ..' pi 1915.... 35.62 24.28 ¦ 35.50 30.90 27.30 29.30 26.80 35.10 30.00 33.30 36.00 ' ¦'¦'¦¦ M ¦•¦..¦¦¦ 1920 28J4 20.74 .26.00 32.00 28.00 36.00 27.00 33.00 25.00 28.00 25.00 . t; 1923 30.19 21.79 30.00 31.00 35.00 29.00 34.00 29.00 30.00 30.00 31.00 S 1930 29.52 20.86 32.00 26.00 30.00 29.00 25.00 22.00 31.00 25.00 30.00 w Average 30.89 21.91 30.88 3958 30.08 30.82 28.20 29.78 29.00 29.08 30.50 C 10-ycar-avengc 1926-3S 21.57 14.06 28.01 , 17.96 20.61 18.24 17.66 16.24 18.17 15.86 17.01 i&lt; of Cf«o =ra'ble Crainfall.. .... .... 2.87 12.02 9.47 12.58 10.54 13.54 10.83 13.22 13.49 W Per cent increase ;. ¦ ' . ' --.¦¦ . ¦ ' ¦ ¦ .S&gt; over 10-year average.. .... .... 10.25 66.93 45.95 68.97 59.68 83J7 59.60 83.35 79.31 g &gt; Compiled from Tables 9to 18. ' .~-'. , . ~~~~. ... :. - v.- ¦ . ~~' ~~. § 31 </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Tabli; 2-\^~Yiclds^o/jrrops ,n years of favorable rainfall ' (continued). t I'rccjpil.iiion. central Nchr. ' &gt; IWlry (l,,,ihfli per acre) § "23 35.19 2 "79 mm jooo £ ?m! 2"00 32O ° 2"°° 2"00 "•«&gt; g iSIW*" 2I" !ls " jl 22- "2 »5 S3 !S:^ S3 £S 85 « ftr'Si'i^"'*" °° 3 "75 """ '"^ 9» »-W ».6O 6.62 9.11 » over 10. y ear averse 38«1 W 0! 18 . W „.,, 31 . 57 3, 27 3 , „ WJ|) g teW* I**1** 2157 HO6 12- 7' "15 ":is SS II:II giS li: 4 52 § *.'£?££?* 2-21 7M WIS 10- 82 '3-»3 10.89 9.09 8 .12 8. 17 » .vc, IQ-yc, averse ... 5 ., 6 3039 ,¦ „ U _ M S8 _ H r 32 </seg>
         <seg id="p033">.¦ Table 24. — Yields of crops in years^oj favorable rainfall 1 (concluded); .. £ . ¦¦¦• Precipitation, central Ncbr. S coiu '' ' • ¦.'••'¦¦: ¦ '¦• ' ¦¦—' .. • Year ~ ' I Growing Bluff Buffalo Dawson '. Hall Lincoln Adams Gojpcr 'Kearney Phelps § __^ Annual : I leaion . _^_ '. - ' ¦ ' . ¦ ¦ 3 '¦ . ' . v ¦'¦':'¦ '¦'•'¦ :-'.¦¦ ¦ Wheat (bushels per acre) :.¦.''¦ :¦ ¦ ."¦. .ti 1915 ...;:. 35.02 24.28 • 24.40 16.50 19.10 15.80 23.10 13.70 20.30 16.30 19.10 § 1916 18.85 13.02 26.50 22.50 19.40 19,60 19.10 17.60 16.40 18.70 19.70 w 1920 28.24 20.74 20.00 10.00 .; • 11.00 11.00 16.00 11.00 10.00 12.00 12.00 S 1921 :.'.. 21.70 16.53' 22.00 11.00 8.00 14.00 8.00 9.00 8.00 10.00 ' 7.00 S 1923 30.19 21.79 16.30 . 9.00 10.00 11.00 7.00 -9.30 8.50 6.90 5.30 g 1924 23.43 17.79 . 20.60 17.90 15.90 21J0 16.60 20JO 1450 17.90 14.00 1930 ;.... 29.52 20.86 24.40- 22.00 21.70 22.00 21.90 15.00 20.00 17.00 20.00 3 1931 ........; 18.75 9JO ISJO 20.90 21.50 25.00 13.00 20.00 19.00 22.00 21.00 , w Average .... .... 21-18 16.22 15.82 17.42 15.59 14.56 14.64 15.10 14.76 ,_. 10-year average, 1926-35 .... .... 19.25 14.02 15.20 15J6 12.83 13.11 13.10 12.71 12.31 PS Increase in years .¦-¦," . . ', ¦-.' ' . . ."¦ ,' ¦ . '2* of favorable rainfall.. .... .... 1.93 2.20 0.62 2.16 2.76 1.45 1.54 2.39 2.45 S Per cent increase :¦¦ " ' . S3' over 10-year average;. ;....., .... 10.02 15.69 4.08 14.15 21.51 11.06 11.76 18.80 19.90 W ¦Compiled from Tables 9 to 18. . S3 ' " '.'.: " ¦' ¦.¦¦¦¦¦.¦¦¦¦¦ ¦¦ ¦'•."'-.'¦ ; ' '". ¦"¦ ' ¦•¦'¦.. . 8 33 </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 Table 25.— Aljalja acres irrigated, water used, average yields with and without irrigation, and increased yields due to irrigation. 1 ..„, Mc"BC Avcn.sc yield '?««Kll „ Acres inches yield due irrigated applied Irrigated I Dry land to irrl' Per acre (tons) I (loin) Eation ]9W 8.0 UM 3.80 1.50 2.30 "27 3.0 9.87 4.00 2 00 2 00 1928 5.0 9.35 5.76 2.00 3 76 "M 1.0 11.30 5.6(1 1.00 4 60 "JO 3-0 5.67 5.70 3.00 2.70 «' 1-0 33.72 5.00 2.50 2.50 ™ HO 29.07 5.50 2.00 3.50 J9" 40 22.01 4.35 2.00 235 934 10.0 16.88 3.00 1.50 1.50 •»« 20 28.14 3.50 2.00 150 Average 5.4 1X.15 4.62 1.95 2.67 ' Harry E. WeaUy, Pump Irrigation ai the North Platte Experiment Substation, Nebraska Experi - ment Station Bulletin 301. " Table 26.— Corn for gram, acres irrigated, water used, average yields with and without irrigation, and increased yields due to irrigation 1 Average Average yield Increase Increase Acre. inches Li yield per inch Year irrigated applied Irrigated Dry land per acre water added . P" acre (bushels) I (bushels) (bushels) (bttsheli) 1925 35? 11.20 43." 7 5 36 •&gt; 1? 1«« 3°.* III.]" 411.5 2.5 380 37 "2' 36.5 .).&lt; ft,.,) ai o 18 0 19 1528 31 .0 .-, «:,, 3 l- 273 27 1929 359 16 44 47! 14 2 1?5 Vrl 1930 h:o 15...4 %/, So Si 3!o 1931 _ 32.3 14.56 49.1 14.0 35.1 J.J 1933 42 9 |j.r, i4.'i 24(1 30Q i'j 1931 2.1.' :i.H7 5n.l jo* ?-1 Average. 32 4 1J74 is.s 18.5 37.3 j'.6 'Hl' n E,, VVi? ak' V',,'', l"n'' ''"f-1"0" •" &lt;h&lt; No"h ¦"&gt;«« Experiment Subtalion, Nebraska Eiperi - ¦No yield ,n 1932 on jeeount of lu,l 1 Total corn irngjled 37.7 itn. Orjm yields secured on only iavo acres. Table 27 —Estimated yields oj corn (bushels per acre) on some valley farms in 1917, annual rainfall approximately 20 inches. 1 **«f Average Average Increased Farm Acres „(».,,„ yield yield production Dumber irripled h J" lr ,i ß a,ed P? r«™ (ac"nche.) ''¦- '""&gt; m 2 40 5 l 5 52.5 27 5 25 n j ¦ s a a i I; | 1 I H I 1 :': Avcraee. 41 4.60 54.7 30.S 239 Per cent increisc "&gt;y -. due to irrigation • • • /7i6 mC lS*J"mL7nl p" s'"""' ''"""' '"":a'iO" '"«"¦«-¦" ¦" N-rf"»"». Nebraska Expert- </seg>
         <seg id="p035">i Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley Reservoir . Table 28.— Numbers and percentages of winter wheat yields of designated bushels per acre resulting from 'seeding in dry soil and in soil wet Uf different depths at three Kansas stations compared with seedings at North Platte, Nebraska. 1 ¦ '. ¦ "knil moisture con- N""b" Percent dition at lime | North „ .1 North . . ¦•:..; of seeding Kansas |: . ¦ pbttc Kalm* I Plane . " ' Failures Dry &#132; 27 in 38 ; 11 in 18 71. 61 wlVioo;::::::.::..:.:..:. u\«» «¦»« » g w« 2 tea 5 in 34 2 in 6 !• » Wctlfeilormore::. \ 6in 61 2in 18 10 .11 ] Yieldi of 10 bushels or more '.:'¦'.' n 1 7in 38 3in 18 18 17 W«2,te!.,...: .... «jn34 . ,}!»«, : S g -Wet 5} feet or more ? . 51 in 61 ..21in 2&lt; :.-... M »8 &lt; .'.. J yields of 20 bushels or more iw I 0 in 38 0 in 18 0 0 85/¦•f«:::::!::::;:::-:;:; ;«]•»¦ [¦"« 1? S •„ I &lt;„. ... 10 in 34 4 in 6 29 67 W« I fc":o'r'more:;...;... 43 in 61 .: . 18 in 24 .- 70- 75 . &gt; Yields of 30 bushels or more Dry /.;.'...: ..: : oin3S oin 18 0 0 Wet 4 f001..., :....... ¦ OinSJ' ' sin 22 0 . 23.. Wctifcct.. ;...:... 3in34 3 in 6 9. 50 W« B feet or more 14 in 61 9.in 24 23 .38 'I A. L. Hallsted and O. R. Mathewi'j Soil Moiiturc and Winter Wheat, Kanm Agricullural Ex - ncritjicnt Station Bulletin 273 (data in Plans for 1937 Asronomy Work, Nebraska Agricultural College Extension Service). ... ¦ ¦ . . ¦ .. .... [Table 26 gives results from irrigated corn at the North Platte Experi - mental Substation. The nine-year average yield was 55.82 bushels. Dry land test plots over the same period yielded 18.54 bushels an acre. Some estimated yields on irrigated valley farms cooperating with the station are shown in Table 27.' These data for corn in 1927 give an average of 54.7 bushels on irrigated land. Dry land yields were 30.8 bushels. Results in these experiments are higher than the estimated yield for the area. Forty bushels is probably the minimum. It will be exceeded on many individual farms but the high results that are often obtained on small acreages can scarcely be expected over a broad area. Spring-grain yields in the years of high rainfall show substantial in - creases over the 1926-35 ten-year average for the area, but the average '• bushels per acre are lower than in Scotts Bluff county. At the Scotts Bluff Field Station, in a test of 21 irrigated rotations, oats produced an average ot'M bushels per acre over a nine-year period. In this time there was one year of water shortage and two other years when climatic conditions were unfa arable while the oat crop was maturing. In a previous 14-year period of tests, extending from 1912 to 1925, the average yield was 61.9 bushels. 7 Oat yields within the irrigation district in the favorable years averaged 34.1 ijSttpncn H. Hastings, litigated Crop Rotations in.^Y«tcrn Nebraska, 1912*34, Technical Bulletin 512J U. S. Department of Agriculture, p. 9. . ' .-."... . ' </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Table 29.— Annual precipitation, ram/all during the growing season in centra! Nebraska, and acreages and yields of £ potatoes and sugar beets in Scotts^u^county^andjn^uOalo. Dawson, Hall, and Lincoln counties} &gt; &#132; I Growing J" j ~ j~~: ft *¦""" I .ca.o/ Ac,c JB . | Yidd Ac TOt , | Yield Ac,» cc | Yield Ac,c, B , | Yield Ac,c., B . | Yield ? Potatoes 1*126-1930 G A«OP 23.0! ,5.01 9JHU W) .m 1.67U.8 , M .20 gj iil'o" 79.00 i^ 1 Sugar llceu 1925-1930) g (,\crri, ion* per acre) I::: I i Hill I | | i i a r 1 Nebraska Asric.illiir.il Sl^listics. ' — ? 36 </seg>
         <seg id="p037">Table 30.— Annual precipitation, rainfall during the growing season, and acreages and yields of potatoes and sugar g beets in Scotts Bluff county and in Adams, Gosper, Kearney, and Phetps counties. :¦'¦'. ¦-¦¦'¦ o Precipitation, central Nebr. Scottißlufl Adaml Goiper Kearney phcl P' g&lt; Annual | ISTo!* Acmsc \ Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Acreage | Yield Aroie | «eld g ..¦' .. .. . •-¦¦¦¦'¦ Potatoes 1926.1930 .'¦., .. • . '¦'¦" ¦ - '¦'. ¦ a ¦'.'¦ ¦'¦ V" ' (Acrcl, bushels per acre) . ¦¦'..;. ¦ ¦¦'¦'¦-. .'S 1926 2089 13&lt;0 3,138.0 174.00 1,211.0 33.00 nB.OO 32.00 541.00 40.00 336.0 41.00 . . H?:::' UXS .ISOS 5696.0: 175.00 1458.0 90.00 182.00 77.00 «5.00 87.00 366.0 , ¦ 78.00 g 1928 20.50 12.65 10,501.0 170.00 1.651.0 88.00 222.00 73.00 643.00 100.00 368.0 95.00 g 1929 21.83 13.07 9 224.0 151.00 1.308.0 56.00 237.00 49.00 477.00 55.00 334.0 44.00 . R 1930: "'I . 2J.H lots 9M9.0 179.00 .IJSI-O 64.00 227.00 55.M . «1.00 74.00 J41.0 65.00 Aven.EC. 23.01 15.01 7,646.2 169.80 1,383.8 66.20 225 JO 57.20 557.40 71.20 349.0 64.60 g ¦'-.: •.•'¦ .. ; / ¦¦¦¦'.••' :'¦•¦-'. S UB ar Beets 1925-1930) ' ' ¦ ' ..'. ¦" ': ¦-¦-'¦¦&gt; , • '¦¦¦¦•¦ -. '¦¦. ¦¦¦¦ ¦'.¦¦¦. . ¦ (Acres, tons, per acre) . , .. ¦ .- ?S 1M5.... 20.54 14.79 38.996.0 15.80 ¦.:.'¦ ..... ,369.00. 13.00 .... ..... g 1926.... 20.89 13.40 50,064.0 12.20 ...... .... ..... .... 112.00 8.00 .... .... S 1927 ... 22.16 15.08 52,535.0 13.20 .... ¦¦¦¦¦ 216.00 11.10 .... .... r" 1928.... 20.60 12.65 53,752.0 12.40 .... ..... .... 52.00 8.10 .... •-.; % 1M29 ... 2I.RS 13.07 55,404.0 .1.1.98. .... .:.... •,•-¦ 400.00- 10J5 50.0 10J5 1930.... 29.52 20.86 49.098.0 14.84 ..... .... ..... ¦¦¦¦ MJ.OO 11.49 152.0 10.00 g&gt; Avenge, 22.60 14.98 49.974.8 13.40 .... ¦¦¦¦¦ ; ¦¦¦¦ 229.17 10.32 151.0 10-13 fjj sNcbrailca Agricultural Sutlstics. . ¦= 37 </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Table 31.— Total cultivated acreage and acres and y.clds oj sugar beds and potatoes in Scotts Bluff county and in «* groiips i&gt;l_coiinlics in central Nebraska. 1925-1910. g (Tliouiaii.l, „( aC rci; lam per .ictt) t5 | te I i I 1 fill! (Tlimis.inili of acres; bushels per acre) H acreage in potatoes 4.50 q 40 C from Nebraska Aj-ricultiirat Scitijtics, 1930, p. 10. ~~ "" ~~ m -Compiled from other lablcs. H 3 Total cultivated acreage, eight year averaee. 5 ~ - — - - »— 38 </seg>
         <seg id="p039">'¦¦..'' Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley; Reservoir Table 32.—Potatoes—acres irrigated, water used, average yields with and without Irrigation, and Increase in yields due to irrigation} f V-'.?? A™«"""d JXZ?!L Year 1,,l P «d ; uppl.cd | duM.^ {Bui.) (fl«.) (Bur.) 1025 3 50 19.00 478.5 100.0 378.5 IBS &#132;S5 2575 283.0 102.0 181.0 ,927 V 4JO 17.11 290.0 150.0 140.0 m::::::::. m u.® «°-° ?™ \va imo 2.00 16.30 327.0 100.0 227.0 1530 2.00 3UZ 215.4 109.8 105.6 Ml 200 3646 408.0 78.0 330.0 wU;::::::: » U.» 350.0 w.o 253.0 1933 I -50 52.94 ; 331.0 52.0 279.0 !,« "¦ {Jo 33.75 290.0 0.0 290.0 93S ¦¦¦¦¦ 05 2017 293.6 50.0 243.6 Avcr^.V.7. Mb 25.38 . 3333 M.5 233.t 1 Harry E. Weakly, Pump Irrigation at the North Plane Eipcriraettal Station, Ncbralka Experiment Sttlion Bulletin 30t, p. 10. ¦ ••/,... bushels. The ten-year average for the eight counties was 24.25 bushels with nine-tenths bushel advantage to the valley counties. The Scotts Bluff county ten-year average was 42.79 bushels. Barley yields in the four-year period were 30.81 bushels. Ten-year average yields in the valley counties were 22.2 bushels, while the upland counties averaged 20.6 bushels. Scotts Bluff county got 43.32 bushels over the ten-year period. It seems reasonable to assume that irrigated oats and barley within the area will yield 45 bushels per acre as an average. Wheat yields for the wet years and the years immediately following them averaged 15.51 bushels. The Scotts Bluff yields for ten years averaged 192 bushels. This figure does not represent the average yield of irrigated wheat, for Scotts Blul county has a part of its acreage on dry land. In the case of wheat the amount of soil moisture at seeding time seems to be a more important factor in determining yields than subsequent rain - fall. Data supporting this statement are presented in Table 28. .When wheat was planted in a dry seed bed at the North Platte substation failures occurred in 11 plantings out of 18, or in 61 per cent of the trials. Compar - able figures for three Kansas stations showed 27 failures in 38 trials. There were only two failures in 18 trials at North Platte when the ground was wet to a depth of three feet or more at seeding time. Under the same con - ditions six failures in 61 trials were recorded at the Kansas stations. When the soil was wet to a depth of three feet or more, yields in three-fourths of. the trials at North Platte equalled or exceeded 20 bushels an acre. Results at the Kansas stations showed similar yields 43 times in 61 trials under like conditions at planting time.. At North Platte yields of 30 bushels or more were obtained nine times in 24 trials with three feet or more of wet soil when the wheat was planted. Kansas results under the same conditions showed high yields 14 times in 61 trials. From these results it seems reason - able to anticipate 20 bushels of wheat on the average in this area, where </seg>
         <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 Table 33.— Crops now grown in the area that will benefit from irrigation, approximate average percentage of cultivated acreage in each crop, aver - age acreage, average yield without irrigation, average yield in four years of favorable rainfall, average yield in Scotts Bluff county, estimated average yield under irrigation, and increases due to irrigation} (Yield (bushel! or loni) Percentage ,„ _ - of 10-yar £&#132;;. at |. cultivated JVCI»Ee Without Average Scorn mitcd mXi Crop acreage acreage irrigation 1 1"" Bluff average increase incropi f000"' 10-year ol f"" 5?""^ under due to (average) «»&gt; average •?"?, 10-"ar Irri- irri- ramfall average „,,-,„„ lioß Alfalfa 12.6 173.10 1.82 2.87 2.77 3.0 1.18 Barlrv 3.8 68.49 20.84 29.59 44.22 45.0 24.16 Corn 55.1 1.073.50 17.67 29.68 27.91 40.0 22.33 Oati 7.5 136.09 22.90 33.17 41.99 45.0 22.10 Potaioei 0.1- 7 AS' «-«0 ' 169.65' 170.0 i05.Z0 Sugar been 0.4' 7.49" 13.39- 10.2 Wtoi 20 2 462.44 12.70 14.76 ' 19.57 20.0 730 1 Compiled from other tables. 1 Five-year avenge, 1926-1930. 1 Sii-year average, 1925-1930. 4 Average eight yean including [our years of favorable rainfall and four years following. moisture at seeding time can be controlled by irrigation. This estimate is probably the minimum average. Potatoes and sugar beets are not grown commercially to any extent except in the valley counties where water is now available for limited irrigation. Data are not available for these crops over the 26-year period. County potato acreages and yields for the five-year period 1926-30, and corresponding figures for beets over a six-year period are shown in Tables 29 and 30. A summary by groups of counties is presented in Table 31. This information for more recent years cannot be obtained at present. The figures for the valley counties include potatoes that receive water as well as those depending upon rainfall. Acreages here were higher than in the upland counties. Average yields in the valley counties were 89.5 bushels sn acre; in the upland group they were 64.8 bushels. Yields in Scotts Bluff county averaged 169.8 bushels for the five-year period. Data from the North Platte substation presented in Table 32 show an average yield of 333.3 bushels over a ten-year period. Growers in the Kearney area watei - ing from wells sometimes get yields in excess of 300 bushels, but the soil here contains a high percentage of sand and is probably better adapted to potatoes than soils in the irrigation district as a whole. On the average, irrigated potatoes will probably yield not less than 170 bushels an acre. Ample moisture is required to grow sugar beets successfully. For this reason the acreage in the upland counties is small (Table 31). Yields in the two groups of counties averaged 10.21 tons per acre for the six-year period. They are nearly the same in each group, indicating that practically all of the acreage is watered. Tonnage per acre in Scotts Bluff county has averaged 1339 over the six-year period. The Scotts Bluff Field Station has secured yields in excess of 21 tons per acre by increasing the </seg>
         <seg id="p041">Tables 34 and 35 '&lt;.—Estimated 'acreage of present crops that will be irrigated, ten-year average yield and total pro- m duction without irrigation, estimated yield and total production with irrigation, and increase in production due g to irrigation (bushels ortons; carloads). ..'• :' : o ; Average ; Average ' '. Average Production Production Incrcaiein Incrcaie _ Crop : .'.'¦' acreage yield yield . .without with . . production in tcrmi g . irricated - without . wiih .. . irrigation - irrigation . . due to ' of _, ¦¦ ¦ :' irrigation irrigation irrigation carload. O Table 34— ikrigation from kingsley reservoir, 500,000 acres 3 Alfalfa ..:!.... 63.000 1.82:. 3.0 114.660 189,000 . 74,340 7,434 .¦ SS Barley .... 19 000 20.84 45.0 395^60 855,000 459.040 353 .« Baney ....... M 17.67 40.0 4.868,085 11,020,000 6.151.915 ¦'••?l S oiu ' .... 37J00 2250- 45.0 ¦ 858,750 1,687,500 828,750 518 2 Poutoel ....... 2&amp;0 64.80 . 170.0 .129,600 .340.000 ' 210.400 ¦ 351 X Sucarbeetr 2000 .... 10.2 20,400 20,400 1,700 ?) w£i ..:::::: 101:000 12.76 20.0 ; 1,282.700 2,020:000 737300 491 | Total ...;.......;. 500,000 ' 1... .. '\ V ..... : ' ....- ,'. ; .;....... ...... ' 14,948 TiBLE 35— : IRRIGATION FROM RETURN FLOW, 250,000 ACRES ¦ 3 Alfalfa '.. ' 31,500 1.82 3.0 57.330 94,500 37,170 .3,717 JJ S-,]" ¦ - 9500 20.84 ¦ . 45.0 997.980 427,500 229,520 176 r; So™.:::::: 137750 . 17.67 . 40.0 2,434,042 5,5i0,0p0 3.075.958 2.051 g Oau . 18.750 22.90 . 45.0 429.375 843,750 414,375 2&gt;9 ' Foutoel 1........ i:000 64.80 170.0 64.800 170,000 105.200 175 gS Total .-¦ 250J00 ... ...... •¦ — ¦ — ¦¦ 7.474 | 41 </seg>
         <seg id="p042">rr Tables 36 and 37. — Estimated acreage oj present crops that will be irrigated, ten-year average yield and total pro- 5 duction without irrigation, estimated yield and total pioduction with irrigation, and increase in production due g to irrigation (bushels or tons; carloads). &gt; A««aRC A .erase Production Production fncreMein Increaie g Average y i cl( l &#132;iC J( j production I rtKiuction production in term* o c - rop «,cagc wi ', houl Vith .*"&lt;*"?&lt; w' h *«» ¦&gt;' c 1 irrigated irrigation irrigation irrigation irrigation irrigation carload! r Ta LE 36 INCRF.ASR IN PUMP IRRIGATION. 150.000 ACRES 9 &#132;,..,, ' 18 900 1.82 3.0 34.398 56.700 22,302 2,230 r A"r" ?- 7 00 20 »4 45.0 1 18.7HH 256.500 137.712 106 S' »2'&lt;Bl "'-W -t°° 1.160,425 3.306.000 1,845,575 1.230 W S°f" If 250 22 in 450 257.625 506.250 248,625 155 $ ?„.',„, 600 64.M) 170.0 .W.KBCI 102,000 63,120 105 M ™'L,,-; S» 10.2 6.120 6.120 510 g Wh?at .... 30.300 12.70 20.0 384.810 606.000 221.190 H7 2 Total 150.000 4:,483 Z rp E 37 ESTIMATII) TOTAL INCKEASE IN PRODUCTION ASA RESULT OF BUILDING THE KINGSLEY UAM .„ &#132; " 113 400 1.D2 30 206.388 340.200 133.812 13.381 £ A'[r? 34-260 20.84 45.0 712.728 1.539.000 826,272 635 Z 5"' cy 495900 17.67 40.0 8,762.552 19,836.000 11,073,448 7,382 g X°" 67 500 22.90 45.0 1.545.750 3,037,500 1.491,750 932 § S" 3 600 64.80 170.0 233.280 612.000 378,720 631 SSr been 3600 10.2 36,720 36,720 3,060 69 Whew ... '.'.'.'.'.'.'. 18l!800 12.70 21&gt;.11 2.305.560 3,636,000 1,327.140 884 C Total 900.000 26,905 tj 1— &gt; 42 </seg>
         <seg id="p043">Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley Reservoir fertility of the land through the use of manure and a rotation that in - cluded alfalfa. The most substantial increase in total tonnage will probably come from additional acres planted. Estimated Increase in Production - Most of the material in Table 33 is taken from other data already pre - sented. It shows the farm crops commonly grown in the area, the ap - . proximate average percentage of cultivated land in these crops, the ten year average acreage in each crop, some yield data that are considered helpful in arriving at estimates, the estimated yields under irrigation, and the in - crease due to irrigation. From these data the estimated increase in pro - duction, as a result of direct gravity flow from the reservoir, the increase that will be made possible because of. return flow, and the additional pro - duction on land that will be watered from pumps are calculated and presented in Table 34 to 36. The total, which is the sum of these increases, is shown in Table 37. : "¦•.•'•'.'.'¦ In arriving at the production figures, the acres to be irrigated by water from each source are apportioned among the several crops about as they are allotted in present farming practice. There are some differences when counties or groups of counties are considered. For example, about 12 per cent of the cultivated land in the valley counties is in alfalfa. This figure is raised to 12.6 per cent in calculating increased yields and this percentage of the land that will be irrigated is allotted to alfalfa. The revised percent - age is higher than present practice in the upland counties, but it is not possible to make separate estimates for these divisions since the watered acreage is not assigned to them individually at present. For this reason, the percentage figures used assume some shifting of crops in individual counties and in groups of counties. The acreage in corn and alfalfa in the upland area will probably be increased at the expense of wheat acreage. In any event the percentage of land allotted to alfalfa is low when the feed value of the crop and the benefits from it in added soil fertility are con - sidered. Alfalfa occupies 21 per cent of the cultivated acreage of Scotts Bluff county. ¦ : ¦: Total volume of production within the area will probably not decline materially from the estimated increases as a result of changes in the crop - ping system. Shifts in crops are usually made because of anticipated in - j creased returns from the revised acreage. Income is the result of sale of I products. If it is to be maintained over a long period production must not ; decline materially. ' The estimated total increase in crops, when figured in shipping tonnage, f¦. adds 26^905 carloads of farm products to the annual business available in \ thearea. It is not supposed that all of the increased production of hay and j grain will be moved from the area in this form. Records for the state as a f ' ;•¦ whole from 1921 to 1930 show that 28.7 per cent of the corn, 14.8 per cent | ot the oats, 16.1 per cent of the barley, and 76.4 per cent of the wheat | ¦•¦¦¦ were shipped. 8 The rest of these crops were consumed on farms. Increased ' . ¦ "Nebraska Agricultural Siatiilicl, 1930, p. 89. &#132;: - .'. : </seg>
         <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 supplies of these valuable grains, combined with an abundance of alfalfa hay, will convert central Nebraska barnyards into feed lots for finishing range calves and lambs enroute to market. ¦ Scotts Bluff county with 203,600 acres of its area irrigated, has been a valuable source of well finished meat animals throughout the drouth period." During June, 1937, feeders in this county topped the Chicago cattle market more times than any other county contributing finished beef animals to that important market. 10 The explanation is found in the abundant supply of feed suitable for finishing cattle. The Reservoir Area In order to store water for irrigation in central Nebraska approximately 32,000 acres of Keith county land will be covered by the Kingsley reservoir. Not all of this land is tillable and a part that can be cultivated is low grade soil along the North Platte river bed. If it is assumed that the entire acre - age consists of Grade I and II soils 79.8 per cent of which are cultivated in the county, the annual loss in agricultural production does not exceed 1,100 carloads (Table 40). [f this maximum production is substracted from the 26,905 carload increase on the land that will receive supplemental water in die irrigation district, the estimated net annual increase in all crops is 25,805 carloads. Actual production in the reservoir area is believed to be at least 25 per cent lower than the 1,100 carloads estimate. A large part of the land that will be covered by water is Grade 111 and IV soils. Actual yields on these classes of land are lower than the averages used in the estimates. Details are given in Tables 38 and 39. In working out the estimated production for the reservoir area acreages were allotted to the several crops according to the average percentage or. land planted to them in the county as a whole. A large part of the land tributary to this particular area is used for grazing. Farming practice with- i in the county confines wheat largely to the table land. Desirable land that \ will be covered by the reservoir is used for feed crops.. The estimated l annual production of wheat in Table 40 is 72 cars. An average of only 6.2 I carloads were shipped the past ten years (Table 41). Hay and other forage '¦ crops replaced the wheat. As a matter of course, the major part of these ' crops was consumed locally. \ During the ten year period ending 1936, total outgoing carload ship- ] ments from four stations serving the reservoir area have averaged 523.4 cars annually. It is not possible to determine the exact amount pi this total ; corning from the acreage that will be covered by water. The combined shipments, out and in, averaged 724.9 carloads. More than 72 per cent (72.8) of this total was livestock. Cattle and sheep will probably continue to find their way into and out of the territory surrounding these shipping points after the reservoir is filled. Freight forwarded, other than livestock, averaged 42.7 carloads annually for the 1927-36 ten year period. 'Ncbrailu Agricultural Sutiitics, 1930, p. 6. "Hmingi Duly li;t&gt;unc, July 3, 1937. ¦: </seg>
         <seg id="p045">Table 38.— -Acreage and yield of grain crops and potatoer in Keith county 1 (thousands of acres; bushels per acre). o Barley Corn Oats .' ; Rye Wheat Potatoes 5* Year j : p- : :—; — j— : ; — j ¦ j '¦ j ¦ » "Acres | Yield Acres [ Yield Acres | Yield Acres | Yield Acres | Yield Acrei' | Yield" g 1925 3.00 ; 25.00 66.00 23.00 B.SO 28.00 2.60 12.00 33.00 M.40 0.30 90.00 % 192fi 4.10 23.00 70.00 10.00 11.00 22.00 4.70 9.00 39.00 11.80 0.40 65.00 Z 1927 3.60 34.00 63.00 27.00 8.40 34.00 4.40 16.00 62.00 22.80 OJO 108.00 iSS ¥*&gt; 38- 0() 57.00 24.00 7.50 40.00 4.20 14.00 65.00 . 20.90 . 0.40 110.00 g !2 2J ,lM 2800 «4.00 22.00 7.60 28.00 3.40 12.00 63.00 16.90 0.40 80.00 O £? ¦¦ ' J*-22 '•¦'•¦ ?2-S2 65.00 27.00 5.40 35.00 2.40 15.00 81.00 23.90 0.50 100.00 g 1931 14.00 16.00 79.00 15.00 5.70 .20.00 2.70 8.00 82.00 10.00 . .... 1932 20.00 19.00 106.00. 17.00 8.00 22.00 .150 9.00 32.00 10.10 ... .... 3 1933 18.00 12.00 89.00 2AM- . 11.00 13.00 1.60 7.00 49 00 10.00 n ¦934 9.10 9.30 '77.00 5.40 6.10 9.60 2.40 tSO 6SM .B^o '..'. ,V.. Average 9.42 23.73 73.60 19.44 .7.92 25.16 3.03 10.88 57.10 14.95 0.38 92.17 W Per ecnt of' ¦¦.. ¦. . ';. ¦¦¦¦. . . . ' •'..'. ¦ ¦- 3 cultivated ¦ . ¦-¦ ¦ . ' . .'-..... ' .'.¦.. .¦,-¦ ¦.¦¦¦ ¦¦ . S land In .-'•¦¦: . . . . H crops 4.68 . 36.60 .... 3.94 ... 1.51 .... 28.« .... 0.19 .... m 'Basic Inforfation for a Land Use Program. Nebraska College of Agriculture. to 3 Nebraska Agricultural Statistics. .... . ". tn :¦¦"¦¦¦¦¦¦¦ ¦ .¦ ¦' ¦¦ ¦¦ .-.' ¦¦ ' . ¦ ¦..¦'¦- .'.'¦¦¦¦.. ... 3 45 </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 Table 39.— Acreage and yield of hay crops and sugar beets in Keith county 1 (thousands of acres; tons per acre). ' I Al/alia Wild hay Sugar ban | Acrel | Yield Acres' | Yield 1 Acres * | Yield! 1925 11.00 2.90 43.00 0.60 0.50 15.00 1926 9.60 2.60 10.00 0.70 0.80 9.50 1927 11.00 2.80 41.00 0.90 2.20 9 00 1928 10.00 2.60 41.00 0.80 2.30 8.80 1929 9.10 2.80 41.00 0.90 U0 11.53 1930 9.50 2.80 43.00 0.90 1.00 14.17 1931 10.00 1.60 1932 6.20 2.40 1933 .. 5.60 2.40 1934 6.60 2.20 Average .... 8.86 2.51 39.40 0.83 1.35 U. 33 Average total acre! culi. - valcii (includes wild ivy 201.6 Per cent of cultivated land in crop* 4.41 19.60 ... 0.67 1 Bane Information for a Land Use Program, Nebraska College, of Agriculture. : Nebraska Acncultural Statijtici. Table 40.— Estimated production on land covered by the Kingsley reser - voir, acres of crops taken out of production, ten year average yield, total production, production in terms of carloads 1 (acres, tons or bushels, carloads). Cop Average Average Average Production acreage yield production carloads Alf^lfj 1,126 2.51 2,826 282 Barley 1,195 23.73 28.357 22 Corn 9.346 19.44 181.686 121 Oau 1.006 25.16 25,311 16 Pouioei 48 92.17 4,424 8 Rye 386 10.88 1,200 3 Sugar becti \7l 11.33 1,937 161 Wild hay 5.006 0.83 4,155 415 Whcai 7.252 14.95 108.417 72 Toial 25.536= ... 1,100 ; Compiled from Table 37. &gt; 79.8 per cent of 32,000 is 25,536. It is estimated that 12.395 carloads of construction material, supplies, and equipment will be delivered by the railroad serving the reservoir area while Kingsley dam is under construction. It would require 290 years of normal outshipments, except livestock, from the four stations serving the reservoir area to aggregate this total. But this is not all of the freight that will be made available by the structures that make up the total project. Diversion dams, canals, power houses, transmission lines, and substations will require an additional 6,530 carloads of material and equipment that will be delivered by rail. These shipments will probably be divided between the railroads serving the irriga - tion district, the major part of them going to the line that can make delivery at the most convenient point with respect to the particular project under construction. Gravel, which may be hauled by truck, is deducted in arriving at the above figures. Details of the materials that will be used in the project are presented in Table 1. </seg>
         <seg id="p047">;¦¦¦.¦ - ¦. ' ¦ .¦¦¦ ¦¦ " ¦¦; :.'' ¦ .. pi Table 41.—Freight shipments at Bdlmar, Keystone, Lemoyne, and Martin, Nebraska, 1927-36} -- , . Freieht fonlwqrdcd ..... . ' Freight received O ' V» f W.,ca, | Com | ,*&amp;, [ Llves.oe.cl ™Zs dumber | -jg^ | ' ™^ |M ¦ \ jj^^ \ *£&gt;&#132;¦ g !?« "d "''¦¦ 2-° "d "S- 0 f-O ; 38.0 8.0 . 76.0 36.0 56.0 93.0 Z 1929 . ¦ 6.0 I.o' 17.0 573.0 " 58.0 I*o 5 0 17 0 Jl 0 37 n B4 n *° I9JO ••22.0 1.0 3.0 512.0 Ho° 21.0 1.0 \H 3W 15 ' 93.0 ° ?!{ f° ¦ •¦•: f«-0 13-0 : 17.0 3.0 23.0 24.0 62.0 97.0 }*g I-° ¦ ." ¦¦ f»80 9-0 6.0 1.0 15.0 16.0 36.0 77.0 2 '|J '- 0 ¦ .•• :.. !¦•¦. ¦ j«.O .58.0 15.0 19.0 7.0 9.0 20.0 ¦ 50.0 " 'S •• ..:¦¦.. •• • ¦ 3».0 10.0 ' 9.0 .126.0 28.0: ..-22.0 : 17.0 42.0 -.W 1 Compiled from 51311011 records; Ncbratlta Stale Railway Commission, Rate Department. ' : ~ ' " ~ : r ¦¦¦ ¦-.'¦¦¦¦ ...;'.¦¦ ¦ ¦¦¦ , ¦ ¦'. "¦•.¦•. ';¦¦ .-¦¦¦'.¦¦¦ . . ';¦¦ ,: : ¦¦'•¦¦¦¦".'.¦ ':,;'¦¦¦¦¦.¦¦ /; ¦'¦'. ...'". ¦ ;; ¦;1 ¦'»'¦ ."'¦¦¦¦¦'¦¦....¦¦ ¦ ..' .''. ¦¦ ¦ . ".'¦¦¦¦• ¦ •¦" ' p&gt; 47 </seg>
         <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 Population Table 42 gives the population by census periods for Scotts Bluff county ;md for each of the eight counties that will benefit from Kingsley reservoir irrigation water. Since 1900 population has declined steadily in Gosper, Kearney, and Phelps counties. There were 5.301 people in Gosper county in 1900; in 1930 there were 4,287. The population in Kearney county de - clined from 9,866 in 1900 to 8,094 in 1930. Phelps county had 10,772 peo - ple in 1900; in 1930 there were 9,261. All of the other counties and the district as a whole showed moderate population increases at each of the census periods. In contrast to these conditions population in Scotts Bluff county has advanced very rapidly. In 1900 there were 2,552 people in the county. By 1910, when the first beet sugar plant was opened for operation, the number had increased to 8,355. The increase has continued. In 1930 there were 28,644 people residing there. Through the influence of irrigation this county has advanced from thinly settled arid range country to a more densely populated county than any in the central Nebraska district. Table 42.— Population in nine Nebraska counties. 1 County | 1900 | 1910 1920 ) 1930 Adami 18.840 20.900 22,621 26,275 Buffalo 20.251 21.907 23.787 24,338 Dawion 12.214 15.961 10.004 17.875 Gospcr 5.301 4.933 4,669 4,287 Hall 17.206 20.361 23,720 27.117 Kearney , 9.866 9,106 8,583 8,094 Lincoln .. U.4IG 15.684 23,420 25,627 Phclp. 10.772 10.45] 9,900 9,261 Scorn Blufl 2.552 8.355 20.710 28.644 ' Ncbti.ka Blur Hock. 1934. p. 412. The possible amount of population increase in the irrigation area is variously estimated from 50 per cent over the present number to four times as many. Some increase seems warranted because of more intensive culti - vation resulting from a dependable supply of moisture, but the exact percent - age is difficult to forecast. In Scotts Bluff county the 1910 population was 3.27 times the number enumerated in 1900. At the end of the next decade the number of people residing in the county had increased 2.48 times the 1910 census figure. By 1930 the population was 138 times the 1920 total. The advance will prob - ably be less rapid in the central Nebraska area. Irrigated land in Scotts Bluff county was opened for settlement in 1906 while the land hunger of the homestead period was still great. From time to time other tracts were settled as additional ditches were laid out. It was a new country, thinly settled, with no prior owners holding title to it. People drew lots for the right to possess it. The situation is quite different in the central Nebraska area. There is at present an owner class, many of whom have farms large enough to be economic units under dry land conditions. These holdings will be broken </seg>
         <seg id="p049">Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley Reservoir up slowly. It is doubtful if poulation will increase more than 50 per cent in the first ten year period after water is made available for irrigation. . Size of Farms The number of farms decreased, during the three census periods be - tween 1900 and 1930, in all counties within the irrigation area where population declined. There were also 234 fewer farms in Adams county where the number of people increased due to the growing importance of Hastings as a manufacturing and trade center. In 1900 there were 1,013 farms in Gosper county. The number recorded was lower at each census period until there were only 846 in 1930. Kearney county had 1,509 farms at the beginning of the century. Thirty years later there were 1,249. Farms in Phelps county numbered 1,452 in 1900 and 1,196 in 1930. In the other counties of the district there was either no appreciable change in number of farms or a moderate increase as shown in Table 43. Table 43.— Number o/ farms by census periods. 1 County •. ¦ | 1900 | 1910 \ 1920 | 1930 Adams 1,919 1,831 1,688 1.715 Buffalo 2,381 2,456 2J76 2,429 Dawion ' 1.728 7,09} 1534 2,086 Goipcr 1,013 ' 915 882 U6 Hall ;.:.... 1,617 1,627 1,556 1,628 Kearney 1,509 U76 I JOS 1,249 Lincoln .'..;.. 1,458 1,976 2,024 . 2,189 Phelps 1,452 1,459 1,271 1,196 Scotu Bluff . 421 1,128 1,391 1,793 1 Twcltth census of the United States, Agriculture, Vol. I, p;- 375 ff.. .. ¦: Fourteen cemus of thr Unilcd Slates, Agriculture, Vol. VI, Pan I, p. 690 fl. Scotts Bluff county presents a distinct contrast to these'conditions. It had 421 farms in 1900 and 1793 farms in 1930. There seems to be no marked tendency to increase the size of farms in that part of the area where conditions favor crop production. In similar sections, where available water has made conditions favorable to more in - tensive land use, the tillable acreage has been divided and'the number of farms has increased. No doubt irrigation within the Platte river watershed will increase the number of farms and make it possible for more people to reside there. ¦ Transportation The irrigation district is served by a splendid network of railroads, (Figure 3). The main line of the Union Pacific, paralleling the Platte river, almost bisects it. The main line of the Burlington passes through Adams, Kearney, and Phelps counties along the southern boundary of the watershed area. The Billings line touches the east end of the district at Grand Island. Branches of these roads, extending from Kearney, Hastings, and Grand Island complete the network traversing the area. A Missouri Pacific branch; extending north through Hastings, barely touches the Platte river watershed at Prosser, which is the end of the line. The Chica- </seg>
         <seg id="p050">===== Y^^^ : Carlo a d frcight^lupmcnts. all slulmns. .1da,,,, ami Huffato counties. Nebraska. 1926-35? % Forwank.l ~~ '~=^. -= = £ _ _. _ Received l«2« 948.0 686.0 .M 9.0 9H.0 1110 0 IsOTO '»4 i-S"S "J l 0 ' ¦75A -° 26i ° 3-»"-0 7.537 0 3 JW 851.0 300.0 108.0 800.0 2.1,6.0 ijmi '"&lt;&gt; 7070 S ,'^ ° 522 -° 3.950.0 7 «M g "" '¦"» «'-« «.&lt;H 71.4.11 l»»i.,i 4,»u," I.)' 1 n?in 1.826.0 289.0 4.011.0 7.576 0 r '«¦'" 805.0 202.C 439.0 703.0 IV, 0 ,492 0 1-Jn S'2 ' -sW '° 160 -° 3-&lt;»2.0 7 247 0 '?« 531.0 29.0 302.0 841.0 78 0 S K « " 'l^?, " 2,° ' • *" ¦» «0 2.792.0 6 176 0 tfl '« 75° 2'« 2JO-0 778.0 I ,O*i.o MJ9O 118 0 100 0 i-on t ?«n 376' 0 '¦83 »-° ¦(-021- 0 S I9M "l 0 W.O 150.0 806.0 1.781.0 iOIOO ." I) &#132;% lZ°. 112.'' 0 ¦"' ° '-928- 0 3.865.0 S "2 319.0 1.075.0 679.0 2.567.0 2.655 1) 7 2950 4 n/n •"S' 0 570 -° 2'I&lt;HO 5.861.0 2j 19311 !91.0 1.140.0 789.0 1.873.0 3.926.0 8 119 0 '«l 1?, n .? H 3O' 0 *2M '•7SI -° 5.0 M.0 g 1 if 11 11 1 11 1 is 11 1 (implied from station records, Nebraska Slate Hallway Commission, Kate Department. ~— — - '2, t— * 50 </seg>
         <seg id="p051">Table 45. — Carload freight shipments, 'all stations, Dawsbh and Gosper counties, Nebraska, 1926-35} ' ' ¦!? .. ¦ ::: :— ¦ . :—: ; : .—. :|« V" r ..- Bra'i"* Live- Oilier **•¦! I.imc- Cmiii , ; v1! . ll|rr Total 3 ttl.cat Corn i(1 M , X . t c ., r | o ,, u all LuiiiKr nnjciu ,n,l ,r»,i a»l sl(ltk nr , M ,U »» o : |;r...lucn tarlnidi . sand |ir.«lnclt .tarl«d ¦ ¦.' ¦¦...'..- ." .- ' ','.'. l)a\v»iu county, Nebriuka ... .. ' -¦ ' " -¦ . W '¦• . ¦¦¦ W, 200.0 »l.a '569.0 3.230.0 CWO.O 11.050.0 25«.«l H3.U • 575.0 «I2.(I 415.0 1.216.0 3.245.0 2 1927 346.0 310.0 560.0 2.697.0 5,770.0 9,683.0 2K1.0 149.0 563.0 66').0 ¦ 403.0 1.135.0 3,200.0 P . 1923 • 328.0 1,416.0 718.0 3,024.0 6.128.0 U.6H.0 249.0 142.0 550.0 583.0 774.0 1,171.0 3,469.0 1923.. 377.0 1,131.0 629.0 3,212.0 5,603.0 10,952.0 260.0 117.0 711.0 715.0 614.0 1.415.0 3,832.0 B 1930 . 378.0 781.0 841.0 '2,897.0 6,516.0 . 11,413.0 245.0 260.0 545.0 653.0 430.0 1,253.0 3,388.0 g 1931 . 329.0 1,094.0 1,256.0 3,051.0 3,872.0 9,602.0 221.0 359.0 365.0 452.0 462.0 • 1.135.0 2,994.0 1932 .171.0 665.0 943.0 2,797.0 2,688.0 7,264.0 109.0 106.0 224.0 439.0 396.0 834.0 2,108.0 g 1933 ' 142.0 .426.0 946.0 2,349.0 4.007,0 7.870.0 91.0 183.0 291.0 323.0 385.0 674.0 1,947.0 § (934 49.0 256.0 759.0 3,302.0 7,176.0. 11,542.0 13S.U 136.0 318.0 334.0 379.0 806.0 "2.111.0 g 1935 283.0 34.0 : 649.0 1,301.0 1,474.0 3.741.0 152.0 46.0 196.0 473.0 486.0 952.0 2,305.0 . . Average 1 260.9 . 615.4 .787.0 2,786.0 5,020.4 9.473.7 200.4 .164.1 431.1 524.3 474.7 ' 1.062.1 2,859.7. . g ',"*:'' &#132; ; ' ¦... . ,' . Gosper county, Nebraska ;:. ¦ - ... .. : . 1920 38.0 92.0 3.0 302.0 16.0 .. 451.0 31.0 37.0 . 21.0 45J 10.0 112.0 256.0 , . W 1 ¦ 1927 ¦¦ 51.0 122.0 1.0 238.0 '5.0 417.0 21.0 ¦ 8.0 ...¦ 26.0 60.0 3.0 93.0 211.0 5 1928 86.0 376.0 . 288.0 4.0 754.0 !6.0 13.0 15.0 49.0 14.0 95.0 202.0 § J929 .88.0 187.0 "2.0 342.0 2.0 621.0 17.0 11.0 6.0 66.0 12.0 118.0 --¦ 230.0 - S 1930 71.0 181.0 . 16.0 -298.0 2.0 568.0 -22.0 50.0 9.0 64.0 10.0 108.0 263.0 W 1931 ' 66.0 396.0 1.0 ~ -295.0 66.0 824.0 10.0 4.0 2.0 ' 37.0 28.0 73.0 154.0 * 1932 9.0 41.0 3.0 258.0 59.0 : .370.0 10.0 1.0 .. 48.0. 7.0 56.0 122.0 h3 1933 52.0 112.0 1.0 236.0 37.0 438.0 7.'J 5.0 .. 33.0 11.0 41.0 97.0 m 1934 8.0 79.0 520.0 16.0 623.0 7.0 . .. 4.0 40.0 7.0 53.0 111.0 2 1935 71.0 1.0 1.0 118.0 1.0 192.0 11.0 2.0 15.0 48.0 3.0 63.0 142.0 3 ¦-¦¦¦.. Avcraec 54.0 158.7 2.8 289.5 20.8 525.8 15.2 13.1 9.8 49.0 10.5 81.2 178.8 g 'Compiled from nation records, Nebraska Stale Railway Commission. Rate Department. ¦¦ . ' .* . 51 </seg>
         <seg id="p052">T\i'LE 46. — Carload freight shipments, all stations. Hall and Kearney counties, Nebraska, 1926SS} 3 FnrwanWd Received '"' train anil Live (Hhcr '«" , Mmc anil , Live- Olhcr lo!|" g" Whea. Corn Krain &#132;u ck tj,!™,), &lt;"" Lumlw, cemcnl Erjin Coal , I()ck carload, »" 2 11.11 .(.Hilly. N,1T...k.l G 1926 123.0 211.0 540.0 2 708.0 VMI.O 7.219.0 4«l 0 446 0 1.023.0 1.491.0 2 455.0 4,571.0 10.446.0 E 1927 402.0 167.0 527.0 2 252 0 2,517.0 5.865.0 711.0 2« 0 9G6.0 1.512.0 2.059.0 4.039.0 9.549.0 d 1928 307.0 264.0 462.0 JJ9I 0 2,697.0 6.921.0 525.0 212.0 1.192.0 1.539.0 2.696.0 5,869.0 12,033.0 g 1929 286.0 164.0 558.0 3.058.0 2.848.0 6.914.0 589.0 257.0 1.026.0 1.798.0 2.014.0 6.663.0 12,347.0 S 1930 290.0 165.0 547.0 2.267.0 4.140.0 7.409.0 450(1 424.0 701.0 1.409.0 2,064.0 6.946.0 11.994.0 1931 351.0 68.0 584.0 2.431.0 1.9U.0 7.347 0 222.0 572.0 537.0 1.092.0 1,946.0 6.221.0 10.590.0 PI 1932 195.0 59.0 325.0 3.393.0 1.647.0 5.619.0 130.0 7!,0 54i.0 988.0 2,963.0 4,678.0 9.373.0 |3 1933 273.0 94.0 249.0 3 360 0 1.548 0 5.524.0 152.0 (15.0 333.0 859.0 2.765 0 4.701.0 9,125.0 M 1934 93.0 25.0 177.0 4 213 0 1904.0 6,412.0 146.0 112.0 323.0 1.043.0 1.779.0 4.324.0 7 727.0 S&lt; 1935 137.0 6.0 255.0 2,342.0 1.354.0 4.124.0 180.0 91.0 333.0 1.245.0 1.338.0 5.524.0 8.711.0 9 Average 245.7 122.5 422.4 2,921.5 2.623.3 6.335.4 156.5 276.4 697.5 1.297.6 2.207.9 5.353.6 10.189.5 trt Kearney n.ii.ily. Nc1...,,k.. 2J 1926 391.0 15.0 3.0 9210 1,019.0 2.349.0 63.0 248.0 210.0 319.0 49.0 417.0 1306 0 C/j 1927 926.0 73.0 26.0 583.0 1.210.0 2.819.0 68.0 665.0 217.0 354.0 61.0 433.0 1.798.0 tj 1928 739.0 333.0 21.0 826.0 339.0 2.258.0 59.0 240.0 34.0 341.0 83.0 410.0 1.167.0 5 1929 790.0 118.0 3.0 851.0 589.0 2,351.0 56.0 362.0 44.0 367.0 68.0 419.0 1.3160 S 1930 808.0 138.0 9.0 710.0 565.0 2.230.0 61.0 133.0 22.0 296.0 40 0 483.0 1035 0 2 1931 952.0 285.0 10.0 728.0 311.0 2.286.0 35.0 147.0 12.0 2(19.0 48.0 358.0 809 0 1932 583.0 21.0 (&#132;« 759 0 MO.O 1.999.0 fi.» 20.0 2.0 1%.0 26.0 277.0 536(1 EO 1913 722.(1 121.0 883.(1 2U.11 1.949.0 50.0 20.(1 1.0 215.0 If, 0 271.0 571 II G 1914 284.0 50.0 »29.(l 59.0 1.222.0 14.(1 107.(1 8.(1 160.(1 3.0 215.0 51)7(1 C 1935 439.0 &lt;i.O ¦ 252(1 101.0 800.0 22.0 55.(1 36.0 222.(1 5.0 250.11 590 0 S AWiage 663.4 116.0 7.8 734.2 504.8 2.026.3 44 3 199.7 58.6 267.9 39.9 351.3 963 7 H 'Compiled from Million records, Nrhraska Stiitc lt.ulw.ly OniiniisMini, K.uc IH-parliuenl. 52 </seg>
         <seg id="p053">Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley Reservoir. % ' ~~ ¦ '¦¦' . ¦' .. ¦ ' ¦• . '¦. .-¦.: ¦ *O tj"| qoqqqqqqqq&lt;o oqqqsqqqoan] .£ ~~~ ; ; -:;: . _-• ¦;¦• ¦¦' .¦;¦. "&gt; " . v ¦' ¦ " ¦ " ¦¦¦.-. « . v.-B" qoqqqqqqqqN . oqqqqqqqqqN * I4i- .: -¦¦:;¦ : : 2 j S ;,. —- ' ¦~~~r; .--: : . ; :&gt;-. •:•, ¦¦ S. 'e-8 ' • '.:. ¦ ¦ ¦ '¦'¦¦¦ .*« :¦ . T~ ":"-."¦¦".'¦¦¦ ¦ " ¦ '' ¦ : § 6§c 9qqqqqqqqqo| oqooqqqqoqrN 8 i/;; ¦¦¦¦''¦:'¦¦•¦¦ I;-:-: ".:j '' i ¦S :Jf {oooqqqqoqon j qqqqqqqqqqi; c • S!. -—n 3" " ¦ ' ' C ¦ O ¦ § « "f OqqqqqqqqqN 3 oqe3qqqcsqs?qfli jj =§ 3 ... •.¦ . • •;. ;?¦;. ¦/¦.¦¦ | . •¦;¦.¦' ¦¦.-¦.- ¦'¦¦•¦¦ ,¦' ¦ .-'¦'¦ 1 g ¦¦ ¦•..!! •HSgl3aSigBa-.vaS9B!3B*S*s « ."S ~~ V: ; ; ¦"¦.;¦ '¦¦.¦¦:.; .""" ¦".';¦ • . '"¦¦ ¦•¦. | *^ *2 , „ . ooooooqooon ooqqqqqqqqr] 5 Jfw oC \d orJai\6r*r^ =c *r » ocoo wn'irt r^r^'o^fN « bo v. M — .****«-."« -.-., .- •¦¦;'• ¦,- , •fc. -. . ¦ ;; -¦¦-•¦ •¦¦¦¦: ¦ c H : ||e| |2g2R¥=S2-!8 SSSSS^S^S z :'3 : JL^; ¦:.:- \ ':; &#132; ' i ..¦¦.._ qqoqqqqqejqrj Oqqqqqqqqcn &#132; o . — Mi^m^MMi^r* is «dj —o» •*• o« o; no Q «3 ¦ ¦'- ¦ ¦ . . ¦ . ¦ 5 ¦¦¦ w;; ¦' :._'¦ .;.;. ¦¦¦....-.' ¦ ".- ¦¦. &#132;¦ ¦ g . i-&gt; ' ¦ I ¦ KS3:S6SiSfe!f§2 RiPSSSSSSSIIS^: 'S ' , ¦;¦':'¦¦ v ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ £ | ¦ . j* . o.o»o*o\o'.O.OvO\o\o&gt;i CX O, Oi C\ O. Oj Oj £O* O\ 53 </seg>
         <seg id="p054">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 Table 48.— Carload freight shipments, all stations of all railroads, operat - ing in Adorns, Buffalo, Dawson, Gosper, Hall, Kearney, Lincoln, and Phelps counties 1926-35? Forwar.lcl v"' s,,°'tL\ . , Other T""1 Wheat Corn jn Livestock carloads »« product. ca''&lt;"'ls 1926 1,054.0 2J-U.O 2.395.0 13.536.0 21.451.0 41,678.0 1927 4 262.0 3 OH.O 2.425.0 10.921.0 17.743.0 38,3(H.0 1928 ! 712.0 6 346.0 2.799.0 13.688.0 17,450.0 44,015.0 1929 3,718.0 3."08 0 2.423.0 13.528.0 16,877.0 40,454.0 1930 .1977.0 3.568.0 2.758.0 10.901.0 19.662.0 40,866.0 1931 40M.0 4.M4.0 3.142.0 11.547.0 14,134.0 37,701.0 190 2 101.0 1 SBl.O 2.153.0 12,800.0 9.171.0 28,106.0 I9H 2&lt;iU.O 2 1760 1.984.0 12.474.0 10,871.0 30,118.0 1934 BIW.II 1.074 0 1.229.0 14.979.0 14,328.0 32.419.0 1935 1 'H7.U uO.O 1.238.0 6.212.0 5,932.0 15.379.0 Aicutt 2.'J16.7 :.'.HB.: 2.254.6 12.058.6 14,761.9 34.910.0 Received Lum"- ! zr i ",Hr i L"J| 1 Ut"lock I JSLI &lt;•£* in;,, I ;« n j, «tf, il 4 484.0 fi,510.0 4,008.0 14.668.0 35,020.0 111}: I*/, ii I.TIAO 4 407.0 6.977.0 3.(26.0 13,536.0 33,282.0 jcjjj 17 (SO 15(i'J(l 4 112 0 d.679.0 5.272.0 16,498.0 35,865.0 19:9 1 "sil.O 1.521.&gt;) 3.723.0 7.685.0 3.819.0 17,502.0 36,330.0 1910 !6!6 0 2 651 I) 3.051.0 6,615.0 3.345.0 17,149.0 34,447.0 1931 ] 0(4 0 3 034.'i 2 409.0 5.064.0 3.248.0 14.754.0 29.543.0 191' 51,5.0 504.0 1,640.0 4,696.0 5,049.0 10,543.0 22,997.0 19(1 1,-2.(1 1 IK9 0 15700 3.958.0 5,571.0 10,166.0 23,126.0 I9U (M.D I 0V9.il USD 4.220.0 3.772.0 11.395.0 22,439.0 1*35 S7O 0 1382.(1 1 21').0 5.186.0 3,\48.0 13,007.0 24.8U.0 Amj.-e 1,21/) 0 1.961.5 2.785.0 5.759.0 4,086.8 13,921.8 29,786.1 Co(n(illc&lt;l («im stjtion rcLoi.:», Ncbrjsku State Railway CommiHion, Rale Dcparlincnt. go and Northwestern, leading east from Hastings, has a few miles of track in Adams county, also out of the watershed area. Many miles of improved roads make travel through the area easy. Highway 30, paralleling the Union Pacific tracks, is paved. Number 6 is paved for several miles between Hastings and Holdege. It is either surfaced with bituminous mat or graveled the remaining distance across the area. Paving or surfacing is being extended over the graveled sections. All of the counties have taken advantage of an abundant supply of gravel in the Platte river and have used it to improve roads leading out from villages that serve as market centers. It is possible to drive within a short distance of most farmsteads on all-weather roads. The number of people residing in an area and the industries in which they earn a living have a material influence upon the volume of business transacted. The needs and desires of the population must be met. People must have the necessities of life and the tools with which they work. Many </seg>
         <seg id="p055">...¦¦¦" ' - ¦ » ¦- Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley Reservoir Table 49.— Carload freight shipments, all stations, Scotts Bluff county, jorwarded 1926-35, received 1916-35 1 (all railroads). ¦. Forwarded *«¦¦¦ ~- J*'Li .•¦¦ oto ¦• T""1 Wheat Corn „,.„ Livestock rarlojdl all , • : . : product. ' . ¦ ¦ ca''°jdl 1926 • 389.0 3XI 60.0 2,667.0 8,171.0 U. 290.0 1927 395.0 1.0 214.0 2,238.0 8,526.0 11,377.0 1928 244.0 2.0 158.0 2345.0 9,393.0 12,142.0 1929 345.0 13.0 123.0 2,596.0 9,21^.0 12,203.0 1930 340.0 18.0 205.0 2,041.0 8,800.0 11,404.0 1931 103 0 25.0 242.0 1,786.0 9,238.0 11,394.0 1932 56.0 21.0 12.0 2,089.0 7,685.0 9,863.0 1933 65.0 30.0 35.0 2,029.0 7.243.0 9,402.0 1934 56.0 5.0 35.0 2,599.0 6,360.0 9,058.0 1935 34.0 6.0 25.0: 2,271.0 6,964.0 9300.0 Ilm£ .203.0 12.4 '': Ul.l 2,266.1 8.159.6; 10,7523 Received . . ¦ . Can Can •¦¦¦'¦. Total Cari j imc grain &amp; Cirs Can Other al j lumber cement Krain coal liveitock carloads cwloadi vrml products - '- 1916 836.0 301.0 811.0 1,722.0 1,460.0 6341.0 U. 471.0 1917 790.0 238.0 7«.0 2,661.0 1,360.0 10,637.0 16,429.0 1918 349.0 262.0 587.0 2,326.0 881.0 8,163.0 12,568.0 1919 567.0 201.0 804.0 2,751.0 1,400.0 7,512.0 13,235.0 1920 713.0 338.0 ' 561.0 3,308.0 1,031.0 10305.0 16,256.0 1921 273.0 154.0 428.0 2,888.0 838.0 11,670.0 16,251.0 1922 246.0 169.0 409.0 3,169.0 1,042.0 11,059.0 16,094.0 1923 327.0 202.0 473.0 2,913.0 836.0 11,298.0 16,049.0 1924 264 0 . . 285.0 450.0 3,088.0 1,070.0 12,070.0 17,227.0 1925 332.0 225.0 625.0 3,258.0 1,269.0 11,175.0 16,884.0 1926 558.0 344.0 601.0 4334.0 981.0 XT.804.0 23.622.0 1927 452.0 417.0 566.0 3,970.0 1,542.0 18,590.0 25,537.0 1928 489.0 236.0 641.0 . 3,893.0 1,492.0 16,761.0 . 23,512.0 1929 400.0 296.0 539.0 4,728.0 1,711.0 17,003.0 24,677.0 1930 274.0 166.0 414.0 3,535.0 1,256.0 15,994.0 21,639.0 1931 21610 305.0 . 491.0 3397.0 1341.0 13.051.0 18,801.0 1932 175.0 99.0 554.0 2,682.0 1,096.0 12,042.0 16,648.0 1933 188.0 83.0 397.0 2332.0 979.0 14,428.0 18,400.0 IW4 : 22J.0 74.0 504.0 l,»81O : 1,020.0 9.810.0 13^19.0 1935 247.0 145.0 619.0 1.912.0 1.533.0 9391-0 13J47J) 10 vor • avtrV 322.8 216.5 532.6 3,266.5 1,295.1 14386.7 20,020.2 . ¦ ' Compiled from station records, Nebraska Stale Railway Commission, Rale Department. </seg>
         <seg id="p056">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 311 farm products that may be grown in central Nebraska have considerable bulk in relation to value. High freight rates prohibit their shipment to population centers. They must be processed near the fields where they are grown. In all probability additional beet sugar factories, centralized cream - eries, packing plants, and canning factories will be established within the irrigation area and existing plants will be enlarged. These industrial activities will lead to a material increase in the volume of business transacted. '•' &gt;¦ —I-ufatiiin "I railmails within the eight counties (Adams, Buffalo, Dawson, (i"s[&gt;cr, Ihll, Kearney, Lincoln, and Phcjps). Movement of carload freight in individual counties of the irrigation area is shown in Tables 44 to 47. A summary for the district as a whole is given in Table 48. Similar data for Scotts Bluff county are presented in Table 49. Annual outgoing freight from all stations in the eight counties averaged 3-).9)0.0 carloads for the ten year period ending 1935. Freight forwarded from all siations in Scotts Bluff county, which has but 10.2 per cent of the area of the eight counties, was 10,752.3 carloads or 30.8 per cent as much. Freight received at all stations in the eight counties averaged 29.786.1 carloads. Incoming freight at all stations in Scotts Bluff county was 20,020.2 carloads or 67.2 per cent as much as in the eight counties. It seems evident that irrigation in Scotts Bluff county, where approximately 203,600 acres are watered, has been a vital factor in stimulating business activity. Table 49 also shows the carload receipts for all towns in Scotts Bluff county for the 1916-1935 twenty year period. Incoming freight in the first ten years of the period averaged 15,264 carloads annually, and in the last ten years 20,020 carloads—an increase of 31.16 per cent. By 1925 the industries of Scotts Bluff county were probably more completely adjusted to local production than present industries in the central Nebraska area are to the agricultural output which will result from irrigation. In the first decade after irrigation water is made available annual carload receipts within the area should increase at least 33 per cent. Incoming freight the past ten years has averaged 29,786 carloads. An advance of one-third will add 9,929 carloads to the freight received. </seg>
         <seg id="p057">Benefits of Irrigation from the Kingsley Reservoir BIBLIOGRAPHY &#132;;.•¦ . ¦¦ B6o\s .; . Etchcveny, B. A. Irrigation Practice and Engineering. Vol. I, Use of Irrigation Water. McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., New York City, New York. Nebraska Blue Book, 1934. Nebraska Legislative Reference Bureau, Lincoln, Nebraska. 1' . '. ¦ '.;. .''.:• Reports ..'•¦¦ : ¦ ' ' Brackett, E. E. and Lewis, E. B. Pump Irrigation Investigations in- Nebraska. Bulletin 282, Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Lincoln/Nebraska.. Fellows, A. Lincoln. A Report of Some Agricultural Engineering Phases of the Proposed Tri-county. Irrigation Project of Central Nebraska. Bureau of Public Roads, United States Department of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. Hallsted, A. L. and Mathews, O. R. Soil Moisture and Winter Wheat. Bulletin 273, Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station,.Manhattan, Kansas. Hastings, Stephen H. Effect of Alfalfa and Farm Manure on Yields of Irrigated Crops in tiie Great Plains. Technical Bulletin No. 483, United States Depart - ¦ meht of Agriculture, Washington, D.. C " - • — : Irricated Crop Rotations in Western Nebraska, 1912-3.4. Technical Bullerin No. 512, United States Department of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. Holden, James A. Crop Rotatlon Under Irrigation. Bulletin 190, Nebraska Agri - cultural Experiment Station, Lincoln, Nebraska. Keisselbach, T. A., Anderson, Arthur, and Russel, J. C. Subsoil Moisture and Se - quence in Relation to Alfalfa Production. Journal of the American Society of Agronomy. Vol. 26, No. 5, May, 1934. Kuska, Val. Information in Support of Central Nebraska Public Power and Irrigation District. Val Kuska, Colonization Agent, Burlington Route, Omaha, Nebraska. .- " ..... \ '¦. .. ; ' Russcl, J. C. The Use of Supplemental Water. Agricultural Engineering, Vol. XI, : No. 3.. .¦ . ¦ : : -.-. ' :- ¦: . ' r \ Scoficld, Carl S. Irrigated Crop Rotations in Western Nebraska. Technical Bulle - tin No. 2, United States Department of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. Weakly, Harry E. Pump Irrigation at the North Platte Experimental Substatlqn. Bulletin 301, Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Lincoln Nebraska. Geological Survey Water Supply Paper- 772. Studies of Relations op Rainfall and Run-off in the United States; United States Department of the Interior, Washington, D. C. ¦'.'. '¦ ;',¦' - . . Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1926 to 1930. Nebraska Department of Agriculture, ¦ Lincoln, Nebraska. . '¦"'¦.—¦ Nebraska State Planning. Board. Water Resources of Nebraska, December, 1936. Special Survey Report of the Department of Public Works. Bureau of Irrigation, Water Power, and Drainage of the State of Nebraska. . ¦, ¦ . 15M] </seg>
         <seg id="p058"/>
         <seg id="p059"/>
         <seg id="p060"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>