<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00038">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00038</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  FILLING THE SILO</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Distributed September 15, 1913 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, Nebraska, U. S. A. FILLING THE SILO By J. H. Frandsen Department of Dairy Husbandry DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION C. W. Pugsley, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">By J. H. Frandsen Pfrotn the number of inquiries reaching this depart - re are some perplexing problems confronting the man // silo. With a view of rendering as much assistance as ) the dairymen of Nebraska who are facing the problem For the first time, this brief circular on "Filling the Silo" prepared. I [me to Cut the Corn. — Under normal conditions the best to cut the corn for silage is when the kernels are well dented, about one-fourth of the husks, and the lower leaves are drying More mature corn has a greater nutritive value and will make :r silage than too green corn, providing it contains enough iture to insure good fermentation. Corn cut too green makes : colored, sour silage which is apt to cause animals to scour, ase of extreme drouth, such as many localities in Nebraska : suffered from this year, it may be found necessary to cut corn much earlier than usual. The best guide as to time of ng under unfavorable conditions is when the corn ceases to IF.NGTH Corn Should be Cut. — Corn in good condition to be into the silo will give good results if cut as short as three - •ths of an inch in length. Corn that is quite dry should be into pieces not over one-half inch in length. The finer the cut better it will pack down in the silo, and furthermore, there will ess wasted in feeding as the stock will eat the fine cut silage e readily. As it is quite difficult to pack corn that is rather it should in such cases be cut finer. All corn in the silo lid be carefully and thoroughly tramped down so as to exclude ■Rich air as possible. Iime Taken to Fill Silo. — There is a wide difference of ion on this point as there are advantages to both the rapid slow systems of filling. The system to be used is determined, great extent, by the amount of silage to be put up by one set nachinery. Where a thirty foot silo is filled rapidly, the silage settle considerably, frequently as much as five or six feet. 5 makes it necessary to refill in a week or ten days. The rapid ig is the cheapest method and also gives a more uniform lity of silage. Where slow filling is practiced it is almost for the fanner to have a cutter of his own, otherwise </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 some of the corn at the beginning of the silo filling season would have to be cut too green, and some at the end of the season would be cut too dry. Slow filling makes it possible to utilize the full capacity of the silo as by the time the silo is filled it is also quite well settled. Nearly all argue, however, that slow filling is more expensive than rapid filling. A method often used, is, for a community of from three to six farmers to own a large cutter jointly and fill their silos rapidly. They then make a second round and refill the silos if necessary. Distributing and Packing the Corn in the Silo. — The packing of the corn is a very important part of the work. Thor - ough packing gives better silage and insures a more economical use of the silo because more of it can be put into the silo if well packed. The chief points to be observed are: (i) that the light and heavy portions of the corn should be evenly distributed, (2) that the corn should be uniformly packed and tramped in all parts of the silo. The distributing can be most easily and cheaply done by attaching a distributor to the end of the blower elevator. Thor - ough packing can best be accomplished by keeping the surface of the silage alxmt two feet higher on the sides than in the center. With this method, the center where the corn drops and the men stand a great deal of the time, becomes very solid. When filled in this manner the silage is wedged solidly against the sides in such a way as to prevent air spaces near the wall. The chief reason why silage spoils around the edges is because it is not packed well enough and the air is allowed to enter. The characteristic silage fermentation takes place only in the absence of air. Addinc Water to Silage. — The silage should feel wet after it is in the silo, and if it is not in this condition, water should be added. Corn cut at the proper time need not be artificially moist - ened to make good silage. If, however, the corn is too dry at the time of cutting, water should be added. The silage should be cut in pieces not over a half inch in length and an extra effort made to have it well packed. There are two convenient ways of adding water to the silage. These are: First, by allowing a continu - ous stream to flow into the blower pipe at the time of filling; sec - imkI, by thoroughly wetting down successive layers of the cut corn. Don't attempt to fill the silo with dry corn and then wet the contents by pouring water on the top, as this will require a great deal of water and moreover the water will not penetrate Preventing Waste on Top of Silo. — There will always be some waste on top of the silo, unless the feeding operations are </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 I in immediately after filling. The depth to which silage spoils ts from two to twenty-four inches, depending upon the pre - ions taken to prevent it. Various methods of lessening waste : been advocated. Some tramp or pack the surface of the ;e daily for a week or more. Another method that is some - s used is to thoroughly soak the top layer and seed in with . The oats germinate and form a solid covering which keeps the air. A covering of oat chaff or cut straw may be put on of the silage to protect it, or the ears may be removed from last few loads of corn before cutting and the surface soaked i water. All these methods are quite satisfactory in that they • out the air and thus lessen the waste. froiLED Silage. — The spoiling of silage is due either to a white i or a black rot. The white mold indicates that the silage too dry when placed in the silo while the black rot indicates it was not packed properly, or that air penetrated through sides of the mass of silage. Iength of Time to Stand Before Feeding. — It takes several h:s for the corn to pass through the heating process which iges it into silage. Many people prefer waiting at least ten i before starting to feed. But with this practice there is ivs waste. The corn can be fed immediately after the silo is i, but it will merely be cut corn. It will take several days' ing before the real silage is reached. However, by beginning eed immediately after filling, there is no waste on top of the {9ST of Filling Per Ton. — The cost of filling the silo, includ - the cutting of the corn in the field, hauling it, putting it ugh the silage cutter, trampling, leveling, and covering the varies from about 55 cents to $1.10 per ton, depending upon distance the corn must be hauled, (2) the yield per acre, (3) condition of the weather, (cost being greater in wet weather), the size of the cutter and the amount of motor power, and the efficiency of the help. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>