<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00013.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00013.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ELEVENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE DEPARTMENT OF BANKING SHOWING THE CONDITION OF THE Building and Loan Associations OF NEBRASKA For the Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 1903 Submitted to the State Banking Board Oct. 1, 1903</title>
               <date value="1903">1903</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">ELEVENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE DEPARTMENT OF BANKING SHOWINO THE V OF THE Building and Loan Associations OF NEBRASKA For the Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 1903 Submitted to the State Banking Board Oct. 1, 1903 BY E. ROYSE, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE OF NEBRASKA. Board. HON. CHARLES WESTON. .. .Auditor of Public Accounts and Pre^ HON. PETER MORTENSEN State Trea HON. F. N. PROUT Attorney General E. ROYSE Secretary DODSOX Chi. FRANK S.MIT H Stenographer EXAMINERS. Fred Whittemore, E. E. Emmett, L. V. Haskell, W. D. Hartwell. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">State of Nebraska, Dkpartmknt of Banking, Lincoln, October 1, 1903. To //is- Excellency, John II. Mickey, Governor of Nebraska. And the Honorables Charles Weston, Peter Mortens**, and F. N. Prout, tlm State Banking Board of the State of Qentlbuem — In compliance with section 3a of chapt of the Compiled Statutes of the State of Nebraska for 1908, requiring the Secretary of the State Banking Board to make to the Governor and State Banking Board annual rep. I have the honor to submit herewith the eleventh animal re- port of the department of banking for the period beginning •Jul.v 1, 1902, and ending June 30, 1903, showing the condition «&gt;f the building and loan associations of the state of Nebraska at the close of business June 30, 1903, compiled from annual reports of the several building and loan associations sub initted to the State Banking Board, in accordance with the I isions of the building and loan act, approved April 4, '. Tabulated statements, detailed reports, and such in - formation and comments touching this report as is deemed beneficial will be found on the following pages. Very respectfully E. Royse, Secretary State Banking Board. Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. &gt;F TOTAL NUMBER OF ASSOCIATIO: ASSETS, FROM 1892. THE FII »8, NUMBER OF SHARES IN FORCE AND TOTAl 1ST YEAR THAT AUTHENTIC REPORTS WERE MADE, DOWN TO THE PRESENT TIME. , YEAR NO. OF NO. OF SHARES IN ASB'NS FORCE TOTAL ASSETS NO. OF ASS'NS 892 893 .894 .895 .896 .8*7 .888 .see 900 L901 1902 .903 71 84 H si 73 H Ci fiO 00 58 58 45,012'^ 61,964.1 71,231^ 70,615 64,891% 67,597^ 79,973 89,492 105,625 119,985 130,083 153,424 - 3,564 3. 428 3,332,781 6 3,697.35(1 0 4.314.744 8 5,34.'i </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SUMMARIES "OMPILED FROM THE ANNUAL REPORTS OF BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS FOK THE YEARS FROM \W2, THE FIRST YEAR Unm VBI UOBVBj TO 1903 INCLUSIVE, SHOWING IBM TOTALS OF ALL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS IN THK STATE FOR THE YEARS ABOVE STATED. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF TUB CONDITION OF THB BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THB STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 31st day of December, 1892. Assets. Fir«t mortgage loans $2.23.-1.104 Loans Hwured by stock of ass.xiation 175,100 Keal estate 50,141 Expenses and taxes paid Cash with treasurer Ail other assets Total ?J,'J0J,oD7 67 T Liabilities. Capital stock paid np $1,924,784 12 Premiums paid 393,103 18 393,103 18 Interest received 434. S KlneR collected 33J97 40 116,513 oi&gt; $2,902,557 07 Other liabilities Total Total </seg>
            <seg id="p007">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 7 SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1892. Receipts. Balance on hand December 31, 1891 Dues Interest fines lioans repaid l&gt;ther receipts Total Expenditures. Linns Salaries - - . - Other expenditure 84,478 96 Cash on band . . 70,389 -3 ToUl *l,0L'4.COO 81 Recapitulation Nnmber of shares In force at '.:&lt; ... 41.186 Number of shai Number oi . ic and cai Namber of shares In force at thU date . 44,012 \% </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION'S. SUMMARY OF THE STATEMENT OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of December, 1893. Assets. First mortgage loans $2,RO4..T1« Loans secured by stock of ; ; Keal estate . uses and taxes paid Other assets not enuiuerai. Total Liabilities. Capital stock paid up $2.r&gt;2." Premiums paid 443 $2.r.2r, - 79 74 Interest received ....... b ines collected Other liabilities ' . 140,7 Total |3 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">BIII.DIXC; AND LOAN IONS. 9 SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECKM EXPENDITURES FOR THE YKAH ENDING DECEMBER 30, 1893. Receipts. Balance on hand December 31. 1802 ■t Fines Loans repaid Other receipts Total Expenditure*. r.oann .? 741.' Salaries Mill other expenses Withdrawals "ii hand laneous expenditures Total v RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR 1893. Nuuil I, withdrawn, and cai Number of tone at this date Recapitulation. Number of associations In for. Number of associations di- during year Number of new as.xo.iat ions ci Number of associations in force December 84 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF TUB BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF TIIE STATE OF NEBRASKA, On the 31st day of December, 1891. Assets. First mortgage loans $2 Leans secured by stock of association Real estate uses and taxes paid i ash with treasurer Other assets Total $3,888,001 31 Liabilities. Capital stock paid up .... $2.6f»4." Premiums paid Interest received . . Interest received - collected All other liabilities Total $3,888,001 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 11 SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31. 1894. Receipts. Balance on hand r&gt;o&lt;pmlwr 31, 1893 $ «O 1 ' Dues Dues Interest - . . .' Loans repaid Other receipts L--.3ST 81 Total 1 1 Expenditures. Loans $ Salaries Other expenses Withdrawals Other expenditures Cash on band . . Total *l,444,910 9'.' RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1894. Number of shares In force at last report Number of bI &lt;1 during year Number of shares matured, withdrawn, and canceled Number of sharw in force at this date Recapitulation. Number of associations In force December 31, Number of associations discontinued during year Number of new associations daring year Number of associations in fore* December 31, 1 - 8&gt;; </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF TUE CONDITION OF TUB BUILDINC, AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 31st day of December, 1895. Assets. Klrst mortgage loans $'2.81 S Louis secured by stock association Real estate Expenses and taxes paid with treasurer All other assets Total $:!.:•-' Liabilities. Capital stock paid np »2.744. 1 .rns paid &lt;t received . . Fines collected All other liabilities Total 778 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 13 SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITU I THE YEAR ENDING :R 31, 1895. Receipts. Ilalam-e on hand December 31, 1S1I4 Total Expenditures. Salaries (Jther Withdrawal Other expenditure Cash on hand Tot*l RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE &gt; ENDING DECEMBER 31, Number of shares In force at last report Number of shares Issued during year Number of shares matured, withdrawn, and ca- Number of share* In force at this date Recapitulation. Nnmher of awtoctatlonii in M Number of associations din if year . . Number of associations In force December 31, I 9 Interest I»ans repaid Other i Number of new a si" ye«r </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 14 building; and loan associations. SUMMARY OF T1IK CONDITION OF TUB BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF TUR OF TUB STATE OP NEBRASKA. STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 31st day of December, 1896. On the 31st day of December, 1896. Assets. Assets. mortgage loans $2,832 r age loans • ■ • ■ f- mortgage loans in prw«« nf f &amp;ge loans in Real estate ■ 1T7.4 Furniture and futures ■ • 177.1 Furniture and futures ind fixtures ■ • ■ Cash ■im shareholders . . ihareholders : sea and taxes paid. . 169. -I' id taxes pai&lt;l assets 572 4(1 s Total t»l . . $3 $3, 771,833 53 Liabilities. $2,582,078 82 Dues paid $2,582,078 82 iTemlums unearned 100, S37 65 Proflts undivided Including reserve fund 382.320 47 Profits apportioned to shares In force . . • . 429,408 76 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans ... 10.572 08 Other liabilities ■ • • 266.915 85 Total $3,771,833 53 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER .51, Receipts. Balance on hand December 31. 180 3 . . $ 88.4 st Loans repaid receipts .i Total Expenditures, Loans Salaries Matui ''amines' ........... Cash on hand al Total RECAPITULATION OF SHARK TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR E NDING DEC EMBER 31 • r of shares in force at hi shares m: -r of suar . . • ar cr of shares withdrawn ai r loans made for building purposes i ent year Number of shareholders 18,143 Supplemental Report ■ of sb: inee organization 141.116 of ser f 1 series of i.t of Bh», .drawn an. .-ages in proee- Amount of i: '.ess of forecU^ $ 1 Total appraised value of real estate ai 9 as security . . 111.7 latlons as ■ ■ lateral security - J. 444. 115 00 Value of other real estate held by the associations 182,861 4u Shares Statement. Total number of series Issued .... .ISr? number of shares issued . . . xoiai numDer oi snares issuea ... Total number of shares withdrawn Total number of shares loaned on Total number of shares outstanding .... '■'-$% Recapitulation, Number of associations In force December 31, 1 - iations d! 10 •er of new associations during year Number of associations in force December 31, i - 73 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OK THE CONDITION OK TUB Bl'ILlHNi; AM) LOAN ASSOCIATIONS &gt; OK TIIR STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 31st dky of December, 1897. Assets. Kirst mortgage loans mortgage loans in process of f&lt; Real estate Kurnlture and fixtures J._' Cash 81.177 7J Bzpensea and taxes paid mm shareholders other assets Total 788 08 Liabilities. Dm* p«ia [•remlums unearned Profits undivided including reserve fund - apportioned to gharea iii l&gt;ue tnareholders on Incomplete lnaus. &gt;ther liabilities Total 13,554,788 OS 13,554,788 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 BUILDING AND LOAN IONS. Receipts I'.alance on hand December 31, - .&lt; ."..717 10 Due* Interest $ •■•■•••• I.nans repaid uiber receipts . . Other receipts . Total Expenditures. Expenditures I...ans ises Ixwna Salaries \\ it lull Mat ut' .irnings Matured k; ''tfs ...... i ash on hand Total i ash on band Total RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1897. RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR :&gt;ort :&gt;ort &gt;.t of shares matured during current year -lead mort. -. al :rrent year -lead mort. -. al year •••r nf shan's Issued &lt;Uirin_ year &gt;&lt;t of shares issued during 18. 1 f loans- made for building purposes durii. 18,121 f loans- made for building purposes durii. Number ol I era Number of shareholders Supplemental Report. Supplemental Report. No. nf zatlon Der or »nare« witnarawn ann &lt;*a r ■ • * _:ieps in proces- izatlon • hu « wii an* vsssr7. .:::::..: Amor. - - in process of Total appraised value nf real estate :\ '? 4.346.9.&gt;B lateral security Value of other real estate heid by the associations 1 83. Ill '-■» Shares Statement. Total number of - Km iiuuiiw^i ■ ,, al number of share* i&lt; iwn IIUIMlH'l i' Kl [MM • 1 number of aha: aling .... Recapitulation. Number of associations In fore '3 ■•r of associations diseont &lt;r of new assi J Number of associations in for. 6*&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p018">1 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 18 '• SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF TIIE » BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 31st day of December, 1898. Assets. $2,821,703 11 First mortgage loans . . . $2,821,703 1 1 Klrst mortgage loans In process . . 56.': Klrst mortgage loans In process of fowl Real estate Furniture and fixtures Cash Expenses and taxes paid Due from shareholders 47,4 Other assets 114.047 04 Total 13,428,728 1 Liabilities. Capital stock paid up ft 008,863 53 1'roflts undlTided. Including reserve fund J47 31 «r,3 U Premiums unearned (7 .517 51 hareholders on Incomplete loans Advance payments KM 44 Matured stock unpaid 110,120 6«; Bills payable 5.550 00 Other liabilities 8,858 48 Total $3,428,728 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 BUILDING AND LOAN IONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31. 1898. Receipts. Balance on hand no.pinb.-r 31. 1807 S 77,09* 53 Due* 903,282 04 Interest 253.684 9S Fines 6,^87 48 Loans repaid 417,787 5!&gt; Other - U24 15 Total $1.84^866 74 Expenditures. Loans S 757,104 07 Salaries (61 43 Other expenses ij"4 98 Withdrawals, dues ! Miin&gt;rs " -37 08 Matured stock, dues - 1 39 1 31 Matured stock, earnings ash on hand Total ll.M4.Mf 74 RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31. 1898. . Number of shares In force at last report &gt; 66,232 Number of shares matured during current year 2,329 Number of shares Issued during current year Number of shares Issued during current year ;3S \? Number of shares withdrawn and canceled during current year Id Number of shares In force at this date 79,973 Number of loans for payment of homestead mortgages during &lt; uri year eo.i No. of loans made for building purposes during ar / |M Number of shareholders Supplemental Report. Number of mortgages In process of foreclosure 76 Amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure $ &lt;M ■ Total appraised value of real estate and Improvements held as security 5 Amount of Insurance in force and assigned to the Association as lateral semrity Value of other real estate held by the associations Recapitulation. Number of associations In force December 31, 1807 . ■ 6S Number of associations discontinued during yen ... 4 Number of associations in force December 31. « 04 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF TDK CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF TUB STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, A. D. 1899. Assets. t lrst mortgage loans $2,858,910 72 H mortgage loans In process of foreclosure .57. J estate It!.".." Heal estatf Furniture and fixtures Cash 146.099 Expenses and taxes paid Da« from shareholders 4:2,838 8U Other assets 38,477 17 Total 13,332,781 67 Liabilities. Capital stock paid up $2,868,310 44 HrofltB undivided. Including reserve fund J70. 1 rremlums unearned 45..'. ■lareholders on incomplete loans Advance payments 24,831 18 Matured stock unpaid Bills payable 9,703 32 Other liabilities 4,617 59 Total $3,332,781 67 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE SIX MONTHS ENDING JUNE 30, 1899. Receipt*. Balance on hand December 31, 1898 .,...* 7 . sl6 5« Interest Fines Loans repaid 288.4 Other receipts Total * ■ Expenditures. Loans Salaries other ■ ■ i raw...: earning Matured stock, earnings Cash on band Total *1.2iM,-8» If • Recapitulation. Number of associations In force at this to SO Number of shares in force at this date . . 80. 4»- Number of shareholders ... 13.813 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 BtflLDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE) STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, A. D. 1900. » Assets. First mortgage loans '3, 1 First mortgage loans 1b process of foreclosure Stock loans Heal estate Furniture and fixtures C«.h Itellnquent Interest, premiums, and nn« Kxpenses and taxes paid Insurance paid Other assets HC,5ia 33 Total $3,Cl»7,ao6 0 Liabilities. Capital stock running $2,717,380 04 Full paid stock C64.048 92 Beserre fund '. t ■ :;40 6U Undivided profits ; s41 5", Due shareholders on incomplete loans 41^080 61 Premiums unearned 35,630 O.'i Advance dues 15,970 32 Advance interest and premiums A~. 5,548 36 Bills payable 1 1^050 00 Other liabilities VL 30,465 50 1,050 00 Other liabilities Total v $3, 3,697,356 Ot) </seg>
            <seg id="p023">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 23 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDINQ JUNE 30, 1900. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1890 $ Dues (running stock &gt; 1 Dues (full paid stock) . . Interest Premiums Klnes Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid Keal estate sales Rents Other receipts Total $2,355,535 8» Expenditures. Lo»M *1,128 .-- Salaries Comn Other expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdraws Matin Matin Full p Bills payable ............... Total . . J2.355.535 89 SHARES STATEMENT. ■f shares In force at this date ln'.r.j". f shares Issued since organization ... No. of shares Issued during fiscal year HJH No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year 1CCU No. of shares of running stock In force at this date Mo. of shares of full paid stock In force at this date No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent. . . ... No. of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Ti&gt;0 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 BUILDING AND LOAN i IONS. SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THIS OK TI1K STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. A. D. 1901. Assets. r lrst mortRSRe loans Stock I BWtltc 110/_ Iture and fixtur. ■ . Total ?4.:si» : Liabilities. &lt; k running .... arable Oilier llabilitiefl Total $4.314,744 8. IM'ILDINil AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS </seg>
            <seg id="p025">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 25 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1901. Receipt*. J'.al.im p on hand July 1, ]!&gt;(¥) 'full paid stock) Interi fc^lillIlM [p ami trail Loans repaid ,;„, .,..,; ,is ild - Other receipts ' Total |_ Expenditures. Loam Salarli-s Hater . ml Full El atock. earnings sh en hand payable Total SHARES STATEMENT. Inqnent . . iiici'llatluD for noupa </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June. A. D. 1902. I Assets. First mortgage loans $ » hirst mortgage loans in p -" loans HI - Real estate ■■ HI Furniture and fixtures. . Cash ..: 177.C Cash ..: 1"' Delinquent Interest, premiums, and flues Expenses and taxes paid Other assets Total M.758,2 Liabilities. Capital stock running $3 - Full paid stock Reserve fund ided profits liareholders on Incomplete loan Premiums unearned Advance dues . Advance Interest and premium.* Other liabilities 47. 7 Other liabilities Total $4,758,293 77 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE ENDING JUNE 30, U FISC AL YEAR Receipts. Balance on hand July 1. 1901 j Dues ( running stock " * * * Does (full paid stock).. Interest Premiums ... 8,9«8 80 Membership and transfer i .... Loans repaid Real estate sales Bents Other receipts Total f 3,660. 7 Expenditures. Loan Salaries Other expenses Withdrawals, dues ] Withdrawals, earnings Matu red stock, dues l.s-.".l 44 jaaiurm BIUC&amp;, uuea Matured stock, earnings .'loin ni Bi'tva, » ill um$9 Full paid stock, dues ■ I'.ii'i aim», uues. paid stork, earnings 'ii hand Other liabilities Total SHARES STATEME NT shares In force at this date. : shares iRsued • K shares issued tl shares maturpci seal year ithdrawn shares of running slock in force at thU date No. of shares of full paid stock In force at this date No. of shares loaned on shares on which du inquent area subject to cancellation fur nonpayment of dues l.uy.i </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF Till". CONDITION &lt;&gt;!•' TUB BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF TUB STATE OF NEBRASKA On the 30th day of June, 1903. Assets. First mortgage loan* ? t.Ono • First mortgage loans in process and staii' ■ !«&gt;. ! Total I.". Liabilities. &lt; k running. (Dues and &lt;i ! ■ iare holders on Incomplete loans... Advan.e due. ... 14.0: Adrai ' and premiums 3«». ' Total $5,343,429 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 Bl ll.lil.NU AND LO IONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, ]!VI3 I MI1IIITIIL- ■ full paid stock) ■.■nihlp and transfer 1.«hiis repaid Keal estate sales receipts Total Expenditures. Loan* ■is expenses Wlihdrawals. dues Withdrawals, en Full i expenditures Total SUPPLEMENTAI STATEMENT. No. of shares In force at this date ... :' shares i ■ shares Issued during ar shares matured shares withilinu n ! - - : ;ir 1"7 .'.."■ s shares wlthdni hares of i .......... shares of fall paid stock in force a&gt; shares on 1 No. of share - No. of mortgage;- ami i mount of nme. N No of shares In process of foreclosure, and the :i. name. No. 48 borrowing stockholders ■wins stockhoiil- Average running time of stock matured &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. Fifty-five associations submitted to this department de - tailed reports of their condition on June 30, 1903. During the period covered by this report four associations have discontinued and paid all liabilities in full and five new associations have been organized and authorized to do lmsiness. Three associations had not commenced busi June 30, 1903. The following named associations ceased to do bush and paid all liabilities in full between June 30, 1902, and July 1, 1903: 1. Edgar Building and Loan Association of Edgar 2. Franklin Building and Loan Association of Franklin 3. Scotia Building and Loan Association of Scotia. 4. Prague Building and Loan Association of Prague. The following named new associations have been organ ized during the period covered by this report 1. Crete — Loan and Barf] niation of Crete, July 6, 1902. 2. Laurel — Building and Loan Association of Laurel, Julv 8, 1902. 3. Alliance — Building and Loan Association of Allianct September 22, 1902. Vurora— Building and Loan Association, Aurora, Decem ber 17, 1902. 5. Lincoln — American Home Savings and Loan Association, Lincoln, January 29, 1903. RECAPITULATION. Number of associations in force June 30, 1902 Number of associations liquidates! during the year 4 Number of associations organised during the year ;&gt; Number of associations in force June 30, 1903 59 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">STATEMENTS. 8H0WINQ TIIK CONDITION OF THE FIFTY-FIVE ItUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS IN THE STATE Of NEI'.KASKA AT THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS ON THE 30TH DAY OF JUNE, 1903. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF Till-: CONDITION OF THE ALIilON JtriLDINU AND LOAN A8SN. ALBION, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. P. A. KRAUSE ; President WM. WEITZEL Vice-President D. V. BLATTER Secretary F. S. THOMPSON Treasurer F. A. DOTEN Attorney Directors. H. P. BUI II. MII.I.u\VNi:V. r. A PITTKNOKK K. J. KINUHAM, '.ILL, ' F. 1: 1*1 « Assets. rst mortgage loans $49, First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock leans 4, Keal estate Furniture and stationery. ctik Itelinquent Interest, premiums and fines Expenses and taxes paid &lt; it her assets, tax sale certllkaie Total 154, Assets. First mortgage loans $49. 1 First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure Stock loans 4,s Heal estate Furniture and stationery. Cash Delinquent interest, premiums and tii 1.1 Expenses and taxes pa id . Other assets, tax sale certificate 121 M Total »54,l Liabilities. &gt; Capital stock running (dues and dividends*) $.~.n Full paid stock 1.1 &lt; Reserve fund 1,61 I'ndivided profits Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned SOii M Advance dues Advance Interest and premiums I me treasurer Due treasurer Tot»I ♦54.' </seg>
            <seg id="p033">BUILDING AMI LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. Receipts. Halan * 4 1 in r ance paid 1 To «»l Expenditures 4&lt;;«; c»i &amp; l:a il Total PAL REPORT. PI; r atlnn I'ar v:i $1' shares 1&gt;- f shar ISMItHl liar matured ir har withdra lit tlii- t k In f 1. .... ] v:i loanil ti:l f i Amu MM 4 uriDK tlxral year \n of loam nt of Vv a f - ing n»&lt;ai ir running time of stock matured during fiscal year FOR THE FIS </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB ALLIANCE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. ALLIANCE, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. B. F. GILMAN President W. H. BARTZ . . .Vice-President A. F. BALDRIDGE Secretary GEO. W. CLARK Treasurer B. F. GILMAN Attorney Directors. B. P. GILMAN, W. H. BARTZ. J. F. FLEMING, OKO. W. CLARK, C. C. SMITH. J. J. ADAMS. L. B. Joll S. M. t- IS. M. HAJ11TON. Assets. Flr«t mortgage loans $10,900 00 First mortgage loans in process of Stock loans Real estate Kuinlture and stationery. l'l'lmquent interest, premiums and t'n Expenses and taxes paid ?— '"■-"• Other assets Tot»l .... $11.32148 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends! $ tX Full paid stock »• ' ', '. incomplet. Premiums!: "I IIDH UIIi'UIUCU ■ Advance dues Advance uues Advance Interest and premiums *""* ToU1 $11,321 48 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on band July 1, 1902 fe lance on hand July 1, 1902 Non« es (running stock) Dues (full paid stock) 9. Interest Premiums Fines Membership and transfer fees 125 Loans repaid Heal estate sales Solicitors' fees 140 00 Solicitors' fees Total $11,321 4S Expenditures, Loans $10,900 00 Salaries » ommissious ■ • • Other expenses Other expenses 90 75 Withdrawals, dues .None Withdrawals', earnings Matured stock, dues Withdrawals, earnings None Withdrawals, earning Matured stock, dues N"ii.&gt; Matured stock, earnings '. Matured stock, earnings \ Full paid stock, dues None Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earnings Full paid stock, earnings. ... „ H! Cash on hand Cash on hand Total ••• ~W Total $11,32148 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Permanent Plan of association (serial or permanent) re r m *j? en { Par yalue o i re of stock # '-' Par value • i re of stock • - No. of series issued since organization (if serial) Not serial 5 til » .11 11 '_ ' "A Dlu\» t - o. of series issued since organization (if serial) . Not serial &gt;o. ol ■ at this date !no! ol ■ at this date No', of organization No', of shares issued during fiscal year no. 01 snares lMuea since orKnuizauuu No. of shares issued during fiscal year &gt;o. OI snares issuea uunng nwm jemr No. of Bhares matured during fiscal year No. of Bhares n. :iscal year No. of shares wilhdi i rig liscal year r*yj, vi Dtiat c» hi»»imi*«*iij ..........-.-■■■ No. ol" nhdrawn during fiscal year No of shares of running stock in force at this dat. -■»» f full paid stock in force at this date. . :' shares loaned on So. ol running stock in force at this date. . . r full paid stock in force at this date. . No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares on which dues are delinquent £" ne incellatlon for nonpayment of due&gt; incellatlon for nonpayment of due.- delinquent at this i i ma and fines d '.lid t to foreclosure, and the aggregate .)»ing by borrowing •■ '•ild t to foreclosi' :he aggregate ' amcnnt oTiaine. No No. o! '-ss " of ' 'foreclosure, and the aggregate amount ... \o. ol ess of forecloanre, and the aggregate amoun .•• .,„, ;i III" Hill L Ul Bmur, *. v • - ... n.-*~ «.. Amount of loans on Improved real estate • • • • *10,»W W» Amount of loans on improved real estate • • • JIO.WW W» value of Improved real estate upon which loans have n made • , J-tJ 11 "V Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have u made • ■ , J-tJ 11 "V value of improvements liaised witn lana ance In force and assigned to the association as Appraised value of Improvements Appraised witn iana ance In force and assigned to the aswviatlon as ..-.1 with land »l— &gt;i*" v $12,110 0" llateral serurlty »i^,ii" "" r building purposes during the fiscal year. . I r building purposes during the fiscal year.. I t of homestead mortgages during r payment of homestead mortgages during r. ••••••■•"•■■"• No. of I No. of minors I during n &gt;■ ' ' I'lan of premium ..} ■ • $1 ' year Average ra £2 Av'-raL-e ruu:. .-•■•: ;' i ■ :-d during fiscal year '. Non« </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 BUILDING AND L&lt; • I IONS* STATEMENT OK TIIK CONDITION OK TUB ASHLAND LOAN AND lUlLDlNC, ASSN. ASHLAND, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers, C. N. FOLSOM. . President F. H. CHICKERING Vice-President W. BURT CI.ARK Secretary E. A. WIGGENHORN, JR Trea W. BURT CLARK Attorm Directors. C. N. FOLSOM, i: A. WIGGENHORN, Ja L. R. BRUSH F. H. CH1CKEBING, \V. I5UUT CLARK. JII.IUS OI. Assets. First mortgage loans $ 6.000 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stork loans Real estate ... Furniture and stationery Cash 1.17 I*linquent Interest us«a and taxes paid ... 44 Tax sale certificates 142 M Contracts (real Total $ll,82d Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and divi I $ T ,r&gt;0i Full paid si B«erVefund - 1.4' Doe shareholders on Incomplete loans Advance interest and Dremiums Advance interest and premiums. Total $11.0^8 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 37 &gt; RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Italance on hand July 1, 1!M&gt;2 * :. . i running stock i i full paid Inter. Pre in iu ins ship and trans Loans repaid 1.700 00 Iteal estate sales Uents Uents iid -3 H Total *5.' Expenditures, Loans $1.7 Salaries Commission! expenses irawals, dues Matured stock, dues Mam irning: Full i •■ '*&gt; Full 1 1 earnln Cash on hand. .' 1- 1: ■ """ "" •.«■.« Taxes 31 u._&gt; Accounts received Total »5.(X&gt;2 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Mixed 1'ar value &lt;if earli of st.» k *2W W ilzatlon (If serial) I f shares in :■ ■ . ! "::■•..... •j:&lt;4 ' flharM liutued durine 8m&lt; ■'" i share* of full at this da' £.7"-b, ■ ... f-iti .... ••:• ire. and the aicgregate .-.I real es ... of Improved real estate upon which loans have ■ XI 4 VniirHi-»'il value of impriv •••■ Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association as ( *i:i..ix) nre ■■ urity ••••■, t * '.2«K) tornado torna4a iude for hiiilding purposes during the fiscal year. . ins made for payment of homestead mortgages during ■ during fiscal year :::::::::::.. ■ association ,i of interest charged borrowers during fiscal v™ ■ • • • ■ • JJJ^i \;^ Vuji'n'inir' </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. i STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THB SOUTHEAST NEB. BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. AUBURN, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. A. H. GILMORE President WM. B. SMITH Vice-Presiden R. M. GILLAN Secretary W. H. HAY Treasurer CHAS. O. FRENCH Attorney Directors. A. H. GILMORE, W. B. SMITH. R. M. NOTT, 1. M GILLAN. W. IT. HAT, It. M. UILLAN. Assets. First mortgage loans $140,433 00 mortgage loans In process of . ... 1,672 00 Real estate 4..T Furniture and stationery .... 9»sh :::;:;;; 7.^ Delinquent Interest, premiums and tin '.'.'.'.'.'.'. 4,911 4&lt;&gt; Kxpenaea and taxes paid OUier assets ...... Total $161,026 26 Liabilities. Capital stork running (dues and ilivi- . $ 43 880 14 Full paid stock 102.800 0O Reserve fund 8 &lt; h 8.000 on (led profits Due shareholders on incomplete loans. . Premiums unearned .... Advance dues Advance Interest and premiums 126 05 Total $161,026 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISC AL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1902 (rnnning stock) $13 i Palance on hand July 1, 1902 (rnnnlng stock) $13.' (running stock Dues (full paid stock) Dues (full paid stock) Interest Inter 15,044 on l*romlums ate fees repaid .... sales Premium Certificate fees «o r.o repaid ... ■s Rents Rents Insurance and taxes repaid Total $92,981 Insurance and taxes repaid Total $92,981 70 Expenditures. Expenditures. Loans $42 ssi&lt;ins ~r ririrriirirriiririrrriririiriiiriririrrrriri_ r 'isos • r»s4 o •3 dues Loans $ 42.347 75 salaries :::::::.::::::::::::.:::::.::::.:::.:::::::::.:.: . : ises •s 1 paid Knll paid stock, earnings ". Full paid stock, earnings ". Cash on hand 7,300 9 ash on ha i 7,3 Cash paid for real estate 8.0' Cash paid for real estate 8.9' Cash paid for insurance and taxes 116 0 Total $92,981 7 Cash paid for insurance and taxes 116 07 Total $92,981 70 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPI TAL REPORT. Plan of association (spriai or .permanent t • Permanen Pl&amp;D of association ( • Permanent l'ar \ $100 00 $100 00 if serial) ■a (if serial) ■&gt;n I shares Is 1.14-' i shares is 1.14 Lr ■ ■ No. of shares withdrawn &lt; i&gt;o. of shares of ruin it this date ■■s of fall at this date •a loaned •■s on which d it ires of rui: it this date at this date •a loaned on es on win ivment of dues. .. . Amou; *ij *i^«qU n2 Amount of loan- • • ♦ 1-J8.9.J3 00 Amount of loans Appraised vain. been made VAlllP Of Appraised value ' - upon 11 ii 1 1 i which loans ! I ■&gt; the association as $141.1. lateral se&gt; .; T "» .IT. . sages during •••■••■• * 8 it of advai loans during flscal year o _ \'n of Tion-horrowlna: stoi'knulders Eo. of ii o. of minors hoi in the association rent of interest charged borrowers Muring aanu « m rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers &gt; I « , ~r nramhm " . Monthly ES^t SSSwTto rVi;^ tad ::::::::: loises chareed to reserVo &amp; r,, is declared on " J- 1 ■'■' It of d «J«' '- ■"oaths </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OK THK CONDITION OF THE AURORA IUILDINd AND LOAN \i AURORA, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. B. A. MUNSON President J. B. HUNTER.. President BAILEY ... Secretary SCHOONOVER Trea J. H. GROVESNOR Attorney Directors. N. .1 3. \ Assets. mortgage loans $2,Oi First mortgage l.iariB in process nf ... leans Heal estate . . . ure and stationery. Cash &gt;ient intercut, premiums and Bi • Expenses and taxes paid assets Total 12,167 It Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dlvid ... $7 1,40 Resen nr.s unearn .... Total 12.157 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCA1 YEAH ENDING JUNK 30, l • Receipts. Receipts Balance on hand July 1, lima Balance on hand July 1, 1W&gt; Does I mnniiiK stock I Does (runnn Doe* (full i rshlp and transfer fees i i-paid full paid ... Loan at bank (temporary) . ... Total :S7 00 Loan at bank (temporary; Total Expenditure*. Expenditures. Loan Salar Loans $2,". -s ions *2,f Matured si Full paid s' a hand. . . . Full paid b Loan at bank Loan at bank Total I'LEMEN ITLEMENTAL REPORT. TAL REI'OH T I'lan of as- I'lan of as- |1d $1(1 1 in for at tin ■ MM wllii-h 1" of improx . whirli !■ il whl.li In the assiHiation aa a In. li loai in force and •&lt;1 to the as- $1 ■ v • I ii unent ca. I 1 a ; time of stu'.U matured during li* al year </seg>
            <seg id="p042">4: BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS ST.\ OP THE Till BEATRICE, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903, Officers ihus. j. CHIDISTER Presiden r . u. Hfchb " « "-1-iAMS Se&lt; , WUl* UKAKK -j w. u. mcuikk Attorney Director*. V v kkes W " E WILr ' IAU S. Assets. r irst mortpaee loans trn - ■an« In process of f rurnuure ana stationery ... 3T' iwnnqueni M ' &gt;ilHI flnd ttrna nnld K»rs ana taxes paid une irom scockli • - ■ . . • rot *' apltal stock running (dues and dividends) *o. , "nil nniri wT.i.-L- ' * " ,: na stock. . l*»Rf»rvp fund tpserve iuna Ndirinea pronca &gt;— ■■■rwioWtra on ■remnimx un.arnml iaranc« interest and premiums. . roUI . $72 1 STATE SAVJ M) LOAN AS LOT-IE A. II. 1 .labilities. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISC AT YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1002 fi il .in ms 1 I... an ilu. Abstract ( Total Expenditures, Loan. Salar .. emissions u liar Taxe Furniture and supp Totai » 78 Kh REPORT. SUPPI.K Permanent Plan of association ( [.erm»i I'ar valut shares In for yo. or snares issuea b ■ lurlne fl- 1 Eof shares n No. of shares of ruin full pal.! I full paid stocK in iorce ai i of Inipr. upon which loans have .,,„„„„ • .-n made * Ised value (if Improvements •-•• ance In force and a a " r building 'parpows "•• rnent of hom. 34 value of Improvements • \' :,'"'.' i nine of improvements • ■ ■ - • • nnce in force and a association aa building 'pnrposW rnent of honj. s 31 t^'es during E,,f ent of liomosteaa morigases uui ■ 3t No', fif •■■'••; ;•••• -• ; •; '" n ;••■••■ o. of min n :■ •/ ■ • ig, rate pi rowers during verajte rate p&gt; ' borrowers during I le rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers daring I 7 ■a Average rate per cent of premiums chartted borrowera during , y^ r premium:::::::::::::i:'' la/ o" premium '.'. '. ] '. .' '. .' '. '. '. '. mount or t .\muuii[ &lt;»[ on full i&gt;aid stock &lt;1 - (.f dividends Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year Non« </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF Till: CONDITION OF THE BLAH! lUILDINCJ AND LOAN ASSN. BLAIR, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. F. W. KENNY, SR President F. W. ARNDT Vice-Presid.nt WM. KELLY Secretary C. A. SCHMIDT Treasurer Directors. F. W. KENNY, Sit., r. W. AUNDT, WM KELLY, HARKI si II Mil IT. E. It STEWART, J. W. NEDVELI Assets. nortxage loans • . . . . .... tlonery Kelincpient Interest, premiums nnd tine« F:x] tenses and taxes paid 102 20 Other assets Total Liabilities. Capital stuck running (dues and dividends) a 1.74 on im-omplpti- .earned Expenses ii' Totml .... </seg>
            <seg id="p045">t.- II \ND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YE ENDINi Receipts. Expenditures. l\ F'IM.KMKNTAI. RKl'ORT A A A N I 1 A </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB CIIADKON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. CHADRON, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. B. F. PITMAN President J. BROGHAMER Vice-President J. L. PAUL Secretary J. L. PAUL Treasure A. W. CRITES Attorney Directors. B. F. riTM J. BBOGHAMER, M. TANGLE, A \V. PRITES, I!. L. SCOVKL. Assets First mortgage loans mortgage loans In process of foreclo Stock loans Keal estate $ Furniture and stationery Cash Delinquent interest, premiums and Ra Kipenses and I axes paid Other assets Kills receivable 1.7 Interest same . Total $2,690 84 Liabilities. Capital stork running (dues and dividends I $ : Full paid stork e fund e fund wled profits hareholders on Incomplete loir Premiums unearned and premi Matured rtock I.m Interest, same ... 181 00 Total $2,65* </seg>
            <seg id="p047">17 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE Receipts. $ 54 49 LH Expenditures. g *r Wlthdr* Witbdra » 4'J SUPPLEMENTAL/RKl'OI r i w N ft A </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION &lt; &gt;K TUB (LAY CENTEK 1U IL1HN&lt;; AND LOAN ASSN. CLAY CENTER, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. H. E. McDOWELL President S. M. WALLACE. Vice-President J. L. CAMPBELL. Secretary THEO GRIESS ... Treasun Directors. fka: i TKR, li. II. HI N OUK. A AHD, Assets. $12,400 00 irage loans L'aee loans in Furniture and - lent Interest premiums and tines I Kxpenses and taxes paid Total *«■"" 14 Liabilities. Capital Rtook runninc (dues and divi. V- ] 17i Advant ■ ToUl * 1:i " 44 M </seg>
            <seg id="p049">u BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS !AF RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YE Receipt! S 134 s Balance on band .In - (running - (full pal i ■ &gt; i Insurance repaid * Total Expenditures. r»;i 111 ri" At 1 \\ tt tmraw °*« n nana Taxes and Insurance on mortgaged propert :aKfd propel iota SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. r permanent i*ian oi association isenai or (wi-unim-m i Par v:i fkii ,1.. t .■ k ♦ ' ' »■ No. of shares Us. n No. of - No. of shares matured during fiscal No. of shares withdrawn during ."so. oi snares »iiiium*»u uuiiu - rce at « _1 _ ..« «..lt . in /...■.... A full paid stock in force at tli So. of shares on whi it 1 r meut of di tt ii imuuni oi uu^- """r 1 " i f,,r,v!.i&lt;niv. and No 3 ",'' gm . , .,/! r..-l 1 ,.c!!|l» *t*»H (\nwiun •on which loan- a made a raised value of Improvements - upon uninipro ate »«!.....! . run I ..*!:!!.' Illmtl utili'll lOI ipon which loans bavi I real nd as \ •s durintt Ihf fiscal Tear., luring inn pur|K&gt; : h&lt; Ud loan! d the association. average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal , it of premiums charged t»&lt; par LTera k .lUeT to rexerve fund during' flsc".l i vear kverage running time of stock matured during nsca; . - . m 1 i ENDING JUNE 30, 190; rremiuma Ip and tra l.'ian&lt; repaid Withdrawal Cm i.&lt;&gt;an« ti _ I 1 \i.pi:ii-i'(l value or uni cned to the association &lt;&gt;r advance paym&lt; &lt;io. of i »O. of ! </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE COLUMBUS LAND, LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. J. C. ECHOLS Presiden P. J. HART V HENRY HOCKENBERGER a GUS G. BECHER 1 W. M. CORNELIUS Attorm Directors. G. A. SCOTT, O. L. BAKEE, W. M. COEXK C. L. GERRARD, C J. SCOTT. Assets. First mortgage loans $12. First mortgage loans in process of Stock loans Real estate Furniture and statlui Cash Delinquent Expenses a ( )t her assets Other assets Total $1GT Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues) c Full paid stock Rjijwi jp fund Reserve fund , N I ndivided Drofits Sl,4*3 I'ndivided profits Due shareholders &lt;.n im •■mplete loans Premiums u Advance dues Ml Advance interest ... 88 Xot*l .••• $1GT </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. YEAR Receipts. Balance on band July 1, 1 $ 6. Dues (running stock) Balance on hand J Dues (full paid stock)... . . . Interest . .'. '..... .,7 Premiums Fines Membership and t rai. ... 239 no Loans repaid . . 7,3' None Bents None Total $69,766 80 Expenditures $61.1" ■ Withd None Matin Man 1 stock, ea None Cash on hand 7,398 *C. Prem ms returned returned ,o Total $09,766 80 SUPPLEMEN T AL REPORT. iv $1" No. oi i iranization (If serial i unization (if buna in for 4.1 ::T shares Issued No. of matured 41 I withdrawr ■ shares of running it this date . in for at this date full pa No. of shares loaned on ivment of Total amount of dues delinquent at Amouii Amotii No. of mount ■d real *1JI.I upon whirl ;U b. value of Improvements ' &lt;&gt;f loans upon unh- al estate .■line of unimproved real estate ui&gt;on which loans have .... Amount of Insurance in force and assigned to the ass. colla ity . $io:: No. of ilins purposes during . - ur. . loans made for I ding purpt iurlnj.- of loans made for i t of homei tead i luring fiscal year Amoi of loans during fiscal year None in the association 37 rate ]" harge rt borrowers daring ar 78 • ■ rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers dm yoa r ■ f premium | from loan of dividend lared on runnin \! year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal T jrs and 4 wks </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF TIIK t O.NIHTION OF THE CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSN. CRETE, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. CRETE, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers Officers. M. E. HAIGHT President M. E. HAIGHT F M. H. FLEMING Vice-President M. H. FLEMING Vice-F C. B. GOODELL S C. B. GOODELL Secretary C. B. GOODELL 1 C. B. GOODELL Treasurer » Directors. B. ANDERSON. K .1 RADBMACHER, A B. SHALL, ( IN, i;i:o II. 1IA M E. IIAHJIIT, Directors. M. 11 C. I I.L, Z. WATEBUAN. Assets. First mortgage loans $C First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans Real estate Furniture and stationery Cash 14.". to 1 icllniiiicnt Interest, premiums and fint-s Kxpenses and taxes paid Other assets Total $0,4 Liabilities. Capital stock running $fi &gt; Full i&gt;ald si e fund . . Indlvided profits . . 437 43 IMie shareholders on loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance Interest and premiums. Total $6,448 95 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts, Balance on hand July 1, 1902 running stock i $6.01 1 50 ' I'limiiiii; stock) i full paid rr.-niMna.- Flnm. 114.". ' iiml tran drawing pi 11 Total I ins us ler expenses ... thdrawals, dues . II paid sim k. asb on band Total Expenditures, $!•&gt;. l earnings $6.4 • '•iniiFi other expenses Withdrawals, du ■ mini; k. dues an. inn Full pa Full puid stock, earnin Cash on hand 143 00 Total $6.t SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. IMan of association f serial or permanent i Serial Man of association (serial or permanent i Serial •ar T.i $1" I"ar v.i $1" • aeries Issued k ial &gt; . ial) ... 1.114 &gt;. of .... 1. 114 - ... It this ■ In ■ - &gt;'s of rum ne at this dale at this da: at this dal : shares loaned on : shares loaned on I which dues are delinquent i which il Inqaent Total Amount of inten Amount of loans on $fi. i Amount of loans on $i; Appraised value of ii upon which loa aliie of unimpr a which l&lt; I alue of ir npon which lot v alue of upon uni Appraised value of unimpi uixjn which loan been made Amount of insurance in force and a $6.1' iiling pur|Hisps during tli ir. . Nling pur|Hisea during th ar. . i paymeBt of homestead mo ing tiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans daring fiscal year No. i.i k in the association. fat of interest charged bo yar •■■. 6 Plan of premium Amount ered -serve fund Amotii! :\r vear </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TIIB F AIRFIELD BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. FAIRFIELD, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. C. W. POTTER President A. H. LATZKE Vice President F. ARRAWALT Secretary T. P. SHIVELY Treasurer J. L. EPPERSON &amp; SON Attorney Directors. UIC'IT. OEO. MYATT, C. I.. LEWIS. WM. HOEVET. C. C. PARKER, J. i: BFATZ. Assets. First mortgage loans $13.27" 00 mortgage loans in process of ■ loans . estate Furniture 'and stationery CaRh 2,15 Delinquent interest, premiums and lim&gt;s Expenses and taxes paid None Other assets ... None Total Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividend- $15,114 09 ■paid stock •ve fund 245 00 ided profits JO Due shareholders on incomplete loans 1 'ri'mluins unearned Advance dues None &lt;e Interest and premiums. . Miscellaneous 2 10 Total 510.G61 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. r:e on hand July 1, 1902 $1.»: &lt;runni 7153 (full paid stock) Balance on hand July 1, 1002 mict iiuu paiu siui-Kj t 1,1' Premiums 00 p and transfer fees Loans repaid 1,8' Loans r.i.aid 1,8' Keal estate sales ... None sales ... None Miscellaneous .... 19 15 Miscellaneous .... 19 15 Total t. |6,5T0 39 Total t. |6,570 39 • Expenditures. Expenditures. Loans $1,5' Salaries I ........... Loans ..... $1 51 Salaries I ........... Other expenses 19 OO Other expenses 19 0O Withdrawals, dues , .. Withdrawals, du w unaiawais, aues ... Withdrawals, earnings 1 ' Wj ' 1 Withdrawals, earnings 1 ' Wj ' 1 Matured stock, dues , ,„, „_ Matured stock, di Matured stock, dues I , ,„. „_ Matured stock, earnings *•' Full paid stock, dues Matured stock, earnings I&gt; " Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earnings Full paid stock, earning; (ash on hand 2,1- Miscellaneous 19 65 cash on hand 2 1 Miscellaneous 19 65 10 6r. Total 70 39 Total 70 39 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT I'lan of association (serial or permanent) Permanent I'lan of association (serial or permanent) Permanent $ln of shares In force at k |lo No. of shares issued since i&gt;n No. of shares issued since inn ( shares issued during nw-al year of U .... No. of shares of runn .... 56 No. of shares of runn . . . . :it this dab' No. of shares loa shares on -ji f shares loa yment of dues.... 4 amount of dues g] , $164 00 Amount of li Amount of aid jl I amount of - $300 00 Amount of loans on it of loans on impr ri value of Imp vhich loans have i made made ... L $23,000 00 J ■n ■ n as K collateral security of loans made for building purposes during \he fiscal year. . rof loans made for payment of I mortgages during S Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year |S&lt;' No. of borrowing stock hnldf No. of i _■ stock In the association Average n .t of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 8 Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers' during : » Payable monthly in fifty equal payments 1 to reserve fnnd during fiscal *i ■ alySr} *1' 5 semi annual Average running time of stock matu .... jn mon tn« </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THE EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. FREMONT, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. CHAS. H. MAY President FRANK HAMMOND Vice-President ARTHUR TRUESDELL Secretary CHAS. B. VEARZIE Treasure GEORGE L. LOOMIS Attorney Directors. CI1AS. n MAY. CTTAS B. VKARZIE, GEORGE A VirRRELL, KKANK HAMMOND, GKO. I.. LOOMIS, FRED BADE1 ARTHUR TBLE8DELL, J. C. LEE, FRANK FOWLEI Assets. First mortgage loans |5.~." ■ an* in |' ... Furniture and stationery (ash 3.7 ■ Delinquent Interest, premiums and Bad Kx|«euseK ai i id other assets Contracts for real estate sold Total $73. 1 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and divid $71.' - 1,1 ■ a ri on lni-omplete loai:- ITciuiums unearned Advance dn Advan and premiums. Other liabilities ... Total </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE 3" Receipts. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1. 1W running stock) I I 'I -I'lllillHIS l'reiuiui Fin § Mcmbersbip and transfer f •■&lt;■«. . ■ I -late sales withdrawals anil real estate Membership and tr:r Loans repaid I Males IT .i Sundry accounts Total ■ Sundry a Total Expenditures. Expenditures Loans Loan . '. '.'. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 114 00 ■i IlKlllI nuts ■na returned mis returned Beat estate tax and In- &gt; Total supr AL REPORT. Plan of ass *-" ii tlf serial I . . . $77 *7T nount v Hue &lt;if Improved real estate upon which loans have) :.'5 oo :ilue of improvements ition a *«."«■ '• -.■al year. . luring ■ irinir N i iation it &lt; li: ■ ■ ■ ar $4.7 ar ... 1-4 inoi </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 STATEMENT OF TIIE CONDITION OF THE NEB. STATE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. FREMONT, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. T. L. MATHEWS President &gt;S L. HAMMOND Vice-President l&gt; COLSON Secretary J. T. MAY Treasurer W. J. COURTRIGHT Attorney Directors. HATHEWS. J. T. MAY. : rtlEP. BL. HAMMOND, \\ . UICIIT, COLSON, It. IS. SCUNEIDEB, I WILLIA.V JCUNEIDKR, C. M. WILLIAMS. Assets. First : • .... ind stationery tT_ 4'_i :.. 4?0 «7 nent interest, premhimii and Dim sold on contrart ... -''• "° rship fees 157 28 p fees lnsuraii Total $96,504 17 Liabilities. Capital stork rnnninc ?01 ,,1 ... ... .... 2,300 00 ■•■rest and Drcmii: &gt;t and premiums on certificates of ii . ... 39 08 Total *96,5O4 17 .... </seg>
            <seg id="p059">r,o BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL V Receipts. tal 1 Expenditures. 4 I 1 4 N lf.4 11 1 X Ac &gt;Ted real estate Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have IV 1 v a $148 HO A 1 H&gt; 16 .&lt; A^ ill 4 Ar Amount of dividends year Av Average running time of stock matured during fiscal rear! NDING JUN1 PLEMEXTAI, KEPORT I'll known I on rn year ■ 1 nuriOK flxil year. ... 5 (xrnl annual </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 3UILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS- STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OP THE GERING WILDING AND LOAN A GERING, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. FRED D. WOLT President C. B. WHIPPLE Vice-President PETER McFARLANE Secretary PETER McFARLANE . Treasurer Directors. FRED D. WOT.T. C. IV WHIPTLE, A. IV WOOD C. B. WHIPrLE, J A. BUKTON, U. I Assets. .age loan* $3,000 0« ito.i .- ; . :::::::::::::::::: Farnll nitionery &lt;-.;;, nent interest, premiums and fini 17j &lt;ea and taxes paid Total *5,"40 80 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and divUl ... $3,Ci ::.::::.::::...: itlftf ioans .... ioans B :ied ■::;:::::::::::::::::: ::: ■ ' . nil' i m en - miums and lines .... 2.07 Total * 5 - </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 riii-kim; and loan associations. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts Balance on hand July 1. IMS. . $ • rsliip and •Male sal Total Expenditures Loans Salaries •• • t'omiii "iii 1 1 1 j Other Withdraws I - Wlthdniwals, turning Matun.l Maiur-.l stock, earn Kull p Full ] Cash on band Total Cash on hand Total SUPPLEMEN I'PLEMENTAL REPORT. TAL REPORT Man of association (serial &lt;&gt;r p -.'rial •ar value of en. ♦-" No. of series Is* No. of No. of shai \o. of shai .'o. of sbai •■•'• &lt;o. of sha' ,*\l. V* f-IHW - No. of shares Issued ••••' f shares issued during fiscal year. . No. of shares matured during Ryj. yn Dual • o. of shares mature*! E\i. ui r-ii.ii O. Of Slllll No. of shar in. of shares of run No. of shares of ruin No. of shares of full o. of shares of full it this dar No. of shares 1' which dues a No. of shares loau«il M □ which dues a • duei .... of inipr"» upon whirh loans have of luipr- it of loans upon uni ■ •• • *•■ ised value of unimpr • which loans have been made insura'ncV'ln force and » ass&lt;H-latlon as collateral security A " ' 1&lt; «. f loans made for building puri •&gt;: V*&gt;w ( loans made for payment of hi (loans' during fiscal year No. of non borrowing stovKooiders. . . . No. of minors holding stock In Average ra' - I year I'lan of premium. ■.■.■.■.■.■.■.'.■.'.■.■. ."...■.... Premium i»aid in a,l 1 i ; i u VJ4 |jic^ ui i \a ui .•-••••••••••••■■ Amount cr&gt; .AI11OUUI *'• . ___ Amount of yed Ion- -_ Amonni «! on n. ng n»&lt;al rate per cent of il i««-mi year. .. . Average raic \*?i tmL "i ui ee running time of stock matured during QscsJ year PMl </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. GRAND ISLAND, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. LOUIS VEIT President CHAS. G. RYAN Yiee-Presid&lt;nt CHARLES W. BRININGJER .... Secretary CHARLES F. BENTLEY Trca JAMES H. WOOLLEY Attorney Directors. ii. c. mii.i.f.i;, n. .t. n.utn, C B. NOIUUS. KICUAIU) (iOEHKING, L. ! K. K. IIOltTII, Assets. First mortgage loans $254,400 00 in process of : 9,00 Heal exiai. ind stationery Cuk 16,163 ins and fines HI and taxes paid 1,1 First mortgage loaus settlement, balances aud a&lt; i -rued intin . M ToUl $2S7..'S'J9 6'J Liabilities. Capital stock running (dnes and diri&gt; $270 Full paid stock &lt;1 9.1! a on incomplete loans 1.30.1 14 .... erest and premiums Advance interest and premiums Total $287 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1. 1002 I&gt;ue8 (running stock) Interest ... 19.194 »&gt; ;« 1 ines and transfer fe«« I Payments on set. balance loans Payments on set. balance loans Tax sale certificates redeemed i . . Tax sale certificates redeemed i . . Total Tax sale certificates redeemed Total $133,497 45 Expenditures. Expenditures Loans ••• Loans $ C". Salaries" '. Salaries Other expenses, Other expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, dues' Withdraw;. ,3 Withdrawals, earnings "I .....'........ Matured stock, dues.! . ...'.'.'.:'. Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings Maun ■ a hand • • • Cash on hn • • « Interest paid ou Interest paid ou ■ • • ■ ■ • • «T 5 Tax sa Premiums repaid on matured loans .ib 40 Premiums repaid ed loans Total $139,497 45 Total $139.497 45 SUPPI -I RT. SUPPLEMENTAL Plan of association (serial or permanent) .....' Plan of association (serial or permanent)' .' • Par value • • ♦'-' Par value • • *'-'' .n (If serial) 81 ......... n.M* .n (if serial). ■ • • 8? • •• Ion • -• ..... No. of shares mu i sharrs wltlidr ■■•"' No. of shares matui r shares » ■: shares oi No. of shares of No. of shares of I stock In force at this date No! of shares of No. of shn i No. of shai .... * • * • ... .... amount of due&gt; owing bv owing by \ . jut ol &lt;n of morteair«*s No. '■ of Ban i real KU,i\ vain.' at »nin i vi&lt;l ;il • '■'&gt; which loans liave „,.„ ,,,a,l'. . ■ "• appraisal n whiih loans 1 .... No appraisal Amount of lnsuran.V Yn'force and n "..f ioooo : loanis made for bnlldine purposes &gt;r. . ■•• * "« i* 1 loans made for bulldlne purposes durl' 0 0 No.' of loans made for payment of homestead mor ing ing i r _ ,. ' „ ,. ' ti &lt; during 1 ire rate per Amount of l"ss. : - n iJIMI dv •"• «, c iH/^ $18 ' • veraee rat year.... Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year 814 WMSfca , :::: </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 ClILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF Till: CONDITION &lt;iK THE! HARTINGTON IM'ILDlNr. AND LOAN ASSX. HARTINGTON, NEBRASKA, On t: lay of June, 1903. Officers. W. S. WESTON President A. B. GABLE Vice-President F.O.ROBINSON retary \'S NELSON Treasurer Directors. W. 8. WKSTON, A. B- QABLE, FRANS NELSON, A. Ll'BELET, A. I.ri'.KI.I'V. c;i:&lt;&gt; r. bcoville Assets. First mortgage loans $19,071 tt«tl ••- ... Furnr atlonery ... Cash OUT 1&lt; -i. pri'!iiiiim&lt; and tines lx&gt;linquent imprest, prpmlums and lit, sen and tai ]nl m Other assets . . None Total |2i,( i Liabilities Capital stock running (dues and dividends &lt; $1". Full paid ki • • 1.2 mplete loans ... ' \' o ne .... ... jo7 Advance interest and premiumK. .... Total |21,( </seg>
            <seg id="p065">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 65 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE F YEAR ENDING JUNE 39, 1903. Receipts. Balance on liaixl July 1. 1' $ «7 41 Premiums - : and transfer fees sales Total $7.&gt;- Expenditures Loans /. $2.{K Salaries ■ &gt;miin issions I uses I iwals. dues \ awam. aues i awals. earnings / / Matured stork, dues I , a ~ n „„ n™::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::} 19500 ° Matured stock, earning: ■ii hand Bills payable Interest on bills payable and advai Total $7,815 04 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. nan of association (serial or permanent) l"ar Tn li share of stock i&gt; $1' No. of -moe organisation (Jf^setlal) No. of shares In force at No. of sha 1 . 1 1 1 No. of nha; luring ti- No. of shares matured during fiscal ar. . . shares wlthdm z fiscal year shares of rum i thi» date . shares of running s t thin date ■ full pai.l lU No. ,.f .tt this .late ivment of dues. . . . ivment of dues. ... 3 3 Total a aid Amuui -1 unpaid :-'ages sub i' re, and the aggregate amount of sam. ire. and i te amount :. . real estate |1!&gt; - $10" Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have Apprai- 1 1 estate upon which loans liav Appraised value of lmprovemei, Appraised value of Improvemei, Amount of loans upon unii: Anioui upon unin Amount of Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security $32,000 00 Amount of insurance in force and asalgned to the association as urity . . $32,000 00 No. of loans made for building pur| » al year. . 2 i loans made for bnliding pin » -.al year. . - payment of mortgages during Itacal year 1 r payment of homestead mortgages during ' loans during! fiscal year $4.'." d the association arged borrowers during fiscal if loans during fiscal year $4.." the association urged borrowers during fiscal ir linn of premium lian of premium Amount &lt;•!•••' $30 70 Amount of losses chu Amount cre&lt;l $30 70 Amount of loa* Amount of m running stork during fiscal year $1. Average rate per cent of d '1 during fiscal year. ... 12 Average ra' year. .. . Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year 90 months 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">M 66 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THB HASTINGS BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. HASTINGS, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. GEORGE H. PRATT President HENRY SIEKMANN , . Vice-President WM. M. LOWMAN Secretary WM. M. LOWMAN Treasurer J. H. FLEMING Attorney Directors. BE H. PRATT, JOHN SNIDER. SIEKMANN, FRED L. 1 W. F. BUCHANAN, KZRA LANUEVIN. I ORNELIUS, Assets. First mortgage loana $36,509 Ofi First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure None Stock loans 4,3."&gt;7 Real estate None Furniture and stationery Cash 1,601 Delinquent Interest; premiums and fines Expenses and taxes paid Other assets None Total $62,627 93 Liabilities. Capital stock running (does and dividends) $61,066 80 Full paid stock None Reserve fund 653 9."i Undivided profits 907 Due shareholders on incomplete loans None Premiums unearned None Advance dues None Advance interest and premiums None Total $62,627 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. &gt; RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1. 1902 ... $ 4 i running stock i ... Due* (full paid stock) nins Fines i and transfer f lid 15.'" ind drawing papers Delinquent taxes repaid Total *-»° Expenditures. Loan. *1P* Salaries' '!*'.!!*.! Comm 151 40 ■ i rniii l.ficil n band Delinquent taxes paid Directors' fees uireciure iet» ■ Uebate interest account advance paj "&gt; °" Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. IMan of association (serial or i 11'' ■ in (If strlali -ince organization ■ ar No. of ■r ar -w- g fiscal yearr: in force at thi- ~in force at th'- ma. at ■naiTS oi rimuiiiK aii»t.n m i"i. • k In force at this date k In force at this date on e* "n which dues are delinqnent •••■• iiyment of Total am.... Amom {£, ,,., $89 1« Amount m mm i , amolint tint No. of mortL _ S mm. No ' ...... ' • ■ ■ , Amo'.r i iuprovVd' V^ki mttfi'. ? " '. '. '■ '■ ■■■ ■■■ • ■ ■ • Amount' of loans on improved real estate. \ Apprai- f improved real estate upon which loans Apprn of improved real estate upon which loans hare have value OI impruvwi l«-ni e^mic u ,-... «...^- non nade $1 ~' *pnrnispd value of improvements • insurance In force and assigned to thr l loan™ 1 miSe lr for bulidl'ng pnrposes' diifinR th&lt; '•• loans made for payment of homestead s during nVe' paVments I "of 'loanV during" fiscal year, loans lid ■ • ■ .r« rr hold l |ne Bt&lt; n •. J " '&lt;? rmte per cent of rowers during i $114. ■■■ lateral Security »"»•» ™ loans made for buliding purposes duflng th ir. . loans made for payment of homestead "&gt;K •e payments of loans during fiscal year, loans roMrre 'fond 'ciii rliiK $3.T .1,: , l..&lt; ' :1 I'cil lltirttlLl I!S&gt; 111 1 t'tt I . . . • V- « Average rate per cent of " </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HAVELOrK UL'ILDING AND LOAN ASSN. HAVELOCK, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. SAM'L HINKLE President A. ADAMS ... Vice-President F. L. SUMPTER. B&lt; retary F. B. YOUNG Treasurer Director*. SAM'L HINKLE, F. n. VOI v JOHN RENNAN, &lt;; \V. ANDKKSi T1IOM ISIItlSY. S1M1TER, FRKD KOE11LKU, V. K. I1OKMAN. Assets. Flr«t mortgage loans $31 .300 oo mortgage loans in process of forecl " loans 4T Real estate Furniture and stationery Cash . 0r&gt;7 19 Delinquent interest, premiums and tin Expenses and taxes paid Other assets Total 13^.831 19 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends t ... $18. &gt;. Full paid stock ■ Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums Aiii a ■ and premiums Bills payable , . . 1.000 00 Total *;&gt;2,S31 1» </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1. 1!K&gt;2 $ 1. Balance on hand July 1. 1!K&gt;2 i Jl 51 Premiums None i and transfer fees ... 6,130 00 Bills i 1.000 00 Total $20,933 78 Expenditures. Loans 1 1G, 000 00 Salaries Salaries Commissions Commissions ( it her expenses Other expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings and interest on paid up - Ml 53 Withdrawals, earnings and interest on paid up stock CtU 53 Matured stock, dues Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings Mai in ■ irinin; Full paid stock, dues Full paid it Full paid stock, earnings Cash on hand 957 19 Full iiaid stock, earnings ish on hand 957 19 f Total $20,933 72 Total $20,933 72 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT, SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) Permanent of association (serial or permanent) Permanent I&gt;ar Talue ■ $200 00 $200 00 series issued since organization (If serial) : None t series issued since organization (If serial) : ■ at this date shares Issued since organization 1,044 shares Issued during fi- 241 shares Issued 1.0M ; shares Issued 241 No. of shares n; None - :tudrawn during fiscal year • running stock it this dat&gt; ' shares n; None indrawn al year • running - t this dat. is date :is date ined on ined on No. of shares on whli-h dues are delinquent 11 D whii-h dues are delinquent 11 I yment of dues .... ivment of dues. . . . »70 IMI dnes owl! . - iquent at »70 imi |70 im) : dues owing t&gt;y bor ran and tit d unpaid I unpaid and the aggregate Hid the aggregate real estate $31,240 00 real estate ■ $31,240 00 real estate upon which loans have of improved real estate upon which loans have Appraised value of i Amount of loans upon uni $100 00 in force and assigned to the association v $31.! loans made for building purposes during the fiscal year. . g r payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year 9 avments of loans during fiscal year $3,600 00 9 63 ■ 97 No of minors 1 association 8 Average ra r arged borrowers during fiscal ir 10 l'lan of premium. Amoui &lt;prve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses cha ng ducal jear None Amount of -wal year Amount of ■••ar 7 /I 111* Mill L "1 . 1 '' ar •■ rtiuuiu" tiscftl yrar. ....... Nun*. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF TIIK CONDITION OF TUB HOOPER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. HOOPER, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. JOHN P. HEINE President JOE SAUERS Vice-President GEO. W. HEINE Secretary ED. WEHLING Treasurer B. MONNICH Attorney Directors. ED WKHLINQ, A. If. T1LLMAN, J.\&lt;J - FRITZ, Assets. First mortgage loans $12,800 00 Mortgage loan* in process of i loan* beat estate 1,W Furniture and stationery 50 Cart 1,37s f. Delinquent Interest, premiums and in ... Expenses and taxes paid Other assets Total *15 Liabilities. capital stock running (dues and dlvid . . . $15,740 52 Full paid stock ... Reserve fund 170 U8 1 ndlvided profits I hie shareholders on incomplete loan Premiums unearned Advance dues 12 Advance interest and premiums Total *15,9^J SO </seg>
            <seg id="p071">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 71 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1902 $2 •■ JJuus (running stock) Dues (full pa ill stock) Interest bW) 07 Premiums Fines Membership and trat, . 10 OO repaid 1,5 lients Total $7,970 01 Expenditures. Loans $5,700 00 Salaries 75 00 Commission i ses :%.-. HO a«als, dues 685 OO Withdrawals, earnings yo so Matured stock, d Matured stock, earn Full paid si' Fall paid stock, earnings Cash uu hand 1,378 65 earuin. Cash uu hand Total $7,970 01 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) 'ar value ■•: $- No. of series issued s izatlon I ■ .No. of No. of Ml •ar No. of shares ni N •■s on which does ar shares su \vment of dues... Total : III $i: *45 20 mortgage- e aggregate amount $1,000 00 Appraised value of i of impn- Appraised value of ii of Impni* Amuunt of association as iatii'ii as later;. $20.: $20.- building purposes il year. . purposes il year. . 2 No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during 5 Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year 47 iatlon le per cent of inten- I borrowers during tl 7.8 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. '.'.'.'.'. $S1 76 Amount of red on rnnnlne v..ar $S. Amount of &gt;h\ on fnl Average ra 1 of dividends dei-Iai ■ .061 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. &gt; STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THH HUMPHREY BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSN. HUMPHREY, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. THOS OTTIS ■ President C. H. WALLACE i Vice-President P. E. McKILLI P Secretary J. C. McKINLEY Treasurer Directors. TTIOS. OTTIS, J. C. McKINLEY, W. M. CA.V LIZZIE MUitrilY. P. S. McKILLlP. C. II. WALLACE Assets. First mortgage loans $2,400 00 First mortgage loans In process of foreclosure None Stock loans None Real estate * Furniture and stationery 27 6C rash l,3i M Cash Delinquent Interest, premiums and tinw Expenses and taxes paid . . Other assets Total $3,733 OS Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) .... $3,G73 15 Full paid stock Hescrve fund ... 1'ndivlded profits Due shareholders on Incomplete loans I*remlums unearned ... None Advance dues ... None Advance Interest and premiums .... None Total $3,733 03 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">ftUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION'S. 73 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Receipts. BalaDce on hand July 1, 1OO2 Dae* (running .stork i lialance on hand July 1, 1W2 $1,308 Hues (runninc stork i 7_&gt;4 I M Dues (full paid stock) N st iins Due. ( full paid stock) ■ :::::::::::::::: ims ....,....::::::::::: Membership and transfer fees repaid Membership and transfer fees Keal estate sales Total R«il estate sales "ents ;;;; ..;. Total Expenditures. Expenditures. Loans $1,71 Salaries Loan* $1,700 Salaries Commissions Commissions Commissions Other expenses Other expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdrawal., due. i Withdrawals, earnings Withdrawal earnings ..:.: ".... Matured st &lt; ■ Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings. . Matur Full paid - Kuil jmid - Ki 1 1 1 i i"i it i -- Kiill iriiti Hl'M k fir \ Cash on hau Total Cash on hand. . !,:.&lt; Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT I'PLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Plan of association (serial or permanent) 1'ar value i |1U4i 1'ar value of en $1 oB I if serial) n (if serial) organization shares l«.ued during fls shares I. ing flscal year full paid stock in force at tl| I on full paid stock in force at t!i \; auavuHt. *-i .N'U|.' \ 2 &gt;i 2 W6 if improv tate upon which loans hav of inipn ■ -tate upon which loans have - of Improvements of Improvements loans up'.n iinimpro\ loans upon unimprov*Ml n- Appraised value of unimproved real estate ii|«&gt;n which loans I -•■&lt;! value of unimproved i ujxtn which loans hav .• ■ • Amount of insurance In force and • the association as ■ tirlty ■ loans made for building purposes during the flscal y loans made for payment of homestead mm ring ill year tit of advance pavments of loai borrowing noti borrx ■ minors holding stock In the M4S0ctatBfi&lt; • ranee In force and assigned tb the association as " "«-urlty ... loans made for bulldint; pnrp.&gt;ses during thi if loans made for payment of hoin iring .I year ill year tit of advance pavments of loai H borrowing non borrowing 1 Average rat • of inter. - - during ti vear « Ayerajte rate per cent of premiums char ■i-ar ,. of premlao . Mt«i nds declared on running stock durh .ar nt of dividends declared on full paid st»ck du </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB LAUREL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. LAUREL, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. J. B. FELBER President C. F. FURLEY. . . . Vice-President F. P. VOTER Secretary GUY WILSON Treasurer Directors. J. B. I C. F. FURLEY. OUT WILSON, W. T. GRAHAM, L. J. I W. 1*. \ Assets. First mortgage loans $ 9' First mortgage loans in process of tzsrr..~..7.rr7r..7. state •ure and stationery 107 58 Delinquent interest, premiums nnil find 144 Expenses and tai Other assets ToUl $1,307 68 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) Full paid stock Reserve fund i ...................... .... — -t and premiums ■rship fees ........ Total 1,307 68 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 75 RECEIPTS AN D EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, lfHij I.. ., Nothing ( running stork i $1.; Balance on hand July 1 i full paid stock) Premiums Fines 4 repaid Real estate sales Rents Total $1,404 32 Expenditures. Loans i * 900 00 Salaries '.'..'. S3 "" Commissions [ other expenses ; Iff fl Withdrawals, dues OtS 64 Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured st Full paid - Full paid stock, earnings - Cash on hand Total i l.&lt; supplemental; report. Plan of association (serial or pcrmai •inS rl ,il i i.ni ui oBBWiuiiuii isenai u[ j' # I"ar value of each share of stock. . . ♦'' I if Bfriali 1 f shares in foi &lt;m'.'.'. '.'..'.'.'. '.'. '.'.'.'. ...... shares issued during fi* :' shares matured &lt;1 ir 164 [ shares w'.thdrawn No. of shares of rum ' Hone ps of full : ■ lymcnt of Ainoiiut of dues owing bv «. Aiuom r ♦■ ' A|i|&gt;n\isiil value of Imprm urion which loans have 4 "■'*' value of tmprovem«v value of Impro Mans upon uni; U estate loans upon unii: ll estate ilue of unimpn which loans have None wiliie of uniiup :i which loans have None Amoini In force and a the association as «&lt;&gt;oo rv Amor nance in force and assigned] to the association as No. of loai&lt; buiidlnc purposes during tl ' loans made for payment of homestead moi al year Amount of advance i t loans during fiscal year borrowing r ' non borrowing' i minors holdir . the as« iKe rate per oeut of inter. owers during f vear • ' ee rate per cent of premiu il I y 1 . . . . . .............................. Amount of advai. ts of loans during fiscal year [ion borrow minors holding 7 P,an^;v P Vemium: ::::::::::::;:::::::::::;:::::::::::::::::. ? «j.i. Amom serve fund during fisjal year Ei Nothing Amount of dividends declared on tul Nona </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OK TIIK LEIGH BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. LEIGH, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. J. T. McKINLEY President 'T\ GRAVES. . . H V ice-President J. H. PIEPER Secretary C. H. MARIAN Treasurer Directors. IfcKINLEY, Q RAVES, C. !I MARIAN, K. II Assets. First mortgage loans J8.776 00 ; lire and stationery '. . rash st. premiums and fines ses and taxes paid . . assets Total *■»•" Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) 4.7* I Due shareholders on ini immlrt, • on ini-omplet' ...is anear and premli ToUl *4.770 1 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 77 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts Balance oa hand July 1, 1902 t. $ l.i" Premiums Hents Total Expenditures. Loans j $ 7&lt; Salaries Comml &gt;ther ■ W iiliilniwals, (In Withdrawals, caruiii Mamr. Matured stock. «rp n:- - Full paid stock, earnings Cash on band Total »2. i \f\\. REPORT. l'lan of ns&gt; -••rial or permnti . Far ti f 1" •n (if serial i . No. of shares matur.. ■ •es loaned on j which dues are delinquent : shares sul . . . *1 ' i unpaid . . and the am:: i :. ,.ians nn Improved real esnitt Jt3.T ■ .f ImproTi • ipon which loans liav been made Appraised value of Impn. - Amom. and assit'i axsorlatlon as No. of loans made for building purpoi loans made for payment of h during the fiscal year. . None ul mortgage* during rear Amount of'advn- its of loans dirlng fiscal year No. (I 1 latlon.. N Average ra 1 of inter. - during fiscal "• • ••• Plan of premium :'. Amour ... $17 00 Amount ■ • Amount of Amount of ;nt of dlvid year _-c ratp per &gt;ear. ... 9 Average running time of H &gt;J qurlng fiscal year • N ti- </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 buii.ium; and loan associations. STATEMENT OF TIIK CONDITION OF TUB NEB. CENTRAL JSUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. HOMER K. BURKKT President JOHN GIBSON Vice President M. W. FOLSOM. . . Secretary T. N. BURKET E. P. LEONARD. Manager of Ag&lt; Directors. JOHN GIHS K. P. LEONAHD, H. K. BUI T. N M. W Assets. First mortgage loans J- First mortgage loans in process of t Stock loan- 12.- Ueal ps 3.7. Furniture and stationery Cash 19.i it»nt Interest, premiums and lines •■» and taxes paid s Real estate sold under contract ... 1&gt; ToUl Liabilities. Capital stock running and div *82G,GO6 16 Full paid stock Reserve fund 14.2' Undivided profits ... 43.&lt; Undivided profits Due shareholders on Incomplete loan Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance Interest and pretu </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 BUILDING AND LO .'IATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAl YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. 'I * V 1 Balance on hand July 1, If"" i running stock) I (full paid Fines and transfer f« Loans repaid 191 Taxes repaid Reserve fund Office furniture Tot Expenditures I319.0C.3 40 , Saiariei &gt;a arles • 1 1 i ■• •oiumlsslons Commissions Jther expenses Other expenses Withdraws 1 Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings 238.'" Withdrawals, earnings ... 238,0' Matured Uatun ies Matured stork, earnin Matured stock, earnings Real estate account leal estate account ■ in hand m hand Office furniture Office furniture ••'• Reserve fund leserve fund • • _ Total * Total * SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent^ SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent^ Par value of each share of • • ,-s Issued s W) Par value of each share of • ■ •■•.••• *•' scries Issued s ial) ■ of shares in for. of shares issueil of shares issued during iiscal year No. of shares In force at 1 shares Issued r shares Issued during iiscal year shares matured dn es withdrawn durir,- ir. ...... ( running stock In tore* at this dan .... shares matured during fiscal yar ■ or snares maiureu uuu»k uw «» ■ , res withdrawn during fi&gt; | . . • ■ of shares of running stock In force at this date of shares of full paid stock in fore* at this dati No of shares of full paid stock tn fore* at this da No of sha ■ No of sha Amount of 1 *H Amount of ins and fines flue and nnj $11. No of r amount ofsan $24/ rof nior ' amount of sar $24/ tnn( in process of foreclosure, and Vn n* mnrteaees in nroonii of forecloeure. and an -.lme, Nc Amoir - on improved real estate .• of Improved real estate upon which i Amoui A Pp r:i of lmproTed real estate upon which loans .......:":...... Appraised value of improvements. ... .4,'......... ■ • ■ ■ •• •• Appraised value' of' improvements. .■■•$■■■■■■•;■■ --;■:.■- 1' vements Amount of Insurance In force and assigned to the association as „ collateral security • j-.4oi.mw loans made for building purposes) durii il yea;- . loans made for payment of honiestea-1 fiscal year Amount of Insurance in force and assigned to the association as 111 &lt;M1 sllateral security ■ fui linei m ai'cui itj • of loans made for building pu ■ or loans maae ior duuuuik i&gt;uii»""-» huh of loans made for payment of honv al year fiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans dyrim; Amount of advance payment* of loans during I k kholders f non borrowing stockholders. ■ minors holding stock in the ast • • ■ ■ Amount of advance payments oi ioaus uu . .v.. [ borrowing stockholders tot minors holding stock in th ■■ • • ■„••••. age rate per cent of Interest charged t*. Average rate per cent of Interest charged bor i* Plan of premium • ■ Amoir ing. fiscal year m0U ' i** on full ! JiTil stock dl] SB — b - </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 IU II.UINC AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF TMK CONDITION OF TUB MADISON COUNTY IHILDINii AND LOAN A MADISON, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. C. S. SNYDER President J. L. GRANT Vice-president GEO. E. RICHARDSON Secretary T. F. MEMMINGER Treasurer Directors. C. S. BXYnFR, &lt;MAN. F. A. MAI J. L. GRANT, KMIL WINT1 GBO. B. BICBARI Assets. First mortgage loans * 20 - First mortgage loans in : Stock loans Real estate 3fl4 •;."? Furniture and stationery Cash Delinquent Interest, premiums and tin Kxpenses and taxes paid Other assets, tax sale certificates 77 43 Other assets, tax sale certificate Total $2 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends i t-'.'- Full paid stfx-k . Renerr&lt;&gt; fund Vndivtded profits . . Due shareholders on Incomplete loans. Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance Interest and premli 6 Total $ - </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 IU IUHNO AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE Fl YEAR ENDING 1903. Receipts, Balance on hand July 1. lixrj $ l&gt;uea (running stork) .... l'remiums Fines 4 40 ishlp and transfer fee* sales Money borrowed 3&gt;' h Tax sale certificates 1'ersonal accounu Total * 14,038 1» Expenditures Loans Salaries t'ooimlsslons Other expenses Matured stock, earntn Full p:i Kills payable and Interest 3,. V 7 i m" hand Real e- Tax sale certificates 49 15 Total ., I 14 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. serial Plan of association (serial or permanent) l*ar value of each share of stock $ l*ar v;i No. of series Issued since organization (If sei shares lamed No. of shares matur. :lt this dill :lt this &lt;in 104 4 104 4 HU. VI CUBira Vli "l •^inpayment of 17 . vment of 17 $ $ m&lt;irt(ta&gt;rc- of Mim 1.1" Amount of loan- Appral "f Improi upon which loans have bwn made been made Appraised - runt of i the ass&lt;» collate oulMing purposeH ;ir. . &lt;i rot loans maile for pu.vuient of homestead mortgages during $ - ' ... 14 j.' rate p&lt;i » during fiscal 8 year rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year 1'lan of preniinr * m- ,t of loan AmiMint of \ear 13 ge running time of stock matured during :uonths «J </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OP THE CONDITION OF THH MADISON BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSN. MADISON, NEBRASKA. - On the 30th day of June, 1903. Offi ers. PETER RUBENDAL.L President JACOB HENDERSON Vice-President R. A. MALONY Secretary C. E. PLASS Treasurer Directors. H. E. BECKER, 11. F. THOMAS, BECKER, A. SCI1WANK, JENS JENSEN, A. SCI1WANK, 11. F. THOMAS, A. A. BLEY. Assets. Assets. First mortgage loans .... $ 22.050 00 First mortgage loans .... $ 22.050 00 First mortgage loans in process of I First mortgage loans in process of Stock loans Stock loans Ileal estate 239 07 Iteal estate 23'J 07 Furniture and stationery Furniture and stationery Cash 6,246 24 Delinquent interest, premiums and lines 610 90 Delinquent interest, premiums and li 610 90 ses and taxes paid ... ses and taxes paid. . Other assets, tax sale certiorates Other assets, tax sale certificates Bills receivable 91 50 Hills receivable 91 50 Sundrj accounts 141 Sundry accounts 141 27 Total * 30,047 28 Total * 30,047 28 Liabilities. Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 29,067 04 Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 29,067 04 Full paid stock Full paid stock Reserve fund 620 16 Reserve fund 620 16 Undivided profits None Undivided profits None Due shareholders on Incomplete loans Due shareholders on Imomplete loans Premiums unearned Premiums unearned Advance dues S52 CM&gt; Advance Interest and i 43 50 Sundry accounts 84 58 Total 9 80,047 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 83 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30. Receipts. Balance on hand July I, r $ 7." i running stock j 3,o ' Interest ..'.I 2,158 37 Premiums Fines . . ) Membership and tru&lt; Loans repaid Keal &lt; ■ ■ 8(H) Kenu 114 50 Bills receivable . .' . . ." .' ....... 6&gt;- Bills receivable Tax certificates 37 3D Tax certificates Sundry accounts Total * 14,915 0» Sundry accounts Total * 14.915 00 Expenditures. Expenditures, Loans $ Loans $ 7 Salaries Other expenses Other expenses 0 s '■" Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings Matured stock, earnings Cash on hand Cash on hand Ueal estate expenses Real estate expenses Sundry payments 13 .10 Sundry payments Total * 14.915 W SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Total ... * 14.915 0» SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) serial serial Plan of association (serial or permanent) serial Par value of each sL k * HKi »o No. of series Issued since organization (If serial) ::•' Par value of each share . * No. of series Issued since organization (If serial) M *»4:t .No. »■: No. of shares Is organization No. of shares is organization No. of shares issued during fiscal year No. of shares issued during fiscal year No. of shares Issued during fiscal year No. of shares matured during No. of shares matured dn year No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of running: - rce at this date 643 No. of shares of full paid stock In force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares su latioo for nonpayment of lation for nonpayment of No. of shan 'ion for nonpayment Total amount of nquent at this date $ Total amount of t at this date $ Amount of &gt;winjr shareholders ■ Amount of owing shareholders Amount of dues on Amount of Interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid Amount of Inter. le and unpaid Amount of real estate Amount of ! i-al estate Appraised Talue of : : "al estate upon which !■ been made Appraised Talue of i "al estate upon wbJ been ma. Appraised value of Improvements -J ~ Appraised value of improvements -J Amount of n unimproved real estate Amount of I il estate None Amount of In force and assigned to the association as collateral security Amount of force and assigned to the association as collateral security No. of loan- ide for huildine purposes during the fiscal year. . No. of Ion &gt;r hulidine purposes during the fiscal y ■ar. . No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year No. of loans made for payment of homestead m luring fiscal year Amount of advance : f Joans during fiscal year. Amount of advance : I loans during fiscal year No. of bnrrowin. f borrowing st No. of non-borrowln. No. of non-borrowlii No. of minors holdii n the association No. of minors holding stock in the association. Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers daring fiscal « year Plan of premium MM Amour ! to reserve fund during fiscal year f Dan of premium R**M Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year f Amount o« i ilnrine fi- Amount of divl.! Amonnt of dividends declar.&gt;&lt;1 on full pai None Average rate per cent of dividends &lt;' Average running time of stock ma tared during fiscal year 9 yrs, 2 mths </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF TUB MAYWOOD BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. MAYWOOD, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. C. M. SPARHAWK President A. M. GROGG Vice-President N. H. BOGUE Secretary Directors. ■ VOTKND, HAMILTON, MflirHT, C. M. SPAUIIAWK, A. M. UK"- Assets. First mortgage loans $ 2,800 00 mortgage loans in process of fore loans Real estate Furniture and stationery lent interest, premiums and tim* Exposes and tav -C2 Other aaaeta ToUl Liabilities. ranitnl stork running (dues nnd dividends . $ - Fnll paid b Reserve fund • • " - ided profits . . , ■• • 447 7o Doe shareholders on incomplete loans premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums. iy o^j $ 3,069 52 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">85 UUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE W, IS Receipts. ... * k"i 714 mi a ■ and tra Total $ Expenditures I4r&gt; (K) 4-.' 07 • Maim. on band Total $9909« SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of ass .... Permanent . : . . $ les Issued sin. e organization i if serial: lization (if serial) shares ismied during fls ive withdra h ha res issued during fis ive withdra indrawn cl 17 17 at this dal ined "ii in-d on . i which il i&lt;iuent at Total a, * - - $ 2 - of lmpp&gt;' \alue of i &lt; uixin unimprui leans uixin unimpr" of unimproved real i :i nhlih loans bare f iiiiitii|ii'n\ i'il i iiihiu which luans bav Amoui in ft&gt;r&lt;-e and a the as*Kia[ion as Amoun' a ftm-e and a- .it ion a . . 3.7 r iniiiiliiiir purposes durii ir. . 3.7 tmilillne purposes during the tiscnl year. . of hom&lt; ring 1 Co: loans during fiscal year 1 comnlpted association nrged borri ir . . 7 _ m _ i r cent ol -ing al year, no loans niad. 1 completed Plan of premium, sell to highest bidder | j end* dccla « rate per cent of ■] ing flscai ' •+ •■» </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE McCOOK COOPERATIVE BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSN. McCOOK, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. THOS. B. CAMPBELL President W. S. PERRY Vice-President F. A. PENNELL Secretary L. THORGRIMSON Treasurer C. E. ELDRED Attorney Directors. THOS. B. CAMPBELL, W. B. MILLS, W. S. PEHEY, C. F. LKHN, J. J. GARRAHD, J. A. WII.i V. U. KIMMELL. C. F. LKHN, J. E. KELLEY, E. HANSON, Assets. First mortgage loans $44,300 00 First mortgage loans in process of Stork loans 2.575 00 Stock loans . ™ 2,575 00 Real estate Furniture and stationery Cash I&gt;elinquent dues 10 00 Expenses and taxes paid 139 85 Other assets 61 62 Total $48,G70 95 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $43,292 77 Full paid stock Reserve fund 1,1 87 87 Vndlvided profits 1,305 liareholders on Incomplete loaus 1,605 00 Premiums unearned '•'-'!» ••« Advance dues 350 00 .»&gt; Advance dues Auvance interest and premiums. Total $48,670 95 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Halance on hand July 1, 1902 $ 472 90 Dues (running stock) 11.7 Dues (full paid stock) Interest 12 29 inter Premium Unmhii^Mn 1 m'nW Y»ULf.tJ ' *V«!. f ". '.'.'.'.'.'.'. i -3 7 embership and transfer fees repaid ) ..J -3 79 estate sale teal estate sales Kents enta Total $23,417 79 Total $23,417 79 Expenditures. Expenditures, Loans |10 -oans |10j Salaries 410 00 Salaries 410 0 'ommlsslons ."...." ther expenses 138 84 Commissions ."...." Other expenses 158 84 Eithdrawals, dues .'. '.'. '. '.'. .'. I ithdrawals. earnings atured stock, dues 'ithdrawals, dues ) "ithdrawals. earnings o 00 Matured stock, earnings ' (ash on hand bor n* latured stock, earnings ; on hand ooo r an: i ash on hand bor m estate .. ''I"''; -al estate Tax sale certificates '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 6162 ax sale certificates 61 t T °t»l Total $23,417 79 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial "Ian of association (serial or j Serla Elan or association (serial or pei ar T " t2&lt; 'ar "■ •■&gt;, , *-&lt; N &gt; ot cm' (if serial j .' .' '. '. '. '. '. [ ' .' .' '. '. I No. of series Issued &gt; &gt;n &lt;|f' serial j .'.'! .'.'.' .".'.'.'.'.'.' 31 l.Olt No. or irpanization f shares issued during I. ...........'.'.'"."".'". -'ij* f shares matur. i:hdra»n during fiscal year. .......].....]..".'.' '. 0 No. of t shares Issued during fi- M8U t shares matured dti No. of shares withdra ( r &lt;vt No. of shai' f shares of full ite! '.."'.'.'. "...I aned on .' f lo. of shares on whlrb &lt;J i nquent f shares sn r ,t of dues . . Noi Total ani' x\"n i No. of shares of full ■f shares loant'il -&gt;o. or shares loaned on o- t . No. of shares on whirh d&gt;: •nquent luent No. of shar ,t of dues.'!! ! Non« Total atno' Total tmrnr $10 (X) Amount of dues owl: Amount of .,.', \ \ ' ' ) ' \ ] " aid. ......... •aid ...... ' loans on .!!.".! ' loans on impr h-'mA ralue of tmpr. [ c h loans I $ ~ ■ A mi m: ance in force and assigned to the association as col nrlty $77 No. of loans made for building purposes during t»ie fiscal year.. Amount of advance payments of loan vear $7.'-" No. of borrowing stockholders ....Illliril. No. of non-borrowing stockholders.... mt No. of minors holdine stock In flat Ion. .. '.'. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. ze rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal ■ar 9 Averaze rate per cent of premiums chars red borrowers during year 5 I'lan of premium .' '. '...'..'.'..'.'......*....... Ttlii Amount cr. ■&gt; fund dir ...'. $i : -re fund during fiscal year. Annul! '.' ". j_( Amount of red on nr v»ar $2 '• - Amount of diTlden&gt;N declared on f year Amount of dividends declared on ful -ical year $1 40 Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year f T </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. i STATEMENT OF TLIK CONDITION OF TIIR NEBRASKA CITY IM'ILDINC AM). LOAN ASSN. NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Offi ers. RY FASTEN AN President MIKE SELZER Vice-President W. H. PITZER Secretary H. F. MEYER Trea W. H. PITZER Attorney Directors. JOHN W. 8TEINHAKT, II I E. II. BUHLMAN, I'.ADKK, W. W. MKTZ. Assets. Assets. First mortgage loans * 31 First mortgage loans l» lrsi mongsjc luaun First mortgage loans in proems of ■ • • First mortgage loans in proo&lt;tw of loans Stmk loans Keal estate . . ture and stati"!' Real estate F'urnlture and stationery i •;•.!&gt; 2,31 ■^rin'JT.'n.-^Td.: 1 : 1 "".' 4; Other assets Total » 38 Total Liabilities, Tanltal stock running (dnes ami • * 31 Full paid stock Beaerre fund Undivided profits 'and'pronts a|. ••• '• 3&gt; g-f* m. .irnnlf't' \r.t\; Jjmt shareholder^ on in. ■•nip if IT.miums unearned I 'rfiinums unearned Advan .1 crest and premiums •••■ Total </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. FISCAL YEAR RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Receipts. Balance on hand I running st Hues (rnnn - 1 Premiums ■ rship and trai' n&gt;aid I'remiur term id Real estate sales 2V itcnis i Total $20,141 10 Total Expenditures Expenditures. ,,„,., •. $10.1 Loans : •«&gt;•! saIarl1 lit, earning M :l i II l*i Matin. • arnl Full I T, SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan 0 nenti VcT J'.'. Plan of ass. writ! or permanent I i-aTV N* r of Ion &lt;W serial I urea Issued since oir-&lt; ■ lnrins ti- • n (If seria No. of N loiai aiu.miii in mi. r ■. i ni ',*.*'' l.-.T \ m ,,, - ..ii improved real i-stiite $31.1 of improved real estate upon which leans have .- &lt;&gt;f improvements Bte. s upon unimproved re s up.m unimproved real estate of unimproved real estate upon which loans have of unimproved real estate upon which loans have M '• S SI M I I Amoui "'•' to lne association as urity ▼*■ ■*-*• i- huildinR purposes iluring the fiscal ye il to (I ion as during the fiscal year. . 1 • r payment of home: tead ii .luring • *11 * f- - - . . . Average running time ot stock matured during fiscal year 129 months </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OP THE CONDITION OK TUB NELSON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. NELSON, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. H. E. GOODRICH President HENRY FOX, JR Vice-President W. G. BRADLEY Secretary M. A. RUBLE Treasurer E. D. BROWN Attorney Directors. '■ii, j. m. Li" D. w. r.ritn, W. W. C. It. STONER, Ell K. D I. G. FOSTER, 111 UENHV FOX, Jr. Assets. First mortgage I $18,443 mortgage leans in p Stock loans Keal estate 690 00 Furniture and stationery Cash 248 57 Delinquent Interest, premiums and lint's Expenses and taxes paid . . Due on accounts 378 0!) Tax sale certificates . Delinquent dues 3°J8 Total $20,776 2» Liabilities. Capital stock runnlns (dues and divi. ... $ fl.070 Full paid s&lt; 13.VJ7 73 Reserve fund 943 00 Undivided profits 85 I&gt;ue shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums v: Advance dues Advance interest and pi Due on accounts 00 Total $J0,776 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 91 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE ENDING JUNE 3", 19 FISCAL YEAR Receipts lUilance on hand July 1, 1002 $ 204 Dues (running stock) 1.18 Interest Membership and transfer fees ... .nans repaid leal estate sales ents 1 1 ■ Hents Tax certificates .*.".'. °. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. °. .'.".'.'. °. '.". °. ax certificates F*-«.» b.Ut-WVU* •••■ • • ounts and L. 11 '" (.■counts . and L. 11 11 76 Total Totml Expenditures. Expenditures, L-o? n » •».?■; oans $1." Salaries alarles Tax sale certificates ax sale certificates Other expenses 1 nher expenses !•"•' : latured stock 2.1' Matured stock .'.'.'. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'.'...'. 2.51: Matured stock, ' interest "...'.. Matured stock. Interest paid stock, dues 2l&gt; - ull paid stock, earnings ash on hand - ccounts 200 00 Total »5,845 43 Full paid stock. Full paid stock, ear Cash on hand. .'. - Accounts Total *5.&gt; SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or pormaneut) Man of association (serial w ; Serla •ar v $1&lt;" -Ince organization (if serial) I Par v ... $1' No. of &gt;n (if serial) 12 -'-'I II No. of shares matur. : shares withdr j fiscal yt •* ' shares of run • !' full paid stock In force at t 1 No. of shu ing fiscal year No. of xhares wlthdr; z fiscal ys shares of nun t full paid No. of shares loaned on No. of shares loaned on. . ... No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares on which dues are delinquent. . . ... . , uid the a;:. munt ■unt Co. 5 Amount of loans on improved real estate Amout a on improved real esi it.. . Appra of Impn ■, -tate upon whi ■ n made ! Appraised value of Improved I upon which I P... int of Insurance in force and assigned Co th» association an collateral security $29,895 •• ... Amoui. ance in force and assigned to tht association as collateral security ■ • ■ $29,895 •• No. of loans made for building purposes ar. . 1 No. of loans made for building ar. . 1 No. of l.'iius made for payment of homestead mortgages during No. of 1 ijius made for payment of "S "I Tear Amoi: ; nts of ioans during flscal Amon its of loans during fiscal year '. ii N ■■n.- • ■mm \ ir I harged borrowers during ■ 8 1'lan of premium 1'lan of prem'ium Amount of Amount of Amount of Amount of ijje runnlog time of stock matured during iis. al \»ar. 10 ye*n </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION! STATEMENT OF Till'. CONDITION OF TUB NEWMAN GROVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY. NEWMAN GROVE, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Offi ers. A. T. RODMAN President A. B. MILLER Viee-President C. A. RANDAL... Secretary E. H. GERHART Treasurer C. A. RANDALL Attorney Directors. A. T. HODMAN, \ RANDALL, IMMOCK, A. li. MII.l K. II lilltllAHT. S M .11 KLSON. Assets. mortgage loans $12,200 on _.igi' loans in process of Real •• !■■ lire and station •■s and taxes paid Total $13.' Liabilities. Capital swrk running (dues and dividends &gt; $11 ;.l a 1.7 nplete loan ins unearned Advance interest and preiiii Total </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 (UILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts Balance on hand July 1, 19 * ' i running stock i Does (full paid stock) :.: . 1.079 ims embership and trail C|!.-|i.| J.. hi us repaid sales teal estate sales llnquents repaid Total Tl - Delinquents repaid 1*1 "''' Total $1^ ■' Expenditures Expenditures. Loans t 1 ■'■ ana $ l Salaries larles Commissions oimnlssions uses ■ ■■a ithdravvn les ....'..' Manir.-.l stock, il ; Matin Mai n- Fu II | • Full paid - Full i Full i Cash on hand in hand Delinquent Delinquent Total Total *1- SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of ass I or permanent) Plan of as- or permanent) l'ar value i [ stock I-OD l'ar value". k *-" No. of 4 4 ' &gt; I *lti to forec nl the a. Vmou: iniisiHl value of Improved real i h which loans have Amom A|&gt;praise&lt;l value of improved real estate upon which loans have 'U made been made Appraised value of improvements Appraised value of improvements Amount of insurance in force and ■ ■ the association as Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the associaii f loans made for pa Amount of advn: t loans dn Amount of adv:r f loans during fiscal year [ borrowiii. 34 6 Average rate per cent of Interest chart I year ■ ■ rate per cent of premiums char irowers during fe}■ea^ « n of premium ount credit«i to reserve fund du ount of dividends declared on m k during (iwal year ■ Average rate per cent of dividends &lt;! </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OP THE CONDITION OK TUB ELKHORN BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSN. NORFOLK, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. H. J. COLE President M. C. WALKER . . . Vice-Presldent T. C. ODIORNE Secretary G. A. LUIKART Treasurer Directors. GILBERT Dl T. C. ODIOi H. J. COLE. &gt;UT, M. C. WALKER, Assets. First mortgage loans 931,9 First mortgage loans In process of : ( Real estate Furniture and stationery Cash Delinquent Interest Expenses and taxes paid Other assets, tax certificates Insurance due Total $24. Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $13,709 48 Full paid stock 10 i Reserve fund I ndivtded profits a on Incomplete loans I'remlums unearned Advan ■ Advance interest and premiums .... Total $24,95» 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 95 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1002 ... $1" Does (running stock 1 ' »L » I lull paid stock) Interest , Premiums Flues Membership and transfer fees isr. .......... T. C Total $13,679 01 Expenditures Binaries' ".'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. '. '. '. '. . .' .' ' '.'... $ 9,1' Commissions Other expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Mam Knl I pa Full paid stock, earnings Nod* Full paid ! (ash on hand 1 Judgment account Total $13,679 01 SUPPLEMENT AL REPORT. Plan of association ( l'ar value of ea Perm serial or permanent) ■ No. 01 .f serial). . No. of shares Issued -sued 1 shares of ru No! of '.ount of sail of satn A mom: unproved 1 mint of loans on imp: value of improved npon which loans hare , been made improvements Amount of md assigned to the association as collateral sevurlty No. of loans made for building purposes • ■ No. of loans made for payment of hom&lt; m: al year Amount of advai loans dui &gt;ear $6. T No. of borrowing stockholder*. * Sfl No. of Average ra f arged borrowers during fiscal byear n of premium .Hint 1 ■!■• B r» Amount year Amount of dividends declared on fu s&lt; al year Average rat of divid**' - ... Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year 10 \' t years </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 BriLDIXG AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF Till: CONDITION OF THE (NORFOLK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. NORFOLK, NEBRASKA. NORFOLK, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. H. A. PASEWALK Pre H. A. PASEWALK President DR. ALEX BEAR Vice-Pre DR. ALEX BEAR Vice-President EB. DURLAND See . H. BUCHOLZ... Tre; APES &amp; HAZEN Att&lt; C. B. DURLAND Secretary W. H. BUCHOLZ Trea^ MAPES &amp; HAZEN Attorneys Directors. Directors. M'WAI.K, I M M v ■ DKAN, •UI&gt;. I)R J. I! WII.I.KV. ill, 1&gt; .1 K' IN, HOLZ Assets. ■ans $56 First mortease luans in pi •■■ • : — of l 4:: i . i &lt;;s T.14S 728 8 ttl Total Liabilities k rnnalai i loan ,-e fund ., l.o-i innea 6--'. 1 1 Total *08 8S </seg>
            <seg id="p097">IUIUHNG AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 97 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Ralance on hand July 1, 1002 $ Dues (running stock) st ••••••« 4. Premiums ' and transfer fees Loans repaid 4,2 • sales it Bills receivable. $4,260.63; taxes, $237.28 Advance payments ToUl Expenditures. Loans $20 2 Salaries .'. tM Ou Salaries ticMi ou Advance payments Advance payments Other expenses 314 88 Other expenses 314 88 Withdrawals, dues i , - fia ., Withdrawals, dues i , _ fi _ ., WithilmwaU urnlnix t 1,(88 4J Withdrawals, earnings ( 1 ' 1VS * z Withdrawals, earnings ...\ 1&gt;78S 4&lt;J Personal accounts Personal accounts 422 27 Bills receivable 7 6." Interest advance payments •••••• 117 36 Interest advance payment Interest advance payments 117 36 117 .SO Cash on hand r,0 s4 ince, $88; taxes. $286.46 Cash on hand 69 S4 mce, $88; taxes. $286.46 374 46 ITemlum, $201.30 ; bills payable, $900. . 1,1.. Total $34,790 13 Premium, $201.30 ; bills payable, $9O0. . . 1,1. Total $34,790 13 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Serial Plan of association (serial or permanent) Serial l'ar value of each share of stock $2i : series Issued since organization (if serial) shares In force at this date ■ ( shares issued since organization ' shares Issued during fiscal year ;;•;•• : shares matured during fiscal .enr shares withdrawn during tiv 3o&gt;&gt; Par value of each share of stock f series Issued since organization (if serial) ■ series Issued since organization (if serial) shares In force at this date ■ shares Issued since organization ■ shares issued during ti- Ml I shares matured during fiscal year it this date. . . . : shares loi shares or les are delinquent ■ shan it of dues. .. . $J. i shares sir ivment of dues.... Total amount of dues $'J&gt; Amount of 1 unpaid $-!&lt; Amount of Inten e and unpaid f ; No. of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 $i' -ure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 $i' Amount of loans on Improved real estate Amount of loans on Improved real estate Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of Improvements $71, nt of Insurance In force and assigned to the association as Appraised value of Improvements $71, int "f insurance in force and assigned to the association as ollateral security $65,300 00 $65,300 00 f loans made for payment of bom No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during llscal year $17 _ borrowin. • non-borrowing st" minors holding stock In the association 30 itead mortgages during fiscal year $17.2' f borrowing si f nonbon minors holding stock in the a iatlon 30 Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal jear . . 10 •■ rate per cent of Interest char year 10 Average rate per cent of premiums charged boi jear 1 'luring fiscal 1 B premium Cash •&gt; fund during $lf $ll&gt;' Cash Amount of year 10 V4 years </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THB MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. NORTH PLATTE, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. THOMAS C. PATTERSON President VICTOR VON GOETZ Vice-President SAMUEL GOOZEE Secretary FRANK E. BULLARD. Trea WILCOX &amp; HALLIGAN " Attorneys Directors. IRA L. BARE. AUT1 \M.\K.\. F. T. REDMOND, TIMS V, C. F. SCUAUMANN, J. F. CLA1. JAMES If. R ANN IE, VICTOU VON UOKTZ Assets. First mortgage loans $li:i First montage l.iaus in process of forei ::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: IT ure and stationery Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines 218 Expense* and taxes paid Interest paid Total *12l Liabilities. Capital Rtook running (dues and dividends t $102,748 38 Full paid - incomplete loans Premiums unearned 13.407 Advan Advance Interest i".io oo Tot *\ 1 •#••••••••• S121X42 oO </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 19 $ Dues (running stock i Interest iship and transfer I Taxes and insurance Real estate sales Uents Total $31.- Expenditures, Loans $10 Salaries Other ■ ■ s Matured stock, dti Matured it Taxes and insurance 151 49 Kpaid stock, earnings on hand Total $31 ." Sl'PIM.EMKNTAI, REPORT Dan of a».-' Serial $J ii (if serial) 5,1' 4&gt;- : shares i- •ar ! this date ■• delinquent *?' $1* Funt of |21 of m amount of same. No. 2 $1.1 amount of same, N Amount of value of improved real estate upon which loans have value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate. 4-5 paid off of unlnipi uiHin which loans have $K name In association as O Mineral «.■ $101 loans made for building purposes during the tis.al y.n ade for payment of hoci iring al year Amount of ndvam e jiayments of loai tisrml year, average $r ■ &gt;ck in the as- . ... s Krage rate per cent of Int. year nt of premiums char rs during fiscal « i borrowers during fiscal i prenii nt rreditnl rear .... 10 jra, 1 month </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. OMAHA, NEBRASKA. On the 30tli day of June, 1903. Officers. WILLIAM N. NASON President W. J. C. KEN YON Vice-President GEO. M. NATTINGER GEO. M. NATTINGEK C. W. HALLAR Attorney Directors. HARP. THE© L. RINOWALT, GEO. M. NATTIXGEtt, I 1 P. KYXI WILLIAM N. NASON, i. REYNOL1 W. J. C. KENYON, Assets. Flr«t mortgage loans ... f 0.7."O mortgage loans in process of forecli loans 2.0i Heal estate 5.1 Real estate contracts .... I tan and stationery 412 zient Interest, premiums and fin' 294 "• I Expenses and taxes paid Other assets Total $21,978 63 Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and A inqm-nt $17 lid stock Reaerre fund .led profits Doe shareholders on incomplet&lt; .... ims unearned Advance dues 17:1 01 Edvance interest and premiums. ... arnlngs distributed ... 2.434 Total $21.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAI YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1. 1!K)L' $ 463 08 4.013 05 Interest ".'!.'!!.'.'!.'.'!.'.'!.'.'!.'.'!.".'!.'.'!.'.'.' Interest Premiums Fines 62 89 Membership and transfer fees '. ud 0,7 s Membership and transfer fees repaid Ueal estate sales ■lete loans ■sure ' 3.2 1 Heal estate sa Incomplete loans 14 sure i 8,2 Sundries Total Sundries Total $20,329 03 Expenditures. Loans $ 4,104 88 (Commissions • 'mil missions Other expenses Other expenses Other expense Withdrawal!, dues 11,91 Withdrawal*, dues Withdrawals, earnings 1,631 04 dues Withdrawals, earnings 1 1 04 dues Bills payaMi". earnings Bills payable, earnings Cash on hand June 3&lt; Cash on hand June S 1 Property repairs Property repairs Increase loan IN Total ... $20,: Increase loan Total $20,329 03 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUP! PAL REPORT. Dan of association (serial or permanent) Serial Dan of association (serial or permanent 1 ) Serial I'ar value of each share of stock $200 00 Par value of each share of $2' No. of series Issued since organization (If serial) '" - ! shares in f.irce at No. of series Issued since organization (If serial) I shares in force at 117 No, of shares i&gt; [ shares withdrawn &lt;1 - - No. of shai ithdrawn d Mo. of shares of running ■ f shares loaned on n which d 1 Inqnent .xi. of shares of running i at this ds shares loaned on 'i which du rit ivment of Total amount of due- Total Amount of dut 1^ Annul- '...'. mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 1 - - - real estate. ... .... fin .•d real estate upon which loans have been made $11 ' value of improvements upon unimproved real estate Amount of in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ... $12.: No. of loans made for building purposes during the fiscal year. . No. of loans made for payment cf homestead mortgages du 1 1 year None Amount of" advance payments of loans during fiscal year None No. of bon No of minors 1 the association Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 8 a- Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium '. ** Aba: Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year $1,&amp;&gt;3 - </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OK TUB NEB. LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. OMAHA, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. THOS. A. FRY President DAVID COLE Vice-President D. H. CHRISTIE Secretary D. R. ENNIS Treasurer JOHN L. KENNEDY Attorney Directors. D R. ENXIS. JOHN H BRANDT. : ITRNET, II. ' UII.COX, Til' THOS. A. FRY, HAVII) COLE Assets. First mortgage loans $ 73.no? 50 First mortgage loans In process of I None loans Nmie loans Heal estate 7. .",44 Furniture and stationery v None Cash ' 2,£ Delinquent mis anil lines 2,424 N Other assets, bills receive ate 4,441 Total 104,000 63 Liabilities, Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $83.02."? 37 Fuil paid stock None Reserve fund 710 47 ided profits 02 84 None ided profits F share holders on incomplete loans, raid on li.unn etc 9,811 50 Premiums unearned None Advance dues 45^ 4.". Advance Interest and premiums. T&lt;tfal $94,000 63 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand Julj 1, 1902 $ 3,05« •* Dues (runn k) Interest. Stockholders $21 1- Membership and trat. . y accounts ... Ad\ ance payments ■ - ■ • Total $45, '■ Expenditures, I^oans $27,348 29 Salaries rent, incidentals ■ Withdrawals V 10,260 14 Maun ues I 8 ?'.!'.!! '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'.'.'.'. None Advances and taxes paid $45,997 73 Total SUPPLEMEN- TAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Serial lar va 71 I ir at this date 11 Amour ■■[ *1- T nt of loan- *i.l 11 Amour ■■[ *1- 7 nt of loan- • '•&gt;•■ ■ ised value of Impn !,.,&gt;n ma,le . $ 1 3. ' ' $73,!'' . i mi r»OD« non« N . m which loans have I »••♦•!! • ised value of ui » which loans bare Amount of Insurant in forte and assigned to the association u Amount of association as JiJ.SMJO w $73,900 00 t collateral of loans made for building pu ear. . No. of loai: &gt;r building purposes during the nwal year. . * 4 No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgage* during 11 tfisi al year .., . „ '* ount of ( loans di "* ., ' „# K^, ....... •'' Amount of I loans during B No. of bon 1-J7 * - o Fcent of in wers during »« al year 1 car Plan of premium \ in. .ii ii r credited to reserTe fund dun Amount of losses charged i Enrage ta ; ..f diviti. nil months ers|e running time of stock matured during fiscal year 130 raonins </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TIIB OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. OMAHA, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. GEO. W. LOOMIS President ELMER E. BRYSON Vice-President GEO. M. NATTINGER Secretary LEWIS S. REED Treasurer FRANK H. GAINES Attorney Directors. rpWARP A PARMELEE, CEO. W. LOOMIS W. 8. WRIGHT. H. J. TENFOLD, JiillN II Bl ELMER E. BRYSON THOS. J. FITZMORRIS, W. GEO. M. NATT1NUER. Asset*. First mortgage loans $503,700 "S First mortgage loans In process of Stock loans Rral estate '.'....'. 11,221 10 F jrniture and stationery Caah Delinquent Interest, premiums and lines 2,303 Expenses and taxes paid. otheT assets 1,34 Foreclosures ToUl $043,698 00 Liabilities. Capital stock rnnnlng (dues and cliviil.-nds i $619,107 2« Full paid stock • ■ • Rmwrve fund Reserve fund Undivided profits f.£ Due shareholders on incomplete loans 14,790 11 ITcmlums unearned Advance dues Advance Interest and premiums Total $64 j,698 06 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. FISCAL YEAR Receipts, Balance on band July 1, 1902 $ 2." Docs (running stuck) Doe* (loan stock) Interest Premiums Fines Loans repaid Keal estate sales .. Msures 318 53 Sundry collections 14..; 1 Total $417 Expenditures Loans Salaries , Other expenses Withdrawals, dues Real estate improvements Furniture Foreclosures Sundry collections Cash on hand ".; ".«!» 4.s Total $417 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Permanent I"ar value of each share of stock C series issued since n (if Sim shares in force at Bof sha of »hu .ir f shares of rum No. of shares of full No. (if shares loaned on 3 79t&gt;\ at of interest, premiums and fines due and ou| I Of mi&gt;: -.79 91 of mortKEV' amuunc of 7 Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of i &gt;tate upon which loans i Appraised value of Improvements it of loans upon il estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which lo been made $13. : Amount of Insurance In force and assigned to the asso' collateral security $7S6,890 00 loans made for building pnrposes during thi ir. . 5H loans made for payment of homestead mo: fiscal year 2iM) No. of borrowing stockholders f non bon ( minors b n 7 Average rate I" est cban." fiscal year e Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal _ ye» r ■••-, 2 4 Plan of premium v payment 2 4 runt credited to reserve fund during fiscal year, - to reserve Amount of If during i iT 14 Amount of dividends declared on fi: Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 BUILDING AND WAX ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB OCCIDENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. OMAHA, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. W. J. BROATCH President JNO. F. FLACK President GEO. F. GILMORK Secretary J. A. SUNDERLAND. Treasurer GEO. F. GILMORE Attorney Directors, GEO. F. GILMORE, J. A. St'NDERLAND, W. J. BRO \ P. FLACK, A. 1'. IT KEY Assets. First mortgage loans $S»S.272 •"&gt; _-age loans in process of 1 1.LM.1 Real estate 1.011 4» estate and stationery CaRh delinquent interest, premiums and Him Expenses and tax Real estate sales on 1,11 Total $43- Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and divi. $27 aid stock. 14" Reaerre fund 12. )"4 ded profits ... 4,;il Due share! Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance Interest and premiums. Total $-132,029 76 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">BUILIUNG AND LO • IATIONS. 107 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISC AT YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, II Receipts. Receipts, Balance on hand July 1, 1902 t 1 Balance on hand July 1, 1902 $ T.3R1 45 Dues (run Dues (full I Dues (full I . . ims Loan fees Loan fees Membership and transfer i i.l ■ and transfer i Keal estate sales ea Certificate of deposit a. ck. to C. S. and I. Total Certificate of deposit ck. to C. S. and I. Total Expenditures. Expenditures. t Louis Louis Salaries Salaries Commissions 1 4 30 Commissions 1 4 30 Other expenses Other expenses Withdrawals, dues :rawals. dues Interest on withdraw I Interest on withdraw I Real estate 1.1: unt ii hand S. and L Real estate , 1.1: unt S. and L Certificate of deposit Total Total ■ • • SUPPLEMENT I'PLEMENTAL REPORT. AL RKPORT Plan of association (serial or perma: ilut 1 of ea&lt;-h share &lt;&gt;f stork $ Plan of association (serial or perma: ilut 1 of each share &lt;&gt;f stork $ ! ea issued during fiscal year ■ ■ at this da .... $ 7 .... $ 7 ■■ ■■ L'age* sill. _a«rs In proces' amount of sai line of n-al .-state value of unimproved real ... • mattes in pfoett •&lt;ed value of real .-state • ■f unimpi ... d assigned to the a id assigned to the a 'scs ilurii 90 ses during the ir. . 90 No. of chase of year 1 «'ad mortcage^ Average ra - ■ of premiums charged b Average rat Amount of dlvic! n full pai ■ ' Average rate per cent of dividends declared 10 pei "inning et n paid up stock Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year oiontha </seg>
            <seg id="p108">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THB SEKYATIYi: SAVINGS AND LOAN \ OMAHA, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. A. r. TUKEY. LHAS. C. GEORGE. J. A. SUNDERLANI) GEO. F. GILMORE. GEO. P. GILMORE. GEO. F. GILMORE. Directors. Assets. rirst mortgage loans. i«e leans In process of I Stock lcianit Kcai estate ■teal estate sold on contract iwnnquent interest FinMiMu ami t.ir.. u f.xp*n»«i and taxed paid . inner assets, warrants, pent-ral fund . . L'ertlflcatea u( deposit In national banks rota! _«nnal stock running (dues and dividends) r. PM* rmU . • t ? ck S2S2L5"^L-:: naivldro i)mnts jim Bliareholders on 18j) nnearuiHl lavance dues ""»' $!■ I .IN' Liabilities. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. :iPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE Y EAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1 f (running stuck I full paid stock Warrants Certificates of de -t on warrants and certi' -;t on warr l'rofit and loss l'p'iit and loss Total . lotai * i Expenditures Loans ns expenses. Irawals, dm Irawals, Int Loans Salaries . Salarl Commissions other expenses, rent* i ■ awals, dues . Irawals, In Warrants Warrants Kiill paid ■n ham and certificates of c! • Foreclosure Total SUPPLEMENT AL REPORT Plan of aiw rial or permanent) x lau ui «!»-■* "i K 1 '" 1 " l»ar v;i k ♦ shara Usiied 1 1 this' da't i shar at this date $ - \ e, and the No. oi "ss of foreolnsure, and Amour Appriv upon »li Amnunt of loans upon unimproved r«-: Appraised value of unimproved real • i which loans been made nance In force and assitmed to the ass. K collateral necnrltr . of loans m rirages and of homesteads during fiscal year $ 7 ..•ar Amount of Average rate per cent of divide d during fiscal year. ... 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF TI1K CONDITION OK TUB BANKERS BUILDING AND IX) AX ASSN. OMAHA, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1Q03. Officers. GEORGE P. CRONK President H. VANCE LANE President M. F. FUNKHOl'SEK Secretary L. H. KORTY Treasurer THOMAS D. CRANK . Attorne/ Directors. P cuciNK. KORTY. CKINUHAXL W. D. LINCOLN, H VANCE I.ANK. THOMAS U M. V. FUMKHOI Assets. mortgage loans $ 23 . i_ First mortirasP loanR in pi •■• 4,7- (110 "&gt;i Mid stationery .iient Intot- '•••^ ( &gt; •'•'*» and taxes paid. . -71 08 assets .. Total * Liabilities Capital stock running. (Dl Full paid stock nd -. 2.7 = :,led profits •• ■ T.1H Doe sharp); ■•:!'- ins unearned 10 AdTH' Due Individuals ... 27R 10 Total .... s -- ! </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 BULKING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL V EAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, II ♦ 13.4 - $ irt. s Balance on hand July 1, 1 Due* ( running stock j Dues (full paid stock) ' mS . .' .' .' .' ." ." .' .' .' .' .' .' .' .' ." . .' . .' .' .' .' .' ." .' .' . . . 1.058 20 &gt; and trn n Loans rep;! 28,7 :&gt;er payhu 40 63 ate Advance pay men I'ersonal auconn Advance pa Personal a 14 11 i al ♦ 56,0t; Expenditures. I 56.OCO 13 Total Expenditures Ix,an» $ '• $ Salaries Other expenses 4' expen Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, dues . . .rnlng Withdrawals, earnings Mat iir. }0 g28 3a Matur..! Maim lrnlngs. . . ■ • n hand Matui ■ -arnin. n hand Seal estate al Utal estat * 8UPPLJ RT. Plan of association &lt;■■ Par v ♦ 1 i»n &amp;, ( i ( «- shares ls&gt; res matun &lt; res matur&gt; shares wit I shares withdrawn rea of rum &gt;••" is date ;(s.'i i&gt;" No. of shares Ion i M leu No of shar :iyment of b, No. of sliar r non-payment if - Total amount ol nquent at images In am am loans on Improved real est.i't&gt; of Improved r loans on Improved real estate of iniprm Appraised value of Improvemi'i loans upon unh 'ate value of unimproved real estate npon which loans have been made Et loans upon unii: il estate value of unimproved real estate npon which loans have made inrlon as . • n as ( loans dr. arged bor: Plan of premium ar haw imte •-. • ' of dividends declar..,! during fiscal y^ar. ... Average running time of stock matured during Ill months 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 BUIUUNC AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF Till: CONDITION OF THE PAWNEE CITY SAVINGS AND HUILDIXd ASSN. PAWNEE CITY, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. J. W. BULLARD President W. M. HILLER.. Vice-President R. W. STORY Secretary E. S. McMASTER Treasurer Directors. J W. BULLARD, FULLER, •BY, E. S. ii J. N. R. W. STORY. Assets. mortgage loans $ 9,360 00 .... ■ Keal estate Furniture and stationery None Ca.h quent interest, premiums nnit se* and taxes paid, chars"! &lt;&gt;ff None assets. Insurance premiums paid Total $ 9,532 68 Liabilities Capital stork run nine. (Dues and dividends &gt; Do Reserve fund 143 on .... 80 .... Premiums unearned Advai Advance interest and premium 1 Interest earned on advance payinen Total $ &lt;j </seg>
            <seg id="p113">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 113 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1901 $ 4 Dnes (running stock) 2.f&gt;ss i«&gt; Interest 817 73 Fines Balance on hand Jut; 1, 1901 Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid 900 00 Keal estate sales Bents Insurance premiums repaid 3 90 Total f 4,946 88 Expenditure*. Loan $ 1,500 00 Salaries Commissions 10 Co Other expenses 17 (X» Withdrawals, dues ... 156 0» Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings 671 Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings &lt; ash on hand Interest paid on advancements and matin ... insurance premiums paid 7 60 Total $ 4,946 88 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Pen- Par value of each share of stock $ No. of series Issued since organization (if serial) xso. of shares In force at this date No. of shares Issued since organization Mi No. of shares Issued during fiscal year No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year No. of shares of running stock In force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date ■ No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares s&gt;: atlon for nonpayment of dues. ... Total amount of dues delinquent at this date $ 62 4u Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders Amount of ins and lines due and unpaid No. of mortgage- o foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of sam Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of Improved real estate upon which loans have i been made 16.400 00 Appraised value of Improvements J Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Amount of Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security No. of loans made for building purposes during the fiscal year. . 1 1 • loans made for payment ot homestead mortgages during fiscal year 4 Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year $ r, No. of non-borrowing stockholders jg No. of minors holding stock In the association |sm Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year !. Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during flsi'al year | 40 on Amount of losses chareed to reserve fund during fiscal year. . Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year (now In force) 538 is Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year. ... U Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year .'..' 102 months S </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THB PLATTSMOUTH LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers, W. J. WHITE President W. SMITH Vice-President T. M. PATTERSON Secretary R. B. WINDHAM.. Treasurer R. B. WINDHAM . Attorney Directors. W. J. WHITE, R. R. WINDHAM. J. B. TSAUWICK. I1TII, D. HAWKSWOUTH \YM. I m:\ViiUT1I, J. B. KOUlTKli. 1'ATTElt: Assets. mortgage loans * 28 :&gt;■ -a^e loans in process ot I iO loans 1.9! Real estate 3.1 Furniture and stationery None (&lt;nh 9,994 Delinquent remiums aud lines. . sea and taxes paid 7,3 assets 1 P 028 Total $ 53,826 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $ 38,305 00 Full paid stock None Keserve fund ■-Sf°22 Undivided profits 15,521 33 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans None Premiums unearned None Advance duea None None Advance Interest and premiums None Total .... * 53,826 83 </seg>
            <seg id="p115">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 115 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, IS $ 1,067 70 Does (running stock)..'.. 11,1 Does (full paid stock) Interest .." Does (full paid stock) Premiums Ftnea 57 !»1 Membership and transfer 81 00 Loans repaid 6.3U7 1 1 Heal e«tate sales Warrants Total * 25,210 Expenditures. Loans I Salaries &lt; 93 4"i 4,1' I Matui . .... , None Mai 'ir.'l stock, earnings ■ i nd Warrants Total $ - SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) l"ar value of each share of stuck $ ■ of series issued since organization (If serial) of shares in force at !*M No. of shares in force at il f shares Is- 8.1*4 1 1 shares issued ■ shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year running stock In force at this date... ' full paid stock in force at this d;i No. of shares loaned on ■ shares or ivment of dues. . . . $ 1" Total a at this date Amount of Amoui No. of mortgages sub Insure, and the aggregate am ■ of same. No. 3 !.:!'■ a in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same, No. ] amount of same. - on improved real estate Hue of improved real estate upon which loans have lade — 14.400 00 Appraised value of Improvements Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association as • nrlty 39,700 0O No. of loans made for building purposes during the fiscal year. . as made f 1 mortgages during Amount of adv:i f loans during fiscal year $ 7,;; 133 i the association.. ,; Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers durin. year 8 year • • • ■ 8 Plan of premium None Amount credited to real estate account during fiscal year $ 400 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF TIIK CONDITION OF TUE LIVINGSTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. C. A. MARSHALL Vice-President RY R. GERING Secretary FRED W. EBINGER Treasurer THOMAS WALLING Attorney Directors. D. B. SMITH. HENRY IIKROLD. \V.\I. A. WHITE, wm. noLi.Y. MM HAS C. A. MARSHALL. FRED W. EBINGER, A. II. WECKBACH, IIE.NUV R. UERINO. Assets. First mortgage loans .... $40,721 74 First mortgage loans In process of .... 2,1 Heal estate None Furniture and stationery 1,173 71 IMInquent Interest, premie nd dues 818 30 Insurance and taxes paid and advan 1.1 ■ \i estate contracts Be— ire fund 674 80 Tottl $55 L Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends i $43,920 O&lt;) Foil paid stock None Bye fund 674 N't rlded profits 11,: shareholders on incomplete loans None iums unearned None nee dues Advance Interest and premiums Tot»l $05,982 4U </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNK 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1902 Balance on hand July 1, 1902 9 ' Dues (running stock) 01 00 14.UO1 oo I lues (full paid stock Interest 1'remiuiss and transfer fees 10-1 -5 a ltenu Total *J3.08S S3 Expenditures. Loans *i:s - Salaries 157 WJ ( • iiuuiissinus Other expenses 157 40 other expens. i awals, dues i awals, earnings -1 01 •i stock, dues Matured stock, earnings. . Full paid si' Full paid stock. &lt;l u ■■- -t on bills payable . 21 37 .uid 1.1T3 71 Insurance and taxes paid 49 00 Real estate contracts 817 90 Total $-'3. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT 1'Ian of association (serial or permaaent) l"ar value of each share of stock ... $-' No. of series Issued since organization (if serial). .... Mj« • -•■•• • —^^ m shares in (Si; . • pf iuipp' upon which loans liave Appraised value of Imprm Amount of l"«ns upon uni' il estate Amount of and assigned to the a-*- Mater., |S9,l No. of loan pur|*mes il year. . 3 Firing Amount of "advn : ioans daring flscal year '.:• i the association 3 Ecent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fun Amount of loss. :\r Amount of seal year Amount of dividends declared on fn vear Average rate per cent of dividends declared during flscal year.... Average running time of stock matured during Sscal year m ountiu </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE SCHUYLER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. SCHUYLER, NEBRASKA, On the 30th day of June, 1903. a the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. Officers. MARTIN L. WEAVER President t : J. A. PENCE Vice-President Vice-' 1 FRANK E. MOORE Secretary JOHN J. GARTH Treasurer C. J. PHELPS Attorney Directors. Directors. 8. N. WHITE, V. MALV, E. II. I'UKLI'S, J. 8. JOB ARTIIUlt VAN IK i' Assets. First mortgage loans $ '24 First mortgage loans In pi loans Keal estate 4,7- Furniture and stationery fash Delinquent interest, premiums and fines Ot Expenses and taxes paid. other assets Tax sale certificates 304 K Total *;SJ Liabilities. Capital stock running (does and dividends i $31,509 7'J Full paid stock . f fund 582 84 I "ndlTlded profits 43 04 Due shareholders on incomplete loan Premiums unearned Advance dues 102 44 Advance Interest and premiums Suspense 13 iM Total </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Halance on hand July 1, 1902 I 1,678 50 Dues ( running stock) 6,»5«4 19 Halance on hand July 1, 1902 Suspense Interest Kreclosures 1,1 - ies 7. - -snip and transfer fws .id 8."' Real estate sales Kents Tax sale certificates 307 57 Total *UJ,306 »T Expenditure*. Loans $ 4.600 00 Salaries Tax sale certificates expen Withdrawals, dues 10.7 Withdrawals, earnings 3,7 Foreclosures (ash on hand l..t: •state Suspense Total W-- Total *2:&gt;.303 97 BUPPLBMKNTAL REPORT. SUP TAL RE F ORT. l'ian of association ( ■ Seria Man of associat !?'-: ,-V. •*" $-■ No. of series Issued since organ OB (if serial i shares in force at f snares issued' slSc. .'.'. '. '.'.'.'. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. shares issue.! since orgn ■: shares i- ar : shar ■■■■ iisi-al y •ar ■ar No. 01 at this date ■ in Eo. of u this date •n at tbi il a t»- nquent .... nt .... 1 *1 - T..tal am Amount uf Amount of No of mortnai.'' - il the aj_. of same 13.300 00 Pill of san $3.3 No. of mortgages in amount of « to. of mortal.-.- in ire, and : amount of »:. mount of I. .an. \nimn $-4 \ppral»ed value upon wli have been m upon whii fill Appraised value of Improvements Appraised value of improvements Amount of insurance In force and assigned to the association as collates *24.1O0 00 $0. of loans made fur building purposes durii al year. . Jo. of loans made for payment of homestead murt^aKes during al year Amoui in force and as: No. of loans made for building purpo: ;n I to the icn as $24,100 00 during the fiscal year. . stead mortgages during 5 No. of loans ma&lt;le for payment of home fiscal year f loans during flsial year $102 4 $102 44 loans during I: $10 :t:t 4 ... S Avera. r cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal ir 9 ilan of premium ilan or premium Amount credited to reserve fund dui ••• $122 09 Amount of divi.l -&lt;-al I*" $2,211 61 Average rn it of dividends -cal year mi-annual) 3% Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year ;.j Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OP THE CONDITION OF THE SEWARD EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. SEWARD, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. JOHN ZIMMERER President GEO. F. DICKMAN Vice-President H. A. GRAFF Secretary W. E. LANGWORTHY Treasurer J. J. THOMAS Attorney Directors. J. F. GEESEN, JOHN AMSLER, C. K. HUMPHREY, N. H. FRANKLIN, G. II TERWII.LIGER, IIAB8H. F. W. GOEHNER, Assets. First mortgage loans $41 .." First mortgage loans In process of ■ iure Stock loans Real estate Furniture and stationery Cash Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines and din-.- ($140.75) Expenses and taxes paid . . Other assets. Tax sale certificate Insurance account 21 Total $45,704 M Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $42.^ Full paid stock Reserve fund icied profits MO Due shareholders on Incompleti Premiums unearned Advance dues 51 o "."&gt; Advance interest and premiums 4."&gt; 44 Outstanding warrants 1,491 10 Total M.-..704 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Receipts. Balance on band July 1,1 I ■ running stock) Balance on band July 1, 190; Balance on band July 1,1 I i running stock) ftSSSi.':::::::*.:::::::: 4l Interest Sum,-:::::::::::::::: 41 Ill 45 Fines Ill 45 111 45 Membership and transfer fees ' Membership and transfer feeg " Loans repaid I-&lt;&gt;ans repaid Tax sale certificate r l '■'•» 11 Tax sale certificate redeemed Insurance repaid Tax sale certificate r&gt; Insurance repaid Total 13 80 Total $3^ - Expenditures. Expenditures. Loans ... Loans Salaries expenses Salaries Other expenses 5-! t 55 rawa ! !i dnes . Withdrawals, dues . . V&gt; ithdrawals. earnings Cash on hand Tax sale certificates V&gt; Ithdrawals. earnings Cash on hand Tax sale certificates Insurance : . 34 8o Insurance : . 34 85 Total • •■ W-- SUPPLEMENTAL REPOi Total *32,2 SUPPLEMENT AL RK Plan of association (serial or permanent) Serial I*!an of association (serial or permanent* |2tX No. 01 $:&gt; No. of No of sliar.-s In force at ■ luring fiscal year No! of shares in No! of ■■ar ■ VI Bll« \JUt III.. »I- ............. of shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares matun ( shares withdrawn a] year. . r running stuck in force at thi- No. of shares withdrawn i :ir f running stuck iu force at thil ■ .: io, and tl nut o f gani . $1. ♦ uproved : fll of improved real estate upon which 1&gt;&gt;; on Improyed i f-u.JoU w of Improved real estate upon which loans li &gt; $i.i.4...i 00 uni'mToTedrVaVestaie: ". ! ! '. ! ! '. ! ! ! ! ! '. ! '. '. '. '. *^00 00 &gt; $i.i.4...i 00 .'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. . 1-00 00 &gt;f uiiimp i which loans have real estate upon which loans have $ oOO 00 $ oOO 00 in force and assljjned to the assoclat ance in force and assljirned to the ass.' v arlty uiiij is made for building purposes dnrii « is made for building purposes during the fiscal j« • ns made for payment of tilling us made for payment of ing . .ar advance payments of loans during fiscal year (on June a I year advance pavments of loans during fiscal year (on Jun« ;p ■' , I' 1 ! .;;......... Klation ■n 7 :ed borrowers during • f premiums char ................. I'luii rum tind ilurit Annn r.. Average running oscal year 3 years, 9 mouths </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TIIH SIDNEY LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. SIDNEY, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. A. GRANNEMAN President M. RADCLIFF Vice-President CHAS. CALLAHAN Secretary A. PEASE Treasurer Directors. C. M. WRIGHT. C. P. CHAMBERS, F. 15. TOHIN*. L. JESSEN. M. J. SANDERS, Assets. .... | n.rv id stationery Cash Expenses and taxes paid . . 80 Otner assets Total $10,330 Liabilities. Capital ntork running (dues and divi ... $ 7,490 Full paid II .... Reserve fund 02 11 Vndivtded profits 316 ■'&lt;* Advai and pren: Cancelled stock MM ToUI $10,336 IS </seg>
            <seg id="p123">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 123 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1902 4 01 94 Dnea ( running stock ) Dnea (full paid stock) Interest I'remlums Fines 6 ri«&gt; Membership and transfer I Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid 100 OO 100 OO Heal estate salea Total $2.:. Loans Salaries Commission* other expenses 61 20 ; awals, daes 45 50 Withdrawals, earning Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earning Full paid stock. Full paid stock, earnings. Cash on hand GOO CO Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of ass. or perman nanent Par vi $2( ■ • • shares issued since orga ' shares IssiumI during li- No. of shares m year ■' shares u tiscal year shares wli g fiscal year f shares of Total amount of dues d ....... nt of lotas roal estate *!' uile upon wlii.ii loan* ! b.-en ma. I.. value of i Amount of Insurance In force and assigned to the association aa collateral security No. of loans made for building 1 No. of loans made for building .... $H&gt; Average rai ;&gt;rged bur AYern. nrged :ir c cent of premiums charged Ayern- arged year 6 Average rate per cent of premiums charged ;ir borrower* durin. n loan $37 51 Plan of premium Plan of premium n loan Amount cr. *prve fund dui Amiiiiiit cr. -ifrve fund dur i &lt;&gt;d on ru ' 11 ■ ar u Average rate per cent 6^. Expenditures. $1,535 00 ■ i md </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF Till: CONDITION OF TUB SOUTH OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. SOUTH OMAHA, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. W. P. ADKINS President P. MITCHELL Vice-President JAS. J. FITZGERALD Secretary H. C. MILLER Treasurer A. H. MURDOCK Attorney Directors. F M SMITH. It. C. WALKER, K. L. now O'HERN, MITCHELL, J. II \V. P. AUKINS. Assets. mortgage loans $ 05,133 11 : f 3.i sold on contract 5oU "1 -i and taxes paid. Total |U)1,»15 12 Liabilities. Capital stock running and dividends en Full paid stock '' i vp fund ve fund *.«' I v,iliil nrolits . *** "*&gt; iled profits Ime shareholders on incomplete loans. Premiums unearned Advance dues Auvmite uun ...... Advance interest and premiums Bo av Total $101 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 MILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. BalaDce on hand July 1. 1902 | (.'. itockl hill iiaid - Premiums repaid Real estate sold on contra Real "estate Total $.17 Expenditures Loans Salaries Other expenses Withdrawals, dues 13,' 1 Withdrawals, turnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings Undivided profits ... Reserve fund Cash on band Interest Money borrowed Total $J7. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) Par value $-' No. of series is- &gt;n (if serial). No. of ... No. of shares lamed since organization .... No. of shares issued during fiscal year No. of shares matured during No. of shares withdrawn during flsca No. of shares of running - ... No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this dati No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues ar&lt;&gt; t ' of dm ng by borrowing shn ild No. of ind the a amount of same. No. 1 '0 00 Amoun on improved real estn i ■ $&lt;l I - Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have of Improvements $13'J - upon unimproved real estate $3" value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have Neon made $^"0 00 Amount of insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security $lir, No. of loans made for building purposes during the 11 loans made fur payment of homestead mortgages du ir 18 Amount of "advance payments of loans during fiscal j $2.-' No. of non-bom &lt; kholders No. of minors holding stock in the association... 5 Average rate per cent of interest charge d borrowers durliu year 6 year Average rate ppr cent of premiums chargi ■d borrowers durln; year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year $14 Amount of losses chareed to reserve funri ir $73 00 .\mouut UL losses i ii;t!_' 'i lu reserve lliuu uiiriUK lis&lt;»l *i*Br. ..... j&gt; i . i mi Amount of dividends declared on mi . $.Y ~ Average rate p«r cent of dividends d Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year." -127 months </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 B L HjDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS* STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB CITIZENS BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. SUPERIOR, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. W. S. YOUNG President W. P. LONG Vice-President F. H. STUBBS Secretary W. A. MYERS Treasurer F. H. STUBBS Attorney Directors. ■ SOUTHARD, MARSHALL, 3. H. KE8TERSON W. J. ELLIOTT. W. A. VANTKA1N. Assets First mortgage loans $21,100 00 Kirst mortgage loans In process of f Stock loans ................. 450 OO Real estate 304 61 Kurnlture and stationery Cash lf42 Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines. ■■es and taxes paid 47 91 Total $23 Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends.) Dues, $17,423.48; dividends. $ $-&gt;0 .V&gt;fl 01 Full paid stock ] noo 00 Reserve fund 1,103 80 ided profits Imp shareholders on Incomplete loans. Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance Interest and premiums. Total $23,331 81 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 127 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1002 $ 1 Doc* (running stock) Does (full paid stock) Interest Premiui Membership and tra Real estate sale -&gt;?s repaid 4 75 ToUi $10,127 73 Expenditures Loans $ 3,970 00 I'umni 873 Other Withdraws' 2.7; ::::::::::::: Mat.,,. Mam ,arnit Full paid stock. '. '. '. '. '. .... 1.0' ull paid stock, earnings Cash on hand..' T. ! .' '. '. '. '. '. . '. '. . !••»- ash on hand Total ••• *1O. ! . Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permaneut) P« r ' Ian of association (serial or permaneut) P" 1 ' if serial) •ar va • 1 "' o. of series issued since f serial) o. or force at o. of shares issued since organlxa' shares ni. No. of No. of shares issued since organlzat Kui Minica lOBucii of shares Issued shares ni.i V"V KUl MIULVS IUBIUI of "shares withdrawn &lt;o. of "shares wi o . ol ice at this date i&gt;i " o. of at this date l^u. UL BUIiea n 1 1 utii a«ii' Xo. o! rce at this date No. of share* of full f shares 1, io. of Bhares loi o of shares mi »l. mini i ■ • • mount of , mount of loans on 121.1 i^U. UL CUB1O) H'ftll'-'l Vil - No. of • TotaV A mou i. Amount of ,.,, $21.11 Punt of loans on ,-•■ 121.1 raised value of i: ' whiih loans have been made ppraised value of i: !iaTe been made been made ppraised value of i mom ■ &lt;t unimproved real a which l.vans hare been nurtf ....• o n t* made tount of Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security ■ ■ • • ount of adv;i nts of loans during fiscal year ♦-,SW» W mount of Insurance In force and assigned to the association as collateral security ■ • mount of advic "ts of loans during fiscal year i—aOU 00 o. of borrowlii- f non-borrowing (tockbol'l ■•■; E. of nonbor . of minors In the association o. of minors 1 -iatlon •&gt; • Ferage rate per cent of Interest cl ers daring fiscal year • ••■ •,11«-Vi yeratre rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers daring fiscal Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal verage rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year 10 in Ian of premium, unit irm. 10 per cent mount en -^al year. AmounUf •" mount of dividends declared on full t&gt;a »1 ' AU1UUUI VI ' _ Amount of dividends declared on full pai iscal year ?1&gt; Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year. ... a </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OP THE CONDITION OF TUB TKENTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. TRENTON, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. O. E. REYNOLDS President SINCLAIR HILL Vice-Preaident W. S. COLLETT Secretary A. E. REYNOLDS Treasurer Directors. OS, CHAS. SEELKY, O. II DE WAT.n, A. 'U .1. I. 1 ILL, :&gt;S, C. K. TOWERS, Assets. Assets. First mortgage loans 113.123 20 •iinrtjrapo loans First : . ... 1,17 ... Keal estate ... 42 17 Heal estate Furniture and stationery Cash l.Sfl Furniture and stationery Cash Delinquent Interest, dues and tines &gt;&lt;es and taxes paid I&gt;ellnquent Interest, dues and fines am and taxes paid. . 1.1 Other assets Personal accounts 39 3:5 other assets l'ersonal « l'ersonal accounts Total Total $20,544 43 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends i $ 4.21 4 M Full paid stock T. 1 Reserve fund i.led profits 122 65 &lt; on Incomplete loans Premiums 2,949 62 Premiums Advance dues Advance interest and premiums .... Interest 5.563 «« Fines, transfer! and membership fees ... 557 20 Total $20,544 43 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 i:ni.MN&lt;; and loan associai i RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 10OJ $ Dues (running stock | . .' 1.1 1 &lt; full paid Interest Premiums 4 Ml Membership and trail Ueal . a Itents 117 (N) Total »2,S Expenditures, $ » Salaries »—. Withdraw* Maun ii-iiiik; Full paid stock. &lt;lui Cash on hand Total 12 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Dan of association (serial or permanentt l'ar va $1" &gt;n (If serial i .... e. of fnll paid stock in force at this da&lt; 8 ■it of dues. .. . I and the aggregate fl.1 Ann"!! improved real • V«d real esi i ■ $13 . i-d real estate upon which loans hSTe 1 .. AAA M •as have Appraised value of i Amour Amount ol and assigned to the association as |1»,77 Jilt ' ■ building pjrpmww during tli. \r. . ■urns made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year "• » wing .t... . No. of MM Average ra: owers during flwal year . . .......... Average rate per cant of premiums charged borrowers during Ms, al year I'lan of premium ' ''■ Amount credited to reserve fund during fsral year Amount of loHHeg eha nt of dividends declared on runnlnt: vt *ar Amount of dividends declared on full pai year Averago rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during Osca! ... None » </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THB VALENTINE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. VALENTINE, NEBRASKA. On the 1st day of July, 1903. Officers. JOS. H. YEAST President C. S. REECE Vice-President W. E. HALEY Secretary C. H. CORNELL Treasurer Directors. H. F. MILLER, W. B. HALEY, C. 8. I; L. II. SMITH, B." II. WATSON, C. II. CORNELL, 1. T. KEELICY. W. F. A. MELTENDORFF, JAS. H. YEAST, Assets. First mortgage loans $26,000 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Nor Stock loans 180 Real estate Furniture and stationery Cash 1,387 (14 Delinquent Interest, premiums and fines 167 1- Expenses and taxes paid Other assets Total 129,190 K Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $31,154 12 Full paid stock None Reserve fund 525 00 Undivided profits 16 37 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans None None Premiums unearned 1,493 44 Advance dues None Advance interest and premiums None Fines. Interest and membership fee 2,0~ Matured stock ■ i ti 65 Total $29,190 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipt*. I ice on hand July 1, 1902 $1,487 57 (running stock) 3,268 00 4r. paU1^ k !:::: ::::::::::::::::::::: i.w°K 51 St.". Membership and transfer fees IS 00 Loans repaid 2,183 35 Real estate sales None IS 00 Iteal estate sal Rents None Delinquent interest and fines' '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. . . '. '. '. '. . '. . . . '.'.'..'.... 448 45 Total $9 • I Expenditures, Loans $2,633 35 Salaries 1 1 280 00 &lt; 'ommisslons • None Other expenses' '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '.'.'.'..'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. JJ 00 Withdrawals, dues ". '.'.'.'.'. '.'.'.. '.'. '.'.'.'.'. '. '.'.'..'. '. 3;&gt;« OO Kdrawals. earnings „ 24 86 red stock, dues 3,916 65 o.; Matured stock, dues 313 30 Matured stock, earnings « 515 59 Cash on hand ... 1&gt;3 5I „ Premium, withdrawals . . 170 00 Premium, withdrawals Total $».122 »0 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. Plan of association (serial or permanent) .o S&lt; &gt; r ' a ! $200 00 rvalue of .. n .h share ol $200 00 since organization (If serial) 11 of shares In force at I ! : 267 11 No. of &gt; of shares issued since oricaniiation f *r5 ; shares issued during tisral year 62 t shares matured dm "°. D . t? No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year 23 Kof shares of running stock In I of shares of full paid stock in force at this date None of shares loancl No. of shares loai Bof shares 1 x * 3i of shares on which dues are delinquent ' shares k latioa for nonpayment of dues.... amount of din-- i;ite {166 0O Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders $166 00 nt of Interest, premiums a ■• and unpaid $219 00 rof mortgage ire, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 3 . $2T )f sai Amount of loans on Improved real estate $2ti.. used value of improved real estate upon which loans have $6,090 00 Kbeen made JMH "" raised value of improvemii unt of loans upon unimproved real estate None Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unlmpr upon which loans have been made None Amount of Insurance In force and assigned to the association as nrky $23,150 00 No. of loans made for building purposes during the fiscal year. . S Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year None ■ borrowing stockholders None ' non-borrowing ■ minors holdin. association None lire rate per cent of 'larged borrowers during fiscal 9.6 vear Plan of premium .. .Used to be % earnings each year. No premium charged now int credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Eunt credited to reserve fund during fiscal year" thlnj unt of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year $1,598 60 Average rate per cent of dividends declared during ... 11% </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB SWEDISH MUTUAL LOAN AND lU'ILDINd AS WAHOO, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. NELS BRODAHL President ABJIAHAM HELSING Vice-President J. J. JOHNSON Secretary ALFRED HELSING Treasurer Directors. N. J. ANDERSON, ABRAHAM 1IIXSI r\\ v ABRAHAM HIXSIV CH.\ SI.Mu.N BKKliKNUllW, ,:sux JOHN HEL8INU, RIMON BRBDENBURG, Assets. Assets. First mortgage loans $10,200 mortgage loans In process of foreclosure 18 First mortgage loans $10,200 ::a.ge loans In process of foreclosure Real estate Real estate 1 ure and stationery • ill stationery pplinciuent interest, premiums and tines 3,0o9 i«m» and taxes paid assets 3.-jO Total |11,G15 men and taxes paid assets Total 111.' Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $11,112 &gt;&gt;* Full paid stock Reserve fund rndirided profits nrrli. . 1. 1. ix on incomplete loans Premium* unearned Advance dues Advai and premliuns l&gt;u« treasurer . 4* 01 Total $11,615 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">BUILDING AND LOAN* ASSOCIATIONS. 133 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Halance on hand July 1, 1 Italance on hand July 1, 1002 »1 : LMMS (running stock) 1.1 Dues {full paid stock Interest , 1'reniiiims rship and transfer ft if paid Real estate sales Taxes 14 profit* l&gt;ue treasurer Total $3,121 Expenditures. Loans $l,r.. Salaries ... Salaries ........."................. &lt; ciinun .... .-a 1,1 &gt; .■8 1.1 nings Matui &gt;es Matui Matm ;*s _s Kull pa Kull paid - Full paid stock, .-arn injrs Full pa Cash od band Total $S. I - Cash on hand Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or permanent) I'lan of association (serial or permanent) l"ar value ..f each shi t-X*&gt; (Hi l"ar value .&gt;f each share ol »-•' II 11 ■ ar ll year al year. . roe at this ■lu- shares of rum rce at this «lat .• N'..n.' .... amount ol amount nl Amount uf ....... . .... Amount of I unpaid of i I unpaid ot of I Amount of &lt;&gt;f Improi ius have been made $11 .iied value of impr" 100 '* tit of loans «&gt;n improve*! real n which loans have made $1 ■».'■ i-e&lt;l value of improi 'Hi imi Amount of loans upon uni: ised value of unimproved real n which loans have he*n made Amount of loaus up'iu uni: \alue of unimp on which loans have ■nns bcea made Amount of Insurance in force and • the association as collateral security f 1&lt;&gt; loans nut inent of hom&gt; ■ Amount of Insurance in force and I the association as collateral security $10 * [l I he as- Average rate I" n during fiscal •&lt; year ii ct A verace rate per cent of premiums charged borrower! durisg fiscal ir ... lit Plan of premium. ... Amount credited to n \ag lisral »i it of dividends , during fiscal year -ing fiscal year Erage rate ne ... rage running time of stock matured during fiscal year 10 years, 0 month* </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB WAnOO MUTUAL LOAN AND WILDING ASSN. WAHOO, NEBRASKA. Cn the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. BEN D. RUPP President E. B. COLLIER Vice-President H. M. STRATTON Secretary ERNST HANSON Treasurer E. E. GOOD Attorney Directors. L. J. KUDRNA, L. J. Klim.NA, J. J. JOHNSON, uoon, V. U. CLARK. II. A. rilKl.PS. Assets. First mortgage loans $41,000 00 mortgage loans In process of I nans BOO 00 Real estate Furniture and stationery ISO 00 ( 'ash in hands of secretary nerii interest, premiums and fines 327 41 ~es and taxes paid &lt; ither assets, taxes if treasurer 3.:. ■ Individual accounts Total $46,173 41 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $42,332 77 Full paid stock Reserve fund 49.'. 00 Reserve fund 'led profits s on incomplete loans Premiums unearned 3,T( I Advance dues Advance interest and premiums. ToUl $46,173 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">I»l IiJiINd ANU I-OA X ASSOCIATIONS* 135 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL Y EAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1002 $1.: I running stock) 10, t Interest Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid 17«&gt; tio l!-:il estate sal J. W. Stratton, balance due J. W. Stratton, balance du Taxes Total $1" Expenditures. Loans *11 Salaries other Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Taxes 7... MM Full paid ■! Full paid Itock, n hand ios and interest returned Interest ToUl $15,441 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of as- $1" ization (if seuab Ion ■•■ I shares matured il I shares withdrawn running U this date full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on ... : *i - ••Ing «hu Amount of -s due an Amoi •■ aggregate amount of Bam. *}- of Ban Amount of r.-ai estate -••■ $41' Appraised value of improved real estate upon which 1&lt; ans have hren made \\ \ value of improvements $14.1. Appraised value of lmprov. Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association as urity »'*••• WJ ide for building purposes during the fiscal year. . 9 us made for payment of 1 mortgages during Amount of advai ' ioans during i No. of borrowing .All. Ill WNlU" "'- ..._ No. of non 1 * ' » f minors In the association Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal I Averag^rate per cent Of premiums rrowers during fiscal J Tn^.mY,, m '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.I'.'.'. .'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. HIl: rian' nan of p. "*™«i Average running time of stock matured d&lt; 124 months </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF Till; CONDITION OF TUB SALINE COUNTY BUILDING ASSN. WILBER, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. WILBER, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers. C. DITRAS I C. DURAS President J. A. HOSPODSKY Vice-President J. A. HOSPODSKY Vice-I J. K. MALLAT Secretary J. K. MALLAT £ K. J. SPIRK 1 K. J. SPIRK Treasurer Directors. Directors. I". 8. SAFAHIK, J H. VAN I 'I J. J. MKI.C'KR, V. B. PBUCHA, .1OSKPII t'EKNY, PRANK SAKKK, CHA&gt; \Y, J. 11 BBT, II. BINGEIL Assets. First mortgage loan* $4!&gt;.34O on First mortgage loans In p loans 4.430 ■state 1 ure and stationery Itellnquent In if us and lines Expenses and taxes paid Other aaaeta ToUl fOo.OOo 04 Liabilities. I'anitn! Rtrx-k running (dues and dividends i f.-,t - aid stork . Ilwrv fund &lt; 4 jyy » on Incomplete loans Premiums unearned . Advance dun 182 Advance Interest and premiums. Total $35,1 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipts. Receipts, Ila'anrp on hand July 1 i &gt; $ 1 ' ■rxhlp and tra- tM "" Ila'anre on hand July 1 !Di 1 1 ies Membership and tra Loans repaid Loans repaid Uvula Items T °tal 113 31 1 Expenditures. Expenditures. I*nans i--. nn ; **•»■ ' &gt;t her expei (II her ex Nil hdrav a Is. it Withdrawals. i|u Withdrawn »■_. ............ n hand. . Total . SUPPLJ KT. Tut a SUPPLE REPORT. flan of a*s. I 'HI- 1 ■ ■ .... All. ■ ■ :ir No. &lt;■■( shares of full at this date V.. ..# _ I No. cf &gt;liares "f full at this date No. nf sha No. of ■bam ................. .... Total ani'&gt;-i |o - Amount of $1 i' Amount of ■ivmpnt t;f dues. . . . Total tmnm |o - Amonnt of $1 t» Amount nf air ... N'&gt;n* am- N.&gt;n* No. of .-ate No. of mm $40 $4!) Appri of improved real i hare • JS7 ." • of Improved real ■ n which loans hare • ... 187.7 Apprai iiprnvempntt. . Appra v-oipntt. . Amonnt rf Amonnt rf Amoui ind asslgti. assm-latl&lt;&gt;i: y $33.;. i Imildlns: piiri :il year. . r payment of al yrar Amcmnt . f and assii;; asswxiatl. tiscal year Amonnt of i Amount of advnnre pavmonts of loa: No. of ton No. &lt;&gt;r ? minors &gt; Averape rate per ceil year « Avemire rate per cent of premiums l'lan ■ Lid and paid In monthly Installment fund dii' Average rate per cent of divide* .MM Average running time of stock matu .... 6 yean </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF Tl UTIU.N OF TUB WOOD KIVEIl BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. WOOD RIVER, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, 1903. Officers, E. T. ROUNDS President A. C. WHITE Vice-President W. L. 8PRAGUE " Secretary M. C. WINGERT Treasurer Directors. F T. ROT'NnS, WHITE. W. A. COLWELL, W. J. CONNINGHAM, D. BARRICK, H. M. .ION OBO. W MIL] OBO. W. MILLER, E. J. CLARK. T. A. EVANS. Assets. First mortgage loans $11,000 on loans In i' 300 Stock loans I on Real estate 40 15 Furniture and stationery Cash 8S.1 41 cash Delinquent interest, premiums, and fines lsl tt.'i Expenses and taxes paid. Other assets Total $13,405 51 Liabilities. Capital stock running (dues and dividends) $12,384 30 Full paid stock Reserve fund 300 00 T'ndlvlded profits 1 ... 54 Due shareholders on Incomplete loans Premiums unearned 501 00 Advance dues 151 80 Advan and premiums 13 7o Total $13.405 51 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. FISCAL YEAR Receipts. Balance on hand July 1, 1!K&gt;2 * 2Sn 11 &lt; running stock I I full paid sto.k Interest Premiums Membership and transfer t«M repaid Heal estate sales IT.", chi Heal estate sales 1TB '■&lt;• KenU ToUl |ft.tt Total $3,0 Expenditures. Expenditures. $j.ooo oo In«n&lt; $J.OOO 00 Salaries " Salaries " ■ 40 14 40 14 linings Matured stork, dues .... Matnr&lt;" Matured stock, earnings lid Block, due* Matured stuck, earnin paid slock, due Cash on hand Interest on advance payments 11 42 Kill! paid stoi k, eari;i: _- an hand 9t on advance paym Total t on advance payment Total PPLKMKNTAL RKPOBT. Sl'PPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of ass Rerlal Plan of as« far v. *1" far v. $1' B organization (if serial i 'ii { if serial i No. o&lt; Mi No. of ithdrawn during flsral year of shares matured during fiscal year &gt;'.ne Kof shares wlthdi of shares of run 1 it this dm of shares of full at this date None rce at this dat - at this date None :it tills date ■ shares joa .5 I Rharea on .5 . . . it of dues. . . . »S7 IN&gt; »S7 i&gt;O Am. .in Amini' ■us and fi i re, and the aggregate ■ iid ii.. aggregate Urn --n.— s In proress of foreclosure, and the aiigr. ■ -'lie. ami the aggr. amount of same. N - on improved real estate tV- - .*d value of Improved real estate upon which loans hare j Amotin "n improved real estate .hi value of improved real estate upon which loans have ) been made &gt; $20,000 00 been made &gt; $20,000 00 Appraised value of Improvements ) Appraised value of Improvements Amount of insurance In force and assigned to the association as rarity ■ • J14.S00 no r building purposes durli:. il year.. Fnnt of Insurance in force and assigned to the association as $14.soo no building purposes ;»l year. . vear $«■ khnlders non borrowing stockholders minors holding stock In the association 7 Average rate por cent of Interest charged borrowers during f year , • T1.1 rate per cent of' premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year HI Kof premium, sell to ! .ted to reserve ■ al year * Amount of divi.! n running stock dnrine fiscal jear $T I Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year. ... 74 </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION'S. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TUB YOJIK MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN A YORK. NE3RASKA. On the 30th day of June, 19C3. Officers. GEORGE W. SHRECK President CHARLES A. McCLOUD Vic* President GEORGE R. REED Secretary GEORGE W. POST Tre:i WILLIAM W .WYCKOFF Attorney Directors. HARRIS II. CIIILPS. CHARLES A. McCLOUD, PAVin V.. SEPGWICK. ALFRED B. CHRISTIAN, UEORUE W. POST, W. SCIIREt K NATHANIEL A. DEAN, UEORUG R. SEED, WILLIAM \V. \VV« Assets. First mortgage loans $0O.r&gt;On on First mortgage loans In process of foret I l,3oi Real estate . . . Furniture and «l Cash MOW Delinquent lnten -r.s and fines 2111 Expenses and taxes j.nid Other assets Total Liabilities Capital stork running. (Dues and dividends.) Dues, f dividends, H • $00 815 28 $30,815 28 Reserve fund 1,2 B7 4s Ksbareholder* 01 te loans None turns un. -an,. Ml None I in capital stock 93 00 md pretc!u:is;- B9 4.i Total 102,182 03 </seg>
            <seg id="p141">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 141 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1903. Receipt*. Receipt*. Italance on hand July 1.1' $8,1 I running stock i 1 full paid stock i !iU m 8 :;:::::::::::::::::::: 4 - 703 *« I'.alance on hand July 1.1' 'CO » full paid stork) ... MM RSSiSd.:::::::::::::::::::::::::: *■•• I I •"III I II IUS - . • ■• Klnes 78 73 78 73 Membership and transfer fees Membership and transfer fees repaid i *."•'» M I-.an* repaid 8.M1 mi «."•■&gt; "«&gt; n 1.1 Foreclosures 1.113 85 Total ... *08.- Total J08.226 92 Expenditures. Expenditures. I...nns i . $18.sn« no I...nns i I18.3W 00 S Salaries ? irawala, di ■n hand 2'J&lt;i '.&lt;&gt; i 117". Salaries ? - ■ k 11 Real estate Total $68. - .state Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan of association (serial or iwrmanpntl Both Itr value ..f ea h -»liare "i $1' : series Issued since orgai . . • l-&gt;. ■!•;:: I shares Ik- ar f shares matured during : of -darts » ig tis&lt;al year. .... LMfl • shares of running - rce at this date res leaned on shares oi .... ' shares sul ... amount of due- lute f-H IX) .. It'rs i t of inter aid $10 Appraised value of improved real estate u|H&gt;n whiih loans have a made Jlo:. • Appraised value of r ■it of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised va'ue of unimproved real estate upon which leans have been made Amount of Insurance In force and assigned to the association as ateral security ... J52.673 00 ■ loans made for building purposes during the fiscal year. . 17 17 ■ loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during al year 8 Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year $19,300 n« borrowing stockholder* fitt '" non-borrowing stockholders. . f minors holding stock In the association Average rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year .... T.S Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year .71 year .11 Plan of premium Weekly nt credited to reserve fund during fiscal year ... fr Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year ■ Amount of dividends declared on rnnnln. -Ing fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running '"ar Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year. .. . Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year Sgg weeks </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. While the number of associations reporting at the close of the lacftJ year is the same as that of the previous year, yet a comparison of the summary of (lie reports of the con - dition of the associations at the close of business Jinn 1903, with those of former years found on preceding pi of this rej)ort illustrates a steady, substantial, and ver\ (•factory growth, both in business and membership, and shows the following increases over the report for last year: •ts $585,135 f&gt;l Loans 614,259 4 1 Annual business, about 300,006 on And in number of shares in force 23,341 There are now 20,44&lt;! persons owning shares in Nebraska's building and loan associations. The number of loans in force June 30. IMS, was T.4S0, of which only 2&lt;»S were ■ab - ject to foreclosure, and but forty in actual process of fore - closure. The average rate of interest charged borrowers bv the associations is !S per cent ; average rate of dividends paid by the associations on amounts paid in S'/V. per cent. There are 153,424 shares of stock in force, representing an ultimate or par value of f23,153.07»;.30. There have been no new laws enacted or decisions of the Supreme Court of Nebraska rendered during the period covered by this rejn&gt;rt affecting the business of building ami loan associations except Judge Glanville's opinion in a involving a feature of building and loan practice that. 1 am nappy to say, has long since ceased to exist, and it is to be hoped will not be again practiced by any Nebraska building and loan association. </seg>
            <seg id="p143">143 BUILDING AND LOAN" ASSOCIATIONS. CHADKON LOAN &amp; BUILDING ASSOCIATION, Appellant, vs PATRICK H. HAYS AND SUSIE HAYES, Commissioner's Opinion. Department N&lt;&gt;. i\ SYLLABUS 1. Record examined and held, that the &lt;1 ppeakd from is as favomble to appellant as equity will permit. Glanville, C. The record before us shows that the plaintiff made a I to the defendant August 16, lSS'.l. upon which the defendan realized the sum of |6S4, and secured the same by the inor gage upon which the decree in this case was rendered; tha the payments made by the defendant to the plaintiff froi May lf&gt;, 188©, to March l.~&gt;, 1897, inclusive, aggregate ta sum of $1,4!U, the average time of payment being 3| yeai after the date of the loan; that the defendant has so paid t the plaintiff the amount realised by him on the loan, t&lt; gether with in bereon from its date, to the avei time of his payments, at the rate of .'M.I per cent per annun It also shows that by a aystem of premiums, dues, an fines, and by-laws and amendments to by-laws, and cm dation of series, and apportionment and distribution of miums and profits, non-borrowing members of the plainti &lt; iation, in a series with which that of the defendant consolidated and its premiums and profits apportioned, ha\ been repaid all the money by them invested, with int. thereon at the rate of 30 per cent per annum for the time of their investments; that Boa borrowing meml&gt;ei - the same series with the defendant have been repaid the sum invested by them, together with interest at 16 per cent pe annum for the average time of their investments; that th former series was by this process matured in nit l/)/x </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. ths. while defendant'! run for 117, ami also tliat suits were brought about by changes made after the •late of defendant'! mortgage, to which he never consented. The *-mrt In-low gave the plaintiff a decree for |185.13, and the defendant did not appeal. The plaintiff, still claim ing BOTC money than the defendant received on his loan. brings the case to this court upon appeal, and asks us to examine the record to see if in equity and jjood conscience it is not entitled to a greater sum from the defendant. We copy the following from plaintiffs brief: "We earnestly insist on the entire propriety and justice of the entry in tins court of a decree in favor of the plaintiff for the principal of the loan, fl,20Q, plus interest at ten per centum from April 15, lSi)7, the date of the tirst default, plus fl.80, tines on defaulted dues for three months. f570 dues paid, with seven per centum interest thereon for the average time, which would begin February 1"&gt;, 1898. If by any construction of plaintiffs contract its conten - tion could lie sustained, such a contract would be too uncon - scionable for a court of equity to enforce. There is no merit in the plaintiff's appeal, and as the de - fendant has not appealed we recommend that the judgment of the lower court be affirmed. BARNES AND ALBERT, C. C, Concur Per Curia in Tor the reasons stated in the foregoing opinion, the jodg meiit of the district court is attinued. The so-called home cooperative companies that wen at in their unlawful operations in the state last year have Ik-coiuc very much less active since the rendition of an opinion by the Nebraska supreme court last November, in which the demurrer was sustained and judgment of ouster catered as prayed, in an action brought by Attorney General Front in the nature of quo warranto against the Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p145">145 BUILDING AND LOAN IONS. Iine Company of Omaha. Prior to tbe passage of a bill by Nebraska legislature last winter, introduced bj Senator II. Harrison of Hall county and known as senate tile No. !, there was no specific provision upon the statute books Nebraska governing domestic concerns of this character. «ler tin' provisions of said bill, which has since become a t, all such companies, both foreign and domestic, are iced under the supervision of the State Banking Hoard, 1 a certificate of authority must be obtained by them from d hoard before transacting or attempting to transact husi - ■ in the state. The hill will certainly prove a wise provi - n and serve to protect the people of the state against the ■rations of the many get-rich-quick concerns whose rep tentative^ go about the country proclaiming a mission of ilanthiopy, seeking to roll wage-earners and people with all means of their sayings, building and loan associations. il other legitimate enterprises of the fruits of capital and i xpenence. \ copy of senate tile No. 'I'l'l follows I Section 1. i Installment Investment Compaj Every social i&lt;m, other than building and loan associations, hanks, insurance companies or fraternal beneficial nations organised under the laws of this state, or ad - itted under the laws of this state, to do business herein, Iiich is or shall he organised for the purpose of raising niey from its members or others, by means of stated in illnients or payments, to Im- held, invested or disbursed by id association, whether the money so contributed is paid for shares in such association, or is held by the assoeia - »n for investment and accumulation for the benefit of the ntributors, or as an advance on merchandise, or pro] any kind, to he delivered in the future, or is held by the sociation to be disbursed among the contributors, or any them, in accordance with any agreed plan or scheme, and liether the relation of the contributor to t lit ition i that of a member, shareholder, vendee, creditor or bene- 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. fieiary of a trust; and every incorporated association, every unincorporated association, every co-partnership, every poratioD whether organized under the laws of this or any other state, territory or government, and every individual doing business, or attempting or offering to do business in the state of Nebraska, in form or chancier similar to that hereinabove set forth, shall be known, for the purpOM this ; an installment investment company. Every such installment investment company that is a I dent or a citizen of any other state, territory or government. or that is a co-partnership or unincorporated association, &lt;&gt;f which any member or members is a resident of any other state, territory or government, or is an incorporated I eiation, organized under the laws of any other state, terri or government, shall be further known for the ptirp of this act, as a foreign installment investment company. tion 2. (Contiol of Banking Bo aid.) The auditor of public accounts, the state treasurer and the attorney -genera I. inafter designated as the state banking board, or any i\\&lt;&gt; of them, shall have power to issue certificates of ap - al to any such installment investment company, and shall have general supervision over and control of any ami all such eompati tion 3. (Statement Filed.) Before transacting any business whatever in this stale, excepting that pertaining Tganization such installment investment company shall tile in the office of the state banking board the follow - ing documents, to-wit : 1. A written statement, showing in full detail the plan upon which it proposes to transact bnmn&lt; 2. A copy of the contract which it proposes to make with contribute 3. A written statement which shall show the name and lity of the association, and an itemized account of its actual financial condition, and the amount of its property </seg>
            <seg id="p147">147 P.m. DING AND LOAN i ION'S. ■uid liabilities, ami such other information touching fairs, as said stale banking board, or any two Members there Of, may require. And if such installment investment company shall be a co partnership, &lt;;r an unincorporated association, it shall also tile with the state banking board a copy of its articles of co - partnership or association, and all other papers pertaining to its organisation; if it be ;i corporation organised under the laws of Nebraska it shall also tile with the state hank in^ r hoard a copy of its articles of incorporation, constitul ion, iws and all other papers pertaining to its organisation, and if it he an incorporated or unincorporated association, organized under the laws of any other state, territory or ninient, it shall also lile with the state banking 1m a copy of the laws of the state, territory or governmen under which it exists or is incorporated, and also of its char ter, articles of incorporation or association, constitution laws and all amendments thereof, and all other papi taining to its organisation. All of the above described pa Ml he refilled by the oath of such installment in in-lit company, if it he an individual, or by the oath member of the co-partnership, if it he a co-partnership bj the oath of a duly authorised officer, if it he an incorpo rated or unincorporated association. All such papers, how ever, as are recorded or are on tile in any puhlic Office, sha! be further certified to by the oAcer of wl archives they form a part, as being correct copies of - records or archil Every foreign installment investment company shall appoint an attorney in each county in which it proposi transact or solicit business, who shall be a resident of such county, and shall file with the state banking hoard a wri nstrument duly signed, sealed and acknowledged, author - zing such attorney in such county to acknowledge of process in behalf of such company consenting that </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 lH'II.PINi; AND LOAN !'I()NS. • of process, mene or final, u{&gt;on such attorney shall be taken and held rved apon the company, according i" the laws of this or any other stale, and waiving all claim or right of error by reason of sih-Ii service, or such acknowl - edjrnu lit of service. Brery foreign installment investment company shall Hie anew with the state banking board, annually, in the month of January, and at such other times as the slate banking hoard, or any two members thereof, may deem ex - pedient to demand the same, all statements and documents required by this section to be tiled with the state banking hoard by foreign installment investment companies, before transacting any busiw pt that pertaining to organ - ization Section 4. i Approval of Banking Board, i it shall he the duty of the state banking hoard, or any two members there of, to examine carefully the statements and documents tiled they find that such installment investment com - pany is solvent, that i's articles of incorporation or associa - tion, its constitution and by-laws, its proposed plan of bnsi - - and proposed contract contain and provide for a fair, just ami equitable plan for the transaction of business, they, or any two of them shall issue to such installment im ment company a certificate of their approval; but if they, &lt;».■ any two of them find that such articles of incorporation or association, charter, constitution, by-laws, plan of luisi - or proposed contract contain any provision that is un - fair, unjust, inequitable or oppressive to any class of con - tributors, they shall withhold their approval, provided, how - . that all certificates of approval issued to foreign in stallment investment companies shall Ik- limited to those counties for which said company has filed with the state banking hoard appointment! of attorneys, as required by ion three of this act, and that all certificates issued to such foreign installment investment companies shall expire on the 31st day of January of the following rear. </seg>
            <seg id="p149">149 Evtion .". (CeBTIFICATE NECES8ABY.) ll ■hall not be law - ful 1 any corporation, association, co-partnership or indi - ial, either as principal pr agent, to transact any b in form or character similar to that sci forth in section one of tliis act, except sndi as pertains to its organisation, until it shall have procured the certificate of approval above provided for, nor even then, in any county of this state not included in inch certificate, nor after the expiration or i cation of sudi certificate. No amendment of the charter, K tides of incorporation, constitution or liy laws of buy such bailment investment company shall become operative, n n a copv of 'he game has been tiled with the state banking ti'tl. and a certifi&lt; I obtained, as proi gard to the original tiling of charters, articles of in. poratkm, constitution ami by-laws; nor shall it be lawful ,my such installment investment company to trail husiness on any plan other than that set forth in tli nient required by section three of this act, or to make any contract other than that shown in the copy of the prop contract required to be iled by section three of this until a written statement, showing in full detail, the pro d new plan of transacting husiness, and a copy of the proposed new contract shall have been filed with the - banking hoard, and a certificate of approval of said - banking hoard obtained as to such proposed new plan of transacting husiness, or proposed new contract, in like man ner as aliove provided in regard to the original plan of i - and proposed contra* on »;. (Annual Statement.) Everv such install nient investment company shall, at the dose of busineM June 98th of each year, and at such other times as required by the state banking hoard, or any two members thereof, tile in the office of said state banking hoard a statement verified fthe oath of such installment investment company, if it an individual, or hy the oath of a niemher of the co-part- </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 nill-DIXC AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS, nership, if it 1&gt; partnership or by the oath of a duly authorized officer, if it he an incorporated or unincorporated &gt; iation, setting forth iu such form as may be prescribed .iitl hoard, or any two niemhers thereof, its financial con - dition and the amount of its nd liabilities, and fur - nishing such other information as to its affaii d board or any two lnenihers thereof, may require Any installment investment company failing to file the report required at the dose «&gt;f husiness, .Tune :{&lt;&gt;th of each year, within teu da\ that date, or to file any other or special report herein re - quired, within thirty days after the receipt of a request or requisition therefor, shall forfeit its rights under the certifi - cate of approval provided for in section four of this act ctkm 7. i A&lt; . | The general accounts of every such company shall be kept by double entry, and such com pany, its co-partners or msimring officer shall, at least once a month, make a trial balance of such accounts, which will be recorded in a hook provided for that purpose; such trial balance and all other hooks and accounts of such company shall, at all times during husiness hours, except on Sundays and legal holidays, be open to the inspection of contributor!! to the company. ction s. i Examination i-.y Accountant.) The person or jM'rsons appointed under the law of this state to mcke examination of corporations, firms or individuals doing a banking business, shall make an examination and report of y installment investment company doing husiness in this state, as often as the state hanking hoard, or any two mem - thereof, shall deem it necessary and proper, and at least once a year; and the rights, powers, duties, privileges and compensation of such person or ]&gt;ersons, in connection with such examination, shall he the same as is or may he provided by law with reference to examinations of hanks and corpo - rations, firms or individuals transacting a hanking husin and such installment investment company shall pay the. same </seg>
            <seg id="p151">151 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS, fees for such examinations lie provided by law in case of the examination of banks. And whenever it i&gt;&gt; necessary for examim ,» into another state for the purpose of examining the affairs of any such installment in tnent company transacting business in this pe diem fee of ten dollars (f 10.00) per day and expi the examiner for the time required to be absent from tin stave capital on such examinations shall be paid to 1 1 » • aminer by such installment investment compaa can ined. i-tionO. (Revocation oi Approval — Receiver.) When ever it shall appeal to the slate banking board, or any two members thereof, that the &gt;f any installment in* ment company are impaired to the extent that such a - do not equal its liabilities, or that it is conducting its busi - in an unsafe or inequitable or unauthorised manner, or is jeopardizing the interests of its contributors, or that it is unsafe for such installment investment company to ti act busi id board, or any two members thereof, shall revoke its certificate of approval, — shall cofnmunicate sudi facts to the attorney general, who shall thereupon appl the supreme court, or to the district court where such com - pany is located, or to a judge of either of said courts, for the appointment of a receiver to take charge of and wind up the business of such installment investment company; and if such fact or facts be made to appear, it shall be sutnciei authorize the appointment of a receiver, and the makii such orders and decrees in such cases as equity may require. Section 10. (Misuepukskntation.) Every person wh shall willfully or knowingly subscribe, or make or ■ be made any false statement or false entry in any book « any installment investment company, or exhibit any I paper with the intention of deceiving any person authorize) to examine into the affairs of such installment investmen company, or shall make, state or publish any false statemen </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 BUILDING AXIl LOAN ASSOCIATION* of the financial condition of such installment investment company, shall lie deemed jjuilty of a felony and upon con viction thereof, shall !*• fined not exceeding ten t 1m mi ~ dollars, and be imprisoned in the state penitentiary not than one nor more than five years. Section 11. (UMAUTUOUEBD — PENALTY.) Any pen»M, agent, or company doing business or offering or attempting to tlo business in this state for any such installment in ment company which shall not. at the time, be the holder of a valid, unrevoked and unexpired certificate of approval as rided for in section four of this act, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and npon conviction thereof shall l&gt;e ftned in any sum not exceeding one thousand dollar* &lt;&gt;i by ini]&gt;risonment in the county jail not more than thirty da\s or lnith at the discretion of the court. '•tion 12. This act shall not j^o into effect as to any in stallincnt investment company actually doing business in this state at the date of its passage until October 1st, 1903. ii 13. All acts and parts of acts in conflict with this act ftTC hereby repealed. Approved April S, 1903 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>