<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FIFTH BIENNIAL REP0RT OF The Home for the Friendless AT LINCOLN, NEBRASKA FOR THE BIENNIAL TERM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The Home for the Friendless n LINCOLN, NEBRASKA FOR THE BlhSSlAl TERM ENDING KOI tUBER W, 190* </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OF THE l«tl\KI&gt; OF PrBI.lt' LAND8 AND BUILDINGS H. M. EaTO mer of Public Land- and Buildings George ('. .h skin Secretary &lt;&gt;f - L. &lt;i. Biuw . State Treasurer H-'\. W. T. Thompson .. Attorney General tXl.riTIVK OKFK KKS Kmma C. Johnston .. Bvperintendeat \\ \ v M r\i)v M \\&gt;\ Ix il&lt; H&lt; lAHU \\ . A. WToodwabd, president Lincoln. Nebf Mi-~ Anna Rogbbs, secretary Lincoln, Xebr- J. \V. Johnson Lincoln. Nebr. B. Hnwiiiaii Lincoln, Nebr. I B Stein Lincoln. Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">1 II TH BIENNIAL KKl'OKT OF THE HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS AT LINCOLN. NEBRASKA lis Excellency, George L. Sheldon, Governor, and the H able Hoard of Public- Lands and Buildings: I Gentlemen I have the honor, herewith, to submit to yo biennial report for the Home for the Friendless for tl ng November :{&lt;». 1908. tFor more than ten yean the Home for the Friendless has ate institution. It was formerly controlled byanorganu haritabfe women of Lincoln, who established auxilian various towns in the state for the purpose of aiding the itution. I The object of the Home was to give help anil support to all itute and dependent women and children of the state o( ka who knocked at its doors for protection. It is to be the title "The Home for the Friendless" was not chai ii the institution became the property of the state. \\ • 1 annoyed by tramps asking for shoes, clothing and food e they are led to believe thai the intent of the Home ish such provision to the needy, whereas, it is simply the H le and School for dependent children. Similar institutions in t states under the name of Minnesota State Public Sch&lt; "Michigan State Public School," "Wisconsin State Public School" and "Colorado State Home lor Dependent Children" (expe&lt; have the name changed to "State Public School" i are doing the same work as is l&gt;eing done in our institution with the exception that their work is conducted on a larger scale which is eft. through the efforts of the state agent who looks after the dependent children of the state and sends them to U&gt; cared for in the S Public School until such time as they may l&gt;e placed in hoine - would, therefore, respectfully urge that the legal title of "The I! for the F'riendless l&gt;e changed to the "State Public School." change will save many of the little ones old enough to realize, the mortification of reading in the chiselled stone above the door, the saddest part of their young life's history. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">348 1) COM 's REPORT REPAIRS \\l) I M I'ldiN KMKN I &gt; Many changee have been nude during the past btennium. pound has been purchased which gives the institution a ■ &gt;f me lilnck. With the exception of five fifty foot lots adjoining on the west, the Home grounds consist of one block square. Small cottages have been built on two &lt;&gt;f these lots ami it would U' an advantage in many ways if this property should be - the property of the state. These cottages are almost at our door and could Ik- used advantageously as a quarantine and engineer's cottage. The five lots and two cottages could \h&gt; bought .bout five thousand dollars ($5,000.00). One of the most important, because the most needed, improve - ments made during the pact two years was the erection of a wing en feet by twenty feet, two stories and basement, affording us on the second floor a much needed bath room for the girls' doiini - aad a room in which to place a sick child; a well lighted sewing room and employes' bath room on the first floor, and a cold storage in t he basement. This addition was well and substantially built by I.. C Dybbro A Co., under the supervision of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. The roof of the original building mgled. and nearly five thousand feet of cement walks have been laid. 3125 feet having l&gt;een laid around the back court leading to the cottage for aged women, thus giving a neat and tidy appear - to the rear of UlS buildings. Our greenhouse has been phieed in better condition by the building of new plant bo\Vs. new fratwe work for the glas&gt; in the roof, the filling in of new soil. etc. We el this winter, to have flowers for the sick and for all who care for them. Three good sized window, have been made in the attic of the main building, thus giving more light and better ventilation to the employes' rooms on this floor. One new room for the pur - pose of hospital or other emergency was partitioned off on the north - corner. A bath room is very much needed on this floor. There ■ m for this purpose and will be fitted up as soon as an appropri - ation is available. Inderable repair was made on the steam and water pipes ling to the buildings, which had beeome rusted through and were leaky condition. These were dug up and replaced by new ones. 1 I enough money in my repair fund, I would have built a tunnel underground pij)es, large enough for a workman to enter. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">349 HOME Knit THE FRIENDLESS, LINCOLN Kould be economy in the cud and would save the work of continu - digging and the annoyance of having the ground torn up when ing repairs. An old cistern ol one hundred barrels capacity that had i in. was arched over with brick. A la; d as a "bio* off" for the boilers, that had also begun to cave in. was walled up a distance of twenty-five feel and ached with brick. This i connected with the sewer because the boilers are below the and this is the only means by which the boilers may he cleaned out ; equently it was necessary to put this in as good conditii lile thai it may last until a new boiler room can be built, boiler and engine room is located under our laundry and is all wholly underground. We have two boilers, one fifty hoi anil the other forty horse power. Both these boilers have Service, one for twenty-five years, and the other for twenty \ and need continual repair. The walls of brick have fallen in and while we have patched them up temporarily, new walls mu built as soon as possible after receiving the new appropriation for repairs. Our pump is very small and during the coldest \\v we find it almost impossible to carry off the return from the buildings. tA new steel ceiling was placed on the hall of the second Boor he main building. Painting, papering and varnishing ha - e where necessary and we have endeavored to keep the institu - clean and military throughout. A new bath room has ■d up in the basement for the use of the male employes, ami lerous other minor improvements have l&gt;een made. At the ent time the buildings are in very good repair. \K\\ IMPIKl\ EMENT.S We have occupied one floor of the hospital building and it has been anything but satisfactory to either institution. Our twenty - six little lads have been continually restrained from making a that would disturb the hospital, an unnatural condition for the little fellows from four to twelve years of age who are brimful of frolic and fun. The odor of ether from the operating room bdow ha.- been exceedingly unpleasant in this department, dormitory is unhealthfullv crowded, lieside the dormitory and small bath room on this floor, there are the matron's rooms, tei and bookkeeper's rooms, boys' governess' room, a recreation room in parlor which is also us m for nine of the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">350 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT larger boys, and the school room whii chapeL Our ■I room is not large enough to accommodate the children when meet for Sunday service. I. therefore, respectfully recommend ■in appropriation of fourteen thousand dollars if 14. (MM). (KM Ik? allowed for the erection and equipment of a detached building to the west of the main building and facing South street. This would is the room to successfully cany on the work of the Home, ami at the same time remove the seven employe.- from the j&gt;erilous quarters they now occupy directly over t he boilers. The basement of the new building would afford a loom for ial training and a department for the instruction in domestic Both these are very essential in a school of this kind where children who have a permanent home with us may go out into the world prepared for a life work. Another improvement which would prove of great economy to in ice plant for the manufacture of ice. During the summer our ice bill for both institution- was over eig'ity dollars ($80. (M)) jkm' month. The manufacture of our own ice would cost ■arativelv nothing and would In- a saving to the state of over n-five dollars ($75.00) per month. One thousand dollars (tl.(H)O.(K)) is asked for this improvement. THE FINANCIAL CONDITION The legislature of MH)7 appropriated seventeen thousand &lt;17,&lt;MX).OO) for the maintenance of the Home for the Friendless for the two years ending March 31st, 1909. While I felt ire had not l&gt;een allowed as much as I had asked for. and I had ntiouslv for what I knew would be i to meet our expenses without a deficiency. 1 was determined to carry our tution through on the amount appropriated for the purpose. 1 &gt;rtho|&gt;edie Hospital having failed to receive an appropriation new building, I was confronted with the proposition of their maintenance. Our school building was given over to l&gt;e remodelled for the use of a hospital. With a shortage of room for my employes, Tamped, crowded apartments for the children, we accepted the •ion and did the U'st we could for the maintenance of both tutions. The remodelling of the building gave to the hospital than two dozen new radiators which meant more heat ami a consequent greater amount of fuel to be Imught. The additional numt&gt;er of new bath rooms caused our water rent to greatly increase. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">351 laundry supplies were needed as the employes of the H do the laundry work for the hospital. Their gas bills were ed and paid by us; also the electric light hills until light was furnished by the penitentiary in July, 1908. lee, soap and other supplies not used as food were furnished. It was hard some to know just where to draw the line on furnishing supplies. The food was cooked in the Home kitchen and carried across t lie yard to the several dining rooms in the hospital building. We were cd by members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings that we would lie reimbursed for the maintenance provided, from the maintenance fund of twenty-seven thousand doll I 7,000) appropriated for the hospital. We received on April 23d a warrant drawn on this fund for $.'M74 .'&gt;ti which was placed with the State urer to our credit. In November another warrant was drawn for $2.H9S is and also placed to our credit with the State Treasurer. This may pay our lulls until December 1. 1!M»N at which time we hope to have a third voucher allowed by your Honorable Board, and a warrant drawn on the hospital maintenance fund sufficient to meet the expenses for maintaining both institutions until March 31, 1909, when the new appropriation will l&gt;e available. The total expenditure for the maintenance of both institutions for the bienniuin amounts to $28,530.57. The per capita o 1267.91, which I consider very low considering that two institu - tions are l&gt;eing cared for. With a fluctuating population at have in the Home, our per capita is apt to be higher than thi capita of other institutions who have the same inmates all the time, child who comes to us must receive a new equipment of cloth - ing, etc.. and when they go to a home they take their lx'st with them. It costs more to place a child than it does to keep him in the institution. I feel, however, that our pVr capita will compare favorably with any of the smaller institutions of the state. We have administered the affairs of our institution economically, but not parsimoniously, and our per capita is as low as can be made consistent with the l»est welfare of the children and aged i&gt;eople in our charge. iOur appropriation of seventeen thousand dollars ($17,000.00) maintenance was nearly exhausted June 1st. 1908. The kind - of Warden Heemer in furnishing us light from the penitentiary of great help at this time and saved u : lighting rh heretofore amounted to an e of fifty dollars ($o0 (M)) month. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">352 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Our appropriation is divided into five funds and the amount i for in each fund is requisite and necessary to meet the needs of the institution for t he next biennium. These amounts are asked : onscientiously and not with the thought that the legislature will make the usual "cut." Should any amount remain in the us funds at the close of the biennium, it will revert to the rv. tit is impossible to know the exact cost for maintaining the »e for the past biennium as the expense for maintaining both tutions can not well be separated. Our food has been cooked le same time, our heat came from the same plant, water from same water main. etc. ESTIMATE F"lt CURBENT EXPENSE The following I submit M my estimate of the appropriations that will be required to meet the expenses of the Home for the &gt;r the (K&gt;riod ending March 151st. 1911: I My estimate of the necessary e\|&gt;ense:5 needed for the current uses of the Home for the Friendless for the next biennium is I on an average daily maintenance of eighty-five inm:r We have received into the institution during the past biennium, ,'iildren. and have placed in homes for adoption and other Ofhcers sain r Superintendent |2.(MKt.(K) Matron .. 1.200.00 Physician 1,400.00 Engineei 1,200.00 060 (Ml Head Nona 840.00 Total 17,100 00 Employes' wages Maintenance MHMI Oil _'I).(MH) 00 t)l supplies &amp; travelling expense? ir &amp; improvement 500 00 :{..")( mi 00 ■raCIAL APPKOHIII ATI&lt;&gt;\&gt; Sclic Mil and dormitory building 113400 00 Furnishing for same ice plant 1.000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">353 E children. The average daily number inmates maintained in Home baa lieen MM. and the average in the Orthopedic ptiaJ maintained by the Home has been 42.4, making a 1 age of KHi.7 cared for during the biennium. IIII.DKKN IN THE HuMK At the present time there are sixty-eight (68) children antl six ged women, making a total of seventy-four (74) inmates in the Home, the youngeel one week old and the oldest eighty-two j the two extremes in life. As a rule our children are happy am; tented and M healthy as any children in private home .e food prepared from t he same packagea and of the quality as the food given the officers and employes. There :. charge* for placing children in the Home. Our doors are op. every orphan and half-orphan child who is without a home, and every child who is neglected or ill-treated should also find a : with us. No home or school in the state is looked after n fully nor greater attention given to the sanitary regulation than is given in this institution. Disinfectants are used freely to guard st contagion. The children are fed regularly, bathed regularly, the entile institution is cleaned daily and many of the departments are models of cleanliness. The health of our older children has excellent. With the exception of an epidemic of mild diphtl there has Iteen hut little sickness, which s]&gt;eaks well for the watchful &lt;&gt;f physician and nurses. During the nearly four yean of my Buperintendency we have not lost a gingle child by death oui the nursery; deaths occurring have been among the very young - in the nursery. tAll children in the Home of pro] have attended w larlv and average well in their work. I Our children come to us from all over the state blfl we have been able to receive all that ought to be cared for in this institu - . The county commissioners in every county in the state ought ork in conjunction with the state and send all children of sound 1 and body wlio are without a home, neglected or maltreated those who are in the environments of vice to the home and ol our state has provided for them. In a letter recently re - ed from one of our county attorneys I was asked to take a little ily of four children into our institution. The father was sick without ind the mother wished to send the little </seg>
            <seg id="p010">354 LAND OOlfMISBIO NEB'S KKl'ohT to the reform school not, at the present time, able .pport them. Tin* too bad; they were guilty of no crime. I referred him to you. gentlemen, knowing you were not in favor of innocent children l&gt;eing sent to the Industrial School. Such requ&lt; liis are received frequently. I have wondered why such children are committed to the reform schools and not sent to nstitution and saved the mortification when they arc older, of :&gt;g been an inmate of a reformatory, particularly a little girl. i !&gt;ears the e.\j&gt;ense and why not care for such little ones in •■ Public School"'" Widowed mothers who are away from all day trying to earn a living for their little families find after a time that the street influences have made their girls or boys un ma; ich children, while not criminal, need the discipline and lotion that would encourage them to l&gt;etter living and higher We have had children whose profanity amazed us and we learned that both father and mother emphasized things in l»d spent their nights in drunken revelry, it was not so much to be wondered at. Yet these little ones are very susceptible to the kindly influences of the Home. It is a delight to note how perceptibly the little natures respond to the moulding, and to the .er and govc ho have them in their charge much credit • •. Our children become just as sweet as any children in their but it takes patience and constant vigilance to make them so. There is no greater charity than that of caring for I little hapless ones in the Home; educating and preparing them for useful anil helpful lives. I invite the inspection of the legislature which will soon convene, and the public in general that they may be convinced of this fact. The question of "boarded" children in the Home has l&gt;een a ion of much discussion and I beg to say that there are but five pay anything for their children. I find that there is scarcely an institution in the state but what demands clothing, or pay for clothing, from the county or the parent or guardian who places the .te in the institution. A poor working mother who has paid a nominal sum for the care of her children in the Home, did so that they might not be placed for adoption and taken entirely out of her life, although the same mother allows me to place her child in a home where he can work for board and clothing and go to school. The only difference between the institutions is that one charg&lt; care and others for clothing. However we have but five wh&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p011">HOME FOR THK FRIENDLESS, LINCOLN 355 tribute anything to our cash fund, and it has been my expei that a little cash on hand is a very good tiling to have. I earn, hope the legislature will deal generously with the institution is shaping the lives and destiny of these dependent children. The population of our Home is a moving one and may become greater than it is this year. All our children do not find homes readily. The infants anil smaller children are soon placed but t he older ones on account of lack of intelligence or the early blighting of their morals remain with us indefinitely. Our discipline must — arily l&gt;e firm hut is kind. We endeavor to impress on our children individual responsibility and each child has a certain work to do in the institution every day. Our girls are taught, in a general the principles of housekeeping. Our hoys as well u the girls make their own )&gt;eds, polish their floors and do many of the chores with a cheerfulness that would surprise children in private homes. With so great a numtier to cook for. children would only he in the in the general kitchen: consequently, 1 am anxious for partment f&lt;&gt;r instruction in domestic science. HOW (Hll.DliK \ ARE PLACED After a child lias been relinquished to the Home and hai with us a suitahle length of time that we may understand him. we find a home for him that we feel that he will fit into. As a rule it would l&gt;e an injustice to the child and an imposition on the pe who receive him, if he were placed at once. It is seldom that we have to recall a child under ten years, or have one returned I It is our experience that it is a detriment to the child to have him returned so we exercise the greatest precaution in placing them. In - deed I have placed these children just as conscientiously as I would place my own under the same conditions. I have acted as state agent in looking after these children in homes which work really ought to be given over to the clerk of the state hoard of charities. Most of the homes in which our children are placed are the finest in the state, and many of the children planed are very promising. Recommendations are required from four responsible persons, who are familiar with the home life of the parties applying for a child and can vouch for them as lieing moral, upright people and financially able to care for a child. These recommendatian - investigated by the Superintendent and if satisfied that they are all right the child is placed on four months trial. If after visiting the </seg>
            <seg id="p012">356 iie of t he footer parents, everything ia found satisfactory, ■ re - uislnnent from the Home u given and t he application for adop - is filed with the county judge. The parent- are as proud of child adopted as any parents are &lt;&gt;f their own child. " 1 never to thank God for our beautiful ltal&gt;e ". writes one mother. " We d not live without our little one", writes another. It u ifying to know that a good home is found for the little one*. ioneil and shaped by no will of their own And helple.-slv into life's history thrown." urii Mlllllll Our school is organized into six grades and the school work will compare favorably with the work done in any of our school.-. Our school room is inadequate to supply the needs of our children, ave the kindergarten and primary classes from nine A. If. till M. when the grade pupils march in the and primary Our grades remain in school until four o'clock with \ception of the noun hour. We have a daily attendance of Our school work is graded to correspond with the grade. - in the city schools. When a child leaves our school he has no dif - ficulty in keeping his grades on entering other schools. The boya and girls attend school together and eai together hut in other re - live apart, under separate governess)-. Two of our children - hool for the Blind at Nebraska Citv but return to us King vacations. We have had a number of books sent to us from city library, which added to our collection, makes a nice lii ehooL The children are indeed grateful for the kindness Tided to them. Many of our children are fond of music ami display much talent in this direction. Our Sunday School is held in the school room at 'clock A. M. The superintendent, teacher, bookkeeper and in this service. The afternoon service is held at I*. II. with ion from the young people's societies of the different churches in the citv as instructors. The children enjoy these meetings very much and become greatly attached to the kind young people who give them so much of their time and thought. t Before concluding I would ask your support in the matter of ining an appropriation for a new school building for the Home perienee during the past three I th'it the union of the twit d*i "-^ ■ f rhil iroi n liwivp </seg>
            <seg id="p013">357 be 1 K-st interests of either. ■ from the Hospital and wi The Home should be entireh li our children out of the hospital building there would b&lt; nough for the hospital to entirely itution could furnish the heat, as and still the institution; would be maintain themselves. Our ins the penitentiary does the light, independent of each oth&lt; I wish to express my appreci ion of tin and employee who have labored faithfullv and in this wa\ tuted much to the success of the institution. No ntial to the i uccevful management of an institution as loval and are in perfect accord with each lo our matron, Mrs. Anna M iindy, am I indeed grateful; she 11 in all thai pertained to the l&gt;est its looked after her departments take pleasure in assuring her of upported me faithfully and wt welfare of our institution. She h carefully and economically and 1 my appreciation of her service. ing h( I Dr. Mabel Dunn, who was appointed physician to the Home Governor Ceo. I,. Sheldon, lias been skillful and painstaking in management of the sick and has won the affection of the little in the Home who eagerly look forward to her daily visi §1 extend thanks also to our Advisory Hoard for their Co advice and their kindly interest in all that pertains to our work ii- work the Home. Their words of cheer have often thinned or lifted clouds that come into the lives of tho e who are helping to carry woes of others, and for every word of encouragement I am pro - ldlv grateful. t\Ve are indebted also to the merchants and citizens of Lincoln their kind remembrances of the orphaned ones from tin '. and to the young people from the various churches in the city all who have assisted us in our work I extend my hearty ac- K'ledgement and sincere thanks. tl wish also to express my appreciation of the confident ur work by my retention and reappointment by his excellency. rge L. Sheldon, Governor. I have endeavored to serve him to best of my ability by administering the affairs of the institution manner that would meet his approval and reflect credit on his inistration. To you. gentlemen of the Board of Public Land.- and Buildings, do I owe a debt of gratitude for sustaining me in the management Khful employee and officers wh&lt; ■f. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">358 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT of the institution. \&lt;&gt;u have given me freedom to carry on what- I thought best for the pood of the Home. Our relations have been cordial and pleasant and I shall ever carry with me kindly recollections of your courtesy and cooperation in extending the work of this great charity. Res|&gt;ect fully submitted, Mrs. Kmma ('. Johnston, Superintendent. PHYSICIANS KKl'ORT I became physician to the Home for the Friendless April 1st, Just previous to this a few cases of diphtheria had developed within the institution. Fumigation and quarantine had brought it partly under control and thentwo or three cases which occurred soon ;it once quarantined and antitoxin given. Then were no fatal Fumigation was used wherever there was a possibility of ruination and after a few weeks we were free from the di- In August of that year a l&gt;al&gt;e was brought to the "nursery suffering from whooping cough. This is a very serious disease with infants an«l. either alone or complicated by the summer digestive disorders, was responsible for the death of nine babies. During the early spring of HH)S chicken pox developed among the children, the source of infection l&gt;eing unknown. Nearly all the children had the disease but there were no serious results. Again in April. IMS, om of the older children in the nursery developed diphtheria, the source ritagion l&gt;eing undeterminable. The nursery was quarantined and each child and nurse given a minimizing dose of antitoxin. The • rv was fumigated after the ]&gt;eriod for quarantine expired but the night nurse two weeks later l&gt;ecame ill with the disease, she having doubtless harbored the bacillus in her throat during this period of time, and the minimizing dose which she received l&gt;eing in - sufficient to l&gt;e quite effective. A child which had come to the rv after the period of quarantine became infected from this \gain the nursery was quarantined and the minimizing doses repeated. This is the last case we had of diphtheria. During the early summer of 1908, several of the older children developed mumps; source of infection unknown. The children of the nursery escaped this disease and although there were about thirtv cases in the institution we had no seriou that </seg>
            <seg id="p015">359 HOMK FOR THK FRIENDLESS. LINCOLN 1 1 in** we have had no contagious diseases. Except these infei diseases and the summer disorders of infancy, the children have been quite healthy considering existing condition The problem of more room is the serious one which confronts us. The capacity of the nursery is 4845 cubic feet. It is • well established fact that to retain goad health each individual requires one thousand feet of well ventilated space. Babies especially need an abundance of fresh air, so in a room which should not ac - commodate more than five babies we have always from fifteen to twenty-five. The bath room opens directly into the nursery as also the room in which the milk is prepared for use. Thi :i very unhygienic arrangement. Therefore, a larger and more modern nursery is greatly needed. We should also have a special room for the sick that they might lie at once removed from the nursery, both for their own good and that of those who are well. Also a place of detention for children when received until it is evi - dent that they have or will develop no disease of a contagious nature. We also need a special room or rooms for quarantining con - ns diseases. An extra employe would l&gt;e required to can children in detention or quarantine but the saving of expense to the would more than compensate even if we do not consider the lives of the children. Such improvements would greatly enhance our success in the care of infants. The boys' apartments are also crowded but in spite of this the children have l»een quite healthy. tl wish to express my thanks to the physicians and nurses of the lopedic Hospital for the kind offer of the operating room and r assistance in emergencies. Dr. Orr performed several n operations upon the children of the Home. T ! always been gratis and lv appreciate </seg>
            <seg id="p016">360 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPOHT HOME FOB THE FRIENDLESS Ueport for the Hienniutn. beginning December 1st and ending November 30th, 190S ■ \MI RE&lt; El I'T~ I'.MKi I, By Balance, cash on hand $26* 00 lothing ami care of children 113 1907 tDoiiat ions, sale of hog.-, clothing and cart 1 of chil - draa _'oi . 75 Clothing and care &lt;&gt;f children 89 50 Cinders, r-ale of hogs, clothing and care of children 12S :l Cinders, clothing aad care of children, -ti 50 lothing ad care af children 117 00 June I'av patients in Orthopedic Hospital, clothing and care of children 1 12 50 July Cinders, clothing and can- of children. . 58 )•"&gt; Aug. Cinders, clothing and carp of children ( .l4 _'5 lothing and care of children 70.00 lothing and care of children. . . lb'tMK) lothing and care of children... 51.55 Clothing and care of children .. 108 00 Jan. Old iron, clothing and care of children 4'.' 00 iothinp and can 1 of children.. 14 &lt;&gt;&lt;) (•thing and care of children... :i6.(M) 1 Cinders, clothing and care of children.. . . 39 75 tl Warrant for maintenance from Orthopedic Ho pttal . . 3,474 56 May Clothing and care oi children 56 00 June Sale of hogs, clothing and care of children July Clothing and care of children... 76.00 July State warran iperintendent 9.96 July State warrant N to superintendent.... 16 59 Aug. Clothing and care of children... 7(i 00 Aug. State warrant No. 614, to superintendent. ... 16.15 lothing and care of children.. 41. IX) warrant N iperintendent . .., /"\ 'II' I'll Ji"\ / ki\ </seg>
            <seg id="p017">361 BOME Kon THK FRIENDLESS, LINCOLN Warrant for maintenance from Orthopedic H pita] 19.18 Nov. Cinders, clothing and care of children.. U\ 00 t. Warrant for maintenance from Orthopedic Hos - pital 2,00 &gt; Total 110,51 Total expended . I, 1908, bv balance cash $1,917 7.1 EXPENDED I'M Hi 1. Cash paid for two pigs 4. Traction Company for car tickets.. Dec ."&gt;. Nebr. Paper A Rag Co., for school hooks and tablet* •'). Miller A Paine for six handkerchiefs, (child 15, Mrs. Marv Cokelv for .'? chickens 1 o."i Dec. 1"). Franklin Ice Cream Co., for ice cream 111 is. J. H. Foreman for apples, 121 l&gt;u. at 60c per bu.. !)»■&lt;■. Is. Carl Plenz for fresh vegetables, 2 bu. sweet po- tatoes at i.")c. ."&gt; bu. parsnips at 50e, 2 dm. cabbage at 20c, 2 gal. kraut at 20c t s " 20, Board of Education for school hooks _' 05 20, Sutter-Henry Co.. for Christmas tree and holly 1.15 22. Farmers Grocery Co., for Christmas nuts.... I 82 Dee. 22. Wagner A Walt, for Christmas turkey 22 lbs. at 20c 1 td 24. Traction Co., for car tickets.... .. 5.00 24. F. W. WoolworthA Co., for candy, rubber goods and toys for Christmas . 3.20 Postage stamp- 5.00 Dec. 31, Traction Co., for car tickets bought Sept. 14. . 2 00 1«M&gt;7 Jan. 2. Nebr. Electrical Co., for repairs as per hill on hie 8.78 Jan. :■!. Sloss Bros., for papering parlor. $ 1 1.00, mould- ing. 70c. patching. $5.30 17 (Ml Jan. 7. Nebr. Pap. for tab 1 *;:&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p018">362 Jan. 7. Postage due 7. Rudge &amp; (luenzel for invalid chair to In* paid from donation. 24 (M) 7. C. H. I. k P. H. K. Co., for \ fare to Fairhury, sending child to Home. Dec. l*t. 1906...... H Jan. 7. Money Order &amp; Sunday School Supplies, St. Louie Depository . . 1 . !KS Jan. 8, Fannen Meat Co., for 59| Ib. turkey at I8e iV lbs. chicken at l()c for Thanksgiving 15.60 Jan. 10. J. H. Foreman for 11 bu. apples at H0&lt; 6. 60 Jan. 10. Traction Co., for car ticket- 5.00 Jan. 10. Sutter-Henry Co., for fruit 1 .30 Jan. 14, Worrel Mfg. Co.. Sedalia. Mo., for disinfectant 30.00 Jan. 14. Holconib Mfg. Co., for brushes for toilets, floor. etc 18.06 Jan. 16. Paul Dybbro for oysters for the sick... 1.05 Jan. 16. (ilol&gt;e Delivery Co., for drayage Jan. 16. Farmers Grocery Co., for celery and fruit . .. 2 27 Jan. 16. St. Louis Depository for Sunday School Song Books &amp; money ord&lt; 8.30 Jan. 18, Applegate Chemical Co.. Chicago, for indel- ible ink. J pint 2 . .V&gt; Jan. IV Nebr. State Journal Co., for help advertisement Jan. 21, Western Union Tel. Co., for telegram 27 Jan. 21, Lincoln Transfer Co.. for freight A: drayage. 1 .&lt;&gt;."&gt; Jan. 21. Mayer Bros., for 2 suits at $8.9."). 8 pair pant* at 5Qe, 4 ■toekinj 50c, 8 pair mittens at 25c, Discount. %\ .:&gt;&lt;). 14.81 Jan. 21. Rudge A: duenzel Co., for (HM set casters Jan. 22. H. H. Hetz. for 41 bo. corn at 35c per bu 14.8.') Jan. 24. Mr. Baker, for hauling hogs to market . 1.50 Jan. 24. Rudge A; (iuenzel Co.. for two pattern.- . .80 Feb. 4. Krnst Hoppe for two sleds . .... 1.80 B4. Postage stamp- ."i.OO 4. Traction Co., for car ticket- ."&gt;.00 4. H. Herpolsheimer Co.. for infant's vesta 1.12 18. The Cash Grocery Co.. for fruit 1:15 ■oper &amp; Cole Bros., for packing k lacing.. 2.70 ■oper &amp; Cole Bros., for repairs for engine room 2 . 87 Feb. 1."). V. \\ Woolworth iV Co., for looking glass, etc 1 ,4."&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p019">363 lit. J. H. Foreman, for 12 bu. apple.- ;it 60c per bu. ST.Jii Iel&gt;. '22. The Peoples Stun* for cloaks blankets, shawl- i\: siirls 16.68 cloaks 16.68 If eh. (i. Globe Delivery Co., t'&lt;&gt;r drayage . l.s:&lt; If eh. (i. Globe Delivery Co., for drayage . 1 . s:&lt; If eh. li. Globe Delivery Co., for drayage If eh. li. Globe Delivery Co., for drayage Mcli. 6, Gettier Meat Market for 60 11). turkey at J(U-. for Christmas 12.00 Mcli. (&gt;. (iettier Meat Market for f&gt;() 11). turkev at 20c. for Christmas 12.00 Mch. &lt;i. Traction Co., for car ticket- 5.00 Mcli. ti. Traction Co., for car ticket- 5.00 If eh. ii. Postage stamps .Veto Itch. ii. Postage stamp*. .Veto Mch. ti. \el&gt;r. Taper &amp; Bag (V. for tablet.- Mch. ti. Nebr. Taper &amp; Bag Co.. for tablet.- If eh. 7. Armstrong Clothing Co., fi&gt;r •"&gt; caps at 20c. * 1 .00 J suits of clothes at $1 S4. $:{.tis. 3 suits of clothes at 12.00, *(&gt;.(H) 10.68 If eh. 7. Armstrong Clothing Co., for 5 caps at 20c. * 1 .00 . . 2 suits of clothes at $1 .S4. f^.tis. 3 suits of clothes at $2.00, *&lt;&gt;.&lt;&gt;0 10.68 Mch. S, \\ . A. Doggett for repairing sewing inachini Mch. S, W. A. Doggett for repairing sewing niachini Mch R, Warner i\: Becknian for hahy moccasins. NOc. 1 Mch S. Warner iV- Beckinan for baby moccasins, site 1 s pair shoes. SI . 7."&gt;, 1 pair misses shoes. SI ,:i.'&gt; Mch S. Miller it Paine for A girls' cloaks at S.1.00 (in s Feb. 15.00 Mcli. 12. F W. \\ iiolwort h iV Co., for intise a- per l)ill on file 2 « •"&gt; Mch. 12. J. H. Foreman for Ml bu. apples at liOc per l&gt;u Mcli. 15, Globe Delivery Co., for dray age .25 Mch. 20, H. L. Spencer for hauling refuse 5.00 Mch. 20. Adams Express Co Mch. 29, Griswold Seed Co., for garden seed. S.55 Mch. 29, Frank E. Lahr for wheel-barrow $2.00. 1 12-in. file. 25c, plumbers hammer, 80c, 100 ft. gar - den hose. $14.00. I set flat irons. $1 . 15, flower seed 30e, 3 garden hoes. $1 .."&gt;() Mcli. 29, Nebr. Hardware Co., for oil can 35c, rake handle 20c. snow shovel, 60e 1.15 Mch. 2'.t. Mayor Bros., for 9 children's summer suits 11.88 Mcli. 29, Nebr Paper A Bag Co.. for hooks, pencils, etc. Mch. 20. Rudge it (iuenzel Co.. for hardware as per hills on file. (Aug. 1906 to March 1907) SI. 46 Mch. -W. Mrs. Kirkpatrick for 1 doz. hens and 1 cockerel 9.00 Mch. 30. Money Order to St. Louis for Sunday School Supplies. . . 1.50 Mch. SO. Melick'sStables for livery hire from Nov. 1, 1906 i i .,..,- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">364 :: i .-, 1 10 (ilol&gt;e Delivery Co., for drayag&lt; Street car tickets 1(1.00 Postage stamps 2(1. on Griswold Co., for garden 1(1 10 K. H. fare to Omaha and return $2.00, hack 50c dinner 50c, street car fare 20c, taking baby 3.50 1 11 April 11 April 12 April 12 April 15 Gold A Co.. for bal. due on account Lincoln Carpet Cleaning Co., for cleaning carpet H. L. Spencer for plowing Home lot- 00 Mrs M K. Davey for rent of eight lots for 1 year H. L. Spencer for plowing «V harrowing lots i:&gt;.oo (eight) .-,(1 April 15 April 15 F. E. I.ahr for axe. hatchet saw i\: saw buck. Applegate Chemical Co., for \ Ib. indelible ink 1)0 $4..-&gt;o. money order, 5c April !.") April 15 Kudge A: (iuenzel Co., for 2 carpel beat Nebr. Taper A: Bag Co., for school pencils A pens Globe Delivery Co., for dra; Globe Delivery Co., for dra Harry Porter for 1 box clip April 15 April 27 Mav » ;:■: Kudge &amp; (iuenzel for 5 caps, *1 .90, I boll tape 10c 20 WCstern Union Tel. Co., for telegram to Mahas - ka. Ka: 20 Johnson A: I.ind for fruit l.o:, Krnst Hoppe for potato masher Kudge iV (iuenzel for 2 skeins yarn May 21 10 10 Mav 23 Kudge &amp; (iuenzel for H yard hair ribbon Frank E. Lahr for stove pipe dampen Trickey for two lenses 53 Mav 23 20 24 Express pkg. from Chicago. Hoc, money oraei &gt;c I June 15 Svitter-Henrv Co. for lettuce &lt;S; radishe- Kudge \- (iuenzel for two patterns Globe Delivery Co., for drayage . Globe Delivery Co., for drayage . ]•'. \V. Woolworth &amp; Co., for towel rack A holts K. K. ticket to Minersville. Nebr. for inmate Traction Co., for street car tickets ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p021">365 JSt. Louis Depository for Sunday 8c leave- Globe Delivery Co., for drayage. Sundav School lesson 13, I 1.30 leaves s (llobe Delivery Co., for Globe Delivery Co., for I 18, is, is. 27, is. Globe Delivery Co., for drayage.. 12 is. H. HerpolsheiinerCo.. for 2 yards ea H. Herpolsheimer Co., for 2 yards calico at 6c F. W. Woolworth ft Co., for rubber goods A rib- .'7. F. W. Woolworth A: Co., for rubber | bon 2.05 bon 27, L. M. Russell for fruit trees. (State (i. American 1&gt; Co., for express &lt; L. II. Russell for fruit trees. (8tate Warrant | American 1&gt; Co., for express char© John Spanton for cultivating lota 20. IM) s 27 10. John Spanton for cultivating lots. 2.00 I 10, Harry Poifjer for letter Hie F. W. Wiolworih ft Co.. for two dust pans H. Herpolsheimer Co. for 1 iloz. infants' shirts Rudge A (iuenzel Co., for screen door hooks \V. A. Doggett for sewing machine supplies Day Rubber Co., St. Louis, rubber goods for 20 10, F. W. Wiolworih \- Co., for two 10, H. Herpolshe'nner Co. for 1 doz. inl 10, Rudge iS: C.uenzel Co., for screen d&lt; 10. \V. A. Doggett for sewing machine b rDay Rubber Co., St. Louis, rubbe nursery (&gt;. Jennings ft Graham, K. ('.. mow ■ &gt; nursery Jennings ft Graham, K. ('.. money order for Sunday School Journal k Sunday School Journal. . 1, Armstrong Clothing Co., for boya 13, Mrs. M. McKlroy for girls' hats.. 16, Oliver Typewriter Co., for typewi is. .1. A. Witter for hauling and cult IS. Henry Yeith Co.. for tomatoes 20, Jacob Ritsch for cleaning grease tra] 23, Rudge &lt;$; (iuenzel Co.. for two lamps 25, John Burke, interest on money 1 J3 Armstrong Clothing Co.. for boys' pant Mrs. M. McKlroy for girls' hats. 16 50 Oliver Typewriter Co.. for typewriter ribbon J. A. Witter for hauling and cultivating 6 50 Henry With Co.. for tomatoes Jacob Ritsch for cleaning grease traps Rudge A GuenielCo., for two lamps . . John Burke, interest on money borrowed for purchase of lot purchase of lot rlir. Berkey, car fare to and from C doing carpenter work for Horn 27. Chapman Drug Co.. for 1 pair cr 27. City Garbage Co. for hauling.. 28. Cash for money orders to Broken 1 Mr. Berkey. car fare to and from Capitol, when doing carpenter work for Home is Chapman Drug Co., for 1 pair erutche City Garbage Co. for hauling 3 Cash for money orders to Broken Bow and Mil - ford.. 10 ford. . 2(1. Carl I'lenz for fresh vegetables a 29. Leader Department Store for infan etc 1, Chapin Brothers for plants. Leader Department Store for infants' Reubens, etc ."&gt; 25 1Z li. 6, 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">366 I. AM) COMMISSIONER'S HKI'ORT cm Union Tel. Co., for telegram to Hardy. Nebraska 10 (HI 3 tin 1 no Nebr. Hardware Co., for scythe B. (V- M. R. U. Co. for fare to Beatrice and return Sl.fiO. dinner. 50c. to visit child as per n _M() 1 .50 :; 00 1 Voucher drawn on cash fund with State Trea urer for A. I). Benwav Co I.ivery hire for trip in country to visit child 15 Money order sent in June to St. Louis Deposi- tory for Sunday School Supplies 1.4«» :{. 1' 1(1. (M) 10.50 Silver. Burdette A Co., Chicago, for ri Ward Primers, and monev order I 85 Longmans, Green A: Co., N. Y.. for 1 doi spell - ing books and money ordei 3 S, Columbia Meat Market for spring chicken. 13, GriswoU Seed Co.. for garden seed IS, Traction Co. for street car tickets 15. Gold &lt;!t Co.. for four pair blankets... Franklin lee Cream Co., for ice cream for July 4th 16. A. K. tonkins, for street car tickets I.C. Kly for 1 dry mops. ■'"' \f*Kr H ;ird \vm rt* i 'i » fiir fu*i.'tki&gt; 28 ceipts on file Homer Gooding for 1 bu. a|&gt;pl&lt; v Paine for infanta' wool shirt r-. 1. Chapman Drug ('&lt;&gt;.. for corrosive sublimate 1. Voucher drawn on cash fund with State Trea urer for Nebraska Paper A Bag ('&lt; 3 A. F. W. \\ nolworth &amp; Co., for cruets, vases, etc 3, ('. M. Barnetl for bota 3 :\. Mayer Urns., for boya' clothing :i. 2 sets drawing earda. 4. H. o. Knltz. for piano tuning tizens H. R. Co., for street car ticket&gt; B, Homer Gooding for 4o bu. potatoes at '.•(&gt;&lt;■ per bushel. 23 24 •_»-}. D.C. Heath. Publishers. Chieago, for6 Rmwlen </seg>
            <seg id="p023">367 HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS, LINCOLN Sept. _'•"). St. Louis Depository for Sunday School Sup- plies and money order... SI 50 26, Harry Porter for 1 letter file. 35c, and 1 box car- bon paper, $:?.5&lt;) Sept. 2(i. American Book Co., school hooks.. f. 26, Kxpress on 1 dot. language It . 29, Harry Porter for \ dot. boxes crayola ."&gt;. (lus Ango for 8 doi. bananas 12. Western l"nion Tel. Co., for telegrams Sept. 29, Harry Porter for \ dot. boxes crayola 1 (Ml 77 12. .]. \\ . Moore for 1 basket tomatoes. 95c, 13 squash, $1.95... Oct. 12. Lincoln Traction Co for car ticker 5 &lt;M) Oct. 12. Pacific Kxpress Co., for express on school books Oct. 12. The Parke Grocery Co., for celery. 50e, grapi tide, butter. 73c Oct. 12, Citizens K. R. Co., for car tickets. I 50 I"). H. H. fare to David City and return, to visit child 1.88 22. Rudge &amp; (uienzel Co., for pail. SI . 10, clothes rack. $1 25. . Oct. 24. R. R. fare and livery hire to visit child A Hi Oct. 25, ('. A. Tucker for repairing 4 clocks. 4 (H) Oct. 31, The Sterling for Brownie suits, $2 . 70, 3 waist $1.35 4.05 Nov. 1. F. W. Woolworth A Co., for curtain bands. 50c 1 doz. mouse traps. $1.20 1 7u Nov. 1. Ma!&gt;el Nichols for teacher's manual 1 05 Nov. 8, John Spanton for plowing out potatoes. 1.25 Nov. 8, Chapman Drug Co., for fish food Nov. ( .t. George Barnett for 58 heads cabbage 1 90 Now 9, Kdward Sizer. postage, stamps Nov. !&gt;. Nebr. State Journal for advertising Nov. K). Samuel Lewis for 5 gal. alpine wax varnish and spreader s 7.') N&lt;&gt;\. 13, Nebr. Paper &amp; Bag Co., for school supplies. Nov. 27. H. Herpolsheinier Co., for oj yards fringe 1 .31 Nov. 27. Armstrong Clothing Co., for 5 suits clothing 13.98, 7 waists. 12.84, 2 pair pants. $1.50 Total 118.32 Discount 1* lfi*~n </seg>
            <seg id="p024">(D COMMISSIONER'S UKI'ORT 368 1. Western Union Tel. Co., for telegrams (Oct. 15 $(&gt;.-&gt;&lt;&gt; 1 American Book Co., balance on account, school hooks 94 1. Midland Chemical Co., (Dubuque, La.) disin - fectant and sprayer L3.25 1. ('. H. Five, rose plants for greenhouse... 1. ('. H. Five, rose plants for greenhouse 1. Lincoln Drug Co.. for weights for drug-room e 1. Lincoln Drug Co.. for weights for drug-roon Je 1. Payne A lx*ek. three mattresses 1. Lincoln Journal for advertising for help 1. Payne A lx*ck. three mattresses 1 1 i M i 1. Lincoln Journal for advertising for help M) 2, Tlie Sterling. L boy's suit, S3. 45, 1 cap. Joe. 1 2. The Sterling. I boy's suit, $3. 45, 1 cap. Joe. 1 cap. 50c, "&gt; shirt waists. 12 •")() cap, 50c, "&gt; Bhirt waists, $_&gt; •")() 2, H. Berpolsheimer Co.. 1 child's pattern I.", 2, Beekman Bros., repairing 8 pair shoes, half soles and heel:-. . . Armstrong Clothing &lt; '".. for 5 caps bought in ( tetobet Armstrong Clothing Co., -' pair pants. -&lt;1 .00 ami 1 hoy's suit. ?_' ♦&gt;•• 2. Beckman Bros., repairing 8 pair shoe half soles and heels. . . 4 25 _' Armstrong Clothing Co., for •"&gt; cape bought in Oetobei 2. Armstrong Clothing Co.. 2 pair pants. -&lt;1 .00 and 1 hoy's suit. $2 ♦)•• !5 _'. Hall Bros., for mdse., boughi Nov. _'7 «. W. H. Sawdon. 550 lbs. cabbage and 2 bushels onions.. . . ?:2 6. J. S. IfcGowen, for carting away 2 loads refuse. Hardy Furniture Co.. for 1 rugs for governess' room ! . S. IfcGowen, for carting away 2 loads refuse 7. Hardy Furniture Co.. for 2 rugs for governea room 10.00 7. Lincoln Traction Co., for car tickets is. Lincoln postottice. postage stamps 1, Woolworth £ Co., Christmas candy, $2.00, toys, 85c 2 . 85 2s. RudgC A (iuenzel Co., fruit jars. 30e, sauce-pan. 33e, covered pails. SI .40. 1J doz. girls' caps. $3.00 .") . OH \pplegate Indelihle Ink Co., (Chicago; Indel - ihle ink. 15 4. lk'ckman Bros., repairing shoe 4. Buffalo Specialty Co for Lightning Bread 1 1 . 20 Cutter </seg>
            <seg id="p025">369 .1 11 1 steeper. 7~&gt;c. nut me 1 flour sifter rater. l()c So ■ &gt; "j lees for Christmas I 14. Grawold Seed Co.. lettuce A radish seed A. I). HenwayCo.. looking glasses for bath rooms N. Salsburv for oiling school room floor. Hall Bros., for 3 large pot covers made to order The Lincoln Traction Co., for car tickets bought 17. 17. 21, II i :::: in November, 1907 The Lincoln Traction Co., for car tickets Miller &amp; Paine for towel roller. '20c 6 wooden :!:::: ;: ap trays, tide si. 7(1 !■!: chiefs and bead Conductor bolts. l()c. chimney thim - rakes. $2. 1") Id Carl I'lenz for butchering 2 hogs F. W. Woolworth. curtains and cloak form 1 in 10 /•) 10. (M) 10.00 ) Postage stamps Lincoln Traction Co., for car tickets .!. II. Bari for fresh made hominy. 7 gals, at J0&lt; 3 13 s gallon Mch . April April April 17 .1 II. (iagan for sink pump J. S. licGowan for plowing 17 V. U. Forbes for harrowing and plowing Voucher for incidentals 1.50 M) 111.20 :w Voucher for sodding .-).&lt;&gt;&lt;) M) Voucher for perfecting title on new lots (i7 . .")() M) \V. C. Wilke for patterns J. \V. Moore for vegetable .CO :&lt;o .(&gt;() .so Rudge &amp; Guehxel for 1 wash bowls '.•."&gt; 1 erearawhip, IO&lt;-. 4 lemon aqueesere, 40c .50 Franklin Ice Cream ( napkin rings, 90c, 6 w Discount :;l 1. Kudge iV: Cucnzcl for side combe for Christmas I. H u&lt; l^r*' ft (iuciizcl. I dnz. children's handker- "A. Armstrong Clothing ('&lt;&gt;.. ■&lt; buys' suits clothing. .■&gt;. Citizens Railway, car ticket:-. H. &lt;1. Schmaasen Frank E. Lahr, stove l&gt;le. 10c. :i garden </seg>
            <seg id="p026">370 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 4 to Weeping Water. Falls City. Haddam. Kans . and Fairhury. 112.34, hackl and drives. $1.00 21 W. A. Doggett for machine needles 29 A. Flanagan for school hooks. 90.82, money order. Be ■z K. H. Sizer for ] stamp*. . John Spanton for plowing and cultivating 14. John Spanton for plowing and cultural 11. Kxpress on school books from Chicago IS, Indelible ink. J pint.. Chicago . . 17. Traction Co., for street car ticket 23, Sunday School Supplies. St. Louis 23, Money order 2H. Kxpense visiting children in homes . . . 24. Cash paid on aged woman's ticket to .' 24. Drayage. Miss Hlodgett's trunk to depot 2."). 2 toilet paper holders. 10c each. A carpet h I 17 Traction Co., for street car ticket Sunday School Supplies. St. Louil 23 Money order 23 .05 23 Expense visiting children in home? J4 Cash paid on aged woman's ticket to Ashury Park, N. .1 . .-).(K) Drayage. Miss Hlodgett's trunk to depot 2 toilet paper holders. 10c each, 3 carpet heaters 10c each Amount drawn from Institution Cash Fund for maintenance in June 1 W7 25, Amount paid L. ('. Dybbro for work done on new addition 195.09 :*. K. R. Sizer for postage stamp? 17. Mrs. M. Davev for rent of l&gt; lots 20, hrisman for drayage Demaree for apples 20. 20, T. L. (llennen for $ bushel peaches The People Store for hlankets 4.13 20, Amount drawn from Institution Cash Fund for maintenance in Julv 1,052.04 1 Western Union Tel. Co.. for telegrams (ilol&gt;e Delivery Co., for dray:;-. Caning (i dining-room chairs and rockers Repairing and upholstering '.i rockei- Fred Hvons for corn Chapman Drug Store, whiting Mrs. Oll&gt;erg for house-cleaning John Spanton for drayage F. \Y Woolworth for dolls and toys 3, 4.50 10. .50 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">371 r2\K Traction Co., for ear tick. 29. E. R. Sizer for postage stamp $10. (K) 10.00 Aug. 29, Amount drawn from Institution Cash Fund for maintenance for August. 1.097.73 30, Amount drawn from Institution t'a«h Fund foi maintenance for September 1,209.26 Oet. 30, Amount drawn from Institution Cash Fund for 1.272.40 maintenance for October Oct. 19, Mrs- Olberg for house cleaning. . 1 .25 1 . 25 Nov. 30, Amount drawn from Institution Cash Fund for maintenance for November 1,225.16 Nov. 30, Amount drawn from Institution Cash Fund for maintenance for November 1.225. Id IPPBOPBIATIONH K&lt;)h THE BIENNIAL PEBIOD ENDINti MABCB 31, 1909 Amount 1909 Amounl Appropriation expended to Balance for 1907 Dec 1. 190s Dec. 1. 1906 Appropriation expended to Balance for 1907 Dec 1. 1908 Dec. 1. 1908 Officers 1 salary 800.00 16,309.64 11,290.36 Officers' salary S7.60O.O0 16,309.64 11,290.36 7,500.00 8,983. 20 516.80 Employes' wagea 7,500.00 6,983.20 516.80 Employes' vagi Maintenance 17,000.00 15,474.13 1,525.87 17.000.00 15,474.13 1,525.87 Maintenance School iV chapel supplies t travelling expenses 4(K).(M) l titv . 2:w.:&gt;.i School iV chapel supplie t travelling expenses 400.00 Hid. 45 233.55 &gt;:VA . 55 Repairs. 3,000.00 2,79."). 47 204.53 3,000.00 2,795.47 204.53 ESTIMATE APPBOFBIATION K()K THE BIENNIAL PEBIOD FBOH \PK1I 1&gt;11MA II. IPPBOPBIATION K()K THE BIENNIAL PEBIOD FBOM \PK1I. 1. 1909 TO MAK( H .U. 101 1 1. 1909 TO MABCB 31. 101 1 Officers' salaries Superintendent 100.01 Matron 1.200.0( Superintendent Matron $2,000.00 1.200.00 1,400.00 l'hysician. 1,400. W Head Nurse s 40 0( Engineer l.200.0( tsician. Teacher Head Nurse Engineer. 900.00 840.00 1,200.00 9.000.00 20.000.00 Employes' wage- 9.000. (X Maintenance.. 20,000. 0&lt; tiol SuppBea and travelling air and improvement 500.00 expenses 3.500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">372 HPCCI U. XI'l'KnPHlA TKIN- iid dormitory building.. 112,000.00 iid dormitory building.. 112,000.00 Furnishing for same 2,00 Furnishiiit: for same 2,00 \ Ice plant l.ooii mi ..KHMI.NI- MADE IN THE SEWING ROOM DKTKMBEH 1. I9O( ..KHMI.NI- HADE IN THE SEWING ROOM DECEMBER I, 1901 NOVEMBEB 30, 1906 NOVEMBER 30, MM Is nt~' slips nt~' slips tits' skirts SO nts' skirts SO 180 Infants' diapers 613 pads 23 drawers 5 (Jills' (1: 104 - night gowns - skirt&gt; . . . . -44 - aprons 5fl - under waists 47 Girls' drawers 73 iirt waists s' night shin- shirt waist suits Iti shirt waists 4 night dresse&gt; s 1 rearing saequM 5 1 1 Mull- '-'1 s nrrappers •"&gt; •lannel skirts . 7 muslin skirts . B Curtains 77 ,c cloths 28 .!.- . --'(') • 17 «-ls. heinniod -4 Pillow cases His 192 23 Iron holders -I" </seg>
            <seg id="p029">373 Towels, hemmed. 155 Fancy pillow covers 4 Wash cloths. Table spreads. Broom coven S Wall pockets. Wall pockets. Pillow ticks Pillow ticks Rubber aprons. Rubber aprons Night cups - Night caps Garments repaired l_\"&gt;4o Garments repaired 12,540 I \\\KI&gt; KKIIT ( VNNKl) K1UIT .lolly . glasses 270 Jelly, p. -'To Canned fruit, quarts Canned fruit, quarts Fruit butter, quarts. 177 Fruit butter, quarts 177 Fruit jam. quarts Fruit jam. quart! Sour pickles, gallons. -I « ■ i pickles, gallons. IN Sour pickles, gallons. i pickles, gallons. 1^ Mixed pickles, gallons.. Mixed pickles, gallons.. Tomato catsup, quarts. Tomato catsup, quarts. Chili sauce, quarts. Chili sauce, quarts. Tomato relish, gallons 1"! Tomato relish, gallons. 10 Spiced currents, quarts - 1 Spiced currents, quarts _ 1 Spiced plums, quarts. 25 Spiced plums, quarts Mince meat, gallons. Mince meat, gallons lard, pounds 1 •"&gt;( lard, pownd- 1"&gt;() Pork sausage, pounds l^ Pork sausage, pounds 4 N (•AH 1)1. \ I'Ki &gt; I) I December 1. 1906 to November 30, 1908 Beans, bushels . 14 -. bushels . 12 Corn, bushels 12 Cucumbers, bushels 8 Cabbage heads, dozen "ill Lettuce, bushels 1'otatoes. bushel. 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">374 Spinach, bushels 1 es, buaheli .it) Turnips, bushels 10 •i&gt;. bushels 12 bushels 5 bushel:- 4(1 HK-ll K CHII.DKKN IX THE HOME KilK THE KHIKX DLKSS HV COUNTIES \i;c.; County Male Female Women Butler . . 1 Cb« 3 3 1 ("olfax 1 _ a- 3 . &gt; Fillmore 1 1 1 Furnai 2 Hall 1 1 1 Harlai 1 Emm. l riiev 1 1 11 ."&gt; 1 • Hi 1 iha 1 Pawnee l Phelp&gt; 1 Willow . ._' 1 o -&gt; lers 3 43 26 6 No. of children in the Home Nov. 30, |«M 31 24 • reived since &lt;ls 75 '-' Total 129 M t placed in hoi!.- ~A 68 2 \ I deaths since N,.v HO. 1M6 13 16 1 I children in the home Nov. 30, 1906 43 25 I number of inmates in the home Nov. 30, IMS .4 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">375 lency, Governor George Lawson Sheldon ■ Sir- The Advisory Board of the Home for the Friendless have honor to submit the following report. ;is required by law. I In their judgment, one &lt;&gt;f the most pressing needs of t! • ition is more room. At present, the hoys dormitory and -&lt; n occupy the second floor of the Orthopedic Hospital building. i arrangement seems most unwise. Owing to illness of i le children in the hospital, the building should be comparatively from noise. This is impossible under the present arrangement. the best interests of both institutions, an absolute separation, ir as buildings are concerned, is advisable. We would strongly mmend the removal of the Home children from the Ortho] pital: granting the latter institution the use of the entire build - and the erection of a suitable brick building to be iol rooms and boys dormitory for the Home for the Frien I As there is a lack of sleeping quarters for the help, several of employes l&gt;eing obliged to sleep over the laundry anil boiler i. we would strongly urge an appropriation of 12.000, D estimate given by the State Architect, wherewith to re: finish the third floor or attic of the main building, putting in and water. This estimate includes the cost of remo&gt; few temporary partitions as are now in place there, to tin le barn, where rooms may l&gt;e made for storage or other purp i the additional rooms thus made in the main building, sutti good accommodation could be given all employes and ro used on lower floors for sleeping quarters, could U' used for needs of the children. tit is further recommended that the broken and il iture and other goods which now fill the barn and tin [l in the attic. l&gt;e sold. In order that the state may have full complete use of all buildings, it is urged that all officers and loves l&gt;e allowed to bring to the institution only such furniture an l&gt;e accommodated in the rooms actually occupied by them, that no space be granted for storage purposes other thai ks. § There should l&gt;e some provision made for an industrial or man - training department. These children are to battle with life l early age. and they should l&gt;e taught some trade or oecupt will fit them to become wage-earn. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">376 LAND COMMISSION KKS REPORT One i&gt;f the most important features of the work 0&lt; the Home, is the placing of the children in homes for adoption. Much care should W given to such placing, and a state agent, who could undivided attention to this work, is strongly reco in mended. No mtendent can successfully manage the Home, and at the same attend to the proper placing and subsequent watchful care of the children who are scattered by adoption over the state. Respectfully submitted. lilts. \Y. A. Woodward, President. Anna Rogers, Secretary. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>