<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  ALFALFA MANAGEMENT.</title>
               <date value="1911">1911</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OP THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXIII, Article V. ALFALFA MANAGEMENT. By C. W. Poosley. Distributed May 12, 1911. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. (the xoenti or the umiveiwitv.) E RABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, Pretident, Lincoln. RABLE WILLIAM O. WHITMORE, Valley. RABLE VICTOR O. LYFORD, Palls City. RABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. HONORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE PRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. THE 8TATION OFFICER8. SAMUEL AVERT, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director. ■ DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF. f:AD Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. Alway, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. Chase, B. Sc. M. E., Agricultural Engineering. Pugsley, B. Sc., Agronomy and Farm Management Smith, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. KQass, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. Haeckkr, B. Sc., Dairy Husbandry tifci Bruner. B. Sc., Entomology. B. Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. Sponsler, A. B., Forestry. ■■win H. Barbocr. Ph. D., Geology. SChatbubn, A. M., Highway Engineering. Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulture. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineering. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. Sxyder. M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation. North Platte. Him Venus W. Pool, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. Geoboe K. K. Link, S. B., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. R. S. Trumbuix, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. ■■win Hopt, B. Sc., Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). P. B. Barker. A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Boils). Ellis Rail. B. Sc. A., Assistant in Animal Husbandry. C. B. Lee, B. Sc. Assistant in Animal Husbandry. L. B. Sturdevant. A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology M. H. Swenk, A. M., Assistant in Entomology. T. A. KnssELBACH. B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy (Crops) R. P. Howard, B. Sc. in Agb.. Assistant in Horticulture. V. V. Westgate, A. M., Assistant in Horticulture. W. W. BtiRB, B. Sc, Assistant in Soils and Crops. North Platte; Assistant Agriculturist. Office Dry Land Agriculture, U. 8. Department of Agri - culture. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. Fritz Knorr, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Bubstation. Mitchell. 8. W. Pekin, Farm Superintendent. • M«8. Nelle S. Scott, A. B., Scientific Assistant. Seed Testing. • Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">ALFALFA MANAGEMENT BY C. W. PUGSLEY. In the few pages which follow, an effort will be made to give explicit instructions in regard to the seeding and care of alfalfa. We now have definite information that this useful plant is grown successfully in every county in the state. This does not mean that it can be grown successfully on every farm, for there are certain conditions under which it will not succeed. Sometimes these conditions can be remedied. The two principal causes of failure are poor preparation of the seed bed and competition of weeds. Other common causes are poor seed, lack of fertility, acid land, lack of inoculation, poorly drained land, and lack of moisture. The first six can be controlled by the farmer, and the last two can be largely influenced by him. Wherever it has been demonstrated that alfalfa can be grown successfully, the farmer should grow an acreage large enough to work well in a desirable rotation, and to supply a portion of the roughage needed for the farm animals. I oil. — Any well-drained soil, neither acid nor strongly alka - and containing a fair supply of organic matter, will grow fa. Any land which will produce a good yield of corn will )und ideal. Ground upon which water stands is not desir land. Only soils which have been cropped for a long term ?ars are likely to be acid. Where this condition exists, it be corrected by liming. Alfalfa will grow on rather poor , but will always succeed better on the richer lands. There Id be sufficient plant food to give the plants a good start. Bl'L 1-2 ' AGR EXP STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XXIII. ART. V </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 On the poor lands this can be obtained by the addition of manure. In the drier sections of the state moderate applica - tions only of manure should be made. In such cases, it is prob - able that well-rotted manure is the best. Seed Bed. — Success in getting a stand of alfalfa depends very largely upon the preparation of the seed bed. A poor seed bed probably has caused more failures than any other one factor. An ideal seed bed is rarely found. Its preparation is rather a simple matter, but the steps must be taken at the proper time, and should commence several years in advance. Organic matter, largely added in the form of manure, is of the utmost importance. It must be thoroly mixed with the soil and there must not be a large amount of straw or trash. In most instances it is advis - able to disk before the land is plowed. This will prevent the accumulation of a layer of clods and coaree material in the bottom of the furrow, thus avoiding cutting off the supply of moisture. When the land is plowed, a harrow should follow immediately. There is no better time to break up the clods and save the moisture. This is best accomplished at the time of plowing by the use of an additional horse and one section of har - row, or by a small harrow or pulverizer fastened to the plow. If the land does not have sufficient time to become packed by the rains before seeding, a subsurface packer or a disk should be used. The disk well weighted should be set as straight as possible. This will firm the soil in the bottom of the furrows. Weeds should be kept down and a soil mulch maintained At seeding time the field should present the appearance of a well - prepared garden. In sandy sections of the state, alfalfa may be successfully seeded on breaking, and also on native sod. If the grass is thin and the soil is loose and of such a nature that plowing is not wise, the alfalfa may be drilled in the native grass. This, ordi - narily, is not to be recommended. Where cultivated crops can be grown it is much better to precede the alfalfa by these. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Where it is necessary to check the blowing of soil, it is wise to begin the preparation for alfalfa several years in advance. Manure should be added and stubble plowed under. The alfalfa may be seeded in cane, or small grain stubble, providing this is not too thick. In some instances, on lands which blow, good re - sults can be secured by seeding thinly a nurse crop of barley or some other small grain. The nurse crop should be cut at about the time the seeds are in the dough stage and should be cut high enough to miss most of the alfalfa. This will give some hay. if it has to be raked off, and will stop the growth of these plants at the right stage to save the most moisture. In most sections a nurse crop is not to be recommended. Ieed. — The very best seed obtainable should always be pur - id. It is seldom wise to buy an inferior quality because it eaper in price. The seed should be obtained several months e it is needed, and a sample sent to the Government Seed ratory, located at Lincoln, Nebraska. A free test will be I of the seed, which will show the kind and number of weed i and the per cent of germination. If less than 90 per cent e seeds will grow, or if it contains any dodder or many weed i of other kinds, the seed should be rejected. All seed Id be bought subject to test. It is better to obtain seed which has been produced under litions similar to, or more adverse than, those which exist re the seed is to be used. Seed should never be purchased i the South, and it is usually best to avoid seed grown nnder jation. For Nebraska conditions, seed grown on the Ne - ka divides or on the dry lands of Wyoming, Montana, or the otas will probably give the best satisfaction. One should be ain where the seed is grown, for the ability of the plant to tstand the winters depends largely upon the hardiness of plants which produced the seed. Amount of Sbbd. — It is customary to use about 20 pounds of seed to the acre. If the seed is good and if the land has been </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 properly prepared, this is more seed than is necessary. It takes more seed for broadcasting than for drilling. Some excellent stands have been secured by using as low as 10 pounds of seed to the acre, but. in these instances, conditions were ideal. In the eastern part of Nebraska from 15 to 20 pounds should be used: in the drier regions, from 10 to 15 pounds where hay is desired, and a less amount where it is to be used for producing seed. When alfalfa is to be seeded in rows, from 5 to 10 pounds should be used, depending upon the distance between the rows. Iethod of Seeding. — There are two general methods of seed - n use at the present time. The most common practice is to least. This is ordinarily done by an endgate, a hand or a lbarrow seeder. The best results are obtained where the is disked in such a manner that the ground is left rough ous to the seeding and then cross-harrowed to cover the i. Probably the best method in most places is to drill. A i drill covers all the seeds, and firms the soil around them, increasing the chances of a good germination. It must be remembered that the seed should not be covered too deeply. The proper depth depends somewhat on the nature of the soil. In sandy, loose soil, and soils which do not bake after a rain, the seeding can be deeper than in heavy soils. Or - dinarily, the seed should be placed about one inch deep. It should be remembered that the press drills leave the seed in small ditches. If a rain comes, these ditches are usually washed full of soil and this makes the depth, in many instances, too great. The young alfalfa plants grow slowly, and good stands have often been destroyed because the tender plants in the drill rows were covered with soil by blowing or washing. To avoid this it is best to cross-harrow immediately after drilling. It is almost impossible to regulate the depth with some makes of seeders. Where the depth cannot be regulated, better success will prob - ably be secured by broadcasting. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Ied the alfalfa in rows. This gives an opportunity to culti - the plants. The cultivation is beneficial to the soil and help* ive the moisture. There are several people in the western of the state who are succeeding with this method on the di - lands. Where this method is practiced, it is customary to it least one of the crops for seed, altho in some instances the method has been used to advantage for producing hay. The plan is probably to use a corn planter which has onion seed ■8. This puts the rows the right distance apart to be cul - ed with an ordinary two-row corn cultivator. The cultiva - should be rather deep at first and shallow later on. Spring Seeding. — The time of seeding will depend very largely upon location and circumstances. There are four general methods now in practice. Spring seeding (April or May) is practiced both in the extreme eastern part of the state and in the western part. This method has the advantage of getting the seed in before the early spring rains, and of giving the plantB an early start, but unless the ground has been well handled it has the great disadvantage of making it necessary for the young alfalfa plants to contend with a large crop of weeds. Many fail - ures are due entirely to the fact that the young and tender plants are choked out by a rank growth of weeds. Cleaning the ground by previous cultivation is the safest remedy. When spring seeding is practiced it is better to plow the ground in the fall and leave it rough, if the nature of the soil will permit. If the soil is subject to blowing, fall plowing is often detrimental unless there is present a sufficient amount of organic matter. The fall plowing phould be disked as 8'&gt;on as the ground can be worked in the spring, and !;ej»t diske*. and harrowed at proper intervals to conserve the inoistTire an '. kill the weeds un - til seeding time. Seeding in western Nebraska should not be done until spring rains begin. Early Summer Seeding. — Seeding early in Jane is ordi - narily practiced in the drier regions. This gives a chance to </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 carefully work the ground, to kill a crop or two of weeds, and to save much of the spring rains. If the land is to be seeded in Jane, and has not been deeply plowed the fall before, early spring plowing is desirable. The land should be thoroly har - rowed immediately following the plow. This will break up the lumps and tend to conserve the moisture. In soils which do not readily pack, the field should be gone over with a subsurface packer or a weighted disk set straight, in order to firm the land at the bottom of the furrow. The ground should be kept har - rowed and disked until seeding time. Late Summer Seeding.— August seeding is now becoming quite generally practiced in many sections of the state. Reports have been secured from practically every section, indicating that its success depends largely upon the amount of moisture at the time of or immediately following the seeding. The first week in August is generally best, but the time will depend very largely upon the condition of the soil. August seeding gives a chance to secure a small-grain crop in the sections of the state where there is plenty of moisture. It also allows summer tilling in sections of the state where moisture should be conserved. August seeding enables one to kill the weeds, thus doing away with the greatest objection to spring seeding. Where alfalfa follows small grain, the ground should be disked immediately following the binder, and if there is plenty of moisture the ground may be plowed shallow and thoroly packed. The earlier the plowing, the better will be the condi - tion of the field. The harrow should be used at interval* until seeding time. Fall Seeding. — Seeding in September and in October is not generally successful, altho with a mild winter and an open fall an excellent stand is often secured. Ordinarily it is not to be recommended. If conditions are favorable and there is plenty of moisture, alfalfa may be seeded as late as September 15, but it is not a safe practice to seed lattr than this. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Inoculation. — The results of cooperative tests daring the two years with cultures of bacteria have shown that in most mces artificial inoculation is not necessary to the production good crop of alfalfa in Nebraska. In localities where alfalfa been successfully grown for a number of years, such inocu - &gt;n is probably a useless expense. There are two general ways of inoculating the soil. The best is by spreading soil from an old, well-established and vigorous alfalfa field, or from a sweet clover patch. If a few hundred pounds of this soil is scattered on land which has been properly prepared and manured, and if the soil has not been exposed to the sun or allowed to dry out, good results will usually follow. The other method is by the use of cultures. There are now a number of reliable companies manufacturing the culture. It comes in bottles and is used on the seed. The ordinary cost of a sufficient amount to treat the seed for one acre is about |2.0fl. The United States Government also furnishes the culture in limited quantities and this can sometimes be secured by writing to the Experiment Station. Complete directions always accom - pany the culture. Soil inoculation is more certain and not as expensive as the cultures where there is an old and vigorous al - falfa field near. If alfalfa has never been grown in the community, or on the , or if it is not successful, it is usually advisable to inocn- Wherever alfalfa is showing, during the first year, a weak wish growth either in spots or over the entire field, it miy ' advantage to inoculate the soil. This can be done by ap - ig to the new seeding soil from an old field, or by treating soil mixed with well-rotted manure with the culture and ring this with a manure spreader. Where the speed of the ider cannot be sufficiently reduced, the mixture may be «eat - [ with a fork or shovel and the field harrowed. Clipping Wbkds. — Where the ground is weedy, or where spring seeding has been practiced, it in often necessary to clip the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 weeds. This must be done by setting the mower bar as high as possible, thus saving the leaves of the young alfalfa plant. Ordinarily the clippings should be left on the ground, but if the growth is heavy it will be necessary to rake, in order to prevent smothering the plants. One clipping is usually enough, but in some instances it is necessary to go over the field again. Disking. — After the alfalfa is established, disking of the field is sometimes practiced. This apparently thickens the stand be - cause the disk cuts the crowns of the alfalfa plants and causes them to throw out more shoots. The benefit is often noticeable for only a year or two. Reports from those who have disked indicate that if the practice is continued the plants are usually weakened, and the stand lessened thru root-rot. The use of a special alfalfa disk which has spikes instead of blades is prob - ably beneficial. These spikes do not cut the crowns, and a field gets all of the benefit of the cultivation, and weeds are killed. In western Nebraska disking with a spike tooth disk is prob - ably especially desirable as it tends to keep the surface of the soil in good condition and destroys grasshopper eggs. Where an old field of alfalfa is to be plowed up in a year or two, it is often of advantage to disk with an ordinary disk. The injured plants throw out many shoots in an effort to produce a large quantity of seed, and in this way the yield of hay is quite ma - terially increased. The disk may be used early in the spring, or following any cutting. If tLe object is to kill the weeds, disking should be done immediately following the first cutting. If it is desired to save as much moisture as possible, early in the spring is best. The spring tooth harrow is used in preference to the disk in some sections. It stirs the surface soil and pulls out some grass without greatly injuring the alfalfa plants. Eanure.— In almost all instances the top dressing of alfalfa g the fall and winter with manure is beneficial. The re should be evenly and thinly spread. This is best accom- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 plished by use of the manure spreader. Large lumps of trashy manure should never be allowed to lie on the field. In the drier sections of the state it is better to use manure which is well rotted, altho light dressings of fresh manure give good results. Manure cannot be applied to advantage during the growing sea - son if it is trashy, for it will be raked up with the hay and the quality of the hay thus injured. I'hickening a Stand. — It is often possible to thicken a poor d of alfalfa by the addition of more seed, provided there is afficient amount of moisture to insure germination and rth. In fields where thickening is attempted, the first few ings after the young plants have started must be made with mower bar set high. Unless this is done, the young plants clipped oft" close to the ground and perish. The close clipping tie plants has often been the cause of failures in thickening If the stand is thin all over the field, or if the field has been in alfalfa many years, it is probably more economical to plow and reseed the- entire field, but patches or strips which have been missed can often be disked and seeded. At the proper time in the spring in sections where small cracks appear in the ground, the seed may be scattered and harrowed in with a weighted har - row. The best way of thickening a stand is often with the disk drill. This covers all the seed, thus insuring germination, does not greatly disturb the old plants, and accomplishes at one time and in a better manner the three operations of disking, seeding, and harrowing. Producing Seed. — Unless the section of the state is extremely dry, it is ordinarily beat to use the second crop as a seed crop. If the season lacks a sufficient supply of moisture and it is seen that the first crop will make a heavy setting of seed, it is desir - able to allow this crop to produce the seed. Where a crop of hay and a crop of seed cannot be grown thru lack of moisture, the field may be pastured until the middle of May or first of </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 the state. The seed does not set where there is a large supply of moisture. At the Experiment Station farm at Lincoln a crop of seed is secured about once in seven years. Seed production in western Nebraska is becoming a very profitable enterprise. A self-rake reaper or a binder may be used for cutting, but a mowing machine with a bunching attachment will be found satis - factory. Great care should be taken in harvesting and handling to prevent the loss of seed. A rack with a tight floor is best for hauling. Threshing may be done directly from the field, or the crop may be stacked. The clover huller is ordinarily used. Best results are usually secured if the speed is somewhat reduced. Hat. — In most sections of the state at least three cuttings of hay may be secured. In the southern and eastern parts it is cus - tomary to make four. For general purposes, it is recommended that alfalfa be cut as soon as it begins to bloom. The earlier it is cut, the better will be the quality of hay for hogs and cattle. If the hay is to be used for horse feed it is better to allow the blooming stage to become well advanced. Care should be taken to keep rains from spoiling the hay, but a rain or two does not necessarily ruin the crop. It is usually the best practice to cut in the morning, begin stirring with a side-delivery rake in the afternoon, allow it to lie in the wind - row over night, and stir again with the rake in the morning after the dew is off. It will be ready to stack by the second after - noon, in good drying weather. The hay should not be left in the swath exposed to intense sunshine very long. The leaves wilt too rapidly and are not as useful in allowing the water to evaporate from the stems. Besides, they become crisp and are shattered off. It should be remembered that the leaves are the most valu - able part of the plant. Where rain is inevitable, it is better to put the hay in small cocks. This will shed a certain amount of the rain and will per- Tii it" it to dry out i*RDi(il v whpn irood w^Gflthor com £8 on &amp;£T9.in A </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Alfalfa Management 13 side-delivery rake which does not handle the haj too vigorously, thus shattering the leaves, is almost indispensable in the rapid curing and proper management of the alfalfa crop. I'astueing. — An alfalfa field may be profitably pastured if &gt;er precautions are taken. It is especially valuable for hogs, ood for horses, and if mixed with grasses can be safely pas - d by cattle and sheep. Some farmers practice pasturing with le and sheep and state that their losses from bloat are not it enough to offset the value of the pasture. If pasturing is mpted, great care should be taken to see that the cattle are hungry when turned on the pasture and that they have a suffi - t supply of other forage available. The danger from bloat is ays present. IJfalfa should never be pastured the first year, and should p be pastured heavily. It is better to pasture lightly gh to allow at least two cuttings to be made during the sea - and better results can be secured if the normal number of ings are made. Stock should not be allowed to pasture im - iately after a cutting, unless there is a portion of the field h has not been cut. If the entire field has been cut and i is a large quantity of stock, the alfalfa will very often not 7 rapidly enough to supply the required amount of feed and plants will be injured. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>