<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00011.00001">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00011.00001</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>BIENNIAL MESSAGE OF Gov. EZRA P. SAVAGE, INAUGURAL ADDRESS OF Gov. JOHN H. MICKEY TO THE TWENTY-EIGHTH SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA 1903</title>
		             <date value="1903">1903</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-19</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>

            <seg id="p001">Gov. EZRA P. SAVAGE 

INAUGURAL ADDRESS 

OF 

Gov. JOHN H. MICKEY 

TO THE 

OF THE 

LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA 


OF 

rWKXTY-EIGHTH SESSION </seg>



            <seg id="p003">
OK 

Governor Ezra P. Savage 

To THE 

TWENTY-EIGHTH SESSION 

OK THK 

LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA 

JANUARY 6, 1903 

Tn the Senator* itnil /lepretentativi 1 *, Twetktij-Kiijlith Sfmtimm of the 

legislature of Xebraxka: 

Constitutional environments ami limitations an- siu-h that. t&lt;&gt; 
Ik- further license*}, means an UMMHU} hardship on those who 
l&gt;ear the burden of the cost of public government. The state i.l 
Nebraska has so developed in its industrial, educational ami eonmercial 
resources that it can no longer be subjected t:&gt; that degree 
of restraint embodied in the Constitution as it now exists without 
material interference with its growth and welfare. 

I Particularly is this true in regard to a profitable investment &lt;&gt;t 
; permanent school trust fund. Sec.si of Art. 8 of the Constitnn 
limits the investment of these funds to United States and 
»te securities and registered County bonds of this state, and 
lile no objection can be raised to the quality of the securities 
itinerated, the fact remains that the latitude of investment is inequate, 
necessitating the employment of an intermediary beCvwa 
e contracting parties with consequent loss in the way of rebate 
•osperity has been so general with the American people during </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
4 

the last live years, and money lias becowe so plentiful, that interest 
ra;es on nil stable securities have decreased during that time 
approximately 100 per cent. Five years ago 8 per cent securities 
were obtainable in every market. Today 4 per cent securities are 
difficult to obtain, the general line being below that figure. The 
Constitution prohibits the Board of Educational Lands and Fund* 
from using any part of the trust fund for other than the purpose 
of investment, which prevents the Board or the Treasurer from 
going int&lt; the open market and paying premiums, as do other 
investors. Thi* requires the purchase of securities from or through 
an intermediary and results invariably in the acquisition of securities 
at a considerably reduced rate of interest. The loss thus 
entailed amounts to thousands of dollars annually, nor can I divine 
any substantial remedy independent of such amendment to the 
Constitution M will afford wider latitude in the matter of denominating 
the kin 1 of securities which may be purchased. The 
School Trust Fund has reached enormous proportions with tendencies 
toward a further increase, and until relief i&gt; furnished 
which provide avenues for investment of this fund which do not 
now exist the lx'st results possible will be unprofitable and unsatisfactory 
to the people. During the last two years payments on 
school land sold, despite the liberality of the state in the matter 
of exempting from taxation lands in which it has au equity, have 
greatly increased the trust funds, and notwithstanding that extraordinary 
diligence was practiced by the Treasurer in making investments, 
the amount uninvested was a great portion of the time 
large and its safe-keeping attended by more or less risk. 

If the state be empowered to go into the open market and 
compete with other investors it will not alone prove remunerative 
in the way of saving rebates and discounts, but such an active 
competitor at work in the market will have a tendency to reduce 
interest rates, thereby making a saving to the people both ways. 

The amount of securities held for the permanent school fund 
now aggregates %."&gt;, 380,000. The amount of money which the 
state has forthcoming from sale contracts of school lands approximates 
?5.000,000. Arrangements must be made therefore for a </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
5 

Einuous investment of si trust fund of at least |10,00t,000. 
er prevailing constitutional limitations investment of an\re 
near the full amount of this fund is impossible. 

HKTKKM IIMKNT ASH MUXliJIV 

The government of llic state as now wmrtiffd, BjrMbolnM 
extravagance in a narked degree. Those who framed the existing 
constitution established departments thai tor the next M 
years, under the most favorable circumstances in the gn wth and 
development of tlie state, will be an unnecessary burden on the 
tax payers. The people should enjoy government at the low&lt; &gt;t 
cost consistent with goo&lt;l &gt;er\ice. Any greater cost is a public 
injustice. A careful study of this phase of tlic question justifies 
me in my own mind in recommending the abolition of the departments 
of Auditor of Public Accounts and Commissioner of Public 
I*ands and Buildings, and the assignment of the duties incumWnt 
thereon to those den irtin.Mits ottiuere.l by the Secretary of Slate, 
the Treasurer and (iovernor. With a few additional clerks the 
duties of the Auditor and C tmniisdou -r of Pu'.dic Lands and 
liuildiugs can be performed by the Secretary of State, the Ti 
urer and the (iovernor. thus making a saving o the tax payers of 
approximately *."&gt;o,OUO per year, simplifying government and 
doing away with the necessity of an outlay of at least $TOU,ono 
made necessary for accommodations for the new adjuncts which 
naturally will be created from time to tin.e. 

Iln the conflict for political spoliation the office-seeking i 
(ins to have out-generaled and defeated those who stand for 
Mioiny. with the result that a large number of names have Ween 
led to the pay roll, and bureaus and departments have been 
ablished absolutely without any apparent justification. This 
licv has been pursued bv all political parties until now the state 
9 in its employ at high wages, sufficient officers and empl 
transact ten times the amount of business devolving on them, 
critical investigation will show that in many instances one 
partmeut is duplicating the work of the other with no other 
ject than to find employment for those whom the legislature htm </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 

IlH tiiiii' to tinii' established in |&gt;ulilii- office. It' basilicnsacted 
profwrljr it do— not improve it to have it twice W 
ice transacted and if it he In— rttld improperly the evil can 
iw no less through the medium of limit i)&gt;lii-at ion. Ah the 
raditcd representatives of the people, it in your duty to 
t not one dollar of expense is entailed on them beyond the 
ount required to defray the MM) of gO»MlMHl honestly and 
nomically administered. 

The Hureau of ] lxlitHt rial Statistics in a source of unnecessary 
expense and should l&gt;e abolished. The law pertaining to the col 
lection an 1 c &gt;inpilati»n of in Ins rial stitistic* should I' 
amended as to impose this duty jointly on the Department of 
Banking, and the Department of Public Instruction, and the 
Hoard of Agriculture. By so doing the service can l&gt;e improved 
and a substantial reduction made in public expense. 

tA comparison of expenses incident to public printing fails to 
t if v the existence of the Slate Printing Board or for a specific 
ifopriation therefor and I recommend, as a measure of economy, 
t the law creating the said Board be n pealed and that its duties 
imposed on the Secretary of State. 

Congress is at this time considering a bill which provides for 
the location of a National Fish Hatchery in Nebraska. The 
* 
worth and importance of such an undertaking must be apparent 
to all. The success achieved by the state in the promotion of 
h'sh and game, both by fish hatching and by preventing the whole 
sale and unlawful destruction of game and lab, makes this a very 
desirable field for a national hatchery. The legislature at its last 
session, enacted a law creating a system of game wardens. The 
Workings of this law have been eminently satisfactory and the 
¦mount received from prosecutions and fees almost balances the 
expenses entailed, which makes that department almost self-supporting. 
I recommend that your honorable body memorialize 
congress to pass this measure and that the Nebraska representatives 
in both branches be urged to give it active attention and 
support. Should the measure pass it would be an act of wisdom 
for the state to turn over its hatchery and equipment at South </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
ImmhI to tlio general government at a nominal cost. 

II recommend that the i n :n &gt; :i LT&lt;' &gt; &gt; t&lt;*i i &gt; of the stiitc institutionplaced 
under the supervision of ¦ non-partisan Board of t'-OM* 
1 and Pardons. This boanl should Ik- heavily bonded an. I 
iitld In 1 required lo purchase supplies, inspect institut i&lt; &gt;ns and 
ounts thereof and exercise supervisory control over the several 
titutions. It should also In- empowered and required to provide 
ins of employment for convict laboi ami pass upon all applicant 
for executive clemencw 

The penitentiary should and can 1m' made sclf-Mtppor 
Instead of dealing with contractors, the stale should itself employ 
the labor of convicts in the manuf.iciitiire of clothing, booti 
hIiocs and other materials for the various institutions. With a nominal 
oiitlav for machinery the state can do awav with the no 

L appropriating large sums of money out of the treasurv earh 
r for the maintenance of that institution. 

(iuidel further bv the light of experience and reason. I 
r commend tliat the laws lie so amended as to require rclati\ 
the insane, feeble-minded and inmates of the Keform School to 
Wear the expense of the maintenance of these individuals. The 
State should provide accommodations and medical attention, hut 
this expense, along with the general expense of maintenance, 
xhoiild ix- borne by relatives when financially able to do so, otherwise 
the cost should devolve on the resident count v. 

fl further recommend that the Home for the FriemUeM be 
minated from politics ami placed under the supervision of a 
n-partisau board composed of women residing in the city of 
ncoln. All other Visiting and Kiaaining Hoards, a source of 
iis-iderable expense and often of much dissension, should be 
idisbe&lt;l. 

I The Stale Hoard of Charities lias failed by its achi 'venieiit&lt; 
justify its further existence at public expense, and I p'wpectfullr 
ommend that this work be left to the churches and charitahlv 
lined and that the law creating mid Board he repealed. 

Tlw maintenance of two separate home* for soldiei ¦ </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
I 

*ailort&lt; can by no method of KHMMg be justified. These charuc--, 
by reason of age and infirmity, have l&gt;ei'ii rendered iiuapalil ¦ of 
performing manual labor and those plans which contemplate the | induction 
of food supplies with tliis class of labor must now beahandoned. 
The Home at (Jrand Island never has and never can enjoy 
|»ro|»er sanitary accommodations. The large tract of land owned 
I iy the state at this point is now a source of expense rather than nf 
rt'venue. The Home at Mil ford is better adapted in every way 
and the land owned by the state on which this institution is locate 1 
is of sufficient quantity to answer all legitimate purposes. The 
number of inmates henceforth will by the workings of time, be 
gradually rtduced and I say it with regret and sorrow — it 'will only 
be a few years until the last survivor of thai great conflict will 
have passed away. I recommend, both in consideration of the 
inmates who can Ik- better provided for and of the taxpayers who 
should l»e relieved of all unnecessary burdens, that the property Mi 
&lt; irand Island 1h&gt; sold and the inmates transferred to Milford. The 
expense incident to this change will be trivial com pared with the 
financial saving this will make to the state. 

Kadi stssion of the legislature has witnessed the unnecessary 
Iienditure of :&lt; large sum of money for printing and stationery. 
merous bills are introduced which have mo merit to commend 
in, and, after a great deal of expense has been entailed, fail of 
isage. While many of these bills aim at legitimate achievents, 
not a few of them arc utterly devoid of merit. I theree 
recommend that before a bill may be introduced, it be 
erred to such committee of the house in which it originated - 
i to deal with subjects of that character and shall be entertained 
your honorable body only when its introduction bears the 
•roval of a majority of said committee. Only such number of 
-sons should be employed during a legislative session as is 
ually necessary to transact its business with proper expedition. 

rivil. SKKVKK AM&gt; KI.KCTloN 

t Provision should be made for the election of aM state and 
nty officials biennially at one general election. Conducting an 
tion for a portion of the ticket each year keeps the political </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
9 

affaire of the atata in constant unrest, interferes with business 
interests and MMMOaHWilj entails a large expense upon the people. 
The theory that bv dividing the office* in this way, partisan 
abuses may in :i decree be eliminated, comb its the philosophy of 
experience, and that being the only ground on which the entailment 
of this expense has been excused, further adherence to such 
arrangements is in no sense justified. 

I Nor should partisanship be permitted to interfere with ettincy 
and economy in the management &lt;f public affairs. It 
uld be a measure reflecting sober judgmt nt and reason, one in 
rmony with the most advanced thought of the age, to establish 
system of civil service extending over and including all the 
te institutions and all the departments of state government, 
¦epting the judicial, legislative and executive department*, 
hile recognizing the necessity of political parties, I do not 
lieve that humanity should be required to pay »".ch enormous 
bute to partisanship as i«j &lt; ustomary, neither do I believe that 
; withdrawal of the spoils of office would jeopardise the ¦ 
ice of any political organization worthy of existiucc. A party 
it exists solely for the sake of political spoliation is an ulcer in 
¦ body politic and the sooner it sustains dismemberment, the 
tter it will be for the people 

I recommend %o, that the terms of mmWh of the legislature 
be increased to four years and that it be provided that as 
nearly half of the members as possible hold over alternately so 
that at the opening of each session at least half of the meml&gt;en&gt; 
will be familiar with the duties incumbent on your honorable 
body. It is amazing that our constitution and laws should be so 
constituted as to place such a vast responsibility in the hands of 
men who, however intelligent and proficient they may l&gt;e in other 
respects, are rarely qualified for intelligent legislative services. 
You are required to appropriate millions of dollars of the people's 
money for public use, yet it is doubtful if there be one 
among you aside from the few who have had experience, who is 
prepared to act intelligently or who is a proper judge as to 
whether certain sums or certain appropriations should or should </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 

tiol be made. In making thin statement I Pptak in no sense dihirs|icctfiill_v 
of this l&gt;o&lt;ly. for it l&gt;as been true of every legislature 
before and will he true of every one that shall follow so 1 &lt; &gt; 1 1 ir as 
the practice obtains of electing the full membership at eaeli legislative 
election. What intensifies the evil and the danger is that 
for some unaccountable reason, members of this body are seldom 
returned so that in the great majority of instances counsel and 
experience are lacking. 

t These evile and the remedies involve Constitutional revision 
my object in drawing attention to them on this occasion is t.. 
ken interest in what I consider subjects of the gravest public 
;ern. 

l 1 1 NNTITl T IoN At, (ON V K NT IOS 

Many of the foregoing modifications will require Constitutiouil 
anijudiiK'iit bafore they cm become effective. In view of this 
and of existing financial and revenue conditions, condition* requiring 
earnest and immediate attention, I urgently recommend that 
your honorable body take such procedure as will afford the people 
an opportunity to pass judgment on the subject of a Constitutional 
convention. Submission of amendments without the stamp of 
conventional authority has in the past been attended by great 
expense and very unsatisfactory results and the only effective remedy 
in my judgment is in the sober deliberations of a convention 
created for that express purpose. 

VKTKRlNARV A N" I &gt; l.tVK STOCK 

The live stock industry of Nebraska have grown to such large 
and important proportions as to Income one of the principal 
sources of revenue to the producersof this state. It is of the highest 
importance therefore, that this industry should have the benefit 
of such legislation as will stimulate its growth and as will surround 
it, in a pathological sense, with every possible safeguard. 
Kxisting quarantine legislation, which aims at the prevention and 
suppession of contagious and infectious diseases, permits of the 
exercise of a certain degree of restraint but does not confer on the </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
11 

KoiMtHatcd authorities, ihr uwnwi of power tteopsaary to the full 
realization of the hraeits of the law. Liberality should he exer 
eised toward tins industry in every sense. particularl y in irrnut ttiii 
raiiLfP privileges and in appropriating funds for the m liutcuancc 
of the state veterinary service. 

I Late in the month oj September, 1*01, the main buildin. 
Hospital for the Insane at Norfolk was almost completely 
troyed by tire, entailing a loss of aboal 1145,000. The l&gt;arn. 
fine room and machinery ami several other structures were 
cd. as well as nearly all the furniture of the main building. 
roie efforts on the part of the officials and employees of the 
titution resulted in the loss of hut one life oiil of J'.'f inm 
&gt;m the standpoint of fatality this was the iimM successfully 
Hatred hospital tire ever known ami I embrace this opportunity 
commend the fidelity and heroism of Dr. Frederick F. Teal, the 
terintendent. Dr. (.'. Alexander Young, the physician, and the 
ployees, hut for whose efforts the loss of life would have h 
•at and the loss of property much greater than was unstained. 

It was thought at tin- time that a Majority of the intn.it. - 
could 1m- eared for at that point, hut subsequent development* 
tailed to justify such conclusion. A committee composed of meinl»ers 
of the State Hoard of Charities instituted an investigation 
into the conditions prevalent there and on the recommendation of 

aid committee, all the inmates were transferred to the II. 
for the Insane at Lincoln and the Asvlnin for the Insane at IlaM 

ings. The services of the officers 
institution were dispensed with, 

and employees of the Norfolk 
New additions to the IInspit.il 

at Lincoln and the Asylum at Hastings have made it possible t&lt;&gt; 
provide comfortable accommodations for all the insane, and it is 
:i splendid testimonial to the efficiency of the management of the 
two institutions that the 9*6 inmates from Norfolk, as well H 
other patients that came in the natural course of events, have ban 
well cared for within the funds appropriated for these two institu 
tioiis. The unused portion of the appropriation for maintenance 

Norfolk hospital kom Ixsasi </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 

I the Hospital :it Norfolk amount* to upwards of ?58,600. I'pon 
I removal of the inmates most of the live stock and provisions 
re transferred to the Hospital at Lincoln and the Asylum at 
stings, and the balance Hold ami the proceeds covered into the 
asury. The farm wan leased and an engineer wan placed in 
»rge of the buildings and property at a salary of ? Tii.oo per 
iiith. The value of the improvements, furniture and machinery 
uaining is estimated at alx)Ht 175,000. 

Two yearn ago the sum of (191,975 wan appropriated for the 
maintenance of the Hospital at Norfolk. Of this amount t&gt;4,-ti75 
was for officer's salaries, employes' wages, fuel and lights ami 
incidentals, expenses entirely dispensed with by caring for the 
inmates at Lincoln and Hastings. 

Experience has demonstrated that it is cheaper in the end for 
the state to construct its buildings of fire-proof material. During 
the la*t two years the loss to the state from tire amounted to 
upwards of ?250,000. If property lows were the only consideration, 
that could be remedied by insurance, but a much graver side 
of the question is danger to human life, an element of risk alone 
removable through the medium of iire proof materials. 

I am not in accord with those who seek to remedy the ills of 
corporate monopoly through the public ownership of public service 
corporations. Before relief could come from that source, if 
indeed the proposition be practical at all, endless litigation would 
have to be encountered or the purchaser buy on a basis of i 
•lively capitalized valuation, and, as the law now stands, on tinvalue 
of the franchises. 

A careful study of this question has impelled me to the conclusion 
that there obtains a much more simple and much less 
expensive remedy. Public enterprises of this character should Vmallowed 
the same freedom that is allowed other enterprises. A 
manufacturer requires no franchise in order that he may construct 
and operate his factory. Neither should any public service oor- 

KI.IM1NATK Ml'NK'H'AI. KKA XOI ISKS </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
., 

jdiratioii be reqaired to obtsia ¦ franchise, hdt 

should muni. 

tus he vested with power to grant or refuse franchise* to publi. 
service corporations, nor Ik? clothed with |m&gt;w»t to licenur i»r 
refuse the public use of |iul&gt;lic streets for public purpo«c««. Tie 
streets BTC &lt;le&lt;lic;itt'&lt;l to the public and the sovereignty of a municipality 
over them should never extend to the right to conditionally 
prohibit their use hy the public. It m pro)*&gt;r t 
municipality to Ik- vested with plenary pewei in the 

Iiitary and polioe regulations. It in a fact, however, rxi well 
ormed person will deny that the value of municipal fr 
not so much in the right to operate an in I he ability t«» pr. 
iers from o}K?rating, thertliy cre.iting and inaintiininjj » 
mopoly the lo«jii-:il fruition of which is arbitrary and '¦ 
ideijiiate service with excessive charges accompai || 
y 1m- ciintendcd that this would result in the prom 
jneible and designing undertakings, but this can bv«4VMi 
[1 amply safeguarded by indemnification and )&gt;v charter pr 
is. To guard against the consolidation ol 
is only necessary to stipulate and ciiiImmIs in the ch.irtpr that 
¦ pul)lio shall liave a proprietary interest, and that lh« r 
ishment of control and ownership shall be a w» &lt;fc&lt;* 
occupancy and operation. 

[The people should be coni|&gt;ennated in - 
jiipantv of the public streets by publi &lt;»ralion« and 
this end I recommend that a law ba ¦ «juirin_ 
ense of all such corporations t «&gt; operate to !? continsvii M 
yinent of a fixed per centum of their g*l 
icicipaJ treasury annually. 

I Invested capital should feel and ba Bbm*mI at .-til timea I Mat 
abiding place its safe and secure, and while I raeOTMBtad the 
miuation of the municipal franchise, I do it. not to advocate 
i' enactment of couHscatory legislation. ! what in 
f judgment is a just and efficacious panacea for ilia incident •&gt;» 
Hichised monopoly. The law of industry, carried !&gt;• ita loffiral 
ncliision, rests on the broad basis of "UppK n.d l&lt;-tnai&gt;&lt;i aawl if 
is law shall be afforded an opportunity 'latnral iwilii </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 

«'nc&lt;&gt; uiiol*»trtictcd by legislation calculatf&lt;l to dftTOT foiujK-t itiou 
inany of the abuses which now obtain will soon disappear. 'I'll 
autonomy of sovereign power of the state. should never Ik 1 excr 
I in a hostile or intemperate spirit against the rights of pro| 
erty. For, an the hiisbainlman deserts the land that fails t&lt; 
yield commensurate tribute so capital, seeing its rights enslaved 
deserts and goes to other points where its rights are protected 
Cumbersome taxation and an illiberal invocation of the'sovereig 
power of the state in controlling the great carriers of inland com 
MM is but a response to prejudice, and contains such element 
of reprisal and aggrandizement ax are well intended to distur 
confidence in our wime of justice and honesty &lt;&gt;f purpose. Pro] 
er conversation and regard, therefore, for our mutual welfar 
admotusTies scrupulous avoidance of legislation susceptible u 
sik^K construction and interpretation as to constitute inanil. 
tioiis of prejudice in the distribution of the burdens ami res|M&gt;ns 
bilitie* of public government. 

TIIK TOKRKN- -VSTKM «&gt;K I.AMi III I.K 

I submit to you for your respectful consideration the report 
of the commission appointee] to investigate into the workings of 
the Ton-ens System of Land Titles with a view to formulating a 
title system more simple and perfect than now exists. The report 
is voluminous and undertakes to deal with the subject in detail 
but a casual reading of it does not justify me in my own mind in 
recommending the adoption of the Torrens system. I place it at 
your disposal with a confidence in your intelligent judgment to 
deal with it with that care and deliberate thought so important a 
subject should receive at the hands of a law-making body. 

PAN-AMKRK'AX KX POSITION 

The Twenty-Seventh General Assembly appropriated §10,000 
for a display of domestic products at the Pan-American Kxposition 
at Buffalo. Of this amount $8.21 4. -V.t was expended, leaving 
a balance in the fund of $1,785.41. This is the first time in 
the history of expositions where such good results were aceom </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
1.1 

filled and a large i&gt;:. lance rciii;iiiic«| iiue\|*-iid&lt; 
ffaln «:'.s of good | rn | ortioim ami lh«- i 

II, 



ffor.l. 

iliat it was I he n.eans of utrciifrtbei.ing 


m-. urities and of enlightening nun* ¦• &lt;¦¦ 

resoiir 

rlsi.xS \ i'i ui ii \-i. v 


'Die Louisiana Purchase Kxim 

ition i'i !«• I'chl i' Si I 

rer known. Twentv-thn iim! trrritorwalM 

ami (1250,000 liv Illinois. The federal •_".%. -nmnil da* mpprmt 


which will make the total amount invested »r tli 

largest mm ever io vested in an exponitton 

INehraska l&gt;f ing in t'ie heart of the lerritor\ *i»K 
luisiana Purchase and baiag one of the great iitduitri.tl •tair-of thlion, 
I assumed that self-interest and -&lt;lf pridf jaatMni iwe 
dertaking for the Hiatf. f-teps looking.' l«&gt; the part' 
gre«- coinmeiiHurate with the ini|&gt;ort.-tiice of the |&gt;roje«-t an 
lativt- worth and U'lietit to the state. When I a|&gt;|M 
scion it was intended to hold the ei|M»ition in 
tc of opening was Miilwe&lt;|iieiitly |.o«t|nnied M In tbr 
MM of an appropriation, relying on the patriotism of tbr |*»»- 
B of Nebraska, it was my idea that a Kiifficii-iil aniouni ' 
i^litahle exhibit could Ik- raised by popular mil' &gt; in.l tbr 
inmiHoion was app&lt;iintc&lt;l with that end in view. I app.mtat 
commission, &lt;i. \V. Watllen. K. K. IJrn.-i-, J. Su-r 
n, C. II. Kudge and II. S. \\W\W. Shortly tl 
orton died, resultin&lt;; in the \&lt; -ka of i&gt;i f In ' 

l -|.lcli(li(l .11 ill profitable r&gt;| jn.rt 'in t 1 

resources ami proiliirls of 1 1 ¦ ; -~ 

pnmiMn to l«- lliejjreatwii ncliievt-nirni of tlii* • « 

made appropriation*, rarrrag all the waj !&gt;••' 

(•riation of &gt;&lt;¦_;, .vm liv South Carolina, In - 

:it«'«l $0,500,000, tin- &lt;itv of St. I.mii- ami (be • 

910,000,000, ami, ii|&gt; to the praasat, ibe \.»«t «uin 

Kl Ik-oii appropriate! ;iu&lt;l ootltribotcd for (hi- r P Mar 
ill reaaoBsUc MMmc* of ;i fiirih«*r iarrMM «»f • </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 

1st citizens Sjtti on whom I depended largely for the MMMM of 
undertaking. The rMMMJ thus ocean ioned in tille&lt;l bjr the 
&gt;ointiiieni of Mr. \V. B. Price, and with that change the oomision 
ttnititt as originally constituted. Considerable routine 
rk has been disposed of and a baikling site has Ixeti selected. 
, the postponement affords an opportunity to appropriate fundthat 
purpose, in view of which, the plan for popular nbserip-11 
has bam abaadoned. 

I Nebraska euwrt afford to let this opportunity to promote it&lt; 
rests go by unavailed of, and I recommend that an appropriaof 
at least (75,000 Ik' made for this purpose. 

Additional facilities thovid be provided for the better preparation 
of teachers for school work. Rack year fully 1,500 
young and inexperienced teachers are added to the list and their 
dutie* and responsibilities are such that any defect in their qualifications 
nniHt of necessity work harm to the intelligence of the 
people. 

Our logical duty therefore is to afford the teacher opportunity 
to qualify and to see that this opportunity is embraced. Nebraska 
stands at the head of all the states in literacy and posseseducational 
system that augurs well lor our intellectual future 
Hut, while our public instructors are as good if not above the 
average, there is room for improvement. The Normal at Pern 
and other Normal Schools of a private character, have been of 
great benefit in qualifying teachers. But the facilities arc inadc" 
quate. The numt&gt;er of persons engaged in school work is in 
excess of the accommodations. The Normal department of the 
University is lacking in detail ius'ruction. By reason of the 
improved educational facilities, I recommend that such steps be 
taken and provisions made as will raise the Normal department of 
the University to such a standard as will remove existing defect* 
in detail instruction and as will afford ample accommodations for 
those who cannot be accommodated elsewhere. I also recommend 
that tlw&gt; LWfS i trtaiiMn i t &gt;i •! Vm a *i 1 » 1 -i t L- 

KKl CATION </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
17 

mal instruction compulsory and that no teacher !&gt;&lt;• eligible to 


Kin that capacity who has not attended Normal school for at 
t one year. 

I The Peru Normal School jk possessed of a large and carefully 
;cted school library, but the building occupied by it i&gt; a 
[(den structure built many yean* ago and. in addition to lieing 
m advanced stage of decay, is a veritable tire-trap. I recoinixl 
that a sum of money be appropriate* 1 sufficient to construct 
ibrary building of brick and stone such as will \h' in heaping 
,h the demands and as will be a credit to the state. 1 also 
oinmend that an appropriation be made for the construction of 
hapel, thereby at small cost incieasing the capacity of this most 
portaut educational institution to a very material extent. 

But while recognizing and appreciating the good work of the 
State Normal School at Peru, we must admit the fact that from 
the time of its establishment in 1867 on the batiks of the Missouri 
river near the southeastern corner of the state, the center of our 
commercial interests, the center of the great industries of the 
state, agriculture and stock raising, have swept steadily out 
toward the heart of the state, out from Peru to the northwest, 
carrying with them the center of population and also the educational 
centers, thus leaving Peru with a local rather than a state 
educational value. The school is too far removed from the central 
and western portions of Nebraska, where the children and 
teachers have fewer educational opportunities, either in the way 
of high schools, academies or colleges. I believe that provision 
should be made for normal school facilities for the |&gt;eople of the 
central and western portions of the state, by the establishment of 
a second state normal school west of the sixth principal meridian. 

The State University which is the capsheaf and main pillar t&lt;i 
our splendid educational sjstem, should receive such consideration 
at your hands as so important an institution of learning 
deserves. This institution is maintained at great expense to the 
people, yet the stream of intelligence which continuously flows 
from it into the world of science, art and industry, raising the </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
18 

I. er.il ttandarJ of eJuesiiufi an 1 better equipping all for lives &lt;&gt;f 
.uid neefnlneM, }— till generous consideration of it* 
¦ Is. It would be in keeping with good l&gt;nsiiu&gt;ss Methods for 
ir honorable b&gt;dy to investigate fully into the management 
I need* of this institution before asking an appropriation for 
maintenance with the end in view of correcting abuses, if an\ 
re be, in the lalried employes, and of practising consistent 
nomy. I have had occasion to visit the University several 
m in my official oapaoity daring the last two yean, and it 
irds me miu-h jileasure to bear testimony to the efficiency of 
mcellor Andrews as reflected by the educational achiev mentthat 
institution during his incumbency. 

The law looking to the suppression of adulterant* iu I 
products aims at meritorious attainment, but its dominion icircumscribed 
as to arrest its potency and compromise its efticac\ 
As now constituted it permits restraint to be exercised over dairy, 
cider and vinegar products and adulterations of the same, and with 
that the authority of the Food Commissioner ends. I recommend 
that the law be so amended as to include all food products, for iu 
this age of spirited competition, commercial genius appears to have 
taken refuge behind substitutes, with the result that ingredients 
are frequently employed in the manufacture of food products that 
are unwholesome in a high degree. Impure articles are abundant 
in every market, hence the necessity for care and watchfulir 
The department an now constituted, is practically self-supporting. 
but, if in order to make it what it should be, additional funds 
must be provided, then it is your plain duty to make that provision, 
for, to make Nebraska the dumping ground for food products 
that are exiled from other states by laws aimed at the protection 
of health would be to make a mistake the full consequences of 
which, no mind can estimate. The law should be broadened iu 
l&gt;e and the department be transferred to the University where, 
without entailing any additional expense, it may have the advantages 
of a laboratory and of minds qualified for scientific invest 
tic in and research in chemistry. 

l-iiol) INSPECTION </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
19 

oil. I\»I'K&lt; I |i&gt;\ 

t Increase in tW hm of gaanliae in generating power baa 
ted in mi inferior grade of keronene for illuminating porpi 
e law requires kerosene oil i&lt;&gt; witlistaml .1 certain heal lent !&gt;«• 
»• "flashing" 1 hi t it does not require it to flash within a K 
tree, which owing to tlie extraction of an excessive &lt;|iianlil\ of 

irascoiis matter for ir«soline. has resulted in oil of an inferior quality 
being place*] on the market. Kerosene is so generally uthe 
homes of IBM plate for lighting purposes, th.it the placing ol 
an inferior article on the market works great annoyance and hardship, 
and I respect fully recommend that the inspection law br 
amended so as to include the inspection of gasoline and all oils for 
domestic use. that a maximum as well as a minimum test b&lt; 
lished, and that all illuminating oils shall he of standard qaalily. 

Kiil.m; hai, si i;v i;y 

III order to facilitate and remove obstacles in the way of 
logical research by the federal government, I would respect fall] 
recommend that an act ba pas— d declaring that it i-hall be ! 
for the persons employed in making saiil geological survey to enter 
upon the lands within the boundaries of this state, bat that MM! 
permission shall not be construed as authorising any miner 
interference with private rights. 

INabraakl should co-operate witli the general governinent to 
i&gt; fullest extent in the promotion of irrigation. This state has 
dertaken on its own account to reclaim and place under cultivain 
its arid lands and has thus fai constructed alxMit 3500 milccanals 
covering about 1,000,000 acres of land. Th 
oposed by the general government taken into account the u'reat 
• iintain water sheds, a matter bearing close relationship to indilual 
state iuterests and which perhaps will be the me;&lt; 
judiciting impending conflicts between adjoining states over 
iter rights. And there is even reason whv Nebraska should 

IRRIGATION </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
20 

Esuch ai&lt;l ami enoouragemrat as will have a tendency to stimj 
its promotion. For enlightenment as to defects in our stabem, 
I res;&gt;eetfully refer you to the report of the Secretary of 
State Hoard of Irrigation. 

The legislature at its last session enacted a law creating 
boundary CoMBMMOfl conditioned on the enactment of a siinila 
law by states separated from Nebraska by the Missouri river. A 
other states in question failed to enact such a measure and a* th 
act of the legislature of this slate has expired by limitation, 
recommend that you proceed in the same manner a* your predecc 
and that a copy of your act be furnished the states of Sout 
Dakota ai:d Iowa with a memorial from the Chief Executive o 
Nebraska Betting forth the merits of the provision and solicitin 
the exercise of reciprocal interest. Changes in the channel of th 
Missouri river have resulted in the creation of disputed jurisdit 
tion, and incentive to crime and an obstruction to justice. I)u 
ing the last vear trouble arose between officers of South Dakot 
and residents of Nebraska. Such conditions are calculated to di 
turb the amity between states which for the general welfar 
should always obtain and are well intended to encourage lawlessness 
and crime. Nor can these conditions be repressed without 
Midi joint action as will permanently fix and determine a well 
defined boundary line. 

The National (iuard of Nebraska now consists of 1720 officers 
and privates of which 329 belong to independent companies. 
There are two troops of cavalry — one regular and one independent: 
one battery and one Engineer and Signal Corps. It is in 
brigade formation of two regiments. 

The need of a strong and well equipped militia, a* essential 
to domestic tranquility and to the protection of life and property, 
grows more apparent as our industrial interests expand and our 
population increases. The state's ability to preserve law and 

IKU'MiAKV COMMISSION- 

NATIONAL &lt;UAKI&gt; </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
21 

order ami to protect the rights &lt;&gt;f propertv should never )&gt;e a subject 
for doubt mi the part of anyone. It must always stand prepared 
to maintain the majesty of the law. In the discharge o 
this duty, while trusting largely to the eivil officers of govern 
ment, it must have the support of military force in order that itqualifications 
as a potent guardian may never be called into que« 
tion. There is some opposition to the militia. I regret to say, ii 
the ranks of industry, on the theory that it is nothing more thai 
an instrument of capital and To intimidate labor. This conce| 
tion has no foundation in fact, nor can it be reconciled to tobe 
judgment by any method of reasoning. The militia is a publi 
safeguard, and only those who incline to a physical resistance &lt;&gt; 
law need have anv fear of it. 

(Nebraska's guard service is scarcely adequate to the demand, 
le companies are well officered, well disciplined ami fairly well 
nipped. What is most needed is the removal of statutory ob•uctioiif 
so that another regiment may be organized and equipped, 
lis addition will raise the potency of the guard up to the 
estnt requirements and will make it a useful and effective 
ency in the preservation of law and order. 

II1H Jl'liK'IAKY 

The legislature at its last session (meted a law which created 
a Supreme Court Commission composed of nine members. The 
measure is of doubtful constitutionality, but congested condition* 
required that something be done to relieve the court and remove 
obstacles in the way of the speedy administration of justice and 
this being the only available remedy, it was resorted to. At the 
time of appointment of the commission, there were 1,700 cases on 
the docket. Aided by the Commission, the Court has succeeded 
in disposing of these cases and it is now in a position to iji\i 
early attention to controversies submitted to it for determination. 
The act limits the term of the Commission to two years, ami 
there being no apparent necessity for its existence for a Im 
period than this act provides, I recommend that it be permitted to 
expire and that no appropriation lie made for this purpose. </seg>


            <seg id="p022">
This state lias, however, outgrown the ftdjadteattag mpaeitt 
of thi' court and when revision of the orguk \»W shall be undertaken, 
provision should bi' made for a substantial increase in the 
number of judges. Exercising, us this tribunal does, final judgment 
in cases involving life, liberty and property, every facility 
for a proper administration of justice should be afford* d it. 

DISTRKT idlKl 

It is the concensus of opinion of those well informed on tilt 
Mibject that the state has been pn.digal in the creation of Distric 
Courts and Judges. The stale is now composed of IS judieia 
districts and 28 judges. It requires $70,000 per year for judieia 
salaries alone, to say nothing of the thousands of dollars o 
additional cost for reporters, stenographers and incidental ezpeo 
mm. In many of the districts, particularly in those of mino 
commercial importance, the volume of litigation is by no mean 
sufficiently large to occupy half the time of the court, which 
places the state in the position of paying for services neither 
rendered or required. A retirement of at least one-fourth of the 
judges will in no way delay the administration of justice while it 
will make a waving approximately of ?25,000 per year to the peo- 

RKVKNl'K 

II cannot impress upon your minds too firmly the importance 
making such amendments to our revenue laws as will forever 
I the many gross abuses now so widelv licensed. By reason of 
inqucnt taxes the state has each year been compelled to utilize 
credit until the outstanding warrant indebtedness against the 
leral fund reaches the enormous amount of $1,989, 328. OK. By 
son of delinquencies each year in the payment of taxes, the 
te finds its appropriations in excess of gross receipts to the 
ent of at least $ 100, 000, necessitating the issuance of interest 
iring warrant*i to meet authorized expenditures. 

The Constitution limits the indebtedness of the state to 
? 100,000, vet the state debt is now close to the 18,000,000 mark </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
¦&gt; 

With a stop from farther incre&amp;oe couditioaod only and toitAj M 

23 

th legislation as will coaiprl the pa\ ment of taxes by all bold 
of property. 

I The amount of taxes ilue tlie state ami delinquent December 
(90S, as thoWM by the Auditor's records, was $:l, 4"&gt;". &lt;¦_': 
this amount the sum of 11,181, 1S4.C1 is due hut not ilelin 
cut. Thin makes the amount of delinquent taxes- %-j..W~ 
a sum of |M8,MV.6a greater than the outstanding ohligalionaiiist 
thcgCMfal fund. Of the amount delinquent #1,181, IS4.ttl 
for the tax levied in I 'JO I, mosl of which will be paid into the 
¦asury in the near future, but there still remains after deducting 
'delinquencies for 1*01, a delinquency of * 1 , 1 '.17. 1 To.uT, which 
presents the delinquencies fora period of years prior to 1*01. 
conservative study of tax statistics discloses the fact that the 
Stage annual delinquency is ::o per cent of the taxes levied. 

II t will l»e observed, therefore, that the real source of trouble 
the non-payment of taxes and that the remedy primarily must 
such as will compel payment. 

It is manifestly wrong for the state to be exacting and arbitrary 
with one class of tax payers ami ultra indifferent and lenient 
with others. I have in mind the taxes levied on railroad propoat] . 
not one dollar of which remains unpaid, yet there are those wbc 
advocate the adjustment of the discrepancy U-tween our expenditures 
and receipts, not by requiring the payment of taxes by all. 
hut by requiring corporate interests to contribute a correspond 
ingly greater amount. Injustice is written across the very face of 
this proposition. 

I recommend that the powers of the State Hoard of Kquali/.a 
lion be so extended as to empower said Board to raise as well M 
equalise values, and that comity tre.iHurers be empowered to 
convey title to property on which the taxes are unpaid, making 
ilue provision for redemption of title within a specified time, and 
for interest on money advanced for tax payment. Payment of 
taxes on movable and personal property should l»e due within M 
davs after the assessment, so as to guard against loss ot 
</seg>
            <seg id="p024">
24 

Euirli removal ninl eoBaeqarat extinction of identification. For 
|&gt;roni|it collection of taxes county treasurers should be made 
le on their bond*. 

tWith these modifications a proper enforcement of the proviih 
of our revenue laws coupled with an homst and economical 
niiiiRlration of public affairs will strike an even balatn e 
ween our rect ipts and disbursements and put an end to har:i*discrepancies 
of this character. 

It is important, too, that the law requiring all property to be 
assessed at it&lt; cash value l&gt;e rigidly enforced. With our proper! 
-ised at scarcely 10 per cent of its value, it must result in 
high rate of levy while the low valuation makes it appear th:i 
Nebraska, one of the principal industrial states of the Union, i 
still struggling in the shadows of primitive statehood. Tkoa 
M-eking investment consult our laws and our records and if the 
find that the combined wealth of Nebraska is *174. 000,000 afte 
more than a third of a century of statehood and that the tax lev 
is higher than are interest rates, they will not be likely to take u 
their abode with us. They will assume that the law is enforce, 
and that .*] 74,000,000 represents the aggregate real wealth of the 
state, whereas it represents scarcely more than 10 per cent of it. 

The assessed valuation of the state should not be less than 
* 1.000,000,000 and any lower valuation does the property 
interests of the state an injustice. By raising the assessed valuation 
to this amount, the rate of levy may be reduced correspondingly, 
entailing no extra hardships while it will remove a barrier 
that I am reasonably certain has in its time, turned back Millions 
of dollars seeking investment among us. 

KKCKIPTS 4VD KXI'KN IHTl'RKK 

During the biennium from Dec. 1, ItOl, to Dec. I, 1902. the 
receipts of revenue from all sources, aside from the school, University 
and endowment funds, was PS, 186,077. M and the current 
expenses, for the same period with like exceptions, were 8,87*,-788.1M, 
making the expenditures for the two years 1141,706.57 </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
25 

greater than tin- receipts. In the expenditure*, however. are 
included the deficiencies inherite&lt;l from the preceding administration, 
t.l4'.», 1 12.0.") in deficiency claims, and |U,t8S.M miscellaneous 
claims, amounting to ?182,735.97. This expWM w.i« 
incurred during the preceding biennium and should not therefore 
lie charged up to the current expenses of the last hiennium. On 
thi* basis of computation the current receipts during the la»i 
biennium just closed, were $41,030.10 greater than expenses in 
face of the extraordinary expenditures of *t&gt;3,000 for the Supreme 
&lt;'ourt Commission and stenographers, 175,000 for rebuilding the 
penitentiary. *"&gt;;&amp;amp;gt;, 000 for new addition to the Asvlum for the 
Insane at Hastings, $3o,000 for support of the State Fair, $1 
for the Pan-American Kxposition, and other incidental expeixli 
tures of a similar nature, aggregating *1 2,000, all of which cam. 
out of the current receipts and are included in the current expenses. 
On the whole this is the best showing for economy that ban 
fver been made, nor has there ever been a period when the States 
properties were kept in better physical condition or the iimi.i 
the various institutions better provided for. </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
26 

kKl'oKT oK THK AC IUTOII OK I* I' ltl.I* ' A* r« *\ \ 1 

STATEMENT No. 4. 

r mated receipt* for the Ji*&lt;&lt;tl ]&gt;enotl comm&lt;n&lt;i&gt;i&lt;i April 1. /.'»//, mmd 
ending March SI, 19o.',. li'iseit on tlir actual mMmMnm oj thr In 
proceeding the 1st dny of I) ccinlnr. /.'«/.'. 

Eeral fund levy for 1903 an&lt;l 1904 
eral fund collections on back taxes 
:ing fund collections on back taxes 
rellaneous collections 

2207. 

11617 5S 


From interests on deposits 


From miscellaneous collections 
From fees secretary of slate 
From fees auditor of public accounts 
From fees state oil inspector 


156551 94 

From fees state food commissioner 

From United States government aid S. and S. home 
From temporary school fund collections 

374709 s? 
3*3237 31 
251927 10 
282523 24 

From interest on school land 
From lease on school lands 
From interest on bonds 

Frot 1 interest on warrants 
From jjpme and fish licenses 


fcl temporary I'niversity fund collections 
1 interest on University land 

J ?5£ V, 

From lease on University fund lands 
From interest on Agricultural College lands 
From lease on Agricultural College lands 

&amp;$ 


From United States government aid agricultural and mechanical 

arts fund 

coooo 

rn United States government aid 
station fund 

agricultural experiment 


From University cash fund 
From Normal interest fund 


477O 35 

From Normal School librarv fund 


From state librarv 


From hospital for insane fund 

'354 74 

From convict labor 


r penitentiary land fund 
Total 


$4059031 75 

rn the total income of #4,059,031.75 
the general fund derives 
the school fund derives 
University fund derives 
Normal school fund derives 
state library fund derives 
penitentiary labor fund derive 
hospital for insane fund derives 

f 2079068 00 





Total 




Estimate of expenditures for the fisral perioil cimmem-ing April 

'lite of expenditures for the fiscal period rimmem-ing April 1. 
ami cmling March ,11st. i:»&gt;- r &gt; 

ami rniling March ,11st. IMf 

js&amp;r "" r - ». 
forltOi a. Sl |- II Sup- C. other ti.in 

Total ap 
imprint 'n 
for- 1MH 

A. Sil- It Sup- &lt; . iMIit-r 

b|IMB 

L'^ri-lat:vi i exiMMi^es £1 A IBM) 

it ! v&lt;' ex|HMi-rs si. :n &lt;¦&gt; 

1.VIM0 :fin 

QiviTiior . -MV.-, i). I.VW0 nil r.T7:. 

O ivernor 21353 M 

Com rof public lan.ls A building .WO i II JT^p 300 

loin r of public lands A buildini.-- .".WO i II 

ran :u»&gt; 

-uperinlrndent »*0 I SMI 

State superintendent 

Attorney gropral I9W« On 1:380 SM&gt; ."i«») 

1290 3'«i 

.-«») 

Attorney general ... I'twO til 

Secret an &gt;&gt;f Mate IH«HO LT«i 

Secretary of utatr 

inisd -_&gt;7m 

state treaxarer .. 3B2MO On 

Mate treasurer . IXWI) (X&gt; 13780 l"i&gt;»' '.«&gt;«i 

UTS) laxi 

¦«&lt;«' 

Auditor of public-accounts ... ¦_&gt;-&lt;*0&lt;K&gt; 3KU jiki 

Auditor of public arroutits 

2K0 

3««i 

\11Hitor insurnnr" (Inpartmcnt in.wiili 7HM0 :'7i«i 

\u000dr insurance department . lO.'wtlBt 

TllNO :'7l«i 

\ lintflDt (tiMi.-ra! 7l»«l INI !«*«• SH8 MM 

l««l -JUPIl 

.V.Wm 

Supreme court MKiOO Oil 4:«Ni :.M«&gt; 

4:wn :ano 

flapr— « unit MEiOO Oil 

Si-iti- library l!Ll»Min BDB -JIUNi 


B .ar.l of purclias. A. -upplii- " ikiio -kill 

I! ... r.1 of public Ian I- A bnil'tintc- :imiii&lt;i U000 i4«N) awl 

¦_1»«1 


Konrdof pducntional lan&lt;l~\ fiimls MuNIIO '*&gt;*&lt; 
•nkin« hoard .. HMOOO **&lt;&gt; lv&lt;i 

State banVin.'lKiard HMO 00 

iWO lv«i 

Foo:l riunmi^-ioni-r IHM III f*» JSB1 

KiKt I rojiimis-ionrT KMUO IX) 

D**) :t-l»i 


C..nimissi(.n&lt;&gt;r of labor 10 IX) 01) fW MO 

CHHII »."i&lt;l 

r.Miimissiowr of labor 10 IX) Oil 

Mil 

Si .t,- board of irrigation 14 wi mi H3«i I5«l IKK) 
Iniver^ity sU-'iill HI :««»&lt;»&gt; siniki liClNHI 2T-KMI 

si ,t.- board of irrimtiod 14 wmmi 

1I2«| l.-j**. 

IKK) 

nivarsiti nh.7)ii hi 

:km.i mimi 

liJUil 

r-Kwi 

Stan- Normal S'cIkmiI IMMdl) Ul 

Stan- Normal School IMMOIHNl « 00 KOO 44INI 7.VINI 

8 ijii K*ii 

44KI 

T.V... 

Girls' Industrial School LVB0UI i:*M«i !*&gt;«» K - ini 

flirl*" Indu-trial School I.V&gt;:'0 i^i 

i:*Uii I3M0 

inn 

Him 

Soldi.rs A: Sailor- liom.'. Milfnrrl |V« n iNi »Nfl -"'74 1 KM Ji 

SoWli.Ts.fc Sailor*" home. Milford STO (to 
Sol.liiT- ASailors'bome.OrandlslHDii MTfiJIi no 

&lt;«4ii 237*1 

ifiTill 


Solriirrn&amp;Sailore'hoaie.nrandlslanu 11763)011 30130 WfJii 7K)(| 
[ndastrinl wliool for Bov- . . . lHWdO Otl MOOtl •V-'UHi 

Ma i»i"j«i 

7i (HI 

idastrial whool for Bov- .... '.iini («• 

i.V»i .VJJiii </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
Institute for Feeble Mi mleH Youth VMV*&gt; 01! »*00 M7Mi rirtl 

:f4(»l M7".(l 

liwtitatr for Feebli- Minded Vontli iaiil.il i« 

nmi 


Home for the Friondl.-- .TSJtlC II IVtiK -JiNNUi 

Home for the Friondli -- 

MM ¦Jimm 

-.47:11 JI30B 

Asylum at Hastinits UlinC m '.47:n . 3Kj«»&gt; 

\-ylum at Ha-tinit~ I 

N.braska Industrial Home :r'7iNi '»¦ HTft) HM»i r«rti 

Nrbraika Industrial Hunw :fJ7(m i« 

•1701) HMm 

123X1 

In-iittitefortheDeRf A Dumli 104 TO &lt; ¦ &gt; «aDO :«B0 ir*(» 
: .¦niienliary .... 1*74*0 &lt;W 23000 1"&gt;&lt;)&lt;«I ll'.m HiiOCO 
h«h tame commis-ion. it2m&gt; im IWOO 4(NX) COO 

I ti-i it :!«•- for tlie Deaf A- Dumb 104 l"0 (HI 

:v&lt;^») Men 

ir*ii 

iHOii 

• ¦iiitenliary . ... 1274(«1 00 

son v**») 

I I'm 

MM 

¦»i«m Mm 

fl«h ft nne commis-ion. 213*1)"" 

COO 

State Historical xoeirty i:c«" (» 

State Historic.il socii-ty i:c») (HI i7:»i 4'&lt;»' imm 

TO) *'"' 

lout 

Hrwpita 1 at Lincoln «•'&gt;*») IIUW0 -,17ri0 

H.-pita 1 at Lincoln 1, 

IKSiU) 


-.17.-* 

N.hraska library commission. MOD 00 :1«NI 400O . ... 
reterinarian 0 on 3M0 l'mii 
¦ardof liealtl- - (ODD V - 1 " 1 

N.hraska library commission. iikki («. 

JUW 40W) 

State Teterinarian 

.-.SMI 


ard of liealtl- - com IB 

_'«&gt; 


St it. hoard of charities A cor'ct'n- Mini &lt;»• 2*00 ¦ ¦ 31'Ofl 

SI it. hoard of charities A cor'i-t'n- (Voi "" 

'Hut 

a-ix) 

l»i-trict court J2ia«) (X) J"-4«N&gt; 

I)i-trict court 221000 00 

224U«i 

Fugitives from ju-t ice l.smin ini HM8 
• lourn.-ils. etc :»&lt;««' ini '¦¦" 

Kii.'itivi-froin jnstiee ... isiwd im 

isnoo 

Laws. Journal-, etc 


Mapportnf State Poultry Ass'n 

Siii.porl if State Poultry Ass'n . .Inni 

3»X) 
2non 
.¦¦ono 
ia»m 

Support of StRte DairymHn-^ A-s'n 1*0011 Ki 
Sii|.|-o-t of State B'nlof Hoitieultarr Vim IX) 
SnpiNii t itf StatP B'rd of Atfricnlture 

Support of State Dairymen-s A-s'n L'Orn ) ' ¦ • 'Jinni . . 

Su|.|..tof.St.ileRrdof Horticulture JOrt) («) :«)0 

Sup|HHt itf State B'rd of Agriculture ¦ titliNI 
M bnok* A blank- .... BJM 

H^ti-iiiii' bole- A blanks 

Him 

Procuring A transcribini; abstractor 
land'' -.INK) 01) 

i'rocurinB A- tran-cribinir abstract* 

of land- .... 3«i Oil 


Compiling statute- |INN) M Mi 
\dvet ti-ii»K prop'inals for state pr'ntt i"»0 ini ?rpo ... 

\dvMt ti»ii»K prop'iHals for state pr'ntt "JTiO IK» 

r-4i 

Kefiiiulinif «tate taxes illn.Mll&gt; aa'e'd llW) ("' iflfK) 

Refrnidi-Mrnate taxi- illeiraljjr aa'e'd lixjo mi 

inmi 

Institute for the Blind 47:i"iii ini 1'Hini am 4!«ni 

laatltatfl for the Blind 17990 00 

L'lim aX".il 

4!«&lt;l 
worn 
i»in 

I&gt;ericiHiicies. estimated ..... .... 73000 00 7"&gt;i«ni 

Dpftriencies, estimated ..... .... T.'rfum ut 

Piihlishin^ constitutional amendm'ts 0X10 00 ii.KN) 

Pnbli^hin^ constitutional amcndm'ts i'C*it (Hi 

Wi If hountr rleflciencii'- XMU &lt;f* :iVN&lt;i 
¦ho&lt;&gt;l apportionment i:(4",isi i;7 1343181 H7 
Total wumm n «i:&lt;«« a» oo «saKS oo »i»» r.m m ten 
th " above total of -W.74H. IKfii.lo 

Wi If iMiunty d»'ficii'nci*'- . . . .Tillui (Ht - 

:«X«i 

the amount cliarKeablc to the upiiithI fund U ?.i^«'.'.'il 

the amount cliari:&gt;'ahle to tlie l'uiver~ity fund i- 704-V)!) 

tlie amount chartfeable to the library fund i- 8000 

the amount cliarteahle to the Normal Soiiool fund i» TMi Xi 

the amount i iiarReahir to tlie pt-nitrntiar) labor fund is M841 3K 
the amount rhtrarnhlr tn till lnati|l»TT| -i1um&gt;1 fund i- . . 1MMM W 

Total ui*mmr, </seg>


            <seg id="p028">
28 

I The foregoing estimate of receipts ami expenses is taken from 
e report of the Auditor of Public Accounts (tables 4 and 5) ami 
Vwsed on the receipt* of the preceding bienniiun and estimates 
expense* for the next biennium furnished by the heads of dertments, 
of boards and of institutions. 

It is hardly necessary for me to advise vou that th" estimate 
of expenses is entirely too high and that your honorable body 
would not be justified in appropriating money so largely in excess 
of current receipts. It will be observed that while the estimate.l 
receipts in the General Fund amount to ?•2,O7!',O(i8, the estimated 
expenditures amount to tt,t94.S61.i7. This would mean an increase 
in the interest l&gt;earing debt of the state of over half a million 
dollars, which, in view of the already large in erest bearing debt, 
should under no circumstances be authorized. 

With the exception of improvements at the Peru Normal, the 
penitentiary and a barn at the Lincoln Hospital for the Insane, no 
additional buildings are required. All the other institutions and 
properties are in excellent condition, have abundant room to satisfy 
ordinary demands, so that an appropriation for necessary 
repairs will )&gt;e sufficient. 

I The demand for more land for agricultural purposes in contion 
with any institution should be carefully considered. A- i 
tter of fact, except where physical exercise is beneficial to the 
nates and where they are physically and mentally quali- 
I to perform manual labor, it is cheaper for the state to 
•chase in the open market than to grow the products itself. For 
8 reason demands for appropriations for the acquisition of farm 
ds should be closely scrutinized if not promptly rejected. 

I Of the $tf21,050 asked for construction purposes, only a small 
r cent thereof is actually required and this sum can be reduced 
76,000 without in any sense impairing the public service. 

tThe expenses of the Supreme Court as estimated include clerk 
stenographic hire which two years ago the legislature required 
chief clerk of that department to pay from the fees of the &lt;le- </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
29 

compelled to do differently at this time. In the estimate at this 
time is one extra reporter, ? % 2,000, two stenographer*, $3,500, MM 
deputy clerk. *4.00'i. These appropriations, as well as the | 
for deputy reporter, should not be made. I also recommend that the 
elarfc of the Supreme Court I* 1 made a salaried officer and that he 
l»e required to pay all the fees into the treasury. The income of the 
vlerk from fee? amounts to more than the combined salaries of the 
three judges, to say nothing of his salary of *l,"&gt;uu as Clerk and 
*],500 as Reporter. There is no good reason why the state should 
|»ay for ordinary clerical service approximately five times as much 
:u&gt; it pays for executive and judicial services, and nearly ten times 
as much as is paid for like service by private business concerns. 

It is my judgment that the following estimates represent i\ 
&lt;t-Mve appropriations: 

I The University in its estimate increases its cost of maiutenaiic&lt; 
St4,000 over the appropriation of two years ago. Of this amoun 
0,000 is for increase in salaries and wages. Aside from a rea 
liable appropriation for repairs and incidental improvements, i 
my judgment that no increase is necessary over the appropriatioi 
two vears MfO. 

tThe Girls" Industrial School requires no appropriation for 
istruc.tion and the 410,000 in the estimate of expenses for that 
titutiou sin hi Id be disallowed. 

Unless it be arranged to consolidate the (Irand Island Sol; 
and Sailors' Home with the Home at Milford, as herein i 
mended, the sum appropriated for construction should be 
materially reduced from the estimate of *27,3&lt;mi. 

I The Institute for Feeble-Minded youth asks for *31 
struction. This institution requires a liberal appropriation for 
airs, but nothing more. 

tThe estimate for the Asylum for the Insane at Hastin_ 
t,9M and the amount appropriated two years ago was *¦_ 
reason of the destruction of the Hospital for the Insane at </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
30 

Norfolk, by tire, and the consequent removal of about l-2'i inmate* 
to the Asylum at Hastings, and by reason of a material increase 
in the number of inmates, this institution will naturally require a 
larger appropriation at thin time than was made two year- 
This additional expense, however, by no means justifies an inciea-c 
of 1146,096. The difference in crop conditions compared with 
two years ago, the physical condition of the property now and the 
-ity for practicing economy in the highest decree consistent 
with good service combine to justify a reduction in the estimate 
of this institution. 

The Nebraska Industrial Home asks for an inereasi over two 
\ears ago of $11, MO. It is true that the physical condition of 
this property is not first-class and that there is justification for the 
immediate expenditure of money for repairs. But no such amount 
is needed as is incorporated in the estimates under the head of 
••Other expenses." The sum appropriated two years ¦£•, with 
enough to make needed repairs, will be amply sufficient. 

The Institution for the Deaf and Dumb at Omaha in its &lt;-&gt;ti 
mate places its expenses for the next two years at |&lt;104,3"&gt;U, whereas 
the amount appropriated two years ago was $73,950. There is no 
-ity for increasing the amount of two years ago. as the number 
of pupils is about the same and the physical condition of the 
property is good. 

I The State Penitentiary requires only such increase over the 
jropriation of two years ago as will provide funds for complen 
of the buildings which were damaged by tire two years ago. 

JThe Fish and Game Commission, though somewhat obstruct* d 
the performance of duty through lack of sufficient funds, is not 
titled in its demands for an increase such as it has included in 
estimates, provision for stenographic service at $840 per vear 
all the addition that should be made to the Hum appropriated 
&gt; years ago. 

I The State Historical Society, instead of receiving an increase 
$3,300 as asked, should be satisfied if its appropriation is not </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
31 

The Hospital for the Insane at Lincoln place* its estimates for 
the next two years at 1*40, 8.1U as compared with an appropriation 

&lt;&gt;f *l4"&gt;,ti7') two years ago. The number of inmate- of tliis institution 
like the Asylum at Hastings, was substantially increased 
by the removal of inniatts to it from Norfolk 15ut aside from 
reconstructing a liarn which was recently almost destroyed by 
tire, ami aside from a small appropriation for repair* there is m&gt; 
justification for increasing the appropriation for this institution 
more than one-half the amount asked. An investigation of the 
funds of this institution and of the Asylum at Hasting*, disclosetlie 
fact that these two institutions will have practically no deti- 

tieies April 1. IMS, which, under the circumstances, reflect 
it credit upon their management. 

The sum of tS*4.00Q is the estimate of t''c salary expense! of 
the District Courts. Should the recommendations herein made, 
i. e. that the number of judge* be reduced one-fourth, a saving 
can be made of tott,000 and the amount appropriated should W 

correspondingly lessenei 

tThc estimate for printing laws, journals, etc. , is x'.i.ouo greater 
11 the amount appropriated two years atjo and there being praclly 
sufficient funds for this purpose on the basis of two year((91,000) 
a larger appropriation than that lacks justification. 

Other institutions and some of the divisions of the executive 

Iiartinent have made requests for inert ate in their appropriation* 
hoiit apparent justiticatii n and on I.elialf of the people, upon 
-houlders these burdens must fall, I solicit at your handeful 
and searching inquiry into the subject before passing j 
nt on these demands. 

In raoonuaending these reduetions in the estimates. I am 
guide&lt;l, solely by the lamp of experience. 1 have embraced 
opportunity to acquaint myself with the physical condition of all 
state property ami with current needs in order that in passing 
judgment I might have the Hid and support of ait intelligent understanding. 
I have weighed carefully, every element of merit, having 
in mind at all time-; the welfare of the public charges, no Ism tliau </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
32 

that of tin 1 UU ]&gt;;iycrs. and in reaching a harmonious balance 
between justifiable and unjustifiable burdens. I have taken inl.i 
full account every legitimate obligation modern civilisfttiou 
imposes on organized society. 

fePro?Mrioa should be nadt for paving the State's portion of II 
et between 1+th and loth streets, and for paving the Btato'a 
:ion of Kith street bftWWI II and K streets, i-ondilioneil on 
proc-al action by tlie city of Lincoln. 

CAPITAL ITSIS1IMKNT 

tSoine years ago Nebraska, in |NlfWMUMe of a policy adopted 
organized society in several other states, enacted a law authoiig 
the imposition of the death }&gt;enalty on conviction of murder 
the first degree. The primary object of the law was and i* 
repress the crime of unlawfully taking human life. 

The right of society to protect itself and its institutions must 
always stand unquestioned. But, while there can be no honest 
difference of opinion as to its right to protect, there can be as to 
how that protection shall be obtained. In this our day of 1&gt;.um 
ful enlightenment, we find employed in the administration of jnt»-tice, 
instruments which in the darkest ages represented the most 
vicious form of punishment human savagery and barbarism wa* 
able to conceive. 

(Xor can it be successfully contended that as a preventive cap-1 
punishmei.t is an effective remedy. Capital offenses are cemtted 
as frequently in states where capital punishment is in vogue 
where it is not. 

tin order that your honorable body might have an opportuy 
to deliberate on this subject, with a view to extinguishing 
s provision of the penal statute, I granted a reprieve to ¦ 
illiam Khea. under sentence of death for the crime of murder, 
y ing execution until the second Friday in July, IMS. 

In passing judgment it is well to l&gt;ear in mind that where 
HVere penalties are attached, it ie difficult to obtain conviction. </seg>


            <seg id="p033">
El that leniency is often exercised by jury men ev n in the 
positive evidence because they take into account severity of the 
laity, which often results in the guilty escaping punishment, 
irelv. 

It is well t&lt;&gt; bear in mind, too, that in rive of the &gt;l . 
Colorado, Rhode Island. .Maine, Michigan and Wiscon-in. capital 
punishment is expressly forbidden and that crime of murder is no 
more common, in these states than in states where capital punish 
litest in authorized. 

I Hence, I would recommend that your honorable body | 
braska among states representing the highest type of «'i\ iliza¦ 
and the teaching! of the meek and lowly Nazarine. 

KZKA P. SAVAGE. 

RKCKIPTS AMi IIIMBI'BSKMEHTH \l (JOVKKXOB H OFFICE 
The Bi-Annoal Period from .lanuarv 1st. 1W01, to 

1 )ccember 

1st, I'.mp-j 

KKHIT 


tun Federal (io\ 
iiinent for Sold ien 

Paid into the Statt 
Treasury, as per He 


rm Federal (Joviment 
from sales 

of public land 

.V 460. 09 

I-Ycs for Extradition 

Warrants 

- f or Commissions 

of Deeds 45.00 

Kec'd from trans, of 

*66,303. 34 

111. Illl 

#66,313.34 


&amp; Sailors" Homes... $60,657. 85 ccij.ts 

N. N. &lt;; 5«.8O </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
34 

¦ ..M\ll TATION 

Of Penitentiary Sentences granted by Goveraof Savage: 

Klnier Urback, •"&gt; years for grand larceny. Commuted to :{ 
8 months, 1 day, on represent Uioii of Prison Physician thai 
tlie prisoner was fatally afflicted with tabaVMkMM, and having for 
*everal months been helpless in hospital. May 2, IStOl. 

I Frank Edwards. 3 years for rape. Conditionally commuted 
¦1 years, I months, 1 1 days, it being proven a matt"r of doubt 
ether the crime really came within the classification of rape, 
y 13, 1901. 

Cuylor Sehultz, 80 years for murder second decree. Commuted 
to 10 years and 7 days, it being clearly proven that at the 
time the crime was committed his mental condition was impaired 
by reason of a bullet wound received during the civil war, btiag 
further ascertained that it was a provoked assault followed after 
years of tantalization: also that his aged wife was in distrr««. 
May 13, 1901. 

Edward Johnson, 0 years for burglary- Having lived faith 
fully up to the conditions of bis parole, granted by Governor 
Poynter, he was commuted to 4 years, -i months, 22 da \ 
order to secure desirable employment in another state. May lr&gt;. 
1901. 

I Sherman Taylor. I year for horse stealing, (iiven a reduen 
of 1 day on ac -ount of July 4th. 

Nicholas Fox, life for murder second degree. On petition of 
a large number of citizens and the earnest request of many firemen 
for valuable and heroic services rendered the state in extiiiLruisl; 
ing conflagrations at the penitentiary; on on account of his good 
prison record, and it being proven that there were mitigating circumstances 
attending the commission of the crime, his sentence 
was commuted to 11 years and 7 months. June 24, lltOl. 

§ Charles Moorman, 1 year for horse stealing, given reduction 
day oh account of July 4th. </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
hlian. .1. Yalck, 7 years for |&gt;&lt;&gt;rjury. On the earnest •clichatioa 
in v citizens, and on condition that lie enter into ;i marital com- 

Khich was legally coiiHiiinated in the executive chamber, he 
¦muted to 1 vear. •"&gt; mouths. IT davs. July '••. 1*01. 

¦1:1s. H. King, id yean foraaaaalt to rohaad mnnler. Cowto 
8 years, i molitliH. ¦_' days, to offset I period served in 
mty jail. .Inly 28, L901. 

El ward Moore, l"i years lor murder in seeonil ilegree. 
to H yeai&gt; on a Hpeeial re«|iiest from all tlie prison autlioritier 
id and sufficient reasons. August 1. 1901. 

John T'mM, 1 year for grand larceny. Having paid thi 

Eieutition. over two liuinlre'1 dollars, his previous raconi _ 
being tl« &gt; ill &gt;T fill whether In- committed larceny intentionally, 
the recommendation of the trial judge, lie was commuted 
until* and •'. days. SepteinWr :«, IM1. 

Kv ; &lt;l (ieorge, 1 year for assault to do liodily injury. On tin 
solicitation of many &lt;iti/,ens, including the trial judge, his 
I was commuted to c. months. 7 days. September IS, 

August Kastner, life for murder. Letters and petition for 
executive clemency having been tiled by many witnesses for tin 
state. l»y the trial judge and by the prosecuting attorney, and bj 
many other citizens in which were expressions of doubt as to his 
guilt, and an investigation rather tended to establish his innocence, 
•iitence w:!s commuted to :t vears, r&gt; months. 6 davs. Octo- 

ber U. 1901. 

George Hippie, •"&gt; ears for 

Matt to rape. Commuted on 
many citizens of ('ass (&gt;&gt;unt}. 
to :i years, &lt;t months, -jr, darn. 

:iss- 

Eof complaining witness, 
for evidence brought to light. 
ember 10, 1901. 

Lysle Shew. 1 year for horst 

stealing. &lt; &gt;n petition of trial 
was commuted to ¦_' mont 

Ege and many citizens sentence 
Peeetber -20, 1901. 

I ¦ " I T* t 1 1 ' \" ''II \4'"L?*K Till 4 I * 1 1 1 I H * 'I 'f\\*\\\\*\\\ K.\\\ tb4 b Titliill It'M </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
36 

thousands, of whom many were among the liest citizens of ilu«tatc, 
requesting .in unconditional pardon, sentence w.-is commuted 
tn ."&gt; yean, 7 months, 8 days, December 31, 1901. After month* 
of careful investigation, it appeared to me thai tlierc was something 
¦ore in the sentence than just to appease the Mind Goddem; 
thai it was comparatively excessive five years being the usual 
sentence for nubexdement. I concluded that no harm ooold be 
done to anyone by OOlumUtillg this sentence, anil no good could 
come from keeping him in the penitentiary, lmt some good might 
!«• done his aged parents and liis innocent wife and children. 

Otto Warwick. B years for burglary. Several reputable 
physicians testified to Ii is deploralile physical condition, and on 
Ktrength of this faet, and on request of many petitioners, sentence 
¦ immuted to 4 vears. 4 months, •_'•_' da\s. 

John Cook, 1". yean for robbery. On recommendation of 
chief of police of Omaha, County Attorney Shields. Judge 
KstelK- and principal witness and prosecutor for the state, sentence 
immuted to .". years. February 7th. 1902. 

Leland Spaulding. "i years for rape. Sentence commuted to 
:• months, (i days, on showing ma le of previous good conduct that 
the offense did not constitute the crime of rape, and that Justinwould 
best be subserved by commutation. Feb. I 1 -', 1908. 

IIIerlxTt Miller. •! year* for rape. Commuted to -2 years. 
¦ it hs. B days, on petition of majority of jurors, prosecutin 
irney, complaining witness and her relativi 

I William Scott. ."i years for robbery. On c( rtiticate of pi 
siciai that prisoner was fatally afflicted with consumption, his 
tence was commuted to 2 years, 7 months. -21 days. 

Thomas Sullivan. 1 1 year for murder. Commutation was 

prayed for by numerous citizens of Omaha and recosa mended by 
1 rial judge ami jurors. After careful investigation of the evidence 
ted, sentence was commuted to 4 years, 8 months. 4 days. 
April 17, I'.'u-i. 

Harry Kay. 1 year for larceny. On petition from the </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
37 

mother of the prisoner, the recommendation of the trial judge an. I 
many citizens, sentence wan commuted to s months. 8 days. April 
17, 1MB. 

IBert Martin, I years for horse stealing. This prisoner Mug 
sexual monstrosity, untit for association with men or women, 
¦n in a penal institution, and on the solemn promise of its aged 
•ther to care for it and guard it. and that prison morals imperaely 
demanded its removal, sentence was commuted to 1 year. •'. 
&gt;nths. February 8, l!»0-2. 

I Arthur Johnson, 8 years for robbery. On the earnest solidion 
of Judges Sullivan and Kinkaid and many citizens, giving 
ad and satisfactory reasons, sentence was commuted to •"&gt; _\ • 

tJohn H. Holli8ter, -2 years for horse stealing. On the repntation 
of Prison Physician Dr. Wilmeth. that the prisoner waicted 
with pulmonary tuterculosis and could live but a very 
&gt;rt time, sentence was commuted to 1 year, 4 months, 7 days. 

t Barney McGinn, life for murder. Commuted to 0 years. :! 
nths on petition of trial judge Benj. Baker and prosecuting atney 
on the condition that he shall leave the state immediately 
&gt;n his release and remain away forever. June 30, IMS. 

tChas. H. Park and C W. Wright, 3 years for rape. Comted 
to 1 year, 3 months, 19 days on proof of previous food 
duct and on earnest solicitation from numerous citizens presentnew 
and satisfactory evidence. June 30, 1 90S. 

t James H. Hall, 1 year for forgery. On the representation of 
trial judge (Stull) jail time 1 month. Stfl days was allowed oa 
time. 

I Morton Inwin, 1 year for shooting to kill. On petition of 
al judge and many citizens, commuted to three months, is 
ys, August 1, IWI. 

tAntoine Ladonx. 1 year for manslaughter. On the earnest 
uest of the trial judge (Westover) and many other petitioner*, 
tence was commuted to it months, 4 days. August • &gt;, !'.'• 

Elza L. Lewis, 1 year for forgery. Trial judge llolnns :md </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
38 

Sheriff Branson laid before the Governor evidences showing mitigating 
circumstances and sentence was coinninted to H months. I j 
•lavs. 

I Patrick Walsh, 10 rears for rape. This sentence was conited 
to -i years, 7 months on petition and showing made by trial 
ge, prosecuting attorney and many citizens. August 1"&gt;, 1 ".mi-j. 

John Joy. This prisoner being an escaped convict from Toronto, 
Canada, was released a few days before sentence expired in 
order to honor an application for extradition by His Majesty's 
government and on recommendation of the federal government. 
Oct. 2--», Ifltf, 

Thomas O'Connor, 7 years for breaking and entering. Thi* 
prisoner l&gt;ecame insane and was removed to th&lt;» Hospital for 
Insane, Lincoln. On the promise of hie relatives in Washington 
to take him out of the state and properly care for him. and con 
nidering this proposition was for the best interests of the state 
and on the recommendation of the superintendent of the Hospital 
for Insane, sentence was commuted to '2 years, 2 months, 19 days. 
November 17, 190-2. 

John A. Heming, 1 year ti months for grand larceny. On 
special request of trial judge and sheriff, and petition of many 
citizens sentence was commuted to 10 months, 20 days, December 
8th, 1902. 

Fremont S. Musfeldt and Kitty IX (nee elans) by the Rock 
County- District Court sentenced to I months in county jail and 
tines of $100.00 and $25.00 respectively for criminal co-habitation. 
They have since been married. A large delegation of citizens 
from Rock County prayed for executive clemency and that 
the above named sentence be set aside. Granted September litth. 

t Lillian Stevens, 1 year for larceny from the person. On peral 
request of the trial judge, sentence was changt-d to 1 year in 
uglas county jail. 

A. B. I^awrence, fifteen months for embezzlement. This sen- </seg>


            <seg id="p039">
toni'i' was commuted to four months, twenty-four days on ike petition 

I suffering wife and children, and from tort v-eiirht citizens.. t |, : , !; 
lOT county. Decemiier It, lltOS. 

I John W. Argabright. life for murder. Hundreds of pviiners 
and an equal amount of lettofi from men of high cliar.ietei ¦. 
tiniony given lie fore the coroner's* jury, ami additional evidence. 
shaded by any influence, expressions in writing from a fonarf 
tor— y (ieneral and two former Deputy Attorney (ienerals. all 
this state, each of whom were connected with this case in the 
preme Court, have convinced me that the offense was not and 
ild not be greater than manslaughter: that the convict lia¦((iiately 
punished, and that the ends of Justice demands the rose 
of the prisoner from further punishment. For the f«H¥goia|f 
.son*, sentence was commuted to ten years, two months, twenty 
le davs. December f 8, IMS. 

I Anton (Jloystein, seven years for manslaughter. Sentence 
minted to five years, eight months, ten days for the reason of 
excellent behavior, and many petitioners. DerenilxT ¦_':(. 1 

I Otto Hitchcock, one year six months for grand larceny. On 
trial request of Trial Judge and Sheriff and petition of kmj 
i/.ens sentence commuted to ten mouths, twenty days. Decenr 
- •_'.-), l'-»02. 

Rowland P. Hills, four years for bigamy. Commuted to «M 
year, seven months, twenty-six days. Clemency in this case, con 
ditioned primarily &lt;in long confinement in jail l&gt;ef ore final judgment 
was rendered; on j&gt;etition of eleven of the twelve jurors and a 
large number of citizens. DecemVr -J'.t, IMS. 

Joseph Martin, one year for grand larceny. On new evidence 
produced and on petition of the Trial Judge, Chief of Police. 
County Attorney, and others, this sentence wan commuted t&lt;. 
months, eighteen days. December II, I'.tO-J. 

I Joseph A. HaTW, one year for falsifying Hank Statement, 
minuted to one day on application and recommendation of 
lire Sullivan and others. Januarv 8, 1909. </seg>


            <seg id="p040">
til- 

Governor John II. Mickey 

To THK 

TWENTY-EIGHTH SESSION 

OF THK 

LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA 

JANUARY 6, 1903 

fthr Mtmktn &lt;&gt;f tlif Senate ami Houxe of the Twenty-eighth Le&lt;jl4alire 
Aniembly tf the State of Xfibraxlcu. 

(illNTl.KMKN: 

In MMtoung the office of chief executive of the great ftata 
&lt;&gt;f Nebraska, I am profoundly count-ions of the responsibility 
resting upon me and of the magnitude of the undertaking. W'itli 
me thin in a time for very serious thought. The acts of my 
administration will have more or less effect upon the interests of 
every citizen, and the possibilities of doing good stand out before 
me in such prominence, that I trust my mental perception may 
never be diverted therefrom. As between the executive and your 
honorable body, concurrent branches of our state government, 
there ought to l&gt;e. and I have confidence to believe there will be. 
a perfect harmony in our mutual relations. You are the law-making 
Ixxly and your presence here is proof of the fact that you ;ire 
leaders of thought and controllers of events in your respective 
districts. Much, therefore, will depend upon you, not only in 
the enactment of wise legislation but in co-operating with me in 
the enforcement of the same, to the end that the law rnav he </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
41 

respected and the interests of the peopll best eoMWTVcd. &lt; &gt;ur 
responsibilities art- mutual :»n&lt;l there should Ik- no disposition t&lt;&gt; 
shirk on tlif part of either of us. While we are not all of the 
same political faith, 1 l&gt;elieve we are all patriots ami from our 
several view points are honestly looking toward the accomplishment 
of the greatest good to the greatest number. In the work 
that is In'fore us, we should rise above the exercise of mere partisan 
spirit and occupy a plane of broad toleration and charity. 
My ambition is to Imj the governor of all the people, regard! 
party, and to merit their confidence. 

The necessity for safe-guarding the public purse has been 
pertinently called to your attention in the message of my predecessor. 
Verv many matters pertaining to tin public good will l.e 
brought to your notice, a large portion of them contemplating 
more or less of expense. In the consideration of all these in-«-tions, 
your motto should be "strict economy without parsimony." 
The state should l&gt;e too wise to be lavish and too just to l&gt;e 
penurious. We should remember, too, that we are builders fur 
the future. Our acts are not confined alone to the present but 
like the concentric circles, formed when a j&gt;ebble is dropped into 
the water they extend on and on in their influence and effV 
Legislation, therefore, should be of that broad, unselfish character 
which looks past the present into the future, and contemp! 
coming as well as immediate necessities. It is a great responsibility 
to 1h' permitted to have a rominent part in the development 
of a young and progressive state, so rich in resources and 
bright with promise as is Nebraska, and I trust that this thought 
may be ever present in your work. Above all. we should I 
Divine guidance, (iotl controls the affairs of states and nation*, 
just as he does of individuals, and no people can permanently 
prosper who are not submissive to His will. It is therefore 
important that in all our deliberations we should ba led by Him, 
for in such leadership there is the most perfect liberty, begetting 
a charity which in itself is the fulfillment of all law. I sincerely 
hope that this legislature will achieve distinction for the wisdom 
of its acts anil for the harmony and fraternal spirit which shall 
characterize all its deliberations. I especially challenge your </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
42 

attention to a few matter* of public policy: 

RKVKMK 

The question of revenue is one wliioli vitally concerns every 
interest in the state, and always presents troublesome phases. At 
present, the floating indebtedness of the commonwealth is largely 
in excess of the amount permitted under the Constitution and irapidly 
increasing. There is, no defensible reason for the existence 
of such a condition. It is largely due to the prevalent and 
pernicious practice of undervaluing all forms of property and 
franchises which enter into the makeup of the assessors" schedules, 
the result being that the grand assessment roll is merely a financial 
shadow of the tangible resources and wealth which it is intended 
to represent. With a statutory limitation on the number of mills 
that can be levied, the amount of revenue derived from any given 
assessment is correspondingly abridged and at present is far below 
the amount absolutely required to meet running expen- 
Another important contributory cause to the increasing indebtedness 
is the further fact that many county treasurers are exceedingly 
lax in the matter of tax collection. Large sums are allowed to 
encumber the books year after year, on which collection ought to 
be forced and the proceeds turned into the public treasury for the 
general good. At the present time, the delinquent taxes owed t&lt;&gt; 
the state are approximately $'2,400,000. Of this enormous amount. 
only a small per cent., outside of the taxes of 1901 and 1908, is 
now collectable though it is frequently quoted as an available asset 
for the extinguishment of debt. These conditions are unsatisfactory 
and should be relieved. It is apparent that the state cannot 
ignore its obligations. Its educational, philanthropic and corrective 
institutions must not be impaired in their usefulness and 
the spirit of the constitution must be respected in its limitation of 
indebetness. To harmonize these divergent necessities is the task 
devolving upon your honorable body. As a first step, it seemme 
that the assessment roll should be increased to the proportions 
contemplated for it by law. Section I, Article IX of the Constitution 
makes it obligatory on the legislature to "provide such </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
43 

&gt; 

|&gt;enue as may 1k&gt; needful, by levying ;i 'ax by valuation, so tha 
ery person and corporation shall pay a tax in proportion to tli 
lue of his, her or its properly, and franchises to value to li 
rtained in such manner as the legislature shall direct," etc. Th 
jislature has declared that all personal and real property shall \&gt; 
luetl at its fair cash value and the plain intention of the statute 
to impose upon every person connected with the assessment, th 
ty of enforcing that idea. I recommend that existing laws K 
rrected so as to insure that all forms of real and personal pro) 
y will be listed at full valuation for purposes of taxation: als 
it the laws governing the collection of taxes be made nor 
ingent and effective. I further recommend that the duties o 
• State Board of Equalization be broadened so that it shall hav 
iple power to raise or lower assessments for state purposes ii 
rmony with the full valuation plan, and that county Iniards be 
fen such additional authority as may be needed in order to 
rry out the same idea. It is important that these matters rcve 
your immediate attention, that the resultant laws may lie 
erative for the coming assessment. 

KXl'KRIMAXTAl. FARM 

I Nebraska is distinctively an agricultural and live stock procing 
state. These two industries, with horticulture, are the 
*is of the major part of the prosperity enjoyed by our people. 
hatever tends to promote these interests increases the general 
¦alth in the same ratio. In wise recognition of these facts, the 
,te has long since established an experimental farm near Lincoln 
connection with the State University, where careful and elabor¦ 
tests are made in the production of grains, grasses and forage 
ints, under varying conditions, where the several kinds of live 
&gt;ck which add wealth to the farm are kept for purposes of 
perimentatiou. where horticulture is systematically promoted. 
il from which is disseminated from time to time, facts and data 
ative to the work accomplished. At this farm. too. during the 
liter months, young men and women who desire to acquire 
•unite knowledgi concerning agriculture and animal husbaudary. </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
44 

are fives short, practical coww in tkoee subjects, wder Um 
¦aperriMOfl of the director of the station and his assistants. Such 
imtriM lion is neyrate and distinct from tlic regular agricultural 
DOVI2 as pursued at the I'niversity. 'l'lie good results derived 
trom tliis experimental farm are ebviow to all who keep pace 
with the trend of events. As has been stated, the experimental 
farm is located near Lincoln, in the humid part of the state. 
where the i-limatic conditions are very different from those which 
prevail farther west in the arid and semi-arid portions of the commonwealth. 
The conditions there, in my judgment, demand the 
lUlisliincnt of an experimental farm also, in connection with 
the State University, and under the management of Um board of 
regents, which shall give special attention to tests in agriculture, 
stuck raising and horticulture, under the peculiarities of soil and 
climate there prevailing. Such an institution would give an 
impetus to the rural interests of that part of the state and would 
prove an important factor in the more thorough development of a 
section which is sometimis regarded as being handicapped b\ 
nature but which is rich in natural resources, if agricultural 
energy is directed along proper lines. Our congressional delegation 
has received assurance from the general government that it 
will gladly co-operate in the work, in connection with its irrigation 
and reclamation plaits, and if Nebraska takes the initiative, it is 
probable that our station will become the seat of the government's 
ti and experiments conducted in behalf of the other states in 
this same region. I. therefore, recommend that the legislature 
make an appropriation for the purchase, equipment and maintenance 
of a farm at some suitable point, in the western part of the 
state, t&lt;&gt; 1«- under the control of the State University, and known 
as an adjunct of the same, for the purposes mentioned. 

MI'RKMK I'OIRT COMMISSION 

Your attention is urgently called to the necessity of providing 
for the continuation of the supreme court commission. The 
present commission has performed commendable service and 
reduced the volume of litigation for years pending in the supreme </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
45 


court. While the number of commissioners might be decreased. 
I am firmly of the opinion that the number should not be lees 
than six. considering the rights of litigants, and the imperative 
&lt;iemand of the people that every case should receive fair and full 
consideration. 

I The good name of our judiciary and the value of its opins, 
depend very largely on the care and deliberation given each 
ision. The constitution guarantees to every suitor the right 
appeal to the supreme court; the right to ap]&gt;eal implies a guary 
that the court of last resort will hear and determine the law 
I the merits of the controversy thoroughly. The three ju*;s 
of the supreme court are unable to meet the requirements of 
constitution, in this respect not because of their own inabilii 
as just and diligent judges, but because of the present and 
Teasing volume of business in that court. The supreme court 
now constituted, is an able and efficient tribunal and a credit t&lt;&gt; 
f great state: and yet it must be conceded there is a limit to the 
»acity of a conscientious judge in the confederation and &lt;!¦ 
of cases involving the liberties and properties of the people. 

I, therefore, recommend the enactment of a law similar to 
the one passed by the last legislature creating the present commission, 
so modified as to provide for six instead of nine commissioners. 


ADVISORY HoARD OK PARDONS. 

While 1 have no disposition to shrink from the Constitutional 
and statutory responsibility imposed on the chief executive in the 
matter of exercising clemency toward inmates of the j»enitentiary, 
yet I believe that the public good would be greatly enhanced 1&gt;\ 
the creation of an Advisory Board of Pardons to which should Iw 
referred all applications for relief from punish-neit for penal offenses 
and matters pertaining thereto. Such board should 1&gt;e 
authorized to hear and weigh all evidence on which the appli 
for pardon is predicated and within a reasonable time to report it- </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
46 

t lings to the governor with a recommendation for or against tin 
Tcise of executive clemency, as each individual case may seen 
require. I, therefore, recommend that such board of pardon* 
created, the details to be arranged by your honorable body. 

KIHTAT1OXA1. INSTITl TION&gt; 

tThe people of Nebraska are justly proud of their educational 
titutions. The foundations of these interests have l&gt;een laid 
»ad and deep and may be properly regarded ax the corner stonethat 
degree of eminence and distinction which the mate now 
oys. 

I No other part of our country is blessed with so small ¦ per 
t. of illiteracy or has so much to show, in proportion to popuon, 
in the way of good school buildings, tine equipments and 
c-ially fitted instructors. At the head of these interests, stands 
State University with its numerous departments, closely - 
led by the State Normal. The institutions have done, and arc 
ng, for the state a work greater than can be estimated, the 
uence of which will be felt throughout all time. These interi 
should receive the careful attention of your body and such 
•ropriations should be made as will insure the continuance of 
ir beneficent work on a scale commensurate with the state' f&gt; 
elopment. 

- IITVTIOXAL AMKXDMEXTS 

During recent years a number of attempts have been made t&lt;&gt; 
necure needed changes in the organic law of the state, by subraixsioii 
to the voters of proposed amendments to the constitution. 
I'nder the constitutional provisions, all proposed amendment* 
must be submitted at the general election at which members of 
the legislature are voted for. By the present law such proposed 
amendments, in abridged form, are made a part of the regular 
ballot and a majority of all votes cast must be recorded affirmatively 
for each proposition before it can be adopted. In the 
greater interest attaching to the election of candidates the voter* </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
47 

II sight of tin- importance of constitutional changes and :i 
jority of them fail to vole on the propositions submitted. Ali 
failure to vote is in effect a negative vote &lt;m the question, or 
¦stions, it becomes practically impossible to amend the constiion 
by such means, even in cases where the people an- fftm- 
Uy agreed that the change should 1k&gt; made. As a correction of 
* difficulty and a means of securing the seeded constitutional 
ditications, I recommend that your body propose an amendnt 
to Section 1 of Article XV of the constitution which will 
'vide that amendments to the constitution may In- submitted to 
electors for approval or rejection at a general or special ele&lt;-11, 
and I further suggest that the present election law I. 
as to authorize a separate ballot for the suhmiswi I 
h questions. 

Oil. 1NSI'K&lt; TlilN 

For BUM time there has been very general complaint of the 
(jollity of oil which is shipped into Nebraska for illuminating 
purposes. The trouble seems to be that it is not properly freed 
from its natural impurities, or, in other words, that it is not sufficiently 
refined. Our present inspection law. adequate so far as 
the points covered by it are concerned, was intended to protect the 
public from the use of illuminating oil which might volatizi 
low a temperature as to occasion the danger of explosion. It doe* 
not provide for a test of these impurities which measure and 
weigh, and the presence of which detract materially from the illuminating 
power of the oil with which they arc compounded. I 
recommend that the oil inspection law be so amended as to include 
a test for impurities and that a standard of purity be established. 

During the year 1994, the Louisiana Purchase Exposition 
will be held in the city of St. Louis. It is estimated that not lcs» 
than |30,000,00&lt;i will Ik; expended on this enterprise. The general 
tfnVPrillDPtlt 'I lift "k tlMtlllM'f* 111 t II I * M t '\ 1 t*M 1 1 *L V 4* ' 1 ! F" i fc " Li I V IX \ V* # l 1 1 tt I i 1 * - 

ST. l.ol'IS KX POSITION" </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
48 

Intial recognition, and the o'her states will undoubtedly do so 
their respective legislatures assemble. Nebraska should have a 
•t in this grand display of the world's resources, and especially 
as the event is intended to commemorate the acquisition of the 
st important territory ever added to the national domain, a ter_&gt;ry 
from which the state was carved and of which it is the 
ghtest jewel. Your body should make a liberal appropriation 
the proper representation of Nebraska at this exposition, sub- 
I to such restrictions and details of expenditure as prudent &lt;• 
y suggest. 

I'KXITKXTIARY 

By reason of the failure of the last legislature to make a sufficiently 
large appropriation, the rebuilding of the center and west 
wing of the penitentiary, destroyed by tire two years ago, is not 
yet completed. The stone is practically all laid but the interior 
can not lie finished and made ready for occupancy until another 
appropriation become* available. To this duty, I trust you will 
give early attention. It is almost absolutely imperative that the 
west wing be equipped with from -'&gt;0 to 7"&gt; new steel cells, the 
present cell room being entirely inadequate to the needs of the 
institution. At this time, three convicts are compelled to bunk 
in one small room, the capacity of which is scarcely equal to the 
proper accommodation of two. The result is that these unfortunates 
are crowded together in an almost barbarous manner and in 
violation of the promptings of humane reason and the law of 
health. This condition is in no sense a reflection on the management 
of the penitentiary, but is unavoidable on account of the 
lack of room. I recommend that sufficient appropriation be made. 
both for the completion of that part of the penitentiary which in 
now in process of construction, and for the addition of new cells 
as suggested. 

Fildli CoMMlSsIo-V 

The food commission law should lie made more comprehenmvc 
.\ t 1 1 1* i 'mm 1 1 its 01 &gt;c *r&amp;t 10118 strc confined to tlu* ("!*ii r v &lt;*i lt*r </seg>

            <seg id="p049">
i 

and vinegar products, .ml while the oommMMon having chai 

tin- department has done excellent service in its limited s|.here. 

is evident that a broadening of the enactment would 1 M - of corr 

ponding ben 

tit. The pvblic health is largely dependent on th 

haractcr of food products and certainly it is fitting that a i . 

very existence of our j 

gisla 

Tin 

present law should be broadened so as to include the revnlatioi 

e'ude li 

trol 

mil 

h 

.1,.., 

uld be placed &lt;m the market strictlv on their merits and deoe| 

e 

ty and quality should be made a penal off ease. 'I'h 

hou'.d Im 1 :))&gt; 

i 

t 

i 

I, the exiien 

ma 

t 

I 


in 

No 

svi 

I 

September, 1901, the main building of the asylum for th 

n 

insane, at Norfolk, was partially destroyed bv tire and rendered 

unlit for further use. At that time the institution was carin 

I! 

about :!&lt;i(i inmate*. These were afterwards divided between tl 

» 

imilar institutions owned bv the state at Lincoln and II 

MM were there given the .are and attention which tkeii 

demanded, as well as could !».• done under the crowded eondi 

'I 

Hustings, affording additional accommodations which liav 

Iv 

lent. It is possible that 

t 

short time the state could continue to care for its uuforluna 

in 

the two -institution* named, bat it should be borne in mix 
the Lincoln hospital is now charged with thirty more than it 

¦i parity will justify while the asylum at Hastings has its norms 

capacity filled. It is evident, therefore, that prompt and deeisi\ 

v til 

ii should be taken in order to avoid the i 

v ot carin 

or these sufferers ill anv other way thai 

pit al. The state now has at Norfolk an investment of al 


exclusive 1 ot the partial ruins of the main buiidin*' which ~iN 

intimately connected with th 
should he regulated by proper 

products for 

HMD. Slid 

be ofioe shoald be paid from the general fun 
iaiion shouM In' made for tli.tt parpone. 

n a. i annex has been bail 
,r -i.'.lir ... .,1 1.., 

well ci|iii)&gt;|ifil |i 

n. (1. uninjured building* ami equipi </seg>

            <seg id="p050">
50 

I resent a considerable money value. In view of this investnt, 
of the growing needs of the state proportionate to the 
wth in population and the corresponding increase of dementia, 
I as a matter of convenience to the North l'latte country, it 
ms to me that the institution at Norfolk should bo rehabilitated 
I I recommend a reasonable appropriation for that purpose. I 
ther advise that this, and all other buildings authorized by 
ir body, Ik- made as nearly lire proof as possible, to the end 
t danger to human life and of the destruction of property on 
ount of tire Ik- reduced to the minimum. 

STATK ACCOUNTANT 

I With the gradual increase of state business, it becomes more 
d more necessary that a state accountant should he provided, aw 
adjunct of the board of public lands and buildings, whose duty 
shall be to scrutinize and verify the accounts of the rari— ¦ - 
icers and state institutions, and who shall have authority over 
e books and records of said institutions with a view to reducing 
em to a uniform system. Believing that such an officer would 
nder valuable service to the state and would serve as a cheek M 
travagance in the conduct of state affairs, I recommend that the 
isition be created. 

These are the more important points of desired legislation 
that suggest themselves to my mind. During the progress of the 
session, it may l&gt;e that other matters will arise to which I shall 
wish to call your attention by special message. I trust that the 
utmost of harmony and fraternal good-will may attend all your 

JOHN II. MK'KFV </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>