<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Short Courses or Extension Schools in Agriculture and Home Economics</title>
               <date value="1916-06-15">1916-06-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. 37. BULLETIN OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE. SHORT COURSES OR EXTENSION SCHOOLS IN AGRICULTURE AND HOME ECONOMICS. By C. \Y. PrcsLEY and P. L. Gaddis Distributed June 15, 1916. AT A SHORT COl'RSE AT HERSHEV. nciNC live LINCOLN. NEBRASKA U. S. A. Distributed in Furtherance of the Purposes of the Cooperative Agricul - tural Extension Work Provided for in the Act of Congress of May 8, 1914. University of Nebraska Agricultural Extension Service and the United States Department of Agriculture Cooperating. C. W. PUGSLEY. Director of Extension Senice. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">University of Nebraska College of Agriculture THE EXTENSION SERVICE THE GOVERNING BOARD. iTtir Uegvntn of the I nuer-m Hox. William G. Whitmore, Hon. Frank L. Haller, Omaha. Hon. Edward P. Brown. Davev. Hox. John E. Miller, Lincoln. \ alley. Hon. Philip L. Hall, Lincoln. Hon. Victor G. Lvford. President. Falls City. THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS. Samiel Avery, Ph. D., LL. I).. Chancellor. E. A. Birnett, 1!. Sc OHM, College of Agriculture; Director, Experiment Station. J. S. Dales, M. Ph.. Financial Secretary. EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF. Hildah Peterson. Junior Extension Work. Frank C Dean. A. B., Agricultural Editor. Mai'D Mathes Wilson. 11. Sc, llomt Economics. K. E. Hothwell. Earmcrs' Institute, and Exhibits. H. F. Williams, B. Sc., Fmrm Man - agement Demonstrations. P. L. Gaddis. A. B., Agronomy Short Courses. R. K. Spafford. B. Sc, Assistant in Earm Management Demonstra- L. T. Skinner. I!. Sc. Assistant Junior Extension Work. K. F. Warner. M. S.. Animal Hus bandrv. Maky A. Rokahr, A. B.. llomt hi ultur COUNTY AGRICULTURAL AGENTS. F. M. Seidell, Boxbutte County. A. (i. George. B. Sc, Madison A. H. Beikhokf. U. Sc, Dakota County. C duntv C. E. GiNNti.s. I! ( nuntv. Seward O. H. Liebers, B. Sc. Gage County \. C North. B Count v. Sheridan R. E. Holland, B. Sc, Kimball Countv. R. H. Camp. I! Countv. Thurston THE EXTENSION COUNCIL. Heads uf Departnt- i.t» E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D.. !. H. Frandsen. M. S. A.. Agricultural Botany. Dairy Husbandry F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Lawreni e Briner, B. S( Agricultural Chemistry. Entomology L. W. Chase. M. E.. A. £., H. C. Filley. A. M.. Agricultural Engineering. Fmrm Management W. W. Birr, B. Sc, Alice M. Loomis, A. M., Home Economics. R. F. Howard, A. M. Animal Husbandry. Horticulture. J. H. Gain-. M. D. C, G. A. Loveland, A. M. Animal Pathology. Meteorology. H. E. Bradford, A. B., Prin ifal. School of Agriculture C. W. Pi-csley. B. Sc Pirn-tor. A. E. AlHHH, A. I'.., County Ago Work. EXTENSION SPECIALISTS. 1. 1). Wcmn. A. M.. Agricultural lin- H. F. Wili.ia! &lt;liiiccriut). iUicmcnt f Emma Reed Davisson. Cluhs. I. G. McMillan. B. Sc Pig Clubs. iwmics. D. H. Propps, B. Sc. Dairy Hus- Emma Out. B. Sc, Hon baiidrv. ict I Junior Work). E. H. Hoppert. I!. Sc, H G. O. I'xki H, 1&gt;. St, Dawes County. Agronomy. E. A. Burnett. B. Sc. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SHORT COURSES Or Extension Schools in Agriculture and Home Economics. BY C. W. Pl'GSLEY AXD P. L. GADDIS. THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE SPECIALIZED SHORT COURSE. The special meeting, the farmers' institute, the general short course, the specialized short course — these have been the steps in the development of our agricultural extension meetings in Nebraska. When the Agricultural Experiment Station was first organized, the information obtained was sent out largely thru bulletins. These were useful in giving much information, but sometimes did not answer all the questions arising in the mind of the reader or speak of the local applications with which he was concerned. To meet the demand, men were sent out by the Agricultural College to dis - cuss subjects more fully and to answer any questions arising. These specially arranged meetings drifted into a regular yearly schedule 2nd thus originated the farmers' institute, which is still being carried on in manv communities. In some places the one-day institute was not considered suf - ficient. At such meetings subjects must of necessity be treated very briefly. There was not time for questions and discussions. As some expressed it, they hardly got started in one day. A demand arose for two- and three-day sessions. More work was then sched - uled for places where the conditions warranted. It was finally decided that the most economical use of time was to put on a four-day meeting, which would take up an entire week, allowing one day for the speakers to reach the place and arrange the work and one day to pack up and return. The first one of these "short courses." as the extended institute was called, was conducted at Pawnee City during the winter of 1907 and 1908. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Short Courses in Agriculture and Home licoiiomics For about six years, the short courses were conducted along gen - eral lines. Several men were engaged to talk at different times and upon a variety of subjects. There was a tendency fur the regular extension men to handle so many subjects that they could not be well prepared on all of them Altho this type of course was well received, the results were not as desired. The subjects were treated in a manner too general to admit of detail, which is often of im - portance. The ideas dropped were too scattered to be of the great - est use. The course was so much the same from year to year that it was inclined to grow tiresome after two or three years. A decision was reached about two years ago to treat fewer sub - jects but to handle them in a more exhaustive manner. In the men's work, specialists were secured in the various departments, and have outlined courses in the different subjects covering four days' work. It has been the aim of the Extension Service in selecting these &gt;i&gt;e - cialists to get men having not only an agricultural education but actual farm experience as well. Really creditable work can be done when eight hours of lectures and demonstrations are given on one subject by a man who gives his time and attention almost entirely to that subject. In the women's work, there is much the same specializing. &lt; &gt;ne instructor presents the topics included in the clothing and shelter problems, while another gives the work in food and dietetics. thus far devised. THE PURPOSE OF THE SHORT COURSE When a short course is placed in a community, it is not with the idea that the people do not know how to farm nor to keep home. It is assumed that they know much about their work : that the aver - age man is quite proficient in the management of his farm, but that his experience cannot be extensive enough to cover every phase of farming, stock raising, construction and arrangement of buildings, the use of machinery, and other related subjects. A conference with neighboring farmers and specialists in the different lines should be of much value. The purposes of the short course may be summed up as follows : The specialized week's school, as it has been tried out in the State the past two years, is the most satisfactory meeting or course </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Extension Bulletin Xo. 57, College of Agriculture. 5 /• 1. To give systematic courses on subjects of general community interest. It is the aim of the instructors to make these courses as practical as possible. They are able to do this not only thru special preparation and experience but also thru constant association with farmers in all parts of the S'ate. 2. To keep the fanner .icquainted with the farm practices rec - ommended by agricultural experiment stations and the United States Department of Agriculture. Many results are obtained by the sta- tions which are applicable to the various parts of the State, often being supplemented by cooperative work with farmers. 3. To let the farmer and his wife know what is being done on uccessful farms in other parts of the State, and to give the instruc- leas to carry to other points. The short courses serve as a onnecting link between people in various parts of the State, some f whom are successful in one line of work and others in another. 4. To furnish an opportunity for the men and women of the community to meet and discuss their common problems. 5. To get the boy« and the girls interested in their future work. Simply to know how work should be done is not sufficient. To know- why, adds interest and pleasure to the task, and a little start along this line while young gives the boys and girls an idea of solv - ing their own problems. Many have been led to take up advanced work in agriculture and home economics thru interest aroused at the short courses. 6. To give the farmer who cannot leave his work to attend a longer course, a chance to attend a brief course close enough so that he will not have to leave home for more than a dav at a time. THE PROGRAM. The short course opens on Monday evening and continues four days. The men's sessions are held from 9 to 12 a. m. and from 1 to 4 ]). 111. each day, and the women's sessions from 9 to 1 1 :30 a. m. and from 1 :30 to 4 p. m. The Monday evening session is a get-acquainted meeting. The different instructors briefly outline the work of the week. An ad - dress is usually given and music by home talent completes the pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Economics. gram. Evening meetings later in the week are held when desired, but should not be so numerous as to draw attendance awav from the day sessions where the most important work is done. The in - structors are prepared to give evening talks but special speakers are sometimes secured. 1 Rn'-e work Is siren from } to II l m. each d«y when callml f place of a regular course. 2 Ele-trlcal wiring, ir def-.lred. is rlvrsi inntead of nn# work at a In agricultural engineering is scheduled. It does not take the place or ■I take tl Department Course 1 Course II Course III Couras IV (nurse V Agricultural | Firm Motors Md Firra Engineering Equipment Automobiles machinery Drainair and road building - I 1 I _ _ Amww Soils Orslns Fi.rage crops Animal Husbandry Horses Beef cattla Hots •■• Kutt-htring am' curing of BBBJH Milk Milk and Dairying Productloa milk products Iasetts If. re- Uuaili and Entomology l«tion to sin- hlrd. in rela- ■ ulture and Uon to agrirul- | l:rsllh ture Farm Farm manage- ManageiMOt mwit problesss Marketing HortlciUtiirt F«rm i-rchsrtt and csrdsn Pumoiosj Small fruit Vegetables h= : — Diseates of or- pi lt ,t j Diseases of j chard and gar* Diseases flel&lt; - cro PS den crops Pooltn ram poultry KnoU and Splices an.l be Work- M"*" "«»«» Elfrtrical i Simple elec- Wtri'ia' 3 I trical wiring THE COURSES OUTLINED. AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING. Morning. Afternoon. Farm Equipment Tues. Arrangement of Farm Build- Materials Used in Construction of ings Buildings Wed. The Use of Concrete on the Mixing and Using Concrete (Dem- Farm onstration) Thur. Houses and Barns Silos and Silage Equipment Fri. Water and Lighting Systems Hav Sheds and Hog Houses </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Extension Bulletin No. College of Agriculture. 7 ig. 1. — Farm tra r demonstration t DRAINAGE AMI KoAIl I'.LILIIINC Tues. Needs and Benefits of Tile Planning and Construction of Tile Drainage Systems Drainage Wed. The Business Aspects of Open Ditch Drainage and Drainage Districts Tile Drainage Thur. Factor* Making Good Roads Essentials. Advantages. Costs, and Locations of Roads Essential Fri. Design and Construction of County Road Organization Roads .' / /• / --^-— — --..-. Morning. Afternoon. iIotoks and Automobiles Tues. Engine Fuels and How Used Wed. Lubricating. Ignition, and Cooling Systems Thur. Tractors — Types and Cost Fri. Automobiles — Care and Cost Trouble in Starting and Developing Power Cylinder, Valve, and Other Troubles Valve Grinding, Babbitting, etc. Tire Repairing, Carburetor Adjust- ment, etc. •"arm Machinery Tues. Draft of Wagons and Plows Wed. Corn Planters or Mowers Thur. Tillage Machinery (Illus- trated ) Fri. Hay -handling Equipment Eveners, Pulleys, Block and Tackle Timing the Binder Knotter Plow-setting Demonstration Labor-saving Device* (Illustrated with Models) </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Short Courses in Agriculture and Home L COIIOIHHS Soil 11 AC RONOMT Morning. Afternoon Soils Tues. What Our Soil Is How the Plant Makes Use of the Cultivation Wed. Objects and Method »f Plowing Thur. Farm Manures Fri. Rotation of Crops Manures and Fertilizers Practical Soil Problems Grains Tues. Grain Production in Ne- VVheat Growing braska Wed. Wheat (continued Oats— Smut Treatment Dem ■11 Judgini turn Thur. Adaptation and Judging t Selection of Seed t &lt; mi (.Urn Fri. Corn Growia Cnrn Growing (Eastern Xel Wed. Alfalfa— Seedin Thur. The Cloven Alfalfa— Havin Perennial GflttCI Hoc Paatam ANIMAL HI BANDRT Horses Tues. What Is a Horse Worth? Wed. The Feet and tin- Teeth Thur. Growing and Training the Colt Fn. Feeding the Work Hone Beef Cattle ommon l)is Tues. Beef Cattle and General Judging Bet Farming Wed. Beef-cutting Demonstration Buying at the Stockyards Judging Contest Thur. Care of the Breeding Cow Fri. Feeding the Calf Feeding for Heel Hogs Tues. Selection of the Brood S Farm Butchering i\V Wed. Pork Cutting and Curing Feeding the Dry Sow Judging Contest Thur. The Sow and Her Litter Fri. Fattening Shoats Hog Cholera Sheep Tues. Sheep on the Small Farm Judging Sheep Wed. Shearing Demonstration Thur. The Breeding Ewe Fri. Feeding for Mutton Lamb-slaughtering Demonstrat The Ewe and Her Lamb Internal Parasites Butchering and Com Meat Tues. Butchering Tools. Care of Hog Slaughtering Stock Before Slaughtering Wed. Pork Cutting Thur. Pork Cutfing Beef Slaughtering Beef Cutting Fri. Sausage Making and Stuff- Summer Handling of Meats ing Aote: Lamb slaughtering may be included, if desired Sorghums (Western Neb Fokace Crops Tues. Forest I 'rnps mi tin- Ncliras- Annual Crops for Hay. Fodd ka Farm Silaue Fri. Weedy and Depleted I'a tures Lnsoundneti Care of Braod Mare am liKl^inK I '&lt;&gt;nte&lt;t </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Extension Bulletin No. 37, College of Agriculture. 9 M M \I I HAIHY HUSBANDRY Afternoon. mug pROIHVTIOX The Dairy Type Tues. Dairying as a Business Wed. Relation of Type to Produc- Building Up a Herd; the Herd Bull tion (Demonstration) Tluir. Ke'ping Daily Records Fri. Care and Management Feeding Judging Demonstration and Contest AND Mll.K PRODUCTS Tues. Milk as a I Sanitary Milk Production Wed. Care of Milk and Cream on Testing Milk and Cream (Demon- stration) Farm Herd Improvement Thru Marketing Testing ators (Demonstration) Dairy Buildings BNTOM TION TO AOMCULTVM ami Health Tues. Si me &lt; iencral Facts about The Corn-ear Worm and Other Tm- Inseots and the Harm portant Corn Pests Thev Dn Wed. The Hessian Flv (Eastern How to Fight Grasshopper Xebr.) or Webworms and Other Sugar Beet Insects (Western Nebr Tliur. The Control of Cutworms How to Destroy the Insect Parasites of Domestic Animals ;iml Armvworms Fri. Insects in Relation to the The Relation of Birds to Insect Control pread of Disease \\1\1\1s ami Bum m Relation- to Tues. Pocket Gophers and Their Ar.Rirri.TrRE Ground Squirrels. Kangaroo Rats. Moles, and Field Mice. Their Tninnes and Control ontrol Wed. The Prairie Dog (Western RabH ; t Tninrv and Its Prevention, or WMd F'esh-eatinc Animals. Their \ T al'ie and Tniuries Xebr.) or the Common Mole and Tts F.conomic What Som&gt; of Our Common Ne - braska Birds Eat Tliur. The F.conomic Value of Birds Fri. Hawks and Owls as Related Horn to Attract Birds About the Home to the Farmer irary or local importance will be sub- tituted for anv of the above lectures, if desired FA TIM MANAGEMENT ABM M AXACKMKXT PROBLEMS Tnes. Labor The Farm Layout (Illustrated) £t«e of Farms Wed. I and Rental Thur. Farm Records and Accounts Fri. Diversified and Specialized Figuring Cost of Production Factors Which Influence Labor In Farming come &gt;LOOY (Eastern XebiO Nor : Lectures on insects of tempi </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Economics 10 I The Farm Orchard and Garden Tues. Starting the Farm Orchard Wed. Spraying Thur. Pruning Demonstration Fri. The Vegetable Garden Care of the Rearing Orchard Small Fruit Culture Hints for Beautifying the Home Potato Culture Pomology Tues. Setting Out an Orchard Care of the Young Orchard Wed. Care of the Bearing Orchard Care of the Bearing Orchard — Th« — Priming and Cultivation Spray Schedule Thur. Harvesting and Marketing Renovation of Neglected Orchards the Crop Fri. Pruning Demonstration in Pruning the Neglected Orcliar (Demonstration) the Orchard — Young and Old Trees Small Fruits Tues. Starting the Strawberry Bed Treatment of the Rearing Straw berry Bed — Varieties. Setting Plants. etc Wed. Rlackberrv Growing Rlack Raspberry Growing Starting the Vineyard Thur. Growing Currants and Gooseberries Fri. Care of the Rearing Vines Grape Pruning Demonstration — Ol and Young Vines Vegetables Tues. Planning the Home Veg The Use of Hotbeds and etahle Garden Frame Wed. Preparing the Vegetable Tomato Growing Garden Thur. Cabbage. Cauliflower. T.et K tuce. and Radishes Fri. Potato Growing Maim Potato Growing (continued PLANT PISEASf Diseases of FiEi.n Crops Tues. The Healthy Plant w ed. The Diseased Plant Thur. Oat Smut Fri. Corn and Sorghum Smuts The Healthy Plant (continue Cereal Rusts Loose and Stinkinij Smut of W'beii Weeds Diseases of Orchard and Garden Crops Tues. Apple Diseases Apple Diseases (continued) Grape and Berry Diseases Wed. Peach. Cherry. Plum, and Pear Diseases Thur. Potato Diseases Fri. Vegetable Diseases Potato Diseases (Demonstrations') Vegetable Diseases (continued) Morning. Afternoon. ARKET1NG Tues. Wastes in Distribution Wed. Grain Warehouses Thur. Parcel Post Fri. Limitations of Competition in Controlling Prices. Cooperation Marketing Grain Marketing Live Stock and Livt Stoc Products Farm Profits and Production HORT1CU ,»n 1/rritE. " </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Extension Bulletin No. 37, College of Agriculture. 11 Knots and Hitches — First Year Tues. Rope Materials and Handling Wed. Whipping the End. End Knot Thur. Tying Two Ropes Together Fri Various Kinds of Hitches ii.ic es and Halters — Second Year Tues. The End Splice. The Short Splice Wed. The Long Splice Thur. Temporary and Adjustable Halters Fri. Nonadjustable Permanent Halters ELECTRICAL WIRING FOR BOYS. Toes. Batteries, Electrical Currents, and Combusting Electricity Wed. Magnetism, Telegraph, and Telephone Thur. Induction Coils and Wireless Telegraphy Fri. The Motor and the Electric Light HOW TO CHOOSE MEN'S COURSES. Rope work or electrical wiring is given from 9 to 10 o'clock each day, if desired. The regular courses begin at 10 o'clock. Each course requires 40 minutes in the forenoon and one hour in the afternoon. Aside from rope work and electrical wiring, three courses should be selected. The committee in charge should choose courses that will be most interesting to the community as a whole. Two of these courses must be chosen from one depart - ment, since only two men are available for each point. As an illustration, if Courses I and II under Farm Management and Course II under Agricultural Engineering are selected, the daily program will be as follows : Rope Work or Electrical lems 10:00 Motors and Automobiles. . 10:40 to 10:40 a. m. and 1 to 2 p. m. to 1 1 :20 a. m. and 2 to 3 p. m. Marketing 1 1 :20 to 12 :00 a. m. and 3 to 4 p. m Wiring 9:00 to 10:00 a. m Farm Management Prob- •(. Morning. Afternoon. \KH POULTRY Tues. Farm Poultry on a Business Breeds and Breeding for Increase! Basis Production Weil Housing Winter Egg Production Tlnir. Judging Demonstration The Poultry Industry (Illustrated) l'ri. Saving the Chicks Common Diseases HOPE WORK. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Economics. The number of courses now offered allows eight years' work with - out repetition. As a rule, no point is permitted to choose the same course two years in succession. The same instructor may be had by choosing another course given by him. WOMEN'S SECTION The nature of the work given in the Home Economics section does not permit of such a wide choice of courses as is gives in tin - men's work. The various phases of Home Economies :ire included in each year's work. The programs, however, are planned in such ■ way that there is no repetition of subject matter but rather a defi - nite sequence from year to year. The work is varied to suit condi - tions and the wishes of those attending. The following courses are offered : The Clothing Problem — Conditions in Clothing Industri Use of Dress Form — Selection and Use of Patterns Textiles and Tests in Buying FOOD AND DIETETICS. Lectures. Dtmtiuf rations. First Year Classes and Functions of Foods Vegetable* Inexpensive Fuel for the Body Starch) Foods Foods that Build the Body Milk and I Value of Bread as K 1 Meats Preservation of Foods llu-ad-. i atininir — (Old Pad. Mill Tabie Service Second Year Body Requirements for Food Jellies, Relishes, etc. Cereal Foods Variety in Use of Foodi The Emergency Shelf oa the Farm Food for Children Bread* — Coarse Flours Serving to Large Numbers Eitrgtatj Dinner Meat Substitutes Children's Dietaries Third Year What We Must Eat and Why Fruits The Cost of Food Salads and Relishes Food and the Weather Cookie* and Sweet Bread Food for the Sick Old Pood* in New Way* Serving a Company Dinner Seasonable Dishes A Company Dinner Invalid Cookery TEXTILES AND CLOTHING. Lectures aiui Demonstrations First Year </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Extension Bulletin No. College of Agriculture. / Second (or Third) Year Choice of Materials Garment Making Clothing Accessorie The Hygiene of Clothing hikii (or Second) Year Economy in Buying Clothing Selection of Hats Repairs and Upkeep of Clothing Children's Clothing Fig. 2.— Food demonstration THE HOME. Lectures and Demonstrations Yea he Home and the Home Maker mlding of the Home Furnishing the Home he Relation of the Home Maker ti the Community Skcond (or Third) Year The Home as a Business Institution The Planning of Housework Shopping for the House The Child and the Home Third (or Second) Year The Care of the House — Dirt and It Economy in Cleaning Composition What the Home Maker Should Kn Home Nursing w About Diseases While only three years' work is outlined in this bulletin, older points are furnished with specially prepared programs fitted to their </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Economics. needs. The following program is made up from the above courses for the first year and shows how the daily schedule runs. FIRST-YEAR PROGRAM Morning. Afternoon Tuesday The Home and the Home Maker The Clothing Problem — Conditions in the Clothing Industries Foods — Their Classes and Func - tions Inexpensive Fuel for the Body Preparing Vegetables (Demonstra - tion) Variety in the Use of Starchy Foods (Demonstration) Wednesday Building the Home Textiles and Tests in Buying Bread, the Staff of Life Milk and Eggs as Valuable FoikIs Breads and Bread Making (Dem - onstration) ( Demonstration) Thursday Furnishing the Home Use of the Dress Form. Selection and Use of Patterns The Cutting anU the Buying of Meat (Demonstration) Foods that Build the Body The Cookery of Meats (Demonstra - tion) Friday Home Economics Literature Everyday Table Service The Care and Preservation of Foods The Relation of the Home Make the Community Reception The Cold Pack Method in Canning (Demonstration) REQUIREMENTS FOR SECURING A SHORT COURSE COMMUNITY SPIRIT It is not advisable to put a short course in a community where conditions are not favorable to its success. It costs just as much in time and money to conduct a course with twenty in attendance as it does if a hundred are present. The instructors feel that their time might have been better spent elsewhere and the local people feel that the cost per person attending is too much. Conditions favorable to a short course are indicated by the following 1. A live interest in practical and profitable farming by the farmers in the community. 2. A spirit of cooperation on the part of the entire community 3. Sufficient interest in the short course to be willing to meet local expenses and pledge attendance. 4. A willingness on the part of each one to put the short course first for one week and do his part to make it go. Enter - tainments that conflict with the short course should be laid aside </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Extension Bulletin No College of Agriculture. 15 si t 1 i 'or a week. Where farm sales are dated during short course week, he crowd is divided and neither sale nor short course is the suc - ess it should be. In some places the auctioneers have been noti - ied in advance when the short course was to be held and have •ooperated by refusing to schedule sales in the patronizing terri - ory during short course week; other attractions may be handled ikewise. School boards are often willing to allow the pupils from the high hool, especially those taking work in agriculture and home eco- lomics, to attend the sessions thruout the week. It is usually ;ood practice for them to be accompanied by one of the teachers nd to be required to take notes. If pupils are allowed to at- i/nd only one or two days, the short course instructors should te consulted as to the best time for them to come. The more ma - un' pupils from rural districts can usually profit much from he work, and should be encouraged to attend. BUILDINGS AND FUNDS. The community considering a short course should know in advance the requirements in the way of buildings and funds. Suit - able rooms for demonstration work, as described elsewhere in this bulletin, should be available. The short courses are not carried on to make money, either for the State or for the community. The Extension Service pays salaries, railroad fare, and cost of permanent equipment of the instructors. The local people are expected to pay only local expenses, men as hall rent, entertainment for speakers, groceries. other supplies, and kitchen help for the women's section, advertis - ing, printing, and incidentals. There should be ample funds in sight for the payment of the expenses. It is not expected that any organization or society shall plan a short course for profit. It belongs to the community and at the close of the course, the committee in charge must furnish the Extension office with a complete statement of receipts and expen - ditures connected with the course, together with a report of daily attendance. The financial report should always be published in the local papers. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Economics 16 The exact cost of a short course cannot be given, as it varies greatly with conditions. To give some idea, however, the report of the Springfield short course, 1915, is given below FINANCIAL STATEMENT. Receipts. Balance on hand from last year's meetings $ 94.40 Sale of tickets and single admissions 134.85 Sale of domestic science exhibits and supplies 4.60 $233.85 EXPENMTUI W. M. Kieck, use of opera house $ 15.00 W. M. Kieck. use of citv hall 1.00 $ 15.00 W. M. Kieck, use of citv hall Ed. Hoyt, use of garage 2.S ' Stamps and supplies '. 1 .02 J. C. Miller, printing and advertising 25.50 T. J. Wright, hotel bill 16.50 - - J - - " - "O 7 -■ — J. P. Schaal, sawdust and liaulin j • — ' * &gt; ■ ™"' i — — ..— — . — — -, Geo. Cragle, draying 1 .90 B. L. Schobert, supplies and livery hire G. A. Bates, supplies 4.42 Otto Joern. supplies 6.82 W. M. Kieck, supplies 5.94 Wm. Mueller &amp; Son. coal 40 Herman Schmidt, supplies T. J. Wright, milk 45 Harberg Lumber Co.. lumber 4.21 Telephoning 62 Mrs. Frank McCamlev. cream .60 Labor 3.25 Miss Laura Stacv, labor Clarence Nicholson, janitor work 1 .25 W. M. Kieck, supplies 3.25 Total $109.88 Balance on hand for next year's short course 123.97 $233.85 A pledge guaranteeing the payment of local expenses, with names of at least ten reliable men. is required before a short course is promised. Below is the form used : </seg>
            <seg id="p017">listens n Bulletin Xo College of Agriculture. 17 Ye. the undersigned, jointly and severally agree to make id any deficit which may occur in financing a Short during the winter of 19 Course in Name Address PLEDGES OF SUPPORT AND ATTENDANCE The major part of the expenses are met by selling tickets for the course. The usual price of season tickets is one dollar for men and fifty cents tor women. Daily admission is usually twen - ty-five cents for men and fifteen cents for women. Ten to fif - teen cents i^ charged for evening programs except Monday. One hundred men and the same number of women must sign for season tickets and pledge attendance before a short course will be promised. Below is the form used: ree to take tickets for the if it is secured and agree the course is promised, that We pledge ourselves to at- y t&lt; &gt;r same as soon a nay be promptly met end the short course \ddre ORGANIZATION When the foregoing requirements for a short course are under - tin mI. the next step is to organize. A good live organization with plenty of committees is most essential to a successful short course. A president and secretary or any one or two men or women can - not make a good short course, but all must pull together. It is always advisable for the men and women to work together in arranging for and carrying on the course. This is best realized by having a single organization with separate committees in charge of the men's and women's work. Joint subcommittees should be appointed to look after the different parts of the work. It is sometimes best to appoint only the chairmen of the committees and to let them appoint their own assistants, as harmony in the committee is thereby secured. The money should be kept in a com - mon treasury from which all expenses are paid. ARRANGING FOR THE SHORT COURSE. There should be committees of from one to three members on each of the different lines of work except finance, which should We, the undersigned, a£ &gt;rt course at </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Economics. have a committee consisting of not less than five men and five women. The names of the members of the different committees should be forwarded to the Extension office as soon as the organi - zation is effected. Committees should be appointed on the fol - lowing : EQUIPMENT. The committee on equipment should secure suitable rooms in which to conduct the meetings, and see that such rooms are pro - vided with comfortable seats and other necessary equipment. The room for the women's section should be of sufficient lze to accommodate a maximum crowd. It must be well heated and Fig. 3. Side le view of support for raised seats in stock judging re lines at the top represent banisters where the seat! The ■ m dotted a ri- against a wall. This might prevent an accident. Drawing furnished thru courtesy of Agricultural Engineerinjg Department </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Extension bulletin Xo. 7. College of Agriculture 19 Fig. 4.— Back view of support for stock judging seats. The l"x6"s make view the supports firm and safe well lighted and provided with the proper tables and kitchen fix - tures, a list of which will be furnished by the Extension office upon request. Running water or a well near by is a great convenience. The basement of a church or a lodge kitchen with audience room are often well equipped for the work and are quite satisfactory, if they do not have'to be used for other purposes during the week. When stock judging is a feature of the men's work, it is some - times difficult to get a suitable room. The aim should be to seat everyone comfortably where they can see the stock. This requires good light, proper means of heating, and good seats. In the winter months, the doors cannot be relied upon to furnish light, since for comfort they must usually be closed. A warm room is absolutely essential, as classes sometimes remain there for two or three hours at a time. A garage, sale pavilion, livery barn, </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Ect no mi or vacant store may answer the purpose of a stock judging room if it possesses the above qualifications. Where the room is com - fortable, all the men's work can usually lie given there. When Rk :,-R pe tym seats. There should be three npporti for each length of iilank. If about ten persons are figured for each plank, the number may be suited to the size of the class expected. The evening sessions are joint tciiioni. and if the men's room is not suitable for them, a sufficiently large room &lt;h&lt;aild he pro - vided for the purpose. FINANCE Since the work of selling tickets is a part of its duties, the finance committee should ordinarily l&gt;e a large one. the different neighborhoods being represented in its membership. This cum- stock work is not a part of the program, any good audience r on is satisfactory. The bleacher style of seats, at shown in Figure 3, is very satisfac- tory and almost necessary for stock work. The lumber can 1).' pur- chased and kept from year to year. It quite often comes in handy on other occasions. Sixteen-foot planks are generally used for </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Extension Bulletin Xo College of Agriculture. 21 Si mittee should confer and advise with the other committees that the expenses may be lightened as much as possible and handled in the easiest way. For instance, it is often possible in county seat towns to cut down hall rent materially by using the courthouse rooms for day sessions. It is sometimes possible, also, to meet the cost of printing the programs by getting a few advertisements to insert in them. The main methods of raising funds are : ( 1 ) County appropriations, which are regulated by law. I 2 i Sale of tickets. ( 3 ) Donations. These are often available for prizes in contests and not infrequently for other purposes. STOCK When judging work is to be a part of the program, there should be a committee to confer with the instructor and provide whatever animals are needed. About three animals of the same breed are best for the cattle and hog work. It is usually best to get them from the stockyards, rf possible, rather than from some breeder, as the judge must have full freedom in criticizing. For horse judging, stallions are not as good as work animals. Men who furnish horses should ex)&gt;ect reasonable criticism. EXHIBITS AND CONTESTS, A good exhibit of stock furnishes enthusiasm in a short course and has an educational value when shown in connection with a course along the same line. The premiums should be small, to avoid dissatisfaction with the awards and to place emphasis on the edu - cational value rather than on the prize. Exhibits along other lines should not be allowed to detract from the interest in the lectures and demonstrations. It is best to have a separate room for the exhibits and to have it locked during the class periods. In case of large ex - hibits along a line not included in the short course, the local com - mittee must arrange for a special judge. The Extension office will cooperate in locating a suitable judge. At some of the short courses, contests have been carried on dur - ing the week. Slips of paper are handed around at the end of a period, and the instructor asks a few questions that can be answered </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Economics. in a word or two. This enables him to know if his work has been made clear. Stock-judging and rope-tying contests are also con - ducted in connection with the work in those lines. The papers are corrected and prizes given at the end of the week. Prizes are also sometimes given to those with the best record of attendance. The committee should decide on premiums and prizes and issue a list of the same. PROGRAM. The program committee should secure home talent to fill out the evening programs. An occasional song or reading is not out of place in the day sessions. Usually the community that takes inter - est in the program has a live short course. Sometimes a teacher in the high school is a good addition to this committee. One or two good evening programs are better than more, since the farmers can - not usually attend both day and evening sessions and are too likely to miss the important day work. ADVERTISING AND PRINTING. The short course should be thoroly advertised over the territory from which it is expected to draw. Handbills, posters, and news - paper advertising are all good. The place, date, and interesting features of the program should be announced. Programs should be printed and sent out to the patronizing territory. Banners an - nouncing the short course displayed in town for a period of several weeks are of value. Pennants attached to the automobiles of the community give effective advertising. ENTERTAINMENT. The speakers should be met at the train and shown to their places of entertainment. They usually prefer to stay at the hotel if it is reasonably good, as it is hard for them always to come regularly to their meals. At the hotel they can come and go at any time with - out inconveniencing anyone. RESULTS OF THE SHORT COURSE— FOLLOW-UP WOKK Short course work should produce results of value to the com - munity. We are anxious that all who desire to put into practice work suggested at the short course, shall get in touch with the </seg>
            <seg id="p023">I-.vtension Bulletin Xo. 57, College of Agriculture. 23 instructor and get any further information necessary for the under - taking. Where several cooperators can be secured in any activity of importance to the community, the instructor may be able to return later and assist in planning and carrying on the work. In this way the exact value of the idea to the community may be found out. SHORT COURSES IN HOME ECONOMICS. Short courses in- Home Economics only may be arranged for by writing to the Extension office. The work given is the same as that outlined for women's work in this bulletin. The same require - ments hold as to demonstration rooms and expenses. Women's Fig. 6. — Junior short course at Norfolk. courses are usually held after March 1, as the instructors are busy with combined short courses during the winter months. JUNIOR SHORT COURSES. The junior short courses are conducted in counties at points centrally located. The pupils in attendance are representatives from the school districts in the county. Stock types and judging, rope tying and splicing, seed selection and testing, control of plant diseases, milk testing, and farm accounting are among the subjects handled in the boys' section. In the girls' section, instruction is given in food selection, preparation, and service ; choice of textiles and sewing; and care and decoration of the home. Those interested in securing a course of this kind should address the Extension Service. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Short Courses in Agriculture and Home Economics. AVAILABLE EXTENSION BULLETINS The following bulletins may be had free of cost by residents (if Ne - braska upon application to the Agricultural Extension Service. University Farm. Lincoln. 1. Alfalfa Management. 1911 The Babcock Test and Its Use in Herd Improvement. 1!U4. 2. Cost of Growing Crops in Ne - braska. 11)11. 26. Directory of Nebraska Dairy Cattle Breeders and Dealers. 1I1S. 3. Testing Seed Corn. 1912 4. Cooking and Sewing- 1912 Feeding Alfalfa to Horses. 1914. 7. Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. 1912 Pruning Trees, Nines. and Shrubs. 1915. 8. Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm. 1914. MX Neglected Orchards and Their Care. 1915. 12. Nebraska Boys' Potato Clubs (Growing Potatoes.) 1913. 1. Cooperation. 191 14. The Climate of Nebraska. 1913 Lunches for the Rural 1915. 15. A Course of Study for Home Economics Clubs, l'.n:;. 17. Twelve Lessons fin Foods and Their Preparation. 19i:i. Use of Hog Cholera Serum. 1U15. (4. Second Annual Report of dainty Cooperative Farm Demnnst tion Work. 1914. 1915. 18. Simple Water Systems for the Farm. 1913. \\ . ..clworking F.xercisi- Home and School 19 20. Saving the Corn Crop. l!il 21. Filling the Silo. 1913 Rural Clubs (or W&lt; rm 22. Sweet Clover in Nebraska. 1!U4 ;7. Short Courses i r Exter 2:t. What is a Farm Demonstrator? 1914. Schools in Agricultu He me Econi miov 19 (3-ll- - l«— 10 M.) </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>