<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Immunizing Value of Commercial Vaccines and Bacterins Against Hemorrhagic Septicemia</title>
               <date value="1920-06">1920-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Research Bulletin 17 June, 1920 The Immunizing Value of Commer - cial Vaccines and Bacterins Against Hemorrhagic Septicemia L. VAN ES AND H. M. MARTIN AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE OFFICIAL ROSTER OF THE STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD (the regents of the university) HON. JOHN E. MILLER, President, Lincoln Term expires January, 1921 HON. JOHN R. WEBSTER, V ice-President, Omaha Term expires January, 1926 HON. EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey Term expires January, 1921 HON. PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln Term expires January, 1923 Term expires January, 1923 HON. HARRY D. LANDIS, Seward Term expires January, 1923 HON. FRANK D. JUDSON, Omaha Term expires January, 1926 SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor 1. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BURNETT, D. Sc., Director W. W. BURR, B. Sc, Vice Director W. H. BROKAW, Director of Extension Service THE WORKING STAFF O. W. Sjogre.n, B. Sc. in A. E., Agricultural Engineering W. W. Burr, B. Sc., Agronomy T. A. Kiesselbach, Ph. D., Agronomy H. J. Gbamlich, B. Sc., Animal Husbandry L. Van Es, M. D., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene •J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology and Hygiene P. W. Upson, Ph. D., Chemistry J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry M. H. Swenk, A. M., Entomology Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture G. A. Loveland, A. M., LL. B., Meteorology George L. Peltier, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology F. E. Mussehl, B. Sc., Poultry Husbandry H. C. Fhxey, A. M., Aural Economics W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte E. M. Brouse, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine J. A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell •*L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry W. J. Loeffel, B. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry C. K. Shedd, B. Sc. in A. E., Assistant in Agricultural Engineering P. L. Gadiiis, A. B., B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy F. D. Keim, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene J. W. Hendrickson, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry John Luithlt, B. Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry C. C. Wigganb, Ph. D., Assistant in Horticulture H. O. Werner, B. Sc, Assistant in Horticulture E. W. Goss, M. S., Assistant in Plant Pathology and Physiology J. O. Rankin, A. M., Assistant in Rural Economics •Resigned. ••Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Department of Agri - culture, Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE IMMUNIZING VALUE OF COMMERCIAL VACCINES AND BACTERINS AGAINST HEMORRHAGIC SEPTICEMIA By L. VAN ES AND H. M MARTIN In the course of certain studies having to do with hemor - rhagic septiceniia, we were particularly struck with the difficulties which we encountered in the immunization of susceptible lab - oratory animals (rabbits). Aside from a rather transitory and very unstable immunity secured by the use of an anti-serum prepared by us, there was little or no evidence that injections of bacterins or vaccines, as made in our laboratory, were followed by any degree of resistance against a trial injection of B. bipolaris. This difficulty in no small degree excited our curiosity re - garding the immunizing value of the considerable number of '"Hemorrhagic Septiceniia bacterins and vaccines*' which during recent years have become such a prominent article of commerce. Most of those preparations appear to be based upon a belief that by heating or by other means of killing or attenuation of the B. bipolaris a dependable immunizing agent can be produced, al - though we are not aware that this has been proven to be the case by exact laboratory experiments. In addition we have seen no evidence that the immunizing value of the products mentioned is being controlled by any standard method by either the manu - facturer or the user. Considerations of this kind, however, do not appear to have a restrictive influence on the sale of those substances and we are certain that the amount of money annually expended on them by the raisers of farm animals is quite a con - siderable one. In the hope of securing some information relative to the immunizing value of the agents mentioned, we undertook a series of experiments in which the immunity of the bacterin and vaccine injected laboratory animals was definitely tested by subsequent inoculations with B. bipolaris. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin 17 4 In nearly all the cases, the vaccines or bacterins were pur - chased directly from the manufacturer, selecting those especially which were most conspicuously advertised. The degree of im - munity produced by them was always tested by the use of B. bipolaris cultures or material primarily obtained from the same species as the one upon which the bacterin or vaccine was sup - posed to confer protection. In one instance we w r ere even for - tunate enough to test the immunity of our test animals against the very strain of B. bipolaris found in the preparation. In the matter of dosage, we have with but few exceptions selected the one recommended on the label. In some cases we used smaller, in others larger doses in order to ascertain a pos - sible influence upon immunity by such variations. In only a few instances did the vaccine or bacterin injec - tions produce any immediate unfavorable effect on the test rabbits. In most of those cases there was indisposition or even sudden deaths immediately following the injection and this we could attribute entirely to the presence of preservative agents. With those few exceptions we encountered no trouble caused by the relative large doses. Sample No. 113. The first preparation which we had occasion to give a trial was one sold as a "Mixed Infection Bacterin." This name, at first sight, made it appear that it would perhaps be unwise to expect an immunity against hemorrhagic septicemia from its use. However, in accompanying printed matter the manufacturer assured us that it contained forty-five per cent of B. suisepticus. and because of the further statement that "Each two mill contains the most satisfactory combinations of organisms and in amounts sufficient to insure immunity against each possible infection." we considered ourselves justified in using this bacterin in our tests. In passing it may be of interest to observe that according to the manufacturer's claims it should cause immunity against four other bacterial species aside from hemorrhagic septicemia. To what ex-tent any claims in regard to the latter disease are sustained by our experiments may be seen from Table I. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Hemorrhagic Septicemia Vaccines and Bacterins TABLE I Commercial mixed infection bacterin Injection of one NOTE— The fact that an injection was made is indicated by the X. A dash ( — ) is used to show that no Injection tnok place. It will l&gt;e observed that two of the three rabbits which received the 1 c.c. doses actually survived. Therefore it was thought wise to make some further tests with tlu&gt; same dose. What happened to the rabbits so treated is shown in Table II. TABLE II Commercial mixed j Injection of one Rabbit infection bacterin loopful of culture Date Rabbit No. No. 1/7 1W I 1/14 j loopful of culture B. bipolaris No. 59 Date of deaths Remarks ' .1 Quantity Quantity 1/14 1/27 c.c. c.c. — . 1 5 2 5 3 5 4 5 5 5 6 1 7 1 8 1 9 2 10 2 11 2 12 13 2 2 X X X X x X X X X X X X X ' = x 1 29 1 28 1 15 1/15 1/15 1 15 1/15 1/16 1/15 1/15 1/15 Control I ! Control II I i No. No. 113 1/17 Quantity c.c. t. bipolans No. 59 1/27 of deaths ; Remark ks 1 2 8 4 6 1 1 1 1 1 X X X X X 1/28 1/28 1/28 1/28 1/28 i__ </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin 17 Sample No. 148. The material used in this test reached the lalioratory under the label: "Hemorrhagic Septicemia Vaccine. (Avian)." The detailed account of the experiment is given in Table III. JABLiK 111 I i ii One loopful Fowl cholera culture Rabbit vaccine No. 148 B. bipolaris Date 2/3 avisepticus of Remarks No. Quantity 1 c.c. 2/11 deaths Strain 38 B. I i.. ..!... — x 2/12 2 — X 2/12 8 X X 2/12 4 X X . 2/12 5 X X 2/12 6 X X 2/12 All injections were 7 X X 2/12 made intravenously 8 X X 2/12 9 X X 2/12 10 X X 2/12 11 X X 2/12 12 X X 2/12 I I I I </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Hemorrhagic Septicemia Vaccines and Bacterins 7 Sample No. 17G A preparation sold as "Hemorrhagic Septiconiia Bactcrin for Cattle." The test gave the results shown in Table IV. TABLE IV This preparation was sold to us as "Hemorrhagic Septicemia Combined Bacterin (Bovine)." The immunity of the rabbits treated with this substance was tested with three strains of B. bipolaris of bovine origin. It will be noted that the virulence of one of those strains was lost and that the rabbits with one ex - ception succumbed to a subsequent infection. For details of this experiment see Tables V, VI and VII. Rabbit No. Commercial bacterin No. 176 2 c.c. i 2/17 2/21 Injection of one loopful of culture B. bipolaris No. 156 ■1 28 Dates of deaths Remarks 1 2 3 4..... ! X X X X X X X X 3 1 3/1 3/1 3/10 Subject in poo- condition. f Survived injection of strain ! 1 156, but when injected3/8 \ with strain 59 it died two ( days later. 5 6 7 8 9 10 X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X 3/1 3/10 3/2 3/4 3/3 3/4 f Survived injection of strain I 15*!, but when injected on I 3/8 with strain 59 it died { two days later. J I !_ I J Sampli E No. 359. MP1 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin 17 TABLE VI Injection of Injection of Commercial one loopful one loopful Rabbit bacterin of virulent of virulent Dates No. 359 blood (B. blood (B. of Remarks No. 2 c.c. ; bipolaris) bipolaris) deaths 6/18 No. 214 No. 214 1 7/2 2 7/2 3 7/7 f Was sick for three I days previous to 7/12. ] B. bipolaris in heart [blood. 4 X X 7/16 7/2 7/2 5 6 7. 7/2 8 7/2 9. 7/2 10. 7/2 11 7/8 7/1 7/12 X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X Rabbit Injection of Injection of Commercial one joopful one loopful bacterin of virulent of virulent Dates No. 359 blood blood of Remarks 2 c.c. B. bipolaris B. bipolaris deaths 6/18 No. 172 No. 214 7/1 7/12 No. ! X X — 7/12 I Subject was sick one \ week before death. XX — 7/2 XX — 7/5 XX — 7/5 XX — 7/2 X X 7/2 { Sick for several days. v v Tine. J Marked pneumonia. A A ~ 7/ " J6 1 No organisms in ( heart's blood. XX — 7/2 - X - 7/4 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Hemorrhagic Septicemia Vaccines and Bacterins 9 With the same combined bacterin we furthermore treated three rabbits not less than eight times at forty-eight hour inter - vals. The results are given in Table VIII. TABLE VIII I Rabbit Commercial bacterin No. 359 2c.c. 6/18 Injection of Injection of one loopful one loopful of virulent of virulent blood (B. blood (B. bipolaris) bipolaris) No. 307 No. 214 7/1 7/12 Dates of deaths Remarks No. 1 2 8 4 5 X X X X X X X X X X X X X 7/13 7/7 7/8 7/22 f Pleuro pneumonia B. \ bipolaris in blood. 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X 7/13 7/13 7/4 7/13 7/3 7/13 7/13 Rabbit No. Received 2 c.c. of commercial bacterin No. 359 on the following dates: 6/18 6/28 6/20 6/30 6/23 7/1 6/27 7/3 Injection of one loopful of virulent blood (B. bipolarisi No. 214 7/9 Injection of one loopful of virulent blood (B. bipolaris) No. 172 7/12 Dates of deaths Remarks X X X X X X X X X 7/13 7/10 7/10 7/10 7/10 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 10 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin* 17 Sample No. 485. A product sold as "Bacillus Suisepticus Bacterin (for swine plague)." As the manufacturer of this material in common with others, indicates in his advertising matter that repeated bacterin injec - tions are desirable, we designed this series of experiments so that three groups of six rabbits each received respectively one, two and three bacterin injections while another group of ten rabbits were injected not less than twelve times. All injections were made every other day and were so timed that the entire series received its last immunizing dose on the same day. Ten days later each of the rabbits in this series received an inoculation with 1/10 c.c. of virus mixture prepared by taking the heart blood of a rabbit dead as a result of inoculation with B. bipolaris (from swine) mixed with twenty parts of salt solu - tion and added to equal parts of a 24-hour boullion culture of the same organism. Table IX shows the results of those trials. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Hemorrhagic Septicemia Vaccines and Bacterins 11 H I— I I c o . 11 c = = C hi! b %&gt; u S 5 1 *3 ■s +s w 5s 5-c rt« a B.S 8 8 t 1* 5 5 3 xb •« * ja 5! M I ■gs SI 5m 5 5 — -in ■ Ihta ■||d|| XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXIXXX 35 L^ 2 xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx CZ 2 xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx ,3 2 XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX M II I! _t «N a _a m J XXXXXXXXXX | | | M I I I I I I I I I I I S — ■B S xxxxxxxxxx I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I g I x^xxxxxxxx I I I I i I I || I i I I I I i I 2 xxxxxxxxxx I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I 1 2 \xxxxxxxxxx I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I i I xxxxxxxxxx I I I I I 1 I I M I I I 55 J XXXXXXXXXX\ M I I II I I I I I I I ? xxxxxxxxxx I w " HHHHHrtHrtHNtlNNNNNNNNMTOnM </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 JNebrask mem Station Research Bulletin 17 i!s = ell's fill Bel MiS .a ' &amp;J8 3 ft|l -/• — s; c ■ — 3*1 c • 1 1 5 || sB i II 5?i I i 11 I! HJ ii lea «§§§.§§ 8"Sa mill »OtO COCO II I I I I I I I I I I I l~~ ~~ o» . i jr XXXKKX XXXXXXXXXXXXXXX | I I i: If K«KK«K XKXXKXKKKKKXKg | | I I I 6 55 HNR^ilSV rtHrtHHHHHrtHNNN ss </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Hemorhhagic Septicemia Vaccines and Bacterins 13 i i nan *.§ .3.2.2 ■ I- 7S x Ulttl - s O O O £ 5o C.Q.C * « 2152 -c — £ » BBS « "5 M " 5r 5_ — _^ — 2 o -t: :£ S J.2 * * * S &lt;^ a S s I &amp;c c K « 03 ™ .-tr "C a: J2 «u S» E» •« I. £.Q M Si t)C MB « 1 t: 5 a -2 c £ » ti 'S c.-^ "§ 2 « cS "S-sSSb 5 * -pK^g^g - a x a a : i i I * "S X • SS pQ OQ M GO ■ &amp;■***« .2«o 9» « bc a ca Zxix.^ i~ -T-~--~ ?■ X ii.S'g.a Q •* 9. c* k — •— » sa 5S?^5^ X •92* is « -■ - dlMlM C4C4 MM •H r. m KBH 5 . Hi- r OS in i— i -i j|8= &gt;i a8 S « -5 | ti o I u I u li u I ti u I v u v .i « l. S -S « o «Ssi5 .^^s S.H •»-! *3 •— £ Ho 3 ® o « » ti^ ti -^ §SS c^ ?-§s«» cj d o Odo'dtjuudddutiu MM M OMMMMMM'^'W'*-^"* ■*- i&lt; i-hm eo £ jS hn ** Tf &lt;e n n m n i-i cj w to w n t- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 ETIN 17 HrtHNNNNN N N (MNCvJTO Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bi « » fl|fl|jl a ; mm I j -s «-s § £ *-s i s S3 a tSaSwMQ | 1 |JSn'§|| || * •Q"-^-' — ■ *- — ■ — UOOU «» ' Q NNNNNNNN IM « n'n'Jin" lit i.i" 1 1 1 1 1 1 ii i £ 1 1 1 1 1 i 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 i I I I IWll I I I I 33 N — ■ — § DO IIIIIM^ o £ o i — u o 1 1 II JfeS I u u u u I I u ■♦•*■* H 1-1 c u i.' u — I I I I t! o u o w o o o |] i.' £ I II I 1c i t-ooo»© </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Hemorrhagic Septicemia Vaccines and Bacterins 15 Sample No. 621 This preparation was called on the label '"Hemorrhagic Sep - ticemia Vaccine for Swine." The results of our tests are shown in Table XII. TABLE XII Vaccine injection Rabbit ! No. 621 Injection Dates No. 2/10 2/15 3/1 B. bipolans No. 59 of deaths Remarks sS 1 2c.c. ; 2 2c.c. \ 3 2 c.c. 4 2 c.c. 5 2 c.c. 6 2 c.c. 7 2 c.c. 8 2 c.c. 9 2 c.c. 10 2 c.c. 11 4 c.c. 12 4 c.c. 13 4 c.c. 14 4 c.c. 15 4 c.c. ; 16 4 c.c. 17 4 c.c. 18 4c.c. 19 4 c.c. 20 4 c.c. 21 1 c.c. 2 c.c. ! 2 c.c. 2 c.c. 2 c.c. 2 c.c. 2 c.c. 2 c.c. 2 c.c. 2 c.c. 2 c.c. 4 c.c. 4 c.c. 4 c.c. 4 c.c. 4 c.c. 1 4 c.c. 4 c.c. 4 c.c. 4 c.c. 4 c.c. 1 c.c. 10 c.c. 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 3/9 ; 2/25 ! 2/25 2/25 I 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 2/25 ! 2/24 2/25 2/25 2/25 3/11 f Heart blood containei many B. bipolans. 22 — 23 — 24 — 25 — 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/24 2/25 2/24 2/25 2/25 Control Control Control Control </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin 17 Sample No. 717. A specimen of "Hemorrhagic Septicemia Bacterin (Bovine)." The details of the tests made with this material are given in Table XIII. TABLE XIII I Rabbit No. Injecti ions ba&lt; 5( rterin No. 717 ;.c. I 4/6 ! 4/9 Injections B. bipolaris No. 738 Loopful 4/19 Dates of deaths Remarks 3/31 4/3 4/6 4/9 1 2 8 4 5 6 7 8 8 10 11 to X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X 1/10 1/10 1/10 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/10 1/4 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 Control 4/20 Control 12 18 14 15 16 17 18 1» 20 21 oo 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Hemorrhagic Septicemia Vaccines and Bacterins 17 Vac ■e are than 4 ■1 Sample No. 720. This preparation is sold as ''Hemorrhagic Septicemia cine (Bovine)." The experiments made with this substam given in Table XIV. 1 WJ i Rabbit No. Injections vaccine No. 720 4 c.c. 4/3 I 4/6 I 4/9 Injections B. bipolaris No. 738 Loopful 4/19 Dates of Remarks deaths ; _;. : — — 1 2 3 4 5 e. . :... 7 8 9 10 XXX X X X . XXX XXX XXX XXX XXX XXX XXX XXX 1/10 1/10 1/10 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 4/20 Received more ' \ c.c. vaccine 4/1 11 12 14 15 16 17. 18 19 20 XXX XXX XXX XXX XXX XXX XXX XXX XXX 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/4 1/10 1/4 4/20 4/20 4/20 i 4/20 4/20 4 20 4/20 4/20 Control 4 20 Control </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin 17 Sample No. 735. This material was sold to us under the label "Swine Plague Bacterin." Table XV relates the tests made in detail. TABLE XV Injections Injections bacterin B. bipolaris No. 735 No. 59 Dates 2 c.c. Loopful of Rabbit No. Remarks 4/13 I 4/16 4/20 4/28 5/11 1 2 8 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 L2 18 14 16 X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X 1/50 1/10 5/12 1/50 — 4/29 1/60 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/29 1/60 — 4/29 1/60 — 4/29 1/10 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/30 1/50 — 4/30 1/60 . . 4/29 1/60 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/29 16 17 18 19 » 51 2 X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X f Pneumonia, pericar 1/50 1/10 5/19 ditis. Organs con- i tained B. bipolaris. 1/50 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/29 1/50 — 4/29 Control 1/50 — 4/29 Control </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Hemorriiaoic Septicemia Vaccines axd Bactekins 19 The results of the entire series of experiments as far as the acquisition of immunity on the part of the laboratory animals is concerned arc summarized in Table XVI. TABLE XVI No. rabbits No. of Results CONCLUSIONS It does not appear that the vaccines and bacterins experi - mented with have any antigenic value which expresses itself in actual resistance to B. bipolaris infection. We encountered uni - form negative results, no matter if we injected those substances once or a dozen times; a virus injection was always certain to kill the animals. The indications are that if hemorrhagic septicemia is in reality a frequent and very fatal disease to our farm animals, that the commercial immunizing agents against it are indeed a poor staff to lean on and that if those diseases are at all to be combatted in a serious manner, we will have to look to other methods for relief. (5M) treated and immunity tested bacterin or vaccine injections i Rabbits &gt; Rabbits dead alive Remarks 59 1 47 i 48 20 3 i 10 1OT 1 2 3 4 8 12 56 3 47 0 48 0 20 0 3 0 10 0 Only those rabbits which lived long enough to receive the final virus dose were considered in the construc- tion of this table. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>