<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Lamb Feeding Experiments in the Sugar Beet Growing Districts</title>
               <date value="1926-11">1926-11</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 216 November, 1926 Lamb Feeding Experiments in the Sugar Beet Growing Districts JAMES A. HOLDEK, SUPERINTENDENT SCOTTSBLUFF EXPERIMENT SUBSTATION I'■ ■ ' I , ■ -■■ - - ■ ■ ■ Lamb Feeding Yards at the Scottsbluff Experiment Farm ■ I : * THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Summary o Rations Fed o Initial Cost and Weight per Lamb 7 Appraised Value at End of Test 7 The Price of Feeds .. . 7 Comparing Corn, Barley, and Molasses Dry Pulp When Fed with Alfalfa Hay ■ ■ o Comparing Corn, Barley, and Dry Pulp when Supplemented with Cottonseed Cake (J A Comparison of Corn, Barley, and Dry Pulp when Supplemented with Linseed Cake. &#132; Comparing- the Feeding Value of Cottonseed Cake and Linseed Cake when Fed with Corn jg Comparing the Feeding Value of Cottonseed Cake and Linseed Cake when Fed with Barley 15 Comparing the Feeding Value of Cottonseed Cake and Linseed Cake when Fed with Molasses Dry Pulp 16 Comparing the Feeding Value of Corn Silage, Beet Top Silage, Beet Tops, and Cull Potatoes when Fed m a Ration of Corn' Cottonseed Cake, and Alfalfa Hay ' jg </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY In this experiment there are 3 principal comparisons: (1) Corn, barley, and molasses dry pulp are compared when fed with alfalfa hay, with alfalfa hay and cottonseed cake, and with alfalfa hay and linseed cake; (2) cottonseed cake and linseed cake are compared when fed with corn, with barley, and with molasses dry pulp; (3) corn silage, beet top silage, beet tops, and cull potatoes are compared when fed with a ration of corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. When fed without cake, corn proved to be a better feed than barley and barley was better than dry pulp. The lambs fed corn made an average gain of 30.3 pounds; those fed barley, 27 pounds; and the onea fed dry pulp, 24' pounds. The selling price per 100 pounds was $15.40 for the lambs fed corn, $15.30 where barley was fed, and $15.25 for those fed dry pulp. The net profit per lamb was ?1.75 for the lambs fed corn, $1.61 for the ones fed barley, and $1.24 for those fed dry pulp. When either cottonseed cake or linseed cake was added to the corn, barley, or dry pulp ration, the lambs getting corn made faster gains with less feed per 100 pounds gain than those fed either barley or dry pulp, but the difference m favor of corn was less than where cake was not used. In the lots where cake was omitted, the lambs getting corn made 3.3 pounds more gain than those fed barley and 6.3 pounds more than the ones fed dry pulp, but when cottonseed cake was added to each of these rations the lambs fed corn made just 3 pounds more gain than the lambs fed barley and' only 1.7 pounds more than those fed dry pulp. The lambs fed cottonseed cake and dry pulp made more gains than those fed cottonseed cake and barley. The addition of cottonseed cake to these rations increased both the sell - ing price and the profit per lamb. The selling price was increased 25 cents per hundredweight m each case, and the profit per lamb was increased 22 cents per lamb where corn was fed, 18 cents where barley was fed, and 81 cents where dry pulp was fed. In, each case where cake was used m the ration the pulp-fed lambs returned a higher net profit than those fed either corn or barley, but where cake was not fed the returns were decidedly m favor of corn or barley. It is. doubtful if it is advisable to feed dry pulp unless cake is used m the ration. Cake had a much higher feeding value when fed •with dry pulp than when fed with either corn or barley. There appears to be but little difference m the feeding value of cottonseed cake and linseed cake when fed with either corn, barley, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">or dry pulp. There was a very small difference m favor of cotton - seed cake. When cottonseed cake can be bought for less money per ton than linseed cake, cottonseed cake should be fed m preference to the other. There does not appear to be any great amount of difference m the feeding value of corn silage, beet top silage, beet tops, and cull potatoes when fed with a ration of corn, cottonseed cake and alfalfa hay. The lambs fed potatoes made the most gain and gave the highest profit, with those fed beet tops second, beet top silage third, and corn silage fourth. When each of these 4 lots is compared with Lot 4, which was fed only corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay, the results show that each of these 4 feeds increased the gains per lamb, and that both potatoes and beet tops increased the profits while beet top silage showed the same profit and corn silage showed a profit of 7 cents less. Siloing beet tops increased their feeding value but it is doubts ful if this increase is sufficient to cover the extra expense of siloing them. In this test the tops from 1 ton of beets when siloed had the same feeding value as the tops from 1.6 tons when the tops were piled m the field and hauled to the feed yard as fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Lamb Feeding Experiments m the Sugar Beet Growing Districts JAMES A. HOLDEN The data presented m this bulletin have to do with a con - tinuation of the study of lamb feeding on irrigated farms m Western Nebraska. The results from two 3-year experi - ments have been published m Bulletin 194. In conducting these experiments it has been the aim to gather information on the feeding value of home-grown feeds, especially the by - products of the sugar beet industry, and to find out how these feeds can be combined with feeds shipped m so as to yield the highest return from the feeding operations. The tests herein reported were begun m the fall of 1922 and continued for 3 consecutive winters. There were 13 lots with 30 lambs per lot the first winter and 25 lambs per lot the second and third winters. In this experiment there are 3 principal comparisons: (1) Corn, barley, and dry pulp are compared when fed with alfalfa hay, with cottonseed cake and alfalfa hay, and with linseed cake and alfalfa hay, (2) cottonseed cake is compared with hnseed cake when fed with either corn barley or dry pulp, and (3) corn silage, beet top silage, beet tops, and cull potatoes are compared when fed with a ration of corn, cotton - seed cake, and alfalfa hay. RATIONS FED Lot I—Corn1 — Corn and alfalfa hay. Lot 2 — Barley and alfalfa hay. Lot 3 — Dry pulp and alfalfa hay. Lot 4 — Corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Lot s— Barley, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Lot 6— Dry pulp, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Lot 7— Corn, linseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Lot B— Barley, linseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Lot 9— Dry pulp, linseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Lot 10— Corn silage, corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay Lot 11— Beet top silage, corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay Lot 12— Beet tops, corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Lot 13— Cull potatoes, corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. When the lambs had reached full feed, corn, barley, or dry pulp was fed at the rate of 1 pound per lamb daily, cake at oSM nIZ wt P TV nd sila * c « Potatoes at the rate of 1.6 pounds. Where beet tops were fed, the lambs were given what they would clean up. The lambs m each lot were - • c </seg>
            <seg id="p006">•■■ Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 216 fed all the alfalfa hay they would eat without any waste. No uneaten feed, such as stems of alfalfa, was weighed back and credited to the different lots. The lambs were fed in open lots provided with windbreaks. Alfalfa hay was fed thru panels. The sugar beet tops were thrown into the feed lot and were there eaten by the lambs. Corn, barley, pulp, and cake were fed in troughs which were in separate yards from the feed lots. Silage and potatoes were also fed in troughs, the potatoes first being run thru a root slicer. The lambs always had access to salt, and fresh water was kept in each pen. The daily ration was fed in 2 equal portions — morning and evening. The time required to get the lambs up to a full grain ration varied. The lambs fed the first winter were bought out of a feed lot and were already accustomed to grain and were worked up to a full feed in 10 days. Those fed during the second winter were on full feed in 30 days while those fed the last winter required 70 days before they reached full feed to remain thereon. It was the aim to get the lambs fed during the third winter on full feed in about 30 days, but the day after they reached full feed the lambs failed to clean up their grain and 2 lambs died in a lot where corn was fed. The grain ration was cut down to 0.8 of a pound for a few days and then gradually increased up to a full ration when the lambs again went off feed. The grain ration was again cut down to 0.8 of a pound and held there for 10 days when it was again gradually increased until the lambs were on full feed again at the end of 70 days from the time the experi - ment began. During this time the lambs had been fed a very good quality of leafy alfalfa hay and it is possible that this explains why the lambs were so backward in taking a full feed of grain. When a change was made to a coarse sec - ond-cutting hay the lambs took their grain better without any more trouble. Lambs seem to vary considerably in their capacity for grain. Some lambs can be put on a full feed of grain much quicker than others. The lambs used in this experiment the second winter were much smaller than those used the next winter, yet the small lambs were on full feed in 30 days without any trouble, while the larger lambs fed the next winter required twice as long and with a rather heavy death loss. The greater part of feed lot deaths is due to too heavy a grain ration or to too short a time in getting the lambs on full feed. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Lamb Feeding Experiments initial cost and weight per lamb The initial cost of the lambs weighed into the feed lots after allowing for the shrink to the feed lots and with freight paid to Omaha, was $12.60 for those bought in the fall of 1922, $12.00 for those bought in the fall of 1923, and $13 35 per cwt. for those bought in the fall of 1924, with an average of ?12.65. The average .weight per. lamb was 48 pounds the first winter, 45 the second, and 59 the third, with an average initial, weight of 51 pounds. The average initial cost per lamb was $6.45. APPRAISED VALUE AT END OF TEST All lots of lambs were appraised at the end of each feed - ing test by expert commission men. The market tops, repre - senting the highest price paid at Omaha for western fed lambs on the day the lambs were appraised, were as follows: • Spring of 1923 ?14 25 1924 i 1600 ■W2B ; ;. 1 6 . 8 5 3-year average $15.70 The selling prices here used for the different lots are the average of the three appraised values of that particular lot A charge of 20 cents to cover interest and a charge of 40 cents to cover shipping cost are allowed per lamb. The cost of labor, the value of the manure, and the death loss are not here considered. A shrink of 6 pounds per lamb is allowed from feed lot to- Omaha. • THE PRICE OF FEEDS The prices of feeds herein used are the averages that p're - • vailed during the 3 winters that the tests were conducted. Iney are: Alfalfa hay ; .". per ton ?11 00 Corn silage ; per ton 4QQ Beet top silage per ton 4M Cull potatoes per ton 400 Beet tops (per. ton yield of beets) .40 Corn ••• per cwt. 1.65 Barley • per cwt. 1.20 Molasses dry pulp per ewt t lfl Cottonseed cake (43 per cent) per cwt. 2.50 Linseed cake (34 per cent) per cwt 2 50 ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 216 comparing corn, barley, and molasses dry pulp when fed with alfalfa hay In addition to alfalfa hay, Lot 1 was fed corn, Lot 2 barley, and Lot 3 dry pulp. The lambs getting corn made faster gains, produced 100 pounds gain with fewer pounds of feed, sold on the market at a higher price, and returned a greater profit than those in either of the other 2 lots. The barley lot was second and the pulp lot ranked third. The results are tabulated in Table 1. Table 1 — .4 comparison of corn, barley, and molasses dry pulp when fed with alfalfa hay. Lot No. 1 2 ' 3 Number of animals 80 80 80 Corn Barley Dry pulp Uation Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Average gain per lamb. 30. S 27.0 24.0 Pounds of feed per ion pounds gain: Corn 335 Barley 375 Dry pulp . 422 Alfalfa hay - fi83 770 851 Cost of feed per 100 pounds gain 9.27 S.74 9.32 Initial cost of lamb at J12.B5 "6.45 6.45 6.45 Additional costs per lamb-. Feed 2.80 2.3fi 2.24 interest .20 .20 .20 Marketing -40 .40 .40 Total cost per lamb 9.85 9.41 9.29 Final weight at feed lot 81.3 78.0 75.0 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha fi.H •&gt;.&lt;• 6-0 Selling weight 75.3 72.0 69.0 Selling price per cwt 15.40 15.30 15.25 Receipts per lamb 11.60 11.02 10.53 Profit per lamb 1.75 1.61 1.24 The average gain per lamb was 30.3 pounds where corn was fed, 27 pounds where barley was fed, and 24 pounds where dry pulp was fed. In Lot 1 it required 335 pounds of corn and 683 pounds of alfalfa hay per 100 pounds gain; in Lot 2 it required 375 pounds of barley and 770 pounds of alfalfa hay; and in Lot 3, 422 pounds of dry pulp and 851 pounds of alfalfa hay. The profit per lamb was $1.75 where corn was fed, $1.61 where barley was fed, and $1.24 where dry pulp was fed. By comparing these 3 lots, it can be shown that 100 pounds of corn had the same feeding value as 112 pounds of barley </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Lamb Feeding Experiments and 26 pounds of alfalfa hay, or 125 pounds of dry pulp and 38 pounds of alfalfa hay. The results in Bulletin 194, which are the average of 6 years' tests, comparing corn and dry pulp, show that 100 pounds of corn was equal to 113 pounds of dry pulp and 30 pounds of alfalfa hay. By using the average of the 3 experiments, which represents an aver - age of 9 tests, it will be noted that 100 pounds of corn re - placed 117 pounds of dry pulp and 33 pounds of alfalfa hay. In this test 100 pounds of barley appears to have the same feeding value as 112 pounds of dry pulp and 21 pounds of alfalfa hay. COMPARING CORN, BARLEY, AND DRY PULP WHEN SUPPLEMENTED WITH COTTONSEED CAKE The same rations used in Lots 1, 2, and 3 respectively were also fed to Lots 4, 5, and 6, with the addition of a third of a pound of cottonseed cake daily per lamb. Here, also, the lambs getting corn made faster gains than those fed either barley or dry pulp but the difference is not so much. In the lots where cottonseed cake was lacking the lambs getting corn made 3.3 pounds more gain than those fed barley and 6.3 pounds more than the lambs getting dry pulp, while in the lots where cottonseed cake was fed the corn-fed lambs made 3 pounds more gain than the lambs getting barley and only 1.7. pounds more than the pulp-fed lambs. By adding cottonseed cake to the rations it increased both the selling price and the net profit per lamb. The selling price in each case was increased 25 cents per 100 pounds and the increase in net profit per lamb was 22 cents for those fed corn, 18 cents for those fed barley, and 81 cents for those fed dry pulp. In Lot 4 it required 286 pounds of corn, 92 pounds of cotton - seed . cake, and 552 pounds of alfalfa hay per 100 pounds gain; in Lot 5 it was 312 pounds of barley, 100 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 660 pounds of alfalfa hay; and in Lot 6 it was 301 pounds of dry pulp, 96 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 632 pounds of alfalfa hay. When comparing the feeding values of corn, barley, and dry pulp when fed with cotton - seed cake and alfalfa hay, it can be shown that 100 pounds of corn replaced 109 pounds of barley, 2.8 pounds of cotton - seed cake, and 38 pounds of alfalfa hay, or 105 pounds of dry pulp, 1.4 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 28 pounds of alfalfa hay. One hundred pounds of dry pulp in this test replaced 104 pounds of barley, 1.3 pounds of cottonseed cake, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 216 and 9 pounds of alfalfa hay. The corn-fed lambs sold for $15.65. the barley-fed lambs at $15.55, and those getting dry pulp at $15.50 per hundredweight. In profit per lamb those fed corn made $1.97, the ones getting barley made $1.79, and those in the dry pulp lot made $2.05. Table 2— A comparison of corn, barley, and molasses dry pulp when supplemented with cottonseed cake and fed with alfalfa hay. Lot Xo. 4 5 ; g Number of animals 80 80 80 Corn Barley Dry pulp RatIon Cot. cake Cot. cake Cot. cake Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Average pain per lamb „ 35.4 ' 32.4 337 Pounds feed per 100 pounds Rain: Corn 286 ' Barley 312 Dry pulp 301 Cottonseed cake 92 100 96 Alfalfa hay 552 660 632 Cost of feed per 100 pounds gain 10.06 !&gt;.88 9.19 Initial cost of lamb at $12.65 6.45 fi.45 6.45 Additional costs per lamb: Feed _...._ 3.56 3.20 3.10 Interest _ ,20 .20 .20 Marketing .40 .40 .40 Total cost per lamb 10.61 10.25 10.15 Final weight at feed lot 86.4 83.4 84.7 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha 6.0 6.0 6.0 Selling weight 80.4 77.4 78.7 Selling price per cwt 15.65 15.55 15.50 Receipts per lamb 12.58 12.04 12.20 Profit per lamb 1.97 1.79 2.05 A feed that makes a greater gain with a higher finish and commands a better price at the market has more value than its comparative replacement value of other feeds. In Table 2, when corn is figured at $1.65 and barley at $1.20 a hundred pounds, the lambs fed corn each returned a profit of $1.97 as compared to $1.79 for those getting barley. Barley would have to be figured at $1.01 per hundred in order to make the 2 feeds equal in terms of profit per lamb. The lambs getting dry pulp made a profit of $2.05 per head when they are charged $22 per ton for the pulp. If pulp had been valued at $23.60 a ton, then the profit per lamb would have been the same as in the corn lot. Or, by comparing barley and dry pulp in this same way, when barley has a value of $1.20 per </seg>
            <seg id="p011">■ ■ " - ) ' ' - ' ■ ■ '' ' I" .."■": Lamb Feeding Experiments hundred or $24 per ton, dry pulp has a value of $27 per ton. The above comparisons are when cottonseed cake is fed in' each of the three rations. Where cottonseed cake was not fed, as was the case in the 3 lots reported in Table 1, the corn-fed lambs returned a profit of $1.75; the barley-fed lambs, $1.61; and those getting dry pulp $1.24. By comparing these lots as was done in the preceding paragraphs where cottonseed cake was fed, when corn has a value of $1.65 per hundred or $33 a ton barley has a value of $21.20 and dry pulp $12.40 a ton. That is, the prices of barley and dry pulp would have to be cut down to $21.20 and $12.40 . respectively in order that the lambs in these 2 lots return the same net profit as the lambs getting corn; or, when barley and dry pulp are compared, if barley has a value of $24 a ton, dry pulp has a value of $15.20 a ton. By comparing the relative values of corn, barley, and dry pulp when fed either with or without cottonseed cake, the value of cottonseed cake in a dry pulp ration is very apparent. In the cottonseed cake lots, corn at $33 and dry pulp at $23.60 a ton had the same, comparative feeding value as against $33 for corn and $12.40 for dry pulp when cottonseed cake was omitted from the rations. Also, in the cottonseed cake lots, barley at $24 and dry pulp at $27 had. the same com - parative values; but when cottonseed cake was not fed, dry pulp had a value of only $15.20 a ton compared with barley at $24 a ton. It appears from the foregoing that cottonseed cake contains something that is more deficient in dry pulp than in either corn or barley, so that when cottonseed cake is fed with each it has a much higher value in the dry pulp ration than in either of the other rations. A COMPARISON OF CORN, BARLEY, AND DRY PULP WHEN SUPPLEMENTED WITH LINSEED CAKE . There is but little difference, as will be seen by comparing Tables 2 and 3, in the value of cottonseed cake and linseed cake when fed with either corn, barley, or dry pulp. The difference, if any, seems to be slightly in favor of cottonseed cake. In each case the gains per lamb were a fraction of a pound more where cottonseed cake was fed than where lin - seed cake was used. The appraised value of the respective lots was the same in each case. The profit per lamb was less in each case where linseed cake was used, notwithstand - ing the fact that the linseed cake was figured at the same ■ ■ ■ y . ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 216 price as cottonseed cake, when, as a matter of fact, it usually costs a few dollars more per ton. By comparing the gains made by the lambs fed linseed cake in Lots 7, 8, and 9, it will be seen that those fed corn made 3 pounds per lamb more than those fed barley and 2.1 pounds more than the ones fed dry pulp. Where cottonseed cake was fed in Lots 4, 5, and 6, the lambs fed corn made 3 pounds more gain than those fed barley and 1.7 pounds more Table 3— A comparison of corn, barley, and molasses dry pulp when supplemented ivith linseed cake and fed with alfalfa hay. Lot No. 7 jj ~ Number of animals 80 jq g0 „ . Corn Barley Dry pulp' Rallon Linseed Linseed Linseed cake cake cake Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa ■Vvpraee eain per lamb 35 9 32 2 33 1 rounds feed per 100 pounds gain: Corn 2S8 Barley 3 j 5 P r &gt;" P ul P r.."I 306 Linseed cake . 92 101 98 _ Alfalfa 59ft 671 6 ' 3g i.ost of feed per lno pounds gain 10.,'iO 1(1 00 9 33 Initial cost of lamb at $12.65 cwt 6.45 1; 45 i; 45 Additional posts per Iamb: F ppd 3.63 3.22 3.09 Interest 20 20 20 Marketing 40 .40 40 Total cost per lamb 10.68 10 27 10 14 Final weight at feed lot 86.2 83 2 84 1 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha 6.0 6 0 6 0 Selling weight 80.2 77 2 78 # 1 Selling price per cwt. 15.65 15.55 15'.50 Receipts per lamb 12.55 12.00 12 11 Profit per lamb 1.87 1.73 1.97 than the ones fed dry pulp. The difference in favor of corn was the same for the 2 barley fed lots and 0.4 of a pound variation in the 2 dry pulp lots. The dry pulp had a value a little nearer that of corn when fed with cottonseed cake than when fed with linseed cake. It required a little more feed per 100 pounds gain where linseed cake was fed than where cottonseed cake was used. In Lot 7, the lambs were fed 288 pounds of corn, 92 pounds of linseed cake, and 590 pounds of alfalfa hay; in Lot 8, it </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Lamb Feeding Experiments was 315 pounds of barley, 101 pounds of linseed cake, and 671 pounds of alfalfa; and in Lot 9, it was 306 pounds of dry pulp, 98 pounds of linseed cake, and 638 pounds of alfalfa hay for each 100 pounds of gain made. The replacement value of 100 pounds of corn in this test was 109 pounds of barley, 3.1 pounds of linseed cake, and 28 pounds of alfalfa hay, or 106 pounds of dry pulp, 2.1 pounds of linseed cake and 17 pounds of alfalfa hay. One hundred pounds of dry pulp was equal to 103 pounds of barley, 1 pound of linseed cake, and 11 pounds of alfalfa hay. With the prices herein used, both cottonseed cake and lin - seed cake proved to be profitable feeds when fed with either corn, barley, or dry pulp, with the feed requirement per 100 pounds gain, and the profit per lamb being slightly in favor of cottonseed cake. When fed with either cottonseed cake or linseed cake, dry pulp ranked 1st in point of profit per lamb, corn 2nd and barley 3rd. Many feeders prefer linseed cake to cottonseed cake even when linseed cake costs as much as $4 or $5 a ton more. It is claimed, and justly, that linseed cake is more laxative than cottonseed cake, but where any of the various by-products of the sugar beet industry is used in the ration this has no ad - vantage. Even in rations of corn and alfalfa hay there has been no noticeable costive effect from the feeding of cotton - seed cake. In the 3 years that the experiment was conducted there were, in all, 9 comparisons of cottonseed cake and lin - seed cake made — 3 with corn, 3 with barley, and 3 with dry pulp. The average gain per lamb was the same in 4 of these comparisons, in 3 it Was in favor of cottonseed cake, and 2 in favor of linseed cake. Where there was a difference it was very small. It would appear from this that a feeder is not justified in using linseed cake when it costs more than cotton - seed cake. COMPARING THE FEEDING VALUE OF COTTONSEED CAKE AND UNSEED CAKE WHEN FED WITH CORN Lots 1, 4, and 7, which were fed corn and alfalfa hay; corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay; and corn, linseed cake and alfalfa hay, respectively, are compared in Table 4. The addition of either of the cakes to a corn-alfalfa ration in - creased the gains per lamb, the selling price per 100 pounds, and the profit per lamb. The gains per lamb were increased 5.1 pounds where cottonseed cake was fed and 4.9 pounds where linseed cake was fed. In each case where cake was </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 216 fed, the selling price was increased 25 cents per hundred - weight, and the profit per lamb was 22 cents more in the cottonseed cake lot and 12 cents more when fed linseed cake. Using the profit per lamb as the basis and with the prices of alfalfa hay and of lambs remaining the same as herein used, when corn costs $1.65 a 100 pbunds, cottonseed cake is a profitable feed up to where it costs $63.20 a ton and linseed cake up to $57.60 a ton. Or with both of the cakes at $50 a ton, cottonseed cake can be profitably fed until Table 4— Comparing the feeding value of cottonseed cake and Unseed cake when fed with corn and alfalfa liay. Lot No. \ 4 Number of animals j)0 gg g0 „ Corn Corn Ration Corn Cot. cake Lin. cnke Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Average gain per lamb 30.3 35I 35~2 Pounds feed per 100 pounds gain: Corn 335 286 288 Cottonseed cake 92 Linseed cake 92 Alfalfa 683 552 590 Cost of feed per 100 pounds gain 9.27 10.06 10.30 Initial cost of lamb at $12.65 per cwt. ... 6.45 fi.45 6 45 Additional costs per lamb: Feed, 2.80 3.5fi 3.63 Interest _ ,20 .20 .20 Marketing .40 .40 .40 Total cost per lamb 9.85 10.61 10. G8 Final weight at feed lot 81.3 86.4 86.2 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha- 6.0 6.0 6.0 Selling weight _ _ __ 75.3 SO. 4 80.2 Selling price per cwt 15.40 15.65 15.65 Receipts per lamb , 11.60 12.58 12.55 Profit per lamb I.75 I.97 1.87 the price of corn gets down to $1.42 a hundred pounds, and linseed cake remains profitable until corn gets down to $1.52. By comparing the replacement values of the feeds in these 3 rations, it will be found that 85 pounds of corn and 28 pounds of cottonseed cake in Lot 4 had the same feeding value as 100 pounds of corn and 39 pounds of alfalfa hay in Lot 1, where cottonseed cake was not used. In the same way 86 pounds of corn and 28 pounds of linseed cake in Lot 7 re - placed 100 pounds of corn and 28 pounds of alfalfa hay in Lot 1. In Lot 4, 1000 pounds of corn fed with cottonseed </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Lamb Feeding Experiments cake had the same feeding value as 1007 pounds of corn and 130 pounds of alfalfa when fed with linseed cake in Lot 7. COMPARING THE FEEDING VALUE OF COTTONSEED CAKE AND LINSEED CAKE WHEN FED WITH BARLEY In Table 5 the 3 barley lots are compared. The lambs in Lot 2 were fed barley and alfalfa hay; those in Lot 5, barley cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay; and in Lot 8 they were fed barley linseed cake, and alfalfa hay. Here, also, the lambs ted cake made faster gains, sold at a higher price, and re - turned a greater profit. The lambs fed cottonseed cake made Table ; 5— Comparing the feeding value of cottonseed cake and Unseed cake when fed with barley and alfalfa hay. Lot No. . ■ o e „ ■ Number oC animals 80 8 ° 0 ° Q ■ ni i inn ' Barley Barley naliOn Barley I Cot. cake Lin. cake ■ ' . Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Average gain per lamb 27~i) 5?1 Pounds feed per 100 pounds gain: "~ j couoLe~eTc^ e "r:rzziz:zz| 3 _I f L_ III 3 il_ Linseed cake | • . 101 Alfalfa hay ; ! 770 ggn " gnj Cost of feed per 100 pounds gain • 8 74 9 88 10 00 1 . 11 ! C08t ot lamb at * 12 - 65 Percwt._i 6!45 6^5 6 - 45 Additional costs per lamb: ' • ' Peed __ • ; , 2 .36 j 3.20 3.22 Interest lL; &lt; .20 .20 .20 : Marketing . i .40 40 40 Total cost per lamb !.._! j 9.41 iq'25 10 27 Final weight at feed lot______..^ ! . 78.0 83.'4 83i2 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha '. ! 6 0 6 0 6 0 Selling weight : 72 .0 77!4 77^ Selling price per cwt : 15.30 15.55 15.55 Receipts per lamb \ 11.02 | 12.04 12.00 Profit per. lamb . j 1.6I j 1.79 1.73 5.4 pounds more gain, and those fed linseed cake 5.2 pounds more than those not getting cake. The cake in each case again increased the selling price 25 cents a hundred. Each lamb made a profit of $1.61 where no cake was fed, $1.79 where cottonseed cake was used, and $1.73 where linseed cake was fed; or 18 cents per lamb in favor of cottonseed cake and 12 cents in favor of linseed cake. Had cottonseed cake cost $61.10 and linseed cake $57.60 a ton instead of $50, there would have been no advantage in feeding either, or if .:..-.■ ■ : ■ '■■ '■: '■'■ ■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 216 barley had cost only $1.03 a 100 pounds in the cottonseed cake lot and $1.08 in the linseed cake lot, instead of $1.20, the profit per lamb would have been the same in all 3 lots. The amount of feed required for the gains made shows that 83 pounds of barley and 27 pounds of cottonseed cake in Lot 5 replaced 100 pounds of barley and 30 pounds of alfalfa hay in Lot 2, where cake was not fed ; also, in Lot 8, 84 pounds of barley and 27 pounds of linseed cake replaced 100 pounds of barley and 26 pounds of alfalfa hay in Lot 2. According to the above data, 27 pobnds of cottonseed cake have the same feeding value as 17 pounds of corn and 27 pounds of alfalfa hay; or 27 pounds of linseed cake have the same feeding value as 16 pounds of corn and 26 pounds of alfalfa hay. With the prices herein used this corn and alfalfa hay costs less than the cake which replaces them, yet the lambs getting cake show a higher profit. This is because the lambs getting cake made more pounds gain and brought a higher price when sold. The cheapest gains are not always the most profitable gains — the amount and quality of the gains are even more impoi-tant. COMPARING THE FEEDING VALUE OF COTTONSEED CAKE AND LINSEED CAKE WHEN FED WITH MOLASSES DRY PULP In Table 6 the results from the 3 dry pulp lots are given. Lot 3 was fed a ration of dry pulp and alfalfa hay; in Lot 6 the same ration was fed with the addition of cottonseed cake, and in Lot 9 the dry pulp-alfalfa ration was supple - mented with linseed cake. Here again, and even with a much greater spread than was the case with either corn or barley, cottonseed cake or linseed cake proved to be a profitable feed. A comparison of the corn lots shows that cake increased the average gain per lamb 5 pounds; in the barley lots, the in - crease was 5.3 pounds, while in the dry pulp lots the in - crease was 9.4 pounds. The amount of feed required for the gains made shows that 71 pounds of dry pulp and 22.7 pounds of cottonseed cake in Lot 6, or 73 pounds of dry pulp and 23.2 pounds of linseed cake in Lot 9, had the same feed value as 100 pounds of dry pulp and 51 pounds of alfalfa hay in Lot 3 where no cake was fed. By comparing Lots 6 and 9 it can be shown that 1000 pounds of dry pulp when fed with cottonseed cake had the same feed value as 1013 pounds of dry pulp, 6.6 pounds of linseed cake, and 20 pounds of alfalfa when lin - seed cake is fed with dry pulp. The cost of feed per 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Lamb Feeding Experiments pounds gain was about the same in each case, being the lowest where cottonseed cake was fed. The lambs in Lot 3, where no cake was fed, sold at $15.25 per 100 as compared with $15.50 where either cottonseed cake or linseed cake was fed. In Lot 3 the profit per lamb was $1.24; where cottonseed cake was fed it was $2.05, and where linseed cake was used it was $1.97; or 81 cents per lamb in favor of cottonseed cake and 73 cents in favor of linseed cake. This clearly shows the advisability of supple - menting a dry pulp ration with cake. It is very doubtful if Table 6 — Comparing the feeding value of cottonseed cake and . linseed cake when fed with molasses dry pulp and alfalfa hay. Lot No. . I 3 6 j 9 Number of animals . 80 80 80 Dry pulp Dry pulp ! Linseed Ration . Dry pulp Cot. cake ; cake Alfalfa Alfalfa j Alfalfa. Average gain per lamb ' 24.0 33.7 33.1 Pounds feed per 100 pounds gain: Pulp 422 1 301 • 306 Cottonseed cake ■ - — 96 Linseed cake.--' — I 98 Alfalfa hay , 851 | 632 ; 638 Cost of feed per 100 pounds gain : 9.32 | 9.19 ! 9.33 Initial cost of lamb at $12.65 per cwt._. 6.45 ! 6.45 j 6.45 Additional costs per lamb: Feed : 2.24 3.10 3.09 Interest - — .20 .20 .20 Marketing .' -40 .40 .40 Total cost per lamb 9-29 ; 10.15 10.14 Final weight at feed lot : — i 75.0 84.7 84.1 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha 6.0 ; 6.0 6.0 Selling weight - 69.0 r 78.7 ] 78.1 Selling price per cwt — . 15.25 15.50 15.50 Receipts per lamb _ — i 10.53 i 12.20 12.11 Profit per lamb - 1 .-.-! 1.24 ! 2.05 j 1.97 the comparative prices of cake and dry pulp will ever be far enough apart so that cake would not prove to be a profitable supplement in a dry pulp ration. When figured on the basis of profit per lamb, cottonseed cake would have to cost $100.20 a ton and linseed cake $92.30 when dry pulp costs $22 before it would be unprofitable to feed cake in a dry pulp ration. On the other hand, when cake costs $50 a ton, dry pulp will have to sell as low as $6.52 when fed with cottonseed cake and </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 216 at $8.09 when fed with linseed cake before the cake would cease to be a profitable feed in a ration with dry pulp. There are times when the prices of corn and barley are low enough compared with the price of cake that the addition of cake to the ration would not increase the profit per lamb, which after all is the all-important thing in lamb feeding. But this will hardly happen in the case of dry pulp. As has been shown, when cottonseed cake costs $50 per ton, corn must sell at $1.42 and barley at $1.03 a 100 pounds and dry pulp at $6.52 a ton before the addition of cake in these respec - tive rations would fail to increase the profit per lamb. When cottonseed cake costs only $40 a ton then corn will have to sell at $1.13 and barley at 82 cents a 100 pounds and dry pulp at $5.22 a ton before cottonseed cake would fail to be a profitable feed. COMPARING THE FEEDING VALUE OF CORN SILAGE, BEET TOP SILAGE, BEET TOPS, AND CULL POTATOES WHEN FED IN A RATION OF CORN, COTTONSEED CAKE, AND ALFALFA In this test corn silage, beet top silage, beet tops, and cull potatoes are compared when fed with a ration of corn, cotton - seed cake, and alfalfa hay. The lambs in Lot 10 were fed corn silage; those in Lot 11, beet top silage; those in Lot 12, beet tops; and those in Lot 13, cull potatoes. During the first 2 winters the lambs fed corn silage ranked second in the amount of gain per lamb but the last winter for some unknown reason they fell away below any of the others the gains being only 32 pounds per lamb as against 38 pounds in the other 3 lots. They did well and were appraised within a nickel of the tops. Had not the lambs been weighed 3 times for the initial weight it might be thought that a mistake of 100 pounds was made in the initial weight, but it does not seem probable that such a mistake would have been made each time. The record of the 3 weighings shows only a small variation The error, if any, was not made in the final weight. While the records do not show any error, it does not seem probable that a ration which showed up so well for 2 years would fall so short in the third trial. Also, lambs making so poor gains as these appear to have made would hardly show so good finish; and then again, the feed require - ment per 100 pounds gain shows considerable increase over that of the previous 2 years. By using the first 2 years' results, the corn silage shows a much higher feeding value </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Lamb Feeding Experiments than "when the 3-year average is used. Unless otherwise stated the data here presented are based on the average of the 3 tests. The lambs fed corn silage made an average gain of 36 pounds; those fed beet top silage, 37.2 pounds; those fed beet tops, 37.4 ipounds ; and those fed potatoes, 38.4 pounds. The lambs in Lot 10, using the 3-year average, were fed 282 pounds of corn, 90 pounds of cottonseed cake, 478 pounds Table 7 — Comparing the feeding value of corn silage, beet top silage, beet tops, and potatoes when fed with a ration of corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa. Lot No. ■ 10 I 11 ! 12 13 Number oE lambs 80 CO j 80 80 _ ,. Corn Corn i Com Corn Ration ■ Cot. cake Cot. cake; Cot. cake Cot. cake Cnsilage Bt silage i Beet tops Potatoes Alfalfa Alfalfa | Alfalfa Alfalfa Average -gain per lamb. ... j 36.0 37.2 37.4 I 38.4 Pounds feed per 100 pounds gain: Corn — 282 272 j 270 263 Cottonseed cake . 90 87 I 87 84 Corn silage -- 478 j Beet top silage™ ' 462 Beet tops (per ton of yield) \ i 1.62 Potatoes I '. ! 447 .Alfalfa — - ; i 455 - 476 1455 488 Cost of feed per 100 pounds gain _i 10.48 10.33; 9.95 10.13 Initial cost of lamb at $12.65 cwt | 6.45 6.45 6.45 6.46 Additional costs per lamb: I Peed _ i I 3.77 3.84! 3.72 3.90 Interest : ■ j___j I .20 .20: .20 .20 Marketing , .40 .40 .40 .40 Total cost per lamb : 10.82 10.89 ! 10.77 10.95 Final weight at feed lot :..._ 87 88.2 ! 88.4 89.4 Shrink from feed lot to Omaha. ' 6.0 6.0 i 6.0 6.0 Selling weight :_.. ! 81.0 82.2 ; 82.4 83.4 Selling price per cwt j 15.70 15.65 15.60 15.65 Receipts per Iamb : j 12.72 12.86' 12.85 13.06 Profit per lamb 1.90 . 1.97 • 2.08 2.10 of corn silage, and 455 pounds of alfalfa hay per 100 pounds of gain. By using only the 2-year average it amounts to 261 pounds of corn, 86 pounds of cottonseed cake, 464 pounds of silage, and 392 pounds of alfalfa hay. Those in Lot 11 were fed 272 pounds of corn, 87 pounds of cottonseed cake, 462 pounds of beet top silage, and 476 pounds of alfalfa hay; those in Lot 12, 270 pounds of corn, 87 pounds of cottonseed cake, tops from 1.62 tons of sugar beets, and 455 pounds of </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 216 alfalfa hay; and those in Lot 13, 263 pounds of corn, 84 pounds of cottonseed cake, 447 pounds of potatoes, and 488 pounds of alfalfa hay. By comparing the feed requirement per 100 pounds gain in Lot 4 with those in Lots 10, 11, 12, and 13, the replacement values of corn silage, beet top silage, beet tops, and potatoes are shown in terms of corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay. The replacement values were: One ton of corn silage (3-year average) equaled 17 pounds of corn, 8.5 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 407 pounds of alfalfa hay. One ton of corn silage (2-year average) equaled 108 pounds of corn, 26 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 688 pounds of alfalfa hay. One ton of beet top silage equaled 61 pounds of corn 22 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 329 pounds of alfalfa hay. One ton of potatoes equaled 103 pounds of corn, 36 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 286 pounds of alfalfa hay. The tops from 16 tons of sugar beets equaled 160 pounds ot corn, 50 pounds of cottonseed cake, and 970 pounds of alfalfa hay. Results reported in Bulletin 194 show that when a ration ot corn and alfalfa hay was compared with a ration of corn beet tops, and alfalfa hay, the tops from 16 tons of beets had a feeding value equal to 1 ton of alfalfa hay and 491 pounds of corn. This shows beet tops as having a much higher feeding value than is shown by comparing Lots 4 and U, where cottonseed cake was used in the ration. It appears trom this that beet tops have a higher comparative feeding value when fed without cottonseed cake than when fed with it, altho no direct comparison is available. In the 2 separate experiments reported in Bulletin 194 the lots fed corn, beet tops, and alfalfa hay each returned the highest net profit per lamb of any of the lots in the test. mJx a f , e . c ' corn sila &amp; e w ere appraised at $15.70 per l?LlTt 8 the ,^ P price; the lambs fed beet top silage at $15.65; the ones fed beet tops, at $15.60; and those fed potatoes, at $15.65. The profit per lamb was fl 90 fll those fed corn silage, $1.97 for those fed beet top silage, $2.08 for those fed beet tops, and $2.10 for the ones fed potatoes The potato-fed lambs made the highest profit of any with those fed beet tops second. Using the lambs in Lot 4 which were fed corn, cottonseed cake, and alfalfa hay, as a check the lambs fed corn silage made 7 cents less profit per lamb </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Lamb Feeding Experiments the ones fed beet top silage made the same as those in Lot 4, those fed beet tops made 11 cents more, and those fed pota - toes made 13 cents more profit per lamb. Compared with the prices of the other feeds herein used and based on the profit per lamb, corn silage had a value of $3.14 per ton, beet top silage' $4.00 a ton, beet tops 60 cents per ton yield of beets, and potatoes $5.64 a ton. It would hardly be practical to grow potatoes for feed, but when they are already grown and there is no market for them, as quite often happens, they should be fed rather than left to rot in the cellar and later hauled out and dumped. When they are fed, the expense of sorting and hauling to market and the cost of the sacks are avoided. Every year there are more or less cull potatoes which could be fed to advantage rather than thrown away. The beet tops used in these tests and those siloed yielded about 200 pounds of air-dried matter per ton yield of beets. The silage made from beet tops contained 44 per cent dry matter. On this basis, when comparing Lots 11 and 12 the tops from 1 ton of beets when siloed had the same feeding value as the tops from 1.6 tons of beets not siloed. As to whether it is advisable to silo beet tops rather than to feed them without siloing will depend entirely on the extra expense of siloing. It costs considerably more to silo beet tops than it does corn because it is more difficult to get the beet tops thru the ensilage cutter. With the usual prices of labor and of beet tops. the additional expense of siloing will amount to considerably more than the buying of 60 per cent more beet tops. Unless beet tops can be siloed in a trench silo without the expense of running them thru an ensilage cutter it is very doubtful if siloing is advisable. To. get the most feeding value from beet tops when not siloed, they should be put into small piles soon after the beets are harvested and later hauled to the yards and fed. Pasturing beet tops is not the best practice either from the standpoint of feeding value or from that of the effect on the land. Beet tops vary considerably both in the amount of feed per ton yield of beets and &lt; in the quality of feed. Low land and heavy soil usually produces a larger percentage of tops than upland or lighter soil. The season influences the feed - ing value. If the fall and early winter are ( wet and cold, the beet tops will not cure properly and therefore their feeding value will be lessened. A heavy freeze before the tops are harvested also damages the leaves and lessens their feedintr value - [«, </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>