<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-fifth Biennial Report of the Warden of the State Penitentiary</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Twenty-fifth Biennial Report OP THE Warden OF THE State Penitentiary LINCOLN. NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 434 STATE PENITENTIARY, LINCOLN NEBRASKA OFFICERS OF THE INSTITUTION W. T. Fenton Warden N. T. Harmon Deputy Warden Miss Mixxie Mirphy Matron William Kirby Steward Jamks O'Conxeij Chief Clerk I. C. Mincer, M. D Physician D. G. KA\AXAt(iH Captain of Guards Rev. Thomas A. Maxwell Chaplain Rev. Robert Morax Voluntary Catholic Chaplain C. J. McCarthy Chief Engineer OFFICERS OF THE HANDCRAFT BROOM COMPANY A. T. Johxsox Manager Eii « Mm Steixer Assistant Manager OFFICERS OF THE HANDCRAFT FURNITURE COMPANY L. M. Eastman Manager H. K. Montgomery Assistant Manager and Bookkeeper </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 435 STATE PENITENTIARY, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To lux Excellency, Honorable Keith Xcrille. (ioremor, and to the Honorable Members of the Board of Coin - ininMionern of Mate Institutions, Henri/ denies, SUiih I. II nli in, ill, anil Ktlfieile O. Mili/jiehl (r&lt; nth in fit 1 have the honor of submitting this, the twenty-fifth biennial report of the State Penitentiary for the period be - ginning December 1, 1916, and ending November 30, 1918. Elsewhere you will find complete financial and statistical tables covering transactions of the State Penitentiary for the period covered by this report. During this period we have remodeled the old shop buildings and installed the broom industry on state account, entirely eliminating the contract system. We converted the old gloomy workshop into clean, sanitary work rooms. Machinery was installed and all of the men who were not formerly employed are ijow at work. Our furniture in - dustry has been extended and more room made for the winding department in the brick building which was for - merly a broom shop. The old warehouse building which formerly belonged to the Lee Broom and Duster Company has been purchased, giving us ample storage room for the present time. On the lower floor of the old stone shop building we put in an up-to-date, well-equipped laundry. Our farming operations in the future will be carried on more extensively, as we came into possession last March of the 120 acres purchased. We have leased 240 acres across the road east of the institution, which we are farming this year. However, owing to the continued drought this year, our farm report will not show great profits. I might call your attention, however, tp our report on stock raising, which I think is a very good showing, considering the fact that we were cleaned out by cholera during this biennium. Our auditorium has been painted and decorated, and </seg>
            <seg id="p004">436 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF the dining rooms and cell houses have all undergone a thor - ough cleaning and painting. We put a new Victrola in our inmates' dining hall at a cost of $225.00. It is enjoyed very much by the inmates. It was paid for from the amusement fund which is accumulated each year by giving shows and other entertainments. Two years ago I reported all of the details of the new power plant which at that time was just being completed. During the first six months of the present biennium this new plant gave us some trouble; it was necessary to make a few changes in the line up of the equipment. Since these changes were made the entire plant has given us excellent satisfaction. The plant continues to supply the power for the capitol, governor's mansion. Orthopedic hospital. Ne - braska Home for Dependent Children and Nebraska Hospital for the Insane. During the last six months we have built a new boiler house. This is a modern, brick and steel, fire - proof structure. It was erected over the old building, and the work of putting up the new and tearing down the old was carried on in such a way that the service to the differ - ent institutions was not interrupted. The cost of this build - ing was approximately $14,000.00. Owing to the dry seasons in the past few years we were required to put down a new well and purchase a pump for same. The well is equipped with a Luitweiler double-stroke, non-pulsating pump. It has a capacity of 200 gallons a minute which the well is amply furnishing. The approxi - mate cost of the entire station is $3,000.00. The prison library under the supervision of the State Library Commission receives frequent visits from Miss Nellie Williams who has general supervision of the libraries in all of the state institutions. There are 3,600 carefully selected and classified volumes on the shelves and a complete cata - logue is given each inmate with the privilege of selecting his reading. One of the inmates acts as librarian under the supervision of the chaplain. The present assistant has been in this position eleven months and his record shows that 10,579 volumes have been read in that time; making an average of 961 volumes a month. Of this number 6,064 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 437 were fiction, and 4,515 non-fiction. The character of the reading may be seen by the report for July, 1918. Total i:&lt;4 Thirty magazines are received on regular subscriptions and these all have a wide circulation. It is the purpose to have books read that are of a high character and to keep out such reading as would not be uplifting. Our school during this period has been well attended and under the able supervision of Mr. James O'Connell much has been accomplished in the way of education. The moral atmosphere of the institution is the very best; the religious work having been looked after in an able manner by Rev. Thomas Maxwell and Father Moran, and the several Sunday school teachers who visit our institution every Sunday. Our population has decreased during the present bien - nium by about 25 per cent. The inmates are behaving well, working hard and have saved enough of their earnings to enable them to contribute the following amounts to the support of the war: Subscriptions to Liberty Bonds $3,500.0C Purchase of Thrift Stamps 1.400.0C In addition to this the men of this institution are now providing the funds to care for thirteen French orphans. All of these subscriptions and donations were made cheer - fully; the only regret being that the subscribers were not able to do more to help win the war. In conclusion, I wish to thank my worthy deputy for General works 22 Philosophy 68 Religion 48 Sociology 40 1'hilology Natural science 22 30 I'seful arts 47 Fine arts 32 Literature 55 History 174 Fiction 656 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">438 THIRD BIENNNIAL REPORT OF his assistance in carrying on the important work of the in - stitution. And all my other co-workers, 1 wish to thank for their able assistance during the past two years. I wish to thank the Honorable Board for the assistance and uniform courtesy always extended to me. Very respectfully submitted. W. T. Frntok. Wo nhn. Lincoln, Nebraska. November 30, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 439 BALANCE SHEET HANDCRAFT BROOM COMPANY Resources I Liabilities $50000.00 Capital -'irk IT&lt;|WIWIII Ml . I 2505.86 26044.55 Ul--.4H.fiT Supplies Finisht'd xtoek Accounts rec-ivable !n«litui ion cash . 7834.09 IMU ■ (iain 7347.00 Totals Note — The above balance sheet e»ver- pc nod Irom August. 1917, to November 30, 1918 iciusivr or «ince iho company's incoptic BALANCE SHEET HANDCRAFT FURNITURE COMPANY Resources Liabilities S 52695.94 Capital stock FtiMTgcncy cash Equipment S 200.00 14440.52 20330.58 Supplies 380', .86 5862.35 Finished stock Accounts receivable Bill" receivable 200.00 19782.14 Institution cash Gain 11927.51 $64623.45 * 64623.45 Totals Note— The above balance sheet covers period from June 1, 1917, to November 30, 1918, in elusive. The above gain represents the undistributed K»'n since the company's inception. t 57M7.O0 i 57347.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">440 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS AND CREDITS AND BALANCE OF THE INMATES' CASH FUND December 1. 1916. to December 1, 1918 Notb — Approximate average number of accounts Dec. 1, 1916 to Dec. 1, 1918 was 950 PERIOD Ix-bit-, Credits Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1916 r ■618.42 December, 1916 January, 1917 February, 1917 Mareh, 1917 t 2698.97 UltM 212.V8I 2204.13 MM.M 21WI.IIH S 2966.73 2824.14 2501.93 2276.45 April, 1917 May. 1917 June. 1917 July, 1917.. August, 1917 2671.99 2190.09 2404.93 1834.03 2222.. IK 2484.38 2664.51 2206.30 2708.51 September, 1917 October. 1917 November, 1917 3662.00 4693.42 7962.37 7870.21 6351.07 3409.80 Total for year (39023.12 $39215.00 Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 191 ', $7810.30. Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1917 * 810.30. December, 1917 January, 1918 February. 1918 March, 1918 $2987.35 3193.38 Mtt.ll 3983.72 3837.97 tSM.41 $ 3180.69 2942.18 3320.81 3046.19 April, 1918. May. 1918 June, 1918 July, 1918 August, 1918 3535.52 2B49.96 2531.09 3480.54 2852.30 2809.45 3121.03 2331.50 2475.87 3252.27 2331.34 3985.04 2909.48 September, 1918 October, 1918 November, 1918 2105.95 Total for year $37108.96 $35735.30 Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1918, $6436.64. Grand total for two years $7til32.OK $ 74950.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 441 TABLE SHOWING RECEIPTS IN INSTITUTION CASH FOR B1ENNIUM Beginning November 30, 1! 916, end iing November 3 1 30, 1918 SOURCE For Ye«r ! ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Year ' ending Nov. 30, 1918 Totml lor Biennium Labor: State institutions Handcraft Furniture Co. Handcraft Broom Co Miscellaneous Sale of electricity: Nebraska Hospital for the Insane Orthopedic Hospital Nebraska Home for Dependent Children State House Factories, gross earnings: Handcraft Furniture Co. . Handcraft Broom Co Farm produce Barber shop Photo stand Cigar stand Dininitroom Greenhouse Miscellaneous Hoarders H. R. 720, 1915 Contract labor Interest on Institution Cash Fund $ 2422.2(1 19429.26 3248.57 i (I.Vil.21 1U56.52 55.66 4171.98 74674.77 ' 11365.81 5026.17 131.00 464.75 1495.93 185.10 , 79.75 2515.93 ' 50.52 K556.93 l2.VI.-Jti 338.28 ! t 2757.S7 19179.81 4556.09 1767.26 5228.66 1254.54 Hlti.lMI 2636.94 74190.20 138832.47 IMW.U 83.00 , i.h:i..vi 159 1.1)2 541.90 88.60 1604.45 229.80 683.38 5179.87 38609.07 4556.09 5015.83 11729.87 2311.06 161.66 fiwm.»2 148864.97 150198.28 15615.29 214.00 918.25 3086.95 727.00 168.35 4120.38 280.32 8556.93 4250.26 1021.66 Totata ! (146020.60 (266404.41 I ! $ 412425.01 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">442 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OP INVENTORY OF LANDS, BUILDINGS, FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT AND IMPROVE- MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE November 30, I'll,- Arrv&gt; Acres Uncultivated Cultivated Total Eati- Acra- maud af« Value Garden Farm Orchard (ampu« Waste Land owned by institution :.i m Land rented by institution cashi 111) in 120 19200.00 Land rented by institution shares' . lvi 189 30240.00 Total K2II :l 15 33 $116000.00 ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF Bl'ILDING AND IMPROVEMENT Furniture Equipment Improv Building •mem Total Administration Boiler house KOIl.OO J 600.00 20000 .IN) Brick office Brick shop 100.00 111000.00 12NI6.00 52816.00 Chicken houst Corn cribs 150.00 400.00 150.00 400.00 Cold storage Dairy barn IIHHI.IHI 2800.00 45000.00 25000.00 8000.00 2000.00 150.00 3000.00 2950.00 Dining room and hospital East cell house 400.00 1000.00 400.00 10000.00 10.00 30000.00 16400.00 :I54OO.OO Engine room Garage 38010.00 300.00 1000.00 20.00 320.00 Greenhouse 25.00 1025.00 Ground improvements Handcraft office. . . 33652.00 :»i: 15.00 '• 37277.00 1500.00 600.00 739.00 2239.00 Hay barn Hog house Hog shed Horse barn Ice house 150.00 180.00 750.00 700.00 100.00 1000.00 300.00 500.00 100.00 700.00 700.00 100.00 1180.00 300.00 Implement house Oil house. . 900.00 1400.00 40.00 140.00 Pump house Smokestack Solitary. 3400.00 4100.00 2500.00 1200.00 4000.00 2500.00 1200.00 Stone shop and laundry Wagon shed 6908.00 350.00 10908.00 IINI.INI 450.00 Wall and towers 70000 .IK) 1000.00 25000.00 40.00 70040.00 Warehouse, broomcorn West cell house 1IMHI.0O 30.00 35000.00 10.00 600.00 60030.0 Yard office 100.00 710.00 Total laMsMJt $ 2389.00 $157831.00 $ 3625.00 $ 459995.00 15 23 416 $66560.00 5IHHHI.(NI 13U00.UU 100.00 J M400.00 mwjN </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 443 Mi I sk: 3 k !■ ? in « "3 i£ 51 ?i i !i E E's I 5 lfc ! Rs ;i« r )« ,- : &lt;2 * his t 1 1 ii I! PIS i B 5 " l*s ! ?l I-" " k [ M :iil^ ! hi \\\\k i 3 I JE S ' * ■s i V J &lt; &lt; I h I( i = " I 'las I I " I , =i' 5 H '\m I liMii i 2l N ill ii 1 a </seg>
            <seg id="p012">444 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 445 | %-"&gt;*- *■ : :.- 3 | ■"_-■" 5x£§2 V X (0 O Q M £1 * i §2 %U m « e • i4eg - CMX S C K w r: S-. xxx X -r M r: N - -5 = E :■« C ? : t z 2 ?: o = I * I z ~ $' y I I jj 1.1 5 * S - ! LJ : ': : B ss « i .!»»... r b 2 K i 5 lijJ||«s ;s i is i j i 5 I ?tl I !N«9ie e f$ u. — ■ — I ■ ■ ■ - — . . i . I | * E I i 1 ! I J = MMM! ; 1 J N i N HI J*J!*' 1 ill *V liilj 33=§5. sjj : z liii §*=!s i -i&gt; i 5 i I &lt; -. z 111 JVI* 3 iii Nil : 3 I sseccci I a [ oBJecio | h z </seg>
            <seg id="p014">446 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OP IS«t888SSSSS2SUttiU si * i^ ,1 = £ 33-2333333333-3-33-33 S2!?i -.8 3 X lit * *• is -i [2 b 1 3 I II £ = z 4 -■ 5 E ? i i j h ! ■? lill ' = j-ifMffjiiSiiiltj 1 j t I |ll si5S§gsgggsssssssg§§!§ •••* z = ft J pglS - s§l U 1 "l" s: : 1 ' 1 ! I ' i i . !s§8Si§s§ig3§g§£SiSSs!s li !" " [ft * ! | ! iUiiiiiiiiiaUiUii ! ; </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 447 "S-'li is -4 55 1 2 :" ■ x N 5 : 8 ,- 1 i 11 ■ 1 1 M \\ : * :1 1 : "|1| 5; a i is || : |: 5 j ! . j 8888888888888888888:2 Is ° [&gt; j w nn ■ nn ' g - 3 "!| 55i?S5 — is x d d — -w * ei d ei so ri *ii d ri c= — c i x 6 ' H\l\iiiiiiiiiiii4iaiUii 5 I S t-Q — *Ot- NKNSO **t- O Q O •«&gt;■ — Q X — I S ' «sw» t-c*s rcoireic : S "» M — - M n |l| :*!:::■:• ' :::|:! = pi?|: 8 S::i s ;;2 ? S5T x c ? i -5 :i a -III! u 1* ill 'as | S HS|aj ."»::.::..:::.. : :- . \ - •s- -7: S- PSja lj „ * ig-SSsiSiaiSiiiiiSiS 5 Sfe -o £ S8SSS T] j[ «*" *"" w " S Cs | 2 2 S |' N S - N- " 22 - 5 « : * gS ?j||»~5 " N ~ 22 - 5 " I •i I- E_- SI I 5? 5 :i;;;::::::;;;::;;:; i i 31 ? Ofi c -F i 1 h : : : J f- i : s I i - I 1 h :::::::::::::::::::: : I 3 Ml;;;;::;;;:;;;;;;; : | &lt; I 1 I s 1 j c lb» S8SS8SSSS8SS88SSSSS5!? Z Hi's S8ss8ssgsgsgs.ssss5.si i 2 1^3 s H : w i- '■-■' M js </seg>
            <seg id="p016">448 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF &gt; :i m ?, -* SSI x = ?5 xs« I 5?t- ec Nt-C* ~i si ■si; i •»»- - a sss -- - "jj" II Hit! iUi s ii i Hi &amp;i&amp;i *ii\ SI | SSSS " N 3 S %?.*■ |^SS 3"? 5 i X ii ill! ■ " S .18 H&gt;^ j i ••• - Lk _ .| SSS3 8 SS S I8S igSl? skglg 1 { 2g|s = -s i =£§ gg«5 sissjg ji I ■ |5_ 2 IT] iiaJ i ii i iji £j£j x » = ! II ijggs -"9 8 8g2 §3«S §25. I,! 8SS3 § SS S SS3 8g"58~"SSaiS ,, v ' ' i S • ° £ I i I Jj£i i ii i jji £iai £ii t l ||| 1 1 ss|s - ~5j s ass I5S2 sss ■ I - !«j * »S S '"8 -'"« =5 I : * 1,1 '88$8 8 8S"TT~g ?SS .Sg 13 i I | s 15 ! - a i ■ ;I * * :s» $ a 1 ' ! ' » c til! Hii i ii i ii Ui ii\ I I LJ - ■" ■ " 1 ■ I •s ! * ' -8 •" 8S8 8 • • ■ S~ST8~ * i| i-'4-!-— — — - - 1*- I 1 yjll ; n i &gt;gg i M i i jg 1 1 HlfiilisiliiliiiiibilJ^lilj 5 Si lTii¥Ti HS=? Sill :8 : «9S : Mil I * i 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 449 *- 11 11 * | s 5 5 I &lt;M*i § i i -2 IIJISSIS a 1 !» '•» 5 11 j X *i U^_ | Jill 8 i ! III s i nil 2 { i W¥l\\ • _ ' * - jP -g-\ ; 5 i Bid ■r ; •* •» r&gt;z ' i— r^ -a « i 2 - • 5 gl 1 ! ! * 1 2 * I : :i : | = 5 51 -s r • i? 5 B»i! £ i° a. 3 Iji r| ii ||i jjj hii |1M|] e \\i I : ; ; M ! 1 Oh; ;t O E I ? 8 ?. = : = s is 2 ! : : s | | : : z » I i ii i i ii I : ill J | : § Mill I — U! : &lt; 111 i &lt; — — p-?g I |l*i L z ] |U] „ ! i * = </seg>
            <seg id="p018">(M THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF S s ■ I I l! !! a - £ 5» a - 5 j E 3 ii \ mi riliii P li*l?ih | gs i» "IS J ft H*I"P| II i _ _ i I S l ill I i ijbi »1« 1 ! t j 1 i mi &lt; '-i ■ h 2 fli I I I II &gt;- E 5 s H a - 5 1 &gt; J ji ||ir""h .IMS : ;|P i| i &gt;!^^ !s c S|:|::| 5 1 I ij I ;;■:;: . is -a ■ . s 8 lj-a:i| * ! .1 ss -is ■c e 3 ; t^»o In II ithis;; h ii ' jiiSplll I 3 H 1 i i , s S 8 • • 8 ?SS. i 1 8 S lie' " ■ |z J ■ ■ - ■ ■o 9 .188888 I 8 h] iliUli </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 451 is i S3S S X*M 2 m IS H 1 isd PJ -5 a|iji"a ; z^ a* 3 ■ £ g-5 ■5|2S! T &gt; : *« |i i$ 8 5 0 x -&gt; ! z^ i a s » * ** I |S g | i ii |ii|«s«i s i : :i * - iz-° i h - ■?; » B« z^ : "-s i^i 2 :§ _ 2 5 j h;: i gi: il^ t a 5 ? ? ? P T. * u : : : : y &gt; I : : : : P E -i 71 u &gt; &lt; J 7 z &lt; z 5 z 5 &lt; i 2 I I &gt; -' 1 : 5 iUr I 41 1 in i^^sl DM V|i&gt;k </seg>
            <seg id="p020">452 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF ii U 1&gt; •3- *■*- t !sfe tfi Z Z^ ?t - S x ■J.I i. i- 5 I &gt;- X t- Sf- II i k -s- ? z- £ &lt; J fl-B I i 22552 S 8 | §| - ""!» 5 1« c in i|i i. ft-S-a! ?|STf: •» •» j«l| f|i«:!|! Ic i Sj. I 3 » -igS la x2 I 311 3il i &gt; * ■ is II !i| a;sa - t- 12 I H liili a * 55s5s S I! &gt; * s § Lu jIS is£&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 453 'including those previously incarcerated in this or other prison: MOVEMENT For Year , For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, I Nov. 30, for 191? 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. On hand orginning of period Admitted: •For first time Readmitted Returned parole or furlough Returned escaped 395 2 397; 395 2 397 239 2 241 139 2 141 S78 4 382 35 36 17 17 52 ... 52 14 14 16 . ... 16 Hi SO . . 1... 2 3 3 I... I Total recovered .686 4 6891 175 2 177 860 6 866 Released: Escaped Discharged at expiration of sentence Died Order of court Transferred . . Paroled, furloughed, or deported during period 5 5 4. ... 4 •.. 9 28 28 34 1 35 62 1 63 2 2. 5 . 5 7. ... 7 .. 3. ... 3, 5 5 8. ... 8 8 8 5 1 6 IS 1 14 267 2 269 203 203: 470 2 472 Total released 313 2 315 256 2 258J 669 4 573 Remaining at end of period Average population 2H1 2 293 158 2 360 it IUMMI I ItU AGE For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. — — 16 and under 18 18 mnd under 21 2 1 and under 25 . 25 and under 30 30 and under 35 :15 and under 40 40 and under 45. . 45 and under 50 50 and under 55 55 and under 60 60 and under 65 65 and under TO 70 and over Unknown .v 12 12 14 14 26 26 46 46 29 1 30 75 1 76 65 1 66 28 28 93 1 94 55 1 56 32 32 87 1 88 42 42 22 1 23 64 1 65 14 14 10 10 24 24 14 14 8 8 22 ... 22 7 7 5 5 It 12 6 6 S S i. ... 9 9 9 4. ... 4 IS IS 2 2 I.... 2 1 1 1 .. .. 1 "i'.'.'.'.'i "i'.'.'.!"i '"t.'.'.'.'i i Totala I 274 2 276 156 2 15(1 430 4 4S4 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">454 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE HI -RACE OF THOSE COMMITTED TABLE IV EDUCATION OF THOSE COMMITTED TABLE V -CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE COMMITTED RACE For Yemr For Ye»r ending ending Total Nov. SO, ; Nov. 30. (or 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. ■Mm Nejro [ndl.n 247 1 248 13S 2 138 383 3 386 26 1 27 18 18 44 1 46 1 1 2 2 3 S TotaU 274 2 276 156 2 168 430 4 484 EDUCATION For Year | For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. W Primary 'ommon school High school or university Totals 23 23 ». ... 9 32 32 26 26 12. 12; 38 38 189 2 191 108 11091297 8 300 31 31 24 1 251 55 1 56 5 5 3 31 8 S 274 2 276 156 2 168 430 4 484 CIVIL STATUS For Year I For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, ' Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 ; Biennium ■ — M. F. T. I If. F. T. I M. F. T. Single Married Widowed Divorced TotmU 1S4 ... 1U 102.. . . 102| 266 ... 266 87 S7 47 1 48 1S4 11» 11 1 12 4 .... 4 15 1 16 12 1 IS 3 1 4 IS 2 17 274 2 276 166 2 1S8 430 4 4*4 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 455 Totals 274 2 276 156 2 158J 430 4 434 NATIVITY For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 3U, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 ' Biennium M. r. T. i M. F. T. | M. T. T. nited States: Alabama AffcMMM California Colorado (ieurgia Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas . . Kentucky Louisiana M ichigan . . Massachusetts Minnesota Missouri M ississinpi Nebraska New Hampshire New Jersey New York . ... Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania South Dakota. . . ... Tennessee Texas Virginia West Virginia Wisconsin Washington Wyoming ... . Ne* Mexico 1 1 1 .... I 2 2 2 2 4.4 3 3 2 2 5.5 7 7 5 5j 11.... 12 1 111 18 1H 11 11 29 29 4 4 2 2 6 6 14 14 11 11 25 25 14 14 8 8 22. . 22 2 2 2 2 4 4 2 2 2 2 4 4 1 15 5 :&gt; 3 3.3 2 -1 2 2 -•:&gt; -'&lt; 14 14 43 43 4 4 1 15 5 T2 I 73 47 2 48 IIS 3 122 II 11 1 111 5 5 5 5 10 10 8 8 2 2 10 10 :l 3 6 6 9 9 1 1 1 1 6 . 6 5 Si 11 U 3 3 1 ... 1 4 4 3 . 3 3 3 7 7, 3 . .. 3 10 10 2 &gt; 1 1 :l i 4 . 4 ! 1 1 r, 5 ... 2 2, 2 . 2 1 1) 1. 1 Total native born . 2*7 2 229 ! 132 2 134 (59 4 363 &gt;ther countries: Australia Austria Bohemia . Cuba Canada Denmark . . England France Germany Greece Holland Ireland Italy Mexico Norway Porto Rico Koumania Russia Sweden Scotland Syria I'nknown | ...... 1 li 1 1 I.... 2 3 Si 1 . 1 4. .. . 4 ... 2 . 2! 2 . 2 1 ... l! 1 ... 1 8.... 3 3 ... S 2.... 2 2.... 2 1.... 1 I.... 1 "i.'.'.'.'i ' i'.'.'.'.'i " i.'.'.'.'"i 4.... 4 4.... * 1.... 1 I.... 1 3.... S S.... 3 1 .... 1 2... 2 I.... I 12 12 11 ... 11 23. 23 1.... 1 1.... 1 1... 1 I.... 1 1. ... 1 1 ... 1 4.... 4 4.... 4 2 2 2 ... . 2 4... 4 1 ... 1 1. . 1 Total foreign born 47.... 47 71.... 71 118.. ■ 118 11* </seg>
            <seg id="p024">456 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF ( TABLE VII-PHYS1CAL AND MENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total [,ir CONDITION AT COMMITMENT Biennium M. F. T M T T M. F T 'lenrral health Sound 230 1 231 ; 120 2 122 350 3 353 Diseased 44 1 IS :lti M 81 Mental state: Sane Feeble minded Insane 265 2 267 150 2 152 415 4 419 3 HI 111 :l :i :! Diseased General diseases Syphilis It .... 12 1 1 i,\ Diseases of the nerve system . Diseases of circulatory sysieni Diseases of respiratory' system 1 1 1 1 16 Diseases of digestive system 3 1 4 \1 \Z 1 "t Diseases of genito-urinary system 14 14 25 1 26 39 1 40 Asthma I Hernia 23 23 lil 111 V2 V2 Defects, injuries, amputations Arm 1 Hand I 1 1 3 ... 3 &gt;."* I I Blind, both ajm I. ... 1 1 1 Blind, one eye i. ... 3 :i Deaf, one ear 1... 1 Deaf, both ears 1 ' 1 Kpileptics 1. ... 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE BOARD OP COMMISSIONERS 457 Totals 274 2 276 156 2 158 4t0 4 434 TABLE VIII PREVIOUS OCCl OCCUPATION For Year ending Nov. 30. For Year ending Total Nov. 30, for 1918 Biennium j M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Artist Barber Bell hop Rutrher Bookkeeper Blacksmith . . . I'.Ut i T Baker Cook Clerk Cigar maker Cleaner Carpenter Cement worker Chauffeur Cabinet maker . . Doctor Dancing Engineer Electrician ... Farmer Fireman. . . House work Laborer Lumberman . . Lineman Laundryman Lather Miner . . Machinist Musician Motion picture operator Merchant Nurse Porter Painter Plaster Plumber Printer Rancher Drug maker Salesman Shoe maker Stockman Structural iron worker Steam fitter Teamster Tinner Teacher Tailor Waller 1 1 2 2 1 1 4 4 2 . 2 5. . &amp; 1 1 2 2 14 II 4 I 1 1 2. ... 2 3 3 6 6 1 1 I 2. ... 2 59 1 60 7 . T 1 1| *!::: 71 2 2 2 2 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 1 1 12 12 1 1 3 3 2. ... 2 »... 2 ».... 3 6. ... 6 1 1 2. ... 2 6 6 3 3 1 1 9 • ».... S ».... 3 2.. . . 2 4 4 9 9 2. ... 2 ::::::::: s : : s *.... 4 1 ... 1 2. ... 2 4 4 5 :» 1 ... I ».... 5 1... 1 3. S 5 5 1 1 2 2 14 4 . 4 18 18 5 5 ».... 9 1 1 1 1 1. .. . 1 ».... 3 5 5 3 3 6 6 3 :l !&gt; 9 2 2 2 . 2 2 2l 2 2 ; l . l 2 2 I... 2 1 1 3 ... t 46 461 105 1 106 2 1 2 2l 3 3 41 41 112 112 111 1 I 1 3 3 2 2 II 1 ... 1 I.... I 8 8 20 SO 1 ... t S. ... 3 1 1 3 S 1 1 3 . . . S 1 1 4 4 1 1 7 7 1.... 1 3 . 3 * ... 5 1 . . .. 1 7 .... 7 «... S 1.... 1 ». ... I 1 1 4 . ... 4 ».... 3 «.... 6 2. ... 2 1 1 t ... 6 2 2 11 11 2.... t 2. ... 2 2. ... t 1 . I 4 .... 4 4. ... 4 ».... 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">458 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE IX RELIGIOUS PREFERENCE OF THOSE COMMITTED TABLE X NUMBER OF CONVICTIONS OF THOSE COMMITTED RELIGION For Year For Year vnding ending Total Nov. 30, : Nov. 30, (or 1917 1918 I Biennium Protestant . alh.ilip Hebrew Creek Sot reported M. F. T. M F. T. ', M. F. T. 171 2 173 88 1 89! 259 3 262 76 76 41 41 117 117 1 1 4 4 5 S : ... i ii i 26 26 22 1 23, 48 1 49 274 2 276! 156 2 158! 430 4 434 CONVICTION For Ye»r For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30. for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. j M. F. T. | M. F. T. Fir.-' Second Third Fourth Fifth Sixth Industrial school i 242 2 2441 138 2 140 380 4 384 26 26 17 . 17 43 43 2 2 I.. 1 3 S "i.'.'.'.'i a 4 Totals ! 274 2 2761156 2 158 430 4 434 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 459 I ABLt XI — IU l Admra. Antelope ... Arthur Banner Boone Box Butte Buffalo Burt Butler Boyd Brown Clay Ca»a Colfax Custer Cheyenne . . Cherry Cumins Dakota Dodge Douglas Dawson .... Dixon Dundy Dawes Deuel Furna« Garneld Garden Greeley Gat« Grant Hall Hamilton .... Holt Howard .... Harl.n Jefferson . . Johnson Keya Paha Kearney Keith Knox Kim ball Lancaster Lincoln Logan Merrill Madison Nemahm Nuckolls . . Otoe Pawnee Plane Phelp. Pierce Perkins Richardson . Red Willow . Saline Seward Sioux Scot u Bluff Saunders Sheridan Stan ton COUNTY For Year ending Nov. SO, 1917 M. F. T. 5... 6 . "t.'.'.'.'"t ' "i.'.'.'.'i 8 8 5 5 1. . 1 1 1 1 1 . I.... 1 . ».... S . «.... 4 I.... S . 4 4 1 1 . 1. . . . 1 " r '.'. '. " l . 10 10 100 1 101 *.... 4 1. ... 1 1 . ... 1 2 2 2 2 2 ... . 2 1 ".'.'. 1 1. ... 1 2 .... 2 "u.'.'.'."ik 4 4 1 1 ».... 2 1 .... 1 . t .... 2 2.... 2 7. ... 7. ...^. ....... l... i '"i.'.'.'.'i 2.... 2 1 ... . 1 ».... a . "».'.'.. "i . i.... i. 7 T 4 1 S 1... 1 . 1 .... 1 . For Year ending Total Nov. 30, (or 1918 Biennium II. F. T. M. F. ~t7 5.... 6 i i t si 4 l... i l . . l 1 1 4 4 4 . . 4 «... It 4.... 4 9.... • ..... 5 «... 6 1 1 1 1 1. ... 1 S.. . S 2.. .. 2 «... . « ».... S ..*::: ... 4 ?::: " ' i '.'.'.'.'" i i. '.'.'. i i.... i 4 4 14 14 52 52 152 1 1SS I.... S 7 . . 7 ■"i!!!!"'. a.'.'.', t a.... 2 *.... « 2... t "t.'.'.'.'i 2.'.'.'. 2 I.... S 4.. 4 ■■'i!;;;""'i »:::: • i i i .... i 4 1 5 26 1 27 2 2 6 ... « ■"§::;;■■■• •:::: s i i i .... i I.... 1 2 .... t 1 .... 1 S .... &lt; 1 1 i i ».::: » I.... 2 *.... 4 ».... s s . ... s t .... s ».... t •-... • 21 21 T. ... 7 1 .... 1 1... 1 ... r :::... t ?:::: I i ... i i ... i i. . i i.... i t. ... X I. ... t I.... 2 4... 4 1 .... 1 «... t &gt;.... X X.... X «.... 4 4 ... 4 1 .... 1 I.... 1 2 .... X 11... 11 '"».'.'.'." 'M t.'.'.'. 1 X.... X "'t!!!!'"i »'.'.'.'. t X .... X « 1 7 1.... 1 I.... 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">460 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XI!— CRIME FOR WHICH COMMITTED COUNTY For Year ending Nov. SO. 1917 For Year ending Nov. 30. 1918 Total (or Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. i M. F. T. Sherman Thurston . Thomas Vallsy Washington Wayne York i. . . 2 2 1 1 \ "i;;:: i i... i : ■■'«■.:::"« 5 5 " i l 1 i 2 2, 7. . 1 : l.'... : 2 ! 1 4.. 7 1 1 1 ■-• 1 J Total. Is .274 2 276 ! 156 2 158. i 430 4 43 II CRIME For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30. Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium AbbettinK felon* Assault to wound Assault to injure Assault to rob Assault to kill Assault to rape Arson ... Auto stealing Burglary Breaking and entering Bigamy Carrying concealed weapons Cattle stealing Embezzlement Forgery Grand larceny Gambling Hog stealing Highway robbery Incest Intent to defraud by forgery Larceny as bailee Cheek "No Funds" Larceny from person Manslaughter Murder Obtaining money under false pretenses . Rape Receiving stolen property Sodomy Shooting to kill Selling mortgaged property Statutory rape Sedition. Unlawful possession of liquor Wife desertion Totals M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 1.... 1 1 1 6 I .... 5 5 5.... S 5 . 5 4 4 2 2 6 6 ».... 3 1. . 1 4... 4 4 4 7 7 11.... 11 1 . 1 1 1 2 2 5 5 12 1 13 17 1 18 29 29 U. ... 10 39 39 26 26 13 13 39 39 2 . . 2i I . . . . 2 3. 3 3 3 66 6 ... 6; 6 6 2 2 2 2J 4 4 35 35 21 21 56 5C 45 45 24 21 &gt;.'• «:■ 1 1 1 1 10 10 9 1 10 19 1 20 . . 22 22 7 . . . . 7 29 2» 3 3 4. ... 4 7. ... 7 l . i: i.... l I.... 1 1... 1 2 . . . 2 1 . .. . 1 I.... 3 4 .... 4 ... 16 1 17 2 2 18 1 19 7 1 8 5 5 12 1 13 ... 10... 10 10 ... 10 20.. . 2U 6... . 6 6.... 6 ... 10. . 10 1 . ... 1 11.... 11 3 .... S 2 . . 2 5... 5 I.... 2 1 1 3 . . 3 1 .. . 1 3. 3 4 .. . 4 1 .... 1 1 . .. . 1 2 2 5 5 1 1 6 « 2... 2 2 . . 2 1... . 1 1 ... 1 *.... 4 1 ... 1 ».... 5 j 274 2 2761 156 2 158 430 4 434 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 461 TABLE XIII TERM OF SENTENCE OF THOSE CONVICTED TABLE XIV DURATION OF IMPRISONMENT OF THOSE DISCHARGED AND PAROLED DURING BIENNIUM TERM Death Life 25 years 20 years 1 5 years 12 years. 10 yearn . 7 years 6 years 5 years . . . 4 years 1 years 2 years 1 year 6 months 6 months. In 10 months 12 months to 15 months 12 months to 13 months. . 12 months to 18 months 18 months to 24 months 1 to 2 years 1 to 3 years 1 to 4 years 1 to 5 years 1 to 7 years 1 to 8 yean 1 to 1 0 years 1 to 20 years 2 to ' 5 years 2 to 3 years 3 to 4 years 3 to 8 vears 3 to 1 5 years 3 to 20 years 12 to 15 years Totals For Year i For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, | Nov. SO, lor 1»17 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. H. F. T. I.... 2 «.... X 6 6 §.... S 11 11 1 1 1 ... 1 5 6 6 « 11 ... 11 4 4 I... . 1 i. ... 6 2 . t x. ... t 4... 4 1 1 %.... 5 1... 1 1... 1 1... 1 1. ... 1 i i i .. .. i r 2 i i i i 7 7 1 .. . . 1 ».... 8 1 1 I.... 1 t .... * 20 1 21 11 11 SI 1 32 1 1 2 ... 2 «... . t 1. . . 1 1. ... 1 3 t .. I... 3 i 'ii:::::::::::: ■■■.::::"■, i . i i i 22 22 7 7 29 29 24 24 8 8 32 32 4 4 1 1 5 6 19 19 15 1 16 34 1 35 50 50 32 133 82 183 1 1 I. . .. 1 I.... 2 46 1 47 SO SO 76 1 77 22 22 17 17 S» S» 7 7 7 7 14 . 14 1. ... 1 1. ... 1 2 2 r ... 2 4 4 I.... X t. ... « ! 10 10 3 1 IS IS 2 2 2 2 __1 li 1 1 274 2 276 156 2 158 430 4 434 DURATION OF IMPRISONMENT Leas than 6 months 6 months to 12 months 12 months to 18 months 1 8 months to 2 years 2 ye»r» to 3 years 3 years to 5 vears 5 years to 10 years Totals For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30. tor 1917 1918 Minimum M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 16 16 12 12 28 28 167 167 139 1 140 306 1 307 51 1 S2I 43 43 94 1 95 28 1 29i 23 23 51 1 52 19 19 16 16 34 . 34 13 13 13 13 26 26 3 3 12 It II. ... IS 297 2 299 257 1 258 554 3 567 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">462 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XV— CHARACTER OF PARENTAGE OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year ! For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30. Nov. 30, Biennium PARENTAGE M. F. T. M F. T. ! M. F. T. Both parents dead Father dead 83. 83 47 47 130 130 64 . .. 64 36 36 100 100 Mother dead 46 1 47 26 1 271 72 2 74 Both parents living Unknown 79 1 80 45 1 46 124 2 126 2 2 . ... t\ 4.... 4 Totals 274 2 276 1S6 2 158| 430 4 434 TABLE XVI CAUSE OF DEATH For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for CAUSE 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M F. T. M. F. T. Tuberculosis ■1 Pneumonia, lobar Influenza-pneumonia Septic-pneumonia . . 1... 1 1... 1 ■_' 1 l| 1 ... 1 1 li 1 1 Influenza-gastro-intenstinal complication TABLE XVII ACE AT DEATH For Year ! For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for ACE 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. I M. F. T. I M. F. T. 28 years 49 years I.... 1 I... 1 I 1. ... 1 1... 1 31 years. . 33 years.. 46 years. . 26 years. . ».... 1 1... 1 1.... 1 1 .... 1 1.... 1 1... 1 1... 1 1... 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 463 TABLE XVIII -DISCIPLINARY REPORT FOR BIENNIUM For Year ending Nov. SO. For Year ending Total DISCIPLINARY MEASURE Nov. 30, (or Biennium 1917 1918 M. F. T M. F. T. M. F. T. Number of prisoners reported for bad conduct 180 180 388 S88 166 166 29 29 62 62 162 ltt 313 318 76 76 59 59 126 126 84* 342 701 701 242 242 88 88 188 188 Number of reports for bad conduct Number of times reprimanded and excused Number of Sunday privileges taken Number of other privilege:* taken Number of prisoners committed to solitary con - finement once. 27 27 19 19 46 46 Number of prisoners committed to solitary con - finement twice 5 5 6 6 11 11 Number of prisoners committed to solitary con - finement thrice . . 1 1 10 10 11 11 Number of prisoners committed to solitary con - finement four times 1 1 3 3 4 4 1 1 Number of prisoners committed to solitary con - finement more than 4 times 1 1 30 SO Number of prisoners deadlocked in cell 47 471 Total number of days in solitary confinement Total number of days good time lost 63) 115 461 IM 525 i 295 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>