<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biographies of Members State Board of Agriculture of Nebraska</title>
               <date value=""/>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Biographies of Members State Board of Agriculture of Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p002">JOSEPH ROBERTS Joseph Roberts is a native of Great Britian. He was born in County Cornwall in 1865. He went to school there till he was fourteen years old. At that age, when a mere boy, he availed himself of an opportunity to come to America. He came to Warren, 111. Here continued as best he could, his efforts to get an education. He went to school in the winter and worked on a farm in the summer time. In 1881 he came to Nebraska. He bought a farm five miles west of Hooper which he cultivated during the following two years. The four succeeding years he traveled through the west, as far as the Pacific coast, as agent for Mark M. Coad's Percheron horse breeding establishment. Soon after quitting this he purchased a farm now owned by him about four miles east of Fremont. In 1893 he was married to Miss Emma Hicks, since which time they have lived on the farm in one of the handsomest and best -kept homes in the country. Mr. Roberts has served in public positions, in which he has acquitted himself with credit. He was treasurer of Elkhorn Township three years. He has been a member of the county board of Supervisors for a number of years. When the county supervisors organized as a state association he was chosen its secretary to which position he has been twice re-elected. He was twice elected as the representative from Dodge county to the State Legislature. He was elected a member of the Ne - braska State Board of Agriculture in 1904. In 1905 he served as super - intendent of machinery. He has served as first and second vice presi - dent and two terms as president of the State Board of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">J. A. Ollis was bom in Hancock county, Illinois, Oct. 12, 1869. His whole life, with the exception of two years, in which he taught school, has been spent on the farm. In the spring of 1883 he moved to Valley county and moved upon a farm in Mira Valley. During his 24 years in Nebraska he has five times been elected as a member of the County Board of Supervisors and as representative to the State Legislature in 1900, 1901 and 1911, and to the State Senate in 1913. He was secretary of the Loup Valley Agricultural Society for many years. In 1880 he was married to Sarah G. Kerr and the result of this union is three boys and five girls. In 1896 his wife died and in 1905 he was again married to Elizabeth E. Knott. He was elected as a mem - ber of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture from Valley county in January, 1906, and has served on the board of managers and as second and first vice president. He has been active in the interest of pure bred live stock and is president of the Improved Live Stock Breeders. B. M. WOLCOTT R. M. Wolcott was born in Lafayette County, Wisconsin, April 2, 1859. His parents moved from the Wisconsin farm in the fall of 1861 to western Iowa, where he received an education at the country schools, working on the farm in summer as soon as he was large enough. He came to Nebraska in the spring of 1880 and located on a farm in Mer - rick county, devoting himself to farming and stock raising. He has a large farm in the beautiful Loup River valley. He has been a very suc - cessful exhibitor in the Horse, Cattle and Swine departments at the Nebraska, Illinois, Minnesota and Wisconsin State Fairs, also at the Trans-Mississippi Exposition of which he has the premium ribbons and medals to show. tHe was married July 30, 1903, in Merrick County, Nebraska, to la Adams, and of this union one daughter was born. His wife died ebruary, 1909. On July 17, 1913, he was again married to Evangeline mell of New York City. He was elected a member of the State Board of Agriculture in 1903 to fill a vacancy, and was re-elected in 1904-6-8-10-12-14. Was ap - pointed Superintendent Class D Sheep in 1902-3-4-5-6-7-8, and Superin - tendent of Mercantile Hall in 1909, Superintendent of Automobile Hall in 1910, Superintendent of Class A Horses in 1911-12-13, and was elected Second Vice-President of the State Board of Agriculture in 1914, and </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">William R. Mellor was born June 16, 1860, in a log cabin on a farm in Porter county, Indiana, five miles southwest of Michigan City, where he resided prior to and during the Civil War. After his father returned from the war in 1865 the family moved to Lowell, Massachusetts, re - turning to Michigan City, Indiana, in April, 1867. Here he received a common school education. After leaving school he became a clerk in a dry goods store, which position he held for ten years. In 1882 he became a traveling salesman. October 16, 1883, he was married to Miss Ammie Pyke and in 1885 they moved to Nebraska, residing in Omaha for three months then located at Loup City in June, 1885, where they have resided. They homesteaded on a quarter section of land one mile northeast from the court house at Loup City, living upon said homestead for five years. Mrs. Mellor died in 1913. In 1889 he formed a partnership with J. R. Scott in the real estate and loan business and in 1894 was ad - mitted to the bar. Was elected a member of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture in 1898. Early in the spring of 1900 after the Fair was lo - cated at Lincoln, was appointed a member of the board of managers to fill the vacancy caused by the death of Austin Humphrey in which capacity he served said board during the years 1900, 1901, 1902 and 1903. At the January meeting 1904 was elected president of the board and re - elected in 1905. At the winter meeting of the year 1906 was elected its secretary, which position he now holds. On Sept. 29, 1914, he was married a second time to Marietta Parrish of Lincoln. At the present time he is also the president of the American Association of Fairs and Expositions. GEORGE F. DICKMAN George F. Dickman was born in Cambridge, Massachusetts, Novem - ber 10, 1854, where he received a public school education. His young manhood was spent in commercial life in Boston. On the 19th day of March, A. D. 1879, he was united in marriage to Miss Florence B. Kemp. On January 2, 1883, they came to Nebraska and settled at Seward where the well known firm of "The Babson-Dickman Implement Company" was formed and he has been connected with this organization contin - uously since. Mr. Dickman acted in the capacity of speed clerk at the State Fair held in 1884. He was appointed a member of the Nebraska State Board of Agri - culture to fill the unexpired term of Edmund Mclntyre on Dec. 26, 1906, and elected as a member in January, 1906. He has served continuously since that time and for many years has been treasurer. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">_ i A \* </seg>
            <seg id="p008">GEORGE W. JACKSON George W. Jackson was born in Illinois, April 11, 1858. The earlier yean of his life was spent attending public school and working on the farm. Later he took the western fever and went to the mountains and St several years freighting and driving stage. After returning from mountains he was married to Miss Cora Hoskins, of Illinois, in the • 1886, to which union five children were born, two of whom are liv - one boy and one girl — Earl and Winnie. Both graduate from the State University in 1916. Shortly after he was married he came to Nebraska and settled on a farm in Gage county. After farming in Gage county six years, he purchased a farm in Nuckolls county and moved there in the spring of 1892. He established one of the best herds Ioland China hogs in the state, and was the first to establish the sale sm of disposing of stock in the South Platte territory, shipping to let every state in the union. He was twice elected county clerk, twice elected to the legislature. He was chosen speaker in the 1915 ion. He has been secretary of the Nuckolls County Agriculture So - f since 1905. He was elected a member of the State Board of Agri - ire in 1911, and was appointed Chairman of the Board of Managers WILLIAM JAMES William James came to Nebraska with his parents at the age of four and was reared on his father's homestead in Saline county. He has been closely identified with farming all of his life and has had every opportunity of acquiring a thorough training in the practical side of agriculture by reason of having been engaged in farming from child - hood and going through the blizzards, drouths, and grasshopper periods that tried the hearts of the farmers in the early days. While a boy in his teens, Mr. James was asked by officials of the Burlington Railroad to secure for them a large assortment of the prod - ucts of Nebraska which they wished to send throughout the Eastern States in order to attract settlers. Mr. James furnished them with a comprehensive exhibit which was perhaps the first display of this character that was ever sent out of the state. All of these products were raised on his own farm, he even in those early days having been impressed with the necessity of diversification. He canvassed the entire state and personally selected the products that composed most of the Nebraska exhibits at the St Louis World's Fair and was elected Assistant Superintendent of the exhibit and re - mained with it during the entire fair and saw that the several hundred individual prizes won by Nebraska farmers were distributed to them throughout the state. He was appointed Superintendent of the Nebraska Exhibit at the Portland, Oregon, Exposition, and carried off numerous prizes with an exhibit that elicited the warmest praises from those who saw it In 1906 he was elected a member of the State Board of Agri - culture and appointed Superintendent of Agricultural Products at the Scate Fair which latter position he held until last year when he became a member of the Board of Managers. He was actively associated with the management of the two National Corn Expositions held at Omaha. Mr. James has collected what is perhaps the largest and most complete collection of grasses in the world. Mr. James was engaged by the Chi - cago and Northwestern Railroad to introduce and popularize alfalfa along their line of road and during the past few years his services have been in demand by various agencies in the Southern States with whom he is co-operating in bringing about a diversified system of farming. He is the owner of a large farm in Saline county. </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">Jf. F. McARDLE J. F. McArdle is a native of Douglas County, where he was born on a farm in McArdle township. He lived on his farm until three years ago, when he became secretary of the Farmers' Mutual Insurance Com - pany with headquarters in South Omaha. He has served as secretary of the Douglas county fair and has been a consistent booster for im - proved methods of farming and stock breeding. LESLIE W. LEONARD Leslie W. Leonard was born in Fremont, 111., May 18, 1849. He attended country school a part of the time until he was 13 years of age and a private graded school for about 12 weeks when he was 16 years old. A portion of his time was occupied by working for the surround - ing neighbors and more extensively for a stock shipper named Fisher who placed considerable responsibility on young Leonard in allowing him to purchase and ship large number of hogs and cattle. In the winter of 1873-1874 Mr. Leonard took a contract to haul saw logs from 80 acres of heavy timber to the saw mill, from this contract he made enough money to make a first payment on a sixty-acre farm near his home place, on which he resided until 1884, when he sold out and came to Pawnee county, Nebraska, locating two miles east of Pawnee City. This farm he has since sold and is now residing seven miles west of that place on one of the best stock farms of that county. Mr. Leonard enjoys the distinction of bringing the first registered Poland China hogs to Paw - nee county and has been an extensive breeder of pedigreed stock all during his residence in Nebraska. In 1872 he was married to Miss Ada Malone to which union was born three children. His wife died in 1881 and he has never re-married. Mr. Leonard is quite a noted auctioneer on account of his general know - ledge of the excellent qualities in live stock. He was elected a member of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture in 1905 and has served continuously since that time. </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">PETER YOUNGERS Peter Youngers came as a Christmas present to his parents while residing at Milford, Pike county, Penn., on December 25th, 1852. In 1854 the family moved to New York City where he received a common school education, and was afterwards engaged as an office boy at No. 5 Wall street. His family came to Nebraska and settled in Fillmore county, May 11th, 1871. In 1874 Mr. Youngers took a homestead south of Exeter which he still owns. Here he started the Exeter Nursery in 1878. On Nov. 29th, 1879, he was married to Miss Marilla Nicholson, of Lincoln, to which union have been born three girls. In 1886 he located at Geneva, and in 1889 formed a partnership with Mr. W. J. Brown under the firm name of Youngers &amp; Co., which firm is now one of the largest nurseries in the state. Mr. Youngers was elected a member of the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture in 1898 and has served on the Board of Managers from January, 1899, until 1906, when he was elected president, and served two terms. He was a member of the board of managers until 1915. He has been treasurer of the state horticultural society since 1888. VINCENT ARNOLD Vincent Arnold was born at Muncie, Ind., February 16, 1861. His family removed to Shell Rock, Iowa, in 1867. In 1870 they came to Falls City, Richardson county, Nebr. In 1874 he settled on the farm near Verdon, where he still resides. He was married to Dora A. Kinney of Salem, Nebr., on March 29, 1887. To this union were born three chil - dren, one boy and two girls, all of whom are still living. In politics he has always been a Republican and has served nine terms as assessor of his home precinct. He has been prominent in the work of the Congregational Church of Verdon, Nebr., for more than thirty years. He filled important positions in the Richardson County Agricultural Society for a number of years, serving four years as sec - etary and two years as president In January, 1902, he was elected a member of the State Board of Agriculture, in which position he has served continuously ever since. During his period of service he has served one term as Second Vice-president of the Board; three terms as Superintendent of Camping Grounds; one term as Assistant Superin - tendent of Swine; one term as Assistant Superintendent of the Agri - cultural Hall; one term as Superintendent of Dairy; and two terms as Judge of County Collective Exhibits. </seg>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014">W. C. CALEY W. C. Caley was born at Stockport, New York, September 10, 1854. He came west when a small boy and located in Iowa where he received his early education and taught school for a period of six years. On June 12th, 1875, he married Miss Allie J. Wilson, at Waterloo, Iowa, and to them have been born four boys and one girl. They removed to Creighton, Knox county, in 1882, where he has been engaged in farming and stock raising and the real estate business. He was president of the Knox County Agricultural Society for many years, and this society has enjoyed continuous prosperity. He was elected a member of the Nebraska State Board of Agri - culture in 1903, appointed to fill the vacancy caused by the death of Robert W. Furnas in 1905 and again in 1905. He served as second vice president of the board in 1903 and 1904 and has been a member since that time. W. W. COLE Willis Woodington Cole was bom in Bradfoot, Pa., September 14, 1859. Born and brought up on a farm, his father owning a large tract of land alon; the Susquehanna River. Here he attended school in his youth and finished his early education at the Susquehanna Collegiate Institute at Towanda, Pa. Member of the Pennsylvania State Militia for seven years, rising from private to lieutenant while in the militia. Made a record as marksman, having qualified for five years, having a record of forty-five out of a possible fifty at 500 yards; making six straight bulls eye, for which he received the state medal. In 1888 came to Nebraska and located on a ranch two miles from Oakdale. Remained on the ranch a short time, then purchased a drug store in Oakdale. In 1888 was married to Charlotte Shenefelt, to which union was born four children, three boys and one girl, three of whom are living — two boys and one girl. After a few successful years at Oakdale, he moved to Pawnee City and from there to his present home in Neligh, continuing in the drug business. Was prime mover in locating the local telephone exchange. Was elected member of State Board of Agriculture in 1902 and again in 1905. Superintendent of Agricultural Hall from 1903 to 1905. Superintendent of Bees and Honey for two years, Superintendent of Auditorium for a few years, Superintendent of Coliseum 1914, Super - intendent of Newspapers in 1915. In 1910 appointed postmaster under Taft administration for four years. </seg>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016">WILLIAM FOSTER William Foster was born at Iowa City, Iowa, May 29, 1866. In 1877 he with his parents, came to Nebraska via the prairie schooner route and rented a farm eight miles south of Lincoln which tract of land was afterwards purchased and which he still owns. On November 24, 1886, he was married to Mary E. Damrow and to them was born one girl. In 1888 he was chosen as a director of the Lancaster Agricultural Society and has since held all the offices in said Association. The State Commission appointed Mr. Foster as its Live Stock Superintendent for the Trans-Mississippi Exposition held in Omaha in 1898. In 1889 Governor Poynter appointed him as Steward of the Nebraska State Hospital which office he held during that administra - tion. In 1901 he was elected a member of this Board and re-elected in 1903 and 1906. The various boards of managers have acknowledged his worth by continuous appointments as General Superintendent since 1901 and which office he now holds. He was elected a member of the 1916 session of the Legislature and was a loyal worker in the house to secure an appropriation for a new swine farm. W. B. BANNING W. B. Banning was born in Otoe county, Sept. 18, 1869. He was educated in the common schools and then took a business course. He engaged in the grain business at Union in 1866 and became interested in the implement business in 1899. He has also engaged in the lumber business and in real estate. He was elected county commissioner in 1902 and served until 1905. He served in the Nebraska State Senate in 1909 and 1911. For several years he has been in charge of the machinery grounds at the Nebraska State Fair. </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">H. V. RIESEN H. V. Riesen was born January 30, 1851, in Dantzig, Germany. He attended school until his seventeenth year when he entered business life as clerk in a wholesale and import house of drugs and colonial wares. A few years later the Prussian government annulled the privilege of being excepted from the military services, granted up to that time to Mennonites, a religious sect similar to our Quakers, and belonging to this sect, H. V. Riesen declared his intentions to leave his native country. After receiving papers from the Prussian government dismissing him as a subject of Germany, he emigrated to Southern Russia, where his grandfather, in previous years, had acquired property, and where some of his relatives lived at that time. After having lived a few years in the town of Berdjansk on the Sea of Azov, H. V. Riesen concluded to go to the United States of America, and in 1874, after visiting the principal cities of the European continent and England, he landed in August of that year, in New York City, and continued his journey to Burlington, Iowa, where he lived until 1877 as bookkeeper and cashier for a whole - sale drug house. In 1877 he came to Beatrice, Nebr., where he has since lived with the exception of the period from 1882 to 1892, when he lived in Omaha. Most of the time since 1882 he traveled for Eastern wall paper fac - tories, being connected for twenty-two years as Western salesman with the factory of Robert S. Hobbs Co. of New York. This occupation took him to all the principal cities of the United States and Mexico. When in 1905 his oldest son died, he gave up traveling and started with his remaining son a real estate and insurance business in Beatrice, Nebr., where he lives at this time. Some years previous to this time he came into possession of 50 acres of ground on which a half mile race track was built and on which for the past ten years the Gage County Fair has been held. He has been the Secretary and Manager for this fair since 1905 with the exception of one year. CHARLES GRAFF Charles Graff of Bancroft is one of the prominent stockraisers of the state. He has taken a leading part in the movements for the benefit of farmers and stock raisers. He has served in the legislature and has held a number of important positions in his party organization. He has served efficiently and well as superintendent of the horse department at the state fair and is extremely popular with the horse exhibitors. </seg>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">J. H. TAYLOR J. H. Taylor was born in Manchester, England, November 23, 1869. Came to America in 1869 and located with his parents in Newark, New Jersey, and attended common school. Came to Nebraska in 1874, worked as a farm hand until 1881, when he rented a farm for two years. Was successful and purchased the rented land and is still its owner. In 1895 he became connected with the Douglas County Agricultural Society, and made his first exhibit at the Douglas County and State Fair in Omaha and since that time has taken part in all county and state fairs. Was a member and director of the Douglas County Agricultural Society for eighteen years and a member of the State Board for your years. JACOB SASS Jacob Sass was born in Holstein, Germany, in 1871. He came to the United States in 1887 and to Sarpy county in 1894. He has taken a lead - ing part in the good roads movement and the various plans for the ad - vancement of the interests of the farmers of Sarpy county. He has served for two terms a scounty commissioner and served one term in state legislature. He had charge of the machinery hall exhibits at the state fair during the last two yean. </seg>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022">J. E. RYAN J. E. Ryan of Indianola is one of the live wires in the agricultural movements of Red Willow county. He has worked consistently to secure good exhibits from his section of the state and has been enthusiastic in extolling the merits of his section of the state. He is very popular with the farmer patrons of the fair from his vicinity. E. R. PURCELL E. R. Purcell was bom at Springfield, 111., September 9, 1866, and came to Nebraska in 1874. He was educated in the public schools and at Doane College at Crete, Nebr. Moved to Broken Bow, Nebr., in 1884; was married to Miss Grace Cox, December 23, 1896, and their family consists of three daughters and one son. For more than twenty years he has been publisher of The Custer County Chief at Broken Bow, Nebr., a leading county seat weekly. Mr. Purcell served as mayor of Broken Bow several times and for some years has been president of Broken Bow's Commercial club. He has served on the State Board of Agriculture since 1912 and has acted in the capacities of Superintendent of Amphi - theatre and Superintendent of Gates. </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024">JOHN H. HARMS John H. Harms of Upland, Nebr., was born in Petersburg, 111., April 24, 1868, and moved with his parents to Humboldt, Nebr., in the spring: of 1871 and lived on a farm seven miles northeast of Humboldt until the spring; of 1900. He then moved to Franklin county, Nebraska, about ten miles southwest of Upland, Nebr., where he has fanned ever since. While in Richardson county Mr. Harms served for three terms on his district school board. Soon after he arrived in Franklin county he was elected treasurer of his school district there and held the office for twelve years. In 1905 he was elected director of the Franklin County Fair association, which position he has held ever since. In 1906 he was elected member of the State Board of Agriculture. In religion Mr. Harms is a German Lutheran, and in politics is a staunch republican, and has represented his county in a great many state conventions. For a number of years Mr. Harms has served as one of the managers for the Farmers Elevator and Telephone companies. Mr. Harms was mar - ried in 1890 and has five children living at the present time. Mr. Harms for a number of years has been a breeder of thoroughbred Duroc hogs, and is one of Franklin county's most respected and progressive farmers. E. R. DANIELSON E. R. Danielson, an Iowan by birth, came to Nebraska in 1890, resid - ing in Fremont until the fall of 1893, when the family moved to Lincoln, continuing his residence there until 1901 when he moved to Polk county. Engaged in farming and the raising of pure bred live stock, he turned towards the state fair as a school in which to gain knowledge along these lines. Became assistant superintendent of cattle in 1908 and served in this capacity during the years 1909, 1910 and 1911. In January, 1912 was elected as a member of the State Board of Agriculture, was made superintendent of Class "B" Cattle for that year and has been in that position since. </seg>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026">JOHN D. HASIK J. D. Hasik was born in Bohemia, April 9, 1874, and moved to Butler county with his parents in 1880 where he has lived since. He taught school for seven years, carried mail for six years, served two terms in the Nebraska State Legislature, held different township and school of - fices, and was also a president of Butler County Fair Association for two years. He owns and operates a well improved farm near Abie, Nebr., and a cattle ranch near Alexandria, La. Was elected a member of the State Board of Agriculture in 1915. While in the Legislature he voted for the appropriations for the new grand stand, the new Agri - cultural Hall, and all other bills which were promoting and helping the agricultural interests in this state. Helped his community immensely by introduction of improved varieties of corn, wheat, oats, and potatoes. Z. T. LEFTWICH Z. T. Leftwich, one of the pioneers of Howard county, was born in Des Moines, Iowa, in 1850. He lived on a farm during his boyhood, was married in 1870 and took a homestead in Howard county Sept. 23, 1871. He brought the first threshing machine to Howard county in 1872. He erected a water power grist mill on Spring Creek in 1877. In 1884 he built a 125-bbl. roller mill in St. Paul. He was mayor of St. Paul in 1886 and served as president of the State Millers' Association from 1890 to 1894. He is now president of the Nebraska State Live Stock Breeders' Association and is serving his third term as a member of the State Board of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028">C. G. CREWS C. G. Crews was born at Mt. Era, 111., in October, 1851. He came to Nebraska in the spring of 1881 and has lived at Culbertson for thirty - five years. For twenty years he has been a booster for the Hitchcock county fair and has served that organization in various ways. He has at all times been active in boosting agricultural interests. CHARLES STRADER Charles Strader succeeded C. H. Rudge as a member of the Ne - braska State Board of Agriculture. He is a well known Lincoln business man and has been active in promoting the interests of the Epworth Assembly. At the last state fair he had charge of the boys' camp and the programs given and the work accomplished attracted wide attention. </seg>
            <seg id="p029"/>
            <seg id="p030">THOMAS a KEEDLE Thomas B. Keedle, Superintendent of Agricultural Hall of the State Fair, was born in London, England, April 24, 1851. He came to America in October, 1870, and married Mary A. Flack in 1873. To this union was born eleven children, ten of whom are now living. All have settled in the community where Mr. Keedle now lives. Mrs. Keedle died three years ago. Mr. Keedle came to Lincoln, Nebr., in the year 1871. He came to Kearney county in 1884 and settled on a farm about ten miles north - west from Minden, which home he still occupies at this date. By hard work and thrift and by carefully studying the crops best adapted to the soil of his part of the state he has acquired a competency and now has a commodious home as the result of his toil. He has always main - tained a lively interest in the agricultural pursuits of the state and espe - cially of his home community. He has been foremost in every move - ment for the upbuilding of his home community and by unswerving hon - esty and rigid integrity has made himself prominent in the social and business life of his county and is highly respected and esteemed by everyone who has the good fortune to know him. Mr. Keedle having devoted his whole life to agricultural pursuits is especially fitted to be, as he now is, a member of the Agricultural Board of the State Fair, which position he has held since 1893 largely by reason of his interest in the State Fair. His home county for seven successive years won the first prize. For one year Kearney county dropped to second place and then again obtained first place. At this time Kearney county has the distinction of ranking third place in the state. E. VON FORELL E. von Forell was born at Ottawa, Lasalle county, 111., just fifty year ago. At the age of eighteen he settled on a farm near Chester, Thayer county, Nebr. At the age of 20 he tock a year off at a small normal school at Morrill, Kans. Up to this time his opportuni ies for an education had been limited. He applied himself to his work with an earnestness, and at the end of the year he passed the examination and was granted a second gTade certificate in his home county, where he taug-ht for three years. During this time he was married to M ; ss Mary Walker, who also taught school in the neighborhood. In 1889 he entered college where for five years he applied himself to his books, working during vacation to earn the money with which to continue h's studies. His wife also assisted in husbanding the means thus secured, and at times taking up such studies in college as her time would permit. At the age of 29 he received his coveted sheep-skin as well as testing his powers in the world's open arena. In 1895 he was appointed to a position at the State Industrial School for boys at Kearney where he labored for four years as a special field representative, looking after the interests of the paroled boys, as well as finding homes for those about to be paroled. While employed at the Industrial School he was nominated by the populists and later elected to the office of regent of the state uni - versity. As a regent he served two years as president of the board. Here also he took a great interest in the development of the agricultural school. After some years spent in professional life he went back to his first love, the farm. In 1907 he took a claim under the Path Finder project in Scottsbluff county. He has added dry land to his original claim until he now owns about 1500 acres. Acts as secretary and jreneral hustler of the Farmers' Mutual Insurance Company of Scottsbluff and rarries on an extensive auction business in which pure blood stock and real estate receive his special attention. He takes a lively interest in the state fair, and county fairs, and withal tries to keep in touch with all living problems. </seg>
            <seg id="p031"/>
          </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>