<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Relation of Size of Farm to Tax, Labor, Improvement, and Other Farm Expenses in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">June 1937</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">The Relation of Size of Farm to Tax, Labor, Improvement, and Other Farni Expenses in Nebraska Bulletin 308 June, 1937 L. F. Garey and R. W. Hecht ¦ Dciiartmcnt o£ Rural Economics •¦-•"' P. ot, ¦¦•¦. ¦ "'_¦' ¦.:.¦;¦..; ¦ '.';'¦¦¦¦'¦..:' '.. - . "|.*-. ¦ . ''.-.'¦ ,' ~ '¦ . /rt I^^^^B .I^^^^B! I^^^^B I'nuluciive Fccil and -irraxe* Improve- Machinery Hired Cropi Hones Mitcellan- HvcMMk Mi]ii&gt;lics .I menu ¦':¦-¦ labor . ecus ; Pi tribution of Cash Farm Expenses ¦ • ¦ '¦ ¦ .¦''/¦ . "¦¦..¦.'¦..' '¦ '" ¦ ' '¦:' - .-¦'¦ - "-. ¦¦¦ :¦¦ ¦ ¦ ¦¦ ¦" ¦¦¦ I ;¦¦ . ¦ ¦". ¦ '.¦¦¦. : ¦ '¦" :.//¦¦' ¦¦;¦;¦"'.; . ¦¦; '¦¦':¦¦ : ¦. ¦ - '¦¦¦¦¦'¦'¦¦ :-\ : ..;'¦ The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture ..¦¦¦l ' Experiment Station, Lincoln ; i W. W. Bun, Director </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Summary 2 Intrnilu.lliin J Quills,- nt Inliirm.ili'in 3 I&gt;» s, nptx.n n( lajkiiv(s 5 I hMrihiitmn "I Cash la|»ii«s—.All Records 7 11..W .mil nuchini-rt t \|nnse 7 Ml ln.M,,vk is.pe.isi 10 l-'ml. urain. .mil supplus 13 !&gt;"!' rt|«ll'» 14 1..1..T 16 ¦I-"" 1? Impim mi n[s 19 1n,.1 &#132;,,,1 Varul.l, h|«.i«. 20 iVIi In i, ..ml IM, ii.,. . 22 SUMMARY Hi, amount nt t.nm , \p&lt; live writs will) the size nt the business as indicated by lli. i.rts |icr I.iiiii hi.l mth tin .iniiiunl ill ..ish income from tile (arm. In tin ..ink [\jn n[ prmliiiumi tin l.iryi larms have- mure expense than the small ianiis. .illlmuvli tin i\i»n-i ni,i,.im- ,n j Oiwct rale. The ratio of cash expense In t.,*li m.mill iv liiulhi .hi -mi-iI! Linn, than nn l.irjje nnt-%. indic-.itint! ilwi small farms li.ik h- ]. ..mlhlii\ &#132;t in^li uiurii- ill. n l.uai l.irills. In m iiiul. mm&gt; in. M.,-. «ith tin m/i ..i the l.irii) hut the tax per acre decreases. I'mli r ...mi ..tn.liii.in. ih, i,,ml .nn,unit .if i.i\o p.ii.l &#132;n large farms may lit- less than [hat imiil .hi .in.ill i.ninv ;uriki,l.irK wliin ill. upc &#132;l prnducliim nn the lar^e farm is '&#132;. illdll.i.l fll.lfl ill.lf -ill lit' sNl.ll/ /.Mill. lii on,ill. i.iiijlil, i\|»-iM- ii-.uli ill Mi.,n ilinu innime than lived expenses. IKm,i,ii. ih.i, |. .in iiKlin.iuuM in i\|unil s.iri.,l&gt;l, ,\|K-nses more ilian tixal expense wlun in,,in,. nun.iM'. i\ni&gt;t vilnr, n is ninss.irv tn replace some capital which may h.i\i li,,n ilqiletul iluiini: I'inmls &#132;i 1,,u iiunim. Tin v;re.itest expansion in variable , \in us.. is i,,i firmhtitMt iiiisf.^k. r.Min.i. us, up ilmr nuJnniTi anil im|irn\eiin nt. ivllrn times are hail rather ifian iiuK.,s, tluir uuUlunln,ss t,. ui.imi.im tluir capital. When times return ihev re - |.U, ilmr ili|iliinl &#132;i|iit.il «it/i ni« ami mure nmilern machinery ami impriivcmenis. 11,,.,u5, i.t this tlun is in,in &gt;.in.in,.n in iln- ixpiiis, lor machinery and improvements than lii &#132;n.iiii it, ins smh .is ir,,p expeme, which lias a mure direct bearin.u "n in- Mi, .nn,.unl ..I iiicnm, Ktt atu r cash expenses have been paid is an indication of ih.ii I, It I'm Ininc .mil i.ipital nlilicalimiv l-irj..- (arms not onl\ have more total cash mi,inie. liv" in,,r, fin iiMiii; and capital obligations alter tile variable expenses are ilnliiiuil. This i|.,is n,,t iuci-s,irily mean that livinn levels are hi)ihvr nn larsc tban on .mall ijrms. luvjihc- cj|iiul ohlij;.iriiins on l.ir^e larnis may he greater than nn small i.irins. In low-incoiiH pirimls this .iiiiount is less than in hijjh-income iieriods. Because ilr. \.in.ilil, ixpinses in tanning \.ir\ less than the cash income, it becomes evident ih.it shanks in innniu atlnt the level ol laim living more than changes in cx - [lemliiuns. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Relation of Size of Farm to Tax, Labor, Improve - ment, and Other Farm Expenses in Nebraska - ! L. F. CAREY AND R. W. HECHT' jThc true economic condition of agriculture cannot be determined with - out a study of the expenses as well as the income from farming. It is difficult to obtain a record of the expenditures connected with farming and make proper allocation of them. Many farmers do not keep a record of their farming business and at the end of the year when they arc making a summary of their year's activity, their results are based largely on estimates, which permit a certain amount of error. The local condition of agriculture can be reasonably well ascertained where records are kept by jfarmers in sufficient numbers to be representative of an area or a locality. : .. ;ln studying the expenses of farming over a period of years it should be recognized that the information obtained during the more recent years is likely to be more nearly accurate and complete than that obtained in earlier years. As a result greater reliance can be placed on the more recent reports, mot only because of a greater number of records and a larger amount lof information but because more nearly accurate and complete methods arc used in securing the information. '.¦''&lt; The purpose of this study is to analyze the cash farm expenses of Nebraska farmers and to determine the influence economic conditions have on Jrcrtain expenditures in a farm business and the relationship of these expenditures to income and size of business as indicated by the acres per .forth.: ';¦'¦¦; :. : ¦"¦:¦-•• '¦;¦: ¦ ¦ . ] SOURCE OF INFORMATION . ;Thc information used in' this study was obtained from; farmers in Nebraska during the 21-year period, 1914-34. Information was obtained by means of farm-management surveys and farm account books. .All data obtained from' I?J4 to 1919 and part of the data obtained from 1920 to 192) were from farm-management surveys. Part obtained from 1920. to. 192; and all from 1928 to 1934 were from farm account books. Although the (lata obtained in the account books were generally more nearly accurate andj more, detailed, the pertinent information did not vary greatly from that | obtained in the surveys. No differentiation has been made between the survey records and farm account books in this study and the data were classified and treated in the same manner. For purposes of comparison the state was divided into five districts. Figujre.il shows the division of the state into districts, and reference will be madejto each district by number in the discussion which follows. The districts should not be interpreted as representing type-of-farming areas. The number and distribution of records appear in Table 1. The records were from different parts of Nebraska but more were obtained in the eastern than in other parts of the state. Because of this, that portion of .'Tllis Imllelili is bated on djia met] in a Master's thesis by the junior author while a graduate assistant in the Department of Rural Economics. " . . : " •.. :;- ; -¦..V¦'¦.¦¦ -¦' ' ¦¦-¦:' -... </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 In. 1- DiMriiis mm which the state has been divided for purposes of this study. I hey do not represent typc-of-farming areas ami should not be so interpreted. the state is treated more extensively than areas in the state where records were fewer in number and covered a shorter period. The number of records decreased considerably during the war period and less importance is placed on the information obtained during this period than for the periods preceding or following. In all, (\l^ records were used for the period covered in the study. The data were collected and summariz.cd by the Deji.irmicnt of Rural Economics. labli \.—Xumber oj farm records in each oj the five districts jrom 1914 to 1914 ; I II 111 j |v v r:' 4. -'f ' ~ •¦ !: ;¦; ( ; « '«' :' '&#132; » '•¦r is is S l«-") '«' If. H II - uf &gt;»«l 4"" l.'l 4^ |] ,- 111 "J1 «¦ I* :« % f "« mi fi ')&gt; 7-n "" &lt;«&gt; in ,2 -.', r&gt; ?i? TOTALS ' 3.M9 |,m"j 0,12 &#132;H 20 , -^ The records were fairly evenly distributed among different kinds of tenure. There were 2,097 records from owner-operated farms, 1,88) from part-owner-operated farms, and 2,376 from tenant-operated farms. In Dis- </seg>
         <seg id="p005">!¦¦¦ '¦¦¦'¦¦ '¦'¦•¦ :: ¦"¦ '¦'¦ I Relation of Size of Farm to Farm Expenses . tricts I and II more of the records were obtained from the tenant-operated farms, and in Districts 111 and V, more were obtained from owner-operated farms. Table 2 gives the number of farms by districts according to the kind! of tenure. ¦ Table 2.— Number of records by districts according to kind of (enure T&gt;-&lt;in. District District District Diltrict District Tm ,i I II 111 | IV V oal Owners 1,244 . 347 217 189 100 2,09? ftrt-oivncri 930 287 195 .. «5 « 1,881 Tenants 1,475 464 189 190 58 2,376 Total &#132; 3,649 1,098 602 SM 201 6,1U The data obtained from year to year were not always from the same farmers. Many who submitted records in 1914 were not farming in the latter part of the period. Consequently there was some change in the men who submitted these'records as well as a change in general economic con - ditions and general farming practices during the period. I DESCRIPTION OF EXPENSES Farm expenses may be grouped under two heads, those that are cash or out-of-pocket expense, and those that are non-cash. Although the non - cash expenses may not be immediate out-of-pocket expense, they eventually have to be met and are legitimately a part of the expense of operating a farm business. This bulletin will deal only with the cash expense in the operation of the farm business. Before a complete discussion of cash expenses could be prepared, it was necessary to ascertain just what items were included and what items were excluded in this category. For the sake of uniformity and for pur - p/ses of comparison all the cash expense items were classified under twelve heads. Only expenses that pertained to the actual farm business were in - cluded, because neither the farm surveys nor the record books gave informa - tion concerning household or personal expense. 2 ;•¦;,. Horses purchased.—This division of expenses included horses and mules purchased, cost of transporting the animals to the farm, and breed - ing fees. This division of expense was designated as horses purchased even though the other items were included. Productive livestock purchased.—Productive livestock included all live - stock other than horses and mules. The items placed in this division in - cluded purchases of productive livestock, icost of getting them to the farm, breeding fees for productive livestock, custom hatching, and bee supplies. Feed, grain, and supplies.—All purchases of, grain, hay, concentrates, salt, and other feeds were placed in this division as well as the cost of trans - porting the feed to the farm. Items of pasture hire and feed grinding were likewise entered here. : 'The results of a study of apenffii of the household by Muriel Smith, State Specialist in Home Mangcmcnt, appear in Nebraska Agricultural Extension Circular 11-114. ' . </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 Machinery.—The machinery expense included the purchase of machin - ery, repairs, and replacement of machinery, fuel, oil, and grease. Harness, small tools, portable hog or poultry houses, miscellaneous truck or tractor hire, rental of other equipment, egg cases, electric power and light, and horse shoeing were considered as an equipment expense. The proportion ot the automobile expense which should be charged to the farm was left to the judgment of the fanner. The part charged to the farm varied from one-half to the entire amount. Whatever proportion was charged to the farm was placed under the head of machinery expense. Improvements.—This item included new improvements, repairs on im - provements, paint, insurance on buildings, and fruit trees. Expense in - curred on the dwelling was considered a personal expense and was not in - cluded as a part of the tarm expenses. Any assessments made against the tanner for the construction of irrigation or drainage projects were placed under this item. Livestock expense.—This division ol expense included expenditures for scrums and medicines, veterinary services, livestock insurance, registry and transfer tecs, sheep shearing, sacks for wool, culling and caponizing thickens, brooder oil and fuel, and the freight or trucking charges on live - stock shipped in when the particular kind of livestock was not indicated. Crop expense.—Tlic amounts spent for seeds, twine, crop insurance, fertilizer, threshing, shelling, baling, silo filling, combining, and other work constituted the major items placed in the category ot crop expense. Hired labor.—Only two general items were placed in this division, namely hired labor and employers' liability insurance. Almost every farm studied had hired some labor either by (he day, month, year, or for par - ticular )o\is vuch as corn husking. Family labor.—AH labor performed on the farm by members of the family other than the operator was called family labor. In most cases members &lt;,t the family do not actually receive a cash wage. Nevertheless, the larmer is required to provide food, shelter, clothing, and services for the members i&gt;[ the family, and so an amount was included in the cash expense to represent the cash equivalent oi the items provided by the operator. Then, too, had not this labor been available it would have been hired ;iml a cash wage paid. Board for hired labor.—This division of expense was in some ways sim - ilar to unpaid family labor. It was in the nature of a cash expense but may not under certain conditions have all the essential features ot a cash expense. This item was omitted from the cash expense of the records for the period 1920 to 1928. On the basis of monthly wage and board rates available from other sources, the board for hired labor was computed for this period. Taxes.—Real estate and personal taxes constituted this item of expense except in the irrigated sections where assessments for the maintenance and operation of irrigation were included. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Relation of Size of Farm to Farm Expenses Miscellaneous.—Those items which could not be placed in any other division were entered as miscellaneous. When insurance on an item was not specifically listed, the insurance premium was placed in this division. It also included telephone and telegraph charges and assessments charge - able to the farm, railroad or bus fare spent in conducting the farm business, subscriptions to farm papers, membership dues of farm organizations, sums spent for rodent poison, and other miscellaneous items. FIXED AND VARIABLE EXPENSES Cash or out-of-pocket expenses can be divided into two classes, fixed and variable. The former is an expense that continues regardless of the variation in production while a variable expense is one that varies largely in proportion to the production. In this analysis machinery expense, taxes, improvement expense, and horses purchased have been considered fixed expenses. Some individual items included in these four classifications may not, under all circumstances, be fixed expenses, but because of the im - possibility of separating them in the early records, they have been so con - sidered in this study. Productive livestock purchased; feed, grain, and supplies; crop expense; hired labor, family labor, board for hired labor; livestock expense; and miscellaneous expense have been considered as variable expenses. These expenses are considered direct production expenses. CASH FARM INCOME j The cash farm income includes all items for which cash was received, such as sales of crops, sales of livestock and livestock products, sales of machinery, custom income from machinery, labor off the farm, sales of improvements, custom income from improvements, sales of sand, gravel, posts or lumber and other miscellaneous income which came from the farm.- : , .*¦'.'" . . /."• .''¦¦....' &gt; ¦¦'-¦.' . j DISTRIBUTION OF CASH EXPENSES—ALL RECORDS I The cash expense for the farms included in the study averaged $2,026 per farm and varied from $994 per farm in 1922 to S4,(MB per farm in 1920. It should be pointed out in this connection that the price of farm products in Nebraska was lower in 1921 and 1922 than at any time during the period from 1916 to 1929 and that the purchasing power of farm pro - ducts was lower in 1921 and 1922 than at any time during the period from 1910 to 1929. Under such circumstances the natural thing for farmers to Ido is lo curtail their expenditures. On the: other Viand, both the prices received by farmers and the purchasing power o£ farm products were higher in 1920 than at any time from 1910 to 1929, except for the years 1917 and 1918. Under such circumstances an increase in the expenditures of farmers would be expected. Table 3 gives the expenses per farm for the period 1914 to 1934 for all farms included in this study. • HORSE AND MACHINERY EXPENSE The amount spent for horses purchased averaged $49 per farm an - m ally during the period 1914 to 1934. It varied from nothing in 1920 </seg>
         <seg id="p008">. I ABi-i- 3.— .Iftragt uf cash expense mid income per farm. 1914 to 1914 S ,„, I Number 1,. 11'iudur.ii ™ I ''" d- Im.i, | ' ¦"'" Li«- ~ Labor j Board I Toui Toul £ ( arml Hor' c&gt; |vc,,A *'»"¦ ¦,;, "»P"&gt;W ""k Crop -— ." ; " lured Taxc. Uuc. ca.h ca.b X J I | ll»c.inct | ,, lp| ,|, c i [ ""¦¦)! niriM, . «|«-ri&gt;, cut'"' "'" d I' Jmily | jjhoj _J expcnie income &gt; 1914 -'64 *&lt;'&gt; 52W 51 -4 SIH SIIH S-'.t 51M 5234 SI Its Si 4 SIIS SH SI,4(M $2,797 &gt; 1915 C"l 5 '^ -''- 1 H.s |&gt;.i in la |U5 HS I|3 33 102 21 1,368 2,783 S "" "^ "" "« -**l IW I4S 22 in- m (J2 47 106 JO I ,»il 3,729 O 11)17 2S lUJ in !•• 'If' I 1"' » ]»l 200 101 46 111 40 1,929 3.994 r I9IM ¦" '" l'" t &lt;"¦'' 2^(l :ii 31 2is 3:5 72 SH 99 2S 2,019 5,712 1919 '] -'" ':l "''l M" *' 31 M 462 411 78 183 64 3,645 6.162 J |f):" ' "" !.'»¦' M 4 IT 134 IV2 (,7« 180 MS 175 99 4,048 ft.066 r "2I KS 2" M-! 3ir 111 112 4') _'M (.1/2 107 49 5(4 30 3,197 4,609 fr] 1922 2S '•' ¦" 41 I" 19 117 H" 113 19 272 29 994 1,878 ¦&lt; 1923 :6 -' 34(. stl JSI 1.111 4.1 111 156 78 46 237 35 2.162 3.305 f 192' t " 7 IS '*• 257 h,4 G4 31 62 143 24 30 I7S 12 1,193 2,318 S 1925 1(1 "• l-H W 'J-1 I'll 52 m 202 47 75 263 51 2,864 5.422 [n 1926 ** v' '¦"' "IK !29 «4 41 111 210 48 84 222 40 2,547 4.598 Z 1927 74 *¦ *i; s»&gt; W J 112 47 150 259 58 36 233 38 2,283 4.094 1928 'Jli 22 W' J 51S 572 20s 46 152 315 61 38 294 54 2,843 4.698 if 1929 Hl 3i I" 0 &lt;¦"-' Ml) 240 43 152 460 13S 44 292 58 3.859 6,28! % 1930 ~&lt;&gt; ¦» MO 79.1 175 58 194 322 165 41 288 35 3.44,2 5.247 5 1931 "92 2» 4»1 406 430 69 45 ]2 s 193 147 32 264 26 2,271 3,635 1932 ~70 2S 262 299 276 49 26 87 135 125 21 241 18 1,566 2,187 B0 1933 737 31 291 282 259 58 26 »2 127 121 24 210 18 1,560 2,512 Q 193 * &gt;- 3&lt;H « 21" 557 371 57 24 94 87 112 17 19S 22 1.801 3,034 r ° r"" al "^M 49 392 392 371 98 33 118 183 122 30 213 25 2,026 3,369 g GO 8 </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Relation of Size of Farm to Farm Expenses to $214 in 1919. There was a genera) decline in the amount spent dur - ing the period. The price of horses declined rather rapidly from 1917 to 1923 and remained fairly constant thereafter until 1929. Because of- the decline in the price of horses and because motor power had not made extensive inroads on the farm until after 1920, the expenditures for horses were greater in the earlier than in the latter part of the period. ! The amount spent for machinery averaged $392 per farm for the period. It|varied from $113 in 1914 to $940 in 1929. There was a general increase in the amount spent for machinery during the period, noticeable par - ticularly during the five-year period 1924 to 1929, when the price of horses was fairly constant and the price of machinery decreased. The relation - ships are given in Table 4. Table A.—Relation between the index of the price of horses and machin - ery and the amount spent for each per farm, 1914 to 1934 ..'. .:: -.-¦¦'¦ Indexof.theprice l ' Amountipent •'.' • (1923-1925=100) per farm for Nebraska ¦.'.- tear • ' _____^^__^^_^_^_^^^_»^.^ ...:.-¦ ... Honei '|¦_ . Machinery Horses .- | . Machinery 1914 176 93 $65~ ~~ 5113 ~ 1915 174 91 95 .125 1916 -'. 178 91 150 .164 1917 ISO 90 .103 ' ¦ 336 1918..................... 165 119 111 150 1919............ 158 , . 118 2H ,810 1920. ...;........... 129 :¦-. 113 .. 644 1921 ....;.. 108 ; . • 125 '.'¦: 20 151 1922 106 ¦'¦ 97 13 ¦' ¦ :. .' 138 1923. .......' 98 ' n 25 353 1924......,........;...... 100 106 - 18 ' 164 1925...................... 102 101 16 668 1926...... 97 101 49 329 1927.. ...,;....;..¦ 102 100 39 ¦ 392 •1928... '..,.'. ;.. 102 ... . 100 . 22 572 1929 98 .' 99 33 940 1930.........:; 84 95 43 798 1931. .• .;...'. "A 93 29 . 430 1932 ¦ : 78 . .. 85 .¦ ¦: 28 276 1933.... 99 • 84 31. . .589 1934.............'. : 110 ¦•" .90 , ¦; ¦ 48 374 VCureau of Labor Statiitict. Indexes are for.the entire United Sfales. ".. The amount of horse ; expense as given in Table 5 represents a small proportion o£ the total cash farm expense. In low income years farmers turn toward horses as a source of power, because after the horses are once pur - chased there is very little out-of-pocket expense, while with the use of motor power there is a continuous out-of-pocket expense. The amount Table s.—Relation pj cash income per farm to expenses for horses and ¦' farm machinery, 1914 to 1934 ¦ When cash income wal of Cash eipenie total eipeme yean Horses I .Machinery Horses | Machinery Below average'.,. i .......'. 8 $49 $268 3.1 , 165 Above average.........,.......' 13. ;50 544 1.8 19.6: Average or t0ta1...... ....... 21 . 49 371 2.4 jjj </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Acricl-ltural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 spent per farm varied from $28 in District V to $54 in Districts I and IV and averaged §49 per farm for all districts. The amount spent for machinery varied from $269 in District 111 to $674 in District JV and averaged $375 per farm for a)l districts. The large amount spent in District IV is because most of the records in this district were obtained after 1928 when the expenditures were comparatively high, and the scarcity of records during the early part of the same decade when the expenditures for machinery were low. As the size of the farm increased in District I, there was no definite trend in the amount spent for horses. In Districts 11, 111, and V there was an increase in the amount spent. In District IV there was no definite trend upward as the larms increased in size until the farms reached over T\hli. f&gt;.— Relation oj size of farm to the amount of cash expenditures per jcirm /or horses and machinery by districts, 1914 to 1934 X r Iji.i.i. r I Olwrur II District V '¦'¦'',„ ' *'," C " ! ' •!¦""" '"' (M/c" l l-M*U«f-l«&gt; M" t T | EH!""" '"' i &#132;„,, .&lt;: i : -;- ,:„., im ,s:» sn» w s:h S2W hi :&gt; ¦ -¦¦ jm r: .&lt;: i:» 165 19 35-t ::i '¦¦¦ :;- &lt;n _&gt;;&lt; 4&lt; &gt;4i J62 27 .w mi -i. 1": ¦¦•¦ • iii i: .^s^ 3d9 5c en ¦¦.l-"-" -¦ •¦ *l: 511 (.1 4~ 5-M 786 Inn ¦¦"' ¦¦: ' -: i Ml 4" '&lt;S: 3.2T0 7.1 1.311 r _, ¦¦&lt;-:&lt;,¦ II! IH&gt;lnn IV '•tr.^c A\crjue ¦r .- ¦ , l/r 1 «!*..«&gt; f.ir | sjl . c F.spcmt. tiT I - l.'fi M.. , Mj.Jim.. , Hor/r/ HjeUarry i •»»¦! :&gt;• ii' ¦;¦• &gt;k.: ¦ n» Sto swi .in «« &gt;j ;m .&lt;i.i .«i JSS **»i 4--" y :,,! ,r 50i s}i 'i*' ' ¦: n :¦»», mo s^l 71.1 .''Ml i |4. Si. Hi 1 ll.| J2 U/J o.cr :.i.n • .*f,: .*. 4i'j i fir.i 22f, 792 2.(mi) acres. In all districts the amount spent for machinery increased as the size ol the farms increased. The rate of increase was less in Districts HI and IV ihan in other districts. Grazing is important in both of these districts and undoubtedly accounts for the relatively small amounts of machinery expense, particularly in District 111. There is sortie grain farm - ing in the southern part of District IV and on the smaller farms in this part ot the district there is very little grazing, which accounts for the larger amounts spent lor machinery on the smaller farms than is true in the other districts. ALL LIVESTOCK EXPENSE :1 The amount spent for productive livestock averaged $392 annually for the period, and varied from $41 in 1922 to $860 in 1929. Practically all of the productive livestock involving this cash expenditure consisted of cattle ' Monti purjnicil noi included </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Relation of.Size of Farm to Farm Expenses and hogs. The expenditures for productive livestock averaged higher for the six-year period 1925 to 1930 than for any other six-year period from 1914 to 1934. During this period the purchasing power of both cattle and hogs was at the peak of a cycle. 4 0 |— ¦ ;—— ——— ¦ ¦ —— . .jj -~-y &gt;\ ;=¦-. ¦ s"\ ¦¦¦--.' &lt; \ / V ¦"¦: PURCHASING J \ £ .'¦»'. / ¦ ¦ ' POWER PCfIHfAO/ \ """ I • .¦¦/¦¦ \—--V.&gt;' A g \/ ' \ / ".' ! . ¦ ¦¦¦.:' - NUMBER \ •¦.'".¦¦¦ y .0 ; I * 't ' I II I I I I I l^'S.lX I I I ' t I jj .1914 1919 I9Z# 192» 1934 Fig. 2. —Purchasing power in dollars \ier head and number of cattle, other than milk cows, in the United States from 1914 to 1934. Large numbers of cattle mean Joiv . purchasing power and small numbers mean high purchasing power. High points in the purchasing power have occurred about every 16 years 15| ¦;..;. , . "1 ! JO ¦¦:".' ': '-' ¦ / \ Nyf*oefiS ¦¦¦'-¦¦ 012 ¦ ¦ ¦" " / ' 1 '• / \ "S3 - &lt; . / &gt;—V- PUBCHASIKfc POWER PER HE"AO \ I \ l\ ¦ i 2•¦¦/'.¦ : \ / \ -" "¦ •'¦ ¦¦¦¦.''¦¦¦"¦ ¦ ¦¦'¦ ¦''.¦¦¦'¦':¦.¦ :¦ : . .• "' -. ' " 3I l i i t ' ' ' ' ' ' ' ¦ 111 1 ti 1 l. 7 MM . , 1919 1924 ¦¦ ¦' 1929 ¦-¦ in* Fig. 3.—Purchasing power in dollars per head and number of hogs in the United Suites from 19M to 1934. Except for the period 1917 to 1920 when there was a rapid rise in prices*-the purchasing power of hogs was. low when the numbers were larjge and high when the numbers were small. The low point in purchasing power oc - curred every five to six years.. .. ' </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 Table 7.—Relation of cash income tier farm to livfstoc\ expenses, 1914 to 1934 ""'" aih locome "" ,„„ Productive I , I Productive! —7" , *"* .iret.dc I °"\"' ) |; vaMc|c I Other' Below average ~" 8 $265 524~ 16.7 1.5 Above average 13 607 46 213 1.7 Aiera ß c or total 21 392 33 19.3 1.6 1 Doci not include horses purchased. An increase in the amount spent for livestock does not always mean an increase in the number purchased. An increase in the price of cattle and hogs, as shown by their respective cycles, was the result of a decrease in numbers. The relationship of the supply of cattle and hogs to their price is shown in Figures 2 and 3. The increased amounts spent for productive livestock in certain years may be due more to an increase in price than an increase in number purchased. The livestock expense per farm averaged $33 annually for the period and ranged from SlB in 1915 to §134 in 1920. This item is largely in the form of service to all livestock and does not constitute an important item of expense in the farm business. In general it averages from $1.00 to $1.75 per animal unit. The expense of productive livestock consisted of nearly one-fifth of the total expenses for the period and constituted a higher proportion in the Table B.— Relation oj size of farm to cash expenses for productive livestock and other livestock^ expense combined, per farm, 1914 to 1934 District I TViurict 11 District V "¦"¦f, &#132; Expense Ec^c [ Eipcme 3&amp; * t, or E 7 h f3rm "ock ' '¦""' itock ' "r^ stort i Ann Acre, ,l rrf , Aml fnder HI 102 5259 100 S2H P0 S5« Hl-220 .174 3-H 172 128 165 983 221-300 254 435 253 256 262 «I 301-420 359 804 351 266 369 538 •421-640 m 1,377 511 454 546 676 Over 640 692 1,618 941 258 3.240 594 District 111 District IV "' &lt;"m ,of live- of ,° e f. farm ) .roct' fa™ , ack ¦ j Acres Ami Acres Under 201 150 5193 [45 S 2n B 20J-360 2M 351 310 19 361-520 455 206 453 260 521-760 632 362 640 278 &lt;61-2.«» 1.1« 257 1.161 C 26 O«r 2.000 3.262 437 2,863 988 1 Hones purchased not included. </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Relation of Size of Farm to Farm Expenses ! good than in the poor years, as shown in Table 7. The average amount spent in good years was more than double that spent in the poor years. Expenses in the form of services to livestock made up less than two per cent of the total farm expenses. Only in District I is there a consistent relationship between the size of the farm and the expense for! productive livestock and other livestock expenses (Table 8). The farms over 2,000 acres in size in Districts 111 and IV are practically all "livestock ranches. There is not the need for the purchase of produc - tive livestock and feed under such conditions, the productive livestock pur - chases being limited to those for the breeding herd and the feed purchases to those for carrying the livestock through the winter. On the other hand, the purchase of productive livestock in Districts I and V consisted mainly of feeding animals to be finished for market. Livestock is relatively less import - ant in the agriculture of District II than in the other districts; and conse - quently the expenses for livestock are less per farm. In general the relation o(. livestock expense to productive livestock purchased is rather constant in the feeding sections of the state. V . . FEED, GRAIN, AND SUPPLIES "] . The cash expenditure for feed, grain, and supplies, most of which was feed, averaged $392 per farm annually during the 21-year period. It varied from S4l in 1922 to $1,065 in 1920, the latter amount not being repre - sentative because of the small number of farms involved. I The two principal factors which cause a variation in the!amount of feed grain purchased by farmers are the quantity of feed produced and the ratio between the price of grain and the price of livestock.* An un - usual surplus of feed grains was produced during the years |1920, 1921, and 1922, which undoubtedly accounted for the small amount purchased in 1922. Farmers purchase more feed grain when the ratio of the price of feed grain to livestock is favorable, that is, when the priceiof grain is low compared to the price of livestock. The average feed-grain-livestock ratio in the United States for the period 1858 to 1934 was 49.8. The ratio was above this average 35 years during the period, below during 39 years, arid the same as the average for three years. Farmers spent more for feed grain during the six-year.period from 1925 'to'l93o,.than for any other six-year period from 1914 to 1934. During these six years the feed-grain - livestock ratio ; was never above 46 and averaged 38 for the six-year period. Table 9 gives the relation of feed-grain-livestock ratio to the amount spent for feed and supplies for the 21-year period, 1914' to 1934. In the feeding section of northeastern Nebraska there is a close relation - ship between the amount spent for productive livestock and the amount spent for feed and supplies. In District 111, which is predominandy graz - ing, especially in the northern part, the relationship is fairly dose. In the other districts no definite relationship was found. The relative prices of feed i * The feed-Rrain-Uvejtock ratio is the ratio of the value ol a invert amount o£ Brain to the value of the liveitock products produced from that grain. : </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 Table 9.— Relation of feed-grain-livestoc\ ratio to amount spent for feed per farm, 1914 to 1934 .. , Average Amount _ When fed-cram- ¦v""1&gt;" feed-train- spent Vc/ ""&lt; livciiock rauo was °f livestock for feed o£ ""al . 2!J2 per farm "Pc"" Below ihe avenge 12 36 5455 27.4 Above the average 9 60 350 13.8 Average or total 21 -f&lt;j 392 ¦ 19.4 grains and forage are considered in the purchase of feed. In sections where the carrying of livestock through the winter constitutes the principal live - stock problem, a larger proportion of the feed purchased is likely to be in roughage form, while in sections where fattening for market is the live - stock problem the reverse is more likely to be true. (See Table 10.) T\BLt 10. — Relation of size oj jarm to amount spent for feed and supplies per farm by districts, 1914 to 1934 Kjl ,. r District I District II District V "¦ s"r , , . Expense Expense Expense Ha,,,, •*&gt;"«' .„,„,, A.trace ,„,„.,, Average fw ! fccd "" and supplies lUC anil supplies "zc and supplies • 1w Acrei Jem In.u-i HI 102 5329 100 5250 90 5367 I"" --" n "I 17: 29S 165 305 --1 -*«¦ 2" 267 253 3»8 262 211 JOM&gt; &lt;V&lt; 57&gt; .15] 43-1 369 319 «1 Wl 497 W 511 737 5-16 271 '"" "4" W 1|367 941 f^ 3.240 1,713 Rjn&gt;:&lt; . ""'r »' 'II District IV "' *"c , Expense Expense ¦lUrm A.e^c &#132;„,„,, Average J,^ . . "" jn.l supplies "" and supplies ¦&lt;"¦&lt;¦• .tern 1'"'"-"' I" 524» H8 5236 " 2J4 ."« 310 139 *;«" «5 219 453 201 !•¦'/* M- 3-« M 0 19-t ' ¦'-'"„ U« 41* 1.161 309 "-"• -""" , 3JM 4^ 2JB 486 Only in District 1 was there a continuous increase in the feed and supply expense as farms increased in size. In District II there was a continuous in - crease up to the largest-sized farms. In the other districts, the type of live - stock production shifted more to grazing as farms increased in size and less feeil was needed. CROP EXPENSE . The amount of crop expense averaged 5118 per farm for the 21-year period, and varied from $62 per farm in 1924 to $392 in 1920. The cost of twine, threshing, and shelling constituted the major portion of this class of expense. The crop expense was highest from 1918 to 1921 and aver - aged 5287 per farm annually for the period. The expense of threshing and shelling is principally labor, which was higher during this four-year </seg>
         <seg id="p015">. Relation of Size of Farm to Farm Expenses period than before 1918 or after 1921. Twine costs were also high (luring that period. In later years twine and threshing costs have been lower be - cause ofthe increased use of the combines and this has had some influence on the amount of cash expenses for crops. Crop expenses must be paid in years of low income as well as in years of high income and although there is some variation in the amount spent on crops the variation is not so great as in most of the other variable items of expense. (See Table 11.) Table 11.— Relation of cash income per farm to crop expense, 1914 to 1934 ¦ I Number I Per cent When ciih income was oE . : . ««P of tout ' - ' ¦ ¦ • I ynn expense | cipenie Below average................' »''¦'.. $93 -.'. 5.9 Above average ;,.' ...-: 13 159 5.7 . Avenge or total..; ¦. '. ....' . 21 ¦¦ . 118 '¦ 5.8 . Table 12.— Relation of size of farm to amount of crop expense per farm by districts, 1914 to 1934 Ranee District I Diilrictlt Muriel V in size ' . Avenge | ¦ Crop Average. | Crop Average I Crop. ¦°E 'alm size I expense size 1 experue tue 1 eipenie Acres Acres - ¦ Acres Under Ml 102 ¦ 568 100 US 90 5262 141-220 174 .99 .172 . 73, 165 243 221-330 254 138 253 104 262 233 301-420 359 160 . 351 126 369 270 • 421-640 ..&gt; 497" . 18» . 511 126 . . 546 337 Over 640 892 199 Wl 102 3.240 -.- 497 . .;¦¦)'.: iagt-'.:''.': v DisttictlU piMricylV , ;¦- '-in *iie. ; ¦ Avenge. 1 - Crop Average I Crop "!l"a iiie I eipeme lize I CTpenle '.-¦' Acres' : .¦: Acres ' Unilcr 200, ...;...... 150 552 .148 JUS 201-360 ...: ..: .284 ¦ ,76 . 310 . 95 .jCI-520 .:. 455 88 453 105 521-760 ....;:...... : 632 77 640 136 761-2,000 ................:............. 1,143 90 1,161 150 Over 2,000...............;...... 3,262 .69 2,863 \ . 207 : Although the average amount of crop expense .was greater in the good than in the poor years, the proportion of the total expenses remained approximately the same. The variation in the price of certain of the items of crop expense ifl good and poor years and the failure of some crops in poor years account .for the difference in the amount spent. lFrom the very nature of the crop expense the amount would increase as;the acreage of crops increases. In practically all districts there was an increase in the acreage of crops as the size of the farm increased but at a slower rate. Because the crop expense varies directly with the acres in crops and because the proportion of the farm devoted to crop production decreased as the farms increased in size, the rate of increase in crop expense was slower than the increase in the size of the farm. In Districts I, 11, </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 111, and IV, the kind of crops grown required less expense than those grown in District V, where sugar beets and potatoes play an important part in the cropping system. Because of the direct relationship between the crop expense and acres in crops, one should not expect as much economy in crop expense with increase in acreage as he would in machinery expense. LABOR The expense of hired labor, with board and family labor, averaged §335 per farm for the 21-year period, and varied from §216 per farm in 1934 to ? 1,042 in 1920. Less was spent for hired labor in 1934 than in any other year during the period. The crop conditions in the state in 1934 were such that less hired labor was required than for normal years; thus a larger proportion of the total labor cost ivas family labor. During this year family labor, not including the cost of its board, constituted 52 per cent of the total labor expense, while in 1920 it constituted but 18 per cent. In 1929, another good year, it was 21 per cent. A significant condition causing a variation in the amount spent for hired labor is the amount of cash farm income. In general more is paid out for hired labor in years of high incomes than in years o£ low income. Table 13.—Relation of cash farm income to amount paid for hired labor, including board for hired labor, per farm, 1914 to 1914 Per cent hired „ Averase per (arm labor was of: Per cent all Number j 1 — labor was of When caih income wai , of Hired All Total Total totalfatm yean l abor |,bor 'abor "¦£"l eipcmc expcnle expense Below the a^ B &lt; H SI" 5267 57.3 9.C 16-5 Above the »vera ß e li 3li «3 "&gt;¦' "•' MJ Average or total 21 V.I 335 63.6 10.5 16.5 In good years hired labor constitutes a larger proportion of the total labor expense than it does in poor years. While a cash wage may not be paid to family labor a charge has been made against it because, were it not for the family labor, other help would have to be obtained and there would be a cash expense. In general the expense of labor increases with the size of the farm but not at the same rate. A proportionately smaller area of the farm is devoted to crop production as the size of the farm increases and often the type of production is shifted to a less intensive type with increases in the size of the farm (Table 14). In District I, where production is on an intensive basis and where most ot the land is in farms, an increase in the size of the farm is accompanied by an increase in size of productive enterprises. An expansion in crop enter - prises means additional labor at approximately the same rate as the expan - sion of crop production. However, in rough sections the large farms are likely to be more largely devoted to cattle grazing, which requires less labor </seg>
         <seg id="p017">I ...'¦"'..' ¦ '.'¦'**; ' " - | : Relation of Size of Farm to Farm Expenses . Table H.— Relation of size of farm to the labor expense per farm by dis - ; ¦ ¦ tricts, 1914 t0"1934 x : Range ¦ Di*l"« I ¦¦' District II District V 'V f l2c Average I Labor Average | Labor Average [ Labor rm - sjzc | expense size 1 expense size | expense : . ' Acret '. . . Acrct ' --. ,4crei Under H1.... 102 5135 100 554 SO $731 141-220 ..;. 174 225 172 104 165 1.091 221-300 254 375 253 185 262 781 30M20 359 . 536 351 293 369 1,215 421-640 ......; 497 846 511 524 546 764 Over 640.....;., ¦..",. 892 • 945 941 235 3,240 1,887 Rjnsc ¦ ¦ Diitrict 111 Distrtcc IV '" 'ize . Average ~j Labor " " Average j Labor - °'»™ lize I cipcnie ila | expeme ¦-. ' • ¦'. ¦ - Acrct ' . ."¦ Acret - ¦ ... ¦Under 200.. .;...... 150 $115 148 $238 201-360 284 . . 252 310 159 361-520 ; 455 265 453 193 521-760 ............ 632 237 640 258 761-2,000 1,143 .. 432 ¦ .-1,161 547 Over 2,000; 3,262. . 590 .. 2,863 760. 1 Includes family labor and board for hired labor, ¦ - than that in level sections where crop production predominates. This was the situation in the group o£ farms over 640 acres in size in District 11. The relatively large expense on small farms in District V is due to the production of sugar beets and potatoes in that district. In Districts IV and V the labor expense on the large farms is less because of the large amount of cattle grazing in those districts. ,•;¦¦¦: ' '¦''¦: .''• .taxes ... • ' : : - ¦ . The amount paid for taxes includes that for real estate, personal pro - perty, and irrigation, and averaged $213 per farm for the 21-year period. It varied from §99 per farm in 1918 to $534 in 1921. The large amount of tax in 1921 was due to.the fact that most of the records for that year came from District V, where irrigation is important, The tax on water used for irrigation purposes is included in the total tax item and consti - tuted approximately two-thirds of the total taxes paid. However, for all farms throughout the period real estate taxes constitute the largest pro - portion of all taxes assessed,. . The real estate taxes vary with the price of the land, on the whole. Where unusual services are demanded in a locality, the real estate taxes may be higher than on the surrounding land even though the surround - ing land may have a higher valuation. The peak of taxes is reached several years after the peak of land values, is readied. Figure 4 shows that the peak of land values in the United States was reached in 1920 and that the peak of land taxes per acre was reached in 1929, Taxes are levied to pay for services and are reduced when less service is demanded. i &#132; ¦...¦¦•• - : '• . •¦ -: ' .: ¦ ' .'¦¦¦¦'. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 1401 A. LAND VALUE 120 ¦ / / B^AL ESTATE TAVES \ **-* -I ii i I I I L__l 1 1 1 1 I—l—J ,94 1919 1924 «2» '"* l-ii,. ¦). —Liml lalut 1 and real estate taxes per acre in the United Slates, 19H to 193-1. Increases in lanil values preceded increases in taxes and decreases in land value pre - ceded decreases in taxes. The peak in real estate taxes per acre was not reached until nine years alter the peak in land values had been reached (1923-1925 = 100). ¦T.irm Rc.il l-.Mate Situation. 1435-1936," by B. R. Staubcr and M. M. Regan. Tarlk \S. — Relation oj cash income to taxes paid per farm, 1914 to 1934 Number _ Per cent Wlifn ..i.h income »j&lt; of '**" of loul years [^ expense Hi-1.,h- die .nrrjuc « S'Bs "¦&lt;&gt; Al&gt;mr Ihe i.oitr II J«0 9.3 Mtr.,« nr irul -' -13 '"¦6 There is likely to be an increase in taxes during a period of good years and a decrease during .1 period of poor years. The taxes paid during the poor years constituted a larger proportion of the total expenses than they did in the good years. In poor years farmers curtail certain of their other expenses. This is particularly noticeable for machinery, improvements, labor and livestock. Almost without exception, as the size of the farm increased there was an increase in the amount of taxes paid per farm. Table 16 gives this relationship. Although the total amount of the taxes increased as the size of the farm increased the taxes per acre decreased. The unusually large amount ot taxes per farm in District V is due primarily to the tax on water used in irrigation. The taxes on land in the irrigated section are higher than on non-irrigated land in the same section because of a higher valuation placed on the irrigated land. The higher valuation is the result of greater production. The farms over 640 acres in size are for the most part outside of the irrigated section. The tax rate on these large farms is so low in some instances as to make the total taxes per farm actually less than on smaller farms. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Relation of Size of Farm to Farm Expenses Table 16.— Relation of'size of farm to taxes paid per farm by districts, i 1914 to 1934 Ringc Diiuict I District 11 District V S&amp;. A%r I T,, a *gy I TaK . I*™*l Tatc ,_ - «4cr« . . Acra : Acres Under M 1... 102 5122 100 596 90 5350 141-220 ;•..;¦ 174 169 172 124 165 483 _ 221-300 ........:: 254 245 253 179 262 607 301-420 359 297 351 203 369 646 m-6W 497 429 511 296 546 1,041 O"r 640.- 892 476 941 191 3,240 629 Range District 111 District IV " . Sfc . ag i w ] r m , . ' Acres Acres Under 200........... :.;.... 150 5123 148 . 5132 201-360.... ; .284. 158 310 US 361-520 455 182 453 . 133 521-760 632 179 640 168 761-2,000 .......' 1,143 238 1,161 254 Over 2,000.... 3,262 356 2,863 309 IMPROVEMENTS . ; The expense for farm improvements averaged $98 per farm for the . 21-year period 1914 to 1934, and varied from $49 in 1932 to $312 in 1921. More is spent on farm improvements when the cash income is high than when it is low. Table 17 gives this relationship. Table 17.— Relation of cash income to expenses for farm improvements per farm, 1914 to 1934 ' : . . . Number Expense ' Percent . Whrn cash income wil . . of • of/arm oftoul ¦ ¦ yean . improvement expense , .. Below tfic average :........^....... ...: . 8 : ¦ 567 : .' 4.2 Above the average 13 150 ' 5.4 . Avenue or total 21 98 •¦ 4.8 : For the eight years when the cash income was below the average of the '; 21-year period from 1914 to 1934, the average expense per farm for im - provements was $67 and for the 13 years when the cash income was above ; the average it was 5150. For both die period when the income was below i the average and for the period when it was above the average, the expense ' for farm improvement constituted about the same percentage of the total •; expense, 4.2 and 5.4 per cent, respectively. The proportion that the im - | : provement expense was of the total fixed expense, however, was noticeably I,"' less for the period of low income (Table 19), indicating that there was ,'; more variation in expenses for improvements than for some other items !••'. in; the fixed-expense group of the farm business. ;j : ;In general improvement, expense increased with the size of the farm j although not at the same rate. The capacity of a set of buildings which v '¦'¦ "i ¦ ¦:¦ '¦'.¦¦ '¦"¦: .¦¦"-'.'. '"'"¦¦ ¦; ¦i:; ''. .'¦-.; .. • . </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 provide for the needs of the farm does not need to increase as rapidly as the size of the farm, because of a decrease in the intensity of operation with an increase in size (Table 18). Table 18.—Relation of size of farm to expense of improvement per farm by districts, 1914 to 1934 RanEC P»'"« ' District II District V '" "« . Improve- Improve- Imprmc - oll'im Average men , Mcagc mat A.CMJ.-C £ m _ "zc expense expense expense "•"•• •&lt;'¦'&lt;•&lt; Acrci F," ds' Hl &gt;02 575 100 $46 90 SI7I »-g0 174 85 172 55 165 223 ' "300 :54 101 253 65 262 301 2»-«» J59 145 351 88 369 64 421-640 497 171 5M 122 546 4P °»" M 0 892 172 HI 77 3,240 128 . g la[e District 111 District IV ln il7c Improve- Improve - rfbnn Average £ at Average m£™* !lff expense |«= expense ¦&lt;"¦« rfom m'm -°° ... 150 535 148 591 g^ ;. ::.:::: | ,JS ,§ °'" -000 i£62 197 2,863 191 FIXED AND VARIABLE EXPENSES The annual cash fixed expense, which consisted of that spent for horses, machinery, improvements, and taxes, averaged $731 per farm for the period from 1914 to 1934. It varied from §402 in J914 to $1,505 in - 1929. High fixed expenses can in nearly all cases be traced to unusual expenditures for farm machinery. This was particularly true in 1919 19^0 1925, 1928, 1929, and 1930. Table 19 gives the distribution. ' The cash expense for machinery constituted 50.7 per cent of the fixed expenses for the 21-year period. The proportion of the fixed expense at - tributable to machinery was larger in the latter part of the period than in the earlier part, while that attributable to horses was smaller in the latter than in the earlier part of the period. This was due partly to a shift from horse to motor power on farms and to more efficient machinery. The price index of both farm machinery and horses was lower in the second half than in the first half of the period. In all the years, except one, when the amount of the expense for farm machinery was above the average, the amount of the cash income per farm was above the average. Although expense for farm machinery is classed as a fixed expense, an increased amount is spent on machinery for upkeep and new purchases when the purchasing power of the farm increases. In years of low income farmers continue to use their old machinery, thus reducing their capital in this part of their investment below the normal </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Relation of Size of Farm to Farm. Expenses ,: Table 19.— Distribution oj cash fixed expenses per jarm for the years when the cash income was above and below the average for the 21-year period, 1914t0 1934 , ':, - ¦ . - ¦ \ . Number ¦ . Amount spent per farm for . When cash income was of ' ' j 71 7~. "T~. j ~Z Total I "¦¦ years Horses j Machinery | Improvements f Taxel . Below the averaj-c!........ 8 $49 : $268 : $67 $185 $569 Above the average....... v J3 50 544 150 260 I,OM . "¦..'-.¦ Per cent ; Below the averaec ;....« 8.6 -17.1 11.8 32.5 100.0 Above the averaje......... 13 5.0 51.2 11.9 25.9 100.D amount. In years of high income they replace their depleted capital in such investments by purchasing more than the normal amount of machinery. With two exceptions, as is clearly indicated in Table 20, the fixed expense per farm increased with the size of the farm. The rate of increase or fixed expenses was much slower than the rate of the increase in the size Table 20.— Relation of size of farm to fixed expense per farm by districts, ¦';-.'" 1914 to 1934 RaIIKC '.. &#132;' . District! District I! District V in SI2C ' Average j Fixcil Average j Fixed Average J Fixed of farm ' ¦ ) expense size I expense size I expense ¦ ¦ Acres . Acres ¦' . Acres Under H1.,............'. 102 S«5 100 S.U9 90 SB-H 141-220 : . 174 . 58) 172 3M 165 1,079 221-300 254. i 7f.2 ' 253 - 528 262 UlB 301-420 .........;. .359 . I.OIC 351 707 369 1,401 421.640 497 1,360 511 956 546 2,261 Over MO W . 1,548 941 1.243 3,240 2,171 Range District 111 District IV '""¦}" . Avcracc .1 Final Aicrjcc j Filed . - uf larm size I cxprnic si/c I expense ' ¦ .. ¦ . . :'. . Atm ¦...','• Actet Under 200. ...........,:.......:.... 150 5336 148 SMI MI-360 :.................. 284 -54« 310 70? 361-520 .:....... &#132;,455 522 453 776 521-760 ; &amp;l- '570 ' &lt;H0 «8(1 761-2,000 1,143 723 1,161 1,277 Over. 2.000. 3,262 1,062 2.853 1,518 of farm. This would indicate that there are certain items of fixed expenses that, without much, increase, serve the needs of large farms about as well as of small farms. The fixed expenses in District V were larger than in any other district. Taxes in this district constituted approximately 45 per cent of die fixed expenses. It will be recalled that the tax on water for irrigation purposes constituted about two-thirds of die total taxes. The variable expense averaged $1,295 per farm for the period. It con - sisted of all items not included in the fixed expenses, and ranged from $516 in 1922 to. $3,092 in 1920. For purposes of convenient analysis the variable expense is grouped under five heads—all livestock except work horses, labor, crops, feed and supplies, and miscellaneous. Table 21 gives </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 the amounts spent per farm for each of these groups of variable expense lor years with cash income liclow and above the average for the 21 years. Table 21.— Distribution oj variable cash expense per farm jor the years when cash income was below and above the average \or the 21-year period, 1914 to 19 }4 Number \in..iml ..I utuMc c«|ierne per farm When ..i&gt;h income wji of , I . , I _ FcedanJl . . Toljl __ yean I"""** | U»r | Cn.|« »,pp|i cl |MlKclhncou» Below Ihe ivcucc X S2W 5267 S'&lt;! 5346 S2O 51,015 Ahcvc ihc averace U (of «2 1W 171 .M 1,7t/j I'er teni Below rhe -nrr.i;:e * .V 5 26J 'i.2 3-1.0 2.0 100.(1 Aho.c Hie j\er., K r I! in'l 2v(. 1.1! 26.6 1.9 11)0.0 It is significant that when the farm income was above the average the amount spent for productive livestock was not only relatively higher but higher in dollars spent than tor any other classification listed in Table 21. Furthermore the amount spent for livestock in good years was two and one-third times as much as that spent in poor years, indicating that produc - tive livestock is a flexible phase of the farm business from the standpoint of expenses. This is undoubtedly due to the fact that changes in-income from productive livestock can he realized more quickly than from the other classifications listed. It is also important to note that the amount spent on crops constituted approximately the same proportion of the total variable expenses in both high- and low-income years, and that the pro - portion spent for feed and supplies was high in the low-income years and considerably lower in the high-income years. The rate of increase in the amount spent on crops and labor in good years over poor years is prac - tically the same, indicating a close relationship between crops and labor. (n general the amount of variable expense increases with the size of the larm. The type nt agricultural production in District V is such as to require more expense than that in the other districts. On farms in the same locality where intensive livestock feeding is done, variable expenses are higher than on farms where no feeding is done. CASH INCOME AND EXPENSES Cash income provides the means by which the direct expenses for oper - ating the farm business are met. For the period 1914 to 1934, it averaged 53,366 and varied from 51,828 in 1922 to 56,162 in 1919. The index of prices received by farmers in Nebraska during this period varied from 58 in 1932 to 226 in 1919, with 1910 to 1914 considered as 100. The index of prices paid by farmers in the United States for commodities used in production varied from 99 in 1914 to 192 in 1919, with 1910 to 1914 con - sidered as 100. Table 23 gives the cash income and index of prices received and prices paid by farmers in good and poor years. The average cash income per farm for the poor years was $2,684 and •or the good years §4,516, an increase of $1,832 or 68 per cent. The prices </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Relation of Size of Farm to Farm Expenses Table 22.— Relation, of size of farm to variable expenses per farm by dis~ tricts, 1914 to 1934 .Range "-. Districtl District II District V !!}','*' .\vcrage ( Varialilr Average ' I Variable Avera s e I Variable" ; &gt;ize | expense size I cxpenic size I expense Actet - Acrct Acres i?,' 1 ™¦'•" •¦¦..••'¦••' l&lt;l2 SW 10" 5567- Xl 51.934 . H "220 174 .1020 172 ¦. J 622 165 2,6.) ;, 2-3 M..... 254 1,341 ... .253 956 262 1.726 ¦«"•¦•»• ¦¦•¦• •¦ -359 . UfiJ 351 ... 1,144 369 . 2,387 421-640 ..." ;.... 497 3,411) 511 1.869 546 2,050 Ovrt-H0 892 4.198 941 1.09S 3,240 4.673 , &#132;¦¦'•' IfciUßC . ¦--¦.¦¦' District 111 District IV ••' j Z'htm ; Average I Variable Average I Variable i _ ; ; size I expense size | expense . ' \ Acre. . ' . jtcrti ' ¦'¦S l/';f; 2M-•¦•••¦' " '¦¦¦'¦:¦ ls° S6K&gt; '¦": "» W25 . SJ-JS ¦•¦¦-• ¦ ••.•••. 284. ;-. 1,048 310 457 *'¦«" ¦—•-.. • ¦ •¦•'•¦ 455 W 45.) 780 s;'( * •¦¦ •¦¦¦ : 6i2 l.tai mo. 889 /61'2-"fL, ' "•¦¦¦• ••• '•NJ '-219 l.l" 1.552 ""' 3,262 -1.583 ¦ 2.8 M 2,322 received by farmers in Nebraska were 61 per cent higher for the good years than for the poor years. The average variable cash expenses per farm for the poor years aver - aged 51,584 and for the good years 52,773, an Increase of {1,189, or 75 per cent. The prices paid by farmers for commodities used in production in the United States were only 38 per cent higher for the good years than for the poor years. The increase in the fixed expenses from the poor to the good years was 76 per cent and in the variable expenses 74 per cent. Table 23;— Cash income and variable expense per farm and index of prices received and paid by farmers, 1914 to 1934 ¦'. ¦':.¦ Number - Index of prices' .Vlicn cull inenmc vvas of f-ash Variable Received by Paid by mrs "&gt;-»"« expense /armen in farmcri In • ¦ ¦¦ ¦ "" ' ¦" ¦ : Nebraska the V. S. Below llic. average ....;.......'&gt; :, 52,6«4 . 51,5«4 95 1 |09 ¦ -Abate the arcrasr ................ 1.1 4,516 ' 2,773 IS3 ; 150 Average or loul '•'•¦'." -1 3 '3M . 2.026 13s 131 'For farmers in llic United Slates (I'JIO-M = 1011). . ~ \. For the poor years $1,1.00 were left with which to pay for the family living, use of capital and management, while for the good years $1,743 were available for these purposes. There, was a drastic curtailment in the | replacement of farm capital used in production, such as buildings and ; machinery, during the poor years, and a considerable expenditure for ¦'" replacement during the good years. There was an increase in the expendi - ture for improvements of 124 per cent from the poor, to the good years and for machinery 83 percent. 1 ¦ . ¦;":/¦¦;' ¦¦!¦¦.¦ •. '..¦¦¦-. '¦¦-':¦ i; ,;: ¦ ,;: v/;;;....: ;; '¦¦¦ ¦ / \. :.. ¦¦ ./ \ .¦' . ¦•:¦ ;.¦'¦; ¦'.¦¦ ':¦¦:¦¦¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦¦¦ ": ¦....¦¦¦¦' </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 308 In general, as farms increased in size the cash income was greater and the amount left after deducting the variable expenses was greater. Because the type of agricultural production in Districts 111 and IV is more extensive than in the other districts, the farms are larger, thus mak - ing two size groupings advisable. However, the same general relation - ship of size to income exists in the two groupings. It should not be inter - preted from the foregoing that all farms should be increased in size. Some Table 24. — Relation of size of (arm to cash income and variable expenses per farm Cnh uuonif Cash income Si/c iiroitp AtTOvc Si/c Rroup Atxivc Hi.in.n I. 11. V Toul variable [Jiitricn 111, IV Total variable expense expense Irliler HI 52.36.' S«O3 I'iiilrr 2KI ¦ . SI,KM 5776 141 22" :.r/»2 1.136 2()l.ifiO . . 2,2-47 . 894 -'-'I "&gt;' i.HI 1.519 161-530 .. 2,4.73 1,008 '"14-'" fl!.' 2,210 521-711) ... 2,7112 975 01 Mn I, r: 2.532 rr.l-2.fKKI -1,1.H 1,25-1 "'&lt;' M" * -"•' MSJ. (Ucr l.txtn .... 5;H70 2,281 Tj ¦ — ————— —~^_^_—^—__^_^^^^^__ O /*^^ l***^ \ \ /nR LIVIWC AND yv \ / / \ \ /CAPITAL OBLIGATiOMs/ \ \ K2 " rniAU J \ y /V / VAfl|ABL £ EXPENSE , ' expense olllllll'' ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ i i ¦ , I '"&lt; '»'• i»»4 1929 19J4 Tk;. s.—The Kiul i-j»h inoimc .mil variable expense /ic-r farm for [lie farms studied, l')H lo l'ii-1. Durins jit-rioils of rapidly incrcasinj; prices of farm prmlucls, such as IVIS i.i I'M'i anil I''27 tn l')2'', ihe amount available for living and capital nlili^ati'Tix incrtascs, hm in pt-rinds ol declining prices it tlccrcascs. farms arc at their optimum size now when the capacity of the operator, including his finances, are considered. In some cases they are too large. Figure 5 shows the income, expense, and amount left for living for the farms studied from 1914 to 1934. The amount left for living and capital obligations was less during the low-income years 1921 to 1924 and from 1930 to 1934 than during the high-income years from 1917 to 1920 and from 1925 to 1929. This was due in part to the failure of variable expense to decline as rapidly as the cash income in low-income years. (5M| </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>