<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00077.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Twenty-fifth Annual Report 1933</title>
               <date value="1933">1933</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF Fire Prevention Twenty-fifth Annual Report 1933 CHAS. W. BRYAN GOVERNOR LTNN J. BUTCHER 8TATE j-^ j^g,^ </seg>
            <seg id="p002">The Record of the Year 1933 DEATHS FROM FIRES AS REPORTED BY THE NEWSPAPERS OF THE STATE AND BY FIRE CHIEFS— SUFFERERS FROM BURNS AND INJURIES, PROPERTY LOSS IN IN THE STATE TOTALS $1,833,880.00 There were 1,969 fires reported to the Department — some of which i were very destructive. COMPARATIVE FIGURES FOR TEN YEARS FOR 1933 Deaths, 55: Fires, 1,969; Property Damage, $1,833,880.00 FOR 1932 Deaths, 55; Fires. 2,325; Property Damage, $3,060,344.00 FOR 1931 Deaths, 61; Fires, 2,085; Property Damage, $3,106,633.00 FOR 1930 Deaths, 34; Fires, 2,102; Property Damage, $2,641,425.00 FOR 1929 Deaths, 48; Fires, 2,001: Property Damage, $2,945,866.00 FOR 1928 Deaths, 79; Fires. 1,365; Property Damage, $2,061,853.00 FOR 1927 Deaths, 45; Fires, 2,102; Property Damage, $2,461,245.00 FOR 1926 Deaths, 29; Fires, 1,744; Property Damage, $2,878,677.00 FOR 1925 i Deaths, 49; Fires, 1,577; Property Damage, $2,230,715.00 FOR 1924 Deaths, 34; Fires, 1,485; Property Damage, $1,880,870.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Twenty -fifth Annual Report OF THE State Fire Marshal LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL To His Excellency, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of the State of Nebraska. Your Excellency: In compliance with the law governing this department, which pro - vides that a report of all business transacted, orders issued, and acts performed by the State Fire Marshal, his deputies and others constitut - ing the department be made to you, annually, I take pleasure in sub - mitting this the Twenty-Fifth Annual Report. We appreciate the advice and council you have given us during the past year. The department has been operated well within the funds at Its dis - posal, and whatever measure of success has been obtained has been due to the courteous, loyal and united efforts of everyone connected with the department, the volunteer fire department organizations and the public. Our present deputies and their districts are as follows: M. Henry Mockenhaupt, Inspector West Section of State Louis J. Henning, Inspector South and East of Platte River Howard N. Downing, Inspector ...North and East of Platte River Horace M. Davis, Investigator, _ At Omaha Floyd A. Atkins, Investigator Out-State Sigrid Williams Secretary Dorothy McGinley 7 Stenographer The entire force has worked earnestly and consistently in an effort to reduce fire hazards, and I am pleased to report that their efforts ln this direction have been rewarded in a very gratifying manner. Respectfully submitted, Lincoln, Nebraska, January 1, 1934 LYNN J. BUTCHER, State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Fire Prevention Week Proclamation OCTOBER 8 to 14, 1933 In accordance with the proclamation of the President of the United States and the annual custom in Nebraska I am glad to designate the week of October 8th to 14th as Fire Prevention Week. By proper ob - servance it can be made one of the most useful of all the special days and weeks recognized throughout the state. The State Division of Fire Prevention in co-operation with the Department of Public Instruction is providing a course of study in fire prevention for the schools in accord - ance with legislative enactment. The enormous yearly fire losses cer - tainly justify careful and frequent instruction in this subject and make Fire Prevention Week, too, very much worthwhile. While our fire losses in Nebraska decreased slightly in 1932 over 1931, they are still unreasonably and wholly unnecessarily large. The deaths from fires in 1932 in our state totaled fifty-five, while two hundred twelve persons suffered painful and severe injuries. Gasoline explosions and the starting of fires with kerosene accounted for thirty-three of the deaths and seventy-nine of the injuries. Property loss was still over three million dollars with the following as the leading causes, given in the order of their importance: (1) Sparks from chimneys; (2) Defec - tive chimneys; (3) Careless smokers; (4) Bonfires and burning grass. Year after year these same causes result in disastrous fires which can be and should be prevented. NOW, THEREFORE, I. Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Nebraska, do hereby proclaim the week of October 8th to 14th as Fire Prevention Week and urge that it be so observed in all our schools and homes as well as by civic organizations and with appropriate programs in other public gatherings. May this observance spread information about the prevention, restriction and extinction of fires that will end their severe and unnecessary losses. In witness whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and caused the seal of the Governor to be affixed. Done at Lincoln, Nebraska, this 30th day of September, 1933. I CHARLES W. BRYAN </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 1933 TAX LIST OF INSURANCE COMPANIES PAYING 96 of 1% TAX FOR 1932 BUSINESS DUE JAN. 1, 1933 Aetna Fire Ins. Co _ „.... . $340.07 Agricultural Ins. Co 76.48 Allemania Fire Ins. Co 1.17 Alliance Assurance Co 5g Alliance Ins. Co 17.55 , American Alliance Ins. Co 30.85 American Central Ins. Co 46.52 American Druggists Fire Ins. Co 13.43 1 American Eagle Ins. Co „ 37.95 American Equitable Ins. Co „ 28.36 American &amp; Foreign Ins. Co ] 17.26 American Home Eire Assurance Co 41.66 American Ins. Co. of Newark „ _ 166.25 American Union Ins. Co „ 2.34 Anchor Ins. Co 2.33 Associate Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co 24.53 1 Atlas Assurance Co 27.41 Automobile Ins. Co 34.56 Bankers _. Shippers Ins. Co 9.89 Belt Fire Ins. Co 1.71 Birmingham Fire Ins. Co ... .84 Boston Ins. Co ' 37.03 British American Assurance 32.20 British General 1.97 Buffalo Ins. Co _ „ 51.60 Caledonian of Scotland 47.02 California Ins. Co 1.02 Camden Fire Ins. Ass'n 39.96 Carolina Ins. Co _ 8.44 Central Manufactures Mutual 18.48 Citizens of New Jersey 14.04 City of New York Ins. Co _ 25.17 Columbia Ins. Co 8.68 Commerce Ins. Co _ 6.08 Commercial Union Assurance ___ 52.07 Commercial Union Fire Ins. Co . 2.00 Commonwealth Ins. Co 62.65 Concordia Fire Ins , 48.21 Connecticut Ins. Co 284.28 Continental Ins Co 211.30 County Fire of Philadelphia ... 7.99 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">STATE OF NEBRASKA : 1 Detroit Fire &amp; Marine 22.48 Druggists Mutual Ins 9 49 Dubuque Fire &amp;. Marine g7.g 2 Eagle Fire Co. ._ _ !.02 Eagle Star &amp; British Dominion . 11.23 East &amp; West Ins. Co. _ _ IO.59 Empire State Ins. Co 6.54 Employers Fire Ins. Co _ _ 85.71 Equitable Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co „ 23.71 Eureka Security Fire &amp; Marine 6.56 Farmers Fire (Mutual) „ 13.46 Farmers National Cooperative Elevator Mutual Ins. Ass'n 18.00 Federal Ins. Co .11 Federal Mutual Fire Ins „ 4.02 Federal Union Ins. Co _ „ 12.11 Fidelity &amp; Guaranty Fire Corp .'. 17.11 Fidelity-Phenix Fire Ins. Co _ 217.78 Fire Association of Phil _ 36.51 Firemen's Ins. Co „ 226.00 Firemen's Fund 51.19 First American Ins. Co 8.75 Fitchburg Mutual Fire _ 6.02 Franklin Fire Ins 103.63 Franklin National ; 3.16 Fulton Fire Ins _ „ „ 19.05 General Exchange Ins. Corp _ _ _ 94.95 General ins. Co. of America 3.09 Glrard Fire &amp; Marine „ 32.91 Glens Falls Ins. Co 170.2. Globe &amp; Rutgers Ins. Co _ 682.09 Grain Dealers Nat'l Mut'l 207 09 Granite State Fire Ins. Co _ 32.08 Great American Ins. Co 276.67 Hanover Fire Ins. Co 85.66 Hardware Dealers Mutual Fire „ „ 97.10 Harmonla Fire Ins. Co 100.36 Hartford Fire Ins Co 679.20 Home Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co - 8.86 Homeland Ins. Co. of America 2.71 Home Mutual Ins. Ass'n of Iowa _ _ 12.27 Home Insurance Co „ 662.47 Homestead Fire Ins. Co _ 27.28 Hudson Insurance Co „ 20.81 Imperial Assurance Co 4.72 Implement Dealers Mutual Fire 10.79 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Importers &amp; Exporters 7.10 Indiana Lumbermans Mutual _ 4.76 Insurance Co. of North America 432.60 Insurance Co. of State of Pa. _ 35.45 Inter-Ocean Reinsurance &gt; 66.01 International Ins. Co 167.15 Iowa Hardware Mutual Ins _ _ 1.41 Law Union &amp; Rock Ltd „ 30.50 Lincoln Fire Ins. Co 4.85 Liverpool London &amp; Globe s 187.94 London Assurance Corp _ _ _ 20.80 London &amp; Lancashire _ 71.91 London &amp; Scottish Assur. Corp. Ltd .62 Lumbermens Mutual Ins. Co 13.60 Manhattan Fire &amp; Marine - 3.71 Maryland Ins. Co 11.75 Massachusetts Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co 11.43 Mechanics Ins. Co 61.31 Mercantile Ins. Co ."„. 151.12 Merchants &amp; Manufacturers Fire Ins. Co 6.95 Merchants Fire Assur. Corp 79.56 Merchants Fire Ins. Co 42.51 Merchants Ins. Co _ .". 46.41 Mercury Ins. Co ..; 39.29 Michigan Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co. 47.79 Michigan Millers Mutual Fire Ins 40.84 Millers Mutual Fire Ins. Ass'n 34.95 Millers Mutual of Texas 14.62 Millers Mutual Fire of Penn _ . 8.73 Millers National Ins. Co 37.97 Mill Owners Mutual Ins. Co 94.74 Milwaukee Mechanics . 82.65 Minnesota Implement Mutual . 41.88 Monarch Fire Ins. Co 39.04 National American Ins. Co 309.54 National Ben Franklin Fire 74.00 National Fire Ins. Co 981.92 National Implement Mutual 2.03 National Jewelers Mutual Fire 4.18 National Liberty Fire 104.08 National Reserve Ins. Co 34.91 National Retailers Mutual 35.02 National Security Fire . 262.58 National Union Fire Ins. Co. „ 266.03 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">- STATE OF NEBRASKA Netherlands Ins. Co „ • , 9 52 ' Newark Fire Ins. Co. 61 94 New Brunswick Fire Ins. Co 46.27 New England Fire Ins. Co H 95 New Hampshire Fire 102 27 i New York Underwriters Ins. Co 115.02 New York Fire Ins. Co 18 08 Niagara Fire Ins. Co 26.66 North British &amp; Mercantile Ins. Co 137.78 North Carolina Home Ins. Co : 1 H Northern Assurance Co. Ltd 25.48 North River Ins. Co 43 59 Northern Ins. Co. of N. Y 25.52 ' Northwestern Fire &amp; Marine 52.07 Northwestern Mutual Fire Ass'n 187.08 ! Northwestern National Ins. Co 91.95 Norwich Union Fire Ins. Co 25.90 Occidental Ins. Co 2 30 Ohio Farmers Ins. Co. .., 5g Ohio Hardware Mutual Ins. Co. 09.93 Ohio Millers Mutual 3 g A Old Colony Ins. Co g 82 Orient Ins. Co 12156 Palatine Ins. Co. Ltd 7 ig Patriotic Ins. Co. 2 70 Pennsylvania Fire Ins. Co 103.61 Pennsylvania Lumberman's Mutual Ins. Co 16.14 Pennsylvania Millers Mutual Fire 11.88 Philadelphia Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co 63.51 Phoenix Assurance Co. Ltd. of London 21.85 Phoenix Ins. Co 190 8 o Potomac Ins. Co 0. 58 Preferred Risk Fire Ins. Co 7 1.56 Providence Washington Ins. Co _ 43.37 Prudential of Great Britlan 33 g5 j Queen Ins. Co 13 3 72 ! Reliance Ins. Co. gg Retail Hardware Mutual 81.91 Rhode Island Ins. Co 34.74 Rochester American Ins. Co. of N. Y 12.54 Rocky Mountain Ins. Co 4 g4 Royal Exchange Assurance 56.73 Royal Ins. Co. Ltd 200.94 Safeguard Ins. Co _ -15 5- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Scottish Union &amp; National Ins. Co 80.66 Seaboard Fire &amp; Marine 5.76 Security Ins. Co .-. 110.78 Security Mutual Fire Ins. Co _ 12.79 Sentinel Ins. Co . 11.95 Skanciia Ins. Co _ 22.62 Southern Fire Ins. of N. Y 6.49 Springfield Fire &amp; Marine 424.60 Standard Fire Ins. Co. 2.48 Star Insurance Co 36.32 State Assur. Co. Ltd 5.42 State Farm Mutual Auto Ins. Co „ 66.21 St. Paul Fire &amp; Marine „ ." 450.25 Stuyvesant Ins. Co 40.65 Sun Insurance Office _ 69.66 Sun Underwriters „ 7.66 Superior Fire Ins. Co. . 11.24 Sussex Fire Ins. Co 73.42 Svea Fire &amp; Life Ins. Co. Ltd _ - 21.71 Transcontinental Ins. Co _ 12.04 Travelers Ins. Co _ 182.09 Twin City Ins. Co „ 24.88 I'nion Assurance Society Ltd 4.43 Union Fire Accident &amp; General Ins. Co „ 1.50 Union Ins. Society of Canton Ltd .23 Union Marine &amp;. General Ins. Co : 2.01 United Firemen's Ins. Co 5.06 United Mutual Fire Ins. Co , 44.41 United States Fire Ins. Co 139.96 Victory Ins. Co '. _ .86 Virginia Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co '. .30 Westchester Fire Ins. Co „ 161.71 Western Assurance 18.01 Western Fire Ins. Co 7.16 Western Mutual Fire Ins. Co 75.78 Western Millers Mutual Fire _ „ 28.20 Western Underwriters Mutual Ins _ 2.71 World Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co 7.25 Yorkshire Ins. Co 40.08 114,466.93 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">STATE OF NEBRASKA TOTAL TAX COLLECTED $14,456.93 Balance on hand January 1st, 1933 in treasury 23,545.84 TOTAL FUND AVAILABLE TO COVER 1933 EXPENDITURES- 38,002.77 The above figures show the amount of tax money on hand to cover the expenditures for the year 1933. These expenditures were as follows: SALARIES $12,534.66 OFFICE EXPENSE Printing $ 251.22 Stamps 375.00 Supplies 315.50 Tel &amp; Tel 169.58 Investigation Expenses 930.43 Miscellaneous 47.20 TOTAL :, 2,088.9.. 2.0S8.93 INSPECTOR'S EXPENSES (TRAVELING) Railroad Transportation 89.1.1 Hotel Expenses 3,277.65 Auto Expenses, Taxi and Carfare 3,606.34 Miscellaneous 378.65 TOTAL 7,351.77 7,351.77 .' FIRE REPORT FEES Paid to fire chiefs for reporting 1932 fires.. 1,007.00 1,007.00 TOTAL EXPENDITURES for 1933 $22,982.36 $22 &lt;&lt;S2.36 Total Funds 3R.022.77 Total Expenditures Jan. 1 to Dec. 31, 1933 22.9S2.36 BALANCE ON HAND JANUARY 1, 1934 $15,040.41 SUMMARY OF ACTIVITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT Inspections made ; 12,504 Written orders issued 17,621 Written orders complied with- while inspectors were in town 2.375 Written orders complied with and reported O. K. to office 1,788 Buildings ordered repaired by this department Ill Buildings reported demolished by order of this department 51 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">— • DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Court orders issued on buildings to be demolished 4 Public buildings changing doors to swing outward (churches, hotels, schools, hospitals, lodge halls, dance halls and theatres) 47 '-'■■.,*- New fire escapes installed: Schools _ 3 Apartment houses, dance halls, lodge halls and theatres 8 Iron fire escapes ou schools lowered to floor level and doors placed as exit to escape in place of windows and en - capes repaired 18 Schools extensively repaired 55 Moving picture theatres extensively repaired 27 -"ublic buildings receiving extensive electrical repairs 101 'anic bar locks installed on public buildings 60 kerosene tanks removed from store buildings 88 RESULTS OF INVESTIGATIONS ANALYZED All requests from fire chiefs, adjusters and local officials for assist - ance in investigating suspicious fires during the year have been met ana our best services gladly furnished. I There have been thus investigated 189 fires where the presumption of criminality was in question. Of this number 30 have been farm fires, and 19 clearly of incendiary idiigin; with 13 traceable to the property owners and 6 credited to malice. Two farmers are being treated in insane institutions, although neither is classed as a pyromaniac. Of the total suspicious fires probed for criminal motive the reports [indicate that 57 were traceable to carelessness or accident, leaving 132, jor almost seventy per cent, accredited to incendiarism. Malice or spite induced 26 cases. Property owners to the number of 106 are chargeable with having burned their own homes or stores to collect insurance. Sixty-three investigations out of a total of 189, or 33 percent, were made in Omaha with 9 percent of the population of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">STATE OF NEBRASKA DISPOSED OF AS FOLLOWS Arrested 15 i Sent to Insane Hospitals 3 Confessed 1 . Convicted and paroled : 1 Tried and acquitted 1 Held to District Court 3 Cases dismissed 6 Thirty-six cases are pending in district, supreme or federal courts where arson defenses are plead by the insurance companies. Thirty - three of these cases are contingent upon the determination of criminal charges. CAUSES OF FIRES AS REPORTED BY THE FIRE CHIEFS OF THE STATE DURING 1933 Omaha Lincoln Bai- Total ance of State Unknown causes 91 45 246 382 Sparks from chimney on roof 123 38 140 301 Defective chimney 31 4 118 153 Cigarettes, cigars and pipes 53 4 43 100 Overheated stove, furnace and pipes 28 3 66 97 Defective electric wires and accessories 24 3 51 78 Gasoline and kerosene stoves 5 7 60 72 Incendiary 8 2 33 43 Communicated 15 1 34 50 Spontaneous combustion, oil mops, paint, rags, green hay, etc ~ 4 ~ S"* Children and matches 29 2 31 62 Rubbish In basement ignited by sparks 24 2 12 38 Bonfires and burning grass j 14 3 46 63 Hot ashes against wood I 8 5 21 34 Inflammables too near stoves and stove pipes.. 2 1 26 29 Oil burners ..._ 6 9 16 31 Lightning 1 2 18 21 Careless use of matches 6 2 15 23 Gasoline and kerosene explosions 14 0 23 37 Short in auto wires — . 16 0 25 41 Brooders and incubators and stoves 4 6 25 35 Motor back fires, auto and tractors 5 0 11 16 Thawing out water pipes 7 1 14 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">. DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Klectric curling and flatirons 7 i 2 10 Blow torch and acteylene 7 2 3 12 Heating oils and greases on stoves 2 1 14 17 Washing clothes with gasoline 1 i _o 12 Miscellaneous 10 4 33 47 Oil lamps, lanterns and candles 1 0 10 11 Starting fires with kerosene and gasoline 0 0 8 8 Mice and matches 10 7 8 Gas stoves and heater explosions 0 0 16 16 Fire-place 2 2 5 9 Sparks from engines 3 1 6 10 Motion picture films ignited 0 0 2 2 Fumigating 2 0 0 2 Hot exhaust pipes 4 0 5 9 Fireworks 1 0 9 10 Overheated motors 2 0 10 12 Total number of fires 575 156 1288 2019 Less communicated fires 15 1 34 50 560 155 1254 1969 CLASS OF PROPERTY PARTLY OR ENTIRELY BURNED Omaha Lincoln Out- Total i. state Dwellings j 339 g3 640 1062 Stores 43 5 g 6 134 Private an.l commercial garages and tire shops 46 15 62 123 Granaries and sheds 24 3 74 101 Restaurants 4 2 16 22 Apartment and rooming houses J 17 8 8 33 Store houses 7 0 18 25 Chicken hatcheries and brooders 9 9 41 59 Autos and trucks 28 4 59 91 Barns and stables 16 3 127 146 Picture shows and theatres _ 10 5 6 Schools 0 1 13 14 Elevators _ 0 0 16 16 Manufacturing 11 6 9 26 Hotels .„„.._ 3 2 8 13 Railroad buildings and cars 7 2 9 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">STATE OF NEBRASKA Offices 3 0 9 12 Storage and filling stations _ 4 0 17 21 Cleaning establishments . 3 2 4 19 Churches _ 3 1 7 11 Banks 0 0 4 4 Laundries 0 0 1 1 Dance halls and lodge halls 0 16 7 Pool halls 2 0 5 7 Cream stations 0 0 11 11 Blacksmith shops 0 0 4 4 Stockyards 10 0 1 Lumber and Coal yards 1 2 8 11 C^ub and road houses 4 0 0 4 Orphanage 1 o 0 1 Barber shops 0 0 7 7 Soft-drink parlors 4 0 .1 5 Hospitals 0 0 3 3 Miscellaneous 1 3 10 14 Jails 0 0. 2 2 I TOTAL 582 152 1290 2024 ! OUR COOK WAS A TREASURE i HER WHEAT CAKES A PLEASURE I HER COFFEE WAS FINE 1 AND HER WAFFLES DIVINE I BUT SHE LEFT IN A HURRY AND SHE HASN'T BEEN SEEN SINCE SHE STARTED THE FIRE WITH A CAN OF KEROSENE MOTHER BUSY IRONING, ELECTRIC HEATING FINE PHONE RINGS MERRILY, DEAR FRIEND ON THE LINE CONVERSATION LENGTHY, IRON FORGOTTEN QUITE | FIRE DID ITS BEST, BUT WE MUST MOVE TONIGHT THE MORAL OF THIS TALE IS WHAT MIGHT BE EXPECTED BfiFORE YOU LEAVE YOUR IRON, BE SURE IT'S DISCONNECTED </seg>
            <seg id="p017">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION FIRE LOSS FOR THE THIRTY-TWO TOWNS OVER 2500 POPULATION— WITH THE EXCEPTION OF OMAHA AND LINCOLN DURING 1930-1931-1932-1933 Popula- No. Per Capita Loss By Years Town tion Fires Loss 1933 1932 1931 1930 Filrbury 6,192 21 1,017.00 .16 .64 1.27 6.12 McCook 6,688 21 1,500.00 .22 5.66 1.59 1.90 Gtering 2,531 4 764.00 .30 .32 .27 .09 Superior 3,044 8 1,725.00 .36 1.27 1.30 1.28 Chadron 4,606 22 1,900.00 .41 7.82 2.52 1.64 pjalls City 5,787 26 2,670.00 .44 6.66 .98 30.72 Sidney 3,306 2 1,820.00 .55 .1.82 145 1.41 Blair 2,865 12 1,746.00 .62 .35 .41 .13 Wahoo 2,689 7 1,793.00 .66 1.41 3.95 3.56 Wymore 2,680 10 1,823.00 .68 3.82 2.04 11.23 Grand Island.... 18,041 41 12,371.00 .69 2.34 11.39 7.88 Scottsbluff 8,465 1 5,975.00 ' .70 1.68 1.10 2.37 Hastings 15,490 46 11,097.00 .71 1.24 2.15 1.88 AJlliance 6,669 17 4,816.00 .72 1.29 1.17 .11 Worth Platte 12,061 11 9,825.00 .80 .39 .50 .32 cjolumhus 6,886 20 5,506.00 .81 .54 3.99 1.46 Y|ork 5,712 16 5,035.00 .88 .33 2.12 3.63 Crete 2,791 11 2,502.00 .89 2.70 .34 3.10 Beatrice 10,297 22 9,595.00 .93 18.56 10.61 5.06 Norfolk 10,717 12 12,183.00 1.13 1.65 3.60 10.23 Holdrege 3,263 6 3,736.00 1.14 2.03 .57 4.17 Broken Bow .... 2,715 2 3,800.00 1.39 4.56 1.46 2.62 Nebraska City.. 7,230 11 1,064.00 1.47 1.58 .82 3.55 Lexington 6,192 4 10,710.00 1.72 1.94 23.94 5.24 Auburn 3,068 16 6,053.00 1.96 1.40 2.67 4.78 Aurora 2,715 8 5,895.00 2.17 1.04 1.19 1.05 So. Sioux City.. 3,927 25 9,398.00 2.40 3.63 2.34 3.35 Kearney 8,575 15 25,699.00 2.99 1.19 4.65 1.44 Seward 2,737 13 8,978.00 3.20 1.61 .24 4.67 Plattsmouth .... 3,793 9 15,290.00 4.04 2.25" 2.37 3.92 Fremont 11,407 38 62,730.00 5.49 7.81 8.10 4.36 Schuyler 2.588 3 198,650.00 76.75 .89 11.74 .67 TOTAL LOSS 447,720.00 THE FIRE LOSS OF THESE THIRTY-TWO TOWNS REPRESENT ONE-THIRD OF THE TOTAI OUTSTATE FIRE LOSS. Schuyler had one fire, that of Wells, Abbott, Nleman Elevator Com - pany fire, total loss $197,000, placing Schuyler at the end of the list. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">FIRE LOSSES BY COUNTIES C0UNTY Val. Bldg. ins. Bldg. Dam. Bldg. Val. Cont. Ins. Cont. Dam. Cont. Adams 122,025.00 72,100.00 7,539.00 55,530.00 43 625.00 4.160.00 ISpe Y-— 1 44,075.00 27,970.00 13.295.00 19.630.00 9.650.00 7,103.00 Arthur No reports received Banner -. • No reports receive. Blaine - "J ""So 00 7 663.00 13,548.00 11.700.00 4.104.00 f yd * 1 5 ' 761.00 5,600.00 3,800.00 738.00 g 22, ri.. 3 4: 3 25.00 23,500.00 17.605.00 30.615.00 23,160.00 2,015.00 ~ £■* : N ° reC T 8 ?00.00 6.300.00 12,300.00 3.600.00 2.850.00 | C ,erry « s 5 U 000 00 3 525.00 17.600.00 16.000.00 2,499.00 eye " ne : 7 S 0 ' ' H.100.00 H.000.00 7.270.00 4.847.00 Clay , ' 0 65 0 00 H6125.00 161,275.00 27.850.00 24.951.00 ° 0,laX 'J 'Jo 6 500 26.471.00 20,600.00 8,250.00 7.411.00 CumiDg ' 7 ' £ 8 420.00 11.950.00 5,850.00 3,065.00 SS ::: S S££ 10:193.00 1^5.00 12,500.00 2,7^0 dK ° la 5 300 00 2,800.00 275.00 850.00 none none DaW6S , ' Jo. 37 000 00 13,555.00 42,665.00 28,100.00 29,275.00 \l e T.ZZZZZZZZZZZ So. SSSL L A400.00„„ _ 1L050.00 5,000.00 97,00, .; </seg>
            <seg id="p019">"l)i___E7. 77777777777777E .sTiooToo' 1s.200.oo ' 23.2e5.00 14,175.007^ 5,400.00 11, 255.00 Dodge Z. 294,935.00 180,692.00 56,258.00 106,745.00 67,740.00 24,650.00 COUNTY Val. Bldg. Inn. Bldg. Dam. Bldg. Val. Cont. Ins. Cont. Dam Cont. Douglas 40,550.00 . 30,200.00 10,119.00 18,550.00 14,950.00 1 564.00 Dundy ..' 5,325.00 2,400.00 4,525.00 2,955.00 1,400.00 1,975.0. Fillmore 1,150.00 400.00 950.00 250.00 none 50.00 Franlclin 21,400.00 12,900.00 6,058.00 15,040.00 12,080.00 3,223.00 Frontier 3,400.00 1,500.00 3,400.00 3,000.00 1,600.00 2.700.00 0 Furnas 222,075.00 139.875.00 25,420.00 59,375.00 35,400.00 19,640.00 Sj Gage ...11. 237,485.00 150,226.00 24,648.00 77,130.00 73,270.00 10.891.00 w Garden No reports received § Garfield . No reports received O GoS p- r 300.00 none 300.00 260.00 260.00 260.00 *l G r a nt 4,800.00 3.000.00 620.00 600.00 400.00 10.00 | Gre eiey 5,325.00 3,100.00 70.00 2,600.00 1,250.00 25.00 gj Hall 316,225.00 289,000.00 9,151.00 303,085.00 282,150.00 13.860.00 g Hamilton 18,675.00 14.450.00 5,160.00 14,565.00 3,775.00 10,150.00 | Harian 52,250.00 30,250.00 9,022.00 13,790.00 10,500.00 3,811.0. | Hayes No reports received 2 Hitchcock 46,050.00 11,725.00 3,450.00 22,150.00 21,400.00 1,350.00 g Holt 49,050.00 24 550.00 6,560.00 35,880.00 17,475.00 2,927.00 £ Hooker 6,000.00 3,800.00 275.00 2,800.00 1,800.00 90.00 Howard 25,225.00 19,160.00 8,501.00 6,612.00 2,900.00 759.00 Jefferson 164,970.00 156.800.00 7,120.00 38,400.00 32,700.00 1.917.00 Kearne ~ 15,000.00 8,650.00 3,015.00 6,000.00 2,300.00 700.00 KeIth 193,300.00 104,000.00 11,180.00 51,250.00 37,250.00 10.301.00 Keyapaha No reports received Johnson 83,055.00 56,100.00 28,045.00 24,937.00 26,373.00 13.754.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Kimball ....... - .'. 2,000.00 1,500.00 1,100.00 1,400.00 800.00 1,400.00 Knox 52,400.00 33.900.00 12,786.00 21,625.00 13,950.00 6.643.00 COUNTY Val. Bldg. 1ns. Bldg. Dam. Bldg. Val. Cont. Ins. Cont. Dam. Cont Lancaster 31,250.00 27,600.00 12,110.00 19,185.00 800.00 18,436.00 ' Lincoln 54,000.00 38,400.00 14,770.00 22,800.00 11,100.00 5,700.00 Logan 6,500.00 5,000.00 785.00 3,500.00 3,250.00 2,025.00 Loup 600.00 300.00 150.00 125.00 — — 125.00 McPherson No reports received Madison 122,925.00 88,850.00 17,405.00 75,670.00 19,212.00 4.734.00 Merrick .- 48,845.00 29,300.00 18,666.00 25,367,00 14,200.00 11,287.00 w Morrill 7 16,730.00 12,250.00 3,440.00 13,600.00 — £ Nance 20,700.00 13.900.00 1,960.00 13,720.00 2,700.00 | Nemaha 46,750.00 37,800.00 3,318.00 26,250.00 11,075.00 2,890.00 Q Nuckolls 57,850.00 38,200.00 7,030.00 23,525.00 13,220.00 1,500.00 « Otoe .'. 119,250.00 95,800.00 27,182.00 81,655.00 62,300.00 11,207.00 2 Pawnee 44,575.00 34,600.00 18.6-10.00 15,825.00 8,250.00 6,000.00 gj Perkins 12,250.00 9,700.00 4,690.00 16,600.00 11,500.00 6.975.00 P Phelps 11,935.00 9,200.00 8,286.00 4,525.00 1,850.00 1 800.00 «j Pierce 30,950.00 18.400.00 1,428.00 14,215.00 7,500.00 . 1.330.00 £ Platte 129,995.00 83,700.00 12.987.00 45,815.00 22,565.00 4.877.00 Polk 14,650.00 11,250.00 2,910.00 4,940.00 2,650.00 630.00 Redwillow 46,255.00 3G.700.00 1,350.00 9,765.00 5,700.00 345.00 Richardson 114,740.00 83,625.00 19,675.00 52,135.00 27,825.00 10,352.00 Rock 7. 1,275.00 350.00 197.00 975.00 — Saline 34,460.00 57,800.00 S.108.00 20,540.00 20,287.00 3,805.00 Sarpy :..".. 10,300.00 9,200.00 870.00 1,300.00 ... 100.00 120.00 Saunders 61,850.00 41,200.00 11,190.00 28,610.00 21,980.00 6.048..0 Scotts Bluff 82,215;0O - - 44,650.00 - 10,547.00 27,235.00 16,300.00 3.607.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Seward ...7... 66,410.00 46,300.00 20,329.00 49,585.00 "V 33,000.00 28.274.00 Sheridan 3,475.00 1,250.00 2,600.00 1,250.00 15.00 45.00 Sherman 7,000.00 5,000.00 850.00 14,600.00 12,000.00 5.C25.00 Sioux - No reports received Stanton 2,000.00 1,000.00 ;', 550.00 500.00 300.00 Thayer 43,400.00 30,450.00 4,525.00 11,870.00 7,100.00 4,867.00 Thomas 4,300.00 • 3.200.00 3,600.00 600.00 200.00 100.00 Thurston 8,750.00 4,050.00 3,150.00 4,960.00 3,000.00 1,295.00 Valley 37,025.00 19.800.00 30,060.00 9,017.00 2,100.00 3,667.00 § Washington 31,285.00 25,860.00 8,830.00 13,295.00 7,800.00 2 425.00 % Wayne 55,350.00 41,050.00 4,469.00 23,525.00 13,700.00 5,942.00 O Webster 90,700.00 69,700.00 4,385.00 13,900.00 8,700.00 1,155.00 *• Wheeler No reports received § York 75,400.00 56.725.0U 43,440.00 23,752.00 20,370.00 13,701.00 « 7 7/7 7 E- N | Val. of Ins. on Dam. to Val. of Ins. on Dam. to § Buildings Buildings Buildings Contents Contents Contents o OUTSTATE _ 4,537,970.00 3,f*43,018.0o 914,602.00 2,181,810.00 1,407,477.00 438.356.00 * LINCOLN 1,658,705.00 1,317.100.00 31,074.00 973,490.00 886,990.00 14,711.00 OMAHA 4,055,217.00 3,208,987.00 204,353.00 1,304,985.00 977,703.00 230,784.00 GRAND TOTAL- 10,251,892.00 7.569,106.00 1,150,029.00 4,460,285.00 3,272,170.00 683,851.00 TOTAL VALUE OF BUILDINGS AND CONTENTS O.V WHICH FIRE LOSSES OCCURRED 14,712,177.00 TOTAL INSURANCE ON BUILDING AND CONTENTS ON WHICH FIRE LOSSES OCCURRED.... 10,841,275.00 I TOTAL LOSS ON BUILDING AND CONTENTS WHERE FIRES OCCURRED 1.833.S80.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">STATE OF NEBRASKA RURAL FIRES The farm fire loss, as reported by fire chiefs in the different towns of our state, Is only a small percent of the actual fire loss in tho rural districts, for only the fires where the department is called to participate are reported to this office. These losses are included in the total fire loss as reported by counties. Loss of buildings $220,709.00 Loss of contents 77,750.00 TOTAL LOSS $298,459.00 Country fires invariably result in total losses. Few of the rural communities are equipped and organized for fighting fires. More homes are destroyed by fire than by wind. Defective chimneys and flues are the cause of many great losses of farm property. Every farm should be equipped with ladders long enough to reach the highest point of any of the buildings, and water buckets should be kept handy, so that In case of lire they can be readily filled and used to extinguish tbe fire. Starting and hastening fires with gasoline or kerosene causes the great - est sacrifice of life and property. During the late depression many farm - ers have had their telephones removed. This is an added menace, for how may he call the fire department, or his neighbor, in case of fire? It therefore, behooves the farmer to make a rigid inspection of his prem - ises each day, eliminating the fire causes, so that the great unnecessary fire loss may be reduced. FIRE PREVENTION CAMPAIGN ON RURAL SCHOOLS During the month of August letters were mailed to 6,126 rural school teachers, containing a poster depicting "Thirty-five Common Causes of Fire ln the Home", that we recommended framed and placed in each rural schdol — and a questionalre covering fire hazards in the school buildings to be filled in by the teacher and returned to the State Flr» Marshal. Orders were then Issued to the Board Members in accordance with the information on the questionalre. By December 31st about 2,000 schools had complied with their orders, and when school takes up in September, 1934, we hope to have 100% compliance. It was found that more than 75% of the school doors opened Inward, which Is In violation of the state law. In almost every Instance heavy screens were nailed on windows — very few, if any, of the schools were epuipped with fire extinguishers — stove pipes were too close to wood, </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION i and there were either no stove boards underneath stoves, or the ones there did not extend far enough to be a protection from hot coals ana ashes. TOTAL DEATHS FROM FIRES Men ..•- 20 Women 16 Children 11 Firemen 8 TOTAL 55 CAUSES OF DEATHS Kerosene explosions 5 Starting fire with kerosene 12 j Gasoline explosions 8 Clothing caught fire from stoves 2 Cleaning clothes with gasoline 3 Playing with matches .'. 1 1 Electricity _ 2 i Automobiles 3 Miscellaneous „ 11 Firemen fighting fires ... 8 TOTAL 55 TOTAL IN.JURIES FROM FIRES Men _ 90 Women _ 34 Children 7 23 Firemen injured 47 TOTAL 19. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">STATE OF NEBRASKA CAUSES OF INJURIES Cleaning clothes with gasoline 10 Kerosene explosions .'..-. 12 Gasoline explosions - 47 Fire works - 6 Automobiles 11 Firemen fighting fires 48 Electricity 2 Filling kerosene lamps and stoves 2 Heating oils b Playing with matches 5 Miscellaneous 45 TOTAL : 194 FIRE PROTECTION IS NOT ENOUGH A short time ago in an Iowa city, a mother of two children pul five gallons of gasoline in the electric washing machine in the basement of her home. Then she started the motor. A terrific explosion followed immediately. The mother was killed, the father injured, and r.he home wrecked. A few moments later a spic and span, well equipped ami well trained fire department was at the curb. All of the fire departments in the world could have been there — but the mother was dead. The only thing which could have saved her was effective fire prevention educa - tion, and of course that has to be done before the fire. "I HAVE TOO MUCH HAIR," SAID ANGELINE AS SHE CLEANED HER GLOVES WITH GASOLINE "IT'S FAR TOO LONG AND IN THE WAY, TAKES AN HOUR TO COMB IT EVERY DAY. I'LL HAVE IT BOBBED AND BE IN STYLE AND LIVE REJOICING ALL THE WHILE." SHE RUBBED HER GLOVES, GOT ALL EXCITED AND, OF COURSE, THE GASOLINE IGNITED AFTER THE FIRE, SHE SAID. WITH A SOB, "NOW I NEED HAIR INSTEAD OF A BOB." V </seg>
            <seg id="p025">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Deaths From Fires AINSWORTH— Burns suffered while kindling a fire with kerosene caused the death of Mrs. Leo Fry (see injured) ARNOLD — Mrs. August Blixt died of burns suffered when a kettle or soap she was boiling down ignited setting her clothes on fire. AUBURN — Joseph T. Boyles Jr., 25, was burned to death when the ;plano he was flying struck a tree, (see injured) BEATRICE — While starting a fire in a furnace with kerosene, James R. Starkey, 45, received burns causing his death. BIG SPRINGS — The charred body of Henry Kallsen was found beside the furnace — it was apparent he had started the fire with kerosene. BLAIR — John Murray, 56, died of burns suffered when he stumbled, breaking the kerosene lamp, spraying flaming oil over him. BOELTTS — Little Alice Hilmer, 11, was horribly burned, causing her death, when her dress became ignited from a burning log. (see in - jured) BROKEN BOW— Mrs. Mary Atkisson, 38, died from burns received in a gasoline explosion. BROWNVILLE — The two year old daughter of Wilson Sigerson died from severe burns received when the mother attempted to start a fire in the kitchen range, using gasoline. CALLAWAY — Robert Bennett, 24, died of burns sustained when he started a furnace fire with kerosene. CAMBRIDGE — Irvin Juehn, 23, was fatally burned when his bed caught on fire — being a cripple he was unable to save himself. CHADRON— In an attempt to light a gas water heater, it exploded, caus - ing the death of Mrs. Lenora Vannetta. COZAD — Mrs. Gusta Herbst died from burns received when gasoline exploded with which she was cleaning a clock. Her husband, watch - ing the job, lit his pipe, resulting in the fatal injury. DALTON — Small two-year old child, of Harley Ellis died of burns re ceived when the home burned. FAIRBURY — Herbert Hansen was killed while filling the lamp causing an explosion and his 2 yr. old son Robert Dean died ot burus suf - fered in the explosion, (see injured) </seg>
            <seg id="p026">STATE OF NEBRASKA FREMONT — Mrs. Frank Tomas, 24, received burns that proved fatal, while starting a fire with kerosene. FREMONT — Marjorie Barrett, 15, died of burns suffered when she poured kerosene over a fire in the kitchen stove. GORDON — Gasoline ignited while filling a grain combine engine causing the death of Lawrence Johnson. KEARNEY — Burns from an electric heating pad caused the death of .Miss Florence Baker, 46. GRAND ISLAND — Cooped in a boy's clubhouse which became a blazing crate, Donald Brown, 11, suffered fatal burns. He had a lighted candle from which he was to light fire cracker punk. The burlap tacked inside the crate made escape impossible. KEARNEY — Leona Belle Browne, 23, died of burns accidentally receive - while kindling a kitchen stove fire. KEARNEY — The charred body of Ferdinand Mauler, 47, was found in the ruins of his burned home. LOUP CITY — An explosion, caused from gasoline being used for cleaning clothes, resulted in the death of Helen Lorchick. (see injured) LYMAN — Milton Floyd Milberger, 8, died of burns suffered when he used kerosene to start, a fire. LINCOLN — Mrs. William Waybright, 37, was critically burned, when she mistook gasoline for kerosene in speeding the furnace fire. McCOOK— Burns proved fatal to little Joseph Schilz, 6, when the play house on the school ground was found in flames. The teacher pulled Joseph from the fire — evidently he had been playing with matches. NELSON — Peter Jensby, 61, was found fatally burned by firemen when they were summoned to extinguish the fire. It is believed ho tried to pour oil in the stove and his clothing caught on fire. NORFOLK — William Eastburn's charred body was found behind the wheel of his burning car, in a closed garage. Cause of fire u_k_own. OMAHA — Adam Sassenberger, 79, suffocated as blaze cut off exit when fire gutted the Sacred Heart rectory. OMAHA — George Ferris, 3, was burned to death at St. James' Orphanage when a flannel tent covering the boy's bed was ignited, due to de - fective wiring in the electrical appliance with which he was being treated for croup. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION OMAHA — Pouring gasoline over the clothing of her five month's old boy and herself caused the death of the baby and Mrs. Elizabeth Flynn, 28. OMAHA — Jens Sorensen, 70, was fatally burned following an explosion when he used coal oil to hasten the fire. OMAHA — Little Raymond Andersen, 4, died from burns suffered when he took gasoline and poured it over a dead duck's body, lighting a match to burn it. (see injured) OMAHA — Julius Agazoni, 82, was burned to death following a gas stove explosion in his home. OMAHA — A motor truck, loaded with wood, plunged into a ditch and burned. Fred Mitchell, 34. was pinned under the burning heap, and it was found impossible to extricate him. (see injured) OVERTON — Matt Wilson died from injuries suffered while blasting a hole for the installation of a septic tank, a stick of dynamite explod - ed at his feet. OMAHA — Battalion Chief Howe lost his life in the Browning King fire, January 3rd. ROCA — T. Otway Cherry, farmer, was fataUy burned following an ex - plosion while building a fire with kerosene. SCOTTSBLUFF— Mrs. John Hlegel, 26, died of burns suffered when her husband poured kerosene on the fire in the cook stove, causing au explosion, (see Injured) SIDNEY — Mr. Walter Mathews .was fatally burned when an oil refining tank exploded, (see Injured) STANTON — Richard Kirkland, 35, died of burns received when his live - stock truck turned over and was destroyed by Are. STANTON — Ed Beeler lost his life when his house burned — it is be - lieved he suffocated while attempting to put water on the fire. TECUMSEH— Mrs. Lillie Young, 59, was fatally burned when a pan of kerosene was upset on a kitchen stove. TOBIAS — Mrs. Harry Spicka died as a result of burns suffered when a kerosene lamp exploded, (see injured) WEST POINT — Attempting to start a furnace fire with kerosene caused the death of Helen Will. YORK — Mrs. Gene Murray succumbed as a result of burns received when her clothing caught fire while too near the heating stove. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">i STATE OF NEBRASKA Injuries From Fires AINSWORTH— Leo Fry and two children were severely burned while attempting to drag Mrs. Leo Fry from the room, hex clothing envel - oped in flames, (see deaths) AINSWORTH— O. E. Taylor suffered third degree burns about the head and chest when his car was consumed by fire following a crash. AINSWORTH— An explosion of solvent in a cleaning plant caused burns to Glen Johnson's legs and abdomen and also burned Henry Sawyers about the face. ALLIANCE— When a gasoline heater exploded, H. McClean was burned on the arm. ARAPAHOE— Ray Swertfeger was painfully burned when an acetylene torch exploded. ARNOLD— Ed Johnson saw a prairie fire approaching— he sought safety by standing on the seat of his lister, from which he had hurriedly un - hitched the team. His face and arms were severely burned. AUBURN— Barton Furlong and E. D. Karsten were testing a plane— it struck a tree and caught on fire— they were slightly burned (see deaths) BARADA— While pouring gasoline on ant hills, Henry Arnold, 21, spillea some on his overalls. When he struck a match his garments ignited, burning his legs. BARTLEY— Ed Taylor was severely burned about the face, and hands when trapped in the wreckage of railroad cars. BAYARD— Mrs. Charles Suit was painfully burned while cleaning cloth - ing in gasoline. The explosion lifted the small wash house off Its foundation and blew two persons out of the doorway. BEATRICE— Son of Mr. and Mrs. G. F. Smith was burned on tbe back while escaping from the burning bed room— caused by cigarette left burning. BENSON-Roth Mr. and Mrs. Olds were singed about the face and hands in trying to save their personal effects from the burning home, re - sulting from the flareup of a gasoline stove. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION BOELUS — Henry Hilmer was severely burned about the hands and arms when he endeavored to tear the burning clothing from his daughter's body, (see deaths) BLAIR — While cleaning clothes with gasoline, Mrs. Edna Nobel and daughter, Elizabeth, suffered severe burns. BLAIR — Earl Jenkins, Jr., 14, was badly burned when he backed into a bonfire built by ice skaters. BRAINARD — As Joseph Matejcek was throwing kerosene, from a can, on burning stumps, his hand slipped and splashed oil over him, inflict - ing severe burns on his left shoulder, arm and hand. BRIDGEPORT — Walter Blanton, 6, and his brother, 3, were burned se - verely as the result of an explosion from gasoline when poured on a fire. BRIDGEPORT — Loyd Payne received burns when gasoline exploded as he was attempting to light the gasoline stove. BROWNVILLE — Mrs. Wilson Sigerson was badly burned when Fhe at - tempted to start a Are in the kitchen range with gasoline, (see deaths) COPENHAGEN — Mrs. Albert Kerchoff escaped death when her dress became ignited by flames from a brooder stove. Her dress was burned off to the waist — she rolled on the ground extinguishing the flames. COZAD — Miss Mabel Lindell, teacher, suffered severe burns from a blast of oil to boost a slow fire. CRAB ORCHARD — Martin Lovitt, 14, had a narrow escape when he at - tempted to hurry a smouldering fire in the furnace with kerosene — an explosion followed in which he was burned about the face and neck. CRAWFORD — R. C. Franks, Fritz Pierson and Stanley Meidel narrowly escaped death when Meidel applied an acetylene torch to a leak in a l gasoline tank. Gasoline had been drained from the tank and com - pressed air forced into It in an attempt to remove the lingering fumes. DESHLER — Henry Fangmeyer's son was burned about the face when he ■i opened a door of a blazing barn. DORCHESTER — While starting a fire with kerosene an explosion fol - lowed burning James Hulse badly. DORCHESTER— C. D. Ward was standing close to a gasoline engine when It backfired. He had a can of gasoline In his hand when he jumped, splashing the liquid over his face and head, causing severe burns. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">STATE OF NEBRASKA FAIRBURY — Frank Lea's hand was burned; Art Richardson's clothing caught on fire, causing second degree burns to his entire right side when a fire cracker was lighted in the car setting off other fire works. FAIRBURY — Mrs. Herbert Hansen was painfully burned when an ex - plosion occurred as Mr. Hansen was filling the lamp, (see deaths) FAIRBURY — Mrs. L. Peasley was cleaning a hat with Napatha _as in the front room of her home, the fumes ignited from the heating stove, causing slight burns to her hands and scorching her hair. Mr. Leigh, a neighbor, was burned about the hands and legs while endeavoring to extinguish the fire. FALLS CITY — When the gasoline stove flared up, Mrs. Judy was burned on both hands. FALLS CITY — Mrs. J. Martin was painfully burned when the gasoline can ignited while filling the stove.. FREMONT — Hans Nielsen, Jr., applied gun powder paste for relief from poison ivy — a cigarette spark ignited the powder and he was severe - ly burned. GERING — A son of John W. Cross was burned on the arm when a gaso - line stove exploded. GRAND ISLAND — Gerald Caredis, 12, may lose the sight of his right eye as a result of a fire cracker explosion. GRAND ISLAND — Endeavoring to put out the fire in his garage, before the fire department arrived, Chas. Powell was painfully burned. HARTINGTON — Accumulated gas fumes In an empty tank, that Olof Klanderud was preparing to weld with a blow torch, exploded. In - juring himself, Irving Kleinberg and Dale Mallat. HASTINGS — When cleaning a vacuum sweeper in a pan of gasoline, Mrs. Geo. Munson turned on the switch. An explosion followed, setting fire to her clothing, burning her painfully. HOOPER — Mr. Soren Nelson was badly burned about the hands and face while trying to get his horses out of the burning barn. HOWELLS — Joseph Pimper, 33, was slightly burned when his truck was wrecked and burned. JUNIATA — A stick of dynamite exploded in the hands of Laverne Her - rington, 27, causing the loss of his right hand, burns to his chest and face. KEARNEY — Karl Randecker, a machinist, was severely burned about the face as an explosion occurred while he was welding a leak in a gasoline truck. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION KEARNEY — Leona Brown, 23, school teacher, was given an even chance to live after the explosion of an oil can with which she was start - ing a fire. LAUREL — Anna Raasch poured gasoline instead of kerosene on the kitchen fire to hasten it. The can exploded, covering her with the flaming liquid — her clothing was completely burned off. LINCOLN— Mrs. Charles E. Mitchell, 28, was painfully burned about the arms and face when the gasoline in which she was cleaning a garment exploded.. LINCOLN— Four University students were painfully burned when a ni - trous oxide machine exploded during a laboratory period— they were Lucille Mills, Charles Werner, Elmer Razloff and Banks Gayman. LINCOLN — Louis Shcultz, 62, was burned by a corrosive plumbing mix - ture that exploded. LINCOLN — Fire, started by the overflowing of a gasoline stov-i, caused slight burns to Charles Deneke's face. LINCOLN— Wilson Robinson suffered slight burns when the bake oven exploded. LINCOLN— Small son of Mr. and Mrs. Beebe was slightly burned when .■•:■ a fire cracker exploded. LINCOLN— Edward Denery, 53, was severely burned while asleep in a box car — a stranger dropped a match in a pile of papers on the floor, setting his clothing on fire. LINCOLN — Lola May Feldt, 2, suffered mild burns on the chest, arm ond mouth while playing with matches. LINCOLN — Captain Short of the fire department was burned on the ankle by hot tar that caught on fire. LINCOLN — Mrs. Jack Pickle suffered slight burns when the lunch car was totally destroyed by fire caused by the explosion of a gasoline stove. LINCOLN — James Little, Jr., 2V. years old, played too near the gas stove — his clothing caught on fire — he fanned the flames by running and collided with his little 6 months old brother, who was also slightly burned. LINCOLN — In attempting to throw an exploded oil stove out of the kitchen, Calvin Pierce, 15, was severely burned on both legs. LINCOLN — Father Qulnn was burned when the Sacred Heart rectory burned, (see deaths) </seg>
            <seg id="p032">STATE OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN — When fire destroyed a wagon load of hay, Lee Brooks suf - fered severe burns on his left hand while releasing his team from the blazing wagon. LOUP CITY — Mrs. Floyd Lewandowski was burned about the face when the gasoline stove exploded while refilling the tank. LOUP CITY — Mrs. Bruno Lorchick received painful burns when she attempted to extinguish the flames in her daughter's clothing caused by gasoline exploding as she was cleaning clothes. MADRID — Some lard was placed in the oven and forgotten — it started to burn and Mrs. Minnnie Selle threw some water on it — inflicting severe burns on the arms, legs, face and back of both herself and Helen Selle. MARSLAND — Rev. Priestly, 71, pastor of the M. E. Church, suffered burns on his left hand when a welding tank exploded in a garage at the rear of his home. MELBETA — While attempting to extinguish a fire in the radio, started after a transformer line burned out. Mrs. A. R. Keever suffered severe burns. MINATARE — While cleaning clothes in gasoline, Mrs. C. N. Van Dyke was slightly burned. MINATARE — C. Lane, gas fitter, was badly burned on face and arms in making his escape from a gas filled basement, ignited from the furnace. OCONTO — The car upset, pinning Mick Wilcox underneath it, the muffler of the car pressed against his back causing a burn one foot long and six inches wide. OHIOWA — Charles Johnson, fireman, was injured falling from a fire truck when returning from a country fire. OMAHA — Wlnnifred Wermuth, 37, was severely burned about the face and hands while attempting to extinguish a fire caused by an over - heated stove. OMAHA — Jacob Oster and William Jones were burned in an explosion at the Nebraska Grain Company elevator. OMAHA — A gas stove exploded severely burning Mrs. Minnie Iaenihan. 55, and Helen Karls, 14. OMAHA— Charles Slutzky, 4, was playing with a candle beside the gas stove, his clothing caught fire, he ran into the street — Keller seized him, smothering the flames, burning both hands. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION OMAHA — Richard Brubber was slightly burned when rescuing three animals from a barn that was destroyed by fire, caused from spon - taneous combustion. OMAHA — Rosetta Loncar, 3, was severely burned on the left thigh and abdomen when her clothes were ignited while she and her sister Patsy, 5, were burning papers in the kitchen stove. OMAHA — Fred Giventer, 25, suffered second degree burns to his hands, arms and abdomen when his trousers he had washed in gasoline eaught lire as he struck a match to light a cigarette. OMAHA — Jerry Bogatz, 5, was badly burned when his clothing caught lire as he watched a bonfire. OMAHA — See Millard Hotel fire "write-up" as to number of firemen injured. OMAHA — Colored janitor was badly burned while heating wax — eaus - ing the Browning King fire loss. OMAHA — Mary Sanderson, 6, poured gasoline into an old abandoned automobile, then lighted a match. An explosion followed enveloping her in flames, searing the greater part of her body. John Taylor, 64, who witnessed the explosion, was severely burned in seeking to rescue the child. OMAHA — While fire destroyed the building where two Creighion foot - ball men had sleeping quarters, Verne Wolf of Chappell suffered a badly burned right hand and Maurice Archer of Ewing a badly injured wrist. OMAHA — A motor truck, loaded with wood, plunged into a ditch and burned— Oscar Thornton was thrown thru the windshield, being severely burned and cut. (see deaths) OMAHA— Lloyd Michaels, 9. visited the fire station with other, in his school class, where firemen told the pupils what to do when cloth - ing caught on fire. Jimmy Callahan, 4, was playing with a paper jack-o-lantedn when his clothing caught on fire — Lloyd remembered the instructions, pushed Jimmy to the ground and rolled him over and over extinguishing the flames before he was badly burned. OMAHA — Orval Knight, 26, was burned seriously when an open can of gasoline he was carrying caught fire. OMAHA— While heating tallow in oven, Harry Olson and Ben Meisted were burned when it ignited. OMAHA — N: J. Nelsen, 72, suffered burns in tearing the burning cloth - ing from his grandson, (see deaths) </seg>
            <seg id="p034">STATE OF NEBRASKA OMAHA — Fred Fitzwilllams, switchman, was burned on the left hand while putting out a fire in the building used as Switchman's iocker house. OMAHA — While fighting a fire with a garden hose, L. Gallett was burned about the face and hands. OMAHA — The Selden car caught fire and Robert, 10, was burned when gasoline saturated his clothing — his father crushed the boy to his chest to smother the flames, seeing this was fatal he dropped him into the Platte river. Howard Selden was slightly burned OMAHA — When their house caught on fire, Mrs. Eva McCutcneon wus slightly burned. OMAHA — Fire caused by a leak in the gasoline stove inflicted burns on the right hand and face of Harvey Salyards. PAXTON — Mrs. E. A. Hammond narrowly escaped death when her gaso - line stove exploded. Her son Harvey threw his coat over her head extinguishing the flames. PENDER — Frank Hanika went, to sleep in his auto — he had been smok - ing — the cushions caught on fire and he was severely burned. NIOBRARA — Geo. Hofferer was slightly burned on one hand w bile car - rying a can of gasoline out of a burning house. NORFOLK — R. Lenz was burned when the house caught on fire. RAVENNA — John Benisek was painfully burned as be escaped from his burning home. SALEM — Charles Rolf was burned seriously wn.n his clothiug became ignited from a grass fire — Albert Goll was burned about the hands when he attempted to smother the flames. SARGENT — Roy McGregor suffered severe burns on his arm and hand while preparing to fill a gasoline lamp that exploded. SCOTTSBLUFF — Flesh was torn from the palm of the hand o:' Paul Kirk, 36, when a Roman candle he was holding backfired. Hts arm was burned deeply. SCOTTSBLUFF — R. H. Jones sustained slight burns on his leg when a fire cracker exploded that was thrown into his trouser cuff. SCOTTSBLUFF — In an attempt to remove a burning auto from the gar - age, Ray Schnell, 18, and Alex Fritzler, Jr., 16, were burned about the hands arms and legs. SCOTTSBLUFF — Donald Baker, 7, suffered severe burns when he backed into a bonfire. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION SCOTTSBLUFF— John Niegel's clothing was a mass of flames when he poured kerosene on the fire in the cook stove — he plunged into the water tank, thereby saving his life, (see deaths) SEWARD — Mrs. Anna Kinnamon suffered severe burns caused by the exploding of a gas stove. SHELTON— The pilot light in the boiler room of the Shelton public schools had gone out when O. M. McKnlght lighted a match, an ex - plosion followed burning him severely about the hands and face. SIDNEY — Mrs. O. D. Slayther of Sidney was burned when gasoline with which she was cleaning clothing exploded. SIDNEY — Charlton Bently, 33, was seared on hands and face when an oil refining tank exploded, (see deaths) SPALDING — A cleaning fluid exploded burning Leo Kauffman on the face, arms and legs. TILDEN — Arthur Hansen took a stick to measure the gasoline In his tractor tank, then lit a match to look at the stick, an explosion fol - lowed, burning him severely. TOBIAS — Mrs. Spicka and little son were badly burned when a kero - sene lamp exploded, (see deaths) ULYSSES — Barney Prech's hand was burned while removing a can of gasoline discovered near the fire of his slaughter house. ULYSSES — Adley Powers suffered a badly burned arm when a can of gasoline exploded. UNION — When two automobiles collided Mrs. Roy Williamson, Mrs. Marie McKinzie, and Mr. Roy Williamson were seriously burned. VESTA — Adolph Alberts was burned about the face and hands when gasoline he was using to clean out a supply tank exploded. WALTHILL — Larry Hogan, night watchman, had 197 pieces of skin transplanted from his right thigh to his left leg, covering tnlrd de - gree burns suffered when his pants leg caught on fire while burn - ing papers. WATERBURY — Leslie Sigman, 14, was nearly burned to death when he threw kerosene on live coals in the kitchen range — the luel ex - ploded spraying him from head to foot with burning oil. WOOD RP7ER — Gay Garrison, 37, sustained second degree burns over a considerable portion of his body when the contents of a can of flam - ing gasoline was accldently thrown over him. WYMORE — Mrs. Frances Hansmire was severely burned when an oil stove exploded. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">STATE OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN FIRE LOSSES IN 1933 TOTAL $46,955.00 The city of Lincoln ended the year 1933 with a fire loss of 55 cents per capita on the 865 fires which occurred during the twelve months. The total fire loss sustained tor the year was $46,955 as compared with $75,508 for 1932. These and other interesting facts are included in the annual report which Louis Hansen, chief of the fire department, has submitted to the city council. February Worst Month Although November ranked highest in the number of alarms being turned in — there being 114 fire calls made during that month — February saw the heaviest toll of fire loss in the city during the year. As com - pared with a total loss of $1,S16 for November, the February losses totaled $13,280, January with a loss of $8,558, was the second highest month in fire damage. Of the city's total fire loss of $46,955. pli but $6,000 was covered by insurance. The total value of buildings and contents involved in 1933 fires was $2,649,245 but insurance covered would have covered losses in the amount of $2,197,400 had destruction been complete. Chimney sparks were classified by Chief Hansen's report as being tho principal traceable cause of building fires. A total of 69 fires were traced to tbis source and 32 other fires were also caused by defective flues. Careless smokers caused 8 fires and carelessness in the use of gasoline or kerosene was the reason for 28 fires. A total of 317 fires were assigned to miscellaneous known causes and 67 were listed as arising from unknown cause. Fourteen of Suspicious Origin None of the 1933 Lincoln fires were large enough to extend. to an ad - joining building. Of all the fires, 264 were in frame buildings, 55 were in fireproof buildings, 80 were in brick and stone buildings and 365 were fires other than building fires. The year saw only 14 fires which were of incendiary and suspicious origin and forty-two suspects were questioned by the bureau of inspec - tion in connection with 16 fires whose origins were investigated. Twenty of the alarms which the department received were purely false and there were a number of others where no fire existed but where occupants of the property involved smellcd smoke or found conditions which they thought required investigation. Lincoln's fire department, which operates at the present time with a total personnel of 103 persons, worked on a budget of $176,774 of </seg>
            <seg id="p037">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION which $172,724 went for salaries and pensions. The remaining $4,050 was used for buying needed equipment and the like. Chief Hansen re - ported. HOW ARSON CASES ARE LOST Public sentiment against the crime of arson is apt to be measured by the damage done, either loss of life or huge waste of property, al - though crime is crime in any event. Potential fatalities and possible conflagrations may follow- from the thoughtless, but criminal, intent to destroy an individual and unprofitable building. The difficulty of proving arson is often charged to the fact that the fire usually destroys the physical evidence. But here is a rase that is quite different: A witness testified in the preliminary hearing that he saw another man push some shavings under the corner of a shed with his foot, that he saw him reach into his vest pocket. Just at that time an automobile honked nearby and the witness stepped around the corner to see if the car was coming that way. He was back in five minutes and found a fire burning, hut the man was gone. A photograph taken soon after showed the mark of a corduroy trousered knee in the dust. The evidence showed that the suspected man wore corduroy trousers on that par - ticular day. The judge asked, "Did you see the accused take a match from his pocket?" "No." "Did you see him get down on his knee?" "No." "Did you see him strike a match?" "No." "Did you see him place a lighted match to the shavings?" "No" "Case dismissed," declared the judge. It seems unbelievable that an examining magistrate would have waived away such effective evidence, no matter how circumstantial, if a huge fire had resulted. Not more than a dollar's worth of damage resulted, but an operating mill and elevator, worth $100,000, was Im - mediately at hazard and more than twenty people were sleeping in a frame rooming house near by. Another interesting case: A warrant was issued for a man who was closely connected through circumstantial evidence with a mysterious fire. It was known that he had driven out of town very late that same night and had not returned. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">STATE OF NEBRASKA After watchful waiting the sheriff located the suspect in another state and brought him back. While he was In jail awaiting preliminary hear - ing an insurance adjuster compromised the claims against his com - panies for a very small amount. The Insurance agent testified that the insurance companies involved had settled, thereby disclaiming any de - fense on an arson count The judge seemed to think that tho contro - versy was solely between the accused and the insurance companies' and refused to hold the man for criminal trial in district court. A man with a shady reputation bought a store in a Nebraska village. He and his wife were active in church and civic affairs. He was a good advertiser and did a good business. When his store burned following an unexplained explosion his admiring neighbors were so genuinely m sympathy with the new "live wire" that they would not afford local assistance to the investigators. After making a satisfactory insurance settlement the village idol started on a deliberate program of boating his bills. With no new or additional facts before them the villagers agree. since he left town, that he was not only an incendiarlst but a bootlegger and a hypocrite. ) POSSIBLE PROFIT FROM TOTAL LOSSES Out of 189 cases investigated by the state fire marshal's agents dur - ing the past, year, 109 of them seem to have been prompted by The in - surance carried. But more careful culling brings the number down to 69 fires that officers agree were set, or procured by the property owners A liberal estimate of the gross values of properties involved amounts to $537,650. If these properties had been totally destroyed and full insurance received the owners would have collected $766,250, and have profited $229,000, nearly fifty percent above actual values. An old frame building in a sand hill village carried twice its value in insurance. The owner and occupant was a "Swapper" and drifter. He was a friend of the fire chief. An adjuster looked at the ruins before the fire was out and made a hurried adjustment so that he could get home for Sunday. He committed the companies he represented to total losses. A subsequent change In head of the volunteer fire department brought out a report that resulted In a belated investigation. In the meantime the beneficiary of the incendiary loss had dropped out of sight. How manyj parties were at fault? A beautiful dwelling in swank, suburban Omaha burned one evening wbenl the family and the servants were all conveniently away from home. Rags i saturated with inflammable liquids had been laid up the stairways fromitho first to the third floors, all of which were beautifully furnished. Bundles of matches were placed at strategic places. Cupsfull of turpen - tine Jwere thrown under beds and dressers. There were at least thirteen </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION separate and distinct fire centers in that many rooms. The assured claimed that valuable silver plate and jewelry and clothing had been stolen. The investigation disclosed that the property was insured for more than its value, that the house had needed redecorating and that the furnishings were out of mode. Cash money was also needed to meet pressing debts. The fire was clearly incendiary and the motive plain, but a family alibi is hard to break down without positive witnesses to - the overt act. In this case local politics tended to obscure the issues. In some counties it is the'"practice for people to report rural fires immediately to the sheriff, who goes immediately to assist or tn detect crime as the case may be. The same practice is followed In unprotected towns, those having no local fire department and no water systems. It is noteworthy that where this custom is followed and where the sheriff, and often the county attorney, cooperate there are fewer crooked flres than in other counties. Attorney General Paul Good and his deputies, especially W. C. Ramsey of Omaha and William Wright of Ihe Lincoln office, have been cordially helpful in assisting the State Fire Marshal's office and county attorneys in the investigation and prosecution of arson cases. The prompt interest of many sheriffs and county attorneys have goie a long way in preventing future flres by their willing disposition to make rigid investigations of suspicious circumstances. THE GENERAL ARSON STATUS During 1933 Nebraska suffered its worst epidemic of incendiary flro losses. The number of suspicious fires, warranting investigation by the state fire marshal's office was greater than in any previous year; and of the cases investigated a larger proportion showed to be of incendiary origin. The loss of life and the loss of property, due to incendiarism, exceeded the record of other years. The experience of Nebraska is not wholly unlike that of other and neighboring states where fire records have run closely ln parallel for a decade or more. Those who have studiously sought for reasons for the recent high ratios in incendiary losses are generally agreed upon the substantial facts: (a) That the economic depression, which has resulted in shrinking incomes and lowered property values, has had a consequent effect upon society and has reduced the public morale to a point where moral hazard has come to be of equal, or greater Importance than physical hazard, (b) That insurance companies have not used due dili - gence in considering moral hazards and have permitted their agents to bind them for indemnities far in excess of the marketable values- of the properties covered. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATE OF NEBRASKA The arson division of the state fire marshal's office is maintained primarily to aid local officials in ferreting out incendiarists. Investiga - tors are sent to different communities on call of village, city or county officers, who are directly charged with local law enforcement. The state law further contemplates that adjusters and officers for fire insur - ance companies shall report to the Lincoln office when they discover flres of Incendiary or questionable origin. The state fire marshal may, when he thinks a suspicious fire is not being efficiently and fully inves - tigated by local authorities, take complete charge of the Investigation and may demand the assistance of peace officers. He may also invoke the assistance of the state attorney general's office if county attorneys are indiffferent in affording aid. It is at once apparent that the best results follow a wholehearted co-operation among local officials, the fire insurance representatives and the state fire marshal. The National Board of Fire Underwriters maintains a bureau for in vestigating arson cases and welcomes calls for assistance in important cases. It is a matter of common knowledge that convictions in arson cases are difficult to get in tlie courts. Fire hugs may seldom be photographed while torching their own or other people's properties. Witnesses to the overt act are infrequent and the rules of evidence are apt to preclude statements not directly made but which are circumstantially valueable The physical evidence of incendiarism is generally destroyed before even the most efficient fire department can get to the scene. THE OMAHA FIRE RACKET The most spectacular fire that ever occurred in Nebraska wis the burning of the Millard Hotel in Omaha, February 8, 1933. But leading up to it the writer assumes that it will be of public interest to go back to July of the preceding year when a mysterious explosion and fire occurred at Fourteenth and Douglas Streets in Omaha. Three brick buildings, three stories high, occupied as a general store, a cigar store and gambling house, and a picture show on the ground floors, and with small shops above, were leveled by a terrific explosion that broke windows throughout the neighborhood. The resultant fire destroyed what was left of the buildings and all the contents. The apparent Indifference of local authorities warranted the state fire marshal's office, in conducting a long, expensive hearing, that re - sulted in nothing beyond the conclusion of the investigators that the explosion was planned and carried out by experts, probably 'mported </seg>
            <seg id="p041">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION for the purpose. Fire insurance companies resisted payment, because of the explosion, but finally compromised. Within two months there had been four successful gasoline explosions in poor houses that carried more insurance than they were worth. As the depression became more acute, more laboring people were thrown out of employment and boot - legging became less profitable, there occurred from one to a dozen "flash fires" each month in Omaha right up to the time of the Millard Hotel fire. The marked similarity in the nature of the fires and the general locations, the fire companies' abysmal lack of clews led to the conclusion that most, or all, of them were the work of hired Hessians. LET THE SELLER BEWARE Under interrogation one property' owner stated, through an inter - preter, that he had built his house out of second hand lumber at a maximum cost of $1200. He had procured a loan upon his real estate for $1000 and this was secured by an insurance policy in that amount, with a mortgage clause to the loan company. He had then been solicited by unidentified persons to write more insurance. He procured four other other policies, without mortgage clauses for a total of $5000 on hi. very indifferent house. While he and his large family were all away from home the house was discovered to be on fire. The firemen found rags saturated with tar and kerosene tucked behind the baseboards, the rags connected by equally saturated fuses. The house was saved with small flame damages. Asked if he thought it right to secure so much insurance on his cheap property, the owner replied that that was for the insurance companies to decide. On the occasion of the Browning, King &amp; Company fire in Omaha there was wide spread criticism, of the efficiency of the Omaha fire de - partment and the opinion was current that the department's morale was broken down. Complaints were sent to the National Board of Under - writers and- experts came to Omaha to determine the facts. Engineer Rathburn was In Omaha for that purpose at the time of the Millard Hotel Fire. THE MILLARD HOTEL CATASTROPHE The Millard Hotel, an historic five story brick structure covering a quarter block at Thirteenth and Douglas Streets, Omaha, was reported to be on fire between 10 and 11 o'clock on the night of February 8. 1933. Nearly all of the fire fighting equipment in the city responded. IL was a bitter cold night with the thermometer recording 16 degrees below zero. The fire started on the second floor, north side next to the alley. It was there that the firemen were centered In, their battle with the flames when the north wall collapsed and burled several firemen who were on ladders. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">STATE OF NEBRASKA Although the hotel was advertised as fireproof and was equipped with a sprinkler system it is admitted that the system was out of order on the night before the fire, and all of the firemen who have testified swear that the sprinklers were not working at any time during the fire. The pipe men who were directing their hosesl on the] seat of the fire, in the rehearsal room, directly over the office, have testified that the fire was unnatural and did not yield to water, that "fire seemed to drip from the ceiling." After the north wall fell there was an unusual collapse on the south side of the building, wholly away from any Are and Immediately above the valves that connected the city water system and the impotent sprinkler system. City Inspector Clarence Urban was in the basement at the time to investigate the conditions of the sprinkler valve3 and was killed, probably Immediately crushed under the debris. There were about 60 registered guests at the hotel, and about half of them, were in their rooms when the fire broke out. All guests escaped alone or assisted, without many serious accidents but few were able to save any of their baggage. Many were permanent guests and lost every - thing they had. Some theatrical people had valuable stage properties in their rooms, in the rehearsal hall or in the basement. Everything was lost. On the afternoon following the fire Harry Weiner, the owner of the hotel, was interrogated at the police station by representatives from the county attorney's office, but not under oath. After an interval of several days public sentiment warranted the calling of a coroner's jury to in - quire into the causes of the deaths of seven firemen. Harry Weiner did not testify at the coroner's Inquest. No substantial facts regarding tbe deaths or the origin of the fire developed. Criticism by the National Board experts, as published in the World- Herald and the Bee-News, prompted the Omaha city commission to hold an open hearing as to the efficiency of the city fire department. Nothing came of it. THE STATE STEPS IN With a mere shred of Information the state fire marshal's office -opened an investigation, with the cordial assistance of the attorney general's office. The county attorney and the city fire commissioner's offices cooperated. The testimony of almost one hundred witnesses was taken over a period of five weeks. Many investigators were assigned to the case and some excavating was done in the ruins of the hotel brildlng. The result of the prolonged hearing was a complaint, drawn by the Douglas county attorney and signed by a deputy state fire marshal, accus - ing Harry Weiner of having caused the fire and being the cause of the </seg>
            <seg id="p043">DP7ISION OF FIRE PREVENTION resultant loss of life of one of the seven firemen. He waived examina - tion in municipal court and was held under bond to the district court. Two weeks were consumed in the trial in criminal court and resulted in a divided jury. The case is yet pending another trial in district court with no date fixed. In the meantime Harry Weiner has filed suits against the Insurance companies for recovery on policies totaling more than $150,000. Some of these* cases have been transferred to federal- court and one Insurance case that was started in the district court of Douglas county has been appealed to the state supreme court from the directed verdict for the plaintiff by the district judge. During the pendency of the criminal case in district court the Omaha city commission condemned the Millard hotel, which had already been razed by Mr. Weiner to the third floor. This action has tended to strengthen the claim of Mr. Weiner for total loss, under the "Valued Policy" law. The question of the value of the building has' been dispute - by expert witnesses. But it is very generally agreed that the amount of insurance carried on the building and contents greatly exceeded the value of the properties. This question has been -raised and ur?ed as showing a motive for incendiarism, rather than as a ctefense as to fixing the amount of damages. \. In the seven months preceding the Millard Hotel fire there had been 71 suspicious fires investigated in Omaha by the state fire marshal's office. With a few notable exceptions there have been almost none dur - ing the ten remaining months of 1933. There are at least two reasons: One, that insurance companies have cancelled many policies where the moral risk has been in question, and reduced indemnities in other cases. Second, that a determined investigation of incendiarism and the tiial of suspects on criminal', charges have given pause to some who havo here - tofore found profit in the arson racket. MILLARD HOTEL DEAD AND INJURED Those who lost their lives In discharge of duty on the night of Febru - ary 8, or the morning of February 9, 1933, during Omaha's worst fire are: Franklin Kanq Louis Morocco Thomas Shandy Edwin Schmidt John Cogan Clarence Urban John Brandt And the following firemen were injured, more or less severely. Some - went back to work after a few days and others are permanently disabled and retired: </seg>
            <seg id="p044">STATE OF NEBRASKA Ray Murphy Joe Fitzgerald Ed Dodrell Paul Westerhausen Charles Huston Jinimie Donahue Michael Geddings Fred Jacobson Harold Woden Wlllard Nichols Lawrence McKenna Charles Climes Wm. Bales Thomas Lynch John Jackson Michael O'Neill Alyin Clinchard George Cogan Joe Faus Walter Hoye John Williams Jack Mattern George Winslow Albert Newton Ashford Grady Some of the men killed were married and had families who will be entitled to draw pensions, or disability allowances from the city treasury. It would be impossible to accurately estimate the drain upon the tax - payers for years to come to reimburse financially those who wore in - jured and the beneficiaries of those who lost their lives in the Millard hotel fire. THE WORST LOSS IN ITS CLASS According to the records compiled by the actuarial bureau of the Na - tional Board of Fire Underwriters the Millard Hotel stands out alone in its class as to loss of life and property for 1933. In an oil refinery plant in. Arkansas seven lives were lost and In _ similar plant in California nine persons were killed. In a pyroxylin factory in New Jersey an explosion killed 10 people and Injured 50 others. At Wickliffe, Ohio, nine women patients were burned to death in a cottage attached to an insane sanitarium. DIVIDED RESPONSIBILITY— WHO BLAMABLE The laws of Nature argue that there can be no justification for waste or the deliberate destruction of property. It is against the laws ot Nebraska for a man to destroy his&gt; own property, above a certain low minimum value, whether It be insured or not. Defrauding an insurance company is also forbidden by the criminal statutes. Insurance com - panies cannot pay in losses more than they take in from net premiums. Insurance rates are based upon experiences in communities, influenced by fire prevention facilities and the law enforcing temper of city or county officials. Honest property owners are thud penalized in the way of unnecessarily high fire insurance rates in order that the unscrupulous </seg>
            <seg id="p045">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION racketeers may sell out to the insurance companies, who have' recently been recognized as the only cash customers. Nor are the insurance companies blameless. The fire companies have suffered from the depression. Their premium incomes have fallen off and home offices have pressed their state agents for balances and the state agents have in turn urged local agents for increased volume. The. experiences of an arson investigator lead him frequently to wonder whether the local agent, or sometimes the state agent, of a fire company is the agent of the company or the agent of the' assured. All too frequently his influence is toward hush-hushing any investiga - tion of suspected crime and urging for a generous and prompt adjustment and settlement of the insured's claim. VALUED POLICY LAW INVITES CRIME In such times as these Nebraska's "Valued Policy" law tends as an incentive to criminality. It invites the racketeers, the crooked Hwyern and those of our population who are un-American minded, to match their wits against the insurance gamblers, who have the ultimate ad - vantage of gathering with one hand what the other hand carelessly throws away. However worthy its purpose in restraining insurance ngents from overwriting property values for the sake of premiums and commissions, no statute is justifiable if it results in inviting incendiarism and crime. BURN YOUR OWN HOME The editor's note under the above heading in the August, 1933, num - ber of the New Outlook, says: "Arson, as a way out for the harassed American home owner, is becoming increasingly popular. Paul W. Kearney, who tells of the new Burn Your Own Home movement, has made numerous studies of man's war against fire." Student Kearney states in his opening paragraph in the New Out - look article, from which we are privileged to quote at length, that the popular slogan of the prosperity era was, "Own Your Own Home." The substitution of a word affords a catchy, thought provoking text. Quoting: "In the bereaved days just mentioned arson was just another mer - chandising stunt, if you didn't sell your goods to the public you could sell them to the insurance company, net a neat profit on an inflated policy and resume business in a new store — with a new Insurance cover- </seg>
            <seg id="p046">STATE OF NEBRASKA age. The current; transference of arson from the store to the dwelling Is approaching the dignity of a national pastime. "Inasmuch as these opportunities still exist it is not surprising that 1933 is proving the best arson year in our history. All over the country residential flres are thirty to forty per cent higher than for the same period last year — and last year they were fifty per cent higher than they were six years ago. "Don't assume for a minute that it is confined to a few large cities; it prevails from coast to coast in towns large and small; It prevails even on the farm to such an extent that excellent authorities estimate one - third of our rural flres to be incendiary. Quite recently an official of a Federal land bank expressed dismay at the frequency with which their "demands" for overdue payments are being answered by notices of fire losses." "President C. W. Bailey of the National Board of Fire Underwriters reported a "disquieting increase" in suspicious fires among home owners all over the country, observing that it is "only [too evident that many, hard pressed by mortgages and other debts, have been able to resist the temptation to turn their dwellings into cash." If this seems a mild protest at the collapse of human integrity then remember that in - surance people have long) played ostrich with regard to the' arson ques - tion — four out of five will still blandly deny the facts that they know so well a mistaken effort to avoid encouraging the practices In others. "In this Year of Our Lord arson seems to be unanimous; dues the idea intrigue you? "First of all, you take out $15,000 or $20,000 worth of fire insurance on your $2,000 worth of belongings — or if you have a small policy already, treble it. Nobody will ask you why — nobody will even inquire If you have that much property. Ally they ask is that your premium check clears the bank. This done you set fire to the place, taking pains to be away at the movies, or visiting your Aunt Sarah, at the proper time. "If you want to avoid the pitfall (possible detection through amateur - ishness) engage one of the many professionals who specialize in this work for anywhere from $200 a job in the smaller communities to $1,000 ln cities where living standards are higher. "In case the burden of collecting seems too complicated then get a smart public adjuster to represent you; they seem to have nol difficulty doing business with first-line insurance companies. "In many states the statutes covering arson are so archaic that an intelligent law clerk could defend you successfully. You'll get further aid too, from your fellow citizens on the jury and even in the witness </seg>
            <seg id="p047">' DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION chair, who seem Imbued with the notion that it really Isn't such a serious thing to stick an insurance company: "They can afford it." "Officials who are not afraid to push in arson cases get little help in their efforts to check this crime; in many states they don't sven get help from the law itself. In those commonwealths operating under the "valued policy" law this erstwhile safeguard for the policy holder has become a standing invitation to the incendiary. "Anybody can buy an insurance policy, as big a policy as he wants to pay for, and no questions asked. Why do the companies permit such gross over-insurance? Apparently because they can't bear to disappoint an applicant. "They say, of course, that if a man is damn fool enough to pay those premiums, why shouldn't they take them and prove fraud when the time comes? The answers cornel thick and fast, but three are enough. First, the man who is willing to pay such premiums is not a damn fool hut an obvious crook, and if the company bothered to find out how much he was over-insured they'd know it without waiting for a fire. Second,, the taxpayers who support the policy, and the courts, are the real damn fools; they foot the bill for the belated proof of fraud. And last, but not least, the attempts to prove fraud are so seldom successful; so the tax - payers not only pay for the futile prosecution, but for the insurance loss out of premiums which have been scaled to cover such contingencies. "As long as that situation prevails, arson will continue to Increase, offering a greater threat to the life and property of the average innocent man and levying a steadily mounting tax on his anemic check-book for the support of more and better prosecuting officials. When) that, situa - tion is remedied by an improved viewpoint among those most airectly concerned with the arson problem, we won't need^ that much publicized Model Arson Law. because arson will then have lost Its principal zest and the "Burn Your Own Home" movement will collapse for lack of profit.' </seg>
            <seg id="p048">STATE OF NEBRASKA Why Should Firemen Make Inspections? 1. Fire hazards can be removed or safe-guarded. 2. An inspection provides the fire department with a "battle map" In event of Are. 3. An inspection gives the fire department a personal contact with the public. EVERYBODY'S JOB Just as "every fire is your fire," fire prevention is everyone's re - sponsibility. American genius has solved many 'ntricate problems, but the fire waste is still with us. No one individual or group can solve the problem. Teamwork is necessary. The fire department, the press, the Insurance men, the service clubs and commercial groups, the schools, the clergy, the women's groups, the boy scouts, and many other organiza - tions must band together in the common cause if the "Fire Demon" is to be defeated. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION FIRE CHIEFS TAKE NOTICE Also Mayors or Chairman of Town Board in Towns Where a Fire Department Has Not Been Organized. The law requires you to report all fires — where the loss Is $5.00 or more — to the State Fire Marshal at Lincoln, Nebraska, within seveu days after fire. The Fire Marshal furnishes you with the proper blank forms on which to make these reports — all you have to do is write this office for them. One dollar is paid the chief or mayor for each complete re - port forwarded. BUT YOU MUST MAKE A COMPLETE REPORT— filling in each blank space on the report. If It Is not complete, it will be returned to you for correction. The following spaces must be filled in. Name of town ? County ? If farm, give distance from town ? Name of occupant ? Building constructed of what kind of material ? How many stories high T Condition of building as to age ? State whether building was a dwelling, store, manufacturing plant, garage, barn, etc., state what kind of business, if a business place. Value of building ? Insurance (amount in figures) _.? Loss ? Value of contents ? Insurance ? Loss ? Value of automobile ? Insurance 7 Loss ? BE SURE AND READ DIRECTIONS FOR MAKING OUT REPORTS BEFORE SENDING THEM IN Remember to place the value of building and contents and the insurance on both, even though there was not a loss on both — as this will give you a better record for your fire department — showing how mucu you have saved the people of your town. Be sure to give the CAUSE of fire, in your opinion, and also advlso in what part of the building the fire started. Typewrite your reports, if possible. If not, write as plainly as you can, and be sure to print your name on the report, as well as writing It. All fire chiefs are furnished with a deputy fire Inspector's card, signed by the Governor and State Fire Marshal. This is beneficial when making inspections and on the investigation of fires. Remember, the law makes you an assistant in fire prevention. When new chiefs are elected, the secretary should notify thin office at once giving the name of tbe chief, so that we may know on whom to call or write in case of necessity. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">STATE OF NEBRASKA FIRE DEPARTMENT OFFICERS TO BE ELECTED IN JANUARY We respectfully ask and recommend that all fire chiefs in Nebraska be elected during the month of January. It would not be a difficult task to change the date of your annual meeting to some day during the month of January, making this fact known by letter or printed notice that at your next regular meeting this proposition would be voted on, and if a majority of the members present at that meeting, vote to change the annual meeting It would be carried. In that way the Fire Marshal would be able to have a complete and up-to-date list ol all chiefs in this state. ADJUSTERS MUST REPORT SUSPICIOUS FIRES Section 44-706, 1929 compiled statutes — Every adjuster, who investigates any loss claim in this state, shall ascertain whether there be double, or over-Insurance upon such risk and the facts and circumstances so far as practical pertaining to the original or happening of the hazard or peril insured against; and In case he believes fraud has been committed or attempted to be committed, he shall promptly report the premises to the Department of Insurance, and in case of fire insurance to the fire marshal as well. FIRE CHIEFS MUST REPORT FIRES Section Sl-5506, 1929 compiled statutes— section 6. FIRE CHIEFS DUTIES. — The chief of the fire department of every city or village ln which a fire department is established, the mayor of every incorporated city in which no fire department exists, the town clerk of every organ - ized township or Ihe county commissioner in every commissioner dis - trict in counties not under township organization without the limits of any organized city or village shall investigate or cause to bo In - vestigated the cause, origin and circumstances of every fire occurring in such city, village, township or commissioner district by which property has been destroyed or damaged when the damage exceeds five dollars; that all fires of unknown origin shall be reported, and such officers shall especially make investigation and report as to whether such fire was the result of carelessness, accident or design. THE NEBRASKA STATE VOLUNTEER FIREMEN'S ASSOCIATION The Nebraska State Volunteer Firemen's Association met October 17-19, 1933, at North Platte, Nebraska, and a very fine program was put </seg>
            <seg id="p051">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION on. The firemen from over the state were shown every hospitality by the citizens of North Platte — and there was a large attendance. The newly elected officers for 1934 were as follows: Robert Barlow, Sidney — President John R. Manners, Wahoo — First Vice Pres. Cliff Galley, Columbus — Second Vice Pres. Louis A. Novak, Norfolk — Secretary-Treasurer Walter C. Rundin, Wahoo — Chaplin Omaha was selected as the next convention city, for October 16-1T - 18; 1934. The fact that Omaha and Lincoln were admitted to the con - vention by a vote of the volunteers, as honorary members, will mean much to the volunteers, for the Omaha and Lincoln paid firemen, who are on constant duty, can impart and instruct the volunteers in the knowledge they possess, so they will be more proficient In their work when called on flres and also learn to prevent flres. The Nebraska Volunteer Firemen are becoming better each year and the citizens In the towns where these firemen are active should give them evory co - operation and be grateful for their protection. STATE FIRE PREVENTION ASSOCIATION "ORGANIZED FOR ESTABLISHMENT OF PROPER SAFEGUARDS AGAINST LOSS OF LIFE AND PROPERTY BY FIRE AND TO ASSIST AND COOPERATE WITH CHAMBERS OF COMMERCE, TRADE AND CIVIC ASSOCIATIONS IN FIRE PREVENTION ACTIVITIES" the Ne - braska group is affiliated with the National Fire Prevention Association. Its local membership is co-incident with the special and state agents of fire insurance companies operating In the state. The most effective work done in this, or other, states is periodic inspections of cities and villages. Groups of insurance men, along with representatives of the State Fire Marshal's office, undertake to make about eight inspections in various parts of the state. Following a day of inspecting business properties and public buildings an evening meet - ing is held, usually under the auspices of tbe community club, at which fire prevention is broadly discussed. City inspections are usually held upon the invitation of chambers of commerce or city authorities. The purpose of city inspections is more educational than commercial. Hazards are pointed out and recommenda - tions made that have an Influence on basic fire insurance rates. A speaker's committee is maintained by the State Association, and, in co-operation with the State Fire Marshal's office, welcomes invitation from schools and civic organisations for public addresses ov. fire prevention. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">STATE OF NEBRASKA National Fire Protection Association The National Fire Protection Association was organized in 1896 by a group of men interested in reducing the fire losses throughout the United States and Canada. The object of the Association is "To pro - mote the science and improve the methods of fire protection and pre - vention; to obtain and circulate information on these subjects and se - cure the cooperation of its members In establishing proper safeguards against loss of life and property by fire." VOLUNTEER FIREMEN The Volunteer Firemen of Nebraska are being urged to become members of the Volunteer Firemen's Section of the National Fire Pro - tection Association. At the thirty-seventh annual meeting of the National Fire Protec - tion Association in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, in May, 1933, a conference 01 members enthusiastic over this Section was held, and at that conference the following five points were set forth as a guide for the organization of this section: 1. The Interchange of experience among volunteer fire departments. 2. The development of a medium for broadcasting new develop - ments and new ideas of benefit to volunteer fire departments. 3. The development of standard practices and methods for fir - fighting by volunteer fire departments. 4. The promotion of fire prevention work in rural districts. 5. The promotion of the organization of a new volunteer lire com - panies and extension of the service of existing companies where necessaiy. You can improve your fire fighting ability by educating yourseli through the Volunteer Firemen, a professional journal pertaining to Volunteer Firemen only, and published by the National Fire Protection Association. Every Department joining the National Fire Protection Association entitles every member of the Department to the Volunteer Fireman, the monthly journal of the Volunteer Firemen's Section, and also entitles them to have access to the Information Bureau maintained by the Na - tional Fire Protection Association. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION In the interests of Fire Prevention, I am eager that every volunteer fireman in Nebraska shall interest himself in this organization, and be - come an active member. For full particulars, write to Percy Bugbee, Assistant Managing Director of the National Fire Protective Association, 60 Batterymarch Street, Boston, Massachusetts. Take this matter up with your town or city council. They owe this assistance to their Volunteer Fire Department. A LOT FOR THE MONEY The membership plan for the Volunteer Firemen's Section requires a minimum dues of ten dollars from a volunteer fire department before the department is eligible to membership in the section and the indtfvl - du'a! members of the department receive copies of Volunteer Foremen. If we could place before the members of the volunteer fire department at ono of its meetings a pile of the material that the department would receive in the course of a year for its ten dollars we think there Is little question that every volunteer fire department would join the section. Twenty copies of Volunteer Firemen are mailed every month to twenty individual volunteers in the department which total two hundred anu forty copie_ or the magazine. The headquarters of the department re - ceive four copies of the N. F. P. A. Quarterly, a magazine of ono hundred pages each issue, a copy of the Proceedings running to four or five hundred pages, a copy of the monthly News Letters, posters, regula - tions, pamphlets, and educational material of every style and variety. The regular N. F. P. A. material. If kept at headquarters, becomes an invaluable reference library for every member of the department. We know and we feel that volunteer fire departments are beginning to realize that membership in the Volunteer Firemen's Section brings a lot for the money. The following towns in this state have already joined: Blair Bellevue Wahoo Hay Springs Bancroft. Aurora Ansley O'Neill Ashton Franklin Friend Auburn Osmond Greeley </seg>
            <seg id="p054">STATE OF NEBRASKA COOPERATION OF STATE FIRE MARSHALS The establishment of the Volunteer Firemen's Section of the National Fire Protection Association has met with a very enthusiastic response from the various state fire marshals In the United States ano provincial fire marshals in Canada. Over a dozen of the fire marshals have offered every cooperation in the organization of the sections and the securing of interest in their states or provinces. Letters to every volunteer fire department in their states have been sent out by State Fire Marshal Joyce of Maryland, Slate Fire Marshal Strohm of Iowa, and Slate Fire Marshal Butcher ot Nebraska. The state fire marshals realize the importance of the volunteer fire departments in the control of fire waste In their respective juris lici ions. State fire marshals also realize the helpfulness of the National Firo Pro tection Association because of their affiliation with the Association through the Fire Marshals Section. We believe that the development of our Volunteer Firemen's Section will bring greater cooperation than ever between the state fire marshals and the fire departments which will prove of mutual advantage. My only object in coming here was to be of help. I'm like the man who wanted to help the small boy who was turning in a fire alarm from a street box. Said he: "Sonny, can 1 help you?" "Sure mister, pull down the hook." "Now what do I do?" "Now you'd better run like the devil." TO PUT OUT A FIRE IS GOOD— TO PREVENT ONE IS BETTER... , — Contributed by Geq. B. Campbell. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION NEBRASKA EDITORS, CITY COUNCILS AND TOWN BOARDS. CHAMBERS OF COMMERCE, BOY SCOUTS AND CAMP FIRE GIRLS AND ALL OTHER ORGANIZATIONS We take this opportunity to thank you one and all for your splendid cooperation given us in fire prevention lines. Fire prevention is the cheapest form of protection, no matter what it costs. No matter what use the building may be put to — keep It free from rubbish, guard against the accumulation of waste of any kind, and you will have taken the greatest possible step toward immunity from fire. No matter how many precautions may be taken to prevent flres— they will start — for we are all human, and, therefore careless, and as long as the human element enters, some points will be overlooked, some opening will be left for fire to enter. Even though every step is taken that can be foreseen to prevent flres, we must not stop, but be prepared to fight it when it comes. Fire prevention, as well as fire protection', should cover tbe civic authorities realm of activities, both in the matter of clean street and vacant lots, cutting of grass and weeds and the beautifying of the town, generally, by encouraging the painting of buildings, the planting of trees and shrubs, and the growing of flowers In every spot where they will show off to advantage. ' '-.. Purely accidental flres are few in number and are not the cause of the serious fire waste of our state. People as a rule do not commit crime without an incentive and a motive. With the criminal class, the arson gang, the pyromaniac, or those who are hopelessly involved in debt, it is an invitation to have a fire. Much can be done thru the initiative of leaders in various commercial bodies in establishing higher ethical standards and cooperating for the purpose of eradicating vicious and unfair practices. If the public conscience is sufficiently aroused, the better side of a man's instinct will respond, even though under more unfavorable surroundings he were criminally inclined. The atmo.pher. we breathe has an influence on our lives. Fire prevention is infectious — let us all try it and see how quickly it will spread over our town. The fire marshal's office is ready at the public's call to make In - spections, consult with builders and property owners, make investiga - tions, address schools and furnish data for newspapers — with!, the limitations of the law and funds available. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">STATE OF NEBRASKA Sample Ordinance Ordinance No An ordinance to impose a special occu - pation tax on fire insurance companies doing business in the City of - , Nebraska, for the support and maintenance of the volunteer fire department of said city. Be it ordained by tho mayor and council of the City of , Nebraska: Section 1. — That for the use, support and maintenance of tbe volun - teer fire department of the City of , Nebraska, regularly organized under the laws of the State of Nebraska, an occupation ta_ of five dollars per annum be and the same is hereby levied upon each and every fire insurance company, corporation or association doing business in the City of Nebraska. Section 2. — Such occupation tax shall be due and payable nn the - day of of each and every year and upon the pay - ment thereof by any person to the City Treasurer, the Treasurer shall give a receipt therefor, properly dated and specifying the person pay - ing, the name of the insurance company, the amount, and for what tlm_ said tax is paid. Section 3. — -The money paid into the City Treasury, under the pro - visions of this ordinance, shall constitute and be known as the special occupation tax fund of the volunteer fire department of the city or and the same shall be used exclusively for the support or such department. Section 4. — The City Treasurer of ; shall upon proper receipt being given, pay to the treasurer of the Volunteer Fire Department all moneys collected for such occupation tax. Section 5. — Each and every insurance company, corporation or association doing business in the City of shall pay to the City Treasurer of said City of the said sum of five dollars as provided for by Section 1 of this ordinance, on the day ot of each and every year and on failure to pay the sane, as herein provided for, the said city may recover the same in a civil action brought against said insurance company, corporation or association. Section 6. — All ordinances or parts of ordinances in conflict with this ordinance are hereby repealed. Section 7. — This ordinance shall be enforced and take effect from and after its passage, approval and publication as by law provided. Passed and approved this day of , 19 Attest: City Clerk Mayor </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>