<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00006.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00006.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Board of Fish Commissioners OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1900">1900</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change>
            <date>2007-09-06</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OK THE Board of Fish Commissioners OK THK STATE OF NEBRASKA 19OO LINCOLN, NEB HCKTCK-WOODRUrF PRIKT1HG CO . PRINTERS 1900 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">' </seg>
            <seg id="p003">RobertS. Oberfelder, President, Sidney, Neb. W. L. May, Vice President, Omaha, Neb. D. W. Barnes, Secretary, Valparaiso, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT Yai.takaiso, Neb., Dec. 15, l!'&lt;»o. To kit excellency William A. P&lt;iyiitii\ Governor: Sir — We have the honor to submit herewith a report of the work of the Fish Commission for the period commencing Aug. 1, 1899. The date of the last report being Dec. 15, 1897, the time intervening between that time and Aug. 1, 1899, is ac - counted for in the changing o| superintendents. During the winter of 1898, spring and summer of ]898 some dissatisfac - tion in the management of the hatcheries was manifested, which culminated at the meeting of the board of fish commis - sioners in the latter part of July, 1899. At said meeting Mr. W. J. O'Brien tendered his resignation and Mr. Adam J. B was chosen to succeed him as superintendent. During the time since the change in superintendents closer attention has been paid to the delivering and distributing of fish than formerly given to the applicants for tish of all kinds, both for food and ornamental purposes, if not in as large amounts as asked for, in such numbers as to equalize and give some to every appli - cant, thereby giving better general satisfaction than heretofore. Mr. D. W. Barnes, one of the fish commissioners, has been going with the fish car on most all of the trips, seeing to it personally that such applicants received a part if not all he Kas been the purpose of the commission to pay more at - to the hatching and distributing of fish rather than to king the hatching grounds a summer resort. (he report of the superintendent submitted herewith showa letail the number and kind of fish distributed and the p»r - to whom they were shipped. It is believed that the dia - ution has been more general over the state than formerly, inquiries regarding fish culture have been promptly an - swered and the many letters received by the commissionera from the different parts of the state, showing the successful </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 planting of fish sent or delivered to private parties, and of fish planted in the public waters of the state by the commissson leads us to believe that great good has been accomplished and that those having received fish are well satisfied with the result. The increasing demand for fish and for information as to the manner of planting, propagating, and caring for fish of all kinds shows that the people of the state are taking a greater interest in fish culture and this industry is growing in favor each year. I At the meeting of the Board in Dec, 1899, after carefully amining the amounts appropriated for the different funds for i benefit of the commission it was found that the necessary )or fund was running so low that it was deemed advisable to t down the force at the hatcheries, this amount of help it is soon seen could not accomplish the amount of work to ike as large a showing as in former years; but there being other remedy the two men, Messrs. Straight and Barnell, ver faultered for a moment but tackled the herculean task thout a murmur, taking the spawn from the trout in the cold gather of Dec., 1899, and Jan., 1900, besides attending to I other work connected with the hatcheries. Taking and itching some 60,000 brook and rainbow trout, between 45,000 id 50,000 being distributed. On account of money, which e legislature failed to appropriate for the purpose, the com- tission could not procure any pike eggs, as had been the cus - m in the former years. As to the amount of money the commission asks the legis - ature to appropriate for the benefit of this institution we ask uit a committee be appointed, composed of members of the louse and senate to proceed to the hatcheries and make a care - ul examination of the grounds and buildings, giving the coin - mission an opportunity to show and explain where every dollar asked is needed, and how it is proposed to spend it. About ie 20th of April last, the superintendent notified the commis - on that the stone dam across the canon below the spring touse was about to give way. The chairman requested Mr. •. W. Barnes to proceed to the hatcheries and see what was </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 necessary to be done. Upon examination he found it was ab - solutely necessary to remove the dams and rebuild them com - pletely. Teams and men had to be got, which at this time of the year was no easy matter. The stone had to be quarried and hauled, and sand taken from the river bed, cement shipped to Meadow from Omaha, seven miles away. The whole causing an enormous amount of work for both men and teams. Three of the old dams were removed and new ones built. No. 1 being 31 ft. in length, 6 ft. high, 3£ ft. thick. Ho. 2 was 34 ft, long, 7£ ft. high and 4 ft. thick. No. 3 was 38 ft. long, 74 ft. high and 4 ft. thick, and a wall in the race near the hatching house 34 ft. long, 5 ft. high, 3£ ft. thick, making a total of 3,616 ft. of solid masonry, built of the best material so as to stand for all time to come. Two more of these dams will have to be built the coming season. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 STATE FAIR EXHIBIT. (Exhibits of fish and products of the hatcheries and of th inner of hatching fish was made at the State Fair in Lincoh Id under the superintendence 1 of Commissioner R. S. Ober der, Superintendent, assisted by Commissioner Barnes am iperintendent Sloup. The commission was complimente( rv highly on the State Fair exhibit. The display at the fisher ilding forming one of the greatest attractions on the fa ounds. The main exhibit of live fish was made in twenty aquariums each eight to ten feet long, including one large circular tank twelve feet across in the center of the building holding about 100 barrels, ornamented with all kinds of pond and water lillies, forming a very attractive feature of the exhibits There were also a half dozen of glass globes in which ornamental fish were shown. The varieties of fish displayed were: brook, rainbow, and brown trout, one to four years old; large mouth black bass, six months, one year, and four years old; wall - eyed pike, two and three years old; ring perch, croppies, ruck bass, channel, spotted, and yellow catfish, pickerel, German carp, six months, one year, and four years old; sheepshead, black suckers, blue gill, black-eared and rainbow sun fish, bull heads, eels, shovel nose and rock sturgeon, lake lawyer, buff - alo fish quillback, black horse, tench, red horse, long and short nose gars, hickory and gizzard shad, darters, golden bream, chubs, gold, silver, and pearl fish, Japaense fan-tails, and native minnows, and several specimens of deformed fish, fresh water clams, frogs, snapping, mud and soft-shell turtles: a number of jars of alcholic specimens, showing fish eggs and tish in the various stages of development. The smallest live fish shown would weigh about one half ounce, while the largest was a channel catfish weighing ninety-eight pounds which at - tracted much attention. commission would recommend that the legislature make me appropriation for the purpose of aiding the people at and </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 REPORT OF FISH COMMISSION. near South Bend and tbe hatcheries for the purpose of rebuild- ing the bridge across thePlatte river, so the car could be loaded at that place and visitors could visit tbe grounds without so much inconvenience as now. The fund appropriated by the last legislature for all pur- poses was so small that we had to economize on every hand, the amount was as follows: For expense of enforcing fish laws, (one hundred dol- lars) $ 100 For new apparatus and repairs and repairing and build - ing ponds, (nine hundred dollars) 900 Painting and repairing fish car, two hundred dollars &gt; . . 200 Necessary labor, (one thousand dollars) 1,000 ■ rocuring and transporting fish, etc., (fifteen hundred dollars) 1,500 Bridge tolls, fish feed and feed for teams, (six hundred dollars) Salary of superintendent per annum, (twelve hundred 1,200 dollars); (twenty-four hundred dollars) 2,400 Total $7,900 Of this amount a considerable portion of which waj ex- pended previous to August 1, 1899, leaving a balance in the various funds up to this time not expended by the present board. The following is the separate amounts remaining not expended: Salary of superintendent $ 600 00 Enforcing fish laws 56 00 Painting and repairing, etc 34 00 Procuring and transporting fish 192 05 Bridge tolls and fish feed, feed for teams 53 00 Total balance at this time 91,137 34 With some bills yet outstanding in some of these funds which will leave very little, if any, in the several funds by January 1. With $1,256.60 unpaid bills as a deficiency fund which goes before the present legislature, $1,247 of which is </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 for necessary labor, leaving $9.60 of the deficiency amount, which belongs to printing and necessary repairs. The commissioner is indebted to the railroads of the state for the many courtesies received and for the free transporta - tion of the car and employes at all times when requested by the Board. In conclusion, we desire to extend our thanks to the super - intendent, Mr. Adam J. Sloup, for the efficient manner in which he has conducted the affairs of the institution. We also wish to commend the services of Mr. C. E. Straight and Summer Barnell, who have continued to remain, and have performed their work as faithfully since the labor fund has been exhausted, drawing no pay since February, 1900, stand - ing up for the state as nobly, and doing their work as faith - fully as though they were drawing their pay each month. Respectfully submitted, The Board of Fish Commissioners. By. D. W. Barnes. Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 SUPERINTENDENTS REPORT 1899 AND 1900. STATE FISH HATCHERIES. To the Honorable Board of Fish Commissioners: Gentlemen — Appended hereto you will find my report of work done during the time intervening from August 1, 1899, to the present time. I have exercised much care in making my tabulated statements plain and accurate, so that the citi - zens of any county where there is any interest taken in the industry can see what the commission is doing on behalf of the peopie in the matter of fish culture. My opportunities have been somewhat limited, from the fact that not enough money was appropriated to properly conduct the institution as it should have been. In December, 1899, by direction of the Board I had to cut down the working force to two men, there - by allowing the grounds to be somewhat neglected, as all the time was taken up in caring for and hatching of the young fish. It is true, there has been considerable work in the way of repairs, such as keeping up fences, repairs on house, barn, pond, etc. . There has been hatched and planted during the time I hare been in charge, in round numbers, by actual count, 250,000 of tish actually raised at the hatcheries. The different varieties of fish distributed consists of the following: Wall-Eyed Pike, Black Bass, German Carp, Rain - bow Trout, Croppies, Striped Perch, Channel Catfish, Rock Bass, besides about 15,000 Gold Fish for ornamental pur - poses. I find that my predecessor, according to his books distrib - uted, since his last report, 5,942,500. Making a total of 6, - 192,500 distributed since his last report. kOf this number about 95 per cent were delivered direct to plicants, direct from the car, and planted with scarcely any is and no cost to the applicant and at little cost to the state, </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 balance being shipped to the applicants by express, for the purpose of stocking private ponds. In addition to the work of batching and distributing this large number of fish, there has been considerable work done in the way of keeping the ponds, buildings and fencing in repair. The bridge across the Platte has broken down, necessitating going to Louisville, a distance of eight miles, for all of our snpplies, which takes up too much of our time. I think that this industry should be encouraged for there is a growing demand for fish even to the gold or ornamental fish, there being a greater demand every year for this latter kind, both private parties and for teachers in the public schools, which alone will pay the state the amount it costs. In conclusion, I would say that if the number of visitors who have visited the hatcheries is any criterion to judge by, the institution is growing in popularity, as there has been a constant stream of visitors at the hatcheries the past summer. Several special excursions being run to South Bend over the B. &amp; M. R. R. so the visitors could visit the hatcheries. A new cement floor should be laid in the hatching house, some new perforated zinc trays are needed, the barn is in bad shape and needs repairing as is also the superintendent's resi - dence, which should be plastered, a new roof should be put on and painted inside and out, new fences should be bnilt, around the entire grounds and the remainder of the stone dams will have to be rebuilt. In conclusion, I want to extend my thanks to the Board for the kind treatment and the many courtesies shown me. I also wish to extend my thanks to Messrs. C. £. Straight and Sum - mer Barnell for the efficient and able manner they have as - sisted me with my work during the time I have been Superin- Respectfully submitted by ADAM J. SLOUP, Superintend' ii(. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT Showing the Number and Kind of Fish Distributed, and the Parties to Whom They Were Shipped. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Applicant. Postoffice. County. IF. Wennel Steiner C. Mahan Fremont C. Jenkens Neligh Thorton Neligh Johnson Joy Erb Joy F. Roberts Joy A. Robertson Joy D. Gallentine Turner I.Evans O'Neill C. Motr Harrisonville E. Downew Harrisonville M. Hunter Harrisonville W. Phillips Star aerPhillips Star ink Hern Star L. Bright ONeill Lewislette ONeill J. Worst O'Neill Ellis Star . W. Merideth ONeill W.Bradt O'Neill atrick Regan O'Neill H. Gerrard ONeill S. Kinch O'Neill Casey O'Neill ames Brennan O'Neill . E. Deyorman O'Neiil . B. Berry Paddock .B.Anderson Star dolph Pekrson Agill . Emerson .... Catalpa a A Johnson Wood Lake }. A. Johnson Wood Lake 1. J. Anderson Cody Ingle Chadron L W. Bowe Chadron . T. Sear Chadron . M. Jackson Chadron . A. Moonnan Chadron . R. Monkers Chadron ). S. Pope Crawford . S. Tucker Glen ' . S. Johnson Glen . H. Russell Glen \ Force Andrews erraan Pankonin Grout . Employes South Bend. . Schweser David City Scnweser David City Z. H. Cornell Ithaca . A. Armstrong Greenwood '. A. Armstrong Greenwood . A. Armstrong Greenwood .W.Simpson Guide Rock Pawnee Dodge Antelope Antelope Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt. Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt J Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Holt Cherry Cherry Cherry Dawes Dawes Dawes Dawes Dawes Dawes Dawes Sioux Sioux Sioux '.. Sioux Perkins Sarpy Butler Butler Saunders Cass Cass Cass Webster </seg>
            <seg id="p015">REPORT OF FI8H COMMISSION. 15 Kind of Fish. No. Where Planted. Date Delivered 1 Carp 800 Pond. 2 B. Trout 2500 Sprint April 3, 1899 April 3, 1899 April 3, 18M April 8, 1899 April 3, 1899 April 8, 1899 April 3, 1899 April 3, 18V9 April 8, 1899 April 3. 1899 April 3, 1899 April 3, 1899 April 3. 1899 April 3, 1899 April 8, 1899 April 3. 1899 April 3, 189* April 3, 1899 April 3, 1899 April 3, 1*99 April 3, 1899 April 3, 1899 April 3, 1899 April 8, 1899 April 3, 1*99 April 3. 1899 April 8, 1899 April 3. 1899 April 3, 1899 April 3. 1899 April 3, 1809 April 3, 1*V9 April 3. 1899 April 3, 1899 April 8. 1899 April 8. 1899 April 8, 1899 April 8. 1899 April 8. 1899 April 8. 1899 April 8, 18M April 8, 1899 April 8, 1899 April 8, 1899 April 8. 18M April 8. 1899 April 17. 1899 April 12. 1899 April 13, 1899 April 13. 1899 April 18, 1899 April 15, 1899 April 15. 1899 April 15. 1899 Spring Lake. .. \ erdigris Lake 8 B. Trout 5000 4 B. Trout 5000 5000 Verdigris Lake.. 2500 \ Black Bird Creek 5 B. Trout 6 B. Trouj 2500 Black Bird Creek. 7 B. Trout 2500 Black Bird Creek. 8 B. Trout 2500 Black Bird Creek . 9 R. B. Trout 2500 Spring Branch 10 R. B. Trout 2500 Oak Creek 11 B. Trout 2500 Verdigris Lake . 12 B Trout 2500 Verdigris Lake . 13 B. Trout 2500 Verdigris Lake . 14 B. Trout 2500 Verdigris Lake . 15 I B Trout 2500 Verdigris Lake 16 B. Trout 2500 Verdigris Lake 17 B. Trout 2500 Loose Creek ... 18 B. Trout 2500 Little Eagle Creek 18 B. Trout 2500 Littla Eagle Creek 2&lt;) B. Trout ' 2500 Steel Creek 21 B. Trout I 2500 j Red Bird Creek 82 B Trout 2500 I Blue Bird Creek. . 88 I B. Trout 2500 Spring Branch 24 B. Trout 2500 Spring Branch. . . 25 B. Trout 2500 Verdigris Creek. . 25 B. Trout 26 B. Trout 2500 Red Bird Creek.. . 87 B. Trout 2500 Red Bird Creek 28 B. Trout 2500 Little Eagle Creek 29 R. B. Trout 2500 Spring Creek 28 B. Trout 80 B. Trout 2500 | Apple Creek 81 B. Trout 2500 \ Red Bird Creek. 82 B. Trout 2500 Little Eagle Creek 83 B. Trout 10000 Evergreen Creek . 34 B. Trout 10000 Fairfax Creek 36 B. Trout 10000 Medicine Creek 86 | B. Trout 5000 I Bordeaux Creek. . 87 IB. Trout 2500 Bordeaux Creek. . 88 B. Tront 2500 I Bordeaux Creek. 89 B. Trout 2500 Bordeaux Creek . . 40 B. Trout 2500 Bordeaux Creek .. 2500 I Bordeaux Creek.. 41 B. Trout 2500 Bordeaux Creek.. 43 B. Trout 2500 Spring Lake 43 R. B. Trout 2500 Spring Branch 44 B. Trout 2500 Pond 45 B. Trout 2500 i Pond « 46 I B. Trout 2500 I White Rive 47 Carp 110 Pond 48 W.I. Pike 2500 | Elkhorn River 49 Cap 100 ; Pond 60 R. B. Trout 500 | Pond 51 Carp 100 I Pond 52 Carp 100 | Rock Creek 53 Catfish 50 Rock Creek «4 Pika ! 35000 ! Rock Creek </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Applicant. Postoffice. County. W. II. Duhani Roca Lancaster William Ernest Graf Johnson , William Ernest Graf Johnson W. WcOmber Crete Saline W. C. Ault Beaver Crossing Seward T. Crane Beaver Crossing . . . Seward H Michael Beaver Crossing . . . Seward By Corcrew Seward Seward I Brothers Aurora .... Hamilton Wood Brothers Aurora Hamilton Frwl Meyer Blue Hill Webster Fred Meyer Blue Hill Webster H. G. Cas* Aurora Hamilton S. We lister Wescott Custer G. Mitchell Clay Center Clay A. Peterson Saronville Clay P. J. Coulaon Saronville Clay F. Fowler Fremont Dodge K..v &gt;Jye Fremont Dodge W. Fruf Fremont. . . . ; Dodge H. C. Mahome Fremont Dodge Mahome Fremont Dodge Fred Baainsheia West Point Cuming J. P. Browder Dodge Dodge By Car Crew Stanton Stanton 8. W. Sell wen k Norfolk Madison Burt Mapes Norfolk MmUmm O. H Moas Battle Creek Madison W. B. Fuerst BatileCreek Madison 8. T. Napper Battle Creek Madison H. Miller BattleCreek Madison By Car Crew Oakdale Antelope &lt;i. W. French Ewing Holt G. W. Freneh Ewing Holt G W. French Ewing Holt S. D. Gilletine O'Neill Holt Q.W. Bishop Wheeler Wheeler Fred Thornton Nelighe Antelope K E Slaymohe Atkinson Holt W. J. H. Sterns Atkinson Holt B. Fullerton Atkinson Holt B. Fullerton Atkinson Holt W A. Ellis Dorsey Holt J.L.Gordon Newport Rock O. Timmerman Inglis Holt By Car Crew Long Pine Brown &lt; . J. Anderson Cody Cherry C. J. Anderson Cody Cherry J. M. Lane Cody Cherrv J M. Lane Cody Che rv C.E.Williams Rushville Sheridan E. D. Satterlee Chadron Dawes J. E. Hartwelf Crawford Dawes F. E. Wheeler Crawford Dawes D. S. Pope Cmwfurd Dawes </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 REPORT OF FI8H COM MI8SIOH. Kind of Fish. No. Where Planted. Date Delivered. 1 Pike 25000 Dunham April 15, 1899 •&gt; Pike | 50000 Crust Lake April 15, 18M a Black Bass i 100 Crust Lake April 15, 18M 4 Pike 500000 Bine river j April IB, 1899 o Pike i 25000 Pond ! April 15, 1909 ■ Pike 25000 Pond I April 15; 1899 • Pike 25000 Pond ; April 15. 18W 8 Pike 400000 Plue river I April 15,1899 « Bass 200 Pond April 15, 1899 Catfish 50 Pond April 15. 1H99 11 Pond April 15,1899 V&gt; r .P-: 100 u Cattish 100 Pond ■ April 15, 1899 u Carp 50 Pond I April 15, 1899 14 Carp 100 Pon.l Pon.l | April 15, 1899 Little Black i April 15,1899 15 Pike.. I 100 10 Black Bass I 400&lt;00 Pond ! April IS, 1899 IT Pond Cattish 50 Pond April 15,1899 l.iukfsLake April 19. I nay Liickf-s Lake Ap il 19,1X99 Laekei Lake April 1 Campbell Lake May 1», 1899 Pike 50 IS Pike 25000 «» Pike 2.5000 &amp; Pike 85000 'li U1....1- n«_-.. nnn W U5000 May 111, 1899 ( taapbell Lake ! May 19, 1899 Bl:&lt;ckBass 200 588 Pike aOOUOO *f Catfish 50 "-'•&gt; Pike 50000 * Pike 25000 Klkhorn River May 1H, 1899 Pond Mey )»! 1899 Klkorn River May m, 1-99 Pond .!..... May 1»! \m 'J5000 - 7 Pike 75000 ** Pike 70000 *» Pike 50000 30 Pike 50000 31 Pike 50IHH) 3a Pike 250000 ■■ Pike 50000 •&gt;■* (iittiisli 100 •&gt;T Henderson Lake j May 19. 1K'.»9 Battle Creek . . . . '.'. '.'.' May 19! 1999 Lilllhy Lake I May 19^ 18:* Klkhorn River May 1»! 1899 Battle Creek May 19, 1*99 Klkhorn River '.'.\ May 1»1 18S9 25O0U0 O'Connor Lake May 1U.' 1899 O'Connor Lake May 19! 1 8U9 ittiish I 100 *5 Black Bass W Pike 2.1000 3 ? K. B. Trout 25000 38 i R B Trout. r",(MM) O'Connor Lake..! '. '. . May 19! 1899 Pon.l . May 19. 1899 May 19^ 1890 Pond 19.' 1899 &lt;» R B Trout 5000 8 » Pike 25000 4« Pike 25000 Verdigris River May 19! 1899 Newton Lake M:.y 19.' 1899 40 Pike 25000 Eagle Lake May 1»| 1899 41 Pike HMO Kiijrle Lake. 42 ! R. B. Trout ....... 2500 * 3 R. B. Trout 3500 May 19! 1899 Kagle Creek May i»! \ma 3500 Pond May 1»; 1889 *■* K B. Trout 2500 OakCaeek. May 19. 1899 46 Carp 100 Pond 4«J R. B. Trout 25(0 May 19. 1899 Pine Creek. 47 R. B. Trout 2500 Medicine Creek 5(1000 Ander-on Lake May 20. 1899 48 Pike May 20. 1H99 49 R B. Trout 2500 Spring Pond Spring Pond May 20. 1899 80 Croppies 100 May 20. 1899 May 20! 1899 51 R B. Trout 2500 Lonoke C.ieek 52 R. B. Trout 1000 &lt; 'hadron Creek. May 20. 1899 H May 20. 1899 R. B. Trout •J500 Pond M R.B. Trout 25000 Squaw Creek. May M, 1899 Pape's Ijike </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Applicant. Postoffice. County. I H. G. Newcomb J. H. Peabody J. B. Johnson By Car Crew By Car Crew Fred Jewell Fred Jewell Fred Jewell L. Heon By Car Crew G F. Phillips (;. F. Phillips C. C. Redwood C. F. Bake Matt Leach S. B. Cran* S E. Crans Chas. Stelnic L. Smith J. F. Worrel F. Danwalter J. Hocking J. C. Kesterson J. C. Kesterson Armour &amp; Co D. H. Corrig Co. Fish Com J. Wood H. Roepker C. Bosseliuan S. L Wisner J. Bosselman LP. Judd L P. Judd Walt Jewell Walt Jewell D. Fitzgerald A. G. Kyburn J. W. Griffin K. Emanuelason R. Kmanuelason R. Emanuelason. \yers S. Ayers S. Ayers J.C. Wolf J. C. Wolf S K. Crans S K. Crans J. W. Welpton W. M. Iddings J. H. Barrett F. D. Bedin R H UlaiilTor ±j • ii&lt; umuiivi Crmwford Crawford Glen Milford Ulysses Platte Centre Platte Centre Platte Cent.e Platte Centre Columbus Columbus Columbus Geneva Fullerton Fullerton Albion Albion Central City Central City Kearney Steinauer Demon Denton Fairbury Fairbuay Memphis Clear water Denver Springfield St. Liberty Worms Grand Island Grand Island Columbus Columbus Piatte Centre Platte Centre Shelton Big Springs Sidney Lodge Pole Lodge Pole Lodge Pole Lodge Pole Lodge Pole Lodge Pole Ix&gt;dge Pole Lodge Pole Albion Albion Ogallala Lapeer Ogallala Corbin Kearney Dawes Dawes Sioux Seward Seward Platte Platte Platte Platte Platte Platte Platte Nance Nance Nance Boone Boone Merrick Merrick Buffalo Pawnee Lancaster Lancaster Jefferson Jefferson Saunders Antelope Sarpy Howard Hall Hall Hall Colfax Colfax Platte Platte Buffalo Buffalo Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Cheyenne Boone Boone Keith Cheyenne Keith Dawes Buffalo </seg>
            <seg id="p019">REPORT OF FI H COMMISSION. Kind of Fish. No. Where Planted. Date Delivered. Pike Pike Catfish Pike Pike B. Bass Croppies Pike Carp Pike Croppies Bass Bass Bass Bass Bass Fike B. Bass B. Bass B Bass B. Bass Carp Pike ...'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Pike Pike Pike Carp Cattish Catfish Catfish Catfish R.Bass Perch Perch R. Bass Sunfish Cattish R. Bass Carp Cattish B. Bass Catfish B. Bass Perch Cattish Perch B. Bass Croppies Catfish Carp Catfish Oroppies 25 00 50000 60 400000 500000 250 150 25000 200 500000 200 200 100 100 100 200 25000 100 100 110 350 100 100 200 250000 500000 10000 30000 130 35 35 35 50 50 50 50 50 200 35 200 200 100 100 100 100 100 50 50 50 50 35 50 35 100 100 Crawford Lake. . . . Crawford Lake Crawford Lake Blue River Blue River Shell Creek Shell Creek Shell Creek Pond Sioux Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Beaver River Beaver River Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Little Blue River... Silver Lake Clear water Creek.. Clearwater Creek . . Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Deep Nole Creek.. Duck Creek Echo Pond May 20. 1899 May 20, 1899 May 3o! 18M May 80, 1899 May 30. 18W May 30, 1899 May dO. 1898 May 80, 1899 May 30, 1899 May 30. 1899 May 30, 18W May 30, 1899 M«y 30. 189» May 30. 1890 May 31, 1899 May 31, 1898 May 31. 1899 May 31, 1899 May 31. 1899 May 31, 1899 June 3, 1899 June 3. 1899 June 3, 1899 June 3, 1899 June 3, 1899 June 8, 1898 Oct. 23. 1899 Oct. 28, 1899 Oct. 28, 1899 Oct. S3, 1899 Oct 28, 18» Oct 23. 1899 Oct. 23. 1899 Oct. 23. 1899 Oct. 23. 1899 Oct! 38,' 1899 Oct. 28. 1899 Oct. 23. 1899 Oct. 23. 1899 Oeti 23l 1899 Oct. 23. 1899 Oct. 23. 1899 Oct. 28, 1899 Oct. 23. 1899 Oct. 23, 1899 Oct. 23. 1899 *&gt; Oct. 23. Ih99 Oct. 23. 1899 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Applicant. Postoffiee. County. T. Murphy Shelton Buffalo H. Slearly Shelton Buffalo H. Miller Alda... Hall H. Miller Alda Hall F.Jewell Platte Center Platte W.H. Cogil Central City Platte D. J. Poynter Albion Boone D. J. Poynter Albion Boone C. P.Bake Fullerton Nance L. F. Phillips Coluinbus Platte S E. Crans Albion Boone W. N Miller Alda Hall T. E. Wheeler Crawford Dawes N.W.King Crawford Dawes F. W. Uarington Crawford Dawes F. W. Darington Crawford Dawes E. A. Thompson Crawford Dawes E. A. Thompson Crawford Dawes J. P. Green Crawford Dawes G. E. Dariogton Crawford Dawes J. Milne Crawford Dawes S. M. B. Stewart Crawford Dawes S. M. B. Stewart Crawford Dawes J 'J'. Stewart Crawford Dawes F. Welling Crawford Dawes W. P. Bornem Crawford Dawes J. Butterworth Crawford Dawes E. J. Lerenr Crawford Dawes E. J. Lerenr I Crawford Dawes J. Hiblen Hanison Sioux J. Nolen Harrison I Sioux E. F. Roberts O'Neil Holt (J W. Schwenk Norfolk Madison V (.'. Kasmussen Bute Boyd N. Bowen Roy Holt J. T. Green Badger Holt W. Anderson Badger Holt J. Yandenburg Badger Holt J Fulk Green Valley Holt J. Krikac Bute Boyd F. Sinnerd Napier Holt W. A. Kenneston Spring View Keyapaha J. N orris Johnston Brown J Bowman Valentine Cherry Newberry Cody Cherry Newberry Cody Cherry Newberry Cody Cherry S. V. picker Rushrille Sheridan W.Melcher Rushville Sheridan J. Milne Crawford Dawes H. Jarrett West Point Cuming J.Myers West Point Cuming F. Sonnenschein West Point Cuming C. E Thompson West Point Cuming </seg>
            <seg id="p021">KEPOKT OF Fli H COMMISSION. Kind of Fish. No. Where Planted. Date Delivered. 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 i Cattish Carp R.Bass Catfish K Bass Catfish Simtish Croppies R. Bass Croppies Cattish Black Bass Cattish Catfish Black Bass Catfish Perch Catfish Caltish | Cattish Catfish Black Bass Cattish , B. Bass S B Bass ! Catfish R Bass i Cat&amp;ih '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'.'.'. R. Bass Catfish R. Bass Cattish Carp Carp Carp Croppies R. Bass B. Bass B. Bass Croppies B. Bass B. Bass Carp Carp B. Bass Catfish B. Heads B. Basi* Croppies B. Bass Croppies B. Bass 15. D&amp;SS ............ 40 50 100 40 100 35 200 200 100 200 50 35 75 35 35 50 35 75 35 35 35 35 50 35 35 50 35 50 50 35 75 35 75 35 50 50 50 75 75 75 75 75 75 50 35 50 75 35 100 75 75 75 75 75 75 Wood River Worm Slovgh Pood Cedar River Shell Creek Pond Beaver River Pond Beaver River Beaver River Beaver River Beaver River Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Oct. Oct. Oct. Oct. (»Ct. Oct. Oct. Oct. Oct. Oct. Oct. Oct. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Not. Not. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Not. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Not. Nov: 23, 1890 23, 18»9 23, 1899 23, 1899 23. 1 99 23. 1899 23, 1899 33, 1899 23, 1899 33, 1899 23. 1899 23,1899 23, 1899 1899 23. 1899 23. 1899 23, 1809 23, 1899 23. 1899 23, 1899 23, 1890 23. ltO9 23. 1899 23. 1899 23, 1890 33. 1899 23, 1899 23. 189* 23, 1899 23. 1899 23,1899 33, 1899 33, 1899 23. 1899 28, 1899 33. 1899 28.1899 83, 1899 33, 1899 38, 1899 23. 1899 23, 1899 23, 1899 28, 1899 28, 1899 23, 1899 23, 1899 23, 1899 28, 1899 23, 1899 23, 1899 33. 1899 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Applicant. Postoffice. County. Norfolk M I B. Napes Pierce Pierce . Pierce Pierce . Creighton Knox. . Creighton Knox. . Battle Creek Madiso Fierce Milling Co. Pierce Mil ling Co. W. A. Hufainith.. W. A. Hufainith. . A. Wendt Knox. Madison. Battle Creek Madison.. Battle Creek Madison. . Battle Creek Madison. . Battle Creek Madison. . Battle Creek Madison.. Battle Creek Madison. O'Neill Holt Lodge Pole Cheyenne Lodge Pole Cheyenne Lodge Pole Cheyenne Sidney Cheyenne I Wendt Miller Miller H. Moas. . . P. Napper P. Napper. D. Leonard I » Ml 13 R. S. Oberfelder. R. S. Oberfelder. R. S. Oberfelder. W. C. Couch 14 15 1« IT Euger Bros. . . Lehmhukl . Lehmhukl . . o. Simmons, o. Simmons. Toban Sidney Cheyenne Cheyenne is Lodge Pole. 15» Lodge Pole Cheyenne 30 Lodge Pole . Cheyenne Cheyenne ■21 Lodge Pole. n Lodge Pole Cheyenne Sidney Cheyenne Colon Saunders . Fremont Dodge . . . Fremont Dodge . . . West Point Cuming.. . West Point Cuming... West Point Cuming... m G. W. Gillard . . C. E. Olson Ray Nye H. C. Mahanua. A. Pospisil 24 25 M 27 M I Myers Moores. . . Schorfen Pospisil. . P. Green: n :»&gt; West Point West Point . Cuming West Point Cuming 31 Cuming n Lovoca Cherry n KT. Notoling. L. Babbitt . . B. Fobs Badger Holt :u Crawford Dawes a-, Sterling Johnson 3.; W. D. Akins W. D. Akins. W. D. Akins. J. Shea Western Saline 57 Western Saline n Western Saline ■ Diller Jefferson 40 J. Shea. Diller Jefferson 41 KE. Larkin. Miller Edgar Clay M Pleasant Dale j Lancaster i Abbott Hall H. Togel. 44 B. F. Garner . B. F. Garner . C. Corniolius. H. Schmidt. . . T. Buschaw . . J. Myer Hickman Lancaster 4.". Hickman ; Lancaster « Blue Hill Webster 47 Blu.' Hill Webster 4* Blue Hill Webster 49 Blue Hill Webster 50 K. H. Wearer. C. Freas . . . Wallace Perkins r,i Madrid Perkins 5 H. Parkorim Grant Perkins Wauneta Chase M Imperial i Chase IB </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 REPORT OF FISH COM MISSION. Kind of Fish. No. Where Planted. Date Delivered. 1 B. Bass 75 Pond. Nov. 88. 18W Nov. 23. 1899 Nov. 23, 1899 Not. 23. 1809 Nov. 23. 1899 Nov. 23. 1899 Nov. 28. 1899 Nov. 28. 1899 Nov. 23. 1899 Nov. 28. 1899 Nov. 83, 18M Nov. 23, 1899 Nov. 23. 1899 Nov. 23, 1899 Nov. 23, 1899 Nov. 83, 1899 Nov. 23, 1899 Nov. 28, 18V9 Nov. 28, 1899 Nov. 28. 1899 Nor. 28. 1899 Nov. 2a 1899 Nov. 28, 1898 Nov. 23, 1899 a B. Bass I 75 Pond. 3 Croppies 75 Pond. B. Bass 75 Benkle Creek. 4 5 Croppies 75 Benk e Creek. 0 Croppies ! 75 Pond 7 Cathish ; 40 Pond K R. Bass i 78 Battle Creek. R Bass 100 » Battle Creek. 10 R. Bass I 75 Battle Creek. 11 C Pond ,'roppies 76 12 R. Bass I 75 Pond. 18 B L Bass 75 Pond. 14 Cattisk 100 Pond. 15 Perch 100 Pond lti B. Bass J50 Pond Pond. 17 Catfish 85 ix R. Bass 200 Pond. 10 Catfish Pond. 50 20 R Bass 100 Pond. Carp 50 Pond. 21 22 R.Bass 100 Pond. H R. Bass. 100 [ Pond N Cattish I 100 inn Pnml Pond. Nov. 23. 1-99 M Catfish... 100 Silver Creek. 26 B Bass 100 I. inch Lake. Nov. 22, 1899 '_&gt;7 B.Bass 100 Pond. Nov. 23. 1899 100 Pond 28 B. Bass. Nov. 23. 1899 29 Carp 50 Pond. Nov. 23, 1899 30 Croppies 100 81 Carp 50 30 Croppies. Moore's Lake. Nov. 23. 189» Pond. Nov. 23, 1899 32 Croppies 100 Pond . Nov. 23, 1899 Pond I Nov. 23, 1899 38 Catfish 35 84 Carp 50 Pond Nov. 28. 1899 35 Catfish 35 Pond ; Dec. 7. 1899 8« Catfish 35 Pond Dec. 7. 1899 87 Catfish 35 Pond Dec. 7, 18b9 38 Carp 35 Pond i Dec. 7. 1899 89 Sunfish 100 Pond I Dec. 7. 1899 40 Carp 85 Pond Dec. 7. i89» 41 Perch 75 Pond I Dec 7. 1899 42 B. Bass 75 Pond Dec. 7, 1898 4H Carp 40 Pond Dec. 7, 1899 44 Carp 40 Pond I Dec. 7, 1899 45 Carp 40 Pond I Dec. 7, 1899 4« Catfish 35 Pond Dec. 7. 1899 47 Perch- 75 Pond De&lt;- 7, 1899 Pond Dec. 7, i899 48 Carp 40 49 Carp 40 50 Carp 40 Pond Dec. 7, 1899 Pond Deo. 7. 1899 4(1 51 Carp 40 Pond Deo. 7, 1899 Pond Deo 7. 1899 52 Carp 40 53 Carp 40 Pond I Dec. 7. 1899 54 Perch 100 Pond Dec. 7, 1899 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Applicant Postofflce. County. D. J. Richman Bartley Red Willow 1 »J. Richman Bartlev. Red Willow 3 A. VanSickle Benkleman Deuel Deuel 3 A. VanSickle. Benkleman. 4 D. L. Hi ties. Haigler Deuel 5 D. L. Hines. Haigler D^uel 6 J. R, Kendry Lincoln Lancaster 7 Planted by Crew. Bordeaux Dawes 8 Holt 9 T. Blanden. Inglis A. G. Holt. Johnston Brown 10 Cherry 11 M. V. Nicholson. Valentine J. Smalley. Crawford Dawes 19 F. A. Hirmon. Chadron. Dawes 13 T. L. Goff. Chadron. Dawes 14 J. Buy man. Chadron. Dawes 15 F. Block Chadron. l)awi-s 16 Cherry 17 C. Russeter Coey. R. Ingle. Chadron. Dawes 18 Planted by Crew. Andrews Chadron iy Planted by Crew. Dawes 20 F. E Wheeler. Dawes 21 Crawford A. T. Hughson. Harrison Sioux 23 H. S. Cox Chadron Dawes 28 C. J. Anderson . Cody .... Kushville. Cherry 24 G. Tirmire Sheridan 85 W M. Green Chadron. Dawes 26 C Main Chadron. Dawes 87 S. Adams Chadron Dawes 98 W. E Weber Creighton Antelope 99 C. L. Bright. O'Niel Holt Holt SO W. J. Evans. O'Niel 31 kj. Gilligan . M. Dotty ONiel O-Niel Holt 82 Holt 39 W H.Wilson. ONiel Holt 84 G. Rock. ONiel Holt 85 C. L. Bright. O-Niel Holt Holt 36 F. Root Ingles. 37 W. A Wheeler. I Ingles. Holt 88 P. Root. Ingies. Holt 39 G. W.Fairchild. [ Kennard. Washington 40 tv. Isaac Peters Fried Henderson Fremont 41 Dodge 43 M. Fowler F.Robler '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Fremont. Dodge 43 Fremont. Dodge 44 Scribner. Dodge 45 F. Steinhofel. Crowell Dodge 46 G. W. Schwenk. Norfolk. Pierce I 47 J. F. Chapman Oakdale. Antelope I 48 J. F. Chapman. Oakdale. Antelope j 49 J. Allstot Clea: water. Antelope 50 KM. MiKaney M. Smith Clearwater Ewing Antelope 51 Holt 59 Halt 53 Holt 54 Boyd 55 J. J. Jansen. Ewing. J. J. Jansen. Ewing.. . I Atkinson. 55 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">REPORT OF KI8H COMMISSION. 25 Kind of Fish. No. Where Planted. Date Deliver d. &lt;*rp-, 40 pond ::::::::::: Dec. 7,iw» 1 £Sft « P » nd . • !&gt;«•. 7. 1899 . o Snntteh ioo Pond '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'. \\ \ W £ 189» i s 4 £ eri : h - 100 Pond De«-. 7' 1899 5K-*tbsh 3.3 p on d De^. 7.1899 0 Suuhsh 100 Pond Dee 7 1899 7 Karp 100 Pond Dec. 7 8 R- irout 10000 BonloCk &amp; White R Dec. 7 1899 9 5-I n&gt;ut «» Bi,» Sandy April 10. 1J.00 t 4 Cattish. I i r, i i 1S99 it 1K00 10 R. Trout 500 Fairfax Creek.' rairf ax Creek April 10.1900 Book Creek April 10.1900 •'""'I April 10. 1900 Pond April 10. 1900 "on&lt;l April 10, 1900 Pond April 10. 1900 Pond April 10. 1900 Pond ... April 10. 1900 Bordeaux April 10. 1900 White River April 10.1900 Bordeaux April 10. 1900 11 R. Trout 11 R. Trout 500 12 R. Trout 500 13 R. Trout. 13 R. Trout 500 14 R. Trout 500 15 R. Trout. 500 500 18 R. Trout 500 17 R. Trout 50(1 18 R. Trout 1000 19 R. Trout 10000 10. 1900 20 R- Trout 10000 April 10, 1900 21 R Trout I 500 Square Creek ! April 10.1900 28 R. Trout 500 Kyle Creek i April 10.1900 23 I R. Trout | 500 —J ™ *- ■~~«» I n|nn 11 ■, JOTAI Pond 1 April 10. 1900 Pond April 10. 1900 Pond April 10. 1900 Pond j Amil 10. 1900 •_&gt;4 R. Trout I 500 25 I R Trout 500 26 R Trout 500 Ajiril 10. 1900 27 ! R. Trout too Poml April 10. 1900 28 R- Trout 500 Pond 500 Pond 500 Pond 500 Pond April 10 1900 29 R. Trout. April 10. 1900 30 R- Trout. April 10. 1900 April 10, 1900 81 R. Trout. 32 R. Trout 500 500 Pond 500 Pond April in 1900 33 R. Trout ! 500 Pond ...... 84 I R. Trout 500 Pond April 10, 34 R. Trout.. April If. 35 R. Trout 500 Pond '.'.'.'.'.'"'"'''. April 10. 86 R. Tront 500 Yvrul ........... April 10, 1WK) 37 R. Trout 500 i Pond ....... '.'. '.'. '.'. April 10. 1!«fl. 38 R. Trout." '.'.'.'.['.'.'.'.'.1 500 ! Pond '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. April 10 W0 39 R. Trout 500 | Pond April in l'.too 40 I Carp 100 Pond 41 Carp 100 Pond 42 Croppies 200 Pond 43 Croppies 200 Pond ().-t 10 Oct. 10 Oct. 10 Oct. 10 44 B. Bass I 3110 I Pond ..... ........ Oct. 10. 45 Carp 100 1 Pond Oct. 10 1900 4« Carp 100 Pond Oct. 1" 1W&gt;. 47 B. Bass 200 Pond . . . ' Oct! 10! 1900 48 B Bass 200 Pond I Oct. 10 1900 I Oct. 10. 1900 49 Croppies 200 Pond I Oct. lo! 1900 50 Bullhead 500 | Pond Oct. io! 1900 51 Catfish 100 ! Pond Oct. 10. 1900 52 B. Bass 200 Pond ic! 1900 53 Catfish 100 Pond 'Oct. 10.1900 54 B. Bass 200 j Pond j Oct. 10! 1900 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 REPORT OF FISH COMMISSION. Applicant. Postoffice. County. L. J. Fritchiff Atkinson.. Newport... Newport .. Ainsworth. Ainswarth. Ainsworth. Ainsworth. Johnston.. Johnston. . Johnston . . Cody Boyd .. Boyd.. Rock.. Rock.. Brown Brown Brown Brown Brown Brown Brown Cherry Cherry i Chas. Aster. Geo. W. Greer. C. Howe. P. D. McAndrews P. D. McAndrews 5 K. S. Rising. Gus Hoefs. . &gt; J. Wilson 9 R. E.Jones. 10 E. 8. Rosseter. 11 A. E. Barnes Cody 13 F. P. Green. Gordon 13 H. B. Brown ! Rushville Sheridan Sheridan 14 Max Amande Rushville. . . . May Springs May-^Springs Crawford . . . 15 Win. Sandon. Sheridan Sheridan Sheridan If, Win. Sandon 17 J. Barker. 16 W. Martins J. Smally j Chadron. . I Crawford Crawford Dawes. Dawes lit 20 Dawes Dawes 21 Crawford Ithaca ■ C. L. Miclenne Dawes •23 VT. H. Shoemaker. Newhaka . Spring Hill Saunders 24 J. P. School Cass 25 E. Tigh Louisville Pender Carpy 26 J. Otteman. C«S8 '-•7 J. Otteman Pender. . Ithaca Murdock . Murdock. Thurstou 28 kMilans R"(?e Thurston Saunders 29 :» F. Ruire. Cass Cass. 31 A. O'Kinayer. Ithaca Ithaca 3-J Clans From Claus From Saunders. Saunders. Sannders Saunders. Saunders. Keith 33 Ithaca. . . Ithaca. . . Wahoo.. Ggallala. 34 C. Anderson ■ G«o. Votepka. 36 W. A. Paxton 37 W. Neville North Platte. North platte. Boelus M W. Neville Lincoln.. Lincoln.. Howard . Howard . Hall.... U . Kenyan. 40 C. T. Kenyan G. Kochler I Boelua 41 Grand Island Fairfield 42 *8 W. Wolf. L. B. Reiber Jenny Bros Silver Creek. Columbus... . Columbus,.. . Clay Polk 44 45 Jenny Bros Colfax. Colfax 4(5 L. T. Connoly Burwell 47 J. Cannon. Wood River Wood River Garfield . Hall 4* J. Cannon. 49 J. J. Corey Wood River . Wood River. Kearney Hall Hall 50 J. J. Corey. 51 C. A. Murch C. A. Murch Hall. 53 Kearney. Shelton . Otrallala Buffalo Buffalo. I5.'J J. D. Lippencott 54 55 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">REPORT OF FISH COMMISSION. 27 Kind of Fish. No. Where Planted. il)ate Delivered. 1 Catfish . . 2 B Bass.. 8 B. Bass . 4 Croppies. 100 Pond Oct. 10, 1!K» 200 Pond Oct. In, 1900 300 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 200 Pond Oct. io! 1900 5 Carp Pond Oct. 10, 1900 6 Cattish 7 Cattish 8 B. Bass » Carp . . Pond Oct. 10, 1900 7 Catfish 100 I Pond Oct. 10, 1900 8 B. Bass 200 Pond Pond Oct. 10, 1900 » Carp 100 Pond Pond Oct. 10, 1900 10 B. Bass 300 Pond Pond Oct. 10, 1900 11 B Bass 200 Pond 200 Pond .u.ii I D 1 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 12 B. Bass 200 Pond I Oct. 10, 1900 18 Catfish 100 Pond Pond Oct. 10, 1900 14 Carp 100 Po*d 14 Carp .... 15 I Carp .... 16 I Croppies. Oct. 10, 1900 15 Carp 100 Pon.l 100 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 16 Croppies 200 Pond Oct. 10, 1U00 17 Perch 300 Pond 17 Perch Pond ] Oct. 10, 1900 18 B. Bass 1» Carp 18 B. Bass 200 Pond 200 Pond ! Oct. 10, 1900 1» Carp 100 Pond 100 Pond ! Oct. 10. 1WO0 20 B. Bass 200 Pond ■I B. Bass 21 Perch. j Oct. 10, 1900 -1 Perch 300 Pond Pond ; Oct. 10. 1900 300 ■ Carp M Carp 100 Pond 100 Pond I Oct. 10.1900 "-J3 Catfish 200 Pond 28 Cattish Pond 200 Oct. 10, l'JOO 24 Carp 200 Pond 24 Carp 200 j Pond Oct. 10. 1SHH) 85 Catfish 200 Pond •-'j Cattish 200 Pond Oct. 10, lltOO '■*&gt; Cattish '■*&gt; Cattish 200 Pond 200 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 «7 Cattish W Cattish 200 Pond Perch 200 Pond Pond 200 Oi-t. 10, l'JOO 2* Perch 200 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 29 Cattish 30 Cattish 2» Cattish 600 Pond 600 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 30 Catfish 200 Pond 200 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 31 Perch 81 Perch 200 Pond Pond. 200 Oct. 10, 1900 82 Cattish 400 r-&gt;od 88 Catfish -Kill I v &gt;nd Oct. 10. l'.lOO 83 Cattish 83 Catfish 400 Pond 400 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 84 Perch 200 Pond 84 Perch 200 Pond Oct. 10, 1900 85 Catfish '%&gt; Catfish 400 Pond 400 Pond Oct. 10, l!»00 86 Catfish 400 Pond 86 Catfish 400 Oct. 10, 1900 37 B. Bass 200 Pond 87 B. Bass. 200 Fond. Nov. 10, 1900 88 B. Bass 89 Perch 88 B. Bass 200 Pond Pond Nov. 10. 11)00 200 3» Perch 30 " Pond 30' Pond Nov. 10, 1V0O 40 Carp 100 Pond 40 C»rp 100 Pond Nov. 10. 1900 41 B Bass 200 Pond 41 B Bass 4- Cattish 200 Pond. Nov. 10. IHOO 4- Catfish 100 Pond Nov. 10, 1D00 100 Pond 48 Carp 100 Pond 48 Carp 100 Pond Nov 10. 1900 44 Carp .*.-.. ion Pond " C"P 100 Pond Nov. 10, l»0O 45 I B Bass. 45 B: Bass 200 Pond 200 Pond Nov. 10. 19nO 4« Perch 200 Pond 4« Perch Pond Nov. 10, 1900 20&lt;» 47 Perch 200 Pond 47 Perch . . 48 B Bass. 200 Pond Pond Nov. 10. 1900 48 B Bass 200 Pond 200 Nov. 10, 1900 4» Croppies 80 B. Bass ** Croppies 200 Pond 200 Pond Nov. 10. 1900 50 B. Bass 200 Pond 200 Pond . Nov. 10, 1900 51 Cattish 51 Cattish 1(10 Pond 100 Pond Nov. 10. 1900 52 B. Bass 52 B. Bass 200 Pond 200 Pond Nov. 10, 1900 ±^i-»». ivi iwvr 53 Perch 200 Pond 200 54 B. Bass. 200 Ponn Nov. 10. 1900 :W0 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Applicant. Postoffice. County. A. E. Jacobs. Ogalalla Keith 1 M. H. Tobin. Lodge Polo. Lodge Bole. Cheyenne 2 M. H. Tobin. Cheyenne 8 Cheyenne 4 Cheyenne 5 R. Kruger. Sidney Sidney R. Kruger R • r » E Kruse Sidney.. . Sidney... Sidney... Sidney... Sidney.. . Kim ball. Kimball. Cheyenue 6 Cheyenne. A. Gunderson. - A. Gundarscn. Cheyenne.. Cheyenna. . Cheyenne........ 1 Cheyenne 1 Cheyenne 1 Cheyenne 1 Cheyenne 1 Cheyenne 1 Cheyeune 1 Banner 1' C. ChamlKTs C. Chanil»ers A. Forshing. D. H. Eventt. J. Knuse Sidney Sidney J. Knuse. J. A. Olson Sidney.. Sidney.. Kimball Kimball P. Lungwall. A. Forshing 17 1). H. Everett. Banner I 18 A. B. Persenger Lodge Pole. Lodge Pole. Lodge Pole. I Cheyenne I 18 A. B. Persenger Cheyenne 20 Cheyenne 21 J. C. Wolf. 31 J. C. Wolf. Lodge Pole. Lodge Pole. Lodge Pole. Lodge Pole. Lodge Pole. JvOdge Pole. Chevenne. Cheyenne H. F.inanuelson Cheyenne 28 Cheyenne 24 Cheyenne 25 R. I. Oberfelder. M R. I. Oberfelder. •25 tl. Ol&gt;erfelder I. Oljerfelder Cheyenne.. 36 t heyenne 27 « F. Diekenson Lodge Pole Cheyenne ! Cheyenne ! Cheyenne 2 Cheyenne i Cheyenne I Cheyenne i Cheyenne I Cheyenne I Cheyenne ', Jefferson I Jefferson i Jefferson J J Simons. Lodge Pole H Barrett. Lodge Pole Lodge Pole L. (ianson. F. Lehmkiihl Lodge Pole. Lodge Pole. ]&gt;odge Pole. Lodge Pole. Lodge Pole. I. Lchmkuhl . Lehmkiihl ■ F. Booth F. Booth J. Ruppel. j Plymouth Plymouth Plymouth Sterling. . D. Hokhoker L. Napier. ■ C. B Foss. Johnson 40 E. A. Westcott Malcolm. Seward . Lancaster 41 KB. Hickman Eichmier Seward 49 Plymouth Malcolm Jefferson 48 H. M. Westcott Lancaster 44 H. M. Westcott Malcolm. Lancaster 45 R&lt;v T. Sperlein Wood Bros Smart ville. Aucora . . . Johnson 46 Hamilton 47 Wood Bros. Aurora York.. Hamilton 48 &lt;;. H. Poden York 49 J. V. Wood. David City Humboldt. Butler 50 K L. Crane. Richardson 51 § Dan waiter Danwalter Pleasant Dale. Pleasant Dale. Lincoln Lancaster 52 Lancaster 58 J. L. Milne. Lancaster 54 C. Johnson Dorchester. Saline 55 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 ! No. Where Planted. Date Delivered. Kind of Fish. 1 B. Bass 200 Pond Nov. 10.1900 •&gt; Perch 200 Pond Nov. 10. 1900 3 Croppies 200 I Pond Nov. id. 1900 4 B. Bass 200 P.»n«l Nov. 10.1900 5 Perch 200 Pond Nov. 10.1900 6 Carp 100 Pond Nov. 10. 1900 Perch I 200 Pond Nov. 10, 1900 8 Croppies 200 Pond Nov. 0.1900 9 B. Bass 200 I Pond Nov. 10. IU00 10 Perch 200 I Pond Nov. 10. 1900 11 Carp 200 Pond Nov. 10.1900 12 Carp 200 Pond Nov. 10,1900 13 Cattish '-'00 \ Pom I Nov. 10.1900 14 Carp 2i « I Pond Nov. 10.1900 15 Carp 200 Pond Nov. 10, 11-00 16 Carp 10 M Pond , Nov. 10. litM) 17 Carp 100 Pond Nov. 10. im 18 I Carp I 100 Pond l Nov. 10, 1900 1» I Catfish | 100 I Pond Nov. 10, 1900 t Perch 200 Pond Perch 200 Pond Croppies 200 Pond Pe ch 200 Pond Nov. 10. 19.-0 Nov. 10, ltd Nov. 10, 1900 Nov. 10. 28 Pe ch 1900 24 B. Bass 200 I Pond Nov. 10. 1900 25 Croppies ' 200 Pond Ndv. 10, luon 26 Perch I 200 Pond Nov. 10, 191-0 27 Catfish 200 Pond Nov. 10. luon a Cattish. 100 Pond Nov. 10, 1900 98 C«rp j 100 I Pond 100 Pond No*. 10, 1900 100 Pond 30 Carp i 100 | Pond i Nov. Ki. im 31 Carp : 100 Pond 100 Pond Nov. 10, im 82 Cattish 100 Por.d 100 Pond Nov. 10. 1900 33 Perch ! 200 Pond 200 Pond Nov. in. 1900 200 Pond Nov. 10. 1 ■*.-? M Croppies 1WM, 85. Cattish i 100 Pond 100 Pond Nor. 10. 1900 36 I Penh i 200 Pond 200 Pond Nov. 10, 1IKM. 37 Carp 200 Pond Nov. 22, iuon 200 Pond 88 Carp 200 89 Carp 200 Nov. 22 1900 200 Pond Nov. 22 1900 40 Carp 200 200 Pond Nov. 22 ISM 41 Catfish 100 100 Pond Nov. 22. 1900 4$ Catfish 100 100 Pon.l Nov. 22 1900 103 Pond No\ 1900 BCarp 103 Perch 200 200 Pond 44 Perch Nov. 22, iwm 100 Pond Nov. 23, 1900 ECarp 100 B. Bass 100 46 B. Bass 100 Pond Nov. 28, 1900 47 Catfish 100 Pond Nov. 22, MM 200 Pond 48 Perch 200 Nov. 22, iwm ECaro 200 Carp 100 Catfish HO 200 Pond Nov. 22 IMI 100 Pond IMI Nov. 22, HO Pond Pond Nov. 22. 1900 53 Cattish 100 100 Pond Pond Nov. 22 1900 53 Carp 100 100 Pond Nov. 22, .900 54 Croppies 200 Pond Not. 23 IMI 55 I Carp | 100 Pond Nov. 22, 1900 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">\ \ Applicant. Postoflice. County. »O. Huston O. Huston R. Christinsen C. Larson F. Beal W. A. Burnell • • • J. H. Weaver F. C. Buschaw E. A. Stone C Sievers F. E. Swasmer J. Wagner L. B. Clough C. W.Cussll T. J. Smith F. M. Smith F. Montmorency W. R. Winges — . Plontedby Geneva Geneva Miuden Minden Minden Lawrence Wallace! Blue Hill Ong Bloomington Trenton Culbertson Benkleman Benkleman Beukleman Benkleman Benkleman Benkleman Benkleman Filmore Filmore Kearney Kearney Kearney Webster Perkins A. Webster Clay Franklin Hitchcock Hitchcock Dundy Dundy Dundy ». . Dundy Dundy Dundy Dundy B IS 13 14 15 M 17 is 19 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 L Kind of Fisb. No. Where Planted. Date Dei vered. at"sh J. Bass ullheails B. Bass atfish ■n&gt; »n&gt; arp B. Base B.Bass »n&gt; B. Bass B. Bass B. Bass erch B. Bass Croppies Croppies 100 200 500 200 100 100 200 100 200 300 100 400 400 400 400 400 500 500 500 Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Pond Nov. 22, 1900 Nov. 22, WOO Nov. 22, 1800 Nov. 22. 1900 Nov. It, 1600 Nov. 22, 1800 Nov. 22, 1900 Nov. 22, 1900 Nov&gt;-22, 1900 Nov. 22, 1900 Nov. 22, 1900 Nov. 22, 1900 Nov. 22, 1900 Nov. 22, 1900 Nov. 22, 1990 Nov. 28, 1900 Nov. 22, 1900 Nov. 22, 1900 </seg>

         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>