<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Vitamin A and the Vitamin E Content of Field-Cured and Artificially Cured Alfalfa Hay</title>
               <date value="1932-10">1932-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 62 The Vitamin A and the Vitamin E Content of Field-Cured and Artificially Cured Alfalfa Hay I. L. HATHAWAY, H. P. DAVIS, AND R. R. GRAVES LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OCTOBER, 1932 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY A comparative study of the vitamin A content of field-cured and artificially cured alfalfa was made by comparing the growth produced by 124 rats receiving alfalfa hay as their source of vitamin A. From the results of this study, m which the experiments were duplicated, it is concluded that under the conditions of these experiments the artifi - cially cured alfalfa was twice as potent m vitamin A as was the field - cured alfalfa. The comparative study of the vitamin E content of these hays was made by comparing the number of litters produced by groups of female rats which received graded quantities of either field-cured or artificially cured alfalfa as their source of vitamin E. It is concluded that the artificial drying of the alfalfa tended to preserve its vitamin E content to a greater degree than did field curing. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Vitamin A and the Vitamin E Content of Field-Cured and Artificially Cured Alfalfa Hay I. I*. HATHAWAY AND H. P. DAVIS Department of Dairy Husbandry and R. R. GRAVES Bureau of Dairy Industry. United States Department of Agriculture 1 The high nutritive value of alfalfa has been one of the factors responsible for its extensive use m the rations of domestic farm animals. It was pointed out by Maynard (22) , m a review of the literature m 1929, and later confirmed by still others (32) , that m general the vitamin content of milk is dependent upon the vitamin content of the ration of the cow. Bethke, Kennard, and Sassaman (2) reported a similar relationship between the vitamin A and vitamin D content of the ration and the occurrence of these vitamins m egg yolks. As milk and eggs are possibly the most important, year-round sources of vitamins m the human diet and as these foods are of the utmost importance m infant and child feeding, any agricultural practice which may affect the nutritive value of the rations of the animals which produce these foods is, there - fore, of interest. With the development of artificial-heat drying of hay arose the question of the effect of the curing process upon the nutritive value of the hay produced. It is well known that some vitamins are heat-stable^ while others are heat-labile, and also that artificial drying uniformly re - sults m the production of hay having a choice green color. A number of investigators have noted an association of green - ness m plant tissues with vitamin A content (4, 5, 6, 8, 10, 15, 16, 18, 24, 26, 35). Hague and Aitkenhead (14), however, re - ported that while bright green color is associated with quality m field-cured alfalfa, green color is not necessarily an index of vitamin A preservation since a sample of hay was turned from a bright green to an olive-drab color by autoclaving, without apparent destruction of the vitamin. In view of these facts it was thought advisable to make a study of the com - parative effect of artificial and field curing upon the vitamin content of alfalfa hay. REVIEW OF LITERATURE The results obtained by a number of investigators indicate that the nutritive value of hay may be influenced by the cur - - ITbU is a report of a co-operative experiment between the Bureau of Dairy In - dustry, United States Department of Agriculture, and the Dairy Husbandry Depart - ment of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 62 4 ing process. Dutcher (9) noted that practical feeders have ob - served that bright green alfalfa, properly dried and cured, is superior to the light-colored crops, bleached out by unsatis - factory climatic conditions or careless agricultural practice. Steenbock (31) and co-workers m studies designed to test the stability of vitamin A reported that alfalfa hay, cured under a skylight m an attic and allowed to remain there for many months until completely bleached, no longer possessed any growth-promoting properties for rats. Bethke and Kick (3) exposed alfalfa hay to the sun, rain, and dew for several days and reported a marked loss m its vitamin A content. Russell (27) studied the effect of artificial drying upon the vitamin A content of leaves from alfalfa plants, and from the results obtained concluded that the green leaves of the artificially cured plants contained seven times as much vitamin A as the brownish-green leaves from the field-cured plants. Woodman, Bee, and Griffith (36) made two inquiries into the influence of artificial drying on the digestibility of young leafy pastur - age. It was shown that the digestibility of young grass is not reduced when it is dried at the temperature of steam or by direct heat m a kiln. Bechdel (1) fed mechanically dried, mixed timothy and clover hay to grade Holstein heifers and stated that "the explanation would appear to be that the high heat employed m the presence of air m this particular type of drier, which is no longer on the market, destroys vitamin A or a similar dietary factor necessary for growth and well - being of young cattle." The influence of the method of curing Kudzu hay upon its vitamin A content was investigated by Sewell and Cottier (28). Samples were field-cured, cock - cured, or shade-cured. These writers stated that although the samples were fed at levels too low to constitute a Sherman unit, the results indicated that m vitamin A potency shade - cured, cock-cured, and sun-cured hays rank m the order named. Kiesselbach and Anderson (17) reported briefly the results of experiments by Mussehl m which two lots of chicks were fed artificially cured and field-cured alfalfa hay, re - spectively. They reported that differences m growth due to feeding the alfalfa cured under these two extreme conditions were not significant. The studies of Hague and Aitkenhead (14), unlike those of Russell, were made with the alfalfa stems and leaves ground together. The results showed that the artificial drying tended to preserve the vitamin A content while the "field-curing process caused a market diminution m the vitamin A content. They also presented evidence which indicated that enzymes are the important factor m the de - struction of vitamin A during the field-curing process. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Vitamin Content of Alfalfa Hay 5 EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE The samples of alfalfa used in these experiments were ob - tained from Brook-Hill Farm, Genesee Depot, Wisconsin. 2 The hay was cut on July 15 at 9 a. m. The day was clear and dry. At 3 p. m. when the plants were wilted, but not dry, they were raked and at 5 p. m. put up in small cocks. On July 22 the hay was hauled in and stored. On August 4 it was chopped, blown into bags, and stored in a dry warehouse. All possible precautions were taken to keep the loss of leaves at a minimum. This hay was undoubtedly superior in all re - spects and had much less loss of leaves than ordinary field - cured hay. The sample which was artificially dried was ob - tained from the same field and cutting. It was hauled to the drier as soon after cutting as possible. The drying was done in an Arnold drier and required less than 15 minutes. In other words, the field-cured hay was cured in cocks in the field for eight days before being stored, while the artificially dried hay was dried and stored within an hour after cutting. It was not possible to determine either the maximum tempera - ture to which the hay was subjected in the drying machine or the temperatures in the different parts of the drier, since it was constantly revolving while in operation. The color of the artificially dried sample was a dark green, while that of the field-cured sample was an olive green. The results of the fodder analyses are shown in Table 1. Table 1. — The comparative composition of the field-cured and artificially cured alfalfa * _ _ Nitrogen . Method of drying Moisture Ash Nitrogen Crude Fat Iree Crude - protein extract flbcr P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. Field 10.0 6.9 2.65 16.6 2.2 38.2 26.1 Artificial 9.5 7.2 2.79 17.4 2.8 37.3 25.8 1 These samples were analyzed by Mr. C. B. Parker, U. S. D. A., Bureau of Dairy Industry. VITAMIN A STUDIES The management of the rat colony and the procedure for the determination of vitamin A was essentially the same as that outlined by Davis and Hathaway (7) except where other - wise indicated. The breeding stock was maintained on the Steenbock Stock Ration, composed as follows: 'Brook-Hill Farm was owned by Mr. Howard Green. The writers are indebted to Mr. Green and his men for their kind assistance in obtaining these samples. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 62 6 Stock Ration I Yellow corn 76.0% Ground alfalfa 2.0% Linseed oil meal 16.0% Sodium chloride 0.5% Crude casein 5.0% Calcium carbonate 0.5% The materials were finely ground and then 5 per cent by weight of butter was added. In addition to this ration the animals received lettuce several times each week. Pied male and female rats, 24 to 28 days old and weighing between 35 and 45 grams, were fed a vitamin A free basal ration composed of casein, 3 18 per cent; corn starch,* 78 per cent; and salt mixture (McCollum No. 185) (23), 4 per cent. One gram of dried yeast 8 daily was fed separately as the source of vitamin B and vitamin G. The antirachitic factor was supplied by irradiation of the corn starch and the yeast with a Cooper-Hewitt quartz mercury vapor lamp 6 run at 2.4 amperes, 250 volts. One hundred grams of starch or yeast was spread uniformly over an area 60 centimeters square in metal trays and then irradiated for 40 minutes at a distance of 60 centimeters. All experimental animals received dis - tilled water to which iodine was added once each week, ac - cording.^ f-he method of Sure (33). The rats were weighed three time's per week and a record of the amount of food con - sumed was kept. The litters were allotted so that, as far as possible, related animals were in each group of the experi - ment. A negative control, receiving only the basal ration, and a positive control, which received the basal ration supple - mented with 0.1 cubic centimeter of cod-liver oil " daily, were selected from each Utter except when several litters were started on the alfalfa supplements at approximately the same time. The feeding of the alfalfa was begun when ophthalmia was in its incipient stage or when there was a cessation .of growth. At this point various percentages of the finely ground alfalfa were incorporated into the basal ration by replacing a portion of the corn starch with an equal quantity of alfalfa. The plan adopted was similar to the method for the quantita - tive determination of vitamin A as recommended by Sherman and Burtis (29) . A unit was to be the minimum quantity of alfalfa required to cure induced symptoms of vitamin A starvation in young rats and to cause an average gain in * A special grade of purified casein (No. 453) was purchased from the Casein Com - pany of America, New York City. It whs extracted continuously for five days with 95 per cent ethyl alcohol. 'Powdered starch was obtained from the Corn Products Refining Company, New York City. * Compressed yeast was furnished through the courtesy of the Fieischmann Yeast Company. It was dried in a current of air at room temperature, finely ground, and fed without farther treatment. •Uviarc Poultry Treater. Type R. I. Special 100. 7 Standardized cod-liver oil from Mead Johnson A Company, Evansville, Ind., was used. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The Vitamin Content op Alfalfa Hay 7 weight of three grams per week. The vitamin A potencies could then be determined by: a comparison of the unit of each type of alfalfa. The field-cured hay was fed at slightly lower levels than the artificially cured hay, since the results of other investigators as well as the difference m color of the two kinds of hay suggested a difference m vitamin A content. The pre - experimental or depletion period generally lasted for about five weeks; while the feeding trial was carried on eight weeks. The results of two experiments are summarized m Table 1 and are statistically examined m Table 2. In the first experi - ment each kind of alfalfa was fed m three different amounts. Male and female rats were used m Experiment I, while only male rats were used m Experiment 11. The field-cured alfalfa was fed at 1, 3, and 5 per cent levels, while the artificially dried sample was fed at 0.5, 2, and 4 per cent levels. The groups fed 3 per cent and 5 per cent of field-cured hay made about equal gains. The groups fed 2 per cent and 4 per cent of artificially cured alfalfa also made similar gains. It was therefore evident that these groups received so much alfalfa that an amount of vitamin Am excess of unit requirements was supplied and hence no differences m growth became ap - parent at these levels. One per cent of field-cured alfalfa pro - duced an average gain of 63.4 ± 3.14 grams, while only one - half that amount of artificially cured hay or 0.5 per cent gave an average gain of 76.0 ± 4.64 grams. When this difference of 12.6 grams was divided by its probable error, a value of 2.25, or approximate odds of 6.26 to 1 were obtained. Since only differences of at least 3.2 times the probable error, or odds of 30 to 1, are considered significant, it is evident that no difference between the vitmin A content of one per cent of field-cured and 0.5 per cent of artificially cured alfalfa was established. In other words, the results indicate that under the conditions of these experiments the artificially cured alfalfa was twice as potent m vitamin A as was the field-cured. As it was shown by Sherman and Burtis (29) that this method for the quantitative determination of vitamin A is most deli - cate when the rats make an average gain of 3 grams per week and since even the smallest gains made by our rats were much m excess of this amount, a second experiment was conducted m which smaller amounts of the alfalfa were fed. In this trial 0.5 per cent of field-cured alfalfa was compared with 0.25 per cent of artificially cured alfalfa. The group fed 0.5 per cent of field-cured hay made an average gain of 23.9 ± 1.1 grams, while the group fed the 0.25 per cent of artificially cured alfalfa made an average gain of 21.6 ± 1.78 grams. This difference of 2.3 grams divided by its probable error equals 1.08, or approximately odds of 1 to 1. It is evident </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 62 8 Table 2. — Summary of the average gains m weight of rats fed various percentages of alfalfa hay, field-cured, or arti - ficially cured, as the sources of vitamin A F ,r:r T^g | n a^. | P. ct. P. ct. No. Grams Grams Grams EXPERIMENT NO. I 3-0 »•• 11 95.4 187.6 92.2 5 -° •••• 11 89.2 180.1 90.9 °-5 11 93.2 169.2 76 0 2.0 11 93.2 178.1 84.9 ••". 4.0 11 89.3 176.7 87.4 Positive control i 8 94.5 176.1 81 6 Negative control * 6 9JU. 80.8 2 Died EXPEMMENT NO. II OTS ~ 19 106.6 13(Ui 2JT9 0.25 14 104.3 125.9 216 Positive control 6 110.3 213.5 103 2 Negative control 4 99.5 76.72 Died controls received 0.1 c.c. of cod-liver oil daily as the source of vitamin A, while the negative controls received only the vitamin A free diet. 'Average weight at death. that the difference was not statistically significant and that the conclusion drawn from Experiment I was confirmed. VITAMIN E STUDIES It has been shown by Evans and Bishop (11), Sure (34), Mattill, Carman, and Clayton (20) and confirmed by many investigators that rats are unable to reproduce if maintained on a diet deficient m vitamin E. We have been unable to find any comparative studies of the vitamin E content of field-cured and artificially cured alfalfa. The individual variation of rats m response to vitamin E has made comparative studies of this vitamin rather unsatisfactory. Such variation has been noted by Evans and Burr (12), Mattill and Clayton (21), and Sim - monds, Becker, and McCollum (30) , as well as by many others. From the nature of assay results the methods for the study of vitamin E are essentially qualitative rather than quantitative. Munch (25) stated that the quantitative accuracy of the method appeared to be about 50 per cent. In other words, the effect of doses differing by 50 per cent may be determined. Despite the limitation of the method it was thought advisable to attempt this study. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The Vitamin Content op Alfalfa Hay 9 Table 3.— Average gains in weight of rats produced by alfalfa hay, field-cured or artificially cured, as the source of vitamin A — statistical examination of results * I Mean gain per animal and -..__. _,_ . „i_«». „ , . P. E. of the mean _"___P ■ Difference ApP^L Rats in group — means ana r. r,. odds of difference P. E. of P. Field-cured Artificially cured I Field-cured | Artificially cured P.ct. P.ct. j Number \ Grains Grains Grams EXPERIMENT NO. I LO 1 Ol II I 63.4 ± 3.14 76.0 _ 4.64 12.6 ± 5.60 -25 6.26-1 3.0 2.0 11 92.2 ± 3.21 84.9 ± 4.44 7.3 ± 5.47 1.33 1.63-1 5.0 4_ 11 j 90.9 ± 3.65 87.4 ± 4.20 3.5 ± 5.56 0.63 less than 1-1 EXPERIMENT NO. II 0J5 i (T25 19-14 2 I 23.9 ± 1.1 21.6 ± 1.78 I 2.3 ± 2.09 L08 H 1 The follow. nfr formulae were used in these calculations: (1) M= n M=arithmetical average. 2x— !Ulm o f tne varlatra. n=tolal varistcs. ._.--. |/_(Fd') S. D. = Standard deviation. (2) S.D.= V — F = frequency, d = deviation of a class from the mean, n = number of individuals. .6745 S. P. (8) P. E. of the mean = .- ■ P. E. = probable error. ( 4 ) P. E. of a difference = Va» + V a = P. E. of first mean. b = P. E. of second mean. • There were 19 rats in thc group receiving field-cured alfalfa and 14 rats in the group receiving artificially cured alfalfa. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 62 10 The comparative study of the vitamin E content of the field - cured and the artificially cured alfalfa was made by comparing the number of litters produced by groups of female rats whicli received graded quantities of either field-cured or artificially cured alfalfa as their source of vitamin E. Female pied rats, 24 to 28 days old, were placed on a vitamin E deficient ration essentially the same as that employed by Evans and Burr (13). It was composed of casein, 8 32 per cent; corn starch, 30 per cent; lard, 9 22 per cent; yeast, 10 per cent; cod-liver oil, 2 per cent; and mineral mixture (McCollum No. 185) (23), 4 per cent. This ration has been fed to 200 females and in no instance has initial fertility been encountered. Evans and Burr (12) obtained four cases of initial fertility in 200 cases. The females were maintained on this ration until they were 90 to 120 days old and then mated for a period of 15 days to males previously shown to be fertile by matings with stock females. Each female was weighed three times per week, during this period of mating, and until 21 days after separa - tion from the males. Only those females which showed re - sorption of a fetus as evidenced by their weight curve were used for the vitamin E tests. The weight curve of the preg - nant female on a normal ration generally shows a steady rise until parturition, at which time there is a precipitous fall in the curve. On the other hand the weight curve of the preg - nant female on a vitamin E deficient ration shows a steady rise until about the fourteenth day. From this time on there is a gradual diminution in weight and the period of gestation passes without a litter being cast. During this selection 35 females were discarded, as it was not clearly evident whether or not they had resorbed a fetus. Beginning with the twenty-second day after the males were removed from the females, graded quantities of the field-cured or artificially cured alfalfa were incorporated into the vitamin E deficient ration. This was accomplished by replacing a por - tion of the corn starch with an equal quantity of the finely ground alfalfa. After the females had been on the supple - mented rations for four days they were again mated. During this second gestation period the females were weighed daily and watched closely to detect parturition. As our cages were not equipped with any special device, such as the one described by Long and Evans (19), for determining the number of young dropped, our counts may not be accurate since some pups are at times devoured by the mother shortly after birth. In three cases it was not possible to determine whether a litter •The casein, starch, yeast, and cod liver oil were the same brands and were pre - pared in the same manner as described under Vitamin A studies. •The lard, labeled Star Lard, was purchased locally from Armour &amp; Company. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Vitamin Content op Alfalfa Hay 11 had been dropped or a resorption had taken place. These cases, therefore, were not considered m the tabulations. In order to obtain some idea of the smallest quantity of alfalfa which would permit successful casting of litters, a pre - liminary trial was first run with 24 females. The results are shown m Table. 4. Table 4. — Summary of the number of Utters dropped by rats fed artificially cured alfalfa as the source of vitamin E — preliminary trial Sources of Vitamin X Female* Llttera Resorp- Young Youne m group dropped tions dropped weaned i No. No. No. | No. No. Alfalfa (per cent) \ 5 6 I*6 1 0 10 6 2 4 15 2 15 6 6 0 34 27 Ground wheat (per cent) 15.. 4 3 1 14 6 Vitamin E free ration 2 0 2 0 0 From the results of this preliminary trial it seemed that from 10 to 15 per cent of artificially cured alfalfa was re - quired to furnish sufficient vitamin E to allow successful cast - ing of litters. Therefore, m comparing the vitamin E content of the field-cured with the artificially cured alfalfa (Table 5) the former was fed at levels of 10, 15, 20, and 25 per cent, while the latter was fed at levels of 10, 15, and 20 per cent. The 25 per cent field-cured group was added so that m case this type of alfalfa should have a lower vitamin E content, as was found with the vitamin A, the minimum quantity re - quired might still be determined. Negative controls received only the vitamin E free ration, while positive controls were fed the vitamin E free ration supplemented with 15 per cent of ground whole wheat. Since the supply of alfalfa unfor - tunately became exhausted, it was necessary to terminate the experiment after the females had cast a litter or the period of gestation had passed. From the results shown m Table 5 it is evident that 15 per cent of artificially cured alfalfa furnished sufficient vitamin E to permit the successful casting of litters, since each of the females m the 15 and 20 per cent groups produced a litter. Identical results were obtained with 15 per cent of the arti - ficially cured alfalfa m the preliminary trial. On the other hand only five, or 50 per cent, of the females m the group fed 15 per cent of the field-cured alfalfa produced a litter. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 62 12 TABLE 5. — Summary of the number of litters dropped by rats fed various percentages of field-cured and artificially cured alfalfa as the sources of vitamin E Source of viUmin E jffffg, | Litter Rgorp- Ygg, No. No. No. No. Artificially cured (per cent) 10 12 6 G 29 15 12 12 0 107 20.. 12 12 0 125 Field-cured (per cent) 10 10 3 7 16 15 10 5 5 22 20 12 11 1 87 25 ; 11 9 2 ! 82 Ground wheat (per cent) 15 4 3 1 33 Vitamin E free ration 7 0 7 0 At least 20 per cent of the field-cured hay was required to approximate perfect reproduction of all females m the group. Furthermore, 15 per cent of the field-cured hay resulted m no better reproduction than 10 per cent of the artificially cured hay. It seems evident, therefore, that the artificial drying of alfalfa tended to preserve its vitamin E content to a greater degree than did the field curing. Since as little as 3 per cent of field-cured alfalfa was suf - ficient to supply enough vitamin A for good growth and since 20 per cent produced good reproduction, it seems that a short - age of these vitamins would never be responsible for failures m growth or reproduction m livestock having a good grade of field-cured alfalfa included liberally m their ration, even though the minimum requirements are smaller with artificially cured than with field-cured alfalfa. This statement is made on the assumption that farm animals respond similarly to rats. It remains for future investigation to establish whether there is a relationship between artificial and field-curing practices and the vitamin content of dairy and poultry products. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Vitamin Content op Alfalfa Hay 13 LITERATURE CITED 1. Bechdel, S. I. FECTED BY HIGH TEMPERATURE IN THE PRESENCE OF AlR. Penn. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 266, pp. 21-22. 2. Bethke, R. M., Kennard, D. C, and Sassaman, H. L. 1927. The Fat-Soluble Vitamin Content of Hens' Egg Yolk as Affected by the Ration and Management of the Layers. Jour. Biol. Chem., 72:695-706. 3. Bethke, R. M., and Kick, C. H. 1929. Vitamin A Content of Alfalfa Hay. Ohio Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 431. 4. Collison, D. L., Hume, E. M., Smedley-Maclean, I., and Smith, H. H. 1929. LXXIII — The Nature of the Vitamin A Constituent of Green Leaves. Biochem. Jour., 23:634-647. 5. Crist, J. W., and Dye, M. 1929. The Association of Vitamin A with Greenness in Plant Tissue II — The Vitamin A Content of Asparagus. Jour. Biol. Chem., 81:525-532. 6. Crist, J. W., and Dye, M. 1931. The Association of Vitamin A with Greenness in Plant Tissue III — Vitamin A Content of Asparagus Grown under Light of Various Qualities. Jour. Biol. Chem., 91:127-134. 7. Davis, H. P., and Hathaway, I.*L. 1931. The Vitamin A Content of the Milk of Holstein, Ayr - shire, Jersey, and Guernsey Cows. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 54, pp. 3-6. 8. Drummond, J. C, Channon, H. J., Coward, K. H., Golding, J., Mack - intosh, J., and Zilva, S. S. 1924. The Influence of the Administration of Certain Oils on the Nutritive Value of the Butterfat of Cows on Winter Rations. Jour. Agr. Sci., 14:531-547. 9. Dutcher, R. A. 1921. Factors Influencing the Vitamin Content of Foods. Jour. Indus, and Engin. Chem., 13:1102-1104. 10. Dye, M., Medlock, O. C, and Crist, J. W. 1927. The Association of Vitamin A with Greenness in Plant Tissue I — The Relative Vitamin A Content of Head and Leaf Lettuce. Jour. Biol. Chem., 74:95-106. 11. Evans, H. M., and Bishop, K. S. 1922. On the Existence of a Hitherto Unrecognized Factor Es - sential for Reproduction. Science, 56:650-651. 12. Evans, H. M., and Burr, G. O. 1927. Vitamin E — The Ineffectiveness of Curative Dosage when Mixed with Diets Containing High Proportions of Certain Fats. Jour. Amer. Med. Assoc, 88:1462-1465. 13. Evans, H. M., and Burr, G. O. 1928. Development of Paralysis in the Suckling Young of Mothers Deprived of Vitamin E. Jour. Biol. Chem., 76:273 - 297. 14. Hague, S. M., and Aitkenhead, W. 1931. The Effect of Artificial Drying upon the Vitamin A Con - tent of Alfalfa. Jour. Biol. Chem., 93:657-665. 15. Harrow, B., and Krasnow, F. 1924. Feeding Experiments on Rats with Plants at Different Stages of Development, Part II. Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol, and Med., 21:232-234. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebe. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 62 14 16. Jameson, H. L., Drummond, J. C, and Coward, K. H. 1922. XL-Synthesis op Vitamin A by a Marine Diatom (Nitzschia Closterium W. Sm.) Growing m Pure Culture. Biochem. Jour., 16:482-485. 17. Kiesselbach, T. A., and Anderson, A. 1931. Quality op Alfalfa Hay m Relation to Curing Practice. U. S. D. A. Technical Bui. No. 235, pp. 16-17. 18. Krammer, M. M., Boehm, G., and Williams, R. E. 1929. Vitamin A Content of the Green and White Leaves of Market Head Lettuce. Jour. Home Econ., 21:679-680. 19. Long, J. A., and Evans, H. M. 1922. The Oestrous Cycle m the Rat and Its Associated Phen - omena. Uni. of Cal. Memoir, 6:15. 20. Mattill, H. A., Carman, J. S., and Clayton, M. M. 1924. The Nutritive Properties of Milk III — The Effectiveness of the X Substance m Preventing Sterility m Rats on Milk Rations High m Pat. Jour. Biol. Chem., 61:729-740. 21. Mattill, H. A., and Clayton, M. M. 1926. Vitamin E and Reproduction on Synthetic and Milk Diets. Jour. Biol. Chem., 68:665-685. 22. Maynard, L. A. 1929. The Influence of the Nature of the Ration of the Cow upon the Nutritive Value of the Milk. Cornell Vetr., 19:124-137. 23. McCollum, E. V., and Simmonds, N. 1918. A Study of the Dietary Essential Water-Soluble B, m Relation to Its Solubility and Stability Towards Re - agents. Jour. Biol. Chem., 33:55-89. 24. McLaughlin, L., and Haber, E. S. 1929. The Relation of Vitamin A Content to Size of Leaves. Jour. Biol. Chem., 84:249-256. 25. Munch, J. C. 1931. Bioassays — A Handbook of Quantitative Pharmacology. Pub. by Williams and Wilkins. pp. 846-847. 26. New Jersey Agr. Exp. Sta. Annual Report, p. 6. 1931. 27. Russell, W. C. 1929. The Effect of the Curing Process upon the Vitamin A and D Content of Alfalfa. Jour. Biol. Chem., 85 :289-297. 28. Sewell, W. E., and Cottier, G. J. 1931. Influence of the Method of Curing Kudzu Hay on Its Vitamin A Content. Ala. Agr. Exp. Sta. Annual Rpt., p. 45. 29. Sherman, H. C, and Burtis, M. P. 1928. Factors Affecting the Accuracy of the Quantitative De - termination of Vitamin A. Jour. Biol. Chem., 78:671-680. 30. Simmonds, N., Becker, J. E., and McCollum, E. V. 1928. The Distribution of Vitamin E. Jour. Nutr., 1 :39-47. 31. Steenbock, H., Hart, E. 8., Elvehjem, C. A., and Kletzien, S. W. F. 1925. Dietary Factors Influencing Calcium Assimilation VI — The ANTntACHrnc Properties of Hays as Related to Cli - matic Conditions with Some Observations on the Effect of Irradiation with Ultra-Violet Light. Jour. Biol. Chem., 66:425-440. 32. Steenbock, H., Hart, E. 8., Harming, F., and Humphrey, G. C. 1930. Fat-Soluble Vitamins XXX — The Antirachitic Value of Cow Milk as Modified by the Feeding of Irradiated Yeast. Jour. Biol. Chem., 88:197-214. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Vitamin Content of Alfalfa Hay 15 33. Sure, B. 1923. Dietary Requirements for Reproduction I — The Nutritive Value op Milk Proteins from the Standpoint op Repro - duction. Jour. Biol. Chem., 48:681-709. 34. Sure, B. 1923. Dietary Requirements for Reproduction II — The Existence of a Specific Vitamin for Reproduction. Jour. Biol. Chem., 58:692-701. 35. Widmark, E. 1924. Der Zusammenhang zwischen der Bildung des 4- Vitamins UND der Farbstoffen der Pflanzen. Skand. Arch. Physiol., 4ij 1 31-38. 36. Woodman, H. E., Bee, J. W., and Griffith, G. 1930. Nutritive Value of Pasture V — Pasture Grass Conserva - tion : The Influence of Artificial Drying on the Digesti - bility op Pasture Herbage. Jour. Agr. Sci., 20:53-62. [SM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>