<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00043.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00043.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Food, Drug, Dairy, and Oil Commission to the Governor of the State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1918-12-01">1918-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOK THE PEKIOD FROM DECEMBER 1. 1916 TO NOVEMBER 30, 1918 BY OTTO MURSCHEL D.pu,, Commie, </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Th« York Bl.nl Book C York. Ncbr..l. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">NEBRASKA FOOD, DRUG DAIRY &amp; OIL COMMISSION Keith Neville, Governor. &lt; )tto Mnrseliel Deputy Ooaunimoaer \V. S. Frisbie. State C'heniiKl Herbert L. Cushinif Hecretan J. B. Mover Assistant Deputy Hotel ( 'nnunissioiter K. (J. Batty Assistant 8t«te Chemiri Leslie McCain Dairy Clerk Alice M. Ollis Oil Clerk Kinin.i ( 'onenu Bookkeeper Weights and Measures Clerk ( Minda Waehtet Clara Miskell Kxtra Clerk INSPECTORS Food. Dru?. Dairy &amp; Oil K. C. Kemlile .1. I'. Turner (ieorire S. Mayo Ai.ton .1. Tusa V. K. 8talil I'.V. Holm M. H. Bloom \V. II. I in IT. mi I... I. Klynn I. F. Tiller .). W. McKissick A. L Wagawr Mdl A. Rrhmeid P. J. Bijrlin &lt; Hiver LaMeie Carl Lamhiecht II I.. Fillman F. F. ( 'ampbell Lloyd S. Taylor Mis. Marie Weekes \V. S. Austin I&gt;. W. lle.ox Weights and Measures Inspectors W. II. Barkalow Wm. .J. Murlev (Jeo. F. Keenim Seed Inspector and Analyst Commissioner !•'. \\ . Kchaupfi Jay &lt; )livei H. Feme Peck </seg>
            <seg id="p004">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Hon. Keith Neville, Governor. Dear Sir: I beg leave to submit herewith as ordered Kl»w, a re|)ort of the Nebraska Food, Drug, Dairy &amp; Oil nmission for the biennium beginning December 1st, 1916 I ending November 30th, 1918. Respectfully, OTTO MURSCHEL, Deputy Commissioner. Pitted lit Lincoln, Nebraska, Dec-ember 1st, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT There will be no attempt in this report to cover all of the various activities of the Department in detail. A glance at the numerous lines shows why such a report is im - practicable. In compliance with the statutory provisions the report will be made as concise as it is possible to make it and still give the facts. We prefer that the work of the Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission be judged by the results obtained during the past biennium rather than by a recounting of those results as we see them, set forth herein. The Statutes provide that this Commission shall en - force laws dealing with the following: Food, Drugs, Dairy, (Gasoline and Kerosene, Agricultural Seeds, Weights and Measures, Hotels, Feeding Stuffs, Livestock Remedies, Paint and Linseed Oil, Cold Storage, Commission Merchants and Imitation Butter. Naturally some of these depart - ments overshadow the others. The results obtained in all lines under our supervision are not due so much to prosecutions as to the process of education resulting from the efforts of the Department and its inspectors. In no sense should the work of the Depart - ment be judged by the number of prosecutions recorded. A prosecution did not necessarily follow the securing of evidence that might have substantiated such action. Many instances were found where a technical violation of the law was purely unintentional and, whenever there seemed to be an apparent readiness on the part of the violator to cor - rect conditions, the Department was disposed to give him an opportunity to do so. It is safe to state that the campaign of education as to proper methods of handling foods and other items under the supervision of this Department is beginning to show splendid results. There is an apparent desire on the part of the manufacturers and dealers throughout the state to comply with the laws and the regulations set forth and administered by this Department. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 BIEXNIAL, REPORT OP THE WAR CONDITIONS Many of tlip plans of action formulated early in the »inium were of necessity abandoned, due to the changed litions resulting from tlie entrance of our country into war. The ever present tendency to substitute inferior pro - ducts for staple articles of food became more prevalent Mixing manufacturers and dealers. War conditions furn - ished an excuse for all sorts of requests for permission to place on the markets products that were not in compliance with the standards established by law and the regulation* i'f this Department. I While the matter of food conservation was left largely he State Food Administration, it became more apparent n ever that one of the best means of conserving food was endeavor to set' that food, wherever manufactured or 1, was handled in the most sanitary manner possible. We e BO ouytad in every way possible with the State and National Food Administration in placing before the deal - ers and the people of the state regulations issued by the r'ood Administration. In many instances our inspectors have called upon dealers to investigate reported violations of the Food Ad - ministration regulations. They were instructed at all times to report any violations observed, to the County Food \dministrator. They were particularly called upon to do this at the time when the "meatless" and " wheatless" days were being observed. HOTEL COMMISSION Daring the last session of the Legislature, at the sug - gestion of Governor Neville, the Hotel Commission was con snlidated with the Food, Drag, Dairy, and Oil Commission, the Deputy Food Commissioner becoming also the Deputy Hotel Commissioner, provision being made for an Assistant Deputy Hotel Commissioner. This combination has proved very satisfactory. Never in the history of the state have the affairs of the Hotel Commission been as well cared for M they have during the pant biennium. With the Food and Oil inspectors available for use in the work of hotel inspec </seg>
            <seg id="p007">FOOD. DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION lion there lias been a notable improvement among the hotels and rooming houses of the state. For the period beginning April ."&gt;, 1!M7, and ending De - cember .!1. 1917, tlie license fees from tlie hotels, restaurants and rooming houses amounted to $5,463.00. During the period beginning Jtunmrj 1, 1918, and ending November •&gt;&lt;), 1918, the fees amounted to $7,2.'i&lt; U«t. Daring the period heginning Jnne 19, 1916, and ending April 5, 1917. while the Hotel Commission was separate and distinct from the Food. Drag, Dairy and Oil Commission, the fce&gt; amounted |o ¥l\97o.&lt;Mt. A coinparison of these figure* offer nmvinring evidence that the consolidation of the Hotel Commission with the Pood, Ding, Dairy and Oil Commission has pro - duced lietter results in every way than could have been &lt;&gt;1&gt; tnined under the old system. SAVING THE EGGS At the rc&lt;|ue-t of the Food Administration an egg sav - ing campaign was inaugurated bjr this Depai tment. A .joint bulletin was issued providing that all produce dealers should he licensed and ie&lt;|uired to candle all eggs pnr chased. The purpose was to educate the producers to mar - ket their eggs often enough and to rare for them in such a way that the loss thw to poor handling might )&gt;e eliminated. The theory was that if tlie purchaser rejected the had eggfl Had refused to pay for them tlie producer would noon learn that it was best, if considered only from a financial stand - point, to deliver none hut edible eggs. Inspectors were instructed to take note of the proper handling of eggs at express ofiices and other points of de - livery and rejH&gt;rt to the Food Administrator any HaW* where eggs were not being properly handled while in tran - sit. Several inspectors reported instances where egg* were left on trucks on the station platform in the hot sun lor hours at a time. These cases were reported at once to the Pood Administrator and the action taken was such that long before the end of the season very few violations were reported. Every Pood Inspector gave numerous demonstrations throughout his territory showing the proper method of candling, and identifying, for the merchant, the various </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE type* of bad eggs. In many instances niercliiints wrote in asking that an inspector be sent to instruct them in regsird to egg candling. The Department was always glad to com - ply with these requests. t Inquiry made among the large produce dealers of the te reveals the fact that our Egg Saving Campaign has •duced a remarkable improvement in the quality of the cs received by them. Early in tlie campaign an improve - lit in the quality of the eggs was noted and after a few nths the situation became so much better that the cam gn was pronounced a success by praetially every produce tier in the state. The joint bulletin issued by the Federal Food Admin istration for Nebraska and the Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission follow: Federal Food Administration for Nebraska. RULES REGULATIONS AND SUGGESTIONS GOVERNING DEALERS IN EGGS. All dealers in eggs, irrespective of the amount of their business, who sell eggs to others than consumers, are re quired, under proclamation of the President issued May 14th, to come under license by June first. Application for such license should be made to License Division, l T . S. Food Administration, Washington, 1). C. Upon making such ap - plication, dealers may continue in business without actual receipt of, such license. Careful and conservative estimates show that for the past five years, during the period from June 1st to October 1st, twenty-five per cent (23%) of all eggs were a total loss and forty per cent (40%) materially depreciated in food value. These losses were due to improper handling by pro ducers and dealers. With the present shortage of food and its importance in winning the war, the Federal Food Ad - ministration for Nebraska feel it incumbent upon them - selves to pass such rules, regulations and recommendations governing the handling of eggs, as will eliminate in a large measure, the waste accruing. The State of Nebraska has stringent laws and regula - tions governing the handling of eggs, which make it un- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">FOOD. DRUG. DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 9 I.iwful tor producers or dealers to market eggs unfit for liiniuin consumption. Tlie wasting of any food products be - came of careless handling or improper care, is deemed under the general law and special regulations of the Tinted States Food Administration, to he wasteful practice, and M such is forbidden. With the purpose in view of assi&gt;t ing in the enforcement of the egg laws of the State of Ne - liiaska, and the 1 emulations of the Food Administration, the Federal Food Administration for Nebraska hereby de - clare the following rules, regulations and suggestions to lw necessary in preventing wasteful practice, and the sale of spoiled eggs. Therefore, on and after June 1st. 1018, the rules, regulations and suggestions given below, shall be in lull force and effect. Failure to observe the regulations of the Food Admin - istration or the laws of the State of Nebraska, by any lic - ensed dealer in poultry and eggs will result in the revocation of their United States Food Administration license, or the infliction of other severe penalties. The marketing of eirir - unlit for human consumption by any party also subjects such party to prosecution and fine, upon conviction, under I iie laws of the State of Nebraska. 1. The first licensed buyer of egns (the huckster, the local retail merchant, or others) must candle every lot of ( ggs that he buys. (This should be done before settlement is made.) An Egg Candling Certificate shall be placed on the top filler of each case of eggs candled by any and all licensed receivers and subsequent handlers. 2. The licensee shall discard all eggs known as "yolks siuck to the shell," "heavy blood rings," "partially latched," "moldy eirgs," "black rots," and any other eggs of an unwholesome nature. 3. The licensee shall pay only for good edible eggs. 4. The licensee shall return to the producers, if possi - ble. the "rejects" for the producers' own examination. ."). The good eggs shall be kept in a cool, dry place nn ti&gt; sold or shipped. 6. When shipped, eggs shall be forwarded by train, auto service, or otherwise, as soon as possible, and within a reasonable time. 7. Eggs known as "large hatch spots," "heavily shrunken eggs," "settled yolks," and "leaking eggs." are </seg>
            <seg id="p010">» 10 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE fit for consumption but will not stand transportation. They should be uxrd by the home community. S. All '•checks" and "•cracks" shell egjpi sliould be hipped in cases stenciled that tbey contain rrnrk ««r check shell e^s. !•. All receivers of Pgg* should use care and intel'i ;eiice in handling them. They may not be forwarded will, fl recandlinsr. always keeping in mind that it is a waste eggx, lillers. Hats, and valuable transportation space to s!:ip ••rejects" or other euus of doubtful character. 10. •• K'e.jects" shall not he sold for human consump l"&lt;«)|). DRUG, DAIRY AN' I) (HL COM MISSION I'oK NEBRASKA, KKIWRAL I'ool) a I) M1NISTUATION FOB NEBRASKA, Cm don \V. Wattle Administrator PURE FOOD WEEK l&gt;y proclamation (iovcrnor Neville asked that the week liegitlltittg Maicli ."), |91K, he observed as Pure Food Week. 'I his practice has been followed in Nehmska and other slates for sometime and considerable sjnod has seemed to re suit from its observance. The dealer, who was at iii&gt;t inclined to regard it with slight interest, has learned that it afford* a splendid opportunity to make a display that will stimulate trade. The proclamation ixstted by the (inventor and the MM i-sued by this Department follow: PROCLAMATION Never in the history of the Nation has Pure Food been as essential to our well iM'injr as at the present time. In this period of National crises when the obligation to feed a considerable portion of the population of the world rent* ipoii our country, when our people are asked to eat less that our Allies may eat more, the &lt;|iiestion of Pure Food lakes on an added importance and significance. To impress these facts upon all concerned, I, as Gover - nor of Nebraska, designate the week beginning March nth. Otto Mursrllel, 1 &gt;i'|&gt;nty ( 'ominimioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 11 .;s Pure Food Week and bespeak for the Pure Food Depart - n.ent of the State (iovernment, the hearty co-operation of tlii' people of Nebraska, to the end that the Department will be the better able to protect the he;ilth of our |&gt;eople and incidentally render more efficient and effective assistance t&lt;« the (Government in the winning of the war. KEITH NEVILLE (iovernor of Nebraska. PURE FOOD WEEK The Governor has designated the week beginning March !t. as Pure Food Week. With this proclamation is &gt;ued by the (lovernor, this department is in hearty accord. The entire working force i&gt; pledged to co-oj&gt;erate in mak - ing the Pure Food Week really mean something to both tiie manufacturer and the consumer of food products. The ability of a country to produce food has always been a ]&gt;o - teiit factor in the world's history, but never has there been a time when the importance of this item has be n so keenly felt as it is today. Today the central theme is the conservation of food. No one thing can contribute m Brack to the conservation of food products as the packing, handling and selling of all food products in a sanitary man ner. Contaminated food is not edible and every food pro - duct that is unnecessarily rendered unfit to eat must be re placed with that which is fit for consumption. This in volves waste. The manufacturer must exercise care to !• ake certain that his product reaches the dealer in perfect condition and the dealer, both wholesale and retail, must ( xercise every precaution to safeguard its journey to the ultimate consumer. The Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission exists for the purpose of rendering service to the people of Nebraska. ( &gt;nly with the co-operation of the public can it attain it - greatest usefulness. Bulletins dealing with food sanitation are here for those who request them. Our inspectors are always ready to investigate complaints. This department is busy every week in the interest of Pure Food, but let us all March 5th, 1!)18. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE make a supreme effort during the week beginning March 9th, to cany the message of Pure Food to every jwrson in the great food producing state of Nebraska. Dated at Lincoln, March 7, 1918. XKBRASKA, FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION, By OTTO MURSCHEL, Deputy CommisRioner. THE STATE FAIR Following the custom of previous years, the Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission has furnished inspection service on the State Fair grounds daring the fairs of 1917 and 1918. Fjach inspector was assigned a certain nmuhev at eating establishments and it was his duty to inspect then every day and see that none but sanitary food was served to Fair visitors. For a few years previous to this Administration it wrai held that the sale of hamburgers in any form was not to be permitted. This Administration did not adhere to this rule. AVe have held that any food product that was sold anywhere in the state in compliance with the laws of Ne - braska might be sold during the week of the State Fair pro - vided the product was pure and wholesome and handled in n sanitary manner. This Department maintained a booth in the Agricul - tural Hall where a force of inspectors was kept throughout the day explaining the various phases of the work of the Commission in its relation to the people of the state. Sam - ples of medicines, extracts and preparations of all kind? that had been placed off sale were exhibited and the reason for the action taken explained to those interested. An egg candling demonstration was in progress during each day of the Fair and proved to Ik? one of the popular features of the Department's exhibit. The State Seed Analyst was present with an exhibit in - i hiding field and garden seeds and weed seeds common to Nebraska. Special attention was given to noxious weeds, particularly showing the manner in which they infest the leguminous plants. The collection of weed grasses ex - hibited was without doubt one of the largest collections ever </seg>
            <seg id="p013">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 13 exhibited. Demonstrations of the work of analyzing and testing seeds were given by the State Analyst and many of those who saw the demonstrations at the Fair later sub mitted samples of seed to the laboratory to be tested. This fives some idea of the value of the educational work car - i ied on by the Department during the Fair. A Weights and Measures inspecting outfit was ex - hibited, consisting of a complete set of standardized test weights, balances, standard measures, both linear and volume. The exhibit also included a household scale such iis is used for testing retail purchases, the idea of the latter l&gt;eing to encourage co-operation with the Department. Ow - ing to the enoinious number of sales taking place every day, it is beyond the possibility of this Department, or any other law enforcing department, to have a perfect enforcement of the Weights and Measures Law. as regards the weights of commodities purchased by individuals. For this reason we suggest that every household be equipped with a scale so that all purchases liinv he weighed. Tt will facilitate this 1 &gt;epartinent in locating those dealers who are dishonest and. furthermore, the wide use of scales in the household will have a moral effect on dishonest dealers far greater than the prosecution brought by this Department. Bulletins dealing with all of the laws that are given 1o this Department for enforcement were distributed at the Department booth at the State Fair. There was a very manifest desire on the part of those visiting the exhibit to have copies of these bulletins, especially the ones pertain - ing to the lines in which they were most directly interested. The State Fair affords the best opportunity to educate Ihe people, of the state as to the purpose of the Department and the services which it is in a position to render. For this reason we believe that the exhibit of this Department was well worth while. COMPLAINTS The work of the Department could be still more ef - fective if i&gt;eople would report whenever conditions exist not in compliance witli the law and if purchasers would notify the Deputy Commissioner whenever merchants sell them food that is not fit for consumption. Numerous com- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE 14 &lt; plaiata have been made to the Itepartweat and in every in - stance tliese have been investigated. Tlie people of the state should know that a complaint, in order to he thorough - ly investigated, must he sponsored by someone. In several cases wheie we have known of tricky and unscrupulous dealers, it has been difficult to get sufficient infoimation to start a prosecution because those who possessed the infor - mation and had goffered most at the hands of these partic - ular dealers, lelused to give their names or appear in court. Tlie Depi.i tmeiit invites complaints ;md will give them care ful attention whenever the party making the complaint is willing to rex eal their identity. THE DAIRY INDUSTRY In the year 18S0, 65,000 lbs. of butter were mannfar - tured in the creameries of this state. Figure* for that year give 10,000 lbs. of butter produced on farms and in fac - tories and that this butter was produced by 161,000 dairy cows. Since that time to the present day. a period of 'M years, the total production has increased, but the significant fact to note is that by far the greater part of the butter pro - duced today is produced hi the creameries of the state Bad not on the farms. In 1890 the butler manufactured in creameries was ap - proximately C!&gt;S,000 ITis. In 1900 this had increased to 11,700,000 Tbs. and in 1910 the amount was 24,000.000 ms. During the past year the amount of butter manufactured was 46,800,000 lbs. The greatest increases were from 1880 to 1890 and from 1890 to 1900 but even with these enormous increases the amount manufactured has more than doubled from 1900 to 1910 and from 1910 to the present year, seven years dur - ing which the production has almost doubled again, so that by comparing these ten year periods we see a very favorable increase in the amount of this valuable product manufac - tured in the creameries of our state. Exact figures are not obtainable as to the amount of butter manufactured and used on farms or sold locally but it is safe to assume that at least 10,000,000 ms. and more likely 15.000,000 lbs. of butter are thus manufactured and consumed every year at the present time. This would make </seg>
            <seg id="p015">FOOD. DRUU. DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 15 si total atf about HO,O0O.U0U tt&gt;s. of batter produced in Ihi slate (luring the past year. Ihiriiix the "!7 year*, the rattle From wliicli this butter "as produced hare iaefwaaed in awnber from ltil.tMKt to (i7t»,&lt;H)O at tin- prevent time. A eoinpai ison of t lie rot* of in - ere;ise of the nnnil)er of dairy cattle Known that they hare not increased in so ure.it a proportion as has the Imtter pra duct ion. This nia\ lie taken as an eneouraging sijrn for it indicates thai xinrt 1 the early days of the industry the char nrter and &lt;|iiality of the dairy herds lias been iiieieasinir and hence there lias been a marked increase In the production of hulter fat. We can and should, however, still im-rea-c the produc - tion in this state, not only of butter but altM of other dairy products. In spite of the enormous amount of butter made in this state we still are not listed a- one of the leading dairy states in point of value of dairy production and in spite of the fact that ( &gt;maha manufactures more hotter than any city in the world. Since the war opened we realize more than ever hefort 1 the value of dairy products and particularly of hatter. This is shown by the fact that the price of Imtter and the price paid for Imtter fat is about double that of former years. The reason for this groat value is due to the filet that of all our food materials the fats are the highest in energy value ami those dairy products richest in fat are naturally the most valuable. While the present prices may lie somewhat hiirher than will obtain after the war is over, it is not reasonable to sup - por-e that the price will ever Hfpiia be very low. The farmer need not hesitate to invest his capital in the dairy business. At this time attention should be paid to increasing the butter fat yield. Kvery opportunity should lie taken to .-ave and conserve the other product.- of the dairy. The sale of cottage cheese made from separated milk should Ik - encouratred. Nothing should be allowed to aa to waste. We sometimes marvel that creameries are able to turn out as good a batter product as they do. As to the scionti - fa art of butter making we know but little but from the standpoint of reason we assume that not even a i-eientific process can produce perfect butter from imperfect cream. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 BIENNIAL KKI'OKT OK THE Feed, stabling, processes of milking, condition of milk pails, ■trainers, rreaan separator*, etc, are all elements with which we must reckon. Care of the cream at the farm, transporta - tion to tlie shipping point, care at tlie station and in transit to the factory are other steps wherein the cream may suffer damage all detrimental to the character of good batter. This Department is doing all that is possible to increase the amount el good cream even to having the cans of indi - vidual shipper* closely scrutinized at railway stations. Our int'pertora are instructed to give all possible assistance to route men and station operators concerning the ways and means of bettering the quality of cream. It would seem that to still farther increase the produc - tion of dairy products in Nebraska we should first of all seek to increase the number and quality of oui dairy herd* by the introduction of pure bred cattle. We should seek to con - .-ei ve all dairy products and to this end encourage the erec - tion of cheese factoi ies and milk condenseries. We should tee that milk and all other dairy products are handled in a cleanly and sanitary manner and that loss through im - proper and careless handling be reduced to a minimum. For this purpose we have the Dairy Laws enforced by this De - partment. It lias been our aim at all times to enforce these laws and to co-operate with the producer to the end that we ma&gt; secure an increased production and better quality of daii ' products so that we may build up a large, permanent industry and place Nebraska in the front rank of the dairy Rtatea of the Union. We would suggest that provision be made for the nn ployment of two competent dairy inspector* who shall be specialists in this line of work and preferably graduates of an agricultural college. The salary should be sufficient to insure the securing of the services of none but high grade men as it would be impossible to hold men of this kind at the salary which the present law provides. We l&gt;elieve that every daily in the state should be com - pelled to pay a nominal license fee, not so much for the sake of the fee in itself as for the means this would provide for keeping a check on the dairies of the state. Then in case a violation of the Dairy Laws the license could be revoked and the offending party put out of business. Such a system </seg>
            <seg id="p017">FOOD. DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION 17 vould certainly insure a more wholesome regard on the part of the dairymen of the state for the rules and regulations promulgated by the Dairy Commissioner. GASOLINE AND KEROSENE INSPECTION Every barrel of gasoline and kerosene coming into the state has been properly inspected. The quality of the gaso - line has been fairly uniform and only in a few cases has it been necessary to condemn any of the petroleum products shipped into the state. The Department instituted a number of crusades at dif - ferent times to compel filling stations to quote only the cor - rect gravity of the products which they are offering for sale. In one particular instance a dealer received a car of naptha and the ins] lector's test showed a sj&gt;ecific gravity of 52.70. The denier was instructed that the product could not be sold as gasoline but in spite of this fact he placed a placard on the filing device at the station calling the product "Liberty (Jasoline" and was selling the' same at a price less than the prevailing price for a standard grade of gasoline. The in - formation was filed with the County Attorney and the dealer prosecuted and lined under the (Jasoline and Kerosene In - spection Law. The records of this office indicate that there has been hnost a M*/&lt; increase during the past biennium in the use of petroleum products in this state. Due to the increased use of petroleum products in the state during the past two years the fees collected at the rate of six cents per barrel almost equalled the amount collected for the biennium preceding when the rate was ten cents. Even with the advanced cost of operation due to the general economic conditions there will remain a large surplus over the necessary expense of inspection. In accordance with the Supreme Court decision of Feb - mary 1917, in the case of the State vs. the Standard Oil Company, which provided that under Article VII of the ( onstitution of Nebraska, no fee could be charged in excess of the amount necessary to cover the cost of inspection, the </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Legislature of 1!M7, reduced tlie oil inspection fee from ten To preclude the possibility of the present hi w being held in violation of the constitution and the Supreme Court de - cision ((noted above, it will lie necessary for the meaning Legislature to so ainend Chapter 53 of the session laws of Nebraska for 1917 as it pertain* to oil inspection fees so thai the fee collected will be only such as is required to cover the cost of inspection. It is the opinion of this Department, based on the exper ience of the past biemiiinn that the fee should be reduced to not less than three cents a barrel. If the consumption of (gasoline and kerosene should continue at the present rate, .i three cent fee will be sufficient to cany on the work of in - spection and provide for any now nfonwi emergency w hich inav arise. I'nder the present system of inspection, oil station n^ents take a sample from each car of gasoline or kero-eiu before it is unloaded. This sample is held pending the ar - rival of the inspector. We believe that this plan could !»■ improved by stationing inspectors at the various points in the state where the tank cars arrive for distribution. In this way expenses could be greatly reduced as live compet - ent inspectors could do the entire work under such a plan. In the end this should mean a reduction in the price of |&gt;" troleuni products to the Nebraska consumers. LINSEED OIL The Department has received but little complaint rela - tive to the adulteration of linseed oil sold in the state dur - ing the past two years. We have had numerous inquiries from firms dealing in this product asking for the attitude of the Department relative to substitutes. Tn reply to men inquiries we have advised them that there was no objection to the placing on the market of a linseed oil sub - si itute providing it was marketed as a substitute and not j;s linseed oil. We have felt that, if it were possible to man - ufacture a satisfactory substitute at a greatly reduced price, the Department would not feel justified in depriving i coplc of the state of the advantage that might come from the sale of a cheaper product. Great care has been exor- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 19 &lt; ised to make certain that these linseed oil substitutes were mU &lt;nily its substitutes ;ind not as the product which they vi'iv supposed to replace. WEIGHTS AND MEASURES Provision was made during the 191 &lt; session of the I, en islature for three additional Weights and Measures' in spectois. This gave the Department six inspectors for this branch of the work. It li;is been impossible, however, to hare six nien employed nil of the time during the paid two yeans for this reason: it required some little time to give the men added to the force proper training to fit them for th^ work of inspection. Probably at no time were there more than five qualified inspectors ;it work. Death claimed one of oar most efficient men and two others resigned after a few months of service. Willi six men working regularly we believe that it would be possible to cover the entire state once a year. We believe that a saving of time and expense could be effected by providing an automobile for the use of tlie Weight* mid Measures inspectors. The trans - porting of one thousand pounds of weight* which it is nec - essary for filch inspector to carry involve- no small item of expense. Train service is such that inspectors are some times compelled to waste a half day remaining in a tunnli town alter their work lias been completed. It is possible that the number of inspectors could be reduced to four if automobiles were furnished to them. While the inspection fees have hardly own m*lf-»*a»tnin - ing. it is doubtful if it would be advisable to increase them. The suggestion has sometimes been made that the matter of fee.- for work done by the Weights and Measure* inspect ors should be dispensed with altogether. There is a feel - ing that there would be more whole hearted co-operation on the part of dealers and merchants if the inspector could come to them for inspection work alone and not in the dou - ble capacity of inspector and collector. The work of the Weights and Measures inspector* has been done fearlessly and conscientiously. A scale that was off has been condemned in every instance. Some com plaint lias reached the Department that the inspectors had condemned scales without making any attempt to repair </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE ti.em. Parties expecting their scales to be repaired have evidently been misinformed as to the scope of the law. There have been oases where the inspector could correct the scale or measuring; device by making some minor adjustment and uently this has been done. As we interpret the law. this is not a duty that is required. Numerous requests have been made for sj&gt;ecial inspeetions where partial have in stalled new scales. Owing to the expense involved in trans porting test weights it has not seemed advisable to oomph with these requests. Every county has been completely covered before talk ing up the work of the adjoining county. The inspectors have followed their fixed territories and in this way the en- tire state has been covered. When a new scale is installed the presumption is that it N f or reft and the Department has so considered it until inspected and found otherwise. We believe that it is safe to say that in general, tin law ii a popular one with the people of the state. Following we give a summary of the inspections made Summary of inspections made by the Weights and Measures Department from December 1916 to December Sealed Condemned Adjusted Platform scales 5670 i&gt;(iO 28 Stock scales 9."&gt;0 159 31 Wagon scales 2815 295 61 Automatic scales 8(55 47 9 Spring scales 196 22 4 Hopper scales (546 55 11 Pumps 3204 154 47 Measures 4816 497 12 Counter scales 6136 239 40 Weights 3058 86 103 lkmnant scales 249 74 11 Slot machines 30 3 Dump scales •) Track 3 28,580 1,891 357 &gt;' </seg>
            <seg id="p021">FOOD. DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION 21 COLD STORAGE Then arc nt the present time twenty-four cold storage varehoftHm in Nebraska, sis defined by tin- law dealing with the subject. These warehouses have been rigidly inspected with 'the result that there have been but verv few instances where inferior storage prodaeti have been offered for sal'-. Some complaint lia.s reached the Department relative to the storage of poultry from which the viscera has not been drawn. Carefully conducted experiments carried on r.nder the direction of experts and extending over a conxiri- eralile period of time have revealed the fact that the mi- drawn poultry keeps the best. As Ions? as the bird remains intact there is less chance for action of the bacteria that produce putrefaction. Cold storage warehouses must ic port quarterly as to the quantity and kinds of food held in storage at a temperature of 40 degreea or less for a period of sixty days or laager. An idea of the amount of food i'i cold storage in Nebraska can be obtained from the folio wine summary compiled from the report* filed in thi&lt; office lor the quarter ending October 6, 1918. Butter (jMHinds) 2,44:).94S Kggs (cases) 90,401 Frozen eggs (pounds) 366,820 Poultry (pounds) 4")4,*;j:; Fish (pounds) 229,368 Beef carcasses (pounds) 124,306 Beef trimmings (pounds) 296.515 Beef cuts (pounds) lo'i.TOS Pork outs (pounds) 42,407 Pork trimmings (pounds) 107,414 Mutton cuts (pounds) 5,4&gt;4 Mutton trimmings (pounds) 46,597 Veal cuts (pounds) 5,750 Veal trimmings (pounds) 2,1 9H Sweet Piekle meat (pounds) 4,321 ,44&lt;i Dry Salt Meat (pounds) 6,166,486 Dried fruit (pounds) 953,350 953,350 Apples (barrels) 1,190 Apples (boxes) 708 Nuts (pounds) 629,761 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE LABORATORY The Lnltoratory reports show for the hienniom, 1.171 rlicinicjil analyses. 'I'liis lisriuc is appreciably less than the number of analyses reported for the hicimium just preced - ing. Tlieie arc scvcnil reasons lor this; th«' chiel' one is the fart thai hnttcr fai determinations on &gt;amplrs of milk and irvani liava ii'»t heea inchnled in the total nnraher of analytic* nn was the case during- tlie last bienninin. Those detenninatimai have, for the most part, brea made by our in s|i('itur&gt; in the field who were fully competent to make these te-N and milk and cre.ini samples were only sent to this laboratory when ;: ioon&gt; &lt;oiui&gt;lete analysis \va- tlionuht to be necessary. Daring the rammer of 1917 for a period of a little over two niontlis no work was potwible in the Lahora tory due to extensive efcaagM which were heing made in en lariiint;- the Lahoratorv spai-e hy tlie addition of an entirely Dew room and installing the necessary equipment. This work necessitated virtually a complete suspension of activi - tio&gt;. conse(|iieiitly a great falling off of the masher of analy -e&gt; possible. Another reanoa for the difference iu the niun - lei r«'ported consists of the fact tli.it in the past two years K timber of special invostiffations have been conducted in l.;il'oi-,itoi y which entailed in ever^ r instance a more lpli-te analyvifl than ordinarily given for the defection &lt;&gt;f dnlteinnto and violations of on r Food Laws. An attempt has been made in the past two years to in - ie*tigate one kind of food product during a given period which facilitates the chemical work in the Laboratory and at the same time furnishes n more or less complete survey I'Ynit cikes (pounds) ."'.T"-".) Soft drinks (kej«:s) MoIhhncm (barrels) Lard and &lt; 'ooking compounds (pounds) .... Kraut ( pounds) Condensed milk (pounds) Candy (pounds) Vegetables (crates) ( 'ranberrim (barrels) Misc. fruit (crates) 404 14»2fi 157,001) 20,4 lifi 36.1C0 102.(i7s .1? m </seg>
            <seg id="p023">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION &lt;.i &lt; oiiilitioiis in the State of the kind of food product under examination. Amonjr the different classes of foods, wliicli have l&gt;een investigated in this manner are syrups, flavoring extracts, coffee, ciiinied goods, ice cream, milk, butter and non-alcoholic beverages, In connection with these analyses, lists have been. com 1 4 led from time to time of the various brands of food pro - ducts which have been found to be adulterated or mi* - branded and copies of these lists have been sent to our in - spectors with instructions, that where the violation in mainly a technical one, to inform the dealer the sale of these brands should be discontinued until requirements are com - plied with. This we feel lias been conducive of much good as it iias eliminated prosecution, in a jrood many case*, of dealers whose irootls were obtained frcm manufacturer* outside of the State The manufacturers Hading the sale of their products stopped were in nil eases prompt to take steps to make their floods conform to our State Laws. This sy.-tem seems to us preferable to haphazard purchase of various food samples at one time and we feel that the | ent system should be extended to other lines of food pro ducts \vl ich have not as yet been thoroughly investigated With the Many inveotigntiom of the I abomtory otic of the most noteworthy was one that led to the discovery of conditions of the Union Parking Company at Omaha. Daring the early spiing of 1917. Many samples of ranned Wans packed by the above concern were examined in the Labora - tory and as a result of our examination an investigation was made at Omaha where it was found that this concern was parohaoing chiefly cull benns from the Michigan Reid? and were parking these under a number of brands. Since these beans represented an interstate shipment, the officials of the Bureau of Chemistry. IT. S. Department of Agricul - ture, were notified and in conjunction with them this De partment effected a seizure of approximately eight ear load* of beans, which was said to be, at that lime the birgexi atfal ure of food products ever consumated in the United States At the same time, following proeedin.es in bankruptcy, the Inion Packing Company was dissolved and if etaasd tic manufacture of food product* in Nebraska. (die of the most fiei|uent form* of adulteration prac (iced at the present time is the addition of water, chiefly </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE in certain canned goods. Investigations in the Laboratory tto the discovery of large amounts of water in sauer - lt and hominy in this state. In both cases large amounts liese goods were seized and sent out of the State, in one ■ M the result of a prosecution. Several .cases were id. where milk had been watered and in each instance practice was promptly stopped by the Department. Much laboratory work outside of that necessary for the enforcement of the Food and Drug 1 Laws has been done, especially since the United States entered into the world var. Among those for whom we have done analytical work are; the War Department; I. S. Food Administration; Bureau of Chemistry of the U. S. Department of Agricul - ture; the State Council of Defense; D. S. District Attorney for this District; (iovernor Neville and many County Attor - neys in Nebraska chiefly in connection with the enforce - ment of the Prohibition Law. In addition to the above we have had numerous requests from individuals for the analy - sis of various food products which were suspected of con - taining ground glass or poison. While no provision is made by which we have author - ity to make analyses of samples other than those submitted by our inspectors, we have in every instance carefully in - \cstigated all samples submitted which were suspected to ( «&gt;ntain glass or poison. In spite of the wide-spread rumors through the newspapers, of ground glass in food stuffs, this Laboratory has not in one instance found ground glass pres - ent in any food stuff submitted. We have found pieces of glass and splinters in two or three instances; in one case a &lt; oiiMderable amount of glass being present but no infor - mation \v;ts at hand showing in what manner it had been A summary of the food situation from the Laboratory Kdpoint shows that while the crude forms of adultera - of foods are no longer practiced and the addition of preservatives is not nearly so common there is still much adulterated food being offered for sale. The detection of this adulteration has become increasingly more difficult since adulterators have kept pace with the times and many d ( them employ expert chemists to direct their efforts. The general trend of such adulteration is by the substitution of products inferior to those for which they are sold. Many </seg>
            <seg id="p025">FOOD. DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL, COMMISSION 25 cases of misbranding are continually found among products offered for sale and continual vigilance on the part of the Food authorities is necessary to prevent the public from be - ing imposed upon by adulterated or inferior goods and mis - leading labels. At tlie bwgi—i»g of this hiennium the Chemical Labor - atory was situated in one small room which was entirely inadequate and not properly arranged for systematic chem - ical work. The Laboratory was in charge of the State Chemist, \V. S. Frisbie. who was leappointed by Governor Neville and has served throughout the Bicnninin. The Legislature at the session in 1917 ma.le provision for the appointment of an assistant chemist and after the Labora - tory had been enlarged and provision was made, an ssist - n« chemist, K. (J. Batty, was appointed in September, 1917, who has rilled this position to date. This arrangement has been eminently more satisfactory than the former since by this means a more complete analysis lias been possible of different classes of food stuffs and such investigatioiuil vork, as above mentioned, has been ttoac which otherwise could not have been accomplished. There is most urgent need at the present time for the employment of ■ harliiri ologist in the Laboratory in order to properly investigate the dairy situation in this state. This is the only means by which it is possible to check the efficiency of pasteui ization and to safeguard the sale of milk where pasteurization is not practiced. It is felt that some provision should be made for such n position at the coming session of the Legislature. SEED LABORATORY During the years 1917 and 1918, 3216 samples of seed were voluntarily sent to the Seed Laboratory for test. These samples required approximately seven thousand tests as most of them were tested both for purity and "Termination. There were also 671 official seed inspection samples col - lected during this time and these were also tested for pur - ity and germination. The number of samples received during 1918 repre - sents an increase of 7(5% over those of the previous year. This increase is due to several facts: (1) The Pure Seed Law passed by the Legislature in 1917 called the attention of the farmers to the necessity of </seg>
            <seg id="p026">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE 26 i li-iiiK'i m(&lt;1 and made it potitiible for t lie residents of the Ktatc to have samples of seed letted free of charge. tij) The present administration has shown an honest ra to co-operate witli the fanners ill making the new law iTcitivc as the Lei-i-latuie intended it should be. It given publicity to the fact that seed would be tested free barge and has installed a better equipped laboratory for &gt; inn on the work. t ('■'.) Bvery effort lias been made to eo-operate with County Agents and the Couneil of Defense in aiding raltarifto to obtain viable crop seeds and keep their - Hiid fields free from weed seeds. (4) To a constantly increasing demand everywhere for a higher .made of tgi iraltnral seods. FURTTY TESTS In 1914 the Seed Laboratory was established in order that t'annei js and seed dealers might be able to obtain better grades of seeds. When samples are si-nt in they are tested and report made as to their parity and germination. These te-t&gt; have undoubtedly greatly aided fanners and other buyers of seed. I 'The examination of various samples of seed from dif - nt part.- of the state are also of vahw to the Seed Lnbor - y in that they give information rejyarding the condition eed glow a in various localities. For instance, the al - a of tlie 1918 crop in certain sections of the state shows alarmiug condition with regard to dodder infestation, d from these fields will be given special attention. The following is a copy of a report illustrating the ■thod used in informing the farmer or seed dealer of the iditioa of the seeds which he sends in for testing: </seg>
            <seg id="p027">FOOD, DRUG. DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 27 KEITH NEVILLE. Governor OTTO ML'RSCHEL H. KERNi: PECK Commissioner Comml55ionrr SUte Seed \nalyit DEPARTMENTS Food. Drue. Dairy and Oil Pure Seed and Feeding Stuff Sta-.dards Of Weight* and Vl^iurri Paints and Linseed Oil COMMISSION l.ini nln Cold Storaicc .Itilin Doe, NccittsbliilT. Nebr. (Vtober Iti. 1!U*\ A GERMINATION TEST IS BEING MAM AMI \\ [I.I. Hi; REPORTED LATER r. fer*&gt; M Seed x..,.,| II Pure seed Includes all seed of the kind being -xiiiiiiiit-d Inert matter includes brokoa M«4s, ciirt. rtMM, stick.-, r iiaff. and other similar material. Foreign seed includes all seed except those of the kind beins examined FOKKUiN SKK1) IXfl.l I»KS THK KOM.O\VI\&lt;. Appruximatf Ippi \llli;ttr \ ttt.l l&gt;er p-'un-l I- il mpL Indian mustard Russian thistle Var.-li elder v- Swe"t ilcver II 190 8S || Rl 340 lUxl.l.r seed to 2885 Alfalfa seed. It is unlawful to sell this seed in tlie Stato of Nebraska, OTTO &gt;IIHSCHKI.. Deputy Commisvloner Seed Analyst l&gt;cput&gt; ST.VIK OK \K1!I!.(SKA 1 (IOI&gt;. Mtl'O, HAIRY AND oil ItepoH &lt;&gt;f Parity Tr&gt;i &lt;&gt;r s&lt;-. &lt;1 Itci civ«l (&gt;&lt;:&lt;&gt;1mt Hi. l!i|S. 742f, Itox" \lfall:i M 7 Salt bush Lambv rpi-irter Grefii foxtail Approximately one Dodder </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Final Report of Germination Test of Seed Received October 10, 1U18. Duration oi Germination j Hard Seeds Tct No. Sender', MarW Name * Seed | fc?^ J Fe7 Cent 7242 I "Able 1 Alfalfa 6 7 4:'.6 I "Burr" ! Red Clover If 10 According to the Nebraska Seed Law. "Credit shall be given a ger - mination test of one-third the hard seeds." Among many kinds of leguminous seeds, such as red clover and alfalfa, some seeds .remain hard at the end of the time usually allowed for a germination teat. These so called "hard seeds" have unusually hard seed coats, preventing them from taking up water readily. While some of these hard seeds will remain in water or in the ground for a long time without germination, they are practically all good seeds, growing quickly at any time if the seed coat is scratched or broken or has become sufficiently softened so the seed can take up water. BThe presence of a large percentage of bard seeds is of considerable i&lt;al importance, as a good stand may not be obtained on account eir delayed germination. OTTO MURSCHBI., Deputy Commissioner Seed Analyst. KEITH NEVILLE, Governor OTTO MURSCHEL M. FERNE PECK Commlnloncr Deputy CommUsioner State Seed Analyst DEPARTMENTS STATE OF NEBRASKA F ood. Dru,. Dairy and Oil •XM&gt;I&gt;, DKUO, DAIRY AND Oil. Pure Seed and Feeding Stuff COMMISSION Standard. CM Weight, and Meagre. PalnU and Linseed Oil Lincoln Cold Storage .Inhii Dot'. Scottsbluff, Nebr. October 16, 191 H. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">FOOD, DKUG, DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION 29 GERMINATION TESTS The number of germination tests during the past year an exceedingly large increase over previous years. Modern electrically heated and regulated germination ap - paratus has been installed which was especially adequate to meet the emergency rising from the serious condition of the 1917 seed corn. Weather conditions were such that the corn was frozen, causing it to be soft and to have very poor germinating qualities. This Laboratory found that 207c of the corn sent in for test had no viability whatever. Every effort was made to give warning of this condition and to assist the residents of the state of Nebraska to secure good, viable aeed. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUMMARY OF PURITY AND GERMINATION TESTS FOR 1917 AND 1918 Kind of Seed Number of. Average iieiccut of purity and samples 1 germination germination 1916 and 1917 1917 and IS is -^ ? '_ t ! § . f II I . : S I Si x I ,p x ■ •&gt; Alfalfa I 221! 4321 97.01 7 1 19 96.64 n s K&lt;m1 clover 77 Ml 92.72 7". IS !•:!.:* 2 78 AUike clover I 24 31 IS.*I 77 II !&gt;:!.94 80 White clover i 14; 27 s».6"&gt; 74 22 xx.4i 68 ..., Sweet clover | 201 34 1 97.84J 72 16 92.42 64 •jr. Millet 50; 97 37.00 13 t7.M 9 1 v Cane 67. 333; 92.88 *■ 91.87 rt 2 ... Timothy 341 531 97.16 I] 97.6!) 86 Blue grass j 20 49' 76.60 29 84.08 Orchard grass 101 31 72.33 83 Broiue grass | 13 9 75.20 64 &gt; 89.70 81 KaBfir corn 9 42 | 71 97.47| 58 Sudan grass 4 37 76 I 93.40J 75 Wheat 1 17 | 98.851 76 Corn 5 1.183) 98 Meadow fescue I 6 8 96.8."., 78 Tl Meadow fescue Meadow fescue I 6 8( 96.8."., 781 Kape | |« It i 99.40 93 Red top ; 12 1 9 1 70.52 .".2 79.24 61 KeteriU j 5 8 89' I 58.19 41 Milo II 8 83 Oats I 91 75.33| 78 Buckwheat 21 | 98^02 Barley I 5 I 98.04 93 Per. rye grass | 3| 1 Italian rye grass i l| II 74 Pacey's rye grass I II I 70 English rye grass | 1 Hye | if II I 97.631 85 Be^t« II 5| 77 Beans 1 2| 9 95! 82| Carrots 1[ 21 | 45! Muskmelon | 2} I 81 Watermelon I 1 61 Other vegetables 16 i Winter vetch 3 1 Mixtures | 2| 181 Indentifications I 9 Miscellaneous 81 15 •Hard seeds. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">FOOD. DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION- 31 EQUIPMENT .Besides the new electrical gejininator, the Laboratory is also equipped with Torsion Balances for purity determin - ation, glass topped stands for purity analysis, sieves of dif - ferent niesli for separating the weed seeds from crop seeds as well as various crop seeds from each other, tripod, lens and microscope for identification of small seeds, a mechan - ical mixer and divider for obtaining representative samples &lt; i' seeds, besides an electrically driven seed blower or sep - arator which saves much time in making purity tests by leadily removing chaff and other light weight inert matter from pure seed. RULES FOR SEED TESTING Tile rules used in the seed testing work are those recom - mended by the Association of Official Seed Analysts of North America at its annual meeting held at Detroit, June 19-21, 1917. EDUCATIONAL WORK It has always been kept in mind by the Department that Ihe seed work could be done more efficiently if the agricul - turists of the state realized the necessity of helping them - selves to keep their fields free from noxious weeds and also when purchasing sr^d preVMt paying for unvinble crop seeds or a considerable percent of weed seed. To this end every possible opportunity has been seized to bring the «.nestion of seed purity to the attention of the public. The Seed Analyst has addressed fanners' meetings and lias visited several county fairs besides the State Fair for the past two years where an exhibition has been given demon - strating to the farmers the necessity of securing only good seed to insure efficient food production. Ever}' effort has been made to assist the residents of Nebraska who buy or sell seed to become familiar with the State Seed Law and its requirements. Many violations were found to be unintentional and due to misunderstand - ings in regard to the provisions of the Law. When the vio - lators were informed they immediately complied with the requirements. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE RECOMMENDATIONS The greater part of the seed analyzing and testing is done between January 1st, and June 1st. The great num ber of i&gt;ereons taking advantage of this service at the pres - «nt time makes it impossible for the State Seed Analyst to do both the purity test work and also the inspection of seed being sold by wholesale and retail dealers throughout the state in a manner adequate to the present conditions. For this reason it is very desirable that provision be made whereby the Deputy Commissioner shall be authorized to employ a person to be an assistant to the Seed Analyst es pecially in the inspection work which must necessarily be done simultaneously with the testing in the laboratory. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">FOOD. DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION 33 SUMMARY OF INSPECTIONS December 1, 1018, to December I, 1018 Bakeries - 980 Bottlers CO Cars, Oil and Gasoline 23.S79 Cold Storages 435 Confectionaries S.522 Cieam Stations 3.144 Creameries 229 Dairies and Milk Plants 57* Drug Stores 701 Fish Markets 23 F'ood Factories 165 Groceries 7.9SC Hotels 3.143 Meat Markets 3.05 X Mills and Feed Stores 441 Hacking Houses 35 Paints and Oils j« Restaurants 2,530 Retail Fruit Stores 51 Scales, Weights and Measures 1J.144 Seed 508 Slaughter Houses SIC Wholesale Fruit Stores 31 Wholesale Grocers 53 Produce „ 219 Fair Grounds ~ 2,009 Miscellaneous 440 Total 51.394 Chemical Analyses 1,17 1 Seed Analyses 3,454 Sanitary Orders Issued 1,028 Prosecutions Cl </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE RECEIPTS BY MONTHS From nwrmber I, 1916, to November 30, 191H (iii.Iumw) DECEMBER, 1916 Receipts l.l. rs and Samplers % 98.00 Imitation Butter 448.28 Creameries 5.84 Tag* and Stickers 295.00 Live Slock Remedies 5.00 Copies of Oil R.port 10.00 oil inspection Fees 7,819.35 iits and Measures 406.95 Miscellaneous 186.29 Total $ 9,274.71 JANUARY, 1917 Receipts Testers' and Samplers' permits $ 80.00 Retail Imitation Butter License 90.85 Commission Merchants License 100.00 Cold Storage 100.00 Tags and Stickers 323.15 Live Stock Remedy 40.00 Seed Teata 6.00 i la n eo us 78.43 Copy of Oil Reports _ 10.00 -iits and Measures 470.50 Oil inspection Fees 13.741.0.". Total „ $ 15,039.98 Keceived from C. E. Harman. Deputy Commissioner 1,000.00 Total ? 16,039.98 FEBRUARY, 1917 Receipts ri and Samplers $ 106.00 detail Imitation Butter 43,79 Commission Merchants' License 10.00 Tags and Stickers 202.25 See.l Tests 12.50 Miscellaneous 5.51 I opy of Oil Reports _ lO.Oti Wrights and Measures 372.6'. Oil Inspection Fees _ 9,170.90 Total % 9,933.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">FOOD. DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION 35 MARCH, 1»I7 IC&lt;Ti-i|&gt;i- Tpsters and Samplers $ 176. ••' Retail Imitation llutter 30. u:. Retail Ice Cream bottlers 1 ,1 Ta*.s and Stickers 53:1 ..p.", Live Stock Remedy I* Seed Tests 19 Miscellaneous 1' 1 ■ ' Copy of Oil Reports In I Weights and Measures 4.'!' Oil Inspection Fees 12,678 Total % 1 3.!«m I 1 1 U'ltll.. 1917 Receipts Testers and Samplers s Retail Imitation Butter 77 C'» Wholesale Ice Cream 1.72 Retail Ice Cream 2.011 Tags and Stickers 4 | :,.im» Live Stork Rtmody M.M Seed Tests 8.5n Miscellaneous H.I I Copy of Oil Reports It.M Weights and Measures 482.35 Oil Inspection Fees 6,9' Total $ 8. 1 1 MAY, 1917 Receipts Testers and Samplers $ M "" Retail Imitation Butter in:: 114 Creameries „ 1.7" Wholesale Ice Cream .84 Retail Ice Cream I.M liottlers l» " " ( ommission Merchants 1 1 Tags and Stickers 365. 55 Miscellaneous 24.1 1 Weights and Measures 47C.35 Oil Inspection Fees l.ti s Hotel L.icens« 14.00 Total $ S.17" 4 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE 36 JUNE, 1017 Receipts Testers and Samplers $ 2.00 Retail Imitation Butter 9.24 Tags and Stickers 72.25 Live Stock Remedies 60. 00 Hotel License 30.00 Miscellaneous Collections 34.30 Weights and Measures 747.85 Oil Inspections 8,214.98 Total $ 9,170.62 JULY, 1»17 Receipt* Testers and Samplers $ 3,368.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter 375.00 Retail Imitation Butter _ 2, 685. On Creameries 1,402.00 Wholesale Ice Cream 320.00 ketail Ice Cream 84.00 bottlers 3 3 O.o.i Tags and Stickers 239.5" Live Stock Remedies 5.00 Misiellaneous Collections — 28.: (old Sidage Inspections 335.00 Hotel License 2, Weights and Measures 985 Oil Inspections 8.99S Total $ 21,692.6!! AUGUST, 1»17 Receipts Testers and -ample s $ 188.00 Ketail Imitation Eir.ter 1 68.90 Creameries 9.16 Wholesale Ice Cream 30.00 Ketail Ice Cream 3.00 Feed Tests 1.00 Tags and Stickers 340.00 Live Stock Remedies 35.00 Cold Storage 185.00 Hotel License 942.00 Weights and Measures 1,177.3' Oil Reports „ _ 10.00 Oil Inspections 9,731.94 Miscellaneous 44.58 Total _ $ 12.865.88 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">FOOD. DRUG. DAIRY AND OIL, COMMISSION 37 SEPTEMBER, 1917 Receipts Testers and Samplers $ 204.00 Retail Imitation Butter _ W.M Creameries : 30.00 Wholesale Ice Cream 5.00 Retail Ice Cream 4.00 Tags and Stickers 157.50 Live Stock Remedies 10.00 Hotel Licenses 544.0" Weights and Measures 973.30 Copy of Oil Reports 10.00 Miscellaneous 2j is Oil Inspection Pees 10,133.80 Total $ 12,762.8 s OCTOBER, 1917 Receipts Testers and Samplers $ 116.00 Retail Imitation Butter 936 57 Tags and Stickers 1,450.00 Hotel License 455.00 Copies of Oil Reports 10.00 Weights and Measures Inspection Fees 735.75 Miscellaneous Collections M SI Oil Inspection Fees 10.803 S 6 Total $ 14.530.6r. NOVEMBER, 1917 Receipts Testers and Samplers $ 138.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter 33. 33 Retail Imitation Butter ■ 358. 3c Creameries 6.67 Retail Ice Cream 1.00 Itottlers 500 Tags and Stickers. 355.00 Live Stock Remedies. 15.0U Hotel License 608.00 Miscellaneous Collections 23.67 Weights and Measures 675. in Copies of Oil Report 10.00 Oil Inspection Fees 8,576.75 Total f 10,806.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE IlKCKMItKlt. 1917 H«v«-i|ils Tnurs and Samplers $ M.M ketail imitation Ilutter 12::. i Tags and Stickers 804.00 Live Stock Remedies 5.0(&gt; Hotel License Mi-rellaneous Collections 2j.r,t; Copies of Oil Report .... 10.no Weights and Measures ."iB5.ii 7 Oil Inspection Fees 6,3»6 Total | H.3 10.31 JAMAUY, I1HM Receipts TeM. rs and Samplers TXail Imitation Huiter tiO.14 Creameries 10.00 Bottle; s 5.00 Tags and Stickers 322.70 Live Siock Remedies • 1T..00 Miscellaneous Collections 26.56 Copies of Oil Report 10.00 Hotel License 28J.O( Weights and Meaesures 701 Oil Inspection Fees 8.443.OS Total $ 9.9U1 KKIiKl AKY. lilts Receipts Testers and Samplers $ 1^4 Wholesale Imitation Butter I Retail Imitation Butter 172.4! Tags and Stickers ::j4 Live Stuck Remedies :;0.00 Miscellaneous Collections 19.81 Copies of Oil Report Id. 00 Hotel License 4 4 6.00 Weights and Measures 647.7 Oil Inspection Fees 5,770.52 Total $ 7.578.6H </seg>
            <seg id="p039">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 39 MARCH, 1918 llwei|&gt;ts listers and Samplers $ 154.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter 8.3$ Hetail Imitation Butter 133.09 lietail Ice Cream 1.00 Tags and Stickers 3«1.40 Live Stock Remedies 20.00 Miscellaneous Collections 13.16 Copies of Oil Report 10.00 Hotel License 390 00 .......... ... ............... . U »/ ■ ' V Weights and Measures 691.35 Oil Inspection Fees „ 6,65(.62 Total * 8,438.84 AI'HIIi. 1918 Receipt* Testers and Samplers $ 150.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter .;_•;, Ketail Imitation Butter 66.32 IJetail Ice Cream 3.00 and Stickers 212.C3 Live Stock Remedies 35.00 Miscellaneous Collections || f% Hotel License 312.00 Weights and Measures 7.-^ M ( opies of Oil Reports 15.00 Oil Inspection Fees • 10.648.2C Total $ 12,218 4s MAY, 1U18 Kecfipts ■tan and Samplers $ 128.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter 4.17 Ketail Imitation Butter 26.75 l.ottlers 5.00 me! Stickers ■. 535.93 Live- Stock Remedies 5.00 Miscellaneous Collections 15.54 Hotel License •!.(• Weights and Measures 939.9'' Copies of Oil Reports 10.00 Oil Inspection Fees _ 12,807.84 ToUl $ 14,539.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 BIENNIAL REPORT OP THE JUNE, 1018 Receipt* Retail Imitation Butter $ 19.66 Tags and Stickers 228.75 Live Stock Remedies 25.00 Miscellaneous Collections 14.30 Hotel License : 8.00 Weights and Measures :. 455.10 Copies of Oil Reports 15.00 Oil Inspection Fees 9.606.6S Total $ 10,372.49 JULY, 1018 Receipts Testers and Samplers $ 3,064.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter 500.00 Retail Imitation Butter 4.125.00 (rcameiies I.W7.M Wholesale Ice Cream 280.00 Ketail Ice Cream ~ 67.00 Bottlers 290.00 Tags and Stickers 16rf 0i told Storage Inspection 600.00 Miscellaneous Collections 24.41 Hotel License 3,564.00 Weights and Measures 807.80 Copies of Oil Reports 10.00 Oil Inspection Fees .*. 10,396.00 Total * 25.994 21 AUGUST, 1918 Receipts Testers and Samplers $ 260.00 Retail Imitation Butter 120.62 Wholesale Ice Cream 5.00 Retail Ice Cream 1.00 Tags and Stickers : 102.0t&gt; Live Stock Remedies 10.00 Miscellaneous Collections „ 40.85 Hotel License 816.00 Weights and Measures 810.10 ( opies of Oil Reports 10.00 Oil Inspection Fee* 12,040.38 Total _ _ $ 14,215.95 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND Oil. COMMISSION 41 SEPTEMBER, 1018 Receipt* Testers and Samplers t 146.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter 20.84 Retail Imitation Butter 593.73 Creameries 60.35 Wholesale Ice Cream 20.00 Retail Ice Cream 1.00 Tags and Stickers 230.00 Hotel License MS.M Live Stock Remedies _ 35.00 Miscellaneous Collection* 26.96 Weights and Measures 507.20 Copies of Oil Report* _ 20.00 Oil Inspection P«e« 10,942.90 Total _ $ 13.5S1.9S OCTOBER, 1»18 Receipts Testers and Samplers _ % 90.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter 11J.50 Retail Imitation Butter „ 1.675.65 Creameries - 17.60 Ketail Ice Cream 1-00 Tags and Stickers 1,022.51' Hotel License _ :!92.'i" Miscellaneous Collections 21.53 Weights and Measures _ 624.66 Copies of Oil Reports 20.00 Oil Inspection Fees 1 12.103.80 Total i 15, (&lt;81.03 NOVEMBER, 1918 Receipt* Testers and Samplers $ 98.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter 33.35 Retail Imitation Butter 383.15 Wholesale Ice Cream _ 10.00 Tags and Stickers 577.50 Hotel License , 129.00 Miscellaneous Collections 24.10 Weights and Measures 608.75 Copies of Oil Reports 20.00 Oil Inspection Fee* 7,292.36 Total $ 9,1 76! 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE EXPENSES BY MONTHS 1918 (inclusive) From December 1, 191B to November 8(», DKI'KMKKI!. UMIi K\|M»nses Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Kxpense of Deputy Commissioner 10.70 Salary of Secretary 90.00 Salary of Chemist 150.00 Kxpense of Chemist 27.65 Salary of Seed Analyst 9.00 Salary of Clerks 155.00 Salary of Food Inspectors 3,437.00 Kxpense of Food Inspectors 1,733.49 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 697.50 Kxpense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 460.09 Books and Printing 245.06 Telephone and Telegraph 81.31 Postage 200.00 Office Supplies and Expenses 119.36 Laboratory 18. 2G Total $ 7,642.7 JAN'UARY, 1917 Expenses Salary of Deputy Commissioner. C. E. Harman $ 33.60 Salary of Deputy Commissioner 174.73 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 3.50 Salary of State Chemist 150.00 Expense of State Chemist 30.20 Salary of Secretary 78.30 Salary of Clerks and Stenographers-.. ..• 164.0" Salary of Seed Analyst 76. SO Expense of Seed Analyst 20.10 Salary of Frank Maloney, Food Inspector 22.50 Kxpense of Frank Maloney, Food Inspector 3.90 Offire Expense 151.00 Laboratory Expense , 15.64 Postage 100.00 Printing 45.25 Attorney's Fees in Oil Case 250.00 Total _ $ 1,319.22 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 43 FEBKUAKY, 1017 Expenses Salary of Deputy Commissioner S 2M Expense of Deputy Commissioner 14 9'". Salary of State Chemist 150. On Expense of State Chemist II II Salary of Secretary 90.0" .Salary of ClerkB and Stenographers _ 175."0 Salary of Extra Help 88.95 Salary of Seed Analyst 108.00 Expense of Seed Analyst t.15 Salary of Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors !.((*. SO Kxpense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,338. 1" Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 342.00 Kxpense of Weights and Meeasures Inspectors 240.25 Office Expense and Equipment (41.93 Laboratory Expense 3.00 Postage 200.00 Attorney's Fees in Oil Case 250.00 '■Vic-phone and Telegraph 20.10 Express .99 Total $ «, 585. :.l MARCH, 1017 Expenses Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 12.70 Salary of Secretary _ 90.00 Expense of Secretary 8.00 Salary of Chemist 1 50. 00 Expense of Chemist .'4.86 Salary of Clerks and Stenographers 175. 00 Salary of Seed Analyst 121.30 Kxpense of Seed Analyst 10.97 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,614.49 Expense of Food, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 39 1.9&lt;* Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 310. 5" Kxpense of Weights and Measures Inspector* Office Expense 70.03 Ol'flre Equipment and Supplies. : 2.247.98 Postage , 400.00 Telephone and Telegraph 24.95 Express _ 4.02 Printing 5«75 Total $ 7,081.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE APK1U 1917 Expenses Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors....^ % 1,873. OH Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,171.74 Sslaty of Weights and Measures Inspectors 378.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 277.16 Express 2.33 Office Expense 25.00 Total $ 3,7 27.2:! MAY, 1917 Expenses Salary of Deputy Commissioner for April and May $ 416.6t&gt; Expense of Deputy Commissioner for April and May 16. i'.", Salary of Secretary for April and May 266.66 Salrry of Clerks and Bookkeeper 583.31 Expense of Clerks 16.10 Salary of Chemist for April and May 400.00 Expense of Chemist for April and May 61.0.". Salary of Assistant Deputy Hotel Com. for April and May.... 233.3" Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors. 2,178.50 Kxpense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,150.5 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 429.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 289.99 Salary of Seed Analyst for April 120.00 Expense of Seed Analyst _ 19.67 Books and Printing 299.35 TelegTaph and Telephone 24.65 Postage 200.00 Office Supplies 263.30 Extra Help _ 41.67 Laboratory Supplies 14.67 Salary of Dep. Hotel Commissioner, P. F. Ackerman 16.67 ToUl „ $ 7,041.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION 45 JUNE, 1917 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner _ $ 208.34 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Salary of Secretary 133.34 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.36 Salary of Extra Help 34.10 Salary of Chemist 200.00 Expense of Chemist €.10 Silary of Seed Analyst for May 130.00 Expense of Seed Analyst 15.38 Salary of Seed Analyst for June 130.00 Expense of Seed Analyst for June 55.30 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,209.00 Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,107.01 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors (70.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 374.80 Books and Printing 293.75 lelrgraph and Telephone 18.72 Office Supplies and Expense 69v'.t" Total $ 4.745.10 JULY, 1917 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 5.20 Salary of Secretary 133. S3 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Salary of Chemist _ 200.00 Expense of Chemist _ 47.05 Salary of Seed Analyst _ (4.25 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper _ 333.32 Salary of Extra Help _ S3. 33 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,477.50 Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,130.49 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors (50.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 449.21 Books and Printing „ 284.(5 Telegraph and Telephone H.I7 Postage _ 200.00 Office Supplies and Expense _ 145.93 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE AI T GU8T, 1»17 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner ? 208.33 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Expense of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 8.80 Salary ot Chemist M4.SS Expense of Chemist 7.00 Salary of Clerks and Stenographers 333. S- .-alary of Kxtra Help 83.33 Salary of Food, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,514. IK i:\pense of Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,481.15 S; lary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 765.00 K\pense of Weights and Measures inspectors 58ft. 12 Salary of Secretary 133 3? Offire Supplies and Expense 218.20 Books and Printing 146.25 Telephone and Telegraph 23.00 laboratory Expense 291. 9* Total $ 7.126.81 SEPTEMBER, 1917 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner _ % 20S.33 Kxpense of Deputy Commissioner 7.25 Salary of Secretary 106.67 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125. OH Salary of State Chemist 200.00 Salary of Assistant State Chemist 97.22 Kxpense of Stati Chemist 7.2 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.34 Salary of Extra Help 83.33 Salary of Seed Analyst 135.00 Kxpense of Seed Analyst 7.50 Salary of Food. Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,542.00 L'xpense ol Food, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,550.45 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 820.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 6-68.32 Hooks and Printing 805.20 Telegraph and Telephone 39.02 Office Supplies and Expenses _ 134.75 laboratory Expense 826.70 Total _ $ 8,687.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">FOOD. DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 47 OCTOBER, 1017 Expense Salaiy of Deputy Commissioner S 208. 34 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 153.82 s'alary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Salary of Secretary 90.32 Salary of State Chemist 200. 0«&gt; Expense of State Chemist 23.10 Salary of Assistant State Chemist 83.34 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.34 Salary of Extra Help 83.34 Salary of Extra Help 13. 8» Salary of Seed Analyst 130. 'Hi Expense of Seed Analyst 4.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,348.00 Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,405.81 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors (20.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 485.73 Office Supplies and Expenses 704.42 Furniture and Repairs 294.18 Hooks and Printing 54.50 Telegraph and Telephone 17.07 Hostage 200 00 Laboratory Expense 25C.95 Total $ 7,8:t NOVEMBER, 1017 Kxpense Salary of Drputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Expense of Deputy Commissioner •. 2.00 Salary of Secretary 133.33 Salai y of Chemist 20&lt;V.).i Kxpense of Chemist 16.47 Salary of Assistant Chemist 100.00 Salary of Asst. Hotel Commissioner 125. n '&gt; Expense of Asst. Hotel Commissioner 31.41 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.32 Salary of Extra Help 83.33 Salary of Seed Anay st 135.00 Exppns-e of Seed Analyst I I Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,39S.«&gt; Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspector 1,684.8'. Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 635, On Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 392.42 Books and Printing 438.90 Office Supplies and Expenses 22.79 Telephone and Telegraph 20.05 Laboratory Expense &gt;7.TS Total t 7.075.98 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE DECEMBER, 1917 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner f 208.34 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 3-85 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Expense of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 7.30 Salary of Secretary 133.34 Salary of Chemist 200.00 Expense of Chemist 129.93 Salary of Assistant Chemist _ 100.00 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.36 Salary of Seed Analyst 125.00 Expense of Seed Analyst 9.25 Salary of Pood, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,499.50 Expense of Food, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,545.09 Telephone and Telegraph 29.16 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 565.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 411.08 Books and Printing 769.55 Office Supplies and Expense 61.52 Furniture and Repairs 62.30 Laboratory Expense 542.90 Miscellaneous 7.28 Total _ $ 7,868.75 JANUARY, 1918 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner _ S 208.33 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Salary of Secretary 133.33 Salary of Chemist 200.00 Expense of Chemist 29.50 Salary of Assistant Chemist 100.00 Expense of Assistant Chemist 2.88 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 319.87 Salary of Seed Analyst 130.00 Expense of Seed Analyst _ 3.60 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,396.50 Expense of Food, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,487.13 Salary of Weights and Measures Ispectors 670.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 497.22 Books and Printing 103.38 Telegraph and Telephone 27.19 Postage _ 200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 49 Office Supplies and Expense MM Miscellaneous 23.00 Laboratory Expense 51.14 Total | 6,730.3 1 FEBRUARY, 1918 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208 33 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 21.35 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Expense of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 20.54 Salary of Secretary 133.33 Salary of Chemist 200.00 Expense of Chemist 11.62 Salary of Assistant Chemist 100.00 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.32 Salary of Extra Help 71.42 Salary of Seed Analyst „ _ 140.00 Expense of Seed Analyst 13.93 Solary of Pood, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,614.50 Expense of Pood, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,625.74 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 725.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 484.73 Books and Printing 61.10 Telegraph and Telephone 19.85 Office Supplies and Expense 37.07 Total _ $ 6,946.83 MARCH, 1018 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.34 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 25.01 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Expense of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 13.80 Salary of Secretary 133.34 Salary of Chemist 200.00 Expense of Chemist •. 13.93 Salary of Assistant Chemist _ 100.00 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.36 Salary of Extra Help 83.34 Salary of Seed Analyst 120.00 Expense of Seed Analyst „ 8.10 Salary of Pood, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2.188.50 Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1.3»7.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 555.0 Kxpense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 384.01 Books and Printing 276.28 Telegraph and Telephone 19.40 Hostage 200.00 Office Supplies and Expense 128.7" Furniture and Repairs 8.64 Miscellaneous 37.48 Laboratory Kxpense 21.12 Total $ 6,581.62 VI'KIL. 1918 Kxi»eiiH« Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ MS. Expense of Deputy Commissioner 4:1.68 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.110 Expense of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner. Salary of Secretary 133.33 Salary of Chemist 200.00 Exiimse of Chemist 16.05 Salary of Assistant Chemist 108.33 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper IZ Salaiy of Extra Help 70.00 Salary of Seed Analyst 130.00 1- MM-nse of Seed Analyst 17.74 Salai% of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,476.00 rxp.'iise of Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,702.62 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 760.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 629. S4 Books and Printing 623.85 Telegraph and Telephone 19.52 Hostage s 200.0" entire Supplies and Expense 12.5 Miscellaneous 1 3.9S Laboratory Expense 12.7-1 Total $ 7.849.25 MAY, 1B18 Ex|ienae Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Kxpense of Deputy Commissioner 20.95 Salary of Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Expense of Deputy Hotel Commissioner 10.3fi Salary of Secretary 133.33 Expense of Secretary 8.61 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">FOOD, DRUG. DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION 51 Salary of Chemist 200.0" Expense of Chemist 21. 7» Salary of Assistant Chemist 108. S3 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.31 Salary of Extra Help 76.00 Salary of Seed Analyst 130.00 Expense of Seed Analyst 23.70 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,739. 50 Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,777. «7 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors. (10.00 Expens eof Weights and Measures Inspectors 506.77 Rooks and Printing 17S.S0 Telegraph and Telephone _ 18. OS Olfice Supplies and Expense 38.7* Miscellaneous 4.55 Laboratory :,« 6J Total % 7,226.16 JINK, 1918 Kx|*"nse Salary of Deputy Commissioner .:..% 208.33 Kxiiense of Deputy Commissioner 25.03 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Expense of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 9.43 Salary of Secretary &lt; 133.34 Salary of Chemist 200.00 Expense of Chemist 27.8."&gt; Salary of Assistant Chemist 108.34 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 316.69 Salary of Extra Help 83.33 Salary of Seed Analyst 135.00 Kxpense of Seed Analyst :!7 .22 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,7(9.00 Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,828.52 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 560.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 553.69 Books and Printing T l&lt;6 s\ Telegraph and Telephone 23.55 Postage 300.00 Office Supplies and Expense „ 20.15 Furniture 80.03 Miscellaneous 104.96 Laboratory 8.72 Total $ 7,704.99 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 BIENNIAL REPORT OP THE JULY, 1018 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner _ $ 208.33 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 16.00 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Salary of Secretary 133.33 Expense of Secretary 8 - 45 Salary of Chemist ~ 200.00 Expense of Chemist 15.40 Salary of Assistant Chemiet 116.66 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.32 Salary of Extra Help 166.66 Salary of Seed Analyst 125.00 Expense of Seed Analyst *-75 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,470.00 Ese of Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspector* 1,838.6s of Weights and Measures Inspectors 495.00 se of Weights and Measures Inspectors 510.64 1,838.6s Books and Printing - 206.50 Telegraph and Telephone . 29.26 PogUge 300.00 Office Supplies and Expense 27.95 Furniture and Repairs 48.00 Miscellaneous 6 - 76 Laboratory - 161.59 ToUl » 7,544.28 AUGUST, 1918 Kxpcnse Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 26.20 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Expense of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 17.34 Salary of Secretary 133.33 Salary of Chemist 200.00 Expense of Chemist \12.2Z Salary of Assistant Chemist 116.66 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper _ 333. S2 Salary of Extra Help 204.29 Salary of Seed Analyst 135.00 Expense of Seed Analyst 19.80 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,572.50 Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspector 1,936.90 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 600.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 643.34 Book» and Printing - 208.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">FOOD. DRUG. DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION 53 Telegraph and Telephone 18. CO Office Supplies and Expense 95.15 Miscellaneous .... , ,.. 7.07 Laboratory _ ~ 41.CS Total $ 7.814.91 SEPTEMBER, 1918 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.34 Expense of Deputy Commissioner 75.72 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 126.00 Salary of Secretary 133.34 Kxpense of Secretary 18.17 Salary of Chemist 200. on Expense of Chemist 8.79 Salary of Assistant Chemist 11«.«6 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.36 Salary of Extra Help _ 125.00 Salary of Seed Analyst 135.00 Expense of Seed Analyst MM Salary of Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,842.00 Expense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,944.43 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors C15.00 Kxpense of Weights and Measures Inspectors _ (21.66 Books and Printing 545.37 Telegraph and Telephone 31.40 Postage 200.00 Office Supplies and Expense MM Laboratory 47.84 Total $ 8,422.48 OCTOBER, 1918 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Kxpense of Deputy Commissioner 34.2.1 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Kxpense of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 53.51 Salary of Secretary 133.33 Expense of Secretary 23.89 Salary of Chemist _ 200.00 Expense of Chemist 10.58 Salary of Assistant Chemist 134.99 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.32 Salary of Extra Help 115.59 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Kxpense of Alice Ollls ' 17.51 Ex|*-nse of Clara Mlskell 17.41 Salary of Seed Analyst 130.00 Kxpense of Seed Analyst 66.00 Siiluiy of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors. 2,603.50 K:.pense of Food, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,128.64 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 495.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 482.94 Books and Printing 243.75 Telegraph and Telephone 16.60 Office Supplies and Expense 139.30 Furniture and Repairs 4.80 Miscellaneous 5.55 Laboratory „ 61.06 Total $ 7,774.85 NOVEMBER, 1918 Expense Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Hxpense of Deputy Commissioner 45.83 Salary of Secretary 133.33 Kxpense of Secretary 39.49 Salary of Chemist 200.00 Kxpense of Chemist 7.70 Salary of Assistant Chemist 133.33 Salary of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 125.00 Expense of Asst. Deputy Hotel Commissioner 22.71 Salary of Clerks and Bookkeeper 333.32 Salary of Extra Help 83.33 Salary of Seed Analyst 135.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,718.00 Kxpense of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,065.60 Salary of Weights and Measures Inspectors 615.00 Expense of Weights and Measures Inspectors 703.68 Books and Printing 666.00 Telegraph and Telephone 3.61 Ofnre Supplies, Expenses, etc 129.75 Miscellaneous 16.68 Laboratory 85.22 Total „ $ 8,470.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION 55 KKCKIITS December, 1916, C. K. Harmon, Commissioner $ 9,274.71 January. I'M 7. Otto Murschel, Conimissioner- Kroni C, K. Harmon l.ou From collections 15.03J.S8 February. 1917. Collections . 9,*33.*0 March, 1917. Collections 13,904.11 April. 19 17. Collections V I 'i ; &gt; I May, 1917. Collections 9.17U.4 1 ,iuiic. 1!H7. Collections 9.170.62 July. I '.'I 7. Collections 21.6 AagtUt, I'.'IT. Collections 12.^ September. 1M7. Collet tion.s October. 1917. Collections 14,530.* .\o\ ember, 1»17. Colleetions bt&gt;i ember, lit I 7. Collections 8.0IO jiinuary. IHIn, Collections 1 •■;; February, 1918. Collections .. 7.5" March. 1918. Collections 8.. April, It IS, Collections 1S.21S.4I May. 19 is. Collections 14.".:'9.i June. 1918, Collections 10 .:;:_■ IS July. 1918. Collections .■".'.i'u j 1 August, 1918, Collections 14.^1". 9.' September, 191S, Collections 13.531.98 October, 1918. Collleitions 15.981.0: November. 1918. Collections 9,176.^1 Total $298. « </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE RECEIPTS i:KCEIIT8 BY KOIHCKS. C K. HAKMON, DKPl'TY OOMMlSSIOXKIt December, 1916 Tester and Samplers $ 98.00 Imitation Butter 448.28 Creameries 5.84 Taps and Stickers 295.00 Live Stock Remedies 5.00 Copy of Oil Reports 10.00 Oil Inspection Fee« 7,819.35 Weights and Measures 406.95 Miscellaneous 186.29 $ 9,274.71 UKCKIITS BY SOURCES, OTTO MIRSCHK1., HKI'lTY COMMISSIONER January, 1B17, to November 30, 1918 ( . E. Harmon. Deputy Commissioner % 1,000.00 Testers and Samplers 9,032.00 Imitation Butter Permits 12,669.18 Wholesale Imitation Butter Permits 1,127.14 Commission Merchants License 120.00 Cold Storage Permits 100.00 Tags and Stickers 9.344.4 1 Live Stock Remedies 375.00 Sted Tests 46.00 Miscellaneous 597.45 Copy of Oil Reports 240.00 Weights and Measures 15,632.47 Oil Inspection Fees 220,590.7.1 Retail Ice Cream 173.00 Wholesale Ice Cream 672.56 Bottlers 646.90 Creameries 3,134.38 Hotel 12,737.00 Cold Storage Inspections '. 1,120.00 Feed Tests 1.00 $298,633 9". </seg>
            <seg id="p057">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 57 DISBURSEMENTS December, 1918, C. B. Harmon, Commissioner S 9,274.71 January, 1917. Otto Murschel, Commissioner — Salary and Expense 1,319.22 February, 1917, H. C. Lindsay, Clerk Supreme Court 7,421. 53 Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 123671.... 100.00 Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 123672 ... 100.00 Salary and Expense C, 5(5. 51 March, 1917, Salary and Expense 7,081.54 Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 124844.... 10.00 Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 124845... 5.51 H. C. Lindsay, Clerk Supreme Court 2.611.20 April. 1917, Salary and Expense 3,727 H. C. Lindsay, Clerk Supreme Court 7,870.18 Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 126943.... 1,568.83 May, 1917, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 127545. ... S, 753. 95 Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 127623... 10.00 H. C. Lindsay, Clerk Supreme Court 429.40 June, 1917, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 128474.... 5,229.70 July, 1917, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 129455. ... 8,533 68 August, 1917. Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 130376 ... 20,467.66 September, 1917. Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 131269. ... 12.518.01 October, 1917, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 132130.... 12,855.48 November, 1917, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 133087... 13,043.59 December, 1917, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 134048.. 13,781.11 January, 1918, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 134788... 9,758.47 February, 1918, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 135852... 8.400.96 March, 1918. Geo. Hall. State Treasurer, No. 136838. ... 9.856.0.' April. 1918, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 137816... 7,519.83 May, 1918, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 138806... 8,978.41 June. 1918, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 139845... 12,759.58 July. 1918, Geo. Hall. State Treasurer, No. 140595... 13,099.67 August, 1918, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 141371. ... 24,(71.11 September, 1918, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer. No. 142180... 13.476.57 October, 1918, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, No. 143003.... 14,112.89 November, 1918, Geo. Hall, State Treasurer 14.9SS.62 December, 1918, On hand and bank 19,756.60 ToUl 1298,633 95 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE KKtAPITlLATlOX December 1, 1916, to November 30, 1918, Inclusive Commissioner $ 1,000.00 Kt-ceived from C. E. Harmon. Deputy Amount of Fees Collected .' 297,633.95 $298,633.95 Paid out on Vouchers assigned to Deputy Commissioner * 18,693.50 Paid to H. C. Lindsay, Clerk Sup. Ct 18,332.31 Paid to Geo. Hall, State Treasurer 232,577.83 Disbursed by C. E. Harmon 9,274.71 $278,878.3:. $278,878.35 Balance on hand and in bank. December 1, 1918 $ 19,735.60 Received from C. E. Harmon. $ 1.000.00 Received lees from January 1 1917 to November 30, 1918 297,633.95 $298, 63?,. 95 Expense. December. 1916, C. E. Harmon I 7,642.75 Expense. January. 1917, to November 30, 1918 160, 897.4T. $168,540.20 Paid to H. C. Lindsay, Clerk Sup. Ct 18,332.31 Paid to Geo. Hall, State Treasurer, prior to April 1, 1917 225.51 Disbursed by C. E. Harmon 1.631.96 Cash on hand November 30, 1918 19,766.60 $208,486.58 $208,485.58 Balance in State Treasury, December 1, 1918 $ 90,148.37 Balance on hand and in bank, December 1, 1918 19, 755.60 Total $109,903.97 </seg>
	        </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>