<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00022</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  HOW TO COMBAT THE MELON APHIS</title>
               <date value="1911">1911</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Agricultural Experiment Station LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. V. S. A. PRESS BULLETIN No. 34 '■iited June 96, 1911) HOW TO COMBAT THE MELON APHIS BY M H. SWENK The Melon Aphis: ". winged female aphis of usual color; 6, newly young aphis; r, adult wingless female aphis; d, last stage of nymph nged female aphis; r, dark colored winged female aphis sucking juice rhe surface of the leaf; f, melon leaves showing aphids clustered on r surface and the characteristic curling caused by them. All greatly pi f which is reduced. (Rearranged after Chittenden, Circular u of Entomology, U. S. Department of Agriculture.) </seg>
            <seg id="p002">HOW TO COMBAT THE MELON APHIS THK XI i HIS ( ipkU &lt;i&lt;i**ni)ii Glover) Without quei MM generally injurious insect pest of the cucumber and m&lt; least in Nebraska and the surrounding states, is n winch attacks and destroys these vines. Kor mam has greiii p of melons and pickles la the 1 i'es where ih- tiles are much gn.v braska Kansas, Oklahoma, and Texas, but east cf the ginia. Maryland. Delaware, and " the West Indies Mexico it is an insect of tropical or:. INJURY.- The melon aphis, like all nds or plant the juice of the plants by n ik and by thus dramir l leaves of their sap The aphids collect on the ui face of the leaves of the affected plant, and I • f their pi pow -ase soon have an enormous number of Ind sap and tl They sei forms a thin on the ut Ihere. an.: selves, give a char ippea ranee to the Imi leaves. In cases • -id under normal ■ infestation at all i plant is simu 1 dies down V imbers are mi melons, and their foliage Is also n are the melon leaves. In addition to the cucumi squashes, pumpkins, and goun aphis feeds upoi ; common garden veeet a number of ornamental plants such as* and a Ion? Beds. Th&lt; weed, . ragweed, burdock P common ones I especially those first mentioi LIFE HISTORY- The in all its yet quite email and just 1&gt; southern Nebraska, tl&gt; they probably fly in from weeds they have spent the winter. Cool, ra r*pid multiplication of these ap! plants, the aphids reproduce very rapidly, ■ six to a dozen young per day In about eight birth th&lt; adult and is itself is a small, soft-bodied, sluggish p one-twelfth of an inch h fifth to one-fourth of an inch. The </seg>
            <seg id="p003">i goes on thruout the summer and early and from time to time winged individuals are produced, these being st in the latter part of the summer. The uphills continue abundant it umber and melon plants until the vines have been killed by I in early September they begin dispersing, probably to Wf are not sure just where they go or how they pass the I arently they hibernate mere or less act: ■I in Colorado they have been followed upon out - • rd's purse, thru the winter for two seasons and :thout finding either males, egg-laying females, or eggs likely that the species ordinarily has no sexual forms or n some localities. I he melon aphis has a large number of natural ene: iding principally internal hymenopterous parasites and predaceous lad&gt; ■ n(i larvae, syrphus fly larvae and lacewinged fly larvae. These m food supply when the aphis increases in numbers, and some - least a partial control of the aphids and save a part of the them all the ladybird beetles and their larvae are probably the liable and effective, while the small hymenopterous parasites are -■ly valuable and sometimes rapidly reduce an abundance of • ids until they are practically exterminated in that particular infes- ii artificial control of this insect there is no avoiding the fact thai »e have here a pest hard to deal with and one which requires a great deal . • • .iid careful work to master. Methods of treatment include both - Hid fumigation, but spraying seems to be the most practical and i method, at least in our experience. It is important that the tie done at the first indication of an abundance of wingless n the vines, before the insects have had time to cause any no wilting or curling up cf the leaves. In order to do this the vines must ver frequently and the lower side of the leaves examined thoroly mist lie rt-peated whenever it is noted that the aphids are re - nts. In spraying, the application of the wash should rsprayer, or. if the vines are still small, by very care - lift ins them back and spraying the under surface of the leaves and • g them in their original position. Badly curled leaves should hand and the under surface drenched with the wash. As an ,i piece of gas pipe with one end bent at the proper angle or .m albov attachment and a Vermorel nozzle attached to will be fcund quite satisfactory, and a bucket pump operated by two one to wi imp and one to direct the spray, will be found advan - wash. Care should be taken not to apply with too M be injured. In selecting a wash, avoid kerosene emulsion or other strong oi'v ac have found that in order to kill these hardy and re*: n or oil must be used so strong that the exceed: ;ire invariably badly burned, thereby either killing or ereatly injuring it. We have found the commercial diluted one part to fifty parts of water to form against this aphis, destroying all with which it to i"-«&gt;pare and apply. Very satisfai - ilso be obtained by using a soap-and-tobacco wash and one half pounds of soap in one-half gallon cf </seg>
            <seg id="p004">1 rheapei usually done with earboa bsulphid One ver&gt; easy way s, fit th&lt; and • • r them, .. sbcut a tfa*pc«nfi-l to • t of space w.ihin el. 1^ of space w.lhin '..■ Th I this t ■ ; plants to hit-eninie . All weed^ food and ,hu. p. I .• </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>