<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FIFTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska State Industrial School For Boys, KEARNEY, NEBRASKA, 1910</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">OF THE Nebraska State Industrial School For Boys KEARNEY. NEBRASKA 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">SUPERINTENDENT'S BIENNIAL REPORT Fo His Excellency, Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor, and The lieve that we have done all that we could under the condil that existed when we took charge of the work. The population during the first year of the biennium was on the decrease. From 137 boys, the number turned over to us the population decreased until November, 1909, our number was reduced to 78. Under these conditions the expenses per capita for the first year were excessively large but since that time new boys have been committed, paroled boys have been returned until it this date we have an attendance of 139. This not onl\ ables us to keep up the routine work of the institution hut enables us to give the boys better school advantages. Bei maintenance per capita shows a material inc ing the last year of the biennium. ecu nearly a failure and we have barely \ ed from our crops the rental cost of the land. This has added to our expense without any compensating returns, but in spite of these adverse conditions, by careful management we will the biennium with only a small deficit charged up aprainst our maintenance fund. Could we have had good crops there would have been a surplus in every fund. We pre- sent elsewhere a table which shows the amount of ground tilled and the amount of crops produced. In this connection we want to call your attention to land rents. For several years an increased charge has been made for table land near the institution until a price of $7.50 per acre demanded. This we deemed so high that we refused to the land. The owner then rented the same land to a private Durinjr the biennium droughi conditions ha\ liled Honorable Board of Public Lands and Building Gentlemen: — In submitting to you the fifteenth biennial re- of the Nebraska State [ndnatrial School for Boys. svith sonic degree of satisfaction. Not because the result- alished have been all that we have desired, but because w« </seg>
            <seg id="p004">154 I^ANI) COMMISSIONER'S REPORT individual at $5 per acre, which shows a determination on the part of the owner* of land to hold the state up, as it were. for nil they eould get. We notice that in a number of the bi - ennial reports superintendents have recommended the pun of land, and we wish to renew the recommendation. We have already paid out for land rents an amount sufficient to have pur - '1 more land than we need but still the st;ite does not own a foot more of ground than it dfd when the school was • lished. Good business policy would surest tliiit land be pur - chased instead of rented. We would raggesi that an a] priation sufiicient to purchase not less than a half-section, and more would be better, be made by the coming legislature so that the needs of the school will be provided for. This land should be purchased below the ditch so that we could have the benefit of irrigation. During the past biennium we have had to go two miles or better in order to get land at a reasonable rental. We have no pasture land to speak of and have been compelled to rent land in order to have pasture for our stock. There is a tract lying immediately west of the school land which should be purchased for this purpose. You will notice that our Permanent and General Repair fund has already been exhausted. For the biennium of 1907-1909 $8,000 was appropriated for this fund, but for this biennium only $5,000 was appropriated. In this connection we wish to call your attention to the report of Mr. P. A. Barrows, who made the inventory of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings prep - aratory to turning the institution over to us. A careful perusal of this report will give you a clear idea of the condition of the property when we took control. Notwithstanding this unfavor - able report the legislature cut down the general appropriation more than $17,000. Because of these reductions we have been compelled to adopt the strictest rules of economy in order to keep within our means. It will therefore be necessary for the in - coming legislature to make more liberal appropriations so that the needs of the school may be met. The institution needs an appropriation of not less than $15,000 for repairs. This would enable us to thoroughly overhaul the shop building which con - tains rooms for the different trades departments, appartments for the employes, dining room for the boys, and the general </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 156 Iery for the institution. The building needs a thorough reno - on from basement to garret. The work on the tunnels which never been completed should !&gt;&lt;■ pushed to completion. J; t be repaired. Steel ceilings are needed in many of the dings. New floors must be laid and general repairs of all Is must be made. Heretofore only such repairs as it was erative to make have received attention, so that at this time ill be ncessary to do more work on the buildings than has l done for a number of years. One of the urgent needs of the institution is a hospital building and we would suggest that an appropriation of $4,000 be made for this purpose. Several times during the last few years epidemic diseases have made their appearance and have become not only a menace to the inmates and employes of the school but there has been the additional danger of carrying the disease to the nearby city. We have been compelled to close one of the grade buildings and use it for hospital purposes. This interferes with our school work. We therefore hope that an appropriation can be made for this much needed improvement. In the trades departments much new equipment is required. Additional machinery should be purchased for the shoe ihop. More supplies are needed in the printing shop. New machines and equipment for the tailor shop should be purchased and the manual training department should be enlarged and equipped. The equipment in the laundry is old and obsolete and while we have been able to make it do this biennium still it should be thoroughly overhauled and new machinery installed. tit will be remembered that in November, 1908, the barn, ther with all of the horses, was destroyed by fire. An •opriation of $5,001) was made for the barn and a like appro - tion was made for horses and equipment. We now have a splendid brick structure 32x90 feet in size, nicely equij and we did not use all of the appropriation. Diligent care was used in purchasing horses and we have twenty-three head of good, young, sound horses that are a credit to the state. This appropriation will be entirely exhausted by the end of the bien - nium, but we are now well equipped in this department. For years the water supply has been a serious problem. The pumping plant has been moved several times and wells have </seg>
            <seg id="p007">\~-i~tiint Sii|&gt;«rinteiideiit I). W. Miller </seg>
            <seg id="p008">158 been driven in many placet without satisfactory results. Prior to the time that we took charge of the institution unsuccessful efforts were made to increase the water supply. Finally two five - inch wells were driven and for a time it was thought the problem was solved but as Tin- dry weather continued the water level went lower and the pumps had to lie lowered in the pit. About the time the institution was turned over to us the water began to raise and the pumps had to be again placed upon the original level. Later on the supply again diminished and after consulting with experienced well men we decided to drive two additional 5-incfa wells from thirty to fifty feet from the original wells. This has been done and we believe we now have an inexhaustable supply of good water. Where, heretofore, it took from seven to ten hours steady pumping in order to fill the standpipe the same results can be obtained in half the time. This has materially reduced the consumption of coal. (By carefully overhauling our heating and steam cooking pment. stopping the leaks and waste of water, we have been to reduce the amount expended for coal about $2,000, not - standing the fact that our coal has cost us from 35 to 75 s a ton more than in the preceding biennium. B During the biennium we have received 156 boys by commit - ;, 55 have been returned from parole and there was 148 boys tendance at the close of the former biennium. This makes al of 359 boys to be accounted for during this biennium. I We have paroled 192 boys. One was released because he reached the age limit of 21 and twenty-seven have escaped have not been captured. This leaves us an attendance of boys at this time. We are deeply gratified to note that the attitude of the Juvenile Judges and officers of the Juvenile Court has changed in favor of the school. The first year we were here only 64 were committed to us. The last year we received 92. We believe that we have had a good deal to do with this change of sentiment in favor of the school. We have given the boys close personal attention and have insisted that all officers and em - ployes be just and fair and work with us for the upbuilding of character. The boys have been better fed, better clothed, and their moral condition has steadily improved. Out of the 192 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The 1) &lt;.r;nlr &lt; &lt;&gt;tt;iirt&gt; The E Grade Cottage </seg>
            <seg id="p010">160 Kthat we have paroled but 55 have broken their parole and returned to the school. Most of these boys were paroled by er superintendents. This is an exceptionally good record. We have adopted the policy of segregating the smaller boys from the larger and older ones thus avoiding the evil influence of the boy who has learned too much of the worst side of the world. The establishment of a band and the adoption of mili - tary drill under a competent and enthusiastic instructor has added new life and new incentive to the wurk of the boy*. We are keeping in close touch with our paroled boj letters and by reports received from juvenile officers and friends and other officers who report on the boys in their locality. Many of the boys have completed their trades and have taken their places in the world as wage earners. With the improvements that we have in mind in our trades departments for the coming biennium we believe that we will be able to do much more effective work along this line than has been done in the past. are insisting that a boy complete his trade at least to that point where he can earn reasonable wages in his chosen occu - pation before he is released. Boys have left our printing office, our bakery, our laundry, our machine shop, and tailor shop who are making good. I We believe that the energies of the school should be directed to the upbuilding of character, second to educating the along the lines most necessary for a business or mechanical »r, and third for the teaching of a trade or profession that enable the young man to become self-supporting. The boy leaves the school with no knowledge of a trade or occupa - must find employment in the common walks of life. Here leets with his old associates and sooner or later, no matter good his resolutions may be, he falls and is returned for her term. In our school work we have not been following the regular course of study but rather have been giving to the boys such subjects as we deem the most essential. It must be borne in mind that most of the boys whom we get are boys who have not attended school. In fact, two-thirds of our commitments are for delinquency. The boy of twelve or fourteen who has only reached the fourth or fifth grade in the common school, because of non-attendance, does not feel at home with children of those </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">162 Ies and is forced out of school work because he does not want e in school with the smaller children. We therefore exert energies along lines most needed for experience has taught hat when a boy is paroled from this school, in most cases, ichool days are over. We believe that the parole system now in vogue should be modified and that every boy should remain here until he has acconplished given results or has reached his majority. We found, when we took hold of the work, that the objective point : controlling every boy. was tin- cancellation of his demerits in order that he might be released. Within the last few months a number of boys have come to the office with the request that they be permitted to stay with us six months or a year and in some cases even longer in order that they might complete the work that they had undertaken. This change of sentiment on the part of the boys is indeed gratifying and with the co-opera - tion of parents, friends, and juvenile officers our sphere of use - fulness will be greatly enlarged. We believe that the school is entering upon a wider and broader career of usefulness than it has ever attained and in order that it may fulfill its mission it should have the hearty support of the legislature and close supervision by the Hoard oi' Public Lands and Ruildings. We therefore submit to you for your consideration the foregoing recommendations and suggestions Very truly yours. C. B. MANTEL. Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">One of Our Winter Sport* Ihe A Knide &lt; otlaire </seg>
            <seg id="p014">P. A. BARROWS' REPORT 1 o the xionorsnlc oo&amp;rd ox if UDiic xjRdqs jiiki ]&gt;iiii&lt;iin^s i I Gentlemen : — Pursuant to your instructions, on January 909. I went to Kearney to invoice the Boys' Industrial School aat place. I was assisted in the work by Mr. Fairchild, the - ;oing steward, and Mr. Austin, the new steward, assisted by superintendents of the different departments. In this work xsonally inspected every article found in the invoice given ou and its true condition is given as near as possible. Every •tesy was shown me by all of the officers and employes con - ed with the institution and I believe the work is as thoroughly ; as it could have been. Administration Building. The Administration Building is in very bad shape, especially the windows and doors, and it is necessary in moderate weather to keep up considerable steam in order to keep the building warm. The windows and doors are loose and the casing shrunken to such an extent that the wind comes through them very much. During the storm of January 28th the suction of the wind through the building was so strong that two of the windows in the Library were forced out. To give you some idea of the amount of the wind that passed through the building I would say that during the time that the carpenter and his assistants were nailing up the windows I was compelled to hold the door between the Library and the Main Hall with all my strength, at times being forced away by the strength of the wind that passed through the building and out of the broken windows. The front porch is also in very had condition and the steps should be repaired or replaced by new ones in a very short time. Industrial Building. I The Industrial Building is nearly in the same condition as Administration Building regarding the windows and doors, a great deal of repairs should be put upon this building, :h are needed greatlv. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The B Grade Cottage </seg>
            <seg id="p016">166 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT &lt; &gt;n account of the poor condition of the rooms in this build - ing the management is compelled to place some of the employes in the guest rooms at the tliffrent eottagea, thereby crowding these eottagea out of the accommodations they really need. These rooma at the Industrial Building should be thoroughly over - hauled so that the employes could all be accommodated in the same building. Cottages. tTlie cottages, at least one or two of them, are certainly in 1 of repairs at the present time, the plastering being off in e places and ■ general cleaning up should be given them in way of new woodwork, especial attention being given to the •s and roofs. Furniture. tThe furniture throughout the whole school is in very | r ition, a great deal of it being unfit for use, probably of it is in such shape that it is worthless, and is being used after being tied or nailed up in order that it may not fall eces. Beds and Bedding I Very little of the beds and bedding of the institution is in t could be called good condition. The iron beds in use in boys" cottages are in very bad shape. The springs which a part of the iron beds have become worn out to such an nt that those sleeping upon them are obliged to lay to • extent in the shape of a letter "V. " The mattresses are ist entirely worn out and have been patched and mended [ they will last but very little longer. Machinery. I As the board is aware some time ago the horse barn was led. and it became necessary to fix up some building which d be used for the purpose of sheltering the horv Mary the use of the institution. The implement sheds were fixed for this purpose, and by reason of that the machinery has 1 paeed in different buildings and some of it is unsheltered. In the attics of the different buildings and especially the Industrial l&gt;uildin &lt;r can be found a lar^e accumulation of worn- </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">168 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT out clothing, old bed steads, furniture and other truck, the accumulation of years, that should be destroyed. I would sug - fMt that the authority be given to the new superintendent to make a thorough cleaning of all of this waste material, so that the buildings may not be endangered from fire. It seems that the accumulations above mentioned have been stored by former superintendents because of the lack of authority to dispose of such accumulations. tin the industrial building and especially in the basement are pge number of old el nd dark rooms which should be &gt;ved by cutting out unnecessary petitions, throwing these rent apartments into fewer and larger rooms. The&gt; particularly objectionable on account of the filth that cumulates in them, and the danger of the boys secreting them es in order to make their escape. ctfully submitted, </seg>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENTS Printing I Printing — "the art preservative'" — is one of the departments rein a boy is equipped with a trade the market for which is r overstocked. Our shop is only fairly equipped with ma - pry and material. The work turned out will compare fav - ly with the ordinary printshop outside of the city of year we entered into competitive bids for some of the I printing and all the work turned out met with the approval lie offices for whom the work was done. The shop should quipped with up-to-date machinery and we eonld then do a i share of the ordinary printing for the state. Tailoring. In this department we manufacture all of our clothing, shirts underwear, uniforms, and all sewing necessary for the in stitution is done here. We also make the citizens suits for th« boys when ready for parole. New machines and some other equipment is much n as everything in this department has seen years of •erviee. A number of boys who have learned their trade here are on the road to a successful business career. Shoe Making §A good shoe making and repairing department is an absolute ssity in an institution of this kind. For an active, energetic is hard on shoe leather. I This department should be fitted up with the latest impr linery for manufacturing and repairing shoes. If this was we could easily make all the shoes for the many institutions ate. furnishing a better shoe and at a less cost. Could department be enlarged it would open up for the boj r field of usefulness and they could, when they leave bere, ready employment in the cities from which so many ot </seg>
            <seg id="p021">1 i ■- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">172 Bakery and Kitchens. P teach tin- art of supplying the needs of the innei i this department has gone out many hoys win Kid salaries and need never lie oui of work. The ■ entire institution is done in this department and are food enough for anyone. Early in the biennium we were compelled to put in a new ovell and We selected olle of the "' Robert s " portable style. This oven is in more common use than the old brick structure, and with its modern equipment a boy is able to go into an up-to-date shop and know just what to do. Laundry. t Cleanliness is in xt to Godliness, and so we have a laundry rhich the boys are taaffBt modern laundry work. Here more » a thousand pieces are bandied every week and the boys instruction in handling all kinds of garment! from the finest t waists for ladies to the ordinary overalls and blankets. §\Ve must have this department fitted up with new machinery verythinp in this department has been so long in service it is about ready for the scrap pile. Carpenter Shop. To keep up the repairs about an someone on the job all the time. I'hanic all the time and he has a meet the needs of his department work that is necessary. Here In institution of this size requires We employ a first class me- let.iil of boys large enough to A boy here does the actual s the labor of his hands tiring forth good results. He does not spend his time in tin iiiff of useless articles but he is taught how by doing. We want to see this department enlarged and a thorough course of Manual Training established. This has only been par - tially done. All our industrial departments require new equip - ment hut none more than this. Engineering. Hen- is where actual work is again done. We employ two skilled mechanics and under their direction the departments of heating', lighting, power and plumbing are maintained. Here ajrain boys are taught how by doing. All plumbing, electric </seg>
            <seg id="p023">! &lt; r 2 ■ 1 IT^fl r a J i </seg>
            <seg id="p024">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 174 battery of four eighty horse power boilers give them an ample opportunity to learn how to fire and handle a steam engine. They are taught how to handle a power pump, how to lay water mains, how to tap these mains and lead water into buildings and make the necessary connections with bath tubs, lavatories, and various fixtures. In fact, they are taught to do the practical every-day things that will come to a man who follows either one of these vocations. Green House Because of the conditions that prevailed when we assumed control our green house was neglected but this fall a com - petent florist was placed in charge and the work is progressing nicely. It will be necessary to make extensive repairs qn the green house. The roof will have to be taken off. new ribs put in and the glass will have to be reset. I We d&lt;M-m this as one of the essential departments of the tol. The study of plant life, how they are germinated, and conditions most favorable for their growth. These all ap he developing mind. Besides these, the budding flower and it awakens in the boy a love for the beautiful and this alone potent factor in character building. Farming and Gardening. tin these days when we hear so much and read so much about ck to the Farm" and "Returning to Nature" we will have ipology to make when we advocate the purchasing of more I so that farming may be carried on under the most favorable litions. During the past two years we have paid out $3,010.00 rent of land, and for the past ten years the state has paid land rent an average of $1,500.00 per year. In view of these 8, do you wonder that we urge the necessity of buying land? t There is no more healthful or better occupation than farm - gardening, and the other lines of industry that go to make igrieultural occupation. The boy is taught to do the work issary to a successful career as a farmer for he does all the al work under skilled direction. What more can we do for boy who has a desire to follow this occupation ? Many of our i are placed on farms directly from the school and most of n stick to it, and were it not for the fact that the parents </seg>
            <seg id="p025">STATE INDUSTRIAL. SCHOOL, KEARNEY 175 ( of so many of the boys live in cities, we would be more success - ful in getting the boy into this life. We believe that more good can be accomplished along reformatory lines by getting the boy away from the old environ - ment and where he will make new acquaintances and get in touch with nature than in any other way. We have so much faith in this that we believe that this phase of the work should be broadened and extended. Dairying and Stock Raising I This is only another phase of agriculture, for they are inter - ?ndent. Several years ago an effort was made to cull out poor stock and substitute thoroughbred stock. The Holstein - •sian breed of cattle was selected. This has only been par - y successful. We believe that a more general purpose breed Iattle should have been selected, as we not only need milk - lucing animals but we need beef producers as well. We have some very nice cows and heifers and the herd is on increase. Under the head of stock-raising we want to say a word about the raising of hogs. We have been particularly fortunate during the term we have been in charge. Last year we raised about 200 head and this year we have had over 300 head. There are a number of improvements that could be made which would »tly aid in bringing about greater success. First, our land Id be fenced hog tight ; sec. aid. more alfalfa should be sown, third, new buildings, pens, and sheds should be provided. feel that if we could be properly equipped we could make one of the must profitable departments of the school. Educational. tTo make progress along educational lines with the boy who dropped out of his school work early or who has never gone ehool only when compelled to. or the boy classed as the &gt;rt." is a problem that will tax the energy, the patience the ingenuity of the person engaged in the work. We cover all subjects from second grade including the eighth and in some instances take up ninth grade work. How - ever, in a school of this character it is impossible to follow the regular state course of study and so we endeavor to give the boy the subject matter that he most needs, laying especial </seg>
            <seg id="p026">176 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT stress upon the essentials. A few things well done is of much more value than many things commenced but nothing finished. This is especially true in educational work. I The plan of our work contemplates that each boy is at labor hours per day and four hours in school. In following this progress is slower but we believe more thorough. The i is not all that it should be owing to the fact that the age time that a boy is here is about sixteen months. They dropping in at irregular periods and many times do not a any grade or class. Then owing to our parole system are permitted to drop out in the middle of a term when i is only partially done, thereby not getting the greatest unt of good from their work. »\Ve believe that a new rule should be adopted which will except in special cases, permit a boy's release under a two 3' course and that when the school year begins no boy Id be released until the close of the school year. In this we are sure that much more good can be accomplished. tin connection with the work we are now doing we believe a course of stenography and typewriting should be estab - d, for there are many of the boys who would take to this ; and become successful. This would require some little nse but we believe it would pay. We would need four ve machines and the necessary books, charts and other gs. We could then do this work creditably. Music. IWhen we took hold of the work the band was disorganized, instruments ready for the scrap pile and nothing had been I along this line for more than two years. f\Ve now have a splendidly equipped band of twenty-five &gt;s, and are working out material for an institution orchestra, results have been very gratifying so far and we hope ti department broadened and extended. There is nothing that touches and appeals to the heart or life of a boy as music. It awakens in his breast the dormant quality that too often have been stifled by the rough knocks of the world. We, have been surprised and deeply gratified at the results accomplished and we are looking forward with anticipation that we believe will be fulfilled. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">r : (i I 1 &lt; w I I Library s tairlv library was provided l&gt;ut nt wear and sonic little abuse lias nearly d I this net of the school. We hope to be m )&gt;1 purchases of new hooks this next Farm Produce Grown and Land Rented 1909 Acn Jllsllels 1,400 2,300 2.500 Val 4« i-n .,,1 If •Ilte.l r ar mine, H 'asture. 280 acre I 5 ll.Ml t* I S r Slid Hill 1.440 heat 800 and Rented Farming, Pasture, Coal Consumed. $18,4 15,91 tDeeeml Dee. -ml er 1, 1906, to November 30, 1908 er 1. 1908, to November :i&lt;&gt;. 1910 Different in our favor Itil KM !£ &gt;•) 1910. Acre 4.") 1IMI 50 339 acre J10 acres. $1,430 00 :no oo </seg>
            <seg id="p028">178 What We An appropriation for : Superintendent Assistant Superintendent Steward and bookkeeper Chaplain Physician Total $ 12,000 00 __$ 32,000 00 Officers and employes wages Maintenance 60,000 00 Permanent and general repairs Equipment trades departments Machinery, harness and equipments 20,000 00 5,000 00 3,000 00 Total ....$132,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">PHYSICIAN'S REPORT C. B. Manuel, Superintendent, State Industrial School, Kearney, Nebr Dear Sir:— IFor the past two years, I have been the physician and eon at the State Industrial School, and I submit my report le work done. When I took charge of the work the institution was in anything but a sanitary condition. The sewer pipes opened into every building with no traps to prevent the sewer gas from permeating every building, with the results we soon had an outbreak of diphtheria and before everything could be re - paired and disinfected we had over forty cases of that disease besides many cases of sore throat and tonsilitis. tVVe have had one case of smallpox, one of scarlet fever, one nencing phthisic, one typhoid fever, one gun shot wound, fracture of ferner, one fracture of both bones of the leg, mber of other fractures and dislocations, a good many cases linor surgery, a number of abscesses, sprains and other Ties. The cases of sickness consisted largely of colds, hs, bronchial troubles, bowel diseases and almost any of the that boys are subject to, including venerial diseases, h some of the boys had when admitted to the school. attend to this work I have made 440 i &gt;75 exrmina - ; and prepared medicine in all cases that lequired it. I have no deaths to report, nor was any boy sent home when bad sick to shirk responsibility. I thank you all for your assistance rendered. Very respectfully yours. J. L. BENNETT M. D. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>