<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00025">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Spraying Tree Fruits</title>
               <date value="1928-03">1928-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Circular 36 March, 1928 Spraying Tree Fruits C. C. WIGGANS AND E. H. HOPPERT Department of Horticulture |V* .-•;■•. • ''.S_S Kfl S_eßi|V 4P * *w^^**^k__B Hare£r *' an "^^jwjas HvGH ■ j ■ THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OP AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR. Dirbctor </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS General Considerations 3 Spray Materials 4 Dry vs. liquid applications 4 Arsenate of lead 4 Nicotine sulfate 5 Liquid lime sulfur 5 Dry lime sulfur 5 Bordeaux mixtures ... 6 Dry-mix sulfur lime 6 Oil sprays 6 Spreaders 7 Quantity of material needed 7 Table of Dilutions.. 7 Spraying Equipment 8 Small capacity outfits 8 Barrel outfits .. !) Power outfits 9 Rods vs. spray guns .... ... . 10 Dusters ... .. 10 Spraying Management 10 Timing the sprays 10 Handling observation cages . .11 Thoroness 12 Number of applications 12 Spray Schedules ... . 13 Insect Pests ]G Aphids Ifi Codling moth . 16 Curculio 18 Leaf-eating insects 19 Scale insects . . IS) Borers . 19 Buffalo tree-hopper 20 Orchard Diseases 21 Apple blotch ...... 21 Apple scab 22 Sooty-blotch and fly-speck. . . 24 Blister canker 24 Cedar rust ... 25 Fire blight . 26 Plum pockets .. 26 Brown rot ... . .27 Cherry leaf spot 27 Peach leaf curl 28 Peach scab 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Spraying Tree Fruits C. C. WIGGANS AND E. H. HOPPERT GENERAL CONSIDERATIONS The production of sound, clean, fruit is unquestionably one of the major problems facing the modern fruit grower. Cul - ture may be neglected and pruning delayed for a time but the omission of sprays for even a single season demonstrates their absolute necessity. This applies equally to the commercial grower and to the farmer or gardener who has only a few trees. . Spray materials and methods have been developed because the fruit grower has been compelled either to find a remedy for his troubles or go out of business. Early in the history of the industry, sprays were not considered essential — in fact were almost unknown. However, the introduction of foreign pests and the increased damage from native ones because of the destruction of native host plants, together with the modern demand for high quality fruits, have forced the grower to spray, in order to have healthy plants and a salable product. Spraying is a fairly expensive process but one which will pay big returns if properly done. It is about the only insurance the grower has against complete failure and it is one which he cannot afford to neglect. Spraying must be considered as a protective rather than a curative process. A worm inside the fruit or a disease spore already established will develop normally regardless of the number of sprays applied later. This means then that the protective covering must be applied ahead of infection or emergence and the application must be frequent enough to keep all parts, including new growth, well coated with the protective material. Again, not only must the spray be timely but it also must be adapted to the particular pest or disease and to the fruit being sprayed. For example, Bordeaux mixture and concen - trated lime sulfur are effective as fungicides but cannot be used in peach spraying because of foliage injury. Nicotine sulfate controls plant lice but has no effect on the codling moth. Arsenate of lead will protect fruits against the cur - culio but not against borers. Bordeaux mixture is more de - sirable than lime sulfur against apple blotch, tho either will control scab. And still further, certain diseases such as fire blight and blister canker and also certain insects such as the buffalo tree-hopper are not affected by any spraying treat - ment. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 The proper spraying of the small home orchard often pre - sents quite a problem to the owner because be lacks necessary equipment. Moreover, in the rush of other summer work, the relatively small job of spraying a few fruit trees is likely to be neglected. One solution for this problem is found in the formation of a community spray ring. Under this plan a number of small orchard owners combine in the purchase of a good spray outfit which is then operated in a fashion similar to that followed with a community threshing machine. An - other plan calls for a single owner for the outfit, who then does custom spraying for his neighbors. Either plan is suc - cessful only in case the one doing the spraying uses the right materials at the proper time and does a thoro job. SPRAY MATERIALS Dust vs. liquid applications. — Nearly all spray materials may now be had in either liquid or dust form. Which one • shall the Nebraska orchardist use? Spraying is a disagree - able, tedious job. Dusting is much faster and more con - venient on rough ground and also eliminates spray injury. Net costs are very similar, the higher labor costs of spraying being offset by the use of larger amounts of material in dust - ing. One of the drawbacks to the wider use of dusts is the difficulty of securing good coverage in windy weather. Hence, dusting is frequently done at night. The value of any spray material, however, depends upon its efficacy in controlling the particular pests or diseases for which it is used. Some preliminary experiments at Shubert, Nebraska, conducted in 1927 by the Department of Horticul - ture, indicate that spraying is more effective than dusting in the control of the codling moth. Altho some other experi - ment stations have reported fair success in worm control, yet the satisfactory control of fungous diseases on the apple with dusts has not been secured. On the other hand, dusts are successfully used to control cherry leaf spot in the nursery, to combat peach brown rot, and to destroy plant lice. In view of the variable results already reported, it would seem wise for the Nebraska fruit grower to continue the use of liquid applications, at least until dusting materials and methods are better perfected. However, dusting might prove to be very profitable as a supplement to spraying in very rainy seasons when it is difficult or impossible to apply sprays. Arsenate of lead. — This is the most common and the safest arsenical to use on fruit trees. It is effective against chewing insects only. This material comes in powdered form and is generally used at the rate of iy 2 pounds to 50 gallons </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Spraying Tree Fruits of water. In order to insure uniform suspension it is advis - able to mix the poison in a small quantity of water before it is placed in the spray tank. It can be combined safely with either Bordeaux mixture or lime sulfur. Nicotine sulfate. — This is the commercial form of tobacco extract and is approximately 40 per cent nicotine. It is used in combating sucking insects, such as plant lice, and may be distributed either when dissolved in water or as a dust when mixed with hydrated lime as a carrier. The standard liquid dilution is 1 part to 800 (•_% pint in 50 gallons), while the ordinary dust is made by mixing 1 pound of nicotine sulfate to 20 pounds of hydrated lime. This dust is 2 per cent nico - tine, commonly known as 2 per cent dust. The fumes from nicotine dust are sufficient to kill plant lice, but if the liquid is to be effective it must come in contact with the insect. Since the lice are generally found on the lower leaf surface, it is necessary to direct the spray upward in order to reach them. The liquid form is more effective and spreads better if 2 pounds of laundry soap is dissolved in each 50 gallons. Nicotine sulfate may be combined with other insecticides and with fungicides, tho in this case no soap should be added. Liquid lime sulfur. — This is a concentrated solution of lime and sulfur in chemical combination and is available from several reliable manufacturers. It can be made satisfactorily at home, but the commercial product is much more uniform in concentratioL, and, in quantity, can be purchased at a rea - sonable price. When diluted 1 gallon of solution to 8 of water, it is the standard remedy against scale insects, but at this strength it can be used only during the dormant season, on account of foliage injury. For summer spraying against fungous troubles the regular dilution is 1 to iy_\ gallons in 50 of water, the amount depending upon the time of application and the fruit being sprayed. It should never be used as a summer spray on peaches and in very hot weather must be applied with caution to other tree fruits. Dry lime sulfur. — Lime sulfur solution when dried and powdered is sold by a number of concerns as dry lime sulfur. Early tests with this material did not give as satisfactory results as were secured with the liquid form, but there has been considerable improvement in its manufacture in recent years. The home orchardist will probably find the dry form more readily obtained and more convenient to handle. The ordinary recommendations call for the use of 3 pounds to 50 gallons of water for the summer spray and 12 pounds to 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 gallons for the winter application. Approximately four pounds of the powder contains active ingredients equal in amount to those in one gallon of the commercial liquid. Bordeaux mixtures. — This well-known efficient fungicide is a chemical combination of copper sulfate, lime, and water. While it may be used at various strengths for specific pur - poses, the standard formula is 4-4-50, or 4 pounds copper sulfate (bluestone — blue vitriol) 4 pounds stone lime 50 gallons water The copper sulfate is dissolved in 25 gallons of water and the lime slaked and suspended in the other 25 gallons. The solutions are then poured together into a third container or into the spray tank. Fresh hydrated lime (6 pounds) may be substituted for the stone lime, if desired. Bordeaux mixture must be freshly made for each applica - tion and used at once since it deteriorates rapidly: Prepared Bordeaux mixtures in either paste or powdered form are not as satisfactory as the fresh home-made product. Copper sul - fate should be handled in wooden or earthenware containers and all working parts of the sprayer in which Bordeaux mixture is used should be of brass to prevent corrosion. The use of Bordeaux mixture in the early summer sprays will cause russeting on apples if the weather is cool and damp. On the other hand, for the control of late summer diseases, such as apple blotch and black rot, it is more effective and less dangerous than lime sulfur. Dry-mix sulfur lime. — This spray mixture was originated at the New Jersey Experiment Station and is recommended to replace self-boiled lime sulfur for use on peaches. It is simply a mechanical mixture of sulfur and lime. The formula by weight is as follows : 8 pounds superfine sulfur 4 pounds hydrated lime Vz pound calcium caseinate The materials are screened and then thoroly mixed. The mixture may be stored indefinitely if kept dry. Twelve and one-half pounds of the dry-mix is sufficient for 50 gallons of spray. Oil sprays. — Various oil mixtures, homemade and com - mercial, have been used effectively during the dormant season against scale insects and aphids and also against red spiders. The Nebraska grower is seldom interested in these sprays be - cause of the relative scarcity of dangerous scale insects in this state. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Spraying Tree Fruits Recently, however, certain proprietary brands of oil have been recommended for summer use on apples as ovicides or egg-killing agents. One gallon of oil to 100 gallons of spray is usually recommended, but it can be combined successfully with few materials, aside from arsenate of lead. In hot dry weather there is some danger of burning the leaves and hence the quantity suggested above should not be increased. The value of these mixtures as ovicides may be questioned but they do serve as spreaders for arsenate of lead. They prob - ably should not be employed in late summer sprays because they tend to interfere with the proper coloration of red var - ieties and also because they increase the amount of spray residue left at harvest time. Spreaders. — In addition to the oils mentioned above, other materials may also be used as spreaders. These agents all tend to distribute the spray as a thin film over the entire surface rather than as distinct drops. Soap will accomplish this purpose, tho commercially the calcium caseinate com - pound is generally used. The latter is sold under the trade names "Kayso," "Spreado," etc., and is used at the rate of y.s pound to 100 gallons of spray. It can be used safely in any combination spray. Spreaders also tend to make spray material — especially lead arsenate — stick more tenaciously. The recent agitation against the presence of excessive arsenical residues on ripe fruit indicates that it may be unwise to use spreaders, es - pecially oils, late in the season. The commercial grower will do well to keep himself informed as to the amount of arsenical residue tolerated on interstate shipments of apples. Quantity of material needed. — The quantity of material needed for a single tree depends upon its size and the number and thoroness of the applications. Assuming that four sprays are given, an average-sized 20-year-old apple tree will require 20 to 25 gallons for the season. Multiplying this amount by the total number of trees of similar size will give the total amount of diluted spray needed. From this figure the number of pounds or gallons of spray materials to order can be com - puted. The spray schedules given later indicate the materials recommended and the number of applications advisable for the various fruits. TABLE OF DILUTIONS The table given herewith indicates the amounts of the various materials needed to make up small quantities of spray at the dilutions given. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 table of dilutions Amount of material needed for — .Material and strength , , „ , , . 1 gal. .1 gals. 10 gals. oO gals. Lead arsenate— 1 lb. to 50 pals. IT. 3 T. '.V, oz. 1 lb. 1 V4 lb. to 50 gals. 1 4 T. 4 4 T. &lt;i oz. 1 4 lb. Liquid lime sulfur - 1 gal. to 50 gals. 3 11. oz. ~&gt; pt. *» qt. 1 gal. 14 gal. to 5(1 gals. 1 11. oz. 1 pt. 1 ''.-, qt. 1 4 gal. 1 gal. to s (dormant I 1 pt. .1 pts. 1 gal. 5 Vagal. Dry lime sulfur— - ;S lbs. to 50 gals. 1 oz. :. oz. 10 oz. :i lbs. 4 lbs. to 50 gals. 1 oz. ■J 1 .-, oz. 11 oz. libs. 12 lbs. to 50 (dormant l :1 m, 10 oz. 1 U lbs. 12 lbs. Bordeaux mixture 1-1-50 Copper sulfate 1 „z. Tn oz. 10 oz. 1 lbs. Stone lime * 1 n&gt;, :!':•. oz. 10 oz. 4 lbs. Nicotine sulfate - 1 part in K00 1 tsp. 1 T. 34 T. 4 pt. * Fresh hydrated lime may be substituted by increasing the quantity one-half. SPRAYING EQUIPMENT A spraying outfit consists essentially of a pump, hose, cut - off rod, and nozzle. Nearly all types of pumps are equipped with an air chamber to provide a more steady pressure, and the larger ones also have an agitator to keep the spray ma - terials in uniform suspension. There are many types of such outfits, and one can be found to tit almost any need. Several of the more common ones are described briefly below. In the selection of an outfit, among the features to be considered are its ability to deliver the needed quantity of material at a satisfactory pressure, and also its durability. Small capacity outfits. — In this classification are included all atomizers, bucket pumps, and knapsack sprayers. Their capacity is limited and they are not well adapted to the spray - ing of large fruit trees. The bucket pump, however, can be used with a fair degree of success where only a few trees are to be sprayed. It should be equipped with at least 15 feet of hose and an extension rod so that the top of the tree can be properly sprayed without using a ladder or climbing the tree. The rod may be the ordinary bamboo type or even a quarter - inch gas pipe properly threated. A cut-off between the hose and rod is very convenient. The best nozzle for general use is one of the 45-degree disk type. The angle between the rod and the nozzle enables the operator quickly and easily to change the direction of the spray so that all parts of the tree </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Spraying Tree Fruits and fruit can be reached. If the angle nozzle is not available, the same results may be secured by using a straight angle and a 45-degree elbow or by bending an iron extension rod. Barrel outfits. — The greater capacities and higher pres - sures of these outfits make them more suitable for farm orchard use. They may be had with either single (Fig. 1) or double action pumps — the latter type being suitable for use in orchards of 250 trees or less. Such outfits may also be used by small spray rings. They should be mounted on i 7 1 I JJ' I Fig. 1, — Single action barrel sprayer. Suitable for use with 100 trees or less. Note agitator, pump, cylinder, and air chamber. skids or they may be placed on a wagon. All accessories named for the smaller outfits should be included and the hose should be at least 25 feet long. Power outfits. — A power sprayer is an essential part of the orchard equipment of a commercial grower. A large spray ring will also find its use advisable. A gas engine furnishes the power and a multiple-cylinder pump delivers a large amount of spray material at a uniform, high pressure. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 Two or more 50-foot leads of high pressure hose are em - ployed and the rod and nozzle may be replaced with the spray gun. They vary greatly in size, capacity, and cost. Rods vs. spray guns. — In recent years an appliance known as the spray gun has come into general use with power sprayers. It replaces the spray rod, nozzle, and cut-off and is so constructed that either a fine or a coarse spray may be had at the will of the operator. Considerable controversy has arisen as to the relative values of the two types of equipment. A careful operator can do good work with either, but the aver - age operator will possibly be somewhat more efficient with the rod. The gun is somewhat wasteful of material but the # saving in time offsets this undesirable feature. Because of its large capacity the gun can be used only on outfits main - taining high pressure. Unless the operator is willing to regulate the gun according to the distance from the part being sprayed, considerable damage to the fruit or foliage may result. For close spraying the fine mist should be used, while the top of the tree can be reached only with the coarse spray. With heavy use, the opening in the disk of the spray gun becomes enlarged, thus increasing the amount of material passing thru and also the coarseness. Hence this disk should be replaced whenever necessary. Dusters. — Outfits for the application of spray dusts are also available in both hand and power types. With these the spray materials are distributed by being slowly fed into a stream of air generated by a fan. It is doubtful that any - thing except a power duster should be considered for use with tree fruits. spraying management- The right material and the proper equipment for applying it by no means insure satisfaction in spraying results. Time - liness of applications and thoroness of coverage are of prime consideration. Timing the sprays. — Unless the material is on the tree before the infection or infestation occurs, its value is likely to be small. On the other hand, if it is applied too soon, new growth is entirely unprotected or rains may wash off the greater portion of all materials on the tree. Proper timing is therefore of great importance. Thru the years that spraying has been in general use, there have developed the so-called spray schedules. In accordance with such programs, sprays are applied to the various fruits at rather definite stages of development. For average seasons </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Spraying Tree Fruits such schedules are quite satisfactory. Frequently, however, failures to control the codling moth, or some other pest, have been encountered and are explainable largely as due to weather variations. Hence, the up-to-date fruit grower no longer relies entirely on. the old established schedules but supplements these by actual observation of emergence and by temperature records. These measures have special value in codling moth control in apples, since they enable the grower to determine very definitely when the cover sprays will be effective. Such observations made in connection with spraying ex - periments at Shubert showed that moth emergence was about three weeks later in 1927 than in 1926. Thus a spray schedule adapted to 1926 would .have been entirely inadequate in 1927. The only way to secure such information is thru the use of observation cages. • Handling observation cages. — In late summer the larvae of the codling moth crawl down the trunk of the tree and spin their winter cocoons in some protected place. In the spring the moth emerges and lays eggs, vyhich in turn hatch into worms that enter the fruit. The question in the mind of the fruit grower is, "At just what time are egg laying and hatch - ing taking place?" In order to determine this, some larvae — 50 to 100 in number — should be collected in April and placed in an ob - servation cage. (Collection of larvae may be greatly simpli - fied if a few trees are banded in August, since many of the descending larvae will seek protection under the burlap band.) The cage may be any sort of container which will keep the moths from escaping and at the same time permit them to be watched. A fruit jar with some small holes in the zinc lid or a tight wooden box with a fine screen cover will serve nicely. Some small pieces of corrugated packing board placed in the cage furnish excellent places for pupation. The cage is then placed under as nearly orchard conditions as possible — in fact is often placed in a more or less shady place in the orchard itself. Daily observations of moth emerg - ence are taken. The appearance of moths within the cage — usually about the time the calyx spray is applied — means that moths are also flying in the orchard. The emergence period may be prolonged for a considerable period, depending upon weather conditions, and it is not uncommon to find the late moths of the first brood appearing along with the early ones of the second. Life cycle studies of this insect have shown that egg laying normally begins about three days after moth emergence and that these eggs hatch six to eight days later. Observations </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 have also shown that egg laying occurs mainly in the evening but does not take place if the temperature at 8 p. m. is less than 60 F. Therefore, in a cool season emergence is de - layed, and along with it the egg-laying period. On the other hand, unduly high temperatures hasten both phenomena. Hence, it is only by keeping observation cages and tempera - ture records that the orchardist may know about such occur - rences and judge the proper time for cover spray operations. Similar records of emergence for the second brood may be obtained by collecting wormy apples in early summer and placing them in a similar cage. Here, however, temperature records are not as important. Normally these moths will emerge in early July. Such observations indicate when the later cover sprays will be most valuable. Thoroness. — Too much emphasis cannot be placed upon the necessity of doing a good job of spraying. All parts of the fruit and foliage and even of the branches and trunk of the tree should be reached or complete protection is not se - cured. Spraying time is no time to get in a hurry. Too often the grower is content to cover only the outer parts of the tree, forgetting that the central portions must also receive atten - tion. It is especially important in the control of the codling moth that the top of the tree be thoroly sprayed since here is where the greater share of the eggs are deposited. Hence, the use of a tower on the sprayer in mature orchards may be al - most a matter of necessity. In the hands of careless operators, the high pressures and large capacities of the modern spray gun have not increased the thoroness of spraying. A coarse spray resulting from worn disks often leads the man manipulating the gun to think that the job is finished before it really is. Number of applications. — The number of applications required depends upon the season and the fruit under con - sideration. Also, the commercial grower will use a larger number than the home orchard owner because of the greater necessity of keeping his fruit clean. Then, too, one season may develop pests not present in damaging numbers the pre - vious year. An orchard regularly sprayed will not require as many applications as a previously neglected one. Young orchards can also be kept clean with fewer sprays than older ones. The same statement would hold with respect to new orchard regions as compared with longer established districts. The spraying program is more important in years of light crops than is generally realized because of its effect in holding in check the infestation of the following year. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Spraying Tree Fruits spray schedules The spray schedules recommended for use with the various fruits in Nebraska are given herewith. These are based upon experiences of the past and ordinarily will give satisfactory control of pests and diseases which regularly occur. It is not expected, however, that they will fit all conditions in a given season or all seasons. They are simply suggestive and must be adapted to fit particular conditions. __ \£ ,\ _^eW_____. ~~ "' 11V. . _?— **^tfy^J^H w^___ -.-r^?" TH 7j^*PB -t___-^______B____. PlG. 2. — Flower stage of apple at. Fig. 3. — Apple fruits at proper proper stage for cluster bud stage for calyx spray. Petals spray. Flowers have not yet have fallen and hence danger opened. of injury to honeybees is past. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 spray schedule for apples and pears j ■ No. I Name and time Materials to use Pests and diseases 1 of application controlled I 1. Cluster bud — 2 to Lime sulfur (\'r_ gals. Scab 1 6 days before liquid or 4 lbs. dry) Curculio flower opens Lead arsenate 1 Ms lbs. Leaf-eating insects (Fig. 2) Water 50 gals. _J , 2. Calyx spray-im - mediately after Same as above petals fall Same as above Codling moth (Fig. :i&gt; :.. 1st cover spray — Lime sulfur (1*4 gals. varies with sea- liquid or .'! lbs. dry) Same as above son- normally Lead arsenate 1*4 lbs. Blotch about 2 weeks Water 50 gals. Sooty blotch I after calyx ap- Spreader (if desired) plication '-j lb. 1. 2nd cover spray— Same as above Same as above 2 weeks later i ii. 2nd brood cover Same as above except I Same as above spray— normal- in hot seasons lime ! Green fruit worm Iv early in July sulfur should be omitted _ , j Ii. 2nd cover spray — Same as above | Same as above 2 weeks later I i Note: For home orchards applications Nos. 1. 2, .'!. and 5 are most important. In bad codling moth years a 3rd cover spray 2 weeks after the sec - ond may be necessary. Where blotch is severe. Bordeaux 1-4-50 should be substituted for lime sulfur in the third and subsequent sprays. If scale infection is present, lime sulfur 1 to X should be applied just before the leaf buds open. In orchards where several varieties are found, the calyx spray is timed for the late blooming sorts rather than the early bloomers. This application may be applied effectively for a period of 8 or 10 days. Never spray when trees are in full bloom because of the injury done to honey bees. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Spraying Tree Fruits spray schedule for cherries j No. I Time of appli- Materials used . Pests and diseases I cation controlled | I 1. | Immediately after Lime sulfur (1% gals. Curculio the shucks or liquid or 4 lbs. dry) Leaf spot I husks fall Lead arsenate 1 Va lbs. Brown rot ___ Water 50 gals. I 2. | About 3 weeks Same as above Same as above later I 3. I After fruit is Lime sulfur as above Leaf spot harvested. Nee- or I essary only if Bordeaux 4-4-50 leaf spot is I troublesome SPRAY SCHEDULE FOR PLUMS | No. I Time of appli- Materials used Pests and diseases 1 cation controlled i . """ — ~ ~ ~ -^—^—^—^ 1. Immediately after Lime sulfur (1% gals. the shucks or liquid or 4 lbs. dry) Curculio I husks have Lead arsenate 1 x k lbs. Brown rot dropped Water 50 gals. 2. About 3 weeks Same as above Same as above later __ . , . ',',. About middle of Lime sulfur (1 gal. Brown rot I July liquid or 3 lbs. dry) Note : If plum pocket infection was bad the preceding season, lime sulfur 1 V-i to 50, or Bordeaux 4-4-50, should be applied just before the flower buds open. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 spray schedule for peaches No. Time of appli- ( Material used Pests and diseases cation controlled 1. Immediately after Lead arsenate 1 lb. Curculio the shucks or &lt; Stone lime '■&gt; lbs. Brown rot husks fall j Water 50 gals. I If brown rot is present | add 12'is lbs. dry - mix sulfur lime 2. About 2 weeks Same as above Curculio later Brown rot Scab Note: If peach leaf curl was present the preceding year, a special spray of r.-5-.iii Bordeaux or 2 l _ to :l gallons of lime sulfur to 50 gallons of water should be applied just before the bujls swell. INSECT PESTS * Aphids. — Aphids or plant lice are present almost every - where and in some form are found attacking the various fruits. These pests suck juice from the plant parts, thus making the leaves and fruits misshapen and hard to cover with spray material. These insects multiply very rapidly and hence incomplete control measures soon mean a new infesta - tion. Aphids on the plum are very common, altho as a matter of fact certain species which live on the roots of tree fruits may be of more serious economic importance. Control. — Seldom do these pests demand special attention, but when they are present in damaging numbers they tan be controlled by spraying with nicotine sulfate, ' ■&gt; pint to 50 gallons of spray. This substance may be applied along with the other spray materials. Each individual insect must be hit with the spray or it will not be destroyed. When aphids alone are present, the use of nicotine dust is also satisfactory. Codling moth. — This is undoubtedly the worst pest with which the Nebraska apple grower must deal and in recent years the orthodox control measures have not been working well. The small grayish-brown moths emerge from the overr wintering cocoon about apple blossoming time, and about 10 or 12 days later the tiny worm starts into the apple. Dry warm weather hastens both moth emergence and egg hatch - • The following brief description. ,,{ the mi'ri- rorumcin cm-hard diseases nnd insect pests are triven so that the urctwer may learn to reeocniw the various orchard enemies. The list is by no mean- complete, hut in controlling the troubles here discussed the orchardist will likewise control most of the others. A few pests anil diseases are in - cluded for which there is n&lt;» &gt;| ific spray remedy, hut other means of control are succested in such instances. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Spraying Tree Fruits ing, while cool weather delays these processes. After about three weeks of burrowing around the core of the fruit, the full grown worm, one-half to two-thirds of an inch long, emerges and spins a cocoon in some protected place on the tree trunk. (Fig. 4) ■ ■ HIS ■ d Ml Fifi. 4.— The codling moth; a, adult moth; b, magnified egg; c, full grown larva; d, pupa; e, pupa in cocoon, reduced one-half; f, 'moth on bark, natural size. (From Simpson, Farmers' Bulletin No. 171, p. 6.) The second-brood moths appear from these cocoons in early July and a second life cycle, similar to the first, is then begun. A partial third brood may appear in hot dry seasons. The larvae of the second and possible third broods are the ones which overwinter in cocoons and produce the spring brood the following year. Emergence data show that the various broods overlap some - what — the stragglers of one group appearing with the early ones of the next. This means that worms are present in greater or lesser numbers from late May until harvest time. Since the worm stage does all of the damage, control measures are directed largely toward the destruction of the worms altho sanitation will also destroy appreciable numbers of pupae and some adult moths may be trapped. The control of the first - brood ivorms is of special importance. Control. — The use of lead arsenate, V-k pounds to 50 gallons of water, offers probably the best means of controlling this </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 pest. The calyx spray, the first and second cover sprays, and the early July spray are of special importance. A severe in - festation may call for additional applications at two-week intervals. Adult moths may be trapped in considerable numbers dur - ing the season of heavy flight. Moth traps made of shallow pans baited with freshly fermented cider are placed in the tops of trees about the time of the first moth emergence. Moths are attracted in considerable numbers and are drowned in the cider. The bait should be renewed daily. This also helps in supplying information as to when sprays should be applied. Still another method of some value in helping control codling moth consists in the destruction of the larvae. The prompt removal and the disposal of all culls take many worms so far away from the orchard that the adult moths cannot return. Also, a clean-up campaign in and near the packing shed will destroy many overwintering larvae. Extra sprays or extra heavy dosages near the packing sheds may also be advisable. Curculio. — Two snout beetles, the plum curculio and the apple curculio. do considerable damage to fruits. The plum curculio (Fig. 51 is by far the more important and does great damage to plums, cher - t 1 ries, peaches, and apples, but the apple curculio con - /•£8j||5^ 1 r / fines its activities almost Z_m£~. entirely to the apple. The / apple curculio is found y nS_IV v ,um on ' J a ' on S the south - y*P) ern border of the state but A ' n t' me 't ma J' become a §| rather serious pest to ap- pie growers. ®/ These beetles pass the , j^ I winter as adults, hibernat - i Ah . &gt; ing in rubbish about the \ _W&gt; orchard. They appear in ' early spring, soon after the blooming period, and begin feeding upon the l*~, j. young fruits. The cres - w .ss^ &lt;4*&gt;- cent - shaped punctures I ■— ' " made for egg-laying pur - poses also soon appear. Fig. 5. — Various stages in the develop- The egg hatches in a few ment of the plum curculio. days, and the larva begins </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Spraying Tree Fruits to burrow about in the fruit. Infested apples generally drop, or if they remain on the tree, develop into misshapen, lop - sided culls. On the other hand, attacked stone fruits usually remain on the tree but at harvest time are found to be wormy. The plum curculio grub pupates in the ground and emerges as an adult of the next generation in July. It is at this time that the main damage to the apple occurs. In addition to the damage already noted, the curculio punctures also serve as entrance points for disease spores and the larvae of other insects. Control.— Lead arsenate, iy_&gt; pounds to 50 gallons of water, offers a means of partially, but not entirely, controlling. these pests. . The apple curculio is apparently somewhat harder to handle than the other species. Spraying in either case should be supplemented by clean culture and general orchard sanita - tion so that winter quarters for the adults are not readily found. The destruction of adjacent wild plum thickets is also of value and the disposal. of fallen fruits is recommended. One Iowa grower has reported that pasturing hogs in his apple orchard has practically eliminated apple curculio in - jury. Spray applications should be made just after the shucks or husks drop off of stone fruits and again about 3 weeks later. The cover sprays are the effective ones in .the case of the apple. Leaf-eating insects. — The caterpillar or larval stage of various insects, such as tent-caterpillar, cankerworm, etc., lives upon the foliage of various fruit trees. Many of these appear in colonies but seldom is the infestation general enough to be serious. Control. — Arsenate of ledd, iy_&gt; pounds to 50 gallons of water, will control these pests. Generally, in an orchard that is regularly sprayed, they require no consideration, since the arsenicals in the regular sprays hold them in check. In young orchards, however, it is sometimes necessary to make a special application to care for the situation. Control measures must be prompt or the tree will be defoliated. Individual colonies may be destroyed, either by removal of the branch or by the use of a torch. Scale insects. — Certain sucking insects known as scale insects protect themselves thru the formation of a downy or waxen scaly covering, and hence must be controlled thru the use of a caustic or penetrating spray. Fortunately for the Nebraska orchardist, scale insects are seldom of importance in this state. The oyster-shell scale — so called because of the shape of the mature insect — is perhaps most common. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 Control.— These insects, regardless of the particular species are controlled by using either concentrated lime sulfur i gallon to 8 of water, or an oil spray. The application must be made during the dormant season. Just before growth be - gins is probably the most effective period. All parts of the tree, especially the younger portions, must be thoroly drenched or the application will not be effective. In cases of light in - festation, annual applications may not be necessary. Borers.— Certain types of insects, instead of devouring portions of the foliage or fruit, burrow their way under the bark or into the wood of tl le tree. The peach-tree'borer is the most serious of these, altho frequently apples mav also be aamaged considerably by other species. Thev remain in the tree trunk lor varying periods of time, weakening or killing the tree thru partial or complete girdling. (•,,„&lt; ,-n! sprays are of no value in the control of these pests. They must be either dug out bv hand or killed thru the use ot fumigating agents. Paradicldorobenzine ■• , to l ounce per tree, can be effectively used on peaches to control the peach-tree borer, but only in case the tree is 5 years of age or older. This material is placed in a ring about 2 inches from the tree about October 1 and covered with 2 or .5 inches ot soil. All younger trees must be wormed by hand. Buffalo tree-hopper.— This insect, in common with sev - eral others, deposits its eggs in the small twigs of an apple tree and thus weakens the twig. It does no other damage. - r t§ Bft /* «. _^__m \\\\\\Wk a4S&amp; B____fek - *5 "**•''' St__L_r ifi_k -v r*\SssT&amp;&amp;wmmr%m¥ Fig. fi.— Apple blotch on fruits. Cracking is common in severe cases. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">. Spraying Tree Fruits Fig. 7. — Apple blotch cankers on apple 'twigs. From such cankers the infection is carried to the fruit. Control. — Since this pest when young feeds upon weeds and grasses, control measures consist .in keeping the orchard clean, especially when the trees are young. Even in cases of non - cultivated orchards, the damage can be materially lessened by frequent mowing of the weeds or grass. ORCHARD DISEASES Apple blotch. — This fungous trouble does considerable damage in certain seasons, especially to such varieties as Northwestern, Duchess, Missouri, and Ben Davis. It affects fruits, twigs, and leaves. An irregular star-shaped splotch appears on the fruit surface in midsummer and becomes darker as it gets older. (Fig. 6) Infected fruits often be- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 come misshapen. Small black pimples containing spores de - velop on them. Such spores are largely responsible for the later or secondary infections. Twig infection occurs on new growth as a canker with roughened bark. (Fig. 7) This canker enc&gt;cles the twig and later gives off spores to cause the fruit and leaf infections. Spore formation may continue in such cankers for several years. Leaf infection often occurs in the petiole which in turn causes twig infection at the node. Control.— Bordeaux 4-4-50 is more effective in the control of blotch than lime sulfur, 1 " :, gallons to 50 gallons of water Lime sulfur is satisfactory in mild cases, but it must be used cautiously in hot weather. Protective measures against this disease are combined with the codling moth cover sprays — that is, they are applied 2 to 3 weeks after petal fall and 2 weeks later. Later applications at intervals of 2 weeks mav also be necessary altho as a rule blotch in Nebraska is not severe enough to justify more than one additional spray. Pruning off the cankered portions during the dormant sea - son is a very important means of control and should be em - ployed wherever feasible. Apple scab.— This disease is found on the fruit and leaves, causing the characteristic grayish scab spots on the fruit and the light brown areas on the leaves. (Figs. '8 and ,- - - - . - .9) Affected fruits !''; » , often become dwarfed I ]Hn^NB*j jt Amu I ' SSm\\\\\m ;.s?.; ; .... . old leaves are capable —— HMBmaa^ __:'. .•__ of causing widespread Fig. 8.-AppIe scab on leaves. Such in- infec t ion th .e following f ection appears early in the spring fol- s P r l n g if environ - lowing damp, cool weather. mental conditions are </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Spraying Tree Fruits E ______ ' _______ ?&gt;^\ ' ___________________________L _■__•" _5r2_k '^N 1 'Jn ■H Bffe '* x9f » to ' . r^ r ' Jstt" 3r* ___^\_f '' ______ Se.' , Fig. 9. — Apple scab on fruit. just right. Cold wet seasons are very favorable for scab development. A crop of summer spores from these early infections pro - duces the "late scab" on fruit and leaves. Infections rarely occur after warm weather begins. Control. — Scab is essentially an early summer disease. The control of the early infections means almost complete absence of disease later. Bordeaux mixture or lime sulfur at the usual strengths are effectice control agents, but lime sulfur is to be preferred because it does not cause russeting. Ordinarily 3 spray applications are sufficient — the first being applied just before bloom, the second just after petal fall, _^____*T ' / &lt; £__Pj____________B____k£xv _____ '£vP^^___________________________t______ ii'- ______ __________________ -_fl_H ' ____1 _Kv#it^___________________________^_______________________ ' ___r ___r __\w Fig. 10. — Sooty blotch. Found usually only in low places or in very - wet seasons. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 and the third 2 to 3 weeks later. A July application may also be of value when late scab is prevalent and even a fifth appli - cation in August may be advisable for susceptible varieties at such times. Varieties vary widely in their susceptibility to this trouble, the Delicious and Winesap being quite suscept - ible, the Jonathan moderately resistant, and the Grimes quite resistant. Sooty-blotch and fly-speck. — In low places and in damp seasons, apples, especially the uncolored varieties, may de - velop a fly-specked or even a clouded appearance. The blotches appear in midsummer. The damage is only superficial but the appearance of the fruit is greatly marred. (Fig. 10) Control — Lime surfur or Bordeaux mixture when used in the scab and blotch sprays will also keep this trouble tinder control. Blister canker. — This disease has killed great numbers of apple trees in Nebraska, especially of the Ben Davis and Gano varieties. The disease is distinctly a heartwood para- r ________^____^ site and may be working in - ' areas. Fig. il.— An advanced stage of As the cankers increase in blister canker, showing the typ- age, these protuberances de - ical " nail head " appearance. ve l op j n t 0 the characteristic "nail head" stage. (Fig. Ill Here also spores are produced which serve to infect wounds on the same or adjacent trees. The infection may grow for from one to many years be - fore it shows up on the surface, the interval depending upon the variety and vigor of the tree. The branch or the entire tree dies whenever the canker girdles that portion. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Spraying Tree Fruits Control. — Spraying will not control this disease. Orchard management designed to keep canker out of the planting is the most effective means of combating it. Among the meas - ures to be considered in this connection are: First, avoid the susceptible varieties. Second, keep the trees in a vigorous growing condition by spraying and cultivation. Third, prune carefully, avoiding large wounds as much as possible. Dis - infection of pruning tools used on cankered areas is also worth while. Trees with canker in the heartwood should never be pruned heavily. Pruning-wounds on cankered trees should be covered with either a pruning compound or an asphalt paint to retard girdling as long as possible. Fourth, prevent the spread of infection by removing and destroying all branches which show cankers. Cankered areas on the trunk may be shaved away or covered with asphaltum. An affected tree is doomed but may produce several profitable crops before it finally dies. Fifth, spray well the trunk and larger branches in early summer so as to kill any spores which may be exposed on pruning wounds and old cankers. Cedar rust. — This disease is found quite commonly wherever the red cedar grows. It passes two winters and i one summer on the I : &gt;y :'..'" '■'•/■'-■ '.'-_•/.•' ;• .-' ■" ■ - ' I tions are sent out from the galls on FlG. 12.— Cedar apples or galls on the cedar, the Cedar during Spores from these galls produce the cedar rn ; nv nprinHa i r, rust on apple leaves and fruits. ral " y P . 10a JL 1 " early spring. These produce millions of dust-like spores which may be carried even 3 or 4 miles by the wind. They germinate on the leaves and fruit of the summer host, producing orange-colored spots. Infections on the leaves may be so numerous as to lessen leaf efficiency materially. The infections on the fruit are usually near the calyx end. From the apple, in due course of time, spores are carried back and reinfect the cedar. Control. — Spraying is not considered a practical means of controlling cedar rust, altho sprays applied according to the regular schedule may be of some value. The destruction of </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 cedar trees or the removal of the galls before the spores are distributed presents the only absolutely effective means of dealing with this trouble. Certain varieties, such as Jona - than, Wealthy, York, and most of the crabs, are much more susceptible than the Winesap and Delicious. Where cedars are too abundant or too valuable to be cut out, the very sus - ceptible apple varieties should not be planted. Fire blight. — This bacterial disease attacks the blossoms, leaves, and woody parts of various species. The damage is often quite severe in the case of the pear; and a few varieties of apples, such as Yellow Transparent and Jonathan, are sometimes seriously injured. Ordinarily it is confined to the blossoms, fruit sours and young twigs of the apple but winter or "hold over" cankers on the trunk are sometimes found. Whenever any part of the tree becomes girdled the portion beyond the girdle dies. This girdling frequently occurs on the trunk of the pear and thus the whole tree is lost. Fire blight is also responsible for the "collar blight" and "root blight" sometimes found. The bacteria gain entrance to the host either thru blossom tissue or thru wounds on the twigs or leaves. Infection is carried to the blossoms largely by insects. Other agencies, such as wind-blown rain, are also partially responsible for the spread of this disease. From the initial infection the dis - ease progresses down the spur or twig and usually forms a canker on the larger branch. This canker frequently serves as a "hold over" canker, thus allowing for infection the fol - lowing year. Fire blight is easily recognized by the browning or blackening of the leaves and bark. The leaves also are very persistent. Blighted pear trees often show premature autumn coloration of the foliage. Control. — Because this infection is found only in the cortex of the plant no spray program will control it. Removal of sources of infection during the dormant season offers the only effective way of combating it. Hold-over cankers should be located and destroyed and all blighted twigs and small branches removed. Also, all fruit spurs and water sprouts coming directly from the trunk or main branches should be cut off. This is especially desirable in the case of the pear. Very vigorous trees are more likely to become blighted than those making a slower, better matured growth. Hence, pear trees are usually grown in sod and often in relatively poor soil. Plum pockets. — Elongated, swollen fruits are frequently found on plum trees in early summer. These are hollow and </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Spraying Tree Fruits . __ contain only a partially de- A W^S^^,*" lvater &gt; or standard Bordeaux I ■ I &lt;^T ' w *^ c0 . ntr °l tms disease if it VjL| ■ •%§■ ily is a PPJied just before the \Wt_K ftcj* Wm blossoms open. Diseased -.&lt;/'?THtffr^ v *w. fa» H twigs should also be removed LJ^P ■'ir^&amp;S. l/~iY I Brown rot. — This disease »^&gt; I w»2b _»L I * s res P° ns ib^ e f° r rapid tg_J^'f ™ F * I rotting of peaches, plums, pjH^ I' Hi apricots, and even cherries, _lQF' ■ I ■' ust before or after they — ____z_______ | ripen. A small, circular, Fig. 14.— Plum pockets. Note the grayish-brown decayed area, enlarged, misshapen, infected usually at an insect punc - f ruits - ture, appears and rapidly en - larges until the whole fruit is involved. Hot, damp weather is very favorable for its spread. Affected fruits may either drop or dry up and hang on the tree until spring. From these come the spores for the next year's infection. Control. — Lime sulfur, 1% gallons to 50 gallons of water, can be successfully used on cherries and plums but the dry - mix sulfur lime, l&amp;y_\ pounds to 50 gallons of water, must be applied to peaches. In bad seasons three applications may be necessary — just after the husks drop, three weeks later, and in early July. Controlling the curculio will aid materially in lessening the loss from brown rot. Dusting may be used successfully to control this trouble on the peach. Cherry leaf spot. — In early summer small purplish spots appear on the upper surface of cherry leaves. These later become brown and the center drops out, thus giving a "shot - hole" effect. The whole leaf generally turns yellow and drops prematurely. Early infections come from spores produced on old leaves but the midsummer spread is from spores pro - duced on the living leaves. Damp, cloudy weather in mid - summer greatly increases the infection. Badly infected trees, especially of the English Morello type, may be entirely de- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 36 Fig. 1.1. — Cherry leaf spot. foliated. Young trees are affected more severely than older ones. (Fig. 1.3) Control. — Lime sulfur or Bordeaux mixture at the usual summer concentrations will control this trouble. As soon as the husks drop, 3 weeks later, and just after the fruit is har - vested are the proper application dates. Peach leaf curl. — This fungus attacks the current sea - son's growth, doing the chief damage to the leaves. Very early the infected leaves become much wrinkled and mal - formed, and yellow and reddish in color. They later drop off. thus forcing the tree to form a new set of leaves. The crop may also be a total or partial loss. Several such defoliations may cause the death of the tree. The disease is most severe in cool seasons and in the cooler peach-growing regions. Control. — Since this is a very early disease, control meas - ures should begin during the dormant season. Lime sulfur, 2\'o to -i gallons to 50 gallons of water, or Bordeaux 5-5-50. may be used satisfactorily and with safety any time before the spring growth begins. Peach scab. — Peach fruits are often severely damaged by peach scab. This disease is also found on twigs and leaves. A portion of the peach becomes blackened and shriveled and may even crack open. Infection occurs 3 or 4 weeks after bloom. Control.- — Dry-mix sulfur Ume, 12\'.&gt; pounds to 50 gallons of water, should be applied about 2 weeks after the shucks drop and at two-week intervals as the severity of the disease demands. Dusting has been successfully used for the control of this disease in some sections. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>