<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00026</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBR., U. S. A.  BUNT, OR STINKING SMUT OF WHEAT.</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">I BUNT re. I q 1 The bunt \i.w. Experiment Station 'resa Bulletin No. 28 utfii April /; OR STINKING SMUT OF WHEAT. in I. l&gt;. IIKAI.I). ted liy two different typei of smut: the hich destroys the entire head, transforming lery mass of black spores; hunt, or stinking ill'ecis only the berry, the other parts of the ig practically normal. There are two differ - bunl preraleat, lmt both affect the wheat in ml they can only be separatee! by a micro- ation of the spores. Nearly all of the bunt proved to be Tittetie foetmm$, the smooth- 's. while TUletia tritid, the rough-spored (in exceedingly rare. f wheat has been especially abundant in cer- ol.N, NEBRASKA, U.S.A. PREVALENCE. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ti received Barest that the true nature of the disease and il tive measures that should be employed are no wn by the farmers and grain dealers of the stale. tunt has affected not only varieties of spring whea it has Im'cii very prevalent in a large portion of tl B whore winter wheat varieties are grown. Tl aapaayimg map (ftg. it. based upon specimens &lt;• led. gives the distribution of the disease in the stat Fie 1. Distribution of stir Almost all of the samph l-ereiv tially smut resistant. be necessarv to treat hut the reports in leed of this varietv for tion of smut as well as in the case of ■pring wheat v, rieties. No samples of smutted wheat have been obtain* from the eastern part of the state, but it has probably !»•« present in small quantity. Platte river were &lt;&gt;f the Turkish Red variety, w ■ajority of samples from north &lt;&gt;f the Platte wen irheat Turkish Red wheat lias general •alh 11\- litM'tl cdl &gt;; </seg>
            <seg id="p003">■ NT OK I N.I IK he smut hiis canted onlj a slight km rs the loss luis been serious. Om eonnpaad - •Mmil wheat \v;is too hailh smutted for mill Another corrapoadeal reported a kw per Imslitl on sale price, without mentioning &lt;s from reduction of yield. Figure il shows adly sniutieil sami&gt;le of wheat, a. normal ber - ries; b, smutted berries. ■matted Maple of wheat &lt;&gt;l&gt; &gt;f the state. This lot of wli«»t it- western part nut by weight, 17.7 jkt rent nt l»v count. mtamed 9.08 per cent of measure, and 2l.lt:', (per i •e: SYMPTOMS. " oration of a badly Juiit. or stinking smut, is not as noticeable in the Held 1 1- fiipiii** (if 1 • 1 1 1 ii t -in it 1 t i ~ i _ </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 destroy the head. Its presence in ■the characteristic odor, by the deeper ri cted heads, and generally bv the fact that ■ more spreading than in 1101 nation will show in the plan black smui "bernee" of near \ with i tli in membrane. A &lt;|iiit&lt;' frequently present on The smut niav be verv 11 Klery mass of sport lodged apon the n *s collect particuli of hairs &lt;ir "hru wheat is frequent ly dai her of spores collected Km. When tin be dei. twith the obliter can lie easily try interior i tit; LIFE IIISI Every spore which find grain of wheat is capable of repr« wheat plant takes place. I'm- this i ment which will kill the spores of tl jurinjr the vitality of the wh normal conditions, the smut siior the young wheat seedling has si;n produces a short, septate filai more tufts of FI shaped gporidia. Th rid Biiini lively incnnRp cs i tiix. ::. in are it is from tln-s.- s|&gt;m pive rise to secondary &lt;&gt;\;il nporidii </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I Tilhtia foetans). a, head of smutted ins smutted "berries" protruding from between the mut lierries; c, normal berries: d, smut berry, crushed mass of black spores which Oils the whole interior; thru the middle: f, smut spores, much minating spore, showing H-shaped sporidia, some ivhich have produced secondary sporidia. (Fig. g, redrawn from ammrl and King </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 H lied ;il II ion i f 1 1 i rfh the young seedling. After the smut tangos has gaii entrance into tlie seedling it grows upward tin tissues of the stem but gives little external Indicat its presence until the heads arc produced, when it t rates the berries or kernels and forms the eharaet smut "berries" which have been described. All i heads produced by an infected stool are smutted, an erally all the berries of a smutted head tre deatroye PREVENTION Ey seed treatment, the bant of wheat and the sn ; can be almost entirely prevented, while the pi unit in barley, sorghum and rve can be verv i Iiened. While the hot-water treatment is •ather laborious treatment to employ. t it has been verv largely superseded ii some of the chemical treatments. The p Itinents. I lie in chemical treatment is to u spines of the smut and n&lt; sating power of the seed. &lt; &gt;m of many d tried up to this time, only a part have such as potassium snlphid, corrosive i sulphate or Milestone, and formalin. I mi years the use of formalin has verv great » satisfactory results obtained justify its contii ince the formalin steep is generally sueeefl to employ, it may be especially recommended. inalin is a solution of formaldehyde, and the conn article is 40 per cent. This strength is always und&lt; in recommending the amount to be used in seed trea The treatment of seed may be carried out as folb t Place the seed to be treated upon the clean tl granary, or upon a canvas in the open, or in book able place. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">&lt; t t f hit ion of fomiiilin by adding tin* rum water in the foUowtag proportioas: tmt for hunt of wlicat or loose smut of o;its; lmi gallons for barley or sorghum smuts. (1 not be made up until it is needed for rength by standing. lie formalin solution over the seed, and I" intil the surface of each grain is thorolv ened. For sprinkling the seed, a common garden •ing pot may be used to good advantage. Shovel the grain into a heap and cover with a canvas i t sacks to prevent the evaporation of the formalin. At the end of two hours, uncover and spread the grain i&gt; dry. It will probably be neeesaary to rake or shovel •ain over several times to dry sufficiently to prevent nation. If treated in the granary, the floor should rilized with formalin solution before beginning oper- If the grain is to be returned to the same bin it occupied before treatment, the bin should be ii- washed with formalin solution to prevent any &gt;n taking place. For the same reason infected &gt;uld be avoided or sterilised. formalin treatment may be carried out in a slightly ni way. and some may prefer it to the method al f outlined. The writer has found the following od very satisfactory : Prepare a solution of formalin of the strength indi Put sufficient of the solution into a barrel to im &lt;e a sack of need i thirty-five to forty gallon- Pnt seed to be treated into sacks i one and a half to bushels i and dip each sack into the solution, allowing remain ten minutes </seg>
            <seg id="p008">4. Kemove tin" sack iintl drain, allo&gt; the itaep to run back into the barrel. TI very easily carried out bj arranging the barrel m block and tackle can W employed for raisii the sack ■ ks for two lion a beap ami covet- with canvas of w. previous treatment 6. At the end of two hours spread out pains to shovel over often enough to preven ii red treated bj either of the n own as soon as dry, or it nia\ 'in stol \ !&gt;&lt;■ rt'plciiislKMl ;is often as MCMMUy. The &lt; .".. Si-t away in the v </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>