<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00026</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Second Biennial Report of the Board of Examiners of Defectives</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Second Biennial Report OF THE Board of Examiners of Defectives To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF ■M' 582 MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF EXAMINERS OF DEFECTIVES W. S. Fast, M. D., Chairman Superintendent, Ingleside Hospital for the Insane, Ingleside D. G. Griffiths. M. D., Secretary Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth, Beatrice G. E. Chaki.ton, M. D. Superintendent, Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk J. D. Case. M. D. Superintendent, Nebraska Hospital for the Insane, Lincoln B. A. Fimcle, M. D. Superintendent, Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 583 BOARD OF EXAMINERS OF DEFECTIVES To his Excellency, Honorable Keith Neville, Governor, and to the Honorable Member* of the Board of Com mis - missioners of State Institutions, Henry Gerries, Silns A. Hoicomb, and Eugene O. Mayfield. Gentlemen: We submit herewith the Second Biennial Report of the Board of Examiners of Defectives, covering the period beginning December 1, 1916, and ending November 30, 1918. This Board was created and appointed by the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions complying with Chap - ter 237, Laws of Nebraska, 1915, entitled "An Act to auth - orize the sterilization of feeble-minded and insane inmates of state institutions, in certain cases, and to provide for the appointment of a commission, and to define their powers and duties in connection therewith". There have been ten meetings of the Board of Exam - iners of Defectives held during the past two years. Meet - ings are called by the chairman on request of the superintend - ents of the different state hospitals. Appended to this re - port will be found five tables: Table I, referring to the Ingleside Hospital for the Insane; Table II, the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane; Table HI, Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska; Table IV, Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth; Table V, combined report of the action of the Board as it pertains to all of the institutions. There was a total of 235 patients examined in four state institutions. The institutions were given authority to sterilize 77 patients before parole or discharge be granted, 43 patients have been sterilized, the remaining 34 patients still remain residents of the institutions, they being as yet, unable mentally to take their former place in society. Section 1 of the law governing this Board reads as follows: "Sterilization of feeble minded or insane inmates of state institutions. — Hereafter no feeble-minded or insane </seg>
            <seg id="p004">584 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF inmate, physically capable of bearing or begetting off - spring, shall be paroled or discharged from the institution for the feeble-minded, or the hospital for the insane, nor paroled from the penitentiary, reformatory, industrial home, industrial schools or other such state institution, except as hereinafter provided, or by order of a court of com - petent jurisdiction." It will be noted that the Board has not been called upon to examine any patients from the State Penitentiary, the Nebraska Industrial Home, State Industrial School, nor the Girls' Industrial School. All patients examined were from the three hospitals for the insane and the institution for feeble-minded. The Board has adopted and followed a conservative policy in dealing with applicants for sterilization. No contro - versies have been invited nor entered into, prejudices in most cases have been overcome and religious scruples have always been respected. No patients have been sterilized without full consent of the relatives and the consent of the patient him - self. Authority to sterilize has not been given in any case until after careful consideration of the personal and family history of the patient and the Board convinced that the patient was capable of bearing or begetting offsprings and that the offsprings "would inherit a tendency to feeble-mind - edness, insanity, or degeneracy, and that such children would probably become a social menace and that procreation by such inmate would be harmful to society". In every case operated upon, recovery was prompt and complete. Respectfully submitted W. S. Fast. Chairman, D. Q. Griffiths. Secretary, G. E. CHARi/rox, J. D. Case. B. A. Fixk'.e. November 30, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 585 INGLESIDE HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE, INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA Table of Patients Coming Under the Observation of the Board of Examiners of Defectives for the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918. TABLE I M F T Number examined 50 44 94 Authority given for sterilization be- fore parole or discharge 12 4 16 Authority given to parole or discharge without sterilization 24 30 54 Action deferred 14 10 24 Total 50 44 94 • * Sterilized according to law 12 1 13 NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA Table of Patients Coming Under the Observation of the Board of Examiners of Defectives for the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918. TABLE II. M F T Number examined 36 46 82 Authority given for sterilization be- fore parole or discharge 15 16 31 Authority given to parole or discharge without sterilization 13 22 35 Action deferred 8 8 16 Total 36 46 82 • • » • Sterilized according to law 4 10 14 HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA, NORFOLK, NEBRASKA Table of Patients Coming Under the Observation of the Board of Examiners of Defectives for the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918. TABLE III M F T Number examined 35 21 56 Authority given for sterilization be- fore parole or discharge 23 4 27 Authority given to parole or discharge without sterilization 5 16 21 Action deferred 7 1 8 Total 35 21 56 • Sterilized according to law 10 3 IS </seg>
            <seg id="p006">586 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH, BEATRICE, NEBRASKA Table of Patients Coming Under the Observation of the Board of Examiners of Defectives for the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918. TABLE IV M F T Number examined 2 1 3 Authority given (or sterilization be- fore parole or discharge 2 1 3 Authority given to parole or discharge without sterilization Action deferred Total 2 13 • • • • • Sterilized according to law 2 13 Combined Tables of Patients from the Ingleside Hospital for the Insane, Nebraska Hospital for the Insane, Hospital for the Insane of Ne- braska, and the Nebraska Institution for the Feeble-Minded Youth, Coming Under the Observation of the Board of Examiners of De- fectives for the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918. TABLE V M F T Number examined 123 112 235 Authority given for sterilization be- fore parole or discharge 52 25 77 Authority given to parole or discharge without sterilization 42 68 110 Action deferred 29 19 48 Total 123 112 235 • * * • Sterilized according to law 28 15 43 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page Board of Commissioners of State Institutions, Lincoln 5 Board of Examiners of Defectives 58 1 Girls' Industrial School, Geneva 181 Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska. Norfolk 33* Hospital for Tuberculosis, Kearney 381 Ingleside Hospital for the Insane, Ingleside 2(7 Nebraska Home for Dependent Children. Lincoln 563 Nebraska Hospital for the Insane. Lincoln 305 Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford 4(5 Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth, Beatrice 151 Nebraska School for the Blind. Nebraska City 491 Nebraska School for the Deaf, Omaha 531 Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home. Burkett 231 Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 4W Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Milford 2S3 State Industrial School, Kearney 1H State Penitentiary, Lincoln 4SS </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>