<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00065.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00065.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>State of Nebraska Department of Trade and Commerce Report Of Building and Loan Associations 1927 Showing the Condition of the Building, Loan and Savings Associations June 30, 1927</title>
               <date value="1927-12-01">1927-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE REPORT OP BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 1927 Showing the Condition of the Building, Loan and Savings Associations June 30, 1927 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">York Blank Book Co.. York, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Merle N S. L C Richard H. V DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE REPORT OF BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF NEBRASKA 1927 EXAMINERS P. D. Marshall, Chief Foster C. A. Lau Hestbeck L. E. Martin J. Hornsby Henry H. Schleuning Fred E. Allen Geo. B. Wilson J. P. McLain Fred W. Babka H. Larson Lyman C. Sorensen Davis </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Lincoln, Nebraska, December 1, 1927. To His Excellency, Hon. Adam McMullen, Governor, Executive Offices, Lincoln. Dear Sir: We submit, herewith, for your consideration, a report embracing statistical and other information taken from the records of this office concerning the Building and Loan Associations of Nebraska. The financial statements show the condition of the various Associations on June 30, 1927. Respectfully submitted, DEPARTMENT OF TRADE AND COMMERCE Clarence G. Bliss, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">BUILDING AND LOAN STATISTICS JUNE 30, 1927 Number of Associations _ 8$ Shares in Force 3,348,806 Number of Shareholders 235,581 Number of Borrowers 55,991 Number of Loans for New Buildings 1,694 Appraised Value of Property Loaned On $ 270,139,445.70- Pledged Insurance, Fire 174,154.694.00 Pledged Insurance, Tornado 216,675,627.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATEMENT Of the total number of associations, numbers of shares in force and total assets, from 1892, the first year that authentic reports were made down the present time. to Number of Number of Year Associations Shares in Force Total Assets 1892 71 45,012.5 % 2,902,557.67 1893 84 61,964.1 3,653!o96!83 1894 86 71,231.5 3,888,00l!31 1895., 81 70,615 3,929|778!27 1896 73 64,891.75 3,771,833!53 1897 68 67,597.5 3,554J88!o8 1898 64 79,973 3,428,728.11 1899 60 89,492 3,332,781.67 1900 60 105,625 3,697i356.06 1901 : 59 119,985 4,314,744.86 1902 58 130,083 4,758, 293^97 1903 59 159,424 5,343,429.38 1904 60 174,022 6,217,350.40 1905 59 196,030 7,269,297.48 1906 61 220,648 8,961,788.11 1907 66 315,372 11,422,890.86 1908 68 372,826.77 13,415,822.89 1909 70 438,054.19 17,094,771.57 1910 70 512,344.71 21,327,766.83 1911 69 602,159.94 24,885,285.15 1912 68 668,122.85 28,946,108.63 1913 70 740,925.29 32,746,726.24 1914 72 816,571.25 37,138,413.21 1915 71 891,333.79 41,660,870.53 19J6 72 1,007,346.63 47,917,847.08 1917 73 1,122,518.01 54,545,629.78 1918 73 1,190,784.02 57,151,545.70 1919 74 1,356,423 65,768,059.56 1920 74 1,917,062.10 77,939,337.40 1921 76 1,693,747.% 84,071,013.57 1922 80 1,906,856.82 91,994,729.57 1923 82 2,128,081.31 108,798,586.16 1924 84 2,393,339.79 123,021,650.27 1925 84 2,795,564 141,435,903.98 1926 83 3,056,562 153,128,474.87 1927 83 3,348,806 155,213,560.85 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">ABSTRACT OF THE REPORTS OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF NEBRASKA AT THE CLOSE OP BUSINESS JUNE 30, 1926 83 ASSOCIATIONS REPORTING RESOURCES Mortgage Loans $ 137,580,984.32 Loans in Foreclosure _ 751,852.24 Stock Loans _ 1,592,251.08 Office Buildings 1,428,704.15 Furniture and Fixtures 67,477.34 Other Real Estate 1,513.251.88 Real Estate Sold on Contract 1,153,096.91 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 3,492,219.60 Cash _ 4,489,926.64 Delinquent Interest, Fines, etc 266.957.26 Taxes Paid 303,923.14 Other Assets 487,830.31 TOTAL % 153,128,474.87 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends „ $ 104,410,914.46 Paid-up Stock 41,056,832.74 Incomplete Loans 1,995,481.12 Reserve Funds 3,952,578.75 Undivided Profits 947,132.49 Other Liabilities 765,535.31 TOT AL. % 153,128,474.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">ABSTRACT OF THE REPORTS OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF NEBRASKA AT THE CLOSE OP BUSINESS JUNE 30, 1927 83 ASSOCIATIONS REPORTING RESOURCES Mortgage Loans % 138,454,897.80 Loans in Foreclosures 1,061,179.27 Stock Loans 1,345,741.04 Office Buildings 1,390,258.78 Furniture and Fixtures 107,679.63 Other real estate 2,235,343.74 Real Estate Sold on Contract 1,355,536.92 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 3,355,855.95 Cash 4,753,290.74 Delinquent Interest, Fines, etc .... 312,475.79 Taxes Paid 230,038.46 Other Assets _ 611,262.73 TOTAL $ 155,213,560.85 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 107,879,609.41 Paid-Up Stock 39,968,886.31 Incomplete Loans „ 1,020,107.18 Reserve Funds .... .. . 4,374,842.17 Undivided Profits 1,133,977.63 Other Liabilities 836,138.15 TOTAL $155,213,560.85 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">o i— i g " " 3 &amp; i s § 2 s £ B 5"S"3SS8 £ XSSS82RR8SR a s* S 5 is" s" s " I S = " * ft 1 C; N " ■ a &amp; 5 S3«3g j ISnSss i S ooSoON j : « i - 5 S OC .-4 ssssas i s 5 si si s s m qc ■-■ 55 « i a I i 9 5 0 — . B 10 O i— i s si § k i 3 S S S j i f«n cc &gt;o o i 5 S fe S : - 8i (?i — g- *Q ri S5 S S S K: ffi s* 2 S S S s ' li ■ e ■ 1-1 S 4| S &amp;s I jttft iSS S S — l£ : S ""&gt; :t^r^ tft ■ i oc -^ i co t^ p^ » J _»_ s i * a ! is : ! a a ft i \ii \ !i i [is s O A « V m N 2S O cc Q O T s 1 1 s s I s t«» « \O a IS ! !S2 Ki \t | i^S 8 l»" M a m m X. .-I I i i M j | ; || i I j j ■ : I I j j { j ! Mil i I I I ! I if" I I I i i I a — I f J ■&gt; o a ; i ■ : : ■ : H'n 1 ill] * cr. &lt; 2 ! i i i I i ; I j c } j • i MJ j || j : *t | : j iitl::: : U\\\\ i - - - ■ III i I i fijill </seg>
            <seg id="p011">m - : assa"iia5 3"s"3 J§ « «M" « „" *Q* m I? ({SftSl i. I •M ■H o •• n | n cm" II I ■ 8 « S 8 S 85 88S8 S8 S ■« 5 i a 5- 5 3 S S g S g i I i i3SS"SSS8*"*S a - J rf R I E a s s s ; s s 6 «n \fl f^* o n Q N « N S N V (*9 \O O ts C4 ft s i I 03 [8JS23aS!!fSSS ft RS5SR* . iisassSsssis § sissss 38S8S88SSSS S iS'gSgg [■:::::::. , : : ■ -. • in B 5 M B 5 U | j«U | ! | | I | | ! | N I I I I I 3 m | I i } I j I i iiQij: i : W fid ! t : t 1 ! j '• ! I M I I 1 \\*A I j I 111 1 1 §81331 |f ' i llllillllll Ililil I </seg>
            <seg id="p012">«N6MO&gt;otr«s¥N S 5 it S a S3 R 5 3 » OP »-« ff r* fi V I in 1 SI IS 3 2" B R " * - H T-H p» t-T en •-• &lt;n So a 5 a •ft II 1 1 1 111 II I II II I Illillllll I INIII ! 1 1 1 ! I M II II f ! I ; I I I i j } | ! I 1 I I { I I j I I I" [fllllflc] j I I I J I j i ! I | I ! I i ! i i i ! i i j i Is] Mil ! i I II] I* j I i I ill j P IJJU if i'jilj \{\\ \vv\\\ I iJiMf iJJ 'fiiwl s,..;;* it.: Mi »!: h ii« liiasiilSI iilill U, J j OS K tn U C H O PS P. a ps D O </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 13 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE ALBION BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALBION, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 39 OFFICERS P. A. Krause President W. B. Martin Vice-President K. A. Doten Secretary F. S. Thompson Treasurer O. M. Needham Attorney DIRECTORS P. A. Krause, W. B. Martin, F. A. Doten, F. S. Thompson, R. I. Blatter, W. S. Price, G. K. Pittinger, C. A. Bull, R. T. Flotree, R. C. Burt. John S. Papez. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 194,500.00 Stock Loans 4,900.00 Furniture and Fixtures 11.57 Other Real Estate 3,933.23 Real Estate Sold on Contract 2,130.70 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 633.45 Total I 206,108.95 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends I 173,079.65 Paid-up Stock 17,395.55 Reserve Funds 11,800.00 Undivided Profits 2,466.81 Spec. Reserve for Del. Interest 633.45 Bills Payable 640.00 Treasury Overdrawn _ 83.49 Total % 206,108.95 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS the Year Ending June 30, 1927 the Year Ending Loans made Running stock and June 30, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS $ 27,100.00 dividends 27,674.50 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 21,021.12 Cash on hand last report 4 21.021.12 Loans made $ 27,100.00 Dues (running stock) - - 15,980.99 Dues (running stock) - - 15,980.99 Running stock and dividends 27,674.50 Paid-up stock 23,400.00 Paid-up stock _-.._ 23.400.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 64,241.40 Paid-up stock and dividends 64,241.40 Repayment of Loans 47,100.00 Real estate sales .... :._. 2.200.00_ Repayment of Loans 47,100.00 Expense _ 1,615.09 Expense _ 1.615.09 Real estate sales _ _......-. 2.200.00 2.200.00 Real estate account 5,141.18 Real estate account 5,141.18 Interest, fines, etc. 15,455.35 Interest, fines, etc. 15,455.35 Other disbursements 20,223. 0B Other disbursements 20,223.08 Other receipts 20.837.79 Other receipts 20,837.79 Total $ 145,995.25 Total $ 145,995.25 Total $ 145,995.25 Plan of Association Plan of Association .Formerly Serial now Permanent Formerly Serial now Permanent , . | 100.00 5,722 Shares in force at this date Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock Par value per share of stock. $ 100.00 far value per snare ui siuik » *** ~'ZZ Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 134 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE ALLIANCE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALLIANCE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 118 OFFICERS P. W. Harris President Charles E. Slagle Vice-President M. S. Hargraves Secretary R. E. Knight Treasurer R. O. Reddish Attorney DIRECTORS P. W. Irish, W. C. Mounts, E. D. Henry, Frank Abegg, J. D. Emerick ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 393,185.00 Stock Loans 12,250.00 Purniture and Fixtures 818.49 Liberty Bonds 36,130.44 Cash 23,292.72 Taxes Paid 1,671.93 Insurance Paid 119.18 Total $ 467,467.76 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 333,301.03 Paid-up Stock 117,335.00 Reserve Funds 16,831.73 Total $ 467,467.76 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 3O, 1927 E RECEIPTS n hand last report $ 45,845.54 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 45,845.54 Loans made $ 151,162.78 Loans made $ 151,162.78 Dues (running stock) 51,868.88 running stock) 51,868.88 Running stock and dividends.. 93,845.24 Running stock and dividends.. 93,845.24 Paid-up stock 23,705.00 Repayment of loans 141,412.02 p stock 23,705.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 31,955.15 Paid-up stock and dividends 31,955.15 nent of loans - 141,412.02 Expense 3,480.32 Expense 3,480.32 Interest, fines, etc. _ _ 41,592.01 t, fines, etc. _ _ 41,592.01 Otner disbursements 26,000.28 Otner disbursements 26,000.28 Other receipts 2,020.32 receipts 2,020.32 Total $ 306,443.77 Total $ 306,443.77 Total $ 306,443.77 Total J 306,443.77 Plan of Association. of Association Permanent Permanent Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock is in force at this date No. 5,337,925 $ 200.00 No. 5,337,925 alue per share of stock $ 200.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. red during year. Mos. 118 118 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 15 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE SOUTHEASTERN BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AUBURN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 101 OFFICERS Win. B. Smith President R. E. Harmon Vice-President J. M. Gillan Secretary B. C. Howe Treasurer Edgar Ferneau Attorney DIRECTORS Wm. B. Smith, R. E. Harmon, J. M. Gillan, B. C. Howe, Edgar Ferneau, Geo. E. Codington. ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 375,040.00 Loans in Foreclosure 5,228.54 Stock Loans 341.00 Furniture and Fixtures 400.00 Other Real Estate 14,676.55 Real Estate Sold on Contract 2,493.12 Cash 32,590.74 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 2,757.20 Taxes and Insurance Paid 40.56 Other Assets (Liberty Bonds) _ 1,300.00 Total % 434,867.71 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 99,557.53 Paid-up Stock 304,500.00 Reserve Funds 14,800.00 Undivided Profits 15,945.28 Advance Interest and Premium 64.90 Total % 434,867.71 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 33,306.80 Cash on hand last report $ 33,308.80 Dues (running stock) 33.099.26 Paid-up stock - 107,100.00 Repayment of loans _ 55.485.00 Loans made ™__ $ £7,350.00 Loans made .$ 67,350.00 Dues (running stock) 33.099.26 Running stock and dividends.. 30,025.86 Running stock and dividends.. 30.02S.86 Paid-up stock - 107,100.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 116,431.63 Paid-up stock and dividends 116,431.63 Repayment of loans _ 55.485.00 Expense 6,107.52 Expense 6,107.52 Real estate account 3,073.28 Other disbursements 34,423.59 Real estate account 3,073.28 Interest, fines, etc - 26,500.02 Interest, fines, etc - 26,500.02 Other receipts 1,918.80 Other receipts 1,918.80 Other disbursements 34,423.59 Total t 257,411.88 Total — $ 257,411.88 Total _ 4 257,411.88 Total _ 4 257,411.88 Permanent Plan of Association Plan of Association Shares in Force at this date Shares in Force at this date . Par value per share of stock. .No. Par value per share of stock * 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Class "A" months 84 Class "B" months _ 144 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE AURORA BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION AURORA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 119 OFFICERS B. A. Munson President W. E. Reber Vice-President Jas. Schoonover Secretary Jas. Schoonover Treasurer J. H. Grosvenor Attorney DIRECTORS B. A. Munson, W. E. Reber, E. C. Rhinehart, J. A. Isaman, H. E. Newton, T. R. Work, G. R. Blomstrand, Arnold P. Isaacson, Jas. Schoonover. ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 116,800.00 Furniture and Fixtures 170.20 Cash : 1,292.46 Taxes Paid 1,397.56 Total $ 119,660.22 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 61,643.14 Paid-up Stock 54,450.00 Reserve Funds 2,883.16 "Undivided Profits 683.92 Total $ 119,660.22 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1027 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report - 4 3,102.96 Loans made __$ 15,500.00 Dues (running stock) 16,849.72 Running stock and dividends.. 12,585.64 Paid-up stock 10,950.00 Repayment on loans _-.. 4,690.00 Interest, fines, etc. 8,063.59 Paid-up stock and dividends 12,160.53 Expense _ 779.71 8,063.59 Other disbursements 2,890.02 Other receipts 259.63 Total $ 43,915.90 Total 4 43,915.90 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date.. Par value per share of stock No. 256% ..$ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 127 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 17 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE BEATRICE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 124 OFFICERS C. P. Pall President Ernst Schaekel Vice- President F. H. Graf Secretary F. B. Sheldon Treasurer F. B. Sheldon Attorney DIRECTORS H. E. Sackett, Ernst Schaekel, C. P. Fall. ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 944,643.00 Loans in Foreclosure 10,750.00 Stock Loans 550.00 Other Real Estate 7,500.00 Real Estate Sold on Contract 370.85 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 3,800.00 Cash 117,447.57 Agents Accounts 2,069.85 Total _ , $ 1,087,131.27 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 434,326.13 Paid-up Stock 602,650.00 Incomplete Loans 5,155.14 Reserve Funds 45,000.00 Total $ 1,087,131.27 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS the Year Ending June 80, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS Loans made _4 121,600.00 Running stock and dividends- 145,049.83 the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 83,417.37 Cash on hand last report $ 83,417.37 Loans made ._..._ % 121,600.00 Dues (running stock) 156,089.88 Dues (running stock) 156,089.88 Running stock and dividends- 145,049.83 Paid-up stock 124,850.00 Repayment of loans 124,682.00 Real estate sales 5,000.00 Paid-up stock Paid-up stock 124,850.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 146,159.13 Paid-up stock and dividends 146,159.13 Repayment of loans 124,682.00 Expense Expense 8,881.13 8,881.13 Real estate sales 5,000.00 5,000.00 Real estate account 12,500.00 Real estate account 12,500.00 Other disbursements 156,709.10 Other disbursements 156,709.10 Interest, fines, etc. 66,617.63 Interest, fines, etc. 66,617.63 Other receipts 30,242.31 Other receipts 30,242.31 Total $ 590,899.19 Total $ 590,899.19 Total $ 590,899.19 Total $ 590,899.19 Plan of Association Plan of Association „ Permanent No. 29.162 % _ $ 100.00 Permanent .No. 29,162% Shares in force at this date.. Par value per share of stock.. Shares in force at this date... Par value per share of stock 4 ioo.oo </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 145 OFFICERS Philip Graff President J. E. Lang Vice-President M. F. Eickmann Secretary Carl Sonderegger Treasurer Rinaker, Kidd and Delehant Attorneys DIRECTORS Philip Graff, J. E. Lang, Carl Sonderegger, Henry T. Jurgens, John W. Delehant. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 1,205,124.46 Loans in Foreclosure 17,300.00 Office Building 8,500.00 Other Real Estate 12,892.75 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 6,576.95 Cash _ 38,910.72 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 5,615.28 Tax Sale Certificates 16,113.93 Certificates of Deposit 58,000.00 Court Costs Advanced 163.91 Total I 1,369,198.00 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 664,511.80 Paid-up Stock 636,725.00 Incomplete Loans 438.00 Reserve Funds 28,000.00 Undivided Profits 39,523.20 Total $ 1,369,198.00 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report 4 38,533.92 Cash on hand last report 4 38,533.92 Loans made _ .$ 98,529.02 Loans made _ .$ 98,529.02 Dues (running stock) 287,037.78 Dues (running stock) 287,037.78 Running stock and dividends- 225,580.23 Running stock and dividends- 225,580.23 Paid-up stock 137,225.00 Repayment of loans 95,260.23 Real estate sales 994.74 Paid-up stock _.__ 137,225.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 182,961.32 Paid-up stock and dividends 182,961.32 Repayment of loans 95,260.23 Expense _ _ ll.sii.? Expense Expense _ _ ll.^iv? Real estate account 3,776.43 Other disbursements 230,991.95 Real estate sales 994.74 994.74 Real estate account 3,776.43 Interest, fines, etc. 87,381.81 Interest, fines, etc. 87,381.81 Other disbursements 230,991.95 230,991.95 Other receipts 106,920.74 Other receipts 106,920.74 Total ! $ 753,354.22 Total $ 753,354.22 Total $ 753,354.22 Total $ 753,354.22 Plan of Association Plan of Association Permanent Permanent Shares in force at this date . Par value per share of stock. Shares in force at this date -No. 27,861 V* $ 100.00 .No. 27,861% Par value per share of stock $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. red during year. Mos. 130 130 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">\ BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 19 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 112 OFFICERS A. H. Kidd President W. C. Black Vice-President E. L. Hevelone Secretary L. C. Crittenden Assistant Secretary E. L. Hevelone Treasurer Rinaker, Kldd &amp; Delehant Attorneys DIRECTORS A. H. Kidd, W. C. Black, E. L. Hevelone, H. L. Dempster, D. G. Mc- Gaffey ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 5,825,775.00 Loans in Foreclosure 74,234.84 Stock Loans 18,535.00 Furniture and Fixtures 1.00 Other Real Estate 62,668.68 Real Estate Sold on Contract 45,909.42 Cash 155,392.14 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 11,967.07 Total $ 6,194,483.15 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 3,776,833.84 Paid-up Stock 1,590,925.00 Incomplete Loans 17,850.98 Reserve Funds 207,206.15 Undivided Profits 174,386.68 Reserve for Taxes 776.70 Home Office Building Account 5,000.00 Savings Stock and Dividends 421,503.80 Total $ 6,194,483.15 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report A 268.W6.O3 Loans made 4 1,458,579.39 Loans made $ 1,458,579.39 Cash on hand last report $ 268.W6.03 Dues (running stock) - - 939,691.31 Dues (running stock) - 939,691.31 Running stock and dividends.. 494,572.74 Running stock and dividends.. 494,572.74 Paid-up stock 304,500.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 501,160.23 Paid-up stock 304,500.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 501,160.23 Repayment of loans 773,292.21 Repayment of loans 773,292.21 Real estate sales 11,815.14 Expense _ 42,121.51 Expense - _ - 42,121.51 Real estate account _-. 10,281.18 Other disbursements 364,170.60 Real estate sales 11,815.14 11,815.14 Real estate account _-. 10,281.18 Interest, fines, etc - 361,874.84 Interest, fines, etc 361,874.84 Other disbursements 364,170.60 Other receipts 211,666.12 Other receipts 211,666.12 Total $ 2,870,885.65 Total $ 2,870,885.65 Total $ 2,870,885.65 Total $ 2,870,885.65 Plan of Association Plan of Association Permanent Permanent Shares in force at this date Shares in force at this date . Par value per share of stock. No. 177,549 Vt, No. 177,549% Par value per share of stock _ $ 100.00 $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. red during year. Mos. 118 118 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE BLAIR BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BLAIR, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 67 OFFICERS J. S. Roberts '. President P. W. Arndt Vice- President S. W. Chambers Secretary W. Chambers Treasurer Reed O'Hanlon Attorney DIRECTORS J. S. Roberts, F. W. Arndt, S. W. Chambers, Reed O'Hanlon, Ed. Matthiesen, John McKay, J. H. Stewart. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 130,889.00 Other Real Estate 4,071.11 Real Estate Sold on Contract 7,250.00 Securities, Tax Sale Ctfs 3,560.7 5 Cash 2,963.93 Total $ 148,734.79 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 48,204.64 Paid-up Stock 90,800.00 Reserve Funds 4,500.00 Undivided Profits _ 5,047.65 Due F. W. Arndt on Hall Contract 182.50 Total $ 148,734.79 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 9,775.71 Leans made _ _$ ■ 19,300.00 Dues (running stock) _ 21,606.48 Running stock and dividends.. 16,355.31 Paid-up stock 8,200.00 Repayment of loans 14,425.00 Paid-up stock Paid-up stock and dividends 17,551.91 14,425.00 Expense 1,730.12 Real estate account 3,954.04 Expense Real estate sales 1,390.85 3,954.04 Interest, fines, etc. 11,114.79 Other disbursements 9,026.30 Other receipts __ 1,402.85 Total i 67,917.68 Total .$ 67,917.68 Shares in force at this date No. 307 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 115 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE KNOX COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BLOOMFIELD, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 155 OFFICERS E. H. Mason President J. J. McCourt Vice-President H. F. Friedrichs Secretary H. F. Friedrichs Treasurer W. D. Funk Attorney DIRECTORS H. L. Andresen, A. C. E. Filter, J. J. Killackey, Win. Busskohl, John Volkers, E. H. Mason, J. J. McCourt, H. F. Friedrichs, Wm. Krohn. ASSETS Mortgage Loans ? 81,475.00 Stock Loans 2,930.00 Furniture and Fixtures „ 256.85 Real Estate Sold on Contract _ 2,850.00 Cash f,2A«.97 Taxes Paid „ _ _ T54.80 Taxes Paid Total $ 93,887.62 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 61,929.06 Paid-up Stock „ 27,900.00 Reserve Funds • 775.00 Undivided Profits 3,283.56 Total * 93,887.62 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June SO, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Dues (running stock $ 19,331.93 Dues (running stock $ 19,331.93 Loans made ~J$ 20,465.00 Loans made $ 20,465.00 uues siock -^ j»,.wi.7o Paid-up stock 12,600.00 Repayment of loans 3,325.00 Interest, fines, etc 5,679.26 Paid-up stock 12,600.00 Running stock and dividends.. 7,192.92 Running stock and dividends.. 7,192.92 Repayment of loans 3,325.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 4,000.85 Paid-up stock and dividends 4,000.85 Interest, fines, etc 5,679.26 5,679.25 Expense ** 730.27 Expense *- 730.27 Other receipts 600.35 Other receipts 600.35 Other disbursements 9,147.50 Other disbursements 9.147.S0 Total $ 41,536.54 Total $ 41,536.54 Total $ 41,536.54 Total $ 41,536.54 Plan of Association Plan of Association Permanent Permanent Shares in force at this date. Par value per share of stock.. Shares in force at this date .No 196 Par value per share of stock , -. , 1 100.00 4 ioo.oo </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE BROKEN BOW BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BROKEN BOW, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 173 OFFICERS W. A. Baldwin President A. F. Mackie Secretary DIRECTORS M. M. Runyan, W. L. Schnabel, C. R. Luce, Win. C. Schaper ASSETS Mortgage Loans ? 15,306.73 Cash 202.79 Other Assets 174.20 Total $ 15,683.72 I LIABILITIES unning Stock and Dividends $ 8,121.46 LIABILITIES Paid-up Stock 6,600.00 Reserve Funds 50.00 Undivided Profits 78.41 Bills Payable 500.00 Membership 60.50 Dividends 273.35 Total * 15,683.72 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report _$ 297.30 Cash on hand last report $ 297.30 Loans made 4 13,550.00 Loans made _ $ 13,550.00 Dues (running stock) 6,838.02 Paid-up stock 5,600.01 Dues (running stock) 6,838.02 Running stock and dividends.. 222.26 Running stock and dividends.. 222.26 B-up stock 5,600.01 yment of loans 536.91 Paid-up stock and dividends 296.13 Paid-up stock and dividends 2%. 13 Repayment of loans Other receipts 536.91 Expense 334.80 Other disbursements 2,352.79 Total * 16,755.98 Expense 334.80 r receipts 3,483.75 3,483.75 Other disbursements 2,352.79 Total 4 16,755.98 Total $ 16,755.98 Total * 16,755.98 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE LONE TREE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CENTRAL CITY, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 165 OFFICERS Rob't. Rice President M. A. Larson Vice-President T. W. Lock Secretary T. W. Lock Treasurer P. S. Heaton Attorney DIRECTORS Rob't. Rice, M. A. Larson, A. N. Johnson, Fred Fouts, T. W. Lock. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 45,950.00 Cash 5,162.15 Taxes Paid _ 31.43 Total % 51,143.58 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 17,917.39 Paid-up Stock 32,950.00 Reserve Funds 202.35 Undivided ProBts 73.84 Total t 51,143.58 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year KniUng June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 588.36 Cash on hand last report —$ 588.56 Loans made I_$ 28,850.00 Loans made $ 28,850.00 Dues (running stock) 12,800.86 Dues (running stock) 12,800.86 Running stock and dividends.. 4,630.96 Running stock and dividends.. 4,630.96 Paid-up stock 22,150.00 Paid-up stock 22,150.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 1,092.24 Paid-up stock and dividends 1,092.24 Repayment of loans 2,200.00 Repayment of loans 2,200.00 Expense 1,055.29 Interest, fines, etc. 3,143.82 Interest, fines, etc. 3,143.82 Other disbursements 5,293.70 Other receipts 38.95 Other receipts 38.95 Total * 40,922.19 Total $ 40,922.19 Total t 40,922.19 Total t 40,922.19 Permanent Permanent Plan of Association Plan of Association Par value per share of stock Par value per share of stock. ..» 100.00 $ 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE ENTERPRISE LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION CAMBRIDGE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 131 OFFICERS R. H. Rankin President Williams Vice-President L. Rankin Secretary S. Keith Treasurer ler &amp; James Attorneys DIRECTORS W. H. Faling, D. F. Neiswanger, James John, C. M. Brown, R. H. Rankin, Geo. Williams, J. H. McKean, A. E. Thorndike, A. A. Mousel ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 126,150.00 Cash _ 3,357.79 3,357.79 - o ,oo i . i ;» Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 125.08 Taxes Paid 494.70 Insurance Paid „ 129.20 494.70 129.20 ■ Total $ 130,256.77 LIABILITIES LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 107,445.78 Incomplete Loans „_...__ 800.00 Reserve Funds 1,597.27 Undivided Profits 3,289.80 Loan Stock _ 17,123.92 Total „ _ $ 130,256.77 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending June 30, 1927 I RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 2,780.12 Loans made _.$ 43,697.85 Dues (running stock). Running stock and dividends, Paid-up stock 58,976.69 Paid-up stock 36,323.52 Repayment of loans 18,255.70 Expense 973.45 Interest, fines, etc. 8,822.11 Other disbursements 8,018.20 Other receipts 178.40 Total $ 89,013.02 | Total $ 89,013.02 ■ Plan of Association Shares in force at this date Permanent .No. 3,348 Par value per share of stock % 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 81% </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 * STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE CHADRON BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CHADRON, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 160 OFFICERS Edwin D. Crites President Charles P. Coffee, Jr _ Vice-President Charles F. Coffee, Jr. B. F. Pitman Secretary-Treasurer Edwin D. Crites .' Attorney DIRECTORS Edwin D. Crites, Charles F. Coffee, Jr., B. F. Pitman, Willis Schenck, Oscar S. Renfro. -&lt;£jL ASSETS «^ Mortgage Loans * 179,100.00 Loans in Foreclosure 4,200.00 Stock Loans 1,610.00 Furniture and Fixtures 224. Other Real Estate 4,086.1 Cash _ 17,167.77 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 356.70 Taxes Paid 1,645.32 Insurance Paid for Customers 48.00 Total I 208,437.94 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends _ % 93,938.37 Paid-up Stock 82,400.00 Incomplete Loans „ 857.00 Reserve Funds 4,750.00 Undivided Profits _ 6,746.04 Trust Account _ 10.38 Prepaid or Cumulative Stock 19,735,15 Total _ $ 208,437.94 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 3,513.77 Cash on hand last report $ 3,513.77 Loans made $ 42,850.00 Loans made — ._ $ 42, 850. TO Runing stock and dividends.. 33.175.2S Paid-up stock and dividends 28.32S.29 Expense 1,618.54 Real estate account 1,909.89 Dues (running stock) _._ 51.231.S4 Dues (running stock) _._ 51.231.S4 Runing stock and dividends.. 33.175.2S Paid-up stock , 38,050.00 Repayment of loans 26,277.50 Interest, fines, etc. 15,221.49 Paid-up stock 38,050.00 Paid-up stock and dividends 28.32S.29 Repayment of loans 26,277.50 Expense 1,618.54 1,618.54 Interest, fines, etc. 15,221.49 Real estate account 1,909.89 1,909.89 50,404.34 Other receipts 23,989.01 Total $ 158,283.31 Other receipts 23,989.01 Total $ 158,283.11 Other disbursements 50,404.34 Other disbursements Total $ 158,283.31 Total $ 158,283.31 Plan of Association Plan of Association Permanent Permanent Shares in force at this date.... Par value per share of stock Shares in force at this date — —^% iKS ..No. 5,135 Par value per share of stock ..% 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE CLAY CENTER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CLAY CENTER, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 92 OFFICERS C. D. EIHb President N. W. Johnson ~ Vice- President H. B. Campbell Secretary H. B. Campbell Treasurer DIRECTORS Geo. S. Ward, E. W. Orr, J. W. Whitlam, Jas. T. Johnson, W. A. Ward, H. B. Campbell ASSETS Mortgage Loans I 41,100.00 Other Real Estate 957.23 Cash 709.89 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 411.59 Total $ 43,178.71 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 27,746.53 Paid-up Stock 11,500.00 Reserve Funds 2,300.00 Undivided Profits 1,632.18 Total : $ 43,178.71 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS the Year Ending June SO, 1927 the Year Ending June 3O, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS Loans made ._ .$ 8,550.00 Running stock and dividends.. 23,788.66 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 5,292.42 Cash on hand last report $ 5,292.42 Loans made .$ 8,550.00 Dues (running stock) 9,753.00 Dues (running stock) 9,753.00 Running stock and dividends.. 23,788.66 Paid-up stock 15,400.00 Repayment of loans 13,250.00 Interest, fines, etc. 4,439.99 Paid-up stock 15,400.00 Paid-up stock and dividends ..'.' 14,595.94 Paid-up stock and dividends ... 14,595.94 Repayment of loans 13,250.00 Expense ____— 373.36 Expense 373.36 Real estate account 54.81 Other disbursements 772.55 Interest, fines, etc. ■■ 4,439.9* Total $ 48,135.32 4,439.98 Real estate account 54.81 Other disbursements 772.55 772.55 Total $ 48,135.32 Total $ 48,135.32 Total $ 48,135.32 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date No. 948 Par value per share of stock $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 73 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE COLUMBUS LAND, LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 21 OFFICERS D. W. Viergutz President L. F. Gottschalk Vice-President Henry Hockenberger Secretary Gus G. Becker Treasurer DIRECTORS E. P. Dussell, C. C. Hardy, J. W. Herrod, J. H. Galley, Jacob Louis. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 1,094, 800. (To ASSETS Loans in Foreclosure 2,820.18 Stock Loans 2,500.00 Other Real Estate 2,171.77 Real Estate Sold on Contract 843.37 Cash : 22,259. 48 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 3,486.30 Total % 1,128,881.05 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends , $ 397,006.50 Paid-up Stock 705,700.00 Reserve Funds 26,158.44 Undivided Profits 16.11 Total $ 1,128, 881. OS Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 12,771.82 Loans made ._ .4 418,800.00 Dues (running stock) 148,907.32 Running stock and dividends.. 125,881 18 Paid-up stock - 193,100.00 Repayment of loans 317,800.00 Paid-up stock and dividends- 167,157.59 Expense . 7,252.75 Real estate account 3t7.G7 Real estate sales 127. do Interest, fines, etc 72,011.52 Other disbursements 56,825.44 Other receipts 31,565.87 Total 776,284.03 Total __$ 776,284.03 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date - Par value per share of stock ..No. 23,393 T 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE ABLE BUILDING, LOAN &amp; SAVINGS ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 126 OFFICERS Henry Ragatz President I. Speice „ Vice-President C. Echols Secretary A. Boettcher Treasurer DIRECTORS Henry Ragatz, W. I. Speice, J. C. Echols, W. A. Boettcher, Louis Lightner. ASSETS Loans * 1,161,250.00 Loans _ _ 500.00 Real Estate 1,959.23 Estate Sold on Contract 3,797.20 1, State and Municipal Securities, Liberty Bonds 1,950.00 20,396.25 it Interest, Fines, Etc 3,292.17 Paid 562.31 Total % 1,193,707.16 LIABILITIES Stock and Dividends $ 446,294.60 Stock _ 707,400.00 ste Loans 2,800.00 Funds 33,868.84 33,868.84 Undivided Profits 3.343.72 Total $ 1,193,707.16 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June SO, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS on hand last report $ 19,649.58 Loans made $ 219,500.00 (running stock) 198,865.66 Running stock and dividends.. 153,968.00 up stock 86,600.00 Paid-up stock and dividends. 149,436.87 Loans made 5 219,500.00 :k _ 86,600.00 Paid-up stock and dividends! 149i43s;87 of loans 176,975.00 Expense _.___ 10,411.16 estate sales 3.43S.53 Real estate account 7,104.71 tst, fines, etc. 80,670.56 Other disbursements 41,108.34 receipts : 15,322.75 Total $ 581,519.08 I Total S 581,519.08 of Association Permanent is in force at this date _ .No. 25,350 % B value per share of stock $ 100.00 age running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 116 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE GLOBE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION COLUMBUS, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 157 OFFICERS Theo. Moersen President John L. Pittman Vice-President P. P. Luchsinger Secretary H. A. Viergutz Treasurer Albert &amp; Wagner Attorneys DIRECTORS Theo. Moersen, John L. Pittman, P. F. Luchsinger, H. A. Viergutz, Josef Fischer, Carl Roelle, John Hinklemann, W. J. Wass, Robert Pohlner. ASSETS Mortgage Loans _ S 284,600.00 Stock Loans 3,400.00 Office Building 5,500.00 Furniture and Fixtures 1,100.00 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 28,000.00 Cash „ 16,882.68 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 1,217.45 Total $ 340,700.13 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends _ % 93,214.36 Paid-up Stock _ 239,700.00 Incomplete Loans 1,916.75 Reserve Funds 5,050.00 Undivided Profits 819.02 Total $ 340,700.13 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 80, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report 4 12,081.02 Loans made . $ 65,400.00 Running stock and dividends- 34,656.80 Paid-up stock and dividends- 46.754.89 Dues (running stock) 42,163.15 Paid-up stock 25,400.00 Repayment of loans 72,000.00 Interest, fines, etc. 24,366.63 Paid-up stock Expense 2,521.00 24,366.63 Real estate account 220.92 Other receipts 10,379.42 Total * 186,390.22 Other disbursements 36,836.61 Total $ 186,390.22 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date .. Par value per share of stock .No. 6,691 .1 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year, Class "A", months 62 Class "B" months 1 8 v»ww _~ , —aw — m~~* ......... . ............ null a I t H ' </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION CRETE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 117 OFFICERS Robert R. Hastings President Ed. M. Parker Vice-President W. S. Collett Secretary .Secretary W. 3. Collett Treasurer Robert R. Hastings Attorney DIRECTORS Robert R. Hastings, Gerard V. Rademacher, Thomas J. Dredla, Ed. M. Parker, B. G. Miller, J. G. Miller, R. M. Pflasterer, W. S. Collett. V. J. Shebl. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 224,550.00 3,710.00 116.33 4.061.10 693.38 2,043.70 196.09 $ 235,370.60 $ 161,796.15 66,327.15 425.94 5,976.28 845.08 $ 235,370.60 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1027 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report _ 4 5,237.05 Loans made - $ 51,365.00 Dues (running stock) 33,974.50 Running stock and dividends.. 42,325.17 Paid-up stock 191,341.17 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 189,232.26 Repayment of loans 44.515.00 Expense 3,037.47 Interest, fines, etc. ' 15,522.85 Other disbursements 7,912.27 Other receipts 3,281.60 Total $ 293,872.17 Total % 293,872.17 Serial 6,089 100.00 Plan of Association.. Shares in force at this date .. Par value per share of stock. .No. % Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 138 Stock Loans Furniture and Fixtures Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc Taxes Paid Other Assets (Insurance) ■ Total LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends Paid-up Stock Incomplete Loans Reserve Funds Undivided Profits Total </seg>
            <seg id="p031">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 31 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE CULBERTSON BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CULBERTSON, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 166 OFFICERS G. G. Eisenhart President Peter Spahn _ Vice-President Jos. Heizenreter Secretary O. P. Simon Treasurer DIRECTORS G. G. Eisenhart, Peter Spahn, Jos. Heizenreter, O. P. Simon, Ed. Wacker, Henry Kleven, J. M. Crews, J. Brantley, M. M. Bree. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 30,600.00 Stock Loans 2,190.00 Cash 1,816.49 Total $ 34,606.49 LIABILITIES Running Sto^k and Dividends ■- $ 34,269.67 Reserve Funds , 313.61 Undivided Profits , 23.21 Total $ 34,606.49 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending June SO, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS I lans made $ 10,190.00 I ians made $ 10,190.00 Cash on hand last report $ 2,125.97 Cash on hand last report % 2,125.97 ? inning stock and dividends- 4,223.45 'Expense _..... 138.34 ? inning stock and dividends- 4,223.45 Hues (running stock) 10.79S.44 Dues (running stock) - 10,795.44 Repayment of loans 870.00 Repayment of loans 870.00 Interest, fines, etc. 2,576.87 870.00 'Expense — — — — . 138.34 Interest, fines, etc. 2,576.87 Other disbursements 1,816.49 Other disbursements 1,816.49 Total , 4 16,368.28 Total . ..% 16,368.28 Total $ 16,368.28 Total $ 16,368.28 Plan of Association Plan of Association. ZZZZZZIno! Se m * loo.oo Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock. Shares in force at this date ..No Par value per share of stock * 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">OFFICERS C. F. Clark President Krahl Vice-President J. Stead Secretary F. Havelka Treasurer Roper &amp; Fuller Attorneys DIRECTORS C. F. Clark, George Krabl, R. F. Havelka, L. B. Fuller, W. J. Stead. G. A. Bryant, S. J. Hyatt, G. M. Diextra, J. S. Harper. ASSETS Mortgage Loans ...$ 407,700.00 Loans in Foreclosure 3,200.00 Other Real Estate 24,062.09 Real Estate Sold on Contract 2,183.90 Cash 18,707.99 Taxes Paid 2,409.08 Advance Costs, Foreclosure 219.20 Office Supplies _ 25.00 Total % 458,507.26 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 97,802.55 Paid-up Stock 348,935.32 Incomplete Loans 2,251.98 Reserve Funds .' 6,486.03 Undivided Profits 2,504.63 Real Estate Contract •- 526.75 Total _ $ 458,507.26 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending June 80, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS on hand last report t 13,607.31 Loans made . , „.$ 195,200.00 ■ .iirfii &gt; III aUC i i i 9 ]yj ( ,tUl/. UL* Running stock and dividends.. 61,096.93 (running stock) 73,468.86 ics (running siockj ...... /j.'wo.oo lid-up stock 228,363.75 Paid-up stock and dividends'. 135,509.42 lyraent of loans __——- _ 108,100.00 Expense 14,299.11 estate sales 238.25 Real estate account 24,062.09 Other disbursements 30,520.88 Interest, fines, etc. Other receipts 32,505.61 4,406.65 Total $ 460,690.43 Total $ 460,690.43 Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date .No. 10,139.35 Par value per share of stock. $ 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">ANTELOPE COUNTY BUILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION ELGIN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 169 OFFICERS Geo. N. Seymour _ President Henry B. McCampbell Secretary R. C. Huffman Treasurer Ralph Kyger Attorney DIRECTORS Geo. N. Seymour, Henry B. McCampbell, R. C. Huffman, E. W. Lehr, J. D. McCarthy. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 12,350.00 Stock Loans 100.00 Cash 343.91 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 73.33 Total $ 12,867.23 LIABILITIES Runing Stock and Dividends $ 3,317.26 Paid-up Stock 8,900.00 Undivided Profits 649.97 Total I 12,867.23 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1027 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 1,133.96 Cash on hand last report J$ 1,133.96 Loans made —■ ■ -..$ 1,850.00 Loans made - $ 1.850.00 Dues (running stock) 1.269.78 Dues (running stock) 1,269.78 Running stock and dividends.. 551.40 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 4,397.92 Running stock and dividends.. 551.40 Paid-up stock 3,800.00 Paid-up stock 3,800.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 4,397.92 Interest, lines, etc 869.19 Interest, lines, etc 869.19 Expense ..- _ 99.72 Expense .._ _ _... 99.72 Other receipts — ___ 243.40 Other receipts — 243.40 Other disbursements 417.31 Other disbursements 417.31 Total :.-.$ 7,316.35 Total :._$ 7,316.35 Total $ 7.316.JS Plan of Association Plan of Association. Permanent Permanent 373% Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock. 373% Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock - $ 100.00 ? 100.00 • ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE FAIRBURY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FAIRBURY, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 117 OFFICERS H. Diller President E. L. Simpkins Vice- President F. A. Houston Secretary Emma Conerus Assistant Secretary 8. R. Merrell Treasurer F. L. Rain Attorney DIRECTORS E. L. Simpkins, S. R. Merrell, S. H. Diller, C. B. Porter, J. W. Buswell, F. A. Houston, F. L. Rain, J. A. Axtell, H. E. Potter. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 415,450.00 Loans in Foreclosure 2,150.00 Furniture and Fixtures 494.00 Registered Warrants : 60.00 Tax Sale Certificates 1,493.38 Cash 25,822.73 Total % 445,470.11, LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 324,348.71 n.u ■ o* i- i i o ooc en Paid-up Stock 112,286.50 Reserve Funds 8,100.00 Undivided Profits 734.90 Total - $ 445,470.11 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1027 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report - S 4,043.07 Loans made -...$ 81.950.30 Dues (running stock) - 105,427.48 Running stock and dividends- 88,900.66 Paid-up stock 40,100.03 Paid-up stock and dividends. 32,848.50 54,300.00 ! Expense - Repayment of loans - 54,300.00 Interest, fines, etc 29,699.85 1.921.82 29,699.85 j Other disbursements -..-. 27,949.12 Total % 233,570.40 Total ...4 233,570.40 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock. .No. 9,971 $ 100.00 77 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 35 STATEMENT OF THE CbNDITION OF THE HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION PAIRBURY, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 156 OFFICERS B. G. Dawson President George White ....Vice-President C. J. Bachoritch Secretary L. S. Rasse Treasurer E. A. Wunder Attorney DIRECTORS George Busboom, E. L. Jenkins ASSETS Mortgage Loans , $ 324,110.68 Real Estate Sold on Contract 1,050.00 Tax Sale Certificates _ 2,083.49 Cash 4,661.98 Paid Stock Dividends 3.53 Total $ 331,909.88 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends f 194,907.06 Paid-up Stock 131,450.00 Reserve Funds 4,000.00 Undivided Profits 1,552.62 Total $ 331,909.68 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 3O, 1027 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report 4 729.88 Dues (running stock) 107,698.00 Cash on hand last report 4 729.88 Loans made _ $ 89,337.43 Loans made _ $ 89,337.43 Dues (running stock) 107,698.00 Running stock and dividends.. 87,617.10 Running stock and dividends.. 87,617.10 Paid-up stock ._ 55,500.0] Repayment of loans 48.140.00 Paid-up stock 55,500.03 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 47,779.89 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 47,779.89 Repayment of loans 48,140.00 48.140.00 Expense - 4,165.88 Real estate account 114.57 Expense - 4,165.88 Interest, fines, etc. 22,016.94 Real estate account 114.57 Interest, fines, etc. 22,016.96 Other receipts 1,779.34 Other receipts 1,779.34 Other disbursements - 6,849.31 Other disbursements 6,849.31 Total 9 235,864.18 Total $ 235,864.18 Total . 4 235,864.18 Total _ 4 235,864.18 Plan of Association Plan of Association. Permanent Permanent Shares in force at this date Shares in force at this date .No. No. 8,834% </seg>
            <seg id="p036">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HOME BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION PALLS CITY, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 138 OFFICERS R. R. Rule President jn. xv. uuic r icsiucul W. G. Goldner Vice-President W. L. Redwood Secretary L. P. Wirth Treasurer Treasurer R. C. James Attorney DIRECTORS R. R. Rule, W. G. Goldner, W. L. Redwood, L. P. Wirth, Wm. Uhlig. ■ Mortgage Loans Loans in Foreclosure O*~-l. T — — — _ ASSETS .$ 347.S50.00 4,500.00 P: Loans 4,315.00 iture and Fixtures 394.46 • Real Estate 8.585.72 19,569.97 quent Interest, Fines, Etc 1,482.00 i Paid and Insurance Premium Paid 889.90 Total $ 387,587.05 T/TARIOTITCK 4,315.00 394.46 8.585.72 19,569.97 1,482.00 % 387,587.05 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 143,662.64 nuuuiug oium diiu _-*i v iucuud -.-------.-..——-.- — ....... j. -x &lt;j, v \i ** . u Paid-up Stock 227,100.00 Incomplete Loans 4,325.00 227,100.00 Reserve Funds 4,170.26 ■ Undivided Profits 6,847.15 rtaHnmmnt Tntavoot 1 -. S 9 ftft Delinquent Interest 1,482.00 Total $ 387,587.05 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS the Year Ending June 30, 1927 the Year Ending Loans made June 30, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS $ 116,619.50 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on band last report $ 23,396.91 Dues (running stock) _ - 52,306.60 Paid-up stock 66.412.00 Repayment of loans 72,880.00 Cash on band last report $ 23,396.91 Loans made $ 116,619.50 Dues (running stock) 52,306.60 Running stock and dividends.. 27,138.05 Running stock and dividends.. 27,138.05 Paid-up stock - 66,412.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 63,590.30 Paid-up stock and dividends- 63,590.30 Expense 3.848.55 Expense 3.848.55 Repayment of loans __..____ 72,880.00 Repayment oi loans _____ /..oou.uj Real estate sales 42.00 Real estate sales 42.00 Real estate account 7,677.72 Real estate account 7,677.72 Other disbursements - 23,827.90 Other disbursements 23,827.90 Interest, fines, etc. 24,830.13 Other receipts 2,834.38 Other receipts 2,834.38 Total * 242,702.02 Total % 242,702.02 Total 4 242,702.02 Total ..$ 242,702.02 Plan of Association Permanent 100.00 in </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 3 OFFICERS Frank Hammond President Frank Fowler '"".".'.Vice-president .Vice-President Jas. A. Donahue _ Secretary Chas. B. Veazie _ Treasurer .Treasurer George L. Loomis Attorney DIRECTORS Frank Hammond, Frank Fowler, Jas. A. Donahue, Chas. B. Veazie, George L. Loomis, Fred Bader, Frank Hanlon, John C. Hein, Will R. Rowe. ASSETS Mortgage Loans :...% 1,768,500.00 Loans in Foreclosure 9,053.64 Office Building 11,000.00 Cash 46,041.66 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 3,117.60 Total $ 1,837,712.90 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 770,207.10 Paid-up Stock .-. 1,027,190.00 Incomplete Loans 4,039.22 Reserve Funds 34,500.00 Undivided Profits 1,776.58 Total % 1,837,712.90 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year finding June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 3,968.70 Cash on hand last report $ 3,968.70 Loans made _ 4 470,300.00 Loans made 4 470,300.00 Dues (running stock) — 513,339.84 Paid-up stock 259,400.00 Repayment of loans 309,300.00 Dues (running stock) — 513,339.84 Running stock and dividends- 408,133.89 Running stock and dividends- 408,133.89 Paid-up stock 259,400.00 Paid-up stock and dividends- 305, 765. OS Paid-up stock and dividends. 305,765.05 Expense 8,483.09 Repayment of loans 309,300.00 Interest, fines, etc 121,644.46 Interest, fines, etc 121,644.46 Other disbursements 139,140.85 Other disbursements 139,140.85 Other receipts 124,169.88 Other receipts 124,169.88 Total .._ $ 1,331,822.88 Total $ 1,331,822.88 Total $ 1,331,822.88 Total $ 1,331,822.88 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date No. 36,018 Par value per share of stock $200.00 and $100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 117 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NEBRASKA STATE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FREMONT NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 55 OFFICERS Dave Rowe President Dan V. Stephens Vice-President G. A. Olmsted Secretary A. J. Eddy Treasurer W. J. Courtright Attorney DIRECTORS T. L. Mathews, Dave Rowe, Dan V. Stephens, Paul Colson, G. A. Olmsted, A. J. Eddy, Chas. H. Hawley, W. J. Courtright, S. S. Sidner. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 5,031,859.09 Loans in Foreclosure 29,469.95 Stock Loans 25,598.00 Office Building 55,093.77 Other Real Estate 129,614.05 Real Estate Sold on Contract 25,113.88 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 243,485.10 Cash 146,842.90 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 11,491.12 Taxes Paid 18,239.75 Total $ 5,716,807.61 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 2,260,610.93 Paid-up Stock _ 3,134,600.00 Incomplete Loans 13,123.91 Reserve Funds '. 200,000.00 Undivided Profits 108,472.77 Total $ 5,716,807.61 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 3O, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report _$ 56,340.56 Loans made _ _...$ 1,006,968.00 Dues (running stock) 614,599.66 inavic - _ — $ i .iHjo.yvo.y*} Running stock and dividends .. 630,284.67 Paid-up stock 1,112,100.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 943i779.75 Repayment of loans 811,633.00 Expense - 1 92,875.88 Real estate account 87,450.22 Real estate sales .__ 47,399.70 Interest, fines, etc 386,673.06 Other receipts 193,960.63 Other disbursements -. 471,348.09 193,960.63 Total — 4 3,222,706.61 Total 4 3,222,706.61 Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock. .No. 120,536 t 1 00 00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 39 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION GRAND ISLAND, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 22 OFFICERS Richard Goehring President Guy L. Harrison Vice-President ..Vice-President John A. Ferguson Secretary W. B. Hilbert Assistant Secretary S. N. Wolbach _ Treasurer Horth, Cleary and Suhr Attorneys DIRECTORS Richard Goehring, Guy L. Harrison, R. R. Horth, C. W. Brininger, L. T. Geer, August Kruse, August J. Baumann, J. R. Fulton, August Meyer, John A. Ferguson. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 2,225,600.00 Loans in Foreclosure 4,667.50 Stock Loans 11,300.00 Office Building 12,000.00 Cash 7,1 90.89 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 1,533.40 Taxes Paid 3,482.10 Settlement Balance Accounts and Insur- ance Premiums Advanced 29,266.07 Total $ 2,295,039.96 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 1,336,811.30 Paid-up Stock 827,800.00 Incomplete Loans 5,400.00 Reserve Funds 93,000.00 Undivided Profits 11,588.26 Dividends on Paid Up Stock Payable July 1, 1927 19,521.40 Interest Paid in Advance - 919.00 Total $ 2,295,039.96 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1027 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report 4 37,199.80 Loans made $ 563,900.00 "I'nninij stork and dividends.. 1.13,386.20 Dues (running stock) _ — 408,920.50 Paid-up stock - 182,200.00 Repayment of loans 261,446.15 Paid-up stock and dividends- 293,847.50 Kxpense ___„_„ 14,622.94 Interest, fines, etc. 128,057.45 Real estate account 1,095.64 Other receipts 12,916.42 Other disbursements 23.888.04 Total Jf 1,030,740.32 Total $ 1,030,740.32 Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force st this d&amp;ts .No 50,500 * Average running time of stock matured during year.. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HARTINGTON BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HARTINGTON, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 100 OFFICERS R. G. Mason President Dr. M. E. Eby Vice-President P. O. Robinson Secretary DIRECTORS R. G. Mason, Dr. M. E. Eby, H. D. Spork, G. O. Mengsbol, S. H. Morten. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 383,575.00 9,928.90 5,500.00 100.45 748.61 2,934.87 1,056.05 2,004.45 $ 405,848.33 $ 215,468.33 144,800.00 1,500.00 10,000.00 11,493.30 21,325.00 1,261.70 $ 405,848.33 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 619.30 Loans made % 123,746.90 Due* (running stock) 53,201.00 Running stock and dividends. 39,965.58 Paid-up stock 57,100.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 27,961.36 i-aiu-up siuck Repayment of loans Repayment of loans 44,216.00 Interest, fines, etc. 30,313.77 Expense _ 2,626.09 Real estate account 5,517.25 Other disbursements 26,755.51 30,313.77 Other receipts 41,122.62 26,755.51 Total 226,572.69 Total _$ 226,572.69 Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock. No. 8,109 $ 100. 00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 90 Stock Loans Office Building Furniture and Fixtures Other Real Estate Delinquent Dues, Interest, Fines, Etc Taxes Paid Total ! LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends _ Paid-up Stock „ Incomplete Loans Reserve Funds Undivided Profits Bills Payable Dues &amp; Interest in Advance , Total </seg>
            <seg id="p041">HASTINGS, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 103 OFFICERS H. C. Haverly President L. J. Siekmann Vice-President F. A. Tripp Secretary Secretary P. A. Tripp .".Treasurer J. W. James Attorney .Attorney DIRECTORS H. C. Haverly, L. J. Siekmann, H. B. Cornelius, H. E. Stein, J. W. James, R. R. Damerell, M. M. Haynes. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 666,652.01 Loans in Foreclosure 3,100.00 Stock Loans 23 462.10 23,462.10 Furniture and Fixtures 950.00 Other Real Estate 6,144.91 Cash : 1,617.67 Taxes Paid 1,105.35 Insurance Advanced 973.60 Insurance Account 1,621.42 Advanced on Collection &amp; Foreclosure Account 1,824.58 Printing and Stationery „:. 352.22 Total $ 707,803.86 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 384,883.06 Paid-up Stock 213,525.00 Incomplete Loans 2,491.40 Reserve Funds 16,905.00 Undivided Profits 6,960.21 Insurance Account _ 550.51 Prepaid Stock 82,488.68 Total ¥ 707,803.86 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 4,379.97 Dues (running stock) 77,276.52 Loans made ___$ 178,385.82 Running stock and dividends. 98.215.20 Paid-up stock 82,475.00 Paid-up stock and dividends- 88,899.65 Repayment of loans 128,637.99 Real estate sales 46,215.86 Interest, fines, etc. 49,714.88 Expense ' 40,164.73 Real estate account 6,144.91 Other disbursements 11,122.85 Other receipts .™ 34,232.94 Total $ 422,933.16 Total f 422,933.16 Plan of Association.. Permanent Shares in force at this date .... Par value per share of stock.. ..No. $ 1,193 100.00 138 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HAVELOCK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HAVELOCK, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. Ill OFFICERS W. F. Ackerman President E. E. Anderson Vice- President Ira J. McDonald Secretary Cobe S. Venner Treasurer DIRECTORS W. F. Ackerman, E. E. Anderson, Fred Kroehler, Cobe S. Venner, Ira J. McDonald. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 379,475.00 Loans in Foreclosure 1,873.48 Stock Loans , 2,277.00 Furniture and Fixtures 1,280.00 Other Real Estate 11,850.81 Real Estate Sold on Contract 5,108.38 Cash 5,790.11 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 4,535.40 Taxes Paid 8,856.44 Other Assets /• 1,929.63 Insurance 1,014.2a Total % 423,990.48 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends I 254,356.29 Paid-up Stock 153,750.00 Reserve Funds _ 11,000.23 Undivided Profits 4,883.96 Total $ 423,990.48 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report f 6,118.89 ih on hand last report % 6,118.89 Loans made 4 16,122.00 Running stock and dividends.. 93,120.36 Loans made _...$ 16,122.00 Dues (running stock) 53,632.13 Paid-up stock 44,850.00 es (running stock) 53,632.13 Running stock and dividends.. 93,120.36 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 44^433.62 id-up stock _ 44,850.00 44,850.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 44,433.62 Repayment of loans 36,070.00 Interest, fines, etc. , 30,586.36 Repayment of loans 36,070.00 Expense 5,711 98 Expense ... 5,711.98 Interest, fines, etc. , 30,586.36 30,586.36 Real estate account 4,396.75 Real estate account 4,'396.'75 Other disbursements 12,998.49 4,396.75 Other receipts , 5,525.82 Other receipts , 5,525.82 Other disbursements 12,998.49 Total J* 176,783.20 Total i 176,783.20 Total 5 176,783.20 Total $ 176,783.20 Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock. Shares in force at this date .No. No. 9,128 $ 100.00 9,128 100.00 Par value per share of stock $ Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 113-115 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 43 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HOLDREGE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION HOLDREGE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 154 OFFICERS R. G. Phelps President E. A. Roth Vice-President Frank A. Anderson Secretary G. H. Titus Treasurer Frank A. Anderson Attorney DIRECTORS R. G. Phelps, E. A. Roth, Frank A. Anderson, G. H. Titus, R. H. Perry, Harold Hjelmfelt, H. W. Ekberg, L. T. Johnson, L. B. Titus. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 59,499.66 Cash 4.22 Taxes Paid 452.76 Total $ 59,956.64 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 43,461.55 Paid-up Stock 8,100.00 Reserve Funds 3,500.00 Undivided Profits 4,739.15 Other Liabilities (Fees and Fines) 155.94 Total $ 59,956.64 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report .$ 174.04 Loans made — — $ 15,900.00 Cash on hand last report .$ 174.04 Dues (running stock) 17,971.08 Dues (running stock) __ 17,971.08 Running stock and dividends.. 31,508.94 Running stock and dividends.. 31,508.94 Paid-up stock 10,100.00 Repayment of loans 18,303.42 Paid-up stock 10,100.00 Paid-up stock and dividends- 2,135.26 Paid-up stock and dividends- 2,135.26 Repayment of loans 18,303.42 Expense 534.58 Expense 534.58 Other disbursements 10,039.40 534.58 Interest, fines, etc. 6,880.50 Other disbursements 10,039.40 Other receipts 6,689.14 Total $ 60,118.18 Total 60,118.18 Plan of Association.. Permanent Shares in force at this date . Par value per share of stock. 2,479 .No $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 82 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">OFFICERS C. D. Heine President W. P. Basler Vice-President Norman E. Shaffer _ Secretary Jacob Sanders Treasurer DIRECTORS C. D. Heine, W. E. Sanders, Jacob Sanders, W. F. Basler, Norman E Shaffer, Roy E. Bott, J. E. Stipsky, J. D. Kirsch, Edwin Edelman. ASSETS Mortgage Loans - $ 86,250.00 Furniture and Fixtures , 25.0ft Cash 81.22 Total % 86,356.22 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends ? 57,988.05 Paid-up Stock _ 26,200.00 Reserve Funds 1,974.53 Undivided Profits 193.64 Total % 86,356.22 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1027 RECEIPTS 1 DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 7,123.20 Loans made 4 16,000.00 Dues (running stock) 17,669.22 Running stock and dividends.. 19,601.54 Paid-up stock 900.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 5,705.49 Repayment of loans .- 10,300.00 Expense 354.14 Interest, fines, etc. 5,942.77 Other disbursements 274.02 Paid-up stock Total _ 4 41,935.19 I Total $ 41,935.19 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date No. 968 Par value per share of stock $ 200.00 Average running time of stock matured during year 10 yrs. 6 Mos. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HUMBOLDT BUILDING, LOAN &amp; SAVINGS ASSOCIATION HUMBOLDT, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 123 OFFICERS L. S. Hackett President James B. Davis Vice-President M. Louderback Secretary I. Shirley Treasurer DIRECTORS L. S. Hackett, J. B. Davis, F. R. Butterfleld, Otto Kotouc, John Klossner, M. M. Ramey, I. Shirley, B. M. Dorland, M. Louderback. ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 81,339.75 Stock Loans 2,875.00 Other Real Estate 8,272.82 Cash 3,352.65 Tax Certificates 298.00 Total $ 96,138.22 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 39,443.70 Paid-up Stock 52,100.00 Reserve Funds _ 1,638.65 Reserve Funds Undivided Profits 2,956.87 - Total 9 96,138.22 * Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 80, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report 4 3,051.10 Loans made $ 19,280.00 Running stock and dividends.. 9,137.73 Paid-up stock and dividends. 20,719.07 Dues (running stock) 13,573.55 Paid-up stock _. 26,000.00 Repayment of loans 5,415.00 Expense 827.37 3,751.58 Interest, fines, etc. 5,676.10 Other disbursements Total .._._ $ 53,715.75 Total * 53,715.75 Permanent Plan of Association. Shares in force at this date .No. 2,177 Par value per share of stock. $ 100.0O ±*ar vaiue per snare 01 siuca, — # avw.ww Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 320 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE KEARNEY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION KEARNEY, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30. 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 144 OFFICERS S. A. D. Henline '. President G. E. Haase '. Vice-President Arthur Barney Secretary Arthur Barney Treasurer J. N. Dryden, Attorney DIRECTORS rA. D. Henline, G. E. Haase, J. N. Dryden, N. P. McDonald, Ray E. Turner, J. R. Elliott, Arthur Barney. ASSETS Mortgage Loans . % 513,745.00 Incomplete Loans 10,165.25 Furniture and Fixtures 300.00 Other Real Estate 18,306.06 Tax Certificates 6,472.48 Cash 5,018.22 Total % 554,007.01 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 273,934.52 Paid-up Stock 271,962.87 Reserve Funds ; - 8,078.42 Undivided Profits -"- 31.20 Total « - % 554,007.01 .• Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 32,378.39 Loans made -. _ _ J$ 115,765.47 Dues (running stock) 137,773.03 Running stock and dividends.. 110.225.67 Paid-up stock 41,895.50 Repayment of loans _ 83,515.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 84,073.67 Expense 19,326.85 Other disbursements 14,668.93 Expense Interest, fines, etc. _-.. 36,691.66 14,668.93 Other receipts 11,807.01 Total % 344,060.59 Total 4 344,060.59 Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date .. Par value per share of stock. ..No. 2,719 $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 119 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE LAUREL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LAUREL, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 116 OFFICERS J. B. Felber President D. D. Coburn Vice-President J. B. Bessire ; Secretary J. B. Bessire Treasurer F. P. Voter Attorney DIRECTORS J. B. Felber, D. D. Coburn, J. B. Bessire, F. P. Voter, J. D. Lutton, C. A. Morten, F. I. Solso. ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 65,100.00 Other Real Estate 907.39 Cash 8,397.73 Other Assets 279.94 Total * 74,685.06 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 64,183.44 Reserve Funds 3,000.00 Undivided Profits 2,499.12 Other Liabilities 5,002.50 Total $ 74,685.06 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 8.153.05 Loans made $ 14,700.00 Running stock and dividends.. 14,936.65 Dues (running stock) 21,495.39 Repayment of loans 5,700.00 Paid-up stock and dividends. 6.503.25 Interest, fines, etc. 5,413.61 Expense 317.84 Real estate account 907.39 317.84 Other receipts 5,002.5t Real estate account Other disbursements — - 8,399.41 Total $ 45,764.54 Total $ 45,764.54 Plan of Association. 5S Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock. ..No $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">.Secretary Treasurer .Attorneys L. C. Oberlles, Frank Parks, H. H. Wilson, E. F. Snavely, Charles Olson, W. A. Selleck, E. W. Brown. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 1,365,150.00 Loans In Foreclosure 23,500.00 B Loans 1,925.00 Building 10,000.00 Furniture and Fixtures 338.59 Real Estate 31,419.75 Estate Sold on Contract 3,432.66 I, State and Municipal Securities 31,323.96 3,207.34 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 7,203.03 Paid 6,245.95 Total % 1,483,746.19 B LIABILITIES ng Stock and Dividends $ 801,519.86 Paid-up Stock , 631,200.00 Incomplete Loans 20,334.10 Reserve Funds 29,424.16 Undivided Profits 1,268.07 29,424.16 Total $ 1,483,746.19 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June SO, 1027 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 38, (82. 08 Dues (running stock) 525,099.54 Paid-up stock 148,975.00 Loans made $ 173,971.06 Running stock and dividends.. 421,100.88 Paid-up stock and dividends' 269]496]44 Kup SIOCK no.y/j.uu 'ment of loans 180,429.33 estate sales 9,756.95 »t. fines, etc. _ 94.250. 1* Expense _ 13,704.80 Real estate account _ 32,927.64 Other disbursements 105,048.73 Total Plan of Association Permanent . ± iau ui aoi3ui.ittiiuu Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock. .No. 33,882 $ 100.00 restate sales 9,756.95 st, fines, etc. . 94.250.1* receipts 19,056.49 Total $ 1,016,249.55 .$ 1,016,249.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE FIDELITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 136 OFFICERS W. A. Forsyth President J. G. Hornung Vice-President E. M. Forsyth Secretary Sterling F. Mutz _ Attorney DIRECTORS W. A. Forsyth, J. G. Hornung, W. C. Hornung, S. E. McCue, E. M. Forsyth. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 633,125.00 Loans in Foreclosure 4,054.24 Furniture and Fixtures 888.30 Other Real Estate 1,572.89 Real Estate Sold on Contract 13,355.91 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 20,011.93 Cash 29,125.73 Taxes Paid on Certificate - 2,216.97 Total ¥ 704,350.97 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 381,933.58 Paid-up Stock 288,650.00 Incomplete Loans _ 4,568.70 Reserve Funds 16,300.00 Undivided Profits 12,898.69 Total $ 704,350.97 Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June SO, 1027 DISBURSEMENTS Loans made $ 103,838.14 the Year Ending June SO, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 17,807.62 Cash on hand last report 4 17,807.62 Loans made ..... $ 103,838.14 LiUdlls IDdUC ■ .■■ ii ii ■. ■ i w 1UJ V oJOp if Running stock and dividends- 245,205.58 Dues (running stock) 234,679.77 Dues (running stock) 234,579.77 Running stock and dividends- 245,205.58 Paid-up stock 57,200.00 Repayment of loans 127,380.74 Paid-up stock 57,200.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 99,745.78 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 99,745.78 Repayment of loans 127,380.74 Expense Expense 6,663.90 6,663.90 142.28 52,716.84 Real estate sales 3,655.41 Real estate sales 3,655.41 Real estate account . Other disbursements Real estate account 142.28 142.28 interest, fines, etc. 52,303.47 Interest, fines, etc. 52,303.47 Other disbursements 52,716.84 Other receipt* 15,285.51 Total $ 508,312.52 Other receipts 15,285.51 Total $ 508,312.52 Total $ 508,312.52 Total $ 508,312.52 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date No. 6,333 Par value per share of stock $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 128 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HOME SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 147 OFFICERS Frank Mills President George E. Hager Vice-President R. E. Harrington Secretary Christy E. Brookman Assistant Secretary E. M. Bair Treasurer J. A. Brown and George E. Hager Attorneys DIRECTORS J. A. Brown, E. M. Bair, George E. Hager, R .E. Harrington, Frank Mills. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 1,756,100.00 Stock Loans 7,320.00 Furniture and Fixtures 2,085.97 Other Real Estate 74,673.16 Real Estate Sold on Contract , 11,433.41 Cash 62,942.13 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 19,632.75 Taxes Paid _ 1,600.15 Other Assets 935.99 Total % 1,936,723.56 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends - $ 1,124,092.50 Paid-up Stock 773,100.00 Reserve Funds 20,355.45 Undivided Profits 3,665.61 Other Liabilities 10.00 Notes Payable 15,500.00 Total * 1,936,723.56 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report ~$ 62,702.51 Loans made __.$ 490,236.00 Running stock and dividends.. 419,996.58 Dues (running stock) 505,272.94 Paid-up stock _. 357,200.00 Repayment of loans _. 213,005.60 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 229,641.80 Expense 33,556.84 Real estate sales 9,044.31 Interest, fines, etc. 130,374.58 9,044.31 Other disbursements _ 137,105.72 Other receipts •2,937.00 Total $ 1,310,536.94 Total 4 1,310,536.94 Plan of Association- Permanent Shares in force at this date .. Par value per share of stock ..No. 101,253 100.00 $ Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 114 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 51 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE LINCOLN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 130 OFFICERS E. W. Brown President H. H. Wilson Vice-President E. F. Snavely Secretary E. F. Snavely Treasurer Burkett, Wilson, Brown &amp; Wilson _ Attorneys DIRECTORS E. W. Brown, Frank Parks, L. C. Oberlies, W. A. Selleck, H. H. Wilson, Charles Olson, E. F. Snavely. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 1,672,475.00 Loans in Foreclosure 30,500.00 Stock Loans 4,480.00 Office Building 10,000.00 Furniture and Fixtures 577.00 Other Real Estate 78,358.09 Real Estate Sold on Contract 10,621.21 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 72,685.16 Cash , 27,794.01 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 14,827.41 Taxes Paid 9,798.23 Other Assets; C-D's 6,426.18 Total $ 1,938,542.29 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends - % 1,052,356.00 Paid-up Stock 777,450.00 Incomplete Loans 74,710.03 Reserve Funds 33,961.04 Undivided Profits 65.22 Total % 1,938,542.29 Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS Loans made __$ 318,130.59 the Year Ending June 30, 1027 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report -$ 86,015.57 Cash on hand last report X 86,015.57 Loans made $ 318.130.S9 Running stock and dividends- 531,422.13 Dues (running stock) 537,909.73 Dues (running stock) 537,909.73 Running stock and dividends- 531,422.13 Paid-up stock 149.52S.00 Paid-up stock 149,525.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 156,23a26 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 156,230.26 Repayment of loans 327,210.37 £*P«nse 18,915.23 E*Pense __ 1 18.915.23 Real estate account 43,075.22 Real "estate sales 16,241.98 Real estate account 43,075.22 Interest, fines, etc - 113,884.23 Interest, fines, etc _ 113,884.23 Other disbursements 197,770.50 Other receipts 34,757.05 Total * 1,265,543.93 Other receipts 34,757.05 Total 4 1,365,543.93 Total Permanent Permanent Plan of Association. Plan of Association- Shares in force at this date . Par value per share of stock. Shares in force at this date ._ No. 55,107 % $ 100.00 .No. 55,107% Par value per share of stock | 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">LINCOLN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 150 OFFICERS Julius Reusch President Adolph Lebsack, Jr Vice-President E. C. Boehmer. Secretary Theo. H. Berg Treasurer -Treasurer Fbu. a. joerg Treasurer ehmer and Boehmer Attorneys DIRECTORS Julius Reusch, Adolph Lebsack, Jr., Theo. H. Berg, A. H. Koop, R. A Boehmer. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 986,625.00 Loans in Foreclosure 14,500.00 Stock Loans 5,245.00 Furniture and Fixtures 2,746.20 Other Real Estate 21,703.98 Real Estate Sold on Contract 6,652.40 21,703.98 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 20,465.66 Cash • 28,768.66 Tax Sale Certificates , 2,698.08 28,768.66 Total % 1,089,404.98 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 559,327.67 Paid-up Stock 510,335.00 Incomplete Loans 3,870.31 Reserve Funds 15,000.00 Undivided Profits _ 872.00 Total $ 1,089,404.98 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures RECEIPTS for the Year Ending June 30, 1027 DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 47,412.20 i on hand last report $ 47,412.20 Loans made .$ 220,255.00 Dues (running stock) 477,543.76 Paid-up stock 126,010.00 i (running stock) 477,543.76 Running stock and dividends. 453,918.00 -up stock 126,010.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 180.922.16 lyment of loans „ 206,404.00 Expense 9,925.92 estate sales 894.80 Real estate account .__ 18,548.52 rest, fines, etc. 71,296.40 Other disbursements 196,191.75 r receipts 150,200.19 receipts Total i 1,079,761.35 Total $ 1,079,761.35 Total Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock.. ..No. 22,792.10 $ 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NEBRASKA CENTRAL BUILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 85 * OFFICERS Homer K. Burket President John Oibson Vice- President W. M. Folsom Secretary rrt -vt n » j — T. N. Burket _ Treasurer — ■ — - • — ■•— ™»»......— ............«.....—....«... A » bUOUl 1^1 j. a. Piper „ Auditor E. R. Butler Manager of Agencies DIRECTORS Homer K. Burket, J. A. Piper, E. R. Butler ASSETS Mortgage Loans f 8,537,601.15 ASSETS Loans in Foreclosure 287,100.00 Stock Loans 8,490.00 Stock Loans Office Building, Furniture and Fixtures 41,892.80 Other Real Estate 224,742.44 utner ±teai tistaie ZZ4,/4Z.«4 Real Estate Sold on Contract .'. 126,255.51 Cash ___.__....._I™..~™™"" 356,359.04 Taxes Purchased 73,302.41 Bills Receivable 6,276.77 Total ~ $ 9,662,020.13 - LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 4,113,943.06 Paid-up Stock — 5,003,692.81 Reserve Funds - 272,850.28 __ _ * ■ , - ,-. n . . * nn-ip-AAnrv Undivided Profits .' 271,533.97 Total _ $ 9,662,020.12 Total Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 80, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 204,065.40 Dues (running stock) — 1,637,012.04 Paid-up stock 1,177,759.03 Loans made $ 1,911,355.63 Riming stock and dividends. 1,427,757.41 Paid-up stock and dividends- 1,111,699.49 Repayment of loans 1,612,845.69 Other disbursements nents 1,333,815.14 Real estate sales 243,789.96 Other receipts 909,155.55 Total $ 5,784,627.67 Total $ 5,784,627.67 Permanent 224,413 •i AA A A Plan of Association.. Shares in force at this date . Par value per share of stock. ..No. 100.00 122 $ Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 54 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE PEOPLE'S SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 172. • OFFICERS Dr. W. C. Becker President L. H. Pauley Vice-President Harry R. Ball Secretary Harry R. Ball Treasurer DIRECTORS Dr. W. C. Becker, L. H. Pauley, Harry R. Ball, Dr. Carl J. Norden, Lester M. Buckley. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 14,650.00 Stock Loans „ 295.00 Furniture and Fixtures 275.42 Cash 468.19 Total $ 15,688.61 LIABILITIES • Running Stock and Dividends % 5,804.67 Paid-up Stock 8,820.00 Incomplete Loans 483.59 Reserve Funds 17.48 Undivided Profits .'. 62.87 Other Liabilities 500.00 Total $ 15,688.61 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 249.98 Dues (running stock) 6,116.90 Paid-up stock 10,900.00 Repayment of loans 361.70 Cash on hand last report $ 249.98 Loans made $ 12,292.50 Loans made $ 12,292.50 Dues (running stock) 6,116.90 Running stock and dividends- 2,231.74 Running stock and dividends- 2,231.74 Paid-up stock 10,900.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 3,857.34 Paid-up stock and dividends- 3,857.34 Repayment of loans 361.70 Expense 290.83 Expense 290.83 Interest, fines, etc. Interest, fines, etc. 803.85 Other disbursements 16,700.00 Other disbursements 16,700.00 Total .$ 35,372.49 Other receipts Other receipts 16,9*0.06 Total $ 35,372.49 Total Total X 35,372.49 Shares In force at this date — Par value per share of stock.. Shares In force at this date .No No. 915% $ 100.00 Far value per share of stock % </seg>
            <seg id="p055">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 55 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE PROVIDENT SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 139 OFFICERS Frank E. Gillan President H. E. Sidles Vice-President F. B. Sidles Secretary A. L. Beghtol Treasurer F. B. Sidles Attorney DIRECTORS F. E. Gillan, H. E. Sidles, F. B. Sidles, A. L. Beghtol, C. A. Eigle. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 1,754,650.00 Stock Loans 24,497.75 Furniture and Fixtures 2,692.26 Other Real Estate 5,019.76 Real Estate Sold on Contract : 2,715.25 Federal, State and Municipal Securities, Bonds 124,928.79 Cash 21,124.47 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 6,024.62 Taxes Advanced » 5,696.74 Total I 1,947,349.64 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 1,375,274.64 Paid-up Stock 631,975.00 Incomplete Loans — 3,700.00 Reserve Funds 36,400.00 Total * 1,947,349.64 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending June 80, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 73,029.19 Dues (running stock) 601,451.87 Paid-up stock 59,175.00 Repayment of loans _ 295,946.54 Loans made _ - $ 443, 702. 99 Running stock and dividends.. 489,351.89 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 239,410.51 Expense 20,084.88 Repayment oi loans _ 47j,jto.ji Real estate sales 3,535.00 expense — aj,uo^.oo Real estate account 7,269.65 Other disbursements 179,781.73 Real estate account Keai estate sales — j.joj.w Interest, fines, etc. 131,159.711 179,781.73 Other receipts 215,304.35 Total $ 1,379,601.65 Total % 1,379,601.65 Plan of Association. Permanent ..No. 62,302% Shares in force at this date . Par value per share of stock. $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 56 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE SURETY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 170 OFFICERS W. N. Watson President ■ TV . 1^1. naiouii ....... _..... rrcBJUcIll. S. J. Hyatt Vice-President G. M. Harman Secretary G. M. Harman Treasurer Roper &amp; Fuller Attorneys DIRECTORS r. N. Watson, S. J. Hyatt, C. F. Coy, A. H. Forke, Floyd Pope, R. V. Koupal, R. C. Roper, G. A. Bryant, J. E. Evans. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 118,950.00 Stock 5,000.00 Other Real Estate 10,900.00 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 8,030.15 Cash „ 5,761.30 Taxes Paid 653.15 Accounts Payable 99.04 Total $ 149,393.64 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 61,663.03 Paid-up Stock 85,319.20 Incomplete Loans 993.75 Reserve Funds _ 890.00 Undivided Profits 461.66 Accounts Receivable 66.00 Total $ 149,393.64 Receipts and Expenditures (or the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 5,655.16 Dues (running stock) 53,749.56 Cash on hand last report $ 5,655.16 Loans made $ 51,200.00 Loans made $ 51,200.00 Dues (running stock) 53,749.56 Running stock and dividends- 39,970.48 Running stock and dividends.. 39,970.48 Paid-up stock Paid-up stock 42,816.65 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 15,125.70 Expense 10,496.55 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 15,125.70 Repayment of loans Repayment of loans 39,216.40 Expense 10,496.55 Interest, fines, etc, Interest, fines, etc. 11,626.07 Real estate account 10,900.00 Other disbursements 27,347.50 Real estate account 10,900.00 Other receipts Other receipts 1,976.39 Other disbursements 27,347.50 Total $ 155,040.23 Total * 155,040.23 Total - 4 155,040.23 Total - 4 155,040.23 Plan of Association.. Plan of Association. Permanent Permanent ■es in force at this date . value per share of stock. Shares in force at this date .No. 11,890.91 No. 11,890.91 Par value per share of stock. $ 100.00 1 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE UNION LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 135 OFFICERS A. W. Miller, Sr President H. H. Miller Secretary-Treasurer Jno. M. Stewart Attorney DIRECTORS A. W. Miller, Sr., H. H. Miller, John M. Stewart, Dr. B. F. Bailey, Albert W. Miller, Jr ASSETS Mortgage Loans _ $ 3,492,575.00 Stock Loans 9,256.24 Furniture and Fixtures 11,465.65 Other Real Estate 77,923.08 Real Estate Sold on Contract 32,571.64 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 301,706.86 Cash „ 16.317.8C Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 23,961.08 Taxes Paid 38,013.76 Tax Sale Securities 3,493.34 Int. on Municipal Securities, Taxes, Etc 11,185.23 Total f 4,018,469.52 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 2,519,868.32 Paid-up Stock 1,195,650.00 Incomplete Loans 179,020.98 Reserve Funds 114,456.11 Undivided Profits 9,474.11 Total $ 4,018,469.52 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June SO, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Dues (running stock) 4 1,928,058.77 Loans made 4 958,631.28 Paid-up stock 222,100.00 Running stock and dividends 1,538,148.69* Paid-up stock and dividends. 383.215.20 Expense 51,404.34 Real estate account 58,330.33 Repayment of loans _ 712.1S3.76 Real estate sales 35.322.22 Interest, fines, etc. 239,736.48 Other receipts 652,647.21 Other disbursements 800,288.60&gt; Total S 3,790,018.44 Total $ 3,790,018.44 Plan of Association. Permanent 97,077. 5» Sharer in force at this date . Par value per share of stock. ? 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. US </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE UNITED SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN* NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 171 OFFICERS Walter H. Jurgensen President Margaret Jurgensen Vice- President Sam C. Zimmerman Secretary Geo. S. Adams Treasurer Adams &amp; Zimmerman Attorneys DIRECTORS Walter H. Jurgensen, Margaret Jurgensen, William Krull, Geo. S. Adams, Sam C. Zimmerman. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 145,800.00 Stock Loans 230.00 Furniture and Fixtures 586.09 Cash : 5,252.90 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 398.60 Total $ 152,267.59 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 107,588.37 Paid-up Stock 31,400.00 Incomplete Loans 8,304.05 Reserve Funds 222.12 Undivided Profits 4,743.26 Other Liabilities 9.79 Total $ 152,267.59 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report S 1,639.82 Cash on hand last report $ 1,639.82 Loans made $ 117,300.95 Loans made _._$ 117,300.95 Dues (running stock) _ 110,612.06 Paid-up stock _ 48,430.33 Repayment of loans 6,105.00 Interest, fines, etc 6,004.33 Other receipts 10,049.75 Dues (running stock) _. 110,612.06 Running stock and dividends.. 23,055.67 Running stock and dividends.. 23,055.67 Paid-up stock _ 48,430.33 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 26,051.95 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 26,051.95 Repayment of loans 6,105.00 Expense 544.00 Expense _ 544.00 Other disbursements 15,888.74 Interest, fines, etc 6,004.33 Other disbursements 15,888.74 Other receipts 10,049.75 10,049.75 Total $ 182,841.31 Total $ 182,841.31 Total ...$ 182,841.31 Total $ 182,841.31 Klan of Association fiares in force at this date Par value per share of stock Plan of Association. Permanent Permanent Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock. ..No. No. 128,666 $ 100.00 128,666 $ 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HOME BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION McCOOK, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30. 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 158 OFFICERS D. W. Colson President F. M. Kimmell Vice-President J. N. Gaarde _ Secretary M. O. McClure Treasurer J. F. Cordeal Attorney DIRECTORS D. W. Colson, F. M. Kimmell, J. N. Gaarde, Lester Kort, C. R. Wood - worth, C. F. Dann, M. O. McClure, J. F. Cordeal, C. B. Stephens. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 255,825.00 Loans in Foreclosure 5,305.50 Stock Loans 8,714.27 Furniture and Fixtures 789. 6&amp; Other Real Estate 7,561.83 Cash 4,635.01 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 1,037.27 Taxes Paid, Tax Certificates 1,676.26 Delinquent Dues 849.75 Expense 1,039.31 Commissions 37.95 Interest Paid 2,260.13 Insurance Paid to Protect Loans 249.55 Prepaid Dividends 336.95 Total $ 290,318.43 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 178,215.41 Paid-up Stock 99,354.43 Interest Received 9,640.75 Reserve Funds 2,188.27 Undivided Profits 217.17 Membership 68.90 Fines 54.44 Prepaid Dues 476.00 Insurance Collected 103.06 Total $ 290,318.43 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 5,277.01 Loans made $ 62,988.27 Dues (running stock) - _ 41.968.25 Running stock and dividends.. 27.463.21 Paid-up stock - 36,054.78 Repayment of loans 32,144.51 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 33,749.54 Expense ___-. 2,184.73 Interest, fines, etc -... 19,386.34 Real estate account 746.85 Other receipts 6,792.47 Other disbursements 14,490.76 Total .* 141,623.36 Total $ Ml, 623. 36 Plan of Association. Shares in force at this date . Pcir v&amp;lu6 Dcr s heir 6 of stock * </seg>
            <seg id="p060">OFFICERS C. H. Boyle President v». xi. Duyiv rreaiueiiL H. P. Waite Vice-President J. G. Schobel Secretary J. G. Schobel Treasurer C. H. Boyle Attorney DIRECTORS r. H. Boyle, H. P. Waite, L. W. McConnell, C. J. O'Brien, P. Walsh, Jos. Mokko, Elmer Kay, R. H. Gatewood, Walter Stokes. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 929,565.00 Loans in Foreclosure 31,461.22 ■ Loans 27,655.00 ture and fixtures 965.64 Real Estate 12,526.64 K9 QAK Q A 27,655.00 12,526.64 53,345.80 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 2,980.49 Paid _ 14,346.98 Expense 1,498.90 Interest on Full Paid Stock 302.53 Total _ $ 1,074,648.20 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 784,577.05 Paid-up Stock 232,300.00 Reserve Funds 27,542.88 Undivided Profits 29,807.52 Prepaid Dues and Interest 420.75 Total $ 1,074,648.20 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS the Tear Ending Jane 30, 1027 DISBURSEMENTS Loans made 4 217,335.00 Running stock and dividends.. 135,696.49 the Tear Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Han hand last report 4 7,059.03 (running stock) .._ 147,260.50 ip stock _ 12,800.00 ment of loans 210,170.00 •state sales 3,109.90 Cash on hand last report .$ 7,059.03 Loans made 4 217,335.00 Running stock and dividends.. 135,696.49 Dues (running stock) 147,260.50 Paid-up stock _ 12,800.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 51,150.19 lYuiiuuiK siui.ll rfllU U1VIUCI1UV. iOJ.KTO.tV Paid-up stock and dividends.. 51,150.19 Repayment of loans 210,170.00 Expense 4,932.28 Heal estate sales 3,109.90 Real estate account 214.40 Interest, fines, etc. „ 89,618.24 Other disbursements 77,308.79 Other receipts 16,619.48 Total $ 486,637.15 Total 4 486,637.15 Total 4 486,637.15 Plan of Association Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock Plan of Association .Serial and Full Paid No. 13,100% Serial and Full Paid Shares in force at this date _ No 13,100% $ 200.00 Par v&amp;lu6 per share of stock ......... S Average running time of stock matured during year. Mob. T^o y y q I ii o D^r Su£HT6 OX S t-OC iv •&lt; 200.00 ired during year. Mos. 119 119 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">CERTIFICATE NO. 7 OFFICERS C. S. Snyder President W. H. Field Vice-President A. E. Ward Secretary A. E. Ward Treasurer M. B. Foster Attorney DIRECTORS C. S. Snyder, W. H. Field, M. B. Foster, I. M. Dawson, F. H. Davis, C. B. Pearse. ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 669,310.80 Loans in Foreclosure 20,950.00 Stock Loans 2.395.50 2,395.50 Office Building 9,564.00 Furniture and Fixtures 371.60 Other Real Estate 32,139.48 Real Estate Sold on Contract 3,500.00 Cash 9,228.97 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 3,177.30 Taxes Paid 2,820.17 Other Assets 8.18 Total $ 753,465.90 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 245,437.54 Paid-up Stock 473.100.00 Reserve Funds 16,419.95 Undivided Profits 8,744.41 (Inventory) Transfer from Undivided Profits „... 9,564.00 Jennings Foreclosure 200.00 Total % 753,465.90 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending June SO, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 28,136.41 Loans made $ 156,336.20 Running stock and dividends- 45,103.14 Paid-up stock and dividends- 109.659.56 Dues (running stock) 53,798.87 Paid-up stock 117,000.00 Repayment of loans 81,070.00 Expense .,,,, 6,781.85 Wral estate sales 7,777.15 Real estate account 16,236.11 Interest, fines, etc. 58,118.36 Other disbursements - 16,252.78 Other receipts — _- 4,468.85 Total $ 350,369.64 Total $ 350,369.64 Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date ..No. 8,119% Par value per share of stock _ $ 200.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 62 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NEBRASKA CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 30 OFFICERS W. W. Metz President H. D. Thiele Vice-President Win. H. Pitzer Secretary H. P. Meyer Treasurer Wm. H. Pitzer Attorney DIRECTORS H. F. Meyer, William H. Pitzer, F. M. Cook, John H. Petring, John C. Miller, E. J. VonGillern, E. G. Mueller, Lloyd E. Peterson. ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 1,025,561.50 6,521.40 17,314.86 1,550.36 20,191.13 2,155.81 42,534.34 55,753.62 5,650.76 2,099.55 186.04 $ 1,179,519.37 $ 548,014.15 601,000.00 23,102.33 7,402.89 $ 1,179,519.37 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June SO, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report _ .$ 76,587.57 Loans made $ 256,277.47 Dues (running stock) 162,027.81 Running stock and dividends. 111,678.08 Paid-up stock 226,350.00 Paid-up stock and dividends. 177,945.86 Repayment of loans 92,588.57 Ex0ense 7,013.22 Real estate sales 3,937.40 Interest, fines, etc. 67,783.06 Real estate account 18,619.42 67,783.06 Other disbursements 80,677.30 Other receipts 22,936.94 Total $ 652,211.35 Total _.- - $ 652,211.35 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock 18,634% .No $ 200.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mob. 134 oans in Foreclosure &gt;. tock Loans 'urnlture and Fixtures •ther Real Estate Leal Estate Sold on Contract 'ederal, State and Municipal Securities delinquent Interest ■axes Paid asurance Paid Total LIABILITIES tunning Stock and Dividends 'aid-up Stock Leserve Funds ndivided Profits Total </seg>
            <seg id="p063">- 63 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NUCKOLLS COUNTY BUILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION NELSON, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 129 OFFICERS H. E. Goodrich President W .A. McHenry Vice-President C. R. Imler Secretary W. W. Hawley Treasurer T. W. Cole Attorney DIRECTORS H. E. Goodrich, W. C. Hall, P. A. Peterson, W. W. Hawley, F. E. Bottenfield. J. E. Portwood, W. A. McHenry, E. E. Hedgecock, B. L. Stahl. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 166,725.00 Loans in Foreclosure 1,000.00 Stock Loans 2,825.00 Other Real Estate 4,944.57 Real Estate Sold on Contract 733.92 Cash 3,963.49 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc. , 1,404.22 Taxes Paid 1,309.26 Expenses Paid 200.60 Interest Paid 135.75 R. E. Expense 11.10 Total | 183,252.91 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 119,540.33 Paid-up Stock 52,050.00 Reserve Funds 5,622.80 Undivided Profits 5,909.78 Rents 80.00 Payments on R. E. Contract 50.00 Total % 183,252.91 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report .$ 10,708.81 Loans made _$ 16,628.85 T^"" = (running stock) 23,372.29 Running stock and dividends.. 19,293.86 Paid-up stock 7,600.00 Repayment of loans ..._ -..- 5,879.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 11.1*7.6* Expense 1,264.51 R*"*l estate account _— 58. 70 Real estate sales 900.00 T -'-rest. fines, etc 12,704.22 Other disbursements 14,O4.» Other receipts 1,946.15 Total $ 63,110.47 Total $ 63,110.47 Plan of Association. Permanent </seg>
            <seg id="p064">STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NEWMAN GROVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY NEWMAN GROVE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 63 OFFICERS E. H. Gerhart _ President ■ C. J. Peterson Vice-President H. L. Gerhart Secretary H. L. Gerhart Treasurer ..Treasurer DIRECTORS E. H. Gerhart, C. J. Peterson, H. L. Gerhart, C. E. Barrett, C. H Morian, F. H. Price. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 156,300.00 Other Real Estate 21,100.00 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 800.64 Cash 2,623.00 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 1,236.20 Total $ 182,059.84 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 125,315.36 Paid-up Stock 48,187.95 Reserve Funds 3,268.00 Undivided Profits 288.53 Bills Payable 5,000.00 Total $ 182,059.84 h Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS on hand last report $ 278.43 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1027 DISBURSEMENTS Loans made $ 56.356.13 the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report S 278.43 Loans made $ 56.356.13 Running stock and dividends.. 22,970.25 Dues (running stock) 28,471.20 (running stock) 28,471.20 Running stock and dividends.. 22,970.25 -up stock 44,787.95 Paid-up stock and dividends 37,127.50 Paid-up stock and dividends 37,127.50 Paid-up stock 44,787.95 Repayment of loans Repayment of loans 54,056.13 Interest, fines, etc. 9,270.79 yment of loans 54,056.13 Expense Expense 1,610.60 est, fines, etc. 9,270.79 Real estate account 8,074.32 Other receipts 5,430.30 ( receipts 5,430.30 Other disbursements •._ 16,156.00 Total .$ 142,294.80 Total Total $ 142,294.80 Total 142,294.80 Plan of Association Serial Shares in force at this date No. 1,963% Par value per share of stock $ 200.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 105 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE SECURITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NEWMAN GROVE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 153 OFFICERS President . Secretary-Treasurer Oeo. H. Gutru. Thos. O. Field. H. Halderson Attorney DIRECTORS Geo. H. Gutru, S. M. Juelson, Thos. O. Field ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 19,300.00 Other Real Estate 12,114.42 Real Estate Sold on Contract 1,800.00 Cash 12,736.48 Taxes Paid and Expense 1,481.94 Other Assets (Time Certificates) 3,330.00 Total $ 50,761.84 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 6,661.02 Paid-up Stock 35,672.04 Reserve Funds 6,698.14 Undivided Profits 361.74 Rents 1,368.90 Total $ 50,761.84 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS le _ $ 2,000.00 Cash on hand last report $ 19,631.94 Loan-; made Running stock and dividends.. 4,863.87 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 27,089.07 Dues (running stock) _.. 1,716.96 Paid-up stock 13,927.60 Expense L 345.81 Repayment of loans 12,800.00 Real estate account 4,314.42 Interest, fines, etc 2,571.53 Other receipts 747.25 Other disbursements — 12,782.11 Total —..$ 51,395.28 Total _...$ 51,395.28 Permanent Plan of Association. 3,569 100.00 Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock. ..No. I I </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE ELKHORN BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 12 OFFICERS J. W. Ransom President C. E. Doughty Vice- President Earl A. Ransom Secretary Jabe B. Gibson Treasurer R. J. Shurtleff Attorney DIRECTORS J. W. Ransom, C. E. Doughty, C. J. Hibben, M. Havens, Jabe B. Gibson. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 386,125.00 Stock Loans 750.00 750.00 Furniture and Fixtures 1,300.00 Other Real Estate 5,450.88 Real Estate Sold on Contract 14,133.90 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 150.00 Cash .4,049.07 Taxes Paid 6,169.15 Total $ 418,128.00 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 184,890.46 Paid-up Stock 214,490.00 Reserve Funds 8,385.89 Undivided Profits 10.361.65 Total $ 418,128.00 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 2.0W.2O Loans made _ $ 98,050.00 Dues (running stock) 57,083.80 Paid-up stock 133,475.01 Running stock and dividends. 42,500.31 133,475.01 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 143,138.09 Repayment of loans 87,075.00 Real estate sales 18,796.63 Interest, fines, etc. 31,373.69 Repayment of loans Expense 4,590.92 Real estate account 38,373.41 Other disbursements - 10,528.51 31,373.69 10,528.51 Other receipts _ 7,314.92 Total _ ___ 4 337,181.24 Total _ &gt; 337,181.24 Plan of Association. Permanent Par value per share of stock $ 200.00 Average running time ot stock matured during year. Mos. 132 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 67 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NORFOLK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORFOLK, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 5 OFFICERS H. A. Pasewalk President J. C. Stitt Vice-Presideni C. A. Durland Secretary-Treasurer Mapes &amp; McDuffee Attorneys DIRECTORS E. F. Huse, J. C. Stitt, John C. Koerber, A. T. Hutchinson, H. A. Pasewalk, G. B. Christoph, J. B. Maylard, S. G. Mayer, John Welsh. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 1,618,600.00 Stock Loans 62,312.54 Office Building _ 18,145.43 Other Real Estate 108,257.58 Real Estate Sold on Contract 27,376.93 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 10, 476. OS Cash 12,085.99 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 6,172.73 Taxes Paid 31,967.65 Total $ 1,895,394.93 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 1,163,683.72 Paid-up Stock 657,300.00 Reserve Funds 20,191.74 Undivided Profits 54,219.47 Total $ 1,895,394.93 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 29,600.02 Loans made .$ 278,669.19 Dues (running stock) 253,430.67 Running stock and dividends.. 248.499.92 Paid-up stock 209,500.00 Repayment of loans 282,992.64 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 339.901.82 Expense _ _ 14,014.49 Real estate account . 82,750.30 Real estate sales _ 65,357.99 Interest, fines, etc 136,741.26 Other disbursements _ 116,185.55 Other receipts - 102,400.69 Total $ 1,080,023.27 Total 4 1,080,023.27 Plan of Association.. Permanent Shares in force at this date . Par value per share of stock. .No. 48,36a i 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">.Secretary Treasurer .Attorneys DIRECTORS [M. D. Earnest, G. G. Gowen, Frank Johnson, Geo. E. Johnson, A. T. Jones, H. C. Sample, A. A. Tschauner. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 26,175.00 Other Real Estate 921.69 Real Estate Sold on Contract 2,707.00 Cash ... 513.53 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 252.06 Total $ 30,569.28 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 22,210,58 Paid-up Stock 6,500.00 Incomplete Loans 95.07 Reserve Funds 625.51 Undivided Profits 1,138.12 Total % 30,569.28 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS the Year Ending June 3O, 1927 the Year Ending June 3O, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS I^oans made _ - _ $ 6,300.00 Running stock and dividends. 13,720.37 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report 4 517.88 Cash on hand last report 4 517.88 Loans made $ 6,300.00 Dues (running stock) 15,729.10 Running stock and dividends.. 13,720.37 Paid-up stock _ 1,500.0(1 Paid-up stock and dividends. 2,141.08 Paid-up stock and dividends. 2,141.08 Repayment of loans 3,970.0(1 Expense - 667.30 Expense 667.30 Real estate sales 3,663.93 Real estate account Real estate account 3,155.73 Interest, fines, etc 2,411.09 Other disbursements Other disbursements 2.456.84 Other receipts 649.32 Other receipts 649.32 Total $ 28,441.32 Total $ 28,441.32 Total Total __ $ 28,441.32 .$ 28,441.32 Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock Average running time of stock ..No 963 $ 100.00 matured during year. 9 or 10 Years </seg>
            <seg id="p069">BUILDING AND LOAN STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NORTH PLATTE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 32 OFFICERS Thomas C. Patterson President Shares in force at this date No. 26,978% Par value per share of stock $ 200.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 128 Victor VonGoetz Vice-President H. D. Wiese Secretary £H. Munger..... Treasurer lligan, Beatty &amp; Halligan Attorneys DIRECTORS Thomas C. Patterson, Victor VonGoetz, Geo. W. Finn, Ira L. Bare, W. R. Maloney, Prank N. Buchanan, M. J. Forbes, W. W. Cum- ming, Harry M.' Porter. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 2,332,400.00 iOans in Foreclosure 6,200.00 Stock Loans u. 34,400.00 Office Building 28,586.89 Furniture and Fixtures 1,608.17 Other Real Estate 7,448.32 Real Estate Sold on Contract 3,796.23 Cash 24,096.50 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 2,153.65 Tax Sale Certificates 7,675.87 Total $ 2,448,365.63 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 1,085,473.70 Paid-up Stock 1,256.900.00 Reserve Funds 75,600.00 Undivided Profits 30,391.93 Total .-. $ 2,448,365.63 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending Jane 30, 1927 Receipts and Expenditures for 1 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS ■Cash on hand last report -$ 28,132.81 Loans made _$ 437,400.00 Dues (running stock) — - 262,173.93 Running stock and dividends.. 114,450.14 Paid-up stock 1,385,300.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 1,508,655.38 Repayment of loans _. 258.898.02 Expense 12,511.98 Real estate sales _— 4,000.00 Real estate account -_ 13,779.60 Interest, fines, etc — 172,406.99 Other disbursements — 38,000.02 Other receipts _____ 13,885.37 RECEIPTS &lt;Tash on hand last report .$ 28,132.81 Dues (running stock) - _ 262,173.93 Paid-up stock 1,385,300.00 Repayment of loans _. 258.898.02 Real estate sales __ 4,000.00 Interest, fines, etc 172,406.99 Other receipts _____ 13,885.37 Total $ 2,124,797.12 Total - $2,124,797.12 I Total $2,124,797.12 Plan of Association Permanent Plan of Association </seg>
            <seg id="p070">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 70 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE BANKERS SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 80 OFFICERS E. E. Kiplinger President C. L. Waldron _ Vice-President J. W. Severns Secretary J. S. McGurk Treasurer C. L. Waldron Attorney DIRECTORS E. E. Kiplinger, C. L. Waldron, J. W. Severns, J. S. McGurk, A. B. Olson. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 609,480.00 Loans in Foreclosure 38,600.00 Stock Loans 14,579.92 Office Building 208,533.14 Furniture and fixtures 3,969.71 Other Real Estate 3,542.52 Real Estate Sold on Contract 22,935.30 Cash 28,894.38 Taxes Paid 2,217.75 Foreclosure Account 4,990.57 Sundry Persons and Accounts 17,984.58 Total : % 955,727.87 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 822,831.66 Paid-up Stock 45,450.00 Incomplete Loans 16,334.08 Reserve Funds 13,357.31 Undivided Profits 1,754.82 Mtge. Ass'n. Bldg 56,000.00 Total % 955,727.87 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1937 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 33,426,10 Dues (running stock) 550,114.96 Cash on hand last report $ 33,426,10 Loans made 4 94,231.98 Loans made _ * 94,231.98 Dues (running stock) 550,114.96 Running stock and dividends.. 718,179.10 Running stock and dividends.. 718,179.10 Paid-up stock 3,000.00 Repayment of loans 291,732.06 Real estate sales 2,500.00 Paid-up stock Paid-up stock 3,000.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 64.019.04 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 64.019.04 Repayment of loans 291,732.06 Expense __ _. 9.984.54 Real estate account 6,450.00 Expense __ _. 9.984.54 Real estate sales 2,500.00 2,500.00 Real estate account 6,450.00 Other receipts 217,697.51 Total $ 1,098,470.63 Other receipts 217,697.51 Other disbursements ...._ 205,605.97 Other disbursements 305,605.97 Total $ 1,098,470.63 Total * 1,098,470.63 Total i 1,098,470.63 Plan of Association.. Plan of Association. Permanent Permanent STiares in force at this date Shares in force at this date ..No. 20,659% No. 20,659 % </seg>
            <seg id="p071">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 71 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE COMMERCIAL SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 86 OFFICERS W. P. Adkins President Frank Koutsky _ Vice-President Jas. J. Fitzgerald , Secretary Alvin Johnson Treasurer A. H. Murdock Attorney DIRECTORS W. P. Adkins, Frank Koutsky, L. F. Etter, S. N. Wazynkewicz, A. H. Murdock, E. C. Kohansky, Jas. J. Fitzgerald. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 3,533,025.00 Loans in Foreclosure 71,015.14 Stock Loans 39,473.35 Office Building _ 38,000.00 Other Real Estate 28,917.59 Real Estate Sold on Contract 12,186.93 Federal, State, and Municipal Securities 8,156.46 Cash _ 75,805.82 Delinquent Interest 5,406.77 Total » 3,811,987.06 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 3,511,069.86 Paid-up Stock - 121,443.25 Incomplete Loans 11,728.92 Reserve Funds 155,000.00 Undivided Profits 12,745.03 Total ., * 3,811,987.06 T • Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 76,759.69 Cash on hand last report $ 76,759.69 Loans made . % 840,624.90 Loans made $ 840,634.90 Dues (running stock) 1,265,959.44 Dues (running stock) 1,265,959.44 Running stock and dividends.. 991,409.82 Running stock and dividends.. 991,409.82 Paid-up stock 19.988.1S Repayment of loans 644, 197. If Paid-up stock 19.988.1S Paid-up stock and dividends. 25,587.33 Paid-up stock and dividends. 25,587.33 Repayment of loans 644, 197. M Expense 28,509.44 Real Estate Account 33,944.13 Expense Expense 28,509.44 Other receipts _ 762.3S0.57 Other receipts 762.350.57 Real Estate Account ...- 33,944.13 33.944.13 Other disbursements 849,179.39 Other disbursements 849,179.39 Total $ 2,769,255.01 Total * 2,769.255.01 Total $2,7®,255.01 Total $2,769,255.01 Plan of Association. Plan of Association "~""'"""Z~". "."".No! 5 9 , 3 0 6 \ $ 200.00 Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock Shares In force at this date .No. 59,306% Par value per share of stock | 200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">LOAN ASSOCIATIONS BUILDING AND STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE CONSERVATIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 58 OFFICERS A. Baird President A. Lyons ■ Secretary t&gt;ert McMillan Treasurer ...i.. rbert McMillan Treasurer R. Donley Assistant Secretary ..Assistant Secretary Clark W. Carnaby -Assistant Secretary Wayne C. Selby Assistant Secretary .Assistant Secretary DIRECTORS Edgar A. Baird, Erastus A. Benson, Arthur W. Bowman, Randall K. Brown, Robert Dempster, Charles C. George, Byron R. Hastings, Frank T. B. Martin, J. Herbert McMillan, James C. Robinson, James A. Sunderland, Henry A. Thompson, Charles M. Wilhelm. ASSETS .$22,076,595.00 69,078.86 168,417. 7» 119,035.55 240,000.00 478,498.20 t 94,795.21 1 Securities 1,584,315.80 1,030,17 6.54 5tc 17,400.93 $25,878,313.88 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $22,517,076.51 Paid-up Stock 2,095,494.30 ruiu-up oiucn 2,U90,494.ov Incomplete Loans 275,546.38 Reserve Funds 975,000.00 Undivided Profits 15,196.69 975,000.00 15,196.69 Total $25,878,313.88 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending June SO, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Loans made _ $ 3, 769,581. 0? 1 on hand last report $ 830,686.17 3 (running stock) 7,573,794.00 l-np stock .._ 475,069.65 i^uaiis mauc _ .s./oy.Ml.uy Running stock and dividends.. 7,828,989.30 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 434,498.95 3,515,577.69 Expense Expense ____ 199,401.21 Real estate account 189.030.8S Other disbursements 1,918,951.36 8,926.93 189,030.85 fines, etc 1,183,259.52 1,918,951.36 753,138.80 414, 340, 452 . 76 Total 414,340,452.76 n of Association Permanent .res in force at this date No. 619,002 No. 619,002 Pge Loans In Foreclosure [jOCLUB Building e Block Real Estate state Sold on Contract 1, State and Municipal Securities lent Interest, Fines, Etc — • Total </seg>
            <seg id="p073">OFFICERS C. C. Haynes President v/. «_,. nay ues rresiaem H. C. Lane Vice-President r^j. ijttue ...._.___..._.—-.—.......-......._. ............ v icc-r resiucuL A. Gross Vice-President H. L. Helfrich Vice-President G. D. Taylor Secretary G. D. Taylor Treasurer M. O. Cunningham Attorney DIRECTORS C. C. Haynes, H. C. Lane, J. A. Gross, H. L. Helfrich, G. D. Taylor, E. Hodge, Fred Schollman, L. K. Brown, H. O. Cunningham. ASSETS Mortgage Loans _ $ 93,000.00 Stock Loans 4,029.50 Furniture and Fixtures 3,156.21 Other Real Estate 4,383.02 Real Estate Sold on Contract 3,116.75 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 9,950.00 Cash 9,250.78 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 195.88 Taxes Paid 113.78 Notes Receivable 2,205.78 Total $ 129,401.70 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 109,362.62 Paid-up Stock 19,289.45 Incomplete Loans 29.01 Reserve Funds 681.87 Undivided Profits 38.75 Total $ 129,401.70 Receipts and Expenditures RECEIPTS for the Year Ending June SO, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 8,971.00 Loans made $ 34,520,12 Dues (running stock) 104,807.15 Running stock and dividends.. 88,611.16 Paid-up stock 13,374.52 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 7,521.83 Repayment of loans 15,952.00 Expense 2,929.98 Real estate sales 3,773.89 Real estate account 4,383.02 Interest, fines, etc. 7,090.72 Other disbursements 18,316.37 Other receipts 2,313.20 Total * 156,282.48 Total } 156,282.4 Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date . Par value per share of stock ..No. 4,004 4.0U4 * 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NEBRASKA SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 27 OFFICERS Robert S. Wilcox President Thos. J. Fitzmorris Vice-President John R. Brandt Secretary C. P. Brinkman Treasurer E. M. Morseman, Jr Attorney DIRECTORS Thos. A. Fry, Robert S. Wilcox, Thos. F. Godfrey, Thos. J. Fitzmorris, Byron R. Hastings, Bartholomew Julien, C. F. Brinkman, O. D. Kiplinger, Homer O. Wilhelm. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 2,963,525.00 Loans in Foreclosure 3,965.97 Stock Loans 54,781.58 Other Real Estate 9,302.37 Real Estate Sold on Contract 13,193.04 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 59,400.00 Cash 134,806.43 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 333.49 Accrued Interest on Bonds 645.74 Total $ 3,239,953.62 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 2,562,090.62 Paid-up Stock 564.850.59 Incomplete Loans 16,381.53 Reserve Funds 76,000.00 Undivided Profits 20,630.88 Total $ 3,239,953.62 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS the Year Ending Jane SO, 1927 the Tear Ending June 30, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS Loans made _ _ _ $ 567,317.51 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 73,586.17 ish on hand last report $ 73,586.17 Loans made _ $ 567,317.51 Running stock and dividends.. 940,554. S3 Dues (running stock) 789,580.59 hies (running stock) 789,580.59 Running stock and dividends.. 940,554.53 Paid-up stock 80,873.87 Repayment of loans 667,822.62 'aid-up stock 80,873.87 80,873.87 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 141,438.22 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 141,438.22 Repayment of loans Repayment of loans 667,822.62 Expense 32,210.22 Expense ...._ 1. 32,210.22 Real estate sales 16,967.28 leal estate sales 16,967.28 Real estate account 14,421.10 Real estate account 14,421.10 Interest, fines, etc. 186.43S.53 merest, fines, etc. 186.43S.53 Other disbursements 200,027.83 Other disbursements 200,027.83 Other receipts 80,703.35 )ther receipts 80,703.35 Total $1,895,969.41 Total $ 1,895,969.41 Total $ 1,895,969.41 Total $ 1,895,969.41 Plan of Association. 'l&amp;n of Association „ Permanent Q* # a a 9^ f jm i </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE OCCIDENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 51 OFFICERS Kirk Griggs „ President J. E. Davidson Vice-President John F. Flach „ Vice-President W. R. McFarland Vice-President Geo. T. Morton Vice-President E. N. Bovell Secretary T. F. Wiles &amp; E. H. Westerfield Attorneys DIRECTORS John F. Flach, J. E. Davidson, John T. Brownlee, W. R. McFarland, George T. Morton, I. W. Carpenter, Kirk Griggs. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $17,447,508.29 Loans in Foreclosure 191,311.77 Stock Loans 25,634.66 Office Building 248.000.0* Other Real Estate 391,378.14 Real Estate Sold on Contract _ 260,135.23 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 12,916.55 Cash _ 508,776.82 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 99,560.00 Total $19,185,221.46 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $10,379,951.41 Paid-up Stock 8,137,210.38 Incomplete Loans — 55,928.34 Reserve Funds : — — 556,663.10 Tndivided Profits 55,468.23 Total $19,185,221.46 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 300,722.08 Loans made _$ 1,759,125.90 Dues (running stock) _ — 5,285,767.28 Running stock and dividends.. 5.041,809.86 Paid-up stock 986,468.61 Repayment of loans 3,484,833.61 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 3,199.7O2.»'i Repayment of loans 3,484,833.61 Expense 234,230.67 Real estate sales 268,481.81 Real estate account 500,264.03 Real estate account 500,264.03 Interest, fines, etc. 1,420,485.43 Other disbursements 2,240,588.36 Other disbursements 2,240,588.36 Other receipts ■ 1,228,962.78 Total $12,975,721.67 Total $12,975,721.67 Plan of Association. Permanent 253,895 Shares in force at this date . ...No. -$ </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 42 OFFICERS W. R. Adair President J. T. Helgren Vice-President M. M. Robertson Vice-President A. A. All wine Secretary-Treasurer Sidney W. Smith Attorney DIRECTORS W. R. Adair, G. W. Loomis, M. M. Robertson, J. T. Helgren, A. A. Allwine, Sidney W. Smith, Chas. E. Black, Joseph Barker, R. J. Dinning, L. C. Sholes, C. O. Talmage. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $31,753,694.43 34,275.20 529,202.46 585,000.00 11,000.00 48,064.27 518,519.57 718,876.08 1,237,672.21 24.564.35 26,403.39 48,456.10 $35,535,728.06 $32,861,500.50 1,527,948.98 205,371.23 875,000.00 65,907.35 $35,535,728.06 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 80, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report _ _$ 1,264,760.11 Cash on hand last report $ 1,264,7(0.11 Loans made _ $ 5,118,303.77 Running stock and dividends.. 10,131,993.99 Paid-up stock and dividends- 457,633.19 Loans made _ $ 5.118.303.77 Dues (running stock) - 9,826,570.49 Dues (running stock) - 9,826,570.49 Running stock and dividends.. 10,131,993.99 Paid-up stock - - 315,080.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 4S7.633.19 Repayment of loans - 5,696,635.12 Expense 210,339.38 Real estate sales 10,403.03 Real estate account 54,152.85 Interest, fines, etc - 1,916,100.56 Other disbursements 7,415,203.31 Other receipts 4,358,077.18 Other receipts 4,358,077.18 Total $23,387,626.49 Total Total ___._$23,387,626.49 Total __$23, 387,626. 49 Plan of Association. Plan of Association. Permanent Permanent Shares in force at this date .-$ I in Foreclosure Loans Building ture and Fixtures Real Estate Estate Sold on Contract al. State, and Municipal Securities luent Interest, Fines, Etc Paid Sundry Persons and Accounts Total ! LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends ! Paid-up Stock Incomplete Loans Reserve Funds Undivided Profits Total ! </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Lee A. Smith, Alfred G. Ellick, D. H. Christie, P. C. Hyson, Hugh W. Williams, J. Arthur Christie, Alfred I. Creigh. ASSETS Mortgage Loans I 1,084,295.00 Loans in Foreclosure 10,886.90 Stock Loans 23,100.00 Furniture and Fixtures 1,629. 90 Real Estate Sold on Contract 13,250.00 Cash 26,477.58 Taxes Paid 6,192.06 Real. Estate - 600.00 Total I 1,166,431.44 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 1,079,763.27 Incomplete Loans „ 45,938.32 incomplete L,oans „ «»,»3g.j2 Reserve Funds 22,550.00 neserve r uuus &lt;i,99u.uv Undivided Profits 17,144.24 Other Liabilities 1,036.61 Total I 1,166,431.44 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane SO, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Loans made * 194,980.00 DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 25,090.20 Cash on hand last report $ 25,090.20 Loans made $ 194,980.00 Dues (running stock) 365,331.27 Repayment of loans 198,010.00 Real estate sales 1,857.03 Dues (running stock) 365,331.27 Running stock and dividends.. 366,912.80 Running stock and dividends.. 366,912.80 Repayment of loans 198,010.00 Expense - _ 10,902.32 Expense Real estate account 10,902.32 Real estate sales 1,857.03 1,857.03 Real estate account 2,457.03 2,'457.O3 254,693.60 Interest, fines, etc — 60,483.85 Interest, fines, etc -..- 60,483.85 Other disbursements Other disbursements 254,693.60 Other receipts 179,173.*) Total $ 829,945.75 Other receipts 179,173.*) Tot»l f 829,945.75 Total $ 829,945.75 Tot»l * 829,945.75 Plan of Association. Plan of Association Permanent Permanent 5i. , asi Shares in (orce at this date Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock No. 22,331 Par value per share of stock </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS i STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 137 OFFICERS J. H. Beveridge President R. H. Thurston Vice-President R. H. Thurston Vice-President L. D. Spalding Secretary L. D. Spalding Treasurer C. E. Herring Attorney Attorney DIRECTORS J. H. Beveridge, R. H. Thurston, L. D. Spalding, C. E. Herring, F. L. Nesbit. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 706,169.47 Loans in Foreclosure 25,150.00 Stock Loans _ 21,833.62 Furniture and Fixtures 2,936.39 Other Real Estate 56.894.8S Real Estate sold on Contract 23,836.64 Cash 36,351.81 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 1,699.62 Taxes Paid , 4,427.36 Other Assets 540.29 Total $ 879,840.08 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 770,076.61 Paid-up Stock ~ 86,079.58 Incomplete Loans 11,767.75 Reserve Funds 11,279.31 Undivided Profits 435.92 Other Liabilities 200.91 Total * 879,840.08 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS the Year Ending June 30, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS Loans made .._ 4 154,747.63 the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 38,471.15 Cash on hand last report $ 38,471.15 Loans made 4 154,747.63 Dues (running stock) 332,897.13 Dues (running stock) 332,897.13 Running stock and dividends 316,833.58 Running stock and dividends 316,833.58 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 25,409.75 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 25,409.75 Paid-up stock 21,850.00 Repayment of loans 152,230.59 Paid-up stock 21,850.00 Repayment of loans 152,230.59 Expense 12,801.95 Expense 12,801.95 Real estate sales 2,495.72 Real estate sales 2,495.72 Real estate account 47,587.89 Real estate account 47,587.89 Other disbursements 60,532.21 Interest, fines, etc. 50,185.33 Interest, fines, etc. 50,185.33 Other disbursements 60,532.21 Other receipts 19,783.10 Other receipts 19,783.10 ' Total $ 617,913.02 Total $ 617,913.02 Total $ 617,913.02 Total $ 617,913.02 Plan of Association. Plan of Association Permanent Permanent Shares in force at this date Shares in force at this date ..No. 41,584% </seg>
            <seg id="p079">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 79 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE STANDARD SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 167 OFFICERS V. A. Johnson President John A. Anderson Vice- President John A. Swanson _ Vice-President O. W. Johnson Secretary-Treasurer DIRECTORS John A. Swanson, A. W. Johnson, A. G. Swanson, H. M. Soennichsen, S. J. Gottnied, Amos Grant, Carl Johnson. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 380,356.65 Loans in Foreclosure 1,132.51 Stock Loans 25,615.00 Furniture and Fixtures 1,626.52 Sundry Accounts 1,438.25 Other Real Estate 19,366.31 Real Estate Sold on Contract 12,666.31 Bills Receivable 2,080.16 Cash on Hand and in Banks 8,875.57 Delinquent Interest 2,990.91 Total _ f 456,148.19 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 395,182.31 Paid-up Stock 55,751.84 Incomplete Loans 4,374.44 Reserve Funds 800.00 Undivided Profits 39.60 Total * 456,148.19 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 11,775.16 Cash on hand last report $ 11,775.16 Loans made $ 101,758.91 Dues (running stock) 165,377.04 Dues (running stock) 165,377.04 Running stock and dividends. 151,410.14 Running stock and dividends. 151,410.14 Paid-up stock _ 39,500.00 Paid-up stock _ 39,500.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 18,189.07 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 18,189.07 Repayment of loans — 57,846.43 Repayment of loans - -... 57,846.43 Expense 5,426.2+ Expense 5,426.2+ Real estate sales 410.98 Real estate sales _ 410.98 Real estate account 21. 616.20 Real estate account 21.616.20 Interest, fines, etc. 27,428.44 Other receipts 295,897.08 Other disbursements 299,834.57 Other disbursements 299,834.57 Interest, fines, etc. 27,428.44 Other receipts 295,897.08 Total __ $ 598,235.13 295,897.08 Total — _* 598,235.13 Total $ 598.235.U Total $ 596,235.13- Permanent No. 11,627 % $ lOO.Ofr I Plan of Association. Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock. Shares in force at this date No. 11,627% J 100.0fr Par value per share of stock </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE UNION BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 162 OFFICERS F. C. Horacek President x- . v. iiui c*is«n. .............. .......... x: I ODIUCUl Joseph T. Votava Vice-President Lad. V. Tesar _ Secretary Emll Kavalec Treasurer .Treasurer Joseph T. Votava Attorney DIRECTORS • F. C. Horacek, Joseph T. Votava, Lad. V. Tesar, Emil Kavalec, Vaclav Tesar, Chas. F. Hermanek. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 359,950.00 Stock Loans 3,800.00 Furniture and Fixtures 1,375.00 Cash 7,704.81 Taxes Paid 839.36 Total $ 373,669.17 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 364,586.14 Incomplete Loans 4,501.10 Reserve Funds 2,998.93 Undivided Profits 1,583.00 Total % 373,669.17 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 3O, 1927 RECEIPTS | DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 24,447.40 Loans made __.$ 94,705.00 Dues (running stock) 176,317.10 Running stock and dividends.. 171,648.12 Cash on hand last report $ 24,447.40 Running stock and dividends.. 171,648.12 Pient of loans 54,875.74 | Expense 3,406.40 t, fines, etc. 18,228.08 Other disbursements 34,447.62 receipts 30,338.82 Repayment of loans 54,875.74 Total $ 304,207.14 1 Total $ 304,207.14 Plan of Association Permanent __ , _ . i«. j * »j q .nj. j. Par value per share of stock $ 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE PROTECTIVE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ORD, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 151 OFFICERS M. B. Goodenow President Geo. R. Gard Vice-President Jos. P. Barta Secretary Geo. R. Gard... Secretary Claude A. Davis Attorney DIRECTORS M. B. Goodenow, George R. Gard, Jos. P. Barta, Claude A. Davis, C. A. Hager, L. D. Milliken. DIRECTORS ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 461,350.00 ASSETS Loans in Foreclosure _ 1,240.70 Stock Loans 425.00 Office Building 10,000.00 Furniture and Fixtures 1,600.00 Furniture and Fixtures Other Real Estate 6,747.03 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 575.00 Cash , 22,252.96 Taxes Paid 8,188.19 Insurance Paid 25.00 Total * 512,403.88 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 300,246.25 Paid-up Stock 201,325.00 Reserve Funds 9,738.83 Undivided Profits 1,093.80 Stock and Dividends % 300,246.25 3tock 201,325.00 runds 9,738.83 1 Profits 1,093.80 Total $ 512,403.88 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending Jane 30, 1987 DISBURSEMENTS RECEIPTS Loans made _4 129,450.00 Running stock and dividends.. 88,867.40 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 87,364.73 Expense - 5,355.64 Real estate account 4,632.10 Cash on hand last report 4 8,810.73 Dues (running stock) — 109,232.63 Paid-up stock 97,775.00 Repayment of loans 68,476.00 Real estate sales — _ 125.00 Interest, fines, etc. 35,000.33 Other disbursements 37,692.50 Other receipts 33,942.68 * 353.362.37 Totml 4 3S3.362.37 Total .._. Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date No. 23,424% Par value per share of stock $ 100.00 Plan of Association.. Far value per share of stock </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE PLATTSMOUTH LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 26 OFFICERS C. A. Johnson President R. A. Bates Vice-President E. P. Lutx * Secretary F. T. Ramge Treasurer P. i . xvaiugc i reasurer . E. Martin Attorney DIRECTORS E. H. Schulhof, H. F. Goos, T. J. Janda, Win. Schmidtman ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 280,141.13 8tock Loans 22,490.00 Furniture and Fixtures 283.02 Other Real Estate 13,360.48 Cash 5,617.93 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc _ 2,436.28 Taxes Paid 2,154.63 Insurance Paid 80.80 Total I 326,564.27 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 246,832.17 Paid-up Stock 34,900.00 Reserve Funds 12,728.97 Undivided Profits 16,191.13 Bills Payable 15,912.00 Total $ 326,564.27 Receipts and Expenditures for Receipts and Expenditures for RECEIPTS the Tear Ending Jane SO, 1927 the Tear Ending June 30, 1927 DISBURSEMENTS Loans made .$ 34,660.00 Running stock and dividends.. 91,497.40 RECEIPTS Due« (running stock) $ 46,919.50 Due« (running stock) $ 46,919.50 uues muukj ? w,717.jw Paid-up stock 9,400.00 Repayment of loans 69,238.87 Real estate sales 6B1.42 Paid-up stock Paid-up stock 9,400.00 Running stock and dividends.. 91,497.40 Repayment of loans 69,238.87 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 28,910.39 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 28,910.39 Real estate sales 681.42 Expense 7,230.61 Interest, fines, etc. 26,242.82 Real estate account ..__ 2,361.28 Real estate account Other receipts' 33,036.58 Other receipts 33,036.58 Other disbursements 20,859.51 Other disbursements _ - 20,859.51 Total $ 185,519.19 Total $ 185,519.19 Total 4 185,519.19 Plan of Association. Plan of Association Serial Shares in force at this date Shares in force at this date .No. 3,744% Par value per share of stock - $ 200.00 Shares in force at this date .No. 3,744 % _ % 200.00 200.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 132 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE LIVINGSTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION PLATTSMOUTH, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 93 OFFICERS H. M. Soennichsen President Dorothy Svoboda Secretary Dorothy Svoboda _ Treasurer DIRECTORS H. M. Soennichsen, William Hassler, A. L. Tidd, John J. Svoboda, Win. Schmidtmann. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 800.00 Loans in Foreclosure 655.85 Stock Loans 2,320.00 Expense 3,344.65 Other Real Estate 38,367.41 Real Estate Sold on Contract 1,850.00 Cash 799.77 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 1,688.42 Other Assets 275.74 Total % 50,101.84 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 14,365.81 Paid-up Stock 12,625.58 Unpaid Stock _ 1,406.00 Unpaid Interest 282.42 Rent 7,433.67 Other Liabilities 63.31 Profit and Loss - 13,925.05 Total $ 50,101.84 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE SEWARD EQUITABLE BUILDING &amp; LOAN ASSOCIATION SEWARD, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 96 OFFICERS J. F. Geesen _ President M. C. Miller „ Vice-President Vice- President H. A. Graff Secretary W. E. Langworthy Treasurer J. J. Thomas Attorney DIRECTORS L. E. Ost, S. D. Atkins, Roy R. Schick, Frank Hints, Robert T. Cattle. Win. Luehman, Roy M. White. ASSETS Mortgage Loans * 385,725.00 17,790.00 5,383.60 923.00 3,710.73 1,773.45 3,684.22 68.20 $ 419,058.20 $ 284,135.35 105,150.00 15,811.23 10,679.09 3,154.33 128.20 .* 419,058.20 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Dues (running stock) .$ 73,295.50 Paid-up stock 2,700.00 Loans made 4 48,710.00 l'Uans jnauc 9 w,/iu.uu Running stock and dividends.. 45,299.63 Repayment of loans 33,323.98 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 23,495.18 Real estate sales Interest, fines, etc. 308.50 Expense 3,308.96 28,272.15 Real estate account 391.33 2,615.00 Other disbursements - 19,310.03 308.50 Other receipts Other disbursements — - 19,310.03 Total $ 140,515.13 Total t 140,515.13 Plan of Association Permanent r ia.11 ul juauuiaiiuu . ............................................... rcimaucui Shares in force at this date No. 8,915% Par value per share of stock I 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year — 6 years 7 months » Stock Loans Other Real Estate Real Estate Sold on Contract Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc Tax Sale Certificates Insurance Total LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends ! Paid-up Stock Reserve Funds Undivided Profit — Surplus Reserved for Paid-Up Stock Dividend Advance Interest Total - </seg>
            <seg id="p085">E. D. Worden Treasurer C. S. Radcliffe Attorney DIRECTORS DIRECTORS C. P. Chambers, Marius Christensen, Leslie Neubauer, E. D. Worden, Herman Schroeder, Leon Fine, E. S. Stokes, Dr. F. A. Barger, N. W. Ladegard. ASSETS auuu .M. u Mortgage Loans $ 55,700.00 Furniture and Fixtures 260.55 Other Real Estate 9,673.61 Real Estate Sold on Contract 50.00 Cash 230.57 Tax Sales 980.11 Furniture and Fixtures Real Estate Sold on Contract Tax Sales Total $ 66,894.84 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS RECEIPTS Cash on hand last report $ 1,1**-" Cash on hand last report $ 1,144.77 Dues (running stock) 23,298.99 Loans made .— .._.._...$ 22,000.00 Running stock and dividends.. 14,642.63 Expense . 318.58 Real estate account ..., ■ 500.00 Other disbursements 1,104.39 Loans made % 22,000.00 Dues (running stock) 23,298.99 Running stock and dividends.. 14,642.63 Repayment of loans 4,600.00 Real estate sales 3,500.00 Repayment of loan* 4,600.00 Expense ~»— —__—__«_——«• 318-58 Real estate sales 3,500.00 3,500.00 Real estate account ; 300.00 Interest, fines, etc. 4,760.44 Interest, fines, etc. 4,760.44 Other disbursements 1,104.9 Other receipts 1,261.40 Other receipts 1,361.40 Total $ 38,565.60 Total $ 38.565.60 Total $ 38,565.60 Total $ 38,565.60 Plan of Association.. Plan of Association. Permanent Permanent MS\S2VS.- ..No. 908 Par'value pe^share of Sm*TZ $ 200.00 ±aJL OaiCB iim i' i */ov.aa Total 9 66,894.84 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 55,269.66 Paid-up Stock ~ 5,063. 64 Reserve Funds — • . 2,344.00 Undivided Profits _ 2,687.41 Rente 1,530.23 Total $ 66,894.84 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE CITIZENS BUILDING. LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION SUPERIOR, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 47 OFFICERS J. H. Laird President C. H. Jensen Vice-President H. S. Nelson Secretary H. S. Nelson Treasurer P. H. Stubbs Attorney DIRECTORS J. H. Laird, C. H. Jensen, C. H. Fitch, John Eyre, W. J. Elliott, J. M. Silver, M. A. Sanders, J. C. Norgaard, H. 8. Nelson ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 250,600.00 488.20 2,900.00 15,442.99 577.00 $ 270,008.19 $ 81,972.30 159,700.00 1,049.08 15,000.00 5,630.17 4,656.64 2,000.00 $ 270,008.19 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending June 30, 1027 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report $ 13,918.65 Loans made _ - _...$ 61,450.00 Dues (running stock) .__ 30,869.17 Running stock and dividends.. 15,259.88 Paid-up stock . 46,600.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 37.903.85 Repayment of loans" 20,450.00 Expense 2,592.48 Real estate sales 3,600.00 Other disbursements 18,667.99 Interest, fines, etc. 20,436.38 Total 135,874.20 Total $ 135,874.20 Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock ..No 5,052 100.00 $ Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 73 Kture and Fixtures Estate Sold on Contract Paid in Advance Total LIABILITIES I Ing Stock and Dividends '. up Stock lplete Loans ve Punds r ided Profits ends on Paid Stock red Stock Total _ </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE TECUMSEH BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION TECUMSEH, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 122 OFFICERS P. A. Brundage President E. D. Hedrick Vice-President J. B. Douglas Secretary Harry Phelps Treasurer Jay C. Moore Attorney DIRECTORS P. A. Brundage, J. B. Douglas, E. C. Hedrick, J. A. Lawrence, Adolph Kovarik, W. M. Sherman, C. M. Shaw, Harold Sullivan, Dr. A. P. Fitzsimmons. ASSETS Mortgage Loans f 1,202,600.00 Loans in Foreclosure 4,716.18 Stock Loans 13,570.00 Office Building 7,800.00 Furniture and Fixtures 500.00 Other Real Estate 3,276.03 Real Estate Sold on Contract 1,892.35 Cash 32,459.31 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 2,260.85 Taxes Purchased 1,679.01 Total _ $ 1,270,753.73 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 478,004.86 Paid-up Stock _ 764,100.00 Incomplete Loans _ 8,200.00 Reserve Funds 20,149.37 Advance Payments 299.50 Total _ % 1,270,753.73 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Loans made _ _.$ 318,885.00 Cash on hand last report $ 46,912.20 Dues (running stock) 153,584.28 Running stock and dividends- 54,465.45 Paid-up stock 377,600.00 Repayment of loans _„_... 251,895.00 Real estate sales .__ 6,000.00 Paid-up stock and dividends- 395,132.68 Expense „ 16,526.80 Real estate account 3,276.03 Other disbursements 141,386.26 6,000.00 Interest, fines, etc. 77,502.56 Other receipts . , „ 16,178.18 Total $ 929,672.22 Total $ 929,672.22 Plan of Association. 25,290 100.00 Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock ..No. $ Average running time of stock matured during year — Class "A" 77% Months Class "B" 112% Months </seg>
            <seg id="p088">STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION TRENTON, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 74 OFFICERS L. L. Darby: President J. P. Allen Secretary O. H. Thomas Treasurer Secretary J. F. Ratcliff Attorney DIRECTORS BA. T. McCoy, J. W. Ireland, J. P. Allen, O. H. Thomas, J. F. Ratcliff L. L. Darby, E. J. Walters. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 34,500.00 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 576.20 Total $ 35,076.20 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 23,969.00 Paid-up Stock 4,850.00 Undivided Profits 6,257.20 Total $ 35,076.20 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS . DISBURSEMENTS Bon hand last report 1 908.36 Loans made $ 12,500.00 (running stock) 10,481.00 Sunning stock and dividends.. 737.95 up stock 4,850.00 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 6,200.00 Repayment of loans 1,500.00 Expense _ 347.61 Interest, 6nes, etc. 2,604.40 Other disbursements 576.20 Other receipts 18.00 2,604.40 Other disbursements 576.20 18.00 Total S 20,361.76 I Total $ 20,361.76 Plan of Association Serial Shares in force at this date -No. 916% Par value per share of stock $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mob. 76 Serial 76 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">Mortgage Loans $ 130,350.00 Furniture and Fixtures 396.84 Other Real Estate 13,585.33 r*nr,u in no? qi Other Real Estate Cash 10,927.93 Other Assets 7,972.02 Total $ 163,232.12 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 71,338.47 Paid-up Stock 87,250.00 Reserve Funds 4,500.00 Paid-up Stock Reserve Funds Undivided Profits 143.65 Total $ 163,232.12 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June SO, 1027 RECEIPTS I DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report 4 15,507.62 Loans made _ $ 6,100.00 Dues (running stock) 51,179.20 Running stock and dividends.. 56,158.64 l^u c5 \ run n lit k 9 LUv k j ltl ■■■■■» x* y* «u i xv li n n in ■£ s lcjc k aim u i v iQcncis jo x Jo • ut Paid-up stock _ _ 29,450.00 Paid-up stock and dividends- 49,662.97 D_- ~.~..* „.' 1--... 1C CCA nA TT - 1 ni -&gt; tO Repayment of loans 25.550.00 Expense _. 2,012.38 Interest, fines, etc _ 10,792.72 Other disbursements 24,214.63 24,214.63 Other receipts 5,669.08 Total 4 138,148.62 ! Total $ 138,148.62 Plan of Association .......... .......... . Permanent </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE VALENTINE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION VALENTINE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 65 OFFICERS "H. W. Hoenig President E. C. Davenport Vice- President F. A. Cumbow Secretary Chas. Lewis Treasurer Walott &amp; Walcott Attorneys DIRECTORS W. T. Kincaid, E. B. Foster, J. W. Tobien, Geo. C. Tobien, John M. Tucker. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 62,325.00 Stock Loans 2,900.00 Other Real Estate 16,261.18 Real Estate Sold on Contract 5,450.00 Cash _ 889.66 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 747.60 Taxes Paid 420.18 Insurance Premiums Charged Loan Accounts 325.44 Total $ 89,319.06 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 53,112.11 Paid-up Stock 26,450.00 Reserve Funds 6,500.00 Undivided Profits 3,256.95 Total $ 89,319.06 Receipts and Expenditures for the Tear Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS Loans made $ 2,500.00 Cash on hand last report $ 1,891.07 Cash on hand last report $ 1,891.07 Loans made $ 2,500.00 Dues (running stock) 6,184.70 Repayment of loans 1,932.78 Interest, Anes, etc. 4,803.25 Dues (running stock) 6,184.70 Running stock and dividends.. 494.47 Running stock and dividends.. 494.47 Repayment of loans 1,932.78 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 10,580.40 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 10,580.40 Interest, fines, etc. 4,803.25 4,803.25 Expense 771.39 Expense 771.39 Other receipts .................. 1,076.95 Other receipts .................. 1,076.95 Real estate . 544.28 Real estate . 544.28 Other disbursements 998.21 Other disbursements 998.21 Total i 15,888.75 Total J% 15,888.75 Total 4 15,888.75 Total 4 15,888.75 Shares in force at this date ... Par value per share of stock 765 % 200.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 127 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE WAHOO MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION WAHOO, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 55 OFFICERS B. E. Hendrlcks President A. Z. Donato Vice-President Geo. F. Frush Secretary Jas. L. Kudrna Treasurer B. E. Hendrtcks .....Attorney DIRECTORS Jas. O'Donnell, R. F. McCreery, Ernest Hanson, J. M. Ohslund, F. J. Kirchman, L. J. Kudrna. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 506,150.00 Stock Loans 2,900.00 Furniture and Fixtures 400.00 Federal, State, and Municipal Securities 2,250.00 Cash 18,114.95 Total $ 529,814.95 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends $ 390,577.95 Paid-up Stock 123,150.00 Incomplete Loans 2,200.00 Reserve Funds 12,800.00 Undivided Profits 1,087.00 Total ; * 529,814.96 * Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report -.$ 31,195,16 Loans made -._._ % 106,800.00 Dues (running stock) 73,892.00 Running stock and dividends.. 10,445.00 Paid-up stock 8,625.00 Repayment of loans -. 34,881.67 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 27,443.79 Expense 2,724. IS Other disbursements _... 39,164.95 Interest, fines, etc. 28.730.57 Other receipts' _ L — 9,253.52 Total $ 186,577.92 Total $ 186,577.92 Plan of Association. 12*464 Shares in force at this date .. Par value per share of stock ..No. 100.00 $ Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 127 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">A. N. Dodson, Jr Vice-President A. W. Fridrich ; Secretary J. J. Novak Treasurer .Treasurer H. V. Jelinek Notary DIRECTORS fin. Skopec, Anton Shimonek, George Shestak, E. J. Prucha, Wm. Bohaeek, V. J. Kohout, A. W. Fridrich, J. J. Novak. ASSETS Loans $ 117,200.00 Loans 5,200.00 281.7(5 rquent Interest, Fines, Etc 111.50 Total _ $ 122,7 93.26 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 113,199.21 Reserve Funds 4,900.00 Undivided Profits 54.05 Klvanced Dues and Interest 40.00 lie. Donoiiia a ar\{\ An Bills Payable 4,600.00 Total .....% 122,793.26 » Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane 30, 1927 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Loans made $ Cash on hand last report $ 4,093.97 Dues -(running stock) - 36,666.50 Repayment of loans 24,250.08 Interest, fines, etc 7.0"9.?n $ 34,450.00 Running stock and dividends.. 41,338.23 Expense 629.68 629.68 Other disbursements 281.76 Other receipts 4,600.01 Total .._ _| 76,699.67 Total $ 76,699.67 Plan of Association. Serial 1,417 Shares in force at this date .No Par value per share of stock $ 200.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 76 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS 93 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE WOOD RIVER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION WOOD RIVER, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 37 OFFICERS J- E. Hoye President E. B. Persson Vice-President W. L. Sprague Secretary J. J. Carter Treasurer Horth, Cleary and Suhr Attorneys DIRECTORS J. E. Hoye, E. B. Persson, E. H. Benson, O. K. Winn, E. T. Rounds, J. W. A. Hoppel, C. L. McGlasson, D. V. McKee, Charles E. Majors. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 90,700.00 427.00 500.00 3,664.90 1,124.42 6.25 % 96,422.57 % 89,715.66 5,192.45 511.83 1,002.63 $ 96,422.57 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June 30, 1927 RECEIPTS RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS DISBURSEMENTS tish on hand last report .$ 1,655.80 Cash on hand last report $ 1,655.80 Loans made $ 11,700.00 Loans made $ 11,700.00 Dues (running stock) 19,279.18 ues (running stock) 19,279.18 Running stock and dividends.. 35.025.29 Running stock and dividends.. 35,025.29 Repayment of loans 22,573.00 epayment of loans 22,573.00 Expense 583.39 Expense 583.39 Other disbursements 3,671.15 .CXpCIlSC JOO.J3' Other disbursements 3,671.15 interest, fines, etc — 7,471.85 Interest, fines, etc — 7,471.85 Total -* 50,979.83 Total .* 50,979.83 Total $ 50,979.83 Total $ 50,979.83 Plan of Association Permanent Shares in force at this date No. 2,580 Par value per share of stock $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 114 Loans in Foreclosure Stock Loans Cash Delinquent Interest, Pines, Etc Insurance Premium Total LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends R serve Funds divided Profits Advance Payments Total </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE WYMORE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION WYMORE, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 142 OFFICERS J. A. Reuling President W. L. Jones „ Vice-President Jno. W. Smith Secretary Lyman Bednar Treasurer C. B. Ellis Attorney DIRECTORS J. A. Reuling, W. L. Jones, Lyman Bednar, W. A. Stahl, Frank Meyers, W. A. Dawson, Jno. W. Smith. ASSETS Mortgage Loans % 430,975.00 Furniture and Fixtures 891.87 Other Real Estate 6,462.20 Real Estate Sold on Contract 4,586.60 Cash 9,438.95 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 66.75 Taxes Paid 7,200.84 Insurance Paid on Loans " 307.17 Total * 459,929.38 LIABILITIES Loan Payments $ 67,312.36 Running Stock and Dividends „ 62,017.71 Paid-up Stock 292,400.00 Incomplete Loans 1,301.10 Reserve Funds 18,908.70 Undivided Profits to Pay July 1, Dividends 14,989.51 Notes Payable 3,000.00 Total $ 459,929.38 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending Jane SO, 1027 RECEIPTS DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report 4 22,463.69 Loans made 4 C8,975.O0 Dues (running stock) _.. 74,636.70 Paid-up stock _ 85,300.00 Repayment of loans 60.00 Interest, fines, etc. 31,601.76 Other receipts 17,791.51 Running stock and dividends.. 7,445.13 Paid-up stock and dividends.. 68.655.94 Expense I 4,349.39 Real estate account 3,988.76 3,988.76 17,791.51 Other disbursements _ 78!439!44 Total $ 231,853.66 Total _$ 231,853.66 Plan of Association. Permanent Shares in force at this date Par value per share of stock .No. 10,279 $ 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 108 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE YORK MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION YORK, NEBRASKA At the close of business June 30, 1927 CERTIFICATE NO. 51 OFFICERS Geo. W. Shreck President C. A. McCloud Vice-President H. T. Frazier Secretary W. L. White .". Treasurer W. W. Wyckoff Attorney DIRECTORS N. A. Dean, E. B. Hanna, W. H. Read, G. H. Holderman, W. W. Wyckoff. ASSETS Mortgage Loans $ 134,700.00 Loans in Foreclosure ($5,700.00 less credits $617.30).... 5,082.70 Stock Loans 15,800.00 Furniture and Fixtures 389.00 Other Real Estate 407.69 Federal, State and Municipal Securities 5,000.00 Cash 17,431.18 Delinquent Interest, Fines, Etc 158.84 Properties from Settlement Account 7,146.74 Insurance Advanced _ 15.00 Total % 186,131.15 LIABILITIES Running Stock and Dividends % 167,446.25 Dues and Interest Prepaid 37.70 Reserve Funds 9,000.00 Undivided Profits 474.82 Loan Repayment Undistributed 1,000.00 Settlement Account Balance 8,172.38 Total * 186,131.15 Receipts and Expenditures for the Year Ending June SO, 1927 RECEIPTS I DISBURSEMENTS Cash on hand last report .._....$ 4,868.87 Cash on hand last report .._...4 4,868.87 Loans made $ 60,300.00 Dues (running stock) _ 52,588.60 Running stock and dividends- 71,669.95 Repayment of loans 78.600.00 Expense 3,363.82 Interest, fines, etc. 14,194.58 Other disbursements 32,880.66 Other receipts 17,962.38 Total .._ _ $ 168,214.43 Totml * 168,214.43 Plan of Association Serial Shares in force at this date No. 4,857 Par value per share of stock % 100.00 Average running time of stock matured during year. Mos. 87 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>