<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA.  THE DETERMINATION OF HUMUS.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">(This is a technical bulletin, issued in a limited edition, and U not sent out to the regular mailing list, but ma; be had on application.) The University of Nebraska. b ur i^ i^ Err i rc OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station THE DETERMINATION OF HUMUS. By F. J. Alway, E. K. Files, and R. M. Pinckney. June, 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD I OR ABLE CHAKLE9 S. ALLEN, Prmiitnt, Lincoln. OR ABLE WILLIAM (1. WHITMORE, Valley. OR ABLE VICTOR G. LYl'ORD, Falls City. ORABLB CHARLE8 15. ANDKKSOX. Crete. OKABLK GEORGE ( '&lt; H'l'LAXD, lOlgin. BONORABLE PRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. THE STATION OFFICERS SAMUEL AVKRV, Ph. D., LL. U., Chancellor, ex offieio. K. A. BURNETT, B. 8c., Lhrtetor. J. S. DALKS, M. Ph.. Financial Secretary. \VM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF. KEAD WlLCOX, PH. D., Agricultural Botany. ALWAY, PH. D., Agricultural Vkmmktrm. '. Chase, B. Be. M. K.. Agricultural Enginuring. . Smith, 11. Sc . Animal Husbandry. I. Gain, M. D. C, Animal l'atliobxjy. i. Haeckek, U. Sc. A., 1) i'u ii Husbandry. 'RENCE BRUNER, B. Sc. , EiitMlwlogij. . Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. nk J. Phillips, 14. F., Forestry. Kkwin H. Barbour, Ph. D., Otology- E. CHATBURN, A. M., Hiijlnr.ni Enyiueeritiy. . Kmerson. B. Sc, Horticulture. O. V. P. Stout, C. K., Irrigation EitgDieeriiuj. G. A. Loveland, A. If., Meteorology. - l J n;sLKv. I ; U Agronomy. W P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent ExperinmUul SHbttotioit, N'&lt;rtk PUttte. Miss Venus W. Pool, a. If., Assistant m Aiiriadtund Hotnny. G. Herbert Coons, A. 11.. Amkkuit in Agricultural Botany. K. S. TRUMBl'LL. A. M., Assistant in Agricultural CfcCMMfey. P. B. Barker. A. 15.. AmittmM in Aijruunjny (Soils). T. A. Kiesselbach, B. Sc, AsxistiDit i,, Bxptrimtmtnl Ajtnmtmu (CrojM). Kkwin Hopt, B. Sc, Aamatant in Agronomy (Crops) ■3. STURDEVANT, A. M., M. I).. Assistant in Aiiliuul I'otlwlwjy H. SWENK, A. M., Amststiu.t in Entomoiou*. R. F. Howard, B. So. in Agr., Assistant in ' Horticulture. IW. BURR, B. Sc., Assistant in Soils anil VrOf*, A'oct/i I'latte; Assistant Agriculturist. Ojfice Dry l.'iml Agriculturt, I . S. htfiaitineni of Agri - culture. James Cowan, Superintendent Mxptrimenial Subwtatim, Valentine. F. Knorr, B. Sc, 6 mknt Experimental Substation, Mitchell S. W. Perin, fWia Superi)Uendent. •Miss Louise M. Allen, a. M., Scientific Assistant, Seed Testing. •Mrs. J. A. Scott, A. B., Scientific Assistant, See'i TuUng. •Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture (,., m.i.t. or ,.. um , vi ...tv.) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">INTKoDIVTION The term humus is used in this country with two distinct meanings, the one including the whole of the more or less altered organic matter in the soihand the other only that portion of the black or brown material soluble in dilute alkalies. In the present article, the term is used to signify only the part of the organic matter dissolved by ammonia after lime and magnesia have been previously removed by treatment with dilute hydrochloric acid. The results obtained by treating the same soil with 4 per cent ammonia solution differ by from 10 to 230 per cent, according to whether the Hilgard method or that of the Association of Official Agricultural Chemists, which is commonly spoken of as the "official" method, be employed. As the most important d;it;i on humus have been obtained by Hilgard and u than can in no way be compared with data obtained by the A. O. A. C. method, we undertook to determine the causes of the differences in the results as well as the reliability of the two methods. While but a comparatively small amount of data based upon tkt of the A. O. A. C. method has been published, it is still commonly accepted both in America and in England 1 as a reliable method and is the one in common use. Humus as defined above is the matior mnrt of Grandeau and the different methods which have been proposed for its determination are modifications of his original method. These modifications have been limited chiefly to the treatment of the soil after the preliminary extraction with dilute acid and the subsequent washing with distilled water. In Grandeau 's method 2 10 grams of the soil, fraed of lime and magnesia, was mixed with 1 Hall, The Soil, 2d edition, p. 165 (1908). 2 Traite d' Analyse des Matleres agricoles, 3d edition, I, p. loo Bt F. J. Ai.ww, E. K. Fii.ks, and H. .M. 1'ixckney. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">The Determination of Humus 4 tie sand and "placed in a small funnel at the bottom of which fragments of glass or porcelain. The whole was moistened ammonia diluted with its own volume of distilled water allowed to digest for some time (three or four hours)." ammoniacal solution was displaced by adding water ; or water to which some ammonia had been added. The filtrate evaporated to dryness in a weighed platinum dish, dried, bed, ignited, and weighed again. The difference between i two weighings gave the amount of humus, and that be - a the second and the weight of the empty dish the amount nmus ash. Hilgard 1 modified the Grandeau method by placing the soil in a filter (of paper) and then covering it with a disk of filter paper, before the preliminary treatment with dilute hydrochloric acid and distilled water. The soil was then treated with 4 per cent ammonia water until the filtrate came thru colorless. Huston and McBride 2 made a critical study of the Grandeau method as used by Hilgard and as a result recommended a method, which soon after, with a few minor modifications, was adopted by the Association of Official Agricultural Chemists. They de - termined the humus in eight different soils, four of which were of a peaty nature, both by the Hilgard (called by them the Grandeau) method and by their own. They found the results obtained by the latter to be from 20 to 117 per cent higher than those obtained by the former. Assuming that this increase was due to the more complete extraction of humus by their method, they regarded the method of Hilgard as unreliable. What they had, in fact, done was to incorporate a large amount of clay with the humus. Upon ignition, after drying, this clay lost water, thus increasing the total loss in weight on ismition which they, like Grandeau and Hilgard, considered to represent the humus. Both the latter, however, obtained ammoniacal filtrates practically free of clay, this bciner retained by the soil thru which the ammonia had to pass. To the entire failure of Huston and l Bui. 38, Bur. of Ctoem., U. S. Dept. of Agr., p. 80 (1893); J. A. C. S., p. 41 (1894). t Bui. 38, Bur. of Ctaem. p. 84 (1893). </seg>
            <seg id="p005">McBride to take cognizance of the greatly increased amount of so-called "humus ash" obtained by their method is due their erroneous conclusions as to the reliability of the Hilgard method. They seem to have paid little or no attention even to the color of the filtrate obtained by treatment of the soil with ammonia. Otherwise they could not have considered their method as ap - plicable to all of their eight soils. Thus, in discussing the ques - tion "Is it possible to complete the extraction of Grandeau's method in a reasonable time?," they state that, "this was found to depend upon the kind of soil. With a soil like No. 6 and No. 8, using disk niters, the whole amount of extract could be removed in a few hours***." They took the residues resulting from the extraction of soils Nos. 6 and 8 by Hilgard 's method and treating these as tho they were fresh soils applied their method with the result that they obtained a loss on ignition (considered by them to be humus) equal to the humus obtained from the original soil by the Hilgard method. This ability to obtain as much loss on ignition when their methcd is applied to the residue of a soil from which all maticre noire has been extracted by the Hilgard method «s is obtained from the original soil by the latter method, which we have confirmed as described below, should have indicated the faulty part of their method. About the same time Snyder 1 published the description of a modification of the Grandeau method very similar to that of Huston and McBride up to the point where the soil shaken with a solution of ammonia had been allowed to settle. ' ' After settling, the dark colored solution is decanted into a filter, a fresh fifty c. c. portion of the dilute ammonia solution is then added to the flask, and the same treatment repeated. It usually requires three or four such treatments before the filtrate becomes clear; the contents of the flask are then brought on to the filter, and require but little further washing in the usual way before this part of the operation is completed." This modification of the Grandeau method he devised in order to overcome the dif - ficulty experienced in obtaining a complete extraction of the hu- t J. A. C. S., 16, p. 210 (1894). </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 The Determination of Humus I with ammonia, to lessen the time required for the extraction, to avoid the diffusion of ammonia fumes characteristic of the inal method. "The results obtained by this method of treat - t are much higher than those obtained when working in the il way. This is to be expected, inasmuch as more complete ex - tion of the humus materials is obtained by using the glass - pered flasks. Duplicate results with the ordinary Grandeau lod are far from being concordant, while with the glass-stop - d flasks reasonably concordant results are secured." Frear 1 in 1901 pointed out a serious source of error in the official method, giving an instance of a soil in which the loss on ignition (called humus) as determined by the official method was due principally "to the water of combination given up by the hy - drated minerals that passed through the filter with the humus.'' He stated that the suspended mineral particles "passed through single and double filters and single and double hardened S. &amp; S. Filters***. Only upon use of a Pasteur filter were we able to secure a clear solution. The filter was covered with dark colloid - al matter. Xo data have been accumulated to show the effect ot such filtration upon the humus in solution; therefore the results of analysis of the filtrate cannot be regarded as trustworthy." Cameron and Breazeale 2 two years later determined the hu - mus in six soils using both the official method and the modification suggested by Frear, viz., the use of a Pasteur-Chamberland filter. They obtained only from one-half to one-twentieth as much humus by the latter as by the former method. They called attention to the fact that it was not certain that some of the humus had not been absorbed and thus removed from the solution and that "humus determinations are tedious, especially if recourse must be had to I Peter and Averitt, 3 referring to the unreliability of the offi - method, suggested that the results so obtained be corrected by Ktmg one-tenth of the weight of the so-called "humus ash." 1 Bui. 69, Bur. of Chem.. p. 40 (1902) S J. A. C. S., 26, p. 29 (1904). I Kentucky Bui. 126, p. 63 (1906). </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The Determination of Ilumus Mooers and Hampton 1 introduced a modification of the Hus - tnii-McIiride method intended to remove th ided mineral matter. "The ammonical humus extract containing day in suspen - sion is evaporated to dry ness over a steam bath, by whic-h means the clay is flocculated so that after extraction with 4 per cent am - monia it can be retained by a common filter paper. Two evapora - - and filtrations arc Decenary as a rule in order to a filtrate in which the hwnms is determined as usual." I'sinir live ■oik they compared the results obtained by their method with those obtained by the official method, iin.l by the Cameron and Breazeale modification, and with the Peter and Averitt corrected results. They concluded that while the official method irave results far too high, the Cameron-Hrea/.e;ile Method gave results from 'W t per cent too low, and that a correction of 14 per cent gave more lienily correct results than that of 10 per cent. R Notwithstanding the various criticism! of the Huston and Me - rle method which have appeared, it is still retained as the nuth - of the Association of Official Agricultural Chemists. 8 THE SOILS USED. Etn the soils used, we had representative! of the arid soils, IX, and XIII ; of the semiarid soils, III, IV, V, VI, VIII and and of the distinctly humid soils. VII and X. The other sam - belong to the eastern portion of the transition region of the t Plains. No. I. A composite of surface six-inch samples from a field of upland loess near the Nebraska Experiment Station farm at Lin - coln. The field had been in cultivation for about forty years, with heavy applications of barnyard manure during the last twelve. Normal annual precipitation, 28.66 inches. I No. II. A composite of surface six-inch samples from a vir - prairie near Broken Bow, Nebr. The soil is loess, tho more ly than No. I. Normal annual precipitation. 2~&gt;.:r&gt; inches. l J. A. C. S., 30. p. 805 (1908). 2 giii 107 ( Revised ) Rnr of Oh em D 19 (1908) </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 No. III. The surface four inches of soil from a virgin prai - rie near Madrid in western Nebraska. A sandy loam residual soil. Normal annual precipitation, 17.12 inches. tNo. IV. A composite of many samples taken at a depth of ve inches from both cultivated and prairie fields near Moose , Sask., Canada. The soil is a heavy lacustral clay derived 1 the drift material and deposited in glacial Lake Saskatche- Normal annual precipitation, 15.6 inches. iNo. V. The surface foot from the virgin prairie near Leth - »e, Alberta, Canada. A clay loam, probably similar in origin o. IV. Normal annual precipitation is about 14 inches. KNo. VI. Surface six inches from virgin prairie near Solano, leastern New Mexico. A loam of residual origin. Altitude ) feet. Normal annual precipitation is about 16 inches. No. VII. Surface soil from near Cloudcroft in the Sacra - mento Mountains, New Mexico. A black loam. A dense growth of coniferous trees covers the mountains at the altitude where the sample was secured, viz. 8,900 feet. Normal annual precipitation, 25.14 inches. I No. VIII. Surface foot of soil from Parsons' dry land ird near Parker, Colorado. Normal annual precipitation is t 17 inches. INo. IX. Surface six inches from recently broken grass land sulphur Spring Valley, Arizona, eighteen miles north of Doug - which lies on the Mexican boundary. Soil of alluvial origin, mal annual precipitation, 10.5 inches. I No. X. Surface foot from a bog near Fremont, Nebraska, soil is so little above the level of the Platte River that it is •ated at all times of the year. No. XI. A composite of surface six-inch samples from long cultivated fields near Pendleton, Oregon. The soil is commonly known as "volcanic ash" but i3 a residual soil derived from basalt. Normal annual precipitation, 14.2 inches. No. XII. Surface six inches from long cultivated field east of Fresno, California. A red loam which had never been irrigated. Normal annual precipitation, 9.00 inches. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 BXo. XIII. Surface six inches of sandy alluvium near Delano, fnrnift. The field had beefl under "dry farminir" alxm •s, being non-irrigable. Normal annual precipitation, 6.07 Xo. 143:1. From the same prairie as No. III. Nos. 902 to 917. Similar to No. I but taken to a depth of 12 COMPARISON OF RKKl'LTS OBTAINED HV DIKFKIJKXT MKTHODS. With all the methods the soils were treated similarly previous to the application of ammonia, the lime and magnesia being washed out with 1 per cent hydrochloric acid and the acid removed by washing with distilled water. It was found economical of time, as most of the soils were of fine texture, to use an ordinary filter in a funnel without suction, rather than a gooeh crucible with an asbestos filter. Tn all determinations a 4 per &lt;-ent solution of ammonia was used. Freshly distilled ammonia was used because an ammonia solution allowed to stand in bottles of ordinary glass soon Ives enough to seriously affect the amount of residue remain - ing after the ignition — the so-called humus ash. The humus ex - tract, by whichever method obtained, was placed in a platinum dish, evaporated on a steam bath, and dried at 110° C. Numerous comparisons showed that the same results were obtained as by drying at 100° C. and the time of drying instead of being 12 to 24 hours was reduced to 2 to 4 hours. I Table I gives the humus and humus-ash as obtained by the erent methods, the percentages given in the table being the •ages of two, and in most cases of three, determinations. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">The &gt;et jrrninahon o/ J umus H - ' • ' • R«S« H t-*»-^©r^coao^H &amp;h 8 »;« — &amp;h8 • • X &gt;- ~ M r^ '- — — — » iSSciia 35 -r n S 3: OS CJ « » CT&gt; I I b|S*S52E c ,» I— I — &gt; . — I I ;- — — © — 3:©=: *&gt; Sr-r-xt-^X) B-8 jri • •- • SS5SS s '-' ' * a^ » •r. i a T 9 £ ■ 9 = S * im « ia &gt;r\ s i — '5 ■I. ;- -^ ift &lt;m — ?) -»&lt; — &lt; 5 2 ' s? |&gt; V w — ~ © --C — -f "■i o^i« — i- ci — - *« I l l &gt; ,» tccVCtSH "" S _" co — — ri 7i" -* n — a 's ' 1 — ~^ — — MCCC ,« S O « O O C CC **• S r-i M i-l •— Cl I-" - 1— « ,&lt;u s x; •»" sc x © x L „ 8 f : : : '■&amp;&amp; • • • • V. HI : :« :*« •S os-g n n ■■-- St « pd to o S S 3 | M </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Determination of Humus 11 The results for the humus will be considered first. While those obtained by the Hilgard method in no ease agree with those obtained by the Huston-McBride method, they in all cases agree with those obtained by the two methods in which the clay is removed from the humus extract, viz., the Cameron-Brea - zeale and the Mooers-Hampton. In the case of only Nos. VII and X does the humus found by the Huston-MeBride method approach that obtained by the Hilgard, being less than 15 per cent higher, while in all other cases it is from 50 to 280 per cent higher. In the case of all except Nos. VII and X a correction of 10 per cent of humus ash gives results still much too high. When this correction is raised to 14 per cent, the results agree fairly well in some cases, but are too high in some and too low in others. When the data from individual determinations are considered, it is evident that in many cases the agreement of the averages is due to low results being counterbalanced by high ones, as may be seen from Table V. I The so-called "humus ash" shows still more variant results i does the humus. The amount found by the Huston-MeBride hod varies from 4 to 38 times as much as that found by the Hil - 1. In general, the higher the ratio of ash to a tual humus the ter is the error in the amount of humus found by the Huston- Jride method. In the majority of cases less ash is found by Cameron-Breazeale method and still less by the Mooers-Hamp - than by the Hilgard. There is, as shown below, no definite re - in between the humus and the ash, the latter varying by 100 cent in the case of duplicate determinations in which th&lt;&gt; Its for humus agree. THE HILGARD METHOD. The importance of a thoro examination of the method which has been used by Hilgard is due less to the probability that it will be used extensively in the future than to the fact that upon it de - pends the value of so much of his work upon humus. For this reason it is important to consider just how he himself has used the method. In practice he has continued the treatment with am - monia until the washings were colorless or so nearly so that the un- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 The Determination of Humus .vcl liunius would make no appreciable difference in the re - sults. This is indicated in his letter to Huston 1 in April, 1892. Altho it is not specifically stated in the various publications describing his method, 1 it should be self evident that, when the soil is being washed with ammonia in order to dissolve out the tnnlicre MHTtf, the washing should be continued until the ammo - nia no longer brings away any "black matter" as indicated by the color. After one has familiarized himself with the method, he can judge from the intensity of the color of the washings whether enough humus remains to cause an appreciable difference in the results. That ten days or even longer may be required to complete the extraction in the case of some soils we have found to be true, but this does not at all invalidate the accuracy of the method. Hilgard himself regularly reported the amount of humus ash. He obtained the filtrates clear, before transferring them to the plati - num dishes for evaporation. In a private communication in 1907 he &lt;1 that where his students obtained turbid solutions he had '.hem make use of a I'asteur-Chamherland filter before evapora - tion — a practice wh/&lt; h. m shown below, does not introduce any error. 1 Bui. 38, Bur. of Cbem., p. 84 (1893). J Ibid., p. 80; J. A. C. S., 16, p. 34, (1894); Circular No. 6, Uni. of Calif. (1903). </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Determination of Humus 13 Table II. — Agreement of duplicate determhtatioim by the llilgaixi methml. Determinations Difference r A H C At. Humus Ash Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent I Table II sliows Um igl'Wtrt of different detfrniinations by Hilgmrd Method when extra— e ean had beta takm not only ;isli ( ut all the humus but also to avoid any of the clay boag ied over the edge of the filter. Further, these determinations ■ made by those who had had nmrh experience with the method they. ac&lt; urdinyly. are more eOKOrdni than the re - 3 obtained in the ordinary course of analysis. The variation reen different determinations of the same soil is indicated in last two columns of the table which show the relation of the IWM to the lowest individual determination. For the humus 1 Humus Ash 2.2&lt;i .til 2.21 4:( " Humus Ash .68 1 M .a ,„ I Humus I Ash .74 i . o.-, .77 ,v Humus Ash l.« 1.112 v Humus Ash 1.58 1.1.4 . ■"&gt;•". V, Humus Ash .70 sii .a "■ Humus Ash 7.30 S.tt 7.:;2 2.77 ™ Humus Ash .fl .SI .7:! .47 .. IX X XI XII XIII Humus Ash Humus Ash Humus Ash Humus Ash Humus Ash ..19 .u 9.46 l.M .49 .27 .44 :i7 .44 .Ii7 9. HO 1 33 .49 .30 .41 3l 43 .19 2.19 27 •&gt; ■&gt;•&gt; "^44 :? 126 I.M ti7 t&gt; "i 1.00 .7H 1 01 .7tS t "4 1 III) .-•1 l.til .M l i« l.til .47 4 "41 .ti7 4 "11 7.33 2.44 7.:u 2.72 0 21 .72 .26 .•".7 .77 .71 .- r &gt;7 .117 | 5 "i 9.."&gt;;{ 9.. 515 1. 35 I "4 .50 .:w .49 .29 2 "io :s7 .24 .41 .:w 19 54 .47 .lti .45 .20 9 M </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 The Determination of Humus this varies from 0. to 19 per cent with an average of 5.5, the greatest difference being shown by a soil poor in humus. The humus ash shows a variation of from 3 to 126 per cent, with an av - erage of 33.2. There is no relation between the agreement of duplicate determinations of humus and that of the corresponding duplicates of ash. I As the results in the above table are not representative of the Its of ordinary analysis, the following two summaries are n, they having been obtained without reference to testing the ibility of the method. In one series of 30 soils with a humus ent varying from 0.54 to 1.53 per cent, the maximum dif - nce between either one of the duplicates and the average of two was 15 per cent of the lower result, while the average erence was 3.5 per cent. In another series of 18 soils contain - from 2.80 to 3.50 per cent of humus, the differences were 8 4 per cent, respectively. Where the ammonia solution was applied continuously to the prepared soils until the washings were colorless, the extraction was in some cases incomplete, but when the soil near the end of the operation was allowed to stand some time between succes - sive washings the extraction could be carried to completion. Samples of the 13 soils, in sets of four, five, or six each, were subjected to the continuous application of 4 per cent ammonia solution until the washings became colorless. Then the receivers were replaced by others and ammonia added to the residues at wide intervals, until after standing 24 hours without washing an application of ammonia gave a colorless filtrate. Determinations were made of humus and ash obtained both previous and subse - quent to the change of receivers. Even where the second filtrate obtained by the continued washing with ammonia was colorless, it was evaporated in a platinum dish and the latter dried, weighed, ignited, and weighed again. The approximate average lengths of time required for the different soils is shown in Table III. The time required to obtain a colorless filtrate by continuous washing varied from 3 to 90 hours. In the case of soil No. X, 19 days' additional treatment was required in order to remove the </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Determination of Humus 15 tions of soils. -ssiKssr ™~-° First extraction. Soil Hilgard method. Time Humus Ash Time Humus Ash Humus | Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent , Per cent IlOhrs. 2.12 .41 ",dav 5 " 1 56 .66 4 •'• Ill 5 IV 18 .(Ht .as .oo I .ai :;•&gt; .15 n I In the case of the soils other than Nos. VII and X the addi - al amounts of humus obtained by the continued extraction were much greater than the differences between duplicate determina - s. The individual determinations obtained at the change of ivers agree almost as well as those indicated in Table II, re all had been carried to exhaustion. The effect of the con - ied extraction, however, is to lessen the differences, that member , set of three which shows the smallest amount of humus at the lge in receivers usually giving the most in the second extraction, increase in ash is in all cases very slight and in most cases slight to be detected. All the residues, except those of Xos. II and IX, were, after the above exhaustive extraction, transferred to flasks and treated with 4 per cent ammonia solution, etc., by the Mooers-Hampton method as tho they had been fresh soils. This gave any of the particles of humus not previously reached by the ammonia an opportunity to dissolve and also subjected the whole of the remain - ing organic matter to 36 hours' contact with fresh ammonia. The averages of the determinations are shown in the last two 2.12 .41 5davs .10 M .00 .00 1 56 Ji5 4 •'• .08 .01 1.01 .71) 1 ■ .00 .00 .00 .00 1.52 .M I • .09 .02 .01 .00 18 " 5 " 40 " 4 " 3 " 90 " 5 " 64 " 1.54 6.-1 .64 . SB B.M .49 .34 .4ti .«" 2.59 .34 .(7 l.lfi .29 .23 5 •• 1 " 7 " I •■ ."&gt; •• lit '• :i ■• T " .07 .00 .« .07 .02 .M .07 .01 .00 .13 .01 .00 .12 .00 .07 .00 .09 .00 "in" .(Ml .00 I </seg>
            <seg id="p016">The Determination of Humus 16 Iie extraction. Before the large amount of suspended clay removed by the evaporation and subsequent filtration it was possible to decide from the color whether any humus had dissolved by this last treatment. The increase for No. VII only 1 per cent and for No. X only 2 per cent. To determine what is the effect of filtration thru a Chamber - land-Pasteur filter upon the Hilgard humus extract, we made use of the humus extracts obtained by continuously applying ammonia to the soils until the washings were colorless. Accordingly the results are not to be compared with those in Table I but with those in the third and fourth columns of Table III. In this case equal portions of the extracts from two or three samples of each soil were combined to form a composite which was passed thru a filter pre - pared as follows: A new Chamberland-Pasteur filter, or one that had been burned out in the furnace after it had last been used, was washed with 4 per cent ammonia as described below until 100 c. c. of the filtered ammonia solution when evaporated in a platinum dish left no residue. The composite extract was then passed thru this filter and three aliquot portions used for the hu - mus determinations. The results of the three determinations, as was to be expected, agreed very closely with one another. The av - erages compared with those of the un filtered extracts are shown in Table IV. While in two cases there is a distinct loss of ash due to filtration, the changes in humus are not greater than the experi - mental error. Accordingly a Chamberland-Pasteur filter so pre - pared may be considered to have no effect upon the amount of hu- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">The Detnmination of Humus 17 Tabi.k IV. — Effect of the Ch&lt;imberLmd-P&lt;t&gt;4eur filter uj&gt;on humus solution. THK HUSTON-McMHIDK Oil "OFFICIAL" METHOD. The analyses were conducted aecordiag to the directions in the "Official and Provisional Methods of Analysis of the Association of Official Agricultural Chemists,' 1 except that instead of usinga gooch crucible for the preliminary treatment of the soils with acid and distilled water, we used ordinary filters in funnels provided with protecting: disks of filter paper, and instead of glass-stoppered cylinders we in most etOM employed trlass-stoppered graduated flasks. The use of gooch filters had not been found economical of time when working with many samples, and numerous compari - sons of the cylinders with flasks had shown that where the soils stood in contact with the ammonia solution for 36 hours the shape of the vessel made no difference in the results. With peaty soils, however, there miffhi 1 e an advantage in using cylinders. Soil No. Before filtration After filtration | L&lt;&gt;-&gt; L&lt;&gt;-&gt; I |[ in IV v VI VII VIII IX X XI XII XIII Humus Ash Humus Ash Hiiinns A-.fi Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 2.12 .41 t.m .44 .M t.tt tV&gt; l.M .Ml l.ul 7ti .Hit TO (12 1.52 .*2 1.56 .39 — M r.i l :&gt;i An 1.5S .4it .01 .&amp;5 .tiT .09 .« l."&gt; 6.71 -2..-)H «.t« 1. 1:&gt; .oil .64 .34 .»&gt;.") .34 —.01 (Ki .56 .67 66 uti .00 ni 8.99 1 a 8.M 1.51 .4!i .:".) AH .SI .01 .:« .a :i2 .15 61 .36 .15 .90 .21 .0« </seg>
            <seg id="p018">The Determination of Humus 18 Table V. — Agreement of duplicate detertninations by the Hueton-McBride method. methods are great and bear no definite relation to the humus ob- Soil Determ inatioas Difference : A Percent c Percent (' Average Humus Percent Percent Ash Percent Percent 1 Humus Ash 3.47 9.95 3.00 6.52 3.51 7.02 3.33 17 7. *3 -,- " Humus Ash 2.52 3 61 2.46 3.58 2.36 4.21 2 45 7 3.80 ■••■*- 111 Humus Ash 2.35 3 58 2.66 3.27 2.09 3 11 2.33 27 3.32 ■"I.™ ,v Humus Ash 3.82 11.40 3.42 8.67 3.62 11 10.03 -*• v Humus Ash 3.53 12.37 3.22 9.28 3.43 13 65 3 39 10 11 77 -«••• " Humus Ash 2.47 10.93 2.14 10. (il 2.34 10.37 2.32 15 10.64 - Humus Ash 8 87 6.01 8.06 10.29 8.10 8 66 8.34 10 8 32 ••••*- " n Humus Ash 2.72 9.33 2.92 15.72 2.46 13.80 2.70 19 12.95 ••• — ••• ■ Humus Ash 1.88 6.80 1.82 6.80 1.85 7.51 1.85 3 7.03 -,„ * Humus Ash 9.80 4.12 10.06 6.08 9.92 5.32 9 93 3 5.17 ■-*" . Humus Ash 92 2.50 .88 1.77 .91 2 34 .91 4 2.20 •«- - Humus Ash .52 3.50 .68 4.00 90 5.20 .70 73 4.23 ••*■• „ Humus Ash .99 1.80 1.03 2.10 1.27 3 01 1.10 28 2.3u ••••«- I As shown by Table V, the d ter in the case of the humus i found in the Hilgard mei lifferenees between duplicates are I and less in that of the ash than thod. The maximum difference I humus between duplicates is 7 ash is 70 per cent, the averag it respectively, against 5.5 and 3 per cent of the lower while that ;e difference being 17 and 40 per I 3.3 in the Hilgard method. The differences between the amount! s of humus obtained by the two </seg>
            <seg id="p019">The Determination of Humus 19 to a considerable extent with the same soil. Thus from Table I it will be seen that for soil No. Ill a correction equal to 40 per cent of the ash is necessary while for X one of only 8 per cent is neces - sary. As pointed out above, even where 14 per oent seems satis - factory for the average of two or three determinations, this is often due to the wide variation in ash between the different determina - tions. Thu3 an the case of No. VIII the average for the three de - terminations is .89 per cent of humus which is not so far from the J.ABLE VI. — Comparison of rest with those of the Hilgard method. tso iiston-} r 'j«. Humus Difference compared with amount found by method of Soil I'U. ■ 1 MeBHd^ _Hilsard_ Difference Per cent Per cent Per cent 401 3.17 3.00 .77 410 5 40 3.47 1.93 411 o.2o 3 23 2.02 412 5 60 3.32 2.28 413 5.20 3 35 I.K 414 5.30 3.40 1.90 41ti 5 00 2.15 417 *&gt;.25 2.t«."» 3.60 418 5.30 2.63 2.77 419 3.85 2.95 .90 420 4.10 2.!i.-, 1.15 421 4.70 3.35 1.35 508 5.26 2.60 2.66 509 5 20 2.60 2.60 I 3.33 2.22 1.11 II 2 45 1.64 .81 III 2.33 1.01 1.32 IV • 3.62 1.61 2 01 V 3 39 1.61 1.78 VI 2.32 .80 1.47 VII X.34 7.31 1.03 VIII 2.70 .71 1.99 IX 1.85 ..")7 1.28 X 9.93 9.53 .40 XI .90 .49 .41 XII .70 .41 .29 XIII 1^0 .65 nusioD- ... , Me Bride ""(fa™ Per cent Per cent 20 3t&gt; 38 40 h!i 36 36 M 43 75 131 119 23 31 31 29 50 Ml 50 100 33 33 50 57 131 M I2r» M 111 63 173 12 14 74 280 69 4 4 46 84 41 71 59 144 Huston- Mc Bride I The success of the attempt to make sj the data from the Huston-McBride metl itisfactory corrections lod would be depend- ent upon the percentage of ash being stated L Even with the ash given, the factor to be used would vary wi th different soils and </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 .71 per cent found by the Hilgard method. This fairly satisfactory average, however, is obtained from three determinations which gave 1.41, 0.72, and 0.53 per cent respectively. I As Huston and McBride have stated, soils extracted by the jard method give an additional loss on ignition (called by them ius) when treated by their method. Ten samples of No. 1433 acted by the Hilgard method were subjected to treatment by Huston-MeBride method. The results ranged from 0.37 to 0.62 cent of humus and from 1.44 to 2.01 per cent of ash. Five ;r soils were similarly treated. Altho the ammonia was colored by freshly dissolved humus, the large amount of clay I in suspension caused a loss on ignition, after the second ex - tion, about equal to that after the first, as shown in Table VII. LTablk VU. — Trecitment of residue* from Hihjard method by on-McBride metlwd. THE CAMERON-BHEAZEALE METHOD. I We used the apparatus devised by the United States Bureau Soils for the Chamberland-Pasteur filter, forcing the solution u the filter by means of compressed air. On the pressure cyl - era, which were silver-plated, the plating was so thin that it i necessary to coat the inside of the cylinder with paraffine to vent the solution of copper. The humus extracts were prepared by the official method and a composite sample of the extracts made by combining equal volumes. The Chamberland-Pasteur filter was washed with dis - tilled water, after which 4 per cent ammonia solution was forced Soil No. First ex Hiljrard raction. method. Second extraction. Huston-Mc Bride method. Humus Ash Humus Ash 902 911 915 916 917 1433 Per cent 2.68 1.24 1 80 1 91 1.88 .82 Percent .44 .26 .35 .62 41 .25 Per cent 1.25 1.83 l.Tt 2.07 1.92 .37 to .tf Per cent 5.77 io.:&gt;i 10.66 12.06 11.21 1.44 to 2.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">The D&lt; t&lt;nni nation of Humus 21 thru imtil a portion of the filtrate on evaporation gave no dues. Then 300 c. c. of the composite humus extract was f&lt; thru the filter and the filter washed by forcing thru 4 par ammonia solution until the washinirs were colorless. Filtrate ;in&lt;! washings were made up to a definite volume and aliquot portions used for the three determinations in the ease of each soil The averages of the three, which were in all eases concordant, are given in Table I. The percentages of humus agree with tfcaM found by the Hilgard method, but the ash is in most cases much lower. While this method, when carried out as just deeeribed, gives satisfactory results, it is so much more tedious than either the Hilgard or the Mooers-IIampton methcd that it is not to \*&gt; recommended. I"nle«s the above prwuUcB be ebserved. the re - sults are not to be relied upon. THE MOOKRSHAMProN METHOD. The percentages of humus obtained by this method within the linrts of experimental error with those obtained by the preceding method but the ash is, in most cases, much lower. As shown in Table VIII the duplicate determinations of humus ■free well, the percentage difference varying from 1 to 1") per cent with an average of 5.7. As in the ease of tlie Hilgard method, the a.-h sin wa ■ much greater variation, ranginir fr&lt; in 0 to 1 ( &gt;J </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 The Determination of Humus Table VIII. — Agreement of duplicate determinations by lh( Mooers-Hampton method. Determinations T. A H Percent Percent 2.07 Ash 72 II Humus 1.61 1 66 Ash .21 2S III Humus 1.05 1.05 Ash .42 4-2 IV Humus 1 .59 1.62 Ash .30 28 V Humus 1.54 1.61 Ash .20 17 VI Humus .91 «.»3 Ash .40 38 VII Humus 7.50 7.44 Ash .38 62 VIII Humus .74 78 Ash .15 12 IX Humus .62 80 Ash .20 23 X Humus 9.S6 9.48 Ash .60 72 XI Humus .49 51 Ash .10 15 XII Humus .39 38 Ash .08 08 XIII Humus .43 44 Ash .21 19 THE SNYDER METHOD. §As this method appears to have been used by no one except author of it and as it offers no particular advantages over the i^ird and the Mooers-Hampton methods, we gave it a careful with only a single sample of soil, one from the loess of eastern I Humus 2.01 ations erence C Average Humus Ash Percent Percent Percent Percent 2.12 2.07 5 .0 .71 2: 1.61 1.63 3 .31 .27 M .M 1.03 7 .41 .42 2 1.60 2 29 4 1.52 1.5rt 6 Ar, .27 164 .91 .92 2 .38 .39 5 7.4H 7.47 1 .7rt .55 100 .84 .79 14 .10 .12 50 .67 .« 11 .16 .20 44 9.64 9.56 2 .80 .71 33 .50 .50 4 .13 .13 50 .34 .36 15 .08 .08 0 43 2 20 10 .ebraska. The results were as : foil Hows : inyder Method: 1 2 Average. Humus 2.44 2.38 2.41 Ash 1.56 1.58 1.57 ters-Hampton Method : umus 1 2 Average. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Determination of Humus 23 This indicates that the method can be used to obtain results com - parable with those of the other reliable methods. It is likely, how - ever, in unpraoticed hands to give too hisrh results. THE INFLUENCE OK THK STRENGTH OF THK AMMONIA ROUJTION. Huston and McBride reported experiments made to determine the influence of the strength of the ammonia solution upon the amount of humus dissolved. They used the Hilgard method as well as their own with ammonia solutions of 2, 4, 7.3, and 8 per cent. Their results in general indicated that the stronger the am - monia was the more humus was dissolved. This was not an un - varying rule, however. We have tried ammonia solutions of the strengths of 2, 4, 8, 16. and 28 per cent in the Mooers-Hampton method. The six soils um(1 were similar to Nos. I to IX, but on account of uur supply of II to IX being exhausted, similar, instead of identical, soils were ir=ed. Two or three determinations were made in the case of enih Foil. The averages are shown in Table IX. I Soils Nos. XIV, XV, XVI, XVII, and XVIII are similar to II, VII, VIII, VI, and III, respectively, having been taken the same localities and lo the same depths. Tab Ml IX. — Comparison of result* lining nmmonin Molutiona ifforent strength*. Strength Soil number B al ?" I XIV XV XVI XVII XVIII Average ma I tion TTnmim Simmon Humm Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 2 2.01 1.72 6.53 .. r &gt;3 .94 1.2H 2.18 4 2.12 l.*2 ti.34 .KO 1.16 1.31 2 24 8 2.1H 1.85 S.tt .H2 1.12 1.40 2.24 Ifi 2.34 2.0tt H.62 .«7 1.17 I.fi4 2.42 28 2.14 6.63 .71 1.23 1.77 Humus ash ] 41 .33 .an .30 .19 2ti .23 .34 .33 1.72 1 30 8" I. Ill 'J3 : ; 1 ,M I* lti .19 .20 .18 .21 .32 43 24 .lti 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 The Determination of Humus In all hut am lasc more humus was dissolved by 4 per cent ammonia solution than by 2 per cent. Practically the same amount was dissolved by 8 per cent as by 4 per cent ; more by 16 per cent, and in most cases, still more by 28 per cent. It is evident from the table that slight variations in the strength of the ammonia solution above or below 4 per cent are not of much consequence. The amount of ash varied independently of the strength of the SUMMARY. Kl. The Hilgard, Huston-McBride, Cameron-Breazeale, and ers-Hanipton Methods for the determination of humus wer. - pared, using arid, semiarid, and humid soils. 12. The Hilgard method, as used by its author, was ftund to entirely reliable and satisfactory results. In the case of soils in humus and those of very fine texture the method is at time-; tedious. t3. The Huston-McBride or "official" method gives results •h are entirely unreliable and which, in the case of most soils, far too high. The errors incidental to the method are of such iture that it seems impossible to apply to the results any (factory correction formula. 4. The humus extract obtained by the Husttn -McBride method, after being passed thru a properly prepared porcelain filter, give-, results which are concordant with those obtained by the Hilgar.1 method. 5. The Mooers-Hampton modification of the Huston-McBride method gives results entirely concordant with those of the Hilgard method. For some soils it is preferable to the latter, requiring much less time. 16. Ammonia solutions of different strengths were not found have the same solvent power for humus. The differences for engths between 2 and 8 per cent were slight but where solutions from 16 to 28 per cent were used considerably more humus was 7. The amount of so-called "humus ash" found in the case of </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 a soil sample varies from method to method and bears no relation to the strength of the ammonia used. There is little or no agree - ment between duplicate determinations of the "humus ash." Many times as much ash is obtained by the Huston-McBride method as by the other methods. It is probable that the gi eater portion of the "humus ash" obtained by any of the methods is not an es - sential part of the humus. k8. In reporting the humus the per cent of "humus ash" Id always be reported as it serves as an indication of the bility of the humus determination. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>