<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twentieth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Institute for the Blind To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER, 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">Twentieth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Institute for the Blind NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER. 30. 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">466 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF OFFICERS AND TEACHERS N. C. Abbott... Lillian Abbott Claude Watson E. C. Cook Superintendent Matron Physician History and Mathematics Piano Tuning, Broom Making Clark Bruce Jennie E. Johnson Mary French Morton Marion D. Clouse Primary Literature and Geography Organ and Advanced Piano Mary Schroeder Voice and Piano Helen Chase Ruth Sexton Jennie Hughey Mary Cook Violin and Beginners' Piano Domestic Science Girls' Supervisor Boys' Supervisor C. F. Orton Typewriting EMPLOYEES S. Wickline S. J. Yowell D. W. Shinn Susan Wilson Jane Toliver ... Emma Belcher Mae Higgins Rita Peterson Belle Rakes. Engineer Farmer Night-watch Laundress Cook Assistant Laundress Assistant Cook Head Domestic Domestic Lela Holstrom Domestic Domestic Domestic Domestic Irene Me Williams Hedwig Peterson Dora Cook </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 467 To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : I have the honor at this time to submit to you the Twentieth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Institute for the Blind, covering the period beginning December 1, 1912, and ending with November 30, 1914. After an interval of two years, I returned to the Insti - tute for the Blind January 10, 1913, and entered again upoa the duties of superintendent under commission from Gov - ernor John H. Morehead. PHYSICAL PLANT I found the material plant had been greatly improved during the two years of my absence. The immense steel and concrete porches, five in number, the best connected with any Nebraska state institution; the excellent high - pressure heating plant, which is giving splendid satisfac - tion; the new tubular fire-escape for the boys — all these, together with many minor improvements and repairs, at - test the energy of the administration of Superintendent R. C. King. These repairs, though they cost the State con - siderable money, have added greatly to the comfort and beauty of the institution and are permanent. DURING FIRST SUMMER The repairs and permanent improvements are almost entirely done during the summer months, as at that time the pupils are away in their homes. During the first sum - mer of this administration, however, little was accom - plished, as, upon the advice of Governor Morehead (who, by the way, has taken a great interest in this school and to whom we are largely indebted for frequent visits and sug - gestions), I waited until the present Board of Commission - ers of State Institutions should be installed that I might </seg>
            <seg id="p005">468 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF advise with them. As you will recall, the pressure of other duties that fell upon the new Board immediately after tak - ing office upon the first of July, 1913, was so heavy that they were unable to visit this institution until after the middle of August. This gave little time for accomplishing repairs before the opening of school during the second week in September. We did what we could, however, and before school convened the large boys' wash room had been steel ceiled and painted ; the large central basement hall had been thoroughly painted; the students' dining hall gone over, with unsanitary sink removed; a new sink had been in - stalled in the serving room and a large sanitary sink had "replaced the small unsanitary one in the kitchen. OTHER REPAIRS Since the first summer repairs have gone steadily for - ward and the property is undoubtedly in the best and most sanitary condition it has ever been. The start toward steel ceiling the main building was made during Mr. Morey's incumbency. During my former administration, I ad - vanced steadily with the work and Mr. King finished at least one-third of the building during the biennium that he was in charge. I am glad to report to you at this time that all of the main buildings, save a few places, which I think inadvisable to have steel ceiled, and one hall and recitation room, which I desire to have attended to at the beginning of next summer, is finished in this way. It is hardly pos - sible for me to exoress what a satisfaction it is to have this work practically completed. There are no more plaster ceilings to fall on Dupils while sleeping and the saving in fuel is very noticeable. To be specific, during the present administration steel ceilings have been erected in all the rooms and hallway in Paradise Alley (which is the euphonious and poetic name given to the suite of rooms over the chapel) rooms No. 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, and the hall connecting same, the fruit room in the basement, the large receiving storage room, west storage room, dark storage room, hall leading to the storage rooms, rooms 32, 33, 25, 24, 20, 21. four rooms in apart- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 469 ments 42 and connecting hallway, room 48 and large hall - way on third floor in central part. APARTMENTS FOR DOMESTICS When Governor Morehead visited this institution at Commencement time of 1913, he made a thorough inspec - tion of the entire plant and one of his suggestions was rel - ative to the rooms in the basement used for the domestics. Several of these rooms had practically all of the sunlight shut out of them by the great porch on the southwest cor - ner of the building. "You ought not to ask any employee of the State to live in a room where the sunlight cannot enter," said the Governor. As soon as the Board of Com - missioners was installed, I took this matter up with them and the result is that we have abandoned these dark rooms for living purposes entirely, using them only for storage purposes. The domestics are now using the suite of rooms under the hospital which are bright and cheerful. These rooms had for the past twenty years, or practically ever since the west wing was built, been used for storage and it took only the expenditure of a few weeks' work on the part of one man and the purchase of paint and plaster to put these rooms in excellent shape. The contentment there is appropriate to the name applied to the aparments — Happy HoUow. HOSPITAL PUT IN SHAPE Our hospital on the first floor of the northwest wing is not reached save through an outside entry. In this hos - pital there are four large rooms, enough to accommodate easily twelve patients, and two good bath-and-toilet rooms. Since our institution is not in its nature a hospital at all but purely a school, this one ward is amply sufficient for any ordinary demands made upon us. However, when a small epidemic of measles broke out among our younger pupils at the close of the last school year, I found it absolutely out of the question to use this hospital. It was in a state of dilap - idation, plastering off of almost every wall and ceiling and furthermore the plaster not off barely hanging. This con - dition was entirely changed last summer. All of the old </seg>
            <seg id="p007">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 470 plastering was torn off, the rooms were replastered in a thorough and workmanlike manner and beds were pur - chased by the Board. A heavy coat of paint was put on, after the plaster had thoroughly dried, and now we have apartments to meet any ordinary emergency that may be anticipated in the way of sickness. STORAGE ROOMS Up until the time of the advent of the Board, this in - stitution had been accustomed to purchase practically all of its provisions from local concerns under competitive bids at the beginning of each quarter. These goods were de - livered in small quantities from day to day, so that the cook's small storage room adjoining the kitchen was suffi - cient for our needs. As soon as the new Board came into office and began the purchase of provisions in large quan - tities from all parts of the country, the necessity for large storage facilities was immediately apparent. About eight years ago, when the new kitchen was built, there were four rooms in the basement of the boys' wing and the central part of the building abandoned. One of these was already in use on my return for girls' domestic science room. The other three were in a state of dilapidation and dry rot and were the abode of rats and mice. These three rooms and the small hall-way opening into them have been utilized for storage purposes. Cement floor was laid in all of them, cement plaster put on the walls, steel ceiling (mentioned before) erected, and shelving built in. One of the windows was put on hinges and a strong skid-way built down from it. The whole interior was painted white. We now have a sanitary storage place pleasant to work in. One would hardly believe that the unsanitary rooms as they appeared before work began on them could be converted into such satisfactory storage apartments. FRUIT ROOM In addition to fitting out the storage rooms as just des - cribed, we also worked over in the same way the small fruit room on the south side of the basement in the boys' wing. This was repaired in the same way as the other storage </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 471 rooms — cement floor, cement walls and steel ceiling. In addition we added about fifty per cent, of shelving. Each summer we put up from two thousand to four thousand quarts of fruit and other canned goods and this can now be stored away in safety in sanitary quarters. MAIN CENTRAL HALL An improvement that has added as much to the appear - ance of our institution as any is the painting and enamelling of the main entry hall, and the laying of battleship linoleum on the floor. Visitors entering the institution for the first time now secure an impression of cleanliness instead of one of dinginess which I could not under the previous condition avoid. I trust that the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions will permit me, during the coming biennium, to treat the second floor, main hall, in the same way. PAINTING OF ROOMS In previous years it had been the custom of the man - agement to paper the various rooms from time to time. During the administration of my predecessor, began the policy of painting instead of papering the rooms. This costs a little more to begin with but proves an economy in the long run. Besides it is more conducive to the good health of the pupils. His plan I have followed out in rooms 32, 33 and 24. During the coming summer, there are ten or twelve rooms on the boys' side of the building that should be gone over in this way. OUTSIDE BUILDINGS The main building had been painted a gray slate with gray stone trimmings before my assuming the office of superintendent. The other buildings on the place were all of various shades. Our plan is to have them all conform to the same color scheme and we have thus far painted in con - formity with this plan all of the outside buildings save the laundry. During the past summer the cow-barn, cow-shed, horse-barn, buggy-shed, gymnasium, paint-shop and the old ice-house were gone over. We expect to take up the laundry at the beginning of warm weather. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 472 MY FATHERS ADVICE More than twenty years ago, when 1 was sharing sleep - ing apartments with my father, then superintendent of the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane, I was once awakened by the flash of his lantern between one and two o'clock in the morning. He had just returned from a round of the build - ings, a trip of personal supervision that he often made in search of possible fire. Before we dropped off to sleep again, he gave me three rules which in his mind were fore - most in the management of a state institution: "First, get it clean; Second, keep it clean ; Third, keep it from burning up." There may be some doubt as to whether these three principles should be foremost in the management of an institution and, yet, if a superintendent can follow them, he will avoid many pitfalls. KEEP IT CLEAN This institution was clean when Supt. R. C. King turned it over to me. In order to keep it clean Mrs. Abbott and I daily make a tour of inspection of the premises just before dinner and all teachers, employees and pupils expect this and take a pride in keeping the building in shape. In order to keep it sanitary in a larger way, I believe that there can be no better expenditure of the State's money than for paint applied regularly and persistently. My plan would be to have a painter from the middle of May until the middle of September of each year. KEEP IT FROM BURNING UP The danger from fire is one that is always present in the minds of the management of an institution. We have fire drills that the pupils may learn the use of the various exits and of the tubular fire-escapes. Our kitchen range is set on a concrete floor. The chief sources of danger lie in defective wiring, defective flues and spontaneous combus - tion of the coal. All of the wires about our place are laid </seg>
            <seg id="p010">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 473 in substantial steel conduits. About one-third of the build - ing has been wired in this way during the past summer. Last spring the steam coal took fire and we spent a day of anxiety while it was being moved, a shovelful at a time, and the fire extinguished. The smoke and fumes were almost stifling. I am pleased to report at this time that no damage was done, though I spent several anxious hours fearing lest the laundry building might be consumed. The Board has added to our fire equipment within the past year and a half one hundred fifty feet of inch-and-a-half fire hose and coup - lings for the laundry and four hand extinguishers for the main building. We had, before this purchase, seven hun - dred feet of hose attached to the inside riser at the center of the building, distributed on four floors, and a hose-cart with two hundred feet of hose for use at the two outside hydrants. One of these hydrants is at the back of the build - ing and the hose-cart is kept in a small house adjoining the hydrant. The other hydrant is in the front of the building and I think the Board acted wisely in ordering a small ad - ditional hose-cart with three hundred foot of hose to be kept under the front porch and available for use at the front hydrant CEMENT WORK In addition to the cement floors and walls spoken of elsewhere in this report, we have laid cement floor on the north half of the engine room. There in the northeast cor - ner was the fifty-horse-power high-pressure boiler which was needed in our institution to furnish power so long as our heating boilers were of the low-pressure type. When the new heating plant was installed slightly over three years ago, there was no use for this high-pressure boiler. Dur - ing last summer it was removed and, as I have just stated, the floor where it stood and other space surrounding covered with cement. This gives us additional room for the storage of coal. This high-pressure boiler I have offered for sale. Other cement work done during the summer was in connec - tion with our large rain cisterns on the north of the build - ing, a large slab at the entry of the barn for the washing of </seg>
            <seg id="p011">474 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF buggies, a gutter at the entry of our driveway into the grounds, and a low curb around the steps at entry of kit - chen. I judge that additional work of this kind ought to be done next summer under and surrounding the big boys' porch at the east end of the building as well as in all of the area-ways surrounding the building. These are cracked and broken in many places. OLD BRICK UTILIZED The old brick taken from around the high-pressure boiler removed from the boiler room were utilized in large part here at the institution. Particularly they were put into a brick encasement for water pipes at the southeast corner of the cow-barn and into the erection of a bleaching house adjoining the engine room. This bleaching house has supplied a long felt want for the broom-makers who had been using a piano-box. IRON BALUSTRADES The east wing of our building, known as the boys' side, was constructed forty years ago and the balustrades were made only two and one-half feet high. On one of the early trips of inspection, Judge Kennedy suggested the danger to the boys — that one might be thrown or might fall over a balustrade suffering serious injury. To avoid this danger, we strengthened the railings with heavy iron rods, extend - ing them a foot or more above the. old balustrades. While I am unable to report that these new railings are things of beauty from an artistic standpoint, they accomplish the pur - pose intended very well and all danger is avoided. LAUNDRY BUILDING STRENGTHENED When the new boilers were installed slightly over three years ago, the walls on the east of the engine room were torn out and the lower part of the building extended about ten feet. Above the engine room on the first floor is the laundry and on the second floor the broom-shop. These changes in the lower wall so weakened the building that from the vibration of the machinery, large cracks were be - ginning to form and we feared lest the whole might collapse. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 475 By running four rods from east to west along the ceiling of the second floor and tightening with turn buckles, we so straightened this building that it is perfectly safe. ROOFS REPAIRED The roofs of the main building, gymnasium and broom - shop were all gone over by a competent roofer during the last summer, painted, patched and made weather-tight. When such large buildings as we have here are concerned, it seems to me a wise policy to have these roofs gone over every other year and this is the plan that I shall follow in the future. THE SCHOOL So much for the Physical Plant and its improvement during the last biennium. However, this physical plant is not and should not be our main consideration. It is impor - tant only as it ministers to the welfare of the blind and de - fective-sighted people for whom the State of Nebraska es - tablished this institution. The school's the thing. Insofar as the physical plant provides the ideal conditions for the school, it is important. Founded forty years ago on the first of March, 1875, by Samuel Bacon, an educator totally blind, it has provided an education for hundreds of people and done incalculable good. THREE IN ONE The common schools since the founding of the State of Nebraska have been devoted entirely to literary or scho - lastic subjects. Only in recent years have they added to their curriculum art, music and manual subjects. This school for those of no vision and of defective vision has been dedicated from the beginning not only to literary subjects but to music and industrial subjects as well. We have three schools here working together day by day for the harmon - ious developing of all of a student's faculties. LITERARY SCHOOL In our literary school we have a course of study that embraces as nearly as the peculiar conditions will admit the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">476 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF same subjects as are taught in the common schools. For the elementary classes, we follow the course of study pre - scribed by the state Superintendent of Public Instruction with such adaptations aa arc necessary — Arithmetic, Geog - raphy, Language, ( i imnuur, i hysiology and Hygiene, Read - ing, Spelling, U. S. History, Writing and Nature Study. One may hear discussed by oar people the same branches with all the zest that they are discussed by the pupils of the com - mon schools. READING AND WRITING But how can the child n 1 hear someone ask. Of cour print books and write with pt possible. But thanks to the itarians as Hauy, Diderot, Li who realized that the sense o as to do in a large measure t our people read and write th system. ad or write if he cannot see? ;e, our pupils do not read ink - n and ink. That would be im - efforts of such great human - lille, Howe, Waite and Bacon, h might be cultivated so rk of the sense of sight, punctographic tactile OUR BOOKS Our books are printed in the New York Point system. But by using these dots and by changing their position, each letter of the alphabet can be formed. For instance, one dot in the upper space forms "e" and one dot in the lower space forms "t". The capitals are formed by adding suffi- cient dots to make the letter four spaces wide WRITING Not only are the blind able to read books printed in point by the use of the tips of their fingers, but they are also able to write this same system. The ordinary point slate permitting one. to write New York point consists of four pieces — the wooden board with holes along the sides into which is fitted the lower slide. The heavy paper is This was invented by Professor Waite and shares with the American Braille system popular use in the United States. In brief, letters are formed by raised dots. Six of these arranged in columns of two form the basis of the system </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 477 fastened above and the slide ii writer desires. On the outsit slide which has a number of c making the dots in the proper a blind person uses in punchini which resembles very much a p and down as the er is the upper Us that puide the writer in laces. The instrument that thpse Hots is cnllpd a stvlns called a stylus, *ker's awl. The writ- ins? is done from ritrht to le turned over it reads in the pr *o that when the paper is r order. POINT GENERALLY USED This system has adaptations that fit it for arithmetic, music, and all other ordinary uses. There is no claim on the here is no claim on the that formerly occupied a stand &gt;n the front parlor and would cost one not less than two h'indred dollars. This accounts in part for the «reat expense in connection with the educa - tion of the blind. FEDERAL ASSISTANCE The federal government, in appreciation of the enor - mous cost of printing and trnnsnnrtntiner literature for the blind, has made two concessions that are of vast assistance to the sightless. All honks a nd pamnhlets in raised print to and from a free *)"Mic library are trranted transportation through the mails without cost. Also each year there is set aside a sum to be expended for tactile books and dis - tributed to the various schools for the blind in the United States by the federal government. The amount is deter - mined hy the number of punils that receive an education in a school. Fach year this institution has profited in the dis - tribution, our quota bein&lt;r about $150.00. part of us who are interested in the education of the blind children that this system is as rood as people with eyesitrht enjoy. It is not so food. Tt costs enormously. For in- stance, a play of Shakespeare that may be bought for twen- ty-five cents in ordinary print costs five dollars when put into point and. in addition, the volume is larerer by a fourth than an ordinary letter file. If one were to purchase all of Shakespeare's plays in this tactile system, one would have forty volumes, each a&lt; 'aree as the ordinary family Bible </seg>
            <seg id="p015">478 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF ETHEL HILL, BLIND AND DEAF This free transportation to and from public libraries of tactile books has been a great blessing to Ethel Hill in particular. Ethel is almost totally blind and deaf and hardly a week goes by that she does not receive a book from some one of the eastern libraries. She lives largely in the environment built up for herself out of the books that she omnivorously reads. She is taught in a class by herself and her teachers are accustomed to communicate with her through writing letters on the palm of her hand. When I talk to her, it is through large capitals on her back. One of the most startling experiences in connection with my work in this institution occurred one evening when I heard a voice and opened a door into a perfectly dark room. I attempted to pass into the room and switch on a light and stumbled over several blind pupils who were there listening to Ethel Hill reading from Lamb's "Tales of Shakespeare." The children were intensely interested in the story — but Ethel heard not a word that her own lips pronounced. SCHOOL OF MUSIC Each person that enters our school is given an oppor - tunity to learn music. We have three competent teachers and instruction is given repularly in piano, pipe organ, violin, voice, orchestra and chorus work. Arrangements are also made for pupils to become proficient in the various instruments of the orchestra, such as 'cello, cornet, clarinet, drums, etc. Tn this connection I invite your particular at - tention to Table XIV that shows in an excellent way the breadth of our courses of instruction. NOT BY EAR There is a mistaken impression that the blind do not need to learn music but that this acquirement is a natural gift. I suppose that this false impression has come through the performances of such prodigies as Blind Boone and others. This school does not encourage its pupils to play by ear at all. Each student conies down, according to the tac - tile musical notation elsewhere spoken of, the score that he desires to play. He then reads a short bit of the music with </seg>
            <seg id="p016">* &lt; B —■■I ••« §1 00 ■ *i a • 4 . &gt; OS - £1 X* &lt; CQ 1 LlJ = » - Q CQ </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS M his fingers, plays it upon the piano or some other instru - ment and commits the music step by step. A picture that accompanies this report shows Miss Leona Jennings at work committing Schumann's "Soaring" on the piano. With her left hand, Miss Jennings reads from the score to be played with the right hand and commits the same. She then plays also with the right hand, the score intended for the left hand. Her next step is to transfer what she has committed from the right to the left hand and her last step is to com - bine playing the parts intended for each hand with the fingers intended by the composer. This is laborious, but after a pupil has combined the parts, the piece is all his. The Grand Concert given June 8th last in connection with our commencement exercises is a typical program of what the blind pupils can accomplish. RAYMOND OVERTURE .4. Thomas Orchestra PIANO— "To Spring:" Grie.{i Cecile Phillips VOICE— "Little Grey Home in the West" Lohr "My Laddie" Tkayer "I Hid My Love" Gny D'Harddot Merton Conn VIOLIN DUET— "Petit Duo Symphonique" Tours Miss Chase and Henry Gierau ORGAN— "War March of the Priests" Mendelssohn William Koch QUARTETTE— "Spring Waltze" MVdr Cecile Phillips, Bertha Ross Lyle Harris and Frank Feiwalar PIANO— "Barcarolle," Opus 5 Ehrlich Einar Nielsen VOICE— "Sing, Smile, Slumber" Gounoti "The Language of Love" (Faust)) Gounod Elizabeth Leonard CLARINET — "Polonaise" (Mignon) Thomas William Koch ORGAN— "Torchlight March" Guilmavt Leona Jennings </seg>
            <seg id="p018">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF SCHOOL OF INDUSTRY Special instruction is given to pupils along lines of manual training trades and to develop usefulness in the home. GIRLS' WORK The girls are taught raffia, needlework, the making of bead articles, knitting, crocheting, hemming and other allied subjects and cooking. The smaller boys are also admitted to the bead and raffia classes. Our domestic science room, which I have mentioned elsewhere, has been fitted up ad - mirably for our girls, with new sink, cupboards, stove, dishes, utensils and inlaid linoleum. Six girls are devoting themselves for several hours each week to this branch of work and will return to their homes capable of getting up a common meal and will be of great assistance to their mothers. BOYS' WORK As special work for the boys, fitting them to make a living in the world after they leave school, we have chair - caning, hammock-making, fiynet-making, broom-making, piano-tuning, and carpet weaving. Some of the girls as well take pJeasure in learning to net hammocks and fly-nets. BROOM MAKING Not alone are boys admitted to work in the broom-shop but the school has been glad to receive adults, especially those who have lost their eyesight after reaching years of maturity. We have found by experience that men of fifty years may learn to make brooms if they will apply them - selves. Several have left our institution and established small shops where they make brooms, hammocks and fly - nets and are successful in making a living. PIANO-TUNING There is no better field for the young man with defec - tive sight than piano-tuning. It gives a steady income and a piano-tuner of tact and efficiency can always establish a clientele. But the acquirement of the art means a good ear, </seg>
            <seg id="p019">J ; II 1 1//^ Jfi 1 ■ f u &lt; &lt; a: d S | a: £ I u »5 &lt; OS B Q z B £ </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 481 tenacity of purpose and some mechanical ability. Along with the report I am sending a photograph which shows one of the boys at work. We took him just as he was in the tuning room at the regular period. GRADUATES In June of each year we have closing exercises, consist - ing of four different programs. On the last night the grad - uates receive their diplomas. In June, 1913, we had no graduates from the high school but gave diplomas to the eighth grade — George Cozad, William Koch, Robert Mogis, Bessie Sawyer, Elizabeth Leonard, Nola Huit, Cecil Phillips, Irene Griffith, Maurice Adams. On this occasion, Governor John H. Morehead presented the diplomas to the class and Mr. A. L. Bixby, poet laureate of Nebraska, made a charac - teristic speech full of philosophy and good cheer. In June, 1914, six were graduated from the reeular hierh school course — Frank Feddalar, Lela Ruth Phillips, Grace M. Davis, Henry J. Gierau, George C. Rothery, Lyle A .Harris. At the last graduating exercises all of the mem - bers of the Board were present, Judge Kennedy presenting the dirlomas. The State Superintendent, Mr. James E. Delzell, honored us with his presence and delivered an ad - dress on "Optimism." ANNUAL SERMON One of the annual events, occuring during commence - ment week, is the sermon preached to the pupils. It is my desire to secure for this occasion a representative clergy - man who will bring to us a message. For the past two years we have been singularly fortunate. In June, 1913, Bishop Arthur L. Williams of the Episcopal church, Omaha, was the preacher. During the last commencement exercises, we were honored by Bishop J. Henry Tihen of the Catholic church. Lincoln, with an address. It was a rare treat for the school and for the people of this community to hear men of such scholarship and vision. GENERAL MORALE I have never known the general conditions in this school </seg>
            <seg id="p021">482 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF to be better than they have been during the past biennium. It would be difficult indeed to find eighty people anywhere living under one roof with less friction than we are having right here. The standards of honor have been especially high. I attribute this in large part to the high ideals of the older pupils and to the graduates of 1914 who have felt that their influence should be thrown in the right direction. I here express my sincere appreciation of the efforts of the pupils to make and keep this school what it ought to be and what the taxpayers of the State want it to be. One incident in particular, though it is somewhat personal, I feel ought to be spoken of. When in November a year ago I was called suddenly to Chicago where my brother, Luther J. Abbott, underwent a critical surgical operation, I told the older boys of the necessity for my absence. On my return Mrs. Abbottt informed me that there had been nothing to dis - turb the harmony of the school. These older pupils, during my absence had not only seen to their own conduct but had also kept a watchful eye out for the conduct of the younger and less thoughtful. OUR NAME MISLEADING Our official name is "Institute for the Blind" and this name I am sure stands in the way of our securing many boys and girls that ought to be here. The name properly should be "School for Blind and Defective-sighted." As the name now stands, people get the impression that only those totally blind will be admitted here. But this is far from the truth. We will receive all those whose sight is so de fective that they cannot secure an education in the common schools. About two-thirds of our pupils, as a general rule, have partial use of their eyes. Of the twenty-three new pupils admitted during the biennium, (see Table IX), only four were totally blind. LITTLE RED TAPE There is little red tape to be unwound before a boy or girl is admitted here. Teachers, ministers and others in public capacities who learn of children with eyesight so </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 483 defective that they cannot successfully prosecute the studies of the common schools would confer a benefit if they would send names of such children directly to the superintendent of this institution. He will return a blank form and as soon as this form has been filled out and passed upon by the man - agement of the institution the pupil will be eligible. We can easily take care of eighty pupils. We have at the pres - ent time fifty-one pupils and have had at all times during the biennium from fifty to sixty. REASON FOR SLUMP When I was a teacher in this institution eighteen years ago, there were eighty-nine pupils present. What accounts for the decrease? It is partially accounted for by the fact that not all who are privileged to be here have been admitted and partially by the fact that blindness has actually de - creased during the past twenty years. While the total pop - ulation of the State has increased slightly, we may be happy in the thought that blindness has decreased not only rela - tively but absolutely. This decrease in part is accounted for by : 1. Better print in books. 2. Advance in science, as aseptic and antiseptic sur - gery, more skillful operations, greater care of new-born in - fants, greater consideration for expectant mothers, and laws against marriage of blood-relatives. 3. Avoidance of accidents, through supervised play, and a safe and sane celebration of the Fourth. 4. Greater availability of doctors through an increase in number and the use of the motor-car. PARENTS' FFAR FOR THEIR CHILDREN Some children that we have been unable to secure as pupils in our school, though they should be here, are kept at home by the natural fear of their parents lest some harm befall their offspring. This is natural, but unreasonable when all of the considerations of the school are taken into account. Practically all of the time of the children is spent under one roof. Trained teachers and employees are ever </seg>
            <seg id="p023">484 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF on their guard. A night-watch makes hourly inspection of the building, looking into each room where the little children sleep. There is a trained supervisor on the boys' side and another on the girls' side to watch for any indisposition. PHYSICIAN AND EXERCISE As soon as one of the supervisors finds a pupil ailing, she reports immediately to the office and Dr. Claude Watson, the institution physician, is immediately called to prescribe. No one has any chance to get down sick without our being aware of it. Each day there are set periods for walking, general exercise or gymnasium work. In a few cases the physician has limited the amount of exercise that must be undertaken by certain pupils and his instructions are care - fully followed. Thus we fit the amount of walking or other exercise to the conditions of each particular person. LENGTH OF SERVICE In this institution there has been practical civil service, save in the executive positions, in force since its founding. Interfered with a few times, it has now, through the ap - pointment of a non-partisan board, happily become perma - nent. Three of our teachers, E. C. Cook, Clark Bruce and Mary Morton, began their service here more than twenty years a°ro. Jennie Johnson has been a teacher here for al - most fifteen years. All of these just mentioned, save Miss Morton, are totally blind, and each is giving devoted loyal service to the cause of educating those whom the State has put under their charge. Miss Effie Campbell, another teacher who had given more than a quarter of a century to the cause of educating the blind and defective sighted chil - dren, severed her connection with the school by resignation at the becinninor of this biennium. Miss Campbell was one of the three children who constituted the entire enrollment in the school when Professor Samuel Bacon opened the first session almost forty years ago. FORTIETH ANNIVERSARY On March 1st next, we hope to celebrate in fitting man - ner the fortieth anniversary of the founding of our school. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 485 We hope to have exercises, dignified and appropriate, that will reach a larger audience than the bronze plate placed by alumni and friends near the front entry which reads: SAMUEL BACON 1823-1909 FOUNDER OF THIS SCHOOL ITS FIRST SUPERINTENDENT MARCH 1, 1875— NOVEMBER 22,1877 ITS LIFELONG FRIEND AND COUNSELOR HE TAUGHT— "THE BLIND CAN WIN BY WORTH AND WORK" AND PROVED IT BY HIS LIFE The above estimate is $500.00 less than was appropri - ated for the present biennium. The legislature of four years ago appropriated $2,000 for the purchase of two blocks and parts of two others di - rectly adjoining us on the north. This was not nearly enough money to secure the land and the appropriation lapsed. I feel confident that with the amount here asked for we could secure the land. The intersecting street could be closed. This would give the institution a total of about thirteen acres. PiKILL-1 CiU BI MIS PK1! .BJJN Jh 1911 WHAT WE NEED An appropriation for: Superintendent Matron , $ 3,600 1,200 Teachers 11,000 Employees Maintenance 9,000 19,800 General Repairs Adjoining Land 5,000 5,000 $54,600 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">486 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF WORKERS FOR THE BLIND For the first time in the history of the State, The Ne - braska Association of Workers for the Blind met in this institution at the close of last school-year, by special per - mission of the Board, and spent three days in earnest con - ference. It is a hopeful sign when all of those working toward the same end are willing to join hands. All of the thirty-two attending this meeting were genuinely interested in the welfare of the blind at large and of the work done by this institution. Never was a finer body of thoughtful men and women gathered any place. I trust that the Board of Commissioners will permit this association to have their next meeting in the summer of 1915 within these walls. CHAPEL EXERCISES There is a twenty-minute period of each day, beginning at eight o'clock in the morning, devoted to chapel exercises. Usually we sing two hymns, chant the "Gloria," and I read a passage of Scripture. From this general program there are variations. A beautiful poem, the news of the day, a speaker from outside, musical numbers, or a concert by the Victrola may be substituted. On Sunday morning, the stu - dents have their regular meeting of the Christian Endeavor. CHURCH OR SUNDAY SCHOOL Each pupil is expected to attend either church or Sun - day-school each Sunday unless excused for good or sufficient reasons by a supervisor or the superintendent. The choice as to which church the student is to attend is determined by the parents or the pupil — but after a choice has been made, this is not permitted to be changed without permission from the management. No interference is made at all in a pupil's religious beliefs and all contro - versies over religious subjects are strictly tabooed. MUSICAL PROGRAMS The school has been greatly delighted and greatly ben - efitted by several special musical programs for which we acknowledge our thanks: The concert by Mr. Carl </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 487 Steckelberg, Miss Nell Cave, Mrs. Lillian Helms, and Miss Anne Stewart, under the auspices of the Matinee Musicale ; a piano recital by Mr. Arvid Samuelson, under the auspices of Mrs. Minnie Stanford; the two faculty recitals by Miss Eula Dell Marshall, Miss Marjorie White, and Miss Susan M. Brodboll, last year ; and Miss Helen M. Chase, Miss Mary Schroeder, and Miss Marion D. Clouse, this year; and a piano recital by Mrs. Edith L. Wagoner. VICTROLA The Victrola which was purchased a year ago has been of greatest benefit to the school both for entertainment and instruction. Frequently on a dull Saturday or Sunday, when the pupils are shut up within the walls, we borrow records and spend a delightful hour or two. The teachers also use it in their serious work when they have records to illustrate principles and to hold up an ideal before their classes. HOME PRODUCTS CONSUMED Relative to the products produced on our home grounds and consumed within the institution, I have to say, as will be seen elsewhere in this report, that we have very little ground and consequently do not raise much for home con - sumption. During the past biennium, we have always had three cows on the place and part of the time four so that we have been able to supply milk to our younger pupils. We have had from eight to ten gallons of milk on the aver - age daily throughout the biennium. Of vegetables, we have raised one hundred seventy-five bushels of potatoes, (largely on the rented ground spoken of elsewhere), small garden truck for use during the summer, such as lettuce, onions, corn, radishes, beets, tomatoes, etc. As the pupils are not here during the summer months, we have needed to raise only enough for the few who are employed here during the summer months. This fall we raised two tons of millet on the same ground on which we had previously raised po - tatoes. Of fruit from the place, we have used on the table or put up ten bushels of plums, fifteen hundred pounds of grapes, twenty-five bushels of pears, fifty bushels of peaches, </seg>
            <seg id="p027">488 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF fifty bushels of apples and ten bushels of cherries. Of chickens, we have killed about two hundred and have used about four hundred dozen eggs. CONCLUSION I append to this statement several tables that will furnish to the Board statistics of general interest. I feel that the biennium has passed with great success. I have worked hard myself, but the satisfactory results could not have been obtained without the hearty cooperation of teach - ers, employees, Governor of the State, and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions. More largely than to anyone else am I indebted to my wife, Lillian Abbott, whose good sense and tact has been always available. All of which is respectfully submitted. N. C. Abbott, Superintendent. Nebraska City, Nebraska, November SO, 191 U. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 489 ► TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION 'Includes all pupils who had attended previously this or a similar school. TABLE II. SEX AND RACE OF PUPILS ADMITTED Kor Year Kor Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 r Ending MOVEMENT Nov. 30 Dec. 1, 12 to June 30, 13 0, 1913 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov .30 1914 ToUl for Biennium M F T M M F F T T M M r F ' T M F ' M F T T Present at begin- ning of period Admitted : For first time Transferred from other institutions Re-admitted* 27 2 a M I M s i 19 I 3 45 12 4 :i5 ....... H i 60 9 3 27 23 16 7 i 4 50 2:i "j Total enrollment Discharged : Giaduated Transferred to other institutions Expelled _. Left school for various reasons. Died 2:» 1 n 4 52 .... 7 ! 35 26 1 ■1 1 43 4 1 ■ " 10 I 29 72 46 34 80 15 4 16 1 1 1 5 15 13 10 23 Total removals 8 7 1 1 15 (i 21 18 1 29 For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 RACE Dec. 1. 12 to June 30, 13 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30 1914 Total for Biennium M F T M F T M F T M F T White | Negro i Indian etc 2 2 8 4 12 fi 3 9 16 7 23 Totals. 2 4 12 3 9 16 7 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 490 TABLE III. AGES OF PUPILS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year AGE D::. 1. 12 July 1, 13 ending Total Nov. 30 for to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT 6 years _ 1 1 1 1 7 years 8 years _ 9 years 1 1 1 1 112 1 1 1 1 1 2 10 years 1 1 1 1 11 years 2 2 2 2 1 1 1 1 12 years 13 years 1 13 14 4 15 14 years 1 1 1 1 15 years 1 1 1 1 16 years 1 1 1 1 17 years i 1 1 1 1 2 ..._. 2 18 years 1 1 1 1 19 years _ 1 1 1 1 20 years 21 years _ _ _ _ Over 21 years 2 2 3 3 5 5 Totals 2 2 84 12 639 16 723 TABLE IV. NATIVITY OF PUPILS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year NATIVITY Dec. 1.12 July 1, 13 ending Total Nov. 30 for to to June 30, '13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Nebraska 2 2 527 415 11 3 14 U. S., other than Nebraska 224 224 448 Total native born 2 2 74 11 639 15 722 •2 Russia 1 1 1 1 Total foreign born 1 1 1 1 Totals 2 2 7 4 11 7 3 10 16 7 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 491 - TABLE V. NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF PUPILS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year NATIVITY Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total to to Nov. 30 for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium United States both parents Foreign, both parents Mixed Unknown Totals TABLE VI. RESIDENCE OF PUPILS ADMITTED AND OF ALL PUPILS REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year All RESIDENCE Dec.1,12 Jul. 1,13 ending Total Remaining to to Nov. 30, for Nov. 3i Jun.30,13 Nov,30.13 1914 Biennium 1914 Nov. 30, to MFTMFTMFT MFT MFT Nebraska: Adams 1 1 Antelope 1 .... 1 1 1 _ 1 1 Buffalo Cagg ..._ _ _ _. 1 1 Clay 112 1 1 112 13 Dakota 1 .... 1 _ 1 1 1 1 Dixon Dodge 1 1 112 2 4 Douglas 2 6 8 1 1 _ 1 1 ..._. Fillmore Franklin 1 .... 1 1 1 1 1 Gage 1 ... 1 1 .... 1 2 .... 2 4 4 S 3 1 1 Greeley Hamilton 1 1 Jefferson 112 Knox - , 2 2 2 2 2 2 3 4 3 7 Lancaster 1 .... 1 2 .... 2 3 Loup ..._ 1 .... 1 — - 1 1 1 1 1 1 Madison Otoe _ — - 112 112 1 1 Pierce - 1 1 Richardson 1 .... 1 1 .... 1 2 .... 2 2 2 2 2 1 ... 1 1 1 .-- - Sheridan Valley - _ - 1 1 Wyoming 1 1 2; 112 3 14 Washington Totals 2 .... 2 7 4 11 7 3 10 16 7 23 28 23 51 M F T M F T M F T M F T 2 2 6 3 y 5 3 8 13 6 19 1 1 l l 2 2 3 3 1 1 2 ... 2 7 4 11 3 10 16 7 2: </seg>
            <seg id="p031">492 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VII. AGES AT WHICH PUPILS ADMITTED BECAME BUND Number Per Cent AGE M P T i M F T Congenital _ _ _.. 8 3 11 34.8 13 47.8», Under 1 year 1 and under 2 years. 2 and under 3 years 3 and under 4 years. 4 and under 5 years. 6 and under 10 years 2 2 8.7 8.7 10 and under 15 years _ _ 2 1 3 8.7 4.3 13.0 15 and under 20 years _ 2 1 3 8.7 4.3 13 20 and over. Totals - i 16 7 23! 69.5 30.3 100 TABLE VIII. ASSIGNED CAUSES OF DEFECT IN PUPILS ADMITTED Number Per Cent EXTENT OF DEFECT M F T M F T Accident— I 7 1 8 30 4 34 Granulated Lids _ _ _ 112 4 4 8 Ophthalmia neonatorum. 5 4 9 21 17 38 Scarlet Fever _ _.._ _..„ 2 2 8 8 Strain ..._ _ 1 1 4 4 Whooping Cough. _.!..._. 114 4 8 Totals _ _ 14 9 23 63 37 100 TABLE IX. EXTENT OF DEFECT IN PUPILS ADMITTED Number Per Cent EXTENT OF DEFECT M F T M F T No vision...- ' 4 4 17.4 17.4 Partial vision I 12 7 19 i 52.2 30.4 82.6 Totals _ _ _...i 16 7 231 69.6 30.4 100 TABLE X. PHYSICAL CONDITION ON ADMISSION OF PUPILS ADMITTED Number Per Cent PHYSICAL CONDITION M F T M F T Normal _ _.._ 13 6 19 ! 67 27 84 Defective _ [ 3 1 4 1 12 4 16 Crippled Totals 16 7 23 69 31 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 493 TABLE XI. DISTRIBUTION OF ALL PUPILS IN SCHOOL AT END OF BIENNIUM Number GRADE M F T .. Kindergarten 1st grade 3 2 5 3 2 5 2 2 4 2nd grade 3rd grade 4th grade 5th grade 6th grade 7th grade 8th grade 9th grade 10th grade 11th grade Ungraded 12 3 3 1 4 2 2 4 4 3 7 3 3 3 3 6 7 8 15 Totals 28 23 51 Industrial Musical and Bead- work other Special Work: 9 8 17 Broom-iraking Chorus, Jr 7 7 12 8 20 6 9 15 Chorus, Sr Clarinet ... 1 1 Cooking 5 5 4 4 Crocheting 1 1 Hem-stitching Knitting 4 4 4 4 Netting 20 16 36 New York Point Reading New York Point Writing Orchestra 9 5 14 7 18 10 14 25 Piano 1 1 Pipe-organ Piano-tuning Plain Sewing Rug- braiding Violin 7 7 2 2 1 1 3 14 Violoncello 1 1 Voice ""!Z"I!!Z__- 5 5 10 Totals 102 84 186 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">494 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF I Mi MM MM Hil » j ! 1**1 i !„ iiiniiiHlJij s.li illi eg I i«^li!li?5 jj*S t-ir_ diOOOOOOOOOO ST3 ZW OoOOOOOOCjOO S"O P_ flfi ooooocococxoiososoiuSi. * |g 1 "JjMj as lilslliliilMji PJ IO t- M « U5 «O 05 &gt;-l O5 &gt;-l CO ~-"Sji O ' 5 (3 i xooooxocococaafflffi E'S^a* W l-* HrtTHHrtHHHHiHn g^_3 w *J S 8 JlfSiJj^jj 'jtfi S I I I II I i I I : ! l" %l - W I : : i i i : ! I i i "g" 5 = la? ! 11 iiiilli </seg>
            <seg id="p034">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 495 TABLE XIII. ENROLLMENT DURING BIENNIUM December 1, 1912, to November 30, 1914 PUPILS P. O. Address Nativity Date of Admission Adams, Maurice P. Blair Nebraska Sept. 11, 1912 Sept. 17, 1907 Oct. 5, 1908 Sept 11, 1912 Sept. 9, 1914 Jan. 2, 1907 Nov. 30, 1912 Sept. 13, 1911 Oct. 1, 1913 Sept 10, 1902 Sept 10, 1902 Sept. 11, 1912 Mar. 27, 1907 Sept. 10, 1913 Mar. 27, 1912 Jan. 7, 1914 Sept. 2, 1896 Sept. 19, 1906 Sept. 9, 1914 Sept 19, 1902 Sept 19, 1914 Oct. 1, 1913 Nov. 15, 1907 Sept. 16, 1907 Sept 11, 1912 Jan. 8, 1914 Oct. 1, 1913 Sept 19, 1906 Oct. 10, 1906 Feb. 27, 1908 Nov. 27, 1908 Sept. 7, 1911 Sept. 20, 1902 Sept. 15, 1914 Sept. 10, 1901 Sept 1, 1909 Jan. 20, 1913 Alexander, Dorothy Aubrecht, Elsie Milford Nebraska Scuth Omaha Nebraska Dakota City Nebraska University Place. Illinois .... Dunbar 'ndiana .. Baker, William Balch, Earl B Brinson, Nellie J 'ndiana Bullis, George Thomas Beatrice Nebraska.. Carruth, Elsie Greeley Nebraska Conn, Merton V Sutton Nebraska Cozad, Albert H Lincoln.. Nebraska Cozad, George A Lincoln Nebraska Dakin, Mary P Omaha Nebraska Davis, Grace M Franklin Illinois Deppe, Dorothy Dodge Missouri Dvorak, Joseph Madison Bohemia Embody, Charles L Fleming, Kenneth.. Lincoln Ohio Havelock Nebraska Feddalar, Frank Kearney Nebraska Beatrice Nebraska Floyd, Arthur J Gierau, Henry J Wewela, S Dak. Nebraska Grant, Mary York Illinois Griffin, Laura Worland, Wyo. Nebraska Worland, Wyo Nebraska Bern, Kansas Nebraska South Soo Nebraska Griffin, Luke Griffith, Irene Harden, Oscar V Nebraska South Soo Harden, Vinnie Nebraska Hartley, Gale Arthur Nebraska City Iowa Harris, Lyle A Beaver City Nebraska Arcadia Nebraska Hawley. Leo Wallace Nebraska Hendricks. Delia Omaha Nebraska Hill. Ethelane South Omaha Nebraska South Omaha Nebraska South Omaha Nebraska Ellis Nebraska Huit, Grace B Huit, Nola Jantzen, William G Nebraska [Lincoln | Nebraska Jennings. Leona Torrington Wyo.. Nebraska Jones, Walter Dale Kerst, McDonald Lincoln Nebraska Keret, Mark Lincoln Nebraska Sept. 2, 1909 Kirkpatrick, lona South Omaha Nebraska Sept. 11, 1911 Koch. William Sutton Nebraska Sept. 20, 1906 Kuster, Elizabeth Omaha ....Nebraska Jan. 21, 1911 Lair, Leota H Bazile Mills Towa Sept 10, 1914 Lawrence, Lulu May jPierce Nebraska Sept. 11, 1912 Leake. Thomas jElm Creek Nebraska Sept. 16, 1907 Leonard. Elizabeth Plattsmouth Missouri Mar. 3, 1902 Lillie. Rena May Reynolds | Nebraska Sept. 16, 1907 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">496 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF ENROLLMENT 1 DURING BIENNIUM— ( Continued i 1, 1912, to November 30, 1914 December PUPILS P. O. Address Nativity Date of Admission * Martin, Nora .. Mestas, Juan .. Misner, Harley Mogis, Robert Schuyler latonia \u:ora Nebraska Oct. New Mexico.. Oct. Nebraska Dec. Nebraska Oct. Nebraska Sept. Texas Sept. Nebraska Nov. Minnesota Sept. Nebraska Jan. Nebraska Nov. 'llinois Nov. \-&gt;hra.=ka SeDt. Nebraska Sept. Iowa Feb. Nebraska Sept. Nebraska Mar. Neb'aska Sept. Vebraska Oct. Nebraska ] Sept. Npbraska Oct. Neb-aska Oct. Vebraska Seot. Russia Sept. Nebraska Sept. V'hraska. .. Sept. Nebraska Dec. Scotland Sept. Nebraska Nov. T nwa Oct. Nf-braska SeDt. Nebraska April Nobraska Sept. jVebraska SeDt. .Wyoming Sept. 14, 1911 26, 1914 30,1909 11, 1910 10, 1914 16, 1910 1, 1913 15, 1913 26, 1909 10, 1908 1, 1913 10, 1914 18, 1908 2. 1913 16, 1905 6, 1910 13, 1904 1. 1913 10, 193 24, 1904 1. 1912 28. 907 9, 1914 15. 1911 15. 1911 12. 1909 1, 1913 Nebraska City "Hearwater Moore, Willis LeeRoy.. Nielson. Einar George Otlewski, Frank lastings Viup City Geneva. Palmer, Florence Phillips, Cecile Phillips, Lela Jniversity Place Jniversity Place "Allege View Phillips. Earl Robert Ritter. John H..._ "hubert mutton. Roemich. Matilda Ross, Bertha &gt;eighton Omaha Rothery, George. Surratt, Lawrence Sawyer, Bessie Seume, Alma J-braska City "■"airbury ■&gt;rraha Shipp. John Hay Springs Jebraska City McCook Shcckler, Harry- Sheridan, Ruby Fay. Snyder, Mary lodge Stamm, Jacob "ampbell v remont v remont ~oncord "»maha Stephenson, Merle Stephenson. Orval VanScoik. Muriel.. Walker, Wm Warren, Gerald LeRoy Werner. Gerald LeRoy.. Ward, Barney ..... j-»i 1 _ ■■* Dixon.. Wvmore 1, 1913 10, 1913 10. 1913 10. 1911 13. 1910 10, 1913 5, 1911 Wilson. Cleovis M Wittulski. Frederick Wolfenbera-er, Hallie Yoder, Edwin Plattsmouth "&gt;maha Nebraska City Torrington. Wyo </seg>
            <seg id="p036">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 497 t TABLE XIV. ARTICLES MADE BY PUPILS IN GIRLS' INDUS TRIAL DEPARTMENT DURING THE BIENNIUM t&gt; aprons 816 pieces bead-work, small articles, napkin rings, etc. 1 dozen bags, brad 30 1 bead necklaces and coat chains bead lampshade. fi caps, crocheted. 10 curtains, wardrobe. curtains, sash. 2 ■ dish towels hemmed, numerous doll clothes. u lollies, roll stitch. 12 holders. 14 jackets, crocheted yarn. 12 yards lace, crocheted. 7 laundry bags. 1 pair mittens. 4 quilt blocks. sets raffia baskets, trays, mat 15 etf. « slippers. pair x shawls, knitted. bolt toweling made up. 1 wash cloths, crocheted fi &gt; watch fobs, woven e. vokes, crocheted. </seg>
            <seg id="p037"/>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>