<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>MESSAGE OF John H. Morehead Governor of Nebraska TO THE 35th Session Nebraska Legislature 1917</title>
               <date value="1917">1917</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">MESSAGE OP John H. Morehead Governor of Nebraska TOTHK 35th Session Nebraska Legislature 1917 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">To the Members of the Senate and the House of Representa - tives of the Thirty-fifth Session of the Nebraska Legis - lature : GENTLEMEN : Upon taking up the duties of Governor, four years ago, I appeared before your honorable body with suggestions as to the legislation which I then deemed essential for the pro - motion and development of the State. Two years later, it was again my privilege to make further suggestions. After four year's service in the office of Governor, I now appear to make a final report of my administration and to give you a brief outline of some of the most important matters which I feel ought to come before you for consideration. We have three distinct branches of government: execu - tive, legislative and judicial. Of these three, the legis - lative is, of necessity, the most closely in touch with the people, and coming as you do, with new commissions from the electorate of the State, you must be presumed to reflect in the aggregate, the wishes of all the people. Your duty it is to direct, regulate and control the business affairs of the State. You are vested with power to pass laws regulating the life, liberty and property of the people. Great is the responsibil - ity of a body vested with such extraordinary power. But I am sure you are well worthy of the great trust imposed in you. It has been my privilege to serve as a member of the Nebraska Senate, and, during the past two sessions, to work as Governor in conjunction with the Legislature, and my expe - rience has been such as to inspire me with trust and confi - dence in the integrity and high purpose of the men who are selected from year to year to make the laws for our common - wealth. Your duty is to enact such laws as appear to be necessary for the public welfare. As retiring Executive of the State, it is my duty merely to make such suggestions as may put you upon inquiry and lead you to consider matters which may be of public importance. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE 4 Public Expenditures Throughout my administration, I have insisted on the most rigid economy and I still believe that the observance of this rule in both State and Nation is of vital importance. The officer who insists on economy in public affairs may displease those who would profit by its lavish expenditure. But if he is true to the people whose agent he is, he will guard their interests without hope of praise nor fear of censure. When I took charge of the state government four years ago, I found out-standing, a large floating debt. I am glad to report today that although the cost of everything used in our state institutions has advanced, we are practically out of debt, and that of the appropriations made, a large part will lapse. There is also a large cash fund in the State Treasury, placed there by the heads of the different state institutions, which comes in a great measure from the products of the farms connected with these institutions, the labor being furnished free of cost to the state, by the inmates. In addition to this, these farms have been made to produce a substantial part of the necessaries of life for those housed within these institu - tions. Our wards are well housed, well fed and their moral and intellectual developement is constantly advanced. It may also be mentioned that while a general improvement is made all along the line, our taxes have been friaterially reduced and at this time, I see no good reason why the expenses of the State should be increased. The State's depen - dents are entitled to good homes, good clothing, and good substantial, wholesome food, and we ought to provide plenty of attendants so that the health of our wards may be properly safe guarded. I am sure I voice the sentiments of the people when I suggest that you give our institutions sufficient money for their support; this ought to be done, not in a spirit of extravagance but in a careful business-like way that will insure the continuance of an honest, economical and efficient administration. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1916 5 The Banking Department Having been a country banker for many years, and now having had four years experience as Chairman of the Banking Board, I feel that I am able to speak on this department The banks of this State were never in a more flourishing condition than today, but this very condition has a tendency to call into the business those without adequate capital and without the necessary experience in this line of business. In order to protect the people of the State against unsafe banking, the law should be so amended as to absolutely limit the number of banks that may be established, or the banking board ought to be given discretionary power (if the courts do not hold that it already has the power) to grant or refuse charters. This I regard as a matter of first importance. If no check can be put upon the organization of new banks, they will be organized by unreliable parties and by getting protection of the Depositors Guaranty fund, which is provided by the sane conservative banker, they will draw deposits to their banks which later they may loan out on wild cat securities, or invest in fraudulent undertakings and when times of depression come, our whole banking system may be wrecked. I have observed that there is a class of men who may be termed professional promoters who seek to organize banks without regard to the needs for these institutions, sometimes to sell the institution when organized, to concerns already doing business, and at other times merely to get the commis - sion that may be made out of the sale of stock. This is a pernicious practice and the power to protect the public against it ought to be definitely lodged with the Banking Board. Or if not with this Board, with some suitable board or com - mittee that will administer the law without fear or favor. Good Roads The subject of good roads has occupied the attention of our people for many years, and in my former messages, I have urged its consideration. There is nothing that will add more to the value of our State than a general system of good </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE roads. A road can be built and maintained in Nebraska cheaper than almost anywhere else. It has been demonstra - ted during the last two years that convict labor may be profit - ably employed for this purpose. The last session of the Legis - lature appropriated $35,000 to build a road on Holdrege street by the State Farm. A large amount of this work was done by convict labor and a road was constructed with a concrete base, with vitrified brick coating, that I believe will be good for seventy-five years. After paying the convicts $3810.87, which went into a fund created for the purpose of taking care of those dependent upon them, there remained unexpended, $2966.54, thus making a net saving to the State of $6777.41. The convicts were all out on their honor and we had but one desertion ; that was by a colored man who had but a few weeks more time to serve. The Regents of the University allowed us to use one of the buildings at the State Farm where these men were housed. They were furnished supplies from the State Penitentiary, mostly produce raised from the land belonging to the State. In this connection. I wish to give due credit to the Warden of the Penitentiary for his able assistance in demonstrating the use of convict labor in this class of work. When we came to do this work, it wag found that there was more road to be built than the Legislature had contem - plated, because at the time the appropriation was made, it was assumed that the State had land on only one side of the road, while it does in fact have some land on both sides of the road. In connection with this work, there is one bill out - standing in the sum of $994.57 which after full investigation, I am convinced is a legal charge against the State and ought to be paid. But as there has been some question about our right to pay it out of the appropriation as made, we have deferred action until it can be laid before your honorable body. Also, as stated by the city officials of University Place, the city of University Place constructed paving in 1913 on the east side of the State Farm, just north of and connected </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1916 7 with the paving of which I speak. The paving cost, as the officials show, $3579.74. If found to be as reported by the officials, the State is justly indebted for one-half of this amount. The use of convict labor upon our highways is a matter of exceeding interest. I believe it is better for the men who are serving time, as well as more profitable for the State. Road work and farm work, the manufacture of brick for paving, and the securing of rock and sand to be used in the same line of work, are classes of labor in which convicts may be employed. There may be a fear in the minds of some farmers that the construction of permanent roads will prove too expensive, but what money is expened should be put into permanent contruction and where this is done, I am sure the enhanced value of the farm will more than make the difference in the cost A system of good roads will reduce the cost of the delivery of farm produce and this system ought to be encour - aged while the federal government is willing to lend its aid to the enterprise. The experience of centuries has demon - strated the value of permanent roads and shown that they are a benefit to both the country and the city. A large percentage of the cost of marketing farm produce is not due to railroad rates, but to poor roads between the farm and the railroad station. In Europe the land is worth quadruple what better land in Nebraska is worth, largely because her road system has reduced the cost of marketing and made intensive cultivation profitable. It is now time that the progressive farmer of Nebraska should realize these things and take advantage of the opportunity to secure permanent roads with a minimum expenditure of money. I also call your attention to an Act of Congress passed at the 64th Session, "An Act to provide that the United States shall aid the States in the construction of Rural Post Roads and for other purposes." The Act specifies that the Legis - lature before its final adjournment of this session, accept of the provisions of said act, in order to share in its benefits. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE Consolidation of Departments The advantage of classifying the state's business and putting co-ordinate branches under one head has been fully demonstrated by the consolidation of the Pure Food, Drug and Dairy department with the Oil department. At my suggestion four years ago, these departments were placed un - der a single head ; since then they have been operated at a pro - fit to the state and at a great saving to the people in this ; that the department has put an end to short weights, adultera - tions and the numerous frauds that had for years been prac - tised. During the present biennium, the department has been harassed by a technical interpretation of the constitution, making it difficult for the Department head to secure money wherewith to meet current expenses although the department was constantly producing more than it was paying out. While still embarrassed by this unwarranted interference, it was hailed into the Courts by a number of the large oil com - panies that object to paying the inspection fee. Regardless of this, however, Deputy Commissioner Harman has progressed with his work, taken the department out of politics, and made it the greatest business department of the State. We now have one large, efficient department, where formerly we had two, often duplicating work and more often still, failing to get results. The policy of consolidation may perhaps be carried still further to the advantage of the service, by consolidating the Hotel department with the Pure Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil department. But if the commercial travelers, who are more deeply interested in the Hotel commission than any other class of citizens, are unwilling to see this consolidation, the inspectors in the Pure Food, Dairy, Drug and Oil Department should at least be also made inspectors in the hotel commis - sion. This will give the Hotel commission the benefit of fif - teen or sixteen inspectors without additional expense. Dairy Inspectors I recommend that the dairy inspectors be placed under </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1916 9 the supervision of the Superintendent of the State Dairy Farm, who is an authority on dairy products. The State now owns the most up to date dairy building in the United States, and by placing these inspectors under this department they would be under the supervision of a man specially trained in dairy work. He would be able to school them, and they would be able to school those engaged in the dairy business. Thus the influence of the experimental farm would be extended over the State to the great advantage of the producers of dairy products. Printing Commission This department is no longer in the experimental stage, but has demonstrated its value to the public. I wish to recommend that added duties be placed upon the commis - sioner. When this is done, it will be necessary to provide sufficient salary so that he may give his entire time to the office. For the printing of blanks, books, reports, etc., there is expended by the State, nearly $250,000 each biennium. This expenditure is supervised by the Deputy Printing Commis - sioner, but in addition to this there is over $100,000 of public money expended each biennium for stationery and office sup - plies. And this expenditure is made without the supervision of the Deputy Printing Commissioner. Officers and Depart - ments purchase supplies in such quantities and at such prices as the retail dealer may demand. There is no adequate way of maintaining a proper check on this class of expenditure. There is no doubt that much money could be saved the State if the law were so amended that the Printing Department would purchase all stationery and office equipment at whole - sale, keeping the necessary stock on hand in the State House, delivering to the different officers and Departments so much as may be necessary upon proper voucher and by taking a due receipt. Under this system, the State would have the advantage of purchasing in large quantities and at lower prices and this will bring about a saving worth while. No 512311C </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE business firm would permit the expenditure of $50,000 a year for material without some real and open competition, yet that is what Nebraska is doing from year to year. Secretary of the State Board of Pardons The duties of this office are such that one person can handle all the work; that person should be a stenographer and the office should be changed from the State House to the Penitentiary where all the records may be made up and where the Pardon Board and Parole Board hold their meetings. The stenographer's time when not engaged with the Board, can be used to assist with the book-keeping and stenographic work at the Penitentiary and by removing the office from the State House, the records will be more available. At pre - sent there is a Secretary drawing $1500 per year and a stenographer, drawing $840 a year. Under the proposed plan, a capable stenographer can be secured for $100 a month and still effect a saving for the State. The State Capital Building You are on the ground and will observe the condition of the building for yourself. The majority of the people of the state will admit that the building is not in keeping with the present developement of the State. If money is to be spent, it should be expended so as to bring permanent results. If a wing is to be built, an architect ought to be employed to draw plans for a complete building and this wing be so con - structed that as the years go on and the needs of the State require further construction, other wings may be added until a complete building is finally erected. These plans ought to be drawn on lines that will meet the future development of the State and a building ought to be planned which when com - pleted will be a credit to Nebraska. Realizing the difficulty of getting money spent in a careful, economical way, I would suggest that provision be made for a building committee to be composed of a number of public spirited and substantial citi - zens of the State, whose integrity is beyond question, to </seg>
            <seg id="p011">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1916 11 superintend the expenditure of the money and to pass on the plans and specifications when drawn. This committee to serve without pay, except actual expenses. The men comprising the Board of Public Lands and Buildings have so many duties to perform that they cannot be expected to give to the construc - tion of this new wing, the time and attention which the inter - ests of the State demand. If you see fit to handle it in this way, a levy sufficient to build a wing would not prove a great burden to the people. If in your wisdom, you prefer to provide for an entirely new building, a small levy ought to be made to create a fund, which when strung out for a number of years, would prove sufficient for the purpose. Above all, I urge that if any building is erected, it be of a substantial character and one that will be suitable to meet the needs of the State for many years to come. Four Year Term for State Officers I strongly believe in the policy of a four year term for State officers and making them ineligible for re-election. In this way, we can have our business affairs looked after better than when men are elected for a short term and soon feel the necessity of preparing for a new campaign in order to secure re-election. The Short Ballot I would also recommend such amendment to the constitu - tion as will promote the policy so popularly designated as the short ballot. I have given the matter careful consideration and am convinced that it is better to place the power to make appointments for purely administrative officers in the hands of the Governor, or some duly constituted Board, than to elect haphazard, a large number of officers to places which do not attract enough public attention to make them a real issue in a campaign. No one who has witnessed the drift of modern politics can escape the conclusion that the voters con - centrate their attention upon a few of the more important </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE offices and, for the most part, they merely vote their party ticket for the minor places on the ballot It would be the part of wisdom, I believe, to vest these important officers with authority to appoint men to the minor places and then hold them responsible for their administration. Looking over the appointments that I have been called upon to make and seeing the work that my appointees have done, I am convinced that better results could not have been obtained by a direct ballot. In this regard, it is gratifying to know that of the many men I have appointed to fill vacancies to elective offices, practically all have been endorsed by the voters. A notable instance is in the case of Judges. I have appointed six district judges and of these all but one have been elected; his defeat was not due to his failure to give good service, but to the fact that his opponent was a man of unusual strength and popu - larity. Another important place which I filled by appointment was that of election commissioner of Omaha, and it was gratifying to me to note that my opponent in the campaign of two years ago, publicly pledged himself to reappoint him in case he was elected. Election of Supreme Court Judges by Districts I repeat what I have said in my former messages to the effect that I favor a constitutional amendment which will provide for the election of the Chief Justice by the State at large, and the election of the Associate Judges from Districts. Thus giving the different parts of the State representation upon the Court. Our Primary Law I again call your attention to the necessity of an improve - ment in our primary law. The present law, as I believe, has a tendency to keep out of public life the man whom we most need. Candidates come to us at the primary election without endorsement from anybody, without the electorate having any chance of knowing their qualifications, moral standing, </seg>
            <seg id="p013">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1916 13 or anything else. Platforms, declarations, and pledges mean but little when they are to be enforced by a man who is incom - petent, and who has but little regard for organized govern - ment. I hope that a committee will be selected that will give its entire time throughout the legislative session to the improvement of the primary law. Our Public Schools In a former message, I called attention to the method of electing our school officers. By the enactment of the non - partisan judiciary law, we took the courts of the state out of politics. This was a long step forward, and so far as I have been able to learn, it meets with almost universal approval. I feel that it is now our duty to take another advance step. The stability of a republican form of goverment depends upon the intelligence of its citizenship and this intelligence is fostered and developed by our public school system. The schools however, cannot do their best work when enmeshed in party politics. Like the courts, they ought to be free and above political intrigue find J, therefore, recommend the enactment of a law for the nomination and election of our school superintendents, county and state, similar to that under which we now elect our judiciary. I am also in hearty accord with the suggestion made by the Grand Army of the Republic, and other patriotic bodies, that the study of Abraham Lincoln's life and work be made a part of our regular school work. The past generation did not need to study Lincoln in the schools because they had a personal knowledge of his character and achievements. But the generation now growing up must get its information of him in the schools. His life ought to be an inspiration to every American youth and, like American history, I hope to see it made a part of the regular curriculum. Health Department I call your attention to a report made by Dr. Carroll Fox, who is in the emplov of the federal government and who came </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE here at my request, but at the expense of the federal govern - ment, to assist us in getting some legislation to improve our health laws. I regard this as one of the most important matters of this session. It will require some persistent and intelligent work in order to bring a better condition out of the chaos that now exists. Better sanitary and health laws should be passed, and an appropriation providing the neces - sary funds for this department should be made, but the funds should be so expended that they will bring results. The money ought not be used for an unnecessary number of health officers, or to have several departments which are not work - ing in harmony, making conditions worse if possible, than they are now. Conservation of Water Power In each of my former messages to the Legislature, I have stated that I am in favor of the conservation of the resources of the State of Nebraska. Among these, is the proper protec - tion of the water power in public streams of the State. The past sessions of the Legislature have made no appro - priation for this purpose. While there has been little advance - ment made along this line from the State standpoint, private enterprises have made some progress. One corporation has a plant costing more than two million dollars, that is now connected with one of the leading cities of the State. This will enable you to investigate and determine to what extent this power can be used, and as to the advisability of spending the people's money for the developement of the water power. Veto Power Your duty is to legislate and appropriate, the Governor's is to enforce. As I have stated many times, I am not in favor of exercising the veto power freely and in only a few instances have I used this power. The Omaha Lighting Bill was probably the most notable instance. This bill passed the Senate and the House by a very small majority, and nineteen of the Senators and fifty- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1916 15 three of the members of the House, a majority in both houses, afterwards memorialized me to use the veto power. At a recent election, the electorate of Omaha sustained the veto, which I feel is sufficient evidence to justify my action on this bill. It was one of the most persistently lobbeyed bills that was ever presented to the Nebraska Legislature and I trust that your time will not be taken up to such extent as it was two years ago, by such a selfish movement, as I have every reason to believe that one was. This bill was not a municipal bill, but it would have established a dual form of government and enabled them to levy exhorbitant prices on the users of water. The poorest people of the city must use water and many, owing to their financial condition, were unable to use electric light; it thereby compelled the poor peaple to pay exhorbitant prices for water in order to furnish cheaper light for those more financially able to pay. All the rights given to the people by this bill, could be obtained under the Omaha charter, through the proper channels of representative city govern - ment. New Legislation At the last election the people of this State registered their will on the liquor question. By many able lawyers, it is held that the constitutional amendment adopted is self acting, and that further legislation is not required. I do not take issue with this view ; nevertheless I feel that some legislation is necessary in order to get the desired results from this amendment, and I urge such action as in your wisdom may seem best to carry out the will of the people. Conclusion In laying down the burdens of office and retiring to private life, I do it with a heart filled with gratitude to my fellow citizens who have so signally honored me. For four years I have constantly striven to promote the general welfare </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE of the State, and I am going back to my family and friends, feeling that my work has not been in vain. Year by year, Nebraska has advanced in wealth and population, she has also grown in morals and intellect. Our people have been blessed with fertile soil and a healthful climate. Within the life time of a single generation, we have taken a prairie waste, carved it up into fertile farms, and dotted it over with beautiful cities. We have erected temples of learning, and houses of worship, and promoted the cause of justice and humanity. I am no longer charged with official responsibility, but as a humble citizen, I hope to devote the remainder of my years to the service of the State that has so signally honored me. Coming here in my youth, I have grown with the common - wealth; for whatever service I have rendered, I have been abundantly rewarded. Position, however, is merely an out - ward evidence of success. Office can bring no honor unless the incumbrent is worthy of the place and discharges faith - fully and well the duty that it brings. I am sure that you and my successor measure up to this standard of citizenship and I am glad to commit the state to your keeping. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1916 17 Section 9231, Revised Statutes for 1913, directs the Governor to make report concerning Pardons and Commuta - tions. John L. Thomas, sentenced October 28th, 1905 for life, for murder in the second degree. Commuted Jan - uary 12th, 1915 to fifteen years at the unanimous request of the State Board of Pardons. 4503 John Gayman, sentenced January 8th, 1913 for from one to twenty years for the crime of shooting to wound. Pardoned January 13, 1915. This man had spent much of his time in the Asylum for Insane, but at the time of his pardon was considered safe to return to his family and I regarded it an act of humanity to give him his freedom. 6041 3937 Oliver B. Oleson, sentenced January 7th, 1902 for twenty years for murder in the second degree. Com - muted October 22nd, 1915, to nineteen years and seven months, shortening his time five months. He having been a good prisoner, I considered he had earned that much time. 5867 Louis C. Rogers, sentenced December 4th, 1911 for murder in the second degree for twelve years. Par - doned February 4th, 1916. This man was an excep - tionally good prisoner, and as I did not believe his liberty would in any way be a menace to society and that his further imprisonment would do him no good, I deemed it wise to restore him to liberty. 5555 Eugene Jackson, sentenced November 12, 1910 for murder in the second degree for thirteen years. Sen - tence commuted to eight years, September 9th, 1916, by earnest unanimous request of the State Board of Pardons. 6801 Kenneth Murphy, sentenced October 16, 1911 for life for murder in the second degree. Sentence commuted September 23, 1916 to four years and eleven months. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE 18 This was a young man but sixteen years old, a trusted prisoner and developed a strong desire for an education of high degree. The crime of which he was convicted was his first offense. I deliberated for months as to the action I should take in the case and then issued the commutation. 420 Paroled. </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>