<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Value of a Ton of Farm Manure in the North Platte Valley</title>
               <date value="18??">May 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">The Value of a Ton of Farm Manure in the North Platte Valley Bulletin3lB May, 1938 j Lionel Harris ':"' .'. ''\ ¦ -'¦¦':'-. .:•':¦¦¦'. •:. ' W^L^.-..*.. !-»*."' ' 'c- *—ssss^- *k-- '- ¦- :| General view of rotation plots. Scottsbluu" Substation, Mitchell Nebraska Cooperative between Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. and Division of Western Irrigation Agriculture United States Department of Agriculture ' "' ¦'¦']¦ :'. '.¦"•¦¦}¦¦ ' I.- '.' ' The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture ... Experiment Station, Lincoln, Nebraska W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS AND SUMMARY Description nl the Rotations 4 Amount of Manure Produced by Farm Relative Values rjf the Rotations 5 Animals &#132;.11 Results of Rotation Experiments with Value of Manure per Animal Unit of ami without Manure 6 1,0110 pounds Live Weight 13 Two-year rotations, potatoes and Livestock Population Necessary to Pro - sugar beets 6 tlucc Different Quantities of Manure. 14 Two-vcar rotations, oats ami sugar Present Livestock Population and Total beets 7 Production of Manure in the North Two-year rotations, potatoes and Platte Valley 18 „.,„ .. . 8 Present Protluction of Manure as Com- Tbrcc-ycar rotations, potatoes, oats, pared svilh Amount Necessary to ami sugar beets , . 8 Operate Two-year, Three-year, and Six-year rotations, potatoes, oats, Six-year Manured Rotations 19 sugar beets, and three years of alfalfa • 10 The salve of a ton of manure in terms of increased yields in five rotation compari - sons at the Scottsbluff Substation has ranged from 52.32 to 54.62 per ton, with a mean value of $3.72 per ton. The manure produced and available annually for field appltcauon has been deter - mined to be 4.52 tons per unit of 1,000 pounds of live weight for horses, 6.33 tons for dairy cattle, 4.28 tons for feeder cattle, 1.66 tons for feeder sheep, and 5.02 tons tor hogs. These figures represent manure production in the North Platte valley. Based upon the results from the five rotations, the annual value of manure per animal unit has been $16.80 for horses, $23.52 for dairy cattle, $15.90 for feeder cattle, $6.17 for feeder sheep, and $18.65 for hogs. The population of livestock, exclusive of work animals, necessary to produce manure applications ranging from I to 12 tons per acre on an 80-acrc farm, is indicated in this bulletin. The results from the manured rotations and from a manure experi - ment with sugar beets, when correlated with the population of livestock required to produce various quantities of manure, indicate that heavy applications of manure applied annually to the land are not practicable because of the enormous number of animals required to produce such applications, and also from the fact that the greatest value and effectiveness of manure are not obtained in the heavy applications. The results from the rotation experiments and also the manure experiment indicate a high residual value for manure, showing that heavy applications of manure each year arc not necessary to maintain yields at satisfactory levels. Good yields for a period of 25 years have been obtained in a six-year rotation of potatoes, oats, sugar beets, and three years of alfalfa, with a 12-ton application of manure to the sugar-beet crop. This manurial application is equivalent to a two-ton application annually over the whole area of the rotation. . . It has been estimated that the feed produced in this type of rotation is sufficient to care for the livestock required to produce the two-ton per acre application qf manure. Where a four- or a six-ton per acre application of manure is required for the whole' area of a farm, such as is necessary in three-year and two-year rotations, enormous numbers of livestock are needed to produce the required manure; furthermore such rotations produce very little feed for livestock. The six-year rotation, where fifty per cent of the land each year has been devoted to growing alfalfa, has proved to be the most practical, from a rnanure-livestock-fccd relationship. It has also been found to be one of the most desirable rotations from the standpoint of the control of potato diseases. . &#132;..,, The present population of livestock on Federal Irrigated Project lands in the North Platte valley is approximately 0.30 unit of 1,000 pounds live weight per acre, as compared with 1.41 units required for two-year rotations, 0.94 unit for three-year rotations, amJ 0.57 unit for six-year rotations. Increases in the present population of livestock in the North Platte valley ranging from 90 per cent in six-year rotations to 370 per cent in two-year rotations appear to be necessary for the maintenance of the productivity of the soil on the basis of the rotation experiments. , </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Value of a Ton of Manure I UONEL HARRIS] Acting Superintendent. Scottsbluff Substation Where farming is practiced without irrigation in regions of low rain - fall, moisture may be said to be the chief limiting factor in crop produc - tion. Under irrigation farming in these regions, where an adequate water supply has been assured, low productivity is likely to be the chief cause of poor yields. I The establishment, operation, and maintenance of an irrigation system represent costly items, and have to be paid for by crops taken from the soil. Consequendy crop-production costs under irrigation are considerably higher than where irrigation is not practiced. In order to cover these higher production costs and to obtain a profit in addition, high crop yields have to be produced on irrigated farms. ! The harvesting of large crop yields results in a heavy drain on the plant food elements in the soil. If fatimng practices are such that the productivity of the soil is not maintained, crop yields decline and will eventually reach unprofitable levels. Insects] diseases, poor management of larjd and water, and unfavorable climatic Conditions at times limit crop production, but soil conditions unfavorable) for normal, vigorous plant growth are one of the more important causes of low yields in irrigation . farming. ¦' v! ,- . '"' According to Van Slyke 1 approximately 80 per cent of the nitrogen and phosphorus, 90 per cent of the potassium, and 50 per cent of the organic matter of food consumed by farm animals is voided in the manure. It is estimated that 50 per cent of this plant! food can be returned to the soil in the form of mammal applications. Consequently the application of farm.manure is one important means of returning to the soil considerable quantities of plant food elements, thereby helping to check the heavy drain *on these elements incurred by the production of high crop yields. Manure contributes to the productivity of the soil not only by the addition of plant-food elements but also by the addition)of humus, which favors the growth of the soil flora arid improves the physical condition of the soil. The continual production of cash crops, whereby plant-food elements are taken from the soil and removed from the farm without replacement results eventually in low yields and consequently unprofitable farming. By utilizing part of the land for the production of crops which can be fed to livestock on the farm, a considerable quantity of the plant'tood materials taken from the soil is kept on the farm. This plant food material to - gether with humus returned to the soil as farm manure, aids in the main - tenance of the productivity of the soil. ¦ ),':•"¦'¦' The present bulletin deals with the importance of farm manure in the use of land under irrigation farming. It has several objectives: To show the influence of farm manure on crop yields in several irri - gated rotations for a period of 25 years. U. L. Van Slyke, Fertilizers and Crop Production, p. 22J,'Nesr York, 1932. </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 318 To indicate the financial value of a ton of manure in terms of increased yields in various rotations. To compare these figures with the amount of manure produced by farm animals and to show the value of the manure produced annually by various classes of livestock. To show the number of animal units necessary to produce manure for various cropping programs. To show in general the importance and number of livestock required on irrigated farms to insure the maintenance of soil fertility and high crop yields. To indicate the number of animals on irrigated farms in the North Platte valley at the present time as compared with the number needed to aid significantly in maintaining the productivity of the soil. DESCRIPTION OF THE ROTATIONS Of 31 crop rotations started in 1912 at the Scottsbluff Substation, five pairs of rotations have been devoted to a study of the effect of farm manure on crop yields. The manure has been applied at the rate of 12 tons per acre to one crop in each rotation and is equivalent annually to a six-ton application over the whole area of a two-year rotation, four tons in a three-year rotation, or two tons in a six-year rotation. The sequence oi trie five manured rotations is as follows: No. 21—Sugar beets (manure), potatoes. No. 23—Oats (manure), sugar beets. No. 25 —Oats (manure), potatoes. No. 31—Potatoes, oats (manure), sugar beets. No. 61—Alfalfa (three years), potatoes, oats (manure), sugar beets. Each of the manured rotations is comparable with another rotation of the same sequence of crops, but without the manure. The unmanured iotations corresponding respectively to those manured as shown are num - bered as follows: 20, 22, 24, 30, and 60. These manured and unmanured rotations afford a means of determining the value of a ton of manure in terms of the stimulating effect which the manure has had on crop yields. The present study covers the 25-year period from 1912 .to 1936 inclusive. The rotations discussed in this paper have partly been the subject of former publications which have described and analyzed all of the old rotations in operation at the Scottsbluff Substation.- The farm manure used in the experiments has been produced and maintained through the winter months in an open yard, subject to the losses in plant-food elements associated with this method of handling IC. S. Scofield. F.lTect of Farm Manure in Stimulating the Yields of Irrigated Field Crops, lour. Agr Res. 15:493-503. 19R C. S. Sco&amp;cld and 1. A. Holden. Irrigated Crop Rotations in Western Nebraska, U. S. Dept. Agr. C I ' A Holden Crop Rotation! under Irrigation, Ncbr. Agr. Esp. Sta. Bui. 190, 1929. S H Hastings, ElTccr of Alfalfa and Farm Manure on Viclds of Irrigated Crops in the Great Plains U. S. Dept. Agr. Tech. Bul. 4»3. 1935. S. H. Hastings, Irrigated Crop Rotations in Western Nebraska 1912-34, U. S. Dept. Agr. Tech. Bul. 512. 1936. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">The Value op a Ton op Manure manure. The chief losses sustained have resulted from leaching, as the manure has been kept sufficiently moist to prevent excessive fermentation. RELATIVE VALUES OF THE ROTATIONS •_ The relative values appearing in the Mowing discussion have been obtained by subtracting production costs from the gross earnings of each rotation as a complete unit. These values have been computed for the 23-year period 1912-34 by Hastings,» according to the Mowing pro - cedure: The production costs represent the actual cost of performing the various operations necessary in crop production as closely as it was possible to determine them. The production costs lor cultural operations are those recognized as somewhat standardized in the community, for example - contract labor, hauling sugar beets, harvesting grain, plowing, taxes, and irrigation water costs. Other items of expense such as disking, harrowine and planting have been estimated, based partly on the experience of pel. forming these operations at the station as well as on observations made by farmers on the project. \ .I.!'.' Eighteen dollars per acre has been assigned to contract labor in pro - ducing sugar beets; $11 per acre has been allowed for water costs, tool maintenance, repairs, interest, and depreciation; and $7 per acre has been used as the cost of applying manure. The gross earnings of the rotations have been determined by assigning unit values for the varous crops produced. These assigned values were as follows: alfalfa $7 per ton - sugar beets $6 per ton; oats 40 cents per jbushel; marketable potatoes 50 cents per bushel; and cull potatoes 15 cents per bushel. In this dis - cussion, marketable potatoes are .potatoes'that will pass over, a 1% inch screen. -; I ¦ The computations, representing the relative values, obtained in this manner for the 23-year period 1912-34 have been extended by proportion calculations to cover the 25-year period 1912-16. The value of a ton of manure for the 25-year period 1912-36, has been obtained by dividing the tons of manure applied per acre over the whole area of the rotation into the difference in the relative value between the manured and unmanured relations For, the six- and seven-year periods the value of a ton of manure has been computed on the basis of the comparative differences in yields obtained for each period as compared with the differences in yields for the 25 year period. •..'!• i . It should be noted thatthe figures used here are relative figures em - ployed expressly for the purpose of translating acre i returns by weight measure into acre returns by dollar measure. JThe value of manure in all the rotation comparisons in this study is very appareiit. Each manured rotation, however, may not have a general practical application (for example the two-year rotation of oats and sugar beets manured, which is valuable chiefly for the scientific information which it has yielded regard - ing the value of farm manure). The proper I,recognition of the value of farm manure in irrigation farming is the point which docs find an im - portant^ practical application on every irrigated farm. The best types of IS. H. Hastings, U. S.P. A. Tech. Bui. 512 (cited above). '...'•". </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 318 practical rotation programs are indicated in this study. It is not important that farmers follow the rotations exacdy as oudined. Rather it is important that the principles taught by the rotations be recognized and employed by the farmer in the use of his land. RESULTS OF ROTATION EXPERIMENTS, WITH AND WITHOUT MANURE The results from the five rotation comparisons showing the effect .ot farm manure on crop yields, and also its value, are presented in Tables 1 to 5 Mean acre yield data in each instance arc tabulated for three six-year periods (1912-17, 1918-23, and 1924-29), one seven-year period 1930-36 and for the 25-year period 1912-36. The relative values are based upon the 25-year mean data. The per-ton values of manure shown for the shorter periods are associated with the yield differences for the respec - tive periods. In each comparison the rotations are identical except that one crop in the odd-numbered rotation has received manure at the rate of 12 tons an acre. TWO-YEAR ROTATIONS, POTATOES AND SUGAR BEETS No. 20 No. 21 Potatoes Potatoes (manured) Sugar beets Sugar beets The effect of farm manure in a two-year rotation of potatoes and suear beets is shown in Table 1. The 25-year mean yield of potatoes in rotation 21 has been 236 bushels, as compared with 147 bushels in rotation 20, or an increase of 89 bushels per acre in favor of manure. The 25-year Table I.— Value of farm manure in a two-year rotation of potatoes and sugar beets, 1912-36. Mean acre vieltls. 6- ami 7-year periods 1912-36 Rotation Mean Relative No. 111247 1918-23 1021-29 1930-36 ya , ue ; ] ' 528.35 21 —Manured &#132;,, ..., , -jj&lt;cn Potatoes 212.1 154.5 334.1 243.6 236.0 Reets H. 7 16.7 18-5 16.3 16.5 20 —No manure ,„ „„ , .. 7n Potatoes 183.4 108.0 170.1 128.1 147.0 Beets 13.1 10.3 10.2 7.8 10.3 ""TotaTocs 28.7 46.5 .64.0 .55.5 89.0 Beets I.ft 6.4 8.3 8.5 6.2 Value of manure _ -, „« c a r.-j per ton SI .28 §4.06 ?6-»8 56.88 . S 4.62 Yields of potaioci in buiheli and becti in torn per acre. mean yields of sugar beets have been 16.5 tons and 10.3 tons per acre for the manured and unmanured rotations respectively, or a difference of 6.2 tons in favor of manure. Rotation 21 has returned a 25-year mean net </seg>
         <seg id="p007">-.': ' The Vi\i.UE of a Ton op Manure t-y income above production costs of $2835 per acre, as compared with 65 cents per acre for unmanured rotation 20, or! a difference of $27.70 per ;.(¦' acre in favor of manure. Dividing this figure by six, which represents the tons of manure applied annually per acre over the whole area, gives a .".'..•' value for manure of $4.62 per ton&lt; The value of manure per ton by six-, and seven-year periods ranged from $1.28 for the first six-year period to $6.88 for the third six-year period and the seven-year period 1930-36. !,? The manure values are associated with the yield differences for each period j which have been considerably higher in the later periods than in the first j y six-year period. The value of, manure, even in the first six-year period, is }'¦¦ j not insignificant in this comparison. [¦:'.' ! V ,:•:'. TWO-YEAR ROTATIONS, OATS AND SUGAR BEETS j j '¦ N0.22 :N0,23 [' ¦¦';¦'¦. Oats j Oats'-. l':. Sugar beets ¦ Sugar beets (manured) | . The effect of manure in a two-year rotation of oats and sugar beets is ; ..shown in Table 2. The 25-year mean yield of oats in rotation 23 has been 61.1 bushels per acre, as compared with 43.1 bushels in rotation 22, or jy a difference of 18 bushels in favor of manure) Sugar beets in the manured ¦¦¦¦ rotation have returned a 25-year mean yield of 17.9 tons as compared with 9.9 tons in the unmanured rotation, or a difference of 8 tons in favor of manure. The 25-year mean relative value of the manured rota - . Table 2.— Value of farm manure in a two-year rotation of oats and sugar ';-:'. ; beets, 1912-36. \ ¦'¦¦'.:"' Mean acre yields, 6- and 7-year periods 1912-36 Rotation ——— ~ j — rrr : No. 1912-17 1918-23 1924-29 1930-36 M 0?? Rel»tive - • - . - ¦ - yields I value 23—Manured '* ¦' $21.32 Oats .......... 69.5 63.1 64.8' 49.3 6111 Beets ......... 17.4 18.1 .19.8 16.6 17.9 . 22—No manure $ 0.13 Oats 67.3 49.1 31.4 27.3 43.1 Beets ......... 12.8 9.8 . .9.9 7.6 9.9 J-Y DilTcrcnce $21.19 11 j Oats .......... 2.2 : M.O 33.4 22.0 18.0 f I Beets ....;.... 4.6 8.3 9.9 9.0 8.0 ?r ——: ; ; ; . : tj ¦- Value of manure |'-: per ton 51.97 $3.63 54.44 $3.98 &#132;.." $ 3.53 jK Yield; ol sugar beds fitven in tons and oats in bushels per acre. f '¦. tion has been $2132 above production costsj as compared with 13 cents fc: for the unmanured rotation. Consequently [the manure in rotation 23 Q has had an indicated value of $21.19 per acre or $3.53 per ton. The || smallest diffetences in yields attributable-to manure have been obtained \% ; during the first six-year period 1912-17, when manure had a value of |S g $1.97 per ton. The highest differences in yields occurred during the fc, 0, six-year period 1924-29, when the manure was worth $4.44 per ton. F; :,•.': .":¦''.;. ¦. :'•- ;' -;. V - - '¦ ¦. "'' ¦•'¦¦ ¦¦'.¦'¦' ;;' ':" '¦.¦'"¦¦¦' •'¦¦' - f&lt; </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 318 TWO-YEAR ROTATIONS. POTATOES AND OATS No. 24 No. 25 Potatoes Potatoes (manured) Oats Oats The effect of manure in stimulating the yields of potatoes and oats is shown in Table 3. The 25-year mean yield of potatoes from manured lotation 25 has been 241 bushels per acre, as compared with 151 bushels from unmanured rotation 24, or a difference of 90 bushels in favor of the manured rotation. The 25-year mean yield of oats from rotation 25 has been 58.2 bushels, and 43 bushels from rotation 24, or a mean difference of 152 bushels in favor of the manured rotation. The 25-year mean net Table 3. — Value of farm manure in a two-year rotation of potatoes and oats, 1912-36. Mean acre yields, 6- and 7-year periods 1912-36 Rotation N°- 1912-17 1918-23 1924-29 1930-36 R^|jjve 25 —Manured $ 8.83 Potatoes 229.7 191.4 326.9 218.5 241.0 Oats 63.7 60.9 64.8 45.5 58.2 24—No manure —5 5.08 Potatoes . 182.3 121.0 184.7 122.2 151.0 Oats .. 68.9 45.7 33.1 26.9 43.0 Difference $13.91 Potatoes . 47.4 70.4 142.2 96.3 90.0 Oats 5.2 15.2 31.7 18.6 15.2 Value of manure per ton $1.05 51.8b 53.76 52.51 ... S 2.32 income above production costs has been 58.83 per acre for the manured rotation, as compared with a loss of J5.08 per acre in rotation 24. The rotation of potatoes and oats has failed to yield sufficiently to cover pro - duction costs by a 25-year mean annual loss of $5.08 per acre. Conse - quently the value of manure for the 25-year period has been $13.91 per acre or $2.32 per ton. Yield differences during the first six-year period were small, giving a value for manure of 51.05 per ton. In the first six - year period the yield of oats in the unmanured rotation was 5.2 bushels per acre higher than in the manured rotation. The highest differences in yields occurred during the third six-year period, giving a value for manure of $3.76 per ton. THREE-YEAR ROTATIONS, POTATOES, OATS, AND SUGAR BEETS No. 30 No. 31 Potatoes Potatoes Oats . Oats Sugar beets Sugar beets (manured) The stimulating effect on the yields of potatoes, oats, and sugar beets in a three-year rotation is shown in Table 4. To the sugar-beet crop in </seg>
         <seg id="p009">The Value of a Ton op Manure -'--¦- I -¦ I It'll I Bw-' iH sfei."*S Potatoes and sugar beets in Rotation 31. Table 4.—Value of farm manure in a three-year rotation of potatoes, oats, . and sugar beets, 1912-36. R . ' Mean acre yields, 6- and 7-year periods 1912-36 No. 1912-17 1918-23 1924-29 11930-36 ¥?, n I : __)_ yields | value 31—Manured j $2067 Potatoes 246.1 185.5 339.5 !.' 247.7 254.0 Oats ..76.6 72.3 61.0 52.9 65.2 Beets .......... 18.2 16.9 18.8 16.8 17.6 30—No manure $ 2 51 Potatoes ....... 225.4 131.8 218.5 156.8 182.0 Oats .......... 65.4 56.1 36.4: 29.5 46.1 Beets 12.9 9.9 10.4 7.8 10.2 Difference $1816 Potatoes ..; 20.7 .53.7 121.0 90.9 72.0 Oats i 11.2 16.2 24.6. 23.4 19.1 Beets 5.3 7.0 8.4 j 9.0 7.4 Value of manure P« ton $2.80 $4.08 $5.70 ¦[ $5.57 ... $4.54 Yields of beets given in tons and potatoes and oau in bushels per acre. rotation 31 manure is applied at the rate of 12 tons per acre; otherwise rotations 30 and 31 are alike. The 25-year mean yield of potatoes in manured rotation 31 has been 254 bushels per acre and from rotation 30, 182 bushels per acre, or a difference of 72 bushels attributable to the influence of manure. The 25-year mean yield of oats has been 65.2 bushels per acre in rotation 31 and 46.1 bushels per acre in rotation 30, or a difference of 19.1 bushels in favor of manure. The mean yield of sugar beets has been 17.6 tons per acre in rotation 31 as compared with 102 tons in rotation 30. Manure has increased the yield of sugar beets in </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 318 this rotation 7.4 tons per acre. The manured rotation has returned a mean annual net income of $20.67 per acre above production costs, and the unmanured rotation $2.51 per acre. This comparison indicates a value of $18.16 per acre for manure or $454 per ton. The lowest differences in die yields of crops in favor of manure occurred during the first six-year period; the greatest differences in yields occurred during the third six-year period 1924-29. During the first six-year period on the basis of the yield differences as compared with the 25-year mean increases, the manure has been computed to be worth $2.80 per ton, and during the third six-year period, $5.70 per ton. During the seven-year period 1930-36, yield differences indicate a value for manure of $5.57 per ton. SK-yEAR ROTATIONS No. 60 No. 61 Potatoes Potatoes Oats Oats Sugar beets Sugar beets (manured) Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa The effect of manure on the yields of potatoes, oats, sugar beets, and three years of alfalfa in a six-year rotation comparison is shosvn in Table 5. Rotations 60 and 61 are identical, except that the sugar-beet crop in rotation 61 receives manure at the rate of 12 tons per acre. The 25-year mean annual yield of potatoes in rotation 61 has been 311 bushels an acre, as compared with 289 bushels in rotation 60, or an increase of 22 bushels in favor of manure. In the manured rotation, oats returned a 25-year mean yield of 73.1 bushels an acre, and beets 18.7 tons. In the absence of the influence of manure oats yielded 673 bushels and beets 14.2 tons. The yield differences in favor of manure have been 5.8 bushels of oats and 4.5 tons of sugar beets. The 25-year mean yields of first-year alfalfa have been the same in the two rotations —one ton per acre. However, each of the second- and third-year crops of alfalfa indicate a 0.4 ton increase in yield in favor of the manured rotation. The mean annual net income above production costs has been $20.13 per acre for rotation 61, and $12.99 per acre for rotation 60. or a difference of $7.14 per acre in favor of the manured rotation. The manurial application in rotation 61 is equivalent to two tons per acre on the whole area; consequendy the manure in terms of increased yields has a computed value of $3.57 per ton. The yield differ - ences in favor of manure, as recorded by six-year and seven-year periods, are more uniform than in the previous comparisons where the differences have generally been lowest during the first six-year period. In the present comparison the lowest yield differences in favor of manure occurred during the second six-year period 1918-23, and the highest during the third six-year period. On the basis of the yield differences by periods as com - pared with the differences for the 25-year period, manure had a value of </seg>
         <seg id="p011">• The Value op a Ton of Manure Table s.— Value of farm manure in a six-year rotation of potatoes, oats, _^_ sugar beets, and three years of alfalfa, 1912-36. Mean acre yields, 6- and 7-year periods 1912-36 Rotation -. ; — . . . — No. 1912-17 I 1918-23 1924-29 1930-36 S" value* 61—Manured: . ;: $20J3 Potatoes ....... 296.3 277.7 395.4 I 279.0 311.0 Oats 69.7 73.1 95.5 56.8 73.1 Beets ......... 18.5 19.0 .20.5! 16.9 18.7 Alt Ist yr...... 1.6 .7 1.0 1.0 1.0 All. 2nd yr..... 5.0 3.9 5.4 4.7 4.8 Alt 3rd yr..... 5.3 5.4 6.1 i 5.4 5.5 60—No manure ' . i $12.99 Potatoes ......i 278.4 258.7 372.7 ; 251.9 289.0 Oats,..; ; 68.3 68.7 83.6! 513 67.3 Beets ......... 14.1 14.7 15.4 13.0 14.2 Alt. Ist yr...... 1.4 .6 .8- 1.0 1.0 Alf. 2nd yr..... 4.6 4.2 4.6 : 4.1 4.4 Alt. 3rd yr...".. . 4.9 5.6 . 5.5' 4.6 5.1 Difference $7.14 Potatoes ...17.9 19.0 22.7 i 27.1 22.0 Oats .......... 1.4 4.4 11.9 5.5 5.8 Beets ......... 4.4 4.3 5.1 ; ,3.9 4.5 Alt. Ist yr...... .2 .1 .2 .'¦ '.. .. ' Alf. 2nd yr..... .4 - .3 .8 &lt; .6 .4 Alf. 3rd yr..... .4 . - .2 .6; .8 ' .4 Value o£ manure : ' per ton.-....... $3.49 $3.24 $4.45 \ $3.63 ... $3.57 Yields of poutoes and oats given in .bushels and beets and alfalfa in tons per acre. $3.49 per ton for the first six-year period, $3.24 per ton for the second six-year period, $4.45 per ton for the third six-year period, and $3.63 per ton for the seven-year period 1930-36. ! AMOUNT OF MANURE PRODUCED BY FARM ANIMALS The annual production of manure on the basis of 1,000 pounds of live weight, as determined by various investigators, is shown in Table 6.* The figures given represent the total amount of manure produced when it is all saved throughout the entire year. On this. basis the horse unit produces from 10 to 12 tons of manure annually, including bedding, the dairy-cow unit 14 to 15 tons, feeder-cattle, unit 7 to 8 tons, feeder-sheep unit 6to 7 tons, and the pig unit 15 to 18 tons. . For further studies, definite figures have been adopted to represent the manure production of the various classes of livestock in the North Platte 4 For the purposes of this paper it is assumed that an ammalunit of 1,000 pounds live weight Is equivalent to one mature hone, cow, or steer, to 12 feeder sheep, 7 hogs, or 200 hens. It appears reasonable to assume that the weights above 1,000 pounds of mature horses and dairy cows will be offset by the smaller weight of the young stock. The approximate mean weight of feeder lambs while on feed in the North Platte valley is 80 pounds and of feeder steers 1,000- pounds. The mean weight oE hogs is assumed to be approximately 150 pounds. ' </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin-318 Table 6.— Manure produced by farm animals on the basis of 1,000 pounds of live weight, including bedding. Kind of animal ' _^ Source of data j j j j j Horse | Cosy | Pig | Sheep | Steer ) Hen TONS Van Slyke' 12.0 15.0 18.25 9.75 9.0 4.25 Ohio = 11.6* 6.05 7.54* Cornell 3 8.9 13.52* 15.25* 6.22 R. 1.4 14.32 ... 1 L. L. Van Slyke. Fertilizers and Crop Production, p. 225, N. V-, 1932. * C. E. TViorne. The Maintenance of Fertility, Ohio Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 183, 1907. "G. C. Watson. The Production of Manure. Cornell Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 56, 1893. •T. E. Odland and H. G. Knoblauch, A Comparative Test of Different Bedding Materials and Crtem. Supplements with Cow Manure Applied in a Three-year Rotation. Rhode Island Agr. Exp. Sia. Bui 251. 1935. ' Exclusive of bedding. valley. The figures selected aro based upon the data in Table 6, with consideration given to the special conditions under which manure is produced in the North Platte valley. In Table 7 are shown the annual amounts of manure produced and available for field application from the various classes of livestock. These computations are based upon the annual production of manure, and the length of time each year that the manure may be saved for field applica - tion. On the basis of the data in Table 6 it is reasonable to assume an annual manure production for the horse, on the basis of 1,000 pounds of live weight, of 10 tons, dairy cattle 14 tons, feeder cattle 8.67 tons, feeder sheep 6.05 tons, and hogs 15.25 tons. The figures for feeder cattle and feeder sheep are based upon tests conducted at Ohio. However, 15 per cent has been added to the 7.54-ton production (Table 6) obtained at Ohio, to account for bedding. The 6.05-ton production for feeder sheep includes bedding. The 14-ton production adopted for dairy cattle is based upon an extensive test carried on for a period of nine years at the Rhode Island experiment station. Table 7.— Manure production in the North Platte valley. Production per 1000 pounds - Al m™ Animal live sveight Rcco. vc, ry Produ&lt;:n°n period during recovery Annual ) Daily """"' period Tons Pounds Tons Horse 10.00 54.8 s'/i months 4.52 Dairy cattle 14.00 76.7 5Vj months 6.33 Feeder cattle 8.67 47.5 6 months 4.28 Feeder sheep 6.05 33.15 100 days 1.66 Hors 15.25 83.6 4 months 5.02 Hens 4.25 23.3 6 months 2.12 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">The Value of a Ton of Manure The time during which the animals are kept in corrals or stables where the manure produced may be saved for field application varies to a large degree, particularly in the case of horses and dairy cattle. The feeder animals are kept on feed, where the manure produced is available for field application for a more definite period of time.- In the North Platte valley feeder cattle are kept on feed for a period of about six months, feeder lambs about 100 days, and hogs about four months. It will be assumed in this discussion that the manure from horses and dairy cattle may be saved for field application for a period of 514 months each year. On the basis of these figures the following amounts of manure, available for field application, are produced annually by the various classes of live - stock, on the basis of. 1,000 pounds of live weight: horse 4.52 tons, dairy cattle 633 tons, feeder cattle 4.28 tons, feeder sheep 1.66 tons, hogs 5.02 tons, and hens 2.12 tons. These amounts are liberal estimates of the manure available annually for field application from the various classes of livestock in the North Platte valley. Table B.— Annual value of manure recovered and available for field appli - cation per animal unit of 1,000 pounds live weight} Value Annual value per animal unit (1,000 lbs, live weight) Rotation per Dairy Feedcrj | Feeder | ton Horse cattle | cattle I j sheep | Hobs Hens 21 ...... $4.62 $20.88 $29.24 $19.77 $7.67 $23.19 $9.79 23....... 3.53 15.96 22.34 15.ll! 5.86 17.72 7.48 25 2.32 ' 10.49: 14.69 9.93; 3.85 11.65 4.92 31 4.54 20.52 28.74 19.43 7.54 22.79 9.62 61 ..¦¦¦¦ 3.57 16.14 22.60 15.28; 5.93 17.92 7.57 Mean .... 3.72 .'16.80; 23.52 15.90. 6.17 18.65 7.88 'Annual recovery of manure from the horse unit 4.52 tons, dairy-cattle unit 633, feeder-cattle unit 4.28, feeder-sheep unit 1.66, hog unit 5.02, and hen unit 2.12 tons (Table 7). VALUE OF MANURE PER A^^llvlAL UNIT OF 1,000 POUNDS LIVE WEIGHT The value of manure per animal unit as based upon the per-ton values of manure obtained in the various rotations is shown in Table 8. The niean per-ton value of manure, as determined from the five manured rotations at the Scottsbluff Substation, has been $3.72. This gives a mean value of $16.80 for the manure recovered annually from horses per 1,000 pounds of live weight, $2332 for the manure recovered from dairy cattle, $15.90 for the manure recovered from feeder cattle, $6.17 for the manure recovered from feeder sheep, $18.65 for the manure recovered from hogs, and $7.88 for the manure recovered from hens. Of the various classes of livestock, dairy cattle are the most valuable animals on farms from the standpoint of manure production, and feeder sheep are the least valuable as producers of manure (Table 8)^. .'.'' ' I ¦'""¦.'. </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 318 LIVESTOCK POPULATION NECESSARY TO PRODUCE DIFFERENT QUANTITIES OF MANURE The annual production of recoverable manure from the various classes of livestock has been computed to be 4.52 tons for the horse, 633 tons for dairy cattle, 4.28 tons for feeder cattle, 1.66 tons for feeder sheep, and 5.02 tons for hogs, based upon units of 1,000 pounds live weight. From these data it is possible to compute the population o£ each class of live - stock required to produce manure for different applications per acre on a given area of land. Table 9.— Population of livestock required on an 80-acre farm to produce manure for two-year, three-year, and six-year rotations, and for applica - tions ranging from 1 to 12 tons an acre. . Total Population Manuria! 1 application ™" r "*, Uiry Feeder Feeder „ Rotation cattle cattle 1 sheep b T. per A. Tons No. No. No. No. 1 53 8 12 384 74 2 UJ 21 31 963 JB5 6-year (No. 61) 3 213 34 50 1543 297 4 293 46 68 2123 408 3-year 5 373 50 87 2702 520 6 453 72 106 3282 632 2-year 7 533 84 125 3862 743 8 613 97 143 4442 855 9 693 109 162 5021 966 10 773 122 181 5601 1078 Jl 853 135 199 6181 1190 12 933 147 218 6760 1301 1 In addition to 27 lont produced annually by work animals. It has seemed desirable in this instance to determine the livestock popu - lation required on an 80-acrc farm, exclusive of work animals (assuming that such a farm is stocked with six 1,000-pound work animal units, which would be equivalent to two good-sized teams). On the basis of the data in Table 7, indicating the annual production of recoverable manure from horses, the six work animal units annually produce approximately 27 tons of manure. The population of the major classes of livestock required to produce manure, above the amount produced regularly by work animals, is shown in Table 9, for applications of manure ranging from 1 to 12 tons per acre on an 80-acre farm. It is possible to associate the data in 7'able 9 with the manured rotations under discussions in this paper, and also with a manure experiment with sugar beets carried on for a period of ten years at the Scottsbluff Substation. A 12-ton application of manure applied annually to one crop in a two - year rotation is equivalent to six tons per acre over the whole area; in a three-year rotation it is equivalent to four tons per acre over the whole area; and in a six-year rotation, the equivalent application per acre over </seg>
         <seg id="p015">i The Value of a Ton of Manure ! '¦¦..';¦' •!'.¦¦'¦ ' i ¦"• the whole area amounts to two! tons. The livestock population above i V- work animals required to produce manure for these rotations is shown in I Table 9 on an 80-acre farm. In the case of feeder sheep and hogs the ] total number of animals required is shown rather than in units of 1,000 I. . pound live weight. The smallest number of animals is required for rota - { tion'6l, where manure is applied at the rate of two tons per acre. ? -,-';¦ On an 80-acre farm, 21 dairy cattle, or 31 feeder cattle, or 963 feeder \ sheep, or 185 hogs would be required to produce the manure necessary \ for the operation of this farm on the basis of a cropping program similar j to rotation 61. As indicated in the table, this is the population of live - stock required in addition.to six 1,000 pound work animal units (approxi - | mately two good-sized teams).' For the operation of an 80-acre farm in a manner similar to rotation 31 or 21, considerable numbers of livestock j . are necessary to produce the required manure. In a three-year manured cropping program, where 4 tons of manure per acre are required annually for the whole area, 46 dairy cattle, or 68 feeder catde, or 2,123 feeder sheep, or 408 hogs would be required on an 80-acre farm. For a two-year manured rotation on 80 acres, where the manurial application is equiva - lent to 6 tons per acre on the whole area, 72 dairy cattle, or 106 feeder cattle; or 3,282 feeder sheep, or 632 hogs would be required to produce the ¦.manure. Large numbers of livestock are necessary to produce manure for two-year and three-year manured crop rotation programs. Further - more, very little feed is produced in these rotations to take care of the : large number of animals. Consequently a'rotation program similar to ;'¦ rotation 61, where a smaller number of animals is necessary to produce the required amount of manure and where a considerable amount of feed is produced for the animals, is more practicable in the North Platte valley at the present time than the two-year or three-year manured rotation programs. Manured cropping programs such' as Nos. 21, 23,-25, or 31, as discussed: previously, represent rather intensive farming enterprises. In 5 manured rotations similar to 61 the population of livestock required to produce the necesary two-ton application of manure is within the limits of L-- population which would be set by the quantity of feed produced. In rotation 61 it has been: estimated that approximately enough feed has been produced to feed the animals required for a three-ton application of manure. The yields in this rotation have been maintained satisfactorily over a period of 25 years. Consequently rotations similar to this constitute j a well-balanced land-use program for irrigation farming. • Long rotations similar to 61, in addition to constituting well-balanced landruse programs, from a manure-livestock point of view, have been found to be advantageous in the control of diseases of potatoes. R. W. Gpss and iMitrofan Afanasiev, in studying the influence of crop rotations, on potato scab, rhizoctonia, and fusarium wilt, at the Scottsbluff Sub - station, found the minimum of these diseases in potatoes grown in the longer rotations with alfalfa. B It has also: been found that the per - il *R. W. Goss and M. Afanasiev, The Influence'of Crop.Rotations under Irrigation on Potato Scab-, 1 . Rtiiroctonia, and Fusarium Wilt, Ncbr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 317, 1938. . </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 318 ccntage of cull potatoes (potatoes passing through a 1%-inch screen) is greater in the short rotations. 6 Over a ten-year period the mean per - centage of cull potatoes in rotation 61 has been 6 per cent, and in rotation 60 it has been 7 percent, as compared with 18 per cent in rotation 20, 15 per cent in rotations 24 and 30, 10 per cent in rotation 21, 9 per cent in rotation 25, and 11 per cent in rotation 31. The detailed results from an experiment with varying applications of manure have been published by S. H. Hastings, S. B. Nuckols, and L. Harris. 1 Part of the results of this experiment have been tabulated in Table 10 in order to clarify the present discussion. The experiment has been conducted in two series of five plots each. In series I a total of 30 tons was applied in different amounts throughout the five-year period in each of the five quarter-acre plots, numbered 7 to 11. In series 11, plot Table 10. — Rates of application of manure and mean yields of sugar beets from manure experiment, 1926-35. Manurial treatment s. ycar 10-yr. mean (1926-35) Series \j" tons per acre 1926-30 TT, No. j : j muju v:.M. Value manure 1926 ( 1927 | 1928 1929 ) 1930 mean "elds _ |(| 17 6 6 6 6 6 18.0 15.1 . . 8 12 6 6 6 18.2 14.8 9 18 6 6 18.1 14.2 10 24 6 18.2 14.6 1) 30 17.6 14.7 11 7 6 6 6 6 6 17.0 13.9 S 12 12 12 12 12 19.1 16.1 54.40 9 18 18 18 18 18 20.4 17.2 3.30 10 24 24 24 24 24 20.9 17.8 2.57 11 30 30 30 30 3(1 21.8 19.0 2.58 1 The value of manure per ton in terms of increased yields, using the six-ton application (Plot 7. Series 11) as the base. 7 received manure at the rate of 6 tons per acre for a period of five years; plot 8, 12 tons per acre; plot 9, 18 tons per acre; plot 10, 24 tons per acre; plot 11, 30 tons per acre. This experiment has been conducted for a period of ten years, giving five years' results of the immediate in - fluence of farm manure, and five years' results of residual effect on the various applications. The five-year mean yield for each plot in series I was very close to 18 tons per acre. The ten-year mean yield of these five plots ranged from 14.2 tons to 15.1 tons per acre. In series II the five-year mean yield ranged from 17 tons per acre for the six-ton application, to 21.8 tons for the 30-ton application; while for the ten-year period, including the five years when the manure was applied and five years following, the yields ranged from 13.9 tons on plot 7 to 19 tons on plot 11. « S. H. Hastings. U. S. D. A. Tech. Bui. 512 (cited above). 1 Influence of Farm Manure on Yields and Sucrose of Sugar Beets. U. S. Dept. Acr. Tech. Bui 614. 1938. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">The Value of a Ton of Manure The per-ton value of manure in series II in terms of increased yields, above the yields obtained from the six-ton application, ranged from $2.57 and $258 per ton respectively for the 24- and 30-ton applications to $4.40 per ton' for the 12-ton application. These figures are based on the ten-year mean yields. The results indicate that the greatest value and effectiveness of manure are derived from the lighter applications. In series I the applications of manure have been equivalent to 6 tons per year for a period of'five years. During the ten-year period the manurial applications have been equivalent to three tons per acre annually. In series II the manurial applications for the five-year period ranged from 6 to 30 tons per acre. When considered for the ten-year period the manurial applications would be equivalent to half the amount applied to each plot during the five-year period, or a range of from 3 to 15 tons ' per acre. . ; From data in Table 9 it is possible to determine the livestock popula-' tion required to produce the manure for the; various applications up to 12 tons per acre. A large number of livestock is required to produce manure for applications ranging from 6 to 12. tons per acre or more. The number of livestock required for a 6-ton I application of manure has been enumerated under the discussion of the rotation experiments. For applications above six tons per acre the livestock population required is too great to be considered practicable under ordinary conditions. For the ten-year period the applications of manure have ranged from the equiva - lent of 3 to 15 tons per acre. For the three-ton application, 34 dairy cattle, or 50 feeder cattle, or 1,543 feeder sheep, or 297 hogs would be required to furnish the manure (Table 9). The next application for the ten-year period has been the equivalent of six tons per acre on plot 8, . for which rather large numbers of livestock are required to produce the manurel as has been indicated, j The results from the rotation experiments, and also the manure experi - ment with sugar beets, correlated with the data in Table 9, demonstrate the impracticability of making heavy applications of farm manure annually over the whole area of a given amount of land] The problem of securing feed for the population of livestock required to produce manure for applications above three or four tons per acre jwould be too great for the average; farmer to solve satisfactorily. In most instances the. feed could not be produced on the 80-acre farm itself, but would have to be purchased from the surounding area. This practice tends to concentrate manure on certain farms at the expense of soil productivity on the surrounding areas. The farmer, in selling a given quantity of livestock feed from his farm, whether he realizes it or not is thereby reducing the productivity of his soil. The reduction in soil productivity is represented by the manure obtainable from the feed if it were fed on his farm. From the farmer's stand - point and also from the standpoint of a broad land-use program in an irrigated area, it is probably a grave error |to encourage centralized' maintenance or feeding of livestock. A unit of livestock feed contains a certain-amount of fertilizing value in the form of manure, and it seems desirable to hold this manure on the land where the feed is produced. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 318 The results from the rotation experiments have shown that an appli - cation of manure equivalent to two tons per acre annually on the whole area has been very effective in maintaining satisfactory yields of crops for a period of 25 years. In the manure experiment it has been shown that the greatest value and efficiency of manure is not obtained in the heavy applications. The results obtained from both the rotation experiments and the manure experiment, indicate a high residual value for manure, indicating that heavy annual applications of manure are not necessary to maintain yields at a satisfactory level. In rotation 61, where the two-ton. application of manure has given satisfactory returns, 50 per cent of the land has been devoted to growing alfalfa. This crop has no doubt contributed to the favorable results obtained in this rotation. Of the classes of livestock required to produce manure for various per-acre applications, the data in Tablet 9 indicate that dairy cattle yield the most satisfactory results. Dairy cattle are the most efficient producers of manure. They have a high unit production, and their place on the farm is usually more permanent than that of other classes of livestock. From the standpoint of manure production alone, it would seem advisable to encourage increases in the population of dairy cattle on the irrigated farms of the North Platte valley. The sugar-beet crop responds readily to manurial applications. Consequently sugar-beet growers are confronted with the problem of obtaining manure to maintain their yields at profitable levels. At the present time sugar-beet growers have obtained most of the manure for their crop from feeding cattle and sheep. While these practices are not to be discouraged at all, yet it appears that an increase in the population of dairy cattle on many of these farms would be a valuable source of manure for the sugar-beet crop, and also for other cash crops. PRESENT LIVESTOCK POPULATION AND TOTAL PRODUC - TION OF MANURE IN THE NORTH PLATTE VALLEY The livestock population (1935-36 mean) on Federal Project lands and the manure produced by the various classes of livestock, together with the total manure production by all of the major classes of livestock, are shown in Table 11. The Federal Project lands include the area irrigated under federal irrigation projects and comprise approximately 200,000 acres of land between Guernsey, Wyoming, and Bridgeport, Nebraska. The 1935-36 mean population of this area was 60,417 livestock units of 1,000 pounds live weight. Of this number 13 per cent were horses, 29 per cent dairy cattle, 31 per cent feeder cattle, 24 per cent feeder sheep, 2 per cent hogs, and 1 per cent hens. The 60,417 livestock units produced 257,526 tons of manure. Of this total amount horses produced 14 per cent, dairy cattle 42.5 per cent, feeder cattle 31 per cent, feeder sheep 9 per cent, hogs 3 per cent, and hens a half of 1 per cent. Of the various classes of livestock, dairy cattle were the most efficient producers of manure,.fol - lowed by feeder cattle and horses. The least efficient manure-producing class of livestock was feeder sheep. This class of livestock comprises 24 per cent of the total livestock population, but produced only 9 per cent </seg>
         <seg id="p019">The Value of a Ton of! Manure Table 11.—Mean 1935-36 livestock population and manure production on Federal Irrigated Project lands in. the North Platte valley. 1 Livestock M | T 1 Total population, unite ' ¦ y? anui c ' total manure produced Animal ; gft-g- ;£-«-* bye'ach Units Tons Tons P.ct. Horse... ...7,800 4.52 35,256 14 Dairy cattle 17,300 6.33 109,509 42.5 Feeder cattle...... 18,750 4.28 80,250 31 'Feeder sheep •»..... 14,458 1.66 24,000 9 Hogs B .......... 1393 5.02 6,993 3 Hens 716 .2.12 1,518 0.5 :..-'-. Total 60,417 ... 257,526 100.0 1 Equals area irrigated under Federal Projects or 200,000 acres, which is approximately 50 per cent : of the total irrigated area oE the North Platte valley lying between Guernsey, Wyoming, and Bridge - ; port, Nebraska. ' 3 Data furnished by Mr. C R. Gleasoo, Bureau of Reclamation. •Table 6. 4 Toul population of feeder lambs. 173,500. sTotal population ot hogs 9,750. ' of the total manure because of its relatively low unit production and the short time the animals are kept on feed. PRESENT PRODUCTION OF MANURE AS COMPARED WITH THE AMOUNT NECESSARY TO OPERATE TWO-YEAR, raM SDtYEAR MANURED ROTATIONS j The present population of 1,000-pound livestock units per acre and the manure produced per acre as compared j with the number of units and the amount of manure necessary in two-year, three-year, and six-year rotations are shown in Table 12. Livestock units numbering 60,417 on 200,000 acres of land are equivalent to 030 of a unit per acre, and 257,526 tons of manure produced on 200,000 acres of land represent a per-acre production of 128 tons. On the basis of the present production of manure Table 12.— Present population of livestock units and amount of manure produced per acre, as compared with the number of livestock units and the amount of manure required per acre in] various manured rotations. i d Present P°P"'?^". Increase production , Rotation population required Dccaa Ji. * mman producnon peracre peracre peracre P«acre Units Units P.ct. Tons Tom 2-year ...... 0.30 ' 1.41 370 ! 1.29 6 3-year .. 0.30 0.94 213 1.29 4 6-year ...... 030 0.57 90 129 2 '. ' * A change in the present proportionate population of the various classes of livestock would change I ¦ these percentages, owing to the different, annual quantities of recoverable' manure produced by the y. various classes. ¦'.:.; </seg>
         <seg id="p020">.i", Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 318 I .'..'. | by all of the livestock classes in the North Platte valley, 1.41 units of j livestock per acre would be necessary to produce the manure for a two-year • manured rotation, 0.94 unit for a three-year manured rotation, and 0.57 unit for a six-year manured rotation. An increase of 370 per cent above the present livestock population would be required to furnish manure for two-year rotations, a 213 per cent increase for three-year rotations, and 90 per cent for six-year rotations. The present production of manure is approximately 129 tons per acre as compared with the twp-ton-per-acre production required in six-year manured rotations, the four-ton produc - tion for three-year rotations, and the six-ton production per acre for two - year rotations. - These figures indicate that a considerable increase in the livestock population of the North Platte valley would be in keeping with tie best, farm practices for the maintenance of soil fertility, through the use of manure and consequent high crop yields which are necessary for the success of irrigation agriculture. On the basis of the manure produced by the various classes of livestock and the present population of each class in the North Platte valley, it seems logical to encourage increases in the population of dairy cattle more than any other class of livestock. Dairy cattle lend themselves to a wide distribution, and when once acquired are permancnd) a part of the farm. In order to maintain the fertility of the soils in the North Platte valley, efforts should be exerted by farmers first, to increase the population of livestock on their farms, and consequently the manure supplies, and sec - ond, to adopt methods in handling manure which will preserve the plant - food elements lost by careless handling. According to various investigators from 25 to 50 per cent of the value of farm manure is lost by the ordinary methods of handling. These losses can be cut down considerably by preventing losses from leaching, fermentation, and decomposition. Enough bedding should be used to absorb the liquid portion of the manure. The '..-'' high values shown for manure in the rotation studies should induce farmers to give consideration to the production and conservation of manure on their farms. (SMI </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>