<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks VI. The Influence of the Protein Level of the Ration on the Growth of Chicks</title>
               <date value="18??">February 1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 108 The Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks VI. The Influence of the Protein Level of the Ration on the Growth of Chicks C. W. Ackerson, M. J. Blish, and F. E. Mussehl LINCOLN, NEBRASKA FEBRUARY, 1939 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">SUMMARY 1. Two rations containing 16 and 22 per cent of protein respectively were fed to newly hatched chicks in two series of feeding trials. In one series the lower protein level was secured by diluting the higher with 30 parts of starch so that the amount but not the quality of the protein was changed. In the other series the amount and quality of the protein both varied since the two rations were mixed by using different proportions of the base and concentrate to yield the 16 and 22 per cent levels in the finished rations. 2. Comparisons were made of chicks which had consumed equal amounts of feed during the experiment. i. The composition of the chicks at the end of the six weeks' feeding trials was determined and the composition of the gains calculated. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks VI. The Influence of the Protein Level of the Ration ; on the Growth of Chicks C. W. ACKERSON, M. J. BLISH^ AND F. E. MUSSEHL &gt;¦. .. Earlier papers in this series were concerned with rations varying in the ;. source o£ the protein concentrates. Comparisons were made between rations containing different animal and vegetable protein concentrates, or com - i binations of either or both. The protein level was approximately 20 per j cent, as that amount is used extensively in chick growing rations. This I paper reports studies wherein the utilization of food elements was studied | at two different levels of protein in the ration. ; I St. John, Carver, Helphrey, Miller, and Cassel (1) varied the protein I level from 11.5 to 17.2 per cent by increasing the amount of dry skim I milk in the ration from Bto 24 per cent. They concluded that greater | growth was obtained by increasing the protein level for the first 12 weeks | but at a higher cost. St. John, Carver, Johnson, and Brazie (2) increased \ the fish meal supplement of their rations so that they carried 13, 17, and 21 per. cent of protein respectively, and showed that the percentage of pro - ] tein in the ration prior to 10 weeks had little influence on the efficiency of ; protein utilization after that age. Milne (3) compared lots fed 11, 19, 30, ;; and 38 per cent of protein and concluded that economy of gains was high - ¦ est in the lot fed 19 per cent. Swift, Black, Voris, and Funk (4) varied $ the protein level from 12 to 25 percent by changing the proportion of i protein concentrate and studied the retention of nitrogen during four a successive 28-day periods. They found that a lot fed at a level of 15 per | cent protein utilized nitrogen more efficiently, but did not make as rapid I or efficient growth as did the other lots. ¦'.-:. ;:'; i . Other reports on the subject of the optimum protein level for growth 1 and egg production are to be found in the literature, in which conclusions f- are drawn from growth data or number of eggs produced. In.such studies I the protein levels were adjusted by varying either the kind or proportion I of the concentrate. That this arrangement involved changes in protein as ¦j well as other components was noted by Swift and co-workers (4) but they ? felt that their rations were distinguished by their protein contents. I. In Nebraska Ration 8S 1 the protein content is about 20 per cent, of •; which about 57 per cent comes from the base and the remainder from the j concentrate portion of the ration. If the proportion of base and concen - | trate were changed from 85 and 15 (as in 8S) to 95 parts of base and sof | concentrate, the protein content of the complete ration would be about I 15 per cent, of which about 82 per cent would come from the base and / the remainder from the concentrate. It is evident that the quality as well j 'Nebraska 8S it mixed at follows: Yellow cornmcal 31, thorn 20, bran 10, pulverized cats 10, L&gt; alfalfa meal 10, neat meal 5, fiih meal 5, soybean meal 5, calcium carbonate 2, sodium chloride I, and ecu) liver oil 1. . .-.'-..':-¦'¦ . . V. . I :¦'.'¦ '•¦ ' ¦¦¦ ' ' ¦.. ¦¦ ¦• . ¦'.'¦_• ' ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 108 as the quantity of the protein in the two rations at the two levels has been altered to a considerable extent. There are two ways in which the protein level can be increased without changing the quality of the protein. One is to have all the protein derived trom a single source so that when more of the concentrate is added there is no change in the source of protein. Such a ration may be seriously un - balanced as it is well established that a variety of proteins promote better growth. The other option is to mix a ration containing a high amount of protein and dilute it with a non-protein material such as starch to the desired level. PREPARATION OF THE RATIONS The purpose of the experiment reported in this paper was to compare the utilization of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus from rations in which the protein levels were varied first by diluting a high-protein ration with starch, and second by increasing the proportion of protein concentrate in the ration. The protein levels chosen were 16 and 22 per cent. The in - gredients of the rations were the same as those used in mixing the Ne - braska No. 8S ration but the amounts of each were varied in order to obtain the desired protein content in the finished rations. The feeding was carried out in two series with two lots in each series. The rations were designated as 16, and 22, in the first, and as 16 2 and 22 2 in the second scries, /n the first series the amount of yellow cornmeal in the Nebraska 8S ration was reduced by 6 per cent so that the amounts of meat meal, lish meal, and soybean meal could each be increased by 2 per cent to in - crease the protein level of the finished ration to 22 per cent. This ration was called 22,. Ration 16, was prepared by mixing 70 parts of ration 22 t and id parts of cornstarch. Mixed in this manner the quantity of protein was reduced but the quality remained unchanged. The dilution with starch reduced the ash, calcium, phosphorus, fat, and fiber and increased the nitrogen free extract of the 16 t ration as compared to the 22 lf so that the change in protein level was not the only change produced. The cal - cium and phosphorus content of the 16, ration is well above the minimum requirements for growth as summarized by Branion (5). With respect to the calorific values the increase in carbohydrate in the 16 1 ration is very nearly counterbalanced by the decrease in protein and fat, so that the difference in energy values of the two rations is slight. Analysis of the base and concentrate showed that 52 per cent of the protein in each ration came from the concentrate and 48 per cent from the base. In the second series a quantity of each of the base and concentrate of. Nebraska 8S was prepared, on which analysis showed that the former had 15.3 and the latter 55.2 per cent protein. Therefore the base and concen - trate were mixed in the proportion of 93.4 to 6.6 to form ration 16 2 and 79.1 to 20.9 to form ration 22 2 . In the 16 2 ration 77 per cent of the protein was derived from the base while in ration 22 2 47 per cent came from the base, from which it is apparent that the quality as well as the quantity of protein is different. This adjustment of the proportions of base and con- </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Utilization of Food Elements by Chicks centrate to obtain the desired protein levels resulted in a difference of 5 per cent in the amount of protein, and a like difference in the nitrogen - free extract, in the two rations. At the same time minor changes occurred in the calcium and phosphorus content, but both remained well above the minimum levels with a ratio of calcium to phosphorus of two to one. The rations for each series were mixed as shown below. After mixing, the rations were pelleted by means of a 5/32-inch die. The composition of the rations after pelleting is given in Table 1. The experimental variable, with - in the limitations as described above, is considered to be the difference in protein content of the two rations in each series. ¦ ¦¦ :[' :.':-';¦ ¦ ..; '.'•- Rations .' . Ingredients ' .;.-. .¦¦: I ¦;- . 16i 22i 16 2 I 22 2 '.¦'¦ . ', • '..¦".;'¦". Lbs. Us. Lbs. Lbs. Yellow c0rnmca1..........:............... igj 26' 34.46 29.19 Shorts ....,...,..........;.. ; 14.0 20 22.24 18.84 Bran 7.0 10 11.12 9.42 Pulvcnzcd..oaß:.-.;,.,...,-.:¦.:•...: ....:..... 7.0 10 11.12 9.42 Alfalfa meal:. 7.0 10 1112 942 Meat mea1....... ...?.....,.;... 4.9 7 2.20 ' 6.97 Flsh meal .:....,...:.,.;........... :4.9 7 2.20 :\ 6.97 Soybean mea1............. 4.9 7 2.20 . 6.97 Cormtarch. .; ; .. 30.0 0 0.00 0.00 Calcium carbonate .........;... 1.4 2 2.22 1.88 Sodium ch10ride............... .......... 0.7 1 1.11 0!94 EXPERIMENTAL FEEDING The chicks used in the first series were heavy-breed chicks. Most of them were White Rocks, with a few Barred Rocks and Rhode Island Reds. Their average initial weight was 40 grams for each lot, with a range from 36 to 45 grams. The plan for feeding the chicks was the same as that used in previous work at this Station; that is, all chicks of both lots were to receive the same amount of feed daily. However, after two weeks of feed - ing it became apparent that the majority of the chicks of the lot fed Ration 16, could not mainuin the schedule followed by the Ration 22 t lot or previous lots. Therefore only such chicks as could maintain the schedule were carried along, with the result that at the conclusion of the experiment there were eight males left in the 16 t lot out of the twenty chicks started. The twenty chicks started in the 22j lot all finished the experiment. In earlier feeding trials with the protein level the same in both lots it was noted that a uniform daily intake could be maintained without difficulty until a differential response due either to the rations or to sex became manifest. At that time the daily intake had to be adjusted to that of the slower eating females. In work of this nature the effect of sex on the daily intake of feed is noticeable at about the fifth week. In previous work the tendency of the males to consume more feed did not prevent the </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 108 execution of the plan to keep all chicks at the same daily intake of feed. In this instance, however, the females of Lot 16, were unable to keep up with cither the males of their lot or the chicks of Lot 22 2 , and hence they were not retained for the final comparison. In addition it was necessary to re - strict the intake of the chicks of Lot 22! to that of Lot 16 t because of food refusals by the latter. Table I.— Analyses of the rations. Rations Ingredients 16i 22t 16 2 22 2 Water (p.ct.) 12.9 127 8~4 SA~ ¦A t sh "¦•") 6.2 8.5 7.4 8.2 Nitrogen (/&gt;.&lt;¦/.) 2.56 3.50 2.69 352 Calcium (p.ct.) 1.24 i. 72 U9 1-68 Phosphorus (p.ct.) 0.68 0.92 0.67 0 88 Crude fat (p.ct.) 2.7 4.0 4.0 4 2 Crude fiber (p.ct.) 4.9 7.2 7.6 6 'g Protein (p.ct.) 16.0 21.9 16.8 22 0 N-frce extract (p.ct.) 57.3 457 55 .g 5Q 4 Rjtl" C 3* 1.82 1.87 2.07 1.91 The manner of feeding was the same as that used in earlier work (6). The chicks of each lot were kept in separate brooders which were elec - trically heated. The minimum temperature of the room in which they were housed was maintained above 70° F. Cod-liver oil was fed individually by burette at a 0.5 per cent level. The chicks of Lot 22 t and the survivors of Lot 16, each consumed 811 grams of dry matter. The feeding was started December 15 and continued to January 26, or a period of six weeks. At the end of the period the chicks were killed by ether anesthesia and the contents of the digestive tract removed. Live weight, net body weight, and the sex of each chick were determined at this time. The analytical pro - cedure outlined in a previous paper (6), was used, save that each chick was analyzed separately for nitrogen, calcium, phosphorus, and fat. The chicks used in the second series were White Leghorns chosen in a weight range of 37 to 39 grams, with an average weight of 38. With the rations mixed as described above it was possible to keep all the chicks of the high-protein lot and the males ot the low-protein lot on the same feed - ing schedule. The females of Lot 16 2 lagged behind in feed intake towards the last so in order to have them consume the same amount of feed as the rest of the chicks in the experiment they were fed three days longer. Twenty-one chicks were started in each lot. One chick of Lot 22 2 and two of Lot 16 2 were discarded during the experiment because of failure to maintain the feeding schedule. The care and management of these lots were the same as that accorded the lots of the first series, and the analyti - cal work was handled in the same manner. They were fed over a six - weeks period from April 12 to May 25. Initial, interval, final live and net weights were recorded. Table 2 gives the mean net weights and their </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Utilization of Food Elements by Chicks standard errors for the males and females of both lots in each series. Table 3 shows that there were highly significant differences between the mean weights of the chicks at the two levels of protein fed. DISCUSSION The data derived from the two series of experiments are presented in Tables 2, 3, 4 and 5. From an inspection of Tables 2 and 3 it is evident that the rate of growth was influenced by the protein levels of the rations fed. In each series there were highly significant differences between the final net weights of the chicks on the two levels with the chicks on the 22 per cent rations attaining slightly more than 10 per cent greater growth i Table 2.—Mean net weights 1 at slaughter and their standard errors. | Lot . Males Females 1 , ; r — - .'¦ ¦— ——— -—- 1 ¦ ¦ ¦¦'¦ ¦ : -:- :¦¦¦ ¦.¦¦¦;: .'.. .- «&gt; . . -•.: . g. i 16i... ........:..:........;. 334.5+5.6 ......... 22i. ; .............,....;. 382.5+4.4 376.4+3.4 ! 162...... 338.6±3.5 307.6+5.8 222. ¦:..¦¦¦¦¦ 381.6+3.7 361.6+5.3 IThe hb weight ii the weight of the chick after the removal of the contenti of the digestive tract. Table 3.— Analysis of the net body weights. Source of variation ..-' ' d/£ Sum of squares Variance • MALES OF LOT 16l COMPARED WITH MALES OF LOT 221.' ':.. ' 5ubc1a55e5;:.,.,,........;,.....;......; r 11,428.58 11,428.58 ! Error 19 . 4,785.23 251.86 Total .........................;...... 20 16.213.81 . ..... j F=45.38, with a one per cent point of: 8.18. ! . ... MALES OP LOT 162 COMPARED WITH MALES OF LOT 222. Subclasses I 7,85637 7,856.37 ] Error ....,.;...;..v.................. 15 . 1,676.10 111.73 j T0ta1.,.......; 16 . 9,532.47 I F=70.30, with a one per cent point of 8.68. .; i. FEMALES OF LOT 162 COMPARED WITH FEMALES OF LOT 222. ] Subclasses ............,..;............ 1 .15,895.64 15,895.64 I Error ................;......,......-. 20 6,855.32 342.77 ; Total .:..................:,..;....,.. 21 223056 J¦¦ ¦ F=46.37, with a one per cent point of 8.10. ' I on the same dry-matter intake. This difference was observed in both series I and since the two levels were prepared so that the difference in the rations '; in the first series would be quantitative and in the second series qualitative j with respect to the protein, it is justifiable to conclude that the quantity of I protein was the governing factor. The quality of the protein in the 16. j ration was better than that in the 161 ration but no better growth response ! was secured with the former. Tables 4 and 5 show that there were no sig - nificant differences in the calcium and phosphorus contents of the chicks or </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 108 gains made by them. On the lower protein level the males had a slightly lower nitrogen content at slaughter. The percentage retention of nitrogen was greater in the case of the 16 per cent level than in the 22 per cent lots. In the first series the lower content of the ration with respect to calcium ¦ mm?'*' -\&amp;S*- r ?vS£aLM Fie. I.—Representative chicks of Lot 16! (left) and 22i (right), showing the difference in growth and appearance of chicks on the two rations. ¦ -i^B X? * • ' ¦¦¦ »i^H \ F^^^l - 'I'll 4'fa*''^^! ' ' Fie. 2.—Chicks of Lot 16i showing the uniformity of the symptoms exhibited by this lot. and phosphorus at the 16 per cent level caused a greater percentage of retention of these elements than in the 22 per cent lot. The higher protein levels resulted in a greater rate of gain. </seg>
         <seg id="p009">s Utilization of Food Elements by Chicks j' ' • ¦ ' '¦¦'¦¦'¦' .'"'•. | In the second series the males on the 16 per cent level required 286 | pounds of air-dry feed, and the males on the 22 per cent level needed 250 | pounds, while the females needed 320 and 267 pounds, respectively, to pro - duce 100 pounds of gain. Thus the males on the lower level required 15 per cent and the females 20 per cent more feed to produce a like amount of gain, with the rations made up as shown above. It can be shown that I to bring the gain of the lower level lot to that of the higher would require I four more days of feeding, which must be figured in the cost along with j the cost of the respective rations. | / Regardless of the method of preparation of the ration, the lower-protein ¦ lot in each series made the same relative gains in comparison with the I higher-protein lots. However, there was a distinct difference in the appear- I) ance of the chicks fed a 16* percent protein ration prepared in one case : by dilution of a 22 per cent ration with 30 parts of starch, and in the other by varying the proportions of base and concentrate. ; The chicks of Lot 16i showed areas devoid of feathers, due in part to : feather pulling tendencies and also to a deficiency in feather growth. Dur - ; ing the latter third of the experimental period the chicks of Lot 16., ex - | hibited marked coprophagic habits. While most of the droppings passed i readily through the half-inch-mesh false bottom any residues were eagerly I sought. Like symptoms were not exhibited by the chicks of Lot 22i nor i by either lot of the second series. Since the appearance of these symptoms ; was restricted to Lot 16i the cause must be sought in either the starch I itself or in the reduction in the amount of an essential factor in the 22, I ration when it was diluted with 30 per cent starch. If an essential factor | was concerned it was present in sufficient amounts in the 22 X ration and | 70 per cent of that amount was present in ration 16^ On the other hand ':¦ the presence of 30 parts of starch in the latter ration may result in the symptoms noted. The contrast in appearance of the chicks of the two lots is shown in Figure 1, and the uniformity of the symptoms in Lot 16! by I Figure 2. .. ". .-;-. ¦.'' &#132;_,"'; ';¦..¦ ¦ *'¦ -.[ ¦ ...;.: ¦ " ¦¦.;¦¦ .;: I ¦ - * -: '¦:.•¦•.¦ .-' .:'""¦¦.. : ¦- .:..•; ¦¦¦'•¦.¦¦¦•"¦ .¦¦¦'' ' ' -;. ¦ : </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 108 Table 4. — Summary of growth and analytical data on chic\s of first series. In, 22* Males Males j Females Number of chicks 8 13 7 Net weight (g.) 334 383 376 Gain in weight (g.) 296 342 337 Dr&gt; matter fed (g.) 811 811 811 Rate of gain (p.ct.) 36.4 42.2 41.6 Gain per gram nitrogen Icii (g.) 12.4 10.5 10.4 Nitrogen in chick (p.ct.) 3.22 3.40 3.40 Calcium in chick {p.ct.) 0.96 0.90 0.89 Phosphorus in chick (pxt.) 0.66 0.62 0.62 Ratio, Ca-.P in chick 1.45 1.45 1.45 Nitrogen in gain (pxt.) 3.31 3.53 3.51 Calcium in gain (pxt.) 1.04 0.96 0.95 Phosphorus in gain (pxt.) 0.71 0.67 0.66 Ratio, Ca-.P in gain 1.44 1.45 1.45 F.thcr extract (p.ct.) 6.6 4.2 4.7 Nitrogen intake (g.) 23.82 32.53 32.53 Nitrogen in gain (g.) 9.80 12.09 11.85 Nitrogen retained (pxt.) 41.2 37.2 36A Calcium intake (g.) 11.49 15.97 15.97 Calcium in gain (g.) 3.05 3.30 3.20 Calcium retained (pxt.) 26.5 20.7 20.0 Phosphorus intake (g.) 6.32 8.56 8.56 Phosphorus in gain (g.) 2.09 2.28 2.21 Phosphorus retained (pxt.) 33.0 26.6 25.8 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">. Utilization of Fooifc Elements by Chicks Table s.—Summary of growth and analytical data on chicks of second . series. r- ' ¦ " :; '¦ 16 2 22 2 Item • : : -— ¦' • ¦ ' ¦ ' ¦•'. Males Females Males || Females Number of chick 5................. 9 10 8 12 Net weight:(g.) 339 308 382 362 Gain in weight (g.)... ;..... 301 270 344 . 323 Dry matter feel (g.)...:............ 793 794 787 793 Rate of gain (p.ct.)...... 38.0 3-1.0 43.7 40.7 Gain per gram nitrogen fed (g.) 12.9 11.6 11.3 10.6 Nitrogen in chick (p.ct.). 3.24 3.38 3.38 3.40 Calcium in chick (p.rt.).;...... 1.., 0.88 0.90 0.94, 0.92 Phosphorus in chick (p.r/.).......:.. 0.61 0.63 0.64 0.64 Ratio, Ca:P in chick.:.............. 1.44 .1.43 1.48 1.45 Nitrogen in gain (p.ct.)... &#132;.'..:'..'.:.'¦. 3.33 3.50 3.48 3.52 Calcium in gain (p.rt.).. .;..... 0.94 0.97 J.OO 0.99 Phosphorus in gain (p.ct.): .' .... 0.65 0.68 0.67 • 0.68 Ratio, Ca:Pin gain................. 1.44 1.44 1.48 1.45 Ether extract (p.rt.) 5.0 5,0 3.9 5.3 Nitrogen intake (if.)......."......... 23.27 23.31 30.22 30.44 Nitrogen in gain (g.)..... 10.02 9.46 11.97 11.36 Nitrogen retained (p.ct.):,. 43.1 40.6 39.6 373 Calcium intake (g.)..-. 11.98 12.00 14.44 14.55 Calcium in gain {g.).. :.......'.;... 2.83 2.63 3.45 3.19 Calcium retained (p.rt.)............ 23.6 215 235 215 Phosphorus intake (g.)....,.., 5.77 ' 5.78 7.57 7.62 Phosphorus in gain (g.)....... 1.96 1.83 2.33 2.20 Phosphorus retained \p.ct.) 34.0 31.7 30.8 285* CONCLUSIONS 1. In two series of experiments chicks fed rations containing 22 per cent of protein made greater gains on the same dry matter intake over the same period of time than chicks fed rations carrying 16 per cent of protein. 2. The ratio of gain in weight to nitrogen fed was greater in the chicks fed 16 per cent than in the 22 per cent protein lots. i 3. The chicks on the 16 per cent protein rations retained it higher per - centage of the nitrogen fed, but the percentage of nitrogen in the gain was not as high as that in the chicks fed rations containing.22 per cent of pro - tein. ¦. .'.'•;:" ;;•-..'¦ ..; . ;; •¦:.: '.' 4. The slight differences in the percentage retentions of calcium arid phosphorus can be ascribed to the differences in the percentage of those elements occurring in the rations as mixed. ; &#132; 5. The dilution of a complete ration with 30 parts of starch to yield a 16 per cent ration resulted in uniform and definite evidence of depraved appetite including feather pulling and coprophagy. In addition the chicks fed the 16 1 ration were uniformly poorly feathered and had large nude areas. ¦: • / v ¦"'. •; . •'.'. ' .. ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 108 | f Table 4. — Summary of growth and analytical data on chicly of first series. \ ifo 22 ' ! Item Males Males | Females i Number of chicks 8 13 7 Net weight (g.) 334 383 376 1 Gain in weight (g.) 296 342 337 j Dr&gt; matter fed (g.) 811 811 811 Rate of gain (p.ct.) 36.4 42.2 41.6 Gain per gram nitrogen fed (g.) 12.4 10.5 10.4 Nitrogen in chick (p.cl.) 3.22 3.40 3.40 Calcium in chick (p.ct.) 0.96 0.90 0.89 Phosphorus in chick (p.ct.) 0.66 0.62 0.62 Ratio, Ca:P in chick 1.45 1.45 1.45 Nitrogen in gain (p.ct.) 3.31 3.53 3.51 Calcium in gain (p.ct.) 1.04 0.96 0.95 Phosphorus in gain (p.ct.) 0.71 0.67 0.66 Ratio, Ca:P in gain 1.44 1.45 1.45 Ether extract (p.cl.) 6-6 4.2 4.7 Nitrogen intake (g.) ' ilii E53 32.53 Nitrogen in gain (g.) 9.80 12.09 11.85 Nitrogen retained (p.ct.) 41.2 37£ 36.4 Calcium intake (g.) IM9 1557 15.97 Calcium in gain (g.) 3.05 3.30 3.20 Calcium retained (p.cl.) 26.5 20.7 20.0 Phosphorus intake (g.) 6-32 8.56 8.56 Phosphorus in gain (g.) 2.09 2.28 2.21 Phosphorus retained (p.ct.) 33.0 26.6 25.8 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Utilization of Food Elements by Chicks Table s.— Summary of growth and analytical data on chicks of second series. . . Item — : rr= Males Females Males || Females Number of chick 5 ........:,'..'..;;'. 9 10 8 12 Net weight (f.)---. ......... 339 '308 382 362 Gain in weight (g.)~. ............... 301 270 34") 323 Do- matter fed (g.)..... ..;,.. 793. 79-1 787 793 Rate of gain (p.ct.) 38.0 34.0 43.7 40.7 Gain per gram nitrogen fed (g.)...... 12.9 11.6 11.3 10.6 Nitrogen in chick (p.tf.) 3.2-t : 3.38 3.38 3.40 Calcium in chick (p.rt.)...........: 0.88 0.90 0.94 0.92 Phosphorus in chick {p.ct.) . 0.61 0.63 0.64 0.64 Ratio, Ca:P in chick............... 1.44 1.43 1.48 1.45 Nitrogen in gain (p.rt.)............; .3.33 3.50 3.48 3.52 Calcium in gain (p.rt.)............. 0.94 0.97 ¦ 1.00 0.99 Phosphorus in gain '{fix!.)....... ;....; 0.65 : 0.68 0.67 0.68. Ratio, Ca:P in gain................. 1.44 1.44 V 1.48 1.45 Ether extract (p.c/.)................. 5.0 5.0 j 3.9 5.3 Nitrogen intake' (g.)........'. ...;... 23.27 23.31 30.22 30.44 Nitrogen in gain (g.) :...... 10.02. 9.46 11.97 11.36 Nitrogen retained (p.rt.).........:.. 4J.1 40.6 39.6 373 Calcium intake («.)........... 11.98 . 12.00 14.44 14.55 Calcium in gain (g.) 2.83 2.63 3.45 . 3.19 Calcium retained (p.ct.)........... ... 23.6 215 23.9 2\S '. Phosphorus intake (g.)............. 5.77 5.78 7.57 7.62 Phosphorus in gain (?.). 1.96 1.83 233 2.20 Phosphorus retained (p.rt.) ¦.¦¦¦¦...¦ 34.0 31.7 30.8 28i&gt; CONCLUSIONS 1. In two series of experiments chicks fed rations containing 22 per cent of protein made greater gains on the same dry matter intake over the same period of time than chicks fed rations carrying 16 per cent of protein. 2. The ratio of gain in weight to nitrogen fed was greater in the chicks fed 16 per cent than, in the 22 per cent protein lots. 3. The chicks or^ the 16 per cent protein rations retained a higher per - centage of the nitrogen fed, but the percentage of nitrogen in the gain, was not as high as that in the chicks fed rations containing 22 per cent of pro - tein. ."¦'; ' '.V . ¦•'. .-. -. ; '¦:'. -.'I '¦;¦¦' •- .;. 4. The slight differences in the percentage retentions of calcium and phosphorus can be ascribed to the differences in the percentage of those elements occurring in the rations as mixed. 5. The dilution of a complete ration with 30 parts of starch to yield a 16 per cent ration resulted in uniform and definite evidence of depraved appetite including feather pulling and coprophagy. In addition the chicks fed the 16j ration were uniformly poorly feathered and had large nude areas.' - . ¦ . . - . •" . . ' ' ¦¦' :': ¦ ¦¦ ¦¦''--¦' ' '' ;- .. -¦'' ¦' ' </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Aorl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 108 LITERATURE CITED 1. St. loiin. I. L.. Carver. |. S.. Helpiirey. |. P.. Miller, W., and Cassel, L. W. I'UU. Poultry Sci. 'h.lUhii. 2. St. Johv. ). L., Carver. |. S.. lohxson. 0.. and Hra7.il, D. I'W. sth Cnnj;. Momlialc dc Pnllicnltura Atti 2:567-74. i. Milnf. Helkx ]. \'&gt;il. Sci. Ajjr. \2-.MH-2l). -I. Swift. R. W.. Hlack. A.. Voris. L.. and Flvk. E. M. I9JJ. Poultry Sci. 10:2««-')«. 5. Bramon. H. D. 1938. Sci. Aj:r. l»:217-76. (&gt;. AI'KLRSON. C. W.. 111.ISM. M. J.. ASD MtSStHL. F. K. I'MX. Mcbr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Rts. Bui. 100. [2JSM] </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>