<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00090.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0090.0006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Third Annual Report Nebraska Unemployment Comensation Divison 1939</title>
               <date value="18??">February 1, 1940</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEIRASKA R. L. COCHRAN. Cov*mcr THIRD ANNUAL REPORT NEBRASKA UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION DIVISION 1939 _ m TeJp -______r_^ DEPARTMENT OF LABOR NEiHASKA UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION DIVISION STAT. CAPITOL - - - - UNCCM-tl fahrmmrf\,\94Ai </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Office of the Commissioner of Labor Lincoln, Nebraska February 1,1940 Honorable R. L. Cochran Governor of Nebraska ) Lincoln, Nebraska j Dear Sir: - \ '¦• Incompliance With Section 48-711 (a), Comp. Stat, Supp. 1939, I herewith submit the third annual report of the Un - employment Compensation Division covering the calendar year of 1939. • This report was compiled by the Director and members of the staff of the Unemployment Compensation Division. Very truly yours, .-• -;.:::- :V.;B. Kinney ',' Commissioner of Labor 3 </seg>
         <seg id="p004">STATE OFFICIALS R. L. Cochran Governor V. B. Kinney Commissioner of Labor R. T. Malone Director, Unemployment Compensation Division State Advisory Council: Representing Industry: Donald Bridge, Norfolk, Nebraska, Norfolk Cereal and Flour Mill. Wilton Van Sickle, Lincoln, Nebraska, President of Van Sickle Glass &amp; Paint Company. Representing Labor: 0. M. Olsen, Omaha, Nebraska, Member of Plumbers' Union. Attorney for Omaha Central Labor Union. L. 0. Schon, Lincoln, Nebraska, Electrical Contractor, Member of Brotherhood of Electrical Workers. Representing the Public: Hobart Blackledge, Chairman, Kearney, Nebraska, At - torney at Law. Earl Marvin, Beatrice, Nebraska, Editor, Beatrice Sun. Dr. Frederick W. Clayton, Omaha, Nebraska, Pastor of All Saints Episcopal Church. Advisory Committee on Merit Examinations: Charles C. Hellmers, Chairman, District Manager of lowa-Nebraska Light and Power Company, Lincoln, Nebraska. E. W. Augustine, President, Augustine Company, Grand Island, Nebraska. William D. Lane, President, Eggerss-O'Flyng Company, Omaha, Nebraska. Supervisor of Merit Examinations: Dr. E. Glenn Callen, Nebraska Wesleyan University, Lincoln, Nebraska. 4 </seg>
         <seg id="p005">j DIRECTOR'S STATEMENT The successful operation of an unemployment compensa - tion program, (designed on the basis of a federal-state relation - ship, requires! genuine cooperation not only on the part of state and federal representatives, but also on the part of em - ployers and wprkers. This requirement of cooperative effort and its importance was only too apparent during 1939 when benefit payments were first made under the Nebraska Law. The payment of benefits for loss of wages to thousands of Ne - braska workers for the first time required the cooperation of labor, industry and the Federal and State officials. The Division recognizes and appreciates the contributions made during the year by the nonpaid members of the Advisory Council in connection with the amendments to the Law and the formulation of policies and plans for establishing variable employer contribution rates. The Division also appreciates the work of Dr. Lester B. Orheld, University of Nebraska, Dr. L. A. Cusack, Creighton University, and Dr. E. Glenn Callen, Nebraska Wesleyan University, who assisted the Advisory Council without pay as technical consultants. , The following sections of this report contain an account of the activities of the Unemployment Compensation Division during the year in the payment of benefits and the collection of contributions, including an account of the financial status of and changes in the Fund. An explanation of the important legislative modifications made by the 1939 regular session of the Legislature is also included in the report. Since individual employer experience rating will become effective for the first time during 1940, considerable attention was given to this problem during the year in developing procedures and formu - lating policies. The problems involved in this respect are given detailed attention in this report. A characteristically important problem in the field of state unemployment compensation administration is that deal- 5 </seg>
         <seg id="p006">ing with differences in the taxing measures of the federal and state laws, and the conformity of the state law to the federal requirements. Action by the 1939 Congress in amending the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code will re - quire legislative modification of the Nebraska Law if con - formity and approval are to be secured. These changes are pointed out in the respective sections of the report. . With the beginning of benefit operations and experience rating, more and more information and data are becoming available for study and research in connection with improving and making more effective the system of unemployment com - pensation in Nebraska. Due to the absence of information and experience, the original Nebraska Law and nearly all the state laws were based substantially on the draft bills pre - pared by the Committee on Economic Security and the Social Security Board. With the accumulation of actual experience on the state level, changes and modifications can be suggested which will achieve more effectively the purpose and intent of this type of legislation. Respectfully submitted, R. T. Malone, Director Unemployment Compensation Division 6 </seg>
         <seg id="p007">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page I. FINANCIAL STATUS AND ACTIVITY OF THE FUND.. 1 - 8 Total Fund •• 1 Transfer of Railroad Fund 5.......................... 3 Pooled Account... j.-.™ 4 Fund Adequacy............. ........:..... 6 11. COST OF ADMINISTRATION 9-14 . Administrative Expenses...: 9 Amendments .....: 14 til. BENEFIT PAYMENTS 15-81 Amount of Benefits Paid 15 Weeks Compensated and Checks Written.... ....:. 17 Multi-State Payments and C1aim5....... 20 Initial Claims, Determinations and Redeterminations.......... 20 Continued C1aim5........ 25 Size Distribution of Amounts of Weekly Payment 5......:....... 26 Benefit Payment Lag;............................... 27 Disqualifications —.....— 29 Appeals ;.........:........... . 30 Benefit Duration ........:......... ..: 31 IV. CONTRIBUTIONS AND C0VERAGE.......... 33-37 Collections of Contributions and Interest.... 33 Number of Employers, iWage Items and Workers 36 wage 5.......:...... .......L............... ......:.....:..........„. :.... 37 V. 1939 AMENDMENTS ToJtHE LAW............ 38-46 ¦" Legislative Bills Affecting Unemployment Compensation.... 39 Explanation of Legislative Bill No. 447.:.............. ..:....;... 40 . Changes in the Benefit Formula 40 Disqualifications L....... ..::. 41 Railroad Coverage j.... ........:...................... 43 Partial 8enefite.........!...........................:..........;......,.... 43 Miscellaneous Changes .... . 43 Explanation of Legislative Bill No. 44.....:..:................. 44 :.'¦ Disposition of Funds According to Legislative Bill No. 44 45 VI. EXPERIENCE RATING.!:.. ..................:.... „„„.........:.... 47-56 Statutory Standards...... 1...... 47 1940 Variable Rate P1an......... .. . 49 Firms and Pay Roll in Various Rate Gr0up5....... 50 1940 Contribution Yie1d.............................;..........:. 52 I Industry and Size-of-Firm Experience........ 53 Determination of Future Rates 55 Required Legislative Amendments...... 56 VII. SUPPLEMENT ti^i ....:......... ........ 57-59 Legislative Bill No. 5, 1940 Special Session.... ;................ 57 Joint Regulations for Selection of Personnel on Merit Basis 59 APPENDIX A.......:...:......:.:.1.... 60 APPENDIX 8..... .....:........„;...... .....I :.............. 63 7 </seg>
         <seg id="p008"/>
         <seg id="p009">FINANCIAL STATUS AND ACTIVITY OF THE FUND Total Fund The Unemployment Compensation Fund at the close of the calendar year 1939, excluding funds set aside for transfer to the Railroad Retirement Board, stood at $7.86 million. The amount of the reserve for Railroad Unemployment Insurance settlement, including the preliminary and liquidating amounts and 1936 claims for credit, was $1.98 million. The balance sheet for the Fund at the close of the year is shown in Ap - pendix A. The moneys of the Fund are distributed between the Unemployment Trust Fund in the United States Treasury and the Unemployment Compensation Fund Clearing Account and the Unemployment Compensation Benefit Payment Ac - count in the Nebraska State Treasury. All collections upon receipt are credited to the clearing account. By Statute they are then required to be deposited in the United States Treas - ury, from which they are transferred to the benefit payment account in the State Treasury as required. The clearing ac - count is used for depositing all collections for subsequent de - posit in the United States Treasury Unemployment Trust Fund. At the close of 1939, slightly less than ten thousand dollars was in the clearing account. The benefit payment ac - count is used to pay benefit obligations, the funds for which are requisitioned from the United States Treasury Unemploy - ment Trust Fund. Approximately twenty-six thousand dol - lars was credited to this account at the close of the year. In the case of both the clearing and benefit payment accounts, only minimum balances, consistent with the particular require - ments, are maintained. All collections from employers, exclusive of penalty in - terest, are credited to the individual reserves. Trust Fund in - terest, employer penalty interest and other miscellaneous re - ceipts and credits are credited to the pooled account. The total of the individual reserves on December 31,1939 amounted to $7.44 million, and the pooled account balance amounted to </seg>
         <seg id="p010">approximately $421 thousand. These figures exclude $1.98 million set aside for transfer to the Railroad Retirement Board, approximately $271 thousand of which may be re - tained in the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Fund and credited to the pooled account, representing claims for credit under the provisions of Legislative Bill No. 44. ' i At the time benefits were first payable, January 1, 1939, a total of $7.0 million was available for benefit payments. Dur - ing the calendar year 1939, $1.3 million was paid in benefits; during the same period the Fund accumulated to $9.8 million, or a net increase of approximately $2.8 million. These amounts, however, include the experience of railroad employers no longer subject to the Nebraska Law. Excluding railroad contributions, $5.55 million was avail - able January 1, 1939 for benefit payments. During the year, $1.14 million was paid in benefits to nonrailroad workers. The Fund increased to $7.86 million, or a net increase of $2.31 million. The ratio of nonrailroad benefits paid to nonrailroad collections (contributions and interest) for the year 1939 was approximately 33 per cent. The Nebraska total Fund experience of 33 per cent was about 21 points under the na - tional average for 1939, being located in the lower 20 per cent of the states, indicating that Nebraska's experience in the payment of benefits was considerably below the experience of most states. The following chart reflects the 1939 Fund experience in contributions and benefits, as well as the amount of funds available for benefit purposes. The question of Fund adequacy or inadequacy should not be judged solely from the amount of the Fund balance, inasmuch as benefits are restricted not to total funds available, but to the resources of the individual employers' accounts and the pooled account of the Fund. In the chart, the experience and balances exclude interstate rail - roads. When compared with the total taxable wages of the State, excluding railroads, it is found that the Unemployment Com - pensation Fund balance as of December 31,1939 amounted to 6.4 per cent of all taxable wages. The Fund balance amounted to 6.9 times the amount of benefits paid during 1939. 2 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">I Ur€MPLOYMENT COMPEMSA7ION FUYD mix* 1 vaiMKvmjimtmMMt '¦ * ¦ — '¦ — : —— ; —:_ - ¦ ¦ ' ¦ __ .. : •--———-——— »•—j- —.—_ ._ : ¦'-¦-- _¦¦ , t• -— 4— — -r—. — . . ; _ . '" ' __ _^ I :U»» •.' ' ''.-'_¦ .;!«• -.' Transfer of Railroad Funds In accordance with Section 48-709 (c), Comp. Stat., Supp. 1939, relating to the transfer of funds to the Railroad Unem - ployment Insurance Account, $1.98 million referred to in the preceding paragraphs was set aside pending verification and final transfer. The preliminary amount as defined in Section 48-709 (c) is the balance remaining in the reserves of the railroad employers. The preliminary amount as of June 30, 1939 was $1,491,669. Through June 30, 1939 a total of $1, - --658,844 was received in contributions, $624,493 for the year 1937 when the contribution rate was 1.8 per cent, $833,112 for the year 1938 and $201,239 for the first quarter of 1939 when the rate was 2.7 per cent. During the first six months of 3 </seg>
         <seg id="p012">1939, $166,743 was paid in benefits from the reserves of rail - road employers. The liquidating amount, which is defined as contributions collected from railroad employers after June 30, 1939, was $221,744. This amount represents contributions received from railroad employers for wages paid during the second calendar quarter of 1939 after minor adjustments to previous years. Claims for credit based on the provision of Legislative Bill No. 44 in the amount of $271,001 are not in - cluded in the preliminary or liquidating amount, pending a final determination of their disposition. There is a question whether or not the funds covered by these claims will be in - cluded in the transfer or retained in the State Unemployment Compensation Fund and credited to the pooled account. In connection with the transfer of railroad funds, five Nebraska employers have contested the Railroad Retirement Board's de - termination that they were railroad employers. Pooled Account The pooled account balance at the close of the year 1939 stood at about $421 thousand. This was an increase of $338 thousand, $206 thousand of which was due to credits based on the provisions of Legislative Bill No. 44. The increase based on the ordinary receipts and withdrawals from the pooled ac - count amounted to $132 thousand. The $206 thousand repre - sented the funds remaining from the Congressional appropria - tion of $1,330,835.90 after 1,686 employers failed to receive credit in accordance with the provisions of the Law. In terms of the total Unemployment Compensation Fund, the pooled account represents 5.4 per cent of all funds available for bene - fit payments. Interest from funds deposited in the Unemployment Trust Fund of the United States Treasury, yielding approximately 2.5 per cent, was the largest regular source of credits to the pooled account. During 1939 this interest amounted to ap - proximately $188 thousand. Employer interest on delinquent contributions amounted to $5,875 during 1939, while reserve transfers occasioned a charge to the pool of $1,152 due to a 4 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">modification of the procedure for handling transfers of busi - ness. The accompanying. table was designed to show the source of pool credits and charges and the amount of the bal - ance for the three calendar years 1937 through 1939. TABLE 1: Source* of Pooled Account Credit* and Chuyet and Amount of Pooled Account Balance for the Calendar Yean 1937, 1938 and 1939 Item 1939 1938 1937 POOL BALANCE, January 1..........$ 83,193.75 $ 426.25 $ ——. Pool Credits ....399,829.14 82,767.50 426.25 Trust Fund Interest.... 187,678.45 71,723.79 Employer Interest 5,874.74 4,690.45 426.25 Reserves Transferred to P001........ 376.86 6,353.26 .. Portion 1936 Congressional Appropriation „. 205,899.09 Pool Charges 62,113.76 .. Benefits ............. ........................ 60,584.53 Reserve Transfer Cancellations.... 1,529.23 '.. .. POOL BALANCE, December 31.... 420,909.13 83,193.75 426.25 ¦ — '. —¦—-- '. ' Benefits paid from the pooled account during 1939 amounted to $60,585. This represents 5.3 per cent of the total benefits paid out during 1939, excluding benefits paid from railroad employers' accounts. The remainder of the benefits were paid from individual employer reserves. No benefits were paid from the pooled account to workers employed by interstate railroads. Charges to the pooled account were made according to the provisions outlined in Section 48-707 (d) and (c), Comp. Stat., Supp. 1939. If benefit charges exceeded the resources of the individual employer reserve account, including contri - butions due but uncollected, this excess was charged to the pooled account, regardless of subsequent solvency of the indi - vidual reserve. Furthermore, no reimbursement is made to the pool by later contribution payments. Pool charges during 1939 were made because of the ab - sence of resources in 171 individual reserves, or approximately 5 </seg>
         <seg id="p014">five per cent of all accounts active as of December 31, 1939. Of the total, 58 reserve accounts became inactive for various reasons during the year 1939, while 31 active reserve accounts reverted to a solvent status as of December 31,1939 after bene - fits were paid from the pool at one time or another during the year 1939. The remaining 82 active reserve accounts, besides requiring the pooled account to absorb some portion of benefit charges during 1939, were atill insolvent as of December 31, 1939. A classification of the experience of pooled account charges made during the calendar year 1939 is shown in Appendix B. A summary of experience relating to benefit charges and the pooled account is shown in the following table: Number of Amount of Accounts Benefits Total Chargeable to Pool 171 $60,584.53 Active and Overdrawn 82 34,708.91 Inactive as of 12-31-39 58 10,563.51 Solvent as of 12-31-39 31 14,772.77 Not Allocable — 539.34 The amount of $539.34 was charged to the pool, not be - cause of inadequate resources of the reserve accounts involved, but because the amount did not constitute valid charges against the individual reserves. Fund Adequacy Very little is known at this time with respect to the ques - tion of the adequacy or inadequacy of the reserves. The ques - tion of fund solvency in an individual employer reserve scheme of unemployment compensation is limited to the adequacy of the individual reserves and, more important, the solvency of the account that absorbs benefits after the employer reserve is exhausted. In Nebraska this account is termed the pooled account. With respect to the individual reserve adequacy and its relationship to the question of pooled account solvency, serious consideration should be given to increasing the maximum con - tribution rate above 2.7 per cent for those firms whose benefit 6 </seg>
         <seg id="p015">payments over a period exceed their contributions. An ex - perience rating system designed on a sound basis should per - mit rate variation above the standard rate as well as below the standard rate. It is impossible, over a period of at least a major business cycle, to finance benefits from a large number i of individual reserves without imposing a cost exceeding 2.7 ' per cent of pay rolls on certain types of accounts. The impact' of a serious volume of unemployment, particularly after a large number of employers contributed to the fund at very low contribution rates, might endanger the payment of bene - fits if it is not possible to immediately impose a rate adequate to meet benefit obligations. From the point of view of the adequacy of the individual reserves,) a question can be raised about the present standards incorporated in the Law as they relate to the fixing of indi - vidual employer contribution rates. In an individual reserve system from the point of view of fund adequacy, an inverse relationship between the size of the reserve ratio and the size of the rates in the lower groups is probably the most desirable criterion for determining individual variable rates. The question of solvency of the pooled account is an im - portant question with respect to fund adequacy. So long as the pool is.solvent and adequate, benefits will not be denied to workers otherwise eligible. At the close of 1939 after one year of benefit payments, the percentage experience of the pool in benefit payments approximated that of the entire Fund. Com - paring 1939 pool receipts with benefits paid from the pool, excluding in both cases unusual or extraordinary charges or credits, it is found that benefits amounted to about 31.2 per cent of pool receipts. Because of the cumulative effect of de - mands on'the pool as a result of insolvent employer reserves, benefit payments made from the pool will very probably in - crease in the future. On the other hand the principal resource to the pool. Trust Fund interest, will probably level out. It is needless to point out that at least a five- to seven-year period must elapse, during which time cyclical unemployment is com - pensated, before the probable benefit experience of either the pool or the reserves can be estimated with reasonable ac - curacy. 7 </seg>
         <seg id="p016">The 1939 Legislature provided that under certain circum - stances a portion of the current collections of required con - tributions should be diverted to the pool. This is a desirable provision, but could be further strengthened in two directions to safeguard and insure the payment of benefits. The rate of contribution to the pool could be increased and the balance at which the provision takes place could be raised. So long as the pool contribution is not effective until the solvency of the pooled account is endangered, thus seriously threatening bene - fit payments, the statutory provisions relating to this feature of the compensation plan should be designed as constructively as possible to prevent benefit denial to eligible unemployed workers. 8 </seg>
         <seg id="p017">-n- COST OF ADMINISTRATION The entire cost of administering the Unemployment Com - pensation program is paid by the Federal Government through grants from the Social Security Board in accordance with Title 111 of the Social Security Act. Such grants are based on amounts determined by the Social Security Board to be neces - sary for the proper and efficient administration of the State Law. Federal grants for administrative purposes, provided for in Title 111 of the Social Security Act , are made available to the State by the Social Security Board provided the State Law and the State operations meet the standards outlined in the Federal Unemployment Tax Act and Title 111 of the Social Security Act. In order to secure administrative expense grants, the administration of the State Law must meet certain standards of efficiency. The funds are made available to the Social Security Board by Congressional appropriation, being credited initially, how - ever, to the General Fund of the U. S. Treasury from the col - lections under Section 1600 of the Internal Revenue Code. These collections amount to approximately three-tenths of one per cent of the amount of wages subject to the provisions of Section 1600 of the Internal Revenue Code. Administrative Expentei Federal grants in this connection for the year 1939 amounted to $212,145.58 which, together with $12,418.50 re - allotted from previous grants, made a total of $224,564.08 available for administrative expenses. Of this amount which was available foricost of administration, $213,188.96 was paid to defray the cost of administering the program during the calendar year 1939. The balance of funds remaining on De - cember 31 amounted to $11,375.12. The following statement shows the amount of receipts and expenditures during the year and the amount of unused funds remaining at the close of the year: 9 </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Statement of Receipts and Expenditures for Administrative Expenses Receipts: Reallotments $12,483.57 Less Adjustments to Re - allotments 65.07 $ 12,418.50 Federal Fund Grants 154F 212,145.58 TOTAL .$224,564.08 Expenditures: Personal Services $147,844.80 Travel 16,758.06 Postage 13,745.00 Rental of Equipment. 13,437.13 Consumable Supplies 11,802.02 Equipment 4,840.71 Printing and Binding 1,298.42 Telephone 1,149.10 Repairs and Alterations 376.31 Telegraph 317.98 Transportation of Things 254.47 Rent of Premises 87.50 Advertising 21.30 Other 1,256.16 TOTAL .$213,188.96 Unexpended Balance $ 11,375.12 Due to the commencing of benefit operations on January 1,1939, major outlays for administrative expense were greater than the expenditures for the year 1938. Expenditures in - creased from $133.8 thousand in 1938 to $213.2 thousand in 1939, or an increase of $79.4 thousand, which amounted to 59.3 per cent. Practically all categories of expenses were in - creased, the major items, however, being those of personal services, rentals and communications. The category of com - munications includes principally the cost of postage for mail - ing claimant checks, initial and continued claims, employers' reports, etc. 10 </seg>
         <seg id="p019">In terms of total collections during the year 1939, the ad - ministrative cost amounted to 5.19 per cent, as compared to 3:19 per cent for the previous year. In terms of benefits paid during the calendar year 1939, administrative costs amounted to 16.4 per cent. The increase in the ratio of administrative cost to contribution collections was brought about principally by the addition of the claims and benefits functions to the operations of the Unemployment Compensation Division. While $64,645.19 was disbursed for administrative costs during the first quarter of the year, a reduction to $48,882.72 for the last quarter, of the year was achieved. This was a de - crease in quarterly expenditures of 24 per cent, which was distributed among all the major items of expense. The ac - companying table shows a classification of administrative ex - penditures for each quarter, as well as the total for the year and the per cent of the total for the year, expended in each of the categories: TABLE 2: Amount arid Par Cent of Eaoeaditures for AdaiinrtrrsHoii of rii* Nebraska UnomployiMnt Compensation Division During the Catendar Voir 1939 --¦.)¦¦-..- --•.-.''.- - . Category Total for Year Calendar Quarter Ending Per March June September December Amount Cent 31 30 30 31 TOTAI/ .......... «213,18a00 100.0 «04,045.19 *53,9&lt;8.94 *43,757.11 548.582.T2 Personal Services .. 147,844.80 00.4 41,099.57 37,003.40 34,525.70 33 33013 I Travel ;..._ ........... 10,758.00 7.9 5,000.09 4,008.40 3,442.00 3',046\83 Communications .... 15,212.08 7.1 0,004.80 3,043.05 1,308.74 3,354.88 i Bental ............... . 13,524.03 0.3 3,489.38 3,517.00 3,317.25 3,201.00 "j Consumable • Supplies ................11,802.02 5.5 3,497.40 2,709.93 1.013.03 392108 I Kqnipment 4,840.71 2.3 2,370.35 1,145.02 655.03 702.81 Printing unci Binding .............. 1,298.42 .0 433.9S 259.00 355.74 24770 Rcpnlrß una Alterations ........... 370.31 .2 ' 290.21 — 14.95 71.13 Transportation .1. ¦ ot Things ._..: — ,254.47-.'. .1 135.12 24.11 10.00 04.58 Other ......_....—...1,277.40 .0 195.09 212.40 012.75 25050 According to the table it is found that 69.4 per cent of expenditures were made to cover the cost of personal services. 11 </seg>
         <seg id="p020"/>
         <seg id="p021"/>
         <seg id="p022">Other categories ranging in cost from 5.5 per cent to 8 per cent were travel, communications, rentals and consumable sup - plies. Equipment purchases amounting to $4,840.71 were ap - proximately ten thousand dollars less than the previous year. Since the organization of the Division in 1937, $28,309.69 has been expended for equipment, which was shown as an expense in the period in which it was purchased, although it will be in use during future years of operation. The monthly expenditures made to cover the cost of per - sonal services are shown in the following table: TABLE 3: Amount of Monthly Expenditures for Perianal Services During the Calendar Year 1939 Month Amount TOTAL $147,844.80 January 13,758.21 February 14,125.36 March 14,116.00 April 13,008.33 May 12,876.15 June 12,078.92 July 11,711.43 August 11,609.85 September 11,204.42 October 11,066.96 November 11,086.00 ; December 11,203.17 J A reduction in personal service expenditures was re- f, corded from February through October, declining from $13,- | 758.21 in January, 1939 to $11,066.96 in October, 1939. A J slight increase was recorded for the months of November and | December, the expenditures for the latter month, however, ; being approximately $230.00 less than for the same month \ in the previous calendar year. The policy of the Social Security Board during the previ- ; ; ous year required that grants for administrative expense be i 12 </seg>
         <seg id="p023">made on a quarterly budget basis. During 1939, however, a six-months' budget practice for the Division was permitted. All expenditures made for administrative expense must be incurred strictly in accordance with the budget approved by the Social Security Board, as well as within the rules and regulations of the State of Nebraska and the Nebraska Un - employment Compensation Division. Complete audits are con - ducted at regular intervals by the Social Security Board with respect to all grants and expenditures incurred for adminis - trative expense purposes. The administrative expenditures made in connection with the operation of the Unemployment Compensation Division are paid from the Unemployment Compensation Administra - tion Fund, Account No. 154 F. This account is likewise credited with all grants made by the Social Security Board to cover the cost of administering the Unemployment Compensation program. All funds with respect to the Nebraska State Em - ployment Service activities are deposited in and expended from the special Employment Service account of the Unem - ployment Compensation Administration Fund. This is in ac - cordance with the provisions of Section 48-712, Comp. Stat., Supp. 1939. The activities of this account, including funds granted by the Social Security Board for Employment Service, are not included in this report. At the close of the year there were 103 persons on the pay roll of the Unemployment Compensation Division, com - pared to 107 in 1938. Of this total, there were 92 regular and four temporary employees, while seven |persons of the total number of employees were engaged in part-time services on Appeals Tribunals and in activities in jconnection with the personnel merit system. In addition to t}ie regular field staff, which deals with the collection of contributions, the Division had eight persons stationed at the following local offices work - ing in connection with claims and benefits functions: Omaha, four; Lincoln, one; Scottsbluff, one; Staiewide, two. " An important change was-made hi the administrative expense grant provisions of the Social Security Act by the 1939 amendments to the Social Security Act passed by Con - gress in August, 1939. This modification of the Federal Law 13 </seg>
         <seg id="p024">related to the methods of selecting personnel engaged in the administration of state unemployment compensation pro - grams. The amendment provided that the administration of the state law must, after January 1, 1940, provide methods for establishing and maintaining personnel standards on a merit basis. Inasmuch as the staff of the Division, in accord - ance with the provisions of Section 48-711 (d), was selected on the basis of a comprehensive merit system formally adopted by the Commissioner of Labor, the Nebraska standards are in conformity with this provision. Amendments Certain changes in Title 111 of the Social Security Act by the 1939 Social Security Act amendments will require amendment of the State Law. These amendments include the limiting of expenditures of moneys received pursuant to Title 111 of the Social Security Act to purposes found necessary by the Board for proper and efficient administration. These amendments also provide for replacement, within a reason - able time, of funds expended for purposes other than, or amounts in excess of, those found necessary by the Board for the proper administration of such State Law, as well as re - placement of funds which, because of any action or con - tingency, have been lost. A requirement of cooperation with the Railroad Retirement Board and other agencies of the United States charged with the administration of any unem - ployment insurance law was placed on the state by Congres - sional amendment of Title 111 of the Social Security Act. 14 </seg>
         <seg id="p025">-in- BENEFIT PAYMENTS __ Benefits under the Nebraska Unemployment Compensa - tion Law became payable to eligible unemployed workers on January 1,1939. This is in accordance with Section 48-7Q3 (a) of the Nebraska Statutes, which provides that twenty-four months after the date when contributions first come due under the act, benefits become payable. Because of the two-week waiting period and one week to fulfill the requirements of the definition of unemployment, first checks of, the Unemploy - ment Compensation Division were not issued until January 23. An unknown amount of unemployment was accumulated m the form of a back log prior to January 1, 1939. This volume of accumulated unemployment, however, was very probably not as severe as it would have otherwise been if benefits were first payable a year earlier, in January, 1938. Amount of Benefits Paid A total amount of $1,304,523.41 was paid in benefits dur - ing the calendar year 1939 for partial, part-total and total unemployment. Included in this amount, however, was $167, - --174.80 paid to workers who earned wages from employers engaged in the interstate railroad industry. The amount of benefits paid during the calendar year to nonrailroad claim - ants amounted to $1,137,348,61. It should be recognized that during the first few years of operations under a new program such as unemployment compensation, workers are not as familiar with their rights under the law as they subsequently will be. Because of this reason, a certain volume of unemploy - ment during the year 1939 probably was not compensated. In addition, there is some evidence that some employers, moti - vated by the desire to preserve their individual reserves and secure more favorable experience ratings, may have discour - aged workers from filing claims for unemployment compen - sation benefits. It should also be recognized that the types of unemployment compensated during the calendar year 1939 in - cluded principally intermittent and seasonal unemployment. 15 </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Other types of unemployment, including in particular cyclical unemployment, are not generally reflected in the volume of unemployment compensated in the calendar year 1939. For a majority of the workers who established rights dur - ing the year 1939, the total amount of benefits for which they were eligible was determined on the basis of a three- and four-quarter base period with a benefit wage ratio of one to six. The Law before amendment contemplated a-base period of eight quarters with a benefit wage ratio of one to six. While the 1939 amendments effective in June modified the ratio from one-sixth to one-third for a four-quarter base period, a majority of the claimants established their benefit year prior to the effective date of the amendments. Certain other legislative modifications made in the Law by the 1939 amendments will result in a different experience than that recorded for the year 1939. These include, for example, change in the waiting period requirement, provision for compensa - tion of partial unemployment, imposition of more severe dis - qualification penalties, and modification of qualifying provi - sions. Because of these modifications, the single year of 1939 is not a satisfactory index of what the benefit experience will be in the future. Benefit payments reached a high point in March, 1939, when $240,995.84 was paid to eligible claimants. From that point, a decline was experienced, reaching a low point in Sep - tember, when $59,893.65 in benefits was paid. A continuous increase was recorded through the months of October, No - vember and December, reaching a level of $105,714.68 during the month of December, 1939. The chart on the opposite page shows the amount of benefits paid out for each calendar month of the year 1939. The total amount of benefits paid for each month is shown in Table B-4 of Appendix B. The Omaha territory and contiguous counties served by the Omaha Employment Service office received $517,207.96, the largest amount of benefits paid in the State. The Lincoln territory received $136,899.21, while the Grand Island terri - tory received $88,549.42. The amount of benefits paid during each month of 1939 classified by Employment Service office is shown in Table B-6 of Appendix B. 16 </seg>
         <seg id="p027">BENEFITS PAID IN 1939 ]¦''-. . Twwei .:¦¦-. "¦•¦—T I I II I I J , .•¦¦l --— — -zr— ——— — -— I . '. ; sis ¦ : — V— : . — — . _ . ¦.'. j:. say 1 — V- ¦ ¦ — '¦ — '. __ ', j i»'.¦ ——— ——¦ — &lt; —X— — ;—¦ —— —-—__ __ ___ ¦ ¦ ¦ aw. —-—; J — \—— —— ___ : _ v'hjo- * — -V- — —-—__—:— , . . .¦• SO.- — -*- \—— ¦ ; — "—— '. _ •;; ITO-— —; —t- —-—¦ \ ; "' — . —— :—; . ; j. ISO -J : : —— L '_. ; _____ ! ; ; ___ ¦• |.t».— I —¦—• V — . : ; i ¦' ———*- — \ -— ¦ — -—— '. ;| no. ¦—-—¦ — j [ ¦ —t- • —— .__ , ; : ¦ iss ¦ 1 ] ' —a, _— ¦ — -—- _ _____ jno —— —+— —-—¦—-—- -—— V—;—; —_ _ _____ ¦' [¦s» ¦ 1 —:— ; —¦—— - ———. — _ -j''. 40 ¦ I ¦ &gt; : — _— _— ; . . • ..10' ——-y —— ¦ —-— &gt; —-———_.— __ , . • : _ . to. f— — — _ . .—__ - ' _____ - w. f .— ¦ ———.—_—— _——_—: . asc. jw, m m** mk. -mt am. . ml. -ua. sir .- oct. sg_ . oca Weeks Compensated and Checks Written Prior to June, 1939 partial unemployment was not com - pensated under the Nebraska Law. The 1939 amendments effective in June provided for the compensation of wage loss in those cases where the earnings during any week were less than the claimant's weekly benefit amount, regardless of whether the earnings were from his regular work, or from odd jobs and subsidiary employment. Compensation for par - tial wage loss is an important feature of a well-designed sys - tem of unemployment compensation, not only from the point of view of compensating for the loss, but also from the point of view of eliminating abuse and arbitrary treatment of claimants, as well as not penalizing the claimant for accepting part-time work. In compensating for partial and part-total unemploy - ment, the first three dollars of earnings are ignored, thus pro - viding an extra iiicentive for securing part-time work. In 17 </seg>
         <seg id="p028">case of waiting periods for partial and part-total unemploy - ment, the amended Law provides that a waiting period can be counted if the earnings were less than the claimant's weekly benefit amount and the claimant worked less than full-time. The distinction between partial and part-total unemployment lies in the nature and source of the claimant's earnings.' If his earnings were from his regular job or work, the wage loss being due not to a loss of job, but to a reduction of hours and earnings, the claimant's unemployment is considered as par - tial. The claimant's unemployment is considered as part-total if, after losing his job, he secures odd jobs or subsidiary em - ployment. Surprisingly little partial and part-total unemployment was compensated during the last six months of 1939 when the partial provision was effective. Only 4.3 per cent of benefit - paid and 5.2 per cent of weeks of unemployment compensated during the period June through December were for partial and part-total unemployment. Partial unemployment ac - counted for only 1.06 per cent of weeks of unemployment com - pensated, while part-total accounted for 4.13 per cent. Weeks of Unemployment Benefits Paid Compensated Amount Per Cent Number Per Cent TOTAL, June- December $527,165.70 100.00 60,417 100.00 Total 504,325.70 95.67 57,283 94.81 J Part-Total 18,317.00 3.47 2,494 4.13 1 Partial 4,523.00 0.86 640 1.06 I is The small volume of partial unemployment compensated ji during the last six months of 1939 may be due to the absence I of this type of unemployment in Nebraska industry, or it may I be due to lack of knowledge on the part of Nebraska workers .1 about their rights under conditions of partial unemployment, If The monthly payment of benefits and the number of weeks I compensated each month for the three types of unemployment during the year 1939 are shown in Table B-4 of Appendix B. During the calendar year 1939, 150,995 checks were is- I 18 </seg>
         <seg id="p029">sued and mailed directly from the Central Office to 20,676 claimants. The high point with respect to checks written was the month of March, when 28,244 checks were issued. Checks written declined to 6,956, the number issued during: September. The number of checks issued for each calendar month is shown in Table B-4 of Appendix B. Since with very few exceptions each check issued repre - sents one week of compensable unemployment, the volume of checks issued may be taken as the volume of weeks of unem - ployment compensated during each of,the respective months, The following chart, therefore, shows the number of weeks of unemployment compensated during the year 1939, plotted on a semi-logarithmic scale: WEEKS OF UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATED UNDER PROVISIONS OF THE NEBRASKA LAW' I 9 3 9 WgOOIIIIIIIIIIIII¦II'IIj'IIIIIIII I I I I I I I I I 1 I I I I I I I I I I I I I I i tfiOQ ; ¦ ¦--¦ ' |£00 . T . 1,000 --pi ¦ n : - ¦ - ¦ •joo — ' ~ ~ ~W~ S ¦""¦ ~ ~ - 4jo oo ¦*¦ • — — -r woe ¦ ¦ J ¦ t 2 " . tjoa _ _ _. . . . ___...__ . .pool I I I I I I I .-..Li__LJ.i 1,, I ..I iil.il 1 I I I 1 1 ,1 I I I I TI ml I I,! I I I, I I I II I I II 1 I _....-». p 4 if « k i ¦.. n. r* n it «.».¦ n ) n * « to h n n ti t i* .. tmsami W-umt . _wen ¦ _wl ...- . nn m juli mm ttwnmST octowi' -ast-wi wii-w"* ¦ *iuo~«*uxn ym ivmu w occnwmn n» imm tm-mm This chart is based on weeks compensated rather than on the week in which the check was written. The increase; in benefit weeks recorded during the first part of April when the trend was downward, was occasioned by a redetermination of 19 </seg>
         <seg id="p030">benefit rights based on the fourth calendar quarter of 1938 which moved into the base period on April 1, 1939. This re - determination affected only claimants who established their benefit rights prior to March 18, 1939. The monthly volume of weeks of unemployment compen - sated during the calendar months of 1939 is shown in Table B-7 of Appendix B classified by local office. Multi-State Payments and Claims Claimants who filed their continued claims in offices out - side of the State of Nebraska received compensation for 11,861 weeks of unemployment. Total benefits paid for these weeks of unemployment amounted to $116,496.38. These payments were made under a reciprocal arrangement with other states permitting a claim to be filed in a state other than that in which the worker earned his wage credits. The classification by states of initial claims, weeks compensated and amount of benefit payments for out-of-state claims is shown in Table B-5 of Appendix B. Claimants filing their continued claims in the State of California received the largest amount of bene - fits, when 2,934 weeks of unemployment were compensated by the payment of §28,507.37. The contiguous State of lowa ranked second in the payment of $18,296.14 for 1,903 weeks of unemployment. While Nebraska as a liable state under the multi-state reciprocal agreement, received 3,991 initial claims and 19,527 continued claims, it accepted as agent state, 4,106 initial claims and 23,271 continued claims which were forwarded to other states. The mobility of workers from Nebraska from the point of view of unemployment compensation practically offset the movement of workers from other states into Ne - braska. Initial Claims, Determinations and Redetermination* During the calendar year 1939, a total of 44,937 initial claims for benefits was received in the Central Office. Of this total, 6,681 were additional claims and 38,256 were new claims. A new claim is defined as a notice of unemployment filed by a 20 </seg>
         <seg id="p031">claimant to establish a benefit year, while an additional claim is a notice of unemployment filed by a claimant within his benefit year. The concept of an additional claim as it applied to operations during the calendar year 1939 is not clearly de-; fined, inasmuch as the procedure with respect to filing addi - tional claims was conditioned by considerations and require - ments relating to redetermination for claimants who estab - lished their benefit years between January 1 and March 18. This was especially true after October, 1939, at which time a mass redetermination was made. The concept of a new claim, however, has administrative significance as well as a certain amount of economic significance. Monthly receipts of new claims are shown graphically in the following chart: NEW CLAWS RECEIVED 19 3 9 t*u_*-»» '¦- ¦- ¦¦' •:- •¦ '- : :-- ••¦'•¦• ' .". it v II ""1 — I 'j 1" "111 : '^^^:-;^-r¦--h^l;---¦J/^lV^^-•-1-•^l-^--::^^•::^^^ ---I--- "T----I •¦ m .-¦__»;¦. na_ ..an. :. mi :mr .¦ jm .M. ) mm, tf«. tm .¦¦ aw.-. Ma The unusual receipt of hew claims during the month of January, 1939, is due to the fact that benefits were first pay - able and claims were first accepted during that month. 21 </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Because of errors in the determination of benefit rights, due either to erroneous reporting of full-time weekly wage, the amount of the claimant's earnings, or to no reporting from previous employers, a special administrative procedure was set up so that the initial determination of benefit rights could be revised and a redetermination made. This procedure is known as workers' request for revision. During the year, 2,377 such requests were received in the Central Office from claimants who objected to the determination, 2,288 of which were disposed of during the year. Practically all of the revi - sion requests were with respect to new claims filed to establish a benefit year. Because of this revision of benefit rights, some workers who were previously ineligible were found eligible, while other workers experienced an alteration of their benefit rights. In addition, administrative procedure was formulated and designed to handle a request for reconsideration of the de - termination of benefit rights based on the request of an inter - ested employer. During the year 1939, 3,536 separate requests were handled by the Benefit Section of the Division, 619 of which related to questions of stoppage of work due to a labor dispute. From the point of view of the administrative load of the Division with respect to determination of benefit rights, the three fields of determination, including initial determinations and revision of determinations based on the request of the worker and the employer, can be added together. On this basis, the Division received 50,850 claims during the calendar year 1939 that were directly for or incidental to the determi - nation of benefit rights. Of the total 37,952 new claims disposed of during the year, 27,050, or 71.3 per cent, were allowed benefits, while 10,902, or 28.7 per cent, were denied benefits. Of the total new claims disallowed on the first determination, 4,875 were denied because there was no record of wages. These persons earned no wages in covered employment during the qualifying period provided for in the Law. Claimants denied benefits because earnings during tbe qualifying period were insufficient numbered 5,909* These figures relate to action taken by the Central Office of the Division on first determinations. ¦'¦¦:./ 22 </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Reconsideration on the part of the Central Office based upon the request of the claimant or upon the request of the employer modified to some extent the allowance or disallow - ance of claims based on the first determinations. After re - vision and redetermination, it was found that of a total of 37,952 new claims acted on during the calendar year 1939, 27,434, or 72.2 per cent, were allowed and 10,518, or 27.8 per cent, disallowed. The following table shows the new claims allowed and disallowed on the first determination, classified by reason for disallowance: TABLE 4: New Claims Allowed and Disallowed arid Reasons for Disallowance During Calendar Months of 1939 Claims a nlms Keasoas for Dlsnllowanee Month -, Allowed Disallowed XoWhro Insiifflclent .¦_________.' Records WngcCredlts Other Per Per Per ' Per^ ~~ Per Number Cent Number Cent No. Cent No. Cent No. Cent TOTAL ..27,050 H. 27 10,002 28.73 4,875. 12.55 5,000 15.57 118 0.31 January .... 9,912 70.55 4,137 20.45 2,328 10.57 1,788 1»73 '1 715 February ..3,522 78.07. 035 21.33 535 11.03 307 &amp;87 23 051 March ..._... 2,080 77.01 845 22.00 308 0.02 458 11.07 10 050 April .......... 1330 78.52 503 21.48 100 0.83 301 12.85 4» 180 May „.....„._ 1,323 7gBo 358 , 21-20 185 9.83 181 10.78 10 o'fi» June &#132; 1,142 72.51 433 27.49 150 9.52 252 17.91 1 006 July „.._... 804 01.07 537 38.33 100 13.50 347 24 77 Autfllst ...... 595 82.33 541 37.07 183 12.7- 350 24.79 2 014 September _ 707 00.41 388 33.59 151 13.07 237 205" October „. 1,145 05.00 015 34.94 108 9.54 447 2&amp;40 " ." . November. 1,227 03.71 099 30.29 208 10.80 491 2549 December ..1,434 01.02 803 3SJ3B 209 11.50 034 20.82 " _; : ¦ ¦:: It will be noted that after June, when the new qualifying provision based on thirty times the weekly benefit amount ; w?s made a part of the Nebraska Law, the percentage of claims disallowed because of insufficient wage credits increased above the period when the qualifying provision was in terms of sixteen times the weekly benefit amount during the first three of the last four completed calendar quarters. The provisions of the Law, Section 48-702 (a), before 23 </seg>
         <seg id="p034">amendment provided that the base period would extend to include the next to the last completed calendar quarter preced - ing any week with respect to which benefits are payable. The 1939 amendments restricted the base period to a fixed period of the first four of the last five completed calendar quarters immediately preceding- an individual's benefit year. Since the amendments became effective during the second calendar quar - ter of 1939, the extensible feature of the original base period was limited to the inclusion of the fourth calendar quarter of 1938 in the base period of those claimants who established their benefit years between January 1 and April 1, 1939. This limitation of the extensible feature was provided for in the transition provision amendment of 1939, Section 48-722, Comp. Stat., Supp. 1939. The transition provision limiting the extension of the base period decreased the amount of wage credits that would have otherwise been available for benefits. The provision was included, however, to make the change to the fixed base period and to simplify the determination of benefit rights. Since the extensible feature of the original base period was effective with respect to the last calendar quarter of 1938, a redetermination was necessary for every claimant who established his benefit year prior to April 1,1939. Since there were 12,387 such claimants whose benefit rights were affected, redeterminations were made, based either on the filing of an initial claim, or by a mass redetermination completed in Oc - tober, 1939. The elimination of the provision for an extensible base period and the limitation of the base period to four quar - ters rather than eight were probably the most effective changes from the point of view of simplification of benefit operations. A special problem of redetermination of benefit rights was occasioned by the transfer of railroad workers from the coverage of the State Law to the Federal Railroad Unemploy - ment Insurance Act. This problem required the review of all claims, the rights of which were based in whole or in part on wages earned from railroad employers during the claimants' base periods. That part of the claimant's unexpended benefit rights that was initially established using railroad wage credits was cancelled, using as a basis the statutory procedure provided for the charging of benefits. 24 </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Continued Claims 219,686 continued claims received during the calendar year There were, including waiting period and compensable, 1939. Waiting period claims filed during the year numbered 65,536, while compensable continued claims numbered 154,150. The foregoing figures include continued claims filed jay work - ers in other states against Nebraska as the liable state, and exclude continued claims accepted in Nebraska as agent state. The following chart shows the monthly volume and change in total continued claims filed, as well as waiting period and com - pensable claims filed: 1939 CONTINUED CLAIMS FOR BENEFITS IN NEBRASKA ¦ **i°*f_ ¦' ¦ •-¦• ¦ ¦¦¦¦'.¦¦'¦ -. ¦'¦¦'¦. ¦¦ .:" : ¦ ¦ ' ¦ ¦CO . I I ""] j I | I I . I i. I . .•poo yt'i,}J\ ¦ .«»» —* /%% \ ¦ ¦ : — — ivy ii mi £/&gt;_ sspoo —Kw '/y_i&amp;. V77^ — ~~" - -— — ¦ i«poo fyy/'A SgCWv *X,yyS, w»o K////KJSSIS&amp; "wr vfai. ¦ topoo I^wj^^^m*K^M| Y/o\ ! •jooo —^^^Kjr*ysyyx?c_!!_yy^y*j'V-Sv q_i_&lt;yff i _^? v_i__s •coo tj%li|}jjBjx}j)^^ *Z^.jLiMai B-iJy mm. .-na. "» —¦¦ «•» ml jol. sua sn oct. aw oca. Figures on waiting period claims include waiting period claims filed by claimants who were subsequently found in - eligible for benefits. Since the provision of the Statute re - lating to waiting period claims was amended in June, 1939, the original provision in the Law relating to serving an ad - ditional waiting period after the lapse of thirteen weeks did not generally become effective. i 25 </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Size Distribution of Amounts of Weekly Payments To secure a distribution of the size of the weekly pay - ments made during the calendar year 1939, a sampling tech - nique was utilized. For each month during the calendar year, all payments made during the calendar week ending nearest the fifteenth of the month were analyzed with respect to the size of the payment. This sample of the size-of-payment dis - tribution excluded checks which were for less than the regular weekly benefit amount representing final payments of the benefit year. These payments were less than would have other - wise been received if sufficient balance had remained in the claimant's account. The accompanying chart shows the per - centage of checks written for each dollar interval up to fifteen dollars, the maximum provided for in the Statute: CHECKS WRITTEN BY SIZE OF PAYMENT tot*. CkCcxi -mt-tth " i* " „ . —- : •a ¦ - : ' — — I- . .—, _ . ¦¦ . it ' ¦ ¦ ~ mm~ — — — — ¦ MM - -10 ¦ —^m—^m - —. • ' — '—_ '—' —' —^B —^b ™ ' " i — — __ — m_ — M_ — m_ — m_ ' M_~ 7 " •—¦—~ ~—"— — __ — \\\\\\\\ — "___ — \\\\\_ —^B~ ~~ ~~^B~ — —_H —__¦ —__¦ —_H —__¦ —_¦ __B __¦ tfl —_H —_H —*¦¦ __l _H~~.HI l_B^ WWW" 4 ——^b—^B —__h~~t_B —___B —__h~~__h __¦ ____¦ —— ~~__B~ . ¦— _\w — _\w — _\w — _\\\ — __ —^ B_i __¦* i mm —^M—^—^m—^m—^M—^B—^|—^B~~__B _H~ 1 ¦ __¦—^ —__¦ —__¦ —__¦ ~~__h —__¦ —__¦ —_B —_H __¦ __¦ * •100 •ioo «ioo moo H.oo »*.o_ «roo moo« ifcoo »o.w *nea **_» Mj» **« *i» kn •_*. »w- mm fiii %n •?» *m» Htt Hast nln:hui H&gt;st *hm The sample included 34,148 payments for all types of un - employment out of a total of 151,021. Distribution of these payments classified by size of payment for the three types of 26 </seg>
         <seg id="p037">unemployment with the respective per cent is shown in the accompanying table: TABLE 5: Bairafit Pay-rants Itstwd During Calendar Waaks Ending Naaratr Mm FHtMnrh of Each Month Daring tha Calandar Yaar 1939, ClaaalfM by Type of UrampfoynMnr and Sis* of Payment Type ot Unemployment Totnl : ; ¦ Size of Payment Payments Total Part-Total Partial .Per Per Per Per No. Cent No. Cent No. Cent No. Cent TQTAIi ¦¦¦...: 34.14S 100.0 .13,414 100.0 (KB 100.0 105 100.0 Less than $1.00._: _ _ „ _ ~~ _~~""" _ ~ t 1.00 — $ 1.99-.- . 3 0.0 3 jO.O '•'.¦_ . _ .. " $2.00 — $ 2.90 422 1.2 421 1.3 1 .2 1 " $ 3.00— $3.99.....—... 510 l.» 405 1.5 20 3.5 4 2.4 S 4.00 — * 4.99. 809 2.4 099 2.1 77 13.5 33 20.0 $ 5.00 — S 5.09...- 5,093 10.7 5,57 ft 10.7 92 10.2 22 13.3 S 0.00 — $ 0.09_.„ _ 2,945 8.0 2,853 '8.5 77 13.5 15 9.1 57.00 — $7,99— 3,098 10.8 3,021 . 10.8 CO 10.5 17 10.3 $aOO — $8.90 .__ 3,505 10.3 3,431 10.3 58 10.2 10 9.7 $ 9.00 — * 9.99......—.3,400 10.0 3,358 10.0. 38 0.7 10 Oil $10.00 — $10.99. „ 3,022 8.8 2,903 8.8 ] 43 7.0 18 9.7 $11.00 — $11.99—....._ 1,812 5.3 1,759 5.3 40 7.0 13 7.9 $12.00 — $12.99...„ „ 2,044 0.0 2,013 0.0 : 22 3.9 9 5.5 $13.00 — $13.99..-.......:.. 1,281 3.8 1,233 3.8 20 3.5 0. 3,6 $14.00 — $14.99_„ 1,019 3.0 1,001 3.0 14 2.5 4 2.4 $15.00 — $15.99- . . 3,970 11.0 3,903 11.0 i 7 1.2 Of all payments issued during the year, over thirty per cent were for less than seven dollars, while over sixty-one per cent were for less than ten dollars. Prior to June, checks were issued for odd cents, as well as for less than five dollars for a week of total unemployment. Claimants who established their benefit year and rights after June 5, 1939, the effective date of the amendments; had a minimum weekly benefit amount of five dollars, as well as having their weekly benefit amount rounded to the nearest dollar. \ ¦ i ' ¦¦ lenefit Payment Lag ) With respect to securing some measure of the prompts ness in issuing benefit checks, the Division has recorded the time elapsed between the end of the compensable week anß the date the* benefit payment was issued. This measurement gives a significant index with respect to the promptness of 27 </seg>
         <seg id="p038">the administrative machinery in making payments to eligible claimants. The time includes the taking of the claim in the local office, mailing time to the Central Office, review and auditing of the claims and preparation of the check and docu - ments incidental thereto. It does not include the time for signing the check or the mail time in delivering the check; This index was likewise secured by means of a sampling method, using the payments issued during the calendar week ending nearest the fifteenth of each calendar month during the year 1939. As shown in the following table, out of a total sample of 33,507 payments, 28,885, or 86.2 per cent, were paid within one week, while 9.8 per cent were paid in less than two weeks. Four per cent of all payments issued had a time lapse of two weeks or more between the end of the compensable week and the date of the check. These payments include payments in - volved in contests between the employer and the claimant, claims involved in appeal, as well as claims involved in the revision of initial determination because of the claimant's re - quest. ; TABLE 6: Number of Weeks Elapsed Between the End of the Compensable Week and the Date of the Benefit Payment for Cheeks Issued During the Calendar Week Ending Nearest the Fifteenth of Each Month Including First Payments In the Benefit Year and Second and Subsequent Payment. In the Benefit Year Total First Second and Sub- Woffcs Elapsod Payments Payments sequent Payments •' Per Per Per Number Cent Number Cent Number Cent TOTAL 33.-507 100.0 3.743 100.0 29,704 100.0 Paid within 1 week 28,885 50.2 2.050 70.0 25,929 57.1 1 week nnd less than 2 .1.300 0.8 405 12.4 2,841 0.0 2 week" and lens than 3 743 2.2 ISO 4.0 503 2.0 :i weeks Am) lem than 4 224 .0 aa 2.r&gt; 133 .4 4 \wkK anil leas than i&gt; 89 .3 18 ..&gt; 71 .2 .1 weeks and lesn than 0 71 .2 13 ,3 38 .2 0 weeks and less than 7 .Vi .2 18 .5 37 .1 7 weeks and less than 8 31! .1 12 .3 24 .1 8 weeks and lons than 9 27 .1 4 .1 23 .1 9 weeks and less than 10 19 .1 3 .1 10 .1 Over 10 weeka 52 .2 12 .3 40 .1 28 </seg>
         <seg id="p039">I ¦ - ' f !! Disqualifications .'-.- -i-. ; v|j j. j Unemployment compensation laws contain provision, re lading to disqualification of claimants under certaiW condi - tions. Disqualifications incorporated in the original LaW mi; ciiided a deferment of benefits from one to five weeks because of voluntary leaving, misconduct, receipt of other compensa - tion, refusalof suitable work and labor dispute. The 193. ses - sion of the Legislature amended the' Law to include certain other disqualifications such as separation because of marriage, student status, disciplinary suspension and fixed salary, as well as modifying the disqualification basis frona deferment to complete denial of benefits under certain conditions, such as ; gross, flagrant and willful, or unlawful misconduct, 'etc. The following table shows the number of disqualificati &gt;ns im - posed during the calendar year 1939, classified by type of dis - qualification and the industry of the claimant: j TABLE 7: Number of Disqualification! Imposed During tho Calendar Y&lt; ar 1939, &gt; Cla_wYiad by Type of DiHHaKfication and Industry of the CUimlnr ;.¦ - . -•• Con- Mann-Trans- '[-I ( Typeof Btruc- fnc- por- Serv- TJtlu- Dlsanallflcatlon Total Hon tnrlnjr ration Trade Ice tlci, Other TOTAL™ ______ 805 -30 100 552 190 154 46 37 Vqlnnrnry Leavlnff . Without Good Cause 275 20 71 25 OR 73 9 ' 11 Misconduct ..... . _... 200 ._¦'.. 40 25 88 40 9 , 10 Labor Di5pute................ 199 .. l 107 . 1 ' _ „ _ Other Compensation .-. 113 2 22 1 :45 10 10 ' 11 Suitable Work ...... 33 4 7 2 5 15 .. ' Marriage Separation _ 19 .-_¦.'¦¦¦ 3 .. 2 1 11 2 Student Status .......„._.. 17 "•'_.- 0 .. , 5 3 1 2 Disciplinary Suspension 2 _ _ 2 ¦ _ ¦ _' ' _ . Fixed Monthly Salary™ 1 _ .. _ _ „ „ l The largest single reason for disqualification of claimants was voluntary leaving without good cause, which accounted for approximately 32 per cent of all disqualifications. Mis - conduct and labor disputes each accounted for approximately 24 per cent. The remaining 20 per cent of disqualifications were imposed because of receipt of other compensation, re - fusal to accept suitable work, etc. For those cases involved in a complete denial of benefits because of disqualification conditions, it was found that 29 of 29 </seg>
         <seg id="p040">the 206 misconduct cases were denied benefits because of gross, flagrant and willful, or unlawful misconduct. Eight cases of refusal of suitable work were denied benefits com - pletely, while in 19 cases female employees were denied bene - fits on account of marriage. In connection with deferment of benefits because of mis - conduct, it was found that an average of 3.6 weeks was im - posed for misconduct, 3.3 weeks for refusing to accept suitable work, and 4.3 weeks for voluntary leaving without good cause. Appeals During the year, 196 cases involving 405 claimants were appealed either by the employer or by the claimant, or re - ferred for action by the Benefit Section of the Division to the Appeals Tribunal as provided for in the Law. One hundred sixty-eight of these cases covering 168 claimants; were dis - posed of during the year, leaving 28 cases pending, which in-: volved 237 claimants. A classification of the appeal decisions by type of issue and the disposition action is shown in Table B-10 of Appendix B. The following table shows for each month the number of appeal cases received, disposed of, and pending: TABLE 8: Appeal Cases Received, Disposed of and Pending by Months for tho Calendar Year 19-9 - - . , . Disposed Month Received of . Pending TOTAL 196 168 28 January — — - '¦ -Z February 14 2 12 March 54 21 45 April 16 18 43 May 9 31 21 June 12 18 15 July 17 7 25 August 23 19 29 September 11 6 34 October 8 22 20 November 20 8 32 December 12 16 28 30 </seg>
         <seg id="p041">Claimant appeals numbered 130, or about 77 per cent of all appeal cases disposed of during 1939, while employer ap - peals accounted for 38 cases disposed of, or about 23 per cent. Benefit Duration An important feature of an unemployment compensation program is the one dealing with the duration provisions of the law. Besides the weekly benefit amount, the duration pro - visions determine the claimant's total rights to benefits and the effect of the program on his security against loss of wages and against the hazards of-unemployment. ; ..¦' •¦..:•:!¦.-.'."-¦ |- ' ¦-'• Due to the nature and characteristics of the duration fea - ture of the Law, it is not possible to secure a quantitative measure of the actual duration of compensable unemployment until the close of the claimant's benefit year. Since the benefit years established during the calendar year 1939 do not end until 1940, analysis of actual duration must wait until that time. Potential duration information, while available at the time of the establishment of the benefit year, is most useful when compared to actual duration. This information will become available during the year 1940 and will be included in the next annual report. 31 </seg>
         <seg id="p042"/>
         <seg id="p043">-IV- .;. ' j- CONTRIBUTIONS AND COVERAGE ! Collections of Contributions and Interest : ¦ \-\z z'z ¦:-"¦.:•¦¦ :', '! ::: The total of all collections during the year 1939 amounted to $4,106,916.95, or an increase of 5.8 per cent over 1938 con - tribution collections, excluding the credit received from the Federal Government for 1936 collections. Several factors aside from tbe difference in the amount of covered pay rolls for the two years cooperated to bring about changes in the total collections. Collections during 1939 were reduced be - cause of the elimination from the coverage of the Nebraska Law of employers engaged in interstate railroads. Contribu - tions based on wages paid to railroad workers were paid to the Railroad Retirement Board effective with the month of July, 1939. On the other hand, interest earned on the Fund was 162 pei/ cent greater because of a continuously larger bal - ance deposited in the United States Treasury to the credit of the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Fund. A small increase was also recorded in collections from employers rep - resenting payment of interest on delinquent contributions. Another factor affecting the relative collections for the two years was the fact that approximately one-fourth of the 1938 collections were on 1937 pay rolls, during which time the effective contribution rate was 1.8 per cent rather than 2.7 per cent. The net effect of the factors of the difference in rates for orie quarter's collections, loss of the railroad collec - tions, increase in Trust/Fund interest and the difference in covered pay roll was that collections were $216,037.48 above the 1938 level. The monthly and cumulative collections are shown in the following table classified by source: 33 </seg>
         <seg id="p044">TABLE 9: Cash Collections During Calendar Months from All Sources to the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Fund Trußt lintP Total Net Kmployor Emploj-or Fund Conßresslonal Collections Contributions Interest Interest Appropriation TOTAL 51U45.450.00 $9.547,-17.32 $10.»01-44 $250,402.24 yi.330,835.00 IKI7 .. 1.930.874.07 1.030,448.72 420.25 lias .-..1M.fi04.9S 3.097,370.1)0 4,734.73 71,723.79 1,330,535.90 11)311 Total 4.100,910.93 3.913.405.04 :i,530.4U 157,C75.45 January 1.051,589.90 1,011,053.33 484.22 40,052.35 . _ ¦ February 70,921.20 70.371.55 549.41 .March 14.fi12.n0 14.333.8) 478.01 April T72.30.5.US 72f1.2U7.93 '.(54.82 45,115.93 May 18f1,223.8S 155.913.44 312.44 .June 0.490.32 0,183.51 312.81 July ... 945,919.21 59«,995.29 159.27 48,704.05 August 124.5.55.24 123.993.2il 391.95 _ _ September 12.500.01 12,207.08 :B2.!l'l October (i5a.4!)8.(10 (05,102.42 390.12 53,745.52 .. November 211.510.92 210,770.32 734.00 December 14.025.37 14.119.09 509.28 _ _ Contribution collections received during 1939 based on taxable wages amounted to $3,913,408.04. Total collections from all sources, including the 1936 Congressional refund, amounted to $11.1 million since the program was first inaugu - rated. A total of $259.4 thousand was received from interest on the funds deposited in the United States Treasury. The statement of cash receipts and disbursements shown in Exhibit A-2 of Appendix A shows the collection transac - tions during the year 1939 with respect to the various ac - counts maintained in the Unemployment Compensation Fund. The 1939 receipts of interest on the Fund amounted to $187, - -678.45, while interest from employers on account of delinquent contributions amounted to $5,830.46. The above figures refer to collections received during the year 1939. Because the due date for contributions payable on the basis of wages paid by employers during the fourth - quarter of 1939 is January 31, 1940, the collections for this period are not received until that date. The accompanying table shows the amount of contributions and interest collected on taxable wages paid during the four quarters of 1939, as well as collections received for taxable wages, paid during the years 1937 and 1938: 34 </seg>
         <seg id="p045">TABLE 10: Total Cumulativt Colloctioiii to tho Nobraska UMm^oyawNt Compamation Fund from All Sources, Classified hjr Parted for Which' Payments War*. Mad* Total Collections Contributions' Date — —: ———— ———-..: Interest 1 Aye. Qtr. 1 Aye. Qtr.» Amount Collections Amount Collections TOTAL ....:. n2.283.968.7-5 $1,017,183.82= $11,054,118.02 $ 906,_».57« $320,8)0.13 ¦i:- : : I 1930 1,330,835.00 008,120.02 1,330,835.00 908,126.02 _ 1037 _ 2,820,007.40 1,057,727.80 2,800,515.73 1,053,508.40 11,001.73 1938 4,080,311.64 1,020,077.01 3,968,700.48 092,170.02 111,603.16 1939... .4,052,213.75 992,802.75 5 3,845,000.51 (MLO-MC 207,153.24 Ist Quarter.... 974,079.09 074,070.09 . 928,030.93 028,930.98 45,742.11 2nd Quarter.... 1,081,359.74 1,081,359.74 1,032,245.09 1,032,245.09 49,114.63 3rd Quarter .... 887,404.20 887,404.20 : 833,008.08 833,508.08 53,805.0. 4th Quarter .... 1,027,707.04 1,027,707.04 909,300.08 009,300.08 08,400.90 Voluntary ...- 81,003.08 81,003.0S Quarterly contribution collections for wages payable dur - ing 1939 were greatest for the second quarter when they amounted to $1,032,245.09. The marked decrease in contri - butions between 1 the second and third quarter was due pri - marily to the elimination of railroads from the coverage of the Law. Interest collections increased during each quarter of the year, amounting to $58,400.96 for the fourth quarter. Contributions collected for wages payable in the four calendar quarters of 1939 classified by industry are shown in Table B-l of Appendix B. In connection with payment of contributions, the Statute permits a voluntary payment over and above contributions required under the l&amp;w. With the inauguration of experience rating in Nebraska, voluntary contributions were made by employers with respect to qualifying for and meeting certain standards set up in the Statute and experience rating plan. These contributions, received during the latter part of January, 1940, were credited with respect to experience rat - ing to the reserve accounts as of December 31,1939. 'Quarterly average collections, Including Interest, were converted to an equiva - lent of 2.7 per cent of taxable wages, ] . :For the purpose of this table, the Congressional appropriation Is classified as. contributions.;: "Quarterly average contributions were converted to an equivalent of 2.7 per cent of taxable-wages. :'¦¦¦•¦ ,V. ; '.' •Flgntes include Interest on Trust Fund deposits In the United States Treasury and employer penalty Interest. 'Does not Include voluntary contributions. 35 </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Number of Employers, Wage Items and Workers At the close of the year 1939, 3,410 employers were sub - ject to the provisions of the Unemployment Compensation Law, reporting contributions under 3,688 different reporting units. A slight increase was reported over the close of the previous calendar year when 3,337 employers were reporting under 3,637 different reporting units. During the year 34 em - ployers classified as railroad employers were eliminated from the coverage of the Nebraska Law and transferred to the coverage of the Railroad Retirement Board. Wages for individual workers are reported by subject em* ployers to the Division on a quarterly report listing the Social Security number, quarterly wages, full-time weekly wage and other information for each worker. This information is re - ported to the Division on the same report that covers the summary wages and contributions and is used for the deter - mination of benefit rights. During the year 1939, 561,229 individual wage items were received by the Division. These individual records of earnings from Nebraska employers required extensive pro - cessing preparatory to their use in determining base period wage credits. It is estimated that in 1939 approximately 162,000 Ne - braska workers, excluding railroad workers, earned some wages in employment covered by the Law. This includes workers who earned all of their wages in covered employment, and those who earned a part of their annual wages in covered employment and a part in employment not covered by the Act. It also includes workers who earned some wages in covered employment and who subsequently became unemployed. The monthly average of employment covered by the Law for the calendar year 1939 was 102,267. This compared with a monthly average volume for 1938 of 99,862, with railroad employment excluded. A classification of the monthly volume of covered employment during 1939 by industry is shown in Table B-3 of Appendix B. 36 </seg>
         <seg id="p047">Wages Pay rolls of Nebraska employers subject to the taxing provisions of the Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Law amounted to $138.00 million for the year 1939. This amount includes wages paid to railroad workers only during the first two calendar quarters and is not, therefore, comparable with the total wages subject to the Law for the years 1987 and 1938. The total of all wages, including wages paid to railroad workers, that were subject to the provisions of the Law for the years'l937 through 1939 are as follows: Calendar Total Subject Year Wages 1937 -.......—........—-.—...:..........„.5156,678,196 1938 :...............:. ...147,447,075 1939 ................;......— ... 138,001,453 Inasmuch as wages paid to railroad workers were no longer subject to the Nebraska Law after June' 30,1939, and since all railroad contributions after deducting benefits paid were transferred to the Railroad Retirement Board, an adjust - ment for railroad wages should be made in the above figures. Total wages adjusted for wages paid to railroad workers for the three years, 1937,1938 and 1939, are as follows: Total Wages Excluding Calendar Total Wages Railroad Wages Railroads -Year (In Millions) (InMUlions). (In Millions) 1937 $156.7 $34.5 $122.2 1938 147.4 30.6 116.8 1939 138.0 15.3 122.7 The level of 1939 wages subject to the Law, exdudiOg railroad wages', closely approximated the 1937 level of $122.2 million. Wages subject to contribution during the calendar year 1940 will be lessened, because of the limitation of indi - vidual wages to the first $3,000. The amount of 1939 wages and the amount of wages for each calendar quarter during 1939 classified by industry are shown in Table B-2 of Appendix B. 37 </seg>
         <seg id="p048">-v - -1939 AMENDMENTS TO THE LAW Historically, a characteristic of a social insurance pro - gram designed on a compulsory basis is that legislative modi - fications are frequently required. Legislative review] and modification are particularly important and necessary in the early life of a public program such as unemployment compen - sation after the accumulation of experience and testing of certain provisions. It is admittedly difficult, and 'in some re - spects impossible, to draft original legislation designed to al - leviate the consequences of unemployment without finding that subsequent amendments are essential, not only with re - spect to carrying out and achieving more effectively the basic objectives, purpose and intent of the law, but also with respect to administering and simplifying the features of the law. The amendments of 1939 emphasized principally the simplification of the benefit formula. Amendments were made, however, to other sections of the Law dictated by changes in the Federal Law, employer demands for disqualifications, the position of labor with respect to the pool, and the need for clarifying and strengthening other provisions of the Law. The original Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Law was passed and approved in April, 1937 after the 1936 special session failed to adopt the legislation. The 1936 rejected bill was based on a draft Unemployment Compensation Law pre - pared by the Social Security Board in January, 1936. Legis - lative Bill No. 189 passed in April, 1937 was based on a draft bill prepared by the Social Security Board in January, 1937. The draft bill provisions relating to benefit payments were incorporated in the Nebraska bill with very little modification. These benefit provisions of the draft bill were accepted by most states. As a result of the experience of states that began benefit payments in January, 1938, it became apparent that changes would have to be made in the benefit provisions, not 38 </seg>
         <seg id="p049">only from the point of view of administrative requirements, but I also from the point of view of administrative cost and sim - plicity for the worker and the employer. I Legislative Bills Affecting Unemployment Compensation i '\ On this basis the Division recommended certain modifica - tions in the benefit formula. These changes, plus other! miscll- 1 laneous modifications, were incorporated in Legislative Bill- No. 447. Besides L. B. No. 447, four other bills were intrL duced in the 53rd session of the Nebraska Legislature that affected the administration of Unemployment Compen_atiofc. These bills were Legislative Bills No. 308, 448, 271 and' 44. ¦: Legislative Bill No J 308 provided' for the conloliddtion c f alii functions, powers and duties of the Department of fobof with the Workmen's Compensation Court. This bill wSs irf. definitely postponed in committee. Legislative Bill No' 448, introduced by represenijatives of Is bor, provided for i pool fund with merit rating. This.bill Was likewise indefinitely: postponed in committee. Legislate ; Bill No. 271, providing! for more stringent disqualifications of individuals fron-fceW fits, was introduced by representatives 6f Nebraska empKoyerii After several conferences with representatives of employer^ and workers, certain modified,provisjons of LB. No. 271 Werlil consolidated with L. B. No. 447. , . fII -¦ I T ¦¦&lt;'. • . ¦ -II I i'¦ :' .- ' M j Legislative Bill No. 44 was sponsored by representatives'! of employers and was introduced for the purpose of securing! J credit to the individual employer reserve accounts for .Tifldl IX taxes paid to the U. S. Treasury for the year 1936. After}!} aniamendment providing for one-half of the fund bfeingjf credited to the reserves and'the other half to the pool was' eliminated, this bill became effective! June 2, 1939 in itall original form as introduced. [ I'M _ ZZ After consolidation of certain modified provisions iof L. B. No. 271, L. B. No. 447 was subsequently amended to in- ¦ elude a provision for crediting to the pooled account of the Un - employment Compensation Fund a certain per centj of cotitifir butipns under certain conditions, and allowing a certain anioUnt of remuneration to be paid to the Commissionerof LabOr from the Unemployment Compensation Adminiatßation 39 </seg>
         <seg id="p050">Fund. Amendments to the Unemployment Compensation Law made by the 53rd session of the Nebraska Legislature were incorporated in L. B. No. 447 and No. 44. An outline of the main provisions of these bills is included in the following ex - planation. Explanation of Legislative Bill No. 447 L. B. No. 447 as amended was passed by the Legislature and was effective June 5, 1939. This bill was a combination of the original L. B. No. 447 as changed in committee and amended on the floor of the Legislature and L. B. No. 271, providing for disqualification of claimants. The bill in general provided for changes in the benefit formula directed toward simplification, more stringent disqualification provisions in the payment of claims for benefits, elimination of railroad workers from coverage of the Nebraska Law and other miscel - laneous changes, including lengthening of time for termina - tion of coverage, setting up legal procedures for collection of delinquent contributions, etc. An outline of the changes made in the Law is as follows: Changes in the Benefit Formula 1 Base Period. —The base period includes the first four out of the last five completed calendar quarters preceding the first day of an individual's benefit year. The Law fixes the base period to four calendar quarters, whereas the old Law pro - vided for an extensible base period of eight calendar quarters. The change in the base period was made to eliminate the ex - tensible feature of the base period, as well as the overlapping of successive base periods. The shortening of the base period to four quarters was compensated for from the point of view of total benefits by increasing the ratio of benefits to wages in the base period from one-sixth to one-third. The base period is used for the determination of the ratio of benefits, the week - ly benefit amount, and also, under the present Law, for the determination of eligibility for benefits. 'CliaiijrrK iii the benefit formula were bused principally on suggestions ot tbe Bureau ot Unemployment Compensation ot tbe Social Security Board In its "Interim Iteport on simplification of tlie Benefit Formula In State Unemployment Compensa - tion Lairs", Social Security Board, Washington, D. C, October 3, 1938, and otber memoranda prepared by tbe Social Security Board, Including "Quantitative Analyst* of Unemployment Compensation Simplification Proposals", Social Se - curity Board, Washington, D. C, October. 1838. 40 </seg>
         <seg id="p051">Qualifying Wages.—For the purpose of determination of eligibility for benefits, the old Law provided that the individual must earn at least sixteen times his weekly benefit amount in the first three out of the last four completed calendar quarters. This provision was modified to provide that an individual, to be eligible for benefits, must have earned thirty times his weekly benefit amount during the amended definition of a base period; that is, the first four out of the last five completed calendar quarters preceding the first day of an individual's benefit year. Benefit Year.— The benefit year is established with the first day of the first week with respect to which an individual files a valid claim, rather than the first day of the week with respect to which benefits are first payable. A claim is valid if the claimant earned thirty times his weekly benefit amount in insured work within his base period. Weekly Benefit Amount.— -Fifty per cent of full-time weekly wage was retained as the basis for computing weekly benefit amount, but a $5.00 absolute minimum was added, as well as rounding off the benefit amount to the nearest multiple of $1.00. The $15.00 weekly benefit amount was retained as the maximum. However, in cases where the full-time weekly wage is not available, the ratio for computing the full-time weekly'wage was changed from one-thirteenth of the highest quarter earnings to eight per cent. Duration of Benefits. —In view of changing the base period from eight to four calendar quarters, the duration of benefits was changed from one-sixth of wage credits in the base period, or $390.00 per calendar quarter, whichever is the lesser, to one-third of wages earned in the base period with no quarterly maximum. The total amount is also computed to the nearest multiple of $1.00. Sixteen times the weekly benefit amount limitation is retained in the amended Law. Waiting Period.— The waiting period was limited to two weeks in a benefit year, which are served after the beginning of the benefit year. '¦¦ZZ Disqualifications " Voluntary Leave Without Good Cause. —Any individual who has left work 1 voluntarily without good cause, as deter- 41 </seg>
         <seg id="p052">mined by the Commissioner, is disqualified for any week that he does not report in person to a Nebraska State Employment Service office. Misconduct. —ln case misconduct of an individual is gross, flagrant and willful, or is unlawful, all wage credits earned prior to such misconduct shall be cancelled with respect to determination of benefit rights. Acceptance of Suitable Work. —If the Commissioner finds that a claimant has refused to accept suitable work when of - fered to him, all wage credits earned prior to such refusal will be cancelled with respect, to benefit rights. Deductions for Remuneration Other Than Wages.—lf - the claimant receives a retirement pension, other gratuity, or bonus from the employer paid on account of length of service, or for disability not compensated by the Workmen's Compen - sation Law, the weekly prorated amount is deducted from the weekly benefit rate when determining the amount of benefits paid. Receiving or Seeking Other Unemployment Benefits.—lf a claimant is receiving or seeking unemployment benefits under an unemployment compensation law of any state in the United States, he is disqualified during any week he receives or seeks such benefits. High Earnings.—A claimant is disqualified for two months if he has received a fixed salary of $200.00 a month, or $50.00 a week during a specified period and under certain conditions. A notification of these earnings must be made by the employer within five days after separation of an em - ployee. Students. —A person who is registered for full attendance at and regularly attends an established school, college or uni - versity, or has so attended during the most recent school term, is disqualified for any week of unemployment. Disciplinary Suspension. —Partially or totally unem - ployed persons suspended for disciplinary reasons are dis - qualified for not more than thirty days. 42 </seg>
         <seg id="p053">Separation on Account of Marriage.— -If the employment of a female individual is discontinued because of marriage, wage credits prior to her marriage cannot be used in deter - mining benefit rights. ;.¦¦;•¦'. Railroad Coverage The Unemployment Compensation Law will not cover workers employed by railroad employers as defined by the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act, 52 Stat. 1094, after June 30,1939. The Law provides for the transfer of funds to the Railroad Retirement Board on the basis of a preliminary amount as of July 5, and a liquidating amount as of December 31, 1939. The Law also provides for cooperation with the Railroad Retirement Board with respect to the administra - tion of unemployment insurance. Partial Benefits The definition of unemployment under the amended Law provides that an individual shall be deemed unemployed and eligible for partial benefits in any week of less than full-time work, if the wages payable to him with respect to such week are less than his weekly benefit amount. The weekly benefit for unemployment will be paid to an individual for any week of unemployment in an amount equal to his weekly benefit amount, less;that part of any wages payable which is in ex - cess of $3.00. Such benefits shall also be computed to the nearest multiple of $1.00. The Statute also enables the Com - missioner to prescribe special regulations for individuals at - tached to regular jobs in connection with the administration of partial benefits. '¦: '¦•• • ¦•-:'¦'¦[ Z -.'. '.;'"'" '";'"::••-: :'v '''..': '' "' ' Miscellaneous Changes Resources to Pooled Account.—lf the pool balance on the first day of any calendar quarter is less than $100,000, one - fourth of one per cent of the wages payable during the next six months will be credited to the pooled account. This rate for the six-month period will prevail regardless of the contri - bution rate as determined by the merit rating provision of the Law. .. Legal Action for Collections.— The Statute provides that the Commissioner may determine the amount due from an 43 </seg>
         <seg id="p054">employer who has been determined subject to the Law and who failed to file a report or return required by the Commis - sioner. It also provides for the recording of a statement in the chattel mortgage records and the real estate mortgage records of any county, showing the amount of contributions and interest in default. This statement will operate as a lien and mortgage on all personal property of the employer subject to the taxes and liens of prior record. The procedure for a successive employer's liability is also provided for in the amended Law. Charging Employers. —The Unemployment Compensation Law as amended provides for the charging of benefits against the account of the claimant's most recent employer within his base period. This will not necessitate a change in pro - cedure inasmuch as the State Attorney General previously interpreted the Statute to mean that charges should be made on the basis of the most recent employers within the base period. The Statute was changed to give administrative clari - fication to the existing procedure. Due to changing of dura - tion from one-sixth to one-third, the maximum charge against the employer reserve was likewise changed from one-sixth to one-third of the wages payable by the employer with no limi - tation for calendar quarters. Remuneration of Commissioner. —The Commissioner of Labor, for services performed in connection with the admin - istration of the Unemployment Compensation Law, will re - ceive $1,200 per annum from the Unemployment Compensa - tion Administration Fund in addition to the State salary as Commissioner of Labor. Personnel Bond Premium. —The amended Unemployment Compensation Law permits the payment from the Unemploy - ment Compensation Administration Fund of bond premiums of the employees in the Division who are required to work under bond. Explanation of Legislative Bill No. 44 L. B. No. 44 became effective June 2,1939. This bill pro - vided for the crediting of 1936 Title IX taxes to the individual employer reserve accounts of employers subject to the Law as 44 </seg>
         <seg id="p055">of the effective date of the bill. Inasmuch as Nebraska did not have ani Unemployment Compensation Law during 1936, an amount of $1,330,835.90 was appropriated by Congress to the Unemployment Compensation Fund 1 representing 1936 tax payments by Nebraska employers under Title IX of the Social Security Act which were made to the U. S. Treasury. Nebraska was one of thirteen states to receive a part of the Congressional appropriation. 2 ¦'¦'¦¦¦¦ -I .'¦¦'-.¦''.¦ . ¦''¦:' The bill provided that proof of payment must be filed Within sixtyjdays after June 2,1939 by the employer who paid the tax, 4 such tax being paid on or before January 31,1938. -I- '-'.•'¦•-' -.'-.- ¦'.¦•¦-.¦'¦..¦•'¦¦ The amount of the 1936 refund not credited to the em - ployers' reserve on the basis of valid claims filed within the sixty-day period must be credited to the pooled account of the Unemployment Compensation Fund. • r ."¦¦ .'¦.'"¦'. ! ¦¦ '"- "¦'.-' :' . ¦•'¦ - ¦ " ''•'-. Diipotition of Funds According- to Legislative till No. 44 In connection with the disposition of moneys as provided for in L. B. No. 44, $1,124,936.81 or 84.5 per cent of the total amount appropriated by Congress was credited to the indi - vidual employer reserve accounts as of December 31, 1939. Of the total amount, 15.5 per cent, or $205,899.09, was credited to the pooled account as of December 31, 1939. Disposition of the total amount is shown in the accompanying table: TABLE H: Ditpotitiofl of Moneys Appropriated by Confma In Accoitfaiico Wfth tho Prevision, ot L. B. No. 44 RopuMontiiif 1936 Tax Paymoiitf Vnast TiHo IX of ttio Social Socyrity Act Per Allocation Amount Cent Appropriated by C0ngre55..........—.........51,330,835.90 100.0 Credited to Employers as of 12-31-39 1,124,936.81 84.5 Credited to Pool as of 12-31-39.......... 205,899.09 15.5 •Pursuant to Act of Congress, I'lllilie Xo. SKI, 73th Congress* Chapter 735, Ist Session. •The totnl amount of the appropriation to the thirteen states was jM0,501,896&gt;j13. •A question Involving this Issue was raised In the case of Wilson and Co., Inc. vs. Kinney, Commissioner, decided In Dlst. Court of Lancaster Co., Nebr. In this case the court held that an employer who acquired the business of a subject em - ployer, under the provisions of Sec. 48-707(f) stood in the position of his predecessor and was entitled to credit for payments made by his predecessor,, 45 </seg>
         <seg id="p056">While 84.5 per cent of the total amount appropriated by Congress was credited to the individual employer reserves, only 1,643 employers, or 49.4 per cent of all employers, re - ceived such credit. Because of failure to submit a claim, or because of rejection of the claim, 1,686 employers or 50.6 per cent did not receive credit for the Congressional appropria - tion. The accompanying table indicates the number of em - ployers and the number of reporting units that did or did not receive 1936 credit: TABLE 12: Number and Per Cent of Employers and Reporting Units That Received Credit for 1936 Tax Payments Ai Provided for in L. B. No. 44 Number Number Per Reporting- Per Employers Employers Cent Units Cent Subject June 1, 1939 3,329 100.0 3,628 100.0 Received 1936 Credit as of 12-31-39 1,643 49.4 1,731 47.7 Did Not Receive 1936 Credit 1,686 50.6 1,897 52.3 -- It is apparent from the above that a large number of small employers did not receive credit based on the provisions of L. B. No. 44. The credit was received principally by firms with large pay rolls. 46 </seg>
         <seg id="p057">-V - l EXPERIENCE RATINC The concept of varying individual employer contribution rates in, the field of unemployment compensation has been carried over from the field of workmen's compensation. The plan for varying individual employer contribution rates based on the experience of paying benefits was incorporated in the Wisconsin Law prior to the passage of the Social Security Act. It was subsequently made a part of the original Title IX of the Social Security Act, relating to standards for state laws. The Federal Law permitted a state to adopt either an individual reserve type of law or a pool fund type of law. While a majority of the states adopted a pool fund type of law with a system of variable rates, Nebraska was one of five states that accepted the individual reserve plan of unem - ployment compensation. The principal objective of the system of individual vari - able rates in the field of unemployment compensation is to provide an incentive for regularizing employment. This ob - jective parallels that incorporated in rating schemes for work - men's compensation. An additional justification advanced for a system of variable contribution rates in unemployment com - pensation is that of allocating the cost of unemployment to the firms that are presumably responsible for the unemploy - ment. Statutory Standards Provisions of the Internal Revenue Code as amended, Sec - tion 1601 (h), are that credits can be applied" against the Federal unemployment tax of three per cent of wages in ad - dition to the normal credit based on contributions paid to the state fund, if the state law meets certain conditions set out in Section 1602. The conditions of additional credit allowance for a state with a reserve fund type of law are: (1) Compensation must be payable from the reserve ac - . count throughout the preceding calendar year; 47 </seg>
         <seg id="p058">(2) Such account (balance) amounts to not less than five times the largest amount of compensation paid from such account within any one of the three preceding calendar years; and (3) Such account (balance) amounts to not less than 7.5 per cent of the total wages payable by him in the preceding calendar year. On the basis of the above standard number one, the State is permitted to vary individual contribution rates beginning with the calendar year 1940, inasmuch as benefits were pay - able from the majority of the accounts throughout the calen - dar year 1939. However, due to the fact that 1.8 per cent of taxable wages was collected for the year 1937, and 2.7 per cent of wages was collected for each of the years 1938 and 1939, a total of only 7.2 per cent of taxable wages was col - lected through the calendar year 1939 for a firm with a con - stant pay roll. This fell short of meeting the 7.5 per cent indi - vidual reserve requirement incorporated in the third standard indicated above. This deficiency in meeting the requirement of the 7.5 per cent reserve balance standard was overcome by the passage of L. B. No. 44 during the 1939 term of the Legislature. The source of this credit was in the failure of the 1936 special ses - sion of the Legislature to pass an unemployment compensa - tion law. Due to the fact that the Federal excise tax of nine - tenths of one per cent of pay roll was effective with the calen - dar year 1936, these funds were collected one hundred per cent by the Bureau of Internal Revenue and credited to the General Fund of the United States Treasury. Nebraska was one of thirteen states that failed to pass an unemployment compensation law effective in the year 1936. By act of Congress the funds collected for the calendar year 1936 were prorated to the Unemployment Compensation Funds of the thirteen states involved. Nebraska's refund in this connection amounted to '$_, - -330,835.90. This amount was received and credited to the Unemployment Trust Fund in Washington during the month of June, 1938 in accordance with H. R. 8174. The 1939 Ne - braska Legislature provided that these funds should be 48 </seg>
         <seg id="p059">credited to the individual employer reserves under certain specified conditions set forth in L. B. No. 44. Provisions of this bill are described on page 44 of this report. This per - mitted a possible accumulation of 8.1 per cent for a firm with a constant pay roll from the year 1936 through the year 1939. The failure to pass a Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Law effective with the year 1936 postponed the beginning of benefit payments from January 1,1938 to January 1,1939. Because contribution collections were effective January 1, 1937, and because 1936 collections were returned from the Federal Government, the State fund accumulated three years of contribution collections prior to the beginning of benefit operations rather than two years of contributions. This con - dition placed the fund at an advantage over those states that passed an unemployment compensation law effective with the year 1936. . As indicated previously, the standards that are incorpo - rated in the Federal Statute are also included in the Nebraska Law, Section 48-707 (c). 1940 Variable Rate Plan No provision, however, is made in the Nebraska Law for the method of determining the individual rate after a firm meets the statutory requirements other than a general re - quirement that, "... contributions shall be only in such a per centum, not exceeding 2.7 per centum,, as the commissioner finds necessary to maintain such reserve account at seven and one-half per centum of his annual pay roll during the ensuing calendar year." This requirement placed a burden on the Commissioner to determine the method of fixing individual employer rates for the calendar year 1940 to meet the general requirements of this Section of the Law. Accordingly, a study was made of the possible methods that could be used, and a proposed plan was set forth under date of November 10, 1939. 1 Assistance 'This method Is incorporated in a memorandum entitled, "Technical Details of Sating Employers for Variable ItMO Contribution Bates Based on Experience Under the.Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Law", Department ot Labor, Nebraska Unemployment Compensation Division, Research and Statistics. 49 </seg>
         <seg id="p060">and advice during the course of the study were secured from a special committee of the Unemployment Compensation Ad - visory Council, consisting of a faculty member of the Uni - versities of Creighton, Wesleyan and Nebraska. This method provided for a rating based on a compari - son of cumulative benefit experience and cumulative contribu - tion experience through December 31, 1939 -with interval groupings of the experience indexes to establish four rates below the standard rate of 2.7 per cent; namely, 2.5 per cent, 2.0 per cent, 1.5 per cent, 1.0 per cent. This comparison of the aggregate individual employer's benefit experience and the aggregate employer's contribution experience was termed the "disbursement ratio." The plan for 1940 rate variations was presented at a general public hearing and subsequently for - mally adopted and promulgated on December 5, 1939 by the Commissioner of Labor in the form of a general rule. This rule is entitled, "Rule V, Contributions by Employers for 1940." Details of this rule are set forth in Appendix A of this report. As a part of the administrative design of rating indi - vidual employers for the calendar year 1940, it was determined that all contributions with respect to 1939 or prior years of employment which were received on or before January 31, 1940 be credited to the reserve accounts; and all benefits paid on or before January 31, 1940 which were for weeks of unem - ployment within the year 1939 should be charged to the indi - vidual reserve accounts. The same consideration that was given to required contributions was also given with respect to voluntary contributions if received on or before January 31,1940. Firms and Pay Roll in Various Rate Groups Based on the provisions of Rule V, individual employer rates were determined for wages payable during the calendar year 1940. Of 3,395 employers subject to the Law as of De - cember 31, 1939, 2,321 or 68.3 per cent received the standard rate of 2.7 per cent for the year 1940. The remaining 1,074 or 31.7 per cent of the total number of active accounts as of December 31, 1939, received a rate lower than the standard 50 </seg>
         <seg id="p061">2.7 per cent, ranging from 2.5 per cent to 1.0 per cent. Most of the accounts that received a rate lower than 2.7 per cent are located in the 1.0 per cent rate group. The following table shows the number of employers, the amount of annual pay roll and the mean annual pay roll, classified by contribu - tion rates effective for the calendar year 1940: TABLE 13: Number of Employers, Amount of Annual Pay Roll and Maan Annual Pay Roll Clsasffied by Contribution Rates Effective for Calendar Year IMO Employers) IMO Estimated Pay Roll Mean 1010 Effective Itnte ¦ — ; —— . — Annnnl .Number.' Ver Amount Per Pay Roll Cent (In Thousands) Cent TOTAL (Aye. Rate 1.896%) 3,395 100.6 $115,392.21 100.0 $33,9791 2.7% Standard .................... 2,321 68.3 57,089.9 49.5 24,587 Lower Than Standard 2,7% 1,074 31.7 58,302.3 50.5 54,285 2.5 per cent. 27 0.8 ! 518.8 0.5 19,954 2.0 per cent............. 43 * 1.3 1,277.9 1.1 29,719 ¦-, 1.5 per cent....... 82 2.5 ' 8,462.3 7.3 100,472 1.0 per cent...:..,..: ....j 922 27.1 48,043.3 41.6 52,164 ¦ i V As shown in the above table the larger employers in Ne - braska received rates of contributions lower than the stand - ard 2.7 per cent. The average annual pay roll for firms that have a contribution rate lower than the 2.7 per cent amounted to approximately ?54,300, While the average for employers with the 2.7 per cent rate amounted to $24,600. Similarly, the average of $54,300 for firms with a lower rate is approximate - ly 120,000 above the average of $34,000 for all employers sub - ject to the Law. Thisibias in the rates is due to a large extent to the distribution of moneys in accordance with the provi - sions of L. B. No. 44, which was passed by the 1939 session of the Nebraska Legislature. A large number of small firms did not secure credit under the provisions of that bill, \ With respect to pay rolls, it was found that 49.5 per cent of the 1939 pay roll would be subject to the standard rate of 'Adjusted for jirajjes In excess of fI.OOO per year per Indlvidiinl (lint are excluded from doflnciVwngcs effective for the cnlcmlnr yenr IWO. ) 51 </seg>
         <seg id="p062">2.7 per cent of pay rolls during the year 1940, while 50.5 per cent will be subject to rates ranging from 2.5 per cent to 1.0 per cent. The 40.5 per cent of pay roll that received a rate lower than the standard 2.7 per cent represented only 31.7 per cent of the total number of employers. The pay roll sub - ject to the 1.0 per cent rate accounts for approximately 80 per cent of the total wages subject to a rate lower than the standard 2.7 per cent. An industrial classification of firms with the various effective rates for 1940 is shown in Table B-13 of Appendix B. 1940 Contribution Yield It is estimated that the average yield of contributions to the Unemployment Compensation Fund for wages paid dur - ing the calendar year 1940 will be 1.896 per cent. This is a reduction in yield of .804 per cent from the standard rate of 2.7 per cent, or approximately 30 per cent fall in yield. The contribution collections for the year 1940 on a 2.7 per cent basis excluding the $3,000 statutory limitation are esti - mated at $3,279.6 thousand. Because of experience rating, contributions for 1940 will decline to an estimate of $2,302.5 thousand. Because of the change in the Nebraska Law im - posing a limitation of contribution liability to the first $3,000 of wages per worker, it is estimated that contribution collec - tions will further decline to $2,187.4 thousand. The following table shows the estimated contribution col - lections for the calendar year 1940 including the estimated contribution decline due to wage limitation and experience rating: TABLE 14; Estimated Contribution Collections for the Calendar Year 1940 Amount Per (In Thousands) Cent Estimated Contributions at 2.7% Standard Rate Without Wage Limitation $3,279.6 100.0 Estimated Contribution Yield for 1.940 2,187.4 66.7 Estimated Contribution Decline Due to: $3,000 Wage Limitation 115.1 3.5 Experience Rating 977.1 29.8 52 </seg>
         <seg id="p063">In estimating the contribution yield for the calendar year 1940 the 1939 pay rolls were used after correction for an estimate of wages in excess of $3,000 per individual work - er. The total state pay roll excluding railroads but including wages in excess of $3,000 per individual •»/__: $122.67 million in 1939; $116.81 million in 1938; $122.21 million in 1937. The estimate of $2,187.4 thousand as the 1940 contribution yield was based on the 1939 pay roll after correcting for the $3,000 individual wage limitation. Industry and Sixe-of-Firm Experience From the 1939 experience there is evidence that over a period of time the more favorable contribution rates will be {attained by firms engaged in finance, insurance and real estate, communications, and wholesale and retail trade. On the other jhand, such industries as construction, quarrying, service, and manufacturing will be burdened with the higher rates. The cost of 1939 benefits per $1,000 of 1939 pay roll amounted to $3.64 for finance, insurance and real estate, $4.14 for [utilities (excluding railroads), and $7.04 for wholesale and retail trade. On the other hand, the 1939 benefit cost per $1,000 of 1939 pay roll amounted to $36.78 in quarrying, $27.41 for construction, $37.17 for general contractors, and $8.87 for manufacturing. These.compared with a State experience of $8.85 for all industries. ~ | The following chart shows the benefit cost for industry divisions and the proportion of 1939 pay roll that iwill be subject for the year 1940 to a rate lower ;than the standard rate of 2.7 per cent: . 53 </seg>
         <seg id="p064"/>
         <seg id="p065"/>
         <seg id="p066">1939 EXPERIENCE BENEFITS AND VARIABLE RATES PERCENT OF PAYROLL AMOUNT OF BENEFITS WITH REDUCED RATES PER HDOO OF WAGES I|II II I STATE EXPERIENCE I I 1 I f*~ mm mtkm MNNG, QUARRYING, ANO MSCELLANEOUS L__^^_^^____^____i____iß____B_L„; CONSTRUCTION L U---l_____.-____l_____.l___ SERVICE v TRANSPORTATION MANUFACTURING ¦¦«4fflH- -- WHOLESALE ANO RETAIL «fH UTILITIES TTTTTTiri 1 ~~~ FINANCE, INSURANCE, AND REAL ESTATE I -_-B-_rnb i i i i i' i It should be pointed out that in any classification such as industry or size-of-firm, considerable variation is experienced from firm to firm within the group. This is apparent from the distribution of individual firm ratios contained in Table B-12 of Appendix B. As related to size of firm, the 1939 benefit cost per $1,000 54 </seg>
         <seg id="p067">of 1939 pay roll discloses that compensable unemployment for 1939 was more severe proportionally in the smaller thjan in the larger firms. While it is difficult to judge what amount of pay rolls constitute a large firm, particularly as it; relates to the Nebraska economic pattern, it was found for 1939 that the proportional benefit cost increased as the size of the (vari - ous firms decreased. The 1939 benefit cost per $1,000 of! 1939 wages was higher than the State average of $8.85 in the case of all pay roll groups of less than $50,000 of pay rojl, ranging from $11.34 for firms with a pay roll of $30,000 to $50,000 to $25.70 for firms with a pay roll of less than $5;000. All pay roll groups above $50,000 experienced a proportional benefit cost of less than the State average of $8.85. For these groups the cost varied from $8.57 per $1,000 of pay roll for firms with an annual pay roll of $50,000 to $100,000 to $6.631 for firms with an annual pay roll of $1,000,000 or more. Table B-14 of Appendix B shows the benefit! cost per $1,000 of wages for the industry groups and for the various size-of-firm groups. I Determination of Future Rates The experience rating plan adopted for the calendar year 1940 cannot be used for establishing) variable contribution rates for the year 1941 or for subsequent years. Furthermore, the Statute with respect to the fixing of individual rates places the Commissioner in a difficult, if not an impossible 'position, inasmuch as it provides that each individual reserve must be maintained at a given level during the course of the' ensuing calendar year, such level being determined on the basis of (the percentage of the ensuing calendar year's pay roll. This!in - volves a determination of rate based on the projection for each individual account of the ensuing! year's experience' in the payment of benefits, the receipt of contributions and the payment of wages subject to the provisions of the Act. These standards are impossible of realization! without considerable risk and without considerable dissatisfaction among employ - ers. An automatic method of rate determination should jbe incorporated in the Statute, and since Nebraska has the re - serve fund type of law, the reserve ratio method of rate de - termination should be given serious consideration. I 55 </seg>
         <seg id="p068">Required Legislative Amendments Certain changes should be made in Section 48-707 (c). during the 1941 legislative session to bring into conformity changes that have been made by the 1939 Congressional amendments in state standards for reserve fund states with respect to conditions of additional credit allowance. The new standards of the reserve fund states incorporated in Section 1602 (a) (4) of the Internal Revenue Code are as follows: "(3) No reduced rate of contributions to a reserve ac - count is permitted to a person (or group of persons) having individuals in his (or their) employ unless (A) compensation has been payable from such account throughout the year preceding the computation date, and (B) the balance of such account amounts to not less than five times the largest amount of compensa - tion paid from such account within any one of the • three years preceding such date, and (C) the balance of such account amounts to not less than 2V_ per centum of that part of the pay roll or pay rolls for the three years preceding such date by which contributions to such account were measured, and (D) such contribu - tions were payable to such account with respect to the three years preceding the computation date." The changes in the first standard from benefits payable throughout the preceding calendar year to benefits payable throughout the year preceding the computation date were made to permit a computation date other than January 1. A similar change of date is permitted with respect to the stand - ard of the reserve account balance being at least five times the largest amount of benefits paid within any one of the three preceding years. The third standard, however, changes the individual reserve requirement from 7.5 per cent of the single year pay roll to 2.5 per cent of the three preceding years' pay roll. The fourth standard, (D), is made necessary by tbe changing of the reserve balance requirement from 7.5 per cent to 2.5 per cent. 56 </seg>
         <seg id="p069">.-VII.-.' SUPPLEMENT Legislative ¦»•« No. 5,1940 Special Session The special session of the Legislature convened January 2,1940, Included in the Governor's call for a special session was an item relating to amendments of certain features of the Unemployment Compensation Law to bring them into closer conformity with changes that were made in Section 1600 of the Internal Revenue Code by passage of the 1939 amend - ments to the Social Security Act. ".; Accordingly, Legislative Bill No. 5 was introduced, amending certain definitions included in Section 48-702, Comp. Stat., Supp. 1939. The principal changes made in definitions included modification of the definition of wages and employ - ment. The Bill was passed by the Legislature and approved January 12,1940. The definition of wages included in Section 48-702 (m), Comp. Stat, Supp. 1939, was amended to limit taxable wages to the first $3,000 paid to an individual by an employer, with respect to employment during any calendar year. This change in definition of wages with respect to Section 1600, Internal Revenue Code, was effective January 1, 1940, being made by Congress to bring the definition of wages under Section 1600, Federal Unemployment Tax Act, into conformity with the $3,000 tax limit included in Section 1400 of the Internal Revenue Code known as the Federal Insurance Contribution Act. In addition to the exclusion of remuneration above $3,000 from the definition of taxable wages, the following payments made by an employer to or on {behalf of an individual in his employment were also excluded by L. B. No. 5: I (1) Payments on account of retirement, sickness or ac - cident disability, medical or hospitalization expense in connection-with sickness or accident disability, and death benefits under certain specified condi - tions! ¦ ''¦'¦ I. . 57 </seg>
         <seg id="p070">(2) Payment by an employer of a tax imposed upon an employee under the Federal Insurance Contribution Act, Section 1400 of Internal Revenue Code as amended. (3) Dismissal payments which the employer is not legal - ly required to make. The definition of employment was modified in several re - spects. In the first place, the term, "agricultural labor," was broadened to exclude certain types of agricultural labor and other labor previously included as subject employment under the Act, or whose previous inclusion or exclusion was not clearly defined or determinable. The term, "domestic serv - ice," was enlarged to include services performed in a local college, club or local chapter of a college fraternity or sorority. The term, "casual labor," was redefined to include only that labor not in the course of the employer's trade or business. Section 48-702 (h) (6) (F), relating to the exemption of services performed in the employ of the United States Gov - ernment or an instrumentality of the United States was modi - fied to permit the inclusion of certain instrumentalities such as national banks in the coverage of the Law. Section 48-702 (h) (6) (H), relating to the exemption of certain organizations, was broadened to exclude from exemp - tion activities carried on for propaganda or otherwise attempt - ing to influence legislation. Sections 48-702 (h) (6) (J), (X), (L) and (M) were added to the definition of employment. Section 48-702 (h) (6) (J) excludes services performed for an organization which is exempt from income tax under Section 101 of the Internal Revenue Code under certain specified conditions. Section 48 - -702 (h) (6) (X) exempts services performed by a student nurse and services performed as an interne under, certain conditions. Section 48-702 (h) (6) (L) exempts the services performed by an individual as an insurance agent or solicitor if remuneration for such services is solely by way of commis - sion. Section 48-702 (h) (6) (M) exempts the services of an individual under 18 years of age in delivery or distribution of newspapers or shopping news. 58 </seg>
         <seg id="p071">These changes in the definition of employment by Con - gress were likewise occasioned by the desire to make the definitions in Section 1600 uniform with Section 1400 of the Internal Revenue Code. Joint Regulation for Selection of Personnel on Merit Ban's As was pointed out in another section of this report, Con - gress passed the 1939 amendments to the Social Security Act in August, 1939, which included, among other changes in amendment to Title 111 of the Social Security Act, a provision for the selection of personnel on a merit basis. This amend - ment provided that after January 1,1940 the administration of the State Law must include the establishment and main - tenance of personnel standards on a merit basis. The stand - ards established and maintained under the State Law with respect to the Unemployment Compensation Division met the requirements of the Social Security Board in this respect. Due, however, to the fact that the same provision relat - ing to establishment and maintenance of personnel standards was included in other programs of the Social Security Act that involved State-Federal relationship—Department of State As - sistance and Child Welfare, Nebraska State Employment Service and the Department of Health—it was decided in the interests of economy and efficiency to establish joint regula - tions dealing with personnel selection. Therefore, joint regu - lations became effective February 20, 1940. These regulations provide for the conduct of examinations, establishment of classification and compensation plans, etc., as well as setting up a seven-member Merit System Council. 'The plan of operation with respect to Unemployment Compensation under the joint regulations will be substantially the same as under the former regulations. The Merit System Council will perform its work through a Merit System Super - visor. The Supervisor will be located separate and apart from any of the agencies included in the joint regulations. 59 </seg>
         <seg id="p072">APPENDIX A Page Exhibit A-l, Unemployment Compensation Fund Balance Sheet : 60 Exhibit A-2, Unemployment Compensation Fund Statement of Cash Receipts and Disbursements 61 Exhibit A-3, Rule V, Contributions by Employers for 1940 62 EXHIBIT A-1 UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION FUND BALANCE SHEET As of December 31, 1939 ASSETS Unemployment Compensation Fund Clearinir Account $ 0,918.76 Unemployment Trust Fund in U. S. Treasury: Reserved for Benefit Payments $7,824,124.36 Reserved for Payment to Railroad Unemployment Insurance Account 1,984,413.78 9,808,638.14 Unemployment Compensation Benefit Payment Account .—— 26,401.76 Contributions Receivable $ 62,967.85 Contributions Receivable Transferred to Suspense 4,152.28 Dishonored Checks Receivable 1,490.37 Total i $ 68,610.50 LESS— Unrealized Contributions 68,610.50 None Benefits Due from Claimants S 1,193.29 LESS—Reserve for Overpayments of Benefits 1,193.29 None TOTAL ASSETS j -t9.844.861.66 .1 LIABILITIES Overpayments of Contributions and Interest V 2,290.79 Unemployment Compensation Employers' Reserve: Contributions Credited to Employers' Reserve Accounts $8,673,319.49 Contributions Held in Suspense Pending Adjustment 6,939.18 Total $8,680,258.67 LESS—Benefits Charged to Employers' Reserve , 1,213,010.71 7,437,247.96 Reserve for Railroad Unemployment Insurance Settlement Account: Preliminary Amount . $1,491,668.91 Liquidating- Amount , 221,744.14 - 1936 Claims for f&gt;~«' 271,000.73 1,984,413.78 Unemployment Compensation Pool Reserve: Interest in U. S. Trust Fund Account $ 259,402.24 Transfers from Employers' Reserve Accounts 5,200.89 Interest Delinquent Employers' *"-—'"*» 16,622.19 Appropriation by Corikress 1936 Credits 205,899.09 Total ! $ 487,124.41 LESS—lnterest Receivable 5,630.75 I $ 481,493.66 LESS—Benefits Charned to Pool Reserve 60,584.63 420,900.13 TOTAL LIABILITIES , $9.844.861.66 60 </seg>
         <seg id="p073">EXHIiITA-2 UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION FUND STATEMENT OF CASH RECEIPTS AND DISBURSEMENTS For tka Yaar |anuary 1 Through Dacambn 31, 1939 Benefit Clearing- Trust Fund Payment Account Account Account Balance of Cash on Hand 1-1-39 _ $ 204,680.26 $6,856,859.69 None Collections: « Contributions: Year 1937 : : 27,988.49 Year 1938 . 1,123,661.44 Year 1839 ; 2,510,467.91 3,692,097.81 Add—lncrease in Contri - butions Held in Suspense v Pending-Adjustment—— 6,513.06 Net Contributions : _ 3,698,610.90 Railroad Contrlbutlor-—Liquidating Amount 221,744.14 Interest Earned on Trust Fund _ 187,678.45 Interest on Delinquent Employers' Accounts 6,004.86 Dishonored Contribution Cheeks Redeposited 11,910.78 Returned Benefit Cheeks—: ; :—: i 641.46 Refunds of Benefit Overpayments ' ¦ Ij- .—-.——• 2 Tmnnffni T- 4,114,000.00 1,330,000.00 Total Collections $3.938,270^68 I 4,30J,678.45 $1.330.928.17 Total to Account lor___ '. 44,142,950.94 $11,138,538.14 $1,330,928.17 Disbursements: „ „_, ' Benefits Paid— ; — 1,304,523.41 Refunds of Contributions—_ _ 6,183.80 i Dishonored Contribution Cheeks 12,848.38 ; j Transfers Out —— 4,114,000.00 1,330,000.00 Total Disbursements $4,133,032.18 $1,33^,000.00 $1,304,523.41 Balance of Cash On Hand 12-31-39 : -$ 9.918.76 $ 9.806,538.14 $ 26,404.76 61 </seg>
         <seg id="p074">EXHIBIT A-3 RULE V —CONTRIBUTIONS BY EMPLOYERS FOR 1940 1. The contribution rate for the year 1940 of any employer who fails to meet the requirements for a reduced rate as set out in Section 48-707 (c) shall be a sum equal to 2.7 per centum of wages payable by him for employment in said calendar year. 2. The contribution rate for the year 1940 of each employer who meets the requirements for a reduced rate as set out in Section 48-707 (c) shall be as follows: (a) Every such employer whose disbursement ratio for the preced - ing year was more than 13.5 per centum shall pay contributions at the rate of 2.5 per centum of ws ges payable by him for em - ployment. (b) Every such employer whose disbuisement ratio is more than 10.5 per centum but not more that 13.5 per centum shall pay contributions at the rate of 2 per centum of wages payable by him for employment. (c) Every such employer whose disbursement ratio is more than 7.5 per centum but not more than 10,5 per centum shall pay con - tributions at the rate of 1.5 per centum of wages payable by him for employment. I (d) Every such employer whose disbursement ratio is 7.5 per centum or less shall pay contributions at the rate of 1 per centum of wages payable by him for employment. 3. As used in this Rule, the term 'disbursement ratio' is the ratio of all benefits charged to an employer's reserve account within the calendar year 1939 to the total of all credits to his individual re - serve account at the beginning of the year 1940. 4. For the purposes of determining which employers are qualified for a lower rate and for determining experience rating and reserve bal - ances, all contributions with respect to 1939 or prior employment which are received on or before January 31, 1940, and all benefits paid with respect to weeks of unemployment within the year 1939 which are paid on or before January 31,1940, shall be considered as having been paid at the beginning of the year. Adopted December 5, 1939. V. B. Kinney, Commissioner of Labor. 62 </seg>
         <seg id="p075">APPENDIX B Page Table B-l, Amount of Contributions Received from Nebraska Em - ployers Covering Wages Payable for.the Calendar Year 1939 Credited to Individual Employer Reserves, Classified by Industry and Calendar Quarters...... „...;........ 64 Table B-2, Amount and per cent of Subject Wages Payable by Employers for the Calendar Year 1939, Classified by Industry and Calendar Quarters, ;.... 66 Table B-3, Monthly Volume of Covered Employment for the Calendar Year 1939, Classified by 1ndu5try.................;.......:...... 68 Table B-4, Amount of 1939 Benefits and Number of Weeks of Un - employment for Railroad and Nonrailroad Payments '¦ and Total, . : Part-Total and Partial Payments, Classified by Months 70 Table B-5, Number of Initial Claims, Weeks Compensated and Amount of Benefit Payments for Claimants Filing Their Claims From Offices Located Out of the State, Calendar Year 1939, Classi - fied by State in Which Claim Was Fi1ed.......... 71 Table B-6, Amount of Benefit Payments for Each Month of the Year 1939, Classified by Local Employment Service 0ffice............ 72 Table B-7, Number of Weeks Compensated for Each Month of the Year 1939, Classified by Local Employment Service Office...; 73 Table B-8, Number of Initial Claims Received Monthly During the Calendar Year 1939, Classified by Local 0ffice.......... 74 Table B-9, Number of Continued Claims Received Monthly During the Calendar Year 1939, Classified by Local 0ffice......... 75 Table B-io, Appeal Cases Disposed of During the Calendar Year 1939 Appealed by Claimants and Employers, Classified by Issue Involved . .....! ...............). 76' Table B-11, Benefits Chargeable to Pool as of Decembei 31, 1939, Classified by Industry ...' .......'. 77 Table B-12, Experience of Individual Employer-Reserve! Through ' the Calendar Year 1939, Classified by Industry and ly Size of Firm .....................................j........ ...........!. ....:......... 78 Table B-13, Number of Employers With Variable 1940 Contribution Rates, Classified by Industry and by Size of Firm..........„..„.... 80 Table B-14, Benefit and Contribution Experience and the ijlumber of Claimants, Classified by Industry and Size of Firm............................ 82 63 </seg>
         <seg id="p076">TABLE B-l: Amount of Contributions Received from Nebraska Employers for Wages Payable for the Calendar Year 1939 Credited to Individual Employer Reserves, Classified by Industry and Calendar Quarters 1 Total CALENDAR QUAnTER 11139 INDUSTRY tor Year Klrnt Second Third Fourth TOTAL, - - — 51,764.057.4.'l t JCT.iflC.m 11,«12,_15.09 $ 833.508.68 % | 06!),3C6."i3S CONSTRUCTION 217,941.18 a0.020.T8 67,751.15 68,5&lt;f1.48 61.607.15 Building Construction, General Contractors 74,858.01 8,889.21 16,984.25 24,941.99 24,042.59 General Contractors, Other Than Building 109,087.17 15,557.82 33,037.57 34,046.98 26,444.80 Construction, Special Trade Contractors 33,995.97 5,573.89 7,730.07 9,571.51 11,120.60 MANUFACTURING 986,585.63 209,934.49 233.885.19 242,092.98 300,662.97 Food and Kindred Products . 619,001.98 127,842.21 144.165.11 151,003.98 195,990.68 Apparel and Other Finished Products Made from Fabrics and Similar Materials 13.53G.51 3,323.81 3,702.82 3,128.84 3,381.04 Lumber and Timber Basic Products 10,973.52 2.179.05 2,500.23 2,821.2!) 3,472.95 Furniture and Finished Lumber Products 23,872.34 4,395.05 5,168.63 5,277.68 9,030.38 Paper and Allied Products 12,297.38 2,816.84 2,915.86 2,934.54 3,630.14 Printing;, Publishing-, and Allied Industries 126,519.71 30,518.03 32,057.93 30,819.64 33,124.11 Chemicals and Allied Products 29,206.47 6,135.20 7,001.39 7,196.69 8,873.19 Leather and Leather Products 4,748.87 1,114.33 1.133.17 1,225.80 1,275.51 Stone, Clay, and Glass Products — 26,790.72 5,272.07 7,095.53 7,176.63 7,246.49 Iron and Steel and Their Products 33,398.50 7,703.02 7,920.33 8,785.94 8,989.21 Nonferrous Metals and Their Products 17,753.42 3,845.95 ' 4,005.87 4,383.39 6,518.21 Electrical Machinery 6,000.97 1,207.04 1,199.22 1,477.80 2,116.1)1 Machinery (Except Electrical) 39,874.90 8,205.87 9,740.32 10,225.97 11,702.74 Miscellaneous Manufacturing- Industries 22,610.34 5,375.42 5,288.78 5,634.73 6,311.41 TRANSPORTATION 571.679.33 233,695.53 258.723.38 39,336.27 39.924.11. Interstate Railroads' 413,848.13 196,522.62 217,325.51 Street, Suburban, and Interurban Railways, and City and Suburban Bus Lines 30,017.78 7,390.89 7,718.80 7,"463.79 7.444.30 Trucking- and /or Warehousing for Hire 48,313.40 9,208.23 12,453.34 13,671.65 12,980.18 Other Transportation, Except Water Transportation 52,321.23 12,733.63 13,306.60 12,608.31 13,672.69 Services Allied to Transportation, Not Elsewhere Clasaified ; 27,178.79 7,840.16 7,919.13 5,592.52 5,820.98 UTILITIES 282.762.53 67.075.85 69.336.56 70.004.08 75.446.04 Communication:. Telephone, Telegraph, and Related Services — —- 175,674.36 42,236.74 43,602.16 44,329.68 45,445.78 Utilities: Electric and Gas 106,410.46 ~- 24,735.30 25,467.29 26,377.65 29,830.22 Local Utilities and Local Public Services, Not Elsewhere Classified 677.71 103.81 207.11 196.75 170.04 WHOLESALE AND RETAIL TBAP~ 1,213,039.-46 270,711.10 290.333.44 292,855.26 359,139.60 Full-Service and Limited-Function Wholesalers 215,661.03 49,622.65 51,092.34 52,278.19 62,667.85 Wholesale Distributors. Other Than Full-Service, and Limited-Function Wholesalers 250,615.91 56,446.03 61,141.35 . 62,412.67 70,615.86 64 </seg>
         <seg id="p077">•p«rO— jaanawriag P«oj|J»_ »qt o» p—uajswu} oq qi- i 'raorpa| -100 aoftnqi— |uoo eajl auipnpui 'iqunrjasa pBo-iuu jo saauataq »a—&gt;•« '_E6I -runs '"»»»_ 'daio_ '(») goi-8r uorp»s ipi—- jk&gt;u»pjo= o» ui_ -papnraxa oi-t a-a _f;t 'is jaq-aso- jo sa bumu r*np|A|pu| «n o» palipaja 80"fiOO'l8t 1° lunottm »ir» uj suoiinqmuoa AMiriuntpA. 'OKI 'IE &lt;I»'R wojaq Jo uo paAiaofw pu* rrrot Jtad ggfii joj anp suorrnqi-Quoa jtruo ssp-pu| s|na? «m_ t 10'ZK'S at'lW'S K'StO'r -TZBO'S tO'99O'SI -—_u|-«»no p&lt;ra --runs. a||r»)»iuuofi OTBS (_•« ~ 68'iSTI uojionpoj_ B»j&gt;r_iru-N P~» &lt;-n»|oxp,i,-3paiD «•„&gt; ZS'dlt BS'U9 19-SI 09*116. «m»iaH«!iq«jsa *&gt;|_i»s -sip-is pu» nunapuiuy US'KS 19"0Z9 OO'ihi Br"9BS tt'SISZ : : ~— »ntil_»l»~V tnosuanaasrif pus 'isrHapsdg doJO 'su_n_ jtw-1 i;-C2t JO'Stl _,"08 99'8ZS -TOT- ~ ¦—: —: ¦ romj -unoj pus naossM-i 08'OK'C WOSi'r- 19W11 ZB-riB'S 13'SSZ'U ~— — ~ — — Bno_NVTI-~BIM I6'BBl 99'f-I OTOBI SfOK iVM- "¦ — ¦ »»|_isnpui aof-s_ -»«nO 81-06e'l 10'rSr't SiTOZKS 9S-Bt£'l oO'H9'9 suoi,«»|ua».io -,i"uaa,_aii »uo__uok Wm 86'0rS 9r"6» . 18'fiSr EB'OSS'Z r :—— — auoßiunmu pu» saiaualy sot—ii&gt;s-r&gt;iaog pu« pmoissajoid jairjo BC'iW'Z J_-88Z'« Zi'Brl'Z GZ'6-I'Z- - 88'-ir.'6 bk&gt;ia«s (HKg a«no P~« P»IP»n: SS'-S'S 82-6io&gt; 63'WS'S 98-tSt'S Sr'o96'rt : : P»urs«t_ 3_iu;_a«i_ V&gt;K 'saajA, tag pajafasj p u - uor)u~ »_ pua %u*wa*auiy OS'IOS't 69-96r'9 •.. _0"»»»'9 _rWE'9 Cr'9BB'9Z —; T- —". sunpij uonoK U'B2o'l ii'fflO't 66'980'l 8»-ZS6 S6-Bl'r *W. push pu» «»ja-»s •"!»-»•_ «no»u»rr»«IH 89'990't S9-i_X't W896 2fBOo I EO'OSZ't siooqog »p*_ P«» i«iajsun_o_ pua safamav &gt;uau__«.~ai_t SS'&lt;~6'6 BVEWB r»'BJl'6 ofE_)'B SS'Bo9'9B ' — P»B!~"»IO «»u«_»»l_ V&gt;N 'aJoiAasg sssnp-g 9Z't_o'9t 89-S9o'St 10'119'St WSSl'tt 1098803 '. —: — —: — -"^ —r-—- saai-»s nmoaraj • __________ —__—__—_— _______ aaajo pu« 's-ma_ -trasnoß -u|t- oo_ _____ wczr's- i6-i6r'o9 wm'z': zvm'is . si'Bn'oK -— —— — —— —- BaraxsaaNi aoiA-aas U'-S'r 89'1_8'B iip'OUO 'E ¦ Bv'B69'B ¦ 6Z"UO'9I ~ — r?. — — uortsoiqnsoa -ay :saa_io »^ 'su»o— 'aouajnsur '»»»»•_ p—m 096159 rZ'B2S'S r.i'C»S'fi U-16Z'9 OZ'Z6B'&lt;Z — ' «-»loj_ pus -siuaav '«jrKJ_ *»»}»a P»H S£l6S'» Br"69Z'S 9^" Jl'« OfMJO'B 99H6'Et ¦ —sjanoag pan mymßy Mtnunsni SS'ZO9'B TZ"ISE'I, r-i X Zr-Oeo'i -i'gK'Oß P»UI»™iD aiai(»a«n_ toji -u»pua_v aaara_| 09'989'r 02-E96'S .j. »»H*E t_'rS6'E 9S"tSt'9t _U|&gt;iu«h ?ua_q»»AUi pus aupn_ -iijnaag 89'8-t'Z i 6l'ooB'l _____ _________ . ________ — .-..,, -ap-ginog __M_ux pu» ____g cX'lZZ'it Oflsr'W 6l'B6Z'r9 68-IB9'&lt;-3 oS'ZB9't92 ~_XVXBa aV3M ONV •-DNVanSNI '30NVNU 66'Ot Sf 9flfi9'iE ITSX'I£ 69-'SBB'te IS'tK 9SI -T»T""X l!»»aH P«» »I~»IoqM -»»&gt;no UIOI'U' ZZ'ZSI'V SI'OOT'6 -.-¦¦ SZ'ZSO'a 6f9U!'_; — n3|A-&gt;8 -lvdo_ O||qouio^ny pua 'sasarag 'aooßaig -UHIIJ 9r'6lB'B Of'9Bf&gt;'B WOU'B 89'9Zt'8 BE'Sit'rß «w»H '"IWPd P~« anßaa 21'iBS'K Z6'__'oZ Zo'6-!'ije OfSOS'OZ 98'9»'98 - :—! P»WI««»ia ajaifmatia »°N '»»»»_ H»»a_ SB'9S1 81 »B'i9l'tt 6I'BH'K 09'181'Et . 98-851509 s»ho«s»»»v pu« p-nddv IPn»_ 90-Z6B"SZ *r*U&gt;'te SO'OZ'n ScT-BZ9'IZ 81-_«'S6 '¦ »Af)o_lojnv Il»*_ tZ'6Z9'ZE tfZl9'Zs BE'S9S'K 9E-699'61 QS'tSZ'96 " -(saMjg jonbj- sjpnpui) poo_ |PRM 89"ZZ9'69 86'0tZ'Ir S9'olo'Zr SS'SZI'BB oi'6Z9'lBl : as|pusi|aiaH luauag ir»&gt;»H 65 </seg>
         <seg id="p078">TABLE B-_: Amount and Per Cent of Subject Wages Payable by Employers for the Calendar Year 1939, Classified by In - dustry and Calendar Quarters 1 Total CAI.EXDAR QUARTER. IH3II INDUSTRY Amount for Year 1939 Fir»t Second Third Fourth TOTAL .$l3B, 001,452.77 $34.583.911. 11) $38.646,677.10 $31.297,168.72 $33,473 795.76 CONSTRUCTION 8,214,245. 34 1.132.288799 2.178.555797 2,564, 346. 83 2,339,053755 Buildin- Construction, General Contractors 2,8—),689.119 334,173.54 6311,722.15 938,828.23 1116,966.07 General Contractors, Other Thon BuildinK 4,053,317.22 .-,75,599. 24 1.227,948.6(1 1,264,658.15 983,111.23 Construction, Special Trade Contractors 1,331,238.13 222,516.21 310,885.22 300,860.45 436,970.25 MANUFACTURING 35,344.989.96 7,798,381. 87 S. 710,519.39 11.(134,047.74 '.1,801,440.96 Food and Kindred Products 21,072,078.54 4,740, a11. US 5.345,783.32 5,003,401.20 5,982,392.94 Apparel and Other Finished Products Made from Fabrics and Similar Materials ..... 522,298.49 123,104.43 139,926.55 119,333.55 139,933.90 Lumber and Timber Basic Products 400,420.89 80,705.90 92,001.50 104,491.74 128.627.75 Furniture and Finished Lumber Products- 815,445.06 165,752.20 194,742.49 199,050.47 255,804.44 Paper and Allied Products 451,559.78 103,027.44 106,695.35 107.350.73 134,450.20 Printine, Publishing nnd Allied Industries..- _ 4,722,720.04 1,137,038.71 1,193,459.98 1,155,405.52 1,236,702.73 Chemicals and Allied Products 1,052,343.11 227.229.G2 259,313.19 266,544.52 299,255.78 , Leather and Leather Products _ _ 175,884.23 41,271.63 41,969.44 45,402.02 47,241.14 Stone, Clay, and Glass Products 1,021,789.14 195.024.78 271,510.26 273,506.21 278,747.89 Iron and Steel and Their Products— _ 1,252.491.12 285,297.5.8 293,345.50 325,404.89 348,443.0!) Nonfcrrous Metals and Their Products 007,909.85 142,443.5.". 148,360.70 105,849.07 211,310.49 Electrical Machinery 218,063.18 44,764.25 47,171. 5S 58.270.3S 67,856.97 Machinery (Except Electrical) 1,460,365.75 304,043.17 300,810.25 378,744.01 416,702.32 Miscellaneous Manufacturing Industries 905,547.28 205,177.49 214,817.10 231,791.43 253,761.20 TRANSPORTATION 21,314,215.28 5,G80,908.31 9.605,171.97 1,489,005.72 1,539,129.28 Interstate Railroads 3 15,327,709.01 7,278,610.32 8,049,092.69 Street, Suburban, and Intcrurban Railways, and City and Suburban Bus Lines 1,111,709.13 273,730.75 255.550.9S 270,436.48 273,714.92 Trucking- and/or Warehousing for Hire 1,954,605.50 363,0-0.!I4 450,653.5G 335,020.83 575,010.13 Other Transportation, Except Water Transportation 1,920,024.45 472,969.06 494,776.61 468,737.12 483,541.60 Services Allied to Transportation, Not Elsewhere Classified 1,000,107.19 291,665.24 294.765.13 205.811.27 204,862.53 UTILITIES 10,325,470.58 2,484,292.1:0 2.570.079.43 2.628,555.70 2,042.548.49 Communication: Telephone, Telegrraph, and Related Services . 6,470,178.89 1,564,327.03 1,017,117.25 1,041,842.07 1,646,891.94 Utilities: Electric and Caa : 3,823,905.62 916,121.11 943,234.01 976,948.78 987,601.72 Local Utilities and Local Public Services, Not Tai-n-tij.-. ri—.m»tl 31,392.07 3,844.82 9,728.17 9,764.25 8,034.83 WHOLESALE AND RETAIL TRADE &#132;.... - 44,175,276.98 10,091.123.78 10.846,893,10 10.039.782.33 12.297,477.77 Full-Servica and Limited-Function Wholesalers. „ . . 7,870,323.61 1,839,696.58 1,894,232.54 1,938,912.19 2,197,482.30 66 </seg>
         <seg id="p079">"SOU '&lt;* •«¦_ - jay* ««•_ njra-qajf am jo suo]«jaoj- atft-'oi laafqna iou ana —iisnpu; patutfa. araia— &gt;)_{ aqi u[ pa-a-ua s—ucoidu—&gt; — q p)ad &gt;—iraAA, 'OKI 'IB'&lt;t"»W o-ojaq jo uo paajodu a—wa aaq* iaam_o[daia jjsqi 4oj aiq-cad ss'*— jtiuo aapnraut a(q*i «iqj,, E9"Bs_'Hl Zo'o9O'£K W-St'lSl. 9l'f_-'9i Sl'H£'-8r '¦ _up_u«nO pa» -ajttfif arnapiauoK tS'99l'Z S9"SJO'S — "~ OZ'ttl » ———. uon«ipo-_r. «»o-l»Jrtl«N P«« omaituj-j-apn-o C9"ZEE'S K'6W9 OZ'O-S'9 SB'Soi'f- Oo'Bto'OZ — Biuammriiqaiaa oa IA ja s J»l[uiis pua punirt-|-sv SO'iU'6l _l'BtZ'«l 99"9A0'-S rVHS'H SO'9Bo 88 " a-iirr-ixßy snoauanmrit P-» *«aJH»|»»as »o-0 •«a-*_t J|an-i M'r_)'9 __-J__L_____ -0"-8f,*-I O.'Z-t'gl WSS'ir " «m«_t j-ameg pn« naojwAr - o'Rs'm WBo9'i_i si'ssg'ois oo"_B6'9oi ra'-iu'CES ~ — - sno_Nvn_osm ©0"O8s'9 00"99r"9 0u'989'9 WSZt'L OO'SOS 9Z ~ ~ a»m«ip«l »a|i_»_ aaqtO SI-BVI9 89'KJ6'i9 9_"089'68 .B'WO'IS SB'9Bl 09Z — —— «uor)»-iui~_0 diquaquiaja; ,uo-duojl CS'OiS'SS _9"G9S's; 9l"rSo'rZ A9W6I IZ'6K'I6 ~ ~ —: '". '.'". «uon_&gt;n«-I P» - -aapua-v aa(—K_-P, taos pua prao|«oajoj_[. —agio 91'nE'SS 9J"OOS'BS jgWSS 'JC'rrS'cl rr"69r'9rS ~— «ao|A»s qirwH aattO P~» l«ajP»K CI'EK'OH 9S'9IB'S9I t-i'Oai'SSr rS'UO'ttt -C'_o9'te. ~— :— —: P»yi"»IO «&gt;ail*»«ia »ok ¦saaiA-ag pai-pu pua uopas.pojj pua }u&gt;u_ *n— :v 09'EK'OK S9"BK'Zre Sl'CGt'ZtS rS'tOE'lM- i_'l«9'K6 : ~ — ¦»«"¦»!_ uorjoj. 6E'9»'» 66'8a)'6C 10'6SZ'0V fiO_tZ'sS 8r'086'991 —«ap&gt;MX P»»H pu« »»lA-a8 i!«d&gt;H »noaa»rr»atr|_ r_-_9r'6S 9S'B9i'lr tS'fSB'9C OTSUO't-r rZ'Z6O'B9I «looqas »P«X pua [¦r-tatmuoo pua aatauasy iuaa«o|dtua 90'S98'6SU OZ'oeS'ZVS tO-Z-S'oK IO'OrS'EZB Or'-98'9SS'l : ~"P»1«~~I0 ai»q*a«r_ »«N ••9a|A_» s anapafl 96589899 lO'-ll'-SS C_'oBl'-19 9KSOO'9r9 Sl'iBS'KS'B ~ b»|a-»s t~aoa_»j | Sf96i'trS 6t"Br£'BBt 9S'(iBB'Bo. Co'-rB'Oo9 I6'o6B'pBo'Z " ! -»«!_ -uplpo- aatrio ._^ ___— '- .¦: pua 'sdtua_* 'aaanoH gupnoog 'frpioH fims'irt'- Si'SSI'SiO'J l«"l96'oH'Z ES'MS'ESti'l !T9!Z'GgS'B ~ /T ~— — B_IHXBnaNI 30IAH3S Gr'rlO'SSl l£'69r'6H oG"JB9'9tt C6"BM'9EI G9'SH'-83 — ~ '¦ no|»«u|quioo _uv 60'619'rK 68-9rO'SO- EC'IOB'SOS K'Stß'Sßl W0»«'0r8 aiano-a pua '«ttu«v '»-»I»aa »!»»•_ iaa_i I9'ZBS*SSt 59"060'13l IZ'tZO'ilt SB'_6S'Hl SS'B6o'9o3 ~ : "—M«v*»_ pu» «)U9_V aauaanaui »r'B9l'9ir't . H'SSH't-r't 09"9B0'II+'I ZZ'EZr'HlC't S»"SlB'rpi'9 —~— : : -»Ha»a a»u«_n«ai W9SB'_C5 Wi9S'r-8 -B'9Co'2_i 'JS"96B'»Z IJ-'9SO'-OI'I = P»HI"««IO a_allj-»«__- ion '»iaua-v *&gt;aTO!_[ WBr9'oit IBW9H tfSZG'ZCI rS'KI-'gH EZ'ISt'96S ! ~-_u|j|u»a luaumaaui pua tuapna X)ia-»s _________ 88"8_9'99 9I'ZH;'99 I0"88t'gf, ____S9_f______" ¦¦¦ . pin-amo- isrut pua «nu»g »B'B6»'S9S"&lt;; t9"980'888,i; Bt'olt-'tBS'n K'WO'^'B O9'r9o'B-9'6 — 3XVXS3 IV-H attV '_3NVHIISrJI '-OKVN-t WOW'rSS'l" TO"oBr'96S'l SG"99»'tBC'l SS'Br&gt;'96-'t St'9SB'rr9'9 ap'-U, n»»»H P- * »r«*&gt;!on«- aair»o »"085'r9S K'rEG'rSS 98"IGS'8r8 9i'UO'BoB rB'Bt9'_~'t ~~ "— ~ s»|a»s jiwßji aiiqoturnnv Pua 'sa-auao 'Buocmg -a||n_f £S'BrS'rHB 06°t6G'£t8 6»'9t9'918 it"rB6'lJB lS'tU'S9B't ——" : »a«l_ aatnuim pu« -nn«a B&gt;'ol6'oSB 09"0Ir'8ii 08'r96'0ii SS'S99, 9Si rO'lr6'9Bt'S ~ "— '¦ rpa»!««»ID a»q-a»i_t ion 'apwx I!»|aH -9'S66*&lt;!6S SS'W«9 90-f,10'E99 . 99'BSr'OGr 6S"oU'S9t'&lt;: :.-' ! — ~ -Bp«w»V PW pa«T H»W W919'816 SO-t-Gfi 19810816 ot'BJ6'9oB 09'069'tSS'£ : "^ : : MlMwloiay rjti»g Bt'BlB'Z6B 8G'999'6»8 ' 68'.ri'£0S 9S'l_i!'Sti 98'iGt'68r;'8 ' —(w-ojg aonDn aapniaui) pooj |nf»»a SS-gBS'Geo'Z OS"BI9'OS9,I SE'ZSU'SSS't SS'tSZ'tCt't IB"99B'SBS'9 — ¦ ¦ ' a»!pu»qM»H ra-nMQ !,«»» - -rS"io9'BB&gt;'Z 89'8W'ol8'S 09-8-E'S93'Z 9i'KB'SGo'o ZB'r9.'fSl'G " ~~ MaroaraqM. uo|V&gt;un_(-pai|i_rT , pua aa|A-ag-nn_[ uaqx *&gt;mo "a'oiriqi-isia »P&gt;"»1 01jVi. 67 </seg>
         <seg id="p080">TABLE B-3: Monthly Volume of Covered Employment for the Calendar Year 1939, Classified by Industry 1 1939 NUMBER OK COVERED WORKERS INDUSTRY Monthly Average Jon. Feb. March April May June July Aug. Sept. Oct. Nov. Dec. TOTAL. (Includinir Railroads) - 109,800 110,487 114.325 118.541 1-2.707 lgt..~C 103,708 104,637 107,031 106,788 105.005 105.61-0 TOTAL (Excliulinß Railroads) 102T287 03,576 93,. r&gt;37 07.610 101,257 104,I!lli 104,175 1011,708 104,637' 1077031 W?tS 105.005 105,68:1 CONSTRUCTION _..._ 6, US'.) 3.883 3,530 5.587 7.470 8,4511 s,6ffi&gt; S.BS6 8,027 0,024 8.092 6.794 4,537 Building Construction _ 2,336 1,142 1.147 1.690 2.125 2,314 2.801 3.253 3.050 .1,102 2,946 2,610 1,807 Gen. Contractors, Other Than Bldg. 3,645 1.951 1,613 3.000 4.354 5,198 4,895 4,653 4.761 4,745 3,892 2,902 1,772 Special Trade Contractors _ 1,008 700 770 897 1.000 047 970 080 1,077 1,177 1,254 1,282 958 MANUFACTURING 27,053 24,851) 24.478 24,702 25.2--! 26,534 36.958 27,000 27,547 28,150 28,882 28,628 31,686 Food and Kindred Products. _ 16,876 15,399 14,910 14,762 15.057 16.391 16,660 16,800 17,151 17,437 18,127 18,169 21,638 Apparel ft Other Finished Products 532 510 564 610 622 61*7 628 452 460 468 506 506 430 Lumber and Timber Basle Products 301 270 266 274 280 283 297 304 315 326 325 341 332 Furniture and Finished Lbr. Prod. 667 627 644 666 643 640 673 665 671 700 717 715 638 Paper and Allied Products 313 308 300 300 302 308 SOS 304 302 333 344 329 322 Printing and Publishing-— 3.051 3,062 3,054 3.054 3,1)1 2,060 3,096 3,066 3,069 3,094 3,081 3,098 3,002 Chemicals and Allied Products- 891 6)7 615 631 (171 685 731 ;S.i 731 747 721 707 7011 Leather and Leather Product* 171 165 165 172 170 166 172 168 173 181 174 177 170 Stone, Clay, and Glass Products 825 612 648 787 894 920 902 891 934 885 881 826 702 Iron and Steel and Their Products- »0O 835 832 804 850 554 RSO 921 061 958 988 963 895 Nonfcrrous Metals ft Their Products 480 412 426 447 456 400 406 413 400 692 649 485 479 Electrical Machinery ISO 151 154 156 163 161 162 191 200 217 222 191 192 Machinery (Except Electrical) 1,064 979 977 1,001 1,030 1,075 1,118 1,120 1,121 1,083 1,091 1,093 1,074 Misc. Manufacturing Industries 969 903 923 945 973 937 925 928 969 1,029 1,056 1,028 1,013 TRANSPORTATION -_ 20.705 21.612 21.225 22,069 23,389 24,392 4.592 4,662 4,687 4,637 4,703 4,575 Interstate Railroads" — 16,224 16,950 16,715 17,284 18,571 19,401 — — St., City Rys.' and Bu* Lines 750 72a 737 732 767 760 765 767 764 768 760 738 714 Trucking, Warehousing for Hire 1,623 1,282 1,479 1,468 1.631 1,6.2 1,677 1,661 1,740 1,751 1,722 1,776 1,652 Other Transportation, Except Water 1,561 1,542 1,501 1,491 1,552 1,577 1.654 1,566 1,479 1,536 1,539 1,611 1,656 Services Allied to Transportation 742 932 945 819 835 859 865 598 670 632 616 578 653 UTILITIES 7.409 7.256 7,217 7.339 7,348 7,423 7.602 7,679 7.669 7,754 7,433 7,577 7,690 Communication: Telephone, Te'eer. 4,806 4,676 4,690 4,701 4,720 4,782 4,915 4,898 4,842 4,889 4,678 4,863 5,017 Utilities: Electric and Gas 2,644 2,564 2,507 2,601 2,671 2,583 2,630 2,706 2,762 2,815 2,698 2,667 2,625 Local Utilities and Public Services— 49 16 20 37 57 58 57 75 65 50 57 47 48 WHOLESALE ft RETAIL TRADE— 39,828 37,80S 38,182 39,386 39,753 39,711 39,407 39.484 39.618 41,026 41,131 40,975 41,448 Full-Scry. ft Limited-Funct. Wrulrs. 5,351 5,272 5,243 5,314 5,832 5,333 5,385 5,447 5,374 5,403 5,458 5,315 5,338 68 </seg>
         <seg id="p081">"6861 'I Xm r J&lt;&gt; ¦» *&gt;V aaun-nsui )U3iuXo|du»ur_ pao-u»j_ lajspaj »t» °» P«-&gt;J«ua-» «v u»*&lt;o-&gt;. pao-rrs- aitaanpN, "Orel 'IE HW«K H»n— lua a»*o|dina Xq paiiodM ajap njpnpui, 9CS Cli 108 901 6TrB SEI t6l 91G 99i 1W WZ SIS ZS9 -Milt-tan© pu» *-|ufK anp-~-ttO N II 1Z IZ OS 98 8^ SS Or 8J- •BC.GZ OS ZS q»*?_ --WB -™II~n:8 » •»fr'~V 16 E6 18 18 S8 98 lit W SS? 891 .-8 S3 Oil .". "'May •»«-. P»» «u---| spn-»x SS X X 61 61 SZ S* Sit -. 881 OS _U 9* IS »u_a_t -jqrno- P"~ &gt;r»°*»'*n Oir ISB 196 098 ' -J6 168 566 SIZ'l Zil'l orB 6lr BEr ISB .¦'————- saO-NVmaOSIK SI SI SI SI St 91 U . X H U ' W H SI — ~ «.ij»«npui »|A*»s -WOO MB IK 99S 95Z SIZ 691 OCT 89r lIS IB ¦ 99! SSZ SB ««-r»a«!-»»»o dri|M«t~~K Iyo-a_o N U 61 89 63 69 ftf SI 88 98 91 69 H U wpuaay •-is&gt;S-r- P&lt;&gt;_ » 'J 1"- "TH) S9S S9E WE 018 OSS US 188 58S »IS G9S E9E 898 EiS -w-|A_&gt;s ul|K&gt;H -~r»0 P&lt;« l«3!P»K IOS 168 696 956 GrG 896 080't SOO'I BHi 808 Wl ISI Sl6 -0-_'N 'no»aa»;»H pua taatuaanwv 616 WIK Hi 906 168 9SB U8 956 516 056 516 816 : . "'¦¦---- m-pi,. uojiok 981 BSI TH IK 081 IZ\ EEI IK BEt OH 851 ISI tEI -"P«l pu«H » •*-«_ *V*»i\ '"HK BEI 881 8H 8K Z9I SSI SSI HI -I 891 091 £91 ZSI —"looqug paa wpu.„v *u3t_/~td&lt;_a SSt't SIZ'l Sll'l ill' I Stl'l SK'l SOS'l SOS'l H-Z't 060't 6lo'l 9801 E9t'l ".' ' " "O -a "r- ••aaj-ias a»»-|-i a SS»'Z EOS'S SrS'Z !99'8 S5S'5 r99'Z 6W'Z j-9'5 WS Z rSS'Z ESr Z Sfrt'Z 69S'Z : : ' "I*"! r"ae*» d ______ __ZZ_£_ ISZ'B OH'S 118'Z 1085 888 '5 OZE'S _______ OtZ'S .WE gSO'S ..IQI'E — **mO. » KOTOH -annoog ___I_jg »«S*6 ZBl'6 i~6'6 OSl'6 W'6 Zot"6 rSB'C GlZ'Ol UB'G 5f9'6 Olt'O ISZ'6 8890 ¦¦¦- ~ S-THXBnaNI 3DIAH3B 6SC 898 ISE 0»E US 59E 018 098 SSS CSS ZSS StS 098 »*1 '«u»o»_ '-sal •»»a^a_ rog BrB SSB BrB 918 188 U8 OEB 188 118 618 H8 ICB 6SB aj»&gt;|OJa '-n»V: "«»l»»a »»»»•_ nßji. 6_! 18Z 18Z SBZ tS IK rBZ IBZ HZ VZ 995 015 61Z — —wasp-H p«« a»&lt;»av aaownaui SH'S WE ISI'B 081'S Ztl'E Wl'S ESI'S MI'S SII'S ZSO'S ISOE .'Hfl ZH'C ~~~ "»Ii»ao a.aa-tr&gt;a_ 209 109 S6S 809 ZZ9 E59 «9 66S 06S S6S ZI9 059 109 —-«a[»u»_V awia-u awno ta SB ess siz ess \zs esz sss ssz ibz isz I9Z 915 -uw««a ,•**»».». » «j»n»a -iubms 691 BSI &lt;____- 991 891 091 BSI Ist t3I I9t 191 191 091 —gajuwmoQ asn-x P"» «nn»H 0899 089'S 689'S OSI'S 98l'S ril'S SZI'S 169'S 153'S »099 619'S 8099 ISS'S "--ISa TV-H t 'SNI 'aONVNI - ZSS'r 899"1* ISl'r SZl'r SB9'r SOS'r B»'r 6»r'r ¦ 1»&gt; 99r'r WS &gt; IrS'r 85S'f —»P»-x ii»»»h pna »|aM[oqA_ -oipo 86S'l SOr'l C0»'l Z6S't S6E'l 0»'I ZSVI COr'l 86S'l 80E'l SIZ'l SIZ'l 81S't sa_aja D pu« luorros »~lina ZZI'Z 601'Z BEI'S ESI'Z HO'Z 950'Z IOO'Z 95I'Z EOl'Z 6161 986 1 tW'Z W'Z..~rr. ¦»~&gt;l_ «ai«ra!J&lt;i. pua ,«-n»a 608'Z 9Zl'5 OZl's 901'Z 999'Z 199'Z 119'Z E99'Z IW'Z 859'Z 966'Z IDS..MIS •«¦•¦_ waq-Mfa WN 'ap-ix l!»»»H TOl'S 980*5 SSl's BIZ'Z HO'Z I6B'l 066"! OSt'Z 111 Z 888'Z 118 t ISS'I S9O'Z: ' «nw«"MV P«" ta««&lt;ldv im»H ISO'S HO'S 6565 650'S 890'S IZI'B 880'S S5O'S 910'E 1965 1685 668'Z 600'E ~—" "—" »Ar"~~o»«&gt;V r!»»~8I 659'E OE9'S 90l'E 999'E SM'E 6r9'S 919'E Z99'E OW'S CBS*E 6K'S rSS'S 089'E ~("""IS «&gt;n_n: "pui) pooj tm*H lE9'6 OW'O U»'B 6638 9EB't ZZl'l 98l'l Eto'B SrZ'B 95Z'8 IZS'I 81»- WZ'B aa|ptnrq«a|i larouao iiaj»H IoB'9 18«'9 IBl'l lil'l SZO'l EtO'l EW'9 ISB'9 SsB'9 5819 Z99'9 Zol'9 106*9 ". WOO '««&gt;»nq|-»sia ai"»loqAV 69 </seg>
         <seg id="p082">TABLE B-4: Amount of 1939 Benefits and Number of Weeks of Unemploy - ment for Railroad and Nonrailroad Payments and Total, Part-Total and Partial Payments, Classified by Months Month Industry All Type of Unemployment Railroad Nonrailroad Payments Total Part-Tot—l Partial AMOUNT OF BENEFITS TOTAL 5167.17-I.SO 51,137,348.61 $1,304,523.41 51,231,683.41&gt; $18,317.00 $4,523.00 January . 7,75:1.72 24.710.G0 32,470.32 32,470.32 February 47.670.25 173,798.62 221,468.87 221,468.87 March _ 45.367.62 192.628.22 240.995.84 240,993.84 __ April _.... 32.436.56 132,727.25 165,163.81 163,163.81 _ _ May 15.211.4S 99,039.25 117,259.73 117,250.73 June . 11.750.70 73.595.53 55,379.53 84,180.53 597.00 302.00 July 689.67 65,844.61 66,534.28 64,002.28 2,223.00 309.00 August 161.80 69,395.04 69,556.84 66,734.84 2,422.00 400.00 September 39,893.6.1 59,893.65 57,211.65 2,333.00 349.00 October .... ...... 64,3-1.72 - 64,359.72 60,966.72 3,081.00 312.00 November ..... 75,735.14 75,735.14 71,391.14 3,455.00 889.00 December . 97.0U 105,017.68 105,714.68 99,846.68 3,906.00 1,962.00 NUMBER OF WEEKS TOTAL _ 17,934= 133,087 151,021 147.8S7 1 2,494 040 January „ S2S 2,895 3,723 3,123 February 5,198 20,813 26,011 26,011 March 5,266 22,978 28,244 28,244 April 3,350 15,451 18,801 18,801 May 1,950 11,569 13,6-4 13,824 June 1,231 5.655 9,886 9,716 129 41 July 79 7,719 7,798 7,444 309 45 August _ 16 5.071 S.OS7 7,692 335 60 September _ 6,959 6,959 0,579 32S 62 October - 7,382 7.352 6,916 422 44 November . . 5.566 8,566 7.991 456 119 December U 11,729 11,740 10.84G 515 279 'includes 26 checks written for $202.41 on which adjustments were made. :The number of railroad payments is based on two factors: (1) The average amount of all the payments made to claimants whose last employers in their base periods were classified in the railroad industry: and (2) the amount of benefits actually charged to em - ployers whose accounts were transferred to the Railroad Retirement Board in conformance to Section 48-70!) (c), Comp. Stat., Supp. 1939. 70 </seg>
         <seg id="p083">TABLE B-5: Number of Initial Claims, Weeks Compensated and Amount of Benefit Payments for Claimant* Filing Their Claims from Offices Located Out of the State, Calendar Yesr 1939, Classified by State In Which Claim Was Piled ¦•'¦'.. Numberof Numberof Amount of State Initial Weeks Benefit ' ' ' . Claims Compensated Payments TOTAL . _ 3,991 11,861 $116,496.38 Alabama . : ; ¦ 1 14 131,36 Arizona ; _ , ___— -27 68 581.37, Arkansas : '63 220 2,400.47 California _ : ; _ __ j '. 562 .-- 2,934 ¦ 28,507.37 Colorado :—: __ 374 . 1,185 11,721.71 Connecticut - - " ; '¦ 2 Delaware _. : - - ' -• '.': _ * V —— Florida _ . '23 55 501.59 Georgia — —; ; —: ; __ ¦ 5 14 186.00 Idaho ; ____ : ; ; ; 90 193 1,878.41 Illinois _ 114 338 3,692.70 Indiana ___ ; ; : : _•¦ 23 55 501.46 lowa : . ; 594 1,903 18,296.14 Kansas ___ ; ; .351 931 8,861.18 Kentucky __ ;— ; _. 11 . 18 ' , 146.42 Louisiana . 8 6 36.00 Maine -i _—. _ —_ . Maryland - " . S 12 380.00 Massachusetts ' ' • ' 2 1 9.00 Michigan ; 29 96 1,002.80 Minnesota I : _ . 67 .211 2,485.56 Mississippi : 4 1 -6.00 Missouri ; : 45G 1,170 11,230.75 Montana . , '¦ 25 71- 739.00 Nevada 10 ."'.." 24 225.18 New Hampshire ; __ 1 New* Jersey - • —— — New Mexico ; - ; 12 61 865.01 New York - 28 59 564.23 North Carolina.. _—____— - 3 . —__ — North Dakota i_ 5 17 153.02 Ohio MS 68 542.14 Oklahoma ; , __— 111 173 . 1,782.411 Oregon 115 349 3,161.781 Pennsylvania 13 '.' 32 341.00 Rhode Island 1 15 191.00 South Carolina 1 _ ¦ - ; '¦ .. South Dakota i_ - ; 75 231 2,341.54 Tennessee - 10 60 627.15 Texas 136 332 3,548.78 Utah -_ '- 30 84 703.08 Vermont : - _: Virginia ; . 1 8 62.31 Washington 110 373 3,502.52 West Virginia '. 3 14 U1.21 !¦ Wisconsin ; -¦¦-¦. 13 65 765.65; Wyomln. ¦ '.- ' ___. 140 '¦'¦•: 383 3,728.17! District »f rMm-hi. ~7 ¦¦'"¦¦'li" 85.11 , Hawaii __. : ¦ ; ; __ .- ¦ . .; ' 71 </seg>
         <seg id="p084"/>
         <seg id="p085"/>
         <seg id="p086">TABLE 8-6: Amount of Benefit Payments for Each Month of the Year 1939, Classified by Local Employment Service Office' Employment Total Service for CALENDAR MONTHS 1939 Office Year Jununry Fi-hrunry Mnrch April May Juni* July Auirutit September October November December TOTAL $1,304, 6-3.41 $32, 470, 32 $221,465,57 $240,995. S4 $105,103.81 tVJj^jS $55.:179.53 $08,534.28 $69,556.84 $59,893.65 $64.359.72 $75.735.14 $105,714.68 Out-of-State 116.49C.3S 449.59 9.798.9S IS.JI3S.Gtt 12,079.67 11,392.06 5.7-0.75 7,150.00 8.044.50 7,933.00 9,833.00 10,954.14 14,133.00 Alliance _ !1,1HC.05 245.55 2,424. IS 2.005.22 1,017.24 809.23 790.50 343.00 305.1™ 2X2.00 295.00 279.00 430.0(1 Beatrice ..- 39,337.07 1.109.1S 7,004.55 5.102.09 4.502.51 3.007.97 2,:|51.«1 1,582.78 1,469.00 1.318.00 1,805.00 2,350.00 3,850.00 Cbadron 14.555.56 60G.34 3.M-.01 4,188. HI 2.0G2.05 1.370.89 527.U1 2G9.00 221.00 199.14 218.00 214.00 627.00 Columbus ... _ 32,379.24 1.738.31 8,965.08 7,507.57 4.115.13 2.433.2S 1,337.117 7-2.00 591.00 524.00 5G4.00 838.00 2,439.0:) Falls City - 13,017.13 392.52 3,447.31 2,499.05 1.C09.C0 1,123.20 008.43 339.00 409.00 356.00 523.00 720.00 929.00 Fremont 10,091.07 1.5C5.01 10,274.5:1 9,732.07 5,993.12 2,991.11 2,055.K1 1,408.00 1,301.00 1.374.00 1,785.00 2,753.09 5.305.00 ! Grand Inland _ 85.549.42 2,980.45 19.750.511 20.284.42 14.f1CH.7C 9,356.43 5,294.91 3,197.67 2,733.50 2,619.10 2,000.00 2,315.00 3.941. 6S Ha-tinim 44,521.82 1,108. Nil 7,873.70 5.097.17 5.201.74 3,189.85 3,291.50 1,490.00 2,038.97 1,726.00 2,424.00 3,153.00 4.017.C0 Holdrcße . 16,863.71 774.97 3,219.50 3,810.04 1,253.91 685.14 439.70 419.39 648.00 700.00 601.00 750.00 1,564.00 Kearney 34,741.43 1,077.27 7,924.70 7,412.79 3,791.68 3,006.59 1,591.54 674.86 790.00 1,004.00 1,290.00 2,115.00 4,063.03 Lincoln 136,899.21 3,705.89 21,971.22 23,035.79 12,884.89 10,510.14 9,647.59 8,287.69 8,575.00 6,968.09 8,014.00 10,070.00 13,229.0.1 MeCook 22,923.64 723.50 4,594.03 5,328.13 3,204.58 2,077.60 1,502.20 727.00 1,119.00 779.00 744.00 836.00 1,288.00 Minden . 5,699.45 305.92 1,831.02 1,398.90 533.21 242.02 208.78 56.09 72.03 65.00 291.00 326.00 369.00 Nebraska City _ 16,413.60 594.54 3,428.46 3,260.93 1,635.71 653.27 884.73 955.00 532.09 617.00 702.00 925.00 2,219.00 Norfolk 38,908.82 1,562.59 10.452.17 10.054.97 5,295.59 2,222.11 1.648.91 934.76 1,128.09 1,002.00 1,062.72 1,361.00 2,154.00 North Platte 34,028.78 1,087.57 7,936.04 7,079.13 3,900.14 3,577.30 1,052.64 -682.00 665.00 966.00 943.00 1,223.00 2,311.00 Ogallala 6,570.84 150.90 1,092.46 1,172.88 341.15 84.29 169.10 201.09 661.00 349.00 308.00 985.00 1,156.0} Omaha 517,207.96 10,464.94 71,869.73 89,671.57 63,773.89 47,097.28 37,819.21 34,387.14 35,979.20 29,208.00 29,245.00 31,633.00 36,059.09 Plat-mouth 11,673.1)7 744.00 3,772.19 2.515.66 1,063.36 286.94 172.82 222.00 370.00 225.00 215.00 324.00 1,462.00 SeotUbluff.— 57,063.60 913.13 7,351.85 6,275.83 14,765.52 10,713.31 4,290.54 2,479.99 1,944.00 1,379.41 1,137.00 1,604.00 4,209.09 ¦The monthly classification is bailed on the date of tho benefit check. 72 </seg>
         <seg id="p087">TAiLE i-7: N«mlr«r of Weeks Compensated for Each Month of the Year 1939, Classified by Local Employment Service ¦¦ Office 1- . Employment Total .' . CALENDAR MONTHS 1U39 ¦ Service . for" '¦"" —" ~ ! ~ ! "~ '¦ ! \ - ' 01-ce Year' January February March April May • June July August Sept. October Nov. Dee. TOTAI. '__ -. .150,995 3.723 26,011 28,244 18.801 13,824 9,884 7,794 8,083 6.956 7,380 8,560 11,735 Out-of-SUte __ ____ — 11,861 40 ,1,003 1,616 1,241 1,182 918 " 7-T 824 ' SosT 996 1,096 1,384 Alliance _ _ _ 1,124 27 246 303. 115 85 S3 36 42 41 41 44 61 Beatrice __— . 5,041 153 991 1,063 .... 597 405 298 197 193 174 224 286' 460 Chadron— —. __ —. 1,522 55 377 456 217 140 83 30 30 23 18 23 70 Columbus __—: —— _—__ 3,939 205 1,091 948 490 307 174 96 78 107 101 - 93 249 Falls City _ -_ '. ; 1,803 59 509 356 223 158 88 46 54 44 66 91 109 Fremont _— —— — 5,201 100 1,093 1,078 691 364 256 163 163 147 207 317 562 Grand Island—. — _— : —; 9,984 306 2,176 2,241 1,572 1,088 657 389 329 288 233 266 439 Hastings ____ —. — __ . 5,403 149 991 1,073 633 419 373 191 235 217 300 369 453 Holdrege __ — 2,211 102 700 513 173 97; 54 54 77 86 73 04 188 Kearney — ; —: __. ;— '''.'¦ 4,843 132 US4 950 468 380 198 94 101 125 167 261 483 Lincoln — —— __ : _ 16,554 44. 2,657 2,850 1,582 1,329 1,188 998 1,001 848 965 1,181 1,614 McCook'-. : ___ _ 2,763 88 574 655 350 229 186 90 132 102 93 104 160 Mlnden ___ _ ____ — 800 42 255 201 ¦ 82 40 32 8 10 8 34 37 51 Nebraska City ; . 2,243 '-'. 89 499 474 218 85 113 121 69 78 95 119 283 Norfolk—.; __ 4,787 192 1,297 1,254 627 274 203 125 131 123 134 168 259 North Platte . 4,023 129 922 870 645 446 199 82 78 119 ,105 148 280 Oga-sla : :.¦'. 661 17 120 124 44 11 17 21 67 33 29 84 104 Omaha ____ 58,863 1,136 8,107 0,987 7,278 5,519 4,298 4,009 4,206 3,303 3,333 3,572 4, OK Plat-iimth 1,385 87 455 327 132 41 21 26 47 28 26 34 161 Scotubjuff ...... 6,484 114 904 875 1,423 1,225 445 289 226 170 ' 140 173 440 'the monthly classification is based on the date of the benefit cheek. 'The number of weeks is approximately equivalent to the number of checks written. 73 </seg>
         <seg id="p088">TABLE B-8: Number of Initial Claims Received Monthly During the Calendar Year 1939, Classified by Local Office Employment Total CALENDAR MONTHS 11139 Service for Ofllce Year January February March April May June July Auitunt Sept. October Nov. Dec. TOTAL, — 44,937 14.2.511 4.523 8.314 :1.i)09 2.'&gt;:il 2,324 1.514 1.715 1,421 2.051 2.172 2,847 Oub-of-State - 3,986 (ITS 304 SCO 359 2(81 247 227 247 2411 2011 293 380 Alliance 355 122 47 57 20 1:1 |l is II 12 11 al 2(1 Beatrice - 1,088 4SG 105 137 124 87 65 54 411 42 27S 91 HO Chadron 412 178 49 52 21 HI 10 13 X 6 9 23 18 Columbus 959 42S 103 128 55 4S 25 20 25 10 15 43 59 Falls City 557 236 57 58 54 23 15 25 17 7 20 10 23 Fremont 1.504 500 152 170 109 02 57 42 73 40 50 75 102 Grand Island 2,676 978 330 387 307 133 102 71 77 53 52 78 10S Hastings 1,298 452 153 145 121 70 55 47 30 44 74 45 50 Holdrese 665 21i0 67 79 31 20 17 27 23 20 14 27 44 Kearney - 1.307 505 131 141 120 CO 2S 42 33 30 58 77 142 Lincoln 4,576 1,425 410 302 421 273 287 220 170 175 246 270 305 McCook 767 297 101 102 40 38 40 29 23 12 20 24 29 Hinden 213 104 24 15 18 8 5 1 0 7 2 11 12 Nebraska City - 803 277 70 70 41 25 62 24 19 22 24 54 115 Norfolk 1,428 739 13S 154 69 44 53 20 33 20 29 48 75 North Platte 1,369 511 141 205 122 50 00 22 31 32 43 50 96 Ost-lsla 429 104 02 41 25 13 22 30 32 13 3S 28 21 Omaha 17,121 5,129 1,751 1,865 1,010 1,114 1,004 S2l 720 SSO 779 811 859 Plat-mouth ___—- 535 275 10 40 28 11 10 7 7 7 13 27 as Scot-blurt 2,229 512 162 734 202 125 85 CO 69 31 22 48 179 74 </seg>
         <seg id="p089">TABLE B-9: Number of Continued CUimi R«c.ind Monthly During Hie C»tond-r Y»»r 1939, Clmified by Local OHic« Employment Total ¦ CALENDAR MONTHS 1939 Service .'. for. .":¦~— ' " " : : ——- —: : : C^" 6* Year January February March April Way June July August Sept. October Nov. Dee. TOTAL ____ -19.686 23,972 36,858 36.277 25.133 18,483 12,932 9.790 10.391 8,838 9,569 11,315 16,128 Out-af-State .19,528 .827 2,056 2,570 2,049 1J47 1,262 1,053 1,306 1,275 1,451 1,664 2,268 Alliance 1,530 181 . 532 329 144 111 84 40 53 44 51 61 100 Beatrice . _ ___ — 7,188 787 1,315 1,271 690 518 390 233 229 227 502 380 644 Chadron "-'....,' '— 2,209 369 487 524 : 232 202 103 48 42 35 25 44 98 &lt;Mu_ibils — — 5,629 942 1,295 1,183 628 426 196 121 106 131 110 126 365 Falls City _ '. _ 2,706 374 626 399 . 278 179 95 109 64 257 87 95 143 Fremont __— ____ . 7,330 1,019 1,493 1,360. 770 448 275 199 219 210 252 366 709 Grand Island — _ 14,110 1,888 2,868 2,851 2,041 1,242 737 476 410 356 - 290 351 600 Bastings __ ;—.7,121 725, 1,244 '1,260 775 560 435 219 294 272 370 436 531 Boldrege ; . __ _ 3,128 548 841 574 226 US' 02 58 118 102 89 139 i 223 Kearney — .. 6,331 700 1,330 1,212 692 472 258 128 150 158 . 204 331 696 Wncoln ...'..','. .¦¦,..',_' 22,540 2,401 3,373 3,301 2,121 1,755 1,403 - 1,178 1,245 1,016 1,222 1,530 1,992 McCook ;,-¦..,¦¦.'¦; 4,208 584 788 " . 869 462 320 270 146 187 131 86 134 231 Mlnden ___ : 1,005 233 223 203 97 44 33 10 13 24 36 35 64 Nebraska City _ __ 3,290 520 654 554' 243 122 184 131 84 102 110 171! 415 Norfolk ___ ; _ ' 6,678 1,089 1,679 -.1,507 653 1132 250 170 155 148 153 202 340 North Platte -; S,SSS 832 1,324 1,024 800 511 270 103 10S 150 162 202 396 OgaUala = ; 1,090 99 226 149 66 18 36 ' 30 110 51 57 113 135 Omaha —: _ 86,079 8,624 12,550 13,330 9,887 7,946 5,927 4,927 5,164 3,881 4,134 4,555 5,154 Plattamouth ; 2,094 441 , 528 352 152 56 39 60 66 35 36 60 299 ScotUblulT . _ 10,014 789 1,626 1,452 2,121 I.XTC 5!« 359 27S 233 142 330 7:15 75 </seg>
         <seg id="p090">TABLE B-10: Appeal Cases Disposed of During the Calendar Year 1939 Ap - pealed by Claimants and Employers, Classified by Issue Involved Total Appeals Appealed by Claimant Appealed by Employer Issue' Division Action' Division Action Division Action Total Aff. Rev. Mod. Total AIT. Rev. Mod. Total Aff. Key. Mod. Coverage, No. of Workers 46 30 15 1 46 30 15 1 _ _._.;_ Wane Credits, Sufficiency 21 10 9 2 20 9 !l 2 1 1 _ - Coverage, Exclusions __ 20 13 7 — 18 11 7 — - - — — Labor Dispute 19 G 13 _ 11 1 10 _ S 5 3 _ Not Employed 14 S 5 111 8 5 1 _ _ _ — Misconduct. Other Than Gross 11515621353— 3 Voluntary Leavinir 11 7 1 3 5 4 1— 6 .3 _ 8 Suitable Work 851211_— 7412 Misconduct, Gross 4 2 2— 1 1 — _ 3 1 2 _ Ability anil Availability 4 1 3_ 1_ 1— 3 12 — Wairc Credit, Benefit Rate anil Duration _ 2 2__ 1 1 — — 1 1" — — Marriage, Women . 2 2__ 2 2 ___.___. . Claim and Registration 2 1 1— 2 1 1 — — — — — Wane Credits, Other 1 _ 1 — 1 — 1 — — _—-¦'—¦ Student 1 1 — — 1 1 _ _ — — _ — Miscellaneous , 1 1 — — — — — — 11.—.—.. Coverage, Misc. . 1 — 1 — — — — — 1 — 1 ,-i 'Where several issues are involved, the case was classified under the major issue pre - sented in the hearing- and upon which the decision was based. sThe affirmation, reversal or modification of the Division's action is based on t—6 claimant's eligibility for benefits. 76 </seg>
         <seg id="p091">TAIL! B-11: Benefits Chargeeble to Pool as ef Deemster 31, 1939, Classified by Industry Condition of Chargeable Accounts December 31,1939 Chargeable Active and "~" " INDUSTRY to Pool Overdrawn Inactive . Solvent - No. Amount No. Amount No. Amount No. Amount TOTAL _ _ m W0.584.53'82 $34.708.91 58 110.5 C.61 31 114,772.77 CONSTRUCTION of 35.078.66 2? 22,347.24 T 2,863.58 W '1),865.8i Bldg. Const., Gen. Contrs—lo 9,847.89 4 2,430.87 3 1,609.39 3 5,807.63 Other General Contractors 36 21,918.01 22 17,168.78 4 944.61 10 3,814.72 Special Trade Contractors 6 3,310.76 3 2,757.59 1 309.68 2 243.49 MAN-FACTORING . 16 7,391.82 9 6,938.05 6 1,318.34 1 135.13 Food and Kindred Product-—"? 1,533.45 3 470.37 3 1,063.08 _' ' Apparel * Other Fin. Prod. from Fab. ft Similar litis 2 4,,t57.50 2 4,657.50 ¦_' _ '_ _ Fur. ft Fin. Lbr. Products— 2 310.34 1 250.34 1 60.00 _ Stone, Clay, and Glass Products 4 795.27 3 659,84 _ 1. 135.43 Electrical Machinery - 1 27.40 _ 1 27.40 _ Misc. Mtor. Industries. 1 167.86— 1 167.86— TRANSPORTATION _ 8 2,698.48 _* 1,271.51 4 1,426.97 — ____—- ... Trucking- and/or Warehousing. "v ' ~ ; • —' ' '.' for Hire —__ : 6 1,770.23 3 1,241.12 3 529.11 _ Services Allied to Transporta - tion, I Not Elsewhere Classified 2 928.25 1 30.39 1 897.86 — UTILITIES 1 66.59 — , ; _ __-__ 1 66.5.1 Local Utilities ft Local Pub. "" " .~ ~ * Serv., Not Elsewhere Class. 1 66.59 •_ _, ' 1 66.50 WHOLESALE, RETAIL TRD. 63 8,368.32 24 3,580.97 33 3,545.41 6 1,241.94 Full-Service and Limited- '. ¦""" .-' ' . . T"" !.'.""' ¦* — ~' —' *. ' Function Wholesalers _— 4 757.46 1 231.67 i 2 391.03 1 134.74 Wholesale Distributors, Other ! Than Full-Service and Limited- Function Wholesalers : 10 1,394.51 6 443.52: 2 37.75 2 913.24 . Retail General Merchandise 4 215.83 1 .89 2 151.65 1 63.29 Retail Food (Incl. Liquor)—- 5 644.34 2 389.76 2 132.23 1 122.35 Retail Automotive 5 227.39 1 52.13 4 175.28 _ Retail Apparel and Accessories 1 16.30 — 1 16.30 _ Other Retail Trade ; 3 449.61 2 218.35 1 231.26 _ Eating and Drinking Places— 24 3,979.57 7 1,705.08 17 2,274.49 _ Filling Stations, Garages, and Automobile Repair Services— 6 636.82 4 630.57 1 88.93 1 8.32 Other Whsl., Retail Trade—_ .1 46.49— 1 46.49 _ FINANCE, INSURANCE, AND REAL ESTATE . 5 2,619.26 1 71.63 _2 955.44 2 1,592.19 See. Dealers ft Inv. _anklng_.T 1,549.71 — _ 1 1,549.71 Other Finance Agencies— _—- 1 .897.16 — _.'l 897.16 _ . Insurance Agents and Brokers 1 42.48 —— _ — 1 42.48 RI. Est. Dlrs.i Agfa., Brokers 2 129.91 1 71.63 1 58.28 — — SERVICE INDUSTRIES 18 1.455.55 10 537.05 5 453.77 3 464.73 Hotels; Rooming Houses, . ~ Camps, and Other Lodging Places — 5 356.97 4 338.49 1 18.48 _ Personal Services : 4 97.03 2 46.84 1 42.00 1 8.19 Other [Business Services——l 7.30 1 7.30 — ¦' . ¦¦_ _. Employment Agencies and Com- - • mereial and Trade Schools 1 44.36 1 44.36 _ _ Amusement, Recreation, Re - lated Services, N. E. C—— 5 493.35 2 100.06 3 393.29 _ . Nonprofit Membership Org 2 456.54 .- .'____._.'¦ 2 456.54 MISCELLANEOUS __8 2,368.51 J&gt; 962.46 _ ______ 3 1,406.05 Ag. ft Similar Serv. Estab.—"if 357.88 1 27.10 T 330.78 Nonmetalic Mm. :ft Quarry. 6 2,010.63 4 935.36 _. 2 1,015.2} NOT CLASSIFIED - _—_ 539.34 ¦The amount of benefits charged to the pool on account of active, Inactive and solvent accounts will not add to the total charged to the pool because the item of 1539.34 shown under the"Not Classified" item in the industry classification is included in the total, since it was not chargeable on the basis of wage credits to any individual account. 77 </seg>
         <seg id="p092">TABLE B-12: Experience of Individual Employer Reserves Through the Calendar Year 1939, Classified by Industry and by Size of Firm. Active January 31. 1940 1 INDUSTRY ."•§„" _ mil Numlx-r of Aecuuntii With Ratio of J fc| !_§". "g_, fisi 0.1 5.0 10.0 20.0 60.0 100.0 "i g I SJ- S £__ o"e~otnl 0.0 4. -I Sl.ll 19.9 49.9 99.9 -over -8 o-hQ can.- osSo z«l TOTAL - - ¦5&gt;,:1C6.702.i»0 $1,075. 414.07 11. 5 3,395 1.170 .Vifi 4.1 4Kli 494 IS7 81 2,234 CONSTRUCTION 503,505T53 -_1.8C8.3b' 44.1 -11 57 22 15_ 2(1 _____ _____ 3i) *194 BuildinK Construction, General Contractor* ... 152,442.90 52.GG4.03 34.5 7B 20 7 ti S 19 11 5 50 General Contractors, Other Than Buildinc . 2(12,743.53 147.757.3S 56.2 110 IS 5 :i 9 23 30 22 92 Construction, Special Trade Contractors 55,322.10 21,414.95 24.2 fif&gt; 19 10 fi 9 10 S 3 46 MANUFACTURING 2,527,744.50 31a.74G.27 11.2 483 99 104 77 SS _____ 25 9 3_6 Food and Kindred Products.- - _ 1.739.761.56 210,581. 38 12.1 192 31 2&lt;i 40 41 :!7 11 3 159 Apparel and Other Finished Product* 42,580.04 14,023.9:1 32.9 1.1 1 3 2 2 3 2 2 14 -umber nnd Timber Basic Products-. 31,410.70 1.485.60 4.7 7 .... 5 1 1 7 Furniture and Finished Lumber Products 61.556.i18 (1,707.47 10.S 25 4 fi :: 4 5 2 1 21 l Paper and Allied Products - 36,925.05 1,691.28 4.6 fi 2 2 1 1 4 &gt; PrintinK, Publishing-, and Allied Industries.. 389,079.45 19,827.23 5.1 S9 32 2S 111 9 9 1 ;,S Chemicals and Allied Products _ 79,675.22 4,170.23 6.2 32 9 11 5 5 2 23 Leather nnd Leather Products - 14,236.99 545.35 3.8 5 2 2 1 __ 3 Stone, Clay, and Glass Products 85,448.43 21,476.33 25.1 29 „ 3 3 5 11 4 3 29 Iron and Steel and Their Products 103.018.09 11,357.45 11.0 19 2 B 2 5 1 3 ... 17 Nonfcrrous Metals and Their Products — 47,906.24 6,554.03 13.7 12 2 1 4 4 1 10 Electrical Machinery 17.405.41 2.74G.01 15.8 6 1 2 _ _ 3 5 Machinery (Except Electrical) - 117,488.06 7.857.73 6.7 IS 3 5 3 2 .&lt; _. lo Miscellaneous Manufacturing Industries 60,942.70 0,692.27 11.0 2S 7 4 2 9 4 2 _ 21 TRANSPORTATION 416.835.53 50.7G5.70 12.2 111 ______ 11 14 17 _____ 9_ 4_ 77 Street, City Railways, and Bus Lines 88,346.36 6,890.43 7.8 3 1 1 1 ______ 2 TrucMwr and/or Warehousinn; for Hire 130,643.75 26,931.82 20.6 75 26 5 9 12 14 6 3 49 Other Transportation, Except Water 139,000.43 13,055.6!) 9.4 21 1 4 3 5 G 2 _ 20 Services Allied to Transportation 58,847.99 3,887.76 6.6 12 6 1 1 __ 2 1 1 6 UTILITIES ; ¦ 832.281.06 42.682.93 5.1 57 18 12 14 6_ 5_ 2_ — _) Communication: Telephone, Te-Kt-oph 526,661.29 27,904. 7G 5.3 33 15 5 7 4 2 __ __ 19 Utilities: Electric and Gas ! 303,944.97 14,172.15 4.7 19 2 7 7 _ 3 __ _ 17 Local Utilities and Local Public Services 1,774. SO . G0G.02 34.1 5 1 _ _ 2 2 _ WHOLESALE AND RETAIL TRADE 3,373,269.01 305,941.25 9.1 1,769 67S 297 229 251) 230 ______ _24 1,09,-, Full-Service and Limited-Fund. Wholesalers 603,525.19 45,329.84 7.5 218 70 47 37 35 21 6 2 149 Wholesale Distributors, Other—: 702,416.40 57,145.24 8.1 460 262 69 48—40 24 10 7 200 Retail Genera) Merchandise 616,887.47 40,475.72 7.8 94 40 17 12 10 9 G _ ¦ 55 Retail Food (Includes Liquor Stores) 255,033.16 33,034.57 13.0 118 31 13 13 27 26 G 2 S7 78 </seg>
         <seg id="p093">-_-S-?S-Timi-JS^-~~_--r--X- —-2C9.115.88 22.458.81 8.4 153 37 3(1 32 33 13 3 1 118 Retail Apparel and Accessories. .. ... 171,943.74 13,274.60 7.7 100 35 14 18 15 15 3 _ Go Retail. Trade, Hot Elsewhere Classified 235,483.07 24,804.02 10.5 168 66 27 14 25 25 9 2 102 Eatlng and Drinking Places 87,329.81 19.054.33 21.9 134 35 11 7 24 41 . 10 6 99 Filling Stations and Garages : 86,791.42 12,079.95 _J3. 9 100 35 11 IS IS 20 5 3 65 Other Wholesale and Retail Trade-—-—-— 442,718.87 38,213.07 8.6 222 67 52 35 28 36 3— 1 155 FINANCE. INS.. AND REAL ESTATE! 760,640.48 35,010.47 4.6 265 145 63 13 21 17 5 1_ .121 Banks and Trust Companies .22,160.63 329.21 1.5 11 9 1 ¦•_¦'' ' —• 1_ — 2 Security Dealers and Investment Banking. 64,475.05 2,984.90 5.5 23 14 4 2 3 — — _ 9 Finance Agencies, Not Elsewhere Classified— 86,292.61 3,321.94 3.9 39 18 12 3 2 4 ¦'_ _¦•: 21 Insurance Carriers : :: ... ¦ 462,442.78 16,408.75 3.5 91 . 52 27 4 5 1 2 _ 40 Insurance Agents and Broken- '. 37,131.20 837.40 2.3 31 22 6 " _21 — — 9 Real Estate Dealers, Agents, and Brokers— 54,879.51 9,837.18 17.9 53 20 92 8 10 3 1 33 Real Estate, Insurance, Loans, Law.—— 43,258.80 1,291.09 3.0 17 10 4 2 1 — - — — 7 SERVICE INDUSTRIES -- 608,396.70 ______ 13.7 425- 131 46 58 74 79 27 10 295 Hotels, Rooming Houses, Camps 136,851.63 31,645.38 . 23.1.,' 106 28 3 9 22 29 11 4 78 Personal Services 179,332.23 16,813.48 9.4 103 28 14 23 IS 17 12 75 Business Services, Not Elsewhere Classified- ' 96,309.62 7,903.87 8.2 58. 22 911 7 7 1 1 36 Employment Agencies and Schools 14,299.17 1,506.64 10.5 11 5 1 12 1— 1 6 Misc. Repair Services and Hand Trades 11,889.69 994.27 8.4 13 7 1— 3 2 _ '_. 7 Motion Pictures : ' 76,899.09 7,033.61 9.1 45 12 10 7 8 8 _ _ 33 Amusement and Recreation, N. E. C— 39,854.31 12,701.53 31.9 43. 10 1 2 8 9 11 2 33 Medical and Other Health Services - 26,488.82 1,923.44 7.3 .25 11 2 3 4 4 1 ¦¦_.-. 14 Other Prof, and Social-Service Agencies . ' 7,492.34 631.22 8.4 6 1 2 1 1 1 — _ 5 Nonprofit Membership Organizations-. : 16,961.91 2,213.53 13.1 14 0 3 .1 11 2 — 8 Other Service Industries 2,017.89 : 0.0 1 1 — — — — — — — MISCELLANEOUS — 44,023.48 20,034.72.. 45.5 3i_ ¦ 8_ 1 1 4_ 8 9 3 . 26 Livestock and Poultry Farms—. — 3,283.76 1,162.29 ''33.4 3 _.. ._ __ 111 ... _' 3 Truck Farm- and Misc. Agriculture 6,770.00 1,063.41 15.7 6 2 1 1 11 — — 4 Agriculture and Similar Service Estab 635.98 526.81 82.8 3 — — — — . 1 1 1 3 Crude-Petroleum and Natural-Gnu Production 1,056.96 136. GG . 12.9 4 3 _. _.'.;_. 1 ; '_. — 1 Nonmetallie Mining and Quarrying 32,276.78 17,145.55 \ 53.1 18 3 _. — .2 4 7 2 15 SIZE OF FIRM (1939 Pay Roll) TfiTAT-' " '""' $9,366,702.59 51,075.414.67 11.5 3,395 1.170 556 421 486 494 187 81 2,234 Under «5,000 — . —- 167,821.46 48,103.07 28.7 760 482 31 22 40 77 60 48 278 $ 6,000 — I 9,999 .'87,479.66 62,725.91 16.2 748 321 77 61 90. 137 50 12 428 $ 10.000 — $ 19.999 843,960.61 117,658.34 13.9 816 244 134 105 144 141 40 8 674 120,000 — * 29,999— 601,238.46 82,440.20 13.7 327 65 82 45 73 46 •J. , 8 263 $30 000 — $49 999-— 895,m.50 132,931.58 14.9 304 36 V 87 66 49 44 19 3 270 160 000 —J 99 999 : 1,289,162.20 143,740.21 11.1 211 20 80 65 54 24 I ¦ ¦ • 1 ' SS $100 000 — $499 999 ; 2,609,045.03 278,135.04 10.7 171 2 64 54 33 24 3 1 170 $500,000 — $999,999 799,374.66 65,613.45 8.2 15 _ 5 7 2 1 — — J5 $UH»,00;) and over-— .1,773,510.71 144,066.87 8.1 13 — 6 6 1 _.—¦—¦ 13 - 'Excludes experience in contributions and benefits of accounts inactive January 31, 1940. _ -Includes besides regular required contribution payments by employers subject to the Law as of January 31, 1940, credits to certain ac - counts from the 1936 Congressional refund as provided for in L. B. No. 44, and voluntary contributions. .„,_,_ 3The ratio in these columns is also the ratio of 1939 benefits to cumulative contributions computed for individual Arms. . 79 </seg>
         <seg id="p094">TABLE B-13: Number of Employers with Variable 1940 Contribution Rates, Classified by Industry and Sixe of Firm 1 Total No. No. Accounts With Bate ot INDUSTRY' ofEm- plovers 2.7% 2.5% 2.0% 1.5% 1.0% Per Cent —— 100.0 68.3 0.8 1.3 2.5 27.1 TOTAL 3,395 2,321 27 43 82 922 WHOLESALE AND RETAIL TRADE. tW T^M "To* *_2f &lt;=W 'W Wholesale Distributors, Other Than Full-Service ¦ '' " and Limited-Function Wholesalers 460 303 2 ' 9 8 138 Other Wholesale and Retail Trade 222 128 3 1 5 85 Full-Service and Limited-Function Wholesalers 21S 120 1 8 8 s 81 Retail Trade, Not Elsewhere Classified I6S 109 1 2 4 52 Retail Automotive 155 103 1 _ 10 j4l Eating nnd Drinkinir Places 134 IIS 1 1 • — 14 Retail Food (Includes Liquor Stores) 118 91 3 13 20 Retail Apparel and Accessories ICO 66 1 1 2 30 Filling Stations, Garages, and Automobile Repair Services 100 70 — 1 3 26 Retail General Merchandise 94 54 2 — 3 35 MANUFACTURING 453 331 3_ 8\ 17 • 124 Food and Kindred Products 192 138' 3 3 13 35 Printing, Publish!—!, and Allied Industries S9 28 — 2 2 47" Chemicals and Allied Products 32 23 _ — 9 Stone. Clay, and Glass Products 29 26 — _ 12 Furniture and Finished Lumber Products 25 20 — — — 5 Iron and Steel and Their Products 19 13—1—5 Machinery (Except Electrical) 18 13 — 113 Apparel nnd Other Finished Products Made from Fabrics and Similar Materials 15 .12 — ' 3 Nonferrous Metals and Their Products 12 11 _ _ _ • 1 Lumber and Timber Basic Products 7 2 — I—4 Paper and Allied Products 6 3 — — — 3 Electrical Machinery 6 4 . 2 Leather and Leather Products 5 2 3 Miscellaneous Manufacturing Industries 2S 26 _ _ —2 SERVICE INDUSTRIES 425 308 5 6 9 97 Hotels, Rooming Houses, Camps, and Other Lodging Places 106 90 2 2 _"-'_ Personal Services 103 64 2 1 5 31 Business Services, Not Elsewhere Classified——— 5S 38 _ _ — 20 Motion Pictures 45 27 1 _ 3 14 Amusement and Recreation and Related Services, Not Elsewhere Classified 43 3? _ 113 Medical and Other Health Services . ___— 25 18 1 _ '6 Nonprofit Membership Organizations 14 13 1 Miscellaneous Repair Services and Hand Trades— 13 9 •— 1 3 Employment Agencies and Commercial and Trade Schools 11 8 _ _ • _ 3 Other Professional and Social-Service Agencies and Institutions 6 3 _.-_._ 3 Other Service Industries 1 — 1 FINANCE. INSURANCE, AND REAL ESTATE- 265 143 — 1_ 2 119 Insurance Carriers 91 36 _ _¦ 1 54 Real Estate Dealers, Agents, and Brokers 53 42 _.:_'_' 11 Finance Agencies, Not Elsewhere Classified 39 22 ; — 17. Insurance Agents and Brokers 31 23 - 1 . 7 Security Dealers and Investment Banking 23 8 . 1 . 14 Real Estate, Insurance, Loans, Law Offices: i . . Any Combination 17 8 _"'_.¦•¦ _¦ 9 Banks and Trust Companies 11 4 — — 7 CONSTRUCTION 251 224 2_ 1 4 20 General Contractors, Other Than Building 110 99 2 — — 9 Building Construction, General Contractors 76 68 _ — 1 7 Construction, Special Trade Contractors 65 57 .' 13 4 80 </seg>
         <seg id="p095">TABLE B-13—Conrimwd INDUSTRY* T o t U_m!- A***""*™*-* iHA.S.OH'I'A'nON — »~ 'T *? '¦'T'to 1 Jhucldna- and/or Warehousing for Hire-——.-75~ —69 ~ T"^ -"5 Services Allied to Transportation, . ~ ¦ . Not Elsewhere Classified 12 10 » S(re_*&lt;S |''"n*an, and Interurban Railways, ~ "~ "~ vrnrma and Suburban »» "¦&gt;«¦ 3 . i _ __ _ 2 _yTHJT.ES ___ _— : __ 57 , s _. - - _£ Communication: Telephone, Telegraph, and ' ~ ' •' Related Services ' - ' -it -i_ , •,„ Utilities: Eleetrie -n.il.- 19 n ~ ~ 'l Jf Local Utilities and Local Public Services, - - _ S ...?* B"*!**" Cl_«ni«a 5 , - ___________!__ ~ 34 29 T _ Z 1 NonmeUlllc Mining and Quarrying—. ~~js iff —T ""^ 7 Truck Farms, Crop Specialties, and ~^ 1 - . - * ¦ Miscellaneous Agriculture ' 6 5 i Crude-Pc-oleum and Natural-Gas Production.— 4 2 ~ "" ""'.'¦ Livestock and Poultry Farms-—___. 3 _ ~ — — . Agricultural and Similar Service Establishments- 3 3 __ __ __ __ SIZE OF FIRM' 1 i. 7°^^L~~~ — —3 395 --321 « 83 922 .as zy^==i——-ii i |i a »30.000 - .49W" -Sj '¦?!_-¦¦!". 5 .J .J? t SO.OOO ¦¦- 1 99.W -!_'¦ g" ' 1 » W WOO.OOO - 1499.M9 ~ 171 m ' ' 2 2 1? « KOO.OOO — M99.9M —¦ ™ ™A 2 2 J| «_ vI.OOO.OCv and over——__ 13 0 Z Z 1 10 -SS^w"!'™ t?l- 1 1-" nb!. r ? f eml&gt;l°»«s rated as of January 31, 1940. irSSSf cl"8lBe»"™ Code of the Social Security Board, 1939 Edition. one account involving two separate legal entities rated under a joint agree - agr^'e-T °ne acco,mt '"volvins;'three separate legal entities rated under a joint one account involving two separate legal entities rated under a joint agree - v™tio"o*™l£bl!!lTLTmiKi e by the amount of 1939 pay"" ,üblect «•'«•«¦- 81 </seg>
         <seg id="p096">TABLE B-14: 1939 Benefit Experience in Terms of 1939 Pay Roll and the Number of Claimants, Classified by Industry and Size of Firm — . — __ Calendar Year 1939 tS||g . £¦£ INDUSTRY Benefits Pay 801 l Sjj jf .2 g l._ J- wb. o ao TOTAL $1,075,414.6i-'' $121,476,-165.06» $ 8.85 20,676 CONSTRUCTION . . _ _ _ ' J21.866.36' 8,094,655.5T "zTH ' 4,683 Building Construction, General Contractors- 52,661.03 2,791,169.71 IS.S7 1,003 General Contractors, Other Than Building— 147,787.38 3,975,894.63 37.17 3,254 Construction. Special Trade Contractors 21.41-1.95 1.327,591.04 16.13 426 MANUFACTURING 315.7-t8.27 35,584,914.67 8.87 4.820 Food and Kindred Products 210,581.38 21,780,233.69 9.67 3,256 Apparel and Other Finished Products Made from Fabrics and Similar Materials 14,023.93 522,298.49 26.85 228 Lumber and Timber Basic Products 1,485.56 391,561.54 3.77 20 Furniture and Finished Lumber Products 6,707.47 794,284.69 8.44 121 Paper and Allied Products 1,691.28 459,136.28 3.6S 17 Printing. Publishing, and Allied Industries 19,827.23 4,782,434.93 4.15 235 Chemicals and Allied Products 4,170.23 1,071,355.10 3.89 56 Leather and Leather Products 545.35 172,690.35 3.16 17 Stone. Clay, and Glass Products 21,476.33 1,129,126.82 . 19.02 320 Iron and Steel and Their Product- . 11,357.45 1,253,892.43 9.06 195 Nonferrous Metals and Their Products 6,554.05 671,163.73 9.77 85 Electrical Machinery 2,746.01 223,054.89 12.31 79 Machinery (Except Electrical) 7,887.73 1,472,420.00 6.36 73 Miscellaneous Manufacturing Industries 0,692.27 852,261.73 7.55 118 TRANSPORTATION . . 50,765.70 5,585,066.68 9.09 3,640 Interstate Railroads „ " ' 2,871 . Street, Suburban, and Interurban Railways, and City and Suburban Bus Lines 6,890.43 1,111,769.13 6.20 64 Trucking and/or Warehousing for Hire 26,931.82 1,865,550.98 14.44 344 Other Transportation, Except Water Transportation 13,055.69 1,841,751.78 7.0? 238 Services Allied to Transportation, Not Elsewhere Classified 3,557.76 765,994.69 5.0S 123 UTILITIES 42.652.93 10.315,935.20 4.14 521; Communication: Telephone, Telegraph, and Related Services 27,904.76 6,470,178.89 4.31 -.354- Utilities: Electric and Gas 14,172.15 3,822,073.61 3.71 157 Local Utilities and Local Public Services, Not Elsewhere Classified 606.02 23,682.70 25.59 10 WHOLESALE AND RETAIL TRADE- 305,941.25 43,485,732.02 7.04 . 4,687 Full-Service and Limited-Function Wholesalers 45,3-9.84 7,645,755.44 5.93 565 Wholesale Distributors, Other Than Full- Service and Limited-Funct'on Wholesalers 57,145.24 9,217,363.89 6.20 820 Retail General Merchandise . 40,475.72 6,497,487.72 6.23 710 Retail Food (Includes Liquor Stores) 33,034.57 3,262,196.65 10.13 459 Retail Automotive 22,488.81 3,554,306.37 6.33 350 Retail Apparel and Accessories 13,274.60 2,157,196.76 6.15 231 Retail Trade, Not Elsewhere Classifieds 24,804.62 3,043,770.24 8.15 356 Eating and Drinking Places 19,094.33 1.296,189.82 14.73 432 Filling Stations, Garages, and Automobile ¦.----•' Repair Services 12,079.95 1,230,982.69 9.81 182 Other Wholesale and Retail Trade 35,213.67 5,680,482.44 6.85 582 FINANCE. INSURANCE, AND REAL ESTATE 35,010.47 9,615,083.30 3.64 418 Banks and Trust Companies 329.21 280,552.02 1.17 6 Security Dealers and Investment Banking— 2,984.90 625,832.82 4.77 31 Finance Agencies, Not Elsewhere Classified 3,321.94 1,102,546.55 3.04 60 Insurance Carriers 16,408.75 5,853,334.83 2.50 346 82 </seg>
         <seg id="p097">TABLE B-14—CsBrinoBd - _- m Calendar Year 1939 «lS ?1 INDUSTRY Benefit, P-yßoll fjj"* J| ±_:\ ss.; Ii ¦—- : : : ; ___________ Insurance Agents and Brokers— . 837.40 522 558 51 isn v Real gstste Dealer,, Agent., and Brokers- 9.537.1S 661 SB. 40 14 87 142 Real Estate, Insurance, Loans, Law Offices: ...to,_m-.w. h.bi it_ ' Any Combination ¦ - ¦ ¦ - • ¦ i oai m &gt; mq c—. 17 0~. ,„ SERVICE INDUSTRIES Z_gSw S.lHiHisl __S t&lt;H Hotels, Rooming Houses; Camps, and Other : : ' "~ " ' P.^| Brs_'J^_- : ;- ".WS-ffi- 2,026,165.95 15.62 620 "BLSP, Not f r*" f',""""' ?;S :-*S&amp;S ¦'«' S Employment Agencies and Commercial and jM-aneot^pal, Service, and ''"M* . 175'°1U9 «™' » mSESfSSS-L ; "^ " 994.27 1115,003.87 6.01 12 A^^rSr Recreation and Belated ' 7'mM ™ &lt;« Other; Profewional and Soelal-ServtaT .* - d«, 11-. 95 5.62 32 Agencies and Institutions " ¦ 631.22 76 840 19 821 11 Nonprofit Membership Organisations 2,213.53 249|306;00 8!88 41 Other Service Tnrtii«lri._ - 26 905 00 MTSCELLANEOUS —___ _ 20,034.72 ¦ 610.'618."52 32.81 453 Livestock and Poultry Farms 9 __•" 1,162.29 42.228 17 "2752 ' Truck Fsmts, Crop Specialties, and ..•"•-* ¦"'al'" - ¦"" -, MiMeuaneotttt. AgrlcnHare3. ; 1.063 41 ftft (VK n? 19 m Atrricultural and Similar Service . MM.« 88,086.02 12.07 _ E*tabll.h-ii-it» 526 81 9 01101 5.1 ii as Crude-Petroleum and Natural-Gas 9.913.5 D 53.14 66 Production _. - - -¦- - : 136 66 4 18120 32 68 1 NonmetaDic Mining and dnarrying 17,145.'55 466,-09.'33 36.78 386 SIZEiOF FIRM (1939 Pay Roll) TOt AL — ——: t1.0T5.414.67 im.476.468.06 8.85 t'smF'^'am,' — — 48.103.07 1,871,561.65 "afro lw'^~lil'^r : : ' 62,725.91 5,513 936.57 11.38 J JS'SK ~ I M— —" 1«.e68.34 11,577,653.39 10.16 J X'SSJ - | S'gS— : —— 82.440-20 8,023,355.66 10.28 t m'nm ~ I _?'_*?-— " -¦ WW.BB 11,727,281.26 11.34 Sim'Sm ~: Lm'IIS— ~—— —_ 143.740.21 16 776 655.94 8.57 sKS ~ SS'-S- ~ — 278,135.04 33,858,930.12 8.21 S°°oJ?SLr **»,«»_ — —— 65.613.45 10,381,415.00 6.32 31,000,000 snd over „ _ 144,066.87 21,745,788.57 6.63 &gt;™fn^sf ._i!LT nto wh? o^ U,S. i'h,!? lr beneflt ***» --* received their first check :-iffi_^lSsS^_Xl^ ««**,. «•..»-- - the 1937 edition of th. Simitott'^ fa Indo,M ? nto "A*-*-- -a* « 'i*i\ e.S-,-!m PJJ S. ro.. "-?"" 'ndude only experience of active .Mounts a, of January active during some part of the year. - 83 </seg>
         <seg id="p098"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>