<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>...23rd ANNUAL REPORT... OF THE Nebraska State Poultry Association Annual Convention and Exhibition...... Held in Lincoln, Nebraska, January 14th to 19th, 1907</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
            <seg id="p001">..J?3rd ANNUAL REPORT... OF THE cHebraska State Poultry (Association Annual Contention and Exhibition Held in Lincoln, January 14th to 19th, 1907 LUTHER P. LUDDEN, Secretary </seg>
           
            <seg id="p002">Letter of Transmittal Lincoln, Nebraska June 30, 1907. His Excellency GEORGE L. SHELDON, ■ Governor of Nebraska. Sir:- On behalf of the Nebraska State Poultry Association, I herewith sub - mit the annual report. Very respectfully, Secretary. </seg>
           
            <seg id="p003">Officers of the cNjbraska State Poultry (Association for the Ye*r 1906—1907 I I.. NonraJ !S . Johnson Omaha Luther IV Ludden I I. I.. I I HOAKI) &lt;&gt;K MANAGERS I aiTenitj Lincoln w II Officers of the cNsbraska State Pou.try (Association for the ye*r 190. K.\K( I1IVK oKKlt KKS M. Johnson c . i.iwciiin^ Luther I". I. widen I i 1 \ mini HOARD o| MAN M.KKS i olnmbna I i Hradshaw Uinaha I. It. I r, Mi. .lit \ I). ItiirlmiiN. ! l.im-nlii .nii(.i:&gt; I'oi; i H V II. NtaeUabMfc* </seg>
           
            <seg id="p004">of the Tiventy-Third cAnnual Convention of The Nebraska State 'Poultry Association htld a: Lincoln, S^Cebnslut, hnuary 15 and 19, 1907 Lincoln, Nebr., Jan. 15, 1907. LThe annual meeting was called to order at I p. m.. President Nor in the chair. when ttit' secret;! I the 41st name Mr. Lyman moved and Mr. Seabrook seconded. That the further proceedings under the roll call be dispensed with, a quorum bein*: The motion was adopted. 1 announced the regular time and place for the an - ■.i\\! of Mich other Iiumi Ltion. tion then adjourned until Thursday evening at UTHER P. LUDDEX, ■tary. ilar meeting of the State Poultry Association was called to order at 8 o'clock p. m. January 17, 1907, by T. L. N'orval, President. PRESIDENT The first order of hi; he calling of the roll by th&gt; Urr bWhen the 4lid name on the roll was reached A. E. Wagner moved, &gt;nded by Mr. Hardin, that the further calling of the roll bo dis - sed with. Vote being taken the motion was unanimously carried. The minutes of the last meeting were read by the Secretary, and on motion, dulj </seg>
            <seg id="p005">60 Lilture. recognized and pi WHERK Nebraska AC annoui braska that a b: (rounds, and hWHER ■ . Poultry •&gt; • if our &lt;&gt;f a mill r the Seer. I would members of the l«'g]-..i'\' ■ 1 have met a nui. ■ ..'' - to them. b\. lem for 1 It won t hun . to build ii| managemeir , . ■ •■. ■ &gt;, ■}&lt;•■■■ &gt;,.,■ .- \Vrit&lt; (d on r Senator and know him personalh erful foroe. 1 don t care ho« EAlutation, when a letcr con- le will say. I am known u i when they want I And he will pay attention to it and remember it I kn. bill which the people of the state Hid not want an ■ n from -chool district in tl. &gt; hool district in his dill ing him to Tote I will rote to have that bill k man said. "The letter writing </seg>
            <seg id="p006">61 writing will stop when good laws on the statute a your and if they Libout ; d of Agri- lilding on !)*• Board have come into our ■ Hid get a show m a show like this. You will : as now, and they have ar - hat we are •ion be adopted by a rising vote. I do a- ant to see In favor of the Resolution ■te for the Resolution. in the premium U -ar. How about Ki, and LM but t^&lt; the utility birds In far as utility birds go, to are put in the same ave no change what - - added and i arleyed ■at on this premium to the premium list. Now, Mr. urn. I want to thank Qm members for this splendid vote of &gt;lution I have something to carry back that will hat what they have done </seg>
            <seg id="p007">: 1 ask r all m Mr. I I. ! tl move that ti ■ ■ . lull tl 1 think in North Dakota on hand I I ha rifn n nnliniiti </seg>
            <seg id="p008">63 mailing lists certain out The public library at iltry report ;• Till! COi ■ ■inters mplain for nrt didn't take it out &gt;y of thi.- nembership roll has •garni- has to th us TREASURERS REPORT. Officers and Members of the Nebraska State Poultry Asso- iation. it Fair Crounds held on ■ rt in full an itemized ac Hie Annual in- lit for all purposes including Annual exhibition for Jam and v in my I ippropriation of Clay Center $ • Hows $27.7". p. lecturer RriRham . 7 Paid E Board meeting CM 7 l';iid I Cook Johnson expense to Hoard meeting 3.30 ic as Press Agt. . M </seg>
            <seg id="p009">64 - Respectfully S I. L. Lyma: Mr A ft«*&lt; ' r«*t iir ■ ittnd at $ . Mr I .utte: the eon </seg>
            <seg id="p010">65 :. in that matter and that we now give a unanimous rot* :iks for h on, which secured to use the Auditorium. Mr. E led the motion. manimous vote of thanks to Mr. John - mbodied in the motion of Mr. it. that the report of the Treasurer b« ii. was carried il and other committees. uil committee made its report to ■inted to investigate charges preferred nide its report to the Board and its ac - that action Is final, I take it it Is not Iditional report to this meeting. Llence. first relating to th« L'imiuunication and exploitation it was Iplendid reception which the citizens of Seattle 'munch our Battleship Nebraska, I i a of this Resolution. !r. Hardin. I 01 tr away from us as it think. A runner fron ?old me not long ago had bought $45,000 worth of eggs in two counties In for their foreign trade. That was to go to Seattle. •he Pacific ocean to other countries. taken the motion was carried. The then presented communications regarding the seed 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">66 KushingUn agri- ;i ■, to be known as in to urn i M r \\ W. Hardin tl am glad am UM % ry man of 'k Johnnon strliK&gt; hl Mr. Seabrook. I do not think it more than </seg>
            <seg id="p012">67 ght ask mind for a 1 think ■ i&gt;f it I tint it i ion whether we udying in I could ;is to the legal points putting this in the And while a man may id claim a property right to say that \inder ible to do *th&gt; with the spirit and intention of this how it might bring on the association it many conn: charge il conduct is not in the poultry !&gt; il conduct is. and without any dis •Inns ihat he would ilo ten ■ t under this Resolution we would have to in - ■ lution guarantees to every man who i hearing, it would hardly do lor this association &gt; bui - I think the Resolution tlon, such as we have had otherwise, of Investigating this past year. I think ■r than unprofessional. I don't see how we can very well avoid doing what the g&lt; ka of. I think it is not betrayiag any confidence to say that W tht ws reported, in which harges were D nduct, and unprofi - onduct. We could not turn it down. 1 think when a complaint comes i the Board that a member of this association have not dealt fairly nd honorably with their patrons, this association cannot turn that own without making some investigation either by the Secretary or some committee, or i And to do so would look as though we </seg>
            <seg id="p013">68 were somewhat in collusion with the man who was not trying to be trirtly fair. We have to do that, and so this Resolution will not require anything more than we have to do already. We can't find oat anything about a transaction, whether it is fair and honorable or not. until we make a little investigation; and it will not bring • K more before the associat than it would ot! he Board will ■ ssooia - lon when it undertakes to look after these on its own responsi: the Board to pay an- he honor of the assort a.d to look into them when brought before tim. i ust other - member I v as to whether we can for Mr. Seabrook Yes, I inquired about tl. . k~,. «. fr.. abrook I a man whose legal standing is nnqnesti of this Ass. y do that, and that The advice I think was really that if there wa laws of the Association I and take his stock from him, and the o .Trait that. There Is only one question that arises in n &lt;)88, whether it ought not to be limi* induct. in the phraseol - disbonorable conduct. Mr. I. kl move to strike out the words unprofessional and unbusinesslike d to inset t in t of them the words dishonest and dishonor- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">69 &gt;nds the motion. - i iltry dealings were scarcelydishoneat, orable that I should dislike to have them in raska Association. But if you say dishonest or dishonorable • unbusinesslike and unprofessional, I will accept that. iirook, who offered the Resolution, and Mr. he motion for its adoption, the Resolution was Mr. I. I think we ought also to look after these legal entanglements, as «ck into the Association and selling it to some- Lroutte: 1 think we ought to do that. El have changed the Resolution in that respect to read like tnis: stock or membership certificate to the Association, 10 refund the amount paid thereon" knendment was accepted by the mover and seconder of motion to adopt, and win hese amendmens the Resolution was ■ I added to the by-laws of the Association as Article 11. We are now unaer tne head of Miscellaneous Business. ■ral members of the Association why ;ir club ribbons were not offered and printed in the club or association that of - reached us before our pre - found therein. Th. &gt;me who of November, saying, • ■mium list hail been in ary said: "All right, if I am so far behind I will send the ribbons anyway"; but other secretaries, be- I out the slips and advertise it, did not send Li we might tak up the question to wl not we want to take any action in regard to the ition of 1 1 1 ■ w or the question of judges or anything of that </seg>
            <seg id="p015">70 Mr. ! Board what to do i Lin I It has alwa assumed to il </seg>
            <seg id="p016">71 from rh«'re once. n this l.yniaii ;t: Bris- ithing d.-l D what llowlnK $: • il it. and that is why we e have -rani. Hul it That Is Ir liriKham ■ &gt;r makini emarka or quite 4.",m, and a uffrage member of the • I it does seem to me, and I think M ago. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">72 that it is not fair to your presiding officer tba- ild be con - tinued in office with this membership of 450, and not fair to th. berthjp, wit of men capable of filling at officer Hoard. And I feel it n to you now — wbil- ;r a man An office l» to him — yet 1 will sa&gt; president or any other of - me for one year. all. for and f&lt;&gt; ' and mil \nd now ■ take up i Mr. \\ I w wheel comium from ■ d always. Mr. \ 1 tl I wax sr nominated a prasidi Associatioii toniRl • vote ■ Of Cla 1 » I am •' think l great deal in it.- he did for the Associatioii w! nisbed ■ ■lid all this si'lti.-t. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">73 And he has pushed high up, he has done a good is and for tl tiun. and I think it would be members of this Association year. I wanted to nominate Judge ther I.udden on that several times, I me this year he would have to Hut now, do want to ask that you consider ■mains J ■ :n ■lomination a gentleman who has been &gt;n for a number of years, and that is Lincoln. ;nes to permit his name to be used ilnl tnd Dr. Gaiser. I and the i lowed the following iiouncea i Mr. M If. Johnson a= a for the coming year. PI the ballot of the Association for resident ;ed the motion. Ifnt Mr. E. E. he busin. Mr ■■ 1 v whom I think a majority of man who is mid on the square and honest, and who it leal in the la' which came B. Wagner. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">74 Mr H 1 » Mr. I Mr. \\ Mr. ltu Mr U 1 m;tt Mr. \\ LI wtorm tliat lot &lt;j" </seg>
            <seg id="p020">75 motion for tli that I have served ow you have had, and I out of urly all t ;i? it is a ho can do th&gt; .utle money off of it. All m It' I could take it lik*' Kansas an&lt;: ■ &gt; It. I You know how the l|i out of the pittance ril to give, and tl more. hundred ow, 1 think I have hail my full share of about a chicken without lie funniest u-, that heard. uiiiK poultry in '.-.I me tun is I how long tl ifdia on Poultry, and when they got ild know as much as they did before, probably. thai is a habit : or how poorly thi 1th any q f them dally about !!•■ mlddli n time there are court 1 birds. ■ I am will ■it' Hue. I have the other; lnt find him. reUry </seg>
            <seg id="p021">76 Mr. Harris I would rer of the Nebraska Poult •true ted to Lyman as treasurer. tThe mol d un 1 (1 t-mbers just befor* ■' ■ LIs ii rmal ballot for n - Boai have always takes these bal .routte: I m the ). They must have a i Board ■ LMy 1.1 • Mr. I. I U Mr. O. D. Talbot. wl before and was a valuable man at that tin la a man you will di part i • </seg>
            <seg id="p022">77 mation a man from the North Platte, ■mI know him to be a worker and an honest man, irnbus. .nation, an exhibitor, and a man from the Ed. Eggert. more shows and knows more y other man in th- Burhans uiination, Mr. E E. Smith XV. Davis of Weeping Water. I Mr. Seabrook of University Place me of Wilber was also nominated, seconded by Mr. Hardin Vork, and John Bishop of Ulysses and Mr. Whitcomb p.l so nomi vote counted, showed the following l M -■ - n -• ; u i Hardin I " I I ' Kenne.i Moll Hadley .... 2 * </seg>
            <seg id="p023">78 I hi MEETINGS OF THE BOARD OF MANAGERS tThc . informal and after a general 'I: iard 1.1THKR I" I.IDOEN • tary Lincoln, N&lt; 1907. The Board ■ hair. All preaei Dice and Lyman. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">79 That Rhodes tak&lt; ii Rhode* ■M.I buffs. That R&lt; Thp motion I.ITHKR I' LUDDEX Seer. office. l'i- I anil approved complaint irook, Swart/ley and Smith iianniial meeting to investi- Tite&lt;I the follow- REPORT OF COMMITTEE ' .1. ('..ok Jnfa ■id reviewed cviiien. :• i • • - emitted npp in the case. Signed: CHAS. ROSS F. F. DEVORE. A E. WAGNER seconded • : and Bwartilejr That ;l| nl the papers Id ■ rt-tary. Adopted. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">80 Mr Bowers moved and Swartzley seconded That we dec ffice of Y nt and proceed to fill the vaca- -f-abrook n [r. I.yman swonded That w&lt; ii8ure Mr. Johns' IThe chairmai declined itlon aa a If no objection was lotion as amended was - Luddi that 1 Ludd- onded kThat the mai Smith expert i ards in 9 n The H 1.ITHKK P LT'DDEN. ■tary </seg>
            <seg id="p026">81 Iiincoln. Neb., Jsn. 1 1, 1907. ■ lent Norval Id i a by which we 1 the ind that he •ils be I Mr. Black fowls and iiik to the would nil. de- 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">82 DDBN, Thf Board then l.l'THKR I' I.TDDEN. Secret*ry Treasurer L&gt; cuar &gt;on&lt;i for i Th&lt;&gt; - Board th&lt; w, result!! ii of E B. I&gt;ay of Fi A. I). Hurhans wa&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p028">83 r\M) ORDEK IULTKT riON. ■o. W. ■ ind by •her, for the purpose of raska. and ART] ORl'OKATION orporation shall be the Ne- rransactinR i' w shall be .iint y of Lancaster, state of Nebraska. • be transacted by said corpo - mem of the interests and promotion ilinK and management of poultry, by llection and dissemination of re - ,-■ utility br»-. iiital stock, authorized, of said associa - dollars, which shall be divided of fiive (5) dollars each. Fifty per ■aid in cash at the time of line, and the fifty per cent remaining • the call of the board of directors, at any Uiuo of certih L'fk shall entitle the owner thereof (to '■' ■ del but not more k shall be owned by any one person. II The shares of any stockholder who shall neglect or refuse into the tre;i ■ ■ ■&lt; iation such installments or ms of nioi called for by the board dire. erein provided, within thirty days after notice of ch call, shall, if the board of directors so direct, be declared for - &gt;n be forfeited to the association it ution. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">84 Art. 7. The ualifi' act and dp«Hi </seg>
            <seg id="p030">85 . . he day and year L. MEYER, Notary Public. Office. ivember, A. D. in book neous Incorporations, at JOHN C. ALL! retary of State. BY-LAWS. ruary 21. DIT1BS OF OFFICERS. nlf at all meetings, sign all • riiling vote in case of a tie, '.oard of Directors when requested in s of the association, and shall exer - t the presiding officer of a deliberative body. shall perform all duties incident to • ■ of the regular presiding officer. I shall conduct the general correspondence "jy of the same, shall pn tul ;i copy of the answer thereto, to E ociation, if requested, and keep keep an account of all the ill keep the minutes t ion. and have ■.lining to his offid ition, and shall have :ill times for inspection of the Board Pin of tn shall include clerical nil in tl one thousand i 1 'tiging ill lulls r of the President. ition funds ■ in proper form for the ml shall give a bond to the liars, to he approved ike a report at the for the current </seg>
            <seg id="p031">86 far. a: and assets due the a ■epinp Art it the call of shall at all for al in Jan day tl nual ii shall Ai' Order of Business roll call; third, readr I and other commr new b I Art. 11. Ai, her stock t full and fair hearing, found guilty of &lt;i: ,.r or An ; ; i </seg>
            <seg id="p032">87 ■ md forfeit socia- THE LEGISLATIVE ACT LEGALIZING THE NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION 3E ROM Poultry Association; an annual v penalty for the misappropria - sjrantfd lation, whose arti&lt; ■!• .■ of the of state. tion shall hold place rpose f sub - by addresses, ! of managers of the 1 ■ nil not less than two thou- appropriated, for LUditor is hereby . station for defray - ul in pulilishing !icr purpi ii the dis - ihe poultry ling to State 'I OUt </seg>
            <seg id="p033">88 vert a i other » ber sh lest i lUERoHIP I. 4. « K. R • 11. H C 14. - M. H. I M. H. K M. ■ M M 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">89 1 1 1 1 t 1 1 I 1 1 I 1 I Ituntini l l :■■:. 1 1 I 1 1 1 i) I'. Itovel. Aubui n 1 la l 1 1 1 1 1 1 l 1 1 I 1 1 1 1 1 1 Uilo 1 1 1 s!&gt; Ml Lincoln. 1 1 91. \V H Gardner, Fremont. 1 ■»&gt; : </seg>
            <seg id="p035">90 H4. h ■ 141 144. I 147 149 H H. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">91 . : : I t 1 1 1 l 1 1 1 1 l 1 I 1 l 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 l l l 1 1 1 l 1 1 1!M. \\ 1 i I 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">92 -. : 1 1 uprise I I ' l I i i 1 1 211. Ja i 1 214. A 1 ' 1 1 1 ' 1 1 241. I &amp; M X. I 1 1 ■•- I) li I 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">1 1 I ! 1 i : I i 1 1 I 1 I 1 I ] 1 1 I I I '. 1 1 : i l I i l I i l I </seg>
            <seg id="p039">94 Raymond fft Lawr- 312 ; Frank 319. - r b 22« J 1! A. I&gt; Bw icoln m J. .). Hamilton. 1. id Brehrii Mr. and Mrs Mill.-i. K. 333. Orvil ■S4. VirRll K. Shirl.-y. Harvard \V W. Da 336. 8. L. Salisbury, Lincoln . . 337. John L. Lehmon, Weeping Water </seg>
            <seg id="p040">: i I I ■ 1 i l I i I : i ■ l ! I 1 ' I In " l I l l : ! i l ! I ! I : I I 111 P. Hamilton. Plattsmooth . I 381 Oak wood W Farm, WV.'piug Wat. | 1 I I </seg>
            <seg id="p041">96 1 \ </seg>
            <seg id="p042">97 </seg>
           
            <seg id="p043">...INDEX... 22nd and 23rd Annual Reports aching of in N .... appropriations for Moek Certificate*. . red vote on Art. 11 of Bylaws 'i'i li nit .ation Letter. . , M nilnt when heli M Remark* of Nomii _lar for 1' Secured i ncutiator - Wagner's Motion 71 ■• Member of Board '(X 'ii Nominated Member of l!&lt;iard I Sept 7,1908 .Ian. 15, 18, 17,18 .Ian Sept. -'7. 1 ■■ .' 1 .Ian. .laD. 16. I - Jan. 17,1907.. .Ian It*. 1907 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">• - Curl) &lt; &lt;&gt;UIl1 - \V \V. ; Superint- </seg>
            <seg id="p045">SI - • ion L.-wclliiiL ■' •• ■ Nomil Irwin Member o </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Ill (if ' I Mt&lt;Tl I '- Judge* Kirk i u. Davi.I . Law t ■Show !et K.-m;i Nomii </seg>
            <seg id="p047">iilriit by i iarrontte W lleinark 1,71. 7-J Mry Report of. Thanks tary by Terwillijfer ry Nominated fur Secretary by Hurhan^ K« d to RmcnmMm I Motion to Reconsider H Motion by Terwtlligei r I &gt;v Terwtlligw irer . . . . nvr . . . i fur Treasurer by llarn- .1 for TriiiMUvi- My Han I til Semi Annual I90S Annual 1" ■ Annual 19&lt;)6 St-iui \nuual IWM &gt;&lt;mi Annual 1 Annual ISM Annual ISM it ion ■ "i" Remarks i I Report uf dent by Terwillijer Order of Kusim - Pegler. K. A Xouiii lembt-r of lSoard . </seg>
            <seg id="p048">- ■"■■ - Note rhan </seg>
            <seg id="p049"/>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>