<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00030">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Economic Aspects of Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd</title>
               <date value="1930-05">1930-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 46 Economic Aspects of Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd DEPARTMENT OF DAIRY HUSBANDRY LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MAY, 1930 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Introduction 3 Review of Literature. „.... 4 History of the Herd .. 6 Economic Importance of Abortion : 8 Occurrence of Abortion 8 Abortion by years 9 Occurrence by breeds at different ages 11 Recurrence of abortion 16' Occurrence by months during pregnancy 16 Effect of Abortion on Breeding Efficiency 26 Disposal of aborting animals : 29 Livestock sales 30 Effect of Abortion on Milk and Butterfat Production 35 Milk and butterfat production by years 35 Influence of frequency of milking on milk and butterfat production 40 Effect of gestation period on milk production 41 Losses of milk and butterfat due to abortion..... 43 Financial Losses Due to Abortion 52 Acknowledgments 53 Bibliography 53 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Economic Aspects of Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd DEPARTMENT OP DAIRY HUSBANDRY &gt; Disease enforces a toll against the livestock raiser that always reduces his profits and may even wipe out his invest - ment. Healthy herds are essential for efficiency of produc - tion. The loss, therefore, that may result from a. contagious or infectious disease is measured by the lowered efficiency of the herd as well as by the deaths which it causes. The premature birth of calves, abortion, may have several causes. Experience of animal pathologists, however, has indicated that while there may be several causes for premature births, by far the most common is the disease called infectious or contagious abortion and caused by a micro-organism, Bacillus abortus Bang. While other causes may result in abortion, it is always safe to blame that bacillus and treat the disorder as infectious. A dairy herd differs from a beef herd in that there are two sources of income from the former as compared with one from the latter. Milk or one of its derivatives is the chief source of income from the dairy herd, with the sale of ani - mals secondary, while a beef herd depends entirely for its income upon the sale of cattle. Both are affected by irregular breeding habits of the cows, the beef herd suffering the more since the loss of calves reduces its only source of income. In the case of the dairy herd, the milk production is affected by irregular breeding but it is not entirely eliminated. The object of this study is to present the measurable losses due to abortion in a dairy herd of high-producing ability over a period of approximately one-third of a century. The records available provide a rather complete history of what has taken place. In order to set lip a standard of measure - ment, certain normal averages have been established. The methods of setting up the averages are presented in some detail. In establishing these standards no value has been assigned to the items of cost of production, such as labor, feed, and interest on investment. The expelling of a fetus before the expiration of normal pregnancy is ordinarily called an abortion. In this study, any cow that calved before the 265th day of pregnancy is 1 The data presented in the bulletin have been collected from the herd records kept by the Department of. Dairy Husbandry since the herd was established. Dur - ing this time the department has been under the direction of A. L. Haecker, J. B. Frandsen, and H. P. Davis, respectively. The data were assembled by R. V. Morgan and . presented to the Graduate Co'lcce as a Master's degree thesis. -They were revised for publication by H. P. Davis and R. F. Morgan. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 46 considered as having aborted, even tho the calf lived. The dropping of a dead calf, even tho it was carried the normal length of gestation, is considered as an abortion only if the cow retained her placenta or afterbirth after calving. The micro-organism, Bacillus abortus Bang, confines itself largely to the organs of reproduction. The disease has been known since 1567, when Mascall, quoted by Hutyra and Marek (3), called attention to it; it is found in the temperate zone as well as in the tropics ; and apparently it has appeared in all parts of the world. At one time it was thought that the disease had a serious effect upon human beings in the tropics, and some medical authorities at present are trying to establish a connection between contagious abortion in livestock and undulant fever in human beings. In general the economic effect of contagious abortion has been greatest upon cattle, sheep, goats, hogs, and horses, since those are the animals of greatest economic importance to man. Only during the last three decades has there been much effort to control or discover a cure for this disease. While many remedies have been proposed, animal pathologists agree that so far there has been developed no effective cure. Bacillus abortus Bang was isolated and first described by Dr. Bernard Bang (1) of Denmark, in 1897. While any micro - organism that causes inflammation of the tissues of the genital organs or of the membranes surrounding the fetus may cause an abortion, the Bang bacillus is undoubtedly the most com - mon cause. In addition to premature birth, the presence of the disease in a cow may be indicated by her giving birth to a weak, sickly calf, by the retention of the placenta or after - birth at calving, by a discharge from the genital organs fol - lowing parturition, and by delayed conception or eventualfail - ure to conceive. Accidents, while possible, are not so likely a cause of abortion. The agglutination test as applied to the dairy herd at the University has indicated a strong infection in recent years, and while definite serological data are lack - ing for the early years, the evidence pointing toward an infec - tion of contagious abortion is very strong. REVIEW OF LITERATURE Much has been written about contagious abortion, but the literature dealing with the economic side of the problem is very meagre. A few writers have listed figures about the prevalence of abortion, and much has been written regard - ing so-called cures for the disease. Figures covering any con - siderable area which might indicate its prevalence are not available. Zwick and Zeller (9) have shown the occurrence during the months of pregnancy. White (7) and his associates </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Contagious Abortion- in a Dairy Herd at Connecticut have made a study of the financial loss caused by contagious abortion in the college herd in animals react - ing to the agglutination test. Their reacting cows gave a return of $44.01 less per cow per year over feed cost than nonreacting animals. Their figures take into account milk losses, calf losses, and depreciation in the value of the animals as determined by actual sales. The study covers eleven years and during that time the reacting and nonreacting animals were together. The report from Connecticut also brings out the fact that when the losses from premature calving (the calf itself) and from the subsequent subnormal lactation were included, the actual loss per cow greatly exceeded $44.01. The lifetime abortion rate among reactors was found to be 26.2 per cent and the number of abortions per cow a little over one per cent during the average four-year period that she remained in the herd. In the Connecticut studies calves dropped prior to the 265th day were considered as aborted. Barnes (2) states that when 10 per cent of the herd aborts, the equivalent of the whole herd is lost every four years. He further places the loss from abortion in Pennsylvania at $5,000,000 annually. Thompson (6) reports that his reacting Guernsey herd, kept separate from the noninfected herd, pro - duced milk at a cost of 16.8 cents a quart as compared with 10.4 cents per quart for the free herd. Newson and Cross (4) report abortion segregation results at the Colorado Agricul - tural College for dairy and beef herds. According to their report it required ten and one-half months to eliminate the disease from the beef herd in which 16 animals, or 43 per cent of the original herd, were removed as reactors. A loss of $92.38 per head was the estimated sacrifice in depreciation. Eighteen and one-half months were required for complete eradication in the dairy herd after reactors were first removed. Fifteen cows, or 34 per cent of the original herd, were sacrificed at a loss of $70.55 per reacting animal. In these instances, the high depreciation was due to the slaugh - tering of all reactors. The premature calvings previously had ranged from zero to 17 per cent in the beef herd, and from zero to 23 per cent in the dairy herd, during the years 1917 to 1926 inclusive, and in both herds conception was delayed and this caused a considerable loss. Sims and Miller (5) reported the milk production for two years of a herd divided into separate reacting and nonreacting groups. The reacting herd averaged 4,544 pounds of milk per cow in 1923 and 3,262 pounds per cow in 1924, while the negative herd averaged 7,343 pounds of milk per cow in 1923 and 6,291 pounds in 1924. There was no statement of financial losses, except that the reacting herd was discontinued at the end of the second year because of heavy loss. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebb. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 46 history of the herd The data for this study are the records covering the period from October, 1896, to January 1, 1929. The herd was started in 1896 with the purchase of one purebred and eleven grade Jersey cows. In March, 1897, one purebred Holstein cow was purchased. Dairy Shorthorns were added to the herd in 1902 and were continued until 1919. Purebred Ayr - shires were added in 1907 and a year later Guernseys were added. Both these breeds, together with Holsteins and Jerseys, have been continued and at present the herd con - sists of purebred animals of those breeds, all grade animals having been disposed of in 1919. In the early years the prac - tice of taking outside cows into the herd and running them on official tests for production was followed, and University bulls served outside cows until 1921. The general policy has been to develop the herd from animals bred and raised on the University farm and hence comparatively few females have been purchased. Many of the sires have also been bred by the University. While there have been some changes, the general plan of herd | management has been quite uniform. Efforts have been made to have cows freshen each year or just enough over a year to allow for a 365-day record. The milk from each cow has been recorded for each milking in pounds and tenths since 1896 and from that time until 1908 the fat test of the milk has been determined by. means of the Bab cock test applied to a three-day composite sample taken every week. Since 1908 the butterf at test has been conducted under the advanced registry rules, with each milking for the one- or two-day period tested in duplicate by the Babcock test. The average for the period of testing has been used as the butterf at per - centage for the month. The weights of every animal in the herd were taken weekly for the first seven years and in later years animals have been weighed on either one day or on three successive days in the middle of the month. Since the dairy herd was established in 1896, the necessary records concerning management have been carefully kept. Practically all the daily milk weights and butterf at tests have been preserved. Breeding records showing the date of service, date of birth, sex, and name of sire as well as the name of the animal served have been maintained. The data with reference to whether calving was normal or abnormal are available and records of the disposal of animals are quite complete. It has been the practice to have the animals out of doors as much as possible. Usually the milking coWs have been </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd inside only for milking and feeding except during stormy weather. As much as practicable the cows have received their hay from racks in the yard or open sheds. Grain and silage have been fed in the barn, and the quantities fed either measured or weighed. During the summer, pasture has been the main feed until the hot, dry weather necessitated a sup - plementary feed. The roughages used have been alfalfa hay and corn silage with occasionally some other hay used to a limited extent. The grain mixtures have necessarily varied in composition, but corn, oats, and bran have been the founda - tion ingredients with other concentrates such as linseed oil meal, cottonseed meal, gluten meal, gluten feed and other high protein concentrates added to make up a balanced ration. Usually the market price of feeds has been an important determining factor as to the grain mixture. The grain has been fed in proportion to the quantity of milk produced and according to the ability of the cows to produce. In general, one pound of grain for each three pounds of milk has been the rule, with hay and silage fed in liberal quantities. In an effort to keep the herd in a healthy condition tuber - culin testing has been carried on regularly and all reacting animals have been disposed of promptly. All animals added to the herd, at least in recent years, have been tested for tuberculosis before being admitted. While abortion has been present since the early years, no serological tests for the disease were made until 1921. After the first tests were made in that year, serological tests were discontinued until 1927 because of crowded housing conditions and the impos - sibility of separating infected from non-infected animals. In September, 1927, a definite program was established for test - ing every animal in the herd for contagious abortion by using the agglutination test regularly. The dilutions used varied from 1 in 25 to 1 in 500, depending upon the conditions, but in general animals have been considered positive if they reacted to thj l-in-50 dilution. Beginning in 1927 two separ - ate herds have been maintained, based on the reaction of the animals to the agglutination tests. The positive herd is kept in a separate barn with adjoining lots. These are separated from the other lots by means of two fences placed four feet apart and special care is taken to see that there is no drain - age from the positive to the negative lots. Separate equip - ment is used in the positive barn, but the same men take care of both herds. The number of milkings per day has varied for different animals; in the early years twice-a-day milking was practiced, but in recent years many cows have been milked three or four times daily, depending upon their production. This prac- </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd by that organism. The record of the calvings of the herd by years and the data with reference to the average number of cows in the herd, total number of calvings, of normal calvings, of abortions, percentage of abortions, and number of living males and females, are presented in Table 1. Abortion by years. — During 32 years and three months, 1,235 calvings occurred among five breeds of cattle. Of the total number of calvings there were 19 sets of twins, which gives a total of 1,254 calves born. The percentage of twins to all calvings was 1.54 per cent, which is believed to be about the normal rate for cattle. Five normal calves were born for which no record of sex was available and the sex is given for a number of the calves that were aborted. An interesting feature of Table 1 is the proportion of males to females. In general, it has been supposed that there is approximately an even proportion between the sexes for cattle. Our data would indicate that this is not true. In the University herd a total of 569 males and 495 females were born. Stated in percentage this represents 53.48 per cent males and 46.52 per cent females or stated as a proportion an approximate ratio of 8 males to 7 females. During the period there were 180 abortions representing 136 cows or 1.32 abortions per cow. This table quite clearly indicates that, even under conditions of good management, abortion, once it enters the herd, will continue with a tendency to in - crease until satisfactory methods are taken to eliminate the disease. «» as A CrTtnPH I at- l\ 34 f I » f\ "- " 30 I \ 9 1 i»ao a I* n 14 »n&gt;9 32 4*4i it 41 «4i yrU*4*isiMxi**U*i uauiiti iUMW) COV01 CALAlltie '4t*t\B*9 bo'oi'ol'ojWos'cu'OTlWWio '« '« •» - l4 'IS"* - rt '»'l«°zo*i it 15 J&lt; '25 ii fi 'u, VfcAQ </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 46 pti?ctrtT*et o\AE&gt;ot?riori av &amp;hov&gt;n bva THI3tt.Vfc.AQ A*O\)lf6&lt;9 AAjfcRAGfc n .|....\.._ - .&amp;BAPH-2- _ /..\A t, ; ] .. ... 2 • .... ..-.•.---.-•.._........._..... ............ ...__ T _. ...................... ................... c : : '. _ : 1 oo'«*x&gt;'oi UbsMbstiintiH 'n&gt; ii 'a '•■&gt; '\* 'is 14 'it '« 'n 10 1 in nii ■»'»'&gt;? ' ■ ' '."■■'"... T»tt?Ct^TA.Gt. oS ABORTlOfi bls» «.Kov\&gt;n t&gt;v « - t-l\)t Vfc-A-T? NVOV)l/0&amp; AVfct?AeEi. 3 i . ' vi- - &amp;JJA-PH.3. ...7..V 2 C . . . '. J. A ... aU A:.. .y^.—...—J- - -: o 10 --V- •'- --^..-/rri ; — c 6 « \--f--\f- i , _. „ • — — , L_ ■00 to ••! - «t "to 'at oi U 'n at 'oa '» "u 'tt 'is '1* '•» '» 'n '» '» '» 'u '» '» it ta it </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd The trend of abortion is best illustrated in a series of graphs. Graph 1 illustrates the great variation in percent - age of abortion from year to year, and shows sharp rises and declines. There is some indication of periodicity in the number of abortions and this trend may be considered as strong evidence that the abortions • were caused by disease and were not accidental.. It might be supposed that the abor - tion rate would not increase with the increase in number of animals in the herd. !The graphs indicate, however, that as the herd has increased in size there has also been a general increase in the percentage of abortion. The 180 abortions represent 14.57 per cent of the 1,235 calvings. In studying the general trend of abortion it can be seen that the percent - age has increased slowly and steadily. In Graph 1 the in - crease in the slope of the regression line is approximately 20 per .cent. Graph 2 illustrates the percentage of abortion as expressed in 3-year mpving averages and shows more clearly the upward trend of abortion in the herd. Graph 3 illus - trates the percentage of abortion as shown in 5-year moving averages and in this graph the slope of the regression line is approximately 40 per cent, indicating that the disease has increased. In other words, abortion once in the herd does not die out but tends to increase steadily up to a certain definite percentage as yet undetermined. Occurrence of abortion by breeds at different ages. — It has been asserted that certain breeds are more susceptible to abortion than others. In order to present our available data, tables have been prepared showing the total calvings, normal calvings, and the aborting cows that had aborted the previous year by breeds and the averages at different ages. While of course the numbers represented are limited, there is a reasonably close agreement in the abortion percentage for the same age for the different breeds and for the grades. The grade cows have an abortion percentage of 10.92, the Holsteins 14.77, the Jerseys .15.32, the Ayrshires 13.27, and the Guernseys 19.15. The variation from the herd average of 14.57 per cent is very small considering the number of cattle represented. It would seem, therefore, that the resistance of animals of the different breeds to abortion when kept under like environmental conditions is approximately equal. This material is presented in tabular form in Tables 2 and 3. Excepting Holsteins and grades, there were more abortions from two-year-old cows than from cows of any other age. Among Holsteins there were three more abortions for three - year-old cows than for two-year-old cows. Since the num - ber of cows calving at two years of age was much greater than the number of cows calving at three years or older the </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015"/>
            <seg id="p016">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 46 reasons, the fact that 52.22 per cent of abortions occurred at two and three years of age is strong evidence that young animals are particularly susceptible. This is in accord with the belief of most animal pathologists that young females are most susceptible to abortion; from the time they reach sexual maturity until after the first or second calf is dropped. Recurrence of abortion. — For a long time it has been the general opinion among breeders that a cow would abort once, twice, or possibly three times and then become immune to abortion. Table 4 presents the data bearing on the occurrence of abortion in cows of the various breeds with the combined totals for all breeds for the entire period. It must be re - membered that the sale of cows for beef immediately follow - ing abortion naturally had an effect upon the recurrence of abortion in the herd, so that the figures presented do not represent what might have happened had not such disposal been made. From the table it will be seen that 136 cows aborted a total of 180 times. Of (the 22 cows aborting twice, 13, or 59.09 per cent, had consecutive abortions. Of the remaining 9 which aborted twice there was a great variation in the time between abortions. For example, an animal that aborted as a two-year-old sometimes did not abort again until eight or ten years of age. A study of the consecutive abortions indicates that practically all of these occurred be - fore the animal reached maturity. This also was observed in a study of the animals aborting three or four times. Of the 136 cows aborting, 32 aborted more than once. This represents 23.52 per cent of all abortions, or approximately one individual in four could be expected to abort more than once. Doubtless the true percentage was even higher. . Occurrence of abortion by months during pregnancy. In studying the occurrence of abortion during months of pregnancy data are presented gathered by White and his associates (8) at Connecticut and by Zwick and Zeller (9) in Germany, together with data gathered at Nebraska. These data are presented separately and combined in Table 5. Efforts have been made to arrange these data in such a way as to present the figures in a comparable manner. For example, some of the data were expressed in days of pregnancy and these have been changed to months for presentation in the table. The data on abortions during the first months of preg - nancy indicate that some cases of abortion may occur un - noticed. Frequently the average observer is not aware of such an abortion and even under carefully controlled conditions it may not be observed. In the combined data it will be noted that most of the abortions occurred in the seventh month while a higher rate was reported at Connecti - </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022"/>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027">Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd that breeds regularly and drops a normal calf each year represents the ideal. It is important, therefore, to measure the breeding efficiency of a dairy herd, and the effect of abor - tion upon it. In this study breeding efficiency is a term used to describe the relationship between the percentage of abor - tion and cows in the herd, the cows calving, and the cows in milk. A cow is considered as in the herd after the first calving. The highest breeding efficiency would be attained when the percentage of calving was at 100 or slightly above, the percentage of cows in milk approached 100 per cent, and the percentage of abortion was at zero. In Table 7 the herd efficiency for the University herd is shown by year in six-year periods, the arrangement being adopted in order more readily to illustrate any trends that might appear. It might be stated that the average number of cows in the herd was determined by crediting a " cow day " for each day the cow remained in the herd. In like manner, the average number of cows in milk was determined by tabulating " cow days." A study of the table indicates that there is a more or less close relationship between the per - centage of abortion and percentage of cows calving and cows in milk. For example in the six-year period, 1897-1902, the percentage of abortion averaged 15.47, while the percentage of calvings was 106.30 and the percentage of cows in milk was 85.19. In the succeeding six-year period the abortion per - centage was 8.51, the calving percentage 100.35 and the per - centage of cows in milk 91.57. Thus in this later period with the percentage of abortion slightly more than half that of the preceding period, there was a higher breeding efficiency. For the period 1909 to 1914 inclusive, the abortion percentage was 12.23, the calving percentage 95.25 and the percentage of cows in milk 89.77. The succeeding six-year period, 1915 to 1920, showed an abortion percentage of 13.92, a calving percentage of 92.45, and a percentage of cows in milk of 82.11. It would seem that during this period other causes besides abortion reduced the breeding efficiency. In the period from 1921 to 1926 the abortion percentage rose to 18.91, the calv - ing percentage was 95.64, and the percentage of cows in milk 82.30. As compared with the early ones, this period indicates quite forcibly the effect of abortion. The final two years, 1927 and 1928, compare rather favorably with the preceding six- year period. In these two years a large number of cows were sold immediately following abortion. Unquestionably abortion affects, but is not the sole factor affecting, herd breeding efficiency. A study of the table indicates that the percentage of calving taken alone is not a good indicator of herd breeding efficiency, as a high abortion rate in a par - ticular year will raise the calving percentage materially. </seg>
            <seg id="p028"/>
            <seg id="p029"/>
            <seg id="p030"/>
            <seg id="p031"/>
            <seg id="p032">32 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 46 or an average of $110.68 per animal. The average of $148.98 for 309 males of all breeds and ages is believed to be a very fair average price for | the period covered. The years 1920 and 1921 show unusually high prices for livestock sold for breeding purposes. This period was followed by a consider - able slump from which | the livestock industry is just now re - covering. The comparable data for females (see Table 11) indicate that the selling price of females was not as high as that of males. Doubtless this has been affected by the policy, which has prevailed for a long time, of the rigid culling of females. As a general rule females have been sold which, because of low production, advanced age, or poor conforma - tion, did not fit into the herd. Probably the policy of rigid culling has reduced the income which might have resulted from the sale of surplus livestock. That together with the influence of contagious j abortion has unquestionably lessened the income from the sale of livestock from the herd materially. Thruout the years comparatively few females have been sold in order to keep the herd to normal size. An analysis of the data presented in Tables 9 to 11 appears in Tables 12 and 13. In the former the males sold are listed by breeds accord - ing to age and as to whether or not they were disposed of for beef or breeding purposes. The period from 1903 to 1928 showed great variations in prices received for dairy cattle, but the prices received revealed the local demand for males of the different j dairy breeds. Table 13 shows com - parable data for dairy females sold from the herd. The data presented in the foregoing tables dealing with livestock sales are shown in order that the basis for determ - ining the losses due to[ abortion might be apparent. In at - tempting to determine losses due to abortion a normal value must be established for animals of different ages, breeds, and sexes. The average value of calves from one to three months of age was used as determining the value of the aborted calves. To illustrate (Table 12) Jersey males sold for breed - ing purposes at an age of one to three months had an aver - age value of $52.00. In the case of an aborted Jersey male the value used was $52100. In cases where no sex was given the lowest value for any breed of either sex for the age of one to three months was used. In some instances there were no sales of young calves for both sexes of certain breeds. When an abortion occurred in such a case the value for the opposite sex was used.j A few very young calves have been sold for beef, usually because of undesirable conformation or poor development. The point may be raised that the use of </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd the value of every calf for breeding purposes is unfair. It is believed, however, that this is not an unfair method because of the high quality of the University herd. EFFECT OF ABORTION ON MILK AND BUTTERFAT PRODUCTION In any study of the effect of abortion upon milk and butter - fat production a considerable amount of tabulation must be made in order to determine, so far as possible, figures repre - senting average production. Since the production of milk is affected by a great many factors, great care must be exer - cised in determining average production in order that the decrease due to abortion may be accurately determined. It is easily demonstrable that a cow that drops a calf prema - turely usually produces a smaller flow of milk and a smaller amount of butterfat than would have resulted following a normal calving. This loss is perhaps the most important loss sustained by a dairy herd because of abortion. Milk and butterfat production by years. — The actual milk and butterfat production of the University herd by years from 1897 to 1928 inclusive is presented in Table 14. In this table the total milk production per year for the herd was multiplied by the average price of milk per hun - dredweight to get the milk income per year. The figure show - ing the milk income per cow per year was also tabulated. Since butterfat rather than milk might have been sold, figures are presented based on butterfat sales. The total amount of butterfat produced in a year was multiplied by the average price per pound to obtain the income from butter - fat for the herd. This was also divided by the average num - ber of cows in milk in order that the fat income per cow might be presented. The prices for milk and butterfat were obtained from the Bureau of Agricultural Economics at Wash - ington, D. C. In Table 15 is presented the number of calvings per year with the average number of cows in milk and the average milk and fat production per cow. This table presents an in - teresting study of the progress of a dairy herd. In 1921 when the herd came under the present management, more rigid culling was introduced in an effort to raise the average herd production. A large number of cows were also milked more than twice a day. The effect of these practices is evident in a study of Table 15 where it may be seen that the average production jumped materially in 1922 and continued upward. Another important factor in this upward trend has probably been the influence of high-producing daughters of certain sires. The Holstein herd has shown the largest increase in </seg>
            <seg id="p036"/>
            <seg id="p037">37 </seg>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039">39 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 46 production, while the gains for the other breeds have been more moderate. I Of the factors causing an increase it is believed that culling has been the most important. Table 15 emphasizes the fact that without rigid culling a dairy herd increases in production at a very slow rate. The average for the first six years (1897-1902) was 293.11 pounds of butterfat per cojw, actually a little lower than the production for the first year. For the second six-year period (1903-1908) the average production per cow was 313.46 pounds of butter - fat. This was j an increase of approximately 6 pounds of butterfat per cow over the first year and approximately 20 pounds over the) average for the first six years. Stated in an - other way, as compared with the first year, 12 years of breed - ing produced aj 6-pound increase. For the next six years (1909-1914) the average production was 342.06 pounds, while the following six years show an increase to 385.78 pounds of butterfat. The six-year period (1915-1920) pro - duced 92.67 pounds of butterfat per cow over the first period. From 1921 to 1926 the average per- cow was 491.88 pounds. This last six-year period thus showed an increase over the previous six-year period of 106.10 pounds of butterfat per cow. In the first 24 years the increase was 92.67 pounds while in the last 6 years it was 106.10. That such an increase can be maintained is evident from the figures for 1927 and 1928, which are higher than for previous years. The ques - tion of course arises as to what production can be maintained practically. This will be determined by the management, the production of Jthe cows, the sires used, and the amount of disease and culling. Influence of frequency of milking upon milk and butter - fat production. — The practice of milking cows more fre - quently than twice daily will increase their milk flow. This fact is generally admitted altho there are few records avail - able to indicate what increases may be expected under vary - ing conditions. Because of this fact, in determining the losses of milk and butterfat production due to abortion it was necessary to find out what. the. average production of cows in the University of Nebraska herd was under differ - ent conditions of management and for different ages and for different breeds. For example, Jersey two-year-olds milked twice daily could not be compared directly with Jersey two - year-olds milked three times because the additional milking would result in increased production. In making this study of the losses due to abortion, tables were prepared for the average production of each of the breeds of dairy cattle in the University herd. These tables were arranged according to the breed, age of cow, and number of milkings daily. In </seg>
            <seg id="p041"/>
            <seg id="p042"/>
            <seg id="p043">Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd be observed that the length of lactation period following 1 abortion was greater as the gestation period advanced. It is believed that in this respect Table 16 is significant. Table 17 presents comparable data on Jersey cows. While fewer animals are represented in this table, the same general trend is shown as in the previous one. Table 18 shows similar data for animals of all breeds and all ages. This table, with the exception of the abortions at three months, shows a very steady advance in milk production with longer gestation periods. These tables indicate clearly that in general milk production increases with advancing gestation. A study of these tables indicates how it was possible to calculate with considerable accuracy the amount of milk and butterfat which was lost due to abortion. Such calculations are, of course, essential if the financial losses due to abortion are to be tabulated. Losses of milk and butterfat due to abortion. — A study of the effect of abortion upon milk and butterfat production is necessarily somewhat complicated since many of the after effects cause losses that are hard to~measure. Based on the data presented in previous ■ tables the milk and butterfat losses that can be measured are presented on a per-cow-per - day basis in Table 19. The milk and butterfat lost for each cow for each year were carefully calculated and the figures are presented in the above-mentioned table. This table also shows the percentage of abortion, the percentage of calving, the percentage of cows in milk, and the milk and butterfat losses per cow calculated in pounds and percentage of the total | production. The percentage of milk losses per cow based on all the cows in the herd has varied from 0 to approximately 15 per cent. In the first six years the losses were I heavy, with the exceptional loss in 1900 raising the percentage up to an unusually high figure. The aver - age losses for six-year periods have been increasing. For example, the loss for the six-year period from 1921 to 1926 inclusive was 6.03 per cent of the milk production, whereas loss for the period from 1903 to 1908 was 3.3 per cent. In 1927 the loss had grown to 8.51 per cent and in 1928 was 8.44. The losses for butterfat are quite comparable altho the figures vary slightly, due of course to the different values placed upon milk and butterfat. The financial loss per cow due to abortion is always larger when based on milk loss than! when based on butterfat losses, but $27.70 for 1928 on milk 'losses and $21.84 on fat losses are important. In gen - eral there is a trend indicating that the losses due to abortion are somewhat in proportion to the percentage of abortion in the herd. Referring again to the herd breeding efficiency as </seg>
            <seg id="p044"/>
            <seg id="p045">45 </seg>
            <seg id="p046"/>
            <seg id="p047">47 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 46 mentioned previously it will be noted that as the herd approaches the greatest efficiency, the milk and fat losses are lower and as it departs from that standard the milk and butterfat losses increase. FINANCIAL LOSSES DUE TO ABORTION In the preceding tables the losses due to abortion have been presented separately, but in order to translate them into terms of dollars and cents for the herd in any particular year on a per-cow basis, Table 20 has been prepared. In Column 1 the percentage of abortion is given so that the relation of that factor to the various losses can be measured. The method of figuring the various losses has been expressed for previous tables with the exception of the method used for the column giving entire other losses. Other losses reported are of cows sent to the butcher because of abortion or failure to breed immediately following abortion. These losses were calculated by the use of figures presented in the tables showing the sale of animals disposed of at various ages in order to evalu - ate some of the losses due to the untimely disposal of animals for beef. In figuring losses of any character the minimum loss of a breeding animal has been used in cases where there were several ways of measuring the loss. The main financial loss per cow per year based on the sale of butterfat (Table 20) amounted to $2.22 in 1901. That year 7.14 per cent of the cows aborted. The largest loss due to abortion was in 1928 when it amounted to $54.75 per cow, when the percentage of abortion was 18.75.? The first six - year period (1897-1902) showed an average of 15.47 per cent of abortion with a total loss per cow per year of $20.87, based on milk sales, or $17.70 on sale of butterfat. During the second six-year period (1903-1908) the abortion percentage averaged 8.51 per cent, with losses per cow based on the sale of milk amounting to $9.09, or $7.58 on butterfat. The third period (1909-1914) had an average of 12.23 per cent with a total loss per cow due to abortion of $16.26, based on milk, or $13.85 on butterfat prices. There was up to this time a very close relation between the percentage of abortion and the financial loss in dollars and cents. The period from 1915 to 1920 showed 13.92 per cent as the average abortions per year with $26.98 representing the loss from milk, or $22.60 from butterfat. Probably because of the extraordinary in - crease in the sale price of milk and of dairy cattle due to the war period this figure varied and does not show the close relationship which previous periods did. In the period from 1921 to 1926 it will be recalled there was a larger gain in the average production per cow than during the previous 24 years. The result was that while the abortion percentage was </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Contagious Abortion in a Dairy Herd t ioX 9 io the loss per cow from milk amounted to $37.07, or $30.78 from the sale of butterfat. Apparently the higher average! production per cow and greater loss by abortion showed its effect upon this figure. In 1928 the loss due to abortion, had risen to $60.62 from milk or $54.75 from butter - tat, with the abortion percentage of 18.75. Such losses re - present |more than the average farmer gets from a cow in a year and unquestionably the elimination of abortion would in many cases mean the difference between profit and loss from a dairy herd. In thirty-two years there were 180 abortions out of 1,226 calvingsj, or a yearly average of 14.68 per cent. The yearly average! number of cows in milk was 33.55. The financial losses due to abortion are summarized below, based on the sale of milk in the first column and based on the sale of butter - fat in the second. Milk Butterfat _ • . , . .] - ■ . Dollars Dollars Total loss for 32 years 28,561.08 24,208.87 Average 'yearly loss— total 892.53 756.52 Average yearly loss — milk 409.56 Average yearly loss — butterfat 273.55 Average yearly loss — calves ' 340.19 340.19 Average yearly loss — other causes 142.78 142.78 Average yearly loss — per cow in milk 26.60 22.54 Average loss per abortion — total 158.67 134.49 Average loss per abortion— milk „ 72.81 Average loss per abortion — butterfat 48.63 Average Joss per abortion — calf ;. 60.48 60.48 Average loss per abortion — other causes 25.38 25.38 A study of the tables will indicate a wide variation in the losses from year to year. For example, the loss per abortion in 1928 [was over $200. Abortion causes financial losses that are so great as to seriously impair the income from a dairy herd. Abortion pre%'ents profitable production. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The authors wish to acknowledge their indebtedness to Professors L. Van Es, C. C. Engberg, and P. A. Downs for many helpful sug - gestions and to T. R. Pirtle, of the Bureau of Agricultural Economics, U. S. D. A., for price data. ' BIBLIOGRAPHY 1. Bang, B. Die Aetiologie des seuchenhaften (infectiosen) Verwer - fens. i Zeitschr. f. Thiermed., Bd. I, S. 241-278, 1897. 2. Barnes, M. P. Bovine infections abortion. Penn. Dept. of Agr., viii, Vfo. 8, 1925. 3. Hutyra, P.; and Marek, J. Pathology and therapeutics of the dis - eases of domestic animals. Third English edition, V. I, pp. 897- </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 46 4. Newsom, I. E., and Cross, F. Control of abortion disease by blood test and segregation. Colo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 317, 1927. 5. Simms, B. T., and Miller, F. W. Practical results of attempts to control abortion disease. Jour. Amer. Vet. Med. Assoc. lxvii, No. 4, January, 1926. 6. Thompson, A. A. A study of abortion and experimental work at Oak Hill Estate. Guernsey Breeders' Jour., p. 56, July 16, 1925. 7. White, G. C, Johnson, Robt. E , Rettger, Leo F., and McAlpine, Jas. G. Infectious abortion in cattle (Eighth report). Storrs Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 135. 8. White, G. C, Rettger, Leo F., and McAJpine, J. G. Infectious abortion (Fifth report). Storrs Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 123, 1924. 9. Zwick and Zeller. Ueber den inf ectiosen Abortus des Rindes. Arbeiten aus dem Kaiserlichen Gesundheitsamte. Bd. 43. S. 1-129, 1913. . ■- [5M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>