<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1935-04">1935-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 294 April, 1935 Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska H. O. WERNER AND L. L. ZOOK Bulletin 36 of the North Matte Experiment Substation L. L. Zook, Acting Superintendent THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION - LINCOLN W. W. BURR, DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction 3 Experiments m Seed Potato Production 4 Comparison of Seed Potatoes Grown on Irrigated and Dry Land 5 Time of Planting 6 Time of Harvesting 7 Early Harvesting Compared with Late Planting 10 Cutting Vines Early Compared with Harvesting Early 11 Feasibility of Producing Seed by Harvesting Early or Cutting Vines Early 12 Time of Removal of Diseased Plants from Seed Fields 13 Storage of Seed Potatoes 14 Value of North Plattc Seed as Compared with Western Dry-land Seed 15 SUMMARY 1. The prevalence of virus diseases was found to be a major factor causing variations m the seed value of potatoes produced at North Plattc. 2. On dry land the spindle-tuber disease spread less than m irrigated potato fields. Consequently when spindle tuber was present, dry-land seed was more productive. On the other hand when healthy seed was used there was little difference m productivity. 3. Early harvesting of irrigated potatoes resulted m more productive seed than did ■ate harvesting. Tubers harvested late from vines cut off early were intermediate m seed value between those harvested early and those harvested late from uncut vines. Early emergence and good stands were generally forerunners of high .yields. ■4. When potatoes were planted on dry land there generally was very little increase m yield after the early part of August, when vine maturation was generally well under way. 5. If practically free of spindle tuber, dry-land-grown potatoes that had been harvested early tended to be the most productive when planted m irrigated plats for comparison. Tubers harvested from vines just starting to ripen seemed to be more desirable than the very immature tubers harvested earlier. 6. Dry-land-grown tubers harvested late from vines cut off early were less productive m comparative trials than those harvested early but more productive than those harvested late from normally maturing vines. 7. Potatoes stored continually m a potato cellar were more productive than those held m cold storage for all or a portion of the storage period. S. Seed potatoes grown at North Plattc, from disease-free stock, when harvested early and stored m a cellar were nearly as productive as were western dry-land potatoes grown from the same original stock. Therefore it seems reasonable to conclude that the production of seed potatoes (as judged by modern standards of quality) is feasible on dry land m that part of the state. Because of the greater precautions which must be taken, seed production under irrigation seems less desirable for this region than does dry-land production. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Seed Potato Production m Central Nebraska H. O. WERNER ' and L. L. ZOOK = This bulletin reports work done at the North Platte Experimental Sub - station to determine the feasibility of producing good seed potatoes m west-central Nebraska. Good crops of potatoes can usually be grown m this region if good seed potatoes of adapted varieties are planted, and if good cultivation is given. During 23 years, 1912-34, the average yield of all potato plats among the dry-land crop-rotation plats at the Substation was 94.6 bushels per acre. 3 Crops of less than 60 bushels per acre were pro - duced m only five of these years. During the last eight years of the period the average yield was 108.8 bushels per acre. A part of this increase is attributable to the use of a better quality of seed of a better-adapted variety. Under irrigation for the 10 years 1925-34, the yield averages of potatoes on the same farm ranged from 215.4 bushels per acre m 1930 to 479 bushels m 1925. The 10-year average yield was 337.2 bushels per acre. Yields of marketable-size potatoes per acre ranged from 159.2 bushels m 1930 to 401 bushels m 1925. 4 The relatively low yield m 1930 was due to a shortage of water resulting from a breakdown m the irrigation system during a critical period of growth. Weakly 4 reports a greater amount of water used on potatoes than on corn or alfalfa. The 10-year averages were respectively 24.85, 13.15, and 16.30 inches. The amounts of water supplied were such as appeared necessary to keep the crops m good growing condition. The net increased returns per acre resulting front irrigation were $190.16 for potatoes as compared with 515.29 for corn and $10.45 for alfalfa. There has been some difference of opinion among the farmers m this part of the state concerning the advisability of using home-grown potatoes for seed purposes. In the commercial potato regions 150 miles west of North Platte, large quantities of potatoes are grown that meet the precise requirements for seed certification. Instances have been reported where some seed potatoes grown m isolated areas m central Nebraska have re - mained high-yielding for a number of years, but generally lots of seed brought m from the west or north have deteriorated or "run out" seriously m a few years. As very good seed potatoes of certification quality are con - tinually being raised m northwestern Nebraska, it seemed advisable to investigate the feasibility of growing seed potatoes m the locality of North Platte. Although the "running out" of potatoes m eastern and central Nebraska has commonly been attributed to the deteriorating effect of the high 1 Professor of Horticulture, University of Nebraska. Fiji 'vf r ° n f On ?i iSt ' T No 5 th A Plat f C Ex {' T eriment al Substation, and Associate Agronomist, Division of Dry Land Agriculture United States Department of Auriculture. PhttaP, • .1 eT,"^ - V kt L v L - A Zook - Dr y Lan d Crop Production at the North Platte Experimental Substation. Nebr. Aur. Exp. Sta. Bui. 279. pp. 43-44 1933 c i. ?"."*" ?; . Wea A kI &gt;"- Pump Irrigation and Water Table Studies at the North Platte Substation. Nebr. A B r. Exp. Sta. Bui. 271. 1932, and unpublished reports. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 294 summer temperatures upon the tubers, the major cause has been demon - strated to be a virus disease known as spindle tuber. 5 This disease causes a dwarfing of the plant, elongation of tubers, and a reduced yield. It is easily spread from plant to plant by any of a number of insects. It has been shown that vigorous, high-yielding seed potatoes can be produced in regions where such production was formerly thought to be impossible. 0 In order to do this some special precautions have been found necessary to prevent the increase or spread of virus diseases. One or more of the following methods have been used: Planting seed potatoes free of virus diseases, in fields isolated from other potatoes that might be dis - eased, planting late, removing diseased plants as soon as they are dis - covered (referred to as "roguing"), harvesting early, cutting vines off about the time they start to ripen, covering the ground with a straw or litter mulch, and growing the potatoes on dry land or using irrigation water cautiously. Insufficient time has elapsed, since the relation of virus diseases to "running out" of potatoes has been demonstrated, to determine whether with the disease factor eliminated, the vigor and high-yielding power of a line of seed potatoes can be kept up as long in warm regions favorable for disease spread as in cooler regions. EXPERIMENTS IN SEED POTATO PRODUCTION The experiments in seed potato production at North Platte consisted of growing potatoes for future testing on dry land and under irrigation. Certified seed potatoes were planted at different dates, grown with and without a straw mulch, and rogued at different dates; the vines were cut off at different dates and tubers were also stored in different ways. These experimentally produced potatoes were compared when used as seed by planting the latter part of April in replicated plats on alfalfa sod land under irrigation. These comparative plats were generally harvested during the early part of October. The potatoes from all plats were usually graded as to size. Scab and spindle-tuber prevalence were determined for the No. 1 size tubers. 7 The usual wide variations in weather prevailed during the years of the tests. Monthly temperatures and rainfall for the six growing-season months of each year, together with the 27-year averages, are reported in Table 15. The seasonal mean temperatures at North Platte'are just below 65° F., which is commonly considered as the maximum for a good potato-pro - ducing region. The high July and August temperatures which come at the time of maximum vine development are unfavorable for tuberization. High rainfall in the early summer, especially in June, is likely to be accompanied by high humidity, a condition very favorable for the soft-bodied insects E*p H St£' IteT b"" S 32 in m5 TUber SS " FaCt °-' '" SeCd POtat ° Prodaetio "- Nebr. A B r. E^ o «£^-i£^i,&amp;^. 1^ t ?$£'$S! t &gt; 4B "%S a »' Secd Value of and^%^ m a3 1 Jd^ U u^sNT2 P ofN C o e^ b r u b e P ;s ndIe - tUber ' *"" " "* healthy P ' antS ' </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska which spread virus diseases among the plants which, under such climatic conditions, are likely to be very large and succulent. COMPARISON OF SEED POTATOES GROWN ON IRRIGATED AND DRY LAND During six successive seasons Irish Cobbler seed potatoes produced on dry land were more productive than those produced under irrigation, when compared under irrigation in the succeeding seasons (Table 1). At such times the percentage of tubers showing distinct symptoms of the disease Table 1. — Behavior in irrigated plats of Irish Cobbler seed potatoes jrom irrigated and dry-land plats at North Platte. 1 Year of Seed p roduce d Seed produced Seed produced *,!„] under irrigation, on dry land. on western dry land, North Platte North Platte harvested in October Mean total yield (bushels per acre) 1925 279 . 308 477 1926 289 315 346 1927 240 330 349 1928 316 331 1929 309 319 390 1930a 3 211 267 258 1930b' 196 236 Mean yield in bushels per acre of No. 1 size tubers 1925 219 256 399 1926 239 264 327 1927 196 261 331 1928 234 ail 1929 287 295 367 1930a 3 152 149 191 1930b 3 138 162 Per cent spindle tubers No. I size 1925 37.3 26.5 0.33 1926 14.7 4.1 1 2 1927 2.4 .0.1 0 2 1928 1.7 0 7 1929 Trace Trace 1930a 3 5.62 0.55 Tai 1930b 3 1.16 0.44 ..'... 1 All data based on single-row plats, generally 3 rods Ionic with from 5 to 15 plats planted in April with each lot of seed. All seed potatoes originally from the same western dry-land farm. 3 Seed stock "a" was crown at North Platte during two years, 1928 and 1929 ; stock "b" was grown there only one year, 1929. was invariably higher in the irrigated than in the dry-land stocks. The smallest differences in yields of No. 1 potatoes between dry land and irri - gated seed occurred during the last two years, when infection was not great. The very high percentage of spindle tuber in the 1925 trials was due to infection from severely diseased lots located in adjacent seed plats in 1924. Most of the spindle tuber found in any year was the result of infec - tion during the previous year at North Platte, because very little was found in the check plats planted each year with seed from the original western source. These results are in harmony with those reported by Werner, 8 t&gt; * H \?L Werner. Some Facts Concerning the Productivity of Irrigated Seed Potatoes. Froc. 16th Ann. Meeting of Potato Assoc. of America, pp. 120-132 1929. Also Pro - ceedings for 1925, pp. 10-22, and for 1926. pp. 58-59. </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 294 Harrington, 9 and Edmundson, 10 who found that when seed stocks were free from virus disease the culture, whether irrigation or dry land, had no appreciable effect upon the seed value of the tubers. TIME OF PLANTING Immature seed potatoes produced by planting late were found to be superior for seed purposes to more mature tubers produced by planting early (Table 2). When the seed-producing plants of early plantings were exposed to infection by spindle tuber, the percentage the following year was very high. It was less as planting had been delayed the previous year. This was especially apparent in the 1926 trials of seed potatoes, which were produced in 1925 in irrigated plats when lots of seed containing much spindle tuber were planted in adjacent rows. Even under those conditions the spindle tuber in seed from late (July 7, 1925) plantings was only 3.4 per cent higher in 1926 than in that from the checks which had been grown on western dry land. Table 2. — Relation of date of planting to seed value the following year.\ 1925 history Production record. 1926 planted Vines Total yield Yield No. 1 size SPJJ^ubers Planted ripened (bu. per A.) (bu. per A.) (Percent) Seed plats not isolated — considerable spindle tuber in adjacent row AprU 16 August 24 191 127 63.1 May 1 August 28 243 169 37.7 June 1 September 10 291 249 12.0 July 7 Never 296 242 5.8 Seed plats isolated and rogued April 16 August 24 317 276 5.4 July 7 Never 339 310 0.7 Western dry land 346 317 2.4 1 Seed tubers grown under irrigation in 1925. When seed plats were isolated within an irrigated cornfield and rogued, the yields the following year were considerably higher than those from seed out of the non-isolated fields and compared very favorably with those from seed that had been grown on western dry land. The percentage of spindle tuber was very low; in fact with seed from the July 7 planting the percentage of spindle tuber was lower than in seed from the western dry - land stock. Similar results were secured with tests of seed produced in 1924 and compared in 1925. The question now arises as to the feasibility of late planting as a means of raising seed potatoes at North Platte. During two years when potatoes were planted in irrigated fields on different dates the yields fell off rapidly as planting was delayed beyond the middle of May (Table 3). The loss in • F. M. Harrington. The Influence of Irrigation on Seed Potatoes. Amer. Potato Jour. 3:203-205. 1926. Also 5:7-8. 1928. 10 W. C. Edmundson, Effect of Irrigation Water on Vigor and Vitality of Seed Potatoes. U. S. D. A. Tech. Bui. 216, 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska Table 3. — Yields in bushels per acre obtained under irrigation from plant - ing potatoes on different dates at North Platte during two seasons when crops were harvested after vines matured. Total yield U. S. No. 1 grade Date ■ j — 1925 I 1926 1925 1926 Bu. Bu. . Bu, Bu. April 16 528 458 495 397 May 1 474 452 May 19 45S 492 399 440 June 2 291 266 June 17 260 222 222 173 July 7 145 76 137 29 yield by planting for seed as late as June 1 or later was much greater than was the increase in yield the following year when such seed potatoes were planted. Factors contributing to the poor stands and low yields from late planting were weakening of the seed by long storage, the stunting of young plants by the hot and dry atmosphere, and the killing of the plants by early frosts. The first two are more difficult to cope with on dry land than in irrigated fields. It is now thought that better stands of stronger plants might be secured by the use of cold storage for sufficient time in late winter to prevent excessive sprouting, by the proper preparation of the seed bed (as by irrigating before planting), and by healing cut sur - faces of all seed potatoes before planting so that they will not rot. TTME OF HARVESTING Early harvesting of seed potatoes has been found more desirable than late harvesting. This was found to be the case with both irrigated and dry-land-grown seed, but especially with the former (Tables 4, 5, and 6). When plants were exposed to infection from spindle-tuber plants located in adjacent rows in the 1925 irrigated seed-production plats, the highest yields in 1926 were produced by seed stocks harvested on July 15 and August 11 (Table 4). The increase in spindle tuber probably accounted to a considerable degree for the low yields from late-harvested stocks, although the greater dormancy of late-harvested potatoes may have con - tributed to the late emergence. Late emergence was in itself detrimental to yields, but it probably was not nearly so important as spindle tuber. Table 4. — Relation of time of harvesting to seed values the following year (all lots planted April 16). 1925 history Production record. 1926 Maturity Plants Total Yield Spindle Harvested when emerged on yield per No. 1 size tubers, harvested 25th day acre per acre No. 1 size Percent Percent Bu. Bu. Percent July 15 0 67.5 320 242 1* 0 Aueust 11 35 38.3 311 248 41 S October 6 100 23.3 191 127 63.1 Western dry-land check 1.7 346 317 2.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 294 The checks with a low spindle-tuber content, even though they emerged late in this case because of low storage temperature, were still most pro - ductive. When potatoes were exposed to only such spindle tuber as the low amount occurring in the western dry-land certified seed which was used, the percentage of disease found in the comparative plats the next year was rather low. In a test conducted in 1927-28, potatoes harvested in irrigated plats in mid-July or early August were more productive in the comparative trials the next year than were those harvested the 22nd of August (Table 5). Those harvested in late September or early October were least productive. Associated with this lower yield from the 'late-harvested stock was a small Table 5. — Production in 1928 from Irish Cobbler seed potatoes harvested early or from vines cut off early in both isolated-rogued and isolated - unrogued plats in 1927 (10 replications of 45 hills each). Previous , Pla "*f Fin -i Spindle No j ■ Av. yield Av. total treatment-1927 ■ ™«£»» SEd tnbm Tubers No. 1 size yield Zlst day bmnq No j slze per acre - per acre * Percent Percent Percent Percent Bushels Bushels Isolated and rogued in 1927 Harvested July 11 80.3 94.3 1.98 85.0 260 305 Vines cut July II ■ 66.9 ST^ M 87^0 255 • 293 Harvested Aug. 1 62.7 94.3 1?71 89/7 283 316~ Vines cut Aug. 1 63^5 94J) 2J&gt;4 8J7J) 244 2 78 Harvested Aug. 22 35.3 83^7 3^90 881 234 266~~ Vines cut Aug. 22 42.0 hSA 4JJ5 86^ 218 256 Harvested Oct. 6 37.1 83.5 2.11 86.8 217 250~ Isolated and not rogued in 1927 Harvested July 11 74.7 98.6 1.82 88.3 293 331 Vines cut July 11 6TA 95J) 2.8D 85.9 244 284 Harvested Aug. 1 62.3 94.7 6.23 90.1 293 325~ Vines cat Aug. 1 60.2 92.9 3.69 86.3 240 278 Harvested Aug. 22 38.1 82.0 4.92 HtJ 231 264~ Vines cut Aug. 22 48.2 88.8 9.58 86.9 234 270 Harvested Sept. 28 44.9 85.1 2.57 85.9 210 244~ New western dry-land check gluj 311 331 1 When vines were cut. tubers were harvested on Oct. 6 or Sept. 28. * In order to be significant, yield differences must be 25 bushels or more. increase- in the percentage of spindle tuber, a distinctly slower rate of emergence, and a lower final stand of plants. These latter two conditions may have resulted in part from the increased spindle tuber, but again the greater degree of dormancy at planting time was probably also an im - portant factor. With healthy seed stocks grown on dry land, time of harvesting was found to be of somewhat less significance. However, during the three years of this experiment early harvesting appeared to be somewhat more desirable than late harvesting. Irish Cobbler potatoes harvested on August 10 at the time vines were just beginning to mature were possibly more productive than those harvested on July 20 when vines were still green and tubers were quite immature (Table 6), but with the Triumph variety </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska the stock planted June 20 was most productive. Earliest emergence of plants generally occurred with seed stocks harvested August 10 and latest with those harvested in October. The very immature condition of the tubers harvested July 20 resulted in more shriveling and the production of slightly weaker and later sprouts. This slightly delayed emergence was generally undesirable, because the plantsj^encountered more days with temperatures unfavorably high for tuberization. However, in the hot summer of 1931 this delay was advantageous to late-harvested Irish Cob - blers, for their plants attained maximum size during August and were in good condition to produce tubers in the cooler, shorter days of August and September. Consequently Cobblers harvested late in 1930 were the most Table 6. — Yields (bushels per acre) in irrigated fields at North Platte from seed that had been harvested on various dates, stored in different ways, and grown for one, two, or three years on dry land at North Platte. Grown on dry land at North Platte one year. Harvested tested in 1929 — storage as follows ' previous . ■ Cold storage, CeliaT _ , , . _ „ year Cellar, first 30 days, first 30 days. Cold storage. Cellar. Llnco '" Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln North Platte Triumph July 20 267 259 248 257 259 August 10 239 280 244 260 263 September 1 277 249 243 206 261 October 2 247 254 260 198 246 Western dry-land check 303 Irish Cobbler July 20 360 323 333 317 319 August 10 393 358 325 331 372 September 1 380 334 316 319 341 October 2 . 321 320 298 313 Western dry-land check 390 Harvested Grown at N. P. Grown at N. P. Grown at N. P. Grown at N. P. Grown at N. P. previous one year, two years, one year, two years, three years, year tested 1930 = tested 1930 - tested 1931 * tested 1931 * tested 1931 » Triumph July 20 220 . 238 400 391 373 August 10 196 185 September 1 193 168 October 2 202 192 340 395 333 Western dry-land check 214 398 Irish Cobbler July 20 236 267 439 424 404 August 10 278 235 421 408 September 1 220 210 444 437 October 2 230 217 455 425 426 Western dry-land check 258 465 1 Potatoes did not go into the storage at Lincoln until four or five days after harvest - ing. They were shipped by ordinary freight. - Cold Btorage at Lincoln was used for seed for the 1930 and 1931 trials. In order to be considered statistically significant, differences in yield as estimated * from probable errors (calculated but not printed) would need to be approximately 20 per cent for 1929 and 1930 trials and 10 per cent for 1931 trials. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 294 productive in 1931. The Triumph vines were more advanced and as a result their late-harvested stocks were again least productive. Because of the earlier development and maturity of tubers of the Triumph variety on dry land, their stocks harvested on July 20 were more frequently superior to those harvested August 10 than was the case with the somewhat later Irish Cobbler variety. The Triumph potatoes used were from a medium-early strain produced in western Nebraska. There was a slight tendency for late-harvested tubers to produce a lower percentage of No. 1-size tubers than did those harvested early. As the amount of spindle tuber in this test was negligible, its prevalence is not reported. Table 7. — Yield and percentages of No. 1 potatoes when North Platte dry - land-grown Irish Cobblers harvested on different dates were planted at Lincoln in 1929. Harvested at North Storage at Lincoln Platte in 1928 „ I Cold storage. I Cellar, I _ ,. Cellar I first 30 days ! first 30 days I Cold storage Total yield — bushels per acre July 20 240 218 219 236 August 10 210 217 209 207 September 1 201 205 190 155 October 2 176 197 195 178 Western dry-land check 242 No. 1 grade — per cent July 20 81.4 69.5 72.3 79.7 August 10 79.4 79.0 79.1 77.1 September 1 77.9 72.8 66.7 69.5 October 2 61.1 79.3 71.7 67.5 Western dry-land check S6.8 In a test of these North Platte grown Irish Cobbler potatoes planted at Lincoln on March 31, 1929, the lots harvested July 20 were the most pro - ductive, followed in order by those harvested August 10, September 1, and October 2 (Table 7). When the seed potatoes had been stored continually in the cellar or in cold storage the percentage of No. 1-grade tubers was greatest with the stock harvested July 20 and very definitely decreased to least with the stock harvested October 2 (Table 7). When potatoes were transferred from one type of Storage to the other, this tendency did not occur. EARLY HARVESTING COMPARED WITH LATE PLANTING In the seasons of 1925 and 1926, when spindle tuber was a very prom - inent factor, early planting combined with early harvesting seemed to be more desirable than late planting and late harvesting, if the seed-producing plants were in the field about the same length of time and if total yields only were considered. However, yields of No. 1-size tubers produced by the two methods were almost exactly alike (Table 8). The percentage of No. 1-size tubers from early-planted and early-harvested stocks was greatly reduced by spindle tuber. Early plantings are more subject to infection by </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska means of insects than late plantings, because atmospheric conditions arc generally more favorable for the soft-bodied insects which spread spindle tuber. The earlier emergence of the less-dormant, early-harvested tubers is a definite advantage for that practice, but in this test it did not offset the disadvantage of more spindle tuber. An important limitation on late planting is the great difficulty of getting good stands in this locality (see pages 6 and 7). Table 8. — Relation of length of time tubers were left in field to their seed value the following year, when spindle tuber was present in adjacent rows of seed field. 1926 history Production record, 1926 „. I „ i Days in Total yield i Yield No. 1 ! Spindle tubers Planted | Harvested ) field per acre I size per A. No. 1 size No. Bit. Bu. P. ct April 16 July 15 00 320 242 12.0 July 7 October 6 91 296 242 5.8 April 16 Auuust 11 117 311 248 41.5 June 1 October 6 128 2UJ 249 12.0 CUTTING VINES EARLY COMPARED WITH HARVESTING EARLY Since early harvesting has been found to be a desirable practice and since most of the improvement in seed value is due either to escape from spindle tuber or to the more complete emergence from the dormant period, cutting vines off early and allowing potatoes to remain in the field until fall would seem a meritorious practice. A number of European investigators l1 " 14 have reported that tubers harvested late from plants which were cut off while still green produced a higher yield than did those from vines allowed to ripen naturally. Seed potatoes harvested from irrigated plats on October 6, 1927, from vines that had been cut off on July 11 produced significantly higher yields in 1928 trials than were secured with tubers harvested the same date from vines that were allowed to mature naturally (Table 5). Yields of tubers from vines cut July 11 were higher than those from vines cut August 12, which in turn were higher than those from vines cut August 22, while those from naturally maturing vines were the lowest. As in the case of tubers harvested early, emergence of plants was earliest, stands were best, and spindle-tuber content was least when vines had been cut off early. Seed potatoes from vines cut early were, however, not so productive as were those harvested on the same dates (Table 5). Early vine cutting was of less value when seed tubers were produced from seed stock relatively free of disease in isolated, rogued plats on dry 11 P. Knurr, Versuchsercrebniflse auf dem GesamtKebiete des KartofTelbaues im Jahre 1919 und 1920, Arb. Forschungsinst. Kartoffelbau. Heft 5 und 6, Berlin, 1922. 11 R. MUnter, Unreife oder reife KartolTeln als Sastgut, Deut. Landw. Presse 49:9-10, 1922. 13 J. O. Botje*, Experiment-; Regardinc the Use of Immature Seed Seen at Oustavold During Conference, Report of International Conference of Phytopathology and Economic Entomolocy, Holland, pp. 143-47. 1023. 11 H. C. MUller and E. Molz, Effects of Stimulation and Depression on Productivity in Potato Culture (Trans, tille), Dcut. Landw. Presse 51:(a)91. 1924. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 294 land (Table 9) In five out of six tests, seed lots from vines cut July 20 Tnd in ,ev C Prod /T e than those harve «ed in October from uncut vines and in seven out of ten tests those from vines cut August 10 were superior. 110 SI f lficant ln dlff «&lt;^ in the seed value of tubers fromvines cut July 20 or August 10. Seed tubers from vines cut on July 20 were inferior to those harvested on that date. Y Table 9.-Yields (bushels per acre) in irrigated plats from lots of seed grown on dryland at North Platte which the previous year or years zz cZ e X on di§erent dates or harvested iate &gt;'™ «™ *« . N.P.. *£■£* y g" p at yearat yeay Harvested Aug. 10 239 Tsk ~ ~ Vines cut Aug. 10 2g2 »« . »» -. Harvested Oct. 2 247 2 n, 192 , jr ~ 1^— Western dry-land check 303 " — — „ . Irish Cobbler is a= tig g s y^ 8^ Aug: IS:::::: ggj a gg5 «| Harvested Oct. 2 or 10 313 - 230 2^ TT. Western dry-land check 390 256 " FEASIBILITY OF PRODUCING SEED BY HARVESTING EARLY OR CUTTING VINES EARLY Dart W of e rL Plamed ° n J and J durin S latter half of April, the greater part of the crop was produced each year by August 10 (Table 10). TAB wV n °Zj° tal ykld m u pCr aC&gt;e by Va&gt;!ous date *' °» dry land, the ground" '"*'' ""^ °'' "'"" "*" CM °^ at the °f Harvested or Triumph Irish Cobbler vines cut off T ~r . "&gt;28 I 1929 ) 193Q 1928 [ 1929 j lg3Q Harvested Juiy 20 m *| «* ST Vines cut July 20 » 169 53 \H ? 1 73 vfaSTiSt aZ. iqV::::::: m «; .,".: | 0 3 i g« "^i~ S^Sg gg.Vzzz: tig g n ut "~^S I No.' Mmteuit.^ N °- 2 sized tubCT8 ' whi &lt;* •« lar E e enough to plant, but not •Harvested October 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska Frequently the crop harvested in October weighed less than that harvested in August. This shrinkage probably results from loss of water through the skin of the potato or through the partly green top. There may also have been some loss of dry matter by respiration of tubers or even by resorption for growth and respiration of maturing tops. Generally fewer bushels of potatoes were harvested if vines were cut early than if the tubers were harvested on the same early date. By weighing tubers stored in the cellar, the shrinkage on the most mature tubers harvested July 30 was thought to be 6 per cent in 20 days and between 8 and 9 per cent by 40 days after harvest, and when harvesting was delayed until September 3 the shrinkage was 4.5 per cent and 7 per cent respectively. Thus the shrinkage in stor - age was not much different from that which occurred in the field from Table 11. — Bushels per acre of Irish Cobbler potatoes harvested on various dates in irrigated fields at North Plotte, when western dry-land-grown seed was used. Dates between Total yield U. S. No. 1 grade which harvested 1924 | 1925 | 1924 ' f 1925 j 1926 Hii. If a. IS u. It a. Bu. Bit. July 6-12 42 102 16 37 July 15-17 100 180 321 73 131 256 July 24-25 150 266 128 218 July 3-Auk. 1 211 309 369 190 269 304 Aub. 8-11 303 468 287 431 Auk. 15-18 333 414 313 364 Sept. 3-8 420 504 438 372 475 386 Oct. 5-12 [ 390 528 458 376 495 397 either cut or uncut vines. Furthermore, when tubers were harvested in October they shrank at a more rapid rate than was then occurring with early-harvested stock. As early harvesting gave the most desirable seed and since storage will need to be provided in any event, it is more desir - able and less laborious than early vine cutting and either is preferable to late harvesting. Early harvesting causes considerable loss in yield, especially in irrigated fields (Table 11). Because of this loss in yield with either late planting or early harvesting, the production of seed potatoes in irrigated fields in central Nebraska may not be economically advantageous. TIME OF REMOVAL OF DISEASED PLANTS FROM SEED FIELDS At the present time there are practically no strains of seed potatoes available that are entirely free from spindle tuber and other virus diseases. As a consequence, it is necessary to rogue, i.e., remove from the field, any infected plants that are found there, if a stock of seed is to be maintained. In regions where these diseases are spread easily or rapidly, this is very important. Early roguing was found to be a quite useful practice in a test con - ducted at North Platte under irrigation. In 1925 infected Triumph seed </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 294 was planted in every fifth hill of a planting of very good Irish Cobbler potatoes. The Triumph plants were removed from different plats at various periods In addition some plats were planted without any infected Triumphs m isolated and unisolated areas, and in one plat no roguing was practiced At the end of the first season there was no evidence, in tubers harvested of any increase in disease. However, when the potatoes were planted the next year the percentage of spindle tuber increased as roguing Table 12.— Increase of spindle tuber and effect upon yield the following year when sp.ndle-tuber plants (which comprised 20 per cent of the plants tnthe seed plats) were removed from the seed plot on different dates. (All plantings m mid-April in irrigated fields.) Spindle tubers — No. 1 size ' Treatment in 1925 " 7ZZZ YieId '" 192 5 1926 comparative seed plat comparative plat in 1926 Check (western dry land) *" „*"* B^" No spindle tubers planted— plat isolated...'."'"."' "" 14? HI ?»• T n , dI £ tUb ? S P Ianted -Plat not isolated 2.8 22~4 Io4 Spindle-tuber plants removed- 30 * ££=== ;1 S IS! August 10 zzzzzzzzz: li g-f ?°2 Not removed ;_J ij }jj 1 Many spindle tubers are No. 2 and No. 3 size. " had been delayed the previous year, and the total yield of potatoes de - creased proportionally (Table 12). Very similar results were secured when this was repeated in 1926-27. Evidence from other plats and places suggests that such great increases in spindle tuber would not have occurred on dry land, so with thorough roguing even better seed could be produced there. STORAGE OF SEED POTATOES For the production of early potatoes in the west-central part of the state, sprout growth should be under way at planting time. If the seed potatoes are dormant, emergence is generally slow and uneven, thus giving the equivalent of later planting and resulting in lower yields than if the 7 J 5 lc " dor ™ nt -Other workers""" have reported that potatoes ?n*£ fl tO R WerC leSS P rodlIctive than those stored at 38° to W b. The exact method of storing the seed is somewhat immaterial if tne seed is in the proper condition at planting time Potatoes stored in the cellar all the time were generally the most pro - ductive and those held in cold storage continually were least producti%'e in tests conducted after storage during the winter of 1928-?9 with the potatoes harvested on different dates (Table 6). Potatoes held in the cellar PP.'l4W8 B lS e "' StOrORe ° f SeBd p0tat0CS - Ohio A * r - E *P- Sta. Bi-monthly Bui. 12. Sta."Rp,_ J ; p Pi Xm S d . 2 7- F ' FIint&gt; ThrCe Tem " e ""»-e, for Seed Potato Storase. III. Cha^r-. 2S"£JEi_£ o^pX^ts.^. L a m A bar T d ech an B u , G '5.To 2 ? eWey - *— </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Seed Potato Production in Central Nebraska thirty days after harvesting and then placed in cold storage were generally slightly more productive than those continually in cold storage, whereas potatoes held in cold storage the first thirty days and then in the cellar were superior to both the other treatments involving cold storage. How - ever, this early cold-storage period caused delayed emergence, which prob - ably accounted for lower yields than with cellar storage. Yields from potatoes stored in the cellar at North Platte were generally lower than from those stored in the cellar at Lincoln. This may have been the result of some frost damage which occurred in the North Platte cellar. The cellar temperature at Lincoln ranged from about 70° F. in July to 35°-40° F. in mid-winter and 50° F. during early April. Cold storage was at Lincoln at a temperature of 36°-42° F. Potatoes were shipped to Lincoln by freight and were in the respective storages within a week after harvest. Results with Irish Cobblers in the test at Lincoln were of a similar nature (Table 7). VALUE OF NORTH PLATTE SEED AS COMPARED WITH WESTERN DRY-LAND SEED Western dry-land-grown Irish Cobbler potatoes were more productive when planted under irrigation at North Platte than seed of the same stock grown at North Platte either on dry land or under irrigation. However, when the yields from the highest-yielding North Platte lots were compared with those from western stocks (Table 13) the differences were generally small, especially in the last three years reported (1929-31), when seed stock was practically free of spindle tuber. Early-harvested dry-land stock was most desirable. Some of the differences in yield were due to storage conditions. Table 13. — Comparison of highest yields in bushels per acre from Irish Cobbler seed potatoes grown at North Platte with yields from western dry-land-grown seed during seven successive seasons. Highest yielding _ V -._ North Platte seed Western Year — dry-land Dry land I Irrigated seed Bushels Bushels Bushels "25 312 279 477 "26 3U 320 34G "27 333 253 349 1»28 331 331 1929 393 309 390 1930 267 211 258 "31 455 4G5 In 15 out of 18 comparisons, higher yields were produced by seed stocks grown at North Platte for one year only than from those grown there for two or more years (Tables 6 and 9). In an experiment conducted in cooperation with the Department of Agriculture of the Bermuda Islands, </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 294 Triumph seed potatoes harvested at North Platte on August 31, 1928 (from dry-land April plantings) and planted in Bermuda about October 1, greatly outyielded seed potatoes that had been grown at Alliance and •Jwt 1 !*? ° n thC S3me datC fr ° m P lantin e s made on May 12 and June 5) (Table 14). This increase occurred whether the potatoes were treated Table 14.— Yields from Triumph potatoes grown at Alliance and North Platte when planted in Bermuda as a fall crop in 1928 (all seed lot&lt; harvested August 31— yields in pounds per 50 feet of row). T^ent or seed « isjssss- 1 'szsisss- April 15^ Planted May 12 planted June 5 Pound* Pounds Pounds Ethylene chlorhydrin in Nebraska 116 64 68 Ethylene chlorhydrin in Bermuda 132 84 56 Check — no treatment.... 77 48 44 with ethylene chlorhydrin (to break the rest period) either before ship - ment to Bermuda or after arrival there, or if not treated at all. The seed potatoes from North Platte had more nearly completed their rest period than those from Alliance; hence they started to grow earlier, produced a better stand, and yielded more when harvested in mid-winter. Apparently the relative merit of seed potatoes grown in different places will vary ir compared at different times of the year. It seems, therefore, that production of seed potatoes on dry land in the vicinity of North Platte may be considered feasible if good seed stocks are grown by proper methods in isolated fields. Table 15.— Monthly rainfall and mean monthly temperature for the growing seasons during which seed potatoes were produced at North Platte. Year [ April [ May | June | July j Aug. | Sept. | Ap^j" s ° e n t. (a) Monthly precipitation in dry-land area (inches) 192 20? iio 8 ill J-2J i-35 2 - 04 10 - 89 1926 037 T'29 ?'m H? 2&gt;46 l ' 20 12 - 48 1927 £74 233 III H\ 2 20 "O 11-68 1928 T 42? i'-l Hi 3 £ 3 3 ' 42 18.86 i^LjOLJLJLJLJL 1907-33 2.14 2.95 3.25 2.85 2.46 1.32 14.97 (b) Mean monthly temperature in dry-land area &lt;°F ) "26 63 II S II t\ 59 61.5 1926 47 64 fi- -? I? 66 66.0 1927 50 So B5 -o 7 S 60 64 - 6 1928 45 61 K? '-\ 68 64 63 - 2 1929 50 ge B7 ~ I? 61 62-2 1930 54 \% b- H V 68 64.2 1931 49 \\ « T4 65 65.5 27-yr. av. 48 57.7 68.3 74.5 72.4 63.6 64I1 f5M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>