<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1933-07">1933-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 283 July, 1933 Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska T. A. KIESSELBACH, ARTHUR ANDERSON, AND C. A. SUNESON Department of Agronomy An increase field op a new early-ripening and bunt-resist, lnt selection op turkey wheat THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Summary 4 Introduction 6 The Shift from Spring to Winter Wheat 5 Original Sources of Turkey Wheat 6 The Origin of New Varieties 7 Wheat Improvement at the Nebraska Station 7 Comparative Variety Tests „ 8 Yields of Crimean (C. I. No. 1435) and Cheyenne ....13 Periodic varietal fluctuations during 23 years 14 Pure strains vs. strain-mixtures 15 Supplemental Experiments —.16 Hessian fly _ 17 Winterhardiness — 18 Smut .'. _ 19 Milling and baking tests 20 Description of Important Varieties of Winter Wheat 21 Blackhull (Nebr. No. 1004, C. I. No. 6251) 21 Cheyenne (Nebr. No. 1050, C. I. No. 8885) 21 Kanred (Nebr. No. 1006, C. I. No. 5146) 22 Kawvale (Nebr. No. 1052, C. I. No. 8180) -.22 Kruse (Nebr. No. 1058, C. I. No. 11,524) 22 Minturki (Nebr. No. 1012, C. I. No. 6155) 22 Nebraska No. 60 (C. I. No. 6250) 23 Oro (Nebr. No. 1032, C. I. No. 8220) 23 Tenmarq (Nebr. No. 1030, C. I. No. 6936) 23 Turkey selection (Nebr. No. 1069, C. I. No. 10,016) 23 Turkey (known under a variety of numbers and names) 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY Spring wheat constituted 84 per cent of the total wheat acreage grown m Nebraska m the early 1890's but only 5 per cent of the total acreage from 1926 to 1930. The change was primarily due to the in - troductions of Turkey winter wheat from the area of Russia lying to the north and east of the Black Sea. Spring wheat is now largely confined to the three western tiers of counties m this state. It is estimated that fully 99 per cent of the winter wheat acreage m Nebraska is of the hard red Turkey type and one per cent or less consists of soft red varieties. Of the hard red winter wheat acreage it is estimated that 65 per cent now consists of Nebraska No. 60, 15 per cent Kanred, and 20 per cent ordinary Turkey under such names as Kharkof , Malakof , and Crimean, together with a number of selections whose identity has become obscure. The Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station maintains a winter - wheat improvement nursery m which selections and crosses are made for specific objectives. Field observations are supplemented by bunt and Hessian fly nurseries and controlled hardiness tests. These nurs - eries and those of other states and of the United States Department of Agriculture serve as a continual source of new varieties to be tested for yield and other characters. An effort is made to include m yield tests the most promising new selections produced elsewhere as well as m Nebraska. Nebraska No. 60 was first distributed to farmers m 1918. During 20 years m station tests it has yielded 2.0 bushels or 6 per cent more per acre than the original Turkey. It is characterized by superior winterhardiness and good grain quality. Cheyenne is the most recently distributed variety produced m the selection nurseries of this station. Selected from Crimean (C. I. 1435), it has surpassed the original by 14 per cent m a five-year field-plat test, while m a preceding five-year nursery test it proved 21 per cent better. During the last five years, Cheyenne proved superior m yield to the 65 other varieties tested. In addition to high yield it is characterized by strength of straw, shatter resistance, and Hessian-fly tolerance, and is satisfactory m cold endurance and milling characteristics. The more recent nursery program has resulted m the isolation of lines that are resistant to both bunt and Hessian fly and appear desir - able otherwise. These are being tested for utility. A number of the more important varieties and interesting new selec - tions are described m some detail. In a winter-wheat improvement program, growing the best selection individually has proved preferable to growing a mixture of a number of selections. A comparison of Nebraska No. 60 with the original Turkey wheat during a 23-year period illustrates the need for testing varieties over a number of years before their relative merits can be reliably estab - lished. This is due, m part, to differences m the response of varieties to seasonal variations. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Winter Wheat Varieties m Nebraska * T. A. KIESSELBACH, ARTHUR ANDERSON. AND C. A. SUNESON Among the crops grown m Nebraska, winter wheat is surpassed m importance only by corn. Approximately 3i/ 3 million acres have been grown annually during the past five years, with an average annual production of 54 million bushels. The use of adapted, productive varieties is| essen - tial. The results reported herein summarize the winter - wheat improvement work conducted at the Nebraska Agri - cultural Experiment Station. THE SHIFT FROM SPRING TO WINTER WHEAT Prior to 1895, spring wheat was the predominant type of wheat grown m Nebraska. Because of thfe lack of winter-resistant varieties and methods for their success - ful production, winter wheat had been unable to compete with spring wheat. Failure of the winter varieties avail - able to the early settlers caused it to be taken for granted that spring varieties should be grown. Mennonitl immi - grants are credited with introducing the so-called [Turkey type of hard red winter wheat into Kansas and Nebraska from Russia m 1873. While this and later importations of similar wheat have been the foundation of nearly all winter wheat grown m Nebraska, a general adoption was delayed until superiority became thoroughly demonstrated, fwithin 20 years after the introduction of Turkey wheat it was grown on a quarter of a million acres m this state] and its spread thereafter was far more rapid. Acreage data (Table 1), as summarized for 5-year periods; show that only 16 per cent of the wheat acreage during 1891-J95 con - sisted of winter wheat, whereas it comprised 95 per cent during 1926-30. Based on annual state-wide crop statistics during the 40-year period of 1890-1930, the yield of spring wheat has averaged 12.8 bushels per acre, compared with 15.7 bushels for winter wheat. Comparative yields' on the Experiment Station Farm at Lincoln have been 17|and 35 bushels per acre, respectively, for standard spring and winter types as an average of 22 years, 1909 to 19|30. In this connection, it may be pointed out that conditions at Lincoln are generally more favorable for wheat production, particularly winter wheat, than for the state as a whole. The superiority of hard red winter wheat over) spring wheat has been definitely established wherever sufficiently winter-hardy and otherwise adapted varieties are available. 1 Co-operative with the Division of Cereal Crops and Diseases, Bureau of Plant Industry, U. S. D. A., since 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 Table 1. — Annual acreages and grain yields of spring and winter wheat grown in Nebraska during successive 5-year periods between 1891 and 1980 x Acres harvested Percentage of Yield Acres narvesteq entire acreage per acrc Period sp r i n g Winter All Spring Winter Spring Winter wheat wheat wheat wheat wheat wheat wheat Thousands of acres P. ct. ' P. ct. Bu. Bu. 1891-95 1,848 352 2,200 84 16 11.0 11.0 1896-00 2,021 302 2,323 87 13 13.4 14.6 1901-05 813 1,867 2,680 30 70 13.1 19.3 1906-10 279 2,370 2,649 11 89 13.5 18.6 1911-15 256 3,236 3,492 7 93 12.7 16.6 1916-20 472 2,812 3,284 14 86 11.8 14.3 1921-25 230 3,198 3,428 7 93 11.4 14.0 1926-30 186 3,473 3,659 5 95 15.8 16.9 Average 12.8 15.7 1 Calculated from revised estimates supplied by the Division of Crop and Live - stock Estimates, United States Department of Agriculture. Data from Nebraska Agricultural Statistics (1923-24) were used in Be par a tine the spring and winter wheat acreages and in reporting; the yields per acre prior to 1900. Spring wheat is now largely restricted to western Nebraska, where it is relatively better adapted than elsewhere in the state. The distribution of winter wheat in Nebraska for 1930 is shown in Figure 1. ORIGINAL SOURCES OF TURKEY WHEAT The original Turkey wheat introduced by the Mennonite immigrants came from the region of Russia lying to the north and east of the Black Sea. This wheat, grown for many years under the relatively adverse conditions of Fig. 1. — The 1930 winter wheat distribution in Nebraska. Each dot represents 1,000 acres. (Data from Nehraska Agricultural Statistics for 1930.) </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska Russia, has proved well adapted to those sections of the United States having rather similar climate and soil and now known as the Hard Red Winter Wheat Region. Many subsequent introductions have been made from thte same general region in Russia and collectively they are commonly called Turkey or Crimean wheat. Frequently these; intro - ductions carry specific names denoting their* source, such as Kharkof, Malakof, and Crimean. Federal or state numbers have been assigned to most of them, although the identity of some has been lost and they are known only by the type name of Turkey or Crimean. While these wheats are all well adapted to Nebraska, some of them hav'e been found to differ materially with respect to various char - acters such as smut and cold resistance. THE ORIGIN OF NEW VARIETIES Since the Turkey wheats have proved so well adapted to the hard red winter wheat area, further improvement has been effected through selection of strains within commer - cial lots or through hybridization to combine desired characters of two or more sorts. Differences between some of these commercial introductions and selected strains con - cern such characters as disease resistance, winterhardiness, grain characteristics, lodge and shatter susceptibility, earliness of maturing, height, tillering, and productivity. It has been the purpose of investigations at experiment stations to compare and improve varieties and to increase seed supplies of the better ones for farm use. The more important Nebraska results follow. WHEAT IMPROVEMENT AT THE NEBRASKA STATION Beginning with 1902, the Nebraska Experiment Station undertook the further improvement of Turkey wheat by selection and crossing. Several thousand strains have been grown in the nursery and the more promising of these ad - vanced for testing in field plats. In the earlier years, the improvement work consisted largely of making numerous selections and testing these for yield and protein content and for favorable vegetative habits. As the characteristics of wheat and their niode of inheritance came to be better understood, additional ob - jectives have been stressed, with the purpose of overcoming individual weaknesses. At various times during the past 30 years selection and breeding programs have been in - itiated, followed by the testing and distribution of out - standing new varieties. The chief of these efforts knay be summarized as follows: (1) The 1902 selections from Turkey (Nebr. No. 1) resulted in the distribution lof new </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 strains known as Nebraska No. 42 and No. 48. (2) The 1908 selections from the same commercial Turkey wheat brought forth Nebraska No. 60, which has since been widely adopted throughout the state because of its superior winterhardiness and grain yield. (3) Subsequent to 1922 extensive selection within commercial varieties has been largely confined to Crimean (C. I. 1435) and Nebraska Turkey, No. 1011 (So. Dak. 144), as these had proved out - standing in earlier tests. The productive and lodge-re - sistant Cheyenne variety originated from the Crimean 1435 and has recently been distributed for use on Nebraska farms. A number of Turkey selections that are decidedly resistant to stinking smut or bunt and apparently somewhat resistant to stem rust were isolated from Nebraska Turkev 1011 through the use of artificial bunt and rust epidemics. More recently, selections have been made from this com - mercial Turkey which are very resistant to both bunt and Hessian fly and possess other attractive qualities. (4) Numerous hybrid selections are also being grown. Some of these are very promising from the standpoint of special characteristics such as "fly" and bunt resistance, cold en - durance, strength of stria w, earliness of maturity, and other desired qualities. Many of these new Nebraska selections have been com - pared with standard varieties already available to farmers and with outstanding new sorts developed elsewhere. From time to time the less promising have been dropped from the tests and new ones substituted. The purpose has been to secure the most productive and otherwise desirable wheat for Nebraska, whatever its origin might be. Accord - ingly, special effort has been made to include in the collec - tion of varieties here tested any hard winter sorts which have gained prominence in other states. comparative variety tests The comparative variety tests conducted in field plats at the Nebraska Experiment Station during the last 9 years are summarized in the following tables and discussion. In addition, comparative yields are reported for a limited number of wheats that have been tested over a 23-year period and also for a number of miscellaneous tests. All but three of the varieties tested in the field plats belong to the hard red winter type. The results for 66 varieties of winter wheat which have been grown in field plats at the Experiment Station during two or more years since 1924 are reported in Tables 2 and 3. The original Turkey (Nebr. No. 1) has been grown in </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Table 2. — Annual and average yields of winter wheat vari - ... eties and selections grown m field plats at the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station during the years 1924-82 1 Description"" | Yield per acre | ~ Variety or Neb. C I Annual I Average selection No. No. I I I i i I I '24J I '28- I '30 - - '82 I '32 \ '32 &amp; t = ffi| gfe§3 £ HfiSS | fiß I £ ES£F= » i?: « 18 "" " :S « is 5 :? S3 SS3 JSS S3 g &amp;£^= : SS £S &amp;S3S3 S5 StS S3 11:1 S3 12:1 111 S3 g^....:::::::::::::::: !!. 1 ft? jg S3 111 £S3&amp;•SI g; da? 53 £!££? JJ« 2908 31.2 16.4 16.7 86.7 23.8 85.5 40.6 42.4 23.4 29.4 33.1 86 4 2SS.-5- :::::::::::: SS hss g:5 653 11:1 11:1 K3 S3 83 £ SflS iig |^...z:::::::r. gS3 ifi ig 83 S3 S3 S3 Si S3 11:? 11:1 S3 S" 03 ™ JOlB 6166 29.6 11.9 9.6 33.2 20.8 31.9 41.2 43.6 29.1 27.9 33.3 88 0 $*£«* 1015 6690 30.6 13.2 11.2 33.4 23.6 27.4 39.2 39.4 31.7 Wft 32 2 36.8 N«S 'Si m S«n 52*5 Mi* 1 14 ° 866 238 336 426 44 - 8 289 S O - 3 34 - 7 38 - 8 Nebr. 60... 60 6260 88.4 16.1 16.8 88.6 27.1 38.8 88.6 44.6 26.0 30.8 34.8 86.0 Turkey sel 812 .. 86.4 18.6 18.6 37.6 26.9 86.6 87.1 44.8 26.8 30 7 34.0 86.9 ?£*£ re M J 4 -7 16.6 14.1 89.0 21.3 86.4 44.0 44.2 24.8 30.4 834 87 7 Turkey seL 10 82.6 14.4 16.6 88.1 26.6 34.6 40.7 44.2 26.0 30.8 34.4 87.0 Tu^ey gel 11 80.6 16.6 14.7 38.2 28.0 83.2 48.6 43.9 26.1 30 3 34 8 37 B Turkey sc! 6 6249 80.9 16.9 16.0 39.7 26.4 33.4 40.9 43.7 23 7 30 1 33 6 36 1 Turkey ael 80 7368 80.6 16.7 16.5 87.4 20.2 84.1 89.9 44.0 26.9 29 3 32 8 36 6 Turkey seL 47 82.6 16.8 18.9 87.2 19.2 84.4 39.8 44.2 23.1 29.0 32.1 36.7 Tenmarq 1080 6986 „ 26.1 33.2 47.0 49.2 33.0 ...1.. 87.5 43.1 Turkey 1027 38.4 24.7 37.2 40.0 46.8 26.0 ...1.. 34.7 87.8 V™ • — 1082 8220 28.8 83.9 39.3 44.9 29.6 ...L 34.3 37.9 J° bre d • •■ 1023 6934 18.7 14.6 34.8 21.9 35,6 37.2 38.3 80.0 ..... 82.6 86.2 Kharkof sel 1031 6938 28.2 29!s 34.4 86.6 23.8 "I 29 4 313 Crimean 1002 1435 82.8 16.6 15.6 34.3 26.6 85.9 41.0 46.8 23.4 80,3 34.7 37.1 Cheyenne 1060 8886 24.6 89.0 47.4 48.1 88.0 ...1.. 89.4 44.6 Crimean seL 1042 24.8 88.0 40.8 47.2 84.0 ...i.. 86.9 40.6 Crimean set 1044 24.8 88.7 41.2 46.6 29.4 ...L 36.0 39.1 Crimean seL 1047 24.5 87.4 44.0 46.2 27.0 .J... 35.8 39.1 Crimean *el 1048 22.8 88.9 89.9 46.4 30.1 ...L. 86.6 38.8 Crimean sel 1049 „„ „ 24.4 87.1 40.5 48.0 27.4 ...... 85.6 38.6 Crimean sel 1041 _ 21.9 88.4 40.S 46.4 29.4 ..J... 35.3 38.7 Crimean set 1048 26.1 36.9 41.1 46.2 26.9 ..J... 35.2 38.1 Crimean sel 1046 22.8 86.9 40.6 46.4 27.8 ...L. 84.8 38.1 Crimean sel 1086 28.6 86.2 44.2 46.6 24.0 ..!.. 84.7 37.9 Crimean seL 1040 „.. 25.8 87.8 40.9 40.4 28.2 ..J... 34.6 36.6 Crimean seL. 1046 24.6 84.2 40.1 46.8 26.7 ..L. 34.5 37.9 Crimean sel 1085 22.2 87.8 44.6 46.3 22.6 ..J... 84.4 37.6 Crimean sel 1089 24.2 86.1 40.8 44.6 26.6 -L. 84.31 87.1 Crimean seL 1088 23.8 85.7 40.6 44.8 26.8 ..J... 34.1137.2 Crimean seL 1087 „ 22.7 86.6 41.2 44.8 24.31 ..i.. 33.8 36.6 Tenmarq sel 1065 46.7 48.0 87.4 ..!.. 44.0 Kawvale 1052 8180 42.2 48.9 44.1 J 43.4 Fulhard 1051 8257 „ „ 44.1 40.8 40.8 ..1.. .. 41.9 Beloglina sel 1054 8884 _ „ 42.8 45.4 29.7 j S9.S Superhard 1066 8054 40.1 44.6 82 6 ' 89 1 Early Blackhull 1057 8856 84.8 41.8 80.2 ..! 55.6 Kruse 1068 11624 85.2 89.7 80.9 ..J 36.3 Quivira 1063 88861 38.2 43.8 22.5 ..i 34.8 Turkey I 10111 [26.8 16.4 15.5 36.2 24.0 36.7 42.4 47.9 30.8180.7 86.4 40.4 Turkeys sel 1063 10094 44.6 44.2 30.61 ..J 39.8 . Turkey sel... 1066 10096 44.6 46.1 29.1f ..! 39.6 Turkey sel 1070 10098 43.8 44.4 81.4 ..! 39.7 Turkey sel 1069 10016 „ 42.8 45.6 29.0 l ..J... .. 89.1 Turkey eel 1067 11506 41.6 44.2f 28.81 ..1 38.2 Turkey sel 1068 10097 „ 42.5 43.81 26.11 J. 37.5 Turkey sel 1062 10016 43.1 41.0 27.9 i 57.&amp; Turkey sel 1066 10096 42.6 43.4 26.2 ..i 37.1 Turkey sel 1064 44.0 40.7 25.5 ..1 86.T lowin ... 10691 100171 40.1 29.3 .j Hays No. 2 1071 1 6686 [ 45.3 31.0 .1 :.: ..::. Differences necessary for I I I I I I I i Ti statistical significance ' | 4.451 3.28| 5.67| 3.09| 8.87| 8.17| 6.641 5.22| 7.11| 1.65| 2.42. 3.68 - - IThe varieties were replicated three or four times annually m plats averaging 1/30" acre m size. The wheat was drilled at normal dates and rates. A standard Turkey wheat was grown on every sixth plat. Generalized varietal yield errors I have been calculated on the basis of check plat variability wherein the correlation has been removed for checks spaced 12 or 18 plats apart according to the number of varietieil under test. The values of significance indicated are twice the standard error of a difference. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 TABLE 3. — Comparative heading and ripening dates, plant height, test weight of grain, and relative grain yields of winter wheat varieties and selections grown at the Nebras - ka Agricultural Experiment Station during the years 192U to 1982 S-veur nvorxrn Relative erain Description (WSO-llsIf ?**&gt; «« , * _ various periods * Date of *» _ Test Variety or Nebr. C. L g » weight 1924- 1928- 1980 - seiection No. No. Head- I Ripen- g « of 32 32 32 I ] ing I ing grain In. Lbs. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. Turkey' 1005 5/29 6/29 38 60.3 104 103 103 Kanred 1006 5146 5/28 6/29 38 58.5 102 101 97 Kharkof 1010 1442 5/29 6/29 39 59.2 102 103 104 Turkey 1020 5/29 6/29 38 59.3 101 99 97 Iowa 404 1016 5580 5/28 6/29 38 59.3 101 98 96 Minturki 1012 6155 5/29 6/29 42 59.0 101 103 100 Blackhull 1004 6251 5/25 6/28 38 60.8 100 101 102 Turkey 1019 5/30 6/30 38 59.2 99 97 95 Malakof 1017 2908 5/31 6/29 39 58.4 97 95 91 Turkey 1021 5/30 6/30 38 59.2 96 94 90 Montana 36 1018 5549 5/31 6/30 39 68.5 96 95 92 Karmont 1014 6700 5/31 6/29 39 58.2 95 96 95 Turkey 1022 5/29 6/30 37 59.0 95 94 91 Bacska 1013 6156 6/29 6/29 41 58.8 92 96 98 Minard 1015 6690 6/1 7/1 41 59.6 91 93 95 Turkey 1 5/29 6/29 39 60.2 100 100 100 Nebr. 60 60 6250 5/30 6/30 39 60.0 102 100 93 Turkey sel..... 312 5/29 6/29 39 60.3 101 98 93 Turkey sel 69 5/30 6/29 39 59.2 100 98 97 Turkey sel..... 10 5/30 6/30 39 68.9 100 99 95 Turkey sel 11 5/30 6/30 39 58.9 100 100 97 Turkey sel 6 6249 5/29 6/29 39 60.2 99 97 93 Turkey sel 30 7358 5/30 6/30 40 59.5 97 95 94 Turkey sel..... 47 5/30 6/30 39 58.7 96 93 92 Tenmarq 1030 6936 5/26 6/28 39 58.5 108 111 Turkey 1027 5/29 6/29 39 58.3 100 96 Oro 1032 8220 5/30 6/29 40 59.4 99 98 Iohred 1023 6934 6/29 6/29 41 61.0 94 91 Kharkof sel 1031 6938 6/2 7/1 42 56.7 85 81 Crimean 1002 1436 5/29 6/29 39 59.6 100 100 96 Cheyenne 1050 8885 5/29 6/29 38 59.6 114 115 Crimean sel... 1042 5/29 6/29 39 59.0 106 104 Crimean sel... 1044 5/29 6/29 39 58.9 104 101 Crimean sel... 1047 5/29 6/29 39 69.3 103 101 Crimean sel... 1043 5/2S 6/29 39 58.9 103 100 Crimean sel 1049 5/29 6/29 38 58.7 102 99 Crimean sel... 1041 5/29 6/28 39 59.2 102 100 Crimean sel... 1048 6/29 6/23 39 58.4 101 98 Crimean sel... 1045 5/29 6/29 39 58.8 100 98 Crimean sel... 1036 5/29 6/29 38 58.8 100 98 Crimean sel... 1040 5/28 6/29 39 59.1 99 94 Crimean sel... 1046 5/29 6/29 39 58.7 99 98 Crimean sel... 1035 5/29 6/29 39 59.9 99 97 Crimean sel... 1039 5/28 6/29 39 59.6 99 96 Crimean sel... 1038 5/29 6/29 39 58.9 98 96 Crimean sel... 1037 5/29 6/29 39 58.9 97 94 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska Table 3. — Comparative heading and ripening dates, plant height, test weight of grain, and relative grain yields of winter wheat varieties and selections grown at the Nebras - ka Agricultural Experiment Station during the years 192U to 1932 — (concluded) v «*«- A..AAA-— Relative grain Date of 'S J= Te3t Variety or Nebr. CI. , ;« weight 1924- 1928- 1930 - selection No. No. Head- I Ripen- g_\__\_ ot 32 32 32 ing ing grain In. Lbs. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. Tenmarq sel 1055 5/26 6/28 39 58.7 113 Kawvale 1052 8180 5/27 6/27 41 58.8 112 Fulhard 1051 8257 5/25 6/27 39 60.4 ... 108 Beloglina sel 1054 8884 5/29 6/29 39 58.7 101 Superhard 1056 8054 5/25 6/27 37 60.9 101 Early Blackhull 1057 8856 5/18 6/23 35 61.5 ... 92 Kruse 1058 11524 5/30 6/29 41 59.9 91 Quivira 1053 8886 5/26 6/27 37 59.6 ,;. 90 Turkey 1011 5/28 6/29 36 59.8 101 105 104 Turkey sel 1063 10094 5/29 6/28 37 60.6 103 Turkey sel 1065 10095 5/29 6/28 37 60.6 102 Turkey sel 1070 10098 5/26 6/26 36 60.7 102 Turkey sel 1069 10016 5/26 6/26 37 60.7 101 Turkey sel 1067 11506 5/28 6/28 39 60.0 98 Turkey sel 1068 10097 5/28 6/27 38 59.9 97 Turkey sel 1062 10015 6/28 6/28 38 60.7 96 Turkey sel 1066 10096 5/27 6/27 36 61.0 96 Turkey sel 1064 5/28 6/28 37 60.5 95 'These relative yields are based on the original Turkey (Nebraska No. 1) and are calculated from the data in Table 2. Deviations of 5, 7, and 9 per 1 cent from the basic variety are required for statistical significance during the 9, S, and 3 year periods, respectively. all variety tests since 1900 and is used as a basis for com - parison. For convenience, the varieties have been grouped and summarized according to the duration of their tests. These varieties may be classified as follows: (lp three commercial lots designated as Turkey (Nebr. No. 1 and No. 1011) and Crimean (C. I. No. 1435), which have be'en used as foundation varieties for the Nebraska selections which immediately follow them in the tables; (2) six additional lots of Turkey wheat (Nebr. Nos. 1005, 1019, 1020, 1021, 1022, and 1027) of indefinite origin except that thpy were secured from various communities in Nebraska where they were considered to be outstanding varieties; (3) tvyo addi - tional lots of Turkey wheat of known origin, Kharkof and Malakof ; (4) fourteen of the most promising selections made from various lots of Turkey wheat by the. U[ S. De - partment of Agriculture, various state experiment stations, and private individuals; (5) five varieties, Minturki, </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 Minard, Tenmarq, Tenmarq Sel., and Quivira, originating as hybrid selections from crosses with a Turkey wheat as one parent; and (6) three soft winter wheats, Kawvale, Fulhard, and Kruse. Nine-year comparison. — Twenty-six varietes were tested during the 9-year period, 1924-32. The original Turkey (Nebr. No. 1) averaged 30.3 bushels per acre or 0.4 bushel above the average yield of all varieties. The highest - yielding variety, a Turkey wheat (Nebr. No. 1005) secured from Seward county, Nebraska, averaged 31.4 bushels per acre. Because of variability in annual yields and the small difference in mean yields, inherent difference in yielding capacity of these two wheats does not appear to be def - initely established. On the other hand, two varieties, Bacska and Minard, because of their rather consistently lower yields, are inherently less productive than the orig - inal Nebraska Turkey. These two varieties are not tvpical Turkey wheats. Five-year comparison. — During the 5-year comparison, 1928-32, these same, 26 varieties maintained a somewhat similar relationship, compared with the original Nebraska Turkey as in the 9-year period. A comparison of 21 addi - tional varieties was obtained during this 5-vear period. Two of these appeared to be inherently higher'yielding and one lower yielding than the original Turkey used for com - parison. The highest-yielding variety during this period was Cheyenne, a stiff-strawed, shatter-resistant selection from Crimean (C. I. No. 1435). The average yield of Cheyenne was 39.4 bushels, compared with 34.7 for the original Nebraska Turkey. Tenmarq, a selection originated at the Kansas Experiment Station from a cross between Marquis spring wheat and a Crimean selection, was the second-highest-yielding wheat during this period with an average yield of 37.5 bushels per acre. The lowest-yield - ing wheat was a Kharkof selection (Nebr. No. 1031) secured from McDonald College, Quebec, Canada. This low yield would suggest that Turkey selections which are productive in one region are not necessarily productive elsewhere. Three-year comparison. — Comparisons are available for 17 additional varieties during the three-year period, 1930 - 32. Two of these, a Tenmarq selection and Kawvale, were significantly superior and one, a hybrid selection by the name of Quivira (Prelude x Kanred) was inferior in yield to the original Turkey (Nebr. No. 1). The Tenmarq selec - tion is a reselection made by the Kansas Experiment Sta- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska tion from the original Tenmarq, from which it differs in only minor characteristics. Kawvale is a soft winter wheat which is normally unadapted to Nebraska conditions but was at a great advantage in two of these years because of its high resistance to Hessian fly. Cheyenne and Tenijnarq, which were the high-yielding wheats during the 5 -year period, were also high yielding among the 66 varieties in the 3-year test. YIELDS OF CRIMEAN (C I. NO. 1435) AND CHEYENNE Because of the unusual yield of Cheyenne, it is of interest to contrast its nursery and field-plat yields with those of Crimean (C. I. No. 1435), from which it was selected.] The results for the 5-year periods are shown in Table 4. Chey - enne has been the most productive selection in both nursery and field-plat tests, yielding 21 and 14 per cent more, re - spectively, than the parent variety. Table 4. — Comparative nursery and field-plat yields of Crimean (C. I. 1485) and Cheyenne winter wheat 1 Yield per acre | Variety | Nursery plats * | Field plats 2 | Actual | Relative | Actual | Relative Bu. P. ct. I Bu. JP. ct. Original Crimean 24.8 100 34.7 100 Cheyenne 30.0 121 | 39.4 114 1 Five-year average with 5 to 10 replications per year in B-row nursery blocks during 1925 to 1928 and 1930. 'Five-year average in field plats, 1928 to 1932, from Table 2. Fig. 2. — Cheyenne winter wheat on the left and Crimean iC.'L 1435), from which it was selected, on the right (1932). </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 PERIODIC VARIETAL FLUCTUATIONS DURING 23 YEARS Because of uncontrollable test errors and differing varietal response to variable conditions, several years of testing are required to evaluate varietal differences. This is illustrated in Table 5, wherein yields for four Turkey selections and the parent variety, Nebraska No. 1, are re - ported for a 23-year period, 1910-32. It is very difficult or impossible to control all errors in field tests. These may result in the mean yield of any one variety being somewhat too high or too low. With con - tinued testing, however, the errors will tend to cancel and the mean yield obtained will approach the true mean. The influence of environmental conditions on varietal response can be properly evaluated only by several years of comparative testing. Extreme seasonal variability in TABLE 5. — Comparative yields of Turkey winter wheat and selected strains, 1910-1982 I | Average yields for various periods Variety or | Nehr. 1 Nursery | Field plats selection I No. 1910- 1913-1 1918-1 1923- 1928- 1913- 1 1 12 1 17 1 22 I 27 32 32 Actual yields {bushels per acre) Turkey (Orig.) .. 1 38.8 38.3 31.7 24.2 34.7 32.2 Turkey sel 6 51.0 46.2 32.5 25.2 33.6 34.4 Turkey seL. 60 51.7 43.6 33.3 26.2 34.8 34.2 Turkey sel 11 42.4 44.1 33.2 24.3 34.8 34.1 Turkey sel 10 47.2 43.7 33.3 24.6 34.4 34.0 Relative yields (per cent) Turkey (Orig.)... 1 100 100 100 100 100 100 Turkey sel 6 131 121 103 104 97 107 Turkey sel 60 133 114 105 104 100 106 Turkey sel 11 109 115 105 100 100 106 Turkey sel 10 122 114 105 102 99 106 climatic and soil conditions and in the prevalence of plant diseases and insect pests will tend to increase the time re - quired. This may be illustrated by the comparison of the four Turkey selections with the parent variety, which they surpassed in yield by 14 to 21 per cent during the five years, 1913-17, but failed to surpass during the five years, 1928 - 32. As an average for 20 years they were 6 or 7 per cent higher in yield than the parent Turkey. Comparative annual yields of Nebraska No. 60 and the original Turkey from which it was selected are shown in Figure 3 for the period, 1910 to 1932. The yields for the first three years were based on well-replicated nursery plats and those for the last 20 years on replicated field </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska 1 1 1 1 — | plats. The mean dif - ference for the 20 - l year period in | favor •°V of Nebraska Noi 60 is _\ &gt; 2.0 bushels perj acre, \ » which would appear " A {', A- quite significant. For ll It! / \ i the most part from a 1\]\ / \ A A 'A 1910 to 1932 t» the **° ', M V rl\ — f \f\ 7 7+ yields of the two vari - ■■ L ■■»!.•' 1 f \ \\g\ h If \ eties paralleled each 2 . \ ! \ f V \ A \\ // \ other rather closely. 1" — i ' j— f ' rn — H$ ' Nebraska No. 60 was . 1 h V \ I «' advanced to I field \f/ *\ j plats as a j result M r \~t of its average superi - &lt;j ority in the nursery testing. This evident 10 I superiority was due = j = g£5jJ2«--' primarily to its high I yield in 1910 when the ■ i ■ i i ■ i i ■ i ■ ■ ■ i i i i i i i i i '. ,, . ,, ... . mo isu is2o !_.« mo yield of the original Fig. 3. — Comparative annual yields of Ne- Turkey was depressed braska 60 winter wheat and the original u v vprv . pwrp lnH Turkey from which it was selected. ? y V . er y. S f Ve *X, i 0ag : ing. Again in 1915 and 1916, the yields of Nebraska No. 60 were relatively high because of its greater lodge resistance and ability to mature under moisture conditions which favored lodging. Its yield was also relatively high in 1917 because of its greater cold resistance and subsequent winter survival. On the other hand, the original Turkey was decidedly superior in 1913, 1930, and 1932 because of greater tolerance of heavy Hes - sian-fly infestations. It may be concluded that Nebraska No. 60 is, on the average, a more productive wheat than the variety from which it was selected. Under some con - ditions, however, it may prove inferior. PURE STRAINS VS. STRAIN-MIXTURES Some interest attaches to a comparison of the yields of individual selections with those from a mechanical mixture of the same selections, to determine whether a mixture is better suited to average conditions than the best individual strain. The results for four such 9-year tests ih! which the mixtures were prepared annually by mixing equal amounts of each strain are summarized in Table 6. Two groups selected in 1910 as the five highest and five' lowest in yield among 80 strains were tested comparably! in this </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 Table 6. — The yields of pure Turkey selections grown in. comparison with strain-mixtures Number Yield per acre in bushels Period - . * r ° Wn Year. Selec- Repli- Original S 1 ?^ i^Sf 81 Average *S25_i Ite ■ r,, tions cations variety * 1 _5?* rffldins: of all mixture selecBon Section selection, Mh g ton . Nursery blocks » m£_ I ! I ■ I IS I 2H I 8B - 2 I «•" I 82 - 8 I 82 - 9 1914-22 I 9 I 5 I 10 I 31.8 I S2.B | 28.8 | 81.1 | 82.1 Field plats „*£_! IS I *5 I __f I 5S-2 I 8B - 8 I 82 " 8 I 8 «-l I 88 -9 1924-82 I 9 | 7 1 8-4 | 80.8 1 80.8 | 29.0 | 80.0 | 80.0 fc«_?55*..*"7 * POnp » of 'elections were picked in 1910 from a larger «roup on the - tWdy. *" mverMre ■» beinB the B h'«hest and 6 lowest in yield, respec- SS5??* "* nurser y blocks during the period from 1914 to 1922 in comparison with the original unselected Turkey. Similar field-plat tests were made with 11 Turkey selections during 1915 to 1923 and with seven Turkey selections - during 1924 to 1932, inclusive. In every instance the highest-yielding selection averaged higher in yield than either the respective annual mixture or the original Turkey. Likewise, the lowest-yielding selection generally averaged lower in yield than the mixture or the original variety. The average yield of all selections within a group was practi - cally the same as the yield of the corresponding mixture. It is evident from these tests that where a number of selec - tions differ in productivity, it would be advantageous to grow the most productive one alone rather than a mixture of them. supplemental experiments As far as possible all varieties are compared in supple - mental tests in order to determine their merits more effectively and more rapidly. These tests, for the most part, involve additional plantings independent of the yield test. In addition the most promising varieties are always tested at the branch experimental stations in this state and in co-operative tests with farmers. Through collaboration with the experiment stations of the various hard red winter wheat states and the U. S. Department of Agriculture, a number of the more prominent varieties are also tested in all of the states concerned. As summarized annually by the U. S. Department of Agriculture, these regional data are valuable supplements to the results within the states. For the sake of brevity, only the more important of these supplemental tests made at the Nebraska station will b&amp; </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska here reported for a small group of varieties which includes practically all sorts that are at present of special commer - cial promise in this state. HESSIAN FLY Since injury to wheat by the Hessian fly is recognized as a frequent cause of yield reduction, much interest attaches to the susceptibility of varieties to these insects. Their presence in the overwintering plants contributed materially to winterkilling in the spring of 1932 and to the poor yields during the same year over most of central and eastern Nebraska. During the past three years, special nurseries have been devoted to studying the resistance of a large number of varieties and selections to Hessian-fly attacks of epidemic proportions. Data for a number of common varieties are presented in Table 7. The high resistance shown by Kawvale, the moderate resistance of Blackhull, and the I Table 7. — Comparative varietal fall and spring Hessian-fly infestation at the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Average fall infestation Spring infestation, .. . (3 years) 1932 Variety Plants | Tillers [ggg Plants | Tillers j ffgg P.ct. I P.ct. No. P.ct. P.ct. No. Kharkof 92 38 5.9 87 50 2.4 Kanred 85 42 6.7 88 51 2.3 Nebr. 60 86 34 7.0 88 47 2.7 Blackhull 58 24 3.2 70 31 1.2 Tenmarq 80 32 5.6 82 46 1.9 Oro 87 40 4.6 91 49 2.7 Cheyenne 95 56 8.2 90 56 2.1 Minturki 76 37 5.4 89 50 1.8 Kawvale 7 2 0.2 7 2 0.1 Nebr. 1069 93 46 7.3 91 60 2.4 1 Flaxseed is the name commonly assigned to the paparia of Hessian fly. susceptibility of all the other varieties are evident. A numerical comparison of intensity of infestation, however, does not always indicate the depressing effect on [yield. This was shown in yield comparisons in 1932 under a severe infestation. With Cheyenne the infestation was higher than for any other variety in the fall, and among the highest in the spring, but it tolerated the fly, as is shown by the higher yields reported in Table 2. Nebraska No. 60 seems to be more resistant than Cheyenne to fall infestatio^i, and only slightly more susceptible in the spring, as determined </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 Fig. 4. — Winter-wheat test plats showing differences in varietal re - sistance to Hessian fly under epidemic conditions (1932). The lodged wheat is down because of fly-injury. by "flaxseed" counts. In yield, however, Cheyenne was 50 per cent (13 bushels) superior to Nebraska No. 60, a result which could be foretold by differences in plant vigor, de - velopment, and standing ability before harvest. The heavy infestation of "fly" in 1932 brought to light a rather large number of selections with resistance ap - proaching that of Kawvale. Further testing may show some of these to be superior to Kawvale and thus provide a "fly-resistant", adapted variety. WINTERHARDINESS Winterkilling occasionally causes severe loss in acreage and yields of winter wheat in this state. The most severe losses in the last 20 years occurred in 1916-17 and 1931-32. Losses from this source have been so great that cold endur - ance cannot be overlooked in a wheat-improvement pro - gram. Since severe winterkilling occurs only occasionally in the fields, it has been found desirable to supplement field tests with controlled tests employing artificial freezing. The control equipment described by Peltier 2 is available for the annual testing of new varieties for cold endurance. Results from such controlled freezing tests are shown in Table 8, in comparison with field observations as to winter - killing at Lincoln and Alliance, Nebraska, and in the Federal Uniform Winterhardiness Nurseries at about 30 northern stations each year. The comparative yields for the varieties here considered are reported in Tables 2 and 3. 1 Peltier, G. L., Control equipment for the study of hardiness in crop plants. Jour. Agr. Res. 43:177-182. 1081. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska Table 8. — Comparative winterhardiness of important or promising new varieties as determined by different methods of testing Survival in percentage of Kharkof I Variety Average of 8 Average of 6 or Artificial frees- Uniform winter- Varl6ty replicates at more replicates ing tests with hardiness Lincoln in 1982 »* AI " a " ce in field-hardened nurseries * 193Z plants f Kharkof 100 100 100 100 Kanred 86 110 108 103 Nebr. 60 117 124 116 I 108 Cheyenne .... 102 115 106 ( Tenmarq .... 89 92 88 87 Blackhull .... 68 96 59 78 Oro 113 104 94 100 Minturki .... 127 125 133 119 Kawvale 117 83 110 93 Nebr. 1069.. Ill 118 96 ...J. Nebr. 1062.. 125 133 L 1 From U. S. Dept. of Agriculture, Circular 141. SMUT Bunt, or stinking smut, is another major problem in winter-wheat production in Nebraska. Despite effective seed treatments for its control, smut persists. The XL S. Department of Agriculture has compiled statistics indicat - ing that 28 per cent of the cars of wheat received at Omaha during the seven-year period, 1923-29, graded smutty. This means that the quality of Nebraska wheat is lowered to that extent, and that farmers are penalized as a conse - quence through price discounts and lowered yields. Interest in the bunt problem has been increased by the discovery of resistant varieties. The Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station has under test a large number of highly resistant and otherwise attractive Turkey selections. The high resistance of a selected group of these, when inoc - ulated with local smut, is shown in comparison with stand - ard susceptible varieties in Table 9. These resistanjt Ne - braska Turkey selections trace to Nebraska No. 1011, which is considerably more resistant than Kharkof and other sim - ilar commercial varieties. Among the promising varieties now grown in the state, Nebraska No. 60 shows slight resistance to bunt, [while Kanred and Cheyenne class with the more susceptible Turkey wheats. Some of these new resistant Turkey (selec - tions will probably not require annual seed treatment. It is encouraging to note that a recent bunt-resistant selection has also proved highly resistant to Hessian fly. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 Table 9. — Annual and average percentages of smutted heads produced from seed of well-known or promising new vari - eties inocidated with local smut — f. 929 -32 v . . | Nebr. 1 Percentages of smutty heads variety j Np j 1Q29 | 193Q | •— — [ 193g [ Kharkof 1010 26.0 39.0 52.0 20.0 34.0 Kanred 1006 33.0 36.0 25.0 23.0 29.0 Nebr. 60 60 18.0 40.0 12.0 9.0 20.0 Cheyenne 1050 15.0 20.0 29.0 32.0 24.0 Tenmarq ..; 1030 25.0 27.0 27.0 26.0 26.0 Blackhull 1004 34.0 46.0 26.0 21.0 32.0 Kawvale 1052 6.0 18.0 Turkey 1011 3.0 19.0 8.0 Oro 1032 1.0 0.0 10.0 2.6 3.4 Minturki 1012 0.6 2.7 3.5 0.9 1.9 Turkey sel 1062 1.5 6.5 2.5 0.6 2.8 Turkey sel 1063 0.5 1.5 0.5 1.1 0.9 Turkey sel 1069 0.0 1.5 4.3 0.0 1.5 MILLING AND BAKING TESTS The demand of the milling trade in Nebraska is for hard Ted winter wheat suitable for making light bread. Such wheat is normally characterized by relatively high protein content and strong gluten. Variations in protein content are, however, influenced far more by soil and climate than by heritable varietal differences. For example, the protein content of wheat has ranged from approximately 11 to 20 per cent in different seasons, whereas variations between varieties grown under similar conditions seldom exceed 1 to 2 per cent. Eleven per cent is generally considered about the lower limit for a strong baker's flour. It is difficult to evaluate the comparative baking characteristics of wheat varieties when the protein percentage is lower than this. In commercial practice the protein percentage of flour is standardized by blending. Aside from protein content, however, some varieties are not well suited to present-day methods of commercial baking. For this reason care should be exercised to ascertain that a new variety has satisfactory milling and baking characteristics before it is distributed for farm production. It is highly desirable that there should be regional uni - formity with respect to the type of wheat grown in order that market demands may be most satisfactorily met. Since virtually all of the wheat grown in Nebraska is of the Turkey type, such requirements would seem to be readily satisfied in this state. A rather strong tendency has been noted for protein con - tent to vary inversely with the acre yield of different var- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska ieties grown comparably. The economic question then arises, in connection with the choice of new varieties!, as to which is of greater importance, grain yield or protein per - centage. Evaluation of wheat varieties for their milling and baking value has come to be a problem for cereal chemists. Standardized laboratory tests, made in accordance; with specifications of the American Association of pereal Chemists, not only serve to evaluate varieties but also to indicate the baking procedure needed by the individual samples of flour to give best results. The more im - portant of the varieties herein reported have been (tested by the cereal chemists of the Nebraska Experiment Station and the U. S. Department of Agriculture. While some dif - ferences were observed, all of the varieties otherwise suit - able for Nebraska appear satisfactory for commercial use. description of important varieties of winter wheat It is estimated that of the winter wheat grown in Ne - braska, about 65 per cent is Nebraska No. 60, 15 per cent is Kanred, 19 per cent is ordinary Turkey (under Various names) , and some selected strains of Turkey whose identity has in some instances become obscure, and 1 per centor less is various soft red winter varieties. The following brief descriptions of the varieties that are important com - mercially or are otherwise of special interest may serve to increase acquaintance with them. Both the Nebraska station number and the U. S. D. A. Cereal Investigation number are indicated for each variety. Blackhull (Nebr. No. 1004, C. I. No. 6251). — This variety was selected and distributed by Earl G. Clark, a Kansas farmer, and is now one of the three most important var - ieties grown in that state. As the name suggests, black glumes serve to identify the variety although .certain weather conditions occasionally prevent such coloration. Moderate Hessian-fly resistance and a slightly higher bushel weight are characteristic. The variety is not suf - ficiently winterhardy to be safe for Nebraska. Cheyenne (Nebr. No. 1050, C. I. No. 8885). — This var - iety was selected from Crimean (C. I. No. 1435) in 1922 at the Nebraska station. Field-plat yield tests were first made in 1928, and distribution among farmers in 1930. Limited seed stocks which are insufficiently pure for certification are now in the hands of farmers. A repurified seed! supply will probably be available for distribution in 1933 and this variety will then be subject to certification. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 Cheyenne is characterized by a stiff straw, prolific stool - ing, and a short, erect head. An unusual tolerance of Hes - sian fly, which permits production of fair to good yields despite a heavy infestation, is also a characteristic. Its milling and baking qualities appear satisfactory, except that it is sometimes slightly deficient in protein, probably because of high yield. Cheyenne seems to be adapted to practically the same area as Kanred, which it resembles in many respects. It has been the highest-yielding variety in station tests during the last five years. Nebraska farmers who have grown Cheyenne are enthusiastic over its pro - ductivity and vegetative habits. , Kanred (Nebr. No. 1006, C. I. No. 5146). — This variety was selected and distributed by the Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station. Resistance to certain physiologic forms of stem rust, good yields, satisfactory winterhardi - ness, and good milling and baking properties characterize this variety. The principal fault is a weak straw. It was very extensively grown in Nebraska between 1920 and 1925, but has since gradually given way to Nebraska No. 60. Kawvale (Nebr. No. 1052, C. I. No. 8180).— Kawvale is a semi-soft winter wheat, which was developed and re - cently distributed by the Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station for growing in the soft wheat belt of that state. The salient qualities of this variety are its resistance to the physiologic forms of Hessian fly and leaf rust commonly present. Extreme shatter susceptibility under certain con - ditions stands out among its faults. This and other soft wheat varieties are inherently unsuited to Nebraska con - ditions. Kruse (Nebr. No. 1058, C. I. No. 11,524).— This wheat was recently distributed by F. C. Kruse, of Douglas county, Nebraska, and comes from a selection made in Montana. It is characterized by stiff straw, hairy glumes, and short, soft kernels and is not of the Turkey type. The cold sus - ceptibility and milling and baking characteristics, as well as kernel characters, suggest a kinship with club wheat. The bunt resistance and Hessian-fly tolerance shown by this variety are commendable. During the three years in which it has been grown, its yields have been low even though it has been greatly favored by Hessian-fly tolerance during two years. Mmturki (Nebr. No. 1012, C. I. No. 6155).— Minturki was developed from a Turkey-Odessa cross at the Minne - sota Agricultural Experiment Station. The variety is </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Winter Wheat Varieties in Nebraska winterhardy and bunt resistant, and shows some resistance to Hessian fly. The principal faults in this territory are excessive plant height, late maturity, and tendency for the grain to be rather soft. Nebraska No. 60 (C. I. No. 6250). — This variety origin - ated as a selection from Turkey made at the Nebraska station in 1907. Nebraska No. 60 was first distributed in 1918 and is now the most extensively grown variety ih this state. It is superior to practically all known Turkey selec - tions in winterhardiness and has an average yield advan - tage over the original Turkey (Nebr. No. 1) of 2.0 bushels per acre during 20 years of comparative testing at the Ne - braska station. It has good milling and baking character - istics. The Hessian-fly tolerance of Nebraska No. 60 is be - low that of most Turkey wheats. Oro (Nebr. No. 1032, C. I. No. 8220). — Oro is a smut - resistant Turkey selection made at the Sherman County Branch Experiment Station in eastern Oregon. This var - iety has stiffer straw than most Turkey selections, but ma - tures somewhat later. It has yielded about the same as Nebraska No. 60 during the five years that it has been tested. Tenmarq (Nebr. No. 1030, C. I. No. 6936). — Tenmarq is a newly distributed variety in Kansas, developed at their agricultural experiment station from a cross between Marquis (spring wheat) and a Crimean selection. [It has a fairly stiff straw and short, plump kernels, and it yields well. Tenmarq is not a safe variety for Nebraska because of a winterhardiness record only slighly better than that of Blackhull. Turkey Selection (Nebr. No. 1069, C. I. No. 10,016). — This is one of a group of nine bunt-resistant varieties de - veloped by the Nebraska station, now in advanced stages of testing. One of the group may be distributed in the near future. These selections were made in 1924) from Turkey (Nebr. No. 1011). This particular selection ma - tures about five days earlier than Nebraska No. 60 and is as winterhardy as Kanred. Turkey (known under a variety of numbers and names). — Turkey is a name broadly applied to a large group of rather similar wheats some of which, like Kharkof, Malakof , and Crimean, are known by names of the areas in Russia where they were obtained. All of these wheats lack uniformity. , . I Owing to their suitability for the hard red wmterjwheat area and to the diversity of plant types within eaeh, the </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 283 Turkey wheats have been a fruitful field for plant selec - tion. Such divergent varieties a3 Blackhull, Oro, and Ne - braska No. 60, trace to Turkey wheat. Kanred and Chey - enne, which were selected from Crimean (C. I. No. 1435) are similar in some characteristics, but extremely divergent in others. Some of the unimproved Turkeys deserve recog - nition with our best varieties, being only slightly inferior in yield over a period of years. A Turkey (Nebraska No. 1005) was the highest-yielding wheat during a 9-year period and because of unusual promise in other respects is now being used as a basis for further selection. The im - proved Turkey varieties such as Nebraska No. 60, Kanred, and Cheyenne are favored, however, partially because of higher yields but also because of their uniform appearance and specialized advantages in one or more respects, such as greater winterhardiness, disease resistance, and resist - ance to lodging and shattering. tBM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>