<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Some New Hybrid Strawberries</title>
               <date value="1923-04">1923-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">1 Some New Hybrid Strawberries R. F. HOWARD AND C. C. WIGGANS THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT, DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">were their either SUMMARY Seven hundred and sixty-two new strains of strawberries produced by crossing and inbreeding named varieties. Ten of the hybrids have been retained after 7 years' tests These promising hybrids have been selected largely upon ability to outyield Dunlap, the standard variety for this section. They also produce larger berries thruout the season than Dunlap or Warfteld. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Some New Hybrid Strawberries R. F. HOWARD AND C. C. WIGGANS Approximately 2,000 varieties of strawberries have been originated and listed in the United States. In addition, sev - eral hundred varieties of European origin have been* grown in America, tho less than 50 of these have gained any prom - inence. These varieties have had their origin as hybrids from known parents, as seedlings of known mother parents, and as chance seedlings of unknown parentage. Of the 1,879 var - ieties listed by Fletcher,* 268 are the results of crossing one variety with another, 199 are said to be seedlings of certain varieties, and 1,412 are seedlings of unknown parents. Thus we see that most of our commercial varieties of strawberries have originated as chance seedlings. The principal object of the hybridization work reported in this publication was to determine the possibility of producing superior strains of strawberries by breeding methods. The Dunlap, Warfield, and others now grown in Nebraska are desirable for home use and local markets but are not satisfac - tory for shipping purposes. Good shipping varieties such as Klondike and Gandy are not especially well adapted here. There is need, therefore, for a good, large-fruited variety which will meet trade requirements with respect to shipping and keeping qualities. It is generally known that strawberry varieties, like most of our other improved fruits, do not breed true from seed. The crosses were not made, therefore, with the thought of studying the transmission of varietal characters, tho it has been interesting to note that certain varieties transmit de - sirable characteristics to a higher per cent of their progeny than do others. This tendency is illustrated in the 8 crosses where Enormous was used as the pistillate parent (Table 1). All of the progeny of these crosses resulting from Clyde, Long- • "North American Varieties of the Strawberry" by Fletcher. Technical Bui. No. 11, Agr. Ezp. Station. Blacksburg. Va. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 189 Table 1. — Origin of Seedlings, Number Tested, Sex, and Number Saved. Ma. No. No. No. Saved for Parents Total Stain- Pis- Inter- Plants inate tillate mediate ' Ut 2nd Srd Test Test Mother Pollen Test Aug. Luther selfed.. ■aaer Wood X Clyde LI S i 1 Beder Wood X Dunlap 1 Beder Wood selfed. Biset X Dunlap 1 1 11 BM X Howard 17 2« 1 Bisel X Longfellow Bisel X Splendid. Bisel X Staples. 1 1 ■—lir X Joel :) Buster X Staples 1 Cardinal X Aug. Luther 1 CVde selfed 1 1 1 Ounlap X Auk. Luthe Dunlap X Staple Dunlap selfed _ 1 1 Enormous X Clyde Enormous X Dunlap i Enormous X Glenmary Enormous X Longfellow 1 Easiai i X Parsons Enormous X Splendi.l _ 1 Enormous X Stevens Enormous X Wm. Be! 4 Glenmary X Splend (ilenmary X Stevens Glenmary selfed. Highland X Auk. Luthe Highland X Clyde. Highland X Joe. Highland X Staples Howard 17 X Staples... Howard 17 X Stevens Howard 17 X Wm. Belt Howard 17 selfed Hybird selfe 1 S2 u Joe X Dunlap _. 1 1 Joe X Staples. _ „. l 1 Joe selfed 1 Longfellow X Parsons.. _. 1 Longfellow X Splendid __ 1 1 1 1 Longfellow selfed.. 1 Neff X Beder Wood 1 1 Ned X Dunlap. Ne* X Staples. l 1 Neff X Wm. Bell Ncf selfed 4 1 Parsons X Clyde _ 20 Parsons X Dunlap 36 Parsons X Wm. Belt _ 12 i 1 1 82 I 14 tin 1 . It 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Some New Hybrid Strawberries 1 TABLE 1. — Origin of Seedlings, Number Tested, Sex, and Number Saved — Cont. fellow, and Splendid pollen were eliminated at the initial selec - tion, while Dunlap was the only pollen parent represented after the third selection. The pronounced ability of certain varieties to produce desirable seedlings is further illustrated by the fact that most of the everbearing varieties have come from the variety Pan American either as direct seedlings or as crosses. The Wilson also is known to have produced no less than 40 of our present varieties. Pm rents Mother No. TotaJ SUm- PlanU b— te i i r No. No. No. Pto- Inter- tillate mediate 1st i i r ... Saved Pen i i lavi for ' Te»t ! for Sample X Auk. Luther Sample X Clyde Sample X Dunlap Sample X Joe Sample X Longfellow Sample X Parson* Sample X Splendid__ Sample X Staple*. Sample X Wm. Belt Splendid X Beder Wood .. Splendid X Glenmary Splendid X Wm. Beh- SiHpl.-- X Joe. I Staplei X Parson*. Staple. »elfed... Steven* X Beder Wood..... Stevens X Par*on* Steven* X Splendid- Stevens selfed Wm. Belt X Clyde__.."ZZ Wm. Belt X Howard 17... Wm. Belt X Panona. 2 0 3 2 S I o 7 j ;i I Q ' 12 | f | " j \ i | 2 ] t | 1 | 1 | _____ IS 14 ZZZZZ i i i 0 2 1 t | 0 0 4 I • 0 1 0 I o i I :: « | 0 0_| 0 1 0 I 0 1' o ! o i i I o i o i o i ri oi o i 0 ! 0 ! 0 ! 0 1 0 [ 0 I 2 0| S I 0 I II 2 ! 0 I 0 1 II o I » I * 1 0 I 0 1 0| 0 1 0| 1 0 I 0 I 0 I i I o_ I o 1 u I o i o ! o ! I o 1 0 0 I o I 0 0 0 0_ I o : ! t 0_ 0 1 • •_ I 0 o • 0 II (I ll (I (I t 0 Si- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 HYBRIDIZATION AND TESTING METHODS* In early winter of 1913 several plants of various varieties were transplanted to benches in the greenhouse, where they reached the flowering stage about midwinter. The crosses SB perfected by removing the immature anthers from the ers of the mother parent 2 or 3 days before the pollen of other was applied. Other crosses were made in the field during the spring of 1914. In case of the field crosses it was i Fig. 1. — General view of hybrid test plat, 1920 necessary to protect the flowers from foreign pollen. This was done by means of paper bags, or frames covered with fine muslin. Certain varieties were "selfed," or fertilized with their own pollen. When the seeds resulting from these crosses were mature, the fruits were crushed and the seeds allowed to dry for several weeks. They were then germinated in sterile soil • Moat of the crone* were made by J. R. Cooper, formerly assistant professor of horticulture. University of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Some New Hybrid Strawberries 7 in the greenhouse. A low per cent of germination was secured in many instances. The hybrid seeds and resulting plants from a given cross were kept separate from all other lots. The hybrid plants from the same cross were each given a number; as, Enormous X Dunlap (1), (2), (3), etc. Seven hundred and sixty-two plants were secured. Each plant was transplanted to the field and given sufficient space to establish a colony of daughter plants by means of runners. By this means it was possible to get from 6 to 20 plants from each hybrid on which to take preliminary notes the following sea - son, 1916. Fig. 2 —Near view of hybrids showing plant characteristics During the fruiting season of 1916 it was deemed advisable to discard 654 of the 762 sorts. This elimination was made on the basis of unproductiveness, inferior fruit, deformed fruits, inability to make plants, and susceptibility to leaf-spot. A sufficient number of plants from each of the 108 best hybrids and seedlings were set in the spring of 1917 to establish a 30-foot matted row for further test. From the yield taken in 1918 (Table 2) 72 more were eliminated and 36 of the better sorts were planted (spring of 1919) in 50-foot rows. In the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 8 189 TABLE 2. — Yield of strawberry hybrids Quarts per 50 ft. row — full stand. Hybrid or variety 1»18 1»1» 1920 1921 Avk. ("rates I'.Hm.ji peraen i I r Biad X Howard IT (1) (2) (t) &lt;4&gt; Blister X Staple* (1) &lt;2&gt; Cardinal X Aug. Luther (1) Clyde aelfed _ ( 1 ) Dunlap X Aug. Luther (1) (2) (1) I (4) (6) («) (7) (8) (») Dunlap X Splendid II) Enormous X Glenmary (1) (2) (t) (4) Enormous X Parsons (1) (2) (I) (4) Enormous X Dunlap — (1) ! (2) it) (4) (S) («) (7) (8) (») (10) (11) (12) (It) (14) (15) (1*) (17) Enormous X Steven*. (1) Enormous X Wm. Belt (1) (2) (S) I (4) (5) («) (7) Glenmary X Splendid. _..(1) (2) (I) Glenmary X Steven*. _ (1) Highland X Aug. Luther- (1) (2) (S) (4) 17.S2 9.02 &gt; 14.85 j 10.04 4.»7 7.«8 8.20 «.15 8.20 9.7S 8.71 2.4« 13.11 6.61 10.S4 5.41 5.99 6.25 S.S8 S.07 8.84 1.17 7.27 6.92 5.99 1 :M 10.86 5.84 6.»2 8.09 14.03 8.65 4.15 7.94 17.89 5.5S 5.02 16.75 4.87 7.11 10.SS 17.10 9.58 5.22 6.S0 5.12 7.94 1.64 S.94 7.58 7.17 7.53 4.61 7.06 7.87 4.10 19.16 12.55 14.75 51.92 { 45.0* I 51.28 40.09 32.79 27.10 ' 24.58 ' 10.74 19.11 38.26 32.78 16.19 17.76 i 21.86 , 38.25 ' 27.80 i 11.41 ! 11.41 KM 17.76 tut 32.78 12.78 42.14 1 10.05 ! 17.76 ; 24.58 27. SO 33.47 24.58 51.90 28.69 28.69 23.22 45.08 27.30 , 10.05 40.09 25.96 10.05 31.41 ' 49.18 41.71 10.74 35.51 30.04 27.30 20.04 62.84 42.35 34.24 •S.21 19.11 49.18 28.68 42.35 36.88 69.67 84.16 28.57 21.41 19.87 30.66 25.13 19.41 24.20 22.05 27.80 23.30 11.80 12.44 ! 27.75 28.17 11.72 18.55 22.60 19.01 ■Mi 8.00 7..-," 14. 'Hj MJt UM 1M \ 11.00 UM 1 2M.0 24.88 ! 2S8.1 25.31 2«2.« 22.14 2*1.8 1 25.77 JUT. 4 28.91 295.8 18.49 191.8 16.51 1T1J </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Some New Hybrid Strawberries 9 Table 2. — Yield of strawberry hybrids Quarts per 50 ft. row — full stand — Cont. H &gt; Hiirh Hiith ( II II Staples H.v ■ Ic* Lon Enormou: Ned selfed Ned X Beder Wood Ned X Ounlap Ned X Staples- Ned X Win. Belt Parsons X Dunlar Parsons X Wm. Belt Sample X Staples.... Staples X Auk. Luther Splendid X Clyde Splendid X Glenmary Stevens X Beder Wood Stevens X Parsons. Stevens X Splendid Wm. Belt X Howard 17 Parsons X Clyde i i i T i 1) 1) 2) 1) 2) 3) 4) S) 1» 21 3) 4) 1) 2) S) 4) 5) 1) I) I) 3) 1) 1) 1) 1) It 1) 1) &gt;) 3) 4) 1) 2) i) 4) 1) 1) 2) 1) 1) 1) 1) II S) 1) 2) 1) 1) 4.20 I 25.M I 8.20 ! 17.76 | 32.47 4.1(1 25.96 2S.K | 4.S1 36.88 14.86 | 43.72 | 26.89 | 10.50 23.76 246.5 14.54 I 42.35 | 21.22 | 7.00 21.28 220.8 1347 84.77 8.81 43.72 9.11 21.M 14.11 14.85 | 42.85 I 21.46 7.00 23.91 248.1 8.97 | 64.20 I 27.83 10.00 27.75 ' 287.9 12.70 I 53.28 | 31.96 6.50 26.11 260.9 8.35 | 40.09 19.30 4.76 45.35 6.40 31.40 7.17 16.39 11.75 4.87 20.04 12.38 32.12 13.92 1.12 23.22 8.87 49.18 2.41 21.86 3.22 ! 58.74 2.41 I S9.B0 4.35 30.05 6.66 58.74 2.71 57.37 7.06 | 34.24 8.23 | 38.25 10.91 | 46.46 17.11 17.00 22.89 237.5 18.33 I 51.92 | 19.41 22.60 28.04 290.9 «.«« I 49.18 | 4.25 | 28.68 i 9.63 I 53.28 | 17.08 I 10.00 22.50 233.4 5.53 ! 42.S5 13.17 | 68.74 25.17 26.50 30.89 320.5 20.24 | 46.46 ■ 18.57 I 27.80 I 7.43 I 71.04 I 14.6* 10.00 25.78 258.4 5.12 19.11 | 2.71 5.43 15.02 1.16 | 46.46 11.86 4.60 15.99 166.0 6.04 I 25.96 4.97 | 27.30 4.20 I 23.22 I 1.01 | 82.78 I 9.83 ! 39.61 | 16.37 19.00 20.95 217.3 7.06 I 31.43 I 4.10 I 49.18 I I I 1 i I I </seg>
            <seg id="p010">1ft VfRBAQVA T^YPVWIVf CXIT T^ITT I PTTK 1 5iQ spring of 1922 the best 10 hybrids were planted in sufficient quantity to produce plants for a large number of cooperative tests in different parts of the state. This last selection was made not only upon the basis of past yields and notes on plant characteristics but also upon chemical and storage tests of the 36 kinds that were grown in 1920. The chemical test consisted in analyzing the fruit of the different sorts for moisture, total sugar, and acid content. This test was of no great importance as a means of determin - ing the best hybrids, because it was found that the differences were small. The storage test was made for the purpose of determining the "keeping" and "handling" qualities of the fruit. It was believed that the storage test would be an index to shipping qualities. Representative quantities of the different hybrids were harvested and stored in a refrigeration room that varied between 35 and 40° F. The berries were kept in storage for 8 days and then removed to a room with a temperature of 65 to 75° F. At the end of a 24-hour period notes were made K condition, color, flavor and condition of calyx. The 10 ds for further test are compared in these respects with Dunlap and Warfield in Table 3. Table 3. — Notes on fruit stared eight days Hybrid or varictj Condi- tion C..I... Flavor Condi- tion of cmlyx ' )unlap Varfleld tUel X Howard 17 (1) j Inormous X Dunlap....(5) :normous X Dunlap..(12) Snonnous X Dunlap..(16) loward 17 X Staples _(•) loward 17 X Staples ..(4) i llenmary X Stevens.... (1) ! •arsons X Clyde (2) ' 'arsons X Dunlap (3) I ttevens X Parsons (2) I Soft Firm Firm Firm Med. Med. Med. Good Med. Finn Good Med. Poor Good + Good Good -+■ Good Good Dark Good Good Good Good Firm Poor Fair Good — Poor Poor Poor Fair Good Good Fair Fair Good + Dry Med. dry Med. dry L&gt;ry Med. dry Green Med. dry Green Green Green Green Green </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Some New Hybrid Strawberries 11 Table 4. — Yield of selected hybrids compared with various varieties Average crate* No. of years Hybrid or variety per acre grown Bisd X Howard 17 Enormous X Dunlai* (ll L'M.II 2*2.6 (121 ..(1) 2S7.4 295.8 &lt; ilenmary X Stevens. 171.8 Howard 17 X Staples _.(!) WJ (4» 2M.t Parsons X Clyde. _&lt;2&gt; 287.5 1'ars.mi X Dunlai) (t) 2W.4 X Parsons. (2) 217.8 Alma 128.1 Aroma. _ _.| 14*5 August Luther _ — 1 1«.2 Beder Wood 24*.* Bisel 201.2 Br.ndywine ....- 188.« Kubarh 145.0 Buster _ sMJ 211.8 ardinal hallenge - - - 115.7 hesapeake. _._ MJ MM Climax 1W.5 Ml ommonweahh. M4 Dunlap 218.» ly Oiark _ _ 171.5 Enormous I 'J *.'(.!• Evening Star — S7.f Excelsior 1*4.4 Fendall 254.7 Handy - _ _ CO.* (ilenmary 3T.3 .8 3d Luck _ _ _ :. 121.2 Helen Davis. _ 17».» Heritage..... _ 181.S H iithland 1*2.5 Howard 17 _ 2«7.1 MM Klondike 17*J Longfellow 148.5 Longnetd. _ 72.1 Michel....- 7t.l Neff J'i:i.2 New Home H.I New York...._ 12».4 Parsons __ _ 218.2 Sample 148.1 Splendid. 1 I- &lt; Staple. t»7.« Stevens. _ 135.8 Stevens Early lM.t Texas. 148.* Thompson Ml.C Uncle Jim 88.1 Virginia. 20C2 Warfleid 188.1 Wm. Belt 1815 Yant 91 .( </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 189 12 Some of the hybrids gave very satisfactory yields, com - pared with named varieties (Table 4). The 10 hybrids gave an average yield over a period of 4 years of 266.8 crates per acre, while the 10 highest yielding varieties gave an average of 252.6 crates per acre. The same system of culture was used in all instances. Some of the varieties, however, were grown over a longer period than others. The average yields given for the variety trial are therefore not entirely compar - able on account of seasonal variations. The season at which a variety ripens is of some importance in Nebraska. Early varieties compete with the Missouri- Arkansas berries in the early part of June, at which time the price is usually lowest for the season. On the other hand, seasonal conditions are often unfavorable for late varieties. The ripening period of the 10 selected hybrids is compared with that of different varieties in the accompanying chart. It will be noted that 7 of the hybrids have approximately the same ripening period as Dunlap, while the other 3 are several days later. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Some New Hybrid Strawberries 13 HYBRID OR RIPENING FISEL . HOWARD 17 (I) &lt;0GM0US.DlHJkP-&lt;3l (12) (ISI l&amp;LENMAIiy.JTEVEHS (II |ttC**RDi 7. STAPLE (3) C&lt;H PARSON. CLYDE (21 PARSON.DUNLAP (31 STEVENS.WKR9OK (21 ALMO AROMA AUGUST LUTHER BEDER WOOD BISEL BRANDY WINE BUBACH BUSTER CARDINAL CHESAPEAKE CLARK CLIMAX CLYDE COMMONWEALTH DUNL.AP EARLY OZARK ENORMOUS EXCELSOIR FENDALL. GAKDY GOOD LUCK HtLEM DAVIS HERITAGE HIGHLAND HOWARD 17 JOE | I KLONDIKE LOKW1KLD MICHEL NErr NEW HOME NEW YORK PAR S ON'S sample: splendid STAPLES STEVENS STEVENS EARLY TEXAS THOMPSON UNCLE JIM VIRGINIA WAR TIE LD Wh. BELT YANT Chart showing ripening period of different variet les </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 189 t I I a I* m ■S S s s 41 I aa^ssagsssSSs « »T»»*uu! M -r -r Fi t S $ S 2 ~&gt; *- °&gt; » » t- =0 fh m •&lt; 5 —S3 " " ° " " ♦ ■"» « » H«»- HrtH p^ f— vH *-4 •1 t-MOM TM AX ac P «OI» XXOX X *&gt; — » us hc X5-. - :o NM» t- Oi t-^ u- - I ~ ! ' : I i— us n» S m ?SJ n £ I ■ I ! i ! &gt; Ml I ; ; t- a a e. o S ; ||XXXX X °O* i j^aii^ xxx I1 X |I1I1 Hi </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Some New Hybrid Strawberries 15 The value of a variety depends to some extent upon its ability to produce fruits of a desirable size thruout the season. In size of berry the hybrids average somewhat larger than Dunlap and Warfield, 2 of the standard varieties for the Middle West. Compared with average size of Warfield and Dunlap, the hybrid berries were 27 per cent larger at the first picking, 34 per cent in midseason (June 18), and 12 per cent at the last picking. This is shown in Table 5. These 10 promising hybrids are being tested at various points in Nebraska and other states. In the few tests al - ready made, other than those at the Experiment Station, the Enormous X Dunlap hybrids, particularly, have been superior to Dunlap. The 2 hybrids, Enormous X Dunlap 5 and 12, have shown unusual ability to withstand transplanting. This characteristic may often be an important factor in securing a satisfactory matted row under field conditions. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>