<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Sixteenth Biennial Report of the Commandant of the Nebraska Soldier's and Sailors' Home</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Sixteenth Biennial Report OF THE Commandant OF THE Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home BURKETT, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THIRL) BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME. BURKETT, NEBRASKA OFFICIAL STAFF J. F. Walsh Commandant Aodison Wait Adjutant C. R. Oeveb Physician Noah Hates Assistant Physician Makiloa Atwood Matron F. E. Walsh Head Farmer Alma Weed Engineer Alice Wait Bookkeeper W. N. Palmer Orderly </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 233 NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME, BURKETT, NEBRASKA To hi* Excellency, Honorable Keith Neville, Governor, and to the Honorable Members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institution*, Henry Gerdes, Silas A. Holcomb, and Eugene 0. May field. (!&lt; ntlcmcn: Introductory to our general review of operation for the past biennium, we have to say that conditions have not been favorable for the greater part of the period, in matters economic and natural. War conditions have brought a great advance in prices, thereby creating a deficiency. The weather, having been excessively dry, has curtailed our power to produce much of our needed sup - plies. The scarcity of labor and the high cost of same has been quite a handicap as compared with former years, but, notwithstanding, many improvements have been made. The new commissary and ice plant have been com - pleted, with refrigerating of the storage rooms that join the commissary. This itself is a great economy in prevent - ing spoilage, to say nothing of the saving in the distribu - tion of ice, which, during the warm season, amounts to about twelve dollars per day. The new commissary is a great improvement. It is sanitary, convenient and eco - nomical. The power house has been greatly improved and en - larged. A new roof has been put on, and the boilers have been re-set. A 150 horse-power engine and a new switch - board are improvements that will soon be in use, putting the plant in good shape for a long time to come. The new root house is a building with dimensions 30 by 80 by 12 feet, and is so arranged that about 2 and 2/3 times the area can be used for storage. This improvement, according to cost, is of more value than any other im - provement recently made. It is frost proof, and can be perfectly ventilated. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">234 THIKD BIENNIAL REPORT OF The library is a part of the Institution that is well patronized and enjoyed. Our State Library Commission has taken great interest in its welfare, and has seen to it that plenty of good books and current literature have been supplied. The Hospital of the Home has been well managed, and the patients well looked after by the different physicians who have had charge. The building, considering its age and use, is in fairly good sanitary condition. The death rate has not been above normal. The laundry is in good condition, up-to-date, and is adequate for the service needed. The new bake shop is certainly one of the best and most needed improvements made on the premises. The old bakery was a filthy, unsanitary hole, without any conven - iences worth mentioning. But now we have a good room, clean and wholesome, with a new electric oven, a new dough mixer, a new steel trough and metal bread raising closet and all other equipment necessary for an up-to-date bake shop. There have been a number of needed improvements made in the Administration building. New shower baths have been added to our wash-room, and the old unsanitary toilet arrangements have been removed. The room is now used solely for a toilet room. A new and up-to-date toilet has also been erected in the old jail room. This place was formerly used as a dumping ground. The new arrangement is, of course, a great improvement. Our old bakery has been entirely overhauled, having been re-floored, plastered and painted. This has been con - verted into a ward, accommodating 8 beds. The old brick walks that were on the north and east sides of the main building, were in bad repair and danger - ous for the old people. These have been replaced with good cement walks. The old frame shanties that were used as vestibules were out of repair and unsightly. They have been removed, and new brick vestibules erected. All walks that were in bad repair have been fixed, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 235 and new ones laid, where needed. The lawns have been kept mowed and the flower beds cultivated, so that the place has been fairly presentable. All other buildings have been cleaned up and put in fair shape. The garden has been an important factor in the wel - fare of the Home. We have produced a large part of our best living from our garden, especially were products abund - ant last year. This year was excessively dry, yet we raised an abundance of early vegetables. We have increased our garden acreage from about 4 to 18. The results of our farm and dairy industries will be fully covered in our statistical reports. We also beg to submit the following estimates as rec - ommendation for the biennium 1919 and 1920: for general maintenance; including groceries, flour, and fuel, $260,519, for freight, express, and transportation, $32,934, other maintenance and replacements, $3,850, and for general repairs, $8,500. The most important thing in the way of improvements that we have to recommend is a new hospital. At the present time this home is nearly full to the limit, with the membership of nearly six hundred, and in view of the consequences of the war just ended, and estimating the same at a minimum of 2% of the 40,000 troops from Nebraska becoming incapacitated, would mean a probable increase in membership of not less than 800, and therefore we urgently recommend this hospital. The rooms in this should not be less than 10 by 12 feet, with full toilet arrangement, except bath. In our opinion, this building should be built on land west of the present hospital. The old hospital could be used very nicely and profitably in bringing in the outside colony that was established by the legislature four years ago. This colony is the most expensive proposition in connection with the Home, and if the appropriation for the new hospital should be allowed, the act establishing the above-mentioned colony ought to be repealed. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">236 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF According to architects' estimates, the cost of erecting this hospital would be approximately $149,050. We further recommend the erection of two hollow tile silos, with a capacity of 200 tons each. We look upon this matter as a very profitable investment, as more feed can be gotten off the same ground and all of it saved by means of silos. With this farm of 640 acres, we believe that these silos are both necessary and profitable. It is believed that they can be built for about $1500. A commandant's residence, which would contain the offices, is further recommended. This should be of brick, and at a cost not to exceed $10,000. Every Soldiers' Home, that we know of in the United States, except Burkett, has this necessary convenience, which conduces to the peace of the place and the discipline therof. We also recommend the purchase of a parcel of land, situated on the southwest corner of the Home section, the same to be used for a cemetery. This is badly needed as the old cemetery is nearly full and this is the only high ground that is fit for the purpose. The cost of this land would be about $2800. We further recommend an extension to our green - house, which at present is inadequate for our purposes. We find it necessary to propagate thousands of early plants for the garden, and at present we have scarcely room enough for even the flowers and flowering plants, to set out on the grounds. We have no means of knowing exactly the cost of this expenditure, but name it at $1500. This is based upon a similar improvement at the State Penitentiary. We have covered the cost of two new stair-ways in our estimate for general repairs. The stair-ways on the south side of the main building are old and need replacing. If the improvements above suggested are provided for, the Home will be put in very good shape. Yours very truly, J. F. Walsh, Commandant. Burkett, Nebraska, November 30, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 237 STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS AND CREDITS OF THE MEMBERS' FUND December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918 Note — These are the personal funds of the Members of the Soldiers' and Sailors' Home held in trust by the institution for these Members and received and expended for their sole indi - vidual benefit. Approximate average number of accounts December 1 1916, to December 1, 1918, was 4. PERIOD Debits I Credit* Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1916, $0.00. December, 1916 January, 1917 February. 1917 March. 1917 April, 1917. May. 1917 . June. 1917 July, 1917... August. 1917 September, 1917 October. 1917 November, 1917 Total for year Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 191 Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1917, $ December, 1917 January, 1918 February, 1918 March, 1918... April, 1918. May. 1918. . June, 1918. . July, 1918... August. 1918 September, 1918 October. 1918 November, 1918 S 100.00 86.98 86.98 Total for year I 100.00 | 86.98 Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1918, J86.98 Grand total for two yean I 100.00 $ 86.98 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">238 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF RECEIPTS CREDITED TO INSTITUTION CASH FUND December 1, 1916, to December 1. 1918 AMOUNTS RECEIVED GENERAL SOURCES Totml Dec. 1, 1916 Dec. 1, 1917 Dec. 1, 1916 to I to Dec. 1, 1917 Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1. 1918 Bake oven (old) Burial expenses Cattle t 25.00 $ 25.00 40.00 40.00 3839.60 2763.00 6602.60 Co*l 16.75 192.02 208.77 Drugs 1.60 4.10 5.70 Dry roods 5.K5 5.6.-) Freight refund Groceries . . . . 4.99 11.24 283.50 465.43 4154.19 972.62 16.23 T4U1 lee 5126.81 33.02 33.02 18.52 76.75 95.27 Junk 30.68 56.15 86.83 Maintenance Meals 66.67 138.20 204.87 465.00 310.00 775.00 Meat fryings Miscellaneous Potatoes ... 242.53 ' 51.58 294.11 18.10 41.28 59.38 noo.oo 300.00 Premiums on vegetables Rents . 2.50 2.50 202.02 201.96 42.72 53.65 403.98 Tallow 96.S7 47.50 Tomatoes 47.50 29.10 Trunks (old) 29.10 Telephone and telegram refund .911 .90 Total S 9564.89 S 5643.63 $ 15208.52 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 239 NVENTORY OF LANDS, BUILDINGS, FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT AND IMPROVE - MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE Acre3 Acres Cultivated I ncultivated Total &gt; Esti- Acre- I mated Garden Farm Orchard Campus Waste age Value Land owned by institution 512 • 31 640 i $64000.00 ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF Bl'lLDING AND IMPROVEMENT Building Furniture Equipment Improvement Total Administration $ 110400.00 9408.00 $ 9600.00 $ 1X9408.00 2325.00 3000.00 47325.00 East hospital I brick I East hospital i frame East hospital i frame 42000.00 M00.00 1.000 mi 1020.00 24SO.OO 10000.00 845.00 3000.00 9845.00 (E. of E. brick hosp.i Cottage, N.E. frame hosp .too.oo 60.00 . . . I 360.00 (N. of E. brick hosp. West hospital IIOOOO.OO 4010.00 ; 10000.00 44010.00 Chapel 1700.00 450.00 300.00 2450.00 325.00 Store building Barber shop Engine room New Commissary 200.IH) 250.00 Itllll.lKI 38000.00 : | 48000.00 lOOIIII.IIO 1K000.00 300.00 ! I 18300.00 Laundry* and bake shop Carpenter shop HOOO.OO 7090.00 13090.00 50.00 300.00 Tool room Ml. (1(1 80.00 Farm cottage Morgue 20M.M 290.00 ! 83.00 ; 2373.00 10(1.00 5.00 130.00 Oil house Old cellar New cellar Green house Hose house 50.00 10.00 60.00 100.00 200.00 1011.00 2M0.M 2800.00 2000.00 25.00 125.00 2150.00 300.00 i 310.00 io.no Cottage No. 1 Cottage No. 2 Cottage No. 3 Cottage No. 5 Cottage No. 6 Cottage No. 7 Cottage No. 8 Cottage No. 9 Cottage No. 10 Machine shed ■illixuio 380.00 20.00 2600.00 20.00 20.00 840.00 800.00 10O0.0O 130.00 ; 20.00 1150.00 800.00 130.00 ! 20.00 , 950.00 800.00 130.00 20.00 950.00 800.00 130.00 i 20.00 i . , 950.00 ■IIMP.IM) 140.00 ! 20.00 I . 1060.00 MM1.00 130.00 I 20.00 i 950.00 MHI.IHI 130.00 ! 20.00 1050.00 100.00 200.00 100.00 New implement building Horse barn 2IKKI.IM) 1880.00 3880.00 2(101). 00 225.00 ! 2225.00 Coal house Cow barn 71X1.00 700.00 20011.00 500.00 2500.00 Cow barn No. 2 Hog shed 1900.00 100.00 2000.00 600.00 600.00 Slaughter house Dry goods store Calf shed 50.00 50.00 I 100.00 1000.00 55.00 ! 1055.00 600.00 600.00 Ground improvements 60.00 13281.00 960.00 14301.00 $ 19888.00 $ 91439.00 960.00 $ 370477.00 Totals $258190.00 November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">240 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF sss . 55S -1 -j B ijlf! M* i 3 3 : :? « I ii .» s ? *i 5 -8 II 2-S 2 jZ 1 1 555s 11 1 lllllalzz 1 111 C 5 I 3 oi--n « » — ■; ■; l- - c i: ?. ; i- « icon .rsssi ss s sssssssss § ssi •g 3!sJ22£ »« = asa«ca*ai » sea jri * aiiliiif ii i iiiiiaizz i Hi II SSS2 2? a SSS B §S2S5 - ggg Kef - - a ' -•«•••-- ' « ' a 2 ■ r? i.lSSSS g§ § ggggggggg g ggg g ■; o-Nt- — te » — x KifiN^a m i - — - I •? «•— — ©! — ** O 00— t- aiilj : * *}|| liiU ii i iiiiiaiaa i Hi] ; i ioieo- i- o i" — i-" — i-- — c — nt-N — CO »K -N KM j S j X N«5 NS is! g -^- i J hi'S 5 J]|9 " I* * .-n — - i — If! -tit ■pt.lSggg gg I SSSiSSSSS 8 gggig C X X X CJ — *O X — X X i.- M — X NKX ,- a ! i s 5 3 I 2 S S iiiiis ii i iiiiiai££ i iii! : &gt; o J ! 8222 -? S S2£ n 5S2SS " £33 jj — 7 _- - =~ if: -ji — — x II 00 M*O C400 * igggg §§ § §§g|ig§gi g ggg | § | « I-! -M HI *" ■_rl_J 1^ x ! : 1 8 5 1 I 3 1 1 ;ss i -00 ■ : :i - -O ■ ■■* ■ -^ 1.- ll 1 jlIi-iH^jlf jUliill i jIji I s 1 ihj i SSSg 28 § S2 88288 2 8£ ! z </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 241 ■5 ?! SSlJ •a ;; s 3*1 I - ii : . . ill ■ : :J : **|li U!j! M M i g Mi j j M i j ,|j| | il|i 1 i -1 1 1 HI 3 1 1 pig fljfl 2 ii£i £ j ii i i jj* = £ - j u : 5 i| | « "51= i 5 -a g | 3S| 2 i | 5 5§ : i 1 = X j t-" j 1 ■ L _ I — = 1 h i r ll ■ ■ .8 : : : : ! ■9 ! « ! S S2Sg g g 5g S S SSS S S g g 88 5 = 11 § SSS5 !!^£| 8=3 1 | 2 SI 2 | JtU s 'ii I ll s -sp s s -a 2 | 388 S| I 5 5S i J ! S " " ■ |__ | Uj S SiSS o § 3§ S S SSSg g 8 g g goig 8 || || gtics s s -a = g Sil| 5*25 ||j| - g| iTl — ; — r — : : — ~ ■ — -s -^ i 1 1 S 32*2 a 2 22 2 2 2222 X a a 2 ii\ ■ 1 II |1| » x lp i s "z Z § asai 2| | s 3s ; * I I *j ■«• — i ' S -.IS 8§SS § S "8 S S 8SSg S S g 8 S3 I S I I || | S2§£ 2 S 'S E | S|£| 18 3 5 |i I | I I i iUi £ i ii i i iiii £ £ - * j j j I ~ 1 | I 3 »ssa s a -a 5 5 2 SS | 5J i 5 s§| ; j je» •»« : :::■:• :8 i g = ll- — : . " : : '■ ' z s U I - : Ui I i \\ \ i :J :J : : ::| : 1 0" f. : i4i :g|2 IN : 2 \ 9* ■ 2 \ 5 £ \i :■ J Il!iiiiiliiiiiliiiijiJik*iiijir _1 VM 8 8 SSSS 8 3 3 S 3 2 2 it zi-&lt;u - « • • • •« • • _ -o ■ • _ : o § s si * — - Ifl </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 242 • *"" "3 SCO— wwt-tfi e "V I i C — '~ C C 21 Si n il3i§s!IiiS _ c «; © o to »a 4 ' lOM-rNN t- 5 «.- «M m I c §3§gg§2 II 5ISXSS2 h| « j es §"22 •5 BSt&gt;3*9 P 5B-1 * HIS 15 i~ S i ■ «« ISS§3 hi 1 « £i RMO &lt;* /■ S r. « 1 &lt;■■ fc b. I ai HP ! v * s ,»ii ;J ;liu ; ; ; 1 -?5 1 3 © OOP© . . ■ u ; m 1 ■* — -- — 21 s ssss x S « r P &gt; 1 I p s**gps ;s I §1 il!iPIrP!!l I 1 1 JliFi^ 81 I uooasacoa. | g uouhsxiooc. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS MS * I 3 I - s j z •I A 1 ML lilij : Ijiji ! I ! : s a -a : 3 S- : 3 U = S • 1 PI ft. : | h. : a ° : Id h : S| If L : i I ii s i •■ 3 g --- — § I Tig 3 Hir ! Jlll J i ■ i l la 1 % ; r »i &amp; i ] ; i ; 1 ; f i ! 1 I \ I 1 ii I Si | -if </seg>
            <seg id="p014">244 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF t- - I s i I 1 I | ; i I s I 1 I : I a : Si .« ! if 3 U ; a Si i | ! i i! 1 ] X i 2 5 i 3 j .15 I Hi i iii ! Ij&gt; 5 1 i'T 7 " ! ! * | : I. 1 ! 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OP COMMISSIONERS Ml 245 - t- § i s i 5 « 1 u. E 5 1 H &amp;\&amp;\a%\ : it ill liililiSJI f ag l flTiTT «J H!!!iS e i.j s;s Hili|i 5 li = 1-g i Sip If ||&gt;|&gt;| U * S -ak. Is!??!? is is 1 ?sig ll" &gt; |l sg| c 2 S §1 S H I I as . I ;"; ! ; U * 5 « I &gt; I 3 a §« |_ I •» i m yiijlt-i •• • I* IlLfloL * I • i ■ § S| ?:|S ■I g;M s l h\ "-I: iz ■ ■[ ■ *i| I Mil si I i a ■ • i » illiilN! E2 i I » I «&gt; " z \ • ■ i ■ "8-a i .8.8.8. S f jl I pi i I Ii|ilS-|: J , . I l s ■ • 2 I ;i3 1 3N 1 - 111 I"' s ■ i»i!S||«:: : ■ 2 " 1 2 [ x* I ill I s I; us z 5 BP ! </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Ml THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF _ on o I 1 ! j ■ a I— I- K jj 5! I 3 i5 B Oil I i|H 1 21 ; g|s» £ J li-lwol • a §| I "3 ! : feilj 5 I gg 2 jl« l|HJi |Z A | I ■ 4 III M ! ■*« oo I •* » i « iJ i i '•* ■= « T^ i i M - ||i| sa |; flM!P!l , h \u\9\\ I I s - 1 i '[ p [i i IPIiii'S : ! "" 1 2 I ■ &gt;, go o * SliMlI • -a I : : I J * s S u 15 b l u [ &gt; J J - = « I 3 |ee'«&lt;i i 3 S ! ll"li o- J |l Ji|jg=»SJ : . !*,!?:? :!« o ! | || := . |S 1! ! &gt;!=■: HI 18 . . .18 ,|S:t. : l| „ I 18888 § ii i iiiii I si i &gt; i &gt;&gt; = £S I i||=* -I : |g I I ' Mil lljj i 1 fr * : : :| B 1 88.88 I S «r Hi I s *"" I • Ig I I • ■e I IS 88 18 •js is ill § ! 38 I i. la x K I . •Q I is |» : : H iz- 8 I ' I • i i ! i I ! S8.8.8. 1 8 -1, 2 SSSSiS lib Hr I s .18818 Illil iffii j I 5Ec&gt; I 2 I iFffiw s ■c I IS §§ § h iiiii 1- . §§ § a- = 22 § i J It I {,, I 8V .OCX I ■ u IT j 1? o M:M|; : : : J w Six* I H mi </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 247 TABLE II ACE OF THOSE ADMITTED DURING BIENNIUM TABLE III -CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE I MOVEMENT Of F POPULATION MOVEMENT Present at beginning of period Admitted: For first time Readmitted Returned from furlough granted before commence- ment of period Totals Discharged: Honorably Died On furlough Totals Remaining at end of period Average number in home For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. I M. F. T. M. F. T. 253 210 463 256 233 489 253 210 463 60 30 80 43 24 67 93 54 147 8 3 11 4 3 7 12 6 18 54 55 109 56 44 100 110 99 20* 365 298 663 359 304 663 468 369 837 17 3 20 14 6 20 31 9 40 36 18 54 40 24 64 76 42 118 56 44 100 60 54 114 116 98 214 109 65 174 114 84 198 223 149 372 256 233 489 245 220 465 245 220 465 241 209 450 238 217 455 239 213 452 AGE For Year NoVSo, 1917 M. P. T. For Year , ending Total Nov. 30, for 1918 Biennium 11. P. T. u! W. T. 30 and under 40. 40 and under 50 . . 50 and under 60 60 and under 70 70 and under 80 80 and under 90 Over 90 1 1 1 .... 1 2 4 6 52 27 79 3 2 5 1 1 58 33 91 12 1 IX* 2 10 12 4 14 18 37 12 49 8* 39 128 5 3 8 8 6 IS I... 1 t ... t 47 27 74 10» 60 166 CIVIL STATUS For Year &gt; For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Mov. SO, tor 1917 1918 Biennium 11. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Siafk MinMd Widowed IS 10 26 13 ... IS 18 10 38 10 8 18 26 17 43 36 25 61 S3 15 48 8 10 18 41 25 66 58 33 91 47 27 74 1*5 60 165 ToUU </seg>
            <seg id="p018">248 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE IV NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE V -PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE ADMITTED NATIVITY Mebraaka ['nited States, other than Nebraska. . . Total native born fgsr-.:. ..:::::::.:.:::.:::::. SET :::::::::::::::::::::::: Norway Total foreign bora Totals For Year For Year ending endinf Total Not. SO, Nov. SO, . (or 1*17 1*18 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. i 1 2 S t 1 2 3 45' 28 7S 45 2« 71 90 M 144 46 SO 76 45 26 71 91 56 147 1 1 t 1 1 1 1 1 ... 1 1 I. .. &amp; I... X 7 ... 7 4 2 6 4 2 6 1. ... 2 2... 2 12 3 15 2 1 3 14 4 18 58 33 91 47 27 74 105 60 165 Carpenter Firmer Laborer P«inl»r Engineer Shoemaker. ... Blacksmith Teachers Salesman No occupation Houaewifo OCCUPATION For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. W, Nov. 30, for 1*17 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. I... . 2 ».. .. 3 5 6 ... 47... 47 IS. ... 18 68 65 «.... « 14 ... 14 20 20 1 ... 1 3 .... 3 4 .... 4 2.... 2 I.... 2 1.... 1 I.... 1 2.... 2 1.... 2 2.... 2 2.... 2 1 1 .... 1 1 1.... 1 1.... 1 2.... 2 1.... 1 «... . 3 . S3 SS . 26 26 59 59 ... 58 33 91 47 27 74 105 60 165 Totala . . </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 249 -E VI— COUNT FIT FROM WHICH ADMITTED DURING BIENNIUM I ! ] I Adams Antelope . . Boi Butt.- Butter Brawn Boon* Buffalo Cheyenne Cedar Cuminc CoUax Cherry Cass ClMtCT . ... Dakota Dodge Douglas Dawaon Deuel Fillmorf Furnas Franklin Frontier GarfMd Gate Gosper Greeley Hamilton Harlan Hayes Hiteheork Hall Howard Jefferson . . . Johnson Keith Knox Kearney Lincoln Lancaster Madison Merrick Nuckolls Nemaha Nance Otoe Pawnee « ■■;::::: PUtte Polk Richardson BE:::::::: Sherman Sioux Seward Seotts Bluff . Sheridan Thayer Thurston . Valley Wayne Webster Washington . York Totals COUNTY For Year For Year All ending ending Total Remaining Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for Nov. 30 &gt;»" 1918 Biennium 1918 M. F. T. | M. F. ~tT M. F. T. M. F. t7 55 10 224 77 14 8T15 j 4 1 5 3 3 6 1 .... 1 1.. 1 2 7 » 1 1 1 1 3 1 4 1 1 I... 1 4 1 5 213 112325617 1. ... 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 3 ■■ ... 4 g 7 1 1 2 1 1 2 5 2 7 1 1 2 1 112 3 4 3 7 I ' 1 ' 1 2 13 4*7 1 1145246729 1 1 . ... 1 1 3 I 4 1 1 I.... 1 6 2 8 6 4 10 5 3 8 11 7 18 26 21 47 314 314 628 639 1 1 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 4 2 6 3 2 6 1 I .... 1 1 4 2 6 I.... 2 2..-. 2 7 2 » 2 1 3 2 1 3 7 3 10 3 S « 1 1 6 1 2 3 3 1 4 4 3 7 4 2 6 1 1 2 1 1 2 3 3 2 i i... ..'.'..'.' i'.'.'.'.'"i'"i'"i'"i 8 9 17 5 4 9 13 13 26 26 18 44 1 1 2 I.... 2 3 1 4 6 3 9 1 1 2 2 . 2 3 1 4 6 3 8 2 2 4 2.... 2 I.... 2 2 1 S 5 2 7 4 1 6 I.... 2 I.... 2 9 5 14 3 2 5 4 2 6 7 4 11 6 4 10 2 » t 4 3 7 1 ... 1 1.... 12 2 4 1... 1 1.... 1 S 2 6 1 1 1 .... 1 2... t 4 2 « ».... » .... 1 1 3 1 4 4 » 1 1 1 .... 1 1 1 1 » 2 1 3 1... I 1.... 1 1 1 » 3 2 S I.... 2 2.... 2 2 1 3 1... 1 .... 1 1 1 1 2 1 6 « 2 1 S 1 1 3 1 4 3 2 5 2 1 3 1 1 2 1 1 2 2 2 4 2 3 5 1 ... 1 1... 1 4 2 • 4 1 S .!!!!"!! "V'i - "i"""t;;"'"i"Vi'"i 1 s 4 t. ... t 2.... 2 2 1 s 1.... 1 1.... 1 2 6 7 3 1 4 1 — 1 1 1 2 a • 1... 1 1... 1 6 2 7 1... 1 1 1 7 3 10 58 33 91 47 27 74 105 60 165 278 187 465 278 187 465 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VII NATURE OF SERVICE ON WHICH ADMISSION IS BASED TABLE VIII— STATE OF ENLISTMENT OF MEN AND WOMEN ADMITTED TABLE IX— AGE OF THOSE WHO DIED DURING BIENNIUM SERVICE For Year For Year ending ending Tola'. Nov. 30, Nov. SO. for 1917 1918 Biennium '.. War in which enlisted: Civil War Spanish American War M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 58 33 91 44 26 70! 102 59 161 3 1 4 3 14 Totals 58 33 91 47 27 74 lOfi 80 165 [I. Division of service: a. Volunteers b. Artillery Cavalry Engineers Infantry Musicians Navy 58 33 91 47 27 74 105 60 165 10 6 16 7 4 11 17 10 27 426 459 87 15 1 X I.... 1 42 25 67 32 18 50 74 43 117 3 S 3 » 2 ... 2 2. . 2 58 33 91 47 27 74 105 60 165 I 6 STATE For Year Nov. SO, 1917 M. F. T. For Year .nrting Nov. SO, 1918 M. F. T. Total for Biennium M. F. T. Connecticut Kansas Kentucky low* Illinois Indiana Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Missouri Nebraska New York New Hampshire Ohio Pennsylvania Wisconsin Virtinia r 1S 9 22 20 11 31 3 2 5 2 1 3 4 2 6 7 3 10 1 3 4 1... l" 1 1 2 1 1 6 2 8 7 9 16 2 2 4 3 3 si 4 2 2 6 3 9 1 1 7 2 9 3 1 4 4 5 9 1 .... 1 1 I 1 1 2 1 1 19 11 30 27 20 47 5 4 9 3 3 3 1 4 2 1 3 3 1 4 4 1 5 10 5 15 1 . 1 10 2 12 10 4 14 5 8 13 1 1 Total. . 58 SS 91 47 27 74 105 60 16S 50 and under 60 60 and under 70 .. 70 and under 80 .... 80 and under 90 . . . . Over 90 AGE For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium If. F. T. M. T. T. M. F. T. 1 1 .... 1 1 826 224 5 4 9 27 13 40 28 13 41 55 26 81 5 3 8 9 8 17 14 11 25 1.... 1 I.... 1 2 ... 2 36 18 54 40 24 64 76 42 118 Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 251 TABLE X— PERIOD OF RESIDENCE IN HOME OF THOSE WHO DIED DURING BIENNIUM PERIOD Leas than 6 months From 6 to 12 months From 1 to 2 yean From 2 to 5 years From 5 to 10 years From 10 to 15 years From 15 to 20 years Total For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 *■ r. t. i r 2 1 3 4 3 7 10 6 16 15 5 20' 3 3 6 1 1 For Year ending Total Nov. 30, for 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. 2 1 S 3 1 4 4 4 81 6 6 11 4 S 9l 8 8 16 8 5 1:1 18 11 29 16 7 23 31 12 43 4 2 6 7 5 12 2 2 3.8 I 36 18 '.I 40 24 641 76 42 118 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>