<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00024">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0024</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Cellar and Cold Storage of Sound and Mechanically Damaged Triumph Seed Potatoes</title>
               <date value="18??">December 1936</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Cellar and Gold Storage of Sound and Mechanically Damaged Triumph Seed Potatoes COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 88 H. O. Werner Department o£ Horticulture LINCOLN, NEBRASKA DECEMBER, 1936 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS 3 Miuuu.ir\ huri'.WLUi.n 6 Literature 111. St,.r.ii:&lt;- ..I S..UH.I i~il.ii.k-- . (i.n.r.,1 |,r,K.,lurf. , C.lmulic i.mililuin ilunnc sfnwini: -cjvins i"..mmu\l crll.ir .t"M&gt;:i w ciintmual tnUI storam- " i . 12 him "I pl.Kiiif; |i..t.il"&lt;- mlii culil -Muni' I line ,ii Mimiini.' |».(.Ki«- friuii oiU\ suitaix ''' W.irmini;-u|' |«it.llm- lh.il lv.l l«-n in cold %(.ira(;t -"' lj,lil stnr.isii- in l.iH .mil M'nni; wiili cellar storage .luring the winter .28 Cellar .mil ciilil &gt;'"r..ui "I vickul |»iunn&gt; •'" llk Sli.rjjiC- ..I Mccll.lllK.illl UlllMk-i'il I'ol.lMo '"" Riljlimi ol ti|«-» "I imuri m &gt;K&gt;r.i(tr l»«o Krfiil "I iA|«iMnji iin |'"I.ii.kn i" sumhiru Ix-fiirt nloricc W lll.ii nt in. ilukl »t NiiirJKi 1 HI"'" n" |«UliitN W Si.ir.i.L'i "I -i" -"'l |»"-H"'- i" tl" 1 la" 3J Literature Cirnl. Hi. author acknmvlcilno the assistance of John Pn\\iisil anil C'.i-ori;c Schmi.l in wciuhinß tubers. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">! j SUMMARY }• T'lc relative desirability of storing potatoes in the cellar or in cold storage during various periods was determined; by considering the loss of weight when potatoes were stored in crates and the field performance when such potatoes were planted. Storage of Sound Potatoes 2. Cold storage from harvest to planting time resulted in less weight loss and in a higher percentage of sound potatoes than did cellar storage. With late-June planting, emergence was 1 slightly slower from cold storage than from cellar-stored potatoes, but the stand of plants was much better and the total yield greater. The percentage of No. ]-size tubers was often slightly less.' •'¦ ' 3.:.The use of cold storage within a few weeks or immediately after harvesting, if continued until a week or two before planting time, generally resulted in increased weight losses, because of increased rotting, but did not appear to affect yields the following year, i . •¦'. j . . ;:: .-). Placing potatoes in cold storage about the time cellars began to warm up or about the lime buds began to i elongate into sprouts (during April) was the most desirable and economical of all methods used. With this method losses due to sprout growth and decay were not scfious, the percentage of sound tubers was almost as great as with longer cold storage, and yields were practically as high. S 5. Cold storage beginning in late May or early June was less desirable than earlier transference to cold storage but preferable to continual cellar storage, provided sprouting was not too far advanced. 6. When cold storage was begun in the fall it was found most desirable to continue it until early June. A. midscasonal change from cold to cellar storage resulted in accelerated weight losses, greater total weight losses, greater sprout growth, more decay, slower emergence, poorer stands, and slightly lower yields than when cold storage was prolonged to planting time. . .' ! ¦¦-'/¦ 7. A "warming up" period in the cellar of two or three weeks instead of five to seven (lays before planting increased the weight losses, sprout growth, and usually the amount of decay, and generally did not increase yields to a significant degree. tt. Cold storage in the spring was found to be more essential for potatoes that had been subjected to fall cold storage than for those that had had cellar storage in the fall. Cold storage in the spring only was practically as effective in the preservation of the potatoes, and the yields from these tubers were about the same as when cold storage began in mid-October. 9. Storage losses under various treatments were always greater with immature tubers than with sound, mature tubers. '&lt;¦'.. 10. Best stands and highest yields were generally secured from seed potatoes in which sprout growth was well initiated throughout the tuber. Potatoes that were solid ami almost completely dormant .always produced better stands and higher yields than did potatoes that were severely shriveled because of extensive loss of water and develop - ment of much sprout growth. ; ' . 11. Potatoes stored in sacks lost less weight during the fall and winter'but more in the spring than those stored in crates. There was less sprout growth and rot with crate storage than with sack storage. These differences were probably due to differ - ences in aeration; . ' ¦ . !' Storage of Damaged Potatoes ! 12. Weight losses were always greater with mechanically injured than: with sound potatoes stored under the same conditions. Under the best conditions the sound potatoes in June constituted 85 to 89 per cent of the October weight when whole potatoes were stored as compared with 56 to 68 per cent when tangcntially cut tubers were stored. 13.: With cut potatoes differences in weight loss generally were accounted for by the amount of rot which developed. - ¦.¦¦¦¦ ]¦). The losses in storage increased as the severity of the damage to the tubers increased. The severity could be said to increase as the area of the cut or damaged surface increased. . ¦ . : . ; . </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 15. Exposure of cut potatoes to sunshine increased the weight loss and amount of rot. The loss increased with the increase in the length of the exposure. Exposures to sunshine of lour to eight hours brought about almost complete destruction of the potatoes by |unc when cellar storage was used. 16. When cut surfaces were turned away from the sun, exposure resulted in more loss than when cut tubers were brought into the cellar at once but much less than when cut surfaces were toward the sun. The longer such cut tubers were exposed to the dr\ air. wind, and sun. the greater was the subsequent loss. 17. Least loss occurred when cut potatoes were brought into the cellar promptly. The higher the humidity of the cellar, the less was the weight loss and percentage of rot. IX. The use of cold storage any time before April 1 always resulted in increased weight less and rut. Freshly cut potatoes held in a cellar one week and then moved in cold storage Ins! less weight than when put into cold storage immediately after tutting or it held in cold storage for only the first week immediately after cutting. Practically complete disaster resulted when cut potatoes that had been exposed to four hours of sun were held in coltl storage till April 1 and were then transferred to the . cellar, whereas cellar storage until April 1 and cold storage after that gave satisfactory results but not much Utter than continual cellar storage. I'J. When potatoes were cut into seed-size pieces in early October, about half of the original weight remained .is sounil seed pieces by the middle of June. 21). Losses generally increased as the severity of the exposure increased, due cither to more time, brighter sunshine, less humidity, or more wind. The effect of the exposure temperature was less apparent within the range of the conditions experienced. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Cellar and Gold Storage of Sound and Mechan - ically Damaged Triumph Seed Potatoes •. i U.O. WERNER The specific storage problems confronting the potato growers of western Nebraska and other regions that grow the Triumph and similar varieties are somewhat as follows:. 1. To hold the tubers, which are commonly somewhat immature at digging time, with the minimum loss of weight until they are shipped. 2. To deliver potatoes that will grow promptly when planted by southern growers in January and February. 3. To hold the. potatoes intended for their own planting with a minimum of loss until the middle of June. . With the Triumph variety this brings up the problem of storing large quantities of mechanically damaged tubers that have been sorted out of the seed stock as sold, but which are intrinsically satisfactory for planting if still in sound condition at planting time. -.-.•:¦;'.'..¦'- ' .- .•.¦,;.,:¦- ¦¦'(' Fie. I.—Exterior view of potato cellar in which storage experiments were conducted. The customary method has been to store in cellars on the farm or along the trackside, but this frequently involves delays in getting the potatoes to the distant market, especially in very cold weather when the demand is often very great. To meet this situation large quantities of seed potatoes have been shipped to intermediate points for storage either in common or cold storage. In common storage, shrinkage is frequently excessive because of the higher temperatures. When potatoes have been placed in cold storage early in the fall, it has commonly been found necessary to again sort such shipments before sending them on to the south in midwinter, and at such times considerable quantities of rotting tubers have been removed. In lots moved out of cold storage without resorting, a more or less serious amount of rot has frequently developed before the potatoes were planted. ' . </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 LITERATURE 1 Some investigators dealing with the storage of potatoes contribute basic facts necessary for a more complete understanding of the principles involved or indicate the most desirable avenues of investigation^ approach Relatively high temperatures and high humidity have been found essential for rapid and complete healing of wounds (4) 2 which in turn have been found necessary if losses from rot-producing organisms are to be avoided (24) This can be accomplished by providing these storage conditions for the first week or two after harvest time. Such early storage is reported to have materially reduced weight losses throughout the remainder of the storage season (22). If wound healing has not been complete and storage temperatures have remained high, losses due to rot-producing organisms have been serious (21). , , The use of low temperatures, i.e., 32°-38° F., early in the storage of potato tubers, has been reported to cause serious damage to the buds in the eyes of the potatoes (IS). Prolonged storage at low temperatures has resulted in phys.ologica! breakdown (2i) and an increase in the amount of rot Reported but unpublished work by Bennett (5) indicates that as storage temperatures were lowered from 50° to 32° F the cells lost an increasingly greater percentage of their solutes when disks of tubers were soaked in' water. This process was greatly accelerated at temperatures below 40° F Tcmperalures in the vicinity of 40° F. seem to have been almost as effective in maintaining dormancy (JO) as lower temperatures that were otherwise more injurious. Appleman (2) reported that pro - longed storage at low temperature retarded sprout growth and decreased apical dormnance. In the Marble laboratories dormancy was maintained when potatoes were stored in six-foot bins at a temperature of 30 -35 F., but at 38°-tO ° F. sprouting occurred in February (18). Several investi - gators report less weight loss when potatoes were stored continually at relatively h.gh sloragc temperatures ( 45°-55° F.) than when stored at low temperatures (3V-40° F.), but there is not complete agreement on this point (I, 7, 8. 9, 10, 17, 21). It has been suggested that the greater weight loss of sound tubers stored at the lower temperatures is due to slower corking of the P^'derm (i) This seems plausible in view of the findings of Rhodes (20), that the chemical nature of the old skin of a potato is very different from that of new wound cork. However, as the latter becomes older the composition is more similar to that of old normal periderm. The general conclusion to be arrived at from numerous widely separated tests is that seed potatoes stored at 36°-40° F. are almost invariably more productive than those stored at 32°-35' F. (6. 10, 11, 16, 19, 23. 28). Higher storage temperatures, at least shortly before planting, are especial y important when the potatoes are planted in cold soil, as with the early crop, or when the seed tubers are relatively immature at harvest time. T,~,h „,,,„ cummehewite i!«&lt;» "I 'h' Income ha&gt; heen publuhcil clicwhcrc (27). . hX^lTmliTii p^Jhco refc, ... puhlicalion. ii..d &#132; .he hick of .his talktin. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Cellar- and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes A period of several weeks of warm storage was sufficient to bring about this result. . THE STORAGE OF SOUND POTATOES The object of these experiments was to determine with practically sound, whole potatoes the effect of cold storage during various portions of the storage period and continual cellar storage upon: (a) the weight losses during numerous intervals of storage period; (b) the condition 01 the potatoes at the end of the storage period in June; and (c) the relative seed value of the various lots of potatoes as determined by field experiments. Fie. 2.—^lnterior view of portion of potato cellar at Alliance, showing method of storing potatoes in crates. - - . . GENERAL PROCEDURE j A medium-season tuber-line strain of Triumph potatoes was used in these experiments. Weight records during and at the close of the storage periods were obtained for the) crops produced in. 1931, 1932, and 1933. Field tests of. potatoes stored; under various conditions were conducted during each of the six years from 1929 to 1934. AH. potatoes used were grown on dry land near Alliance. They were generally harvested the last few days of September or the first few days of October. These potatoes were representative of those dug at the be - ginning of the several potato-harvesting seasons and were consequently less mature than most of the potatoes that were stored during the seasons involved. Field-run potatoes, with damaged and rotting tubers thrown </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 out, were used in all except 1932 when, because of their great number, potatoes of less than l'/.-inch diameter were screened out. Field frost was never a factor in these tests. Potatoes were stored in slatted crates except where otherwise stated. During the first three years, 1928 to 1930, these crates were filled in the held and immediately loaded in a ventilated refrigerator car and within a tew days were shipped to Lincoln where they were placed in the respective storages within a week or ten days after having been dug. In the last three years, 1931 to 1933, when storage was at the Box Butte Experimental Farm, the potatoes were brought into the dirt-covered potato cellar (Fig. 1) between two and four hours after digging and were weighed into the various crates either the day they were dug or the following day. In order to avoid uneven distribution of potatoes, one crate for each treatment was rilled and then a second crate, etc. Prior to 1931 only two crates of potatoes were used for each treatment. In 1931 five crates with "50 pounds ot potatoes in each were used; in 1932, five crates with 60 pounds; and in 1933 again five crates of 50 pounds each. The crates were stacked in compact piles with all crates of one treatment in one vertical ¦lack (Fig. 2). At each weighing the position of the crates in the stack was reversed, as was also the position in the bin. In order to determine the extent of the Height loss in the different storages in different portions of the storage season, crates were weighed at shorter intervals in the early and late parts ol the season than in midwinter. During all years the cold-storage temperature averaged between 36° and 41) F. The average seasonal temperature in the Box Buttc cellar Morajji: was between 42' and 44° F. (Fig. 3). During the first four years no special effort was made to control humidity. During the last two years the humidity was increased in the cellar by sprinkling the dirt floor of the driveway and in the cold-storage room by suspending burlap sacks saturated with water. In cold storage the relative humidity was from 70 to SI) per cent during the first two weeks and then gradually increased to the neighborhood ol 90 per cent, around which it remained during the winter months with a slight drop in the spring of 1932-33. During the spring months of 1933 and 1934 the humidity was slightly higher in the cellar storage. A thermograph was always kept in operation in each stor - age to detect any variations in temperature, but the data presented for temperature and humidity are based on wet and dry bulb readings made twice daily with a sling psychrometer swung in the bin containing the crates ol potatoes. Because of the difference in humidity and the consequent difference in the amount of moisture absorbed by crates during the storage season, live empty crates were stored both in the cellar and in cold storage during the last two years. In both these years the weight of crates in cold storage increased considerably more than did those in the cellar. The net weight of tubers was determined by correcting the crate weights on the basis of ihe changes in the weight-; of these empty crates. The increases in weights </seg>
         <seg id="p009">"I Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes of crates in cold storage sometimes amounted to 10.5 per cent but generally were about 5 or 6 per cent. At the end of the storage season the actual weights of ;the crates were very close to the calculated correct weights except in a few cases where moisture had been absorbed from rotting tubers. However, in such instances the calculated weight generally appeared to be the more desirable one to use. Frequently a considerable amount of: moisture condensed on tubers and' crates when they were transferred from cold storage to the warmer cellar so that such lots may have registered a slight increase or at least not a decrease in weight for some days after the transfer was made. ; When potatoes were sorted in June, all sprouts were removed and sound tubers, sprouts, and all tubers showing any perceptible rot were weighed separately. Because some of the sprouts were produced on partly rotted tubers, it was not possible to calculate exactly the ratio of sprouts to sound tubers. . .' • . A statement as to the number and length of the sprouts does not present an adequate picture of the condition of the tubers as to sprout development. Because of this situation the following system was followed in establishing a "sprout index figure". o—No visible evidence of bud elongation. Tubers very sound. : I^-Slight evidence of bud elongation. Tubers very sound. 2—A few sprouts—-none over Vt inch long. Tubers very sound. 3—A fcw.sprouts— Yt to % inch long. Tubers sound, •i—A fciv 'sprouts but none over x/i inch -long. ¦ Tubers sound. ¦ s^-Most' : eyes with sprouts lA to lA inch long. Tubers slightly shriveled, fi—Most eyes with sprouts 'A to 1 inch long. Tubers slightly shriveled. 7—Most eyes with sprouts 1 to 2 inches long. Tubers slightly shriveled. H—Most, eyes with sprouts 2 to A inches long. Tubers considerably shriveled. ') —Most eyes with sprouts ¦i to 6 inches long. Tubers very much shriveled. 10—Must I eyes with sprouts 6to 8 inches long. Tubers very much shriveled. All field trials were conducted on dry land near Alliance in replicated plats which were generally planted after the middle of June. After the potatoes were sorted, the requisite quantity of potatoes was cut for planting the comparative trial plats. The. potatoes were generally cut three days to a week in advance of planting. During this intervening period they were held in small cloth sacks spread one layer deep in the cellar. The relatively high temperature and humidity were almost ideal for suberizatioh arid wound cork: formation (Fig. 3). , CLIMATIC CONDITIONS DURING GROWING SEASONS ] During the years of these experiments climatic conditions were favoi able for starting potato crops in two years, 1929 and 1932, when there was adequate soil moisture at planting time and for several weeks thereafter (Table 1). .Conditions were only fairly favorable.in 1931 and 1934 be - cause of a shortage of moisture soon after planting. The seasons of 1930 and 1933 were unfavorable for starting the crops because of dry surface soils. ¦ ¦!. '¦' ¦• . '.'.- "¦'. . ¦ .'¦¦:.'¦.¦¦. ..' ¦¦ ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 JjIMI!1!!IIIII!I(MIIII I I I I I I I I I I I I I I 1 LJoo m 1931-1932 to — ¦—•^~ - ""* " ¦ * * "*y^^[^ — w RELATIVE HUMIDITY &gt;S/ _ M — , fy| | jp STORAGE y^^ 4S - « COLO HORACE /-*-/ — *&gt; HuPVWMW v "*-^ *0 « - "»¦«» /**- M JS ,—--*¦*.— S*\./*~^ BELATIVE MyMiOiTv \ b 1 W-| V / —» * a A X / w *- W /v A / -»I 3*o- X^^y TEMHMTUB^^^J V J\^^^ I«3J-1934 __ 5S ~ y^^-~-*&lt;?~~^ RELATIVE fUM'OITY &gt;r "" W *s "N^^VZ-v y\ rEMPER*rufiE / -90 4-| lIIIIIIi I I I M i i ; : I ¦-; ¦&lt; i i!:II: ' I I II H &lt;o '. lA.^^,2aAn^^s.^.9.^a^a^ll^a^^3.c^^,^4.3,lQ^.^¦^ T Jl. 1.14.21.28.4.«.i^E6.2,9.«,23130 OCt NCW DEC JAN FES mab apoil MAy junE WEE* EHOiNC. Hid. v--Mc;in ttn)|)cr.uurc anil relative humidity in cellar and cold stor- Jile In u'ccklv iwrimfs ilurinj; the three storage seasons. Table I. — Summary of rainfall prior to and during each crop year oj field trials at Alliance. Crop year i " I ' ' " ~~ Time iormal j 1929 | 1930 1931 1932 1933 1934 Previoui Oci. 1 io Mj&gt; il 9/)4 H. 27 BJH 6.4\ \n.G7 5.03 luw 2.20 11.91 1.31 3.16 O.H 1.93 lull' IST 1.52 0.20 1.45 0.57 0.37 Auguit 1.15 2.98 1.90 3.71 4.12 1.09 Scp.tmtcr 3.2J 2.47 0.96 0.45 1.28 0.66 Toial lune-Scptember 8.15 7.90 4..17 9.77 6.11 4.05 Total for year 18.09 22.17 12.41 15.18 16.78 9.08 Summary' based on records of U. S. Weather Bureau Siation at Alliance for 1928, 1929, 1930 (through |une), and October to March (ot ill winter! until March, 1933. \\\ other can from Station at Box Buttc Experimental Farm. In so far as crop production was concerned the season of 1930 was excellent because of abundant subsoil moisture and fairly abundant and well distributed rainfall throughout most of the growing season. Yields were good in 1929 because of cool weather and abundant moisture in September. The crops of 1931 and 1932 were poor because of inadequate rainfall in July, August, and September (the August rainfall having been </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes of little value because of falling too rapidly and being accompanied by hail). The crogs of 1933 and 1934 were very poor because of dry soil at planting time combined with drouth conditions throughout the remainder of the season. ' ; CONTINUAL CELLAR STORAGE VS. CONTINUAL COLD STORAGE . The weight losses o£ cellar-stored potatoes were always very rapid immediately after harvesting—amounting to 1 to 3 per cent during the first day, 2 to 4 per cent by the third day, and 3 to 5 per cent by the seventh day (Tables I-HI). a After the seventh day the rate of weight loss was much less With the 1933 than with the other crops, that of 1932 con - tinuing to lose weight most rapidly. By December. 1 the weight loss was around 5 per cent in years of least loss and 9 per cent in years of greatest losses. The rate of loss continued at a slightly decreasing rate until the ¦¦¦'¦¦:¦ ' ¦'¦*'-.- ' ' ' ¦' •' ' - '. ¦' ' .1 5 TK'I .-;l ' I I 1,.- k II- I 111 111 Il\ 1 ": WEIGHT LOSSES 4 . V\. . ; POTATOES HELD IN . 5 - VCS .CONTINUAL COLD STORAGE AND - «s»-A&gt;^X V ,: CONTINUAL CELLAR STORAGE - g - V CHOPS 0F1932 AND 1933' • ' - ' ¦'h'M :.i iT: i i : i ;i •'¦'¦ i i \ r-1 IV To I Ib I Ib . I I I I 15^ I E I IU 20 OCTOKB NCKD/BtR DCCEMBO) JftNUAW FtBRUARr MARCH ' APRIL MAY JUNE ' ... .! OWES UPON WHCM TUBERS WERE WtiCHEO . ' Fio. 4.—Weight losses of potatoes held continually in cold storage and cellar at Alliance: Dl, cold storage; Dl 6, cellar storage in 1932-33; DIA and DI6A in 1933-34. In this and later figures broken lines indicate cold storage. early part of May. The cellar temperature generally started to rise above 40° F. about the middle of April, but weight losses were not greatly accelerated until after the middle of May, by which time sprout develop - ment was well under way, and total weight loss amounted to 95 per cent in years of least loss and 14, per cent in years of greatest loss. During the next month or five weeks, weight loss was very greatly accelerated t&gt;y loss of water through the rapidly growing sprouts and the rotting of tubers. By the end of the storage season (June 20-26) the weight losses Were ?Koman numcraU refer to tablcl in the rear that contain detailed weisht-lou recordi. I </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 between 16 and 18 per cent. The extensive sprout growth at this date amounted to 7.6 to 9.6 per cent of the original weight of tubers stored, and rotten or partly rotted tubers weighed an additional 0.9 to 4.5 per cent. The sound tubers suitable for seed in the spring of 1933 amounted to only 69.7 per cent of the weight stored the previous fall and 73.8 per cent in the spring of 1934, or a gross shrinkage of 30 to 26 per cent. The greater losses in 1932-33 were due to the small size of the tubers and to some damage (especially leathering, i.e., loss of outer "skin" or "pcriderm") to the tubers before storage in grading them to remove the potatoes below 11/,I 1/, inches in diameter. Because of this condition these potatoes continued to lose weight at a more rapid rate for a longer period in the tall and then in the spring a considerably higher percentage rotted. Potatoes placed into cold storage immediately after harvesting lost weight more slowly than those in cellar storage, although with the relatively mature tubers used in 1933 there was little difference in the losses in cellar and cold storage until after May 15; in fact, the weight losses were practically identical from April 1 to May 15, 1934. After May 15 [lie losses were accelerated a great deal with the cellar storage but only a little with cold storage. With the more immature and damaged tubers i&gt;i the Wl crop iVic cold storage lot continued to lose weight at almost ihe sanie rale throughout the entire season, there being no great flattening of the curve in midwinter. This, together with the very high percentage of rotten tubers (Table 2) and the shriveled appearance of the sound i,ilx-rs hi June (I'ijJ. '0. suggests that these were never adequately protected In cither or kith a normal or wound pcriderm. Later studies have revealed dun with continual cold storage wounds sulicri/.c but never develop a uomul perulerm. In cold storage- sprouts did not develop. Upon removal trom cold ¦toragc on |unc ID the buds in the eyes appeared to have changed very little il any since October. The sound tubers at planting time in fune amounted to between HO and H7 per cent of the fall weight. After being held in the cellar lor two weeks sprout growth was just commencing. TIME OF PLACING POTATOES INTO COLD STORAGE According to the results of some workers, freshly dug tubers may be seriously damaged by subjecting them to low temperatures. They report that the appearance of the tubers is damaged, the table quality is impaired, storage losses arc increased, and seed value is somewhat lowered (15, 16, 17, 22). They report that damage is more severe with immature than with mature tubers, a fact of importance to the high plains potato growers who raise Triumph potatoes that are frequently quite immature when harvested. Because of the high cost of fall cold storage, etc., it was deemed advisable to determine the effect of beginning the cold storage at various dale's. The rate of weight loss was definitely and promptly decreased when - ever a lot of potatoes was moved from the cellar to cold storage (Fig. 5, </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes 13 Table 2.—Effect of time o)'transferring potatoes \\ro in to cold' storagti-Upon total weight loss and-condition ¦ ' .. 'of tubers at the end of storage period. n-itr ii.in «[„ ' ' »i_..,, ¦ Wciklus in late June as percentages of Percentages of total weight when . ' Lot No. coM s«ra\"c rSc ""*""' °"°"" «'"'" &#132; ¦¦' sorted in late )u,,c Sprolll iMcx storage temperature humidity ;'~ 1~ I---- 1- - - : .1 I - when sorted Sound | Sprouts I Hot [ Total Sound J Sprouts ] . Rot - "'¦'¦ /'.«. I. 11. V.rl. I.cl. /'..«. I.cl. I. Cl. I.cl. '. SEASOS Or - 14.t1.3Z. (OUT OI- COM) STOKACiE lUSK 8; SORTED lUNE 2^ 1&gt; I Oct; 3 ' , ' m.9 2.2 ¦¦'. 0.3 89.-4 . 97.1 2.5 0 4 ft_ »•' ' - &lt;*!• "&gt; : H7.9 1.0 03 . «°.S 97.9 1.1 . 1-I G l&gt; « ¦ Nov. 1. Not recorik-il Tor all »7.7 0.5 0.6 KK.U 98.7 0.6 0 7 0 " ' April I- or the season 55..1 I.G 1.(1 . 87.9 ' -97 1 1811 04 - -'&gt;l3 May I' : «o.i 1.7 a&gt;.i 93.0 5.0 20 8 1)16 Cellar 72^ »3 23 83.2 87.1 10.1 2.» 10 SI-ASON OF 1932-33. (OUT O|- COI.I) STOKACiG |UNE 10; SORTED |UNE 2d) ' ' ¦V^ l&gt; 1 Ocl. 4 39.G 87.7 (n.O 0.0 7.4 87.-1 91.5 0.0 «5 2 .1)3- Oct. 15 - W.S .KM 77.H 1.4 :. 7.5 »(i.3 89.4 1.8 8.8 4 ¦ 1)8 Nov. 1 . -IO.H !¦.(,.•&gt; 79.1 . 1.9 5.5 86.5 91.5 22 0 3 5 1)9 April 1 41J .;... «0.1 .8(1.2 &#132;9 ¦ 3.4 85.5 93.8 2.2 410 6 I" 0 May I 411 86.1 79.0 2.4 3.5 85.5 93.0 2.8 4.2 7— 1)10 Celhr 43.6 M.I 69.7 7.6 4.5 81.8 55.2 9.3 ,5.5 -8 . SEASON OF 1W334. (OUT OK COLD STORAGE lUNE 10; SORTED lUNE 19) ¦'I . . 0.-t. 3 40.5 .85.9 . K6.9 0.0- 1.5 88.4. 98.3 0.0 ' 1.7 2 ¦ »3 Oct. 15 40.8 85.5 C7J 0.0 2.0 89.3 97.8 0.0 2 2 2 1)8 Nov. I 40.9 85.6' 87.7 0.0 1.8 89.5 98.0 0 0 2 0 3 I&gt; 9 April. 1 41.5 82.3 88.2 0J . 1.0 89.4 98.6 0 3 11 4+ nlO May 15 42.S 82.0 83.7 4.5 0.7 88.9 94.2 5:1 ol 7 7+ 1)16 Cellar 44.3 80.9 J^li 9J&gt; 0.9 84.3 87.5 11.4 1.1 10 </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 Table I-II1). Ten or twelve days after harvest the weight loss was con - siderably greater in the cellar than in cold storage (D 3 or 16 and D])\ As the storage season advanced, the immediate cold-storage lot lost more weight than the one brought in after ten days of cellar storage. Conse - quently by late winter the storage losses of the latter were less than when potatoes were put in cold storage at once. When cold storage was delayed |H : ;i i i nil. * (.\ WEIGHT LOSS | V - POTATOES PLACED IN COLD STORAGE - £ « ON DIFFERENT DATES c * STORAGE SEASON OT 1932-1933 o I i ' • ". . /-Ol v - *^ i ~~~~~ ¦' —.r^~^-^-.f """--&lt; i Di 6&gt; \ - *I lo • ; i i i i ih' &lt;^ii S i 15 i i i i 5 i —is 1 ,b jo 2&lt; octteeß NovtMBCR xcembcb janu«?y February march april may june DATES UPON WMJCM TUBERS WERE WGHEO Fu.. t. —Krtici of placin)! potatoes in cold storage on difTercnt dates upon the loss of wdght, m 1932-33, when harvested on October 4. Lots were placed into cold Morale .is follows: 1)1, Oct. -I: 03, Oct. 15; DB. Oct. 31; D 9, Apr. 1; DlO, May 1. All lots transferred back to cellar on June 10. Lot Dl 6 was in tiic cellar continually. i until the end of four weeks (when cold storage was only 2 to 3 degrees lower than cellar storage), the weight losses continued to be greater than when potatoes were moved at the end of ten or twelve days, but by spring the loss was sometimes less than with continual cold storage (D 8). By moving potatoes from the cellar to cold storage on April 1 (D 9) the great acceleration in loss of weight occurring in the spring with con - tinual cellar storage was avoided and final weight loss was only 1.1 to 1.9 per cent greater than with continual cold storage. The percentage of sound tubers in \ate June was essentially the same as when cold storage was used in the fall, the percentage of loss due to rot was generally less, and sprout growth was slightly and desirably more advanced. By delaying cold storage until May 1 or May 15 (D 10) total weight loss was checked almost as much as with April 1 transfer but the net * Parenthetical letters and number! refer to sforapc rrcjrmrnrs. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes 15 percentage of sound potatoes was less, because of the mote advanced sprout development and slightly more rotting (Fig. 6, Table 2). On the basis of net .-.-_ j growth at planting time, ' BB''*%^BK^lifl all cold-storage treatments [J2l S^Bgß were superior to cellar stor- D3^^^' ¦..-¦'i^SWSajH age hut the gains, if any, * fl B&lt;. jflßl '*¦ Bl H by the use of cold storage . ':'^B^'^B''^:vß^9 Hi prior to April I were too "•-¦ ' tice. Cold storage as late as . rJtlK^&lt;m^ Bt^flß^i May 15, while preferable to ¦ ¦ B'l ¦ cellar storage, was less de- |si|^R ?¥^^B ' '; i^H plats the .emergence of -B BY |IhV'' JhVA JBk^' placed in cokl storage at :^^r ?P^: 1 early dates was not greatly by r f-'-'-^-:'&gt;^^^&lt; ¦¦¦-;--¦ -'¦¦,;•¦'¦•-¦'^fci-'' influenced if they were re- P s?t-;'. Av : 'v J^Ht: &gt; '^H^,*aVA moved from cold storage 'i^M V^P'V V^B two or more weeks before JSK^^r^t^Bi &gt;r^ ::-3Mt planting time (Table 3). .tUt&amp;MKt^\^^^*:--i4&amp;i£i&amp;Wi&amp; However, sometimes plants ¦¦A^'fl B'' 1' emerged more slowly from Ipfll'^l Bkl l: i tubers placed in cold stor- t^tff^ J- BW age in May' or early June jT^^.v.'" ' x than from those placed in Cold Storage at an earlier Fu;. 6.—-Sprout development June 26, 1933, date. When cold storage on tubers placed iii cold storage on different . , ¦ ... " . dates and transferred to cellar on June 10. was prolonged until )USt a Lots as arranged from top to bottom were few days before planting, placed in cold storage as follows: Dl, Oct. emergence was- slightly *¦&lt; D3&gt; Ort- 15: DS- Oct. 31; D 9, Apr. 1; slower with early or longer Dl°: % '• Ut DI6 was in the cellar , ¦.'.,¦' , &#132; continually. than with late or short cold storage. Emergence was much delayed when potatoes were put in cold storage as late as June 1 to 4. It was generally slower after continual cellar than after spring cold storage. The final stands of plants were improved by using cold storage on or before May jl to 15 and were best of all when cold storage was used on or before April 1. The use of cold storage directly after digging did not seem detrimental to stands. Lots held in continual cellar storage produced poorer stands than all lots placed in cold storage except those transferred in early June, which definitely produced the poorest of all stands. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 i 16 T^^M penance o, see* potass ,to «-, pW « &lt;W &lt;«K&lt;-» g--jW. Time Mn..&gt;C| ''»j ( : „„„ Ilcm , Mean &gt;'iel&lt;l I No. 1 ii« miocold Mam. K|M | Ivn d i M«n ,lcm, ! Mr.n y.rUl No. I«« , cmrfKmK I o| |)lanl , | per plan, PC acre |*" V 1 '¦")- 5 ')K f.i 73.1 Oci. 1 &lt;L-» *"•' «, J22.7 ')»6 M ™ K \ \ M 300.6 96.4 April 1 IM Mj 5f 7 253.3 95.6 6.» «•? Cellar only __.— — </seg>
         <seg id="p017">I Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes 17 — — T ,— — ,——- •'..'.¦¦•' Table 3.—{Continued)::'" ' ¦¦ " . '¦'"¦ T.'. SEASON OF 1931-32. (HARVESTED OCTOBER 3: OUT OF COLD STORAGE |UNE 8 AND 23; PLANTED JUNE 26) So 1;. 1? ¦», ¦¦¦&amp;? :¦/,&amp; ".-,83 &amp;I '" "* / 6 April 1 23.1 98.5 4.60 . 57.3 31.4 ll'.j 95J 345 553 «¦» May 15 32.5 9-1.2 4,&lt;0 56.7 43^ 28.1 97.7 3.81 gfl# |,| Celtar only 26.9 93.3 4.62 54.3 34.4 26.9 93.3 4.62 54.3 34.4' ' SEASON OF 1932-33. (HARVESTED OCTOBER 4; OUT OF COLD STORAGE JUNE 10 AND 20- PLANTED IUNE 30) "~ ' (3-55)» . . ¦'..•¦ (3.55) ¦• .. Oct. 4 38.2 ' ' {iii&gt; ¦ ¦ . . ¦¦¦' oct. 15 46.7 :'¦...¦ ¦¦•¦.¦¦.: '.'.'. sic '" "¦¦¦ ¦•• ]J°ri'l 1 370 Crop failure; no yields rcccrilcd ••'•' ' Crop failure; no yield, recorded May 1 43:0 ;;;¦ ";I Cellar only ' 34.2 ' ....-¦ J7~ 7~" 3^2 ~~ T~~- ~" "~- ~~- ' ' SEASON OF 1933-34. (HARVESTED OCTOBER 3; OUT OF COI.D STOBAGE JUNE 10 AND 19- PLANTED JUNE 24) ' ' 0c,3 (' 9 T &lt;X?. "f, 5? 'IfP (4- 55 &gt; (4"55) («S) : (16-55) (8-55) April 1 44.6 : 77.8 3.12 20.4 29.7 2&lt;S4 •ict ?'« 10 i t'ci M»V '5 35.9 74J 3.02 20.0 29.8 36.4 78.2 3.22 Io.S .'|| j .- Cellar only 15J 58.9 3.41 15.9 28.3 15.2 58.9 3.41 15.9 1 Represents, as percentages of seed pieces, plants emerging two weeks after planting. ~~ '~.""^ ~ k ¦'' '. ' "Kiimber of plats and number of plants per plat. This system is followed in other similar tables. , </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. sta. Research Bulletin 88 18 There was a general tendency for the number of stems per seed piece to increase as cellar storage was prolonged, /&gt;., when the transfer to cold storage was delayed. Frequently there was a slightly smaller number of stems with continual cellar storage than when the transfer was made in the spring. Total yields produced by seed potatoes placed in cold storage as late as April 1 or even May 15 were practically as great as those from potatoes transferred to cold storage in the fall. The cold-storage lots almost always yielded more than lots continuously in cellar storage. Lots shifted to cold storage as late as June 1 to 4 and left there until a few days before planting in late June generally yielded least of all. The use of cold storage at any period did not seem to have caused any difference in percentage of No. 1 tubers in the succeeding crop. TIME INTO COLD STORAGE AVERACE OF THREE SEASONS-ALL LOTS HARVESTED OCTOBER 2—3 LOT METHOD OF STORAGE IwEIGMT ON JUNE 20 AS PER CENT OF OCT. Wl NO 1 "' I ¦ ' . 0.7- x ,3.1 " DI | INTO COLD STORAGE OCT. 3 HHHH^HT22Z^^^HI!HHfIO£Suj&amp; II ' ' D 3' INTO COLD STORAGE OCT 10 ||^| HHE^H^ I | 0.8-./-2.6 ; D«' into colo storage nov i j^HHUBZiiZI^^^^HHHEIIiSI DS INTO COLD STORAGE APRIL I t^^^HHKl^^l^Hl^HßK^lj^ 010 INTO COLD STORAGE MAT 15 Jl^HHEbbU^^^^^^^ESl!!^ OK 1 CELLAR CONTINUOUSLY 88888 ' I'M ' " 20 40 60 80 HSOUND | ISPROUTS |^%|ROT jgggJWT.LOST I--,,, 7 Hrtcci ni placinn pmatiics in cold storage on different dates expressed as .i (hrcr-yrar awMtic .if the percentages that sound tubers, sprouts, and rotted tubers at iilanriut: time- in )unt- were of the original weights put into storage, as well .is ilw ivrcrnUiK "f wcishl that was lost. When considering weight loss in storage, percentage of sound tubers and degree of sprout development at planting time, as well as stand of plants and yield of tubers harvested in comparative trials, it seems that (a) the use of cold storage within a few weeks or immediately after harvest generally caused increased losses by rotting but was not detrimental to yields the following year; (b) the use of cold storage beginning about the time storage cellars start to warm up in the spring, /.e., April or early May, was the most desirable and economical procedure; (c) cold storage starting at any time except after sprout growth was well advanced (early June) was preferable to continual cellar storage. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes TIME OF REMOVING POTATOES FROM COLD STORAGE Some potato growers have made considerable effort to get potatoes into cold storage or to lower the cellar temperature very quickly, after harvest - ing, for the purpose of preventing water loss, which takes place more rapidly at the higher temperatures. One group of tests was outlined to determine the merits of such early cold storage and to determine the con - sequences of transferring potatoes from the cold.storage to cellar storage at various intervals throughout the winter. In view of some of the recently developed facts concerning the value of high temperatures (55° to 75" F.) for wound healing and the detrimental effect of low temperatures upon newly harvested tubers, all the potatoes of this phase were held in the cellar for seven days in 1931, eleven days in 1932, and twelve days in 1933 before transferring them to cold storage. The difference between the cellar and cold storage temperature was greater in October, 1932, than in 1933. "W lii i. i r i;ii i l ii ii. ' ' I EFFECT OF TIME OF REMOVAL FROM COLD STORAGE. I : V UPON TOTAL WEIGHT LOSS : - * .. \\ . . . . SEASON 1932-1933 &gt;.. ¦ ¦ • . 5* I \\l ALL LOTS IN CELLAR FIRST 10 DAYS Z -&gt; \ 'x » • • - ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ - £¦¦ ¦" \ "%.^ '¦¦¦' .:'-; ¦ ¦¦¦ '. ' ¦¦.¦'.•¦¦ I Up, I I 111 I I 111 111 ff ¦-.•;" D»TES UPON WHICH TUBERS WERE WEIGHED ' ' Fie. B.—Effect of removing potatoes from cold storage on different dates upon the loss of weight in 1932-33. All lots in the cellar from Oct. •) till Oct. 15, when transferred to cold storage, from which they were removed as follows: D 2, func 20: D 3, June 10: D 5, Apr. I; Dl 3, Dec. 1. Lot Dl 6 was in the cellar continually. - . ', ¦'¦ The rate of weight loss decreased promptly when potatoes were moved from the cellar to cold storage in October and then increased when potatoes were transferred back to the cellar on different dates (Fig. 8). The weight loss of the lot removed on December 1 (Dl 3) became greater than that of the lot continuously in the cellar (Dl 6). By April or May of 1933 and </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 1934 the total loss exceeded ' PI6 ""» ""'MI %," that of the continually eel- |Jj " % 'fsgSswl. lar-stored lot (Tables I, 11, B^ HI). This greater loss from I ¦ :'i^^Pf| ¦ these lots removed from ;IBV( lldK cold storage on December H^-'ijk " % I was due to a great in- TjlKr^^ •• ¦'¦-'-¦^mZjjjg^^^''^ crease in the percentage of i's23taJP*tff i^^^^l^JjSfcjfc* ;?.'i rotted potatoes (Table 4, fICT^^W V^£tf i^JßT^' Fig. 10). Sprout growth by .^^B _J spring was much the same liSßiii-ii-SlL'.^T^^B^f ••'•^^Hii (Fig. 9) as with continual ""¦£:".' ¦;-" '-.'. iirV~ '^jß^fc!^!^^^?'"' cellar storage but the per- ;Q5 TT ""~^^^^^~"^^&gt;^~ r' centage of sound potatoes .; . ¦«•¦ S^Hk' • ' '/ was less. •' v'vHJBBs^B Bfc'^Kl When removal from , : vß^jl^.\^^V^9 i^^^^p' ¦ cold storage was delayed J^^BP^. June (D 5, D 4, D 3), the JM^ ¦ rate of loss was accelerated, -, J I'A ft but the percentage of sound "''• B«i'' '^^Br'^^^^ potatoes at planting time ' " T^^|v-=-H,^W^V^^^-.'; increased as removal to the ni--:^^^'~ ¦"¦ "'"" ''"' •:: "-"t¦'•¦¦"•¦'¦¦"-•;¦-¦ .¦.•:¦. - cellar was delayed. All lots flB In cold storage except the ¦¦^¦¦''¦l H,: one removed December 1 '^^^L'.J^T': ¦^Kf'' had a higher percentage of ' ¦'"-'' '¦¦^^&gt;-^'--^j^: ''¦-'l":^-; ':' sound potatoes than those D 2 in the cellar continuously. :-^^P! - This increase in weight of . ¦¦¦„ ¦r-'-$-'&amp;??!~:!''-.:^?^W-'^ . sound tubers by prolonging cold storage was due to a lv- ''~Sprout ll&lt;:™lopnicnt June 26, 1933, on corresponding decrease in '?'"* [ cm'£?J fronJ cold stor?B c L on different sprout growth. The per- tinually. The other lots as arranged from top to centage of rot varied, but bottom were removed from cold storage as fol - was always very low with lmvs: Dl3&gt; Dcc- ': D 5. Apr. 1; D 4, May Ij the lot left in cold storage I)J' |unc I(); D 2' )unc 20 - -until June 20 or 23. The low temperature inhibited the growth of the rot-producing organisms. However, after several weeks at higher temperatures, as with lots removed to cellar on June 10 and May 15 (D 3, D 4), there was a considerable amount of rotting. From the standpoint of preservation of seed potatoes, cold storage be - ginning in the fall was undesirable unless it could be continued well into the month of June. However, it was less desirable than placing potatoes in cold storage as late as May 15 (DlO, Table 2). </seg>
         <seg id="p021">, Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes 21 Table 4— Effect of time of removing potatoes from cold ttoragejigoa total \ weight Joss andcondition of tubers at the .._..—-—¦•--¦ .......,.-..-¦-...-- '~ end of the storage season. . Dale. Kfr-tn Ktr-,n Weight in late June as percentage of original Percentage of total weight when L« N°- "uZ .ioSgc £&#132; October weigh, ,o,,ed in late )unc ¦"?« Horace temperature humidity | Sound .„!-Sprouu | Rot I Total .Sound | Sprouli | Rot . , SEASON OF 1931-32. (HARVESTED OCTOnER 3; INTO COLD STORAGE OCTOBER 10; SORTED )ONE 24) DI6 Cellar • . 72.4 . 8.5 2.3 83.2 87.0 10.2 2.8 10— DI3 Dec. 1 69.» 9.8 4J -83.9 83.2 11.7 5.1 10 D 5 April I Not recorded. for 75.7 8.7 1.4 85,8 88.2 10.2 l.fi 9+ 1)4 May 15 all of (casnn 82.2 4.7 0.6 87.5 84.0 5J 0.7 . 7— D 3 June 8 »7.9 1.0 0.9 89.8 ; 97.9 1.1 1.0 fi D 2 June 23 90.1 0.0 0.0 90.1 100.0 0.0 0,0 2 ~~~~~ SEASON OF 1932-33. (HARVESTED OCTOBER 4; INTO COLD STORAGE OCTOBER 15; SORTED JUNE 26) ~ Dl 6 Cellar 43.6 R6.1 69.7 7.6 4.5 81.8 85.2 9.3 5.5 8 DI3 Dec. I 42.7 . 87.1 63.7 5.7 11.3 80.7 78.9 7.1 14.0 10 D 5 April- 1 42.5 86.7 74.4 53 4.6 84.3 88.2 6.3 5.5 7 D 4 May 1 .41.6 84.0 74.7 4.5 4.8 84.0 88.9 5.4 5.7 5 D 3 June 10 40.3 87.4 77.4 1.4 7.5 86J 89.1 1.6 8.7 4+ D 2 June 20 38.9 87.4 81.1 0.0; 6.6 87.7 92.5 0.0 7.5 0 SEASON OF 1933-34. (HARVESTED OCTOBER 3; INTO COLD STORAGE OCTOBER 15; SORTED JUNE 19) Dl 6 Cellar- 44.3 86.9 73.8 9.6 0.9 843 87.6 11.4 1.0 10 Dl 3 Dec. 1 43.9 85.4 75.1 9.5 0.5 85.1 88.3 11 J O.S 10 D 5 April 1 43.6 85.5 77.0 7.5 0.9 85.4 90.1 8.8 1.1 9+ D 4 May 15 : 42.6 85.7 81.0 5.0 ¦ 1.8 87.8 92J 5.7 2.1 7 D 3 June 10 40.8 85.5 87J 0.0 2.0 89J 97.8 0.0 22 . 2 D 2 June 19 40.1 85.5 87.8 0.0 1.0 88.8 , 98J 0.0 1.1 1 </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 In the comparative field tests, emergence was quite generally most rapid with those lots that were removed from cold storage during the early part of June (Table 5). The tubers removed at this time had a Table I— Field performance of seed potatoes that were removed from cold storage on different dates. ~&lt; .^¦_-g.^si:ar ¦££ az_ SEASON OK 1928-29 .KnMH, &#132;,, ».. INTO M. S TOR«. f . OCT. V. SORTED ,V3NE 13; .¦LASTED JUNE 25) l&gt;lbl .»nl, 9+ 61.1 Ml « ]306 •^1 1 I i i s 1 ' - 9 , 3:» 302-3 '« I::;, ; :- -- '" _J!L__lL_ —¦ ' j - ';-;-;:;:ii r'";;&lt;^ li;NE Tro li 27) v,':,m' | g g || |t M.» " Nl" '" I - '* V 9O 52.7 (3.4 Mr &lt; '«.-r.1.-i ,'„% ,;,- , r , s 57.1 H-1 lull. &gt; J, . &#132;„ 274 «.ll f''-» ;,, vRVfSTH , ,„,., , V1(1 r , ,;r ;; 7 '"---- &gt;----¦- "',, „} i ii;i 54.3 34.4 Crllat &#132;.ly in - ;&gt;' ¦ ]» 55.7 39.5 Apr.l 1 r '- ' &#132;* '% 51.7 29.8 SUv H -' -"' ' i 422 53.H 21-S £» s '"- &amp; ss:" -"^ SFASO\ OF 1912 33 IIIAR VF S TF.,, OCT. &#132; INTO &lt;«,,, STORA,., .XT W. SOKTFU ,tSF. 26, H.ANTF.D (ONE 30) [3-55) 1 CIU, onl, » '« Brc. I '2 j T j Crop failure; Aptil I ¦ ; 8 ' 2 no yields recorded ?'¦"' 2in \ «-7 line 1» et /" lunr 20 I) _ w'6 :,;,,TFI, OCT. 3; ,STO COU, .^ - «™, ,USB *««-, ", S-. '&gt; i S ffi I Bl J JH 1 ji__ji_j^_ "'Xumhr-i in pircnlhnn refer ,0 number of pb.i ami plant, coimntd. </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes sprout index of 3 to 6, indicating that growth processes in the tuber had become very active but that none of the sprouts v/ete over one inch in length. Such sprout growth had not yet caused much tuber shriveling, and the rate of weight loss had just begun to increase as a result of the transfer to the.warmer temperature (Fig. 8). Little water or dry matter was lost from the tubers, because only a few of the sprouts and little of the weight was removed in preparing the seed potatoes for planting. When sprout growth was less advanced, as in the lots removed from cold storage only a few days before planting (index 0 to 2), emergence was slower than with any other treatment except an the year 1928-29, when it was most advanced. In that year the cold-storage temperature had been raised to 45° F. during the last three weeks and sprout growth that year war - ranted an index of 3. I TIME OUTOF COLD STORAGE AVERAGE OF THREE SEASONS-ALL LOTS HARVESTED OCTOBER 2-3 LOT "¦ ¦ " I N0 METHOD OF STORAGE WEIGHT ON JUNE 20 AS PER CENT OF OCT.WI ¦¦! ' ~: : I '¦¦. -1,. ¦ II 2-s&lt;; 1 Die CELLAR CONTINUOUSLY WBBBBHCISBHIMI^B Hi MESS) DI3 COLD STORAGE OCT. If-DEC. I (BBBHIIBJZiHBBHEIi&amp;jISJsJ 0 5 COLD STORAGE OCT. 15-APR. I jHHHBSZIBIHUHEiIkIS^I D 4 COLD STORAGE OCT. IS- MAY 15 IiHIHHEI3IIHiHIHIH£3!SISS&amp; D 3 cold storage oct.is-juneioHHBHS2IHIHIHHESEII '"•! •''¦ i" ¦ ¦ ¦ ' ¦ ¦ ''.'.' 1 ¦ ¦- - ¦ t3,S D 2 COLD STORAGE OCT. IS-JUNE 20 ¦ ¦RfiS] I ' ¦¦¦ : I i - i- i ¦¦ W ¦ 20 .40 . 60 80 H|SOUND FTrgsPROUTS Fio. 10.—Effect of removing potatoes from cold storage on different dates cx - - pressed as three-year averages of the percentages that sound tubers, sprouts, and rotted tubers at planting time in June were of the original weights put into storage, as well as the percentage of weight lost. There was a tendency for emergence of plants from lots removed before early June to be delayed in proportion to the earliness of the removal from cold storage. The plants from the continually cellar-stored tubers were among the slowest to emerge. The earlier the tubers were removed, the greater was the sprout index. The delayed emergence may have been due to the weakening of the seed pieces through loss of a large amount of water and dry matter or to the greatly inhibited development of the buds remaining after these large sprouts were removed prior to planting. In seasons with adverse moisture conditions at planting time, such as 1930 and 1931, itjwas especially advantageous to have sprouting under way, and even an excessive development of sprouts resulted in prompter emergence than a lack of sprout development. j </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. sta. Research Bulletin 88 Best stands were generally procured from those lots left in cold storage until into June, with early June removal being more desirable than removal later in June. There was a reduction in stand in the direction of 'early removal from cold storage. All indications are that when sprout growth is in the condition indicated by index factors i to 6, stands will be con - siderably better than when they range above or below that value. The number of stems produced per seed piece was generally greatest with those removed frotfi cold storage in April or early May, and then generally decreased as cold storage was prolonged. Tubers continually in cellar storage produced fewer stems than those in cold storage for part of the time but frequently more than those in cold storage until very late. Yield differences were not very great and few of them were significant. There was a tendency for yields from lots held in cold storage until June to be greater than from those removed earlier, and more definitely for yields from tubers stored only in the cellar to be less than those in cold storage. The higher yields were generally associated with the better stands. There did not seem to be any relation between date of removal from told storage and percentage of No. 1-size tubers. When cold storage was used in the fall, the best practice for preserving potatoes for late planting seemed to be to continue cold storage until early June because of: (a) less loss of weight; (b) sprout growth being at ideal stage; (c) earlier emergence; (d) better stands; (c) slightly higher yields. Continuance of cold storage in the spring until sprouting commenced in the cellar appeared preferable to continual cellar storage, but cold storage until December or March or April 1 (when sprout growth had not yet started) seemed lo be less desirable than cellar storage. This was because of the increased weight losses resulting from rot in addition to practically the same amount of sprout growth occurring with continual cellar storage. The most desirable ol these treatments did not give results superior to those secured by use of a short period of cold storage in the spring. It may have been equally as good a method as using cold storage&gt;rarting May 1 or 15, but was not as desirable as when cold storage was started April 1. WARMING UP POTATOES THAT HAD BEEN IN COLD STORAGE It has been shown that respiration is greatly accelerated when potatoes are moved from a low to a higher temperature (13) and when they are cut or bruised (1, 12, 14). This indicates that a rather abrupt increase in physiological activity occurs when potatoes are taken out of cold storage, cut, and then planted in warm soil. Because of this and also to give seed potatoes an opportunity to begin sprouting before planting time, some potatoes were removed to the cellar from cold storage on June 8 or 10, while others were left in until June 19 or 20. The additional ten days of cold storage always resulted in a higher percentage of sound tubers, less sprouting, and generally slightly less rotting by trie time the potatoes were prepared for planting (Table 6, Fig. </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes 25 Table 6.—Effect of a short and long "warming-up" period upontotal weight loss and condition of tubers at the end of the storage period when they had been placed in cold storage on different dates. „.,.,... Mean . Mean " . ¦ Percentage of total weight Percentage of original weight &#132; , Lot No. Pe"°orl, s c »°"s&lt; rSc &#132; When sorted &gt; late June when .or.cd in late June '""P- humidity Sound | Sprouts | Rot' | Total " Sound | Sprouts | Hot .. SEASON OF 1931-32. (HARVESTED OCTOBER 2; SORTED JUNE 24) . .-. . . D 3 Oct. 10 to |unc 8 ; 87.9 1.0 0.9 89.8 • 97.9 ].l 1.0 6 D 2 Oct. 10 to June 20 90.1 0.0 0.0 90.1 100.0 0.0 0.0 2 D 9 April 1 lo June 8 Not recorded 85.3 1.6 1.0 87.9 97.1 1.8 1.1 G+ . Dll April 1 to June 20 all of season 87.9 0.0 0.0 87.9 100.0 0.0 0.0 3 DlO May 15 to June 8 80.1 4.3 1.7 Sfi.l . 93.0 ¦ S.O 20 8 Dl 2 May 15 lo June 20 _..... . _ 85.0 0.9 . 0.8 86.7 98.1 : 1.0 . 0.9 ... 7. ; ; SEASON OF 1932-33. (HARVESTED OCTOBER 4; SORTED JUNE 26) D 3 Oct. 15 to June 10 40.3 87.4 77.4 . 1.4 7.5 86.3 89.1 1.6 8.7 4 D 2 O«. 15 to June 20 38.9 87.4 81.1 0.0 6.6 87.7 92.5 0.0 7.5 0 D 9 April 1 to June 10 41.3 R6.1 80J 15 3.4 85.5 93.8 2.2 4.0 6— Dll April 1 to June 20 40.0 86.fi 84.7 0.1 . 3.6 88.4 95.8 0.1 4.1 2 DIO May 1 to June 10 41.8 86.1 79.6 2.4 3.5 85.5 93.1 2.8 4.1 7— DI2 May 1 to June 20 40.5 86.1 79.8. 02 .6.1 86.1 92.7 0J ' 7.1 A ~~~ : SEASON OF 1933-34. (HARVESTED OCTOBER 3; SORTED JUNE 19) D 3 Ocr. 15 to June 10 . 40.8 85.5 873 0.0 2.0 89.3 97.8 0.0 22 2 D 2 Oct. 15 to June 19 40.1 85.5 87.8 0.0 1.0 88.8 98.9 0.0 1.1 1 D 9 April 1 to June 10 41.5 ; 82.3 88.2 0.2 1.0. 89.4 98.6 0.3 1.1 4 Dll April 1 to June 19 40.8 82.7 90.0 0.0 0.5 90.5 ... 99.5 ¦ 0.0 0.5 1 DIO May 15 to June 10 42.5 82.0 83.7 4.5 0.7 88.9 94.2 5.1 0.7 7+ Dl 2 May 15 to June 19 41.7 82.0 87.5 IS 0.7 893 97.8 1.4 0.8 4 </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 12). With storage continued to either date, the earlier cold storage began the greater was the percentage of. sound potatoes. -i With tubers put in cold storage May 15 there was Blf^a^^, "^¦Jhi 'jp ~~| few well-developed, thick blg^^&amp;^SJySl^^S^ sprouts about one-half an %W^^^Kpl]flH^^H| K^flfl^fe' inch long were scattered %fi^| B^^^B^W^^B^^HP:i over the tuber but they g*V-^j|^r' "*".. '^^^'.*. were seldom in an apical position and other sprouts Fig. 11, —Sprout growth on tubers in cold stor - had done little more than *&amp; until June 20&gt; &amp;« having been start to grow (Figs 6 9 Pbccd in coW sloraS= on April 1 (Dll, top 11). All of these treatments U"c) and. Ma£ ' &lt;? 12 ' bottom Unc&gt;- 7°. 1 &#132; , observe the effect of a warming-up period except cold storage trom of ln dayj upon sprout growthi compare May 15 to June 10 were these with D 9 and DID of Figure 6. adequate to restrain sprout - ing to the extent that it should be restrained for mid- or late-June planting. WARMING UP PERIOD IN JUNE AVERAGE OF THREE SEASONS-ALL LOTS HARVESTED OCTOBER 2-3 UETHOD OF STORAGE WEIGHT ON JUNE 20 AS PER CENT OF OCT.WT 03 COLO STORAGE OCT. li TO JUNE 6-10 D 2 COLD STORAGE OCT IS TO JUNE 20 JH^^H^EuH^HH^BSUI 1 . l.2M.»fe* DO COLO STORAGE APR I TO JUNE 0-&gt;Gli|iHHH^s!3]|^Hl^H^E£li^ D II COLD STORAGE APR I TO JUNE 20 ¦H^HH^EZ^^H^^HUKZIIS 0 10 COLD STORAGE MAY li TO JUNE S-'°HH^H^|[£il]HHlHHo£l!^!S D 12 COLD STORAGE MAY 15 TO JUNE jltl 0,7^ v 2.6 20 40 SO 80 »SOUND I JSPROUTS Fie;. 12.—hlTcct lit ;i 10-&lt;iay "warming up" period in the potato cellar after potatoes were hcltl in cold Nt&lt;)ragc for various periods of time. Emergence in trial plats was more rapid with early than with late removal (Table i). This difference was greatest with tubers placed in cold storage in October. With those placed in cold storage in May there was not a great deal of difference. Final stands of plants were perhaps slightly better with tubers in stor - age until the late-June date. However, when placed in storage in October, removal in early June commonly resulted in slightly better stands than removal in late June. </seg>
         <seg id="p027">j ' ¦ Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes The number o£ stems generally decreased with late removal. This was true in all years except 1930, when the lots removed late produced the most stems (Table 3). In 1930 sprouts were more advanced in these June 10 lots than in those removed later and when sprouts were broken off fewer plants developed from the remaining buds than in the case of tubers that had a greater number of dormant buds as a result o£ longer cold storage. Total yield was not influenced significantly in the poor years of 1932, 1933, or 1934. In 1929 late removal may have been a trifle superior. In 1930 early removal was definitely most desirable if tubers had been in cold storage since October or November but less desirable if cold storage had begun in March, April, or May. This is somewhat in line with the effect on stand. ;The slight yield differences in 1932 and 1934 were always in line with stand differences. • , , Table 7.j-Effect of early removal from cold storage upon yield from various tuber lines when planted on two dates at Alliance in 1931. ¦ . Tuber line number and 'type a* to season . I ¦ ; ; Mean of Storage condition 4 I 14 I 21 I 26 I 28 all linel : * . ! Early 1 Medium I Medium I Late | Very late JUNE 16 PLANTING Cellar ....;. ..:..... 126.6 155.2 119J 129.3 . 127.5 131.5 Cold storage April Ito June 6. 154.9 H9.1 H5.9 H3.5 124.1 143.5 Cold storage April lto June 11 125.4 152.1 146.9 134.3 123.1 136.4 |UNE 26 PLANTING Cellar. .......;........:. 99.1 106.7 -110.7 101.1 82.9 100.1 Cold storage April Ito June 6 140.8 . 134J 137.3 115.1 1023 128.0 Cold storage April Ito June 20 137.0 137.2 106.S 87.4 76.9 109.2 ' ' Plats averaged .1/10 acre each with early planting and 1/5 acre with late planting. In 1931 when more extensive plantings were made from five strains that were planted on two dates, after being removed from cold storage on two different dates, the yields were more frequently increased by cold storage than; they were decreased (Table 7). Greatest gains from cold storage occurred when the planting was late. Removal from cold storage ten days before planting generally resulted in a slight gain in yield with June 16 planting; it did result in a gain with four out of five when planted June 26, and the gains were much greater. Evidently a few days of prewarming are sufficient. When sprout growth was ivell advanced in June or had been activated before tubers were placed in cold storage, then prolonged cold storage was most desirable. The better stands with longer cold storage were evidently the result of less decay in seed pieces. This may account for some of the increase in stem numbers, for partly decayed seed pieces produced fewer stems than sound seed pieces. </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 COLD STORAGE IN FALL AND SPRING WITH CELLAR STORAGE DURING) THE WINTER When a period of cold storage was used from October to December (Dl 3), sound tubers in late June constituted a lower percentage of the original October weight than in the case of potatoes stored in the cellar continually (Dl 6). This was due mostly to more rotting (Table 8, Figs. 13 and 15). When some of these potatoes that had been in cold storage until December were again placed in cold storage from April to June 8 or 10 (Dl 5). the percentage of sound tubers in June was increased but was not as great as with lots that had been in cold storage continually 0 \ ; ; ; ;. i m iii j \&gt; EFFECT OF FALL AND SPRING COLD STORAGE - S V UPON WEIGHT LOSS | V N STORAGE SEASON OF 1932-1933 3 b \""v ¦ ? D^^t;-^.. &gt;. i 013—&gt;SVDI5V i \ - j an ' ' ' ' I ¦ V ocroar» 'ncvrußcn oca»Bii&gt;"jANuim rcßavsx march imiif i«v '5 jutic w?° wn upon v/hch njBEBS wtor aCighed '"" 13in7i K'! CCt "' 'a" an SPri"S Per''KlS "' COIII StOraßC UP°" tllc IOSS of WC'Sht in 1J323J. I^t 1)16 w.is in cellar continually, whereas other lots were in cold storage as follow: Dl 3. Oct. 15 to Dec. I; Dl 5, Oct. 15 to Dec. 1 and Apr 1 to June 10; DO. Apr. 1 to [unc 10; D 3, Oct. 15 to June 10. from October to )unc (DJ) or even as great as those in cold storage from only April to June 8 or 10 (D 9). Although there was much variation from year to year the data seem to indicate that the percentage of rot was lowest with cold storage starting either April 1 (D 9) or May 1 or 15 (D 10), next lowest with continual cellar storage (Dl 6), then continual cold stor - age (D 3), next when spring cold storage of tubers had been preceded by cold storage during the fall (Dl 4 and Dl 5), and greatest o£ all when fall cold storage was followed by winter and spring cellar storage (Dl 3). Wiih cellar storage following fall cold storage the rate of weight loss was much more rapid than when potatoes were in the cellar continuously </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes (Dl 3, Fig. 13). This ac- . T?&amp;f+^m?*&amp;Wi-iYv^%^&amp;W!iW celerated rate continued | ;.f3fe^^ i^^ ' ?S&gt; ' 'V**' ' throughout the spring. It \-sBM^t^^mf . "•'^m^^^t^': - was checked by cold stor- jl V'^fl ¦ A B ' age in April or May (Dl 5, f:»v'':^B V ' Dl 4) but not sufficiently * -'¦^^^ I^^ 11 to prevent greater weight -^-jj —....... &#132;. 7 : ',:&gt;:¦. , ¦¦• •'¦¦ losses than when cold stor- 'd&amp;^'-'j- , J^t::'i::^t£\%\ .mi*..' age was used only in the ajj^B. ''''^^^L'^^lL^jflh^ ¦' spring (D 9, DIO). 'll'fl H Ultl The amount of sprout vff^BßßtffiM Br;&gt;i growth was generally in ).....:...'..^ir^^^HßHl^^BHHi^ii^J direct proportion to the I 01^ ~ \ , _. spring cold storage, there was more soroiit erowth FIG- 14-~Sptout dcvl:lo Pment June 26- 1933, was more sprout growm on wben rf .. n cold st than when cold storage was 0^ 15 [o Dec , and May , |0 June 10 . used only in the spring Dl 5, Oct. 15 to Dec. 1 and April 1 to (Figs. 14 and 15). June 10; and D 6, Nov. 15 to April 1. Lots put in cold storage (Number on lower line should be D 6, on May 1 or 15 had more not Dlfi^ FALL AND SPRING COLO STORAGE AVERAGE Of THREE SEASONS-ALL LOTS HARVESTED OCTOBEH2-3 •jj&gt; T METHOD OF STORAGE WEIGHT ON JUNE 20 AS PER CENT Of OtT.WTj " " ' ' ~ . | ,1 - ¦ I I 1^2.4 I DI6 CELLAR CONTINUOUSLY PHIHHOESIIHHIHOZ^£9I Dl 3 COLO STORAGE OCT. 1} - DEC. I |HH^BESIiBIIHBMiSS3] ' ¦ ¦ ¦ | ¦ 1.3t I DIS C.S.:OCT.IS-DEC.I; APR.I-JUNEKJ^BHBBSIHUiHHESiSS D 9 COLD STORACE APR. I- JUNE 10 HHIHHZISHHHHHHHEISj ¦.. " . .]- -.iii, —.I J 0 14 C.S.OCT. 15-DEC.I; MAYIS-JUt£IoHHHHEZs!HHHHIE£XS]I I 3.7-vt-a.O I o io cold 3TOBAOE may i5-juNE io ¦BBBHBuL3HHHBHIHiXiSI9 I¦¦'".¦¦.-. . I o.i-va.s I D 3 COLD STORACE OCT. 15 - JUNE 10 20 40 co ao . ¦¦-. ¦¦ ¦ , HBSOUND I •¦-¦. ISPROUTS V//AHOI Fio. 15.—Effect of fall'and spring cold storage expressed as three-year averages -. . of the' percentages that sound tubers, sprouts, and rotted tubers at planting . time in June were of the original weight put into storage as well as the per - ccntacc of weieht lost. : </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. sta. Research Bulletin 88 rot, more sprout growth, and fewer sound potatoes than those transferred April 1, but the tendencies were all in the same direction. When cold storage was available in the spring even as late as May 1 or 15, there was nothing gained by using it at an earlier date. Stands were better when cold storage was used in the spring months than when it was used only in the fall or not at all. Variations in storage before spring had little effect upon stand if co/d storage was used in the spring. Cold-storage lots had fewer stems per plant than cellar-stored lots, and the prolongation of time in cold storage may also have resulted in a decrease in stem numbers. Yields having been low, the differences were small and probably insignificant. Those from fall-cold-storage and con - tinual-cellar-slorage lots seemed to be least. When cold storage was used only in the spring, yields were as good as with cold storage in both fall and spring. Placing potatoes in cold storage on April 1 was as satisfactory as con - tinual cold storage, and cold storage beginning May 1 or 15 was almost as satisfactory. The use of a fall cold-storage period increased rotting and sometimes sprouting and was of no merit, especially if cold storage was not used again in the spring. J CELLAR AND COLD STORAGE OF SACKED POTATOES On October 9, 1933. 9S sacks of potatoes (100 pounds each), were placed in the cellar immediately when taken out of the field and 122 others were placed in cold storage. On October 19 (by which time cellar-stored tubers had lost 2J per cent of their weight and those in cold storage had" ( lost a trifle less) hall ol the sacks under each storage condition were shifted In the other condition (Table 9). By the early part of March the shipping season to southern seed markets is closed and the potatoes in cellars have not yet started to sprout. For that reason the various lots of potatoes were weighed, sorted, and treated (hot formaldehyde) and some were shifted to other storage conditions. After being treated with hot formaldehyde and drying, the potatoes of the different lots were found to have lost on an average between 0.6 and 0.7 I pounds per sack, except Lots 7 and 8, which lost 1.1 pounds net per sack. This loss was prohably due to the washing off of dirt. After being weighed, halt the sacks of each lot were placed under storage conditions other than that which they had been under. Between May 27 and June 1 all ( lots were again sorted and weighed. The potatoes that were in the cellar from October 9 to March (Lots 5 and 6) and those in cold storage all of this time (Lots 1 and 2) were never moved until removed for sorting and formaldehyde treatment in j March. In each case they were placed in the rear tiers in their respective j storages. I With cellar storage, weight losses had increased considerably by the last few days of May, due to more decay. Sprout growth was well under way but was not sufficiently advanced to involve much loss of material from the tubers. </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Table B.—Effect of a period of cold storage in the jail and spring upon total weight loss, condition of tubers at planting time, and ...' : ....-.: .;'..;¦ field performance. "•'".'"¦- — .-—-~ — --r - — . — I'erccntane. of orißinal weight IVrccntage of loial B*2 . Field performance . " Mean Mean -into storage in laic Julie weight when sorted *| t: : ¦ :— ¦ Tola) Lot No. Time in cold Horace "°™ W hrnnii'liT* I:~'' ' f ~ i \ Em««"« Final' Mean yield. PercemaEC ' . : !&gt;&lt;*¦?.: l:n. Sound | S.-.rout Rot Total Sound Sprout Rot £ji c ' c "° stand p £™* m *'"£" N' 0' ' '"' ¦';: SEASON OF 1931-32. (HARVESTED OCT. li SORTED JUNE 24. PLANTED JUNE 26) : Illii Cellar ' cnniincoiiily ... ... 72:4 8.5 2.3 83.2 87.1 10.1 2.8 10— 26.9 93.3 4.62 54.3 34.4 Dl 3 Oct. 10-Dcc. 1 .... . : . ... .... 69.8 9.8 4.3 83.9 83.2 11.7 5.1 10 30.7 933 4.44 55.7 39.5 Dl 5 Oci. 10-Dcc. 1, April I-Jtmc 8 '.:.-¦ . 79.4 1.7 fi.7 87.8 90.5 I.« 7.7 6- 23.4 97.7 3.82 58.3 42.8 l&gt;9 April 1-lune 8 . . 85.3 1.6 1.0 87.9 97.1 1.8 1.1 6+ 23.1 98,3 4.60 57.7 31.4 . Dl 4 Oct. 10-Dcc. 1, May 15-)unc 8.. ¦" . . 78.1 5.1 3.9 87.1 89.7 5.8 4.5 8— 32.8 98.0 4.23 55.0 36.7 HlO May 15-lunc 8 :..; ... ... 80.1 4.3 1.7 H6.1 93.0 5.0 2.0 8 32.5 94.2 4.40 56.7 43.2 I) 3 Oct. 10-lune 8 .......: .. : 87.9 1.0 0.9 89.0 97.9 1.1 1.0 6 30.4 96.5 4.22 53.7 HA SEASON OF 1932-33. (HARVF.STED OCT. 1; SORTED' JUNE 26; PLANTED JUNE 30) Pl 6 Cellar contlnuouily ............ -13.6 86.1 69.7 7.6 4.5 81.8 85.2 9.3 5.5 8 ... 34.2 '. Pl 3 Oct. 15-Dcc. 1 .". ... 42.7 87.1 63.7 5.7 11.3 80.7: 75.9 7.1 14.0 10 ... 24.2 ; I&gt;ls Oct. 15-Dcc. 1, April 1-June 10 40.7 87.1 73.8 2.4 8.2 84.4 87.4 2.8 9.8 f&gt; ... 46.7 Crop failure— D 9 April 1-Junc 10 . .:.:. 41.3 86.1 80.2 1.9 3.4 85.5 93.8 2.2 4.0 6 :.. 37.0 yields not . Dl 4 Oct. 15-Dcc. 1. May l-|une 10 41.1 87.3. 72.2 2.3 9.1 83.6 86.4 2.7 10.1 6+ ... 44.2 recorded. DlO May 1-lune 10 41.8 £6.1 79.6 2.4 3.5 85.5 93.0 2.8 4.2 7— .:. MS) D] Oct. 15-Itine 10 40.3 87.4 77.4 1.4 , 7.5 86.3 89.4 1.8 8.8 4 ... 46.7 SEASON OF 193334. (HARVESTED OCT. 3j SORTED JUNE 18-19; PLANTED JUNE 24) 1)16 Cellar continuously 44J 86.9 73.8 9.6 0.9 MJ 87.6 11.4 1.1 10 14.1 58.9 3.41 15.86 28J Dl 3 Oct. 15-Dec. 1 . . . ....:. 43.9 85.4 75.1 9.5 0.5 85.1 88.3 11.2 0.5 10 25.0 61.5 3.14 ' 16.27 23.1 I&gt;ls Oct. 15-Dcc. 1, April I-lunc 10 41.1 85.6 88.6 0.4 0.9 89.9 98.6 0.4 1.0 4 44.6 73.4 .3.14 19.15 21.1 D 9 April 1-lunc 10 41.5 82.3 88.2 0.2 1.0 89.5 98.6 0.3 1.1 4+ 44.6 77.8 3.12 20.42 29.7 014 Oct. 15-Dec. 1, May 15-June 10 41.2 85.2 82.9 3.6 1J 87.4 94.3 4.1 1.6 7— 30.9 77.0 3.03 19.68 24.8 l&gt;lo " May 15-Junc 10 42.5 82.0 53.7 4.5 0.7 88.9 94.2 5.1 0.7 7+ 35.9 74.3 3.02 19.97 29.8 D 3 Oct. 15-June 10 . ... . 40.8 85.5 87.3 0.0 2.0 89.3 97.8 0.0 2.0 3 43.6 81.0 2.46 20.82 29.1 </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 32 Table 9.— Weights and condition of potatoes stared in sticks under different combinations of cellar and cold storage in 1914-15. Wei K lit .1* prr.nii.ijjcv of original weifihl on Oct. 9 | i, cneI h | Location in storage bin ""»' ""¦ ; s.lun.t Koc I Total Sh.jiul | R,n | J,«»l l""c 1 Tier | Layer | Titr lljyct ' 1 CoM ColJ Cold 30 2.'»-» l 92.Q 1-29 M.2 KH.I 3.13 91.2 II Rear 1-fj Middle 1-6 2 Cohl Ci.l&lt;l Ollar !ll 1.1121 92 v 1.119 D 3.7 K2.&lt;. 4.10 Ml. 1 ¦&gt; Rear 7 &lt;) Middle 3-» Middle 1-4 Front I ! ColJ Cellar llclljr .'II -&lt;.U2(. &gt;J7.f. 'J2.3 H. 65 W.O H7.li 1.16 »».2 7 Front 1-6 Rear 4-B Middle 1-2 •f Cold Cellar Colil 12 1.197 ')H.\ 92.fi 0.71 93. 5 H7.4 O.fH KH.O (1 Middle I-6 Front 1-7 ¦&gt; Cellar Cellar Cellar 17 1.678 MA 5.37 9i.» Bll.fi 5.40 HC.I 9 Rear 1-4 Rear 1-4 6 Cellar Cellar Cold l(j 1 .Wli 90.7 5.25 9r..0 K5.4 3.06 «».5 3 Rear 4-7 Middle C-8 7 Cellar Cold Cold 31 3.156 97.6 92.5 0.91 93.4 H8.6 1.54 90.1 0 Middle 4-8 Rear 1-6 Front 1 8 Ccllnr Cold Cellar 31 3,114 97.» 93.6 I).IS 93.X 87.2 1.2» 88.5 . Rear 1.4 Rear 1-4 'Layers numbered from bottom (1) to top (9)- </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes When weighed in early March there was little difference in the total weight losses suffered by various lots of potatoes, which ranged from 5.8 to 7 per cent with all except one lot, which had been stored in the three upper layers of a rear tier in the cellar and which lost only 4.0 per cent (Lot 6). Sound potatoes constituted a higher percentage with cold stor - age than with cellar storage, the difference being due to the high per - centage of decaying tubers when the potatoes had been in the same position in the cellar continually since harvest time (Lots 5 and 6). When contin - ually in cold storage after harvest (Lots 1 arid 2), the decaying tubers con - stituted a higher percentage than when the potatoes had been in the cellar for the first ten days after harvest before they were moved to the cold storage (Lots 7 and 8). The percentage of decay in lots held in cold storage the first ten days before moving into the cellar (Lots 3 and 4) was about the same as in Lots 7 and 8 and less than in those continually in either cold storage or the cellar. Better aeration during the first ten days when these transferred lots had been in the front tiers of their respective storages and also some aeration resulting from the shifting from one stor - age to the other may have accounted for the smaller amount of decay in these lots in comparison with those continually in the rear part of the bin in either of the two storages used. The differences in temperature and humidity were not very great, the mean temperature of the cellar for these,first ten 1 days having been 47.1° F. and the relative humidity 73.2 per cent in comparison with-42.7° F. and 77.6 per cent in cold storage. At the end of the storage season the highest percentage of sound tubers (based on weight into storage) was found in the lot held in the cellar the first 10 days and then in cold storage until June 1 (Lot 7). The lot continually in; cold storage (Lot 1) had only 05 per cent less weight of sound tubers but 1.59 per cent more rot developed between March 1 and May 27. There was little other difference between lots that were shifted from one storage to the other ten days after harvest (Lots 3,. 4, and 8), the weight of sound tubers having ranged from 87.0 to 87.2 per cent of the original weight, and decay from March 1 to May 27 from 0.64 to 128 per cent. Thei lowest percentage of prime tubers and highest percentage of rot again occurred in the lot continually in the cellar (Lot 5). Placing potatoes in cold storage from March 5 to. June 1 increased the percentage of sound tubers to 85.4 per cent and reduced the decay to 3.06 per cent (Lot 6). This |was not quite as good a showing as when cold storage was used from either Oct. 9 or 19 (Lots 1 and 7). Using cold storage until March and then cellar storage (Lot 2) was almost as undesirable as con - tinual cellar storage. In fact the total weight loss of 10.6 per cent after March 5 with spring cellar storage in comparison with a total loss of 7.7 per cent with continual icellar storage indicates that had the storage been prolonged spring cellar storage would have been an inferior method. The relatively better results secured with the lot held in cold storage the first 10 days and then in the cellar till June (Lot 3), than with continual cellar storage (Lot 5) was not entirely due to the early cold storage but probably due to another factor, i. c., that of better aeration, as the lot </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. sta. Research Bulletin 88 transferred from cold storage (Lot 3) constituted the entire front tier from October to March 1 and the top of the rear tier and bottom of the middle tier from March 5 to June 1, whereas the continually cellar-stored lot was always in the bottom four layers of the rear tier in the bin. Sprout growth was well under way with all lots that were m the cellar in the spring. Differences in the extent of the sprout growth can be attrib - uted to differences in amount of time in the cellar and position in the bin. The only lot in cold storage showing any appreciable sprout growth was the one that had been in the cellar until March. .... .f &#132; These potatoes that were stored in sacks lost less weight during the fall and winter than those that were stored in crates, but they lost more in the spring. In the lots continually in the cellar from October 3 to March 1, the loss from lots in crates (Table 111, D 9, DlO, D11.D12, Dl 6), that were shifted at least once a month for weighing, varied from 8.0 to 9.1 per cent, in comparison with losses of 4.0 to 5.2 per cent for lots in sacks, That were in the same position in the rear tier of a bin all o£ the time (Lots 5. 6, Table 9). In cold storage crate-stored lots lost 7.9 to H. 5 per cent (Table 111. Dl), in comparison with losses of 5.8 to 6.3 per cent in sacks (Lots 1 and 2, Table 9). , Each time the crates were moved for weighing, some dirt was rubbed off the tubers and sifted out of the crates, thus accounting for some but not all of the greater loss. By June 1 the total weight loss in continual cellar storage had been 10.6 per cent with crates and 13.9 per cent with sacks and in cold storage 9.7 per cent with crates or 8.8 per cent with sacks (Tables 111, 9). With cold storage from March 5 to June 1 (atter previous cellar storage) lots in sacks lost 11.5 per cent with cold.storage from April 1 to June the loss in crates was 9.7 to 10 per cent. When cold storage continued unt.l March 1 (after which cellar storage was used), sack - stored lots lost 16.9 per cent and crate-stored lots out of cold storage on April 1 lost 14.6 per cent. Percentages of sound and decayed potatoes tor sack and crate storage cannot be compared directly, because the two series were terminated on dates three weeks apart. However, as there was a relatively much smaller amount of decay in all crate lots when sorted on June 19-20 than occurred in sacked lots when sortedon June 1, it is evident that crate storage involved less loss due to decay (Tables 4, 6, 8,»). The data indicate that potatoes stored in sacks lost less weight during the fall and winter, but more in the spring than did crate-stored lots. These various data indicate further that the extensive aeration provided by crate storage is not necessary in the fall and winter, but also that sack storage might be improved by providing for more aeration than was received by those in sacks in this experiment. In the spring when sprout growth is occurring, crate storage seems to be more effective in preventing weight loss than sack storage-principally by decreasing the amount or decay which probably results from the less humid atmosphere immedi - ately around the tubers in crates. When the temperature differences were as small as in this experiment, which was started on October 9, a short period of cellar storage was of no particular advantage except in that the </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes shift at the lend of 10 days provided some much needed aeration. Pro - longed fall cold storage was undesirable unless continued till the end of the storage season. THE STORAGE OF MECHANICALLY DAMAGED POTATOES Mechanical damage has constituted the most serious grade defect of western-Nebraska potatoes for a number of years. According to the records of inspections made in the bins of certified potatoes the percentage of mechanically injured potatoes during the years 1928 to 1935 amounted to 31.1, 16.0, 16.6, 23.6, 17.6, 18.8, 9.5, and 12.7 per cent or an average of 19.5 per cent for the eight years. These averages are based on the annual inspection of 200 to 380 lots totaling from 86,000 to 700,000 bushels. , As the certified seed producers constitute the most expert group of growers, these figures are more likely to understate than to overstate this situation as it applies to the potato regions of the state. As it is necessary to remove such damaged potatoes when sorting for the seed trade or for marketing as a creditable table-stock grade, the wisest procedure would seem to be fo avoid the damage. Even though much progress has been made in that direction by some producers, complete elimination of the loss seems impossible because of unavoidable circumstances which fre - quently arise. Although such potatoes cannot be sold advantageously, they frequently represent considerable salvage and are suitable for seed purposes on the producing farm or locally if they can be kept in sound condition until planting time, that is, until the middle of June. In order jto determine how best to meet this situation, studies have been carried on to determine: (1) the rate and extent of the wound heal - ing process, (2) the rate and total extent of weight loss, and (3) the con - dition of the tubers at the end of the storage period in June, when (a) different types of wounds were, concerned, (b) injured potatoes were ex posdd to the sun for various periods of time before storage, and (c) injured potatoes were held under various storage conditions. In this bulletin, re - sults of studies along these lines are reported except those pertaining to the wound-healing process, which will be reported at art early date in another publication. All potatoes used in these experiments were stored in slatted crates, at the rate of 25 or 30 pounds per crate with two crates for each treatment. ','.:.. ¦'.'¦ RELATION OF TYPES OF INJURIES TO STORAGE LOSSES The potato harvesting operations result in various types of damage in varying degrees of severity. Potatoes subjected to the types of damage most frequently experienced were exposed to the sun for a period of four hours immediately after being injured and before being stored in the cellar, for the purpose of determining the effect of sun exposure on subsequent losses/ I. '¦:' •¦' '-" ; ¦¦'. .'":.' ;.-' " I.' In 1932 the project was started on October 1, when the exposure; time for the various lots began as follows: Lot A 2 at 9:50 a. m.; A3 at 11 a. m.; : ¦¦:•-. ¦;¦--,;.¦ - • : .:=¦ ..;.. . .-.. .. - ¦ { . </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 Al at 11:20 a. m.; A 4 at 11:30 a. m., and A 6 at noon (£or description o£ treatments see Table 10 or Fig. 18). On this day the Wraturc rose from 72° F. at 10 a. m. with 53 per cent relative humidity to 83 F and 52 per cent at 1:30 p. m. and then shifted to 79 P. and 55 per cent at 4 p. m. The sun was shining brightly all day but there were some clouds until 10:30 a. m. The total wind movement for the 24-hour period beginning at 8 a. m. October 1 was 100 miles. On October 1, 1933 &gt; when another set of damaged tubers was exposed the four-hour exposure erf half of the tubers of each treatment began as follows: A 110.45 a. m,, AZ lla m- A3 11:10 a. m.; A 4 and A 7 11:15 a. m.; A 6 and A 8 noon. Tubers of the second half of each lot were exposed in the same order,staitihg.at 1-30 p. m., with lot Al and at 2:15 p. m. with lot A 8 On this daY the temperature and relative humidity were 47° F and 27 per cent at 11 a m • 50° and 16 per cent at 1 p. m.; 50° and 19 per cent at 4 p. m., and 46&lt; and 29 percent at 5:30 p. m.; and the day was cloudless but quite hazy owing to dust carried by a strong wind which continued until 3 30 n m The total wind movement for the 24-hour period beginning at 8 a.' m. on October 1 was 179 miles. On the whole the exposure cond.tions were less severe than in 1932. Table 10.— Effect of type of injury upon loss of weight during the first two week,* of cellar storage in 1933, Weight loss to various dates as percentage of weight immediate!)- after injury lot No. Tint of iniury T Oct. 1 ' , Oct. S '. 0«.5 I Oct. 7 | Oct. H Al T.,n 8 cn1,.,l i«l« J-_ )Jn , 6 . 0 20 .0 II I™%JKL i. i: i« !fi A 7 Bruises b» dropping ... &lt;•¦" 2() -. 1 4 , A» Complete to.h.n W IJ-? '« ' 2» „ C . 5 . \1 -Whole tubtrs »H -1 ~ , , . i^nata under Oct. I represent losses llurinc A hours of sun exposure. The loss of weight from tangentially cut potatoes after cuts were ex - posed to the sun four hours was very rapid. During these four hours ot sun exposure they lost as much as in the first two weeks in the cellar (A 2) whereas whole tubers lost only 0.9 per cent or one-sixth of the weight lost in the first two weeks (Table 10). Although the rate of loss then decreased somewhat, it was still very rapid throughout the entire winter and was accelerated as the cellar warmed up in April (Al, fig. lo). Whole tubers that had been exposed in the field in the same manner in 10.33 (A 9), lost only about 8 per cent during the first two weeks or hrst month, about 4 per cent from November 1 to April 1, and a total of 16.5 per cent by June 20 in comparison with losses of 14, 11, and 39 per cent during the same periods fram tangentially cut tubers. In June, the rot constituted but 0.9 per cent of the fall weight of whole tuber, as com - pared with 18.2 per cent of those cut tangentially, but sprout growth weighing 9.6 per cent with whole tubers was about three times as great as with cut tubers (Fig. 18). </seg>
         <seg id="p037">i Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes ¦"¦¦¦•nri -I II I I l I Ill( "I ¦ :'¦¦¦: EFFtCTOFTYPEOFIMAJRir .- UPON TOTAL WEIGHT LOSS I '...¦¦- POTATOES STORED IN THE CELLAR _J I ' JL AFTER TOUR HOURS EXPOSURE TO SUNSHNE . j rH - SEASON of. UJ3-834 i ccwwt "W»wiittMDiiiMjwr rtanuwr U«CM moL MM ** I .' - * . Dtta urn wh«h Tuaos «X"C mcms * a\ iFig. 16.—Effect of type o£ injury upon loss of weight. : Tubers were exposed to four hours of sunshine Oct. I 1 before being stored in the cellar. Treatments and weight losses of tubers during the first two weeks •".¦'•-.] arc reported in Table 10. ....-.¦ 37 </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 11 jm^,:: ¦ , . ¦ , ;¦..' ':; "44- "! ¦'¦ -: ¦¦¦¦¦ : ¦•¦¦: '¦¦¦¦ ' A 7 Fie. 17.—Sound tubers (left), rotting tubers (center), and sprouts in June, 1934, in lots subjected to various types of injury the previous fall, prior to exposure to sunshine {or four hours and storage in cellar. Descriptions of treatments arc given in Table 10 and data concerning condition of tubers of various lots in Fig. 18. 38 </seg>
         <seg id="p039">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes 39 STORAGE OF POTATOES DAMAGED IN VARIOUS WAYS (ALL LOTS STORED IN CELLAR ON AND AFTER OCX 1-2) [TIT ' "! I I WEIGHT ON JUNE i 5-» AS I TYPE or INJURY YEAR PERCENT OF OCTOBER WEIGHT . ~ •• ¦' '¦ ~ I I I 3.3, I I I A| TANGENTIAL HO2-3 |BBEfc3B^KJaitMHE&amp;IMBj knife cuts i»33^» WKMSSWKMI2^2]^^^E3BBm it 32-3 &gt;^«-7^fIBBBBff?F'^HBBW^^BB A 2 TRANSVERSE HALVES L —Tr^^^m ~^"^^ 1933-4 p23i^2S^SHBHSS3^HI longitudinal 1932-3 ES2Sc^BH^BKS2HIB^HHB| halves 1933-4 h^MVaS^^T^BMSgMri 1932-3 A 4 DIGGER CUTS , | | | JJJI3 A 8 CUTS INTO TUBERS 1933-4 pBBMEUUBJIK£|PBm| A 7 BRUISED BY DROPPINC 1933-4 ]|Hi^BE!!DHHHE£!I3EiE9B AS COMPLETELY rEATHEWI H33-4 ¦B3Tv^^i-U///WMBgST7MWHI — i i ——^—r '- - '- "= '¦ - r- - ; •¦. ¦. -. - 3i%* ¦ * ~l ¦ - checks- U32-3 HHHHS3I^H^^^QE!£9J NOTDAUAOED 1933-4 iHI^iHZO^I ISE2ZS9B j , 20 40 »0 »O 100 , ; —SOUND riTIsPROUTS P7ZJKOT BBS*,**™ 7 Flo. 18.—Effect of different types of injuries, prior to four hours of exposure to : sunshine and cellar storage, upon condition, the following June. Whole tubers of Dl 6 were not exposed to sunshine for more than about 30 minutes. The rate) of loss and total weight loss was proportional to the area of the wounded tissue, the losses from tangential cuts (Al) being less than those from transversely halved tubers (A 2), which lost less than those halved longitudinally (A3), but with both there was little change in the rate of loss throughout the winter., The weight loss from tubers cut tangentially with a blunt knife and then dusted with dirt so as to simulate digger cuts (A 4) was greater earlier in the season than from tubers cut tangentially with a sharp knife. However, during both win - ters, the curves for weight losses crossed during February or March so that during the spring those cut with a sharp knife were losing most weight. The reason for this midwinter shift is not understood. Possibly the pseudo - cicatrice formed by the dirt and debris on the surface of the rough cut permitted better wound healing' (by preventing desiccation) during late winter as the temperature was rising. When the cutting was done with a blunt edge (A 4) rather than with a sharp knife (Al) a definitely higher percentage of the total original weight consisted of sound tubers in June </seg>
         <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. sta. Research Bulletin 88 (Figs. 17 and 18). Likewise the weight of sprouts was greater but decay was less. Sharp cuts directly into the tuber caused least weight loss. It was generally only 5 to 6 per cent greater than with whole tubers. Potatoes bruised by dropping on a heavy plank (A 7) lost weight a little more rap - idly during the first three months than did those with sharp cuts into the tubers (A 6). Later the weight loss was at about the same rate. The percentage of sound tubers in June was slightly less with the bruised potatoes than with the other lot, apparently because of greater water loss by evaporation, the tubers having shriveled to greater extent (Figs. 17 and 18). The amount of rotting was relatively low with these bruised potatoes. Feathering, that is, practically complete removal of the periderm by rubbing the tubers with burlap (A 8), caused more rapid and more ex - tensive weight loss than did any other type of injury, being worse than cutting tubers into half. In June the weight of rotten potatoes was much greater than in the other lots. The percentage of so-called "sound" tubers was not as low as with those cut in half, but, with the feathered tubers, although "sound" tubers had not rotted they were practically worthless, having shriveled very much and mummified so that they produced only very weak sprouts. For table or seed purposes practically all of these pota - toes were worthless by early spring. In commercial practice the periderm is seldom removed as completely from any tubers as in this experiment. Many tubers are not only feathered but frequently receive some other damage at the same time. In 1952-33 some damaged tubers of each treatment when brought into the cellar at once after wounding lost less weight throughout the season and decayed less than did those exposed to the sun for four hours after wounding. It has been shown that turgid Triumph potatoes crack less if they are exposed to the sun for a few hours before handling (25). It has also been found desirable to have cut surfaces practically dry before placing them in storage so as to avoid infection by rot-producing fungi (24). On the other hand it has been shown that sunshine and dry air are very detrimental to the wound-healing process (20). In view of these findings it was deemed advisable to determine the effect of different degrees of exposure upon the keeping quality of cut potatos. EFFECT OF EXPOSING CUT POTATOES TO SUNSHINE BEFORE STORAGE Potatoes cut in half were exposed to the sunshine in single layers with the cut surface either directly toward or away from the sun both in 1932 and 1933. When cut surfaces were turned away from the sun the pieces were placed with cut side down on wire frames so that they were about one-half inch above the ground and so that air could circulate quite freely on all sides. After such exposure they were all stored in the cellar except as otherwise noted with lots BU and 812. In both 1932 and 1933 the experiment was started on September 30. </seg>
         <seg id="p041">' Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes f - .: . ¦ . - Table 12.— Atmospheric conditions on September 30, 1932, when cut . tubers were exposed. ¦ • 7~ : " '. : ~ '¦ Temperature *j°*°f 1932 lot 'Exposure Period oils were in sun during exposure hum | dity number .... ¦.•! ... during ¦ -..-¦.•-. ""B^ ! M°de exposure i CUTS TOWARD SUN B2 1 4 lo 5 p. m....... ; 77-72 75 70 B3 4 . 1:30 lo 5;30 p. m , 81-67 79 70 B4 5' 8:30 a. im. lo 5:30 p. m 81-67. n W ! CUTS SURFACES DOWN D 5 1; 12 noon (o 1 p. m 79 79 75 B6 4 11 a. m. io 3 p. m 81-76 19 78 B7 8, 8:40 a. m. to 5:40 p. in..:.... 81-«7 79 75 Total wind movement for 24-hour period beginning 8 a. m, September 30 wm 76 mile». Some of the exposures were not placed as well as they should have been in so far as time of day was concerned. On September 30, 1932, the sky was clear and light very bright. The lot exposed to sun for one hour (B2) received little light effect as the sun was very low at that time of day. Temperatures were high for harvesting potatoes, but the humidity was unusually high for western Nebraska. The cellar temperature was 73° at noon and dropped to 68° at 5:30 p. m. and to 53° by the next morning. The humidity in the cellar was low. In each year two lots of 30 pounds each were used.. In 1933 the day when cut tubers were exposed was cloudless but the light was less intense than in 1932. A strong wind and much dust in the air caused the light to be rather hazy in 1933 and the temperature and humidity were both very much lower than, in 1932, having averaged 46° F. and 24 per cent to 27 per cent, respectively, most of the day (Table 12). The cellar temperature was between 55° and 59° and humidity 31 to 34 per cent throughout the day. During the next few days the cellar temperature varied between 57° and 70° F. The humid room temperature was between 155° and 69° F. (generally 58° to 60° F.) and the relative humidity between 73 and 83 per cent. Table 12.— Atmospheric conditions on September 30th in 1933, when cut tubers were exposed. . . '..'¦' :! Temperature Mode of during exposure relative tot No. Exposure 1 Period cuts were exposed to (Un humidity Range Mode durinf; ... ¦ ¦ exposure . °F. °P. P.ct. B2 '.";. 1 1:30 to 2:30 p. m ; 46-45 46 26 B3 4 11 a.m. to 3p. m .; 48-46 46 M B4 8 B:3Q a. m. lo 4:30 p. m 48-39 4g 27 ¦ 1 Tubers with cut side down (/.?.,* 85, 86, E7) were exposed during approximately the same periods, the exposure period being only 30 minutes later for lots exposed the tame length of time. The total wind movement for the 24-hour period beginning September 30 at 8 a. m. was 153 miles. </seg>
         <seg id="p042">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 tv": : i '. ' i —i —i —i i i i ! i&gt;. EFFECT OF EXPOSING POTATO HALVES i\ TO SUNSHINE » \ UPON WEIGHT LOSS IN CELLAR STORAGE ¦ i - 1 \^ StASON OF SU lUA ! . xv\ ¦ -• L_ [ i i [\l - ocm &gt; &lt; \ ¦•&gt; i i * i v i o ij »\£ h-F-T-y- OOCIK* -&lt;N*l-«» HCIWMB J.M*" ftß^Wrt «*»O **¦¦«. M«T JUWt " o»n:s uocn ruetw «m *tixo Fie. 19.—Effect of different degrees of exposure to sun - shine on Sept. 30. 1933 upon loss of weight from potato halves in the ensuing storage season. Treat - ments and weight losses during the first two weeks arc reported in Table 13. 42 </seg>
         <seg id="p043">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes BZ a. ¦jDC - ; ¦••¦¦ ' '¦•- :'. '. - ¦¦•¦•¦ ;;, :;:-¦¦¦:.;¦... •¦..- &gt;, : s,' Fie. 20.—Sound and rotted tubers and sprouts in June, 1934, in lots of halved potatoes that had been subjected to various degrees o£ ex - posure to sunshine before being stored in the cellar. Description of each of these treatments is shown in Table 13 and data concern - ing condition ol tubers in various Jots in Figure 21. 43 </seg>
         <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. St\. Research Bulletin 88 cellar storage of cut potatoes after exposure to sunshine (all cuts exposed on october i or 2) __ METHOD Of HANDLING WEIGHT ON JUNE 15 AS I m SEED BETOHE STORING YEAH PERCENT OF OCTOBER WEIGHT IN CELLAR I . I NOl TO CELLAR O3?-3 JBHGJ33B!MBt[I^I^E3I^B( tcTsu" at on" 333-4 hHHZ&amp;i2HBEZ2S3BiIb^Hf CUT one 1932-3 pSMESS^JK^BIMMM^ B* hour 1933-4 ¦o^SBBEEiSi^^^^EJnHBHI EXPOSED SIDES roUR 1t32-3 Ko^^^^^[^^^3H|||H TO SUN EICHT 1939-3 WP/,i s£»/i%^^^BKl%&amp;B^M^^^Bl SUN hours 033-4 pHQ^HEIISSHIBSiSH^BH one KO2-3 |IH2^^l^l^lu^H£^HlE^3lßHH| Bi Burnt CUT houh im3^ taBHEIHBIWi^3E!3]|rt SIOCS FOUR 1032-3 BMIoBT/S&amp;Stt //^B HWS^C^B STORING kw/ky HOURS 1933-4 taßß^ZSJHU^^^^H^^Hl^^ from EICHT '»3g-3 pa^-f^'MHgggi^flHU^ SUN HOURS '»33-4 311 j^To^ hJSL HUUID ROOM BiT3-4 T^T^^BW'fV^|M^ ft-«CMJ — ~" one wlth 1 mllqoi.i , 3 i \ 311 m^?" ™£N ""••*" »3&gt;4 pMBEJZDM^K^^77^ 20^ 40 « «0 100 B(SOUND [^SPROUTS r Fu,. 21.—Eftcct of ilitTcrcnt Jcj;rccs of exposure and suhsequcnt cellar storage durinj; the winter of 1933-3-f upon the condition of tuber halves the follow - ing June. Except in the humid room, conditions were less favorable for healing wounds on the first few days of 1933 than in 1932 but this was more than offset by the damage from brighter sunlight in 1932. Although the weight losses were of a similar nature in both years, they were more rapid early and slightly greater with more rotting in 1932-33 than in 1933-34 (Table 13, Figs. 19, 20, and 21). These seasonal differences arc partly due to the small size of the tubers in 1932, which increased the ratio of the cut surfaces to the weight of tubers and thereby provided increased opportunity for rotting to occur. With whole tubers exposed to the sun for one, four, or eight hours before cellar storage, the weight loss was about four per cent greater throughout the storage season than with whole unexposed tubers (Dl 6), but at the end of the season in June the total loss was only about two per cent greater (810 and Dl 6 in Fig. 19) and then the condition of the lots was not significantly different. Lots of whole tubers exposed longest lost most weight before being placed into storage and during the early </seg>
         <seg id="p045">i Cellar and Cold Storage op Seed Potatoes 45 pare of the storage period, but after January 2 there was little or no difference. . . When cut! surfaces were exposed to the sun (82, 83, B4) the weight loss was greater during all of the storage season than when they were turned down I(B5, 86, B7) and generally least of all when cut potatoes were brought; into the cellar at once after cutting (Bl). As the length of the exposure period was increased the weight losses also increased (Fig 19). Exposure of one hour with cut side down (B5) resulted in a loss curve very similar to that produced when cut tubers were brought into the cellar at once (Bl). Likewise loss curves for lots exposed one hour toward the sun (B2) and four hours away from sun (B6) were sim - ilar, and likewise were those for the lots with cuts toward the sun four hours (B3) and the one exposed eight hours with cuts away from sun (B7). Table 13.—Effect of different degrees of exposure to sunshine upon loss of weight from potato halves during the first 15 days of cellar storage .. in 1933. 4:¦ -¦¦ :¦' :"':' : • ¦ ¦ ¦¦¦"¦ : j '.'..¦'• Weight loss to various dates calculated" as percentage ¦ I of weight immediately after injury Lot No. - Treatment * : ' . Sept. 30 | Oct.l ( Oct;3 j Oct.s j Oct. 7 j Oct. M : B 1 To cellariat once, nofcipojcd - ¦ ! „_ . - t0 , un i 0.7» 1.7 4.7 6.0 8.2 10.8 B2 Cut,sides toward son 1 hour.. 4.8 63 9.5 10.8 14.2 16.0 Bi Cut sides toward sun 4 hours... 8.3 9.5 123 13.8 163 193 B4 Cut sides toward sun 8 hours... 12.2 143 17.0 18.7 20.8 24.7 B 5 Cut sides away from sun 1 hour. 3.0 35 6.7 8.2 10.0 12.0 B 6 amides away from sun 4 hours : 6.0 7.2 10.0 11.4 13.0 160 B 7 Cut sides away ffom son 8 hours 95 10.0 12.7 H.B 16.0 17.2 BU Cut sides away from sun 1 hour, then inj humid cellar one week 32 23 3.7 .6.8 72 10.8 812. To humid;cellar at once, not ex- ¦: . ¦ . . ' ' . __ posed lo sun :. 0.5 0.5 15 2.5 33 83 810 Whole tubers in sun 8 hours ... .3.2 4.0 4.2 5.7 63 75 Dl 6 Whole tubers into cellar at once 0.0 0.9 12 1.8 4.1 J.S 1 All lots cicept 810 and Dl 6 consisted of tuber hakes. aData under.Sept. 30 represents losses during exposure period. .' - -¦ 3 Potatoes were transferred to cellar after time designated. Exposing cut surfaces to the sun either one, four, or eight hours re - sulted in very!low percentages of.sound potatoes in June (Figs. 20 and 21). In 1933-34 about half of the tubers exposed for one and four hours with cuts toward the sun, were still sound in June but in 1932-33 the percentages were much lower. The more irapid and extensive losses with the tuber halves of Lot A 2, which was exposed on October 1, 1933 (Fig. 16), than that with B3 (which was given the identical treatment on September 30, 1933) is ex - plained by the] fact that A 2 tubers having been exposed one and one-half hours later inithe day encountered more of the maximum light hours and a temperature that was four or five degrees higher and relative humid - ity generally seven to eight per cent lower than were encountered by tubers of B3 on the previous day; Similar differences in 1932-33 may be attributed to the higher temperature and lower humidity again encoun - tered by Lot A 2 when exposed. : ¦¦| ¦ '¦:¦¦"'¦"¦';•'. !'¦'¦ ¦¦' • ' ¦¦' ¦ : - '• ' ¦¦'.'. . : ¦¦¦¦¦-¦" ':¦'".T .- ;: :¦ v : ¦"¦ ; •.-¦:'.-- '¦ "'"¦ :: -: ' ' -'-. </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. sta. Research Bulletin 88 Placing cut tubers in a humid room in the cellar for one week before storing them in the regular cellar storage resulted in very much decreased weight losses and a higher percentage of sound potatoes (811, B12). When placed in the humid room at once after wounding, the result in June was that the sound potatoes amounted to 64.3 per cent of the original October weight (B12). Rotting was only about one-third of the amount occurring when cut tubers were put into the cellar directly. Thus storage of cut seed in a humid atmosphere for one week compared favorably with cellar storage of whole tubers with which 70 to 74 per cent of the original weight occurred as sound tubers in late June. When potato halves were held in the sun for one hour before placing them in the humid room (Bll) the weight loss prior to November 1 was about the same as th.it of the lot placed in the cellar at once (Bl). From then on, the hunnd stored lot lost less but it always lost more than the lot which did not suffer an exposure to the sun before it was placed in humid storace (Fig. 19). b EFFECT OF METHOD OF STORAGE UPON CUT POTATOES The atmospheric conditions under which injured potatoes are held has been shown to he a very important factor in the healing of wounds 14. 21)). Cut potatoes were held under various storage conditions to de - termine the effect of these conditions upon weight losses and decay. Tubers of medium size cut in half were used in this project in 1932 Inn in 195? when tubers were larger, tangential cuts one and one-half inches in diameter were made. Each year two lots of 30 pounds of potatoes (alter having been cut) were used for each treatment. The methods of handling and time of exposure in 1932 of the various lots are described in Table 14. 1 \ble 14.— Treatments used and atmospheric conditions at time of exposure on October 5, 1932. I Temperature I, \ li V\rm\uTt ! ' Relative I SUrt [ Finish "Umidi"' °F. °F. P. a. &lt; 1 Sun 4 hour,: then cold storage 9:30-1:30 54 67 05-20 t 4 Sun 4 noun; .hen cellar imnsc 9:45-1:45 55 67 60-20 &lt; Sun 4 hours: then cellar 3 days 10:00-2:00 56 (A 50-18 ( '• Sun 4 hours; then cold storage 3 days . 10:15-2:15 57 69 45-18 r '&lt; Sun 4 hours; then cellar until April 10-.20-2-.ZO 58 70 40.18 ' '" Sun 4 hours; then cold storage until April 10:30-2:30 60 71 30-20 loi.il wind mDierncnt for the 24-hour period beginning at 8 a. m. on October 5 u-ai 135 miles. The temperature rose from 54° F. at 9:30 a. m. to 71° at 2:30 p. m. The sun was bright all day. The relative humidity decreased during this period from 65 per cent to 18 per cent. The cellar temperature was be - tween 54° and 68° F. and relative humidity between 43 and 30 per cent. Cold-storage temperature was between 37° and 39° F. and relative humidity between 55 and 60 per cent. The last lots that were exposed (C 9 and CIO) </seg>
         <seg id="p047">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes beginning at 10-.20 or 10:30 a. m. were exposed to higher temperatures and lower humidities and consequently lost one to one and one-half per cent more weight [during the four hours in the sun than did those exposed for four hours after 9:30 a. m. All, potatoes used in 1932 had been dug on October 1 so they had already undergone the customary post-harvest shrink - age by October 5 when cut surfaces were exposed. In 1933 the exposures were made on October 2. This was a calm, hazy day with about 30 per cent of the sky covered with clouds at the begin - ning and 15 to 20 per cent at the close of the exposure periods. The total wind movement for 24 hours beginning at 8 a. m. was only 41 miles. -¦—If I- I I 111 I' I I'l I Ml - '-.. ¦ ; EFFECT OF TYPE OF STORAGE . . Jv .UTON TOTAL WEIGHT LOSS rSk. POTATOES WtH TANGENmAL CUTS i 1 V^. SEASON OT lU3-534 — Fig. 22.—Effect of type of storage upon total'weight loss of potatoes with tangential cuts in storage season 0f'1933-34. Treatment-arid-weighf losses during the first two weeks iarc reported in Table 15. </seg>
         <seg id="p048">Nlbraska Acrl. Exp. sta. Research Bulletin 88 ¦ ¦¦*' 1 ¦¦ KittfiL' ¦' ':" ' '' ¦ ' ¦''¦"'¦¦'*¦¦¦" "¦' ' ¦ " no .¦;¦ "^ : ——¦¦--. -"-¦:._: -:f*fp. ~' ¦ Qg \^ ' J!^::-":-;---'"; j rtF . !¦ ¦ -^- "¦ ¦ '"- "•¦"¦""¦ '-;'¦' ¦'..'-''""':_:-..-.,..Jr:Li • -::.:-_,'•:-,-*: Uj'^;^'^^^'^^^^^^^^^^^i^^^.^ J&gt;j Fie. 2i. — Sou nil ami rotting tubers antl sprouts in June, 1934, in lots of potatoes with tangential cuts after four hours' exposure to sun at harvest lime and .storage under various conditions. Description of treatments is shown in Figure 24 anil Table 15. 48 </seg>
         <seg id="p049">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes ¦I ¦¦ ¦¦ ' -..¦¦¦¦ : .;; -.-.; -¦' *¦" ¦' '"-¦¦'¦' •' j ''-¦ ¦-' ¦ ¦ l"-v/ejKi^^^Bt'*%.''" '' •" '" ¦'' ' Fie. 23.—(Continual) 49 </seg>
         <seg id="p050">was between 63 an d 70 per cent relatlVe humit% Md in cold Lage (S Sfit S f" greater during the last five mnnfhc k Vls\f 1 '- lotal shrinkage was "me. By the middle of June t n "«J«™ .^ .'^ USCd a" the the lots placed in the cc hr a tonC Ir I '"'^ fCT rOttCfl P°tatoes in once ha/broken d^^wJ^jftS g^ » C°W --"JT. * two seasons the sound tuirs suitable for ? n,. 24)-. Con^quently ,„ the 56 and 68 per cent of the October II P I S P Ju"e amounted t0 but only to 21 and 37 per cent when cl Cd'ar St°rage WaS used SS thi 2 3 *£* Tr about er' at the c/ose °f the - &lt;oes in m,d-fune 'the ot n cold &lt; '""? '" the °f the Dota- J times more and sound tork gC *°? amounti"S to three to five :¦ the cellar-stored s c"k ( F f ,""1^ ell tha" ** ," mudl "f" amounted to less than half of A I I" the SoUnd stock less of the L'W of s Sit tTt f"? R^ rd" H Holding potatoes in cold storage for the first four to seven day, (Cd\ I </seg>
         <seg id="p051">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes 51 EFFECT OF TYPE OF STORAGE UPON CUT/SEED POTATOES (ALL LOTS STORED OCTOBER 1-2] 1 OUt"oF TYPE Or STORAGE YEAR I WEIGHT ON JUNE IS AS "" FIELD - d I PERCENT, OF OCTOBER WIGHT . "~ . &lt;•**""* I I ....[' .'.¦'--' ; Cl TO COLO STORAGE '"*'* PMim/r'&lt;'S™'"////^**X&gt;SBS c 2 at ohcc cellar '^ B^EjflßLJlf S C 3 TO cold STORAGE f 4,*','^^^^^'. *^V\vffiv??] W3-4 |B.ip-///////,««.l/^y///////Kl^t&gt;3 STORAGE COLO STORAGE/ [M ;-3 M7yrttaj K^K^jX^l-^^XS^OOwl C$ FIRST SEVEN I*^^^^^^^ DAYS ONLY H33-4 |BaMJjy-'l'r^™''&gt;'lM " AFTE.R i^-^^^-^ -" 'I • ' . ! 3»C^ . ¦ c 5 CELLAR riRST 1932-3 PBESJM II I &amp;&amp;33.iW$ SEVEN DAYS ONLY U33-4 j^KEMK?7Z?»O.°y/ ' iNV?4.Q&lt;&gt;: TOUR -t . P^^^^L^-J-t r rrrrrnri- iill . C|O COLO STOWAGE ' H32-3 \//////AI.S/////A!S!SWXl!hiA'*BfXlB&amp; HOURS AP"'L I 1933-4 ¦t3.3&gt;//////46.7////// / KxXMXa»,'oyy3Q&lt;? C 8 CELLAR ;1»32-3 JMMSHMWE^^^^I^S^ EXPOSURE [TILL APRIL I 1933-4 W^KM^B^^K/y/^^/ZA^^OJi/Q^, 1932-3 S3&lt;*/&gt;s6s^&gt;6J ¦'¦ '.: •:' ;¦; ¦". ¦•'¦¦; **" .;!••.&lt;* «o. -»o mo. : | . . Maouwo i^&gt;pßouTs Fig. 2-I.—Effect of different methods of storage of tubers with tangential cuts dur - i . ing_ winter of 1933-34. percentage of decay was.very much greater, sprout growth was slightly less, and weight of sound tubers remaining was very much less in mid- June than when tubers were in.the cellar all the time. This system of storage was, however, preferable to continual cold storage (C3)-but was less desirable than four to seven days of cellar storage followed by cold storage (C 5) or continual cellar storage (Figs. 22, 23, 24). When cellar storage was continued till April 1 and tubers then were placed in cold storage (C 9), weight losses were not quite as great as when cellar storage was continued (C 4). With: spring cold storage there was much more decayed stock in June than in continual cellar storage, but the decay was hot severe. During the first season there were more sound tubers in Junej with this treatment than with any of the other storage methods used with sun-exposed tubers but during the second year this treatment was not equal to continual cellar storage. During both years there was more rot when cold storage was used only in the spring (C 9} than when not used at all (C 4). ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p052">NtBRASKA ACRL. ExP. 5tA. RESEARCH BULLETIN 88 j; The most disastrous system was to hold the cut potatoes in cold stor- j: age until April I and then to transfer them to the cellar (CIO). These &gt;j potatoes were almost worthless. No sound tubers were found in June, i\ 1935, and in 1934 they amounted to only 13.3 per cent of the original. ji weight. Most of the tubers sorted out as rotten were quite completely ?j rotted. •; The relative rank of the treatments would appear to have been .is jj follows: i! C 2 —Cellar storage at once, no exposure to sun. C 4 —Cellar storage after four hours' sun exposure. ('. y— Cellar till April 1, four hours' sun exposure. C s—Preliminary cellar storage (four to ten days) after four hours' sun exposure. (/ \ —(.'.old storage at once, no exposure to the sun. (' (v—C'.oUl storage first three to seven days, then cellar, after four hours' sun exposure. ; C }—t; o |d storage at once after four hours' sun exposure. C. 10—Cold storage till April 1. after four hours' sun exposure. Table I l?.— Effect of type of storage upon loss of weight by tubers with tangential aits during the first two weet^s in 1913. | i Wfik-lit Kirn ii&gt; sarimis ibici during: first two weeks ciikuhtnl as percentage of weight ; 1,, ; \,, Muru'i- ir&lt;.tiiu-nr immediately after injury was m.itlc H ] '&#132; ( In ,1! .in I illiM-lllulU I - - ; j ; '—¦ • ¦ tut 2 Oct. 3 !(ki.^ " Oct. 7 I Oct. 14 , i |,| .„.,,., .; &#132;„., " iki ~Y.&lt; i7i i.n Tj , ; &#132;„,, „.».„ „ ,"„,,. 11.1 l H _ U S.S 7.S i \roM ii in sin i huvks ;r , j „ i,, „,„,_, i: i.s f,.i 7.1 i -4 him .i-liir -f-* (•¦* ~J* X-" 11-" -:; c 1 i ,11,r I. .!..&gt;.. rli.ii &#132;.1.1 uiirjiw U S.! f,.} 7.7 &lt;).« .i 1 i. r, ,|,| M.ir.nr (. ,i.iss. thru cclljr 4.» 6J 6.7 7.2 X.7 . ¦?¦'¦ I 'I I rll.ir in l|&gt;nl !. ilirn u.lil miner '.* 5." ('.l 7.(1 10.2 ¦ .". f\u &lt;i,M sliicasr li, \pril I. then L tllji \S *t.\ 1.7 7.3 5.5 '.i 1 ill ll'holr n,l.rrs &#132;,lij u.ir^-r "" H.K l.i 2.2 3.2 ' : II! Whi,l» iulym .ell.it si,,r.n.- "II l.'l I.S ?.( A.I )J The difference in behavior of two tangentially cut lots exposed to the .p. sun four hours before cellar storage (Lots Al and C 4) is again attributed j;j to difference in severity of exposure conditions. In 1932-33 when Al had ,*&lt;l] the most sound potatoes in [une, these tubers exposed on October 1, 1932, ¦'•!&amp; were exposed to both higher temperatures and higher humidity than was J' Lot C 4 on October 5. .'jj! In 1933-34, Lot C 4 had most sound tubers in June, probably as a result .'ijji of the cut tubers having lieen exposed on October 2, 1933, to a hazy, |y partly cloudy, and calm atmosphere whereas cut tubers of Al were ex- (a&lt;| posed on October 1, 1933, which was a very windy day with slightly less ;|j-j. humidity and temperature just a little lower. ii </seg>
         <seg id="p053">Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes STORING CUT SEED POTATOES IN THE FALL The beneficial effect of storing cut potatoes in a humid atmosphere for one week before placing them in cellar storage has been discussed (page 8). When potatoes were cut into seed-piece sizes (10 pieces per pound) in early October and held in the humid cellar for a week and then iri the regular cellar storage (El) the weight losses during the first month ¦¦.; n^ i / i.: - i . i i ¦ i i I i 11 i. I WEIGHT LOST Btf VARIOUS DATES . 1 POTATO HALVES AND SEED SZE PIECES '¦". ' ..' &gt;-ft CUT IN OCTOBER. 1933 . - " l\ MLWO CELL4B ONE WEEK THEN. OPDINAM - ' -¦ - \V - .-:'.'¦"-" CElx*n stowage • . ..... "H|j r; i [ ('¦ -]¦- (I|i || V ¦. ¦ OCTD6EB MXtVBCR OCCncCft JWOWV (QMWr MAACH mH. IMY JUNE .1- ¦. O*TW WON mWCM TVBOa WD&gt;C «KXB Fig. 25.—Weight loss from tuber halves and seed-size [pieces during storage season of 1933-34 when not ex-; . posed to sun after cutting but placed at once into a ... humid cellar for one week anil after that held in the ordinary cellar storage—Bl2 tuber halves, El seed-size pieces, E2 seed-size pieces dusted with lime and sulfur . 'after outing. (Data in Table 16.) were less than.with potatoes cut into half (B12), but after November 1 they were greater (Table 16, Fig. 25). This lesser early weight loss, occurring in spite of the greater area of cut surface, may have been the result of cut seed pieces packing together more closely and this together with the greater evaporating surface resulted in a more nearly saturated atmosphere immediately around the seed pieces than around the more nearly whole tubers with the result that evaporation was less. </seg>
         <seg id="p054">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. sta. Research Bulletin 88 By June 16-20 the potatoes cut into seed pieces had lost 34.1 per cent and halves 26.9 per cent (Fig. 25). This 7.2 per cent difference in weight loss was very largely or entirely accounted for by the greater amount of rot, which constituted 12.8 per cent of the original weight of the seed pieces and only 3.5 per cent of the half tubers. Table 16.—Condition in /une, 1954, of potatoes that had been cut into seed-piece sizes and into halves in October and were then stored in the cellar. Weight in laic June as PcrccntaKCoflot.il . .. Trcilmcnt percentage of original weight when sorted "" ' ° 1 October wdshl in laic June I _ Smm.l j.Sprouil Rot [ Total Sound jSproutl Rot HI! 1'm.,.., 1i.i1.~,Y.-«pWii liTtiin one hour. then 1.c.mi.1 &#132;-ll.ir ™c week 54.1 5.0 4.8 (H.I 78.6 7.2 M.2 lII.' S.imr ... HII lim nut rxpo,c.l to tun M.i i.i 3.5 73.1 86.9 5.3 4.7 I 1 fill ,cc.i |..eir &gt;&#132;c&gt;. Mnrcil in humnl cellar one week 49.J 3.8 12.S 05.9 74.8 i.ft 11.4 I : S.ime .is hi plus lime anil tiillur ¦¦I uri.i.i- 42 1. i.a [Ci.6 f,2jt r.7.7 5.5 2r..S W'hfii the cut surfaces of the seed pieces were coated with a layer of him- .mil .sulphur immediately after cutting- (E2), as has sometimes been rccmnmcnilcil for the purpose of facilitating the healing process and pre-; scmni; the seed pieces, weight loss during the first five weeks was reduced very slightly when compared with non-dusted cut seed. Beyond that time weight losses were greater, having been 38 per cent for dusted and 34,1 per cent Uy |unc -I) for undusted cut seed. This later increase in weight-loss was undoubtedly due to the increased amount of rot, which in June amounted to 16.6 per cent of' the original weight of dusted as compared with 12.8 per cent with undusted cut seed potatoes. Therefore, if cut potatoes are to be stored for a long time, dusting with lime and sulphur does not serve any useful purpose and may be injurious. </seg>
         <seg id="p055">: Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes LITERATURE CITED (1) Applcman, CO, Biochemical and physiological study of the rest period in the tubers of Solatium tuberosum. Md. Agr. Exp, Sta. Bui. 183. 1914. Potato sprouts as an index of seed value. Md. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 265. 1924. (3) : —. Kimbrough, W. D., and Smith, C. L. ¦ Physiological shrinkage of potatoes in storage. Md. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 303. 1928. (4) Anxhwagcr, Ernest Wound peridem formation in the potato as affected by temperature and humidity Jour. Agr. Res. 35:995-1000. 1927. (5) Bennett, J. P. 1( The effect of law temperature on the retention of solutes by potato tissues. Ab - stracis of papers (mimeographed) presented to meeting of Amer. Soc Plant Physiologists, (Pittsburgh). 1934. (6) Bushncll, (John / Storage of seed potatoes. Bimonthly Bui. Ohio Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 12:142-48. (7) Butler, O. ' ; . Storage of potatoes. N. H. Agr. Exp. Sta. Circ. 20. 1919. (8) ; —: — —' . . ¦-. - ;.-' ¦¦¦¦'¦ ..'' ¦ ¦¦¦ ¦ . The effect of the environment on the loss of weight and germination of seed potatoes during storage. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agr. 11:114-18. 1919 (9) Hartman, [John D. ; Effects of [storage temperature on histoiogical and microchemical changes and on propagation value of potato tubers. Proc. Amer. Soc. Hort. Sci. 29:409-12. 1932. Studies of the effects of storage temperatures on the propagation value of potato tubers. Cornell Memoir 168. 1934. (11) Jchlc, R. A., and Hcuberger, J. W. Effect of raising storage temperature o£ late grown Irish Cobbler potatoes Anier Potato Jour. 11:289-92. 1934. • . (12) Johnstone,]G. R. : ' ' Effect of wounding on respiration and exchange of gases. Bot. Gaz. 79:339-40. (13) Kimbrough, Wm. Duke A study of respiration in potatoes with special reference to storage and transporta - tion. Mtl. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui, 276. 1925. ' . (14) Lutman, B. F. Respiration of potato tubers after injury. Bui. Torrey Bot. Club 53-429-55 1926 (15) Peacock, W. M. and Wright, R. C. Low temperature injury to potatoes when stored shortly after harvest. Proc. 13th Ann. Meet. Potato Assoc. of America, pp. 99-101. 1926. (16) ; -p —: . ¦¦¦-...'... '¦' Influences |)f different storage temperatures on dormant seed potatoes. Proc. 14th Ann. Meet. Potato Assoc. America, pp. 126-130. 1927. (17)- : —, . ¦ ¦ and Whiteman, T. M. • ¦. C°"t. roL'L ns, t'lc snrinkn Sc °f^skinned potatoes in storage. Proc. Amer. Soc. Hort. Sci. 2yiTls~ly.. 1932. . - ; . ¦"¦¦'";"' ¦ i (18) Pennsylvania committee on storage investigations. Potato storage investigations 1925-25.] Marble Lab. Inc., Canton, Perm. (19) Pieper, J. J. and Flint, W. F. Thr«' t tcmPcratllr« {or s"^ P°uito storage. 111. Agr. Exp. Sta. Rpt. 1926-27, p. 69. (20) Priestly," J. H. and Woffcndcn, L. M. Thßic!i eaio"?6'-l 1%5° U1923- " *"" propasat;°n cut "f8- Ann- App. </seg>
         <seg id="p056">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 (21) Rhodes, Edgar Chemical nature of the membrane of potato cork. Bio. Chcm. [our. I9:isi-G3. IWS. (22) Smith, Ora Studies of potato storage. Cornell Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 553. 1933. (23) Stuart, W., Lombard, 11.I 1. M., and Peacock, Walter M. Comparative influence of different storage temperatures on weight losses and vitality or seed potatoes. U. S. D. A. Tech. Bui. 117. 1929. (24; Weiss, F., Lauritzen, ). 1., and Bricrley, P. Factors in the inception and development of fusarium rot in stored potatoes. U. S. D. A. Tech. Bui. 62. 1928. (25; Werner, H. O. The cause and prevention of mechanical injury to potatoes. Ncbr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 260. 1931. (26) Tuber development in Triumph potatoes as influenced by time of planting on dry land in northwestern Nebraska. Ncbr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 61. 1932. (27) A renew of the literature on the physiological aspects of the storajjc of potatoes. Nebr. Potato Imp. Assoc. 16th Ann. Rpt., pp. 36-59. 1935. (28) ¦. and Zook, L. L. Seed potato production in central Nebraska. Ncbr. Agr. Exp. Sta. ISul. 294. 1935. </seg>
         <seg id="p057">j Cellar and Cold Storage of Seed Potatoes 57 Table I.— Percentage -weight Josses_by_various^dates with^the^l93l crop-when— potatoes were stored-under different — conditions throughout the storage season. (All lots harvested and stored on October 3.) Date Ccl' :lr ¦¦¦ into cold storage on diUcrcnt data Out of cold storage on- £{" swrage'to Fall and ipring weighed °nly ¦ .¦ ¦ - different date! storasr late June col&lt;i """Be Dl 6 Dl | D 3 J DS | D 9 | lilO Pl 3 | D 5 | D 4 | D 2 D 6 nil | Dl 2 Dl 4 ¦ | W5 Oct. -I 3.4 o.B' 2.1 1.7 2.1 •1 5 ~2A LI " IS r 1.3 L 2 1.9 ~7j ""lj L 8 Oc.t 5 . 3.6 1.6 3.4 .3.0 3.4 2.4 3.5 2.8 3.0 1.6 ¦: 3.3 3.1 2.4 ¦ 3.0 3.1 Oct. 7 4.3 1.9 3.8 3.5 3.7 3.3 3.4 3.2 3.8 3.3 3.7 3.6 2.9 3.5 3.7 Oct. 10 4.8 2.4 4.3 .3.9 4.2 4.1 4.6 4.0 4.2 4.0 4.2 : 4.1 3.6 4.2 4.4 Oct. 20 &lt;Ar 3.4 . 5.0 6.3 6.5 6.2 5.6 4.4 5.1 4.8 6.6 6.5 5.8 5.0 5.1 ¦ Nov. 1 8.6 4.0 5.1 . 7.5 7.7 7£ «.l . SJI 5.5 5.1 8.0 7.5 7J 5.5 53 Nov. 15 9.4 4.9 5.9 8.4 8.4 8.4 6.8 5.8 6.4 5.9 8.8 8.3 8.0 6.1 63. Dec. 1 10.1 5.3 6.5 8.5 9.2 9.2 7.4 6.4 6.9 6.4 9.0 9.1 8.7 6.7 6.8 Dec. 15 10.5 5.9 6.6 8.6 9.3 : 9.4 7.6 6.6 7.2 6.5 9.1 9.2 8.9 7.3 7.1 Jan. 1 10.7 6.5 7.2 9.1 9.4 95 8.2 7.3 7.7 7.2 9.3 9.3 9.1 7.6 7.6^- Feb. 1 11.2 7J 7.7 9.2 9.8 10.1 8.9 . 7.8 8.3 7.7 9.6 9.7 9.4 8.4 8.3 March 1 12.0 7.8 . 8.2 9.8 10.6 10.8 10.1 8.4 8.8 8.2 103. 10.6 10.3 9.4 9.6 April 1 12.6 8.4 8.6 10.1 11.1 11.4 10.9 8.9 9.3 8.6 10.5 11.1 11.0 10.4 10.6 April 15 13.0 8.7 8.9 10.4 1U tU 113 9.4 5.5 8.8 11,0 11.6 1U 10.6 10.8 May 1 13.4 9.0 9.1 10.5 11.5' . 12.0 11.8 10.0 9.8 9.0 11.5 11.7 11.6 11.4 11.0 May 15 13.9 9.6 9.4 10.8 11.6 12.6' 12.4 10.7 10.2 9.4 .12.0 11.8 12.1 12.0 11 2. June 1 14.6 9.8 9.7 10.9 11.8 12.9 13.3 11.4 10.6 9.4 12.4 .. 11.8 12.5 12.4 11.4 June 8 15.3 10.1 9.8 W3. 11.8 13.1 14.2 12.1 11.2 9.6 13.1 11.8 12.7 12.5 11.5 June 15 16.1 10.0 9.8 10.9 11.8 13.2 15.1 13.1 11.8 9.7 13.9 11.9 12.9 12.6 12.0 June 23 16.9 10.6 103 lIJ 12.1 13.9 15.1 14.2 12.5 9.9 15.0 12.1 13.3 125 12.2 1 Figures in bold face represent losses suffered by the dose of periods during which lots concerned had beep in cold storage. For example. Lot D 3 was moved to cold storage immediately after being weighed on October 10 and by the lime of next weighing on October 20 the total weight loss to date amounted to 5.0 per cent of this original weight. ' , ..'-¦¦-¦ ¦'— </seg>
         <seg id="p058">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 88 58 Table 1 1.— Percentage weight losses by venous dates when the I*&gt;i2 crop oj potatoes was subjected to various storage con - ditions throughout the season and mean temperatures during such pciuds. (All lots harvested and stored October 4 lice. 311 111.0 7.1 7.S »-» IK-" »¦'¦ '' *•* "¦',' »¦{ ;-J &#132;, v, 1 &#132; (, 111.11 MKAN irMl'l-KATLHP DUKINi; VAHIOUS XITWAUK I'KUIODS IS lIKiIRKS FAHRENHEIT 1 Sec footnote wiili Table I, </seg>
         <seg id="p059">pELLAR AND CoLD STORAGE OF SeED POTATOES 59 Table 111. — Percentage weight losses by various dates when the 1933 crop of potatoes was subjected to various storage conditions throughout the season and mean temperatures during such periods. (All lots harvested and stored on October 3.) : . ¦ " C'SC 1)16 I Dl I D 3 [ 118 | D 9 I d7o~ Dl 3 [ p; | M ¦) pj pa pn | DI4 j Pl 2 | Dl 5 ¦" O«. 5 TJ~ 1.3 &gt; 1.0 1.5 .2.0 . : 1.7 "74 1.2 U&gt; "il 'TJlsrn H PJ Oct. 7 2.4 2.0 2.1 2.7 2.9 2.8 2.4 2.4 2.2 26 2 5 23 21 ?i i, Oct. 14 3.8 3.0 . 3.3 4.0. 4.0 3.8 3.6 2.9 2.9 37 30 U\\ ¦34 34 O". 31 5.0 4.4 43 5.2. 5.6 5.2 4.5 4.1 4J 48 47 54 fa J'» i« Nov. 15 5.8 5.0 5.6 6.3 6.5 63 5.7 5.4 5.3 58 55 6^ S7: 57 si "«• ' 6-3 6.2 6.0 6.4 7.1 6.7 6.1 5.8 5.7 64 56 6 8 64 5 8 59 Dec. 15 . 6.6 6.« 6.6 6.9 7J 7.0 6.6 6.2 6.0 69 65 70 65 er Ik 1"2 7.4 6.8 : 6.6 7.4 8.0 7.6 7.2 6.4 6J " el 78 70 72 69 Feb. 1 7.7. 7.5 7.4 7.9 8.7 8.3 7.6 7.1 S.B' 7.4 67 84 78 77 75 March 4 8.0 7.9 7.8 8.2 9.1 8.7 8.1 7.3 7.4 8 5 71 as 85 8 1 11 April 1 8.6 8.9 7.9 9.1 9.4 9.1 8.6 8.3 SO i.9 . 7 g 95 87 89 87 April 15 8.8. ¦ 9.0 8.1 9.4 9.6 9.4 9.1 8.4 8.1 89 8.0 96 9 1 92 90 May 1 8.8 9J 9.4 9.7 10.0 9.7 9.1 9.0 8.8 91 77 97 oS o'» gi Mj» 15 9.6 9.4 9.4 93 10.1 10.5 10.5 9.8 B.S 94 91 oi 101 ml II Mny3l 10.6 9.7 10.1 9.8 10J 10.6 11.0 10.9 92 9.7 100 9I 10J ill 21 June 9 12.8 10.4 10.1 9.9 10.5 10.8 12.8 II 9 10.0 100 13 100 10J \H ?7 luncl9 15.9 11.6 10.7 10.5 10.6 11.1 14.9 14.6 12.2 IIJ . 12J . joio loj llj lo'.l MEAN TEMPERATURE DURING VARIOUS STORAGE PERIOPS IN FAHRENHEIT DECREES Ml" ... .... 50.6 47.5 41.4 42.0 50.6 50.6 50.6 50.6 47.5 41.4 42.0 50.6 506 Cold storage ... ... 39.7 39.5 39.4 39.5 39.3 ... ... 39.7. 39i7 *^" ar .... .... ... .... ,¦• . • ;.. ... ¦&#132; .- * JIT' Aft t ¦ Cold itoragc ... 39.7 39.4 39.2 39.1 39.4 ... .. '"' " 39S Ani JO4 sof Cellar ... 61.0 61.0 61.0 61.0 61.0 44.5 50.9 58.2 '.'.'. 509 M 0 «l'o Seasonal mean 44.3 40J 40.8 40.9 41.5 42.5 43.9 43.6 42.6 'O.\ 4318 40.8 41.7 41 j ju 1 Sec footnote with Table I. . . . </seg>
         <seg id="p060"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>