<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Factors Determining Type-of-Farming Areas in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1936-05">1936-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 299 May, 1936 Factors Determining Type-of-Farming Areas in Nebraska L. F. Garey Department of Rural Economics 1/ 1/ . T** "I " cchcral tjaniusj il^T ! w~~l ti .-j *%^i uvtiTocK-1 * —i —l~^i The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONtaNTS Pace Introduction .• 3 Factors Determining Type of Production 4 Physical 4 Biological 5 Economic 7 Other Factors 14 Shifts in the Production of Agricultural Commodities 14 Crops 14 Livestock Units \j Income 18 Areas of Production 20 Description of Type-of-Production Areas 24 Area 143. Range Livestock, Cash Grain, and Potatoes 24 Area 145. Sugar Beets, Potatoes, and Livestock 25 Area 182-A. Livestock and Cash Grain 25 Area 1 83-A. Intensive Livestock Production 26 Area 184. Cash Grain, Livestock, and Potatoes 26 Area 186. Range Livestock 27 . Area 187. Livestock, Wild Hay, and Cash Grain 27 Area 188-B. Cash Grain and Livestock 28 • Area 189. Cash Grain, Livestock, and Pasture 29 Area 193. Livestock and Cash Grain 29 Area 194. General Farming 30 Area 195. Cash Grain and Livestock 31 Area 196. Livestock, Cash Grain, and General Farming 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Factors Determining Type-of-Farming Areas in Nebraska L. F. GAREY 1 "Type-of-farming" is a term used to identify an area in which the agricultural production is characteristic because of environmental condi - tions, regardless of what they may be. It expresses in general the uni - formity of production, not only in the relative importance of enterprises among themselves but also in the practices followed. A type-of-farming area is a smaller territory than an agricultural region, such as the com belt, cotton belt, and the dairy region. There may be several type-of-farm - ing areas in each of the agricultural belts or regions, depending on condi - tions within the belt or region. One is impressed with the wide variation in agricultural production, when passing through a state such as Nebraska. In passing through type - of-farming areas, two kinds of changes are evident. One is a gradual change, which is apparent in the transition zones where farmers have some choice in the selection of their enterprises and are trying to make adjustments to meet economic conditions. The other is a rather abrupt change, since farmers are often limited in the choice of enterprises by soil characteristics and other forces of nature. The problems of the farmers in the second group are also economic in character but of a little different nature from those of the first group. The significant difference between these groups lies in the limitations on the choice of enterprises. The type of production, whatever it may be, is the result of environmental condi - tions which are ever changing and which necessitate continuous attention on the part of the producer. With due consideration to the conservation of their resources, farmers are striving continuously to obtain their production at the least cost. They realize that there are certain commodities in which they have an economic advantage in production and that they must exchange their commodities for things which they cannot produce economically. Because conditions affecting production over a state or region are not uniform, products are produced where conditions for their production are most favorable. As a result the general area for corn production in Nebraska is in the eastern part, wheat in the western, and wild hay in the north central. Not all farmers respond to the forces governing production to the same degree nor at the same time. Neither do all men have equal ability. Consequently the same proportion of farm enterprises is not found on all farms in a locality nor is the same degree of intensity of production fol - lowed by all farmers. The tendency is for farmers to adjust their produc - • \7}}" , buII " in tak " lhc "'"« of Acricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 244. TyDcs of Farming in Nebraska by Hedces and Elliott. Another bulletin dealing with the areas in more detail will be published this year. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 tion so as to obtain the greatest net return, but because economic condi - tions are changing constantly a perfect organization for agricultural pro - duction is never attained. The factors which are significant in determining the character of agri - cultural production in an area may be grouped for the most part as physical, biological, and economic. Under each of these heads will be dis - cussed the related conditions which play a part in determining our types of agricultural production. FACTORS DETERMINING TYPE OF PRODUCTION PHYSICAL FACTORS SoiL— Plant growth constitutes the foundation of all types of agricul - tural production. This raises many problems of adjustment in the pro - duction of crops and livestock. On soils which are suited to general crop production, a certain type of farming may be advised in order to maintain a more permanent agriculture. Acid soils are not well suited to the pro - duction of legumes. On deep rich or alkaline soils another type of pro - duction is preferable. Texture, humus content, character of subsoil, and other soil characteristics have an influence on the plant growth which either directly or indirectly affects the type of farming. The principal soil areas of Nebraska are shown in Figure 1. The drift - hill area in the southeastern part of the state is of glacial origin and covers nine per cent of the total area of the state. Because the soils in this area wash rather easily the problem of erosion is important. These soils will produce a variety of crops but need to be more carefully man - aged than certain other soils. The loess hills and plains areas cover 35 per cent of the state and constitute the most extensive soil area. It is of wind-blown origin, is deep and fertile, and where rainfall is sufficient is very productive. Corn and wheat arc especially well adapted to these soils and alfalfa is, where rainfall is sufficient. The bottom land and bench areas are adjacent to streams and cover eight per cent of the state. They are generally productive, except where drainage is poor or where alkali has developed. They include both first and second bottom land. The high-plains areas are in the western and northern parts and cover 19 per cent of the state. They were formed from underlying. parent material and vary in composition. The sand-hill area in the north central part covers 26 per cent of the state. The topography of the area is irregular, with hills and valleys which are best suited for grazing and hay. Because of the light soil the area is subject to wind erosion, making it inadvisable to cultivate much of the land. Cattle raising is the characteristic type of pro - duction. The outwash-plains area lies to the northeast of the sand-hill area and occupies three per cent of the state. The area is spotted with deposits of gravel, sand, and silt. Where the subsoil is gravelly the risk of crop production is greater than where the subsoil is heavy. The prob - lems of soil blowing and fertility arc important in this area. As pointed </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Type-of-Farming Areas out, soil has an important relationship to type of agricultural production. This relationship in Nebraska becomes more evident by comparing Figures 1 and 15. ESSJh.CH p^^UOUHM™*™* PLA.NS " BZfflDR.PT H.LLS E53 SAND HILLS E53 S^BBNaiB?* "10 &lt;*™ASH PLA.NS LOESS H.LLS Fig. 1.— Soil areas in Nebraska. All of the soil in eastern and southern Nebraska a cither of loess or glacial drift formation, both of which are very productive. The sand-hill area in the north-central part covers approximately one-fourth of the state. (Extension Service Circular 133.) Surface.— Surface characteristics have a direct influence on the type of production in an area. Level land is most apt to be devoted to quick - growing crops, while hilly land is often devoted to pasture and timber. Hilly land in sections of heavy rainfall is subject to damage by water erosion if cultivated crops are grown. For the most economical operation of large-sized machinery, level land is preferable. In the level sections of the state, as in the wheat belt, for example, machinery is used extensively while in the rougher areas smaller-sized equipment is used. In the areas which have a gently rolling topography the problem of drainage is not serious. In the level sections with heavy rainfall, drainage is more of a problem. This is especially true along rivers where alkali is present. Under such conditions the choice of crops is narrowed down, thus having a direct effect on the type of agriculture. Climate.— The climate of Nebraska is varied. There are wide ranges in both the precipitation and the temperature which limit the production of certain agricultural products. The expansion of corn production in eastern Nebraska has reduced the importance of other crops. The produc - tion of corn has increased in regions of scanty precipitation in spite of the adverse conditions for its production. In the areas under irrigation, pre - cipitation is less significant in the determination of the type of agricultural production. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 The rainfall varies from 34 inches in the extreme southeastern part of the state to 16 in the extreme western, the decrease westward being rather gradual for the southern two-thirds of the state. The precipitation in all parts of the state is sufficient so far as the water requirement of plants is concerned. Because of the poor distribution of rainfall and high evapora - tion in the western half of the state the choice of crops generally is limited to those of low water requirements. These factors have a direct bearing on the type of farming followed. Figure 2 shows the precipitation in dif - ferent parts of the state. so tz "o a t* « 28 M re Fig. 2. — Average annual precipitation for Nebraska, 1850 to 1930. Note the varia - tion in the width of the two-inch rainfall bands in different parts of the state. (Extension Circular 133.) The influence of temperature on the type of agricultural production is significant in various ways. The length of the growing season, which is a determining factor in the choice of crops, depends on temperature. Temperature depends primarily on latitude, altitude, and precipitation. Short growing seasons have cool climates as a rule. Because of the short growing season in some parts of the state certain crops are not adapted to these areas. The maximum temperature during the growing season may be too high for certain crops. Cold nights and warm days result in freez - ing and thawing and are injurious to winter grains. Figure 3 shows the length of the growing season in different parts of Nebraska. BIOLOGICAL FACTORS The biological factors which play an important part in the choice of crops and hence the type of agricultural production are plant pests, plant diseases, weeds, and crop adaptation. The Hessian fly influences winter wheat planting in the southeastern part of the state, and grasshoppers often prove injurious to the production of alfalfa seed. Chinch bugs tend to keep down the average yield of barley. Rust hampers the production o£ wheat and oats, and smut is detrimental to nearly all grains. Although these factors may not be the cause for the total disappearance of a crop in </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Type-of-Farming Areas a locality, they may be significant in the determination of the proportion of the crop land devoted to a crop and the part that it plays in the cropping system. The drouths of 1933, 1934, and 1935 and the crop-re - duction program carried out by the government in 1934 and 1935 have contributed to the weed problem. The grass in the pastures has not been able to cope with the weeds during the dry weather, with the result that the weed growth has increased greatly. Land taken out of cultivation has not always had the best of care, with the result that weeds have got a foothold in the crop land. In such cases some shifts in the proportion of V' - t ' - ■ ' ■ 1 1 ■ *^i ■' '^^* 109 lj^t o « \ v ■ *■* s v u *n h • '^" "\ jr..,.' \ »v o 1 v -^ Fig. 3. — Approximate length of growing season in different parts of Nebraska. crops may be necessary when this land is used again for crop production. There is a continuous demand in every locality for varieties of crops which will yield more than those that arc grown there. The development of new varieties and the introduction into a locality of others not grown there will have an effect on the type of production. Because of competition, crops once well adapted to a locality may not be adapted now. ECONOMIC FACTORS Transportation. — Transportation facilities have been a primary factor in the development of the agriculture of Nebraska. During the early develop - ment of agriculture in this state the only means of transportation for most agricultural products was the railroads. In more recent years the develop - ment of highways has played a part in the transportation problem and has had a very definite effect on type of production. The development of the highway system has permitted cross-transportation between towns and has greatly shortened the time required in the shipment of certain com - modities. The introduction of the motor truck has expanded the area for the production of perishable products, such as truck crops, small fruit, and milk, and has made possible the production of these commodities in localities better adapted to their production. Where long hauls are involved, the truck has not changed significantly the type of production. In localities </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 where trucking costs have been less than cost by rail, the truck has been influential in making the production more permanent. The mileage of railroad in the state has changed but little since 1912. The railroad mileage in Nebraska increased from 3,052 miles in 1886 to a high point of 6,178 in 1926, an increase of 102 per cent. Since 1931 approximately 68 miles have been abandoned. Improvement in refrigera - tion facilities and speeding up of trains have helped to expand the pro - duction of certain products. Figure 4 shows the relationship between the expansion of transporta - tion facilities in Nebraska and its agriculture. The improvement of high - ways since 1925 has had some influence on the expansion of land in farms. THOUSAND Or MILES MILU0N3 miujons or hoso of^ &gt;UN0 IN FARMS • '"*% • « . -' .--i-LIVESTOCK __,-__ _ _---~ -32 *■'''/ i „'' / IMPROVCO HQHWAV-*/ /' '' ' I. ,-' __ —""^ RAILROADS ! " 24 4 " / ,'Y — -«^LAND IN CROPS / - 16 I860 1870 1880 1890 iSoiiJ igio I92O 192S 1930 1935° Fig. 4. — The development of transportation and agriculture in Nebraska, 1860 to 1935. There was a close relationship of miles of railroad with land in crops and number of livestock. Market outlets.— The only two outlets for the products from Nebrasks farms are consumption on the farm and sales. Approximately eight per cent of the value of the gross income from farm products was consumed on the farms from 1924 to 1929. In 1934 a little over nine per cent of the value was consumed on the farms. The increase in the percentage consumed on farms in 1934 was because the total production was less than in the preceding years. That which is sold is used for food, clothing, and other industrial uses. The amount which goes into other industrial uses is not known but it is not likely that the type of production in the state has been changed much because of this outlet. The outlet for our agri- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Type-of-Farming Areas cultural products is not limited to this country. A part of the agricultural production in Nebraska, particularly wheat and pork, finds its ultimate outlet in foreign markets, so the nature of our international policy has an influence on the type of our agriculture. If the policy tends to prohibit foreign trade in these commodities, a shift in our production becomes necessary. If it is favorable we may give some thought to the expansion of those commodities in which we have an advantage in production. Fie. 5. — Value of land in 1920. Note the high-valued land in the northeastern part of the state and the low-valued land in the sand-hill section. Fie. 6. — Value of land in 1935. Note the lower value of land throughout the state as a whole as compared to Figure 5. Land prices. — Agricultural land derives its value primarily from its power to produce agricultural products. Other factors which have some influence on its price are distance to market and possible change in value. Based on anticipated future income, the purchase of land by non-farmers </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 for purposes of security also has an influence on the value of land. The last factor is sometimes referred to : as the speculative element. Land near large urban centers is higher in price than land equally fertile but farther away, primarily because of the higher farm value of the products raised on it. The conveniences and attractions offered by cities and towns cause the value of the land adjacent to them to rise above its productive value for agricultural purposes. Figures 5 and 6 show the price of land in the state in 1920 and in 1935. The price of land was highest in 1920 and lowest in 1933. The price in 1935 was 4.3 per cent higher than the low point of 1933. Wages.— Labor is the largest single item in the cost of producing most of our agricultural products. The more intensive the type of production, the greater the proportion labor is of the total cost. Labor is a larger pro - portion of the cost of producing corn, potatoes, or sugar beets than it is of small grains. When wages are high, farmers consider the adjustment of their cropping system so as to require as little labor as possible. This may mean a shift from intensive to less intensive production. Labor is also the largest single item of cost in most things farmers buy. When wages in industry are high they affect the farmer's buying power. Labor is also the largest single item in the cost of transportation. When wages are high, transportation costs are high, and because of the tendency of wages to lag behind the price of commodities, producers of raw materials are penalized when agricultural prices are declining. Competition in agriculture.— Most of the competition which Nebraska farmers are attempting to meet comes from areas where the conditions governing production are similar. The competition in corn production comes from other states in the corn belt, of which Nebraska is a part, so naturally the conditions for the production of corn in the corn belt are quite similar. The same is true for hogs and to some extent for beef cattle. The soils and climatic conditions of Nebraska seem to be better suited to the production of alfalfa than those of other states in the middle west, and this gives Nebraska an advantage in this respect. Because of the long dis - tance to large consumption centers, Nebraska is not advantageously located as far as the production of bulky products is concerned. The conditions suitable for the production of fruit are different from those for other types of production, with the result that only a limited portion of the state is suitable to this kind of agriculture. There is competition in agricultural production among farmers. Educa - tion and research have done much to aid farmers in discovering that cer - tain types of production pay better than others. These aids, along with effective farm practices, have made it impossible for those failing to take advantage of these opportunities to continue in the same line of production. Those who cannot meet the competition either change their practices or go to areas where the competition is less keen. c nearly one ' half of the cro P acreage during the period from 1910 to 1934. Immediately following the war there was a decline in </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Type-of-Farming Areas the production of corn for a few years and an increase in the production of wheat. In recent years the acreage of wheat has been declining as a result of the competition given by corn. The decline in the relative im - portance of oats since 1920 has been due to the greater use of motor power on Nebraska farms in place of horses. The barley acreage has increased because of the development of more suitable varieties and its increased use as a feed. The relative importance of the alfalfa acreage has shown very little change during the last twenty years. There has been an increase in the number of hogs, cattle, and sheep but a decrease in horses and mules since 1910. The increase in cattle kept for milk since 1925 has been more rapid than in other cattle. ;■■»" ___ . 260 • y\ I I CORN ■ P2O i lf\ I POTATOES' 1910 I9IS 1920 1925 1930 1934 Fig. 7. — Relative prices of farm products produced in Nebraska, 1910 to 1934. The price received for crops fluctuates more than that received for livestock commodities. 1910 — 14 = 100. Relative prices. — Farmers are interested ultimately in the purchasing power of the things they produce. If the price of a particular commodity is higher than normal for a period of years, many producers will increase the production of that commodity. Fundamentally it was the price factor which caused farmers of Nebraska to reduce their production of wheat and increase corn and legumes. Livestock and livestock products sold at a relatively higher price than wheat, and the result was an expansion in the number of productive livestock. Not all producers respond to price changes at the same time nor to the same degree, and as a result the shift in enterprises in an area is not uniform. Some respond to price changes </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 quickly and others may require several years to show any response. When once a change is made from one type of production to another, farmers are not likely to return to their former type of production. Figure 7 shows the relative prices of important farm commodities produced in Nebraska . since 1910. Land tenancy. — The percentage of farms operated by tenants increased from 42.9 in 1920 to 49.3 in 1935. The proportion of tenant farmers who rented on a cash basis declined during this period. Fig. 8.— Percentage o£ farm tenancy in 1920. There was a large percentage of tenancy in the cash-grain area of the south-central part of the state. Fie. 9.— Percentage of farm tenancy in 1935. The perccnta B c of tenancy increased in all parts of the state over that of 1920. Compare with Figure 8. In certain sections of the country the highest percentage of farm ten - ancy is found on the highest-priced land. The assumption has been that farms will be rented when conditions make it possible for the income from them to support more than the farm population. Under such conditions the price of the land would rise because of the greater income. There </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Type-of-Farming Areas seems to be no definite relationship between the value of land and farm tenancy in Nebraska. The highest percentage of tenancy appears to be found on medium-priced land or slightly above and a lower percentage on high- and low-priced land. Because of our short-term system of renting farms, tenants in general are inclined to depend on the production of cash grains for a large part of their incomes. There is a tendency for tenant farming to be more prominent in cash - crop areas than in livestock-producing areas; consequently a larger pro - portion of tenant farming is found in the cash-crop areas of southern and western Nebraska than in the east-central part of the state where dairying, cattle, and hog feeding are prominent or in the sand-hill area in the north - central part of the state, where cattle grazing is the dominant type of agri - cultural production. Figures 8 and 9 show the percentage of farm tenancy in Nebraska for the years 1920 and 1935. The percentage of tenancy was highest in the areas where the sale of grain constitutes a large part of the income. Table 1. — Relation of value of land to percentage of farm tenancy in Nebraska. 1920 I 1925 1930 1935 Value of Per Value of Per Value of Per Value of Per land per cent land per cent land per cent land per cent »cc tenancy acre tenancy acre tenancy acre tenancy Umlcr $30 24.3 Under $25 38.3 Under $20 40.2 Under $10 43.0 $ 30-S 79........ 38.9 $ 25-$ 54 45.8 $ 20-$ 49 46.0 $ 10-$ 29 46.3 80-129 45.3 55- 84 46.8 50- 79 48.7 30-49 50.5 130-179 45.9 85-114 49.7 80-109 51.0 50-69 53.8 180-229 45.9 115-144 48.8 110-139 47.6 70- 89 -18.6 230 and over... 46.2 145 and over.. . 44.9 140 and over. .. 43.3 90 and over... 43.6 Aveiuce 42.9 46.4 47.1 49.3 Table 1 gives the percentage of farm tenancy according to the value of land from 1920 to 1935. Because of the wide variations in value it was not possible to use the same intervals in value per acre for the years used. There was a continuous increase in the percentage of tenancy in the first four groups according to value of land in each of the years listed in Table 1, with no particular trend in the two highest-value groups. In general the lowest-valued land is in the western part of the state, including the sand-hill region, and the highest in the eastern part. Use of land. — Three kinds of problems from the standpoint of the soil confront most farmers of today. One is that of fertility, which has been neglected too long. Although crop yields have shown no dangerous de - clines, the time has come when every producer of agricultural products, whether tenant or owner, should give some serious thought to returning to the land that which he has taken out. It may involve the establishment of a new but definite cropping system. It may mean the expansion of the livestock enterprises or even the use of commercial fertilizer. The second problem is that of erosion, which is caused by both wind and water. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 Wind erosion is most serious in the western part of the state on soils under cultivation. There is some damage done, to soils in the eastern part in areas where the soil is light. Water erosion is more serious in the eastern part than in the western, although all rough land which is in cultivation is subject to this kind of damage. In general the seriousness of water erosion is in proportion to the amount of rainfall during the growing season and the topography. The third is that of proper use of land with respect to income. The financial returns a farmer can obtain are after all the test of any plan in farming, for it is only with financial earnings that he is able to carry on his business. The shifting of crop enterprises on his land in an effort to determine a more profitable combination is an alternative open to him in securing a better use of his land. OTHER FACTORS A number of other factors have some influence on the type of pro - duction in an area. Education has been significant in the development of new varieties of crops adapted to certain sections of the state and has resulted in an expansion in the area devoted to these particular crops. It has also had some influence on the practices followed by farmers and to that extent has caused adjustments in their business. Improved methods of breeding and feeding have made livestock relatively more important in certain areas. More profitable combinations of farm enterprises dis - covered through farm-management studies have caused some farmers to make shifts in their poduction. Foresight and alertness on the part of leading farmers in a locality cause these men to make adjustments in their business as economic conditions change. Their influence is felt by others in their locality, who later make adjustments and thus change to some extent the nature of the production. Practices handed down from generation to generation, religious beliefs, nationality, and social conditions are factors which have some influence on the type of production in a locality. The problems of restoring the fertility of depleted soils and the control of erosion need continuous attention. They cannot be solved in a short time. They call for some sort of plan for the utilization of land, which will control these losses to a greater extent than has been done in the past and at the same time return to the producer reasonable remuneration for his labor and capital. Because economic conditions are constantly chang - ing, farm enterprises are never adjusted perfectly. What is best one year may not be best the next. A farmer must always be alert to changing conditions and make his changes in the light of the information available. SHIFTS IN THE PRODUCTION OF AGRICULTURAL COMMODITIES CROPS Crop acreages. — There were some changes in the proportion of crop land occupied by certain crops between 1910 and 1934 that should be </seg>
            <seg id="p015">TyPE-OF-F ARMING AREAS pointed out. Com was the most important crop from the standpoint of acreage throughout the period. The acreage increased 15.6 per cent from 1910 to 1932. During the first part of the period corn occupied a little less than half of the crop land and during the latter part a little more than half. The proportion of crop land occupied by wheat has shown a decrease throughout the period. During the first part of the period wheat occupied about 25 per cent of the crop land and during the latter part about 15 per cent. Oats remained at approximately the same relative importance and occupied about 14 per cent of the crop land. Barley increased after PER CEMT 100 jJJJJi^^JjllJlU^4| _JUJ... JJ LL^-^-^-J-U 1 1 1 1 1 1 IIIIIJJ-'^^U 40 — ■ ~~ — CORN - &gt;" I«O Wl 1920 192S 1030 1834 Fig. 10. — Percentage of cultivated land occupied by crops designated, 1910 to 1934. There was a relatively large proportion of the cultivated land in corn through - out the period. The contraction in the acreage of wheat was absorbed by an expansion in the acreage of corn and barley. 1927 and occupied 5.3 per cent of the crop land in 1933. Rye has always been relatively unimportant and at no time since 1910 occupied more than 1.7 per cent of the crop land. Alfalfa has been the most important of the tame hays and has occupied about 7 per cent of the crop land since 1913. (See Figure 10.) The most important crops included in other crop land have been potatoes, sugar beets, and wild hay. Other crops have not varied much in acreage. A shift from wheat to corn has been the result of greater purchasing power of corn products than of wheat products. Over one-half of the crop land in the state is now in intertilled crops, which means that the tendency has been to shift to the production of higher-value crops. Table 2 gives die percentage of crop land occupied by crops and average acreage by five - year periods, 1910 to 1934. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 Crop yields.— The five-year average yields of the principal crops, except wild hay, are given in Table 3. The five-year period, 1931-35, includes three dry years, which caused the lower yields in that particular period. With the exception of the last five-year period, the yields of barley, potatoes, and sugar beets increased throughout the period. The yields of wheat, rye, and alfalfa showed a slight downward tendency. Those of corn and oats varied from period to period. On the whole the crop yields of the state remained fairly uni - form. Table 2.— Percentage of crop land occupied by crops by five-year periods, ■ 1910 to 1934. Average Period Corn Wheat Oats Barley Rye Alfalfa acreage (000) 1910-14 47.5 25.6 15.6 0.6 0.7 6.3 ~Tt ITotT 1915-19 42.4 21.2 14.2 1.2 1.3 6.9 12.7 14 796 1920-24 43.9 21.4 14.1 1.4 1.2 6.9 11.0 15*214 1925-29 47.2 17.5 12.8 1.8 1.0 6.4 13.4 16569 1930-34 48.8 ,4.9 !2.6 4.3 1.2 6.1 12.0 16^22 Table 3.— Average yields of the principal crops in Nebraska by five-year periods, 1912 to 1935} Cr °P 1912-15 » 1916-20 ' 1921-25 1926-30 1931-35 i . I Corn '*"•&gt; 23-2* 26J2 26\75 2*56 17I7 O"" (*»•) — •: 28.66 32.75 27.76 28 39 2147 Barley (*«.) 23.03 24.04 24.35 26.66 16 25 Wheat (*«..) 18.77 15 qo m 29 ,7 25 , 2 59 R * c &lt;*»•&gt; 16.24 14.67 12.42 12.90 10 26 Potatoes (*„.) 77.79 79 M 81/)5 g3 n j,^ Sugar beet. * (T.) 10.13 12.31 12.32 12 15 MM ** &lt; r -&gt; 2.53 2.35 2.40 K65 ' Slate agricultural census reports. 1 Includes only four years. 'Data not available for yejrs 1912-15. Variation in yields.— Although the yields follow no definite trend over a long period, there may be a wide variation from year to year. The co - efficient of variation is a means of measuring the dispersion from the average in terms of per cent, thus making it possible to compare the varia - tion in yield of different crops regardless of the unit of measure. The co - efficients of variation for the principal crops grown in Nebraska are given in Table 4. : A small percentage of variability indicates a more dependable yield than a large percentage. That is, a yield of sugar beets of around 12 tons per acre is more reliable than the indicated yield of the other crops listed in Table 4. The lower variability in corn yields than in other cultivated </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Type-of-Farming Areas crops is undoubtedly a factor Table 4. — Percentage variability of crop in causing farmers to expand yields in Nebraska. their corn acreage. The acre- . = age of sugar beets is limited to &lt;&gt;op Period %*££ | ..^S the areas where conditions for ~ n 189frl933 26A bu . their production are most Oals 3908-1933 26.9 bu. 21.94 favorable and in Nebraska iiaricy 1908-1933 22.6 bu. 24.25 those are irrigated areas.. The w '»t" wheat 1908-1933 le.obu. 20.40 wider the range of conditions &amp;*£- JSSSS "St » under which a crop is pro- Rve im . l933 n3bu _ 1947 duced the more variable the sorghum grain ... 1921-1933 17.3 bu. 21.24 yield is likely to be; conse- pot «°« 190B-1933 77.4 bu. 20.91 quently it is important to con- = Z 5E S3 sider the conditions governing wiId hay 1912-1933 0.9 t. 18.65 production when contemplat- ' ~ ing adjustments among crop coefficient of variation =—^x 100 enterprises. ™ LIVESTOCK UNITS 2 The number of livestock on the farms of Nebraska varied from year to year during the period 1910 to 1934, but in general there was an up - ward trend. The largest number of units on farms was in 1918 and the next largest in 1934. Cattle, except those kept for milk, were more im - portant from the standpoint of units than all the other livestock combined. Table 5. — Percentage distribution and total livestock units by five-year periods, 1910 to 1934. 1 "*** H^ MUkcow, 3 .»«££, ™£? (000) 1910-M 9.8 15.8 43.6 1.2 1.9 27.7 3,621 1915-19 8.6 12.7 50.7, 0.7 2.7 . 24.6 4,125 1920-24 9.1 11.7 53.1 0.7 2.3 23.1 4,000 1925-29 11.1 11.9 51.9 0.9 2.6 21.6 3.835 ■930-34 10J 12.4 55.9 U) 2.5 17.7 3.944 1 Compiled from state census reports. The largest number of cattle was reached in 1934 and other high points were in 1918 and in 1924. The number of milk cows remained fairly constant throughout the period. There was an increase in the number of hog units up to 1923, when the maximum number was reached. Good - sized corn crops were produced in 1920, 1921, and 1922, which resulted in large hog crops in 1923 and 1924. Although the number of sheep units increased throughout the period, the total number was relatively unim - portant when compared to the total livestock units. There was an increase 'One unit of livestock is assumed to be equivalent to 1 horse, 1 cow, 7 sheep, 5 hogs, or 100 chickens. ' ' ■' ■ ■ - ' -I -.■' ' ' </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 in the number of horses from 1911 to 1916, after which there was a con - tinuous decrease. The expansion in the use of motor power on farms is the main reason for the decline in the number of horses. Figure 11 shows the trend in the number of units for the principal kinds of livestock found on Nebraska farms for the period 1910 to 1934. , The importance of a particular kind of livestock in a farm organiza - tion may be indicated by comparing it with other kinds of livestock. Table 5 shows the relative importance of different kinds of livestock by five-year periods from 1910 to 1934. 000 UMTS 4000r 1 3000 - . *^ ' ~ ™ M^ =^^^^^ ' ***^ — *&amp;*~ tj/*&gt;y" C rz^S^— ■. r ,r ••!*- ~V^\j3 7^1* Luri , , — j* ■ i i i — r&gt;^ =Sc? ~^?f u "- K cows Tk^T * '"'v. rTTTTT " I ' s f i~rX 1 1 I L - -^ *\ I „ -^ — OTHER CATTLE °-^ I I I I I i i i ■ i i i 1910 1915 1920 I92S 830 1934 Fig. 11. — Thousands of livestock units in Nebraska, 1910 to 1934. Changes which are most evident are the increase in the number of other cattle and the decrease in the number of horses. From the standpoint of income, hogs and poultry were about three times as important as the percentages in Table 5 indicate. The most noticeable change in the relative importance of the various kinds of live - stock was in horses, which decreased 39 per cent from the first to the last period. Milk cows decreased 8 per cent. There were increases of 24 per cent in other cattle, 19 per cent in hogs, 40 per cent in sheep, and 27 per cent in poultry. INCOME Nebraska farmers depend on hogs, beef cattle, wheat, corn, dairy products, and poultry products to provide them with the most of their income. Table 6 shows the percentage distribution of Nebraska's farm income from 1923 to 1934. Income from these sources amounts to 90 per cent of the total and the importance of the sources is in the order named. The value of the farm products sold and consumed on the farm </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Type-of-Farming Areas Table 6.— Percentage distribution of the Nebraska farm income by sources indicated from 1923 to 1934. 1 v- | h oe , | *- | pr D x,;| Poultry | whut | c^ | oto i 1923 27.7 27.5 63 el lTs si si " MS "' 1924 2 7.6 20-5 7.5 6.5 15.6 13.4 8 9 418 1925 35.3 21.5 7.6 7.0 9.9 8.4 10 3 428 1926 36.4 24.0 8.6 7.7 10.1 3.1 10 1 417 1927 25.9 17.8 8.7 6.2 17.8 14.5 9 1 453 1928 30.5 18.5 10.6 . 7.8 14.6 8.9 9 1 419 I92V 31.9 19.8 9.8 7.6 11.5 9.0 10 4 452 1930 33.6 21.9 9.1 7.4 9.4 7 2 114 337 193 ' 33.0 25.6 12.0 9.4 5.9 4 2 99 248 1932 27 - 5 22.3 12.9 9.8 4.6 11.9 11.0 167 1933 25.4 20.1 12.5 7.8 12.5 9.2 12 5 187 1934 24.3 31.9 12.6 8.5 6.7 6.4 9 6 216 Avuace 30.7 21.6 9.6 7.5 11.6 8.9 10.1 344 1 Compiled from reports from the Bureau of Agricultural Economics. since 1923 varied from $166,905,000 in 1932 to $452,685,000 in 1927, a variation of 171 per cent. The low income in 1932 was the result of low prices, while the income of 1927 was the result of fairly high prices with good production. The division of the income in 1927 was 60 per cent from livestock and 40 per cent from crops, and in 1932 it was 74 per cent from livestock and 26 per cent from crops. PER CENT V-fTT BE EF CATTLE rT~F?T ;: II 1 IJJMillp LLJJ1ullujJJ1|JJJ[[ 20 ', HOGS to ■ ; 1923 j&gt;4 55 Is 27 26 2» 30 51 35 53 3t FlG 'iO3r~^ &gt;POrt ' On ° f gr °" incomc from indicated sources in Nebraska, 1923 to t j • Cre W3S a Sma " but gradual increase in the proportion of the income trom dairy projects. The same was true with poultry, except for the last two years. That from hogs declined in recent years, while that from beef cattle increased. That from corn and wheat varied but decreased for the period as a whole. (Based on data from the Bureau of Agricultural Economics.) </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 Figure 12 shows the relative importance of specified sources of income from 1923 to 1934. The range in the income from hogs was from 24 to 36 per cent of the total, beef cattle 18 to 32, wheat 5 to 18, corn 4 to 16, dairy products 6 to 13, and poultry 6 to 10. There was an upward ten - dency in the proportion of total income from all livestock during the period with a rather definite decrease in that derived from wheat. This indicates a shift toward livestock with less dependency on cash grains. The proportion of the total income from livestock varied less than that from crops, which was an important reason for the shift toward livestock. AREAS OF PRODUCTION Two important factors that are significant in determining the localiza - tion of agricultural production are unit value and perishability of the product. As a rule bulky products have low unit values and are expensive to transport so are produced relatively close to centers of consumption. Non-bulky products with high unit values, such as wheat, flax, and butter, can bear high transportation costs and are grown at comparatively long distances from centers of consumption. Potatoes, sometimes classed as a bulky crop, may be produced far from consumption centers if their use as seed or their high cooking quality gives them a high unit value. High yields in a particular locality, which reduce the unit cost to the point where growers can afford to ship them, is another reason why they are sometimes grown far from market. All livestock products are produced in con - centrated form and can be transported much farther than the crops used in their production. In general, perishable products, such as milk and most of the truck crops, must be produced comparatively close to points of consumption. Fresh vegetables may be shipped reasonably long distances' when out of season, thus commanding a high price, or where cheap transportation, such as a water route, is available. These are fundamental principles which are significant in determining the distribution of our agricultural pro - duction. Where conditions permit a wide range in the selection of crops such as are found in eastern Nebraska, farmers have a wider choice of enter - prises from which to select than where conditions narrow the crop possi - bilities down to a few. The former conditions permit a choice in the kind of livestock as well as in crops, while the latter limit the choice of live - stock. Because of differences in the opinions of individuals the type of production is likely to be less uniform in areas which permit a wide choice of enterprises than where the choice is limited. One is impressed with the wide range of crops and their relative im - portance in the eastern part of the state. Figure 13 shows the distribution of crops by counties in Nebraska on the basis of the 1930 census report. The length of the bar indicates the relative importance of a crop from the standpoint of acreage occupied. In some counties in the eastern part of </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Type-of-Farming Areas the state over half of the crop land is devoted to corn, while in some counties in the western part very little corn is produced. In some counties in the north-central part of the state, over half of the crop land is in wild hay. In sections where potatoes or sugar beets are grown their importance in the farming business is not indicated accurately by the length of the bar shown in Figure 13. They contribute far more to the income of the farm than the length of the bar indicates. Oats and barley are raised to some extent in all parts of the state and are used primarily as feed, although some are sold as a cash crop. Alfalfa is more important than all other legumes from the standpoint of income and its use as a feed. Figure 14 shows the distribution of livestock in Nebraska on the basis of the 1930 census report. Cattle classed as other cattle are more important from the standpoint of numbers than milk cows, as indicated by the length of the bar. In Douglas county, in which the city of Omaha is located, the proportion of milk cows to other cattle is higher than in the other counties. Hogs are important where corn is grown, as shown by Figures 13 and 14. Sheep are not important in the state but are most numerous in Scotts Bluff county, where they are fattened. Horses are not so num - erous in the western areas, which are devoted to the production of wheat, as in the eastern part of the state where corn has an important place in the cropping system. Scarcity of livestock in an area is due to the scarcity of feed crops grown. In general the greater the precipitation the greater the number of livestock raised because of the wider choice farmers have in the selection of their crops. A better balance between the crops and livestock is found in areas where precipitation permits a choice in crop enterprises. Thirteen type-of-farming areas have been designated in Nebraska, as indicated in Figure 15. They represent areas in which the dominant type of farming is that indicated, and their numbers and descriptive titles are in conformity with a plan adopted and in use by the Bureau of Agricultural Economics, U. S. D. A. The map was the result of a cooperative effort on the part of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station and various federal agencies under the direction of the Department of Rural Economics of the University of Nebraska. Farming throughout an area may not be uniform. There may be small sections within an area where the farming is quite different from that indicated for the area as a whole. For example, cash grain and livestock are the dominant types of production in Area 195, but in certain small sections dairying is predominant. There are similar exceptions in the other areas. The lines separating the areas represent zone-like divisions rather than a sharp distinction as the line indicates. The zone-like divisions may be several miles in width and represent areas in which the farming is chang - ing or in which there is an overlapping in type. They may be considered as transition stages in farming and do not represent a permanently estab - lished type of production. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 ■yT\ ill • : ;-^g$MMi I'll r^rjpl 4 4 J j *$S l F : t^B-^O^^3 III — V — ' ' I j :s — =&gt; s ]N[:4 j i~j it* — -=- ill ~ : -3pr .-^^ l;f ! ! I ! '. "c'd:^, r 1 — 1 ~^ i^ " 1§ i-s 8 -. j J |1J^ B "—H ills — r f j £ </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Type-of-Farming Areas r~-=c! _l — f J ~ | — i — ! .5 1 — 1-1 Y „ w = " __„[ --|~"=-| FH\3 _i _ .3 § ? \ ~^ |^ g r^-5X^ l-^zLT!: j'| _„&gt; j I — as , ; "=- } a -; " Y "^ _s as , as \ _22- _as ,\ 1 -1=;-^; -35 _gf,-*..rg a - 1 — \ p ; f jy^ '- 1 S i . 1 ! «ag __;s __*. [ -js ■ k as 2 "y ! ] ; — 1 — f I if &gt; — s — k H~ '-S3 JE. : J&gt;i "1*° 1 I . . j&gt; -a — ' "— — n &gt; s -y.s _JS __-; S II - l__^ L-— r-Ju jjuj ; ( L -t^TT— S M = ±$;.J, ■ „ ills? - • ' &gt; i C " ' """ " d 6 1 » p _J s • £ </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 «» r 196 T"l | I ~j JSS| yfeLSt-\ Fie. 15. — Typc-of-£arming areas in Nebraska. H3— Range Livestock, Cash Grain, and Potatoes 18R-B— Cash Grain and Livestock ,i^~; Su P r B "', S&gt; Po , tatocs - and Livatock . 189-Cash Grain, Livestock, and Pasture I82-A— Livestock and Cash Grain 193— Livestock and Cash Grain Isi-A — Intensive Livestock Production 19-1 — General Farming liJJ"" 0 " 11 Grain r Livestock, and Potatoes 195— Cash Grain and Livestock tS^StSrSS Hay, and Cash Grain '«*-"«*-* &lt;** °«««. «- Genera, Par ming DESCRIPTION OF TYPE-OF-FARMING AREAS AREA 143 Range Livestock, Cash Grain, and Potatoes This area is located in the extreme northwest corner of the state and includes all of Sioux county except small areas in the southwestern and northeastern corners. It is a grazing area in which both cattle and sheep are important. Potatoes are grown in sections where soil and moisture conditions are suitable. About two-thirds of the soils are grouped as low-producing soils. It is estimated that from 10 to 15 per cent of this land should be in cultivation. The farms averaged 1,874 acres in size in 1929. Only 8.1 per cent of the land was in crops, not including wild hay, 2.1 in wild hay, 8.6 in pasture, and 1.1 in other land including the farmstead. Corn occupied 1.8.1 per cent of the cultivated land, wheat 17.4, oats 11.2, barley 10.2, rye 2.3, and sorghum 0.1. Legumes occupied 18.5 per cent of which nearly all was alfalfa. The principal sources of income in this area are from the sale of cattle and cash crops of which wheat and potatoes contribute the most. These sources account for about four-fifths of the total income. The chief problems in this area are those connected directly with cattle grazing. Some consideration should be given to the conservation of soil resources, particularly to wind erosion. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Type-of-Farming Areas AREA 145 Sugar Beets, Potatoes, and Livestock This area is triangular in shape and lies along the North Plattc river in the extreme western end of the state and is limited to Scotts Bluff county, a small portion of southern Sioux, and a portion along the river in western Morrill county. It is an irrigated area and its agriculture is characterized by the intensive production of sugar beets and potatoes and the feeding of sheep and some beef cattle. The farms averaged 222 acres in size in 1929. There was 48.1 per cent of the farm land in crops not including wild hay, 23 in wild hay, 44.0 in pasture, and 5.6 in other land, including the farmstead. Sugar beets occu - pied 24.1 per cent of the cultivated land, corn 143, barley 11.4, wheat 85, oats 6.4, and rye 0.2. Alfalfa occupied 20 per cent and sweet clover 0.5. The most important source of income in this area is from the sale of sugar beets and potatoes. These, together with the other crops sold, of which wheat is the principal one, account for nearly three-fourths of the total income. Beef cattle and sheep contribute about the same amount to the income and together account for approximately one-sixth of the total. Hogs and dairy contribute about equally but neither is especially significant. The principal problems in this area are those connected directly widi irrigation. Those of water storage and effect of continuous irrigation on soil resources are important. AREA 182-A Livestock and Cash Grain This area is located in the extreme northern part of the state and is limited for the most part to Boyd county. It is a part of a larger area in South Dakota. This area is characterized by the production of livestock and feed grains, but on a less intensive scale than in the area cast of it. The soil was developed on Pierre shale and in general is not well suited to cash-grain farming. The proportion of land under cultivation is prob - ably larger than it should be on the poorer soils. In 1929 the farms averaged 304 acres in size. There was 46.0 per cent of the farm land in crops not including wild hay, 9.8 in wild hay, 40.1 in pasture, and 4.1 in other land, including the farmstead. Corn occupied 58.0 per cent of the cultivated land, oats 22.4, wheat 3.4, barley 2.1, rye 13, and sorghum 0.4. Legumes occupied 8.6 per cent, of which a little over four-fifths was alfalfa. Winter wheat was not important in this area. The income in this area is mostly from the sale of hogs, beef cattle, and some feed grains, of which corn is the most important. The sale of dairy and poultry products and wild hay provides small amounts of income. Some readjustment in the proportion of crop land occupied by im - portant crops is needed. The development of water storage in certain sec - tions of the area would permit occupancy of land not now suited to agri - cultural production. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 AREA 183-A Intensive Livestock Production This area is located in the northeastern part of the state north of the Platte river, and extends westward from the Missouri river from 50 to 150 miles. The area is characterized by intensive production of livestock, par - ticularly beef cattle and hogs. Corn, oats, and alfalfa, the crops best suited to the production of livestock, are the principal crops grown. This area is in the loess hills region of the northeastern part of the state. About 70 per cent of the soil is high grade, and on the whole this is probably the most productive area in the state. There are small areas of low-producing soil which should probably be taken out of cultivation and put into permanent pasture. The topography varies from gently rolling to rough land located along the banks of the Missouri river. The farms averaged 186 acres in size in 1929. There was 69.9 per cent of the farm land in crops not including wild hay, 43 in wild hay, 21.7 in pasture, and 4.1 in other land, including the farmstead. Corn occupied 583 per cent of the cultivated land, oats 22.9, wheat 3.6, barley 2.6, and rye 0.7. Alfalfa occupied ten times as much land as sweet clover, the two occupying 6.6 per cent of the crop land. Hogs and beef cattle contribute about equally to the income and to - gether constitute approximately two-thirds of the total. The sale of feed grain accounts for about one-fifth of the income and miscellaneous live - stock the remainder. Farmers in this area depend very little on wheat for their income. The principal problem in this area is that of soil erosion, which is most serious in the eastern part of the area. The rainfall is sufficient to grow all the crops needed for a balanced agriculture. AREA 184 Cash Grain, Livestock, and Potatoes This area lies directly east and south of Areas 143 and 145 and varies in width from about 65 miles on the northern and southern edges of the area to about 30 miles in the middle. This is an area of light rainfall and the large proportion of farm land in pasture indicates that cattle grazing is important. Crop production centers around the wheat enterprise. Barley and corn are the principal feed grains grown. This area includes the arable table land and transitional soils of north - western Nebraska. Certain parts, such as the Box Butte and Dawes table land, consist of relatively deep and heavy soils which are well suited to cultivation. There is some inclination to extend farming operations into areas of shallow and sandy soils which are not so well suited to cultivation. The farms averaged 853 acres in size in 1929. There was 30.5 per cent of the farm land in crops not including wild hay, 4.4 in wild hay, 62.2 in pasture, and 2.9 in other land including the farmstead. Wheat </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Type-of-Farming Areas occupied 32.5 per cent o£ the cultivated land, corn 24.3, barley 11.6, rye 0.9, sorghums 0.1, and legumes 6.5 per cent, of which alfalfa was the principal crop, and potatoes 2.6. The most important source of income in this area is the sale of beef cattle, about 30 per cent of the total coming from this source. About 21 per cent is from the sale of hogs, 12 per cent from dairy products, 30 per cent from cash grain, of which wheat is the most significant although some barley is sold. The problems in this area are related directly to those connected with cattle grazing, the main one of which is that of overgrazing. Greater adjustments of enterprise in the northern and southern parts of the area are possible than in the middle portion. If irrigation is developed it is possible that there will be new problems in connection with crop adjust - ment in such areas. .wt^a -, O e AKliA loo Range Livestock This area is located in the north-central part of the state and lies directly east of Area 184. It extends northward from the Platte river into South Dakota and varies in width from 100 to 200 miles. The area is characterized by the extremely large proportion of farm land devoted to grazing. The sandy soils and meager rainfall are not conducive to the production of cultivated crops. This area includes the Sand Hills area of Nebraska, which is the largest soil and topographic region in the state. Only about 8 per cent of the area is suited to cultivation. The better soils constitute only about 4 per cent of the total area and are for the most part located along streams. In 1929 the farms averaged 1,716 acres in size. Only 8.4 per cent of the farm land was in crops not including wild hay, 10.6 in wild hay, 78.1 in pasture, and 2.9 in other land, including the farmstead. Corn occupied 41.7 per cent of the cultivated land, oats 9.1, rye 9.0, wheat 3.5, barley 1.7, and sorghums 0.4. Legumes occupied 9.5 per cent, of which alfalfa was the principal one. The income is almost entirely from the sale of cattle. Practically no crops are sold and only a small proportion of the income is from the sale of dairy and poultry products. All the problems in this area are those connected with cattle grazing. Because of the nature of the soil, vegetative growth is not heavy and there is some inclination for soils to blow badly with cultivation or overgrazing. Sheep are not grazed in the area because of the danger of too close grazing, thus permitting wind erosion. AREA 187 Livestock, Wild Hay, and Cash Grain This area is in the north-central part of the state and lies between Areas 183-A and 186 with the exception of Boyd county on the north </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 and a rectangular area on the south known as Area 193. The production is characterized by the large amount of land in wild hay. The land in wild hay is about four-fifths as much as in all other crops combined. Cattle are important because of the large amount of pasture and roughage available. Hogs are grown only lo the extent of utilizing most of that part of the corn crop grown for grain. This area is between the loess hill region in the eastern part of the state and the sand-hill region in the north-central part. It varies from dune sand in the western part to high-producing but not extensive loess soils in the eastern part. Only about 10 p:r cent of the soil in this area could be classed as high-grade land. In 1929 the farms averaged 51:&gt; acres in size. There was 25.3 per cent of the farm land in crop producti n not including wild hay, 19.9 in wild hay, 49.9 in pasture, and 4.9 in other land, including the farmstead. Corn occupied 53.1 per cent of the cultivated land, oats 16.8, rye 8.7, barley 1.1, wheat 1.1, and sorghums 0.5. Legumes occupied 6.0 per cent, most of which was devoted to the producti on of alfalfa. Wild hay is the principal source of income in this area. Other sources of importance are beef cattle, hoijs, and dairy and poultry products. A small quantity of feed grains is so d, consisting chiefly of oats and barley. The principal problem in this area is one of adjustment of crops to obtain a full utilization of land resources. An increase in the acreage of sweet clover would aid in solvin j the soil problem and would provide suitable feed for some expansion rjf the livestock enterprise. ARSA 188-B Cash Grain and Livestock This area is in the southwestern part of the state and most of it is in the southern part of the panhandle . The area is characterized by extensive grain production, most of which i ; wheat, supplemented with the produc - tion of beef cattle and hogs. Frcm the standpoint of grain raising it is decidedly an area of surplus production. This area is a part of the major table-land area of western Nebraska, and the western end of the area cc nsists of shallow, sandy, or gravelly soils which are not suited to cultivation, A larger proportion of the poorer soils is in cultivation than appears to be advisable. The farms averaged 498 acre: in size in 1929. There was 63.5 per cent of the farm land in crops njot including wild hay, 1.6 in wild hay, 31.4 in pasture, 35 in other land, including the farmstead. Wheat occupied 47.9 per cent of the cultivated land corn 16.7, barley 9.6, oats 3.4, sorghums 05, and rye 0.4. Legumes occupied 1.4 per cent, most of which was in alfalfa. The most important source of income is from the sale of grain. Wheat alone accounts for nearly 60 per tent of die total income. Hogs and cattle contribute about equally to the ncome and together account for a little </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Type-of-Farming Areas over 30 per cent o£ the total. Other sources, of which the sale of dairy products is most important, account for the remainder. The problems in the area are confined primarily to the extreme western end and consist of a better adjustment of crops for soil-conservation pur - poses. In the other sections of the area the agriculture is fairly well balanced. ;«*.. „„„ AREA 189 Cash Grain, Livestock, and Pasture This area is in the southwestern part of the state and includes the por - tion of Lincoln county south of the Platte river, Chase county, and the western two-thirds of Dundy. The production is characterized by cash grain of which wheat is the most important and livestock of which both cattle and hogs are significant. A large part of the land in farms is devoted to grazing and for this reason cattle are important. The soil consists largely of dune sand and other sandy soils. Much of the land now being farmed is extremely sandy and should be used for grazing only. The farms averaged 636 acres in size in 1929. There was 34.4 per cent of the farm land devoted to crops not including wild hay, 5.1 in wild hay, 58.4 in pasture, and 2.1 in other land, including the farmstead. Corn occupied 50.5 per cent of the cultivated land, wheat 25.6, barley 4.0, rye 2.8, sorghums 1.9, and oats 1.7. Legumes occupied 3.7 per cent, of which alfalfa was most important. Beef cattle and hogs contribute about equally to the income and to - gether make up about 56 per cent of the total. Cash grain, of which wheat is the most important, contributes about 20 per cent of the income and dairy, poultry, and other sources the remainder. The principal problem in this area is one of obtaining a better balance in production. Soil erosion has been a problem in certain sections of the area in recent years and it might be helped by increasing the area devoted to grazing. AREA 193 Livestock and Cash Grain This is a rectangular-shaped area in the central part of the state and is approximately 100 miles long and 70 miles wide. Its production is charac - terized by feed grains and livestock, of which hogs and beef cattle and dairy are all important. Winter wheat is less important than in the areas to the south, but alfalfa is more important. Soil and climatic conditions are suitable for the production of legume crops. This area lies in the west-central part of the loess hill region and ex - tends north to the sand-hill area. It includes areas of sandy soils along the part which borders the sand-hill region. Approximately two-thirds of the area is classed as very good soil and suitable for intensive cultivation. That part of the area where the topography is rolling is better suited for graz - ing purposes than for cultivation. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agriculture l Experiment Station 299 The farms averaged 285 acres in size in 1929. There was 50.2 per cent of the farm land in crops not including wild hay, 15.3 in wild hay, 41.1 per cent in pasture, and 3.4 in other land, including the farmstead. Corn occupied 56.8 per cent of the cultivated land, oats 113, wheat 9.4, barley 3.4, rye 0.9, and sorghums 0.). Alfalfa was the principal legume and occupied 11.1 per cent of the crop land and sweet clover occupied 0.6. Corn, oats, and alfalfa occupied approximately four-fifths of the cultivated land. Hogs and beef cattle contribute about equally to the income and to - gether are responsible for about otae-half of the total. The sale of feed grains, of which corn is the principal one, and wheat together account for about one-third of the total inconke. ICorn, wheat, and alfalfa form the basis for practically nine-tenths of the j total income in this area. The principal problem in this area is one of a readjustment in crop acreage which would result in a better I balance among farming enterprises. With the natural conditions favorable for a wide selection of crops, a more suitable balance of farm enterprise; should not be difficult to obtain. Soil erosion is a problem in the localities adjacent to rivers and other streams. ABEA 194 General Farming This area is in the southeasterr part of the state and extends from the Plattc river to the southern boundary of the state and from the Missouri river westward from 50 to 80 mles. This area is characterized by the production of grains and livestock on a less intensive scale than in Area 183- A. Corn and wheat are the riost important crops. This area is in the glacial region of Nebraska. The predominating upland soils are Carrington and Shelby, a large portion of which are rela - tively productive. A higher percentage of the rough land and steep hill - sides is cultivated than is advisabl :, with the result that there is consider - able soil erosion. The farms averaged 170 acres in size in 1929. There was 68.5 per cent of the farm land in crops, not including wild hay, 2.8 in wild hay, 23.9 in pasture, and 4.8 in other land, including the farmstead. Corn occupied 52.7 per cent of the cultivated land, wheat 20.0, oats, 13.3, barley 03, and sorghums 0.2. Alfalfa was 13 tim:s as important as sweet clover, the two occupying 5.5 per cent of the cro j land. The sale of hogs and cash grains contribute about equally to the in - come from the farm, and amount to about two-thirds of the total. Dairy and other cattle contribute about the same proportion to the income and account for approximately one-fifth of the total. Miscellaneous sources account for the remainder. The chief problem in the area is soil erosion, which is most serious in the eastern part of the area wher:the land is rough. There is sufficient precipitation for the growing of crops when the distribution is normal. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Type-of-Farming Areas Some attention should be given to practices involving a greater conserva - tion of soil fertility. AREA 195 Cash Grain and Livestock This area is triangular in shape and lies just west of Area 194, extend - ing south from the Platte river to within about 25 miles of the Nebraska- Kansas boundary. It is characterized by rather intensive production of winter wheat, hogs, and some beef cattle. Winter wheat is a rather de - pendable crop in this area and fits well into the farm plan from the stand - point of labor distribution. The topography of the area is suitable to the operation of large-sized machinery, although the farms are not large. This area is in the loess plains region and for the most part consists of level to gently rolling land. The productive upland soils, are Crete, Hastings, and Holdrege which are well suited to cultivation. The amount of poor land in this area is limited although it is cultivated to a greater extent than it probably should be. The farms averaged 196 acres in size in 1929. There was 74.7 per cent of the farm land in crops not including wild hay, 2.4 in' wild hay, 19.5 in pasture, and 3.4 in other land, including the farmstead. Cora occupied 45.1 per cent of the cultivated land, wheat 333, oats 11.5, barley 1.6, sorghums 0.6, and rye 0.2. Alfalfa was the principal legume, which, with a small amount of sweet clover, occupied 0.6 per cent of the crop land. Four-fifths of the crop land was occupied by wheat and oats. Hogs are the most important source of income and account for about 40 per cent of the total. Grain, of which wheat is the most important, accounts for about 33 per cent of the income, dairy products 10 per cent, and beef cattle 8 per cent. Corn and wheat form the basis for over three - fourths of the income in this area. The chief problems in this area are those resulting from unreliable distribution of rainfall during the growing season. Because of this condi - tion producers grow those crops which are more sure and thus keep. the livestock necessary for their utilization in lean years. Because of the crop - ping system thus developed, some attention to the conservation of soil fertility is advisable. Soil erosion is not particularly alarming in this area. AREA 196 Livestock, Cash Grain, and General Fanning This area lies in the south-central part of the state, extending from Jefferson county on the east to Dundy on the west. It extends northward from the Nebraska-Kansas boundary 25 miles in the eastern part of the area, to the Platte river in the central part, and 50 miles in the western part. The agricultural production includes many commodities. Hogs, beef cattle, dairy products, and cash grain, of which wheat and corn are the most important, constitute the principal sources of income. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 299 This area includes the loess hill region of the Republican river valley and small portions of the loess plain area. Nearly all of the upland soils are fertile and suitable for cultivat on. Because of the quality of the soil and nearness to the water, the bottom lands are very productive. The farms averaged 319 acres iA size in 1929. Crop land not including wild hay occupied 54.0 per cent of! the land in farms. Wild hay occupied 2.0 per cent, pasture 39.8, and othei- land 33. Corn occupied 59.8 per cent of the cultivated land, winter wheat 21.6, oats 4.8, barley 2.2, and sorghums 23 per cent. Five per cent of the (trap land was in tame hay, which con - sisted mostly of alfalfa. Hogs constitute the greatest source of income, nearly one-third coming from this source. The income frorri the sale of hogs is equal approximately to that from all other livestock. S leep and poultry contribute only small amounts to the income. The incorhe from the sale of all grains, of which corn and wheat are the most important, constitutes about one-third of the total income. Undependable rainfall is responsible for the principal problems in this area. Because of the varying rainfall it is impossible to adjust livestock to the feed supply. In dry years tie feed supply and pasture will not pro - vide for the livestock that farmers want to keep. In wet years feed grains are sold as a cash crop. It is difficult to establish a legume in the rotation system in this area except in the valleys, and the rainfall hazard makes the planting of a legume too expensive on upland soils. In the valleys where the water table is closer to the surface, alfalfa is the legume planted and because of its high-yielding ability and the cost of seeding it is left on the same ground for several years. I C7HU] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>