<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>CLOVER IN THE SUBIRRIGATED MEADOWS OF THE SAND HILLS</title>
               <date value="1930-04">1930-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 241. April, 1930 CLOVER IN THE SUBIRRIGATED MEADOWS OF THE SAND HILLS E. M. BROUSE Bulletin 3 of the Valentine Experiment Substation E. M. Brouse, Superintendent Drilling red clover into this meadow increased the yield 80 PER CENT ■""-.. I ■ - THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Bubb, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY A definite relationship exists on subirrigated meadows between clover adaptation and the depth to the water table. The water table during March is more nearly at the same depth, one year with another, than at any other time of the season. It is an unprofitable practice to seed clover on meadows where the March water table is more than three feet below the surface. The most profitable seedings are on meadows where the March water table is from 6 to 30 inches below the surface. Native vegetation serves as an indicator for the successful estab - lishment of clover. Good bluestem meadows are the best adapted and meadows showing alkali vegetation should be avoided. Seeding with a grain drill gives better stands than broadcasting, except where the water table is closer than two feet. Disking a meadow before broadcasting proves beneficial. The seeding of clover on native meadows will materially increase the yield of hay. Calves wintered on mixed clover hay will return a greater profit than calves wintered on native hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CLOVER IN THE SUBIRRIGATED MEADOWS OF THE SAND HILLS K. M. DROUSE ' ™J n * the d f y of - the open range there was Htt le incentive to - ward meadow improvement. However, in those early days there were a few ranchers here and there who began to seed adTtl™ nf 6 "I**™ me l° WS - These P ioneers foS t£t the addition of clover in their native meadows increased the quantity as well as improved thequality of their hay. Later! when the open range gave way to the smaller ranch hold - ings, the question of winter feed became more of a problem especially on ranches where the proportion of meadow to grazing land was relatively small. As a consequence an in thfr*J n ? ereSt ? eVeIoped in TmpTvemlnrthVu" h^Jl a fL° V - ers an^ tame » rasses - However, many ranchers stand enthusiasm chilled thru failure to obtain a nf I " 1 o^ 23 th e "Valentine Substation began a systematic study of meadow improvement thru the use of red and alsike clover Hn7rL7™ W ?l l° n £ OI 1 numerous wet meadows in the Sand SIhES? 0 ? + 9°^ Rock ' Brown ' and Cherr y counties. In fanH kt thI°?K f t C l ?Ver W i re S ! eded on meadow ' a . ndat * h . e substation and on ten ranches in Cherry county ™w # Va £- ed from six inches to five feet above the wSfr f k e&gt; + T £ S *i ave , °PP° rtuni ty to study the relation of 1] m^ le t2 stand and growth of alsike, Medium Red and Mammoth Red clover as well as to the method of seed - ing. Results have varied somewhat with the season, but cer - is "sr^^nx," 3 mile posts on the ™ y to ° — — USE GOOD SEED iJZ 00 ? s . eed . mu st be the starting point. Perhaps the most mportant thing to consider in getting seed for northern Ne - braska is whether the seed will be winter hardy. A larire amount of red clover seed is imported annually into the United States from southern Europe. Seed from this source has not proved winter hardy in Nebraska, Iowa, and a number of other states. It is desirable, then, to know that the s^dhS been produced under climatic conditions which are as severe hs ours. Good clover seed should be plump and have a bright luster. These qualities usually indicate viability. Seed offered for sale at materially less than the standard price is likely to be </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 241 inferior in quality. Poor quality usually results in a poor stand and often the introduction of undesirable weeds. It is economy in the end to buy a good grade of seed. One can SSi"! a &amp; Uri &amp; « nd termination test by sending a sample of Nebraska" Analyst, Capitol Building, Lincoln, In Nebraska the standard of purity for red clover is 92 per cent, and of germination 80 per cent. Seventy-five per cent germination is the standard for alsike clover. The vital - ity of clover seed decreases with age. In the spring of 1926 the writer obtained some red clover seed from a rancher who £L^ UrC -^ S 2?- Jt ae 7 en °L ei ? ht years Previously. A plot seeded with this seed resulted in a very poor stand, while on an adjoining plot new seed produced a good stand. SEED INOCULATION Inoculation of seed before planting has in only a few cases given any noticeable results. In no plantings has it been a limiting factor m obtaining a stand. It is possible that there are meadows where inoculation might prove advanta - rtf? U Tf Q Ba * terial culture can be obtained free by writing to the U. S. Department of Agriculture at Washington, D. C or can be purchased from the various seed companies. MOISTURE REQUIREMENT Themost striking thm * to be observed in the clover mead ows of ttie Sand Hills is the definite relation that exists be - tween the stand and growth of clover and depth to ground water. In meadows containing clover it will be noted, gen - erally speaking, that the clover margin follows certain lfnes of land contour. Upon investigation it will be f oundtSt this margin bears a definite relation to the water table This relationship varies with the type of subsoil-the finer thl texture, the greater may be the de R th to water. After boring several hundred holes around the maririn of ffi y r^% meadO^V n ?£ S . and . Hills ' and «eedin™ o?Tand that ranged from six to sixty inches above ground water the following conclusions are drawn. «xuuuu water, tne 1. The water table during March is more nearly at the ! tfmTof^ 2Ur an ° ther ' than at a *r &lt;*£ 2. No meadows with established stands of clover were , gss Kas- th *- "- « conditions, but will seldom survive the TsumnS? </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Clover in the Sand Hills 4. In dry years clover has not been successfully seeded where it was farther than two feet to water during March. 5. On the average meadow the best stand and growth of clover are obtained on the portion that lies between 1 6 and 30 inches above the March water table. It will be noted from the diagram (Fig. 1) that the seasonal fluctuation varies somewhat one year with another. This * s caused chiefly by the character and amount of precipitation, altho structural, topographic, and drainage conditions are important factors. During 1923 the rainfall was practically normal, while in each of the other years there was a deficiency with the consequent lowering of the water table. As a result the stand and growth of clover on marginal land have been materially affected. By marginal is meant land that is a little too high or too low for good clover production — that is to say, meadows lying from three to four feet above water or closer than one-half foot. (See Fig. 2.) In a cycle of wet years the high marginal land is benefited and the low marginal land suffers, while in dry years the reverse is true. To this fluctuation can be attributed the loss of clover stands on marginal land in the Sand Hills. The question then arises, Is it profitable to seed clover on marginal land? As a rule it is not advisable to go to too much expense in doing so. If there could be any assurance as to the duration of the wet and dry cycles one could profitably seed on marginal land. NATIVE VEGETATION AS AN INDICATOR OF CLOVER ADAPTATION In a general way the native vegetation can be used as an indicator for clover adaptation. Meadows or portions of the same that support a good sod of blue stem (Andropogon fur - catus) and Indian grass (Sorghastrum nutans) will produce a good growth of clover. The upper margin is reached when the blue-stem sod begins to" get patchy and bunches of grama, June, and associated grasses come in. At the lower margin of the blue-stem sod where the slough grasses prevail clover seldom thrives. Meadows showing alkali grasses should be avoided. SUITABLE CLOVER VARIETIES Red Clover. — Red clover is by far the most prominent of the clovers. In the Sand Hill region it may be classed as a short-lived perennial, few plants living over three or four years. It is thus advisable under meadow conditions to allow the plant to mature part of its seed each year. There are two recognized varieties of red clover, Medium and Mammoth. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 241 ing may be successfully done at any time up to the middle of August, providing moisture conditions are favorable. The following are some of the seeding methods commonly used on native meadows : 1. Broadcasting, preferably on a light snow, 2. Broadcasting, followed with a top dressing of manure, 3. Broadcasting during winter and then feeding on the meadow, 4. Broadcasting on meadow that has been disked and covering the seed by the use of a drag, 5. Drilling on meadow, 6. Drilling on meadow that has been disked, 7. Seeding on breaking that has been worked down, 8. Feeding hay that contains clover seed on the meadow. Broadcasting directly on meadow is the most uncertain ' method except in wet seasons or on meadows within eighteen inches of water. In only two out of five years has broadcast - ing been successful on meadows lying higher than eighteen inches above the March water table. A dense turf is a hindrance toward obtaining a stand from broadcasting. Consequently, the use of some implement to tear up the turf more or less will prove beneficial. The writer has used the common disk, cut-a-way disk, and rotary spike disk with good results. Cattle turned in on a newly seeded meadow will aid much in getting the seed in contact with the soil. . The use of the drill in seeding clover has given much better results than broadcasting, especially on undisturbed sod. The chief objection to the drill is that it is impossible to seed at a uniform depth, due to the uneven density of sod. Depth-of - seeding tests have shown that it is better to cut just into the sod than to cut deeper than an inch or two. Some drills give trouble by catching roots and aftermath on the disk scrapers at the end of the boot, thus holding the disks out of the ground. A good combination for drilling clover is the common disk equipped with a drill attachment. The question is often asked whether it is advisable to break up a meadow and seed to clover and tame grasses. Generally speaking this practice is not to be recommended. There are few meadows that are of a uniform soil type and lie thruout at a uniform height above water. The March' water table in such a meadow should be within two and one-half feet of the surface to insure good results from seeding on breaking. RATE OF SEEDING If seeded alone, the rate is 10 to 12 pounds of clover seed per acre on breaking or cultivated land. Where seed is broad - </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Clover in the Sand Hills 9 cast on the native sod, 6 to 10 pounds is sufficient if the weather is at all favorable for germination. In fact one pound per acre would place at least five seeds to the square foot. A too-heavy seeding- usually results in a loss of plants from overcrowding. This has been especially true in the drill row where more than five pounds per acre has been seeded. If the drill cannot be closed down to seed this amount, mix some finely-ground corn meal or dry soil with the clover seed. COMPANION CROPS Timothy and red top can well be called companion crops to the clovers. Their soil and moisture requirements are prac - tically the same as for clover. Timothy pairs more with red clover on the medium-wet meadow, while red top pairs with alsike on the still wetter soil. However, it is doubtful if there is much difference in the drouth resistance of the four plants, as indicated by the distance they grow above the water table. These tame grasses add to the volume of hay and on rich soil reduce the lodging of the clover. They also aid in the curing process. For the average wet meadow a mixture of the following proportions is recommended: Red clover 6 pounds, Alsike clover 4 pounds, • Timothy 3 pounds, . Red top .; 1 pound. On very wet meadows the proportion of alsike and red top should be increased. These mixtures are seeded at the rate of 5 to 8 pounds per acre. TIME OF CUTTING MIXED HAY The proper time to cut mixed hay depends upon what class of plants predominate. The greater the percentage of clover, the earlier it should be cut. The clovers reach their highest feeding value when in full bloom, but are more difficult to cure than if cut a little later. Clovers are usually classed as being in full bloom when from one-fourth to one-third of the flowers have turned brown. If native grasses are more abundant than the clovers, cutting should be delayed until it is thought that the increased amount of native hay will com - pensate for the loss in feeding value of the clover. In a meadow where alsike predominates the cutting season may be extended over a longer period due to the fact that the main stems continue to send out new flower stalks. However, alsike is at its best before red clover has reached full bloom. When Medium Red clover makes up the greater percentage of the hay, two cuttings may be taken off in most seasons. It is always advisable to allow a portion of the flowers to mature </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>